My name is Jerry Hartfeld.
I run a video production company,
here in Anaheim, California.
We focus mainly on
reality television shows.
If you ever seen the show,
"Tornado Trackers", it's one of ours.
A tape arrived in the mail.
It was a pilot episode of a new reality
series called "Grave Encounters".
And it was by a young
producer named Lance Preston.
The idea was that him and his
group of paranormal investigators,
would investigate ghost sightings and
hauntings and things of this nature.
And this was, you know, years before
all the other ghost haunting
shows that are out there now.
I mean, I really felt
he was ahead of his time.
My name is Lance Preston.
When I was a boy my
family moved into a house
that I soon discovered was haunted.
The things I encountered,
have stayed with me forever.
Ever since then, I have been
obsessed with trying to capture proof
that these things were real.
Come along with me and my team
of skilled paranormal investigators
as we dare to venture into some of the
most haunted locations known to man.
Spending the night, and
capturing everything on camera.
If you're ready, it's
time to have some
GRAVE ENCOUNTERS
And everything was... you
know, going really smoothly.
I mean, the edits that were coming back
were great.  We were very excited.
We really had some thing, you know.
And then of course, they
got the Episode 6.
Uh, do you have anything
else you want to say?
Yeah!  I want to be
very clear about this.
What you're about to
see is not a movie.
Okay?
This is been assembled from some 76 plus
hours of raw mini DVD source footage
that was shot for Lance's show.
Not a frame of this had been doctored,
hasn't been manipulated in any way.
This is just raw footage,
it's been edited strictly for time.
Cut!
Hello! Hello!
Testing! Testing.
Lance Preston!
Keep a good portion of this
in the back the whole time.
I'm gonna move a little bit, but...
- Are you ready then?
- I'm ready.
You're still in the shot.
I can... I want to get you clean.
- One step back.
- Well, good?
Good evening!
And welcome to another
episode of Grave Encounters.
I'm your host,
Lance Preston, as always.
And tonight I am very
excited to take you inside
one of the most terrifying
locations I have ever seen.
Behind me sits the
Collingwood Psychiatric hospital.
It's one of six buildings
spread over 80 acres of land,
just outside ...
We are gonna pick it up from there.
I'm not gonna do from beginning part again.
And between the years 1895 and 1960,
it played home to more than 80,000
of Maryland's most mentally ill
and disturbed individuals.
After its closure in 1963,
reports of ghostly apparitions,
objects moving on their own.
And sometimes even the lunatic
laughter of the patients
condemned to roam these halls.
Tonight, my crew and I will be
performing an 8 hour lock down.
Trapped inside, during the
peak hours of dead time.
Using the most sophisticated
in ghost hunting equipment
we will be in search of
what's become known as
the ghost of the
Collingwood Psychiatric Hospital.
- Cut.
- Nice!
Yeah?
- Morgan!
- Hi
- Morgan Turner! How are you?
- Yeah.  Hi.
- Oop! Perfect.
- Thanks for coming up man.
Especially to make
you drive all the way.
That's okay.
I'm really happy to do it.
- Is um... is this going to be on TV?
- Yeah, that's what we hope.
Hey, not this part.
I'm just shooting this.
Oh, don't worry about it,
she shoots everything.
I'm here with Morgan Turner,
local town historian.
Morgan is here today to shed some
light on the institute's dark past.
Morgan?  Can you tell us when
the institute was first built?
Well! The history of Collingwood is fairly
typical of similar hospitals of the era.
It was built in 1893... to
address the sort of growing
over crowding problem at the
state hospital in Denver's County.
Mental illness, of course at that time
was not very well understood and
treatments were
still in their infancy.
Psychiatric hospitals like this were
seen as sort of a dumping ground
for embarrassing family
members rather then
a place that they could
go to actually get help.
Right.
The conditions were pretty abysmal.
People have to sleep on the floor, some
times, without blankets or even clothes.
It was really not a
fun place to be stuck in.
Could you tell us about
Arthur Friedkin?
His story is probably the most
infamous about this hospital.
Sure..!  I figured that
you're gonna ask me that.
Friedkin was a
Harvard trained neurologist
who was head physician
here from 1937 to 1948.
He had gain some notoriety
because of his work in
experimental brain surgery.
He was a major
advocate of the lobotomy,
under Friedkin supervision
there were about 140 lobotomies.
On August 15, 1948,
six patients broke out of their rooms
and stabbed Friedkin
in his office.
His body was found the
next morning by a nurse.
Unfortunately, this event
was completely overshadowed
by the death of David Bruce,
the famous baseball player.
It's a crazy story!
So Morgan, in your honest opinion.
Do you believe in ghosts?
I don't know.
But if they do exist, well, this would be
a good place to go looking for them.
The traffic was busy today, so...
Didn't take us too long, it was
about hour drive, something like that.
- Oh God!
- "Death awaits."
- I guess we'll find out.
- That is so lame!
Ah, this will taking a bit, this
old ancient lock here.
I don't even think we should use this.
- You know, it's really cheesy dude.
- Yeah! I don't like that.
Slow motion, music behind it.
Everything's creepy.
- Okay.. come on.
- Good. Here we go.
Okay, come on in.
Oh my God!
So this is the main entrance
to the building here.
Nice!
Yes!
Oh, ho ho, man!
And if you were family member, you have
to check-in at the reception over there.
- This is creepy as shit!
- This is so insane.
Are you getting all this?
Get everything!
I want to do camera
shots of all of this.
Hey you down there.
No smoking, uh.
Can you take that outside?  Don't
even bother inside, please.  Fire exit.
I'm here with Kenny Sandavol.
Resident caretaker, for the past 8 years.
Kenny!  Would you say
that this place is haunted?
Well, I've never done this before.
So, should I talk to you or to the camera?
Yeah..  Don't.
This isn't...
Well, I don't know if I believe in
ghost or spirits or anything like that.
But in my time here I've
seen some pretty weird stuff.
You know, especially working
late night you hear all these
old pipes and the building
sort of make noises and...
Well, it's really hard to
put your finger on it.  But...
I get the sense
that, I'm not alone.
Lets go check it out!
Aha.
Okay.
Uh, like this hallways
go on forever.
Yup!
It's hard to believe this place used to
house thousands of insane people.
There were thousands.
Seem to have darkness
and it's still day time.
- So where is the power socket?
- You scared?
Ah, there's a few newer
lines you can plug into.
I'll will show you where those are.
Hey guys!  If you think it's
dark now, wait till tonight.
Cause none of these lights work,
it'll get very dark.
- So you guys see this window here?
- Yeah!
I lock it up real good in night
come back in morning, some
times this thing's wide open.
What!
Yeah, I can't figure it out.
Its like a... something is
trying to get out or something.
Its a definite paranormal hotspot.
- How is it?
- Perfect.
How is this supposed to help people
if their stuffed in these tiny rooms.
- Oh my God!
- This is officially fucked!
- Is this real?
- Yup, this is totally real.
The guy who lived here was
in here for quite a few years
and this is what he did.
He spent his time
writing on the walls.
So this is the actual
patiented room here?
An actual patient was in here.
Really?
I don't know whether he was right to
the end, but he was here for a long time.
Very creepy.
- What the fuck!?  Kenny!
- This is great!
Oh man, the acoustics
are shit in here.
Supposedly a patient, a young
girl, killed herself in here.
- What?
- Right here?
- A patient killed herself, right here?
- Yes, slit her wrists in this tub.
Oh God, that's so sad.
People say they've heard the sound of
rustling water coming out of this room,
but I've never heard
any thing like that.
Where are we going next then?
Ah, we gonna go down
to the service tunnels.
Can't wait to see all this.
You on it?
- Oh Kenny!
- This is exactly what I was looking for!
These service tunnels
connect all the buildings.
There's about a quarter mile of them.
It's like a maze down here.
You could easily get lost.
One day, I was down here
walking over to the East wing,
and the air got real cold.
It was so still.  I felt like
someone was watching me.
Very eerie feeling.
- What?  What?
- It's just my shadow. Sorry.
This is Garry Crawford.
Crawford Contracting.
He was hired here, quite some
time ago, to do some work?
Is that right?
Back in 93, yeah.  The state was
gonna try and do some renovation here
but eventually they shit-can the idea.
Oh shit, I'm sorry!
- You want me not to swear?
- Yeah, that would be better.
Anyway, me and my guys
came in here for about two weeks.
And you experienced some
supernatural phenomenon?
Well, we were off to start,
some of the guys were hearing what
they thought were weird noises and...
And there were some tools
disappearing over night,
I thought it was looters, but
I never saw anybody, so...
- There was an accident?
- Yeah...
One of my guys on a ladder, in fact, he
was pulling some old wood just over there.
And he swears that something
pushed him off the ladder.
He took a hard fall.
Banged up his knee, and he quit!
Well! that doesn't sound
like a residual haunting.
Its sounds like an
intelligent haunting.
A residual haunting is thought
to be like an echo from the past,
continuing to loop
over and over again.
An intelligent haunting
is actually a spirit
that interacts and has intention.
There are many reports
of people having
been pushed, scratched
and even thrown.
It's rare but it does happen.
So, you both have spent
a lot of time out here?
Yeah, all in high school with bunch of
kids used to come down here and just...
you know, for hang out.
And you saw something here?
Yes.
We were actually right here.
Here.  Making out or whatever... and
I looked up and I swear to God.
I swear to God that I saw someone
right at the end of the hall there.
- He was wearing a... like a white...
- Like a hospital gown?
Yeah, like a white hospital gown.
And he had shaved head. Yeah.
Full spectral apparition.
Why don't we... why don't we grab
an interview with gardener look like?
As long as the lights doesn't...
Excuse me! Excuse me sir!
Excuse me.
I'm shooting a TV show here.
Just wondering if you want to
do a quick interview with us.
I am standing here with the
resident gardener, Javier Ortega.
Javier, have you ever noticed
anything strange around the building?
No.  Not really.
What do you mean?
Well, have you heard any weird
noises or seen any ghostly activity?
I just start to working here.
Just started working.
That's great.
TC can you... ?
Just cut for a sec?
Okay, how about you make
something up for the camera?
Pretend you saw something?
Just...
- I got to get go on to work!
- Okay. Okay.
Wait! Wait, wait... No, no just wait.
Do you have any of the  petty cash or...?
Hey Javier, how does 20 bucks sound?
I am standing here with the
resident gardener, Javier Ortega.
Javier, have you ever seen
anything strange in the past
10 years of working here?
Yeah, I saw a ghost.
Over here.
It was really scary.
A ghost on the exterior of
the building.  Unbelievable.
This is really a paranormal hotspot
unlike anything, we've
ever shot at before.
On three, two, one ...
Because of this location's massive size
and scope, I've called in psychic medium
Houston Grey to assist
in the investigation.
Houston!
Are you sensing anything?
Oh wow!  Wow!  Oh, there's
such an incredible energy here!
It's like hundreds of
voices all talking at once.
The sound is deafening!
There is something else.
I..I... There's something else here.
It's... like a dark spirit.
It might even possibly be a demon.
Now we have got to be
extremely cautious tonight, Lance.
We do not want to be messing
with something like this, at all.
This is it!
Houston, are you feeling anything?
Yeah.
I'm sensing deep
well of sadness in here.
A profound sadness.
I see a patient.
A female patient.
A girl. There is water,
red... red water.
Blood. Blood.  She died right in here.
She slit her wrists in the bathtub.
The caretaker said a girl
killed herself right here.
Houston!
That's incredible.
The spirit is still with us.
Cut it.
Yeah!
- Okay!  Was that too much?
- No.
Come on.
How was it guys?
No, no, no. That was great.
That sounded very real.
Hey Lance!
How do you feel about Show 6?
Feeling good.
It's a good location.
Do you think we're actually going
to see some ghosts this time?
Oh yeah! Hundreds of them.
I'm sure.
Wow!  Maybe you try to
sound a little less skeptical.
I mean, it would be great.
But if we don't, then... you know
whatever, we just want to make sure
we can get some good scares. That's all.
Oh!  Oh, oh hey, TC!
Uh, you want to get
a nice crime lab shot?
Dude, the ground's slippery.
Okay, this is creepy as shit.
I am getting out of here.
Alright, we are about to check in with our
resident Grave Encounters tech wizard, Matt.
Matt!  Why don't you walk us through
some of what are you're doing here?
I've set up ten static cameras
around the hotspots of ghost activity.
So they record constantly the tape.
They are also recording
to a backup hard drive.
And everything gets wirelessly
transmitted back to my computer.
So I'll know what's
happening all the time.
Real quick Matt!
Why don't you walk to us through
what some of the equipment is for?
This is an EMF meter.
And what this does is
it records electrostatic and
electromagnetic fields in the air.
So the basic idea is that
man-made or human EMF
fields will remain stable.
While fields caused by
paranormal activity will
produce spikes in the reading.
Infrared thermometer.
Okay, it's the same idea as the EMF, only
it's used to detect drops in air temperature.
Ghosts are believed to cause
dramatic drop offs in air temperature,
known in the paranormal
community as cold spots.
Testing one, two, three ...
- This is a simple analog audio recorder.
- All right.
- It's used to capture EVPs.
- Oh, now real quick ...
For the audience at home,
explain, what an EVP is...
EVP is Electronic Voice Phenomena
This thing will actually pick up sounds
that the human ear cannot detect.
So when we play it back,
if we hear something,
we'll know that something out there
is trying to communicate with us.
Okay. This is my favorite.
This is a Geiger counter.
You just turn the sound right here,
and you're good to go.
I mean, look at this!
This is freaking bad ass!
That's bad ass.
Listen!, I can guarantee you,
that if there is anything paranormal,
anything freaky happening in
this joint, we gonna catch it.
Alright folks, we're about
to initiate lock down.
My friend Kenny here, the
building's care taker
will be doing us the honor
of sealing us inside.
Kenny, thanks very much, man!
See you at 6 am.
Okay, 6 am sharp.
Good luck!
I am a demon.
A demon child.
I can't wait to see you
there in the morning.
Yeah, you see, we got to spend the
night with these two freaks.
What are you doing?
I'm on with Kenny.
Dude, did you lock the door?
What do you mean?  It's great for
the show, man.  Don't worry about it.
What if I have to get
more equipment after that?
All right!
This is the real deal folks!
This is the by far the biggest
location we have ever investigated
and the most dangerous.
Now, I want to put
emphasis on fact that
this facility was built
very much like a prison.
All the windows are barred.
We literally
could not get out of
here if we wanted to.
We are trapped inside,
until Kenny the caretaker
comes to get us in the morning.
We will be working
in pitch dark.
Capturing everything on three
night vision capable cameras.
Along with the static cams
that Matt set up for us
on our hotspots.
All right everyone! If  you are
ready, it's time to have some
Grave Encounters!
Okay, we're
now roaming the
vast darkness of the
hallways of the institute.
Hallways that have been
abandoned for more than 50 years.
We are in search of spirits
that are unsettled in life
and possibly unsettled
in the afterlife.
- I sense down here is cold
- Cold is right.
This is the hallway
where the apparition
of the patient
with the shaved head,
was seen floating down
at the end of the hallway.
Sasha, Let's do that EVP.
Is there somebody with us?
Are you a patient here?
- Did you use to live in the hospital?
- Play back.
"Is there somebody with us?"
"Are you a patient here?"
"Did you use to live in the hospital?"
There's nothing.
- All right.  One sec...
- I feel like it just sort of a ...
Spirit, you have
nothing to fear from us.
If you are here, show yourself!
I think it's getting colder as we
go on.  It's drawing us this way.
It wants us to go this way.
If there's a spirit here with us,
we want you to give us a sign.
Open the window!
Even just a nudge.
I'm going to use, this still camera to
try to capture paranormal anomalies.
They're not usually
seen by the human eye.
It's better known
as spirit photography.
One more.
We gonna have to wait for
the pictures to be developed.
If there is a ghost behind
me, we won't know until later.
Are you the one, who
wrote on these walls?
Or are you trying to communicate?
Why don't you try and
communicate with me now?
If the patient who killed herself in this
room, in this very tub, is here now,
make yourself known.
I'm really creeped out in here.
Alright, camera 2 and 4 have...
Temperature readings are nominal.
Guys, why do I have to be the
one that sits here by myself?
Houston, do you feel anything?
I'm feeling a very, very
negative dark energy here.
And not just a single energy, a
lot of energy.  Many, many spirits.
If there are any spirits down
here, please show yourselves!
Make a noise for us.
As we said before, it seems like
these tunnels just go on forever.
It stinks in here too.
- Oh, did you hear that?
- I heard that too.
- Okay, we just heard something.
- What the fuck was that?
I don't know, come here.
Over this way. You guys, follow me.
- How is it? Where is it coming from?
- I think this door.
Just down over here.
You want to open this?
You can swing your
camera around and get in?
Yeah, not really, but...
God damn it!
Oh!
Whoa... yucks!
- Rats!
- Are you frigging crazy?
- No way, man!
- Really?
It's not that big of a deal.
Awesome!
- You're such a dork!
- You see, its not funny!
This place is as haunted as a ...
It really is scary.
I honestly scared, okay so...
Sitting in a graveyard, an
inflamed guy is murdering his wife...
Could this be residual
ectoplasmic material
discovered first by the
Grave Encounters team?
Okay, I think we should just do
one more walk-through upstairs.
Give me some V camera
shots down the hallways,
get some of that...
floaty hallway stuff.
Like we did at Plain View Mansion.
Yeah exactly, exactly...
Stuff we can cut into.
Lance you are going to love me.
Mmm...
Shit!
How do you like this?
Hold on, hold on, hold on...
Yes, my dear?
Come on.  Why was
she crying on the phone?
Hi pumpkin!
What's this mummy tells me,
you're afraid of
monsters under the bed?
Didn't we have this conversation?
Monsters aren't real, baby.
They aren't real.
Even they were real, they
wouldn't want to come to our house.
Because you know Daddy will
take care of them for you.
Tell mummy I gave you permission
to lay in bed with her tonight.
Your Daddy won't be
home until morning.
We'll go out for pizza tomorrow, ok?
Dad will be home soon.
Bye bye.
God damn! Its cold in here.
What the fuck was that!
Guys, cut this shit!
I'm not fucking playing!
Ain't the fucking
time to do this shit!
What the fuck!
Hey!
Where are you guys?
Maybe it was the wind or something.
That's solid, alright.  Nothing short
of a tornado is gonna move that.
How much do you think that weighs?
Hey TC, how did it move?
Was it like...?
Whatever it was, it scared
the crap out of me, right.
I have to change my shorts
and I'm getting out of here.
Can you explain it?
I...
I just told you, man.  I was
taping, I turned around like this.
The thing just closed.
And I...
- I thought it was you guys, at first, right?
- You were taping it?
You taped?
I told you that in the first place.
If you guys weren't so busy like...
- Is it you frigging have it on the tape?
- You got it on tape?
Check that out!
- Boy!
- Oh my God!
Okay, that's freaky.
Yeah.
I accept your apology,
I accept your apology.
I cannot believe that you saw that!
Incredible footage you saw just
moments ago, was captured by
cameramen TC.
This door directly behind
me slammed on its own.
Now there's no drafts in room,
there's no windows that could
have caused it to slam on its own.
We are now going to
attempt to make contact.
Is there someone here with us?
Please make a noise.
Tap on something.
Feel free
to slam the door
like you did on TC
just moments ago.
Feel free to slam it
as hard as you like.
So go ahead.
Slam it!
Right wow, please!
Give us a sign!
Spirit, I invoke you to make
an appearance.  Take out...
With... If there is anyone here,
give us a sign...  Fuck!
Fuck!  I thought we were actually
going to have something here.
What the fuck was that?
Jesus Christ!
It was here...
That was really fucking scary guys.
That came from right... right here!
Shit, I can't see anything.
Do you hear that?
What's that?
- What?
- Oh shit...
Holy shit!
Hello!
- What's if...?
- This is really fucked up guys.
- I'm going to...
- What the fuck is that guys?
- What the fuck is that?
- What's up there?
Matt.  Hey Matt, is there
anybody up on Four?
Anybody up on any floor above us?
No.
What the hell is going on?
Obviously, somebody is fucking around
if they know we're shooting here.
Why are we going up here last?
Because this is where the
sound came from.  Jesus Christ.
Hello!
Is there anybody up here?
If someone's here, why
are they fucking with us?
Listen! If there's anybody here
trying to fuck with us, its not funny!
Alright, we'll call the police!
We have a right to be here!
We have a permit, and you don't!
- Hey, can you lower your fucking voice.
- I'm just trying to talk!
- You guys, you guys quiet.
Well, this is something real.
I gonna do EVP.
What's your name?
What do you want?
Are you in the room with us?
Where are you?
Come on, Sasha.
Play back
"What's your name?"
"What do you want?"
"Are you in the room with us?"
"Where are you?"
What's that sound?
No, no, no.  What is that?
What the fuck was that?
- Did you get that?
- Did you see that?
- No way!
- I got it on tape
Sasha!
Please, please, can't even
find you there ... at the lobby!
I need to get out of here.
I need to get out of here right now.
I can't even view.
What are you thinking?
- Just wait a second.
- Wait for what?
We've been shooting this show
for what?  Five episodes?
We've never seen
anything like that before.
I don’t even care!  And I just
need to get the fuck out of here!
Fine!  Houston, you take her down
there and you come right back, okay?
- I think I'll stay down there as well.
No, no.
I need another face on camera.
Lance, I'm really thinking,
I don't think I can do this. I...
Be a fucking professional will you?
Alright.  Stay in the character.
We are on to something here.
Alright!
Don't do this to me
Alright, I'll come back.
Come on sweetheart.
No no no!  TC you're
with me, man. Come on.
Are you kidding me?
Did you see that shit?
We don't get that kind of thing again
man!  You're fucking making millions!
Just moments ago
in this very hallway
we captured undeniable
proof of the paranormal.
Sasha was terrified to the bone because
a ghost actually manipulated her hair.
We're going to try to
attempt to make contact now.
To the Spirit, who
dwells in the hallway
we implore you to show us a sign.
Manifest yourself!
Please!
If you're still with us...
give us a sign.
Make a noise or...
manipulate my hair.
Do you see anything?
No.  Wait.  Give me the
light... no, nothing.
- Don't even think of asking ...
- We are a team.
I think its gone.
You what I think, honestly.
I think it had its fun...
It played this little prank and it
took off.  Maybe that's all they do...
I don't know.
I mean, I don't know.
Come on, you some fucking
in here, do something.
You did it before, do it again.
Are you fucking scared?
Jesus Christ.
Fuck, forget it.
Lance!  Its gone ...
Its left us ...
I'm sensing that it's toying with us.
-  Couldn't have said more...
- Shit.  Give it a rest.
Could we go home now?
Lance, there are people who chase Bigfoot,
look for Loch Ness their whole lives.
All right.
TC, what time is it?
It's 4:40.
So let's go home, man.
When did that guy say he's coming again?
Hey you guys, I think
we have enough footage.
Why don't we just pack up
everything and we get out of here.
- Okay! So we are...
- Yay... We're going home.
I think it's just right up ahead.
Are you sure?
Yeah, this is it.
This is it.
I don't think so.
- This is this the way, right?
- Oh for the look! Fuck, it's a dead end.
Guys.
You see, that's not...
that's not the way. Wait...
Come on, come on!
- TC roll on this, man.
- Roll on what?
- After we're lost?
- We're not lost.
We're not lost,
we came this way ...
And Matt?  Hey Matt, you are...
Are you at the station?
Matt! We're lost in here, man.
We need...
We need some info.
Why the fuck isn't he answering?
- I'm not going that way TC!
- Why not?
Because I'm going back over here.
Yeah.  We... if we stay in one direction,
then we're gonna get there okay?
It's what?
North?
In there and around
the corner, is where
the bathtub was, you know
where the girl killed herself.
Hey, we've been this way before,
we've been this way before TC.
I'm not trying to fight with you.  Just
explain to me when we saw this tub again.
Because this is not the same
fucking tub.  I know it's not.
- TC, come on get up, man.
- You said 6 o'clock?
- Are you gonna sleep there?
- Is Kenny coming at 6 o'clock?
- I'm not waiting.
- Yeah, he's coming at 6 o'clock.
I'm not waiting for you man.
I'm not waiting.
Where the hell were you guys?  You
all hear me calling you on the walkie?
Yeah, you know what?
Two tin cans with a fucking
string on it would have been better.
- We got lost.
- Something wrong with your walkie-talkies?
No!  I was calling you guys!
You didn't hear me on radio?
No, I didn't hear shit.
You didn't hear me?
No!
Because this is why you don't
lock the door, Lance, by the way.
Lance!
Case and point why you
don't lock the fucking door?
Holy shit!
What did you see?
Which one is it?
- That... fuck the hair.
- Oh yeah it is.
That is fuck!
Alright, I'm just gonna... I'm gonna
dump this quick on the computer.
No no no, Matt, we don't
have time for that.
Grab all the static cams.
Get it all together. You know...
Guys, let's all get up and
start packing this stuff up.
Get it ready for
when Kenny comes.
- Can somebody help me, please?
- No no no no.
I need everybody down
here, Matt. I'm sorry man.
It's gonna cut it's side, I know.
- You got your radio?
- Yeah, I got it right here.
- Sure it works?
- Hope so.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah, we got it.
- Okay, I'll Be right back, okay?
- Alright man.
Don't fucking leave without me.
Okay, it's time to get
the fuck out of here.
Hey Lance, are you there, man?
Hey guys, I got something up here.
Hello!
Hey Lance!
Guys, quit fucking around!
It is now approaching morning.
We haven't seen any
activity in well over an hour.
For Grave Encounters,
I'm Lance Preston.
- One more time...?
- No, we don't have...
One more time.
For Grave Encounters,
I'm Lance Preston.
That's all I got.
Fucking, I why I hate this anyhow...
It doesn't really matter, guys.
You know why?
We can always pick this up tomorrow,
there'll be sunlight, we'd be better too.
- Fine.
- You know what I mean?
That’s good idea.
Where is Matt, anyway?
What the fuck is taking him so long?
Matt?
Are you there?
- Lance! Lance!
- Matt?
Radio's not working before.
Guys, I know this
sounds really stupid but...
I'm the last person who wants to go
walking through these halls again.
But it's pitch black, and Matt could
have fallen and hurt himself for real.
She's right, he could be hurt.
- Guys, we have to go look for him.
- Okay...
Alright, this is ridiculous, alright.
Let's go fucking look for him
TC grab the camera.
Sasha grab the camera.
For what?
Listen!  If we gonna go and do this,
then we might as well film everything.
- Thanks for your help, man.
- Hey!
It's no fun hanging around
here I can tell you...!
By myself..!
Jesus Christ.
Matt!
- Matt!
Matt...!
- Matt, where are you, man?
- Where the fuck are you?
Matt!
- What the fuck?
- Shit.
Matt!
Hey Matt!
Why is this shit
everywhere?
Matt!
- Matt!
Alright, alright, alright.
He wouldn't just leave
equipment like this?
No, he wouldn't
It looks like he was just
packing it up anyway.
He's got to be... He's got to be
down one of this ways.
TC, you go that way,
Sasha and I'll go this way
Why will we do this?
That is a terrible idea.
He's got to be here,
he wouldn't just leave
- his stuff here alright...
- Why don't we split up as a ...?
Sasha comes with me.
TC just check that way, okay?
This looks like the living room
after a fight with my girl!
Matt, where are you man?
I want to go home, this is enough!
Freaking us out! Man.
Look for the cigarette butts...!
Come on, Matt!
This is stupid.. Dude!
I don't understand this guy.
Matt!
Come on, dude!
You're gonna get me
a shit with my girl!
It's late!
Fuck man.
You better be dead or dying, bro.
Matt!  I ain't playing with you
right now!  Where the fuck you at?
What the?!
Matt?
Lance!  Sasha!
- Shit!
- What happened, what happened?
- Don't, don't
- What, what?
Are you serious man?
Are you okay?
- What?
- Just lift me
Lift me.
- I swear to God, someone ...
- What?
- I got pushed..
Something fucking pushed me, man.
I was looking for fucking Matt.
I was looking downstairs,
sort of fucking
pushed me, I almost
broke my fucking neck, dude.
I looked back and
there was nothing there.
These things have been messing
with us, alright, all night.
We're getting fucking by them.
- Call him! Call Kenny! The only way...
- Okay! Okay!
- Told you. Just call him.
- Jesus, I'm calling Kenny alright?
Jesus Christ.
Fucking signal.
- Are you okay?
- No, I'm not okay!
Fucking piece of shit.
Alright, I can't get a signal.
Oh God...!
- Let me try.
- Alright, check the phones, guys.
Perfect.
Fucking perfect.
What the hell are you doing TC?
What does it look like I'm doing?
Come here and fucking help me.
- You can't break down the door, TC!
- Just watch!
No!  We're gonna cause
damage to the property.
We're going to
be liable for it, alright.
Just be patient.  Wait!
The guys fucking coming.
See hey!  Come on man!
What the fuck!
That's coming out of your rate.
Does it look like I give a fuck
about the fucking rate.
The fuck can...
I'm tired of this shit.
I want to go home
I want to go back to the fucking
hotel and get some fucking sleep.
Hey, you know what?
Your boy is a no show, okay.
What is he?
An hour late?
So just put the fucking camera...
- Christ!
- Fine. Alright.
- Help me.
- Alright, hang on.
- Do you want my help?
- No, Houston, we're fine with you there.
On three okay?
One, two, three...
One, two, three!
What the hell.
No, this is the fucking lobby!
This is the fucking lobby.
- We came in this way, right?
- Hell, yeah!
Yeah, this is the...
this is the lobby, yeah.
This can't be right.
This is impossible.
- This is the way we... this is
where we put our shit, right?
- Yeah.
This is the way we... this is
how we brought the stuff in.
- This doesn't make sense right?
- I don't understand, shit...
This doesn't make any sense...
This is the way we came in.
If there's another hallway,
it doesn't... I don't know ...
It must have got turned around here.
It must be on the other side
of the building or something.
Lance!
Are those are same doors?
I'm getting sick of this, guys.
Oh, ho ho ho, yes!
Houston, take that.
Take that, please.
Hey, hey, watch your leg, man.
Watch your leg!
Give me your fucking hand, you
sit and watch.  Isn't that fucking...
All right, all right, all right.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
One, two, three!
What is that fucking same...?
What the fuck is going on?
Maybe it's just an exit down to...
like this way to the emergency exit.
Houston shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up.
This, you see?
Now we'll get out.
Give me a fucking second?
- Oh fuck!
- Hey, watch it. Watch yourself.
- We're fucking trapped in here, man!
- No, we're not.
Hey, let's get a tool.
We can try pry the bars out.
I, oh, I got a fucking tool-belt.
Oh, shit, I forgot.
- It's in the van. Outside!
- Oh, fuck!
- You know, how we're locked out?
- We got nothing?
Fucking brilliant idea.
Alright, obviously not all the fucking
windows have bars on them.
Yeah, they do.
No, no!  The one upstairs!  That
one didn’t have any bars on it!  Right?
We just got to find it.
Who knows?
The shit's off...
- Come on.
- What time is it, Sasha?
- 8:34
- You got to be fucking kidding.
- Fuck!
- I told you that fucking ...begin at 8:34.
I have an audition tomorrow!
No one cares about you and your career
inside ... the baggage studio shit!
- Oh! My work's not as important as yours?
- Guys, let me think for a second!
This doesn’t make any
sense, it's fucked up!
I checked the
sunrise times last night.
What's your fucking point?
Should've been bright by 7:45.
But it's still night out.
- The sun is still not up ...
- Didn't make any sense!
It's not fucking funny man..!
Shut up!
This no make no sense.
- I need to get out of this building! Please!
- Somebody help us!
Ok ok ok ok.  Here. Listen, listen.  Well,
let's just try to be rational here, ok?
This is an old building, right?
It's an old building, so it has all
sorts of energy fields, things
and stuff going on, either
could be electrical anomaly,
that has actually moved our clock
faster, something so that you know,
it's actually not really 8.30 but only 6.30.
That would explain why it's so dark out.
And why why... you know,
Kenny hasn't shown up.
- Electric anomaly?
- It's fucking retarded!
Why did you come to believe your fucking
come from idea comes from rational?
This isn't one of your fucking audition
for some science fiction movie!
Because nothing else
is rational here okay.
It is rational as anything else.
I checked my cell phone...
And... it says the time is 1.12.
It's 1:12 pm.
I don’t think that's right.
But I guess it cant be... right?
I don't know.
Everyone's very tired.
So they are just taking a
nap and taking a break.
And we're going to just
wait until Kenny shows up.
I don't know what
the hell is giving me this.
Doesn't makes any sense.
I haven't slept for like 20 hours.
I'm gonna... I'm just gonna set my
alarm for an hour and I'll take a nap.
Houston, what's your problem?
- It's not my problem!
- What the hell are you doing?
- What the hell happened?
- Oh my God!
Someone or something
just broke our lights.
We are in the pitch dark.
All we have is our
flash lights and our camera lights.
- Which you're wasting right now.
- I just checked my cell phone.
And it says it's 8 pm.
So, we slept for 7 hours.
TC went to get a sandwich
and you gotta see this.
Lance!  It stinks...
Close that shit.
What are you...?
Close the fucking thing.. man!
All our food is like that, but
we still have lots of bottled water so...
I don't know, we should be okay.
Why don't we try going
down through the tunnels?
Kenny said that the tunnels
connect all the buildings together,
then maybe we can find a way out
through one of the other buildings.
Are you looking and see
the Great Wall of China?
I'm not going from the goddamn tunnels.
If our lights go out we're fucked.
Eh listen. Remember when you told
me to do the time lapse outside.
- Mm hm.
- I saw a fire escape.
If we get on the roof, probably
climb down and get the fuck out.
Well.  What's the verdict?
Shall we stay in here or ...
I don't care what we do.
Let's just get the fuck out of here!
I really... I don't want
to be here anymore.
- Ok ok.  So everybody, we're gonna
do this.  Everybody wants to do all this?
- To the roof!
- Alright, fine!
Let's pack up all
the gear and let's go.
- Give me some of the light, guys. Come on.
- Here here here.  Sorry.
- We go there?
- Let's wait!
- Lance?
- No, no, no!
TC you knew where we
were going, you said.
I didn't say anything!
Don't put it on me.
No, you said you know
where the ladder was.
No, I said there was a ladder.
- I didn't tell you where.
- Okay. But is it this end?
It doesn't matter.
Was it here?
- I saw from the outside.
- Okay. Got just a ...?
I can't do this, guys!
- Look!
- What the fuck is that?
- Hello! Someone up here?
- We just keep on...
TC!  Is this there?
Don't ask me questions.
Is it staircase or not?
Hey listen, just keep the
light on in front of me.
Move, move move!
Get the fuck out of my way!
- Wait guys!
- Slow Down.
What the fuck, you guys?
Yes, yes.
The fuck, yeah!
No fucking way!
Check this, check this!
That can't be right.
It's fucking solid.
Does it look new?  Does it look
like it's been there for a while?
This doesn't make any sense.
Would you get the fucking
camera out of my face!
- What do you think?
- I don't know, I don't know.
We just left the stair well that was
completely sealed off at the top!
I going to document everything,
when we get out of this.
People are coming to see this.
Look at this!  Okay we came up
4 floors from the stairs, right?
That puts us on the 4th floor.
We came from this way, and
we've gotta at least be here, right?
- Are you sure?
- I don't know ...
- TC, you said one of this floors...
- Lance! Lance! Lance!
What, what?
- What are these?  You were here?
- No, we know we went up a number of stairs!
This has not changed.
This is not opened.
This is not the change.
This says we're on the 1st floor.
Another we keep in mind though.
- Initially this is where we came in, right?
- I know, I know, but...
- TC, are you filming this?
- Yeah, yes, that's fucked up.
What what what?  What the
fuck is that?  Did you hear that?
- Did you guys hear that?
- Oh shit!  What is that?
- Shit! Stop.
- Matt? Matt?
Holy shit!  Over here.
From this foot.  Over here.
Matt! Matt! Matt!
Matt, is that you?
He's not in here.
He's not in here!
Whoa whoa whoa!
That just fucking move?!
Let's get out of here!
Now we wandered the building
to take a look for another stairwell.
And... I don't know.
We couldn't find one.
This building is a fucking maze!
It's like TC said it's...
It's likes just keeps
changing all around us.
We still haven't been
able to find Matt.
I don't know if he's okay.
At least he's not seeing
that same shit as we are!
We are all tired, and we are hungry.
So we gonna try to sleep again.
We're going to
sleep in shifts this time
so somebody can always be at watch.
- TC, you're rolling now?
- Yeah.
We just woke up and
you guys got to see this!
Turn the fucking camera off!
Sasha!  Come on.
We gotta to document this okay.
- I'm sorry. People got to see this.
- No, no!
- Careful! Careful!
- I'm so sorry.
Sasha, we got to tape this down.
This is unheard of.
There is no way someone came in here
and did that without us noticing.
- Dude cut it!  Cut this.
- My pleasure.
Matt!
I swear I heard.
Hello!
Matt?
See?  There, there. Fucking
heard him, I told you guys.
He's alive!
Matt! Are you okay?
Can you hear me?
I'm freezing!
Just tell us where you are.
We'll come and get you..
Matt!
Shit!
He's not there anymore.
We have to find him.
How do we gonna find him?
We can't even find
our way to the front door!
Houston, he can't be far.
Those walkie-talkies are a piece of shit.
Listen, how do we even know its him?
Matt!
Are you in here?
- Sorry, sorry, sorry!
- Fuck!
Matt!  We hear you buddy!
Where are you?
Sasha, try all the frequencies.
It doesn't have that much range.
How far is did you say
you thought it was?
I don't know how far,
the specifications...
- So what did you guess? 200-300-400?
- 200 yards to get a clear signal.
Maybe 300... before it
starts crapping out.  Okay.
Stay together, come on.
That's a dead end!
Dead end.
- Matt!
- Hey Matt!
- Matt.
- Matt!
Where the fuck are you?
Listen guys.  This is
fucking pointless, alright?
If we were to find it, he would...
the range of it no matter what...
Holy shit!
- What was that?
- That was Matt!
What are you doing, man?
What the fuck... ?
Lance! Lance! Lance...
Do fucking something!
Lance! Lance!
Hey you.
Hey!
Who are you?
How did you get in here?
Turn off the light!
Light off!
Did you see her fucking face?
Shut your fucking mouth!
What's happening here?
What is it wrong with me?
Oh my God!
Oh shit! Oh shit!
Shit, we lost him!
Oh shit, we fucking lost Houston!
Matt!
Guys!
Sasha!
TC!
Lance!
Is there anybody here?
TC!
Help! Help!
Help! Please!
Houston's gone.
then we tried Matt on
radio but he doesn't respond.
What the fuck is that?
We keep hearing crazy shit
like that all around us.
Fuck!
I don't think how
long it's going to last.
We are not alone in here anymore.
How is the name on it?
How the fuck is my
fucking name on it?
First, I get scratches on
my back and now ...
What the fuck!
When we woke up, we had this
you got to see this ...
Fuck you. What the fuck, what the fucking
wrong with me, you fucking asshole?
- I didn't fucking mean to, okay?
- You fucking...!
- I didn't fucking mean to.
- You bring us up, you asshole.
What the fuck does this mean?
It means we're fucked.
Okay! That's what it fucking means
This is insane.
Fucking insane!
- Don't look in it!
- Why, what wrong with looking like this?
What the fuck?
Enough, man!
There's something over there.
Here!  Enough is enough!
We keep walking in what
feels like circles and
we... we still can't find
Matt and Houston.
- Will you stop!
- Will you stop what?
Are you kidding me?
Fucking whole shit, we're not making 'em!
- Fucking TV show.
- I'm just documenting stuff, okay?
People will gonna want to see this!
Matt and Houston are gone?
We need to concentrate on
getting out of here and
finding them.
And you're just still
doing this whole shit!
Okay you guys, just
stay together, okay?
- I'm just really...
- Don't worry about it.
- Is that the fastest you have to run?
- Let's go!
Jesus Christ! Come on!
Keep up!
No, no, no, no! Get up!
Are you out of your fucking mind?
- Get up! Get up!
- Come on!
- I can't, I can't!
- Yes, you can.
Come on, you've got to get up.
You got to get up.
Come on.  I know!  I know!  You got
to be strong. You got to listen, ok?
You got to get up.
We got to keep going!
What, what?
Just get over here!
What are you waiting for?
Come in!
Look!
Oh shit!  Is it Matt?
That's him, right?
I don't know, man.
Matt!  Hey!
Matt, get up!
Matt, Matt!
Just shut the fucking room!
Hey Matt?
- Hey hey hey. Stop fucking around!
- Matt, are you okay?
The patient exhibits acute...
disorder linked to childhood phobia.
Jesus Christ!
- Get him the fuck up!
- Let's go! Go!
Come on, get him up!  Pull him over and
let's get the fuck out of this room now.
Get him in here.
Come on.
Put him down on bed,
put him down there.
- You see anything?
- No, its good.
Hey! Where you been?
Where did you get those clothes?
- Well, for God's sake, talk to us!
- You guys, look at his wrist.
Matt? Matt?
Where did you get this?
Where did you get all this shit?
Matt!  What did they do to you?
What did you see?
Nothing is bullshit!
Look, where have you been?
You probably know a way out of here.
You got to know a way out of here.
Of course there's a way out.
We can all leave,
as soon as we're better.
What?  What do you mean
"when we're better"?
What the fuck does that mean?
Well, I wasn't ready yet.
Progress is slow.  But the patient
is responding to treatment.
This guy is out of his mind.  He is
like high or something. He talks of...
- TC!   Shut up!
- You don't need to tell me fucking, fuck!
Don't be sad
Everything is gonna be okay.
He'll help you too.
Oh my God!
- Okay TC!  Go check that door!
- I already did.
Check it!  Not...
if something gets in here man.
Just make sure
there's nothing in here!
We found Matt.
He's all fucked up.
There's somebody I think is here.
What?
- It's okay.
- What are you doing?
I don't feel good.
I think there's
something wrong with me.
Yeah, you feel really warm.
I think you got fever.
- Here.  Have a sip.
- Thank you.
- Get some sleep.
- I can't sleep.
Thank God.
We'll be able to sleep again.
- Come on!
- Come on.
Come on...!
Run!
Come on, get in!
Come on now!
- Did you see anything?
- What is that?
There's blood in the tub!
- What?
- Come on!
...going far away.
Fuck!
Matt.  Matt!
- What he is doing?
- TC!  Get him away from the tub.
Come on Matt!
TC!  What the hell is he doing?
I don't fucking know!
Oh my God!
Help me!
Flip the tub!
- He is gone!
- He is gone?
He's fucking gone!
He just disappeared!
Oh fuck!
No, no!
It is an elevator!
Open it!
It's an elevator shaft.
If we can get down to the tunnels,
we could use them to get
one of the other buildings.
Go!
Fuck, fuck!
Listen! Listen to me.
I believe it's safer in there, okay.
I'm going to get some... and then
we're getting out of here. Okay?
Stay here with him, man. Okay?
What the hell is that?
Jesus!
Is that a tongue?
What's wrong?
Bring the light, bring it here.
There is a ladder. We can use it.
We can use the ladder to head down.
How are we going to get Matt?
I'm going to reach across, and
then you help me with Matt, okay?
Get back there!
Stay back.
Lance! Lance!
Where the hell is
the night vision button?
There it is!
He's gone?
I don't know, he just disappeared.
Go on. Go on.
He may come back. Go on.
- Where the hell is he?
- Matt!
Jesus!  He jumped!
He jumped!
Come on!
Easy.
I got you.
You're okay.
Go on.
It's okay.
It's the tunnels!
We made it to the tunnels.
Come on.
I can't.
I can't leave him.
Come on, Sasha!
Get out of there.
Remember what Kenny said.
They connect the buildings, right!
You need to do this with me.
- I can't do this alone! Okay?
- Okay.
Stay close to me.
Let's go this way.
It can't be too far.
Okay, we can.
Come on...
No! We should hit a...
We should hit a junction by now.
It should have been right around here!
What the fuck!
I can't...
Wait a second!
Sash, you okay?
Oh Jesus!
I want my mom!
It's a...
It's day.
What day is today?
I don't even know what day it is.
We spent all day
walking in one direction and...
we didn't get anywhere.
I figured counting me in the wrong...
Sasha not going to make it.
Who's there?
Who is that?
Sasha?
Sasha, where are you?
Where are you?
Sash!
Sasha!
Shit!
Damn it!
What do you want from me?
I'm running low on battery power.
Now, I only turn on light
only when I need to, now.
But I don't really
need the light anymore!
I just keep walking straight.
I could walk in the dark for hours.
It's kind of like a game.
How long can you go?
Anybody watching ...
Fuck you!
Fuck you, guys!
This is for you.
Don't you hear in these walls?
Don't you hear?
Don't you hear anything?
Come and get me!
Just woke up and...
I don't know how long
I was sleeping but...
There is a door!
You have to see it!
This isn't happening.
Oh God!
Jesus! Jesus!
Its...
It's impossible!
Shit! Shit!
No! No!
I'm not crazy!
No! No! No!
I'm so much better now!
I can finally go home!
For Grave Encounters.
I'm Lance Preston.
Signing off!