Simply Releases Toppers
Simply The Best
Proudly Presents:
Grave Encounters 2
Translated by Simply Releases Toppers
Jolly, Aegis and Depositair
Hello guys, it's Friday, October 30.
And the next thing we are going to talk about
's 'Grave Encounters'.
Grave Encounters.
- Grave Encounters.
It is a record found 'movie.
As Paranormal Activity, REC
or The Blair Witch Project.
They follow a bunch of ghost hunters, who
new reality TV show filming.
That leads to an abandoned psychiatric hospital
in search of the unknown...
Ended much more realistic than they
expected.
They met 'Grave Encounters'
- These effects are well done...
The camera work is terrible.
- The only thing wrong with the film...
it's a good movie, but not scary.
He's fucking scary.
- He's terribly creepy.
You're looking at him and
it plays with your mind.
And there are quite scary in parts.
Faces of people who do so.
You can not tell if this is real.
This is scary,
it's really scary.
This movie makes me so scared
I'm not here to lie...
so much that I almost wet my pants did.
And the end
I must talk about the end...
end because this was one of the worst
end pieces of my life.
I think I have this movie
'Grave Encounters', lets skip.
a scale of four.
I think this was all for this week.
This Movie Madness by Alex.
Log in to my channel
Alex_moviekid88.
Thanks for watching and
a happy Halloween.
Grave Encounters Part 2.
Where are you going?
- Where you're not going.
Lucky.
- Hey, remember me?
Stay with me, motherfucker.
My god, that's another kiss, Tessa.
- Trevor, lazer on.
Are there not some freshmen there?
- I hope so.
I know you do not like to eat a dick.
Come on, make an exception for me.
Are you okay?
Are you Michael from thriller.
Or are you dead Michael.
I'm dead Michael, sweetie.
Where are the kids then?
Are you here filming
with this piece of shit?
My camera may be small but are
I have a huge throbbing penis.
Not like that little of you.
What have we here?
My God.
Jennifer.
- Where's Alex?
I do not know.
- Is he here? Did he come with you?
He's not with me.
- I was really hoping I would see him tonight.
Want tongues? Okay.
I love the balance you.
You should now continue drinking.
Knock on the doors.
Do you really annoy me now?
Learn  once to knock.
- Hey, man.
Put the fucking camera down.
There is a mega party here and
you're masturbating.
Take you kidding me?
Await real vaginas on you there.
And Jen wants your body friend.
Is Jennifer there?
- Like I said, she looks good.
Not as good as this, but...
very good.
I have no costume, I can not go.
- Error.
You have a costume.
I have one won?
No, I do not.
I'm not wearing this fucking.
Yes, you are, it's Halloween.
- I'm not wearing.
No, absolutely not.
I can not believe I've persuaded me
.
Your ass is amazing.
- Look yet.
Cut it out. I'm not so among men.
friend Jack.
Do you listen.
There is no class in the horror movies.
No class, I tell you,
it comes to fast shooting and large lenses.
CGI needs to models to use.
And makeup effects.
- I think you're right.
As earlier.
I agree with you.
- Carpenter, Craven...
where are these guys in our generation?
Where are you?
This school death the new Gravens.
Nobody.
I'll tell you where they are.
They're here, friend.
Speech.
My name is Alex Wright.
You two are fucking...
genius, baby.
Alex's film revolves
ladies and gentlemen.
I will make a horror movie.
I will rediscover the genre.
- Yeah, I guess.
You know it and I know it.
It will be artistic.
a vision.
I will be a visionary, damn.
And I must say that kind of trouble.
Party on, fuckers.
That is delicious.
Sleeping Beauty.
Wake up, bitch.
How do you feel big boy?
Look, who's your friend?
my timeline but I would just check
if I were you.
Why?
There are some funny photos of you on.
From last night.
What have you done?
Tell me what you did.
Keep watching and you'll see.
You grab me at my breasts.
That was the problem,
why did you let me drink a whole bottle of tequila.
You grabbed it and wanted
not return.
Who is this man?
I have no idea.
Look.
Look, that's you.
Why hell.
Why did you put that shit on there?
Take it away.
- No, I did not even getagt.
are my balls.
- I do not care.
fucking a YouTube sensation.
It has 26 hits, my balls go virtual.
Take your fucking kidding me?
- Beautiful photo.
no fool who tries to help me?
You stood in full attention man.
You're almost a star.
- I'm my tag removal.
I get my tag away.
Fuck.
Hello, do you know where I can find weed?
Or marijuana?
Hey friend, I'm looking for weed.
Okay. Dr. Sam.
Good times at the film academy.
Right.
- What are you doing?
I check the news and opinions.
- You are such a nerd.
I do not care.
My opinion is given a name out there.
Watch this only once.
I have a video response.
guy who
"Grave Encounters" distributed.
I do not remember that scene in the movie
Sat
Who sent that video?
"Death Awaits"
The message is "Death Awaits"
Find out where the video comes from.
And the problem is resolved.
Can we please have some
tacos for dinner?
Gary, stop.
That's enough.
provoke not Stacey.
You find it fine.
Gary.
Stop.
Dirty bitch.
Look. I know that tonight
exactly a year ago...
that your father disappeared, but
you must agree to live now.
That provocative bitch.
Hello? Who's there?
Who does this, it's not funny.
Gary.
Where are you?
No. My god no.
I'm sorry.
Okay, let's just go,
I'm cold.
Gary?
No.
And cut.
That was for Marty.
We go straight through to the other shots, okay?
- That sounds good.
Jennifer  My God, you're officially
becoming the next...
queen of scream to be.
- Really?
Alex?
- Yes?
How could a man after his death
back on there?
That makes no sense.
This is a great start.
Believe me, I know what I'm doing.
I am a professional.
- Breasts.
Trev. "Death Awaits" replied.
Yes, and what does he say?
- Look.
What is that?
Is it a phone?
49.14.122.48.
are too many numbers to
a phone to be.
Who is it? Who has sent you this?
- Alex has a stalker on YouTube.
It makes no sense.
I checked the website and
again with Google Maps.
logical, but I do not understand why he sent me to this
.
Wait, go back to the part where
you're talking about...
the length of the songs and stuff.
Okay, 49.14.122.48.
The message of "Death Awaits".
The numbers are latitude, longitude.
I think.
Where do you think they mean?
- Vancouver Canada, the exact location...
a psychiatric institution called...
I think they see the movie Grave Encounters
have recorded.
They call the building
Collen Wood in the film.
'Collen Wood' does not exist, but
... it.
And that's the same bullshit
what we already had.
It was built at the end of the century,
mad doctors, lobotomy.
All that crap...
That's all real, it happened.
There it is.
Where the hell are you?
Male, Trevor check this out ..
Have you seen this? It scares me.
- Look you here for?
Many people believe that this is real
I'm not the only one.
They thought Blair Witch Project really was.
Yes, and Paranormal Activity and
stupid thing in space, on the moon.
It's just a marketing ploy, Alex.
That's exactly what they want you to think.
It's just a movie.
And, I mean it's not even a good movie.
I mean...
look at the special effects.
No single actor in this movie has
something done, since the film was released.
Nothing. Can you explain that?
The caretaker's been dead eight years now.
Kenny Sandoval, committed suicide in 2004...
shot himself with a shotgun.
The guy went crazy.
What about your own film, Alex?
do you a favor policeman who
for details to quickly settle?
Hello everyone. Actually, I have some questions...
where I need help,
to find answers...
about a movie I saw last week,
Grave Encounters.
I try to get in touch with the directors
...
or one of the actors or someone
that has to do...
with the film.
But I can not find any information about them.
There's something about that movie that is not true
and I want to the bottom.
So, if you or someone you know knows how
may come into contact with them.
Please, leave a message.
I would really appreciate it.
Help.
Help. Somebody help me.
Please, why are you doing this to me?
Let me go.
No, help!
It's time for your appointment.
- No.
You fucking psycho.
- It seems that you have holes.
What is that?
No, please no.
- This may hurt a little.
No, no.
Stop.
- What did you think?
Did you like it?
- It was good.
I just need some things to think about.
- You do not seem very happy with it.
Is it my performance?
- No, it was not your bet.
I have several variants
of practice, so we can...
It's not your fault. Okay.
- What about your dick man?
The pictures look great.
It looks good I admit.
But it's so cliché.
A masked man and a tied girl.
We have so often seen.
This is fucking torture porn, man.
Where people love.
You can earn $ 100 million.
- Yes, but I do not care.
I do not know. I must again
quiet about it.
Everyone can go, I have to rewrite it.
Okay, everybody, that's it for today.
Really?
- Great.
Jen, it was really good.
It scared me.
Thank you.
So look more cheerful.
- Film me that.
Okay, so I just picked up my mail and...
And I have a message from the YouTube user who
lately sending messages.
Let's see what he has sent.
This is a picture of Sean Rogerson
when he was younger.
The woman next to him should be his mother.
It came from a phone,
it is a local number from Washington...
so I will try.
Maybe it's about his mother.
Let's see where it goes.
Hello?
- Hello, this is the house of Rogerson?
Yes.
- I'm looking for Sean, is he?
Why do you want to talk to Sean?
- I'm doing a thesis on...
a movie where he participated named
Grave Encounters. I'd like to interview.
It would really help if I'm not the only one who would have had to navigate
.
You do not have to.
The GPS helps you.
Yes, many good friends do that...
- This is the white terminator error.
They do not help us. Computers are
not help us. It's in their nature.
must.
- We seem to be there.
Okay, so what was that girl again?
- Elijah, Trevor I say now for the 18th time.
And they said Sean certainly would be?
Sean would be here at three o'clock and willing
to do an interview.
Let's do it.
- Easily said, let's go.
Wait,
I do it with a big lens filming.
I do not understand why you've brought your camera
.
That's for my documentary
for the 15th time...
Your documentary adds nothing to it.
This is exactly where my documentary about.
- Shut up.
Hello.
- Alex?
Yes, Alex and this is my friend Trevor.
Nice to meet you,
come inside before you catch cold.
Yes, thank you.
- Absolutely.
Guys, wait up.
Would you like some tea or coffee?
I have a nice tea in the pot.
I do nothing, thank you.
I do also nothing, not all of us, I think.
But thanks anyway.
What does the picture look like?
- Prima.
Mrs. Rogerson, Sean is now in the neighborhood?
He just left, you just missed him.
But he comes back soon.
Okay, but Sean lives?
He's okay?
course, I always tease him,
that he is a workaholic.
He is currently working
a new TV series.
He loves acting, he always wanted
actor, even when he was little.
we wait for him
if you wish.
He will be glad to see you,
he loves it when people come to visit.
Sean, lives here?
- His whole life al Yes.
Yes, of course, why wait
you not in his room?
That's what he liked.
It's up the stairs, and then right.
Best Player 1996.
Look at this.
I think here a long time
nobody lives.
That's him when he was younger.
He looks like the "Real Slim Shady".
That's a really bad haircut.
He loved cats.
you?
- Yes, I...
What are you doing here?
Sorry, but who are you?
- I'm the nurse Mrs. Rogerson.
Mrs. Rogerson said we could wait
here.
We have an interview with Sean.
- You must go now.
We were...
- You must go.
You have to leave.
She said...
- Get out.
Get out, now.
We try to steal anything.
- This is ridiculous.
She said we could wait.
We would just like to speak with Sean.
Sean coming soon.
Soon as he is allowed to leave the hospital.
Which hospital do you mean?
What are you talking about?
hospital for crazy people.
You know 'Grave Encounters'?
The TV series?
I helped you to find his name, Lance Preston.
That was his stage name.
- Do not touch camera on.
Out.
- Okay, we're al
more thing.
What happened to Sean?
What happened to
the rest of his team?
She invited us here.
We are her guests.
We just want an interview with Sean.
That's all.
It is not intended that
they answer the phone.
She suffers from dementia, and gets
from January full nursing.
Did you hear that?
She knew 'Grave Encounters'
Look, she's nuts.
- Indeed.
hell.
She waves still.
Man, she makes him.
This should really see.
Yeah, man. She was angry after the play.
Alex, the point is, you said you would
would be there, but you were not there.
conditions showed the
... I know it sounds bad, but...
It was also important for me.
I know, I'm sorry.
- You promised you'd be there.
And you were not.
I searched everywhere for you.
- I know.
I'm sorry, but look at this.
You're obsessed.
It's a movie.
It's not just one damn movie.
Listen to me.
Call the mayor of Vancouver.
They have a file on March 28.
I do not care.
- 2003.
- Okay, then.
know, I'm so damn movie Sat
Do what you want.
You do not worry about me
more to do.
Day Jenn.
- Fuck you, Trevor.
Not now.
What was her problem?
I feel bad about the play...
but what can I say?
This is important.
What?
You're not with me?
I mean, I'm telling you,
from friend to friend, okay.
Jenn is probably the only
girl on this campus...
with the greatest chance
that you do your penis can stabbing.
Yes, that's true.
And now this has been said.
If I were you...
I would drop the conspiracy theory.
Conspiracy Theory?
Dude, I love you, but...
- Look at the evidence.
Missing, missing team.
Possible death.
What do I need to prove?
See what I mean?
every day I wake up next to "Rainman".
Fuck, Rainman was a genius.
Hello everyone, I know it's been a while
ago, I've posted some...
but there are many strange things happened,
during our research and recordings.
I did an interview with the mother
Sean Rogerson.
Listen to me, 'Grave Encounters' is real.
My friends do not believe me.
And I myself probably not.
But I'm not crazy.
I've done my research.
I just need proof.
Maybe we should go back to Takoma,
and read some more articles.
more...
The printer is automatically entered
and starts printing...
without anything I've done.
2384 Melrose Ave Los Angeles.
It looks like a kind of data sheet,
to create a video clip...
that held tomorrow in LA.
Hartsfield Productions.
Where do I know that name from?
Jerry Hartfield, he was producer of
'Grave Encounters'
data sheet that is printed...
for a video, he
tomorrow recording.
You can not just go to LA for two days.
And our movie?
- This is important to me.
you really fly all the way to LA,
for a data sheet?
Come on, I'm only two days away.
I see the problem.
Do what you want.
movie now outside the car,
and we are in LA.
Hollywood.
The film Mecca on Earth.
I would not say that it is beautiful,
because there is a lot of smog, but...
We are now in the studio.
Hi, Hartfield Productions?
Your name?
- Roberto Smith. I have this...
I got this info for my
appointment today.
a video clip.
Okay, Roberto, but within a row,
and park on level C.
Thank you.
- Okay ..
Film Crew.
That's him, that's Jerry Hartfield.
Cut.
Guys, where's the confetti?
We run two hours behind schedule, ahead.
again.
I head toward Jerry,
and try to talk to him.
Excuse me, sir Hartsfield?
Can I talk to you?
- One second.
Who are you?
- Alex Wright, I film a documentary.
I was wondering if you wanted to give
an interview?
You find yourself on my set.
You can stop, because I give
no damn interview.
Security, this man does not belong here.
I know of "Grave Encounters".
I know what you did.
Take him away.
- I know what you did.
I just tried to
with Jerry Hartsfield talking.
He left the security put me out.
He obviously hiding something.
I know not what I can do
more.
Yes?
I will talk to you.
But not here, not for a camera.
Come tomorrow at two o'clock
to my office.
Okay, fine, thank you.
Success.
Test 1, 2, 3.
This will be a good shot.
Hartfield Productions.
How can I help?
I have an appointment with Jerry,
at 14:00.
Alex?
- That's right.
Register.
How do you know?
Tell me honestly.
I know 'Grave Encounters'
was real.
And Sean Rogerson
and the rest of the team is dead.
For the record...
unless your body is found,
you are legally not dead...
but a missing person.
Thank God.
So you admit it, the images are real.
- Yes, every frame is real.
some cheap visual effects after...
we at the last moment
added.
What about the families?
There is something called
a "confidentiality agreement".
Do you have a confidentiality agreement signed
?
course, and arrange for some extra money, they signed
only too happy.
You probably think I
a big asshole, right?
I can not understand why you did it.
When I
images for the first time saw...
scared me to death.
Do you understand that?
I wanted to destroy them first.
But after all settlements
I sat on the edge of bankruptcy.
So, then I got an idea.
Why not release it as a movie?
Maybe we can recoup the cost?
And it worked, because they want a sequel.
'Grave Encounters 2'
Can you believe that?
directors The Vicious Brothers.
Who are they?
Why do not you join me?
Meet The Vicious Brothers.
Day, Jerry.
This is Colin.
And that is Stuart.
are my interns.
I pretended
the directors of the film were.
They arrange everything with the press, and because they are not union
sit...
I do not have to pay them.
You get all the students from UCLA.
And those of USC, and they are extremely rude.
Now you know the truth.
You can not get away.
- We already done.
I will tell to everyone.
Go ahead, who will listen to you?
You're a nobody.
The only reason I agreed
went with this conversation...
was to see whether you
evidence against me.
What you did not.
- I guess we'll see.
We shall then see.
You may go now.
What an asshole.
Who will listen to you?
You're a nobody.
So that's why I had to go.
If this is true, then it is disturbed.
- I did not ask.
What an asshole.
Yes, but he is also right. Because nobody
will believe us, we need proof.
What do you mean by "evidence"?
I've been thinking about...
and this is the movie I want to make.
Think about it, we are
already well under way.
You have it all filmed with your phone.
And you've also filmed.
It's a documentary, but also
a horror movie, right?
Why is it a horror movie?
I received a new message from
"Death Awaits".
He lives in Canada, next to the hospital...
Grave Encounters where they have filmed.
why he knows so much from,
and he wants us into the building meet.
There we find our evidence.
- You want to drive to Canada?
It is a 2 hour drive, we take
Jerry and Tessa with...
and filming everything.
It's a fucking movie, man.
For the 15th time...
I do not drive all the way to Canada
for a crazy idea.
I'll go.
- Seriously?
Can you explain this?
No, but...
- Why did he do that?
I do not know.
Are you in?
You go anyway, right?
photography credit.
You're in?
- Yes, let's do this.
You're my producer,
I need you there.
You can go to Sundance with this material.
This will put us on the map.
Trust me.
Okay.
December 3, 2011
You should give us another time about what
'Grave Encounters' tell.
We are on the way to... hospital.
We're here, right?
How do you know?
- Take it.
Is it illegal to
marijuana across the border to bring?
That is definitely illegal.
I thought Canada had
tolerance?
you kidding?
- Alex go to the side, we have to dump something.
You like to be.
I see it in your eyes.
Do you know the way to... hospital?
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Vancouver.
The forest is closed.
I shall open.
- She's going to open.
That is a tough bitch.
You're kidding.
- See this?
Alex, they have certainly managed
a creepy building to building.
Jesus Christ, this place is huge.
Alex, you know exactly where they
have filmed?
I think it was here,
let's take a look.
the Canadian police.
Seriously?
- Guys, let me do the talking.
Say nothing.
Excuse me, this is private property
Did you see the sign?
Sorry.
- Hello, sorry. We are film students.
We just want a few shots
for our school.
We just want to make some images
from the outside, that's all.
Sorry, but this
buildings are full of asbestos.
That is very dangerous.
You gotta get outta here.
Turn the camera off.
- No, absolutely not.
You may not filming.
You can not film in this area.
I understand.
We al
Give me the tape.
- I do not care.
Give the tapes from the cameras.
Specify the tape.
Damn.
- Keep driving, Alex.
Keep driving.
- What was that guy?
What an asshole.
Why would an agent do?
- I do not know.
Would he be a kind of guard?
What are you doing?
We are thrown,
on our first day.
Here it is.
We just try to make recordings,
the outside of the hospital.
But we were attacked
by a guard.
That our cameras trying to tackle.
He said because "asbestos".
That was clearly lied.
They try to hide the truth.
They're trying to hide something.
They do not want anyone...
We are unstoppable.
- Fuck the police.
Enough, guys.
This movie is retarded.
This is why you are here?
Julie think this is real?
That's what it's all about, Tessa.
I am not responsible for my actions.
I received a new message
of 'Dead Awaits'.
It says that we meet him in the room
in the western tunnel, at 03:00 tonight.
We...
8 cameras with night vision,
we go draw around the building.
This mega camera with high resolution.
A thermal camera.
And an EMF meter.
That's what she said.
Tonight we will try to find evidence...
what Jerry Hartsfield 10 years
trying to hide.
But this film, really.
The spiritual world exists.
And the team of 'Grave Encounters' died
during an attempt to capture.
Here we go.
- Let's do this.
Damn, it's the guard.
Duck.
Jerry, turn off the lights.
- Turn off the light.
Is someone there?
Duck.
Hello?
Okay, I'm on my way.
Okay, go.
- You heard it, now run.
Do something softer.
Wait for me.
- Do not leave me, all those ghosts here.
"Death Awaits".
- "Death Awaits".
It's definitely the right building.
Tess, bolt cutter.
No, I'm doing this.
- Whatever you want.
you serious?
- My God.
This place is not scary.
My God, is that police tape?
Why would the police come here
but if this was a movie?
Because this is not just a movie.
Are you ready?
This hall scares me.
Yeah, I'm so ready.
Okay.
Okay, it's okay.
- Okay, let's go.
Camera 1: Ground floor, East Hall
That way.
- That side? okay.
Demons in the corridor,
demons in my head.
Demons...
Okay, let's go.
We go.
Camera 2: Third floor
patient room.
hurry.
- Wait for me.
Hey, this is where the black die?
Yeah, well the ethnic always go first death.
Camera 5: Third floor, bathroom
Damn man, that's really high.
Come on, man. Let's go.
Soon you fall into it.
Okay, guys, we're going to make the intro.
Camera 7: Fourth floor, Window Room
Room 8: Sub-Level, Tunnels
I can not say.
- Yes, you can.
Alex are crazy documentary,
Take One.
Ready?
It was on March 20, 2002.
Sean Rogerson and a team
of 'Grave Encounters'...
filmed their
sixth episode of a reality series.
in the same building.
They found something terrible, something that
their lives tragically inkorte.
It was sold to the American public
as fiction, but it was actually...
reality.
Later tonight we will meet
an anonymous source...
known only as "Death Awaits".
He was the one who tipped us.
And in the meantime we will
our paranormal research.
Hoping to uncover the truth
after a decade of concealment.
Is everybody ready?
- Yes.
Tess did you?
And 3, 2, 1... Action.
This building is huge
and is super easy to get lost.
So
to ensure that this does not happen...
and we always find our way back,
let this glow-sticks fall behind us.
We have these military GPS.
That we bought in a spy shop,
in case...
one of us, the group lost.
Are we all this.
Damn, blondie. I have headphones on.
Sorry, I think it's safe to say...
that we are well prepared for the worst.
This is the bath, where T. C Gibson...
aka actor Merwin Mondesir, was slain.
Now we try to communicate with the spirit world
.
In the hope that we can achieve Merwin.
I take it, on my recorder.
the spirit of Merwin Mondesir here with us,
speak freely.
Do not worry, I'm sure your wife and your daughter
like something you want to hear.
the spirit of Merwin Mondesir here with us,
speak freely.
Do not worry, I'm sure your wife and your daughter
like something you want to hear.
Great.
- Fuck.
If there are ghosts here with us
speak freely.
Give us a sign, make some noise.
Create a cold place.
Jack, grab the thermal camera.
- Yes.
Okay, yeah.
Man... what the hell?
There is a strange haze behind Trevor.
- You mean... let me see.
I told you this was real.
- What is it?
Let no farting, asshole.
Is it visible on the thermal camera?
- Yes.
Look again.
- Trevor.
You did it, you're a beast.
That's really mature.
- This is insane.
So, what do you think?
This is the tunnel where Sean Rogerson
his last moments in life were spent.
Crazy become pain...
of hunger,
as you get deeper into the tunnels running...
is like you deeper and deeper into the depths of madness
comes.
Taken literally, the tension
in this building, at every step.
What?
- I think it's a bit exaggerated.
What is it exaggerated?
- You should not exaggerate too much about madness.
I get it.
Guys, look.
Jack, take this on.
- Yeah, man.
Seriously, what does this. Why do they do
on the ground?. It's disgusting.
He said we had to meet in
the room, west of the tunnel.
And it does not go further west than this.
What time is it?
- 03:25.
Maybe he's just a little later.
He's just not
without him we have nothing.
The whole project will be a disaster.
What's this?
- No, this is a spirit board.
A what?
- You lay your hand on a piece...
and then try your spirits to communicate
using the letters.
Come on, we have to play.
- This will never work.
Yes, yes.
We do the two of us.
I talk to the spirits of...
we know that many of you here
were mistreated and abused...
and so therefore angry
in the afterlife.
Are there ghosts here with us now?
It's not really...
Do you think
- No, do you?
Who does it?
- I do not.
Sit me not to besodemieteren.
I do not.
- Okay, who are we talking about?
Give me a name?
My God boys.
- Okay, stop.
D. .. E. ..
A. .. T. .. H. ..
A. .. W. .. A. .. I. .. T. .. S
Damn. "Death Awaits"
is not a person.
this State on YouTube guys?
- This is really weird.
What do you want us to do?
My God, what he says.
Take everything.
- Yes, of course.
Damn, all backwards.
Guys seriously, this is not a joke.
Are you okay?
What the hell happened?
Got anything filmed?
- Yeah, I got it.
Alex, I can not fucking believe it.
Okay, what was that?
- What is it?
Great.
- I told you to keep your mouth.
What the hell was that?
not move. Okay. It's good.
you realize that breaking
a criminal offense?
you think I would not see that broken lock?
I understand,
but I'm not leaving without my stuff.
It is not even mine, it's
of our school.
I do not care who it is?
That you discuss it with the police.
God, do not be a jerk.
Shut up.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
He's not.
- You're not a cop
Trevor, shut up.
Thank you, now listen to your friend.
Sir, you do not...
Damn?
- What the hell was that.
Okay, who's there?
Nobody.
- Nonsense. Who else is here?
There's nobody else here.
- Something strange is happening this building.
And I do not know what it is...
- What are you talking about?
I do not know.
- This place is haunted, man.
Do me a favor?
Okay, now you all...
stay here and do not move.
You really should not go up.
- Weapon there and act tough.
Do you want him now?
Shut up and stay here.
Let's get out of here, man.
- No, we can not leave...
If we go now...
- Yeah, come on.
If I go, I leave behind...
the stuff of the University,
$ 50,000 to cameras.
If you stay, you will be arrested.
If you want to leave, go ahead.
I stay, if I do not have the camera and recording...
I have no movie?
Then I fucking movie.
Were those gunshots?
- Yes, that was it.
No, Alex stay here.
Man, let's go.
- Where are you going?
He can hurt.
- He's an asshole.
Come on!
Hello?
Are you here?
Are you okay?
're kidding.
- We gotta go.
I agree with her,
we gotta get outta here.
Wait, we make two groups,
then it goes faster.
you serious?
This is stupid, Alex.
Why the hell should we split?
- Just go fast.
Tes, as we all do,
takes longer.
Fuck you, I will not walk alone.
- Pull yourself. Go Tes.
the camera.
- Are you crazy?
Why are you against it every time?
Why do not we just.
So incredibly stupid,
I do not think we do now.
Can you keep that flashlight there.
Can you please hurry up?
Shoot.
- Take it easy.
Tessa, I found the room.
Where are you?
- At the end of the corridor.
Where?
Damn.
Tessa, come here.
What are you doing?
Jerry, where are you?
My God, Jerry.
Guys, I need help.
Guys hello.
What the hell happened?
I do not know, I heard a bang,
and then he was gone, he must have fallen.
What, what happened?
- He must have fought with anything.
The camera recorded it.
Did you see that? Did you see that fucking.
I want to fuck away.
- Tessa, we gotta go.
Come on.
output, come on here is an output.
Call 911
- It does not work, I have no coverage.
Keep moving, we call when we get outside.
Come on.
Jerry's fucking dead.
What?
- Goddamn.
Here there is no fucking exit.
This is not impossible, look at the glow-sticks.
Maybe the guard moved them.
That is not possible.
Why would the guard do?
- I do not know.
Calm down.
- Shoot.
Where the hell are you.
Okay, it says here that we are here.
Two steps down that way.
This stands on its head,
the exit is that way.
We are on the fourth floor.
- What are you talking about?
Alex, do you look up here for?
- What's the point?
So we can find an exit.
You do not understand,
that card is useless.
My god, this place looks terrible.
Look, would also have been children?
I'll go first.
Do you see that?
- Yes.
He moves.
Take this down?
Trevor, come back.
- Trevor stay there. Trevor stop.
...
What is she doing here?
Hi, I'm Kaitlin.
What is your name?
Will you play with me?
Or do you...
Guys wait.
Slower. Tessa.
Tessa.
- What the hell?
What, what is it?
Did you hear that?
- Tessa.
Where the hell are you?
Fuck.
Leave me alone.
How does this thing work?
Come on.
Boys.
Alex.
Oh God.
Boys.
Where are you?
touch me.
Do not touch me.
Stay the fuck away from me.
My name is Alex Wright.
This is Jennifer Parker and
that's Trevor Thompson.
We came here to find evidence
the movie Grave Encounters real.
fuck all really.
We have Jerry and Tessa already lost.
I do not think they have found.
Do not say that.
There must be a reason why the
has brought us here.
Why you have brought me here?
I do not understand.
He wants me to film everything, but...
I do not know why...
- Turn the fucking camera off.
Somebody turn off the camera.
I let anything happen to you, okay?
done nothing to you.
Why do we fuck up?
What is that?
- Alex, please do not go inside.
What if Tessa?
That's not it.
Turn it off, Alex.
Turn it off.
Turn it off fucking.
the guard.
Is he dead?
I think so.
Turn it off, please.
Get it off me, please.
Why were we so stupid to come here?
I can not believe it.
Guys, look.
It seems so loose.
What? Okay let's go.
Hurry.
Do not just stand there, give me a crowbar.
Shoot.
Come on.
Come on Sean. Come on.
Damn.
Okay, let's...
Let's just leave...
We must return
... - Come on.
Racing.
- Come on Jen, come on.
outta boys.
Jerry.
We should go.
Take that damn camera.
We came out of the building.
We fucking met.
Did you see that?
I told you it was real.
Alex.
- Alex what the hell are you doing?
Alex, come here.
They are dead.
- Think not, grab your stuff.
We must do something,
we can not just go.
I do not know what to do.
Come on, hurry up.
I do not know why you so obsessed
was through that damn movie.
Sorry, I did not
everything that would happen.
Tessa's probably dead.
You and your damn project.
- Keep your own mouth.
What the hell?
No. We were in the hotel.
Do not. That is useless.
- We were in the building.
What do you mean in the building?
Everyone in the building is going
fucking dead.
Pack your bag, okay?
No, I do not wanna go.
- You have to walk.
This is nonsense. Where do we go now?
I will not fucking die.
Then everything for nothing.
I think it anytime from spinning.
What the hell is that?
Are you okay?
Jennifer.
- Alex, where are you?
Where the hell are you, Jenny?
Jennifer, where are you?
- I'm here.
Trevor, converts the thermal camera.
Can you see anything?
- Forward, walk toward my voice.
I'm here.
this way.
What do you see?
- What is it?
Turn that light off.
Please help us.
Please.
- Follow me, come on.
it.
Shoot.
Trevor, is that you behind me?
Get out.
Guys, wait up.
My foot's stuck.
What the hell?
Trevor. My God.
Where were you? What's happened to you?
What happened?
- I do not wanna talk about it.
Who are you?
you live here?
Wait...
You're Lance Preston.
Sean Rogerson actor anyway?
Lived you all the time?
What's he doing?
Hello buddy. You're my friend, right?
My God.
I think I will puke.
Want some?
You must help us to find a way out of this cursed
building.
Are you a patient?
What?
All patients?
Where was your husband?
Sean, we are not patients.
We are film students...
we broke into the building.
Why?
Why would you do that?
I must know the truth about your movie.
What movie?
Good evening and welcome to another episode of
Grave Encounters.
Your Grave Encounters movie...
.
Ashley.
There must be a way out, something.
You must know something.
Katie has the keys.
not fucking touch me.
She comes to us,
wait a few more days.
She does not listen to me.
She committed suicide.
She's not for you.
You must know something, you've been here nine years.
A vent, a fucking window, anything.
2 days, 11 hours.
nine months, two days 11 hours.
Think you here for 9 months now.
You've been here nine years...
not nine months, you understand?
your mom, okay,
I met your mother.
A nice lady.
Nice lady, but she is very sick.
Your mother is very ill.
- Shut up.
Trev, wake up.
Alex, why do you film this?
This guy is completely insane.
- Look, it's like a psychopath.
10 years on this fucking place.
Why did you give him a pair of scissors?
- He does not do anything, it's okay.
I do not trust him.
Sean, what are these drawings?
That's the door.
Is not that nice?
This makes no sense.
No, you know?
It leads nowhere.
It's just a detached door.
You can just through it.
Maybe, maybe not.
Sean
gone through every door in this building.
Except this.
- This is our way out.
He's too fat.
- The bolt cutter cut therethrough.
Got a bolt cutter?
- Yes...
we had a bag of tools,
but we are lost.
Where is it, are you lost?
The building is huge.
It's big.
It's as big as a city.
- It's bigger and bigger and bigger.
It changes constantly.
But there are patterns.
I encountered them.
Where did you get the bag left behind?
I do not know, it was a hall
with all bathtubs in the rooms.
4 hours, 6.
7, 8 pm.
This is crazy, it is a detached door.
That door leads nowhere.
Alex, this is not Narnia.
- No, sorry but this is crazy. It's stupid.
You know what else is weird?
a hotel through...
and end at the same place as
where you started.
We have spared this field
What's in there?
- That's where Dr. Friedkin's.
mean Friedkin doctor?
He was the head here.
I've read about him, he was occult.
Rituals in the basement.
Experiments in the patients.
Where do you get this from?
That's where he went inside.
She opened the door, you know?
Friedkin did.
They took
the real world and the spiritual world...
and he... added together.
Then he drew a hole in the building
and went inside. That door...
is the only way.
You gotta believe me.
Alex, come on.
I can not believe we're doing this,
why we follow him, Alex?
Friend, I have a bad feeling about him.
- We have no choice, right?
I thought you knew where you were going.
- Wait.
.
Come on, let's go.
We will not wait.
Please delete it.
See, I told you?
Jesus Christ.
What was that?
- Listen, come here.
You know you drink water
a fucking toilet, right?
What are you doing?
Jesus Christ.
here, help me.
It should bring us to the other side.
Are you okay, man?
- Trevor.
nothing beats
- okay?
Trevor, the bag there?
- Yes, the bag is here.
What is this now?
- Did you see me?
Where is the bag? Got the bag?
This could work.
- Okay, but what do we do now?
We rest for a few hours.
And then I see what's behind the door.
What are you doing?
- In case something happens to me...
Fuck you, Alex.
Fuck, Jameson.
Fool.
Mom, Dad...
Jason, if you look at this...
means,
I'm probably dead.
So I think, this is my last will and testament
.
I would not be here, but I'm here.
I'll fucking a will.
I'm dying, I just wanna go home.
Hello? Is there anyone?
Hello?
What the hell?
Sean, you scared me, what do you want?
I must do him.
You've done that.
We just woke up.
And Trevor's death, we found him
in one of the bathrooms.
I had to listen to Trevor,
I should trust him.
Sean, took all our stuff. The bolt cutters,
water. What he left behind...
had this fucking bag.
We will never come out of this building,
we die here.
Listen to me, calm down...
- Stop filming me.
Stop filming me.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Listen to me...
because I let anything happen.
Okay?
I let anything happen,
we come here, I promise you.
Okay, now?
- I do not know.
card, the card sucks.
Can you read it?
- Yes, yes, I think so.
Yes, we must go to the room with the door.
We need the bolt cutter...
that's our only chance
to get out of here, okay?
Are you sure it's that way?
They look at something.
It is long since I was on camera.
Maybe I'm a little rusty.
I'm Lance Preston, welcome to a new
episode of "Grave Encounters".
welcome to a new
episode of 'Grave...
I'm Lance Preston, welcome to a new
episode of "Grave Encounters".
The rest of the crew, is no longer with us.
But I'm still here, if we're lucky, we might
make contact with them.
Why did you close the door, Lance?
I want to go back to the hotel.
I feel a dark and evil spirit, Lance.
It may be a demon.
Who plays this character.
I'm outta here. Which way is the room?
What is the correct door?
Finally.
Goddamn, what the hell
.
No.
Nonsense.
You broke your promise.
Liar. All nonsense.
Liar.
Give me the camera.
You said only one of us who
red door could go.
I've even killed
so they would not follow me.
What did I do wrong?
Answer.
Get the others.
How do I do that?
If you do not let me go?
Collect the tapes.
Collect the tapes...
you want me to collect the material.
Yes, I do.
I can try.
Make the movie.
What movie?
What are you talking about?
Hello?
Okay.
Collect the tapes.
I must collect the tapes.
Are you sure we should go this way?
According to the map is here.
Jennifer?
- Here it is.
Wait. Sean told us that we had to avoid
surgical department.
I do not think we have any other choice.
What are these things for?
My god.
Why did Dr. Friedkin this?
- Goddamn.
Alex this is not good.
We gotta go, keep moving.
Let's get outta here.
Come on.
Turn off the light.
not talk, be quiet.
Be still, be still, damn.
Is that Doctor Friedkin?
- Do not, do not.
Jennifer, be still.
Shut up.
Is this a joke or something.
in. Close the door.
Okay, I think we're here.
- You said you could read.
I do my best.
- Are you sure?
I do not fucking.
Damn, Jennifer, look.
How did we get here.
- How do we get the hell out.
It seems that he has already been
do you think he has gone through?
Looks.
We're too late.
- We're too late, he has escaped.
Well, it does not work.
- You killed Trevor, stupid fool.
Your friend was dead,
at the moment he entered the building.
Those were all of you.
Alex, look at this.
He said that if one of us has all tires.
That he can go.
And that would be me.
Now you must stay behind.
I've been here too long.
Have you any idea what ten years here,
can do to a person?
I just wanna go home.
Well, give me the recording of your cameras.
I need to finish the movie.
I give you anything.
This is my movie.
The building says I
the movie must finish.
Give me the damn pictures...
Give me the recordings.
Let him go.
- That is only if he dies.
building chose me and not you.
I need to finish the film.
Are you okay? Is it?
fucking bitch.
I'll kill you.
Hang.
- I can not.
I did what you asked liar.
Alex?
Alex, are you?
He's gone, he's
sucked.
What do we do now?
I try to finish the film.
The film finish.
This was all about.
Why they contacted me.
The building wants an end.
Alex, what are you talking about?
I think I just
the end of my film have invented.
You're the star.
Alex, what are you doing?
You heard him.
One of us will come here.
So what do you think, Jennifer?
You've always said you wanted...
your last film was a hero story, right?
This is the scene, do not make it harder than it needs to be
.
Alex, please...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
Alex. No.
It's over.
Go to sleep.
I did it.
Make your movie.
Others will see it and come.
I will not disappoint you.
Sir, I have a 41 here on the A5.
7823, we have a white man...
with a bag, I call for the strengthening...
Sir.
No, not my camera.
I need him. I'm not going back...
I got my camera.
Where am I?
In what city am I?
- You're in LA.
Jerry, can you tell us how the
Grave Encounters 2 form received?
Well sure, I was as surprised as anyone
when this guy came to my office...
to say that he is the sequel to
Grave Encounters had made. I mean...
I thought he was crazy, but Alex
here...
a talented director and I think
has a bright future.
This has everything. It has ghosts
send messages over the Internet.
Young girls are murdered,
boys are sucked into the walls.
.. it's incredible material.
Hope you enjoyed it.
I want to be clear about something, I made
this error with the first film.
Everything you've just seen
is counterfeit.
Okay, every scene has improved
or manipulated.
It's just a movie.
Is there anything else you want to add
before we close?
Look, whatever you do.
Do not go to that building looking.
not seeking...
It's not worth it.
There's nothing there.
Simply Releases Toppers
Jolly, Aegis and Depositair
www. simply releases. com