[ PROJECTOR CLICKS ]
[ WINGS FLUTTERING ]
>> [ SOBBING ]
>> Lisa.
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA JOHNSON.
LISA!
ME AND EDGAR FOUND THE PIRATE
TREASURE.
MEET US DOWN IN THE SECRET CAVE.
WE'RE GONNA SPEND ALL SUNDAY
MORNING --
[ STATIC STOPS ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ VIDEO GAME PLAYS ]
HEY, WATCH OUT FOR BLINKY, OKAY?
HE ALWAYS TRAPS YOU ON YOUR
LEFT.
>> DON'T!
[ VIDEO GAME FADES ]
LISA, YOU MESSED UP MY GAME!
>> HERE'S YOUR WALKIE.
STOP WAKING ME UP WITH IT, BRAT.
>> EDGAR LEFT IT, NOT ME.
>> WELL, TELL EDGAR HE'S
ANNOYING.
>>   YOTELL HIM.
>> HE'S YOUR IMAGINARY FRIEND.
>> HE'S NOT IMAGINARY.
>> LISA, GO DOWN TO THE BASEMENT
AND START THE LAUNDRY, WILL YOU?
>> I DID IT YESTERDAY,
YOU JUST DON'T REMEMBER ME DOING
IT.
>> STOP BEING A SMART ALECK.
BUSTER BROWN, WHERE'S YOUR
GLASSES?
>> I LOST THEM.
>> WELL, FIND THEM, PRONTO.
LISA, HAVE YOU DECIDED WHERE
WE'RE GONNA GO FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY
TOMORROW?
>> ASK ME TOMORROW.
>> OKAY.
WELL, I HOPE WE GET THERE,
'CAUSE THE CAR'S NOT RUNNING.
YOUR DAD'S BEEN TRYING TO FIX IT
ALL DAY.
>> HE WON'T FIX IT.
>> LAUNDRY, PLEASE.
COLD WATER ONLY.
THE HOT WEARS OUT THE CLOTHES.
>> I DON'T THINK IT'S POSSIBLE
FOR OUR CLOTHES TO WEAR OUT,
EVER.
>> COLD WATER.
[ HARD ROCK 'N' ROLL PLAYS
INDISTINCTLY ON HEADPHONES ]
[ WASHING MACHINE LID CLOSES ]
[ SIGHING ]
>> LISA.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> NOT A SMART IDEA TO GO
ANYWHERE TODAY, PAL, WITH ALL
THIS FOG.
STAY INSIDE, OKAY?
PLAY SOME GAMES WITH ROBBIE OR
PRACTICE YOUR CLARINET.
I'M SURE EVERYONE ELSE IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD IS STAYING INSIDE
TODAY, TOO.
EVEN THE PHONES ARE OUT.
[ TELEVISION PLAYS INDISTINCTLY
IN DISTANCE ]
SOMETHING WRONG LISE?
>> HMM?
NO.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
I MEAN, YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME
ANYWAY SO...
>> THIS IS THE STORY OF PETER
AND THE WOLF.
EARLY ONE MORNING, PETER OPENED
THE GATE AND WENT OUT INTO THE
BIG, GREEN MEADOW.
[ CLARINET PLAYS WITH RECORD ]
>> LISA!
[ CLARINET STOPS PLAYING ]
COME DOWNSTAIRS, WILL YOU?
YOUR FATHER AND I WANT TO HAVE A
TALK.
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
>> YOUR MOM SAYS YOU'VE BEEN
ACTING KIND OF FUNNY ALL
MORNING.
>> FUNNY HOW?
>> WELL, FOR ONE THING, SOME
CLOTHES ARE MISSING FROM THE
LAUNDRY.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE THEY ARE?
>> [ SIGHS ]
HONESTLY, I-I REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHERE THEY WENT.
THE TRUTH IS, THEY'RE GONE EVERY
DAY.
>> AND WHAT DOES THAT MEAN,
"GONE EVERY DAY"?
>> OKAY, IT'S LIKE MOM'S
PANCAKES.
EVERY MORNING, SHE MAKES THEM
FOR BREAKFAST, AND YOU'RE ALWAYS
TRYING TO FIX THE CAR, WHICH FOR
SOME MYSTERIOUS REASON HAS
ALWAYS STOPPED RUNNING.
THEN, MAC AND CHEESE FOR LUNCH.
THEN, WE HAVE MEAT LOAF FOR
DINNER EVERY NIGHT.
AND AT 8:00, WE WATCH,
"MURDER, SHE WROTE" AND GO TO
BED, WAKE UP TOMORROW, AND DO
THE EXACT SAME THING.
>> WELL, YOU AND ROBBIE HAVE
SCHOOL TOMORROW, AND I HAVE
WORK, SO...
>> THERE IS NO SCHOOL.
THERE IS NO WORK.
>> AND WHAT ABOUT YOUR BIRTHDAY?
THAT'S NOT TOMORROW EITHER?
>> NO.
NEVER COMES.
IT'S ALWAYS THE DAY BEFORE I
TURN 16.
IT'S PRETTY FRUSTRATING.
>> I'M REALLY TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND WHERE THIS IS ALL
COMING FROM, PAL.
ARE -- ARE YOU BORED WITH YOUR
LIFE?
IS THAT IT?
I MEAN, ARE YOU ANXIOUS ABOUT
SOMETHING?
>> IS IT A BOY?
>> NO, NO, MUM! GOD, NO!
YOU JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND IT,
LIKE, AT ALL!
>> WELL, EXPLAIN IT TO US.
MAYBE WE CAN UNDERSTAND.
>> THAT'S THE THING, IS THAT I
HAVE TRIED TO EXPLAIN IT MANY
TIMES, AND YOU GUYS JUST NEVER
REMEMBER AND YOU DON'T BELIEVE
ME.
>> BELIEVE WHAT?
>> THAT WE'RE STUCK IN THIS
HOUSE AND WE'RE NEVER GONNA
LEAVE.
>> WHY?
>> BECAUSE ALL OF US --
>> SHUT UP, LISA, SHUT UP!
>> ENOUGH IS ENOUGH, LISA!
Shh.
>> HEY, HEY.
>> IT'S OKAY, BUCKAROO.
Shh.
YOUR SISTER IS JUST PLAYING A
SILLY GAME.
LISA, YOU TELL YOUR BROTHER THAT
EVERYTHING IS OKAY.
>> LISA?
>> I'M GONNA GO FINISH PLAYING
THE CLARINET IN MY ROOM.
LET ME KNOW WHEN THE
MAC AND CHEESE IS READY.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
>> [ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON
TELEVISION ]
SAFE-DEPOSIT KEY --
IS THAT WHAT YOU WERE LOOKING
FOR, CAPTAIN DOWNING?
OR SHOULD I SAY, MR. DOWNING OR
WHATEVER YOUR NAME IS?
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA JOHNSON.
ME AND EDGAR FOUND THE PIRATE
TREASURE.
MEET US DOWN IN THE SECRET CAVE.
WE'RE GONNA SPEND ALL SUNDAY
MORNING THERE.
[ BEEP ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ SIREN WAILS ]
>> LISA?
GO DOWNSTAIRS TO THE BASEMENT
AND START THE LAUNDRY, WILL YOU?
>> I DID IT YESTERDAY.
YOU JUST DON'T REMEMBER ME DOING
IT.
>> STOP BEING A SMART ALECK.
HEY, CHARLIE BROWN, WHERE'S YOUR
GLASSES?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> WELL, FIND THEM, PRONTO.
LISA, HAVE YOU DECIDED WHERE
WE'RE GONNA GO FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY
TOMORROW?
>> ASK ME TOMORROW.
>> WELL, I HOPE WE GET THERE,
BECAUSE THE CAR'S NOT RUNNING.
YOUR DAD'S BEEN TRYING TO FIX IT
ALL DAY.
LAUNDRY, PLEASE.
COLD WATER ONLY.
HOT WEARS OUT THE CLOTHES.
THANK YOU.
[ ROCK 'N' ROLL PLAYS
INDISTINCTLY ON HEADPHONES ]
[ WASHING MACHINE LID CLOSES ]
[ CLANGING IN DISTANCE ]
[ MUSIC SHUTS OFF ]
[ WASHING-MACHINE WATER
RUNNING ]
[ WASHING MACHINE SHUTS OFF ]
[ SIGHS ]
>> THANK YOU, AND WELCOME TO THE
WHITE HOUSE.
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ TELEPHONE RINGING ]
>> IN A MOMENT, I WILL BE
SITTING AT THAT DESK, TAKING UP
A PEN AND SIGNING THE MOST
SWEEPING OVERHAUL OF THE TAX
CODE IN THE NATION'S HISTORY.
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> TO ALL OF YOU HERE TODAY,
WHO'VE WORKED SO HARD AND LONG
TO SEE THIS DAY COME, MY THANKS.
AND THE THANKS OF A NATION GO
OUT TO YOU.
[ TELEPHONE CONTINUES RINGING ]
THEY HAVEN'T MADE THIS THE
FREEST COUNTRY AND THE MIGHTIEST
ECONOMIC FORCE ON THIS PLANET BY
SHRINKING FROM CHALLENGES.
THEY NEVER GAVE UP.
AND AFTER ALMOST 3 YEARS OF
COMMITMENT AND HARD WORK...
[ STATIC ON TELEPHONE ]
...ONE HEADLINE IN
"THE WASHINGTON POST" TOLD THE
WHOLE STORY...
[ RECEIVER SLAMS ]
"THE IMPOSSIBLE BECAME THE
INEVITABLE."
[ STATIC ]
>> EARLY ONE MORNING, PETER
OPENED THE GATE AND WENT OUT
INTO THE BIG, GREEN MEADOW.
[ CLARINET PLAYS WITH RECORD ]
[ CLARINET STOPS PLAYING ]
[ MUSIC SHUTS OFF ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ CLARINET IN DISTANCE PLAYING
"PETER AND THE WOLF" MUSIC ]
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING IN
DISTANCE ]
>> DID YOU WASH EVERYTHING IN
THIS LOAD?
SOME CLOTHES ARE MISSING.
>> YEAH, I KNOW.
>> SO, WHERE ARE THEY?
>> I DON'T KNOW, MOM. OKAY?
THOSE CLOTHES ARE MISSING, LIKE,
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
[ SIGHS ]
>> COME DOWNSTAIRS, WILL YOU?
YOUR FATHER AND I WANT TO HAVE A
TALK.
>> YOUR MOM SAYS YOU'VE BEEN
ACTING KIND OF FUNNY ALL
MORNING.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
>> ...CAPTAIN DOWNING?
OR SHOULD I SAY, MR. DOWNING?
>> [ CRYING ]
[ SLOW FOOTSTEPS IN DISTANCE ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ FLOORBOARD CREAKS ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ CREAKING IN DISTANCE ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ FOOTSTEPS ASCENDING STAIRS ]
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA JOHNSON.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> ME AND EDGAR FOUND THE PIRATE
TREASURE.
MEET US DOWN IN THE SECRET CAVE.
WE'RE GONNA SPEND ALL SUNDAY
MORNING THERE.
>> [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ SIGHS ]
>> LISA?
SWEETHEART, PANCAKES ARE READY!
[ "PETER AND THE WOLF" MUSIC
PLAYS ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ CLARINET PLAYS WITH RECORD ]
[ THUMP IN DISTANCE ]
[ GASPS ]
[ CREAK OVERHEAD ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GASPS ]
[ CLICK ]
[ TAPE PLAYER WHIRRING ]
[ STATIC ]
>> AND...
WE'RE IN FOCUS.
OKAY. [ SIGHS ]
[ SIGHS ]
OUR NEW HOME.
>> [ CHUCKLES ]
[ TAPE REWINDING ]
[ CLICK ]
>> WE'RE IN FOCUS. OKAY.
[ SIGHS ]
OUR NEW HOME.
>> [ CHUCKLES ]
[ TAPE REWINDING ]
[ CLICK ]
>> WE'RE IN FOCUS.
OUR NEW HOME.
>> [ CHUCKLES ]
>> WHO ARE YOU?
[ STATIC ]
[ GASPS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
HELLO?
IS ANYBODY HERE?
WAS THAT YOU PLAYING THE
CLARINET?
ARE YOU TRYING TO CONTACT ME?
[ SIGHS ]
ARE YOU DEAD?
ARE YOU...ALIVE?
>> LISA?
>> [ GASPS ]
WHAT?
>> WHAT ARE YOU DOING UP THERE?
>> NOTHING.
>> SOME CLOTHES ARE MISSING FROM
THE LAUNDRY.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE THEY ARE?
>> NO.
>> WELL, THEY WENT SOMEWHERE.
>> OKAY, JUST GIVE ME A SECOND.
>> [ GASPING ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> WELL, BRUCE, IF YOU GET THE
CAR FIXED, I'D LOVE IT IF YOU
COULD GO AND GET A FEW
GROCERIES.
>> OKAY.
WELL, I'M WORKING ON IT.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHERE TO START
WITH IT, BUT I AM WORKING ON IT.
>> MOM, CAN I GO PLAY WITH
EDGAR?
>> WHAT ABOUT CHOCOLATE
ICE CREAM FOR DESSERT?
>> ME AND EDGAR WILL BOTH HAVE
DOUBLE SCOOPS.
>> [ Chuckling ] NO.
YOU WILL EACH HAVE ONE SCOOP.
GO AHEAD, MR. MAGOO.
LISA, YOU HAVEN'T EVEN TOUCHED
YOUR MEAT LOAF.
>> MEAT IS MURDER.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ON
TELEVISION ]
>> WHAT'S THE MATTER, LISE?
>> SINCE WHEN DO YOU SMOKE?
>> SORRY?
>> THAT'S NOT PART OF THE
ROUTINE.
I-I'VE NEVER SEEN YOU SMOKE
BEFORE.
>> YOUR FATHER ALWAYS SMOKES
AFTER DINNER, BUT HE'S GONNA
QUIT.
RIGHT, BRUCE?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> A SCOOP FOR YOU TONIGHT,
HONEY?
>> WHAT'S WRONG WITH TWO SCOOPS?
>> YOU'RE AS BAD AS ROBBIE.
ONE OR TWO SCOOPS FOR YOU, LISA?
[ APPLAUSE ON TELEVISION ]
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
>> WHERE'S DAD AND ROBBIE?
>> UH, YOUR FATHER IS IN THE
GARAGE FIXING THE CAR, AND
ROBBIE'S UP IN HIS ROOM PLAYING
VIDEO GAMES.
>> WHAT ABOUT
"MURDER, SHE WROTE"? >>
>> OH, SWEETHEART, DO YOU MIND
WATCHING IT UPSTAIRS?
I JUST -- I REALLY WANT TO
FINISH THIS CHAPTER.
[ CLANGING IN DISTANCE ]
[ MUSIC PLAYS INDISTINCTLY ON
RADIO ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
I KNOW. I KNOW, I KNOW.
SEE IF I CAN GET THIS
SON OF A BITCH WORKING.
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW WHY.
I DON'T KNOW WHY IT WON'T WORK.
I DON'T KNOW, I JUST DON'T.
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
LISA?
GO BACK INSIDE, LISA.
I GOT A LOT OF WORK HERE TO DO.
GO ON.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU, UH, GO AHEAD, SWEETHEART.
NIGHT.
>> GOOD NIGHT, DAD.
[ CLANGING RESUMES ]
>> [ GRUNTING ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ FLOORBOARDS CREAKING IN
DISTANCE ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ DOORKNOB SQUEAKING ]
[ GASPING ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ FLOORBOARD CREAKING ]
>> Lisa.
>> [ GASPS ]
WHO ARE YOU?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
>> Lisa Johnson.
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
GET AWAY!
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> LISA?
LISA, ARE YOU THERE?
WAKE UP, PLEASE.
SOMETHING'S WRONG. I'M HIDING.
COME DOWNSTAIRS QUICK.
[ CLICK ]
[ CLATTER ]
>> BRUCE, STOP IT!
STOP IT!
>> WHAT?
>> STOP IT!
[ CLATTER ]
>> [ Hoarsely ] THEN TELL ME
WHERE THEY ARE.
>> I HAVE NO IDEA.
[ CLATTER ]
>> YOU STOLE THEM FROM ME.
>> WHY WOULD I DO THAT, BRUCE?
WHY?
>> YOU STOLE THEM.
STOP LYING!
>> MOM?
>> DAD?
>> LISA, GO UPSTAIRS.
TAKE ROBBIE WITH YOU.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHERE THE
SPARK PLUGS ARE, LISA?
>> THE -- THE WHAT?
>> I HAVE BEEN TRYING TO FIX THE
CAR ALL MORNING, AND I'VE NOW
DISCOVERED THAT IT'S JUST THE
SPARK PLUGS.
THEY'RE MISSING FROM THE ENGINE.
SOMEBODY'S TAKEN THEM.
WAS IT YOU?
WAS IT YOU?!
>> [ WHIMPERS ]
>> NO.
NO, DAD.
I-I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ DOORBELL CONTINUES RINGING ]
MOM, NO, DON'T ANSWER IT.
>> WHY NOT?
>> PLEASE. PLEASE, MOM, DON'T.
>> LISA, I AM NOT GONNA SHUT OUT
THE REST OF THE WORLD JUST
BECAUSE YOUR FATHER GETS UPSET
SOMETIMES.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> [ SNIFFLES ]
>> GOOD MORNING, MA'AM.
I'M FROM THE PHONE COMPANY.
WE'RE CHECKING THE LINES IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD TODAY.
HAS YOUR PHONE BEEN OUT THIS
MORNING?
>> WELL, YES, IN FACT, IT HAS.
>> WE GET A LOT OF STATIC
BECAUSE OF THE FOG.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY FOR THE
INCONVENIENCE.
DO YOU MIND IF I COME IN AND
CHECK THE JACKS?
>> YES, OF COURSE.
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ GASPS ]
>> WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE YOU FOLKS
GOT QUITE A MESS ON YOUR HANDS,
DOWN HERE.
I'LL CHECK UPSTAIRS FIRST.
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
>> LISA? LAUNDRY.
COLD, NOT HOT.
>> LISA, DO WHAT YOUR MOTHER
SAYS.
>> [ GASPS ]
I-I FORGOT SOMETHING IN MY ROOM.
I'LL -- I'LL BE BACK IN A
MINUTE.
[ FOOTSTEPS ASCENDING STAIRS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN AWAKE?
>> WHAT?
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU KNOWN,
UNDERSTOOD?
>> UM...
I DON'T -- I DON'T KNOW.
UM, A-A WEEK, MAYBE.
I-I'M NOT SURE.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT -- WHAT HAPPENED TO US?
I...
[ GASPS ]
>> WHENEVER YOU HEAR STRANGE
NOISES IN THIS HOUSE, OR VOICES
CALLING OUT TO YOU, IGNORE THEM.
PRETEND THEY DON'T EXIST, LISA.
IF YOU SHOULD TRY TO CONTACT THE
LIVING, OR ANYONE ELSE, YOU AND
YOUR FAMILY WILL SUFFER IN WAYS
YOU CANNOT FATHOM.
>> [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> HAVE YOURSELF A WONDERFUL
DAY.
>> OKAY, THANK YOU.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
SO, LISA, YOU GONNA START THE
LAUNDRY?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ON
TELEVISION ]
>> DID YOU PUT SOMETHING
DIFFERENT IN THE MEAT LOAF
TONIGHT, HONEY?
'CAUSE IT'S -- IT'S FANTASTIC.
>> I PUT A LITTLE BIT OF PAPRIKA
IN IT.
THAT MIGHT HAVE DONE IT.
>> MOM, CAN I GO PLAY WITH
EDGAR?
>> WHAT ABOUT CHOCOLATE
ICE CREAM FOR DESSERT?
>> ME AND EDGAR WILL BOTH HAVE
DOUBLE SCOOPS.
>> NO, YOU AND EDGAR WILL EACH
HAVE ONE SCOOP.
GO AHEAD, YOSEMITE SAM.
LISA, YOU HAVEN'T EVEN TOUCHED
YOUR MEAT LOAF.
[ UTENSILS CLINK PLATE ]
>> AH.
THAT WAS AMAZING.
[ SIGHS ]
>> WHERE'S YOUR CIGARETTE?
>> [ Chuckling ] I'M SORRY?
>> DON'T YOU ALWAYS SMOKE AFTER
DINNER?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT, LISA.
I DON'T SMOKE.
>> DON'T YOU START EITHER,
YOUNG LADY.
THE SURGEON GENERAL JUST CAME
OUT WITH A WARNING THAT IF --
>> WAIT. HOW -- HOW CAN YOU JUST
ACT LIKE NOTHING EVEN HAPPENED
THIS MORNING?
>> THIS MORNING?
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT THE
CLOTHES THAT ARE MISSING FROM
THE LAUNDRY?
DO YOU KNOW WHERE THEY ARE?
[ SIGHS ]
HAVE YOU DECIDED WHERE YOU WANT
TO GO FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY
TOMORROW?
YOUR FATHER GETS HOME AT 6:00,
SO I WAS THINKING THAT WE COULD
JUST --
>> SORRY.
>> WHAT?
>> I JUST -- I CAN'T DO IT
ANYMORE.
>> YOU CAN'T DO WHAT?
>> I'M SORRY.
>> WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN EXCUSED, LISE.
LISA, WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
IT'S NOT SAFE OUT THERE.
LISA!
LISA, STOP! COME BACK HERE!
[ Echoing ] LISA!
>> HELLO?
HEY, IS ANYONE OUT THERE?
HELLO?
PLEASE I DON'T WANT TO BE STUCK
HERE ANYMORE.
YOU HEAR ME?
I SAID I DON'T WANT...
>> THERE YOU ARE.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> COME ON BACK INSIDE, PAL,
IT'S JUST NOT SAFE RIDING OUT
THERE.
BRING YOUR BIKE BACK INTO THE
GARAGE.
YOU CAN THEN -- LISA!
[ BICYCLE PEDALS SQUEAKING ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GASPS ]
>> OKAY, NO MORE GAMES,
YOUNG LADY.
GET INSIDE NOW.
MOM'S GOT DESSERT ON THE TABLE,
AND "MURDER, SHE WROTE" IS JUST
ABOUT TO START.
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ CLICK ]
ARE YOU HERE?
I'M SORRY I TOLD YOU TO GO AWAY
LAST NIGHT.
I WAS JUST SCARED.
I KNOW IT SHOULD BE THE OTHER
WAY AROUND -- RIGHT? -- SINCE...
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO'S ALIVE AND
I'M THE ONE WHO'S...DEAD?
GOD, IT FEELS WEIRD JUST SAYING
THAT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW I DIED OR WHY
OR...HOW LONG I'VE BEEN STUCK IN
THIS STUPID ROUTINE WITH MY
FAMILY.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE WE'VE BEEN
SLEEPWALKING FOR A REALLY LONG
TIME, BUT...
NOW I'M AWAKE.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
THERE'S SOMEONE ELSE HERE, TOO.
[ SOBS ]
HE'S DEAD LIKE ME, I THINK.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
HE DOESN'T WANT ME TO BE AWAKE
OR AWARE.
HE TOLD ME NOT TO CONTACT YOU.
BUT I NEED TO FIND A WAY OUT OF
HERE, AND YOU'RE THE ONLY HOPE
I'VE GOT TO FIGURE IT OUT, SO...
PLEASE.
PLEASE JUST TALK TO ME.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
[ SIGHS ]
WHAT'S THE FIRST LETTER OF YOUR
NAME?
YOU HAVE TO MOVE THE PIECE TO
THE FIRST LETTER.
[ SOBS ]
JUST MOVE IT ANYWHERE.
JUST SAY SOMETHING!
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
>> LISA?
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
>> HELP ME, LISA.
PLEASE HELP ME.
>> [ GASPING ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
OLIVIA?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN THERE?
>> LOOK UNDER THE FLOOR.
>> OLIVIA, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
YOU OKAY?
OPEN THE DOOR.
OLIVIA!
>> [ SCREAMING ]
>> [ GASPING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA JOHNSON.
LISA!
ME AND EDGAR FOUND THE PIRATE
TREASURE.
MEET US DOWN IN THE SECRET CAVE.
WE'RE GONNA SPEND ALL SUNDAY
MORNING THERE.
[ STATIC STOPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ FLOORBOARDS CREAK ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ LOCK CLICKS ]
[ WATER DRIPPING ]
[ CLICK ]
[ SPLASH ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SPLASH ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GASPS ]
>> [ GRUNTS ]
[ THUD ]
>> HELLO?
[ GASPS ]
>> HELP ME.
[ SCREAMING ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GASPS ]
>> LISA!
SWEETHEART, PANCAKES ARE READY.
COME AND HELP SET THE TABLE,
PLEASE.
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> YOU KNOW THIS IS HOMEMADE
SYRUP, HUH?
>> HOMEMADE SYRUP?
WHAT, YOU TAP THE TREES IN THE
BACKYARD?
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
>> [ Chuckling ] NO, BRUCE.
>> MOM?
>> MM-HMM?
>> EDGAR WANTS MORE PANCAKES.
>> ASK AND EDGAR SHALL RECEIVE.
[ TELEPHONE RINGING ]
>> [ GASPS ]
>> PHONES ARE WORKING AGAIN.
>> I'VE GOT IT.
[ UTENSILS CLINK ON PLATE ]
HELLO.
YES.
CAN I ASK WHO'S CALLING, PLEASE?
>> [ GASPS ]
>> CERTAINLY.
OH, YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
JUST A SEC.
LISE, IT'S A MR. WOODS.
HE SAYS THERE'S BEEN SOME
CHANGES TO YOUR LAB ASSIGNMENT.
HE WANTS TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT
IT.
LISE, COME ON.
DON'T KEEP HIM WAITING.
I'M SURE HE'S GOT LOTS OF OTHER
STUDENTS HE'S GOT TO CALL.
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> LISE, TAKE THE PHONE.
GOODNESS SAKES.
>> I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU TO MIND
YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
YOU ARE A BUSY BETTY, AND I
DON'T LIKE BUSY BETTIES.
>> [ GASPS ]
WHAT'S DOWN IN THAT ROOM UNDER
THE BASEMENT?
WHO'S DOWN THERE?
I MEAN, THAT'S YOUR SCRAPBOOK
UNDER MY BEDROOM FLOOR, ISN'T
IT?
>> THIS IS MY HOUSE, LISA.
IT ALWAYS HAS BEEN.
>> WHY ARE YOU KEEPING US HERE?
>> STOP OPENING DOORS THAT ARE
MEANT TO BE CLOSED.
>> WHY?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO TO ME?
I'M ALREADY DEAD.
[ CLICK, STATIC ]
>> LISA.
COME AND FINISH YOUR BREAKFAST,
PLEASE.
IT'S GONNA GET COLD.
>> [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> MOM, CAN I GO PLAY WITH
EDGAR?
>> OKAY.
FINISH YOUR PANCAKES FIRST.
>> YOU GET AWAY FROM HIM!
>> LISA, NO! HE'S MY FRIEND!
>> LISA, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> DON'T YOU SEE HIM?!
>> SEE WHO?
>> EDGAR!
>> LISA, STOP TEASING YOUR
BROTHER.
>> I'M NOT! HE'S RIGHT...
>> [ As Pale Man] LISA.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> THEY ONLY SEE WHAT I LET THEM
SEE, LISA, AND SO DO YOU.
>> [ GASPS ]
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
>> MOM...DAD?
[ GASPS ]
ROBBIE?
[ GASPING ]
[ Sobbing ] OH, ROBBIE!
[ GASPS ] NO, NO, NO, ROBBIE!
PLEASE WAKE UP!
MOM, DAD, WAKE UP.
WAKE UP!
PLEASE WAKE UP.
OH.
[ GASPS ]
[ TISSUE CREAKING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ Gasping ] OH. OH.
[ GASPS ]
[ MOUTHING WORDS ]
NO!
[ SOBS ]
NO, NO, PLEASE!
PLEASE, I DON'T WANT TO BE
ALONE!
I DON'T WANT TO BE ALONE IN THIS
HOUSE!
PLEASE!
[ SOBS ]
PLEASE BRING THEM BACK!
PLEASE!
[ SOBBING ]
>> LISA?
>> [ SOBBING ]
>> LISE, WHAT'S WRONG?
TALK TO ME.
SWEETHEART, IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
EVERYTHING'S ALL RIGHT.
I GOT YOU, PAL.
I GOT YOU.
>> [ SOBBING ]
[ CLARINET IN DISTANCE PLAYS
"PETER AND THE WOLF" MUSIC ]
>> Lisa.
>> LEAVE ME ALONE!
[ Crying ] PLEASE!
THIS IS ALL A MISTAKE.
[ SNIFFLES ]
THINGS NEED TO GO BACK THE WAY
THEY WERE.
[ CRYING ]
GO AWAY!
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ WATER RUNNING IN DISTANCE ]
[ FAUCETS SQUEAK ]
[ WATER SHUTS OFF ]
[ GASPING ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ GASPS ]
>> LISA.
[ CREAK IN DISTANCE ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING IN DISTANCE ]
[ CHILDREN PLAYING IN DISTANCE ]
[ DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE ]
[ CLARINET THUDS ON BED ]
[ GASPS ]
[ TECHNO MUSIC PLAYS IN
DISTANCE ]
>> [ LAUGHING ]
>> OLIVIA, COME PLAY WITH ME.
>> OLIVIA?
WE'RE HAVING EGGS AND BACON, SO
COME HELP ME SET THE TABLE.
HOW'D YOU SLEEP LAST NIGHT?
NO MORE SLEEPWALKING, RIGHT?
[ CLANKING IN DISTANCE ]
YOUR FATHER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
>> COME ON.
I KNOW, I KNOW, I KNOW.
GOD DAMN IT. I KNOW.
GOD, THIS SON OF A BITCH.
OH, GOD.
AW, I CAN'T FIGURE OUT WHY IT
WON'T.
[ METAL CLANKS ]
[ SOFT MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO ]
COME ON, WORK.
WORK. COME ON.
I DON'T KNOW, I DON'T KNOW.
SON OF A BITCH.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
NEED SOMETHING, OLIVIA?
[ TOOLS CLANK ]
[ SIGHS ]
NEED YOU TO GO BACK INSIDE,
OKAY?
I'M BUSY.
[ SIGHS ]
[ LIGHTER CLICKING ]
COME ON.
[ Chuckling ] OH, COME ON.
DAMN IT!
[ SIGHS ]
I DON'T WANT YOU COMING IN HERE
WHEN I'M WORKING.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I SAID, GET OUT!
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ COUGHING ]
[ CRYING ]
>> LISA. OH, MY GOD.
ARE YOU OKAY?
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> I THINK SHE'S SLEEPWALKING.
I WAS STANDING IN THE KITCHEN,
AND SHE JUST WALKED RIGHT PAST
ME AND CAME IN HERE.
>> SWEETHEART, YOU OKAY?
>> [ CRYING ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
>> I THINK WE SHOULD CALL A
DOCTOR.
>> THE PHONES ARE STILL OUT.
>> WELL, WE SHOULD DO SOMETHING,
BRUCE.
>> MOM, I'M FINE.
CAN YOU JUST BRING ME SOME
MAC AND CHEESE?
>> YES, OF COURSE.
>> OKAY PAL...
I'M GONNA BE DOWN IN THE GARAGE
IF YOU NEED ANYTHING, ALL RIGHT?
>> DAD?
>> YEAH?
>> DID YOU FIND THE SPARK PLUGS?
>> THE SPARK PLUGS?
>> THAT'S WHY THE CAR WON'T
START.
>> OH, UH, NO.
I'M PRETTY SURE IT'S, UH...
I'M PRETTY SURE IT'S JUST AN
ENGINE VALVE.
DON'T WORRY, THOUGH, I'LL HAVE
IT FIXED BEFORE YOUR BIRTHDAY
TOMORROW, AND WE'LL ALL HAVE A
GREAT TIME.
YOU CAN PICK ANY RESTAURANT YOU
WANT TO GO TO.
IT'LL BE YOUR SPECIAL DAY.
LISE, ARE YOU OKAY?
>> HOW ABOUT WE GO TO HACKNEY'S
TOMORROW?
>> UH-HUH. YOU GOT A CRAVING FOR
SOME ONION RINGS.
>> YEAH AND I'LL -- I'LL GET THE
BUTTERSCOTCH SUNDAE TO SHARE.
>> YOU KNOW MY WEAKNESS, DON'T
YOU?
>> [ CHUCKLES ]
YEAH, I THINK SO.
>> YOU GET SOME REST, LISE.
LOVE YOU.
>> LOVE YOU TOO, DAD.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
OLIVIA?
OLIVIA, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
OLIVIA.
OLIVIA, WHERE ARE YOU?
I NEED YOU TO BRING ME BACK.
I NEED YOU TO SHOW ME EVERYTHING
THAT YOU --
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA.
COME IN, LISA, PLEASE.
[ STATIC ]
>> ROBBIE?
>> HI, LISA.
EDGAR SAYS YOU NEED TO BE
PUNISHED FOR BEING BAD.
HE SAYS YOU'RE A BUSY BETTY.
[ STATIC ]
>> ROBBIE WHERE ARE YOU?
>> THE SECRET CAVE.
EDGAR'S WITH ME.
WE'RE ON A TREASURE HUNT.
[ STATIC ]
>> WHERE IS THE SECRET...
ROBBIE?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
ROBBIE, ARE YOU IN HERE?
[ WATER SPLASHING ]
[ DOOR CREAKS OPEN ]
ROBBIE?
[ SIGHS ]
[ WATER SPLASHING ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> [ LAUGHING ]
>> ROBBIE?
ROBBIE!
[ BONES CRUNCHING ]
[ GASPS ]
OH!
OH, MY GOD.
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA?
>> ROBBIE.
>> HI, LISA.
>> ROBBIE, WHERE ARE YOU?
YOU TOLD ME YOU WERE IN THE
SECRET CAVE.
>> WE TRICKED YOU.
>> WHAT?!
>> I'M IN THE ATTIC, LISA.
I WAS HIDING FROM YOU THE WHOLE
TIME.
EDGAR SAYS WE'VE WON THE GAME.
[ STATIC ]
>> ROBBIE. ROBBIE?
[ STATIC STOPS ]
DAMN IT!
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> DON'T WORRY.
I'LL WATCH ROBBIE FOR YOU.
>> NO, NO, NO!
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO!
NO, NO!
LET ME OUT OF HERE, YOU
SON OF A BITCH!
SOMEBODY HELP ME, PLEASE!
PLEASE! NO!
[ CLICKING ]
[ PANEL CREAKS ]
[ AIR WHISTLING ]
HELLO?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ CLICKING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GRUNTS ]
HELLO?
OKAY.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ METAL CLANKING IN DISTANCE ]
[ GASPING ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
DAD, IS THAT YOU?
[ CLANKING CONTINUES ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
>> [ GRUNTING ]
[ CLANKING CONTINUES ]
>> HELLO?
>> [ SCREAMS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
DID HE GET YOU, TOO?
WHO ARE YOU?
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HIS
PRISONER?
>> OH, MY GOD.
[ GASPS ]
YOU'RE -- YOU'RE
FRANCES NICHOLS.
YOU WERE THE FIRST GIRL HE
KIDNAPPED.
WHO WAS HE?
>> GET AWAY.
I HAVE TO GET THIS DOOR OPEN
BEFORE HE COMES BACK.
>> NO, PLEASE.
TELL ME WHO HE WAS.
PLEASE TELL ME.
PLEASE.
>> I DON'T KNOW HIS NAME.
I WAS WALKING HOME AFTER THE
MOVIES LAST NIGHT.
HE WAS CLOSING UP HIS STORE AND
ASKED IF I NEEDED A RIDE HOME.
WHEN I CAME CLOSER, HE GRABBED
ME, PUT A CLOTH OVER MY FACE.
I PASSED OUT AND WOKE UP HERE IN
HIS CAR.
I WAS TIED UP IN THE BACK SEAT.
AND THE ENGINE WAS RUNNING.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA SUFFOCATE.
>> BUT -- BUT YOU -- YOU DIDN'T?
>> WELL, I'M TALKING TO YOU,
AREN'T I?
AAH!
>> LOOK, THAT MAN THAT KIDNAPPED
YOU, HE'S THE REASON THAT I'M
HERE, TOO, AND MY FAMILY AND ALL
THE OTHER GIRLS THAT WERE
MISSING.
HE TRAPPED US ALL IN THIS HOUSE.
>> [ GRUNTING ]
>> HE WANTS US TO BE ASLEEP.
THAT'S HOW HE CONTROLS US.
>> QUIET.
[ GRUNTS ]
ARE YOU COMING?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> THERE'S NOTHING OUT THERE.
>> WELL, I'VE GOT TO GET HOME.
MY FAMILY'S WORRIED ABOUT ME.
I'VE BEEN GONE ALL NIGHT.
>> NO, YOU'VE BEEN GONE MUCH
LONGER THAN THAT, FRANCES.
YOUR FAMILY HAS ALREADY GRIEVED
OVER YOU.
THEN, THEY MOVED ON WITH THE
REST OF THEIR LIVES.
>> GRIEVED OVER ME?
YOU'RE WRONG.
THAT CAN'T BE RIGHT.
>> WHEN I TOUCHED THIS, WE
CONNECTED.
>> HOW DID YOU GET MY RING?
>> AFTER HE MURDERED YOU, HE
DUMPED YOUR BODY DOWN BELOW.
AND THEN HE BURNED YOU UP...
JUST LIKE ALL THE OTHER GIRLS.
HE WAS A MONSTER.
AND I AM SO, SO SORRY THAT YOU
HAD TO GO THROUGH THAT, FRANCES.
I REALLY, REALLY AM.
BUT YOU HAVE TO WAKE UP.
WE ALL DO.
>> [ SCREAMING ]
>> FRANCES! NO!
>> [ Echoing ] THIS IS MY HOUSE,
LISA!
>> [ SOBBING ]
>> LISA?
[ CLICK ]
LISA, WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN
HERE?
>> [ GASPS ]
>> YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
UPSTAIRS IN YOUR ROOM, RESTING.
[ CLATTER ]
LISA!
>> I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
>> LISA, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> WHERE IS IT?
>> LISA, STOP IT!
SWEETHEART, TALK TO ME.
LISA.
>> IT HAPPENED TO US IN THE
GARAGE, JUST LIKE FRANCES AND
THE OTHERS.
>> LISA, STOP IT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHO'S FRANCES?
>> [ GASPS ]
[ Whimpering ] OH, MY GOD.
[ GASPS ]
IT WAS DAD.
AND YOU -- YOU LET HIM DO THIS!
>> WHAT ON EARTH ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT?
>> YOU DIDN'T EVEN DO ANYTHING
TO SAVE US!
>> LISA, TALK TO ME.
>> WAKE UP, MOM! WAKE UP!
[ GLASS BREAKS ]
I WON'T LET IT HAPPEN AGAIN.
NEVER AGAIN!
[ SCOFFS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ VIDEO GAME PLAYS ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
>> ROBBIE?
WHERE'S EDGAR?
>> HE LEFT.
>> ROBBIE, YOU DO UNDERSTAND
THAT ME, YOU, AND MOM AND DAD
AREN'T ALIVE ANYMORE -- THIS
ISN'T THE REAL WORLD?
>> MM-HMM.
>> WHEN DID YOU FIGURE THAT OUT?
>> THIS MORNING...
AFTER I FOUND MY GLASSES.
>> YOUR GLASSES?
>> THEY WERE UNDER MY PILLOW.
I DIDN'T WANT TO FIND THEM
BEFORE, 'CAUSE I WAS TOO SCARED.
>> WHY WOULD YOU BE SCARED OF
YOUR GLASSES?
>> 'CAUSE I WAS WEARING THEM
THAT NIGHT -- THE NIGHT WE ALL
DIED.
DON'T WORRY, LISA, IT'S GONNA BE
OKAY.
WE'RE JUST LIKE PAC-MAN.
WE PLAY IN THE SAME MAZE OVER
AND OVER, AND WE CAN NEVER DIE.
WE'RE ALWAYS IN OUR HOUSE, AND
THAT'S JUST HOW IT'S GOT TO BE.
THAT'S WHAT EDGAR TOLD ME.
>> [ GASPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ CLARINET PLAYS
"PETER AND THE WOLF" MUSIC ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ MUSIC RESUMES ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
[ MUSIC RESUMES ]
[ CLARINETS PLAY SAME MUSIC ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ SIGHS ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
HI, LISA.
IF YOU'RE WATCHING THIS, IT
MEANS YOU MADE IT BACK.
OR IT MEANS I'M CRAZY.
EITHER WAY, I HOPE YOU FIND
THIS.
THE ONE THING I DO KNOW IS I'M
SCARED.
THE MAN WHO LIVED HERE BEFORE
YOU WAS NAMED EDGAR MULLINS.
HE WAS BORN IN THIS HOUSE.
HE MURDERED ALL THOSE GIRLS OVER
THE YEARS.
[ SIGHS ]
AND THEN HE DIED HERE IN 1983.
MY DAD -- HE'S CHANGED.
MY MOM'S USELESS -- TOTALLY IN
DENIAL.
NO ONE WILL BELIEVE A WORD I
SAY.
I FOUND THIS IN THE GARAGE LAST
WEEK.
IT'S HOW WE CONNECTED.
IT'S YOURS, ISN'T IT?
IT BELONGED TO YOU BEFORE YOU
DIED.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE WHO
UNDERSTANDS WHAT I'M GOING
THROUGH.
HELP ME, LISA.
[ SIGHS ]
HELP ME SAVE MY FAMILY.
[ CLANGING IN DISTANCE ]
>> [ GASPS ]
>> WHERE ARE THEY?!
>> DAVID.
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING FOR?
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING FOR?!
[ DOOR OPENS ]
>> OKAY, I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
DOING.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
>> OLIVIA?
>> WHERE ARE THEY?
>> I'M SCARED.
>> WHERE DID YOU PUT THEM?!
>> WHAT?!
>> YOU KNOW WHAT I'M TALKING
ABOUT!
>> I DON'T.
[ DRAWER OPENS ]
>> DAVID, STOP PLEASE.
JUST STOP.
>> WHERE DID YOU HIDE THEM?
>> I TOLD YOU, I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
>> RIGHT!
[ CLATTER ]
>> WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
WHY ARE YOU ACTING LIKE THIS?!
[ SIGHS ]
OLIVIA, GO BACK TO YOUR ROOM.
TAKE YOUR SISTER WITH YOU.
OLIVIA, PLEASE.
SWEETHEART.
GO UPSTAIRS.
>> DO AS YOUR MOTHER SAYS,
OLIVIA.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> YOU SHOULDN'T BE DOWN HERE.
>> [ GASPS ] NO, NO.
NOW, LISTEN TO ME.
LISTEN TO ME, OKAY?
YOU NEED TO GET OUT OF THIS
HOUSE.
TAKE YOUR KIDS WITH YOU AND
DON'T EVER, EVER COME BACK HERE
AGAIN.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
HE IS NOT YOUR HUSBAND.
>> SHE'S, UH, CONFUSED.
I THINK SHE WAS SLEEPWALKING
AGAIN.
>> HE IS LYING TO YOU.
HE IS LYING.
HE'S TAKEN OVER OLIVIA'S FATHER.
OH, I MEAN -- GOD, I MEAN MY
FATHER.
>> ANNE...
YOU TAKE CARE OF EMILY.
I AM GOING TO TAKE OLIVIA
UPSTAIRS TO HER ROOM.
>> NO!
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT, OLIVIA.
IT'S ME.
IT'S DAD.
>> NO!
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE ]
[ LAWN MOWER WHIRRING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> HEY! HEY! HELP!
HELP! PLEASE CALL THE POLICE!
HELP!
OH! OH!
[ CRYING ]
[ COUGHING ]
>> SILLY GIRL.
>> [ GASPING ]
>> DON'T YOU KNOW A GHOST CAN
NEVER LEAVE ITS HOUSE?
>> [ CRYING ]
>> LISA.
LISA.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> HONEY, WAKE UP.
IT'S OKAY. Shhhh.
IT'S OKAY. IT'S OKAY.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
YOU'VE BEEN OUT FOR A WHILE -- A
FEW HOURS.
YOU COLLAPSED ON THE FRONT LAWN.
I THOUGHT THAT YOU WERE
SLEEPWALKING AGAIN, BUT [SIGHS]
YOU WEREN'T, WERE YOU?
I MEAN, HOW COULD ANY OF US BE
ASLEEP, SINCE...
WE'RE DEAD?
I KNOW.
I FINALLY KNOW.
I'VE WOKEN UP, TOO.
>> BUT HOW?
>> YOU TOLD ME THAT I DIDN'T TRY
TO SAVE US.
BUT YOU WERE WRONG.
THESE ARE THE CLOTHES THAT HAVE
BEEN MISSING FROM THE LAUNDRY.
I PACKED THEM THAT NIGHT.
THEY'RE YOURS AND MINE AND
ROBBIE'S.
I WAS GONNA SNEAK US OUT OF THE
HOUSE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
NIGHT WHILE YOUR FATHER WAS
ASLEEP...
'CAUSE I WAS AFRAID.
I WAS AFRAID OF WHAT HE MIGHT
DO.
WE NEVER MADE IT OUT OF THE
HOUSE THAT NIGHT, DID WE?
>> [ SIGHS ]
HAVE YOU TALKED TO DAD?
>> NO.
HE'S IN THAT GARAGE AS IF
NOTHING EVER HAPPENED.
>> I'LL GO TALK TO HIM.
>> NO!
>> MOM.
>> NO.
>> MOM, TRUST ME.
IT'S OKAY.
ALL OF US ARE SAFE NOW, AND THE
ONLY THING LEFT FOR US TO DO IS
LEAVE.
DAD IS THE LAST ONE WHO NEEDS TO
UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> YOU TRIED TO TELL ME AGAIN
AND AGAIN.
I'M SO SORRY, SWEETHEART.
>> [ SNIFFLES ]
IT'S OKAY.
I KNOW WHAT TO DO.
[ INDISTINCT SINGING ON RADIO ]
>> OH, HEY, THERE, KIDDO.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
>> WHERE ARE THE SPARK PLUGS,
DAD?
>> WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
>> NO ONE STOLE THEM.
YOU LOST THEM ON PURPOSE.
>> LISA, I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
>> YOU HID THEM FROM YOURSELF.
>> [ SIGHS ]
ALL RIGHT.
WHY WOULD I DO THAT?
>> BECAUSE YOU KNEW WHAT YOU
WERE TURNING INTO.
NOW, WHERE ARE THEY, DAD?
DEEP DOWN, YOU KNOW.
>>  SO THAT'S OUR STORY OF
LOVE
THERE'S NO STORY GREATER THAN
THE ROMANCE OF HEARTS
SOONER OR LATER, WE ALL PLAY
OUR PARTS
OUR STORY OF LOVE HAS YET...
>> TAKE THEM OUT.
>> WHY?
>> [ SINGING INDISTINCTLY ]
>> DO YOU FEEL ANYTHING?
>> NOT A THING.
I TOLD YOU, I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
>> PUT THEM BACK IN THE ENGINE.
>> ALL RIGHT, LISA, I'VE HAD
JUST ABOUT ENOUGH OF THIS
NONSENSE.
>> THE ENGINE.
>> TURN THE KEY.
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
[ ENGINE IDLING ]
DAD?
DO YOU REMEMBER?
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED TO
US?
[ ENGINE SHUTS OFF ]
>> I USED ETHER...
ON YOU...
AND ROBBIE AND YOUR --
AND YOUR MOM.
AND THEN I CARRIED YOU...
DOWNSTAIRS INTO HERE...
FROM YOUR BEDROOMS.
[ BREATHING UNEVENLY ]
AND THEN I...
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> AND THEN YOU DID WHAT?
>> GOD.
OH, GOD.
[ Crying ] YOU AND ROBBIE AND
MOM -- MY WHOLE FAMILY.
[ SOBBING ]
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
>> NO.
IT WASN'T YOU.
>> OF COURSE IT WAS ME!
>> NO, NO, IT WAS SOMEONE ELSE.
HE GOT INSIDE YOU.
HE DID THIS TO US.
>> WHO?
[ GASPS ]
[ GLASS BREAKING ]
>> BRUCE!
BRUCE!
>> [ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON
TELEVISION ]
>> CAROL, I'M SORRY.
I'M SO SORRY.
>> WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> WE'RE AWAKE -- ALL OF US.
[ CLATTER ]
>> MOMMY, WHERE ARE YOU?!
>> I'M RIGHT HERE.
[ GLASS BREAKING ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> WHAT'S GOING ON?
[ RUMBLING ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
>> WE NEED TO GET OUT OF THIS
HOUSE.
[ RUMBLING CONTINUES ]
[ GLASS CONTINUES BREAKING ]
>> MOMMY, THE SUN'S OUT!
>> ROBBIE!
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> CAROL!
CAROL!
ROBBIE!
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT, SWEETHEART.
WE CAN LEAVE.
LISE?
>> I LOVE YOU, DAD.
[ Voice breaking ] I LOVE ALL OF
YOU.
>> LISA!
LISE!
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ STATIC ]
[ CLOCK TICKING LOUDLY ]
[ AIR WHISTLING ]
[ MUSIC PLAYS IN DISTANCE ]
>> [ SINGS INDISTINCTLY ON
RECORD IN DISTANCE ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
>> [ GASPS ]
>> [ As Pale Man ] GET OUT OF MY
HOUSE, LISA.
[ CLOUD TICKING LOUDLY ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ Thinking ] WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING, LITTLE BUTTERFLY?
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> YOU CANNOT HIDE FROM ME IN
THIS HOUSE, AND CERTAINLY NOT IN
MY OWN ROOM.
I DON'T NEED YOUR COMPANY
ANYMORE.
I DON'T NEED YOUR FAMILY'S.
I GOT A NEW ONE TO ADD TO MY
COLLECTION.
[ CLOCK TICKING LOUDLY ]
>> OLIVIA!
OLIVIA, WHERE ARE YOU?
OLIVIA!
OLIVIA, BRING ME BACK!
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ POUNDING ON DOOR ]
>> OLIVIA!
OLIVIA, OPEN THIS DOOR RIGHT
NOW!
OLIVIA!
WHERE ARE YOU, OLIVIA?
>> SILLY GIRL.
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
[ CROWBAR THUDS ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ CLATTER ]
I'M HERE.
I'VE GOT YOUR THINGS, SO LISTEN
TO ME, ALL RIGHT?
WAKE UP.
ALL OF YOU, WAKE UP.
>> WE CAN SEND THIS BASTARD TO
HELL, BUT WE HAVE TO DO IT
TOGETHER.
[ SIGHS ]
FRANCES...PLEASE.
[ Voice breaking ] PLEASE.
HELP ME.
[ GASPING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
>> NO ONE CAN HELP YOU NOW,
LISA.
Shh. JUST GO TO SLEEP.
GO TO SLEEP, NOW.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ LIGHTER CLICKING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ GASPING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ TAPE TEARING ]
[ GASPS ]
>> [ HUMMING ]
>> [ GASPING ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
>> [ CONTINUES HUMMING ]
[ CAR DOOR CLOSES ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ RUSTLING IN BACK SEAT ]
HELLO, LISA.
YOU JUST WON'T LET GO OF OLIVIA,
WILL YOU?
SUCH A PLUCKY GIRL.
YOU KNOW, YOU WERE THE SAME WAY
WHEN YOU WERE ALIVE.
TRYING TO SAVE YOUR FAMILY FROM
ME, TRYING TO FIGHT THE TIDE.
AND YET HERE WE ARE, THE TWO OF
US, AND IT ENDS THE SAME.
[ KEYS RATTLING ]
HISTORY DOESN'T REPEAT ITSELF.
IT RHYMES.
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
TIME FOR YOU TO GO, LISA.
>>  THE STORY OF LOVE
IS A STORY OF SIGHS
>> [ HUMMING ]
>>  OF SWEETHEARTS THAT LEAVE
US WITH STARS IN THEIR EYES
THE STORY OF LOVE GOES ON
THROUGH THE YEARS
WITH HEARTACHES AND HEARTBREAK
AND LAUGHTER AND TEARS
THERE'S NO GLORY GREATER
THAN THE ROMANCE THAT'S OURS
[ ENGINE SHUTS OFF ]
>> [ MOANING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ KEYS THUD ]
>> GO AHEAD, STEP ACROSS.
YOUR HOME IS GONE.
YOUR TIME IS GONE.
THERE'S NOTHING LEFT FOR YOU BUT
OBLIVION -- A PLACE WORSE THAN
DEATH.
>> I DON'T CARE.
YOU CAN SEND ME WHEREVER THE
HELL YOU WANT, BUT YOU'RE NOT
KILLING THIS FAMILY TONIGHT.
YOU CAN'T GET THE KEYS, SO YOU
CAN'T START THE CAR.
>> [ LAUGHING ]
OLIVIA'S FATHER LEAVES THE SPARE
ON THE WORKBENCH.
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ SCREAMING ]
NO! NO!
>> I ALWAYS DO ENJOY KILLING
YOU.
>> [ SCREAMS ]
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
>> [ SHRIEKS ]
>> GOODBYE, EDGAR.
>> AAAAAAH!
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
AAAAAAH!
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
>> [ GASPS ]
OLIVIA?
WHAT HAPPENED?
I'M SO SORRY, OLIVIA.
>> IT'S OKAY, DAD.
WE'RE GONNA BE A HAPPY FAMILY
AGAIN.
>> [ SIGHS ]
HAVE A GOOD LIFE, OLIVIA.
[ SIGHS ]
[ STATIC ]
>> LISA JOHNSON.
LISA, WAKE UP.
LISA, I FOUND THE PIRATE
TREASURE.
WE'RE GONNA BE RICH.
COME DOWNSTAIRS SO I CAN GIVE
YOU YOUR SHARE.
HURRY.
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> IT'S YOUR BIRTHDAY PRESENT.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, LISA.
[ STATIC ]
[ STATIC STOPS ]
>> HAPPY 16, SWEETHEART.
>> DAD?
MOM?
WHERE ARE WE?
>> WE'RE HOME, HONEY.
WE'RE FINALLY HOME.
>> [ GASPS ]
>> WANT TO TAKE IT FOR A SPIN?
>> WILL YOU COME BACK FOR SOME
CAKE AND PIRATE TREASURE, LISA?
>> [ GASPING ]
[ SNIFFLES ]
WHAT'S OUT THERE?
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> WHATEVER YOU WANT THERE TO
BE.
>> [ GASPS ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ SOBBING ]
[ SNIFFLES ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
>> Lisa.
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
>>  OH, OH
OH, OH
OH
DOWN WHERE THIS UGLY MAN
SEEKS HIS SUSTENANCE
DOWN IN THE BLUE, MIDNIGHT
FLARE
A GLASS HAND CUTS THROUGH
THE WATER
SCYTHING INTO HIS TWISTED
ROOTS
THEN FROM HIS EYES
SPRING FIREFLIES
BREATHING LIFE
INTO A ROARING DISGUISE
NEEDLES AND SINS,
SINS AND NEEDLES
HE'S GASPING FOR AIR
IN THE WISHING WELL
DUST TO RUST,
ASHES ON GASHES
>>  OH, OH
>>  HAND AROUND
THE KILLING JAR
HAND AROUND
[ INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ SOFT, EERIE MUSIC PLAYS ]