TOHO COMPANY, LTD.
PRODUCTION: TOHO EIZO COMPANY, LTD.
IN COOPERATION WITH P.S.C.
HAUSU
It is hot, push the button already!
Okay!
What refreshing air!
Thanks!
Soon it's summer holidays!
You're going with your father to your summer house...
And you're going with everyone else to summercamp, Fanta!
I want you to come with me!
I'll be bored!
Nevertheless you'll be by the
side of your beloved Mr. Togo!
That was mean!
And you're supposed to be my friend!
Are we going to class!
- Yes.
Tell me, Fanta...
Why did you think me
so strange before?
Because you looked like a
witch from a horror movie.
You really did!
Fanta, you Fancy! - That's mean!
You don't get a copy of the photo!
So, did the photos turn out okay?
- Mrs. Teacher!
Soon it's holidays.
- I'll go with father to Karuizawa!
Really? Are things good for him? - Yes!
Tomorrow he's back from Italy.
Good for you!
And you?
I'm going with Mr. Togo
to his sister.
Ah, how nice.
- Congratulations! - What?
You're getting married!
- How do you know that?
From Mr. Togo.
So, what is he like?
I'm sure he loves you more than anything!
It's definitely the big love!
It is an arranged marriage.
Off into the class!
Yes!
How nice...
Holidays!
Wait for me, Fanta!
I'll give you the copies!
- Great! - Promise!
Hey, wait!
- Hello!
Hello!
Bye-bye.
- Cheerio.
Oshare!
Bye-bye!
Daddy!
Welcome back!
- Welcome!
I thought you weren't coming 'til tomorrow!
How's your work on the movie music going?
Leone said it's even better
than Morricone's! - Really?
You have grown again.
You too, daddy! - Hey!
- Do i get a souvenir?
Sit down a while, please.
What's up?
- Hm...
Now...
In one week the holidays start.
- Yes.
Dad!
Don't tell me, we can't
go to Karuizawa!
But of course we're going!
Of course we are.
What is it then?
Someone's coming with us.
Who? A man? A woman?
Please come out, my precious.
Oshare, is it?
Let me look at you!
Pleased.
She's coming with us?
- Yes.
This is Ryoko Ema.
She is gorgeous!
Many thanks! And you are very pretty
when you smile!
Be nice to me, ok?
Please be nice to her.
Then she will be your new mother.
My new mother?
Now, I've wanted to tell you
for a long time, but...
She designs jewelry.
Even so she's also a good cook,
she makes everything!
You must not sew on
any more buttons now.
And the sleeves?
How mean of you,
to say "even so"!
Why, there he is, good day!
Please listen to me.
It's been eight years
since your mother died.
We should start to slowly bring
happiness back in our lives.
I won't in any case
go with you to Karuizawa!
Hey!
Wait!
Mummy, i'm here again!
Mummy, daddy can't do that, can he?
When I finished first at the
sportfest, daddy cried.
I want to hurt you, dad.
Because i hate you.
There we are, all three of us.
Mother in her silk dress...
Mummy...
How are you, auntie?
Let's sit!
- Yes!
How nice! Holidays by the sea,
the six of us, all together!
But Oshare's going to Karuizawa.
I wish she would come with us!
But Fanta! You will get to spend
ten days with Mr. Togo.
Oh yes, Melody! He is so cool
and very good-looking!
You consider him manly?
Wow, Kung Fu, that was cool!
You are a lot manlier!
Keisuke Togo. The name itself is cool.
Isn't it, Gari?
Listen up. Fanta is a
dreamer, and that's just fine!
I am sorry, Fanta.
- Never mind, Sweet!
Mr. Togo is quite pretty, really.
Do you think his sister, who
leads the camp, is a good cook?
Do you want to get even fatter?
- Mean! I'll hit you!
Stop it! We'll all peacefully
train our bodies there!
Well said!
That's the spirit!
Oh, Oshare! - Good morning!
- Is your daddy back?
Oshares dad is the greatest!
Movie composer, rich and...
Shut up.
I hoot at this daddy.
Hi! Good morning!
Teacher!
- We're in a fix!
My sister's baby
is coming too soon!
But teacher!
- And because of that
she can't bring any guests
this summer.
I'm sorry.
Does that mean our camp is called off?
- What? - yes.
How mean!
- Be a man!
Yes! Take responsibility!
- Don't be so mean to him!
She's right!
- Typically Fanta!
Don't be so mean!
Look, those are mean flowers.
- What?
Calm down all.
- What is it?
Are you coming with me?
- Where?
To Karuizawa? - With your father?
- No, to my mother's parents' house.
To my aunt.
And so I simply invited them
to come along to you, auntie.
I'm sorry that i write this letter,
even though we hardly know each other.
Please don't think anything bad of me.
I'm close to tears at the moment.
I want to go back to mother's home districts.
And to let you comfort me
in mummy's place.
Therefore...
Please let us come.
Oh, aren't you cute!
Where did you come from?
Oshare! Oshare! Oshare!
Bye-bye!
Hello!
KOGARASHI
What have you got, Snowflake? Come here.
You are welcome, Oshare!
I have waited so long
for a letter from you.
Please come to me!
Oshare, come to me. Come to me.
And you had to take extra time off.
I'm sorry.
It's ok.
Let's go, just the two of us.
Yes, let's.
I have really spoiled her
too much.
Precious...
I have an idea!
- An idea?
I'll go after her,
to her mother's home districts.
I want to speak to you alone.
No hard feelings.
This is my first test
as a mother.
I'll be sure to bring it back.
Your gorgeous...
secretive smile.
Ryoko... i'm relying on you.
And I will think it all over
thoroughly one more time myself.
There, in the country.
Auntie...
Good morning!
It's a good morning!
The bucket is stuck!
Ah, it's already eight!
- Oshare and Mr Togo are late!
Hello? Mr Togo? What's happened?
Fanta's crying!
- We'll miss the train!
The injury is not bad.
But I have to see the doctor first!
What? Only one bus a day?
Then I'll follow you with the buggy!
Mr. Togo will follow
us with the buggy!
But where is Oshare?
- She's probably waiting on the platform.
Bye-bye!
- Have fun!
Oshare!
- Oshare isn't here!
Sure, she is here. - But Kung Fu...
- Maybe she's already on the train?
There she is!
Oh, Oshare!
You're late!
We were worried!
I'm sorry. But Snowflake
had suddenly disappeared!
Snowflake?
- Come already, Mac!
Wait, wait!
Chocolate, candy, biscuits,
love and dreams.
Here, here are our places.
- There? - Here.
Snowflake!
So there you are!
That is Snowflake.
- Isn't he cute!
The train leaves the city
with a white dream on board.
It accelerates,
and in the landscape...
What a beautiful rainbow!
- It's only ten!
And smile! Okay!
You always have an enormous appetite, Mac!
- A good indication!
They don't know the agonies of an
empty stomach! Right, Snowflake?
Did you know that?
Old cats can open doors.
But only ghost cats
can close them again.
What is this place anyway?
- What kind of person is your aunt?
My mother and my aunt
were very close.
When I was six, my mother brought
me along to her family once.
Since then I haven't seen
my aunt.
IN 1941 THE WAR WAS RAVING...
In Japan prevailed
The Great War. Ah, that's her house!
My late grandfather was a doctor.
That's my grandmother.
And that is mummy! Pretty, isn't she?
- Her hair resembles yours!
My aunt and her fiance.
- Ah, a cat!
Wow! - He was to take over the practice
after the wedding.
You say "was".
Didn't they marry?
No. The war is to blame. - Tasty!
THE NEXT YEAR
You only think about food!
The draft...
What are they doing?
A promise...
SURELY I'LL COME BACK!
I'LL WAIT.
- How long?
Forever, she means!
How romantic!
- Kiss of Fire!
The men were so masculine in those days!
- Indeed!
But Kung Fu is still cooler!
Why didn't she go along?
With knobs on.
- Right.
It hit him!
He was hit!
AFTER THE WAR...
The soldiers returned after the war
OH NO!
but not my aunts fiance.
She's still waiting for him.
- Ah, how romantic!
How sad.
5 YEARS LATER: PEACE RULES ONCE MORE
That is mum's wedding.
All in white, how beautiful!
I will also marry in white!
Do you think you will marry?
- Of course!
How beautiful!
- There she is!
I wonder how auntie is doing?
When my grandmother died,
my aunt stayed all alone
in this enormous house.
She teaches the piano to the girls
in the neighbourhood.
Piano, you say?
Ah, here it is!
SATOYAMA
Where are you going? - I don't know...
- I'm going that way.
Later!
- Later!
Which way?
That way! - Yes, it's probably that way!
- Let's go!
You show us the way, ok?
MELODY
- Fast!
FANTA
- Okay!
GARI
- "So green was my valley!"
SWEET
- I'm afraid!
KUNG FU
- Always cheerful!
MAC
- Appetite: Unbeatable!
OSHARE
- Oshare!
Terrible, isn't it?
It's as if a ghost could appear anytime!
- No way! Ghosts don't exist anyway.
Sweet, you chicken! Leave the ghosts
to me! - Mmh, tasty!
Hello!
A wonderful landscape!
- It's as if we were in another world!
Fanta, don't say those things!
- What about the things you say!
We're lucky! We'll ask for
the way here! - Hello! Good day!
Good day! - Hello!
- Looks tasty! I want those!
No, don't, Mac!
- Ah, help! - What is it?
Just come! Just come, girls!
Ah... where to?
To the manor!
- My auntie lives there.
You...
You are the niece of the lady of the house,
correct?
You look a lot like her,
especially around the eyes!
There it is, the "Hausu".
That?
Let's go!
- Yes! Many thanks!
They don't make them like that
anymore.
The miss has made her decision...
extrordinarily delighted.
Ah, there it is!
Oh, for real!
- Wow, look at that!
A madhouse!
How big it is!
- An amazing house!
Really amazing, isn't it, Melody?
- Yes! - Wow...
What the..?
Hello, good day!
- Hello!
A telegram!
- A patient, doctor!
Sesam, open up!
- But, but, Kung Fu!
Oshare, you vain thing!
Fashion puppy!
Snowflake?
Welcome.
Auntie!
Ah, you're pretty, all seven of you!
Good day!
You have grown!
Your hair looks like your mother's!
How long has it been since we saw each other?
Since grannies funeral...
That's about ten years!
What? So long?
That's a long time ago...
I have waited for you
all this time.
Please forgive me, auntie.
I heard that you teach piano?
- Yes, i did before.
But now i'm alone.
What has happened to your legs?
Don't worry about it. Now,
that you're here, all is fine.
Stop! A photo! - You must also come,
auntie! - So, come.
Okay, Cheese!
Butter! - Margarine!
- Marmelade! - Sexy!
Oh no, how bad!
Oh please,
don't make such a sad face.
When i'm so happy
that you're visiting!
So, please smile again, yes?
Look here!
Oh, that's beautiful!
- A present for you! Tasty, isn't it?
Mac! Could it be... ...that you
simply took it? - Glutton!
I have paid for it!
It's hair looks like yours, Mac!
So, please come in, everybody.
It is so cool! Very refreshing!
- Melody, stop! - What?
The shoes! - Are you taking something off?
- Ah, again typically Melody!
So, dear chandelier,
be so kind and illuminate? us!
...you must not!
Tada!
- Oh!
Great! Kung Fu, you're awesome!
Do you like to play the piano?
- Yes, a lot.
In that room over there
stands a large wing.
Feel free to play it.
- I'd love to!
A cat that eats geckos.
Strange. - I will clean the house!
Das schafft nicht mal
ein Putzteufel wie du. It is too big!
We'll help you.
- Thank you, it's kind of you.
Ah, Melody's playing!
Your wing, auntie!
Ah, a parlour!
Was this the conversation room?
The Music Room!
Melody!
That is auntie's bedroom!
It's beautiful! - Yes!
- It's full of cat pictures!
Miau, miau!
What is that?
Ah, it's just
a skeleton from visual instruction!
This room was the conversation room
for Oshares grandfather.
Please don't scare us like that!
I have made it into a piano
practice room.
?Yes, that's been here a long time...
Back then there were a lot of rich people
here in the village.
Later on I even had pupils
from the city! I was very well liked.
Auntie...
- Yes?
Doesn't anyone come here for
lessons anymore? - No.
Ah, after this fright
I've become very hungry!
I really have to eat something!
- Mac!
That's ok!
But the problem is...
I'm afraid i can't
do any kitchen work.
No problem!
We'll all do it together!
Ah, then I am thankful!
You have been so lonely, auntie!
Yes, I was really lonely.
But because of that a lot of young girls
visit me now!
Lucky you!
We'll distribute the tasks!
Already done!
- That's right! I'll do the cooking.
And i will clean up! Is there a
broom around? - Yes, in there.
Where is the kitchen? We have to
cool down the melons! - I'll show you.
I want to come along.
- Of course!
A big clock...
I wonder where it is?
Mac, here it is!
- Yes!
Wow! What a kitchen!
- Isn't it?
Dear furnace, the girls
will want to warm you now!
What's a furnace?
- A stove.
What is a stove?
A stove is a stove!
I was alone all this time.
Therefore i've started
to entertain myself with all of you.
Ok then... Dear fridge,
may I cool down my melons?
He's not well. What about
the natural fridge?
The well?
- How cool!
It is outside, come!
It is decided.
I am the boss,
until Mr. Togo arrives. - Done!
I'll be in the kitchen a minute! - Don't
break any plates with your karate!
I won't!
Kung Fu, help!
Step aside for a minute.
Wow!
What have you got there?
- It's just a mouse!
How cute!
- Ah, you've got one there too.
I still remember this well
very clearly.
The water will cool down
the melons. - Mmh, tasty!
Hold the second half!
Okay, one...
...two, three!
What if we can't
reach them anymore?
No problems, Mac. In the old days we
always did it like this. - Oh!
What a strange nickname!
She eats a lot, so we call her
Mac, from the english "stomach"!
Oshare, you tattletale!
Mac, you're so pretty chubby,
real tasty! - That is not nice,
Auntie! Soon I'll starve to death
if I don't get supper!
It was just a joke!
Come, let's make supper!
I'll heat up water for the bath!
- You are full of energy.
Auntie!
- What?
Why are you wearing glasses outside?
I'm afraid of the
strong sunshine.
The fur looks just the same!
Perhaps she came from the picture?
- Pooh! - Fanta, you Fancy!
Not so loud!
Think about auntie!
No worries.
She feels uneasy because of the sun.
But she isn't eating anything!
Surely she's hungry!
One, two...
...three!
- ?Mac, are you going to the bathroom? - No.
The melons? I'm coming!
- Pooh!
Mac!
Ah, thanks!
She is all tousled!
Without glasses you are really
pretty, Gari! - Really?
But
without glasses i can't see!
My condolences!
Let's clear this up fast!
- Yes, then we'll play! - Hide-and-seek!
Mac needs a long time though!
She didn't go until the evening though.
- But...
The well is really close!
- If you worry, go look for her!
She really goes through a lot
of trouble for everyone.
Mac!
Ah, how beautiful!
Where can she be?
Ah, She hasn't taken them out yet.
It really is beautiful!
Fanta...
No! No! No!
- Mmh... tasty!
What's happened? You okay?
- You're completely dirty!
"Love in the mud"?
- Get yourself together! What is the matter?
What has happened?
- Auntie!
She didn't feel well!
- You're making such noise...
The head, the head...
The head, the cut off head!
- Fountainhead, cauliflower head, lettuce head?
The cut off head?
I... i...
In the well! In the well!
I will go check.
You can walk? - When you
are here, I feel better.
Just leave it to me.
Let's go!
- It happened by the well.
Fanta, are you ok? Get yourself together.
All is fine. You poor thing...
So that's it!
- Such rubbish!
Here's your cut off head!
It is cooled down good!
Fanta pulled all of our legs!
Fanta! Do you still think
those strange things?
Stop it now.
I'm going cleaning.
On the way though was a
sweet potato field. Mac is probably there.
She really likes
roasted sweet potatoes.
Maybe she's playing hide-and-seek?
She's really impossible.
I'll go look for her.
Leave some of the melons!
- A big piece for Mac! - Okay!
Say, Fanta...
I'm all sweaty.
Will you come with me to the bath?
You can't go to the
bath before all the others!
It's ok, auntie!
After all, she's our sponsor!
I'm sorry that i bath before you.
- Is ok. I like to clean.
Oh yes!
- What?
Where are the bed sheets?
- There!
Where do you think Mac went?
Don't worry, she'll be back soon.
She hasn't eaten the melons yet.
Ah, i'm thirsty!
Wherever do you think Mac is?
Oh! Did you open the door?
Where could the sheets be?
Sweet!
...eet! ...eet!
It's nice here in the country.
Is the water warm enough?
Yes, thanks!
But I have to wash my hair.
Could you heat up some more?
Of course, Oshare-sugarpuppy!
So, let's begin!
An illusion?
The cicadas are really loud!
Where did Mac go to?
That can't be!
Must have been my imagination.
Sweet?
Aren't you in a good mood!
When i was little, we once went
out to eat with the whole family.
I feel like
I did on that evening!
Fanta, you don't have
to worry.
You'll soon see Mac again.
Excuse me!
- Okay.
What was that?
Oh no, another one!
Auntie
has climbed into the refridgerator!
That's rubbish!
See?
I was so lonely.
That melody...
Melody!
Melody! Melody...
You are welcome, Oshare!
I have waited so long
for a letter
from you.
Please come to me! Oshare,
come to me!
Come to me!
Auntie!
Oh, Snowflake!
Old cats can open doors.
But only ghost cats
can close them again.
No, it can't be!
Melody?
That was Melody!
Quick, let's go!
To the piano room!
That was Sweet!
Sweet!
And away flies the pain!
You have an odd fingerprint!
Why do you make such noise
over this little scratch? - I'm sorry.
But i thought
the wing would bite me.
What? The wing?
You sound like Fanta!
- She does! - Help!
How awful!
- Again!
Sweet is with the bed sheets...
She's sleeping?
- No! Come quickly!
We'll have a look.
Where?
- There!
Sweet!
What's going on here?
- Everything's in a mess!
Sweet?
- Sweet!
Sweet...
- Fanta!
Melody!
- What is it now?
Quickly, go to her!
- No! I don't want to go all alone!
Go now!
Melody?
Fanta!
Do you have a sheet of paper?
Oh, here is Sweets apron!
- And her bra!
What is that?
Has she stripped here
all alone?
Sounds fun. What are you doing?
She can't have simply
disappeared, or?
Snowflake! What are you doing here?
The doll is also naked!
Here are her panties!
They stink!
- Indeed!
I saw it!
The mattresses and sheets
threw themselves at her!
That's crazy talk. - She's
surely in bath washing herself!
I'll go look for her there.
Listen to me,
Mac hasn't come back yet.
All of us are probably going
to disappear. What are we going to do?
Don't worry, Fanta. Your beloved
teacher will be here soon.
He's a man.
You can rely on him!
Perhaps he is your
knight on a white horse!
Oh my lovely Princess Fanta!
OH, PRINCESS FANTA!
Help me, help me!
HELP, MR. TEACHER!
My lovely teacher!
I LOVE YOU!
I helped you! I love you!
The And! No, that's wrong: The End!
Really? That is strange!
- Yet I said it!
Just a moment!
Oshare went to the bath!
That's right! She's not here anymore either!
Maybe she needs the time to
make herself beautiful, as always!
Then she's probably
upstairs. Let's go see!
Come, let's go!
Up here!
She's always putting make-up on for hours!
- She's probably upstairs!
How funny!
Oshare!
- Oshare!
Weird, she's not here either!
- Is everyone hiding?
Oshare!
What the..? Has she also undressed?
What the?
- Oshare?
Got you!
Oshare!
- O gosh, i nearly died!
No wonder, that Fanta
almost died from fear!
Mr. Togo will be here soon.
We'll have to hold out 'til then!
Mr. Togo?
- Yes, with his old jaloppy!
There she goes, as if he
was an airplane pilot!
Airplane!
Oh, nothing, nothing.
Don't worry! If we call the police
in the village, they'll be here shortly!
Where's the phone book?
Wait. I'll call them.
Help, please help me!
I beg you!
Hello?
Help!
- Please, come here!
What's up?
It doesn't work.
It's probably broken.
Where are you going?
- To the police station.
I'll get a policeman to investigate
all this. - You're leaving us here?
In this uncanny house?
Don't fear.
Auntie is still here.
I'll be back soon.
Take me with you!
- We'll go with you.
Don't take a step outside the house,
'til i come back.
Oshare, take me with you!
It won't open! It won't
open! - What shall we do?
Follow me!
Oh no!
- It's closing!
Let me carry noble silk
and go with you to the dance.
My ears are filled
with the sound of singing,
my silver shoes tremble...
Hey, idiot!
Be so kind and go play with your
toy car somewhere else!
I'm sorry!
But there's a jam ahead!
I'm really sorry!
I know that!
I'm afraid!
It's like in a horror flick!
- A really old one.
Step aside.
- Ah, a Karate flick!
Stop that, it's not doing any good.
- Why?
Surely there's a mechanism.
A mechanism?
Auntie lives alone.
So she's set it up so that the doors
close automatically during night.
Do you think she can do that?
- Sure of it. It must be.
I heard a while ago that
she studied music in Tokyo.
So she's educated.
- Educated...
That's it!
- What? - What?
We simply ask her, how to
open the door! - Exactly!
Auntie?
Auntie!
- Auntie?
A human hand!
- What does that mean?
That's Mac's tie!
Could it possibly be...
What do you mean by that?
Oh, nothing, it's nothing.
Melody, give us courage, play something!
No!
I'm afraid!
- Please!
Yes, that's a good idea! - That b
to the g simply strengthens me!
Shouldn't Oshare slowly
be coming back?
Somehow everything happens
as in your fantasy, Fanta.
But... simply too many
unnatural things happen here.
But say, Gari,
what were you thinking a while ago?
Can't tell.
Why?
I'm not sure yet. And Fanta
would faint from fear.
Why?
- No.
That's Oshares voice!
It is! When did she come back?
Oshare!
- Shall we look for her?
Let's!
No! I'm staying here. Okay, Melody?
Shall we go?
- Yes.
Oshare!
Melody, turn around! Melody!
What the? They're gone.
Oh, how indecent!
"Desert, idle days".
Oshare!
Give me the lamp.
That is unscientific. Absurd!
Unnatural and unpleasant!
Strange.
Great! Kung Fu, you're awesome!
Sweet!
Forgive me!
Kung Fu!
It can't be!
I don't believe my eyes!
Is something like that even possible?
What are we going to do now?
Look there, legs out of the room!
Fanta!
Melody!
Fanta! Wake up!
Fanta!
Wake up! Fanta!
Wake up! Wake up!
Don't be like that!
Here, drink that!
Melody! Melody!
You were right!
This house is an angry ghost!
What is that? Goldfish! - Fanta!
Oshare herself is now a ghost!
It can't be! No!
You don't have to believe it. But
the three of us must stick together!
That's right. To survive.
Yes.
These noodles are class!
Many thanks! Here you are!
Ah, there they are!
Thanks, that was delicious!
Excuse me.
Perhaps we'll see each other
again sometime!
Live well!
Mr.?
- That's good as hell!
Fast! That way we can protect
ourselves a little!
"In the village lives no longer
any single young women.
I am all alone."
"But i will always remain
in this house, waiting.
He is surely not dead.
Surely he will be back.
He did promise me."
Strange!
- Fanta!
Oshare? What's happened?
I...
I'm now in auntie's world.
- Auntie's world?
Lips! - Too big! - Auntie
has already been dead for many years.
Many years? And who was
the woman we met today?
She's longing to marry,
and thus lives on after her death.
And when unmarried girls
come here,
she eats them up.
Only then can she
carry her bridal gown.
And now it's your turn.
Nice meal.
We're all going to die!
Away, begone!
Oshare, help us!
We're friends, after all!
Impossible!
Oshare is no longer herself!
Oshare!
- Fight!
Dear God, protect us!
What's that? What's that?
I can't allow that!
- Are you going to leave us?
The telephone!
- I'm afraid!
She said before,
it's broken!
- That was a lie! - Wait!
Trust me!
No! No!
I get no air!
Oshare! Miserable ghost! Come here!
Why, here's no house
to be found!
"I will remain here waiting,
with Snowflake in my arms.
In this house."
Snowflake! Snowflake!
Kung Fu!
We have to kill Snowflake!
Everybody okay?
- Kung Fu, hold out!
Mac!
Sweet!
Melody!
Kung Fu!
She made it!
The diary!
"Surely he will be back.
He did promise me."
Promise...
"I will wait!"
Gari!
The cat's blood!
"With Snowflake..."
"In this house..."
Mr. Togo! - Who knows, if he'll come.
- He promised!
Did not!
- Did so!
He promised me! - But not auntie!
Not the house!
Not the house.
I'm lucky! Where is it?
The girls were...
eaten.
Eaten!
Tasty!
Do you like melons?
- I hate them!
What do you like?
- Bananas!
Bananas! Bananas!
Nanaba, Nanaba, Nanaba...
"Got a letter from Oshare. Finally
girls are coming here again!
Snowflake fetched it."
Snowflake? Snowflake!
I can't see! My glasses!
Gari!
Gari! Gari!
Don't leave me!
Snowflake!
Oshare! Oshare!
It's all made up, isn't it?
That you're an angry ghost...
Thank God! Thank God!
Oshare!
Fanta!
It isn't true, is it?
I'm so tired.
Mum...
With one gaze
you have bewitched me,
in this room,
in which one can see the flush of dawn.
The butterflies,
which from the darkness
into the flowery garden dances,
will soon be here.
Don't you want from this day on
to stay in my house as my wife?
Let us live together in intimate
togetherness!
Pardon, is anyone at home?
Without love
the morning never comes.
Pardon!
Is anyone at home?
Pardon, is anyone at home?
When my hand
touches your body,
the little birds
fall asleep.
My heart's pendulum...
swings alone...
Good morning.
Will you reject
my love?
Oshare!
Don't you want from this day on
to stay in my house as my wife?
Let us live together in intimate
togetherness!
Come.
I'd love to, many thanks.
I'm very happy,
that you come to visit.
How are your friends?
Asleep already?
Now...
They'll soon wake up.
They're all hungry.
One always wakes up,
if one has hunger.
Even when the body decays,
you may always live on
in the heart of another
together with the love
of that person.
Therefore the story of love
must always be retold.
So that the one you love
can live on forever.
Live forever,
the feelings of the beloved,
which never fades,
only one promise...
That is love.
ACTORS:
Kimiko IKEGAMI
Miki JINBO, Oba KUMIKO
Ai MATSUBARA
Mieko SATO
Eriko TANAKA, Masayo MIYAKO
WRITTEN BY: Chiho KATSURA
CAMERA: Yoshitaka SAKAMOTO
MUSIC:
Asei KOBAYASHI, Micky YOSHINO
DIRECTOR: Nobuhiko OBAYASHI