[Suspenseful music plays]
[Clicks]
Woman:
[Laughing] No. No.
Stop, stop.
[Laughing]
Cut it out. Oh!
[Squeals]
[Laughing] Don't.
What's the matter?
Uh, nothing.
I just haven't seen you laugh
like this in a long time.
No, it's, uh... it's nice.
I miss it.
I miss it, too.
We're gonna work this out,
right?
Yeah. Yeah.
[Smooches]
Trevor...
I hope it's everything
you want it to be.
It will be.
- [Smooching]
- [Giggling]
- Oh, shit!
- Aaah!
[Horn blaring,
tires screeching]
Aah!
Ohh!
It's not... it's stuck.
- Calm down. Relax.
- I can't.
[Gasping] I...
Trevor, I...
Trevor...
[Glass breaking]
[Hissing, rumbling]
[Birds chirping]
[Muffled scream]
[Gurgling]
Help me! Somebody!
[Creaking]
No!
[Monitor beeping]
It's nice to see you
again.
It's okay, Trevor.
You're safe now.
Where's Kirsty?
Where's my wife?
This should help you relax.
- [Groans]
-  Just relax.
Okay?
Trevor?
[Echoing] Trevor!
Trevor...
Wake up, Trevor.
[Gasps]
[Creaking]
[Rattling]
[Breathing heavily]
[Whirring]
[Tapping]
[Whirring continues]
[Crackling, rumbling]
[Whirring slows, stops]
It's imperative
that you stay calm.
As you can see,
the thinnest layer of cortex
separates the part of the brain
that feels pleasure
from the part of the brain
that feels pain.
Over the course
of this... procedure,
I will be triggering
memories,
disrupting the unconscious,
so our patient may experience
some... distress.
What are you people
doing to me?
Now, just relax, Trevor.
We're helping you.
Helping you... remember.
[Groans]
[Crackling]
[Groaning]
[Gasps]
[Monitor beeping]
Welcome back.
How are those headaches?
Any change
in the intensity?
[Groans]
Man, what happened?
My name is Allison.
You a dream, too,
Allison?
Still hallucinating,
huh?
I don't know.
Was I before?
I mean, it...
it looked like a dream,
but it just felt so...
Real?
Yeah.
It's probably
the morphine, Trevor.
We're still gonna have to
run a few more tests
to see if we can pinpoint
what's causing your headaches.
With the kind of head trauma
you've suffered,
you're lucky to be here
at all.
I'm gonna see you
through this.
I'm gonna take your word
on it.
Hello, Trevor.
Back again, huh?
What seems to be the trouble
this time?
He came in through Emergency,
complaining of headaches,
blackouts, hallucinations,
acute memory loss.
I recommend that we admit him
until we run the rest of the tests.
Well, I don't see
any abnormalities.
Time to wean you off
those painkillers, though.
Wouldn't want you
getting hooked,
start coming to the hospital for
the sole purpose of getting a fix.
We can't have that.
I'm gonna release you,
save this bed
for someone who needs it.
Hey, doc...
Where's Kirsty?
Where's my wife?
Man: That's what
I'd like to know.
I knocked.
What do you mean
she's missing?
Oh, it's not like we're gonna
stop looking, Mr. Gooden.
I don't give up that easy.
Well, what if I took you
back there, you know,
and walked you through it?
We've done that already...
over a month ago.
What?
You sure
you're okay to drive?
Look, obviously,
I caught you at a bad time.
Go home, get some rest.
You look like
hell warmed over.
Thanks.
Oh, one more thing.
You said you tried to pull
her out of the passenger side,
but the door was locked,
right?
Yeah.
Well, that's strange,
because the report says...
the doors were open
when the car was pulled
from the river.
I'm...
Maybe she unlocked them...
you know, swam out.
Maybe.
I'll double-check.
Could be their bad.
[Sighing] Anyway...
Gotta run.
We'll talk soon.
Sure I can't give you
a lift?
Suit yourself.
[Hydraulic hiss]
[Heavy-metal music
playing loudly]
[Music continues]
Hey, you mind
turning that down?
Well, I, um...
Music... D-Do you mind
turning that down?
[Music plays louder]
[Brakes squeal]
[Hydraulic hiss]
[Heavy-metal music
continues]
[Hydraulic hiss]
[Barking]
[Chain rattles]
[Barking continues
in distance]
[Keys jingle]
Kirsty: Why don't you come
to bed?
Trevor: Okay.
[Laughs]
[Sighs]
Hey,
turn off the light.
[Smooching]
[Exhales]
I love you.
I love you, too.
[ Jingles]
[Birds chirping]
Man:
[Echoing] Marion...
That's him.
You should look,
Marion.
Well, well, well.
Look who decided
to show up today.
Hey.
Bankers' hours
must be nice, huh?
Hey, um, what happened
to you yesterday?
Boss came by looking for you
after you left.
Hey, I got a...
You got a piece of ass,
didn't you?
That's why you didn't
come back from lunch.
Secret's safe with me,
pal.
We'll call it a, uh,
personal day, okay?
Right.
Look, um, forget
I said anything, okay?
Just get some numbers going.
Any numbers at all will do.
Hills have eyes, remember?
[Whirring]
[Beeps]
We're all here for you, Trev.
[Clicks tongue]
[Sighs]
[Telephone ringing
in distance]
[Sighs]
[Seagulls crying]
[Air horn blows]
[Vehicle approaches]
[Telephone ringing
in distance]
[Air hissing]
[Flies buzzing]
[Water dripping slowly]
[Sewing machines whirring]
[Flies buzzing]
[Dripping continues]
I can see
into your soul.
Hey...
65% of all headaches are due
to low blood-sugar levels, Trev.
Yeah.
Grab yourself a cookie.
[Sighs]
[Coin rattles]
[Whirs]
[Thud]
Come on.
[Electricity buzzes]
Oh, now what?
- Aah!
See anything you like?
Well, do you?
[Snapping fingers]
Come on, speak up.
I'm trying to run
a business here.
Right. Uh, I'm sorry. I just, you know...
I just kind of spaced for a second.
Huh. Well, don't let it
happen again.
Right.
Or I may have to
get rough with you.
What?
I know what you like.
- Ugh!
- Hmm?
Trevor, it's me...
Gwen.
Hey, this is moving
just a little too fast here.
Don't tell me
Mr. Mario Andretti's
giving me a speeding ticket.
Hey, wait.
My wife just died, you know.
Come on, what are you...
what are you doing?
I know.
It's perfect.
Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
What the hell
are we doing?
Nothing we haven't done
before.
We'll pick this up
later.
[Door opens]
[Inhales deeply]
Now get some
fuckin' work done.
[Beeps]
We're watching you.
[Camera whirring]
[Sighing] Oh, my God.
[Keyboard clicks,
computer dings]
[Telephones ringing
in distance]
Gwen: Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
[Tape rewinds]
Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
[Tape rewinds]
Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
[Tape rewinds]
Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
[Tape rewinds]
Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
[Tape rewinds]
Mmm, yeah.
That's it, Trevor.
[Beeps]
[Telephone rings loudly]
[Clears throat]
Uh, hello?
Trevor,
this is Detective Lange.
It's about your wife.
[Beeps]
Trevor, are you there?
Hello?
Trevor...
Thank you
for coming down, Trevor.
Yeah.
How's that head of yours
feeling?
It's, uh, better.
Thanks.
We still haven't been able
to locate your wife,
although Missing Persons
turned up some evidence
that suggests foul play
may have been involved.
Foul play? What?
For one thing,
there were no skid marks
on the bridge,
the tires were all intact,
and from what we can tell,
there was nothing wrong
internally with the vehicle either.
It's like the car was driven
off the bridge intentionally.
I just... I just
lost control, you know,
and... I swerved.
We went off the bridge. I tried
to get her out, but I couldn't.
Is there anything
that might have happened
just before that accident
that you haven't mentioned?
Look, I've told you
everything I can remember.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I just...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Don't take it the wrong way.
I'm just a guy trying to do
a job here, okay?
I mean,
between your head injury
and... and the fact
that you're still on
some really strong
pain medication,
you may have forgot something
about the crash that could help us,
and everything
you have told us
could just be
the medication talking.
That's all.
So, we'll be revisiting
things a lot around here...
[Laughing] No. No.
[Distorted audio]
[Muffled scream]
Trevor,
are you still in there?
Uh, she was trapped
inside and...
Well, apparently
she got out,
and therein lies a problem.
I won't keep you.
If we have
any more questions...
[Grunts]... you'll get a call
from myself or my partner,
Detective Givens.
You guys know something
that I don't?
All things considered,
uh...
we probably know
a lot less than you do.
Have a good afternoon,
Trevor.
Yeah.
[Rattling]
[Dog whines]
What's the matter, boy?
[Whimpers]
[Door closes]
[Sighs]
Shit.
[Choking]
[Heaves]
[Gags]
[Choking]
[Vomits]
[Gasps]
What's happening?
[Bottles rattle]
[Roaring]
[Rattling stops]
[Slurping]
[Squealing]
[Knock on door]
[Siren wailing in distance]
[Wailing intensifies]
[Wailing softens]
[Knock on door]
I did it.
Well,
what do you think?
I was gonna get it
on my ass,
but I thought
this was sexier.
[Dog barking in distance]
Hey.
Oh, yeah, that's, uh,
um...
I knew you'd like it.
Oh, uh, you know,
I'm... I'm sorry.
Uh...
I'm having a weird day...
really weird.
Oh, okay.
It's definitely, um...
missing the woman's touch
it used to have.
Yeah. I know.
Well, if you, um...
feel like... talking
or whatever...
you know where I am.
Are you okay?
Not at all.
[Laughs]
Strange, strange,
strange.
[Laughs]
[Door creaks]
[Click]
[Sighs]
[Light-switch cord jingling]
[Exhales deeply]
[Sniffs]
[Click]
Kirsty: How do you feel?
Trevor: What are you
talking about, Kirsty?
It's our anniversary,
Trevor.
It's been five years.
How do you feel?
I feel great.
Why wouldn't I?
You see, tonight, I've got
something planned for you,
something I've been planning
for a long time.
Planning what?
Why don't you just
come to bed, Trev, please?
First things first.
I have a little gift for you.
Something to remind you just
how much you mean to me.
I can't believe
you got me a present.
It's beautiful.
Where did you get this?
See if you can open it,
Kirsty.
[Knock on door]
I can't believe
you got me a present.
You wrapped this yourse...
[Click]
[Knock on door]
[Creaks]
[Indistinct talking
on television in distance]
Hello?
[Siren wails]
[Dog yapping]
Hello?
[Yapping continues]
[Woman yelling in distance]
Miss me?
Jesus Christ, Gwen. You
scared the shit out of me.
What's this?
This innocent bit's
getting a little old.
Don't you think?
Sit.
Don't make me beat you.
Where is it?
Where's what?
[Scoffs]
[Gulps]
You usually have it
up and running by now.
[Chuckles nervously]
[Camera beeps, whirs]
Gwen: Oh, yeah.
You're a bad boy.
Yeah, that's the Trevor
I know.
Uh, nah, nah, nah, nah,
nah, nah...
Oh, unh, unh, unh, unh,
unh, unh-unh.
Get off me.
[Scoffs]
Go ahead, get up.
Get up.
You're kidding me.
Uh, no, I'm not.
You have definitely got
a screw loose.
You can say goodbye
to that promotion.
[Door closes]
[Sighs]
[Camera beeps, whirs]
Gwen: That's it, Trevor.
That's a good boy.
Oh, that's a good boy.
Uh-huh.
I know what you like.
[Moaning] Oh...
Oh, Trevor.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, that's it.
[Breathing heavily]
Oh...
Mmm... mmm...
Trevor, that's perfect.
Oh...
Yeah. Oh...
Oh, come on.
Trevor, mmm...
Mmm...
[Giggles]
Oh...
We're all here for you,
Trevor.
[Moaning]
Hey, loverboy...
You like what you see?
[Laughs]
[Moaning]
That's it, Trevor.
Oh... oh...
That's perfect, Trevor.
Yeah.
Oh! Aah! Aaah!
Gwen! No!
Aaah!
Aaah! Aaah!
Gwen, what...
Aah! Aaah!
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aaah!
Aaaah!
No!
Must be nice.
What?
Getting paid for doing shit.
Look, man...
You don't understand.
I got some seriously
weird shit going on.
That accident fucked you up
more than I thought.
[Telephone ringing
in distance]
Hey, um... you know what?
I'm gonna hook you up,
man.
She'll take
one look at you
and know exactly...
what you need.
[Telephone ringing
in distance]
And, uh...
look busy, all right?
Man: Anybody seen Gwen?
[Birds caw]
[Door rattles]
[Vehicles passing by]
[Horn honks]
[Bell rings]
[Buzzer]
[Door opens]
[Ice cracking]
[Grunts]
Just relax.
Let the needles connect
to your soul.
These headaches
you've been getting...
Do they happen in conjunction
with hallucinations?
Uh, well, sort of.
My head's been in constant
pain ever since the accident,
and, uh, it just seems to increase
whenever I get those, you know...
Dreams?
No, more like nightmares,
really.
I mean...
uh, it just seems so real.
That's your subconscious
talking to you.
It's trying to
tell you something
about your waking life.
So...
[Taps mirror]
What's the mirror for?
To help you look into
your soul.
I can see
into your soul.
You feel desperate...
trapped by a wife who
suffocates you with forgiveness.
You're looking
for a way out.
Yeah.
Something final...
without remorse...
without regret.
Wherever there is hate,
violence, depravity...
a door
will always be found.
This musical puzzle...
created by a Frenchman
named L'merchant.
Merchant and Sage: It is a means
to break the surface of the real.
[Wind whistles]
[Rumbling]
[Bottles rattle]
[Electricity crackles]
Agggh!
Ugh! Agh!
Which do you find
more exhilarating, Trevor...
the pain or the pleasure?
Personally, I prefer pain.
Agggh!
Is there something wrong?
No.
[Coughs]
No, I'm okay.
[Cellular phone rings]
Shall I get that for you?
[Ringing continues]
Hello?
This is Detective Givens,
Mike's partner.
But I don't...
I don't understand.
How could this be a... a homicide
case when there was no murder?
The last time anybody saw
this woman, she was alive.
You seem pretty certain
that she's dead.
Hey, detective, I saw
my wife drown in our car.
Yeah.
Right.
You know, I've done
my homework on you, man.
You're, uh... you're real smart
with numbers, aren't you?
Where are you going
with this?
How many zeros
was your wife worth?
We had nothing.
No.
You had nothing.
She had a nice little
inheritance
stashed away
for a rainy day.
Uh...
I'm sorry, what?
Don't play fucking stupid
with me, all right?
Kirsty's father
and Uncle Frank
had several sizeable
financial holdings
when they passed away...
under some rather, uh...
unusual circumstances.
You know...
I- I don't know.
Kirsty, she never liked
to talk about her past.
Well, maybe that's because
she didn't really trust you.
It seems that she's
the sole beneficiary,
so if Kirsty's dead,
like you seem
so fucking certain,
well, then,
I guess it all...
well, it all goes to you,
Trev.
I swear to God, man, I don't
know anything about that.
[Sighs]
Hmm.
[Snaps fingers]
My partner...
Detective Lange...
he's a little softer
around the heart than I am.
Me, uh...
I'm hard as they come.
When I get a feeling about
something, I'm usually right.
And I got a bad feeling
about you, Trev.
Real bad.
You're obsessed
with that thing.
God forbid we let one event
go unrecorded.
Why don't you come to bed?
Please? Please?
It's our anniversary, Trevor.
Come on.
Trevor:
First things first.
[Click]
[Indistinct shouting]
[Siren wailing]
Just like I thought.
Nothing.
[Chuckles]
[Knocking]
Hey.
Can I, um...
borrow something?
Um...
Yeah, sure.
What do you want?
You.
Uh...
Now...
I'm feeling kind of
weird here, you know?
[Sighs]
[Scoffs]
It's getting hot in here,
no?
You are being kind of...
weird.
It's almost like...
I'm with somebody else.
[Chuckles]
[Ripping, moans]
Tie me up.
[Clears throat]
Come and get it.
Come on.
That's it.
[Chuckles]
[Moans]
[Gasps]
Uhh!
Ohh!
Aah!
[Clanking]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
[Faucet handles squeak,
water running]
Aah!
All problems solved.
[Water dripping]
[Birds chirping]
[Indistinct shouting,
dog barking]
[Baby crying]
Uh...
Man, you're alive.
Ohh!
I have some serious
space issues.
What... did you want?
Uh, right. Um...
We need to talk...
you know, about what we did
last night.
[Chuckles] W-What?
Man: Who the fuck is it?!
Who's in there with you?
Are you having
a nervous breakdown
or something?
Hey.
What can we do for you,
chief?
Who are you?
[Chuckles]
If you know Tawny,
you better know me, pal.
Hey, uh, I'm sorry.
It's my mistake.
I'll talk to you later.
Let's make it much later!
[Giggles]
[Smack]
Get in there.
[Answering machine clicks]
Trevor: Hey,
we're not in right now.
Leave a message
after the beep. Thanks.
[Beep]
This is Detective Lange,
Trevor.
We need to talk
as soon as possible.
There's been an interesting
twist in the puzzle.
[Indistinct conversations,
telephones ringing]
Detective Givens: I'm telling you
right now your boy killed the boss.
As sure
as I am standing here.
[Laughter]
Detective Lange: No, I'm not
too sure about the wife.
It's done.
What are you doing
to find my wife?
Well, I can assure you
we're doing everything in our
power to find your wife, Trevor.
This investigation
is gonna take some time.
I'm gonna need your full
cooperation on this.
What about that message you left
on my answering machine?
What's your relationship
with Gwen Stevens?
What?
We appreciate you
coming down.
- You've been very helpful.
- Yeah, thanks.
- So that's all for now?
- Yeah.
What?
She was my boss.
And that's it?
Yeah, that's it.
What did he tell you?
Nothing.
We leave no stone unturned
around here, Trevor.
You think I did it.
Hey,
I'm on your side here.
Then would you please tell me
what the fuck is going on?
I wish I knew.
Yeah. I'll bet.
[Door closes]
Once you choose to open the
bo x and unleash its power,
there is no returning.
And are you willing
to pay the price?
[Fly buzzing]
No, the price
is far greater,
but you'll learn that.
They all do.
[Wings flapping]
Whoa!
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah, I know,
I was just... you know.
[Chuckles softly]
Can I get you anything?
Uh, no.
No. I'm okay.
[Siren wails in distance]
[Man gasping]
You okay?
I don't know, Allison.
I think I, um...
I think I really
screwed everything up.
Come on, Trevor.
You can't blame yourself.
Yeah.
I miss her.
I miss my wife.
It sounds like you're
remembering more and more,
and that's a good thing,
Trevor.
Maybe you're not the angel
that you thought you were.
[Chuckles softly]
Yeah.
Come on. You're gonna
get through this, Trevor.
[Telephone rings]
Hey, Bret...
Come here.
We need to talk.
Look, Trev,
I'm really, really busy.
I got a stack of reports
due by 3:00.
The suits upstairs are all
over my ass on this one, okay?
- What'd you tell the police?
- Nothing they didn't already know.
What's that
supposed to mean?
I didn't tell them anything
they didn't already know.
Hey, Bret, why don't you help me
out here, man? They think I did it.
Did what?
Killed Kirsty.
I got a... report
to... do.
Just make yourself
at home.
Oh, already have.
[Telephones ringing
in distance]
Why are you here,
detective?
We found this curious
little object
not too far from the site
of the accident.
No prints.
Forensics scraped a little dark
residue that was caked on it.
Want to take a guess
what they found?
Uh, no, but somethin' tells
me that you're gonna tell me.
Blood, Trevor.
Matched some of the blood we
took from the seat of your car.
Can you tell me
anything about it?
I- I-I... It...
[Sighs] It looks familiar,
you know?
Like most things
these days.
I- I think
it was in the car.
Gee... you think so?
Think about it, Trevor.
Give me something
to go on here.
I got Givens ready to drag
you in today on murder charges.
Help me get him off my back...
off of your back.
It was an accident,
detective,
just like I've been saying
all along.
Somebody's gotta believe me.
[Telephone ringing
in distance]
I believe you, Trevor.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
But so far...
I'm the only one who does.
[Footsteps approach]
Hey.
Look, I-I'm sorry, okay?
We need to talk.
[Gurgles]
What's up?
It's getting a little weird
around here, so, um... [Sighs]
I quit.
Today's my last day.
You know, I figured
it was the perfect time
to say "Fuck you" to the morons
around here and make a serious change.
Well, now, Bret, that's...
that's... [Door opens]
[Coins rattle]
[Machine beeps]
[Bag falls]
[Door closes]
Look, uh... i know you got your,
uh, golden egg all lined up,
and that's cool, but the rest of us
gotta make some hay for ourselves,
'cause frankly, this job
ain't paying the bills anymore.
We're not all drinking from the
cash cow, like your wife was.
What are you talking about?
What am I talking about?
Yeah.
The money.
[Camera whirs, beeps]
Don't play stupid, man...
Kirsty's inheritance.
I'm talking about
the plan.
You know,
let's get out of here.
Oh, whoa, whoa.
Hey, whoa, whoa, Bret.
What did you tell Lange?
- Oh, come on, Trev. What the hell's wrong with...
- No, no, no!
Did you tell him about Gwen...
a- about the inheritance?
I didn't tell him
anything.
You know, we're all here
for you, Trev.
Agh! God!
Agh!
[Groans]
I trusted you!
Goddamn it!
How could you do this
to us?!
[Glass shatters]
God!
Shit.
Jesus, buddy.
You all right?
Shit.
I gotta go, man.
Well, let me
give you a...
a ride.
[Grunting]
[Hydraulic hiss]
[Roaring]
Agh!
[Beeps]
[Groans]
Yeah. Hello.
Yeah, hi.
Um, I'd like to speak
to Dr. Allison Dormire.
Hello. Yeah, hi.
What do you mean
she's not there?
S- She's always there.
She's a resident.
All right, hey, look...
Can you... can you please
help me find her? Please?
Hello?
Damn it.
Damn.
Sage: There's
no physical explanation
for these headaches
of yours, Trevor.
Your body's
completely healed.
If there is any pain
in your head...
it's in your head.
Your soul... is locked up
inside you,
and you need to free it,
Trevor.
You blocked yourself
from the healing process,
and that's what
we need to do now...
heal your soul.
The only way to do that
is to give in utterly.
Do you know what I mean
by giving in?
No.
It's about trust.
Do you trust me...
implicitly?
I don't know
what's real...
or what isn't real anymore.
How can I trust anybody?
You can trust me.
Surrender yourself
to your past.
It's the only way you're
gonna become whole again.
Are you willing
to partake?
[Siren wails]
Can you hear me?
Just nod.
You know where you are?
Ambulance.
Remember what happened
back there?
Some woman on top of me
naked, trying to kill me.
Uh, yeah,
not quite that good.
Um, you were riding
on a bus,
and then you just collapsed
onto the floor, out cold.
Do you remember
riding on a bus now?
No.
Oh...
Maybe. I don't...
[Wheels squeaking]
Hello, Trevor.
Well, what'd you do
this time?
Oh, yeah, couple of stitches
will fix that right up.
Hey, where's Allison?
- Allison?
- Yeah, Allison Dormire.
She...
She's a resident here.
I'm sorry. We don't have any
resident by the name of Allison.
Look, my nurse will
numb this up, and, uh...
I'll get right back
to you.
Nurse: It's imperative
that you stay calm.
This might sting a little.
Just relax, Trevor.
- Remember, we're all...
- You're all here for me. Go ahead, say it.
Jesus Christ!
I'm so tired of this shit!
- Trevor! Trevor!
- I'm tired of all you people.
Okay, you caught me.
At least let me finish,
will ya?
I got one puff left.
Knock yourself out.
Trevor? I heard you were looking
for me.  Is everything all right?
Allison, hey.
No.
I'm not all right.
Look, I, um...
think I've done some very...
very bad things.
Everybody does things
they regret.
It's part of life.
Until now, you couldn't
remember parts of your past,
and now they're all
hitting you at once.
It's a shock
to the system.
You can't undo your past.
And sooner or later, you're
gonna have to confront it.
And it frightens me
to think
that I can't be there
for you when you do.
- Hey, buddy...
- Yeah, but I was starting to think I was going,
you know,
insane or something.
- Hey, buddy...
- What?!
Who the hell
are you talkin' to?
- Agh!
- What have you done?!
Detective Lange: What's your
relationship with Gwen Stevens?
I know about Gwen...
and the others.
What the fuck?
Aaah!
[Squealing]
[Thunder crashes]
[Water dripping slowly]
Where are you?
What have you done
to me?
Fuck.
What the fuck
is happening to me?
[Groans]
[Crash]
Where are you,
Goddamn it?!
Poor Trevor.
Who are you?
Still in the dark?
This game is over.
Do you hear me?
Oh, I hear everything.
And soon you will know
everything...
much more than you want,
I guarantee it.
What is this?
Why are you doing this
to me?
Is it so difficult
to face your demons?
Unh-unh. Y...
None of this is real.
You're not real.
Oh, but I'm afraid
I am.
You can't run
from your past.
You killed them.
You killed Kirsty.
You killed Gwen...
and the others.
You killed them.
And now you're trying
to pin it on me.
The killer is amongst us,
yes.
[Water sloshing]
Ow! Fuck!
God... damn it!
[Groans]
[Seagulls crying]
Where you been, Trev?
Been looking all over
for ya.
Jesus!
What are you doing?
Put that thing away.
Tonight was supposed to be
the night, Trev, remember?
Oh, right, uh,
you don't remember anything.
Well, let me remind you
about your plan.
We'd kill Kirsty,
make it look like a suicide.
You'd get all her money,
and we'd split it 50/50... huh?
None of that's
gonna happen now, is it?
No, you had to go solo with
your little car-accident bit,
and then
you fucked it all up.
What were you thinking, Trev...
that I'd look the other way
and forget
about our little deal?
- I don't know...
- What you're talking about.  I know... heard it.
Gotta tell you, buddy... the amnesia
routine's starting to get a little fuckin' old.
Lange's onto you,
and it's only a matter of time
before he's onto me.
I don't want to spend
the rest of my life in prison.
I'd rather spend it
in Hell...
[Gun cocks]
...with you.
[Gunshot]
[Gun chinks]
[Gasps]
Oh, my God, Bret,
what did you do?
[Seagulls crying]
Oh, God.
[Groans]
No, you're not real!
Get out of my head!
[Footsteps running]
[Bell rings]
Sage...
[Groans]
[Door rattles]
Sage...
Oh, no.
Ohh...
[Breathing heavily]
[Doorknob rattles]
[Creaking]
[Rattling]
[Lock disengages]
[Rattling continues]
[Creaking]
[Door creaking]
[Guns cock]
Trevor...
Oh... you don't understand.
I didn't...
Save it.
You don't need
to say a thing.
No, it's, uh...
you know...
You have the right
to remain silent.
What's going on here,
detective?
Please, you can't believe
that I did this.
Detective, believe me.
I didn't do what
you think I did. Please...
Relax, Trevor.
Let's get to the bottom
of this once and for all.
You want to tell me exactly
what happened back there,
or should we just play the
headache game a little longer?
[Telephone rings]
[Ringing continues]
Okay.
We'll do it your way.
This is Lange.
Really?
Well, I-I-I got him sitting
right in front of me now.
[Flogging, man screaming]
Yes...
[Flogging, screaming continue]
Mm-hmm.
Ugh! Ohh!
Aggh!
Ohh!
Agggh!
Thank you.
Well, one thing's
for sure...
This ain't
your lucky day.
They found a body
this morning in the river.
They're bringing it
into the morgue now
so you can identify it.
Is it my wife?
You stay put.
[Window blind rattles]
[Door creaks, closes]
[Door opens, creaks]
You know,
I had you pegged for bad
the minute
I laid eyes on you.
Now, I want you to tell me
everything you remember happening,
in your own words, exactly the
way you told Detective Lange,
but I want you to make
one... minor adjustment.
What's that?
Don't fucking lie
to me.
I just want to see my wife,
man. [Door rushes open]
I thought I asked you
to stay put.
Each killed with a single
gunshot wound to the head...
tortured, then shot.
We find the gun,
we find the killer.
This way.
Sick motherfucker!
Get off me!
They're gonna fry your ass,
motherfucker!
I'm gonna wring
your scrawny fuckin' neck!
Got quite the fan club.
[Man shouting indistinctly]
[Electricity crackling]
Ugh! Agh!
Agh! Agh!
Here we go.
[Buzzer]
[Click]
[Door opens]
[Door creaks]
[Scream in distance]
[Keys jingle]
[Muffled screaming]
[Chains rattling]
[Trickling]
Just about there.
[Water dripping]
[Screaming continues]
[Handcuffs click]
Thanks.
Whoa. What are you...
[Keys jingling]
What are you doing?
I thought you believed me.
Believe?
Here's what I believe,
Trevor...
I believe you and me
have a lot in common.
I believe each of us
are the sum
of two entirely different
people.
No.
I know who I am.
And I'm not a killer.
Denial to the end...
That's what
I like about you, kid!
Good and bad, Trevor...
Honest, dishonest...
Righteous and evil...
That's how
we're all made.
It's a little of both.
It's just a question...
of how much... of each.
[Crackling]
And we're made up of just
the right parts of both.
[Both laugh]
A little heavy
on the evil, huh?
[Both laughing]
It's all good, Trev!
[Laughing]
It's all good!
[Laughter continues]
[Coughs]
[Door rattles, creaks]
[Door creaks]
[Door closes]
[Exhales sharply]
[Coughs]
[Flies buzzing]
What the fuck?
Kirsty?
[Rumbling]
[Bottles rattle]
[Buzzing]
[Crackles]
[Squeaks]
[Rattling]
[Glass shattering]
[Electricity crackling]
[Crackles]
[Rumbling, rattling subside]
It seems you've reached
the end of your journey.
I told you you couldn't
run from your past forever.
Eventually,
it catches up with you,
and you must atone.
And now...
it is time for you
to pay the price.
You were willing to pay
the price, weren't you?
[Music box plays]
I just want to see
my wife.
In time.
Let me see my wife.
I said, "In time"!
Agh! Aah!
Aaah!
Ugh!
[Rips]
[Breathes heavily]
[Ripping]
Agh! Aagh!
Aagh!
Ohh!
[Metal clanking]
Ugh!
[Breathing heavily]
[Groans]
[Metal clanks]
Agh!
All problems solved?
Not so simple,
I'm afraid.
I needed first
to open a door for you.
You were
an interesting study.
Aggh!
Lust, greed, deception...
Fertile ground,
but rather mundane.
[Clanking] Let us take
one final journey together.
Let me help you remember
once and for all.
Kirsty:
What have you done?
It's just a puzzle.
Open it up.
I trusted you.
I trusted you!
Goddamn it!
How could you do this
to us?!
You told me you loved me!
Just open
the fuckin' box.
We were uninvited guests at your
little celebration... [Trevor groans]
Is this what you want?
...unseen by you.
I hope it's everything
you want it to be.
I used you, Trevor.
You were nothing more
than bait...
to lure a far more
interesting creature.
[Clicking]
Kirsty...
We meet again.
[Voice breaking]
How did you find me?
You opened a door
long ago,
and it will not be closed
until I get what I came for.
[Shudders] My soul.
Aaaaaaaaaaah!
You solved the puzzle.
You unleashed the power.
There is no turning back.
I will not rest
until I get what I want,
and what I want is you.
You always knew
this day was coming,
felt it deep within
your soul.
Wait!
[Breathes heavily]
Wait.
What if I make you
a deal?
Interesting.
I will bring you five souls
in exchange for mine.
You would bring them
to me yourself?
You'll get your five.
I was impressed
with her handiwork.
Three of your favorite
companions,
most supple
and delicious...
...and the man with whom
you once conspired
to kill Kirsty...
They are all with me now.
But the balance
is only four souls,
and that, as you now know,
was not our contract.
- Agh! Ugh!
- You have seen many things...
that you will wish
you had not...
All those women...
in our home...
in my bed.
... many nightmares from which
you will never awake.
- No, Kirsty, come on...
- Don't you lie to me!
Don't!
We can make it work,
all right?
We can put the pieces
back together.
- You gotta believe me.
- I am done believing! I trusted you!
I can't believe this shit is
happening, man. I had a fuckin' deal.
No, you had a deal...
but I made
a better offer.
Trevor: Aggh!
And guess what?
He took it.
Welcome to the worst nightmare
of all.
Reality.
[Gunshot]
Aaaaaah!
[Tires screeching]
Aaaaah!
[Gurgling]
[Creaking]
Aaaaaaaaaah!
[Chains rattle]
[Gasps]
[Breathes heavily]
[Water dripping slowly]
Fuck.
[Voice breaking]
I'm the fifth soul.
[Siren wails]
Yeah, that's him.
[Helicopter whirring]
Okay, people.
That's it.
[Indistinct talking]
[Camera shutter clicking]
He just shot himself.
Next thing I knew,
we were in the water.
There...
I couldn't see anything.
I lost him.
You did what you could.
I'm sorry.
It just doesn't make
any sense...
that he would be capable
of murder.
We found the gun in your car.
It appears to be the same.
If it matches, I think we
may have found our killer.
Come on.
Wait a minute, guys,
before you zip him up.
[Camera shutter clicking]
Hmm.
Wasn't your lucky day,
was it?
You checked the oral cavity
for blockages?
Oh, what do we got here?
And we have a winner.
Okay, zip it up.
We'll finish at the morgue.
Wait. Wait.
[Seagulls crying]
Sorry I had to leave you
like that for a minute, Trev,
but I'm back.
Can you hear me, Trevor?
Jesus, Allison.
What possesses you
to talk to cadavers?
What if
there's no afterlife?
Wouldn't you want someone
to talk to you
like a normal human being
one last time?
[Indistinct talking
on police radio]
[Siren wailing]
You're creeping me out,
and I'm the coroner.
[Helicopter whirs]
I've arranged
a ride home for you,
so I guess
you're free to go.
Thank you, detective...
for everything.
Uh, one more thing.
I wonder if you know
anything about this.
We found it in the car.
Yeah. It was...
my anniversary gift.
Oh.
You know, I was gonna
turn it in as evidence...
but I'll tell you what...
Why don't you
take it home?
[Siren wailing]
Something
to remember him by.
[Trembles softly]
Of course.
Thank you.
[Sighs]
[Siren wails]
[Helicopter whirs]
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Music continues]
[Eerie music plays]
[Music box plays]