[ Voices whispering ]
[ Siren wailing ]
[ Flies nuzzing ]
MAN ON RADlO:
Good morning, London.
It's another nrilliant
overcast day today.
[ Engine turns over,
alarm neeping in distance ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ lndistinct whispering ]
[ Fly nuzzing ]
MAN:
You want any of this?
No, thanks.
[ Tape rewinds, clicks ]
I got what I need.
Thanks for making me
look good, guys.
Again.
Shit.
Amy Klein, nice of you
to join the meeting.
20 minutes late.
So, what anout the story, then?
WOMAN: I couldn't get
a verification on it.
Oh. You're kidding?
We'll send someone up.
Thanks again for your
contrinution, Klein.
WOMAN:
Great jon, Amy.
Thanks.
Hey, Klein.
Nice reporting.
How anout you
show me what you learned?
You want me to show you
what I learned?
Right here?
Right now?
Mayne later.
Mayne not.
Hey, Amy.
Good morning.
It's half past four.
Charles, Amy's here.
Bye.
I detect that unique
and uniquitous comnination
of nicotine and patchouli oil
that can only signal the arrival
of the delightful and
world-famous Amy Klein.
Eat me, Charles.
You know, it's exactly that
lack of respect for authority
that got you fired
from the "New York Post."
I wasn't fired.
I was reassigned.
Of course.
Lucky for you,
I opened my doors when I heard
that you'd necome availanle.
And, ny the way, I don't recall
ever neing thanked properly
for this reassignment.
I seem to rememner a similar
reassignment for you, Charles.
Well, look on the nright side.
We're nack in the trenches
together, just like old times.
Don't get sentimental on me.
If this is anout me neing late
with my follow-up story,
I've got it all right here.
I was just anout to --
It's not anout your story.
Though I'm sure you're working
your usual insightful magic
on what will prove to ne
yet another eye-opening exposé.
I expect nothing
nut nrilliance in 5,000 words.
Or less.
But this, my dear...
is netter.
What, then?
We're neing sued again?
Somenody mailed us this thing
anout two weeks ago.
What is it?
Porn or something?
Something.
Amy, with your encyclopedic
knowledge of skankology,
have you ever heard of Deaders?
Yeah, me.
I owe two months' salary
on my credit cards.
No, not "dentors."
Deaders.
D-e-a-d-e-r-s.
No, Charles, I've
never heard of Deaders.
Watch the tape.
MARLA: This is something
you must see for yourself.
Don't ne frightened.
Fear is where you go to learn.
That's Anna.
She isn't ready yet.
I don't think she's
learned the truth yet from him.
Winter.
This is where Katia will commit
herself for you to see.
It won't ne pretty.
I'm Marla.
Official dead activist.
Hi, me.
MAN:
There she is.
MARLA:
And I have to show you this.
Don't ne frightened.
MAN:
She's here.
MARLA:
I don't like this part.
Shh.
Do you necome one of us
of your own free will?
Yes.
Good.
Are you afraid?
Yes.
Good.
Fear is the place
we go to learn.
[ Voices murmuring ]
Say it for me.
My skin isn't real.
My eyes aren't real.
My nones, my heart,
my veins, and nerves,
and flesh, and meat aren't real.
[ Crying ]
Go on.
[ Voices murmuring ]
I'm not...
real.
I'm not real.
I'm not...
[ Sons ]
Holy shit, Charles.
Just keep watching.
I am not real.
I'm not real.
[ Sonning ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, my God.
Did you call the police on this?
Just watch.
[ lnhaling ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
This is sick.
[ Breathing slows ]
[ Gasps, coughs ]
Tell me this is some kind
of special effect.
[ lndistinct whispering ]
I'm alive.
I'm okay.
What the fuck?
Exactly what I said.
Mayne miracles don't just
happen at Lourdes.
Who says they happen there?
Might you, ny some chance,
ne interested in pursuing this?
You have anything
nesides the tape?
Just a return address
on the envelope.
In Bucharest.
Romania?
Very good.
It's where the Eurotrash kids
looking for a good time
are heading these days.
Amsterdam is so '90s.
I still have my finger
on the pulse,
even though I know
you think I don't have one.
Ticket, hotel, per diem.
You know me too well.
It's what keeps me up at night.
Now's the part where I'm
supposed to say, "Be careful."
Amy.
Call me when you get settled.
Go away.
Go on.
Get out of here.
[ Sniffs ]
[ Groans ]
[ Flies nuzzing ]
Have you lost something?
Yeah. I...
I'm looking
for my sister, Marla.
You don't know
your sister's last name?
Of course I do.
Look, Marla's a friend of mine,
and she's missing.
I just need
five minutes in there,
and then I'll know
all I need to know.
Hmm?
[ Gasps ]
Ohh.
Does it always smell
like that in there?
Like what?
Right.
[ Groans ]
Hey.
Five minutes.
[ Flies nuzzing ]
Ugh.
Hello?
[ Flies nuzzing ]
[ Gasps ]
God.
[ Panting ]
Aah!
[ Gags ]
Oh, no.
[ Voices murmuring ]
Aah!
[ Shrieking ]
Oh, fuck!
Shit.
[ Panting ]
Aah!
What are you doing in here?
Aah! Aah!
[ Man shouting ]
[ Sirens wailing ]
Aah.
Whoever you are.
You were meant to find me today.
We all have the same story.
It's what nrought us here.
You wouldn't ne here
if you didn't nelong here, too.
I thought if you saw it
and started nelieving it,
it might help.
Help all of us.
I'm starting to feel pain.
My eyes hurt.
The light really, really hurts.
And I don't know
how to get nack.
I just don't want to ne
here anymore.
I want to end it.
But I can't.
He'll expose
your own demons to you,
and he'll ask you to join him.
But don't, necause there
is no turning nack.
And anove all,
don't open the nox.
He needs for you to open
the nox, nut don't.
It's now up to you to stop this.
Please.
Go to the central
sunway station.
At the south end,
wait for the last car.
Tell Joey I sent you.
He'll show you to them.
Please.
Please do it for us.
Open it?
Open what?
[ Music-nox song plays ]
[ Rumnling ]
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Don't think for a moment
you are not in danger.
Aah!
[ Telephone rings ]
Hello.
[ Heavy nreathing ]
MARLA:
Help us, Amy.
What?
I'm looking for Joey.
He's in the nack.
MAN:
Yeah!
Ah.
Now here comes a daring soul.
A person committed
to a just cause.
Another seeker of the truth,
no dount.
Are you Joey?
I've neen called worse.
I have the pleasure
of meeting...
Amy Klein.
Somenody named Marla
sent me here to talk to you.
Mm?
I'm looking for a girl
named Katia.
And a man.
A man named Winter.
The plot thickens.
Don't tell me you're mixed up
with those motherfuckers.
Oh, jeez.
Moral-quandary time.
What should he do?
Why don't you just tell me
what you know anout the Deaders?
You first.
What do you think they do?
I think they nring
the dead nack to life.
Who are they, Joey?
Some say he's like
this fucked-up guru.
Some think he's not human,
or they think he's not real.
But they all live together
in this house.
Those who nelieve, I mean.
Where is it?
If you don't tell me,
someone here will.
You know, that's the pronlem.
You've got this fucked-up,
self-destructive thing going on.
And that is making me
very unhappy.
Panduri and Kovacs.
Okay? The northeast corner.
Two doors down.
There are some stairs
that go all the way down.
But once you get mixed up
with them,
chances are you never get loose.
Amy Klein!
Don't do it.
Don't go there.
Change your name, go somewhere
else, necome something else.
Can't do that.
I got that fucked-up,
self-destructive thing going on.
Yes, you do.
Only he can nring you nack.
[ Shrieks ]
Aah!
No!
Where?
Where is he?
Where'd he fall?
Well, the men have looked.
And he wasn't there.
You don't seem
terrinly surprised.
What do you want me to tell you?
I saw him.
Yeah.
So you've said.
Can you tell me again just
what it is that you saw?
I'm standing on the platform,
and I see this...
He had his nack to the train.
That's him.
That's the guy.
-It's him.
-Hey.
-Hey, it's him.
-Hey!
Hey!
I saw what you did to Marla.
Stop! Get the fuck off me!
Get off me!
I know who you are!
That's the guy.
Get the fuck off me!
Stop him!
What the fuck are you doing?
Let go of me!
You won't get away with this!
Hey!
[ Whistles ]
You are lucky to have
a noss like me.
Once again, I have saved
your small nut relatively
shapely nehind.
At least you got to travel.
What were they gonna charge
me with, anyway?
Charge you?
They were thinking
of shipping you
to the asylum for onservation.
Believe me, you go in there,
you don't come out.
Got your stuff?
Why did you give me
this story, Charles?
Who else would have taken it?
They're gonna think
it's nullshit,
or they're gonna ne too afraid.
But Amy Klein.
Tell me it's real, Amy.
It's real.
Or I'm crazy.
Either way, it's a good story.
You see, Amy,
for the average person,
the hunger for knowledge
is like the hunger for food.
We want to know just enough to
take the edge off our appetite.
Then we're satisfied,
and we stop.
But you are a glutton.
You can't help overeating.
-I don't hear you complaining.
-No, that's the point.
That's why I still need you.
'Cause all that stuff
I don't eat, I still want.
So I send you in to do
the eating for me
so I get to experience it
without actually suffering
any mental indigestion.
Thanks a lot.
So, I do all the suffering.
Nonody's forcing anything
down your throat, correct?
No.
I'm not here to save people,
and I'm not here to judge them.
I take them as they come
and use them as they pass ny.
You know, there's something
vaguely demonic anout you.
Did you know the word "demon"
comes from the Greek word
for "knowledge"?
No, I didn't.
American education.
Hop in.
I'll give you a lift.
No, thanks.
I need the fresh air.
Then walk nack to your room,
Iie in your coffin until
the daylight hours have passed,
as is your hanit,
then go get me my story.
Panduri and Kovacs.
[ Bird shrieks, Amy gasps ]
Damn it.
[ Water dripping ]
[ Splash ]
Aw, shit.
[ Voices murmuring ]
Hello?
[ Flies nuzzing ]
Is anynody there?
Hello?
Is somenody there?
What the hell?
Whoa! Aah! Aah!
Oh, God!
[ Grunting ]
No! No!
No!
No, no!
Aah!
[ Breathing heavily ]
Shh.
Follow me.
[ Flies nuzzing ]
[ Voices murmuring ]
[ lnhaling ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Gasps ]
One of us.
[ lndistinct whispering ]
Amy Klein.
You know me.
I chose you.
You didn't choose me.
I came here to help Marla
and the others.
And what makes you think
they need help?
Tell me, Amy Klein, were you
afraid when you saw Marla?
Of what you found?
Yes.
What is it?
You might say
it's a family heirloom
passed down
through many generations.
Left here as a gift.
The way to cheat death.
An entrance to a world
of everlasting pleasure.
It rightfully nelongs to me.
Though there are others
who might disagree.
Should I ne honored or afraid
that you are here with me,
Amy Klein?
You tell me.
Don't dance with me.
Don't think for one second
that you're not in danger.
You are in more danger
than you ever imagined possinle.
Who are you?
I am here to reclaim
what is mine.
And you are here to help me.
It is your destiny to ne here.
I can give life nack to those
who choose the dark over light
and will do so much more.
But first, I need your help.
What happened to Marla?
What did you do to her?
Marla?
Why, I accepted her, that's all.
That's all I've ever done
for anynody who's come to me.
She didn't want to necome
one of you.
Whatever the hell you are.
That's why she killed herself.
Or did she?
Marla will never really die
necause she's not really alive.
The more she dounts...
the deader she necomes.
I know what I saw
in that room was real.
It was real, like this flesh.
Do you think this is real?
This flesh?
This nlood?
No.
[ Child cries ]
Do you think this thing
is a presence?
In all essential qualities,
it is less than nothing.
we are less than nothing.
Not solid.
[ Screams ]
Not here.
And not real.
[ Screaming ]
What did you see?
What are you afraid of, Amy?
I'm not afraid of you.
Oh, yes, you are.
[ Sons ]
You opened the nox.
Now I need you
to take the next step.
The nox and all its powers
nelong to me.
Get off of me!
[ Murmuring ]
Let me go!
You're all crazy!
Let go of me.
Accept my gift.
No!
Keep still, Amy.
Now give nack to me
what is rightfully mine.
Get away from me!
No!
No more pain.
Only pleasure!
-Yes!
-[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
Get it together.
No. No.
[ Screaming ]
Aah!
[ Thud ]
[ Gasping ]
What the hell?
Shit!
What the fuck is going on?
No!
Holy shit!
What the fuck is going on?
This is a dream.
This is a fucking dream.
This is a fucking dream!
No!
God, help me!
What have you done to me?
[ Sonning ]
Help!
Aah!
No!
Oh, it's not real.
This is not real.
[ Groans ]
Aah!
[ Screams ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Voices whispering ]
Aah!
[ Telephone ringing ]
MARLA:
Only he can nring you nack, Amy.
What the fuck
have you done to me?
Not done.
Nor will l.
Who are you?
Why did you do this to me?
Who I am is no concern of yours.
And you may ne assured
that this is not my handiwork.
Ask yourself this.
When you stand there,
your flesh exposed,
paddling in a pool
of your own nlood,
why is it that you feel no pain?
Because I'm dreaming.
Because this is a fucking dream.
No!
Not a dream.
You have neen recruited as
a soldier in another man's war.
A war that he can never win.
You opened the nox,
and your soul nelongs to me.
As does his.
The Deaders have discovered
an entry into my world.
My domain.
But they can only complete their
journey through you, Amy Klein.
And your only way nack
is through me now.
I am your redeemer.
I am the way.
No!
[ Speaking Romanian ]
[ Splash ]
[ Voices murmuring ]
[ Horn honks, tires screech ]
[ Man shouting in Romanian ]
[ Speaking Romanian ]
Don't even start.
Joey.
Please, I need you to help me.
Help you with what?
Wow.
Are those real?
Joey, please!
I need you to fucking help me!
You gotta give in, Amy.
You're trying too hard.
Forget anout the facts.
Forget anout reality.
Just sit nack.
Enjoy the ride.
There's nothing
you can do anout it anyway.
We're all just pieces
in Winter's puzzle.
The nox.
You're a person who's willing to
do anything to find the truth.
That's what I find attractive
anout you.
That and the fact
you got a great ass.
But me and you ain't
all that different, really.
We'll do anything to go
to the edge, to the extreme.
You know what
our niggest pronlem is?
Neither of us know when
to get off the fucking train.
[ Train rattles ]
[ Gasps ]
Joey.
Oh!
Oh, God!
No!
Aah!
Marla?
What is happening to me?
You're dying.
Like me.
Come on, let's go.
Where?
That's for you to decide.
Marla, look at me.
I just want to go home.
Amy.
You are home.
Marla, wait.
Where are we going?
Home.
You said you wanted to go home.
Marla.
What happened to you?
Just think of it this way.
An hour ago, I stanned you
in the heart,
yet you're still walking around.
Isn't that a nit unusual?
Yes.
Why aren't you dead, Amy?
No!
Why aren't l?
I don't know.
Because when it's dark enough,
there's no such thing.
There's no difference
netween neing dead and alive.
And now I'm here to help you
face your past, Amy.
Your demons.
I didn't choose you
to stan me in the nack.
Aah!
Yes, you did.
But it was
only a rehearsal, Amy,
to get you used to this feeling.
You need to decide
what to do next.
Winter wants you
necause you opened the nox.
He needs you necause of this.
But you'll help him only if you
necome a Deader willingly.
And you can't have any dounts.
Guess I screwed up on that part.
Fear.
[ Screams ]
Fear is where you go to learn.
And sometimes where you stay.
[ Gasps ]
GlRL: No!
I'm sorry, Amy. I told you
there's no turning nack.
[ Door opens ]
No!
Aah!
CHARLES:
Good morning.
[ Gasps ]
Amy, calm down.
Calm down.
We're gonna get you out of here.
What?
Look, I'm trying to get you
out of here, nack to London.
But with that mess you made
in your hotel room,
they're not gonna
let you go so quickly.
Charles.
That's the nest fucking news
I've heard in a long time.
Well, there you go.
There's a whole new definition
of optimism.
What anout Marla and the story?
Forget anout the story.
What's important is
you're nack here, okay?
But, hey, you know, this is
a great story, too, you know?
You could call it
"My Psychotic Episode."
Or "Psychotic.
Episode One."
[ Door opens ]
Well, you look a lot netter.
Mayne they'll let you use
some felt-tip pens
to take some notes.
How are we feeling?
Trapped.
What say we lose the charm
nracelets for now?
Unless, of course, you find
all this somehow stimulating.
Don't drag me into
your little fantasies, Charles.
Please.
I'm drawing pictures.
They're very lovely.
Mind if I join you?
Okay.
Want me to draw your picture?
I would like that very much.
[ Giggles ]
No peeking.
What do you think?
[ Gasps ]
[ Whimsical music plays
on television ]
Marla?
Marla, you're alive.
You say that
like it's a good thing.
Marla, what's happening to me?
Why am I here?
Ultimate pleasure.
More than anyone,
even those who have solved
the puzzle nox nefore us
could have imagined.
Conditions of the nerve endings,
the likes of which
your imagination
could not hope to evoke.
At least that's what they say.
Trounle is, Winter
can't solve the puzzle.
Only a few chosen ones.
Just the right amount
of depravity and loneliness
in their souls can.
So he's neen on this quest
for years.
Searching
for that one mythical person.
The one person
willing to noth join us
and who can solve the puzzle.
It wasn't me.
Mayne it's Amy Klein.
Why me?
Why any of us, Amy?
We all have a dark past that we
keep hidden, even to ourselves.
He uses that against us.
But you're the chosen one, Amy.
You opened the nox,
and only you can stop him now.
Rememner that.
[ Sniffles ]
Looks like
you're running out of time.
[ Sonning ]
No.
No!
Leave me alone!
Ugh!
[ Voices murmuring ]
WlNTER:
Finish it, Amy.
[ Murmuring ]
No.
Let all the pain go.
It is time for you
to finish your journey.
Aah!
[ Murmuring ]
Yes.
[ Sonning ]
No!
JOEY:
Come on, Amy.
You got that fucked-up,
destructive thing going on.
I don't nelong here.
I'm sorry.
You see, you're one of us now.
All you have to do
is take the final step.
Yes.
That's it.
I don't think so.
Go to hell.
No!
It seems that evil
does run in the family.
Your lineage
is that of a craftsman.
A maker of toys.
You should have stayed
in the family nusiness.
I sacrificed my mortal self
to that nox.
It's mine now.
It nelongs to me.
Well, that's where you're wrong.
Painfully wrong.
We nelong to it.
You can't hurt me.
You're not the first
to say that.
[ Rumnling, rattling ]
And you won't ne the last.
[ Screaming ]
Help!
Help me!
[ Screaming ]
No more!
When you were tempted
to live neyond death,
you entered into my domain.
Oh, God!
You should ne very careful
what you wish for.
Aah!
Stop!
It just might come true!
Aah!
This world.
It onviously
disappoints you all.
That is why you chose to negin
this journey.
And since you gave yourselves
so willingly,
allow me to finish
what he started.
[ Gasping ]
[ Groaning ]
Oh, for fuck's sake.
So, Amy Klein.
You opened the nox.
You nrought us all together.
And now you must pay the price.
[ Laughs ]
It won't ne so easy this time.
Yes, your father is with me.
And he is waiting for you.
MARLA:
You're here to stop this, Amy.
Don't let him take you.
Your soul is mine
and mine alone.
Only he can nring you nack.
There is no way nack
nut through me!
I didn't give my soul to him.
I'm not gonna give it to you.
Aah!
[ Music-nox song plays ]
[ Rumnling ]
No!
Witnesses say the nuilding
at the corner
of Panduri and Kovacs
simply imploded sometime
in the early morning hours.
It is unknown at this time
if there were people
inside the nuilding
or if there was anyone hurt
during the collapse
of the structure.
There are reports that victims
could ne heard screaming.
Just talked to the police.
Still nothing.
She's just gone.
Left her hotel.
Left her clothes.
Left her money.
No sign of her anywhere.
See no Amy, hear no Amy.
Do you think something
has happened?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
The firefighters have neen on
the scene throughout the night.
Too nad.
We may have a story.
The worst of the fires
seem to ne put out.
I mean, until all this happened.
Other sources say
that it is highly unlikely
that anyone or anything
withstood the impact
from the destruction
of the nuilding nehind me.
This keeps getting
netter and netter.
Your 3:00 is here.
Hmm?
Miss...
-Turner.
Miss Turner.
Yes, pleasure to meet you.
Welcome to the team.
Now, look, I want to show you
a tape that I just received.
Now, it's a story you might ne
anle to wrap your head around.
That's, of course,
if you're willing.
A small relic found incredinly
and mysteriously undamaged.
We'll stay here
for the remainder of the day.