It's last break before the climbing!
Have you forgotten anything?
It's too late now anyways.
Are you missing anything?
What?
Nothing.
Are you bothered by Guillaume?
Forget it
You could've told me
Why don't you take
this time to get to know him?
Got everytrhing?
Yeah.
I'm sorry
I had no choice
Don't worry about it
Sure?
It's been four years
since I've seen him.
This trip will change your mind.
It's gonna be fine, I promise.
Attention! Thanks.
We'll be arriving in 20 minutes
You'll see it's really peaceful
Along the Resnjak
There are several sections
the Stairway to Heaven
Purgatory
the Angels' Traverse
the Devil's Gateway.
And after that we arrive at
A ladder leading to a zip-line
Ok
You can ride it in 4 hours.
Then stop for drinks.
Photo?
NO!
You have no choice
Photo!
Come on, guys.
Fred! Excuse me, thanks.
I'd like to be in the center
Vertigo
Croatia, August 18
Oh no, Open the window
Open it
Give me some
Where did you get that?
At the Zagreb Station
while waiting for you
Croatia is so beautiful
Glad to see me?
I can't get the signal
We're leaving civilization
Guest what I've found?
We sang that in high school
Ok
Sing along
This is our song
Without hands
It'll be awesome
It's easy?
Anyone can do it
Don't worry
You're attached to
the lifeline
It reminds me of the Alps
Me, that I'm hungry
Didn't you eat lunch?
Wait up, Fred
Come on. Hurry up.
Isn't it beautiful?
Yeah, it's impressive
Chloe
Chloe, wait
What's with you?
Nothing. I'm happy to see you.
Can't I just tell you that or...
Your boyfriend look jealous
I'll go back to France
So?
What are you doing?
The path is closed
NO
Is there a problem
Apparently
We're screwed
Wait, maybe not
Fred we're not doing it
It's closed
There's not even a ladder
Who cares
Fred.
Come back.
I'll just check something
Fred, dammit!
It looked dangerous
It does, kids
There's a way up
I'll mark out the route
The path is there
Grab the rope
Got it
Fred says there's a way up
It really looks fantastic
If you don't want to go
we'll go back
For me it's ok
It's exciting, isn't it?
It looks completely stupid
At worst, we'll bring you back down
Chloe
It's up to you
Well, here we go
Ok, Let's go
Come on
Shall I stay?
Get up there
Your turn
Go, go
Go ahead.
You'll see
It's good for you but
That's it!
Mademoiselle.
Well done Loic, Continue
You're almost there.
Super.
Use your right hand
Karine told me
She told you what?
About the boy in the hospital
and everything
I know you've done everything you could
You don't know anything
You weren't there
Hold it tight with your right hand
Go up
Slowly
Use your feet. That's it.
Good
Mademoiselle...
Fuck off!
You're doing okey?
Yeah yeah, fine, thanks
What about you?
Yeah?
uh-huh
Ok I'll lead
Karine, stay with Loic
Chloe behind them
Guillaume, you're at the end?
It's important you're always
attached to the lifeline.
And never more than two people
on the same section.
All Okey?
Then, let's go!
In New Zealand,
it's pretty much the same
When are you leaving?
Next year.
After Australia
Canada
and St. Barth
My ass in the Caribbean
And you?
It depends on my posting
Didn't you want to quit?
I don't know yet
We're almost at the bridge
Are you alright?
Yeah
You're pale
Loic pass me your bag
It gets a bit harder now
Don't worry about me
Damn
I've often heard about you
Ok
Here we are
If you want to turn around
it's now or never
Are you okey?
Yes, I'll come
Loic, if you've got vertigo
we'll meet you back at the car.
Well I'm going
Awesome
It's great!
You'll enjoy it
You'll see
it's a blast
Ok
One foot in front of the other
Don't look down
That's good, continue
Great
It's incredible
Isn't it awesome?
It's better than I thought!
Loic?
Loic, come to me
No!
Karine wait a minute.
Come to me
There, come
That's good
There
Keep going
Over there?
Yes?
Come on, damnit!
Go! Go!
You're almost there
That's it.
Don't touch me
I can manage on my own
Fred
The cable
Karine!
Check your rope
and keep going slowly
Don't panic
Hurry up!
It's not gonna hold
Keep going
Continue
Hurry!
Go!
Karine!
Hurry!
Fred!
Karine!
Hold on
Keep holding on
Grab this
Fred! I'm coming
Catch
Shit!
Fred
Fred!
Catch!
Hold it
Pull
Hang on
Pull! Pull!
Hurry!
Don't let it go
It's OK! It's OK!
I've got you! I've got you!
Now, what will we do?
I don't know
We keep going
We have no choice
We must finish the trail before nightfall
I don't understand
can't we just go down
No, not like this
It would be climbing
And we're not equipped for that
Was that the only way out?
Yes
We're screwed because of you.
Get us out of this shithole!
And what's your idea?
Nobody asked you to come!
It's Ok
It's gonna be alright, no need
to yell at eachother.
Ok! Let's move
Shit!
What's wrong?
The lifeline snapped
It's alright Loic
It gets easier
Shit
Loic are you okey?
Calm down
Breathe. Calm down. All is ok.
Damn
How does it look like up there?
Looks like we can make it
I'll come with you
Ok
Ok, Loic
Loic listen to me, you twat
What?
You're a coward
cow... what?
The small slings
attach them to the anchor
I can't get it
I'll help you
There
It's done
Now you're safe
Now attach your harness
No, no, I can't
We'll pull you up. Don't move.
Ok
Loic?
Loic okey?
Are you okey?
We'll go up and then use the tyrolean
Ok
You're tired. Try to relax
And above all, don't move.
Slow down, there's no pitons
If you fall...
I won't
Hurry
We must go around the cliff
Let's tie the rope
Loic, Loic?
Remember what Fred said?
I don't care.
You tell him
Listen
Loic... Loic... Loic
Loosen your grip
Loic, right there
There's nothing, There is nothing here
Loic
Look, how I'm attached
Look, look.
That's it, That's it
It's broken, there's nothing here
Hurry
We'll pull him up from the other side
Ok
Let's go through the forest
It'll be faster
What are they doing?
You see them or what?
Loic calm down
There
Come on! Fred!
I can't follow you
Come
Give me your hand
Go ahead, ok?
Let the rope hold you
Holy shit!
Calm down!
No
It's okey
I knew it was closed.
What?
Let go now
I knew the trail was closed
Let go
Are you crazy?
I thought it'd be OK
Loic!
I screwed up. Damn!
I'll save you
Fuck!
Wait, Let's each pull one side
Go on
I'll come get you
Fred! Fred!
Stop moving
Loic stop moving
I beg you stop
Go help them
Guillaume.
Hurry
But your leg!
Go get them
Hurry
Shit!
Go!
Go! Go!
Give me your hand!
Pull me up
Help me Guillaume!
Look at me, we're not gonna fall
If you stop moving we're
not going to fall
Do you trust me?
Fred!
Chloe please tell Loic to calm down
Help me Chloe
Look at me
I can't see you
I can't
Fred, I can't
Help!
Rope
Go on climb up
It's Fred
Go on, climb!
Karine?
Chloe hurry
I'm cold
Put this on
Let's move now!
Karine?
Shit!
Fred!
Fred?
Fred? Fred?
Fred!
You're sure he was here?
Yes, damn it!
There's blood.
What was that?
It was impossible to open
Fred!
Fred! Fred!
It will be dark soon
Who has the flares?
Not me
Oh fuck
It's in my bag, and Fred got it
What the hell?
You got a problem?
Yes!
The trail was closed, and
there's nothing here
I'm sure he knew about it.
Okey, okey
It will be dark soon
We must go, Fred will find us
What if he's lost?
You just don't give a damn, do you?
We've almost died there, so
don't tell me i don't give a damn
Since the beggining you didn't
worry about shit
Exactly! I'm here for Chloe
Stop!
We'll go find Fred, period!
Fred!
Fred
Fred?
Why am I even here?
Like you don't know
I warn you, when we go down
you'll forget about Chloe
Except Chloe will not forget
yeah right
fucking wanker
come on, go
Stop it!
Just stop
What's wrong?
Chloe?
Chloe!
Chloe answer!
Can you hear us?
Are you okey?
Are you alright?
Chloe, where are you?
Karine?
What are you doing? Shit!
What is that?
Chloe
I see her
Is she alright?
Are you with her?
Is she hurt?
Answer!
Tell us what's happening?
I'm fine
but I can't move
Help me
You have to pull it
wait
Karine
Karine look at me
Pull it out
Loic
Karine
Do it
Loic
Don't touch me
Loic... Loic...
Someone's out there.
Go get him.
Karine, hurry
Do it
Do it!
Karine
We'll find Fred, and go home
Don't worry
There were stakes everywhere.
It was... a poacher's trap
I don't get it
They hunt anything here?
Hunt what?
Karine what can you do?
Karine, what do we do?
We must find help. Karine!
NO... no...
Look at me
Karine look at me
You can't give up, you hear me
Come on
Look at me
Look at me, look at me
Look, everything will be ok
Look
We'll sing
We are young
We run green
Keep our teeth
Nice and clean
See our friends
See the sights
Feel alright
OK? OK?
We'll tie ourselves, and
go along the forest
Ok
Ok we'll do that
Ok?
I'll tie the rope
you go ahead
keep the rope stretched
We go together
Be careful where you stand
Fred?
- Fred?
Fred!
Fred?
Fred? Fred!
Karine?
Karine!
What is it?
Karine! Karine!
Guillaume, hurry!
Chloe!
No! Karine!
Karine...
Karine
Loïc!
Guillaume!
Karine!
Karine?
Karine! Karine!
Chloe!
Stay there, stay there.
Karine!
Don't go there.
Stop!
Karine!
Answer me!
Karine...
Don't stay here, Come!
Come on!
No! Karine! No.
Come come
Shouldn't we do something?
She'll eventually die of cold.
We must find the zip line
Here we go.
Chloe come on
Come
Let's go
Wait
What's that?
It's nothing
Watch your steps there
No choice
Have you seen how's Chloe!
We made a mistake coming up here
Let's go
Looks like someone is there
hush
Fred!
We need to bandage his wounds
Breathe.
Stay with me.
Fred! Fred!
Fred, look at me.
We can't stay here
We need to get away
Not without the flares.
We must return to get the backpack
Fuck!
I'm not going back in there.
I'll go
Anton
Hurry up
What are you doing?
He's alone
Who?
The poacher. He sleeps in a cage.
There are heads
There are bodies everywhere
You got the flares?
Inside
Give me that
I'll carry it.
Give it to me!
Come on Chloe
Huh?
Too bad for him.
What have you done?
He's fucked in this shit
You're sick!
- Chloe?
Chloe? Chloe?
Look at me, Chloe?
Chloe?
Wake up
Look at me
We'll get out of here
Agree Ok?
Try to free yourself
I'm almost out
Go on
Pull!
No... No... No...
NO!
Don't touch her!
Don't touch her! Stop!
Stop! Let her go!
Chloe
Guillaume
Chloe! Chloe!
Guillaume!
Chloe!
Chloe No! NO!
No!
Guillaume!
Chloe!
Chloe! Chloe!
Come here
Come here take me
Here, here, take me
Let her go, take me!
Let her go!
Anton.
His name is Anton!
Chloe talk to him
Come let me out Chloe
Did he hurt you?
We have to find a weapon
We've got to go
Chloe He'll be back.
We have to find the zip line
Take it
We need to find Loic
The zip line
Loic!
Oh no!
Help! Help!
Help!
Loic?
Chloe!
Loic!
Help!
Give me your hand!
Chloe hold me
Chloe!
Give me your hand.
Grab
other hand too, go
Got it
Pull
Come on
Luic
Come on, damn it
Loic!
Come on just pull
Pull, damn it
No. No. No.
Chloe I can't hold on
No!
Don't give up
No...
No.
Loic!
Anton!
NO!
No...
An... ton.
The body of Loic Riveaux was found at
the foot of Veliki in the massive Risnjak...
Chloe, Karine, Fred, and Guillaume
are still missing...
Anton Zomarech kidnapped at age 5
has never been found.
To this day 3270 disappearances
remain unexplained in the Balkans.