(Ig) Everyone in town always
took me for an outsider.
I didn't care.
The only thing that
mattered was her.
She was my garden of Eden.
And God knows how beautiful
it was until that night.
You know, no one is born evil.
The devil himself
was a fallen angel.
But sometimes when
you go through hell...
the only way out is to
walk deeper into the fire.
(Merrin) Are you horny?
(Ig) Yeah, I'm getting warmer.
Oh. Fine.
(Laughs) No.
Yes.
(Kissing)
I'm gonna love you for
the rest of my life.
Just love me for
the rest of mine.
♪ ♪
(Deep rumbling)
(Music plays)
(Protestors shouting)
(Reporter #2) Oh, here he is.
(Music slows down)
(Protester) Murderer!
(Shouting)
(Reporter #1)
Hey, Ig, what does it feel
like to get away with murder?
(Reporter #3) Do you
want to comment on the fire at
the lab in Tacoma last night?
(Reporter #2)
Have you heard that the
police have a new witness?
(Protester)
You should ask God to save your
soul for what you did to her!
I should ask the Devil to punish
whoever the fuck killed her.
♪ ♪
(Connect tone)
Hi, this is Lee Tourneau,
leave a message.
Hi, Lee, please can you
meet me at my parents' house
in like half an hour?
I really need to talk to you.
And start picking up
your phone, man. Come on.
♪ ♪
Are you proud of me, Mom?
I'm so famous people
follow me everywhere I go.
(Lydia) Come inside, sweetie.
(Derrick) You just can't
talk to those reporters.
They'll take whatever you say
and just twist it around.
But if I don't talk
to them, it looks like
I have something
to hide. Right?
And how's Lee
working out for you?
I mean, you still think
he's up to the job?
Yes. No, he's keeping me
out of jail at least for the
time being... and that's got
to be some kind of triumph.
(Derrick) All right, look,
I know he's an old friend of
yours... but you don't have to
settle for a public defender.
I've got the money. I will hire
you the best lawyer in Seattle.
Dad, every other lawyer we
talked to wanted me to take a
plea. Lee is the only one who
believes I'm innocent.
Just don't talk to any
more reporters, please.
And don't admit anything.
I don't have anything
to admit to, Dad.
Look, honey, we don't
care what happened.
You're our son.
That's all that matters.
Oh, sit back down, Ig.
No, if you think for a second...
that I might have killed her,
then why are you protecting me?
Because if I did anything to
her, then I'm a fucking monster.
(Terry) Shoot.
I got it, Mom.
(Derrick) Thanks, Ter.
(Trumpet plays)
(Inhale)
Ig, look, I...
I don't have to go back
on the road next week
if you don't want me to.
Man, you gotta earn a living.
I'll sort things out.
(Lee) Except I need
you to stay, Terry.
The whole family's gotta put
up a united front for Ig.
- Hey, buddy.
- How's it going?
- Lee.
- Hey.
(Lydia) Lee,
if you want some food,
we have a lot of
leftovers from lunch.
Oh, I grabbed something on the
way over, Mrs. P. Thank you.
How you guys doing?
Yeah, Lee, what happened
at the lab in Tacoma?
One of the reporters this
morning told me it burned down.
Yeah, all the samples from
Merrin's body was destroyed.
It's gonna be tough to recover
any blood or DNA at this point.
But that's a fucking disaster
for us, right? I mean,
that means there's no evidence
that anyone else killed her.
- It's not ideal...
- Fuck.
...but I think it's too soon
to panic at this point.
And who is this new witness?
What is that?
I'm trying to figure
that out today and I'm
also getting your confession
to the police thrown out.
Yeah, good. You know I never
confessed to them. They're just
looking for any way to put me
away for the rest of my life.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, it's okay.
Lee can fix anything, right?
We'll see about that.
But you know, you don't
have to convince me.
Ig, I believe you.
If you don't think I'm
capable of murder...
just put me in a room with the
guy who really killed her.
(Squealing tires)
(Men chatting and laughing)
(O'Hara) A little early for you
to start drinking, ain't it, Ig?
They put me on leave at the
station. Apparently, most
commuters don't like it when
their Dj's a murder suspect.
(O'Hara)
Yeah, so maybe you should
take your business elsewhere.
No offense, but you make the
other customers uncomfortable.
You telling me I make these
guys feel uncomfortable?
(Glenna)
Alright, come on. Iggy deserves
a drink as much as anybody.
Thank you.
More than anybody.
Sorry you have to,
like, stand up for me
all the time now, Glenna.
Listen, Ig, if you're looking
for a friendlier place
to grab a drink,
I get off at five.
I appreciate the
offer, but I should-
I'm probably better off,
like, drinking alone.
(Father Mould) Thank you
all for coming tonight to pay
tribute to our dear girl Merrin.
I know that Dale would like to
say a few words to welcome you.
(Dale) Well...
(Clears throat)
it's...
It's real good to
see you all here.
The truth is, I haven't
felt much like...
getting out of bed in the
mornings since Merrin...
Ig Perrish...
he murdered her and he is
still walking the streets.
I treated him like a son for
practically all his life...
And then he
killed my little...
my little girl.
As long as he is free,
there is no way that her
soul can be laid to rest.
So let us all bow
our heads in prayer.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you, everybody.
(Breaking bottle)
Fuck.
(Glenna) Christ, Ig.
Leave me alone, Glenna.
What are you thinking
coming out here?
People could have seen you.
She went to church
every fucking Sunday!
She wore a cross
around her neck.
And did it make any difference?
No. God turned a blind eye
and let her die out
here alone and afraid.
Come on.
(Ig) Fucking God!
- Come on, Ig.
(Ig) For whatever reason,
in this crazy fucked up world,
I was being punished.
When they looked at
me, they saw a devil.
And maybe I did too.
(Thunder)
And now I had to look the part.
♪ ♪
What the fuck?
What?
(Crack)
Geez!
(Evil laugh)
Let me have him!
Send him down.
Give him to me now!
You were in the bathroom
for a long time.
You still drunk?
How do I look? I mean, do
you notice anything unusual?
You mean horns?
Shit, so they're real?
Fuck!
Hey, Ig?
Can I...
Can I have another donut?
Why are you asking me?
One, two, three, four...
five, six.
Do you think it'd be okay
if I had six more donuts?
Yeah. Do whatever you like.
Thank you.
I didn't like it.
My stomach hurts.
Should I have another one?
Why will you have another if
your stomach hurts, Glenna?
Because I wanna get really fat.
I'm worthless anyways.
Nobody will screw me without
being totally drunk.
Everybody in this town
thinks that I'm trash.
Come on, Glenna.
That's not true.
You wouldn't have screwed me
if you weren't blind drunk.
Well...
And I know you were thinking
about Merrin the whole time.
Glenna, you know, I have
no excuse for last night.
I just need to know if I can
eat the rest of this box.
Yeah, go ahead.
Pig out.
I think I'm just
gonna go, Glenna.
Yeah. Thank you.
All right.
♪ ♪
(Loud screaming)
(Mary) Be quiet!
I said stop it!
Stop it and read your book.
(Ig) Hi.
(Receptionist)
What can I do for you?
Yeah, I need Dr. Renald
to look at something.
Well...
that sure doesn't look right.
I'm gonna need you to
fill out some forms.
(Loud screaming)
Stop it.
I said be quiet!
Go over there and
read your book.
(Ig) Growth.
You know, for what it's worth...
I'd like to kick my daughter
right in her spoiled ass.
Do you think I should?
No, of course not. Of course.
Why would you even ask me that?
(Loud screaming)
Maybe I should just leave
her here and drive away.
Divorce my husband.
I could fuck my golf pro again.
(Laughs)
Excuse me?
I'd never been with
a jigaboo before.
But it's true what they
say about black cocks.
I call it my five iron.
(Laughs)
Here you go.
(Receptionist)I feel like I
have to yell at that girl's
mother. I know it's not her
fault that her daughter's
a screechy puke,
but really now.
Go ahead. Why not?
(Receptionist) Ma'am? Do you
think you could show some
fucking consideration and take
your daughter out of here
so we don't have to
listen to her screaming?
What did you just say to me?
I said you should take that
screeching pig of yours
by the hair and drag her
the fuck out of here.
Fuck you!
Shut the hell up, you
dried up old twat!
(Ig) Hey, you don't
want to do this in front
of your daughter.
Come on.
(Loud moaning)
(Loud screaming)
(Little Girl) I hate
Mommy. I wanna burn her in
her bed with matches. I wanna
burn her up all up gone!
You may want to stop
pumping that now.
(Nurse Delilah) Sorry.
My boyfriend's seeing
this girl on the side.
She works at the Bradlees
down by the Marina.
I'm thinking on my lunch
hour I should drive over there
and key her Saab. And put
dog shit on the driver's seat.
Or maybe I should just take
a dump on the seat myself.
(Dr. Renald) Ignatius Perrish.
Long time no see.
Hey.
So, what brings you
in here this morning?
Well, can you see anything
that might be wrong with me?
You mean besides your horns?
Well, no, that's
exactly what I mean.
So you can see them?
Well, shouldn't you both
be shocked or something?
I think if I saw someone with
horns, I'd piss down my leg.
Well, they're kinda
hard to remember.
I mean, every time I look
away from you for a second...
I kinda forget that
you even have them.
Okay, but what are they?
I mean, do you, you know...
do you think they could
they be cancerous?
Could they be some weird
tumor or something?
Well, they're definitely
cause for concern.
They look inflamed.
Do they hurt?
Oh! Yes, like hell.
(Laughs)
All right. You know how
I think we should proceed?
How?
I think I should grind me up
some OxyContin and have a little
snort. I mean, I'd share. We
could get fucked up together.
No! Please, can you just focus
on my problem for a second?
Okay. I'm gonna
try, but it's hard.
I keep thinking about
this girl, Nancy...
Oh God.
That my daughter hangs out with.
God, I want her ass so bad.
Christ, can you just-
How are we gonna deal
with these things on my head?
You fucking patients, all you
care about is yourselves.
Listen, Doctor, just saw
the goddamn horns off.
You sure this is
gonna work, right?
Not at all, actually,
but it'll be fun to try.
What?
(Nurse Delilah)
Now just breathe normally.
(Muffled)
What? No. Okay.
Doctor, please, if you're not
sure about we can just...
It'll be okay. Just breathe.
Just breathe.
Everything's gonna be fine.
That's right.
(Hymn singing)
Have you seen
that girl before?
What's she doing?
I think it's Morse code.
And she's telling you to stop
checking her legs out in
church or she's gonna
give you a black eye.
(Father Mould)
Go forth in peace.
♪ ♪
Eat my guts, Glenna!
Here we go.
Run, run, run!
(Explosion)
Sorry, Scruffy.
(Laughter)
Oh. Oh, yeah.
You sick Fuck.
(Explosion)
Yeah, spread it's legs.
(Eric) Yeah, put them
in one by one, guys.
(Ig) I'm telling you, she
was doing Morse code.
She was sending me a message.
(Eric) Yeah, I didn't even
think you liked girls, Ig.
Always thought
you were a fag.
Shut up, Meatbag.
(Glenna) What's
so special about her?
I mean, it's like y'all
never saw a girl before?
(nervous laughter)
(Terry) You guys are gonna
wanna find cover or else you'll
all be wearing turkey dinner.
Hey, get the fuck out.
What's wrong? What?
(Terry) Shit.
Maybe it got wet.
Give me the lighter. Sometimes
it messes up and stuff.
(Explosion)
(Laughter)
Now you're literally Meatbag.
- Oh, man.
- Oh, shit.
Never looked better.
So what are we
gonna blow up now?
We're not blowing
up anything else today.
I'm saving my last cherry
for something special.
Come on, Eric. Don't be a dick.
The only way I'm giving
up this last cherry bomb...
is if one of you homos
climbs in that shopping cart...
and rides it
down the log ramp.
I'll do it, Meatbag.
Naked.
I'm gonna do it, Eric.
Sure you are.
(Glenna) Igs, don't. Don't!
Don't be ridiculous.
You don't have to do this.
(Eric) You'll get a cherry.
Come on, man.
One left.
(Glenna) Don't do this, please.
You're gonna kill yourself.
(Terry) Dude, if you get hurt,
Mom's gonna fucking kill me.
No. No, I can't watch.
Oh, shit!
Ig! Ig! Ig! Ig!
Oh, my god, he's
hit his head on a log.
Do something.
Do something!
Where are they?
They should be up by now.
(Glenna) Oh my...
(Sobs)
Oh, my god!
(Coughing)
- Iggy!
- Ig! Ig!
Ig.
Hey, Terry, your brother
here's a total fucking lunatic.
You fucking idiot! If Lee hadn't
been here to pull you out...
(Eric) Did you do
mouth-to-mouth, faggot?
Shut up.
Now give me the cherry.
No way. I said ride down naked.
You wore tighty
whities and sneakers.
Eric!
Give him the fucking cherry.
So, you like that
new girl in church?
I don't know her yet.
(Lee) I like her too.
She's not like all the
other girls around here.
I mean, she's
not like Glenna.
She gives handjobs to
your brother and Eric...
because she thinks that's the
only way guys will like her.
But they just
think she's trash.
Maybe I should
give her the cross.
I mean, I am the
one who fixed it.
No! You can't do that.
Okay. What will
you give me for it?
Do you want my cherry bomb?
♪ ♪
(Inhale)
(Merrin) You
fixed my cross.
Yeah.
Did something, you
know, happen to your mom?
(Merrin) She died last year.
That's why my dad
and I moved here.
(Ig) Really?
How did she...
She had cancer.
Is it okay if we don't
talk about it anymore?
Yeah. Yeah, I understand.
Thanks again for
fixing my cross.
Ig!
Did you give the
cherry bomb to Lee?
What happened?
It blew up in his hand!
What?
(Screams)(Doctor)
Let's get him in exam room
number two.
Let's operate right away.
Where is he?
He's in that room.
Hey, look on the bright side.
I still got eight fingers.
I'm sorry.
I wish I never gave you the...
You're not going to tell your
mom who gave you the
cherry bomb, right?
Don't worry about it.
Everything's gonna be fine.
I'm glad one good
thing happened today.
Where are you taking me?
Come on.
Can't wait to show you this.
Wow.
Come on, come on, come on.
Don't fall off.
- Okay.
- Come on, come on!
Don't trip on any roots, okay?
Are you sure you
know where you're going?
You see?
Wow.
How did you find this place?
Just walking through
the woods one day.
Come on.
This is where I come
when I want to be alone.
So now I know
where to find you.
We've got a great hiding
spot where you can hide food...
blankets, anything
else you want to hide.
So you're a Bowie fan too.
Yeah.
I didn't tell you the truth.
Lee's the one who
fixed your cross.
He wanted to give
it back to you, but...
I traded him the
cherry bomb instead.
So it's all my fault.
How is it your fault?
Because if he
gave it back to you,
then he would've
been the one who...
You think you traded
me for the cherry bomb?
You think that's
how things work?
I left it there for you.
It wasn't an accident.
I wanted you to find
it and give it back to me.
I wanted you to
be the one who...
Who what?
♪ ♪
What?
Aw, fuck!
(Loud moaning)
What the hell is going on here?
Hey!
I was gonna operate, but
I sorta got distracted.
We asked you if we
could have sex instead
and you said it was okay.
How could I possibly
say it was okay?
I was under anesthesia.
You sort of nodded your head.
We thought it was okay.
(Loud moaning)
Father Mould?
Get away from me.
Get away.
Please, leave me alone!
No, no, no, no. I'm not here to
hurt you. Please.
Tell me what I have
to do to stop this.
How do I make them go away?
You killed that
innocent girl Merrin.
There's nothing I can do.
No, I No, except
I didn't kill her!
Please, leave me alone!
I didn't kill her,
Father, and now people
are telling me all these
things I don't want to hear.
I mean, there must be
a prayer you can say.
I'll try anything.
You did this to yourself.
What?
You turned away from God.
You cast yourself
into the darkness.
But I didn't do anything wrong.
Every devil used to be an angel.
And now you've fallen
from grace forever.
When Satan was
banished from Heaven...
he was cursed to crawl
the earth like a snake.
There's no hope for you.
What? So that's it? There's
nothing you can do for me?
I've got a rope in
that shed over there.
I could take you out to that
tree where Merrin died and I...
I could string you up.
Unless you'd like to do the
decent thing and hang yourself.
What do you say?
Lee.
Hey.
Everyone in this town
is going fucking crazy.
Yeah, the town's
always been crazy.
No, but I think it's because
of me and these goddamn horns.
Yeah.
Wait, what?
The horns.
These horns.
What are you talking about?
Wait, can't you see them?
Are you high right now?
You been hanging out with Terry?
So maybe...
maybe the horns just
don't work on good people.
Yeah, I think you've been
under an inhuman amount
of stress recently.
And maybe you're just starting
to go a little, you know-
A little, oh, cuckoo.
But if I am this crazy and
I can imagine all this...
then I could easily have got so
drunk that I blacked out that
night and killed Merrin and
just forgot all about it, right?
Mom?
(Hair dryer)
Well, I didn't know
you were coming.
I didn't know where
else to go, Mom.
Something really bad
is happening to me.
Oh, sweetheart.
Why couldn't you
go somewhere else?
What?
What do you mean?
I don't want to hear
about all your problems.
I don't want to know.
Mom.
Sometimes when you talk,
I just want to sing.
La, la, la, la, la, la!
What are you doing? Mom!
I wanna hold my breath
until you just go away!
Ar-Jesus Christ,
Mom, don't Don't!
Stop it!
I want to write you a letter,
a really nice letter...
about how much Dad
and I love you...
and how great it would be for
both of us if you would just go.
But where?
Where can I go?
I don't know. Didn't you always
want to go hiking in Alaska?
Didn't you want to go to
Vietnam to teach English?
Those were things
Merrin and I were
gonna do together.
You know that.
I don't care where you go. Just
as long as I don't have to see
you. Because every time I see
you, it just makes me so...
unhappy.
I just want to be happy
again, sweetheart.
No, I understand.
And I don't want you
to be my son anymore.
Oh.
Are you gonna go away?
(Piano music)
Ig.
I thought I heard you come in.
Yeah, okay, let me walk
you through this, Dad.
This is the part where you
tell me something awful...
you've been keeping to yourself.
Just say it, we'll
get it out of the way.
I don't know why you
turned out like this.
With your brother, it's easier.
We could always
play music together.
But with you, I never
know what to say to you.
Well, that's not bad,
all things considered.
I think about Merrin.
What a beautiful girl she was.
I loved her.
You know, in a way.
I envied you.
I was never in
love with anyone
the way you two were in
love with each other.
You couldn't hear her
laugh without smiling.
It was like music.
And when I think about
what you did to her...
And you never thought maybe...
just maybe that I didn't do it?
Of course not.
You're trying to get
away with murder.
And the worst part is,
I'm helping you do it.
What? What do
you mean by that?
I went to college
with the guy that runs
the state forensics lab.
Dad, are you telling me
that you got your friend to
set that fire at the lab?
When the world comes for my
son with the knives out...
it's my job to stand in the way.
And if you went to jail...
Dad, the evidence you got
burned up could have saved me.
How could you do it?
She was one of the best
people I ever knew!
She was my favorite
thing about you.
Yeah, me, too.
So if you knew how
much I loved her
then how could you ever
believe I'd killed her?
Isn't that why you killed her?
Because you loved her so much...
and you lost her.
Way more people kill out
of love than out of hate.
(Sobs)
♪ ♪
(Lee) What's going on, Ig?
You go home like I asked you to?
(Ig) Yeah, I did that and it
was very enlightening. Did you
know that my dad got his friend
to start the fire in the lab?
(Lee) Hypothetically,
if I did know,
I would legally be required
to tell the police.
But maybe, the fire was a
blessing in disguise.
How? How is it a fucking
blessing? If the lab hadn't
burned down, that evidence
would have cleared me, Lee.
Okay, okay, I know. It's rough
for you staying at your house
right now. Why don't you just
take the keys to my place.
You can crash on the couch.
No, you know what? I'm fine.
I've actually got a lot to do.
I've gotta figure out
who really killed Merrin
and get him to confess.
(Lee) How you
planning to do that?
Lately, I can be pretty
fucking persuasive.
Hey, Ig, nice look for you.
Showing your true nature?
(Ig) You know, I'd
appreciate it if you guys
would all just fuck off.
(Reporter #4) Come on,
Ig, admit you killed her.
It'd be such a
huge scoop for me.
Oh, good to know your
journalistic integrity is
fucking unimpeachable.
Hey, you confess to me, I can
get out of stupid local news.
You know what, I got an idea.
How about you guys beat the
shit out of each other...
and the winner gets an
exclusive interview with me.
♪ ♪
(O'Hara) Thought I told
you I don't want you coming
around here no more, Ig.
Jesus Christ!
Al, you don't want to do that.
You'll get arrested.
I don't give a flying
fuck if I get arrested.
But why don't you
get me a whiskey?
You know you want the money.
What I really want...
is to burn this place down
and collect the insurance.
Well, can you not burn
down the bar right now?
I need your help with something.
If anyone knows anything
about who killed Merrin...
you're gonna have
to tell me now.
The only thing I ever
killed was a couple of dogs.
I run a dog fighting ring
out of a supply room back there.
Jesus, Al, I don't
want to know that.
(Rob) I've been unemployed for
three months and I hate my life
so yeah, I can sure understand
wanting to kill someone.
(Ig) No, Rob, that's
not what I meant. Oh.
(Barfly) I really want
to show everybody my dick.
Oh! Don't.
I want that all the time.
(Stan) The only thing I know
is I got a cousin who's a cop.
He knows who the new witness is.
It's a waitress who served you
the night Merrin got killed.
Said she saw you drive
back to the restaurant and
drag Merrin into your car.
Thanks a lot, Stan.
(Whoosh)
♪ ♪
Hey, my interview!
Okay.
Okay, guys, so...
you're gonna come tomorrow night
to the diner at about 9:00.
I will have hopefully
done the deed by then...
and then we can go
out and celebrate.
(Terry) Fuck yeah. You
want me to bring any goodies?
Ehm...
No, I think me and Merrin
are gonna be happy enough
tomorrow night without
stimulants, I hope.
Yeah, well, I'm a musician and
we always need stimulants.
I understand that.
And I am a state employee
subject to random drug testing.
Sure you're not
rushing into this?
Rushing into it?
Dude, how am I rushing into it?
We've been going out
since we were kids.
(Veronica) Hi.
- Hey.
Hey.
Oh, what's-
is everything all right?
Hey, what's wrong, Merrin?
I don't really know
how to say this.
I'm just gonna go
ahead and say it.
I'm moving to Los Angeles.
Are you kidding?
That's great.
Like, I can get a
leave of absence from the
radio station easy.
I want a change of scene too.
It's not what I'm talking about.
I think that we need to
stop seeing each other.
(Veronica) Hey, lovebirds...
you guys ready to order?
Oh, I don't think we've
quite decided yet.
Okay. Well, I'll come back.
I don't understand.
I thought everything
was going great.
Well, it's just that we haven't
had a chance to ever be apart.
And I've never had the
chance to think about
what I want for my life.
Well, okay, but I know
what I want. I want the
life we've been dreaming
about since we were kids.
But that's the problem.
We've been dreaming about
that since we were kids.
And we're adults now. We
need to start being practical.
I don't know what
you mean by that.
I don't want to
ever be the reason for
any of your regrets, Ig.
But how many times have we
talked about getting married?
I mean, how many times
have we talked about
what we're going
to name our kids?
I'm not even sure if
I want to have kids!
What! Well, you
sounded pretty into it the
last 8,000 times
we talked about it!
How many girls
have you been with?
You know the answer to that.
Just me.
Yeah.
No one does that, Ig.
No one on the whole
planet does that.
You need to see other
people so you can figure out
if I am the one that
you want to be with.
But I don't want to
see other people.
(Thunder)
Is that what you want?
Are you in love
with somebody else?
And how far has it gone?
Answer me!
How far has it gone?
Have you fucked him already?
Please, Ig.
No! Tell me! Tell me
everything that happened.
I need to know.
Have you fucked him already?
Why are you asking me this?
Because I want to know!
I want to know everything.
It's gonna make it easier
for me to hate you!
You deserve better.
Finally, something we agree on.
Please, I'm gonna be lost.
I'm not in love
with you anymore.
Come on, please. We're not
done talking about this.
Please, Ig.
Please.
Yeah, what?
What are you looking at?
(Manager) Sir, sir, sir.
We're gonna have to ask
you and your wife to leave.
Yeah? She's not my wife. She's
just someone I used to fuck.
Hey, easy.
(Puts money down)
Come on.
Hey, Ig, whoa. How'd it go?
You already proposed?
The party's over, Terry.
Go home.
What the hell are you talking
about? Hey, hey! I thought
we were gonna celebrate
tonight. What's going on?
(Car starts)
Iggy, what the
fuck are you doing? Hey!
Merrin, you all right?
(Eric) Good morning, Ig.
Can you roll down the
window so we can talk?
Hey, Meatbag, what's up?
When's the last time
you saw Merrin, Ig?
What's happened to her, Eric?
(Sturtz) What makes you think
something happened to her?
Oh, fuck.
It's all my fault.
Anything that happened to her,
it's all my fucking fault.
(Veronica) So, do you guys want
dessert? Can I get you dessert?
I got a cherry pie.
(Laughs)
Oh, I gotta go.
You could sit wherever you want.
Oh, wait, you're that guy.
Ig Perrish.
Yeah.
I've heard you've been telling
lies about me to the police.
Yeah, I have.
And you know, I don't even feel
a little bit bad about it.
You want to tell me exactly
what you said to them?
Well, I told them that you're
girlfriend forgot her jacket
so I followed her into
the parking lot and I saw you
drive back and scream that
you were gonna kill her.
But you know that's not true.
And that I saw you drag
her into your car...
and then you drove off.
What? Why the hell
would you say all that?
Because I want to be in
all the newspapers and on TV.
I wanna be the star
witness at your trial.
I'm pretty enough
to be on TV right?
Especially if I get my tits
lifted the way that I want.
You're just a
fucking crazy liar!
I know I am.
I'm so bad. I'm bad.
Sometimes when people
ask me what you did...
I say that after you
beat her brains in...
that then you turned her over
and you fucked her in the ass.
You should see their
faces when I say that.
Everybody loves a
good sex murder.
You're insane. And my
brother was here that night
and he saw me leave alone.
I'm gonna release
my own sex tape.
And I'm gonna get
a reality show.
I'm gonna be in US
magazine, smiling.
♪ ♪
Ig!
Oh, Hey, Glenna.
How's it going?
How do you think it's going?
Because it's going
worse than that.
- (Burp)
- You all right?
Whoa. Excuse me.
I think I had something
bad this morning.
Yeah, you did.
I was there.
What? You mean last night?
No, this morning.
You don't remember any of that?
Wow.
No, I must have been
really drunk still.
Why don't you let me suck
your cock in the men's room?
I would really like that.
And I bet it would
make you feel better.
No, Glenna.
Thanks, but not right now.
The thing is, Ig...
I've always been
in love with you.
Since we were kids.
But I guess you
knew that, right?
I guess I did kinda know that.
Yeah.
God, it's just I just wish
that I could leave this town.
And just...
What's stopping you?
You.
Me? No.
It can't be me.
Right? No. Put this shithole
town in your rear view mirror
and do something
good for yourself.
Hey, go.
(Cigarette lighter)
(Terry) Ig, I didn't
know you were here.
Jesus Christ, what the
fuck is on your head?
They're horns, crazy story.
Listen, Terry...
I need you to help me.
No, fucking just
listen to me, Terry.
The waitress from the diner,
okay, she is going to the
cops and telling them that
she saw me drag Merrin into
my car and drive away from
the diner that night.
Jesus, I know for a
fact that's not true.
Well, yeah, you know
that, and I know that
but how the hell are
we gonna prove that?
I mean, Merrin left the
diner with me that night.
What do you mean, she
left the diner with you?
You told me you never saw
her that night at all.
I didn't kill her, Ig.
I would never hurt her. I...
What are you
talking about, Terry?
I was just too scared.
(Punch)
Fuck!
Tell me, Terry!
Okay!
So, what just happened
with you and Ig?
I don't want to talk about it.
Are you sure?
I mean, you're shaking.
Look at you.
You're a mess.
Hey, hey, hey.
Why don't you take one of these.
Just take one.
They're fun. Take the edge off.
I don't want to.
I need to release what
I'm feeling tonight.
God, you're beautiful.
You know that?
Can you pull over?
I need to get out of the car.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, I didn't...
Look, it's the end of the
world out there. Why don't...
I wanna go for a walk.
Merrin, Are you trying to
get yourself killed? Hang on.
Thanks for the ride, Terry.
Come back!
I'm fine now, I promise, okay?
Merrin!
Don't be ridiculous.
Where are you going?
I'll wait for you!
(Turns radio off)
What the fuck?
Merrin.
Merrin!
You fuck!
How could you?
What did you do to her?
Do you even fucking remember
what you did to her?
I didn't kill her.
I loved Merrin too.
Well, if you didn't
kill her, then who did?
(Siren)
Oh, fuck!
(Eric) We got a call on
the radio about some kind
of altercation
going on out here.
We got a pretty good
idea who's responsible.
Listen to me, Eric,
this is all my fault.
(Man) Hey, maestro,
break time is over. Let's go.
Go on back inside, Terry, none
of this thing concerns you.
Yeah, go back inside.
Play a fucking song!
You'd better calm down,
Ig. You don't want to be
resisting arrest. We'd be
inclined to use force.
What are you arresting
me for? 'Cause I got into
a fight with my coward
brother? Is that a crime?
The thing is, this club is
across the county line.
Which means we caught you
fleeing jurisdiction.
For God's sake, talk about
the most obvious kind
of trumped up charge. Fuck!
Go back inside.
(Ig) Fuck you, Eric.
(Eric) Fuck me? You fuck!
I wish we could bring
you in for worse.
I wish I could plant
something on you.
Like maybe a piece of her dress.
That way I could put
you away for good.
For God's sake, Eric,
you've known me my whole life.
You know I'd never hurt her.
Bullshit, Ig! You confessed
to me. Everyone in town
saw you fighting with her
the night she was killed!
That's not what happened.
I said whatever happened to
her was my fault because I ran
off on her. I left her alone.
Whatever that waitress
told you is lies.
Hey, listen, you asshole.
I'm gonna make sure
you get punished for
everything you did to her
even if I have to beat you
to death with my own hands.
(Sturtz) Do it, Eric.
Beat him to death.
That'll give me something
to whack off to tonight.
Only I'll be picturing
both of you naked.
Yeah, I like that.
I like to think about
you naked too, Sturtz.
(Ig) What the fuck?
(Siren)
(Eric)You know, Lee might
have sprung you for now, but
we're not gonna let
you out of our sight.
(Lee) Hey, Meatbag,
leave my client alone.
You're trying to make my life
as hard on me as possible?
Hey, Lee, I know who
the new witness is. It's the
waitress from the diner.
She's lying about everything.
Whoa, whoa, what is this now?
Do I gotta keep a leash on you?
Yeah, and Terry drove away
from the diner with Merrin
that night. They drove
off together in his car.
You're saying that Terry was the
last person to see her alive?
Yeah. I don't think he ever
would have done anything
to her but he can't
remember anything from the...
Why is he confessing this to you
all of a sudden?
Because of the horns, Lee!
Oh, my god, Ig. I can't talk
to you when you're like this.
There's no horns.
You're going crazy. Go home.
Why are you wearing
Merrin's cross?
It's not Merrin's. It's mine.
I've had it forever.
You think I'm an idiot?
You think I don't know what
Merrin's cross looks like?
Yeah, it's hers.
She gave it to me.
Why would she do that?
- Ig, it was...
- What?
There's things about
Merrin you don't know.
There's things about Merrin and
me that I haven't told you.
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
for anything to happen.
You were the one she...
Ig, come on.
You're the reason
she was gonna fucking...
We didn't want to hurt you.
If you didn't
want to hurt me you're
doing a fucking lousy job!
Ig, come on.
Ig. Ig, I'm sorry.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck!
(Lee) You like that
new girl in church?
I don't know her yet.
Ig, you like her enough
to get me to fix her cross.
I like her too.
She seems, you know, pure.
(Dogs barking)
(Slithering)
(Knock on door)
(Dale) Get the
hell off my property.
I know that I'm the last person
you want to see right now...
but you're the only person
I can ask about this.
I have got nothing
to say to you.
I should shoot you
right in the heart.
No.
If you really wanted to kill
me, you'd have already done it.
I know that.
These days, I bring out
the worst in people.
What I want is for you
to tell me the truth
about what you did
to my daughter.
And then I want to kill you.
What I need to know is
did Merrin say anything to you
about leaving me or about
being with somebody else?
You got some kind
of nerve. Coming out here
and asking me if my daughter
was unfaithful to you.
But could you...
Are you out of
your goddamn mind?
Look, you're the only
person she would have told
because you're the only one
who loved her like I did.
Don't you fucking dare
say we're the same.
When I was watching the cancer
devour my wife's insides...
the only saving grace was I
thought that was the worst
thing that would ever happen
to me. But boy was I wrong.
Dale, please, you have
to believe me. I loved her.
But now I don't know if I
even really knew who she was.
You think there is
a chance in hell
I am gonna say one word
to you about my daughter?
If you're looking for
forgiveness or compassion
or understanding, go
talk to a goddamn priest!
I know you killed her.
And I hope you die.
I hope you die...
scared and helpless in the
dirt just like my Merrin did.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have come.
Get off my porch or I
swear I will shoot you.
(Squealing tires)
(Slithering)
(Loud grunting)
(Scraping)
Aaahhh!!!
(Hissing)
Fuck.
Sometimes God works
in mysterious ways.
The horns had revealed
so much already.
Now I can use them to find her
killer and set things right.
(Sfx)
(Scream)
(Hissing)
See, vanity doesn't pay.
And it's gonna be a long
time before you can even
try and look pretty again.
You know, you guys really want
to stop following me around.
Telling us what to do now?
Well...
I mean, wouldn't you rather just
suck each other off right here?
What the hell
makes you say that?
Well, you know, ever since
we were kids I kind of
assumed you maybe had to act
so tough 'cause you were
ashamed of yourself?
Was I right?
When I was a kid, I used
to shoplift gay porno mags
from the drug store.
And my dad found them under
my bed and he cracked
me with his belt.
You see, you both been brought
up to believe it's a sin, but...
it's just being human.
That's why I always wanted
to be partnered with Eric.
I think about him all the
time when I'm whacking off.
I wanna kiss you on the mouth
when you talk dirty like that.
♪ ♪
Have fun, officers.
Oh, Wallace.
Come here.
(Snorts)
Hey, Terry.
Ig. I didn't know
you were gonna come by.
How's it going?
What's that snake
doing around your neck?
I made a new friend.
You want a drink?
Maybe something a
little stronger?
No.
No, I wanna keep my
head clear tonight.
But don't let me stop you.
Do as much as you want to do.
Jesus Christ, Terry, how many
drugs are you doing lately?
If you want to know
the truth, I have...
I've had a hard time
staying sober, you know,
ever since Merrin died.
I've actually been on kind
of a bender myself tonight.
Been having a very good time.
That's good.
I'm glad to hear that, Ig.
Shit, look...
I know things have been tough
for you lately, okay? But...
Well, understandably,
but I just...
(Snorts)
But here's where the fun ends.
This is gonna give me
no pleasure at all.
What are you talking about?
Well...
you're my big brother, Terry.
I have always depended on
you to look out for me.
I have always tried to do my
best by you, Ig. You know that.
Except when you saw Merrin lying
under that tree in that dirt...
you didn't call an ambulance
and you didn't call the cops.
You just ran off
and left her there.
Fuck, Ig, she was already
dead, okay? There was nothing
I could do. The cops would
have thought that I killed her.
Even when I got arrested,
you didn't go to them
and tell them the truth.
No, now why would you?
Why would you do that
unless you were guilty...
unless you actually killed her?
Because I'm your fucking
brother, that's why.
You understand if I-
I mean, they would have just
thought I was helping you.
But you never even
tried to help me.
All you wanted to do
was save your own skin.
You are a selfish
motherfucker, Terry.
And I hate you.
Yeah, you know what?
You're so fucking right.
You're right.
I am evil and you
should kill me, Iggy.
That's what you should do.
You should fucking kill me.
I mean, that's what
I deserve, right?
I mean, after what I did,
that's what I fucking deserve.
The way I see it, I have
every right to kill you...
but I think I'm gonna let you
live and make you suffer.
Why don't you just
finish all that off.
What, all of it?
I think I've made myself clear.
Now there's nowhere left to run.
You are gonna see
everything she saw...
and feel what she felt.
And the worst part is...
you're gonna live
through all of it.
(Scream)
Iggy!
Terry?
Terry! Terry! Terry!
Help! Iggy!
Where are you?
Help me! No!
Punishing Terry was the
hardest thing I've ever done.
But forcing him to face
his demons was the only
way I could help him.
(Lee) Jesus Christ, Ig.
I looked for you everywhere.
(Ig) Look, get out of
here before I do something
we're both gonna regret.
(Lee) We gotta move past this.
This is not what Merrin wanted.
So you're the expert on
what Merrin wanted now?
I was never gonna
tell you anything.
No.
So how long was it going
on between you two?
You don't want to know anything.
Oh, I need to understand.
It was just a couple months.
She was moving
out to California.
We wanted to figure out if it
was real before we told anyone.
And so when she got killed,
did you think it was me? Or like
did you think that I found out
about you and lost control?
If I thought you had
anything to do with this,
I wouldn't be helping you.
Okay, well, I don't want
any more of your help.
Yeah, I'm the only one who can
help you. I'm gonna prove that
waitress is lying. I'm gonna get
Terry to confess to the police.
Just fucking go, Lee.
Leave me alone.
And don't fucking touch me!
(Lee) The cross, dude! Fuck!
Are those horns?
Goddamn right, they're horns.
I'm glad you can
finally see them.
So now you have to
tell me the truth.
Merrin's cross can't
protect you anymore.
Why should I tell you anything?
You're not gonna
be able to help it.
I never meant to kill her.
You fuck!
You fuck.
I didn't mean to do it, Ig.
I loved her just as much as you.
I'm the one who fixed her cross.
She should have been with me.
Oh, you sure as shit fooled me.
I always thought you spent your
whole life trying to be good!
I try and control myself.
But you saved my life when
we were kids. You pulled me out
of the water right here. You're
the only reason I'm alive!
It was the stupidest
mistake I ever made.
I should have let you drown.
(Laughs)
Then I'd be with her now.
That's a fucking lie!
(Chokes)
Thank you for coming to see me.
Listen, I think Ig is
gonna propose to me.
Do you know anything about that?
Maybe.
There are some things
that I've learned about
myself recently and...
I know now that I
can never marry Ig.
Why are you telling me this?
Will you come by
the diner later?
I really think it will
help if you're there
when this is all over with.
Of course.
Thank you.
Terry?
(Lee) It's me.
Oh, Lee, wow, you frightened me.
What are you doing out here?
Come on, let's get some dry
clothes on you. I'll
drive you home. Come on.
No, No.
I want to be alone right now.
You'll get sick.
No.
You okay?
Hey, hey, hey.
(Sobs)
Hey.
Everything's okay.
I got you.
What? What are you doing?
There's nobody here.
It's just us.
You're joking?
I mean, we don't have
to pretend anymore.
It's just...
It's fine.
No, No. No. Stop it!
Don't! Don't do that.
Just get off me!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I just...
I've been waiting for
this for such a long time.
I can't believe this
is finally happening.
I need to touch you.
No.
Feel you, honey.
No, look. Listen,
you are Ig's best friend.
You're my friend.
Please, don't you
understand anything?
I understand everything.
Every time the three of
us hang out together...
it's like there's this
elephant in the room.
'Cause we're so clearly
supposed to be together,
but nobody says
anything. You know?
And we stare at each other.
Merrin, we stare at each other.
No, let go of me. Don't!
You don't know the
first thing about what
I'm going through right now.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
What about all the signals
you've been sending me?
What? Signals, what?
Merrin.
Oh my god, you thought that
I broke up with Ig so that...
No. No.
But you know you love me.
I love you. I love you.
I love Ig so much.
(Slap)Ow!
I love him more than the world.
That's the last thing she
said, that she loved me.
Oohh!!
You want to know
what happened, Ig?
Shut up!
Ow! I love... (Slap)
No, no! Please, no!
Stop it! Help! Terry!
(Slap)
I gave her what she asked for.
Ahh!!
Jesus!
Please, Lee!
It's me! It's me!
I fucked her tight little pussy.
No! No.
(Crack)
Then I bashed her
face in with a rock.
(Ig) No!
(Lee) You know what?
Love made devils of us both.
The way I see it, you
confessed to me...
and you were so
overwhelmed with guilt...
that you killed yourself.
(Hissing)
So much... I always
wanted to try this.
It's gonna be fun.
Okay. Hey.
Aaahhh!!!
(Car starts)
(Eric) Mr. Perrish committed
suicide earlier today.
We have recovered his vehicle.
Perrish's lawyer Lee Tourneau
was the only witness at the
scene. Mr. Perrish confessed
his crimes to Mr. Tourneau
and then killed himself.
(TV Reporter) Is there any
validity to the reports that
no body was found
in the vehicle?
(Eric) Any and all reports
originating outside the Gideon
P.D. should be considered
hearsay and conjecture at
this time, nothing more.
No further questions.
Breaking news this evening from
the police force in the Merrin
Williams case. You have heard
tonight that Ig Perrish has
reportedly driven his
vehicle into the bay.
Although as of now, no
body has been recovered.
♪ ♪
Well, one thing I'll
say in my favor...
I am fucking hard to kill.
(Hissing)
(Dogs barking)
(Dale) Why the
hell aren't you dead?
The truth is I don't know the
answer to that question myself.
I have prayed for so
long for you to die...
but when I saw
the news on the TV...
it didn't help one bit.
I didn't kill her, Mr. Williams.
But you know who
did it, don't you?
You gotta tell me.
What will you if I tell you?
You know what I'll do.
But this is my job.
People say you should
always do the right thing.
Sometimes there
is no right thing.
And then...
Well then you just have to pick
the sin you can live with.
Why don't you come inside.
Yesterday I was wandering around
the house and I found this.
I thought maybe I should
give it to the police, but...
that didn't feel right.
She wanted you to have this.
Thank you.
And there's something
I would like to give you.
Here.
Merrin's mother, she gave
this to her just before she...
You know, son, I think...
I think you need this
even more than I do.
I think you need her
to keep you safe.
(Sizzling)
Well now...
I guess maybe that's some
kind of blessing after all.
(Ig) The horns weren't
a curse, but a blessing.
They had guided me this far.
And when I put on her cross...
I could feel her
protecting me again.
♪ ♪
Dear Ig...
you'll never read
this while I'm alive.
I'm not even sure I want you
to read it after I'm dead.
I think you're gonna ask
me to marry you soon.
You don't know how
much I want to say yes.
But I can't.
What?
The thing is, Ig, I'm very sick.
The sort of cancer I have is
the kind that runs in families.
I saw my mother go through it...
and I saw what it
did to my father.
If I tell you I'm sick,
you're just gonna wanna
marry me even more.
And I'll be weak and say yes.
Then you'll give up your future
and be shackled to me...
as I go through
hell and die anyway.
I won't put you through it.
I love you too much.
My plan is to hurt you,
just enough to push you away.
And hopefully one day
you can forgive me...
and you will move
on to someone else.
You'll have children,
grandchildren and
great-grandchildren. You will
go for long walks in the woods.
On one of these walks,
when you're very old...
you'll find yourself at a tree,
with a house in its branches.
I'll be waiting for you there.
I'll be waiting by candlelight
in our treehouse...
shining the light of my
cross into your eyes.
The first message
I ever sent you.
(Both) Us.
I love you, Iggy Perrish.
Your girl, Merrin.
(Sobs)
Iggy, you're alive.
(Ig) You know-don't.
Iggy...
we have to clear your name.
We need to figure out
who really killed Merrin.
It was Lee.
If you're going after Lee,
then I am coming with you.
Terry, you're not
strong enough for that.
I am not leaving you.
I made myself a promise.
Never again.
If anything happens to me, I
need to know you're all right.
And for Mom and Dad's sake.
(Lee) I'll be damned.
(Ig) You and me both.
What are you doing out here, Ig?
You don't remember anything that
happened between us, do you?
You wanna come inside?
No, actually I was hoping
we could go for a walk.
I mean, nobody's looking for me.
Pretty much everyone in
town thinks I'm dead.
No shit.
So what do you say?
It's just a walk?
Yeah.
Okay.
Why'd you bring us here?
You know why.
Because this is where
you killed Merrin.
What happened to you?
You lost your mind?
Things are gonna go a
lot easier for both of us
if you don't lie to me.
Ig...
I'm your best friend.
You've known me your whole life.
Do you think I had
something to do with this?
Believe me, all I want
to do is kill you.
But I am trying to be human.
I am trying to be the kind of
man Merrin wanted me to be.
And so I am giving you this
chance to do the right thing.
We are gonna go down
to the police station.
Okay.
You are gonna turn yourself in.
(Eric)(Cocks gun)Keep your
hands where I can see them, Lee.
Don't do anything stupid.
Oh, Terry.
(Lee) What the fuck you
doing here, Terry?
(Eric) Terry came to
talk to me just now.
Told me some things about
the night that Merrin died.
Anything he said, he's just
trying to save his own ass.
Go fuck yourself.
Yeah, fuck you too.
You told everybody
that Ig confessed to you
and then killed himself.
At least one of those
things isn't true.
So now I'm wondering, what else
you were lying to me about.
Fuck.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I have to-Okay.
I didn't mean to hurt her.
It was a mistake.
I'm sorry.
Okay. I'm gonna
do the right thing. Okay.
Okay, I'm gonna fix
all of this, okay?
(Eric) You're doing good.
Okay.
That's right.
We've been friends a long time.
(Ig) Fuck, Lee!
(Terry) Why don't you
put the goddamn gun down.
(Gun shot)
(Laughs)
(Lee) Back the fuck up.
Back the fuck up.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
I'm so sorry, Merrin.
I'll see you soon.
Aaarrgghh!!
(Gun shot)
No!
(Gun jams)
Please, Ig.
(Slithering)
Ig?
(Ig) In the end
I embraced the horns.
Like an angel who
fell to earth...
I became a devil one last time.
But revenge is all consuming.
And my time has come
to return to you...
so we can be together again.
No, no, I swear.
I mean, if this isn't paradise,
I don't know what is.
Are you horny?
I'm getting warmer.
Oh, fine.
No.
Yes.
I'm gonna love you for
the rest of my life.
Just love me for
the rest of mine.
♪ ♪