(THUNDER RUMBLES)
WOMAN: Do you hear something?
- Is she up again?
- Yeah.
WOMAN: I'll go.
(VOICE ECHOING) Carrie Anne,
you have to go back to bed.
(GRUNTING)
(WOMAN GRUNTS)
(SPLATTERING, THUDDING)
MAN: Don't! Don't! Don't!
(SPLATTERING)
- MAN: Ah!
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(ACOUSTIC GUITAR PLAYS)
Hey, what time is it?
GIRL: Like 2230.
Oh, my God, that guy was supposed
to be here at one o'clock.
- It's fine, we'll just wait.
- This is so annoying...
Nowhere else to go.
It's a long way back to Chicago.
(HONKS HORN)
Oh, look who's here.
Finally...
Hey!
You must be the Cassidys?
- Yes.
- Dan.
Hi, Dan.
- Dan Gifford.
- How are you?
So sorry, I'm late.
I left my cell at the office.
I'm sure you tried to call.
- I did. Fifteen times.
- Oh, sorry about that.
(FORCED LAUGHTER)
- Let me show you your new home.
- Yes, great.
DAN: I just got to dig up the key here.
How was the drive?
WOMAN: Oh, we were on the road for two
days. Kind of anxious to get settled.
Well, I think you'll be
very comfortable here.
And you'll love the neighborhood.
- Wow...
- Which reminds me...
It's ginormous.
DAN: If you have any problems,
just give me a call.
- Great. Thanks.
- See you at the potluck.
Mom, this is beautiful.
That is all state park.
Can you believe it?
Good backyard, huh?
Ls that Mr. and Mrs.
Dead People's house?
Oh, wow...
I didn't realize it was so close.
GIRL: Nobody lives there, right?
No.
No, the place is empty.
You know, that house is the reason
we can even afford to rent this house.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Double murder, kind of a drag
on the real estate market.
(SCOFFS) People got shot on our block,
nobody ever cut our rent.
Come on, help me unpack.
OK. I just want to look around, first.
All right, fine.
(RUSTLING, BIRD SCREECHING,
WINGS FLAPPING)
(TWIG CRACKS)
WOMAN: Thanks for cooking.
Thank Daddy, he's the one
who taught me how to make this.
Boil the water and put in spaghetti,
and... open the jar thing?
Wow. What a great dad he is.
It's not like you carry that lighter
around because you miss smoking.
Yeah, I miss him sometimes.
I missed him when we were married.
He was on the road
nine months out of the year.
I think this place is going to be
really good for us.
It's just gonna take some time
for me to get used to having you around.
I gave you the biggest room.
- How hard's it going to be?
- (CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
(SOFT THUDDING)
(DISTANT CLATTERING)
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYS)
Um, everyone... This is Sarah Cassidy
and her daughter Elissa.
They're our new neighbors.
They're renting the Reeds' place.
- Welcome to the neighborhood.
- Thank you.
- I made some potato salad.
- Oh, great. Great.
Elissa, do you like to swim?
Pool's at 95. It's like Aruba.
-Hi.
-Hi... Dan...
- Yeah.
- The, um, Jacobson house...
Is anyone living there?
Because late last night
I saw a light go on.
Oh, that'd be Ryan Jacobson, the son.
Really? But you said
it was going to be empty.
No, the son lives there.
ls that a problem?
No.
Good, good.
I mean, we do have a signed lease.
- (SARAH CHUCKLES)
- MAN: There you go.
- Oh, thank you.
- Thanks.
- BOY: Marco!
- CHILDREN: Polo!
- Marco!
- Polo!
That's my son, Tyler.
Honor roll. Student council.
Him and his friends
started this group last year,
famine relief program.
They've raised
about a thousand dollars for, uh...
...Africa or Tibet,
one of those starving places.
Anyway, you should go. Tyler...
I'd like you to meet Elissa.
- Have fun.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Sorry about my mom.
She gave you the full treatment?
Oh, no worries. Moms are like that.
I'm sure you're really a total loser.
(CHUCKLES)
- Do you want to go for a swim?
- No. it's fine. I'll watch.
All right.
- Whoo!
- (CHILDREN SCREAM)
- BOY: Marco!
- GIRL: Polo!
- Marco!
- Polo!
- WOMAN: So, how are you settling in?
- SARAH: Good. Good.
MAN: Have you met your next-door
neighbor, Ryan Jacobson, yet?
No, is he coming today?
The Jacobson boy
pretty much keeps to himself.
WOMAN: Thank God.
Somebody should burn that house down.
- Jenny!
- JENNY: What?
I didn't say
Ryan Jacobson had to be in it.
But come on.
Why is that kid still living there?
He's driven down all our home values.
The town tried to buy the house
and we were going to tear it down
and donate the land to the state park.
- What exactly happened again?
- SARAH: I told you, remember?
The daughter, Carrie Anne,
killed both her parents.
Yeah, that I know, but where was Ryan?
He didn't live with them,
he stayed with an aunt upstate.
And what happened to Carrie Anne
after they got killed?
Well, there was a massive search,
but she drowned in the dam.
But they never found her body,
so some people think
she still lives in the woods.
- What?!
- WOMAN: Tyler... Just ignore him.
- it's just an urban legend.
- Or is it, Mom? Is it?
WOMAN: No, no. There's no way...
TYLER: I'm telling you,
she lives in the woods.
SARAH: Did that freak you out,
what they were saying back there?
Yes. Our neighbors are jerks.
"Let's light his house on fire"?
Real nice. Wonder where they keep
the torches and pitchforks?
Really.
I thought that kid Tyler was OK.
Mm... Jury's still out, but maybe.
Do you think somebody
could actually live out there?
No. No, definitely not.
(TWIG SNAPS)
Hey, come on.
♪ Wouldn't it be sweet?
♪ If you could be in love with me?
♪ The way that I'm in love with you?
♪ it's so easy to do
♪ All you got to do is fa!! in love
♪ Ah' you got to do is fa!! in love... I
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Nice toy.
- Oh, thanks.
Just assuring my friends back home
I'm not hanging myself
from a shower rod.
Well, if you're looking
for something less morbid...
...our famine relief group is meeting
after school today.
You want to come?
I can give you a ride after if you want.
Oh, I can't. I'm going to watch
a movie tonight with my mom.
Too bad.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Hang on, one sec.
- Hi.
- SARAH: Hi, honey.
How was school?
Is your soul still intact?
Relatively. How about you?
Um, OK. But they stuck me
with the night shift.
Already?
It's just my first day,
so I can't really say no.
But I'm not going to be home before ten.
It's fine. Tyler invited me to this...
famine relief group thing,
so I'll just see you when I get home.
Oh, that's great.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
- Bye.
- Well, I guess I can go.
- Cool.
(HIP-HOP PLAYS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- Hey.
- Tyler, what's up?
- So this is famine relief?
- Yeah.
Last year we gave 1200 dollars
to Stop Hunger Now.
It just came straight off
my dad's Optima card,
rather than waiting in store parking
lots and begging people for change.
Put it on our college apps
as community service.
Wow. I have to admit
a certain smarmy brilliance.
(HIP-HOP PLAYS)
- (MUFFLED MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (KNOCKING)
- ELISSA: ls anybody in here?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- (MOANS SOFTLY)
(MOANS)
Are you OK?
Yeah, I just need to rest.
(MOANS)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (VOMITING)
So I'll just wait to pee.
TYLER: There you are.
- Hi.
- You're pretty.
- You're wasted.
And pitifully horny.
- What? I'm joking. Come here.
- No.
- Come here. Come here.
- I don't...
- Tyler, stop.
- Come on.
Tyler, stop it! Get off.
What's your problem?
Asshole.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(DIALING)
This is Sarah, I'm not here right now,
leave me a message.
Hey, do you need a ride?
No, I'm fine. This is my driveway.
No, it's not. I saw you move in
on Sycamore Lane.
I live next door.
It looks like it's going to rain.
Can I give you a ride?
No. I'm fine with walking.
You're ten miles from home,
let me give you a ride.
No really, I'm totally fine.
I'm waiting for my mom.
OK.
(RAIN PATTERING)
- Shit.
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
(MOANS)
(MUSIC PLAYS SOFTLY ON RADIO)
Your parents got killed.
I'm sorry. I know the people
were talking about it,
and I knew I shouldn't say...
I'm going to shut up now.
It's OK.
You just said
what you were thinking.
It's all anybody can think
around me anyways.
That, and why do I still live
in the house my parents got killed in?
Yeah, why do you still live in the house
your parents got killed in?
(CHUCKLES)
My family sent me away
when I was seven.
That house was really
all I had left of them.
But actually living there,
it's been too hard.
I'm fixing it up
and I'm going to sell it.
I heard you singing this morning.
You can hear me
all the way from your house?
(LAUGHS) It was nice.
You in, like, a band or something?
I was, back in Chicago.
My dad was in a rock band.
You got anything good?
Still using cassettes.
(LAUGHS)
Dude, we got to get you
some new music.
Yeah.
I used to have one of these.
Yeah, that was my dad's.
So was this car.
So are you and your mom
in Woodshire to stay?
I hope so.
It's so quiet here.
Not like where I used to live.
It's even quieter at dawn.
Dawn? What are you doing up that early?
I Sit Out back and I Write Stuff.
Like stories. it's easy.
I don't know, it's like...
it's like at that time of the day,
because everyone is still asleep,
all the best thoughts
haven't been taken yet.
(PHONE RING-S)
It's my mom. I better go.
Thank you, for driving me.
Yeah, you're welcome.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Did Tyler's mom give you a ride home?
No. Actually, Ryan Jacobson did.
Ryan Jacobson?
How did Ryan Jacobson give you a ride?
No one wanted to give me a ride,
so I started to walk,
he saw me and gave me a ride.
Why didn't you call me?
I would have come to get you.
- (SCREAMING)
- Carrie Anne, stop it!
Stop! Please, Carrie Anne, stop it!
- OW!
- (SCREAMING)
Stop it, Carrie Anne! Stop, please!
(GROWLING)
-Ah! God!
Sh... sh...
Sh... It’s OK.
It's OK. It's OK.
Why do you do this all the time,
Carrie Anne?
Don't I look after you?
Listen, we have a new neighbor, OK?
Her name is Elissa.
Her and her mom just moved
into the Reeds' house.
And I want you to leave her alone,
you understand me?
Yeah.
Bitch.
GIRL: Hey.
Elissa, right?
-Yeah.
- Hi. I'm Jillian.
. Hey-
- Um.--
- Thanks for tucking me in yesterday.
- Anytime.
I'm not much of a drinker
and I got sick
all over Caitlin's bath towels
and she threw a fit.
Who are these people,
why are you friends with them?
I don't know. I mean...
I used to go out with Tyler,
but he's kind of a dick.
He's worse than a dick.
He's a dick-hole.
Dick-hole is the new asshole.
- Hm.
- Oh, hey. Jake.
Elissa, this is my brother Jake
and his best friend, Robbie.
You guys, this is Elissa.
Yeah, I've been wanting to meet you.
You were in a band.
- How did you know...
- Oh. Google.
Nothing is sacred anymore, right?
Everything's online.
Anyway, we have
the Battle of the Bands coming up.
So, what do you say?
- You want to come sing with us?
- And if you suck?
(LAUGHS)
We don't. Here, that's us.
Listen to it, if you like it,
come check us out, practice tomorrow.
OK, cool.
- Cool. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Bye.
- He likes you.
-I already got a job.
Excuse me, Officer!
Hey, did I forget to sign something?
Oh, no, no.
I just wanted to ask you something.
- I'm Sarah, Sarah Cassidy.
- Bill Weaver, what's up?
I just moved here with my daughter,
who's 17,
and we have a rental on Sycamore Lane.
And you wanted to know
if I thought it was possible
you had a 17-year-old daughter.
I would have to say no.
It's actually about Ryan Jacobson.
He drove my daughter home
the other night.
I was just wondering if you
knew anything about him. If he's...
OK?
Yeah.
Finding out that your parents
were murdered,
by your own sister, God,
that's really intense.
You'd think people would show him
a little bit of sympathy, right?
You know, I drove three hours upstate
personally to tell Ryan.
He was living with his aunt,
a senile old woman.
He had no one taking care of him.
He was taking care of her, actually.
Anyway, he moved back here with her,
she died about a year ago.
The Kid's had a tough, tough life.
Look, I've never had
any problem with him,
and as far as I know,
no one else has either.
But they sure like to bitch about him
and their property values, don't they?
Yeah, I have heard people doing that.
- 710-49 at Main and Jackson. Over.
- Excuse me.
OK.
Sorry. I gotta go.
Thanks, officer.
Oh, hey, no.
it's, uh, Bill, OK?
Bill.
- I'll see you around?
- Yeah.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I... made you a CD.
Wow, thank you.
Oh, my gosh, my page.
Yeah... I wanted to listen
to some more of your music.
That's not weird, is it?
No. Not unless you didn't like it.
No, actually,
I thought it was beautiful.
Good answer. Whoa!
Stocking up
the old fallout shelter, huh?
Um, yeah. I don't like to go to town
more than I have to.
Wow, it's big.
What's up there?
Construction never really got finished
on this part of the house.
I don't have a wall or anything,
but I moved back here when I came back.
It's a little bit small.
Well, at least you're not a sleepwalker.
- ls this the family?
- Yeah.
Oh, Ryan, you're so cute.
And that's Carrie Anne.
Wow. Her eyes are so blue.
Your family looks really happy.
It must've been nice,
having everyone together.
Having two parents.
Carrie Anne was the head of the family.
After the accident, things changed.
Is that when they sent you away?
I've never really talked to anyone
about this stuff before.
ELISSA: What's in here?
I'm so sorry. I shouldn't have...
It's OK, you don't have to go.
I haven't been in here in a long time.
ELISSA: I thought she was 13.
This looks like a little kid's room.
She had brain damage.
- RYAN: We were just playing.
- (GIRL GIGGLING)
Like we did most days.
We ran around, we'd play tag.
Her favorite thing
was to play on the swings.
My mom and dad were inside.
I was supposed to be watching her.
But she kept wanting to get higher.
(GIGGLING)
(INHALING)
Mom!
RYAN: When she woke up,
she was different.
She used to scream all the time,
and she would attack us
and break things.
Is that why there are bars
on all the windows?
Yeah.
She never knew where she was.
She would...
She'd run out into the woods.
They were to keep her in.
Now they just keep the townies
from coming down here.
I don't really like coming
into this part of the house.
Well, thank you.
And I hope you like the CD.
Yeah. Thank you.
- Bye.
(SIGHS)
(GIGGLING)
Elissa?
Can you come help me?
- I have to go to work.
- Hey.
Thanks.
- How was school?
- Mm...
School's school. How's work?
It's OK. I don't know.
The late shifts are kind of tough.
But I like being in the hospital.
I like the drama.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
- What did you do after school?
I, um...
dropped off a CD at Ryan's house.
And he's really sweet...
...and sad...
...and lonely, all at the same time.
He's all by himself in this big house,
with the shades drawn.
You went to his house?
We dropped 'shrooms
and had unprotected sex.
- I know what you're doing.
- What?
- You're trying to save him.
- I am not.
Yes, you are. That's what you do,
you like to fix people.
Oh, yaddayadda-yadda.
Honey, sometimes
people can't be fixed.
(PANTING)
(DOOR RATTLING)
- (ELECTRICAL FIZZLING)
- (MOANING)
(SCREECHING)
(TYPING)
(WHEEZING, MOANING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING, SCREECH ING)
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
Carrie Anne, no! No!
SARAH: See you after work, honey.
- OK, bye.
- Bye.
(RATTLING)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
- <GASPING)
- (LAUGHS)
Sorry.
You scared the piss out of me!
- How did you get in?
- You left the front door open.
(GRUNTING)
(MOANING)
♪ Wake up good-lookin'
and I stay that way
♪ I break a couple hearts
almost everyday
♪ Behind the scenes
I'm better than I am on stage
♪ Pick a book you like
And I'm your favorite page
♪ If you don't know, you're gonna know
♪ That I'm that girl... J'
Mm. Smells good.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Who's that?
- What are you up to?
- (SARAH LAUGHS)
- Hi.
- Hello.
Ryan?
Yeah, I thought it would be nice
if we all got to know each other.
OK.
And I lived with my Aunt Iris,
but she had a stroke when I was 18,
so after she was hospitalized,
I came back here.
Back home.
SARAH: Such a big house.
Must be difficult to pay the bills.
(CLEARS THROAT) You don't...
You don't have to answer that.
My parents inherited the house,
and a little money,
so... when they died, I got it all.
It's not a lot, but it's enough.
And I go to Bridgeport Community
part time, so...
It's not really the greatest school
in the world, I know,
but I'm just trying to get my credits
in line so I can apply for pre-med.
- I want to be a psychiatrist.
- BOTH: Wow.
My mom went to a psychiatrist for a long
time after she broke up with my dad.
Thank you very much
for cooking the meal, Mrs. Cassidy.
- Let's get some dessert.
- Yes.
I just wanted to say thank you.
You're actually the first people
to invite me over since it happened.
Oh... Of course.
(SARAH CLEARS THROAT)
I'm sorry, I need to say something.
Ryan, Elissa has just started in
a new school, and I want her to do well,
and it's really one of the reasons
we even moved here.
And she is in high school
and you are in college...
Mom, what is your point?
I think Ryan knows
exactly what my point is.
We are neighbors,
and I want us to be friends,
but I just have one rule
that I need you to respect.
I do not want the two of you to be alone
in your house or this house
if I am not here.
- You are never here.
- Well, I am here now.
Ryan, can you respect that?
Yes.
- Thank you.
- I should go.
No, Ryan. No, no, Ryan.
No, no, no. You can stay.
- Ryan, please.
- You can stay.
You're really lucky to have a mother
who cares about you.
Ryan, really, it's fine.
You can stay. Really...
Thank you very much for dinner.
No, I... I didn't mean...
I said he could stay!
No, you invite him over
just so you can throw him out?
Honey, I wanted to protect you!
Oh, good! After all these years,
you finally decided to be a parent!
You know, just because you were some
wasted slut in high school,
it doesn't mean I'm going to be.
SARAH: Oh, God,
I invited him over last night,
and then I threw him out
and I told him I didn't want him
to be alone with Elissa.
So Elissa's not talking to me,
and I'm sure Ryan
thinks I'm against him,
like everyone else
in this ridiculous town.
Ryan's a smart kid, I'm sure he gets it.
I mean, I'm not stupid.
I can't keep her away from boys.
But I just don't want her to make
the same mistake I always make,
which is pick the wrong boy.
She just still treats me
like I'm a child.
That's lame.
She was just getting wasted and trashy
and he was so nice and gentle.
She didn't even care, she still talked
to him like he was a monster.
That's what she does.
She picks the most damaged kid around,
and then she makes them into a project.
So I guess maybe I'm worried that, you
know, Ryan 's just part of that pattern.
Hey.
Thank you so much for coming.
I really, really wanted to apologize
-for my mom last night.
- it's OK.
I hope you didn't take her too
seriously. It was just classic paranoia.
- This is my friend, Jillian.
- Hi.
- So can you give us a ride?
- What?
We're not really
supposed to do that, remember?
No, my mom said she didn't want us
alone, but we're not alone.
(JILLIAN SCOFFS)
Yeah. Yeah, OK.
SARAH: It's like I'm trying so hard
to be a good mom,
for the first time,
not really doing a good job.
Sarah, you're raising
a very decent girl who cares.
Stop being so hard on yourself.
OK, thank you for the ride home.
- Bye.
- Bye, guys.
(SOFT ROCK PLAYS)
Again, I mention
how we're not supposed to be alone.
(PHONE RING-S)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
- Hey.
- Hey, I just called to tell you
that I got stuck
with another late shift.
So I don't think
I'm going to be back before 11.
- Are you going to be OK?
- Yeah.
Elissa, I need you to remember
our agreement.
Yes. Don't you trust me at all?
I set our home phone
to forward all her calls to my cell.
You're kind of devious.
I'm only trying to protect her.
RYAN: Yeah, the house was actually
my great-grandfather's.
Which is why it's been kind of hard
to think about selling it,
you know, and the whole
fixing it up thing.
But... I don't know.
I want to show you something.
Here, sit down.
I don't remember much
when I was little.
I remember my mom sitting here
and telling me everything has a secret.
Everything.
And at first I couldn't see it.
But then one day...
One day I could.
See what?
Look, I'll show you.
LOOK.
Oh, my God, it's a face.
I see it.
People don't notice
all the secrets around them.
Even though they're right in front of
them, just hiding, waiting to be found.
I like the way you see things.
I like the way you see me.
(SOFT ROCK PLAYS)
(LAUGHING OVER INTERCOM)
(MUSIC CONTINUES OVER INTERCOM)
(BANGING)
I'll be right back.
- You need to leave now!
- What? Why?
Ryan! Ryan!
You're not supposed to be here, go!
- Ryan, what did I do?
- Go! Just go! Just go home! Go!
So, we'll just do it here. Come on.
- (SCREAMS) Jesus Christ!
- What?
- There was a girl at the window!
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
- Sh, Sh!
- Ray! Ray, come on.
- Really? Carrie Anne's outside.
- OK, unbelievable.
- Ray!
- (GRUNTING)
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
- ls anyone out there?
- (SCREAMS)
Carrie Anne, you're out here?
No, no, no. Come on, Alice.
- Let's go find Carrie Anne.
- Ray, stop being stupid.
- She's out here, right?
- (GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMING) (CRACKING)
- Sh! Sh!
- Ray, I want to go home!
ALICE: Get back in the car, please!
Carrie Anne? Carrie Anne?
No... Carrie Anne, please.
Come here.
(SOBBING) Wake up, wake up.
Carrie Anne, please wake up.
Wake up. Wake up.
Oh, God. What have I done?
What have I done?
I don't know what happened.
We were having so much fun,
and then he just totally freaked out.
JILLIAN: What do you mean freaked out?
(KNOCKING>
- I have to go.
- Wait, Elissa...
SARAH: Can I come in?
I, uh... I wanted to apologize
for the way I handled things with Ryan.
It's fine, don't worry about it.
You know I'm just trying to take care
of you. You know that, right?
Yes.
I wish sometimes
you could tell me things.
That you'd let me help you.
OK. I will.
Um, I got you something for your show.
Thank you.
It's some makeup.
I'm trying to do this mom thing,
you know?
I know.
Don't like the coffee?
Boy, you're really working that
whole Rebel Without a Cause thing
pretty hard over here, huh?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYS)
On the house.
It's OK, I'm not that hungry.
Come on, I'll throw in a glass of milk.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
- Hello?
- RYAN: Elissa, it's me.
I want to see you.
I don't know. I don't really understand.
What happened the other night?
Look, I'm really,
really sorry about that.
Ryan, are you OK?
You don't sound so good.
I just need to see you, there's some...
There's some things I need to tell you.
What?
I'll tell you later, OK?
- Promise?
- Yeah.
JAKE: Come on,
are we going to play or what?
OK, I got to go. I'm doing
Battle of the Bands at school.
You should come.
- RYAN: OK.
- OK. Bye.
What?
Nothing.
(RYAN SIGHS)
Look at this.
Look, the freak finally
decided to show up.
BOY: I hear the retard hooked up
with the new girl.
TYLER: For real?
You tapping that?
I guess it's official.
She will screw anyone.
That's sad.
(KNOCKING>
- You made it.
- Yeah.
I wanted to come.
- I'm so happy you could be here.
- Yeah, me too.
Dude, they're trashing your car!
- (ALL SHOUTING)
- Whoo!
(YELLING)
- What are you doing?
- (GRUNTING)
No, stop!
What are you doing?
- (GRUNTING)
- (CROWD SCREAMING)
No!
BOY: Finish him off, Tyler!
(GRUNTING)
- (CRACKING)
- (SCREAMING)
You little bitch!
He only got one place to go, come on!
Come on!
Ryan! Ryan!
ELISSA: Hey, you assholes!
BOY: Let's go, go, go!
Drive, drive, drive, drive!
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
- Hi.
- SARAH: Honey, where are you?
- I'm at home.
- So, you're not with Ryan?
No.
Well, Tyler was just
admitted to the hospital.
Did he and Ryan have a fight.
Did you see what happened?
Mom, he was defending himself.
Like, six guys jumped him.
- OK, well, I still, I want you home.
- I am home!
- You don't believe me, call me!
- OK, I'm going to call you.
- Hey.
- Oh, hey.
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
(BEEPING)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Believe me now? I'll see you later.
(FAINT RATTLING)
I want Ryan Jacobson arrested, now!
Calm down, Bonnie.
I'm going to take Tyler's statement,
and I'm going to take Ryan's,
and I'm going to speak to everyone
there to find out what happened,
and then I'm going to sort this out.
Your son and his friends
have been picking on Ryan for years,
and you have let that happen.
- Don't give me that.
- Zip it, Ben!
Now, listen, if I find out
that it's Tyler who started this,
he's the one who's going to be brought
up on assault charges, you hear me?
- Why are you always defending him?
- Come on, let's go.
- That animal...
- That's animal's name is Ryan.
I don't give a damn what his name is,
but that animal's going to hear
from my lawyer.
Walk away. Walk away.
You all right?
Yeah. No, I just had a bad feeling.
I'm going to go check up on Ryan.
How about if I stop by your house
and look in on Elissa,
I'll give you a call.
- Just make sure she's there.
- All right, I'll call you.
- OK.
(FAINT RATTLING)
(BANGING)
(PANTING)
(BANGING, RATTLING)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
- (SCREAMING)
- Carrie Anne, stop it!
Get out! Go! Go! Go! Go! Get out!
Go! Go upstairs!
Elissa, please! Could you just go?!
You're scaring her,
wait for me upstairs, please!
Please, just go! Carrie Anne,
please just calm down! it's OK!
RYAN: It's OK.
They're not going to take you away.
Elissa won't tell.
She's not like the others.
- (SCREAMING)
- It's OK. You're OK.
You're OK.
She'll help us.
Yes, that's a good girl. You're OK.
You're OK. You're safe.
You have to promise me you won't
tell anyone about Carrie Anne.
Is this yours?
Yeah.
Promise me you won't tell anyone
about Carrie Anne.
Yeah. Yeah, I promise.
I have to go. My mom called.
(GASPING)
ELISSA: Ryan, please let me go!
Ryan, what are you doing?
Carrie Anne died that day on the swings.
It's done.
It was my fault!
We were trying to hold hands.
Ryan, if Carrie Anne died,
who killed your parents?
I need Carrie Anne.
I can't have you and Carrie Anne.
But if you're Carrie Anne...
No.
No, Ryan! Please!
No, Ryan. Ryan, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Ryan, no, please! Please!
Ryan, where are you taking her?
Please don't hurt her!
- Scream all you want.
- Please, Ryan, no!
- No one can hear you.
- Ryan! No!
DOCTOR: He'll be walking with a limp
for the rest of his life.
- Sarah, can you get me an MRI, please?
- Yeah.
(BEEPING)
- (PHONE RINGING)
- (BEEPING)
(RINGING)
ELISSA: Hey this is Elissa 's cell,
leave a message.
(RINGING)
- Hello?
- SARAH.' Hey, it's me.
I just called home
and her cell picked up,
so she's been forwarding her calls
the whole time.
I think she's with Ryan
Will you go over there first?
- OK.
Ryan?
Ryan, please untie me.
It wasn't your fault
Carrie Anne died, right?
It was an accident.
It was my fault.
That's why they punished me.
They punished you?
I stopped them.
You stopped them?
What do you mean you stopped them?
- BILL: Ryan?
- (KNOCKING OVER INTERCOM)
BILL: Ryan?
Ryan?
- Hey.
Can I come in?
I saw someone
smashed your front window.
It's just kids from town, it's nothing.
I saw what you did to Tyler's leg.
You want to tell me about that?
All I did was fight back.
I'm gonna do my best
to get this to blow over.
But you need to stay out of trouble,
you hear me?
You ever get tired
of playing the tough guy?
I'm going to need you
to come down to the station,
first thing in the morning
and make a statement. OK?
I don't mean to jump all over you,
I just... keep making
the same mistakes.
Oh, um,
you haven't seen Elissa, have you?
I saw her earlier at the Battle
of the Bands. She's not there?
No. No, her mother thought she was
at home, but she's not there either.
She's not here.
I'll see you
first thing in the morning.
(DIALING, LINE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
(RINGING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
Ah!
(GROANS)
(SIZZLING)
-Ah!
(SHRIEKS)
(PANTING)
You could've stopped all of this
a long time ago,
but you didn't.
You knew.
(YOUNG RYAN) Mom! Mom!
It's done.
I don't think you have a choice
but to go along with this, Bill.
I protected you.
No!
- (GROANING)
You protected yourself, even though
you knew what they did to me!
(GASPING)
(GROANING, PANTING)
(SOBBING)
(PANTING)
(STRAINING)
Ah!
Oh!
RYAN: Elissa!
Open the door, Elissa!
You bitch!
(SHRIEKS)
- (KNOB RATTLING)
ASPS
(RYAN GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Sh... Sh...
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Elissa!
(GASPING)
Ryan!
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hi, Mrs. Cassidy.
I'm looking for Elissa.
Is she here?
No, ma'am.
Because she wasn't at home,
so I figured that maybe she'd be here.
She's not here, Mrs. Cassidy.
I wouldn't be angry if...
if she's here.
- Elissa!
- ELISSA: Mom! Help!
- SARAH: Elissa!
- ELISSA: Mom!
Elissa!
(GRUNTING)
(SARAH MOANING)
Ah! Oh...
(RYAN GRUNTING, PANTING)
RYAN: I want you.
I do, but I need Carrie Anne.
I'm sorry I can't keep you, Elissa.
(GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTS)
(ELISSA WHIMPERS)
ELISSA: Please, please, come on.
Come on, come on.
- (FLASHLIGHT CLICKING)
- (ELISSA WHIMPERING)
(ELISSA SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTING)
(HONKING HORN)
Elissa!
Hey.
I'm all packed.
What are you looking at?
What do you see?
I SEE... A TREE.
Why?
Nothing.
Are you ready to go?
Yeah.
WOMAN: Let's get ready
to blow out the candles, baby!
WOMAN: Make a wish!
Make a wish, Carrie Anne.
My name's not Carrie Anne! It's Ryan!
Yes, it is! Your name is Carrie Anne!
Your name is Carrie Anne.