Can you go to Putney, mate?
Hey!
Let's go home, asshole.
Take us to the airport.
Fuck it!
I'll see you guys
tomorrow night.
Hello?
She's OK.
She just had a panic attack.
- Let's get her upright.
- Come on. There you go.
- Hello. Welcome to the house.
- What the fuck is going on?
Now if you listen
and you don't speak...
I'm sure all of your questions
will be answered.
Now you know how you got here,
but I'm sure you're all wondering...
what you all have in common
to be here...
and most of all why.
Why me?
You can search all you want, but
you'll never find a common thread...
because I have chosen you
quite randomly for who you are...
but a little bit more carefully
for what you are.
Now you're probably
wondering right now...
about all those people who are
out there looking for you...
your friends and your family.
Well, please don't bother...
because they've all been
settled with...
quite easily in some cases.
I want you to consider yourselves
to be mice in a laboratory...
rats in a cage if you will...
because this is the ultimate
test of human character.
Only here, this test is
purely for entertainment.
My entertainment...
and what is this entertainment,
you must be thinking.
Well, right now I'm
watching you all.
Yes, I'm using seventy five
cameras...
and just as many hidden microphones,
but don't try to find them all...
because you'll never be able to,
but one of you here...
one of you will win
and the one that wins...
will receive five million dollars
for his or her participation.
I'm sure you've all seen
the shows...
but on my show, all you have
to do to win this prize...
is to be the only one to walk
out of this house alive.
You won't be hearing
from me again.
The rest is up to you.
So good luck and may
the best person win.
- Who the fuck was that?
- Fucking hell!
- What's going on?
- It's OK.
- What are we going to do?
- It's OK, it's OK.
- Well, is that it? Have they gone?
- They can't just leave us here.
- Everyone please, let's keep calm.
- Calm my arse!
He's right.
Everybody calm down...
- and let's think this thing out.
- You don't think this is real!
Come on, this has got
to be some kind of joke!
- Pretty sick joke.
- Yeah well, I'm not laughing.
I need to get the fuck
out of here now, man!
I don't think it's a joke.
It's a game maybe.
He told us only one will live.
What does that mean?
What, is someone going to kill us?
- Oh my God.
- No, they aren't going to do that.
Are you deaf? That's what
he just said, one person lives!
If they're not going to
kill us then who is?
- What else can he be talking about?
- How do you know what he's gonna do?
Because they left me
here with this!
- Fuck!
- Son of a bitch!
- How the fuck did you get that?
- Relax. I'm a cop.
Great! One of us has a gun
and it's a fucking white cop!
- Oh God, don't say that!
- Oh yeah. That's fair, isn't it?
All of us are supposed
to try and survive...
but the copper's
left with a gun!
This is so fucked!
It's fucked, man!
It kind of puts the odds a little
bit in his favour, doesn't it?
It's kind of bullshit,
that's what it is.
Last time I saw one of those it
was in my little brother's head...
smashing his face in the ground.
He was sixteen!
Yeah?
Well, that wasn't me, was it?
- Well, it don't make a difference.
- This is not the time.
Mr. Cop, can you put away your gun?
You're making everybody nervous.
Guys, do we know if we're
alone in here? I mean is it safe?
What do you mean, do you
think there's traps or something?
I think we've got a little bit
more to worry about than that.
- Why don't you shut the fuck up?
- No, you shut up!
This guy wants us
to kill each other.
- What did you say?
- What was that?
You want me to spell it out
for you?
This guy wants us to
all kill each other.
- What does that mean?
- He's asking you if you're stupid.
Hey, don't upset him!
You heard the man.
One will survive, five will cry!
Welcome to the show!
I said don't upset everybody!
- They can't do that!
- Come on, lady!
He's going to do whatever
he wants! Am I not right?
Come on, come on Mr. Cop,
don't bullshit people, tell them!
- You're right.
- Thanks!
But I mean the thing is, they
actually can't do this to people.
- Exactly, it's not legal, man!
- Hello!
Anything happens to me,
I'm going to sue the arse off you!
They don't give a shit about that!
They've got that covered too!
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah!
What's the one gonna do that walks
outta here with 5 million dollars...
tell on them? Tell the cops they
had to kill to get the money?
You'd go down fast and probably
to a psych ward too!
What, do you think he's going
to pay you after you kill for him?
The chances are he's going to kill
you too, you thought about that?
So what do you think we should do
then, Mr. Policeman? Uh?
All sit down and hold hands?
Sing 'Kum bai ya'?
Who knows who's going to do what?
I gotta look out for me, yeah?
Seems like a pretty
good idea to me.
Just sit around and do nothing,
I mean, what's this guy going to do?
- What's he got if he has no show?
- You know what...
it's kinda funny you know so much
about what this guy's going to do...
- and you have a gun, what's up?
- I'll tell you what's up with that!
It seems like I'm the only one here
using my head besides the priest!
You know why they left
me here with this?
In the hopes that I would
pop one of you...
if not all of you.
The problem is they picked the
wrong guy, alright?
'Cause I'm not playing
this game...
not for any amount of money!
- And I will not either.
- Yeah?
I guess we'll have
to see about that.
Maybe someone else will get
that gun and use it to win.
- We could make this energy better.
- Like what?
- Like try to find a way outta here!
- Exactly.
Do you really think he's going
to give us a way out?
Well, we won't know
'til we try, will we?
Whatever!
All you mother fuckers can stay
here if you want, yeah?
This nigger's out!
I ain't being no one's bitch!
Hold on! I've got an idea.
We've got a door there.
Yeah, it comes off.
Come on guys, give me a hand!
Alright, come on,
we can do this together!
Sorry. There's no way I'm picking
that thing up and breaking my back!
Well then, sit on your arse
and shut your fucking hole!
Fine!
OK, ready guys?
On three...
one, two, three.
You got it?
I'll back it up.
You guys walk that way.
Okay.
Alright. On three.
One...
two, three.
- Again!
- Come on!
Everything guys, come on!
- Just keep going!
- Again!
We're fucked!
Son of a bitch!
Forget it!
Jesus!
Nothing. Great!
That gun holds eleven, uh?
- Three shots. Eight left in the gun.
- And?
And... one, two, three, four...
five, six, seven, eight.
You know what?
Give up the bullets, cop!
- Screw you.
- What the fuck did you say?
There's got to be other ways
out of here.
Let's split up and
check the entire house.
Let's look over here.
There are cameras everywhere.
Come on!
- Found something?
- Yeah.
Clear it back, come on.
Come on!
Fuck!
Fucking bastard!
Like the show?
Thank you so much
for your help!
Look at you, sitting there like
the Queen of fucking Sheba!
- Give me that!
- Get your own! Fuck off!
- Shit!
- No way!
One it's not up to you.
It's not a good idea right now!
I'm locking up the rest.
Who the fuck do you think
you are, anyway?
I think we could have
a little talk.
Did you all forget
what the man said?
Only one of us will get out of here.
Have you thought about that?
Well, I don't think any of us
want to think on that level.
Five million's a lot of money. Some
people will do anything for that.
What, and you two bitches think
you could win over us?
You only weigh about
a hundred pounds.
I'm pretty sure I said
nobody's playing this game.
I don't see anyone giving us
any choices, do you?
This is crap.
How do we know who will do what
for that amount of money?
You know what?
You underestimate people, pal.
- Do I?
- What are you talking about?
You've never seen how shitty people
can get when they're desperate...
and they're backed into a corner
and they don't have a choice?
Look at you!
Typical fucking copper!
Listen, I know I've got good
reason to want five mill right now.
- Reason enough to kill?
- We all have choices here.
There'll be no killing.
Yeah, and anybody does
anything like that...
and I will personally see to it
myself that they're prosecuted.
- This is crazy.
- I'll tell you one thing right now.
I'm going to do everything
in my power...
to make sure nothing
like this even begins.
You hear me?
And so we'll wait and we'll see
who will do what. Is that it?
Dinner's served.
Great.
One piece of chicken and one potato
for each, we'll save the rest.
You know what? I'll eat what I want
when I want, thank you.
Maybe I didn't make
myself clear.
I said one piece of chicken
and one potato for each.
Hey, can you quit with this
attitude so we can eat?
Good idea.
This is fucking cold!
Try the potato,
it's even better.
Father, can we pray with you?
Accept our thanks, oh Lord...
for this food to sustain
our life with...
and fill our hearts
with gladness.
And help us, in the midst
of our struggles...
to confront one another,
without hatred and bitterness...
and to work together...
with forbearance and respect
through Jesus Christ...
our Lord and Saviour.
Amen.
- Amen.
That's touching. Can I get back
to my food now?
Any chance I can get the key
to that drinks cabinet back?
- No chance.
- No liquor, please!
Look, I think that we're old enough
to make that decision ourselves.
- I don't eat meat.
- Cool.
There you go.
Now you're not eating meat.
- Hey, wait!
- Split it up between everyone else.
- Yeah!
- It's going back with the rest.
There you go.
That is so sweet.
It's not her fault
she doesn't eat meat.
Yeah it is!
Anybody else got a problem
with the food?
I do!
This tastes like shit!
How the hell do we know they
haven't put anything in this?
Oh my God! Do you think
they could be poisoning us?
I think it's safe to say that
if they wanted us dead...
they'd have done that already
and not waited 'til we ate.
They?
What about one of you lot?
I'm not sure I packed arsenic before
I got snatched off the street.
We should try to keep civil.
I think civil is already
out the window, Father.
We do not even know
each other's names.
My name is
Father Michael Duffy.
Now who might you be?
I'm Jay.
I'm Cynthia and this is
my husband Francis.
- He's a music composer.
- That's enough.
I mean, they don't have
to know any more.
Why, what's wrong with
knowing about each other?
And what do you do?
- I'm...
- She doesn't have to work!
Let's move on.
Max. Clothing designer.
- You're not Max Roy, are you?
- Yeah.
You know, I met you
years ago in New York.
That is so weird.
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
Well, I recognized you.
Claire Levy, yeah?
Claire Levy, everyone!
The big tennis star!
I loved that outfit you wore
at The Open in 1995!
- You know, the one...
- Nobody fucking cares...
- what Martina wore at The Open!
- What did you call me?
Can we move on, please?
I'm Lea. I'm a dancer.
I'm in The Chorus.
- Wow, The Chorus!
- Yeah.
How long have you been
dancing for?
It's not been easy.
How long have you been
playing tennis for, smart arse?
What have you actually won?
And can you tell us
your name?
Shona.
You know what
that is, don't you?
- Yeah, it's a tracking device.
- Then maybe they'll find us?
I'm on parole, man.
If I don't get out of here by
tomorrow, I'm going back to jail.
I had a meeting with
a record label last night.
That's my record deal gone.
Record deal?
Should we know you, superstar?
Well yeah, you should but...
unfortunately everyone
here is white, so...
- So...
- So you can't even dance!
So who's the fucking racist here?
Sorry, Father.
This is great.
Nice dinner.
You should walk with your piece
That's the talk on the streets
I'm at war with that beast
Don't applaud the police
Check on with the fleece
West London to East
I speak tongues like the priest
Get tongues from Caprice
I'm talking to that pussy
With the piece, you should fear me
I love to put holes in police
I'm rowdy
That's why they call me Al B
When I win this five mill
I'll be pushing my Audi, yeah?
What?
Prick!
There's five rooms with
two single beds in each.
And we'll be chosen
by picking names. So...
- I'm not happy about doing this.
- Choose...
- one only.
- I'm not allowed to pick two, am I?
- Fuck!
- No way man, not her!
We agreed that we'd do this.
The happy couple and the priest get
their own and the rest of us pick.
But I didn't think I was going
to get stuck with that, did I?
Shut up, sweetheart.
Eat me!
- Well, there's a ratings winner.
- Jay.
That puts the two of you
together.
No, piss off!
I ain't rooming with him!
- Why, you got a problem with me?
- Yeah I do!
- What is that?
- What do you think, bitch?
- That's just rude!
- You ain't no trophy, honey!
Hey alright, enough!
Fine, now the rooms
are settled...
and I'm going to mine.
Nosey cow!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Look nice. Where was that?
Not that it's any of your business,
but I was doing a photo shoot.
So you used to be famous,
did you?
- Still am.
- Really?
Looks to me like all you do is get
dressed up and get drunk at parties.
Any loser can do that.
Why don't you fuck yourself and keep
your filthy hands out of my shit?
Then don't leave your shit
lying around!
How am I going to last
with only one outfit?
Do you have a family?
I did. I'm divorced.
I got one son and
he's just starting school.
It's not easy
living with a cop.
- Are you married?
- No. Too young for that.
I have one child though.
My dog, Ely!
I'm worried about him.
Don't worry about him,
he'll be OK.
He's alone.
Dogs know how to take care
of themselves, you know?
It's like a bad dream.
Look with compassion, Father...
on the whole human family...
and take away our arrogance
and our hatred...
which infects our hearts...
and break down the walls
that separate us...
and unite us in bonds of love...
and work through our confusion
and our struggle...
to accomplish your purposes
on this Earth.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Amen, Father.
There's no room.
It's too hot.
Plus someone's watching.
That's a lot of money.
The kind of money your
family used to have.
I'm not prepared to kill
to get it back.
Well...
the last few years you haven't been
prepared to do anything about that.
I can't believe you said that!
You haven't made any money
since before we got married!
I'm an artist.
Whatever.
You didn't turn the light off.
Happy?
Merci.
Shit!
- Who was just in here?
- What are you talking about?
Somebody was just in here
looking for this!
- Lf it wasn't him it was you!
- Why me?
Because it wasn't one
of the girls, was it?
Put that down!
- I wouldn't know what to do with it!
- Well, he would!
Would what?
Oh yeah, I get it. All us blacks
are the same, aren't we?
You see him busting a cap
on somebody's ass?
You know, I've had
enough of your shit!
Put away the gun and
let's go now, come on!
- Why is no one asking him?
- Me?
- Yes!
- No, he was with me!
Well, maybe you're just saying
that because he's your husband!
I'm not a liar!
Well, maybe someone else is
in here with us!
- No, it's impossible.
- That only leaves one.
What's everyone coming down
on me for?
- It's not 'cause you're black, mate!
- Listen, what would you know?
- Twenty-year-old white bitch!
- Fuck you!
Shut up!
- What are you two talking about?
- English, speak English!
- What the hell do you care?
- You're not in France now, alright?
Please! We must keep our
differences out of the equation.
For you Father, yeah.
Fuck this bullshit! You expect me
to sleep in this house?
It's not going to work,
you know.
I know how desperate people get
in these situations. I've seen it.
So have I.
Keep the faith in humankind.
Has someone turned
the heat up in here?
There is no control.
- I've looked all over.
- Great!
None of us understand
what's happening.
None of us know why
we're here or what for...
but we have to accept we're
all reluctant neighbors.
I don't think it's fair we don't
know what you're talking about!
Yeah, what are you plotting?
Listen, I said to you
speak English!
- What did he say?
- What are you so paranoid about?
Just let him speak French.
What do you mean what am I
paranoid about? I got good reason.
Now you see, this is
what I'm talking about.
You need to learn to do unto others
as you'd have them do unto you.
Look Father, no offence,
right...
but the second you start quoting
the Bible at me I switch off.
- Amen.
- Speak for yourselves!
No, no, no, no, she's right.
I need to learn to be in touch
with each one of you differently.
The only thing I need to get through
this is in the drinks cabinet.
And some more food.
You know, that's it!
I told you already, speak English!
What's wrong with you?
- Speak English, man!
- What's up, home boy?
What?
Home boy?
What are you talking about?
Hey, wait!
What was that?
- What?
- Listen.
The tag, they found you!
Wait, wait!
What is it?
Over there!
Open up!
Open the fucking door!
- Open up! Open up!
- Open the door!
Cover your ears!
Open up!
Help!
- Shut up!
- Open the fucking door!
I don't wanna die!
Hey!
Welcome to the party.
Here.
- Sorry, sorry.
- Sorry.
- I can't stand this music.
- No, I just wanted to get away.
It's crazy.
So you're a dancer.
A Chorus girl?
Yeah, yeah.
I've done a lot of work
for the theatre myself.
Really?
Like what?
In Europe mostly.
You know, we do it in quite
a different way there.
- I think your wife's really upset.
- Oh yes, she is.
Sorry.
Let me turn this shit off!
It's depressing me.
What's wrong?
Come on!
- Come on!
- Francis is going to see you.
Do you really think
I'm scared of your husband?
He don't take care of his
baby anyway, now come here!
- Stop it!
- Come on!
What do you think
you are doing?
- Francis!
- Shut up, right?
- We were just having fun!
- Fun?
What's your problem?
No! No!
Stop it!
No!
Stop!
Back off!
Cynthia?
You had to do it,
didn't you?
Listen, they both came at me.
I just tried to push her off me
and she tried...
Shut up!
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
God have mercy on us all.
Shit.
Let's move.
I said let's move!
Move!
Is this what you wanted?
Please, for God's sake,
you can stop this now...
before anyone else
has to suffer!
Stay there.
Open the fucking door!
You can't do this shit!
My jacket's in there!
I didn't mean to hit
the bitch, man!
She came at me!
We're going to start to ration.
He's sent even less food this time.
Good idea.
It's getting hotter in here
all the time.
I know. I need to wash these,
they stink!
My fucking food!
I want my food
and I want it now!
We can't keep doing this
to him.
Yes, we can.
He's a criminal.
Innocent until
proven guilty, officer.
And I found him guilty.
I'm not taking
any more chances.
Well then, why should we
even trust each other?
- We're rationing some more.
- Of course.
Are you alright, Francis?
Yeah.
- Would you shut the fuck up?
- Fuck you, bitch!
Why don't you come in
here and...
- You can't starve him, Jay.
- Why not? It gives us more.
Just give him something!
Fine. I'll give him
what he deserves.
Here.
Are you fucking taking the piss?
Hey, feed me!
- That's bullshit, man.
- You think so?
Where's the priest?
No!
- No! Stop it!
- Fuck you!
Get away!
Fucking cop!
Stop!
Get away!
I don't know what to do.
I don't know.
They call me
the Lord of Peace...
but I've come to cast wars
and cause divisions...
for only God, the world, can
the world itself be set afire...
for I am the fire,
I am the light...
I am the light that is
above them all.
I am the all,
the all is ordained to Me...
and they all came forth
from Me.
Who is near to Me
is near to fire...
and whoever's far from Me
is far from the kingdom.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Gird up your loins here now...
which part of the night
the robbers are coming in.
If you want to slay a path for men
take the sword in your hand...
and thrust it through the walls
of your own house first.
In God's name...
God help me in my
hour of weakness...
help me find my strength.
In Your blessing, Father.
- Good work!
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Why is there so much more?
- It's a reward.
- For what?
- For killing.
- That can't be why.
- Why else then?
- No way, that's awful!
- Who cares why, it's more.
If you don't want that,
I'll have it.
No. No you can't
have all that.
I'm bringing him his reward.
That's fair, Father.
- What do you want?
- Apparently our friend over there...
was happy with
what you did.
- Yeah.
- Yeah? No shit!
He sent you extra food
and some wine.
Hey, listen.
See that shit with
your wife and that...
It was an accident, I know.
Bon appetit.
Come on, come on.
'I am the resurrection and
the life', says the Lord...
'And whoever believes in Me,
even though he were dead...
will still live...
and whosoever lives and
believes in Me, will never die. '
Blessed be the name
of the Father...
the Son
and the Holy Ghost.
He didn't strike me as someone
who wanted to die, Father.
- I just left him.
- Fucking bullshit! He killed him!
No, he hanged himself.
I was in my room eating.
Of course, your wife isn't here
to lie for you this time, is she?
- Shut up! Shut up!
- He did it! He did it!
Come on!
Do something!
Are you going to use that gun ever,
'cause if you're not...
- give it to someone who will!
- No look, the priest keeps the gun!
- Someone here killed him.
- Oh yeah!
- Well, maybe he just killed himself!
- Yeah, with your scarf!
Excuse me, you're the one
who gave him his reward!
I won't stand and be mentioned
by anyone, right?
- My wife is dead!
- That's exactly the point!
You think it's his fault which makes
a pretty good case against you!
- I'm a good suspect, right?
- Yeah!
- Why don't you suspect him?
- He's a priest!
So what?
And you know what, he was a priest
when he came here, but now...
I don't trust him, and I don't trust
anyone else in here either!
Well, that's all!
That's the end of it, now stop it!
You must all look
inside yourselves...
and that which you find there
will save you!
Now stop it!
Max!
I'm having a drink
so don't try to stop me!
No, I won't.
I need to talk to you.
I'm very worried.
No, no, no, not about him.
I'm worried about the others.
Hey! I told you,
don't touch my fucking stuff!
I'm only trying it on!
It's cheap shit anyway.
Goes to show what
you know, doesn't it?
You think you're so much better
than me, don't you?
You know, all the tacky jewelry
and flashy clothes in the world...
can't change the fact that
you're a skanky little pike!
Why don't you clean up
your own shit...
- I'm fed up picking up after you!
- Then don't!
I haven't asked you to
and I don't want you to!
- Don't touch my fucking stuff!
- At least I make a fucking effort!
You haven't lifted a finger
since the first day!
You haven't had to work for anything
in your entire life, have you?
Fuck off! You know nothing
about me, nothing!
No, you're a spoiled little bitch
and I'm sick of the sight of you!
Don't ever fucking touch me
again or I'll kill you!
Do you understand me?
And flush the fucking toilet,
you skanky pig!
You know I hate to say it.
Francis, I don't trust him.
Claire and Shona,
they're too irrational.
Lea, she's so sweet,
but, you...
I think I can still rely
on you.
Can I still rely on you, Max?
- So Father, you need my help?
- Yes, I do.
And what may I ask,
is in it for me...
portion wise?
- Hi.
- No, no, no.
It wouldn't be fair.
It just wouldn't be fair.
Stop!
How dare you?
You'll take your portion
and your ration only.
Now put it down!
Now go!
No need to push!
She threatened to kill me.
Let's go.
Now! Go!
Lea!
Oh blessed Lord!
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
They won't stop now.
It's past dinner time, Father.
Better protect the food.
- Should be more this time!
- You heartless bastard!
- What?
- You knew she couldn't take it.
- She was weak, you know.
- What have you done?
Just for the money,
just to win.
- Even your own wife.
- What?
You believe that? Yeah!
Right, shoot me then!
Come on, shoot me!
Shoot me, Father!
Shoot me, do it!
Shoot me!
Shit! Jesus! Max!
Max! My God!
Shoot me!
Yeah! You won't shoot me,
I know that!
I've done something awful!
She told me that she'd kill me,
I had no other choice!
We can survive
if we stay together!
Food is the key.
What are you going to do,
call the cops? 911?
I forgot, the cop is dead.
It's too bad!
- You and me, yeah?
- You know the thing is...
what's in it for me?
Give me the gun.
The gun...
Come on Father,
give me the gun!
Give me the gun
and end it. I win!
You won't do it!
Give me the gun, please!
Give me the gun, let me end this!
Give me the fucking gun!
No, stop!
Stop it now!
She was going to steal
the food!
Let her go!
Don't make me do this!
Please, let her go!
No! Let her go!
Don't make me do this!
Let her go!
Oh blessed Father...
pray for our sinners now,
at the hour of our death.
Please my son, don't.
I'm not your son,
Father Whatever McDuffy!
I won. I won!
I won, Father!
I won!
I won. I won!
Hey, Watcher!
Watcher, I won!
I won it!
Look, look!
Give me my cash!
Give me my money, my cash!
Hey, Watcher!
Hey, Watcher! Hey!
Is there someone here?
Is someone here?
- Shit.
- Hey, I'm here.
I'm here!
Lea!
Where is she?
I'll find you!
Where can she be?
Hey, my Chorus dancer,
where are you?
Where are you?
No!
- You're sick!
- Yeah!
I'm going to catch you!
You're a freak!
I won.