My child, my baby.
Finally inside me.
Nobody is gonna take him from me.
Nobody can hurt him now.
Nobody.
Matthew.
'INSIDE'
FOUR MONTHS LATER
She's better now.
So, Sarah...
Have you picked a name for the baby yet?
All right, We'll be expecting you
tomorrow, at 7.
If nothing happens during the night,
we can induce the labor.
Don't worry, Sarah.
Everything is going to be fine.
Is there someone that could bring you
tomorrow morning?
Normally, we have an ambulance,
But on Christmas eve, maybe...
Yes, someone will bring me here.
Great.
Thank you, doctor. See you tomorrow.
Alright.
Enjoy your last peaceful night.
It won't last long.
I had four children.
I bet it's your first.
The first is terrible.
In my case, it took thirteen hours
for my first to be born.
It sucks. I mean it,
I suffered the worst pain ever.
He made me go through all that,
but was born dead.
You know you can't smoke here.
Everyone around here is a pain in the ass.
Too bad.
I must say, after all you've been through,
you shouldn't be working.
There's no reason to worry,
just a few burning cars.
I'd feel better with you at home,
not taking pictures of riots.
I'll be less paranoid.
Jean-Pierre looks decent.
Have you ever...
He's my boss.
What a shame.
I was hoping to be introduced
one of these days, you know?
So, what do you want to do?
Christmas dinner at my place
or yours?
I'm not hungry, Louise.
I'm really full.
It's going to be alright now.
Listen, I want to be alone, Louise.
Go home, please.
Hello?
What?
I don't give a damn
if he wants headlines.
I don't give a crap!
You can tell him that.
Exactly. So you deal with it.
Explain that to him.
It's 'Burning cars and
total chaos' on the frontpage.
That's my headline, end of conversation.
Thank you.
Ok. No, nothing.
Alright, see you soon.
Merry Christmas.
That bastard...
pisses me off.
The suburbs are burning down
and there's no one there to cover it.
And you, darling, how are you feeling?
It's been hard wihout you there.
They're just a bunch of
bored kids having fun.
Well, there are cars on fire,
the cops are on their toes...
My reporters are idiots.
So much for a Merry Christmas, huh?
Be at my house, 6am sharp?
Really?
I think I better...
Shorten my Christmas Eve,
so I don't keep the lady waiting.
What about you?
Will you be with your mom tonight?
I couldn't care less for this Christmas.
I rather be alone tonight.
You won't say it again next year.
I can guarantee you that.
No, Louise,
you don't need to come tomorrow.
I've told you I'm well enough alone.
We have discussed that already.
Then you'll come on Monday.
No. Jean-Pierre will pick me up.
We just decided it.
I gave him the keys.
No, I'm full.
I'm going to lay down.
Dammit.
I can't see a thing.
Who is it?
Sorry to bother, but I need help.
Can I make a quick phone call?
- Don't you have a cell phone?
- My battery ran out.
- What happened?
- My car broke down in the street corner.
No, I'm sorry, but...
My husband works tomorrow.
He's sleeping already.
I won't make any noise.
It'll just take a minute, I promise.
Please.
No, I'm sorry.
Listen, try... try some other house.
There's plenty of people still awake.
Please, I'll just take a second.
I don't wanna be alone,
with all that violence.
My husband is sleeping, I told you!
Your husband is not sleeping, Sarah.
He is dead.
What?
Open the door, Sarah.
Who are you?
How do you know my name?
Open the door and you'll find out.
I'm gonna call the police, you hear me?
Alright. Go fuck yourself!
Hello?
There's a strange woman by my door.
Please, hurry up.
I don't know what she wants.
She knows my name...
She knows everything about me...
I'm pregnant!
The police will be here in
five minutes! Just get out!
Good evening. Did you call us
about somebody trying to break in?
Yes, it was me. Come in.
Do you live alone?
Yes.
- Another guy afraid to be a father?
- It's not that simple.
- Who's this woman?
- I don't know. But she knows my name.
Which is in the mailbox right outside.
She knows things about me.
Are you sure it's a woman?
Have you seen the face, or...
No. She stayed in the dark.
I tried to take a picture of her,
but this is all I got.
Alright. There's not much
we can do with this.
There's no one around.
Don't worry, she's gone.
I'll lock you up for tonight.
We'll notify the night patrol.
We have all our men in service, but...
we'll send a notification.
They'll show up during the night
to see if you're ok.
Thank you.
- It's very quiet for a Christmas Eve around here.
- It is always like this.
- Good night, m'am.
- Don't worry, she won't return.
Have a good night.
...November 27, and the accidental death
of two French, sons of immigrants.
The riot has spread through the poor
areas of Paris suburbs...
and the big cities.
A great number of innocent people,
police officers and firemen were injured.
More than 300 communities
were affected...
4.900 vehicles have been burned...
More than 2.000 imigrants
involved in the riot...
What do you want?
You're pissing me off.
Comments from the secretary of interior,
disclosed by the press...
Hello, it's me again,
Jean-Pierre.
You must be eating, I guess.
Something weird happened tonight...
and I hope tomorrow you can
blow up some pictures for me.
All right. See you in the morning.
Sarah?
Forgive me. I'm sorry to bother you.
Jean-Pierre Montalban,
Sarah's chief-editor.
Sarah is going to my
Christmas dinner.
I just stoped by to see if she's... I'm
worried about all this violence.
She asked me to pick her up...
she gave me the keys... tomorrow morning.
Anyway, I see her mother has
arrived before me.
When a daughter needs help,
a mother knows.
Sure.
Well, is everything okay?
She went to bed an hour ago.
I better get going.
See you later.
Please, don't go just yet.
Would you have a drink?
I was looking forward to meeting you.
Say you'll accept the drink.
Sra. Scarangella,
are you excited to become a grandmother?
It took hours for her to sleep.
Don't wake her up.
Of course, you're right. I'm sorry.
It's good she's been holding it together.
She's been through a lot because
of the accident. Me too, of course.
These last months
have been terrible.
But I know this birth will
save us. One more drink?
What the hell
My little photographer, always
dropping her pictures around.
When did she take this? Any idea?
She called me about it.
Really? What did she say?
Something was bothering her. It was
a picture she wanted blown up.
Blown up?
I'm not sure what,
she wanted...
to blow it up or
just make it clearer.
That face, for example.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Where's Sarah?
Maybe you should tell us who you are.
You just enter people's houses like that?
Lower your voice, Sarah is sleeping.
Where's my daughter?
So, who are you?
That's you in the picture.
Sarah?
Are you all right?
Mom.
Mom?
Mom!
Sarah?
Help!
Help me! Help me!
Damn!
Who are you?
Open the door!
Open!
Why me?
I want one.
What kind of man would fuck
a crazy maniac like you?
Open up, Sarah!
Don't be afraid.
You don't need this baby anymore.
I'll take care of him.
What are you talking about?
Let's stop by to check on
the lady, ok?
Then we'll take our lucky guy
to the precint. Mr. AbdeI Shani Essadi.
You got the wrong guy, I swear.
I don't play with molotov cocktails.
And if I'm gonna torch some cars, I'm not
bringing my ID in my wallet.
Shit!
- I didn't do anything.
- Don't try to mess with me.
First, we'll see if
Ms. Scarangella is sleeping...
after that we'll lock this
young fella up...
And go back after his friends.
We can't let you spend Christmas Eve
by yourself in jail.
Your friends are loose.
We'll bring them to you, so you can party.
I don't give a fuck about Christmas!
- Okay, you don't celebrate Christmas...
- Excuse me.
Hello? How are you, sweetheart?
- His girl is a pain in the ass.
- Tell me about it.
But he's in the car
with the heat on.
No. We're getting off duty.
We'll check on some woman
and be back right after.
Yes, I love you. Stop it.
- She's giving you a hard time, huh?
- Just a second.
Shut up, okay?
Not you, I'm talking to a punk
in the car.
- Walking through the snow.
- Sra. Scaringella, it's the police.
- Hello, how are you doing?
- Merry Christmas.
We're passing to see if everything's alright.
We've been warned about a
woman disturbing you tonight.
No. It's been hours, I'm fine.
- Don't hesitate to call if she comes back.
- Sure.
Sorry, what's that noise?
It's my old washing machine's coil.
It's cheaper to use it at night, huh?
- Be well.
- Merry Christmas.
- See you later.
- Goodbye, officer.
Man, a coffee now...
No, I'm listening to you.
- Did you forget anything?
- Just a stupid detail.
- Just curious about which name he'll have.
- Who?
Your child.
Keep an eye on her!
Fuck! Arrest her! Arrest her!
Hands behind your back! On the floor, now!
It's a fucking war zone!
It's the police!
Don't move!
Okay, I'm going to remove the scissors.
Don't move.
Open the door! Open the door!
No!
Good, you can make it.
Open the door.
Open the door!
Oh my God!
Sorry, gotta go.
- You'll have to come along.
- What?
Something went wrong.
This is police brutality, man.
You're gonna tie me up like a dog?
Shut the fuck up and move your ass.
- Hey, wait a second!
- Move.
- I wanna get out of here, please!
- Take this!
Let me go!
- We've got get out of this place!
- Come here!
Are you okay?
Stay calm, all right?
It's gonna be okay.
You... put yourself together!
That's alright, I'll be right back. Wait here.
- You! Do you know how to use this?
- No!
Just push the trigger and shoot. Hey!
Just point and squeeze the trigger!
- Please, let me get out of here!
- You're coming with me.
I'll be right back, stay here.
- What happened?
- Is she gone?
She's gone. She escaped through the window.
- She's still here!
- Calm down!
Do you have a fuse box?
You know where it is?
Look at me! Do you know where it is?
Downstairs? Let's go.
Wait, I'm going to give you a gun.
Take this, take it.
Watch out!
Shit!
Do you have any bandages?
Here? In the drawer? Hold this!
Hold the flashlight. Take it!
I can't see. Take it.
Hold up the light, dammit!
That's alright, relax.
- Take off the handcuffs!
- Shut up!
Hold this. Hold the light still!
I need to fix it.
Wait for me here.
Stay still.
- I killed my mother!
- It's alright, just calm down.
- We've got get out of here!
- Damn!
I'm going to call for backup and
an ambulance, ok?
You'll be fine.
Alright.
Ok. Put this on. Can you walk?
Wait in the bedroom. Give me your hand.
Give the hand! Help her.
Can you walk?
Are you alright? I'll be right back.
C'mon, let's go.
Hold the flashlight.
Ok, I'll let you go when the
power is back.
When you get out, find
any police officer.
Hold the flashlight,
there's nobody here!
Don't point it at my eyes!
Fuck!
- What?
- The light beam!
What the fuck is this?
Go back! Go back!
Miss! She is still here!
Come on, get up! Get up! Dammit!
Where are the goddamn keys?
Sarah.
Where are you, bitch?
Could you kill me again, Sarah?
You've killed me once.
My son, my baby.
Finally inside me.
Nobody is taking him away from me.
Nobody can hurt him now.
Nobody.
They say there were
no survivors.
Officer?
The baby is coming out!
The baby...
Mommy!
Calm down.
I am here.
I think it's stuck!
Mommy!