The story of the week
Oh...
Here it goes
5 years ago, when I was 21...
Becoming a vegetarian
was a major trend
So I went on a vegetarian
camp for four days
As soon as we arrived,
we took a walk
The guide pointed to
a clover and said...
'We can eat this' and ate it
Then a few people tried it
It tasted strange and bitter
But we thought it was
a good experience
But they wouldn't
give us any food
When we asked at night
why there's no food...
He said, 'Didn't you eat
the plants during the walk?'
- Who? Who?
- What?
The darn guide said!
'Didn't you eat the grass
on our walk?'
Let go!
Help me!
BEDEVILLED
How many times did I tell you?
Low-income families can
get up to $30,000
But you have no income,
so the maximum is $20,000
But you said I could
I already moved
That was the maximum
Anyway, we can't lend you $30,000
so borrow it from someone
If I could, why would
I ask for a loan?
Then move to a different place
But I paid the deposit
and moved my stuff in!
So, try borrowing
from someone else
Who'd lend money to
a single, old woman!
You should've made sure
before signing the lease
But you said I could
have the money!
I never said that!
Ma'am
Hello? Stop calling, please
I'll be out for a sec
If the manager asks for me...
Please leave now, ma'am
Next Counter Please
I'm working
Sorry, but you're
always so busy
And you never write back
Can't you come fora visit?
I gotta go
They can't see me for sure?
Of course Strictly confidential
They look about right
You're right
Excuse me?
The victim's friends saw them
bothering her at a nightclub
Isn't that all you need?
But they didn't witness the assault
That's why we need your statement
But, I didn't get a good
look at their faces
Just try to remember
It's them, but we have no proof
Sergeant Choi!
Sorry, ma'am
- He doesn't have the ring
-A ring?
Yes One of them had
a ring with a skull on it
The doctor said it
looked like a ring, too
But it's hard to tell the shape
on multiple wounds
Don't contact me anymore
- But if you remember...
- Then I'll call you
But unlikely
You bastards!
Why won't you admit it! You did it!
I'll kill all you bastards!
- Please tell me everything!
- Please!
You said you saw them
Please tell me everything!
You saw them!
Please, say what happened!
You saw them! Please!
Let's not meet again
I got real scary buddies
Fucking up a bitch ain't nothing
- Did they say anything to you?
- No
Would you like to
go inside and talk?
No
-You're back
- She's still here?
Everything's set
Have your landlord sign this
Thank you very much!
Thank you so much Thank you!
What happened?
-What did you tell the manager?
- I didn't say anything about you
Ji-soo, you talk as if
I made a mistake
Of course not I just
felt so bad for her
Are you close with the manager?
Or close with all your male superiors?
Be careful
There's a limit to how far a flirt
can go in the financial world
Ji-soo...
I'm really sorry. A drink tonight?
Ok, let's make up. Where to?
Hello?
Hello!
How about...
Ms CHUNG!
Get out!
Take a vacation
Who is it?
-Who is it?
- The superintendent
- I don't recognize your voice
- I'm a superintendent
What is it?
Your mailbox is way overloaded
On vacation
Up until 10 years ago,
boats went in twice a day
Now there are
only 9 people left
Who are you visiting
on Moo-do Island?
My grandfather used
to live there
-What was his name?
- Suk-hwan KIM
I knew it! You're Hae-won, right?
I thought it was you!
Remember me?
'Course you don't
You were so pretty back then
Still damn pretty
You married?
Of course you are! I'm not
Hurry! Hurry!
-You're Hae-won, right?
-Yes
Really Hae-won?
Don't touch her with
those dirty hands
Sorry
-You're really Hae-won, right?
-Yes, I'm really Hae-won
It's you! Hae-won!
Well, I'm off
She's here
Who? Kim's granddaughter?
You're Hae-won?
It's you alright
You haven't changed a bit
Remember us?
So pretty and white
Is it from drinking Seoul's water?
- That's right
- Of course
That's my hubby
Remember? Man-jong
That's his brother, Chul-jong
Man-jong and Chul-jong
Oh please Don't call 'em
by their names like that
Why'd you come here on vacation?
There's nothing here
City folks like to come for
fresh and water on vacations
This ain't no tourist attraction
-When ya going back?
- I'm staying for about a week
You'll change your
mind in a day
Back to work If it rains,
the potatoes will rot
Aren't ya coming?
Bok-nam, come and help out
After I take Hae-won
to her house
What's Chul-jong and that
old man chewing on?
Don't know?
It's called bozo leaf cuz you
become a bozo chewing on it
Here
It's hot, ain't it?
Remember?
We wrote that there
Your grandpa got mad like hell
Mama?
Go on Say hello
to mama's friend
Come here
What's your name?
Yeon-hee don't know
how to act around others
What grade is she in?
She's 10, but she
doesn't go to school
I want to send her
But Man-jong and his aunt
don't think girls need schooling
Said, if she gets educated,
she'll run away from us
Who doesn't send kids to
elementary school these days?
They even send kids to study
abroad in kindergarten
Really?
I hope I can send her
to school next year
She goes to the school
to read books these days
So I was wondering...
It's been 15 years since
grandpa passed away
How's this place so clean?
Take a guess
I spent three whole days
cleaning this place
Thanks you were saying?
Huh?
You were going to say
something about Yeon-hee?
It's nothing You just got here
You must be starving
I'll go get some food
I'm going night fishing
with Yeon-hee
- Really?
-Yup
You always come
back empty-handed
You love going
fishing with papa?
- Lazy-head not sleepin'?
-You're back?
Was it fun?
Did ya catch anything?
How can an islander
be so bad at fishin'?
You caught no fish
for over 2 weeks
Why, so you can pig
out if I do catch 'em?
Not only me Yeon-hee, you,
and that brother of yours
Didn't I tell you to show respect
talking about me and my family?
Even dogs and pigs learn
if they get beaten Why not you!
You a dog?
Don't eat on the floor
This is why you need
a man around
Even a dozen women
Can't do that
Damn right
Nephew? Can you fix
our shed after this?
Sure
- How about our door?
- Sure
Do it yourself
My nephew's dying
doing all the work
Damn right
He can't die
Without him, we're all dead
Damn right!
What you doing?
Don't just sit there
Make some noodles
-Yes, ma'am
- Finish that up, first
Yes, ma'am
Let her rest,
she must be tired
It's nothing compared
to men's work
What's Kim's granddaughter up to?
Still sleepin'
Damn woman still in bed
in broad daylight
Seoul life must be really hard
A woman's most happy
with a dick in her mouth
Still not married and taking vacation?
Stupid little girl
There's lots of women in Seoul
who ain't married
So?
You've been yappin' about
Seoul a lot these days
- It's so good
- Here, have some more
All this trouble for me
I'll cook for myself now
It's no trouble
Wanna go take a bath
at the pond?
The pond?
Remember where we used to
go when we were little?
No one will look
People here all sleep
after sundown
I'll go first to do some laundry
Hurry up
- Give me your laundry, too
- It's okay I'll do it
With these hands?
No laundry rooms here, right?
Seoul people do
laundry in rooms?
How strange
Bok-nam!
This island has a lot of fresh water
We even had rice
farms in the past
So clean and white
So smooth and slippery
Remember we used to bathe here
at nights when we were kids?
Yeah, the water was
nice and cool
What are you doing!
Oh, come on It's just me
Just scared me, that's all
About what?
Nothing
Bet ya got men lined up
like flies on a corpse, huh?
Phones should work since they set
a base station or somethin' up there
But who knows?
The only phone here is
the one at Auntie's house
What ya doing, Uncle?
You like flowers?
What ya doing, mama's friend?
Mama's friend?
Just call me auntie
Auntie?
That's better
Want me to read it to you?
Fold 'em for me
Your mom will be upset
if you fold up your textbooks
Mama gave 'em to
me to fold 'em
What?
All except this one
Social Studies
-Why not?
- Cuz it talks about Seoul here
I wanna get holes
in my ears like you
Why you
I wish my boobs will
grow big like yours soon
Scream! Scream bitch!
-What's going on?
- It's nothing
She's here again?
I said scream!
What's going on?
Nothing Just foolin' around
Watch Yeon-hee for me?
Stay at auntie's house
Hold hands
Go on
Tell her to sell our honey, too
Yes, ma'am
How can ya eat
listening to that?
When another bitch is sucking
on your hubby's dick
Look at you
You're eatin' like a damn pig
I'm sorry
You're really tanned
Put this on your face It's sunscreen
Don't need your pity
I didn't want to come,
but he paid my boss
three times the rate
I'm sorry Really
Why are you sorry?
You ain't the monster
You'll ruin your body like that
I know-that
What the...
How can you live with him?
I'd run away
Probably kill me if I tried again
Where'd you run away to?
Should've gone to Seoul
No one can find you there
Don't even need this Seoul
water will make you white
Then why you living like that?
Wanna run away together?
We'll go to Seoul and work
at restaurants or something
But a kid needs her father
Who needs that?
I grew up fine without a dad
Oh, right Real fine
Ain't ya fixing dinner?
Hey!
Dumb bitch
-What?
- Get the rest of the honey
The boat's coming in tomorrow
-After I cool off the stings
-Why you little!
Put bean paste on it
-What the hell you up to?
- Stop cursing
What's with your face?
Just stung by bees
You let your husband
get away with that?
It's just a couple of stings
Not that
Right in front of you!
He had sex with a girl
in your room
and you act like it's nothing?
We keep things to
ourselves here
Not like you're gonna take me in
You need someone
to take care of you?
You're an adult
You should take care of yourself
- Come on
- It's hard
Not too close!
5 minutes No, just for
1 minute, please
My baby girl's home
Let's go take a bath
What are you doing?
I wanna be loved by papa, too
You said to try to
get loved by papa
That ain't what I was talkin' about
Where'd you get this?
Did you steal it from that girl?
No
- Then where?
- Gave it to me
The girl gave it to you?
Answer me! Want me to
beat it out of you!
Papa gave it to me!
Why would he give this to you?
What about these bunny undies?
Why's the laundry on the ground?
Did you fight? Over this?
Damn girls
Put it on All over your body, bitch!
Don't get jealous of the kid!
Let's just give it to your mama
I'll get ya something better
Take it and scram!
Get the hell out of my sight
You've been laid off
as per the Employment Law
Manager
The caller you have reached is...
Oh, hi
I'm leaving on the next boat
I had a good rest thanks to you
I'm going be a new me
when I get back to Seoul
Though it won't be easy
to change all of a sudden
Thank you for everything
Can I come by often?
What's this? Blood?
It's not blood
Why's this on your face?
- Hae-won...
-What's with you?
-What?
Can't you take Yeon-hee and
me with you to Seoul?
You can go anywhere you want
But I don't know how
to live on the mainland
It's the same Seoul is
scarier to live in then here
-You said you'd take me
-When? 15 years ago?
Yeah Don't that count as a promise?
Next time After I take
care of something first
Next time, again?
Fine Then just take
Yeon-hee? Please?
Why Yeon-hee?
Don't ask why
Please, I'm begging you
If you take her, I won't call
or write you no more
Oh, come on!
Just tell me If you don't,
I'm not taking her
I think Man-jong... must have
screwed... Yeon-hee
That makes no sense
What?
I know you want
to go to Seoul...
But still, how can you say
something like that?
Try a more believable
lie next time!
You think I'm lying?
You know what
the bastards are like!
I don't know anything!
Reading?
Why do you want
your boobs to grow?
Don't you know?
That's how girls are loved
Yeon-hee... Does daddy love you?
How does daddy love you?
What ya doing here?
Yeon-hee, come here
You're old enough
to earn your keep
Stop idling around
- Take her and feed her
- Sure thing
- But I need that book
- Let's just go and eat
-You should take the next boat
- There's something...
Laws are meant to change
according to circumstances
And Bok-nam's damn
good at lying
She grew up like a beggar
She'll beg like a dog
to get anything
Then let the police investigate
If you're so sure,
why don't you report it?
You know that Yeon-hee is not
Man-jong's real daughter?
What?
If you're not going to protect this
island, stop worrying and go
Mi-ran? It's me
It's Moo-do Island
Remember what you said before?
About going to Seoul?
- Mom
- Quiet
-Where we going? I'm sleepy
-We runnin' away
-Where?
- To the mainland
Papa said the mainland's trouble
-You can go to school there
- I don't wanna go to school!
Then fine
Just go where papa ain't
But I like papa I like it here!
So you don't wanna go?
- If I don't, you're not going either?
- Of course not
If we don't go now, you'll
get beat all your life?
Then I'll go with you mama
Cuz I can't stand
you getting beat
Let's go The boat's comin'
That hurts Not so hard
-You crying, mama?
- Never saw mama cry, huh?
No, I heard you cry and say
you'd rather die than live like this
-What's good about dying?
- I'm sorry. You're right
Rolling in dung is
better than dying
I don't want to roll in dung!
I warned you, not him!
No one else would
come here at this hour
Still, not him You stupid!
Don't worry I don't care
for people's business
Just pay me enough for the boat
Where'd you get this?
Oh no! Look!
Mama! Hurry! Hurry! Come on!
Let's go now!
Man-jong's coming!
Hurry!
Please hurry! He's coming!
I gotta count it!
Shit, I lost my count!
Let's go!
- Hurry!
- Let me count first!
Where's my damn lighter?
Got a light?
- Hurry!
- Hurry up!
We'll go when I'm done counting
One, two, three...
Sis! Sis!
Sis!
Papa!
- Papa!
- Come here, you bitch!
I take in a bitch with a kid!
And you sneak off on me! You bitch!
You bitch!
Don't just stand there!
Stop him!
Break her damn legs!
Like dogs and bitches who try to run away...
Break 'em so she can't go!
Get up!
Stop your brother
She's gonna die!
Papa!
Get up!
Dumb fucking whore!
Warned you to stay away
from people's business!
Stop it, papa!
I'll live with you!
Stop hitting her!
I treated you good!
And you betray your papa?
Is it cuz I'm not your real dad?
I'll show you how papa
can get real mad!
Are you okay!
Stop it! Not Yeon-hee
Careful, Man-jong!
Are you crazy?
You can't throw stones
at your husband!
A woman can get stoned
to death but not a man?
He took you and your kid in!
You should be grateful, bitch!
- Damn right
- Of course
Quit saying that!
Why don't I know
who the father is?
I was raped by more
than one bastard!
- By every single one of them!
- Shut up! You filthy bitch!
- Damn bitch!
- Papa!
You damn bitch!
Yeon-hee? Wake up, Yeon-hee!
- Get some water Hurry!
-Yes, sis
Yeon-hee...
Yeon-hee... Wake up
Let's go to Seoul...
Yeon-hee...
Stop fussin' bitch She'll be fine
with some bean paste Move!
Let go!
Don't touch her! Let go!
Get away!
Thanks for coming all this way
Must be hard taking
care of the elders
Why'd your aunt
call me out here?
How's your father doing?
He said to say hello
when I said I'm coming here
If you told me before,
I would've called a doctor
You need a medical report
to file a death these days
She just slipped and fell
Ain't no different if a doctor sees her
Actually, I can draw up
the report myself
I'm Yeon-hee's grandma
If you look at it,
I'm her grandma, too
How would I look if you are
suspicious of her death
- But her bruises are...
- Bok-nam? Why don't you tell him?
If we were lying, would
her mama stay still?
She's quiet
Then, did she kill the kid?
What did you say?
Move for a sec
What did you just say?
That bastard killed her
He kicked her
She fell
I wasn't gonna say this but...
If you're gonna blame me,
I have no choice
This bitch here tried to pack up
and run away this morning
-Ain't that right?
- Huh? Yes, sir
Were you there too,
when she died?
-You don't believe me?
- Go on I'm listening
I knew she was gonna run away
But she tried to take Yeon-hee, too
I couldn't let that happen
So, I told her to leave the kid
and go if she wants
- I even gave her some money
-Yeah right
You never gave me
a dime all these years!
Then where's that money from?
I stole it
From that bastard's pocket
Boast why don't ya?
Damn thief!
Our nephew's trying to cover up
that run-away bitch's sins
- He's got a good heart
- Good heart my ass!
-Watch your fucking language
- Man-jong
It's money I made from
the honey, anyways!
Fine... I'm sorry for not
providing you with much
There's not much here for her
So I told her to go
and start a new life
But...
- But the kid... Not her!
- Man-jong
Let the kid decide
So? What did she say?
A child would normally
follow the mother
But her mama was so mean,
the kid chose the stepfather
She held my ankle tight
and begged to stay
But she pulled her away!
And fell down Then bumped
her head on a rock
God damn it
Bok-nam? Is that right?
Then what about
Bok-nam's friend?
Did you see the child die?
No I was sleeping at the time
Good work
The honey's for you
in the mornings
A big spoonful when you wake up
I should save good honey like this
Wait Bok-nam's friend said
she's going back, too
Don't worry
You're busy Go on
Get the stuff on the boat
- No, I'll carry them
- It's okay
-What's this?
- Boat fare It's not much
Wait! Wait up!
She got something to say to him?
What's her hurry?
No need to hurry
A boat will come tomorrow
No more buses to Seoul today
Damn right
Bok-nam must be sad
Shouldn't you console her?
Damn right
She could use a friend now
Tell Bok-nam thanks
Seoul girls won't stand
you messing with 'em
Especially with a witness
- Isn't it dirty?
- Nope
You're laughing?
Let go!
Man-jong! Get her!
Stupid Dumb bastards
Boat's in
Don't slack off and dig up
potatoes before it rains!
Damn bitch
Building a grave in the yard
Scram!
Or I'll bury you right
next to that!
Chul-jong! Let's go!
Excited to go into
town, Chul-jong?
Move your scrawny ass
Come y'all and have a drink
So damn heavy Damn it
This is why we need
a man around
They'll be back tomorrow
Stop trembling
Bok-nam, take a break will ya?
Sis?
Don't she look a bit crazy? Sis?
Strange if she weren't
after losing her kid
Let her rest for a bit
She'd go crazy doing nothing
She'll get over it faster this way
I'm doing her good
- I'll go get some fish
- Really, sis?
- Don't Get all excited
- Okay, okay
Damn bitch ain't worth shit
How about a song?
Oh time, do not come or go
My precious youth is gone I'm all old
Ari-ari-rang, Ssuri-Ssurirang,
Arari-ga nat-nae
Ari-rang Arari-ga nat-nae
Were you born a beauty?
I was born an ugly
Ari-ari-rang, Ssuri-Ssurirang,
Arari-ga nat-nae
Ari-rang
I stared at the sun for long
and it spoke to me
Said, if I hold back, I'll get sick!
Say something!
What's going on!
She's... she's gone crazy!
We need a man...
at a time like this
The boat's coming soon
The men will be back
I just have to hang on till then
Auntie! Slow down!
You're gonna fall!
Damn whore!
Damn you! Damn whore!
Stop it, now!
You've done enough!
Damn bitch You're dead now
The men are back
I came to this island
when I was 15
I swam for over 50 years!
You! Stay right here
I'm coming back with the men!
- Did you hear something?
- Hear what?
Nothing
Go check the hives
See if they're okay from the rain
Damn stupid wife probably
left 'em out in the rain
-Wanna stay for a drink?
- Sure!
Damn it, Auntie...
Should've worn glasses
Why were all these potatoes
left in the rain?
Where the hell is everyone?
Damn What's that stench?
Out of Service
Hey, gramps! Everything okay?
Says everything's fine
That man's living long
Remember when all
the men died in the storm
except him?
All the women beat him
saying he killed their husbands
Then they all took turns taking
him home and feeding him
All except my mama that is
Your mom took him up the hill
instead of your home
Where the fuck is everyone?
-Watch your Damn language
- Sorry
Dumbass
Respect your elder first
Stupid bastard
I said, give me some water!
Watch out!
What the hell?
You crazy bitch!
Should tend to
the funeral offerings...
Why'd you kill them!
Crazy bitch! Why! Why!
Why didn't you just kill yourself!
I didn't wanna die
Then I should live it up
You never opened up to me
Treated me like trash
Always cold like a rock to me!
That's why my dick never
got hard in front of you
Is that why you
touched my kid? Huh?
Shut your damn mouth!
If the cops get me,
I'll tell 'em everything you did
Fine
Killing you is self defense
If you kill her, I'll call the cops
I'll kill you painlessly like a pig
What about her?
Make it look like you killed her?
Or take her as my new wife?
What?
Why? Looks like the killer
is scared to die
What would I be scared of?
- I'm just sorry to you, honey
- Honey? Crazy bitch
Does it hurt?
A lot?
Hold on I'll put bean paste on it
Doesn't hurt now, does it!
Doesn't hurt now! You bastard!
You damn son of a bitch!
You son of a bitch!
What the hell? Get up! Hurry!
Let go!
The fuck is wrong with this!
Hurry! Hurry up
you dumb bastard!
What are you looking at?
Hurry up you dumb bastards!
I'm the only one here
You crazy, too?
Damn crazy bitch Shit! Fuck!
Shit!
Hurry! Hurry!
Quick!
Moo-do Island?
At least $100 to go
Right now? Be right there
Hey, Jang!
Sail over after the game
What game? I got nothing I'll go
What took you so long?
Where you headed?
Thinking of going to see Seoul
How long since you
been on land?
Since I was born
So about 30 years
Damn, didn't you go crazy
being stuck there all your life?
Do I look sane to you?
Play me a song, why don't you
Then I won't charge you
Aren't you getting off?
There's a bus to Seoul
on the main road
Have yourself a good trip
What's this for?
There are kind people?
Night Duty Room
Sergeant Seo?
I'll notify headquarters and
check out Moo-do Island
Yes, sir I'll call you from the island
Let go of me!
Go away!
Hey! Help!
Let go!
- Play it
-What?
Like back then
-What!
- The song you played before
- Don't do this Bok-nam
- Do what?
Why are you doing this to me?
You're too unkind
Here Go on
In the village... if someone
would stop working...
Auntie used to say...
'That's like Bok-nam...
not picking out the weeds'
I... can't stand that anymore
I wandered today to
the hill, Maggie...
To watch the scene below
The creek and the rusty old mill
Please have a seat
It was them
You bitch!
You wanna die, bitch?
Dear Hae-won,
I miss you so much
My dear Hae-won,
I need to ask you a favor
You're the only one who can help me
My dear Hae-won
I miss you so much
Your friend, Bok-nam