(narrator)
In the 16th Century,
the mystic John Dee wrote
the "Sigillum Aemeth",
a book of musical chants
that were meant to
summon angels,
but brought
forth demons instead.
Fearing the unholy power of his
dark songs, Dee tried to destroy
the book, but
failed.
Sought by sorcerers and
dark rules for centuries,
the book had
been lost
...until now.
(Men chant in Latin)
(man)
Bequeath protection upon
thine followers who walketh
in the footsteps of--
And your appeasement
of the gods of --
Have failed.
(man)
What seven blood packs
not enough, Ronny?
(man)
Yeah, this shit's never coming
out of my tunic, by the way.
(Ronny)
I don't know what to
tell you guys, okay?
The appeasement fails?
(Eric)
It's bullshit.
You failed, Eric.
Okay?
Maybe if you made
a meaningful sacrifice.
Hey, that's
bullshit, Ronny.
(Eric)
We're over here in the woods
in the middle of the night.
We nailed the chant.
Come on.
Had everything that
game plan laid out.
Can't keep just failing
my appeasements forever.
(Ronny)
I'm sorry.
(Eric)
F you, Hung.
(Ronny)
The appeasement fails because
Eric wasn't meaning it.
He wasn't
being meaningful.
(man)
Bullshit, Ronny.
(Ronny)
I don't know what
to tell you guys.
(Eric)
Sometimes I don't know who's
harder to appease, Ronny.
(Ronny)
If you don't stop complaining,
the gods of --
are going to curse
all your characters
with a case of evil herpes!
Eric, you failed.
Maybe if you made
a meaningful sacrifice.
Guys, how will we ever taste
triumph at Evermore with this
weak bullshit?
Fear not, Sir Reginald, for
I have just the magic needed.
Excuse me while I whipeth
this out.
What was that?
Hey, Dude,
what's that?
What?
Oh shit!
Oh!
Eat paint, -- fuckers!
(Indistinct shout)
(man)
This'll teach you
to play your
fucking wizard
game in our woods.
Run!
Run, you freaks.
Don't ever
come back.
Hey, check
this shit out.
Harry Pooper dropped
his book.
Yeah, tear
that shit.
Come on, man.
Destroy the book.
Rip it
open.
What the fuck?
(Muffled screaming)
Fuck.
Jesus motherfucker.
The book fucked
up your face.
Ahh!
(man)
Be strong,
Sir Reginald.
Be strong, I say.
Oh man.
Fuck.
Shit!
We gotta go back
for the book.
(man)
What book?
I brought that kickass old book
I was gonna use for my spells!
Fuck!
I must have dropped it when
those people attacked us!
Shit!
Fuck!
(man)
Is this it?
That's it.
Whoo.
Thank God.
Sorry about
freaking out.
No problem.
Ronny Kwok, he's gonna
shit when he sees that.
We'll be back,
you redneck cocksuckers.
This I vow.
♪♪
♪ Cast down in divine ♪
♪ Shadows of
our dead minions ♪
♪ Drag me into the abyss ♪
♪ He is reborn
in the dark light ♪
Bleh.
♪ He instigates thy doom ♪
Turn off the music!
Turn it off!
What?
Turn this music off!
Joe, come on.
Come on.
You are
this close.
How close?
Damn, man.
That shit is tight.
It's called "Your
Heart Sucks My Soul."
It's kind of
a love song, you know?
Mm-hmm.
I wrote it as
a surprise for Beth.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Listen, if that song
doesn't say love and commitment,
I don't
know what does.
We need to have a talk.
I am way
ahead of you.
How about you,
me, dinner, tonight?
Somewhere with
a tablecloth?
I got a little something
special I want to give you.
Wait.
Don't tell me it's--
Is it what
I think it is?
No.
Yes.
I don't know.
What do you
think it is?
Don't do anything big
involving jewelry, okay?
I mean, I need to concentrate
on my career.
It's not the right thing
for that sort of commitment.
Oh, no, no,
I get it.
Whoa.
It's cool.
It's
cool.
I mean, why mess with
a good thing, right?
Time out here, Joe.
You're breaking up with me.
Will you listen to me?
You have a college degree
in communications studies.
You could be doing anything
you wanted.
Hold up.
I am doing what I want.
You live in a fake castle
leeching off your accidental
millionaire loser friend playing
black metal in your bedroom.
You will
never change.
Uh, it's doom metal.
Who the fuck asked you?
Well, he's right.
Gilberto, you're
the fucking man.
It was black.
Then we went through
a sludge phase.
Now it's more doom.
I need to focus on
my future, my career.
It's important that
I align myself
with successful people, Joe.
I'm sorry, but
that's just how it is.
(car alarm)
Hey, dude, where's
my plus-3 mace?
Am I thy
weapon's keeper?
Hey, man.
Found it!
Oh, hey, dude.
You bent
my mace.
That's not cool.
Sorry, man.
My mom made me this mace.
It's still
fierce.
♪♪
Ahh!
That's a power ballad.
What's wrong with him?
Oh.
She dumped you,
didn't she?
Fuck off!
Whoa, nice shot.
So your body is already
subconsciously moving on.
I knew that this
day would come.
You had a vision of her just
ripping out my heart, huh?
Yeah.
Thanks for the heads up,
mighty warlock.
I'm a 26-level
wizard, buddy.
I know that you know that;
you're just trying to be
hurtful.
Fucking Beth.
Dude, look, I'm sorry for what
happened, but you two hadn't
been right for each
other for a long time.
It's only the rejection
that hurts.
You'll get over that.
Maybe she's right.
Maybe... I should be
making some changes.
Maybe I should
move out of here.
No, there's no
need for drama.
You always have a place
here at meine castle.
I still love her.
We can't leave
him like this.
I know.
I'll be fine.
Just go.
Go.
Kill your fake
dragons.
This is awkward.
I know what
you need.
Come on.
Come on!
I told you, I don't
do that shit any more.
Yeah and the reason you quit
just kicked you to the curb.
So I think it's high time that
you got back in the saddle.
It's a sativa, dude.
It'll lift your spirits
but not knock you out.
Just do it.
♪♪
I love you.
I love you too, Joe.
(laughing)
Sweet Jesus.
Wait.
Oh no.
Fuck me.
Aye, Sir Dragonoth have been
detained by Minerva,
the sea hag.
His bewitchment by the siren's
song shall be the nail thine
army --,
King Diamond the Red.
We shall see.
Until Evermore.
'Til Evermore.
Eric!
Hung!
Where the
fuck are we?
'Tis the kingdom of Eliphaz,
my naïve friend.
-- and dress me.
Aye.
It just
felt right.
Adventuring is exactly
what thou needst.
"Needst" is not
a word.
Where we are, it is.
I'm taking
this shit off.
Whoa!
Now is not the time
to lose thy nerve,
brave and
scorned warrior.
Thou has been recruited to
fight in the glorious army
of Kabedrah.
The epic battle
of Evermore.
Come, Sir Hung.
(Ronny)
That looks terrible.
My three-year-old nephew
could make a better map.
He's got learning
disabilities.
It'll have to do.
You, my friend,
are on dragon duty.
Take these and make sure that
weeee are good to go.
And Dragon Rider!
Just don't fuck
with my stereo.
The dead meadows
of Bodom.
Grass is nourished
by the blood of heroes.
Hmm?
Are you listening?
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Continue.
And here we have
Fengyrian Falls.
Oh.
Remember, gentlemen, your
supervision of this script and
the monsters contained within
make this event come alive.
Follow me now.
Adventures lie waiting
like sleeping dragons!
Hah?
And here we have
Novum Castellum!
Ah, each band of
heroes will complete
a Class Three quest
this eve.
By gathering at the plains of
Evermore, the battle betwixt
the realms of
King Diamond --
Though there will be a big
surprise in store for all.
And as game master, I will be
watching over all of this.
You can think
of me as God.
Excuse me a minute.
Ah, Gwen.
Just whom
I wanted to see.
I have been watching you these
battle-swept nights of the
campaign and you
have shown your mettle.
So verily, the time
has come for
you to ascend
to the upper realms.
Oh God.
The game hasn't
started already, has it?
We don't have to talk in
Dorkinese yet, do we?
I thought maybe you'd want to be
my assistant head game master
and you could be
my right hand, my right hand--
Ow!
Ooh.
I have an idea of what
your right hand spends
a lot of time
doing, Ronny.
That's really
personal, Gwen.
(Gwen)
Come, Gunther.
I'll take that as
a no for now.
You okay?
Shut your mouth.
Onward.
You shut
your mouth.
Where the fuck
are the keys?
Whoa.
Hey.
Thought you guys only
used foam weapons.
In this world,
young Jonen,
you can only put
your trust in steel.
My elite clientele is willing to
pay a premium for authenticity.
Where the fuck
are the keys?
Come on, Joe.
You played D&D.
Live action role play
is the next level.
D&D was a long time ago.
Yeah.
And you were a legend.
These people here?
They sing songs about the time
that you gave Ronny Kwok's
paladin
demonic syphilis.
Do you remember, remember when
we caught Ronny spanking it to
the succubus picture in
the old monster manual?
Good times, man.
Yeah, and some of us
are still having 'em.
Come on!
Eric's about to level up to
Grand Sorcerer.
I'm packing an
ounce of killer 'shrooms.
And there be monsters in
need of pummelin'!
You have a choice: Join us in
tasting the sweet nectar of
victory or mope around an empty
house all week like a bitch.
You guys do actually
look slightly badass.
It's like
a metal-- cover.
Without the muscles.
All right.
I'm in.
Huzzah!
Please.
Don't make me
rethink this.
Nah.
Welcome to the fields
of Evermore!
Um, Ronny?
Yes,
Travis.
Where are our costumes?
There is no end to
the tricks up my sleeve.
Wardrobe?
(man)
Yes, sir.
Got it.
42 regular.
(Ronny)
42 reg, I think
you'll find it snug.
Great.
(Ronny)
I think you'll find
it freshly laundered.
I'm a trained actor, man.
Not some
fucking stunt monkey.
Weekend improv
workshop, my ass.
Ungrateful.
Ah, greetings,
enchanter.
I have some surprises
in store for you.
Some creatures with a taste
for flesh of the lowest order.
Hmm?
Parasites, charlatans.
War profiteers
of forbidden weapons.
Verily, I say,
let it go, dude.
Well.
Marketplace is a battlefield
and to the victor go the spoils.
Agreed.
I bring news of a legendary
warrior long absent from this
realm who returnth to replace
the estimable Sir Reginald.
The new warrior
is of course welcome.
Wonderful!
Jobreyth of --
shall once more
fight by my side.
Joe Revitt's here?
What the
frack, Eric?
I hate that guy.
Ronald, Ronald,
why be so petty?
I mean, surely, you're not
still sore about
your
syphilitic paladin.
Perhaps, the pages of
your monster manual
remain
stucketh together?
For old time's sake,
he's in.
But... you must accomplish
a level 12 summoning spell
to animate Joe's character
with Reginald's life-force.
Consider it done,
my liege.
Okay, that was
a bit much.
Show-off.
(announcer)
Lo, the adventure
begins!
Please report for
quest assignments.
Step forward when
your group is called.
Freakend Warriors!
The Medieval
Kenevils!
Gnomeland Security.
Fair-Leather Friends.
The Norse
Whisperers.
Heed this reminder.
All guilds must complete their
quests prior to tomorrow's
battle at Evermore.
Also, Ryan the Necromancer
beseeches thy help in finding
his inhaler.
What?
Oh.
His inhaler of doom!
And to the owner of the
sperm-white Toyota Tercel,
thy chariot is blocking
the witches' coven.
Move it or you'll be faced
with a hex of great dark magic.
And you'll be towed.
♪♪
It's a lot like you remember it,
except for sitting around
a table, we do
it for real.
For fake.
Fake-real, dude.
Don't fuck
with me.
And this fake-real
involves, uh, yoga?
Laugh now, but a structured
warm-up routine helps prevent
injury later.
All right-- I'll show you.
Come on.
What?
All right.
Arms and legs,
one point.
Torso's two.
Limb takes a hit, it's useless
until healing's been cast.
Parry disarm can be used once
per melee unless you're up
against a two-handed
weapon.
Grab your sword,
I'll demonstrate.
♪♪
Finish him!
Got an idea.
How about I just
forget the count
and start wailing
on people!
Dude! Dude!
It's honor system,
man.
Okay, you're all set
to join the battle.
I just spoke with Ronny.
Oh, except
lose the sword.
Huh?
Yeah, newbs don't
get swords.
Uh.
Wait, I have to earn the
right to carry a foam stick?
'Tis not the size of the young
knave's blade, but the lust in
his thrust by
which legends are made.
(Eric)
Oh!
Jobreyth!
There is one more thing
you're going to need to do.
Verily?
This is retarded.
(man)
Guys, pentagrams?
We don't roll that
way here.
This is the LARP, not the
Wicker Man Wiccan cosplay.
Nay.
'Tis in the
book, dude.
Okay.
(Joe)
Um, Eric.
They be the rest of our
traveling companions.
Stand back and witness the
spectacle of my animation spell.
Ready?
Oh, for God's sake.
(Speaks foreign language)
Ahh!
Beth?
(Speaks foreign language)
How awesome was that!
Arise, Jobreyth.
Breathe fresh the
air once again.
(coughing)
Me thinks you should not
be so much of a pussy.
Don't tell me you've never
played with fireworks before.
Not like that.
What was with the faces,
the smells, everything?
What was that?
I tell you what
I see.
A warrior...
who can't let
go of his past.
What are you doing?
Wow.
What was that?
Ex-girlfriend!
Jobryeth needeth closure!
It's not like that.
'Tis no matter to me,
apprentice.
(Ronny)
What the shit
is going on?
Why is there smoke?
Eric, I said a basic summoning
spell, not one of your
non-regulation
pyrotechnic displays.
This was more befitting
a 27th level sorcerer.
Which you
are not yet.
What's up, Joe?
Needst I remindst
thou the temple
of awaits.
Don't be
a buzzkill, Ronny.
Ah.
Come, Gunther.
(Ronny)
Buzzkill.
(man)
What?
(Ronny)
Buzzkill.
How you doing
there, Captain Trips?
Verily.
There be
a fungus among us.
Is it your fungus
that's fucking with me?
'Cause if you did slip me some
'shrooms, why's it feel like
I got bent over and taken
advantage of back there?
Perhaps thine reach exceeds
thine grasp, --.
So who are our
comrades, Enchanter?
Right.
That be Lando,
the pious.
Watch him in battle.
Complete weasel,
but entertaining.
You'll see.
Sir Gunther,
the mighty.
Head case
with a big stick.
He is unique and crazy.
And Guinevere the fearless,
who's plus-three ass perfection
should keep
the memory of
She Who Shall
Not Be Mentioned at bay.
Plus-three?
Clearly you underestimate
my endowments.
(monkey sounds)
Look, your party
has disturbed a nest!
Demon apes!
What the fuck?
Play on!
One of the beasts deals Sir Hung
the Glutinous a stunning blow!
♪♪
(man)
Haha!
Great way to spend
the weekend.
Sweating my balls off
in a monkey outfit.
I don't know
where the hell I am.
Who's there?
Hello, apelings?
Dude! Joe!
Little help here.
Huh?
Help us kill
some freaking apes!
You here for the LARP?
The live,
the LARP?
Do you maybe have
a map?
Oh, wow.
'Cause I, um...I sort
of lost my way.
Separated
from the group.
Oh... kay.
Jobryeth!
Gonna... kill... your...
monkey... asses!
Jobryeth takes a
lethal strike to the back!
Huh?
Bullshit--
'Tis a lie!
Halt!
Game master saw a palpable hit
and an unconscious man throwing
weaponry, weaponry that is
beyond the expertise of your
lowly character.
I don't understand what you
said, but I'm gonna sit down.
Three, two,
one, play on!
Got separated
from my group.
You too?
Uh, well, maybe then we should
stick together and both look.
Oh.
Oh, wait a minute, wait
a minute, wait a minute.
If this is some
sort of Furry fetish,
then I don't mind at all!
Oh wow!
Oh, okay,
sure.
From the ground,
thy wounds be bound.
Regeneration spell
successful!
Still thy tongue
lest I remove it!
Lightning bolt!
You my bitch--
Ow!
Same side,
same side!
Be gone, demon apes!
Oh shit.
Damn.
Lando has been dealt
a mortal blow.
'Tis a lie.
I had a spell of simian
protection.
Fine, kill the
brown guy first.
The great ape
has been vanquished!
Huzzah!
Yeah.
Now remember, before
convening at the battle,
this party has a quest
to loot the temple of --
which needeth completion, so...
Perhaps the party should split
up for to
cover more ground.
Capital idea, Sir Lando.
Take Sir Hung the capable
and explore yon forest
for the
fabled temple.
Verily-- We shall meet thee at
Evermore if not before.
Godspeed to you and
thy servant.
Servant?
I'm an apprentice.
Fucketh you
very much.
Easy.
I beseech thee to give him wide
berth as he is pained by a riven
heart torn asunder by the
cruelty of an untrue maiden.
Enough with that
shit, please.
Easy, my liege.
I told these guys
that thou were cool.
Ah, at last.
The simpletons and heretics
have left our brotherhood.
However, it occureth to
me that mine apprentice
has forgotten something.
Yeah?
Thou must return to
the kingdom of Eliphaz.
Uh...
Parking lot.
And fetch the amulet of Kokun
from our transport,
for it shall be needed
at the battle of Evermore.
So go to the parking lot
to get something you forgot.
Aye.
I shall join you
on your mission.
The forest is no place for
an unarmed adventurer.
Let's go.
Act-- It's this way.
(Joe)
Yes.
Hey, man.
(announcer)
Attention
all teams.
Upon completion of your quests,
you may head to the battlefield
to prepare your
camp for the night.
But as always, be on guard for
the evil scourge from beyond
our borders.
You know, those redneck
paintball jerks who crashed
our centaur hunt last week.
Prithee, take care.
Is that you, fellow
denizens of Elves' realms?
Speakers of Elvish?
Um, do you have
a map maybe?
Do I know you?
Are you here
for the LARP?
Was it the robes or the
pointy ears that gave it away?
'Cause I sort of lost my way and
got separated from the group.
Oh, no.
You're one of those freaky
vampire LARPers, right?
Wrong weekend, honey.
I don't mind
at all.
I think thou art marching down
the wrong battlefield, sweetie.
Now if you'll
excuse me.
♪♪
If I didn't know better,
Jobryeth, I'd say you were
having fun back there.
Ooh, no I wasn't.
Okay,
a little.
But you
can't tell anyone.
I wouldn't even know what LARP
was if it wasn't for Gunther.
He's a little
hardcore with this.
Well, at least you're supporting
your boyfriend's interests.
A lot of girls--
Boyfriend?
God, no.
Gunther's my
cousin.
He's a good kid, but
he never breaks character.
Whoa, whoa, wait.
He never breaks
character?
He truly believes he's
in another time and place.
But his folks don't let him
come to these things alone.
So you're
warrior-sitting then?
Well, after the
Medieval Times incident,
I seem to be the
only one he listens to.
The Medieval Times
incident?
Mom thought it would be
cute to take him there.
He jumped the wall and sent the
Red Knight to the hospital.
(laughing)
Sorry.
Not funny.
♪♪
I've got this.
Ooh!
Um, miss.
The fuck?
Spell of protection.
It's too late.
Drop.
To the nether
realms.
My lady?
All I'm saying is we'll be taken
more seriously if we refer to
ourselves as sprites.
Can we please stay
in character?
You guys sound like
a bunch of little girls.
If anyone would know
about little girls...
Okay.
I tried to handle this in
private, but if you wanna
do this here now, standing in
the woods, dressed like fucking
fairies, so be it.
Lo, perhaps thou art
having thine monthlies.
Out of game.
Out of game?
Okay.
Fine-- What the hell's your
problem?
You're the one who
wanted to experiment.
Don't blame me if you can't
handle the consequences.
It was fine as long as it
was all about you,
but heaven
forbid I enjoy it.
You saw her without me.
That wasn't part
of the deal.
I'm heading
back to camp.
Go.
Someday someone's gonna tear
your heart out and you'll
know exactly how I feel.
Sprites!
Let's fly.
You look like one of those...
freaky vampire LARPers.
Maybe we should
stick together.
Maybe.
(moaning)
(screaming)
As you approach the Exalted
Township of Valinore, you notice
that your own path intersects
with another.
Sir Hung, he is
rustling just across the way.
I can hear the breeze
on my skin.
'Tis burnt orange.
-- English.
The fuck's
he saying?
I don't know.
There is electricity
in the air.
Okay, Ronny, so if he goes
insane, can I inherit his
experience points?
You're obsessed
with experience points.
No, let's not talk
about that now.
I'm just saying,
that's a waste of experience.
I can use it.
Kill thy cowardly
tongue.
Oh, holy shit.
(Hung)
Prepare thineself
for battle, wench.
Do I know you?
All right, Hung, I don't know
what you're on, but I think
it's clouding your judgment.
She looks--
Nay, game master.
The scales have finally
fallen from mine eyes.
Miss, are you okay?
Have you been
in an accident?
'Tis no accident!
Go no closer!
Although I have gazed upon thy
visage before, 'tis only by the
light of yon moon has thou true
nature revealed itself!
Okay, Hung, ease up
there, buddy.
I think she
really needs some help.
Excuse me, my lady, do you
really need some help?
Fuck you and the moustache you
rode in on!
(Ronny)
Oh, fuck!
I'm... outta here.
'Tis a cruel act of the gods to
waste such a sweet backside...
on such a filthy beast.
(screaming)
It gets me
every time.
The noise came from
around here somewhere.
Just keep
your wits.
Oh God.
Oh lord, he's dead.
Oh shit.
What the
hell?
I don't understand.
All right, we
gotta keep going.
We gotta get Eric, your crazy
cousin and call the cops.
What was that?
Shit.
Joe, what are
you doing?
There's someone
in there.
I know, that's what
I'm worried about.
You're not sing,
Joe, are you?
What?
Tell me you're
not gonna sing.
Not right now, baby.
No, no, no.
No, no,
no, no!
(Gwen)
Gunther!
Ease up!
Stay your hand,
mighty warlord.
Evil has
befallen him.
His handiwork is
all around us.
We heard you and we thought it
might be whoever... did this.
Where's Ronny?
Lando?
Do not enter.
One cannot
cheat death forever.
This is
not good.
Joe, what the fuck
is going on here?
I don't know
what's going on.
But I want to
talk to Ronny.
Ronny?
You think Ronny is
responsible for this?
What am I supposed
to think?
You guys and your
quest for authenticity.
Oh, come--
Real weapons.
In-game bullshit.
Archaic
books.
Ugh, the evil
book again, huh?
It would surprise me not,
wizard, if thou has not brought
forth something vile and unholy,
a pox upon mankind.
Gunther!
We're out of
game here, man.
Somebody tell me what
the hell's going on here.
Hell, indeed,
is going on.
The wizard
has summoned evil.
And most likely while they
apprentice was in the circle,
he has been made unholy.
Gunther.
I cannot tell you
whether 'twas man or beast,
but I can tell you surely
it was not Jobryeth.
We need to get
out of here.
What we need to do is avenge the
poor souls taken here this eve.
With what?
Foam sticks?
Jobryeth
is right.
We need weapons from my
private reserve of steel.
Thou speakests
sense.
Let us return
to camp.
And arm
ourselves.
While they call for
help...reinforcements.
Very well.
I am
watching you.
We all feel safer
for that.
(Ronny)
Oh fuckity fuck.
Get a hold
of yourself, man.
Get a hold of
yourself, man!
What the fuck
was that, man?
Oh my God,
she was not normal!
She was like some kind
of she-beast from the--
Oh, my sweet shit.
Oh my sweet,
sweet shit.
Eric, you fucking asshole.
I have to
warn him.
Where the fuck am I?
They suck
at making maps!
Where the hell am I!
Why is there
no one here?
Shouldn't
someone be here?
Come on, the best way for us
to help is to drive somewhere
and get some.
That's not what
was agreed upon.
We were to seek vengeance.
Where are
the weapons?
Weapons are
in here, okay?
Now come on,
let's go.
Where the fuck
is my phone?
Anyone?
Sweet Jesus,
man.
Sorry, dude.
There's some weird shit
going on out there, man.
Oh... kay.
We gotta
call 9-1-1.
Do you have
a cell phone?
9-1-1 is just gonna
route a cell call.
What you ought to do is call
the Sky Valley Sheriff directly.
I can get the number.
Call Sky
Valley Sheriff.
(dialing)
(phone ringing)
(man)
Sky Valley Sheriff.
(Gwen)
There's been an accident at
the state park campgrounds.
You gotta get here
as soon as you can.
(man)
Hold up now--
What kind of accident?
Well, there's this
LARP event going on--
Wait a minute, LARP like,
like dressed up like wizards
and shit?
Yeah, like that.
But this
is serious.
It wasn't just one of those
paintballer pranks,
people are in danger.
You stay put.
We'll be
right there.
Oh, thank god.
Tommy!
Tommy, get your
ass up.
We gotta get going.
Hey, Randy.
Rise and shine,
buddy.
We got a cold dish of
get back that needs serving.
Get your cousin and
get your gear.
Imma pick
you up in 10.
(man)
Whoa, this does not look
like regulation game play.
Are you guys out
of game or not?
We're so far outta
game, we're somehow back in it.
I thought you said
there were bodies.
What are you guys up to?
Where be the
game master?
Where be our hordes
for glorious combat?
Everyone else completed their
mission and camped out
on the battlefield.
Are you guys gonna camp
or just stay up all night?
I must fight the evil
at its source!
No!
Gunther!
(yelling)
You guys are
on another planet.
You know drugs are
off-limit out here.
How far's the
battlefield?
Ronny Kwok's gonna
hear about this.
How far!
Take it easy.
Halfway
through the forest.
I'm out.
Great.
Now can we get
the hell out of here?
You kidding?
We can't leave
Gunther.
No.
Joe.
Goddamn it, Joe!
Hey, what
is that?
Are they... I think
they're...
...is that Eddie?
Beth?
Beth!
Holy shit, that's
your psychotic girlfriend?
Ex-girlfriend.
This is so
fucked up.
Guys.
Dude, what...
Hey.
I'll tell you what I see.
Tell you what
I see.
A warrior.
Warrior.
Who can't let go
of his past.
Oh shit.
This has something to do with
the photo of me and Beth
at Prom.
(Eric)
What?
In the book,
the fucking eBay book, man.
What?
Get the fuck out, man.
No, I had the photo with me
when you summoned this...
whatever this
is with the book.
Eric, use the book to
send that bitch back wherever
she came from!
I don't know how?
I just picked a page
at random earlier.
Well then,
just pick another...
pick another page
and hurry the fuck up.
(Speaks foreign language)
Sing it.
Sing it, wizard.
(Sings in foreign language)
(Eric)
That was for Hung!
Take that, bitch!
That was--
served by Eric
the Enchanter.
What?
You just let
her get away.
Excuse me?
She just went off into the woods
to die like a wounded animal.
(Ronny)
Gimme the book.
Fuck!
God.
This is the "Sigillum Aemeth."
Where did you get this book?
Uh, why?
Shut up,
never mind.
Did you read
this page?
Um.
Why?
Did you read it?
Yes, yes!
Holy fuck, yes.
We read it and it scared that
crazy chick back to hell
or wherever the
fuck she came from.
If that doesn't get me to level
27, I don't know what will,
Kwok, so why
don't you pony up.
No, no,
no, no, no, okay.
That all makes sense.
(Joe)
It makes no sense.
It's gibberish--
It makes sense!
It makes sense that
you speak Enochian.
Enochian, what?
You made
that up.
This is the "Sigillum Aemeth."
It is the only one of its kind.
It was handwritten in the 16th
Century by the mystic John Dee
and it has been
lost for generations.
Uh, bullshit.
It came from the internets,
not the 16th Century.
If you're trying to get out
of admitting how awesome I am--
John Dee was trying to summon
angels, but evil travels under
its own power and he actually
summoned demons
and the demons
forged this book.
What are you
saying, Kwok?
Dee tried to destroy,
but he couldn't.
So he sealed it and he hid it
deep underneath his manor estate
and it has been lost
for generations.
But here it is in your
incapable hands and you summoned
a succubus from hell!
(gasping)
And then this lat passage
that you read,
the herald of Abominog.
And in the language lay the name
of the hell lord Abominog and
I hath spoken the name
and hell has raineth down.
(growling)
You didn't injure it,
you ignorant fuck!
You transformed it!
Sorry.
Transformed into
what exactly?
What?
What the fuck
was that?
I don't know.
Ronny Kwok's dragon!
Shit, shit!
Oh my God,
we overslept again.
It's time for Evermore.
Come on.
Grab the fucking horn.
The thing eats
souls, you guys.
We are gonna die.
(horn blowing)
Shit!
Shit.
(Joe)
What?
It's the horn
of war.
It means that the battle of
Evermore is going to start
in 10 minutes.
Why now-- It's like three in the
fucking morning.
It's not supposed to happen
for another few hours,
but Ira is a dick
and did it early.
There's a LARPer buffet on
that field and all those poor
bastards have is
foam sticks.
We have to save them.
Are you fucking
nuts?
No.
I think I've done
enough damage already.
You-- that thing--
that's real!
That thing slaughtered
our best friend.
You gonna
let that stand?
You been out here practicing
this shit every weekend
for years.
Face it,
man.
You've got everything
but you earned nothing.
Are you gonna hide from that
thing the way you hide
from real life?
Or are you gonna man up and
avenge the death of our friend?
The time has come to earn
our valor, people.
♪♪
For Hung.
(announcer)
Steel thyselves,
adventurers.
The time for
battle is nigh.
The fate of the glorious kingdom
of Evermore rests
in the balance.
Two armies fighting for
one prize-- bragging rights on
the Evermore LARP Alliance
message board.
Diamond starts speech.
He rouseth
the troops.
I am well aware that words
cannot inspire courage,
render a timid army valiant and
perhaps words are unnecessary
for you, my brave lot, for
there is no timidity within you.
Oh, wow.
You know, I worked
with him last year.
He's got such a gift
for the theatrics.
Yes, he loves it.
Oh, here
goes Cary.
Here goes.
Some of you are gentle souls in
peace, but when that horn of
battle blows, we must
disguise our fair nature,
summon up our blood!
Draw up our most
terrible aspect!
Unleash our rage!
Fortune is on our side, but if
that fickle bitch should prove
unjust, then go down fighting
like gods and leave your enemies
a bloody and mournful
victory that tastes
like ashes
in their mouths.
I covet only one thing.
Honor
and victory!
(cheering)
Wait.
Verily, that
is two things.
Join me in coveting those same
glories for if it be a sin,
let us be the monks of --!
(cheering)
They shall curse themselves for
not being here, for not being
able to say they fought with
us upon the field of Evermore!
♪♪
(announcer)
Warriors are reminded to remain
honorable in their combat.
No strikes to
the codpiece.
Kwok's gonna be so
pissed he missed this.
No shit.
The horn bloweth.
The battle of
Evermore has begun!
What the hell is that?
I kind-- I lost the
official horn of battle.
This is the shofar from
my temple, so...
(horn blowing)
Evermore.
(cheering)
(announcer)
The battle
is upon us.
Which army shall reap
the spoils of the conquest?
King Diamond's army doth fight
with power and opening a can
of yon whoop-ass
upon their foes.
♪♪
The king's army is holding their
ground, matching them hit point
for hit point.
Calling Ronny's dragon.
Get the hell
out here already.
(announcer)
A dragon hath appeared.
A bounty of experience points
await the brave souls who dare
take on this
ferocious beast.
And please, don't be
douchelords with the wings.
The papier mache
is still drying.
(laughing)
This is the best!
What was that?
Those fuckers
didn't wait for me!
It took us two weeks to
build that thing.
(growling)
What was that?
Get points,
you get points.
Run, puny
humans!
That's perfect,
that's perfect.
Oh, it's getting down.
Hit this one.
Yeah.
(laughing)
Motherfuckers.
Oh yeah.
I got the crip.
We're back,
bitches!
(announcer)
These people are
not part of the game.
Repeat, not part
of the game!
I'm so outta here.
Guild-- Stand and fight
those red of neck!
Together, attack!
Triangulate!
♪♪
Not so fast,
Meals on Wheels.
Ahh!
(screaming)
♪♪
Oh God!
Did it see us?
I don't know.
Ahh!
What was that?
I don't know.
What's going on?
Holy shit,
what is that?
Fuck, fuck!
Holy shit!
What
the fuck!
Shit!
Oh shit!
(screaming)
It's some sort
of giant monster.
Looks maybe
like a --
I don't know.
Maybe an --
Or a -- it could
be a rage Gollum.
Look, it's got the deadly
tentacles, just like
the monster manual--
Shit, how is
this even possible?
I don't know.
Ahh!
Fuck this.
(screaming)
(man)
Fuck!
Okay.
Hold on.
All right, I got a plan.
On the count of three, we're
gonna make a break for the path,
all right?
One--
hey, focus!
Two.
No, fuck
this shit!
I am not moving another
step until somebody tells
me what the hell--
There's something really
terrible coming, you guys,
and we're here
to save-- Oh shit.
Oh.
(car stalling)
Gwen, if the world isn't
swallowed up into hell,
you wanna go see
a show sometime?
Nice timing,
warrior.
Sure.
(Eric)
Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
A show would
be good.
No, demon!
You shall not harm
this quivering boy!
(whistling)
Hey!
Thank you,
mighty warrior!
Can thoust
be Enochian?
(car stalling)
Give us a smile,
sweet cheeks.
Oh yes!
Yes!
Fuck.
God, what
is that?
What is that sound?
She's laughing
at us.
Enough, you bitch!
Fuck.
Find it,
fuck.
Ronny, what are
you doing?
I drive a hybrid,
Eric.
There's no on
button in this thing.
You can speak Enochian
but can't drive a truck?
It's not my fault.
Ronny, I can't find
the spell, where is it?
It's in the back
of the book!
I marked it clearly!
It is in the
back!
Find it, find
it, fuck.
Oh, hey, I got
this going, guys.
♪♪
This shall not hold
the beast for long!
I got it, I got it,
I got it!
(Sings in foreign language)
The gem!
♪♪
Choke on it.
No, watch out!
No!
I'm on
fire!
I'm on fire!
Gwen,
I need you!
You okay?
Why the fuck would
you do that?
I'm gonna stop saving your
lives if you don't show me
some fucking gratitude!
Okay, okay, focus!
Where is the book that
you were just reading from?
We need the book?
No, shit!
No, that's
okay.
This is good.
This is the gem.
When he read the "Sigillum",
the gem glowed,
so that is the
source of the power.
So the book is like an
instruction manual?
Yes!
But it's more like
a recipe booklet.
What does thou need?
I need a banishment spell
but the book is ruined,
so we don't have one!
I'll get your book.
Guys, whatever you're
doing, do it faster!
I don't know,
I can't remember!
There was a --.
There was like a --.
Game master!
Here be
your spell!
Oh my God,
fucking gambit!
It's
a dead head!
What does it say?
It's hot and
it's awful.
I can't...
Calm down now.
Calm down!
(Singing in foreign language)
Oh, no, no,
no, no, no.
Crap!
Ronny!
It's up to you,
Jobryeth.
Eric, the gem combined with
signing, that's what makes
the magic work, right?
Fuck if I know, man.
Are you a wizard
or not?
Yes, yes, yes.
It's definitely
the catalyst.
I think this
song will work-- Fire it up.
Track
two.
Go.
♪♪
♪ Cast down into
thine dark crypt ♪
♪ Shadows of our dead
minions drag ♪
♪ Thee into the abyss ♪
What's he singing?
Sabbath?
Is it
Motorhead?
No, that's a --
Stalker original, son.
♪ Rises bringing
his deadliest gifts ♪
♪ His soul is devoured
in wrath ♪
♪ His dreams are
and yet twisted ♪
♪ In blood red eclipse ♪
♪ He is reborn in
the dark light ♪
It's working!
It's
working!
♪ He instigates thy doom -- ♪
♪ His wings turn the
sky to black ♪
♪ As he makes
this world thy tomb ♪
♪ Lifeless husk -- ♪
♪ From you raise your
blade defeat ♪
♪ The vile
snake your heart-- ♪
♪♪
♪ His wings turn
the sky ♪
Finish it!
♪ To black as he makes
this world thy tomb ♪
♪ Made a sacrifice
of my soul ♪
♪ Before a blazing
funeral pyre for you ♪♪
Drop to the nether
realms, bitch.
You have questionable
taste in women, my friend.
Apparently.
But I have excellent
taste when it comes to music.
Apparently.
♪♪
You're a terrible
bass player!
I know, isn't it awesome?
♪♪
♪ Yeah yeah yeah ♪
♪ At the gates ♪
♪ Yes it's now
or never ♪
♪ A twist of fate
I've seen the bad get badder ♪
♪ Sleepless nights oh ♪
♪ I see nightmare
creatures ♪
♪ Don't turn away
this is your adventure ♪
♪ Silent hero
waiting at the gates ♪
♪ Alone ♪
♪ At the gates alone ♪
♪ I come alive ♪
♪ In the heat
of battle ♪
♪ I do or die ♪
♪ Spill the blood of
your enemies ♪
♪ Sleepless nights oh
I see ghosts and demons ♪
♪ This is your adventure ♪
♪ Saints and sinners waiting
at the gates alone ♪
♪ At the gates
alone ♪
♪ At the gates ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ At the
gates ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ At the gates alone ♪
♪♪
♪ At the gates ♪
♪ Don't look no further ♪
♪ I feel
the rage ♪
♪ And the voices burning
in your soul yeah ♪
♪ You're a nightmare creature
and feel the pain ♪
♪ As it turns to pleasure ♪
♪ Death and glory waiting
at the gates alone ♪
♪ At the gates
alone ♪
♪ At the gates ♪
♪ Yeah
gates ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ At the gates alone ♪
♪ At the
gates ♪
♪ At the gates
alone ♪
♪ At the gates ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Gates ♪
♪ At the gates ♪
♪ Yeah
gates ♪
at the gates ♪♪