Are you sure this is all right,
Mr. Fujiwara?
The boss said so, didn't he?
He doesn't need a bodyguard
in this apartment anyway.
But couldn't we at least stand in
the hall and guard the boss?
Guard the boss when he's fucking a girl?
I didn't mean that.
You're a hitman.
Why don't you shut the fuck up
till you're needed?
Hello.
Is that you, Takeshi?
You are coming home, aren't you?
You won't go away, will you?
I won't go away, Takeshi.
I'm working now.
I'll call you back soon.
Dad. Dad...
Tadanobu Asano
Hideo Yamamoto
Takashi Miike
No!
No...No!
No! Stop..!
How does that feel?
Who?
Who is it?
Ichi the Killer
Hi, Miyu Miyu? It's me, Long.
Inoue, stop it.
I just thought if anything happened
I could blow some fucker away.
Ichi's taking care of everything tonight.
All we do lately is go in
after everything's finished and mop up.
I got it!
I told you to stop!
What are you doing?
If I can't shoot up,
you can't talk on the damn phone.
They're not the same thing.
Give it back!
Let's go.
Let's get started.
What the hell's going on here?
You were the boss' bodyguard last night!
Kaneko was, too.
Don't put the blame on others!
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Do you have any idea?
Don't you have a girlfriend?
No, I don't. It gets lonely, you know.
Why don't you get a pet?
I used to have one. An alligator.
But they're hard to take care of
once they get big.
I flushed him down the toilet
before that happened.
I remember I had a dog once
in elementary school.
What kind?
A mongrel. He was so cute!
But that old guy next door,
he had a German shepherd.
He was always making fun of my dog.
Damn it
So I started praying that something
awful would happen to him.
Welcome.
Is Karen here?
She's over there, please follow me.
And something did.
What?
His dog died.
Oh my God! Really?
Well, I killed his dog.
I strangled it with a skipping rope.
Here, have another.
Kakihara
Did you hear?
The boss disappeared.
Oh yes, I've heard, he took the money
and went off with some fucking
17 year old girl.
If he was going to run off with anyone,
it would've been you.
One of the other gangs took him.
The money, too.
You mean he's killed already...
What are you going to do then?
You've given your whole life to him.
He's not dead. I'm going to find him.
Yes, Yes, you'll find him.
But I think he's already
six feet under by now.
Don't make me mad, Karen.
He's alive.
He's alive. I'm 120%%% sure of that.
He's waiting for me to come and find him.
Yeah, but...
You are the boss's woman.
What the hell are you talking about?
I'm sorry.
Today's my birthday.
Birthday? Is it your birthday?
OK. I'll give you this.
I told you to stop it!
Stop it, idiot.
They were kicked out from the syndicate
Where else can they make
a living but in Shinjuku?
They do all the dirtiest,
murder, arson, smuggling & rape.
everything.
Mr. Kakihara, of the Anjo gang.
How have you been?
So you're back in Shinjuku, huh?
There's nowhere else
we can make a living.
Did you hear what happened
over at your place?
A little bit.
If you hear anything, let me know.
I'll pay well for it.
All right.
Do it quick. Die.
I'm sorry.
I can't hear you!
Hurry up and die.
I'm sorry.
No use apologising.
Stop crying!
You can apologize all you want.
It's not going to cut any ice with me.
You stupid son of a bitch!
I don't want to hear that
you haven't found him yet.
Give it to me.
I want you to turn Shinjuku upside-down
and inside-out until you find the boss!
Don't come back here till you do!
It doesn't look too good, does it?
That doesn't mean I don't think
there's no hope of course...
I'll find him! Please leave it to me!
I'll take it.
It's nothing more than hearsay.
I don't know how true it is.
The Funakis are Sanko Syndicate
members, just like us.
And they've got their office
right here in this building.
All the better to watch
what you're doing,
to see where the boss is going.
Why would they do it?
Well, Mr. Kakihara, three years ago
you cut Mr. Suzuki of
the Funaki Family out of
a porno video sales racket.
Rumour has it that
he hasn't forgotten that.
So Suzuki's behind all this?
It's just rumour.
But I am sure that Suzuki makes
no secret of the fact
that he doesn't think much of you.
He's spread some pretty ridiculous
stories...even that you
and Mr. Anjo were more than
just a gang boss and his capo.
What the hell are you talking about?
Takayama, bring him here.
Bring who here?
Suzuki.
But...
Are you afraid of him?
That's not the problem.
We don't have any proof.
Proof? When did you start
worrying about proof?
I can't believe I'm hearing this
from Takayama.
If we're wrong we'll give the Funakis
the old guy's dead body.
Get going, Takayama!
I got it.
Jijii, just go and buy some shrimps.
Shrimps?
Ouch!
Kakihara? Tempura?
What the hell?
Kakihara! What the fuck is this?
You look great, Mr. Suzuki!
Where's the boss?
The boss? You mean Anjo?
He and that girl took off with
your money, didn't he?
What did you say?
Wait! Stop, damn it! You're doing this
because you think I took Boss Anjo?
I know that you're pissed off
because I cut you out of that video deal.
And that you've been going around
bad-mouthing me.
No, I haven't!
Yes, you have...hasn't he, old man?
Who the fuck are you?
So, Mr. Suzuki, then you aren't
dubbing videos behind his back?
So you are doing stuff behind my back...
OK, it's true about the videos,
I'll admit that.
But I don't know anything
about your boss.
You've got to believe me!
Please! Believe me.
I'll ask you again. Where's the boss?
I don't know! I haven't got any idea!
Boss, that's too...
I wonder how the old man ever managed
to get a camera and a mike in there.
I put it there.
You did?
Jijii asked me to before
I was kicked out of Anjo Group.
You knew Kakihara then?
He wouldn't recognize me.
I got my face changed after
they kicked me out.
Plastic surgery?
Why did you change it to this?
Shut up!
Well, I have to make a call.
Give me a break, damn it!
What the hell?
Is it ...Suzuki?
Kakihara! What the fuck
do you think you're doing?
This? Just a little torture.
What did Suzuki do?
Stop it!
Take that off, Mr. Kaneko.
Who the hell are you?
Perhaps I might first ask what you're
doing here, Mr. Funaki.
We got a phone call saying that Suzuki
was in big trouble with the Anjo gang.
He thinks I took Boss Anjo.
Suzuki wouldn't do anything that stupid!
Let him go.
You wouldn't happen to be mixed up
in this, would you?
What?
Someone told us that Suzuki has
taken the boss.
Who?
This old man here.
Who came to you with the information?
The old man here...
So who?
You! Go and find him!
Welcome.
So you came back...
You're the only one who's happy
to see a girl all marked up like this.
How...
How what?
How did he beat you up yesterday?
What?
Did it hurt?
I thought I was going to die!
The bastard...l wish he'd die!
"Die"...
Yeah! I wish he'd die!
Shall I do that for you?
Huh?
Ten million yen?
No, you dumb ass! A hundred million yen!
That's appropriate.
We don't have that kind of
money at the moment.
OK, then give me the video business
and we'll call it quits.
All of our money disappeared
with the boss.
If you take the videos,
we're out of business.
So you expect to pull a damn fool stunt
like that and get off not paying a thing?
Kick this asshole out of the
syndicate, please.
It's much easier.
You may be right.
I'll make a sincere apology.
It's not the matter of one or
two of your fingers.
I have a taste for sweet things.
So what?
In apology, I'll cut out the part of me
that tastes those things.
What do you mean?
Ka-en?...OK...I'm on my way.
I'm going to look for the boss.
Boss.
Why so late?
I had to stop at the hospital.
The hospital?
Disgusting
Look, it's amazing.
What do you mean?
It's alright. The human body
regenerates itself.
I'm OK now. See?
OK, anyway listen,
remember when you met jijii
and his gang at the club? OK.
And one of this guy was popping veins,
got one of the girls to check it out
and she said it's heroin.
and here, I found this
really fancy place
for heroin. come up, come up.
Who is it?
I'm Karen from "Hirando"
Good morning!
Have you heard from him?
What do I owe you that I'd tell you
something like that?
If you're not here to score,
then fuck off.
When you ask something,
you should be more polite.
What kind of person are you?
This guy is Kakihara, the pierced guy,
of Anjo Group.
I'm coming in.
Hey, who said you can come in?
I don't know about that, but I don't
associate with these bad-mannered guys.
The boss is going to die.
Huh? What's this guy talking about?
If I don't hurry, the boss dies!
I told you, if you're not here to score,
you're in the way,
so get the hell out of here. Scram!
What happens if he dies?!
Jijii! Come back quickly
and give me a hit!
He was already in there when we got here.
I tied him up just in case
he tried to escape.
Where's the old man?
What's this?
That's our office!
I found this.
Boss Anjo...
So it was you who did it!
Where's the boss?
I'll tell you...just get me a hit first.
Where's the boss?! Where is he?
Anjo...has gone underground.
If you aren't going to give me a hit,
then hurry up and kill me,
"Older Brother"!
Who are you?
I know how you work.
If you're going to kill me anyway,
at least do it quick, "Older Brother".
Kano?
That's me.
Kano? You're Kano?!
But your face is different!
So you did this?
It was Ichi who did it.
Who's this "Ichi"?
All I did was go in and clean up
when he'd finished.
But Ichi's next target is you,
"Older Brother".
You were in love with Anjo, weren't you!
But it wasn't because you were queer
or you admired him or anything.
It was because you loved the pain you
felt when he beat you up!
That's why you're looking for
him so hard, isn't it!
So he can hurt you again!
I'm not going to forget
what you did to me!
Kakihara, I'll never forgive you!
I'm going to blow that fucker away!
What did you do with the girl?
He asked where girl with Anjo is.
Girl?
Man want us find girl you take with Anjo.
You give back now.
Wait a minute!
You guys are making a mistake!
We'll kill you!
You no say, we kill whole family.
Will you listen to me, damn it!
It wasn't me!
I didn't have anything to do with it!
Believe me, please!
Ask somebody else, please.
We're running out of time.
Time's up.
What do you mean "Time's up"?
We cut you here. It won't hurt much.
No! Please! Help!
Someone says he saw a man with a torn-up
mouth attack Anjo's office?
That's Kakihara! I knew it!
I can't breathe with this mask.
...Should have made it nicer.
It gets fogged and I can't see
anything when I breathe.
Hi, Miyu Miyu, how are you?
Telling me you've worked all day
and only made 30,000 Yen?!
Stop it! Don't hit me anymore!
Hey, tell me.
You can suck dick and you've got a cunt
and you're telling me
this is all you got?!
No one wants to look at me
because you keep beating me up!
Don't you talk back to me, bitch!
How do you feel, huh?
Oh ! Willy is erect
Who the fuck are you?
Come in here!
What are you doing?
Goddamn peeping tom.
What the fuck is this costume?
What are you doing?
Can't you talk, asshole?
I'm sorry.
What's this "I'm sorry" bullshit?
What's the matter with you?
Why are you crying?
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are!
I'm not.
You're fucking crying!
You ARE crying!
No, I'm not!
What are you doing?
I killed him for you.
I promised I'd kill him for you.
...but don't worry...
I'll hit you instead.
You'll do it for me?
Thank you!
Kakihara, you are expelled
from the Syndicate.
The Syndicate has come to this decision
based on the arrogance of
the actions of you and your men
in the way you have
chosen to search for Anjo,
in your lynching of Suzuki,
and in your refusing Funaki's offer.
Have you anything to say?
Hey, are you listening?
Kakihara!
Is that all you wanted to see me about?
That's all.
Well, thanks for everything.
I guess he's gone.
Hey, Suzuki...you're sure this is
right thing to do?
I don't like how easily he accepted it
and then just walked away.
You don't think he's planning to
take some kind of revenge, do you?
I forgot one thing.
What's that?
I'm taking over the Anjo Group.
Ouch... !
So we've been expelled?
That's right.
So every Yakuza in Shinjuku is
now our enemy.
Anyone who wants out better say so now.
I'm sorry.
I'd like to give back the sake cup
I used to pledge allegiance.
Oh, you do?
They've expelled Kakihara.
Where's the money?
I've put half into the account
you told me to.
Half? You broke your promise.
I'll put the rest in once you succeed.
300 million yen is a lot of money.
What if you blow it?
Next three, four days, you get everyone
out of the Yakuza mansion.
They get in the way. You can do that?
Right. I'll get started on it right away.
You be sure you squash them good.
Where are you going?
What am I supposed to do?
Just wait here. Don't move.
Ichi...
Ichi!
I had a dream... about Miss Tachibana.
The girl who tried to help you when
you were being bullied,
the girl who ended up getting raped?
When they were raping her
she asked me to help.
But my legs were shaking so bad
I couldn't move.
I still have dreams about
her calling to me for help.
You wanted to save her so much?
I wanted to rape her.
You wanted to save her, didn't you?
She wanted it to be me, that did it.
Ichi! Open your eyes, damn it!
You have been expelled from
the Syndicate, haven't you?
If you come, it'll cause trouble...
Who do you think you're talking to?
It hurts.
Mr. Kakihara, stop it, please.
It'll be torn off!
Karen, Karen!
Karen, do something, will you?
Can I do it, too?
Take your shoes off.
Hurry up!
Go and get it.
Come on, hurry!
Hey, give it back to me.
What?
Asshole.
Your dad had to quit the police
because he lost his pistol.
What an idiot!
They're both idiots, him and his dad!
They use tax money to make those guns,
don't they?
Yeah! Give us our money back, asshole!
Come on, hurry and fetch it.
Hey! Hurry up!
Can't you hear what I'm saying?
Hey!
Quit staring! Fuck off, you jerk!
More?
You're my woman now, aren't you?
Do it like you did before, then.
Does it hurt?
Keep going.
Listen, when you're giving
pain to someone,
don't think about the pain that
person is feeling.
Do it like you want to kill me.
The boss was much better than you.
That's enough,
You're not the one.
Hey, come back!
Turn on the TV, Ichi.
The ones you kill are those guys.
Get in fast and finish them off.
I can't
Sure you can!
They're bullies, all of them. They work
for the man you killed before.
They won't be any problem for you.
Just go in there and go crazy.
No way. There's too many of them.
Come on! You want revenge, don't you?
Weren't you going to
kill all the bullies?
Those men extort money from poor people.
They beat up the weak
and strut around like
they're something special.
You've got to take revenge!
See that guy with the shaved head?
Doesn't he look like Imamura
who bullied you in middle school?
And isn't the guy beside him
a dead ringer for Tokito,
the boy who scribbled all over
your textbooks?
Well, Ichi?
He does look like him.
Did you take revenge?
Killing's not nice.
I told you not to worry about that.
They're all just a bunch of bullies.
The people I just killed...
they weren't the ones who bullied me.
They're bad people.
Of course they should die.
How did it feel today?
I don't want to kill any more.
Don't be stupid!
If you don't kill the bad guys,
who will?
I don't want to kill.
You're going to keep on killing them,
aren't you?
I don't want to.
Kill the bad guys.
Kill.
Thank you for saving me.
What's wrong with you?
Are you all right?
What's your name?
Ichi.
We're friends, aren't we?
Fuck!
What is this mess?
Boss... What's this?
So he came after all...
Isn't this something?
I'm scared!
Hey, all of you! Don't run away!
Everything's bursting out...
Aren't you going to run?
I'm sorry, boss. They are all gone.
Don't bother.
Takayama, call the
East Shinjuku Police Station.
Will you report this to the police?
No. I'm going to get them
to give us a hand.
Some kids were bullying me and
this really strong guy came along
and kicked their asses!
You can do karate and all that stuff,
can't you?
Teach me how.