KWAIDAN
A Ninjin CIub Production
Produced by Shigeru Wakatsuki
OriginaI Story by Yakumo Koizumi
ScreenpIay by Yoko Mizuki
Director of Photography:
Yoshio Miyajima
Sound effects by Toru Takemitsu
THE BLACK HAIR
Michiyo Aratama-Misako Watanabe
Rentaro Mikuni
THE WOMAN OF THE SNOW
Tatsuya Nakadai
Keiko Kishi
HOICHI, THE EARLESS
Katsuo Nakamura
Tetsuro Tanba
IN A CUP OF TEA
Kanemon Nakamura
Osamu Takizawa-Haruko Sugimura
Directed by Masaki Kobayashi
THE BLACK HAIR
In old Kyoto there was
a young samurai
who had been reduced to poverty
by the ruin of his lord.
He decided to leave his home
and take service with the
governor of a distant province.
Goodbye.
Stay weII. I can't Iive here
with you. I have a future.
For men, advancement is the
most important.
I can't give it up
just because of you.
I can't bury my future here.
Must you Ieave Kyoto?
I'II work harder than before.
I'II weave day and night.
I'II sIave for a better Iiving.
If I Iose this chance,
I'II be finished.
Don't try to stop me. The new
post wiII bring me fortune.
If you can remarry a man
of some distinction,
you'II have fortune too.
There's nothing more to say.
I've had enough of poverty!
You're going to Ieave
earIy in the morning.
So you better go to bed now.
Take her to the bridaI chamber.
My daughter is finaIIy married.
I feeI reIieved now.
I'm gIad to have you
in my famiIy.
Thank you.
He knows his obIigation.
He'II serve her weII.
PIease, take care of my daughter.
Yes.
The samurai could not understand
the value of love.
He divorced his good wife
and married the daughter of
a noted family to gain position .
And he took her
to his new post.
It was the thoughtlessness
of youth
and the experience of desire.
His second marriage did not
prove a happy one.
His new wife was selfish
and callous.
He soon found every cause to
recall with regret his Kyoto days.
Then he discovered he still loved
his first wife -
loved her more than he could
ever love his second.
And he began to realize
how unfair
and how ungrateful
he had been.
Memories of a woman
he had wronged -
her gentle speech,
her smile,
her pretty dainty ways,
her impeccable patience...
...continuously haunted him.
I quit!
The same oId game!
I'm tired of it!
GirIs, you're dismissed.
You better go to bed now.
Your husband is stiII reading.
How ungratefuI you are!
You've gained position because of
my famiIy's sociaI prestige.
You onIy used me.
You're aIways cherishing your
oId memories.
You're waIking out on me!
The dew won't heIp.
PIease, go to your bedroom
and nurse her Iadyship.
Nurse her? That's your duty.
Don't say that.
She may return to her parents
tomorrow if she wants to.
I can't stand seeing her
dissatisfied Iook any more.
TeII her so.
After aII, I was young
and thoughtIess.
I'II find my ex-wife
whom I deserted
and make amends
for my sinfuI act.
The years went by.
And his official term expired.
It was September 10th when he
reached the street of Kyoto
where his first wife
used to live.
It was midnight and the city was
as silent as a cemetery.
When did you come back to Kyoto?
Now. Just now.
How did you find your way to me,
through aII those bIack rooms?
Stay seated.
Don't bother.
I'II get supper.
I don't want it.
You haven't changed a bit.
You Iook just Iike you did before.
Your face that I couIdn't
forget for a moment...
and your voice that was
so dear to me!
Forgive me.
I was crueI. I was a fooI.
I deserve your hatred.
UntiI the day my officiaI
term expired,
how I Ionged to come back to you!
How deepIy I regretted
my seIfishness!
How wretched I was without you!
How I Ioathed myseIf
for divorcing you!
How Iong I've hoped and pIanned
to make amends!
As soon as I became free.
I wanted to come back to Kyoto
and find you.
I hurried here in the dark.
It's very kind of you
thinking about me so much.
Forgive me.
PIease forgive me.
I was such a fooI!
Don't reproach yourseIf.
It's wrong to aIIow yourseIf
to suffer on my account.
I aIways feIt that I wasn't
worthy of being your wife.
Don't...
I knew that, but I couIdn't heIp
trying to be near you.
Anyway, it was very crueI of me
to have divorced you.
It was because of poverty.
WhiIe you Iived with me,
you were aIways kind.
Why shouId I think iII of you?
I prayed for your good fortune
every day and night.
I'II make amends.
Forget it.
You came a Iong way home.
What greater happiness
than to see you again...
even if onIy for a moment?
OnIy for a moment!
Make it the Iength of
seven Iifetimes!
UnIess you forbid it,
I'II Iive with you aIways...
aIways!
Nothing shaII ever
separate us again.
Your fragrant hair!
It's the same as before.
The same gIossy hair...
dark eyes...
IoveIy nose...
soft cheeks...
and...
I've forgotten my sorrow.
Many things have happened
in Kyoto since you went away.
I imagine so.
I can't teII you everything
in a night.
Soon it'II be dawn.
Yes. This room is very dear to me.
It was our bridaI chamber.
We spent severaI nights here.
I don't want to sIeep now.
I want to taIk of the past and the
present and the future with you
and feeI as happy as I am now.
I aIso feeI as if
this were a dream.
I don't want to sIeep
for a moment
so I can keep you forever.
THE WOMAN OF THE SNOW
In a village of Musashi Province
there lived two woodcutters:
Mosaku and Minokichi.
Mosaku was an old man
and Minokichi, his apprentice,
was a boy of eighteen.
Everyday, they went to a forest
a few miles away
from the village.
One cold day, a great snowstorm
overtook them on their way home.
The boatman had left his boat
on the other side of the river.
It was no day for swimming.
I intended to treat you Iike
the other man.
But I couIdn't heIp feeIing pity
for you
because you're so young.
You're a handsome boy.
I wiII not hurt you now.
But if you ever teII anybody -
even your own mother
about what you've seen tonight,
I'II know it.
And then I'II kiII you.
Remember that.
Understand?
I'II be going now.
We seII wood for a Iiving.
You can't work for some time,
not before spring.
The terribIe coId night
made you iII.
Eat the porridge.
Take care of yourseIf, son.
Or you'II be frozen
and dead Iike that oId Mosaku
whose bIood was aII gone.
If this happens to you again,
you won't survive.
Are you Iistening?
You've said nothing
about that night.
A year passed.
As soon as he got well,
he resumed working.
Every morning, he went
to the forest alone
and returned with bundles
of wood after sunset.
Where are you going
in the evening?
Edo.
Now?
Yes.
I Iost my parents.
My reIatives in Edo might heIp me
find work as a servant.
Brothers?
None?
Come!
That's my house.
Why don't you take a rest?
There's nobody you have to mind.
But...
OnIy my mother and I Iive there.
Come!
Your name is Yuki?
I see, I see.
Going to Edo aIone
sounds very dangerous.
PeopIe are not aIways kind.
Young girIs must be carefuI
not to be bothered by bad men.
Come eat whiIe it's hot.
And Yuki bore him
three children,
handsome and very fair of skin.
She acquired a fame for being a
good wife among the villagers.
It seems she never gets oId.
ReaIIy.
She's as young today as on the day
she first came into the viIIage.
She's a wonder.
Were you at the grave?
Yes. It's my mother-in-Iaw's
memoriaI day.
That's good.
She must be pIeased to see her
nice grandchiIdren
praying for her.
She's happy.
She died praising
her son's wife.
It's not very common.
No.
UsuaIIy, a mother-in-Iaw taIks iII
of her son's wife.
No matter how good the wife is.
That's not true.
Thanks to you, I'm happy.
What a happy coupIe,
you and your husband!
He must be happy.
He has such a good and beautifuI
woman for a wife.
NaturaIIy.
What a young wife!
Most peasant women age earIy
after having three chiIdren.
She stiII Iooks Iike a girI.
She's a wonder.
Put them on.
Is it too smaII?
And the chiIdren's?
I made them.
How nice! AII ready...the sandaIs
for the hoIiday season!
If the thongs are too tight,
I'II fix them.
Now try them on.
Yes.
How beautifuI!
Why the red thongs?
You're stiII young.
I'm a mother of three chiIdren.
Red is stiII your coIor.
Your feet Iook beautifuI.
It fits weII.
Not too tight, not too Iose.
It's exactIy my size.
Your sandaIs Iook beautifuI
and sturdy
so peopIe come to you
for speciaI orders.
This pair is exceedingIy good.
I made them so that
they'II match your kimono.
As if I were going away
on a journey!
I can't buy you a new kimono,
so at Ieast you have sandaIs.
With your sandaIs and my kimono
our chiIdren wiII have
a wonderfuI hoIiday.
How is it going?
A few more stitches.
Why are you watching me
so intentIy?
I just remembered
that night ten years ago.
It's strange to recaII it now
after so many years.
You're sewing with the Iight
on your face
and I'm Iooking up at you
Iike this.
That's why I remembered
that night...
What night?
A strange thing happened
that night.
I can remember it weII as if it
happened yesterday.
I was eighteen then. I never
toId anybody about that night.
I'm not sure it was reaI
or a dream.
It was the night that oId Mosaku
was frozen dead
as if his bIood were aII gone.
I saw with my own eyes a woman
who was bending over him.
And she was bIowing her breath
Iike a white smoke upon him.
Then he became stiff and
couIdn't move.
That woman stooped over me, too.
And I got aImost numb.
Then,
the eyes of the horribIe woman
Iooked very, very beautifuI.
She was so beautifuI
and white Iike you.
Yes!
You Iooked exactIy Iike her
just now.
That's why I remembered.
Once the memory haunted me
day and night.
I became sick after that.
I teII you, it was when I spent
the terribIe snowstormy night
in the ferryman's hut.
I saw very cIearIy the weird
woman who kiIIed oId Mosaku.
I've never seen in my Iife
a woman as beautifuI and white
as her except you.
Of course, she's not a human
being and I was afraid of her.
She was the Woman of the Snow
who was hungry for warm bIood...
...or a dream.
Not a dream.
I...
It was me.
Me!
It was Yuki.
You promised that night you'd
never teII anybody.
You finaIIy broke the promise.
It was a pIedge for Iife
for both of us.
I toId you if you broke it,
I wouId kiII you.
You betrayed me!
Ah, if it were not for those
chiIdren asIeep there
I wouId kiII you this moment!
From now on
you'd better take good care
of those chiIdren.
If they have any reason to
compIain about you
I'II treat you as you deserve!
HOICHI, THE EARLESS
It was early in the morning
of March 24th
when the Genji and Heike clans
fought their last sea battle.