The scorpion is an arachoid species
found in various parts of the world
Its tail comprises
five prismatic joints
The pincers, recalling those of
the larger crayfsh...
...are instruments of aggression
and information
Its tail ends in a sixth joint...
...a sac from which poison
is injected by barbed sting
A lover of darkness,
it burrows under stones...
...to escape the glare of the sun
Antisocial, it ejects the
intruder on its solitude
Such lightning strikes,
such virtuosity in attack
Even a rat, for all its fury,
falls prey to it
Some hours later
Stop it!
Perhaps I just happened to fall?
No. We saw nothing
Is there any news, yes or no?
Yes, the Majorcans are here
Quick, to arms!
To the rear!
What about Peman?
I'm done for
So are we, but we're going
Yes, but you've got accordions...
...hippopotamuses, wrenches...
...mountain goats, and...
Bollocks! Let's go
...and paintbrushes
1930 AD. This stone, on the site
where the Majorcans died...
...marks the founding of
the city of...
...Imperial Rome
Once mistress of the pagan world,
now secular seat of the Church
Aspects of its stoutest pillar,
the Vatican
The landlord's terms are very
favourable. We can move in at once
Longing to see you, very soon noW.
Your loving cousin
But the hurly-burly of modern life
has overtaken the Imperial City
Sometimes on Sundays...
Various picturesque aspects
of the great city
Bandaged?
Yes, it's been sore for over a week
Is Daddy home yet, Mummy?
Yes, he's in the dispensary
Then he'll dress for the party
We went out together this morning...
...and engaged four of them
The little moustached one
sang like the rest
Only a pianist is lacking
But our priest is a fine violinist
I think the musicians we have
will be enough
Six of them placed near
the microphone...
...will make more noise than sixty
ten kilometres away
I know sound gets lost in
the open air...
...but we could bring
the guests in close
Get a move on. The Majorcans
will be arriving at nine
Bastard! Filthy swine!
Keep your trap shut!
Want us to work you over?
Here's a taste of the rough stuff!
Enough is enough; let me show you
who you're dealing with
Let's have a look, then
The International Goodwill Society...
...hereby appoints you
its special delegate
This document testifies to
our faith in you
We pray that you will prove worthy...
...of this trust we place in you...
...and successfully complete
your goodwill mission
On your spirit of self-sacrifice
and your proven valour...
...depend many lives
Children, women, old men
The honour of our Fatherland rests on
the outcome of this noble enterprise
At his magnificent Roman estate, the
Marquis of X prepares for his guests
The Minister of the Interior
is on the telephone
You scoundrel! You are
entirely to blame!
You compromised me, too
Do you realize that
not one child survived?
Many women and old men perished, too
You're bothering me about a few brats?
Filthy ruffian, you've
dragged me down with you!
Dishonoured me!
You can die for all I care!
Then listen to my last words...
Has he gone?
Are you sleepy?
I Was just falling asleep
Where's the light sWitch?
At the foot of the bed
Your elboW's hurting me
Move your head closer,; the pilloW
is cooler on this side
Where's your hand?
That feels so good
Let's just sit here and not move
Are you cold?
No, I Was falling
I've been Waiting so long for him
What joy! What joy in having
killed our children
My love... my love...
Just as these feathers fell,
but a long way away...
...the survivors from the
Chateau de Selliny...
...emerged to return to Paris
120 days earlier, four godless
and unprincipled scoundrels...
...had, driven by their depravity,
shut themselves away...
...to indulge in the most
bestial of orgies
To them, the life of a woman
mattered no more than that of a fly
They took with them eight
lovely adolescent girls...
...to serve as victims for
their criminal desires...
...plus four women well versed
in debauchery...
...whose narrative skills would
serve to stimulate...
...their already jaded appetites...
...whenever interest flagged
Here are the survivors of these
orgies, leaving the Chateau de Selliny
First and foremost of the four
instigators, the Duc de Blangis