Sorry about yesterday when
I saw his body at the viewing.
I should have controlled myself.
No, you had no reason.
Helene did not deserve to see
how you cried over his body.
Do you think I did it on purpose?
I'm not stupid!
She knew that you slept with him.
I thought that you were more mature.
If you had sleep with someone else.
Like an outsider.
We could have kept the family together.
Is that why Ouessem and
Tony are angry with me?
How dare you come?
Does Jimenez know?
- No.
I don't think he'd let her come if he knew.
- We should tell them.
- Forget it.
Jimenez knew she had a relationship with
Rivoallan, and doesn't need to know more.
- Yes, but don't you think ...
- What?
Aurore is one of us,
you're not. So shut up!
We made a mistake,
but today we must be united.
I only have you.
So I said nothing.
I know Ouessem would never understand.
- Ouessem has his principles.
- No.
He has a lot of anger.
Mathias was everything to
me and that bothers you.
No, it's you who bothers me.
You do whatever you want, I don't give a shit.
But lets make you the victim.
I need a soldier, not a crybaby.
Impeccable, as always.
What's this?
- A medallion that was my aunts.
For protection.
I know what you do.
It's not what you think.
- Ouessem, don't lie to me.
Not to me.
I know what you do.
I lost my husband.
And I don't want to lose my family.
Listen well, Ouessem.
You're the one I trust.
So promise me one thing.
Bring everyone back.
Unharmed.
Promise.
I promise.
You'll be OK.
You don't think I knew about Aurore...
I'm not stupid.
He slept with her for 20 years.
But I knew my husband better than you.
Listen to me Frank.
I trust in you.
You have to promise me something.
Promise you will kill the pigs that did this!
Promise me that you will kill them all!
Everyone!
What do you want from me?
No!
- Where are they?
- I don't know who you're talking about!
- I don't know who ...
- Where are they?
- I'll ask you again!
- I don't know what you mean.
Where are the Markudis?
I don't know what you're talking about!
Where are they?
- What's happening?
- Leave him alone!
- Tony, get rid of them!
- What are you doing?
- Out!
- Pigs!
- Don't mess in my private affairs!
- Get out at once!
They have spent two days in hiding.
Where?
- I didn't get it from Rivoallan.
- Do you want to stay with us?
In the northern area.
- What?
- In the northern area.
In the district Charonne.
They are hiding with his men.
Rivoallan ...
was like our brother.
The Markudis killed him like a dog.
I'm not being sentimental.
I just want to kill those bastards.
I want to see ...
how they beg for their lives.
I thought this place was deserted.
We'll be seen.
So what?
We eliminate anyone that gets in our way.
Come on!
Sékounade, Nabil, go home.
- Don't tell us what to do.
Stop bothering us.
Around the back.
Jimenez, I didn't come here for a bloodbath.
Well does it make you feel better?
You don't understand.
We'll have to play dirty.
We're just here for Markudi.
Ouessem, you're a good guy, I know that.
But do not forget why we are here.
Today, we came for a bloodbath.
Come on!
Ouessem, they are the enemy.
Remember that.
THE HORDE
Ohh ..! Quiet!
What's going on?
Who are you?
Relax, I'm the lookout.
Well, I was. There is nothing
more to lookout for in this sty.
Is this a raid?
It's for the immigrants upstairs?
- How many?
Seven, eight.
Not to mention the security guards.
- Anyone else upstairs?
No.
The building is condemned.
The damned bourgeois and we are poor.
Some poor families are here.
Never thought to see it in France.
- Get lost. You didn't see us.
Go on!
Who do they think they are?
This building is mine.
Waste anyone who comes out alive.
Tony, take care of the door.
You two are on opposite sides.
Nobody moves until I give the signal.
We'll teach 'em The Marseillaise!
We have to go.
Finish him, Ade.
He is no longer good for us.
Able to catch them with it.
- Get out.
Believe me, it's better than their pellet gun.
Jimenez!
Tony!
I'll fill you with bullets!
Don't move. Give me that.
What is this?
Let me see your face!
How beautiful.
Who are you?
I'll blow them all away.
- No.
Go on!
Come here.
Hurry!
Go tell the others.
Do not let anyone enter the building.
Nobody!
Let me go, damn it!
Let me go!
Shut up.
I said shut up.
Look at me.
I said look at me.
What are you doing?
How many more are out there?
Look at me!
They came looking for someone?
That's why we are here?
Shit Bola!
My suit!
Shit, I'm not your maid.
You piss me off.
I don't understand a word you're saying.
Shut your mouth.
Shit!
Drop it!
Whether you end up like him?
Look at you cops, so pathetic, with your toy guns.
They hoped to catch us?
In our country, we would have
had you hung by the balls.
What will you do?
Bola!
They can't be alone.
Let's get out of here, before we are surrounded.
We're not leaving ...
...while these cretins don't say what is out there.
Upstairs went all wrong block everything.
Forget it!
They don't want to talk.
He is right, let's finish them off.
There's nobody out there!
We came alone.
Don't lie to me!
Don't lie to me.
You alerted the entire police station?
Answer me!
I don't know who they are!
You can show that gun all you want.
We came here alone, Rivoallan paid for it.
Kill. Kill everyone.
All this for a fucking cop?
What going on, Ade?
What the fuck is this?
Step aside!
Son of a bitch!
It's not possible.
What's happening?
I just killed him.
And he stood up?
Don't move!
My goodness!
Ade!
Shit!
Come on!
It's unreal!
The bar!
Get the bar!
Hurry, up!
Hurry the bar!
They devoured the Czech.
They ate the Czech.
Bola!
Ouessem!
What's happening?
What the hell is going on Ouessem?
Ouessem!
They're coming.
They're coming to get us.
I guess we can leave.
We have to try.
You saw what they did
with the Czech. Ate his face.
Don't be a sissy, Bola.
I'll bust their heads in.
There is nothing to do.
Absolutely nothing.
The judgment is final.
Look at them.
They broke down the doors with one hand.
They rip out your guts with their teeth.
Bullets don't stop them.
You can't kill them,
because they are already dead.
There are thousands of them.
We're screwed.
It won't help if we do anything.
It's a death sentence, don't you see?
We'll all die.
Shut up!
Whatever you want, we'll leave.
What will you do, get down with a rope?
That's the only way out.
And the bodies are everywhere.
How you doing?
Don't listen to him.
Come at once.
Listen, Markudi.
You, your brother and idiot friend...
...are three.
Don't count on these suckers here.
But together we have a chance.
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
You seem to disagree.
You can't do that.
Shut up.
Stop!
Shut up. We agree.
Listen, I'm not your friend.
I don't care for you.
But I want to get out of here alive.
And our chances are better with you.
Or don't you agree.
Or we split up now on this damn roof.
No time to think.
We'll go down together
then we'll part ways.
Separating?
He is deceiving you, Ade.
Your girlfriend here...
can she use a gun?
Don't worry about me.
Control your group.
Control yours.
We need guns and drugs.
Do you have a cache?
Guns, yes.
I can't help with the rest.
Don't move.
They're gone.
They took Jimenez's body.
- Help me.
That's all we have.
Forget your homemade remedies.
This is what he needs.
Stop, Ouessem it hurts.
He is right, this will end the pain.
Are you sure?
See?
He knows what's good for him.
Where're you going?
- I'll be right back. Rest.
Slowly!
He's worse than you.
Why did you join with these cretins?
I know you don't like it.
Neither do I.
But we have no choice.
See Tony.
This is bullshit, Ouessem.
We can't trust those bastards.
You got us into this mess.
- What?
Was it you who got us into this.
No that was you with fucking Rivoallan.
Calling him every night crying.
You said you were pregnant.
When he was looking for these assholes.
Tony told you that?
No matter who, Aurore.
You messed up his head.
This mess is your fault.
When you're finished, we can try it out.
You know this building.
What's the plan?
Avoid leaving traces of blood.
- That's your plan?
This building is rotting.
The elevator only goes to the fourth
floor. And you can't use the balconies.
The service stairs were never
finished. Understand the situation?
Have a better idea, then?
That's what I thought.
Let’s get another ladder.
Wait.
They should be at the entrance.
"They should be at the entrance."
Scary.
Shit!
What was that?
Go, Bola.
Jo.
We need to go, Jo.
Come on!
- Wait!
Tony!
Don't shoot!
Don't worry about it.
Bola!
My leg!
Ade!
Hands off!
What would you do without me?
Tony!
Aurore! Tony!
They need us.
Let it go!
It's too late.
I know these calls.
Go ahead.
What is stopping you?
Two cops killed, and we are stuck with the lame.
You think you're funny?
Shut up, Bola!
Back off.
This is how it keeps track of your group?
You're alone now.
If you want to work with us...
you better stop being so sensitive.
I'm sure she's alive.
If so, hope that she has courage.
Bitch.
Are you okay?
Show me.
The bleeding has stopped.
The dog bit my shoulder.
Can you walk?
Yes.
Holy shit!
Don't move!
Lower your guns, I'm not one of them.
I told you not to move.
You gave them a good beating.
It's good, no?
Like the battle of Dien Bien Phu!
How many did you smoke?
How many did the Chinese smoke?
I didn't say.
A half dozen, I think.
I'm getting rusty in my old age.
What are you doing here?
Keeping the post.
They saw the mess on the ladder?
I blew them to smithereens.
Handmade explosives.
I ran out of grenades in '64.
You live on this floor?
Yes.
You were bitten, weren't you?
Need to take care of it.
I get around, come with me.
Don't trust this old man.
Take his gun.
We will try to find the others.
They got you good.
Shit!
Who's the pussy now?
Let me see.
Move your hand!
Quiet, monster.
We have to avoid gangrene.
What did he call me?
- Forget it.
A cop is sometimes helpful.
- What?
Why is he taking care of me?
Do I look like a nurse?
Want to be alone?
Screw it.
Hey Grandpa. Is there anything
stronger than this to drink?
It hurts.
What are you doing?
I'll have to cut the leg off.
What?
Are you kidding?
If it rots, that won't help get
the Chinese out there.
Cut, cut.
Try it.
- Easy.
Stay out it.
- He's right.
Shut up.
- I have to amputate the leg.
Nobody touches my leg.
Easy.
Back off, grandpa.
I have to amputate his leg.
- He's crazy.
What did he do?
Say it to my face.
- You're crazy!
We must cut off his leg.
No way.
- Stop it.
Easy!
- We have to amputate.
The old man is crazy.
- Amputate, amputate!
Nobody touches my leg.
Enough!
- Stop it!
We have to amputate his leg.
Ouessem should not have said that.
What?
Rivoallan was not your fault.
You shouldn't have opened your mouth.
I know.
When Ouessem knew you
were pregnant, he thought ...
What?
- What that I did it on purpose?
You all think I'm a bitch.
I never said that.
Not my fault.
I regret what happened, that's all.
Repentance?
Think you have time to regret?
What happened?
Want to know?
Damn his apologies.
He can swallow his words.
I owe nothing to anyone.
You mean nothing to me.
Ouessem means nothing to me.
I don't care about anything.
What are you doing?
That's all that matters.
Cuff yourself.
You can't do this to me.
- Cuff yourself.
If you leave me here, I will die.
I beg you.
Please Aurore, don't do this to me.
Cuff yourself now!
You can't leave me here.
If you leave me here, I will die.
I don't want to die here.
- Cuff yourself.
I don't want to die.
I beg you, Aurore.
Don't let me die.
You're already dead, Tony.
Don't worry, it's broken.
- Shit.
You better take care of the monster,
he needs help.
He is fine,
and he's not a monster.
As you wish.
But I know what I'm talking about.
When your friend turns Chinese
we have to take him out.
Those things are contagious.
- You tire me, old man.
See how he speaks, his worm.
- Leave him, Bola.
Ok, forget it.
I was young once.
He is insignificant.
And now?
- Hold it, guys?
We are safe here, I locked the door.
I have a pear brandy.
Fifteen years old.
What do you think?
I can't drink alone.
Their religion does not allow it?
- I don't believe in God.
Call me Rene.
Take it.
Religion is just death insurance.
Right?
And I badly need it now.
Am I right?
This shit is hardcore.
- What?
"Hardcore," brutal.
"Hardcore"?
I'll pass.
Good to see that there are still men like you.
To your health.
Say there, soldier...
you did not learn to make bombs here.
How did you survive?
I have a good hiding place.
I received good training on the front.
If my wife Clemence
was alive, you would have seen.
120 pounds of sagging,
udder banging against her knees...
...hands like hams.
You would think twice before
putting your hands on her ass.
We laugh, but...
A big girl.
You can say that again.
But it must be tough here.
You have to have balls.
And there always comes a sucker
wanting to rule the henhouse.
I see.
- I'm not complaining.
Clem could not stand it here,
but I never cared.
There seems a lot more...
but after Indochina...
no Chinese will keep me, agreed.
Depends on who.
- Don't ruin it, cop.
What? Are you kidding?
You're a cop?
What are you doing here alone?
I came here for justice.
Came to lessen the injustice.
- Didn't go as planned.
Look around you, the world is upside down.
The Chinese are not the first
to cause problems here.
We've been eating shit for 30 years.
Just like Mother Teresa, but getting nothing.
Want to know the truth?
You came because you're like us.
You want to be in the forefront.
Turns you on, no?
Excites you.
We do not know if the epidemic is spreading ...
Turn it up, I can't hear.
Outside is a mess.
I'm with a group survivors.
It's a massacre;
Hundreds are dead.
The army ordered an evacuation.
Downtown is inaccessible.
Hundreds of survivors were
assembled outside the capital...
...and sent to the
military base in Villacoublay.
The capital?
Where is our evacuation?
This reminds me of Abuja.
Going down the stairs, is impossible.
Do I have to spell it out?
The fact that it’s an entry,
doesn't make it an exit.
You guys really want to
wander around, waiting...
...for these freaks who want to eat us?
We should go straight out...
...and run for it.
- Let me get this straight.
Go up the elevator shaft
with my friend José hurt?
Run into these bastards
who want to devour us?
And then run to some military base ...
to end up in a shower with other soldiers...
Who looked at my ass like I'm some chick?
Goofing off in my face?
- If we stay here, we die.
Are you deaf?
We don't know how many
of them are out there.
There's probably a lot after what I did.
I'll take care of the elevator doors.
- You do not give up?
Want to save his skin?
Then listen.
Listen to you.
You couldn't even save your friends.
Bola, not now.
- He's your boyfriend now?
Tell this asshole to leave me alone.
I'll kill this damn cop too old and decrepit.
Bola!
Come on.
Give me the Coke.
Give it to me!
I can't get it.
I'll help.
Smell a little.
- Really?
Don't need it.
This is sugar compared to what I took in China.
It's time for your suppository you shit!
What happened to the ones I killed?
They take the bodies.
Why?
Give me your lever.
Well done, lad.
Where is your spirit?
What you gonna do now?
Who's the idiot now?
What will you do?
It's time for a wheelchair.
You found a way into it.
We'll kill the bitch.
What about boys?
I know what she wants.
Give a kiss to Rene.
Look what that bitch is capable of.
The teacher of the second floor?
You gave it to him?
Go on.
Kiss it.
Kiss it!
Kiss it, come on!
Kiss it, bitch.
Come on!
Kiss!
So.
You want Rene's salami?
Think this is funny?
What's gotten into you?
Answer me!
Think this is funny?
You think you're it?
- Stop by Ade. -
What?
Remember what they did
to us in our own land?
Have you forgotten?
His brother is a problem.
- I don't like how that sounds.
He can't talk to you that way.
Shit!
You have to fix it, Ball.
She has a beautiful corpse.
You scare me, man.
- How so?
Tony!
I'm fine.
Aurore ...
- What?
Where is she?
She tried ...
- What?
What's gotten into you?
Are you mad?
We can't trust him.
You're crazy.
- Let me go.
He was changing.
- He was not dead.
You shot him in the head.
Tony.
He was part of the family.
Leave her alone.
She did the right thing.
- Fuck you!
Let your feelings out!
We need everyone.
Let go.
He won't hurt me.
I am part of the family.
Come on help me.
I'm not a kid any more.
What are you doing?
- Go on!
Calm down, children.
- Shut up.
What are you doing, Bola?
You want to die with these idiots.
Then die with them.
Take their weapons.
That idiot turned his head?
I have no brother.
You treated me like garbage for years.
Not anymore.
Mom was right.
You only think about yourself.
You are weak, Bola.
You know it as well as I do.
Without me, you'd have been dead.
The lame monster cannot save you.
Forget it, Bola.
I'm your only brother here.
You won't last long.
Did you know that?
Shut up, you old fart.
Bola.
You can't go on without me.
I can, Ade.
Without you I will.
Without you.
Bola!
We should have amputated his leg.
He wouldn't have gotten very far.
We can't stay here.
We can't stay here!
We need weapons!
The watchman has a stock.
This way.
We will not win without them.
Ouessem!
Now you're alone, Markudi.
If you want to work as a team ...
you have to trust me.
Come on!
It's like it is asking for help.
No.
They're hungry.
Don't waste time.
Come on.
Didn't I say so?
It's enough to supply an army.
Rene?
I'll smash the lot of them with this.
My love ...
let's make mincemeat of them.
Hey, girl ...
you look like a shrew, now.
Calm down, dear.
Open your eyes, Markudi.
I didn't forget why I came here.
Neither did I.
Come on.
Just a minute.
I will not need the
protector of my balls, now.
Come on, folks.
I'm ready.
Damn!
They were here!
What are you doing, Markudi?
Bola!
Get off it!
Come on, get up, you bastard!
You killed my brother, you bastard!
You know who I am?
I'm a damn Nigerian.
A Nigerian!
Come here!
Get up, you bastard!
You killed Bola,
I'll kill you.
Think you can play with me?
I'm a damn Nigerian you bastard.
A Nigerian damn you!
You killed Bola!
The door!
Hurry!
The exit is around here.
Come on. It's over.
- Leave me alone.
Wake up!
Oh, no!
I can't believe it.
We're trapped!
I need to find it.
The basement!
Come to the basement.
Come on.
I'll keep an eye on them.
You can't.
Let him.
You don't need it.
Come on!
Take care of her.
Go!
Get the fuck out of here!
C'mon motherfuckers!
They're everywhere!
Here!
I'll cover you.
I'm looking up!
Hurry!
Move!
They are worse than flies hungry for shit.
Shut up!
Where is the exit?
Where?
There's a door downstairs.
Are you sure?
The cop died because of their conversation.
Don't need him.
He gave his life for you.
I don't care.
You bastards!
My God.
They bring the bodies here?
It looks like a mass grave.
No.
It's their pantry.
Have enough food.
Good work!
Shit!
Let's get out of here!
They're getting up!
Help me!
My God!
The path is clear.
Here!
Come, children. Hurry!
Shit!
The lady!
Hurry, girl!
Get ready, kids.
Hell begins!
I'm running out!
Markudi!
Quick, boys!
Move!
Tear down that damn door!
Shit!
I'm out of ammunition.
Give me the grenade, quickly.
Hurry up!
Fuck that.
I won't die of a heart attack.
All’s fair in love and war.
What are you doing?
What is this?
Shit, playing soon!
Come to Daddy, its fucking time!
I'll show you what's hardcore.
Relax, relax, relax.
SUBTITLES BY CHIBCHAKAN