It feels as if something awful will happen to me.
As if something bad happened.
It has not reached me yet,
but it's way.
I do not know the value,
but it helps people
order to deal with their loss,
by tales of ghosts and so to think.
Alice had secrets.
She kept the secret,
that she had secrets.
It is difficult for some to understand,
but you should find yourself in debt,
what else you need.
In December 2005
began with a tragic accident...
a series of extraordinary events
a grieving family...
and the Victorian town of Arafat,
in the center
of the media attention brought.
This film is a report
of those events.
JUNE's emergency.
The normally tranquil image
Arafat's reservoir was disrupted yesterday,
by the disappearance
of the 16 year old Alice Palmer...
during a picnic with her family.
We received the call around six hours
about a missing girl,
and the nature of reporting,
We have deployed rescue divers.
Police divers went to ten hours to water,
together with volunteers,
who helped in a fruitless search...
Mat Ali and swam to the middle
of the reservoir.
I could see,
from where I sat on the picnic area.
I think I had 15 minutes in the water,
when I said I went out,
because I was cold.
And I swam back, they did not count,
So I thought that she still wanted to stay.
I remember that Mati is released,
and a few minutes later
I heard him ask where Alice was.
I stood up and looked over the lake
and the water was completely calm.
So I started calling.
I looked over the water,
if I could see her,
and two boys
had checked the bushes.
Alice I could see her towel,
she had left.
So she was not the water come
because then she grabbed her towel.
That was the last time,
I have seen her.
Police fear the worst
for the 16 year old Alice Palmer,
who disappeared during a picnic
with her family.
Police divers...
- They said we had to go home.
And when the divers would find something,
they would let us know immediately.
It felt very strange way in the car,
because there was one empty seat.
One minute she was there
and then...
way.
We stayed that night at the Palmers,
and there have
mainly waiting on news.
In bad news.
That was expected.
Russell called our mobile,
nine hours at night.
He said that an accident had happened
in the reservoir
and Alice was missing.
So we thought it best
for going there.
I remember
June that there was some strange,
to see Iris.
There was something strange between them.
It felt strange,
to have my mother there.
Mom and I there for Alice.
It did not feel right.
It was a terrible night.
The worst night of our lives.
I am later that night,
Alice entered the room.
Her phone rang a few times,
but I have not included.
I remember
that the bed was made.
I remember I thought,
that there are so neat looking.
I got a phone call
Alice's mother, June,
Alice said that she lost
and probably drowned,
and I believed her,
but...
I do not know,
it was hard to accept, so...
Alice, I called her mobile number.
I wanted to know whether it was a joke.
It was a shock.
It felt unreal.
Everything was as always,
but they said that Alice was drowned.
What of that night for you,
the most important memories.
I know that we are wearing the light outside,
that we still
just in case.
Why?
In case she comes home
I think.
The divers found her body Alice
at 21:25.
They used sonar,
to locate her.
She had drifted and ended
on a protrusion of the dam.
I immediately informed the family.
Once we were told,
that they had found the body,
June and I have gone to the lake.
Georgie is Matt remained.
It was all very official and formal,
I had to sign a statement identifying,
June remained in the car.
And in hindsight was a mistake,
so because she could not close.
I could not bring,
Alice to identify.
She had all that time underwater,
and so I wanted her...
so I wanted to remember her.
I thought it was my responsibility,
as Ali's father, you know ..
That is what a man does.
The car hit off
on the back of the reservoir.
The only gear that worked,
was the reverse.
So we drove in reverse
back to town.
It was that or walk
and given the events,
that was the only option.
The autopsy took place on Monday the 27th.
The coroner gave the body Tuesday
the 28th Fri
It was very strange for the Day
with the family to spend,
Alice alone in the morgue.
I do not know, it was like,
if I had not seen her for a week.
It felt unreal.
Death takes everything, eventually.
Death is the meanest was there,
and it makes him not care.
It makes no sense,
to know more about it.
It was a sad day for the family
and the friends of Alice Palmer,
The latest evidence came to honor,
a young woman who died too soon.
She was a wonderful person,
popular, smart, nice,
I... yes...
Alice is remembered
as a happy, cheerful girl,
with great vitality,
described as always...
The Palmers were difficult,
that period.
To think how bad it was then,
you can hardly imagine
how bad it still would be.
Ten days after the funeral of Ali,
January 15,
strange things happened in the house.
Sounds on the roof
and sounds came through the window...
and other movements,
from Ali's old room seemed to come.
We have the door again depended,
of Ali's room
and had an opponent come vermin,
to check for termites.
And it did nothing,
the door remained open and close
and we heard noises from her room.
There was just something strange about that house,
I had a strange feeling
and I can not explain exactly what it was,
but if you go in there,
you get a bad feeling inside.
I began to have nightmares,
which caused so much grief
I sometimes open my eyes wanted.
I was awake,
but I did not open my eyes.
There was one in particular,
very lifelike, and he repeated himself.
Alice came into the hall,
still nadruppend of the reservoir
and stood at the foot of the bed
and stared at us.
It was so frightening,
I dared not open my eyes to do.
By early February
My nightmares were so bad,
I night walks
began to make. Sometimes three hours long,
to not having to sleep at night
with my eyes closed.
Sometimes I
to the homes of other people.
It did not feel as if I did something wrong,
I think I wanted to share a part while
someone else's life.
Georgie, you remember,
how that period was Russell?
Russell was working a lot,
I think that has helped with his grief.
Russell and I met
Gibsland, Louisiana during the CASMAN project in '89.
We have worked together since.
So you know each other a few years.
- Yes, a number of years.
Remember how he was
after the death of Alice, was there anything changed?
The work went on and...
and that was difficult,
I did not know what to say to him.
You did not talk about.
- Not really, everyone mourns in their own way,
and it was not my case
to tell him how he must feel.
But I was worried.
I was really grateful that I had my work,
and since then I felt really guilty,
but I wanted more.
One night I came home late February
of work and I sat in the kitchen,
and I heard a noise from Ali's room.
So I went Ali's room
and I do not know exactly why,
but I sat in the chair
for the sideboard,
and tried to think what I did there,
Ali and then went inside to her office
and they began to sharpen a pencil,
and when she seemed to view an SMS
on her phone,
and I had not.
She was totally unconscious
of my presence.
And what happened then I do not know,
I should have moved the bed,
or sound made with my shoes,
or something and she shivered,
and then I knew,
they knew I was there.
She turned and looked at me,
what felt like forever,
and when she came to me and said go away.
and I got up and went away
as fast as I could.
I heard Russell crying, he was in the kitchen,
Mathew and I found him here.
He sniffed it out,
He was totally inconsolable.
Do you Russell,
when he says he saw a ghost?
Yes, I think he said what he saw,
And he would not...
He is not the man who invents something.
So I think he has seen something.
Whether it's a real ghost or not,
I do not know.
But I am sure,
he has seen something.
I know I tried,
with members of the church to speak,
June and on how to help the Palmers.
But we seemed to do nothing.
Part of the problem,
they were not church goers.
They did not,
how she had to offer them comfort.
I do not even believe where June.
I was most worried about Mathew.
I think, because they were so close.
I made me worried,
about how he would deal with it.
I remember that he was more often alone,
I worried for him.
Mathew came here
in unusual places on his body.
They were unusually
terms of distribution and depth.
We thought an earlier traumas,
but that was not there.
We examined him on inflammation
and poisoning.
We could not conclude,
and a few weeks later
places that disappeared spontaneously.
And we never have a cause
ascertained.
I'm Steve Wilkie,
the best friend of Mathew.
I'm about two to three times a week
Mathew at home.
We are a band together.
We play music at home.
Mathew seemed quieter,
but he was always rather quiet,
so there is no alarm bells went off or something.
I had heard about,
people's homes that went into June.
Mathew seemed not to want to talk
and I have not asked him.
I knew,
he was interested in photography,
and in that period
he more attention.
Mathew came to me
and wanted to know everything about photography,
and I wanted very much to help him,
that's what I do.
He asked me the shirt off my body,
about equipment, techniques, exposure.
He was a great help
and I even hired him.
Mathew, what can you say about the pictures,
of the garden you've taken.
Yes, it comes down,
I was the same picture,
same composition for the three months
photographed before, during four years.
It's just a picture of the garden
and in the distance you see the hills.
It is a little project I started,
From the moment we arrived.
And what was different about the photo of April 28?
The picture was the same,
but it seems,
like Alice in the fence.
Remember how the reaction was home?
I can not say,
the mood was good,
but better than before.
I think that all this gave us something
to focus on.
The photos were taken April 3
and developed on the fourth,
and I looked at them, I think, on the fifth.
And I looked at the dams
and the water and I was pretty happy,
but the next day
I was pointed out by my wife,
that there was something in the background,
there was someone.
When I first looked at the picture,
I did not know what it was.
The figure made me quite upset,
because it certainly looked at Alice.
It was quite a disturbing image.
And I became convinced,
Alice was still alive.
I had no rational explanation,
who was in the photographs.
But I knew something of Alice,
June did not know what.
I have seen the body of Alice.
I did not think she was alive.
I knew it was not.
I became convinced
that Russell had made a mistake.
He himself has said,
they seemed to anybody.
June was so convinced of my error,
I began to doubt himself.
Perhaps I had already decided
Alice that was before I looked.
And the circumstances were so compelling,
I decided that it was.
More than three months after the funeral
of Arafat's teenager, Alice Palmer,
asked the grieving parents,
to exhume her body exhumed
the general cemetery.
The Palmer's doubts
to identify the body.
June and Russell Palmer
asked for a DNA test.
They were not sure whether the body
that they identified was actually Alice.
Alice's body was exhumed,
where the funeral,
dr Slaghter and a representative
of the coroner were present.
Her body was transported
Arafat to the hospital,
where they decreased the DNA samples
and they remained there,
until results were available.
A few days later we received
The preliminary report of the pathologist,
and the identity of Alice was determined
on the basis of comparison.
Only after confirmation
that the body of Alice was
I realized how much energy I had put,
the idea that it might not.
I wanted so badly,
it was a terrible mistake,
if it was mine.
I wanted so badly,
that another child was in that reservoir,
a runaway, a victim of murder,
Just a child of someone else,
long as it is not my child.
While it was not Alice.
Alice was reburied on June 7.
But the question remained,
who or what stood in the photographs.
I kept hearing things and...
- What did you?
I kept hearing noises,
pitiful sounds, noises in the hall.
I thought I put a camera down,
to see if there is something to see.
I watched the video of the first night
and there were images of a figure,
who moved from the bathroom...
the hall to the door.
You listen to Boyd's FM,
it is two minutes to eight.
I am Helen Bath
and we will continue with...
The following line is Margie,
Ray?
Hi Margie, how are you,
what can I do for you.
By that time I decided to ask for advice
to Ray Kemeny.
I had Ray for years followed on the radio,
and the opinions were divided,
some believed in him,
others were not as convinced.
The following line is Annie.
- Hello Annie, how are you.
It is good to me Ray, thank you that you took.
- No problem, what can I do for you?
I would like a normal reading.
Just, not medical?
I am of Hungarian origin,
My parents came here when I was young.
I have a 15 year old daughter,
with her mother who lives in South Australia.
My first name is actually Zsolt,
but I changed to Ray.
This is a more trusted name
for a medium.
The most popular medium of Australia.
Usually my work is about sick,
or dying, or about one third part,
them to experience,
that death is not the bitter end,
that this does not stop everything.
That is one consolation that I would give,
because life after death
is still elusive.
There is someone you really come near,
someone you have not seen.
Someone who comes back into your life,
someone who will give you comfort.
Does anybody on this description?
- Yes, I can propose to someone.
I see you have many problems,
but returnee,
will make much difference and bring comfort.
Thank you Ray.
Bye, Annie.
Where I come from, they cover the mirrors,
to avoid a dead return.
Things like that make the difference.
Hi Annie, I'm Ray.
I liked Ray from the beginning,
He was not what I expected,
I do not know what I expected,
but there was nothing ghostly,
or counterfeiting to him.
Are you ready?
I usually make a video of my sessions,
so they can be judged
by customers.
In particular, if a trance
whether hypnosis is used.
I love a copy
and they get a copy.
I prefer the safe side.
Okay, so you stand for your home,
tell me what you see.
My house, it's a white house,
I walk to the door.
I want you to go inside the house,
walking slowly through the house.
I want you to describe what you see.
And tell where you are,
give me a tour.
Okay, I walk through the hall,
towards Alice's room.
What do you see?
- I see the shoes are Alice.
And what does that tell you, June?
She always had her sneakers
outside her room.
Will you go in her room?
Open the door and just go inside.
You feel safe enough,
to Alice's room to enter.
Open the door.
I go into her room.
You see something, huh?
Tell me what you see June.
Alice sits on the chair,
at the end of her bed.
She looks sad.
I met Ray when June asked
to continue eating after the first consultation.
I have no prejudices
in terms of mediums.
I had asked him not to eat,
June but I wanted not to upset.
He was a nice guy, nothing ghostly
and I behaved at my best.
A couple of days, maybe one weeks later,
I asked the family to hold a seance.
June should like, but I remember,
that Russell refused.
I think Mathew has his father turned talk.
Mathew, how was it you,
that a séance was held in your home.
I was interested,
and curious,
Dad was not so happy,
but I thought it would be interesting.
And I suggested, for the filming,
and I took it with the PT 9, a video camera.
I feel a strong presence of her
in this house.
I think that we found valuable seance,
Ray brought nothing to light,
no signs, or whatever.
So after one hours or so
We stopped.
And the next day,
Mathew then watched the video,
we saw a picture of Alice.
This video was very different
than the previous images.
It was first detailed
and less blurred,
and it was not explained as,
an accidental shadow play,
or digital noise, or...
There was something inexplicable in our house.
Without doubt.
I was worried.
This was uncharted territory for me,
and I sat in the middle.
Ray asked him to help Mathew,
installing three cameras,
together 24 hours a day filming.
There was much speculation about Ray
and what he did.
If people do not know,
true that to gossip and speculation.
I've heard rumors throughout July
on video recordings,
belonging to an "operation"
in the house.
But I had my doubts
about legitimacy.
And your picture of Ray?
- Also very skeptical.
They thought I was a sort of Rasputin,
hypnotized by the Palmers and stole their money,
reflecting the benefits at the expense of Alice.
Mathew seemed hard to have.
I thought I could help
by my presence.
But my main motivation
was professional.
Something happened in that house
and I wanted to find out what it was.
How you reacted to these images?
We were stunned.
But before we realized what this meant,
Withers, the 'video.
Is it what?
- Yes, great.
Can I look?
Cathy and Doug Withers were on April 3
in the reservoir,
Same Day
Bob Smeets which the picture was taken.
A few months later, in late July,
when we viewed the film of the reservoir,
when we encounter...
a figure in the background,
which we identify as Bob Smeets.
What was interesting, because we realized,
that that day was that he was there,
and took that picture, everyone is talking about,
and when all our pictures we have seen,
to see if we figure had also filmed.
Maybe our cameras saw what Bob did.
And we have a figure found
as his picture was shown,
and when we have better views
and Doug has zoomed in on...
I have enlarged on the computer,
from afar it looked like a female figure,
up close you could see that no woman
and Alice was not.
It was Mathew.
Do you believe in ghosts?
Here I was,
Bob Smeets when the picture was taken.
I wore the coat to Alice and I saw a man
on the hill, which turned out to be Bob Smeets.
I did not want the picture,
So I walked away through the bushes.
I torque
that filmed not seen the Withers.
When this came out, asked my dad
whether I had done other things,
and I would not lie,
So I told everything.
I have my father explained,
I was responsible...
the statues of Alice in the hall
and the bedroom,
and I picture the garden April 28 fabricated,
with a photo of Alice.
I told what I had done.
I took two photos, one photo of Alice
and of the garden and overlapped the photos.
This is a picture that I took of Alice.
Mom always spoke about the exhumation of Alice,
and she had always on,
Dad that the wrong body identified
and I knew that with further
would not happen, so I made the picture.
I used an old video of Alice
and I played it off the TV,
with the TV on the bookshelf,
Just a picture in the mirror.
So the reflection of the TV appearance
and the mirror was small.
I pulled the edges of the road TV
and filmed it.
I did the same with the kitchen
and the bedroom.
So really what you see,
Alice is on TV in the mirror.
I wanted people not cheat,
it was more like,
something is better than nothing.
Think,
The result was that heavier June?
I think...
Yes, so it was probably
difficult for her,
but that was not my intention.
I'm not so sure of his intentions.
I know I...
not quite...
I would not say,
I do not believe in what he says,
but I am not convinced,
he knows why he did it.
When it came out people wanted the story,
books, leaves wife,
all, length.
We did not
how we deal with it should go.
We had Mati protect ourselves,
the memory of Ali.
We had no experience in dealing
with interest in something personal,
they wanted to make public.
It went not well with the Palmers,
it went bad, they were heavy.
It was hard on us,
but especially for June.
She could not let go Ali.
She wanted her a little longer hold.
And I think they will not admit,
but she was devastated.
She is an interesting girl,
they seemed not so good to be with June.
They looked much alike,
it was interesting that they're not as good
got along with.
She always seemed very similar
and you saw that Alice looked a lot like June,
but there are things more clear
after the death of Alice,
which give an impression of what they shared.
June was and is still much to itself,
and it appeared that this was also true at Alice.
It is about whether or not parts
their private life, I think.
It is wonderful when children come
and that you have new experiences,
but you always doubt whether you have enough,
or the right thing.
Maybe after that inherits from me,
or maybe my mother.
I myself never to give
for June.
So June is also a little
and she could not fully provide for Alice.
I hope that Alice knew,
how much I loved her.
I pulled some back when she was older.
That would be a pity,
if they did not.
Ray suggested, in order to take Mathew
on one of his Victorian travel
while consultations's itinerary
and we took advantage of it.
I think when I left, I realized,
much I missed Alice,
and I never could talk to her.
I believe that all clients of Ray,
this must learn to deal.
They want someone to talk
or contact
with someone they have lost
and me.
So I was really
one of Ray's clients.
Can you catch?
Let's see what happens.
I know what will happen,
you will hit me,
and then I get angry,
that will happen, no.
Beware.
What are you doing in my room?
- No idea.
When Ray and I went on tour,
we let the two cameras in the rented hall.
I was sure,
that there is something in the house.
And since we were three days away,
we could not change tapes,
So you get some film day and a half,
but we let them run
and we came back August 2
and when we viewed the tapes.
I know that Russell and I were home,
when these images were recorded.
There could Mathew nothing to do.
They seemed to prove,
there a ghost in our house.
The spirit of Alice.
Do you believe in ghosts?
At first no, but...
What is proof?
Yeah, I think they may exist.
Ghosts can be anywhere,
it is a frightening world.
I do not know,
or important to people,
and that helps,
stories come to mind.
It was a big question mark
and I looked at all the previous video
all the videos in the house,
after the death of Alice.
It was while viewing
Mathew's June of material from the hall,
something that struck me in the picture.
There was half figure in the hall,
Mathew not, but someone else,
who in the dark
Alice moved into the room.
At first I thought it was Alice,
then I realized,
it was our neighbor, Brett Tooheys.
What was that man in my house,
in my daughters room,
more than six months after her death.
When I discovered the safe of Alice,
I realized why he had been.
He looked for the band.
That's him.
Alice began to babysit for Thoohey's
in 2002.
And she did 2.5 years long.
The two boys of the Tooheys's
were five and nine years old.
I literally could not believe my eyes.
I felt so sad.
For me, the Tooheys's
collusion with the death of Alice.
I think if they had not been,
They had asked us for help,
and then she had not felt guilty.
Then she had the burden of that secret
not to bear.
Then she had not been isolated.
What do you think of Brett?
If he was at the corner,
I would probably strangle him.
He seemed a nice man,
so to say.
He was never boring or something.
He had a swimming pool
and we swam there in summer.
We were so often with him,
for swimming.
I was shocked because of what had happened,
it took a while before it penetrated.
I had no idea that Alice...
- If someone was.
We were surprised, we did not expect,
she would do.
Why do you think
Alice had the band?
Because they do not wish they had him.
Why?
- They no longer trust them, I think.
They must have been desperate,
for the band to get.
From the moment they heard
the death of Alice,
they have lived in constant fear,
fearing that it would come.
I am glad that he could not find
I'm glad he knows that it is not over.
I personally had a lot to do with the Palmers,
during the search for the Tooheys's.
And we were optimistic about the fact,
they would be found
and would be sued,
but unfortunately the trail went dead.
So the investigation went down.
The police considered,
that even if the Tooheys's been caught,
they would get a suspended sentence,
by the claim that the sex was voluntary,
which was supported by the video evidence.
Jason you knew anything about the relationship
between Alice and Brett?
No, no.
Of course not, if I had known
We had not gone out together, no.
I thought that something was wrong between us.
There were so many unanswered questions,
what they had with him,
when did that relationship?
Did she love him?
We do not know.
The Tooheys's sold their house
and moved 6 months after the death of Alice.
Alice had secrets.
She kept secret, that she had secrets.
That changes the way
when you look at somebody,
if they keep things secret.
I think I knew Alice
and her mother knew one another,
and maybe there was one,
nobody knew, maybe.
I found Ray's business card,
stuck in her diary...
on the page with the date July 12, 2005.
Why did you come Alice?
- Can you interpret dreams?
Sometimes. How do you feel,
when you wake up from such dreams.
They make me a little scared.
Alice was about five months before her death
see me.
She had heard me a few times on the radio
and has an appointment.
Take a deep breath and close your eyes.
I want you to imagine, that for
your house is, say if you see it.
Now I want you to go inside the house
through the front door.
Tell me what you see and where you are.
Ray, why did you not tell June,
Alice had met you before?
I wanted nothing to keep her secret,
it had to make the request from Alice
regarding confidentiality.
I could not move.
The living room is straight and then right
and my room is in the rear
of the house toward the kitchen.
You see something unusual, something abnormal?
No, we felt we Ray
could no longer trust.
He kept that information for themselves
and it felt like betrayal.
June and I wanted to help the family
and they wanted that I helped them, I think.
I had not have done,
if they had known.
There was anger,
Mathew would not talk to me.
What I think they hurt the most was
I did not see the death of Alice coming.
Looking back, it is strange,
someone was following us so,
Perhaps he had us just as much
We like him.
Alice came to me,
because she was upset.
She was a person with problems.
I had a dream last night.
I felt cold and wet,
I felt heavy, like I was drugged,
and when I awoke,
did not feel that way.
I felt confused and not
and I began to be afraid.
I wanted to my mother,
to talk to her.
I went to their beds
and when I stood and looked at them,
I was overwhelmed by a deep sadness.
And then hit the sadness to fear.
I stood there paralyzed with fear
and I realized,
they could do nothing for me.
I've never felt so alone.
Everything felt wrong, my body,
how everything looked when I realized,
that something was wrong with me.
I started to cry,
standing at the foot of the bed.
Low Mungo lies in the southwest
New South Wales,
and that was the location of the school camp
Alice was...
from August 2 to August 5 in 2005.
When she came home,
she said it was fun.
I remember it well,
because without mobile home,
we bought her one months earlier had
and her favorite necklace and watch.
Yes, except about, she said not much.
Kim told only one years later,
about what they had filmed on her mobile.
June why you decided to tell it?
If we would not tell
felt that, whether we could hold anything back.
I do not know why...
I do not know why, but...
why not.
Jason told us about the filming,
the girls were at Lake Mungo.
The girls looked so happy
and she looked so lost out.
I worried and became convinced
that something must have happened.
Kate's pictures with her cell phone,
were made later,
when the girls had spread.
There was a picture of Alice,
poorly identified,
bottom of the picture, kneeling under a tree.
Only after repeated viewing of the film,
we realized what she was doing.
She buried something.
You know what happened that night
Alice can be done?
No, I knew,
that she had lost her mobile phone,
and I knew she was upset.
Because that was pretty obvious.
But I did not know why.
She did not say that they saw something,
she really said anything to me.
I took it so seriously.
It was the consistency, we had fun
and therefore it was probably some of region.
It started quite innocently,
Alice had left the group
and walked around on her own.
But it was clear that something was
so they got upset.
And we wanted to try to find out,
what that was.
We saw the pictures of the phone,
something that she had buried.
We had an idea where the tree stood,
by the video.
We did not go during the day,
to dig where the tourists were.
So we decided overnight to go.
June and I started to dig.
After a while she said that she found something,
and she pulled a plastic bag up.
And in that plastic bag sat the chain of Ali,
her ring, her watch and her mobile phone.
Her most precious belongings,
buried at a school camp.
And we did not
why she had done that.
We knew from the video,
that something buried, but not what it was.
The battery is empty.
Are you afraid to die?
Yes, of course I'm afraid to die.
Is not there anyone afraid of?
Would you tell me,
what happens in that dream?
It feels,
if something bad will happen to me.
It feels like something bad has happened.
It has not reached me yet,
but it is coming.
And it comes closer.
And I'm not ready,
I feel that I can not really do anything.
At a certain point
This figure came to her from the darkness.
I recognized the face immediately.
It was the same face of the body,
I identified with the reservoir.
It was Ali's Ali's face and body.
There is absolutely
no rational explanation,
for what they saw through that phone.
I am convinced,
Alice knew that she would die.
I am convinced.
I think the figure at Lake Mungo
a bad omen for her.
The burial of her possessions
was symbolic, it was a ritual.
I was not convinced,
Ali believed that she would die.
She had morbid thoughts, certainly,
Who does not?
She had nightmares that made her upset
and they did consult Ray.
I do not know if anyone can be convinced
he dies.
And the images of Lake Mungo,
Alice explained how would that have?
How they would have explained that?
I think that Ali saw a ghost.
And they must not know,
it was her own mind.
I think they filmed a ghost.
I believe they filmed the future,
who came for her.
We have discovered the Tooheys's,
Ray and what happened at Lake Mungo.
And when we returned home
The house felt different, it was calm.
I think Alice wanted,
that we would know more about her.
She wanted that we might know
who she really was.
Before she could go.
In the weeks and months after Lake Mungo,
we again began a family feel.
It was hard, but it was better
and we are after all a family.
Good to see you.
- You too, come inside.
Ray called unexpectedly
and said that he came through the city
and asked whether it was to come.
There were six months elapsed
and I thought it could not hurt.
We all felt after Lake Mungo
closing a kind of grief.
For Ray is different,
Ray and we came to our own peace.
I found it strange,
that Ali is so abrupt withdrawal,
and we have not helped,
We have not changed.
I think we collectively took the decision,
to continue.
And move was part of this,
the decision to move.
It will be difficult,
to leave the house.
Sometimes I just forget,
they do not come back.
I forget.
LAST JUNE's CONSULT WITH RAY
Close your eyes.
And imagine,
you back to the house.
See?
Enter the house.
I go through the door.
and...
walk down the hall to the room of Alice.
Someone.
I believe that someone running down the hall.
The door is open.
You know who it is?
Want in?
What do you see?
It is my mother.
What she says?
She says nothing.
I think they do not know,
I am here.
Alice is not.
She is not.
What Alice?
Talk to her, she is talking to you?
- She goes away.
She leaves the room.
She's gone.
Open your eyes.
She's gone now.
She leaves the room.
She's gone.
Sync & Sub Jopie123