Aah!
SubFix by divx.NeKryXe.com
...which was at first thought
to be the site
of an old cemetery, but proved
to be a dry pond bed
containing the remains
of s e v eral dead bodies.
A special forensic team under
the dire ction of the county coroner
has been helicoptered
to the site
to dig out the mass grave
and to try to determine
the victims' cause of death.
We'll bring you
more details...
Stop hiding
underneath those things.
Ryan.
What?
Radio reception's shit.
So's our conversation.
You should be washed
in the blood...
If we beat this thing to death,
we're just going to get mad, right?
I don't want to fight
anymore, okay?
Me neither.
What's the point?
Once we get to Florida,
you're off to New York,
then it's Air Britannia
all the way, right?
We're over if we fight,
we're over if we don't fight.
I just need some time
on my own, okay?
I wanted you on this trip
so we could enjoy each other,
we could talk.
You mean talk or tiptoe around
the real issue with chit-chat?
Now you sound exactly like
my father. Great.
Hey, turn it up.
We're getting something.
...checkpoint at the site
of the mass grave
has caused the
first-ever traffic jam
in the history of the interstate.
So if you're
a curious motorist,
be ready to prov e
you're not a killer,
or you may have to spend the night
with a bunch of dead people.
Stay tuned...
Could be worse.
At least we're not as bad off
as those people in that body pit.
- They were murdered.
- Mmm.
My God, they had
to have been.
They didn't jump in with big
grins and bathing suits.
They ought to fry that sucker
if the find him.
Violence is no answer
to violence.
Welcome to the real world,
Michelle.
One of these days,
you're gonna have to live in it,
no matter where you run.
Welcome to
the red light district.
Are there people
in those bags?
Jeez, looks like we've died
and gone to hell.
...as soon as we
get the details...
Let's not stick around
to meet any of them.
Scotty, get your ass down here.
Make sure you're zipped up tight...
The coroner says
they're all toxic.
Roger, I'm coming down.
Wouldn't want to miss
all the poison pigshit.
Oh, shit.
We got more
over here, Scotty.
Well, fuck me running.
Flash it before
you dig it out, okay?
Yeah, right.
Be careful of that crap.
Blood poisoning.
Yeah. Gas gangrene,
the coroner said,
just from touching
this shit.
Oh God.
Oh man, I think
I'm going to barf.
Not in front
of those news assholes.
Far side of those trees.
Should've listened to my old man
and went into real estate.
Looks like a pretty advanced
stage of decomposition.
It's like those body pits
we found up near Dong Tre.
Just counting skulls,
I'd say we got
40 or 50 bodies here.
Jesus.
Oh, man.
This is fucked.
60 or 70 bodies, yes.
It seems that when corpses
lay around like this
for long periods of time
under conditions like these,
they putrefy into
a substance called adip...
Excuse me, ladies
and gentlemen,
we seem to be
experiencing...
Adipocere, you idiot.
You would know that,
Mr. Pre-med.
Creamy breakdown
of body fat.
Basically, if you're
buried right,
your skin turns
into poison Crisco.
I want to get
out of here.
Uh-huh.
We'll get out of here soon.
Here comes ol' deputy dawg.
Coming from?
- L.A.
- Going to?
Deland, Florida.
Something wrong
with the airlines?
No, I'm delivering this car
to my father.
Do you want to see
the papers?
No, that's okay, ma'am.
Just hurry along.
What happened here anyway?
None of your
business, son.
Just move along
and keep moving.
Don't stop for nothing
or nobody.
Okay.
- Didn't want to be on TV anyway.
- Ryan, please.
Now what's
bothering you, Michelle?
I just want to get
this trip over with.
If I drive all night,
I can.
Do you think whoever
did that is still around?
Nah, whoever did that
is long gone.
Sounded like the bodies
were pretty de composed, too.
- You see, what happens is...
- Ryan, please.
Spare me the postmortems.
Looks like we're about here.
- Where?
- The middle of nowhere.
Aah!
Oh my God.
We can't just
leave him here.
I'll take care of it.
- No, no.
- Michelle.
No, it's my fault.
I'll do it.
I'm sorry, little guy.
Ryan...
I can't do it.
Give it to me.
- Thanks for the ride, mister.
- Sure.
- You drive real careful now.
- You bet.
You ladies are always my favorite.
You know that, huh?
¿Que pasa?
Looks like we got
some customers, ladies.
You stay right here.
You first.
See if the bathroom's safe
for human use.
Dream on.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Hi.
I got ya.
I got ya good.
Five bucks. It's only five bucks.
It's a good picture.
What do you say?
3.69 just for you. Give ya... 3.69.
No, we're in a hurry.
Could you just fill it up, please?
You're in
a big hurry, huh?
I'm gonna service you
real good, ma'am.
Don't you
worry about it.
Little California
Daddy's girl, huh?
Bitch says fill it up. I'll fill it
up for you, mascara face.
Make you moan.
Make you moan
real good.
You're gonna like it.
Mm-hmm.
You like me, don't you?
What's the matter,
shortcakes?
Don't you
get uppity on me.
It's all right, ma'am.
You ain't giving the lady
a hard time now, are you?
I ain't bothering
nobody, mister.
Uh-huh.
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
He's a little touched.
Been that way ever since he lost his
job over at the old slaughterhouse.
Sort of the town loony,
you might say.
Well, looks like you had
yourself a little mishap here.
We hit a little animal
on the road.
Oh? Who's we?
A friend and I.
We, uh...
I killed it.
Well, I wouldn't
worry about that.
There's road kill
all over Texas.
Natural order of things.
Besides...
If you were the last thing
I saw before I died,
I'd die a happy man.
Don't you ever
do that to me, bitch.
- Who's this?
- Hi.
You can call me Tex.
Yippee-yi-ay.
Listen, I'd be glad
to buy you both a beer...
whatever you need... if I can catch
a ride as far as Ronesdale.
Sorry, Tex. We're on
a pretty tight schedule today.
That right?
You in a big hurry?
Well, we could
discuss it, I guess.
Okay.
I got to go to the bathroom.
Is it over there?
Yeah, change your life.
Real nice car
you have here.
Thanks.
You know, if you are
headed to Houston,
that road over there
is the quickest way.
It's a straight shot
on the highway.
Well, it used to be,
but this new road here
is a hell of a lot
quicker.
You got a map?
Yeah, I got a map.
I'll show you.
Okay.
Jesus.
See?
Yeah, I see.
"1973."
That road over there
ought to be right there.
Ain't even on this map.
What's the damn difference?
The distance looks the same.
The difference is it ain't
a good idea to be messing around
these back roads at night when
you don't know where you're going.
Look, man...
I'm just trying to get home.
Yeah, I understand
you're trying to get home,
but listen to me...
we can't help you, okay?
I'm sorry.
Where'd that
little weasel get to?
God damn!
What the fuck do you think
you're doing? Get your hands off!
I'm telling you,
I didn't know!
Get the fuck
out of here!
Let's go, you shit heap!
Skinny son of a bitch!
I was only looking at her!
She liked it fine!
Just ask her!
Why don't you just
shut up, stupid?
You shut up, motherfucker.
This is my place!
I'll do whatever I want
here in my place!
What's wrong?
He's having himself
a peek-a-boo party
with you as the star.
I think I'm
going to puke.
Folks, I think you
better get in your car.
- What's wrong?
- Go! Go!
He's got a gun.
Get the hell
out of here!
God's gift, huh?
Start the car!
...god damn it.
You're too good for me, huh?
You're too good for me?!
Get the hell out of here!
I'll take care of him.
- I'll take you down right here.
- Go, go, go! Come on!
You heifer-butt,
I'm gonna fuck you in hell!
You wanna fuck me, baby,
I know you do!
First time you saw me you liked me.
Kind of guy I am!
Jesus Christ!
- Holy fuck, he dusted him!
- What happened? Dusted who?
- The cowboy! He shot the cowboy!
- What?!
Go! Drive faster! Go!
We got to find the cops.
That town.
What if there isn't any town?
Just drive.
- Drive, drive!
- Where?
Where?
Take the cowboy's route.
- What are you talking about?
- Turn right!
Go, go, go!
It's Armageddon, bitchface!
It's Armageddon, you bitch!
Goddamn it.
Trap is sprung now, honey.
Thought there was
a town around here.
That's what he told me.
Would you just slow down?
I'm not stopping
until we find somebody.
We're going to find somebody.
We're far away from that guy.
He's not going to get us.
Would you turn it off?!
Shit!
- Calm down! It's a tire tread!
- Stop yelling at me!
- If you would just listen to me...
- Shh! Listen.
Hear that?
Yeah.
- Where's it coming from?
- I don't know.
- Oh my God.
- It's coming from behind us.
Fuck!
He's gaining on us!
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
Oh my God!
What do they want from us?
- We hit another one.
- No, it hit us.
He threw it at us.
Where the fuck are they?
We blew a tire.
Why are they
doing this to us?
- Ryan.
- This is not happening.
It's happening!
It's happening to us.
We got to change this tire
and get out of here now.
Okay.
Slow and easy...
'cause I'm about
to fuckin' lose my mind!
Get out the jack,
please.
I'll take care of him.
Come on.
Get the light.
That goes this way.
Let me help you.
We got to move it.
I got to put in
a couple lug nuts.
Did you hear that?
Hurry up. I think that truck
is coming back.
Doesn't sound like
a truck to me.
No, it doesn't.
Michelle, I could use a little
light down here, please.
Finish it, Ryan.
Finish it now.
- Michelle.
- I'm serious.
- Hurry up, Ryan.
- Almost there.
Michelle...
I need the light.
- I mean it.
- Almost there.
It's done?
It's going to have to do.
Let's hit it.
Run, Ryan!
- Get in!
- It's locked! It's locked!
Get in the car!
Go, go!
Go, go, go!
It won't go into gear!
Aah! Go!
Get out of here!
We hit him!
He's coming up
the back! Go!
Yes!
What happened?
Did we lose him?
He cut our trunk.
Jesus.
We have to pull over
so I can fix the lug nuts.
- I'm not stopping.
- I got to finish tightening them.
We're going to lose a tire.
You have to pull over
so I can fix it.
I'm not stopping.
Listen to me, I am not
taking any more chances.
Now you pull this car ov er
so I can fix the goddamn tire!
All right.
Jesus!
Damn it.
Totaled.
Oh, Je...
Jesus.
- Aah!
- Take it easy! Take it easy.
You're going to be okay.
Take it easy.
We got
to get her out.
Please help me
get her out.
I'll get her out.
You just get away from the car.
Get away from the car.
We got to keep moving.
We can't stick around here.
Pal...
You can't even
stand around right now.
You just take care.
There's some people
after us...
A guy with a chainsaw.
- You saw what?
- A chainsaw.
Listen, I don't want you
to move right now.
Sounds like you're
just a few quarts...
shy of a full tank,
you know what I mean?
Hold still.
There's a bunch of guys.
And they have guns, too.
Yeah, I know,
and chainsaws.
Militant lumberjacks...
I see them
all the time.
Here, I want you
to take one of these.
I can't believe it.
I been going up in the hills
every weekend for two years.
I never even seen
another car on that road.
I got a survival camp
with a few buddies of mine.
Trying to keep in training for
the big blowup, know what I mean?
Do you hear what
I'm saying, man?
We're being hunted!
Hunted?
Yeah, right.
I hear you, man.
Ryan.
Okay, take it easy.
Take it easy.
You're all right.
Most of this stuff looks
superficial. Just sit up.
There we go. Okay.
Here, I want you
to take one of these.
Okay?
A little water.
Tex... he's still up there.
Who?
Who are you?
- My name's Benny.
- Ow.
I'm the sorry-ass bastard
you almost hit.
We got to move.
They might find us.
- You people are serious.
- Mister, do you see this?
How many?
We don't know.
Two, maybe more.
One's on foot,
and he's got... that.
That's an awfully big saw.
Tex... did you see him
up there?
No, I couldn't see nothing
except your headlights.
He could still be up there.
We got to go check on him.
Wait a minute.
What did you give us?!
Painkillers.
Might make you a little sleepy.
What?
Are you nuts?
- We have got to move.
- Now, just hold it. Hold it.
I can handle this. I'm prepared
for this kind of thing.
Now you guys just relax,
and I'll go find your friend.
No, man.
They're out there.
Look, pal,
it doesn't make it any
different from anywhere else.
Now, I'll go get some
goodies out of the jeep
and find your buddy.
Stay put, okay?
- Wait.
- Wait a minute.
Just sit down
before you fall down.
Looks like you had
a little mishap.
Hey, mister,
I'm glad you came along.
My jeep and this car,
we had a...
You had an accident.
Already know that.
Michelle.
Michelle, come on,
we got to get out of here.
No.
We got to...
So pretty.
So beautiful, the glow.
Technology's your friend,
you know?
Yeah, right.
Listen, mister,
I got some people hurt down here,
and I need your help.
We got the means.
We got the machines.
Look, buddy, I need you
to help me turn my jeep up.
You mean upright?
Yeah, right side up.
Well, what do you think all thes e
fucking flares are for, stupid?
Yeah.
Thanks a lot, buddy.
Just a second.
I got to get something.
Well, rocket, brother.
Ho, now.
You ready to roll,
young woman?
Just 15 seconds.
Almost home, Lucille.
Push comes to shove.
Damn!
Jesus!
Hey, scumbag! Here!
You want me, not him!
Ohh.
- Michelle.
- Hmm?
I can hear him.
We got to get out
of here.
How long
have we been out?
I don't know.
We have to metabolize
this shit out of our system,
or we're going to be down
for the rest of the night.
We got to find the road...
or a house or something.
Anyplace is better than here.
We're sitting ducks out here.
Where's the goddamn sunrise?
This is going to have
to do for now. Come on.
I can't hear him anymore.
Who the hell are you?
What the hell's
going on?
What's going on?!
Hey, girl, I need
some questions answered,
and I need them
answered right now.
Do you understand me?!
Hey.
Oh god.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you
were hurt that bad.
The party's
still cooking.
They're still out there.
You some kind
of soldier or what?
Just on the weekends.
Wrong weapon, wrong war.
They got us a week ago.
I'm the only one left.
Me and my sister.
Sisters.
We go together.
Week, maybe five days ago.
A week?
What the hell are you
still doing here?
Keep your voice down!
They watch the road.
They hunt people.
They really hunt them.
They trap them
and they kill them.
I haven't been able
to get out of the woods.
We just stopped
to help this guy.
We thought
he'd been run over.
Day before yesterday,
I had to eat a fucking rat raw...
and some berries
that tasted...
tasted like they'd been
thrown up once already.
It's just...
I mean... it...
Thanks for what you did.
Thanks.
Where is the road?
I don't know.
I heard some noises.
Maybe it's
that guy Benny.
Nah, he took off
a long time ago.
Who knows how long
we were out.
- Benny!
- Shh!
Thanks.
Benny!
- I got to go.
- They'll be dead soon.
Maybe I can bring
the bad guys out in the light.
You coming?
All right, you stay here.
Don't move.
I'll be right back.
Hold up.
Keep it.
Thanks.
Eee!
Nice neighborhood.
Damn.
- Come on.
- Aah! Aah!
Oh my God.
Ryan.
Ryan!
Go! Get the fuck out of here!
Go! Get out of here!
Get out of here!
Fuck!
No! God!
Please, no!
Ohh!
Hello?
Hello?!
Wait, wait.
Hey.
It's all right.
I'm not going
to hurt you.
What's your name?
This is Sally.
Owww!
Yakkety-yak,
don't talk back.
Girls, sorry to butt in,
but looks like you had yours elf
another little mishap.
You know, you're late.
Hmm?
Boy, the y just get
dumber and dumber.
Don't they?
No!
I ain't no runt
of the litter,
and I'll prove it
to you one day.
What, you think I'm some sort
of a piece of shit?
There's gonna come a time
when you're going to find out
just what kind of human being I am.
I'm a human being.
Bone patrol
for stupid fuckface, eh?
I'll show you
motherfuckers.
That's the way it is.
Aah!
So...
how you like Texas?
More little nails
if you don't stay put.
Why are you doing this?
Be cause if you don't poke 'em,
then they don't leak.
And if they don't leak,
we can't feed Grandpa.
Silly.
Ruckus, ruckus.
My nap is just a goner.
I certainly hope you children
are pleased with yourselves.
Where's Junior?
He's mopping up, Mama.
That's what you
always say.
Mopping up,
which means you ain't
caught 'em all yet,
just like last time.
Please.
What have we done?
Can't you stop this?
You best shut on up,
or I'll do your tongue first.
That's right.
Best not to get
Mama's dander up.
Brought home
the bacon, Mama.
Come on, Tex.
Give me a hand here.
Pull him around.
Get that trap off.
Fancy sneakers.
All right now...
Okay, don't bruise him.
Pretty good size one,
ain't he?
Yeah, he's a keeper.
We got some dark meat
coming in, too, Mama.
Junior'll be trotting it
in any minute.
If he minds.
Junior's been getting
out of hand lately,
but I got
a present for him.
I got a fine present, going
to keep him in line, yes, sir.
He liked that last
present you got him...
that electronic
thingumajig.
Of course he did.
That's progress, boy.
Technology is our friend.
He might even
learn something.
Ain't that right,
Mama?
What do you think
of our little lady?
Uncertain.
She looks to me like
she might go
all screamy on us, Eddie.
I wish you'd
call me Tex.
I told you.
Oh, I'm sorry, boy.
God damn it, I'm sorry.
Say, how'd you like
to do us the honor
of plugging
that whore up?
Yes, sir.
Hey, Tink,
this one's still kicking.
Yippee-yi-ay.
Hey, if you need anything...
just twitch.
Well, I'm going to go
get Junior's present.
Say, Tex, you want
to give me a hand?
That thing's
so damn heavy.
Don't even think of leaving.
Not before dinner.
Thank you.
? Clean that trap out, Fred?
? Clean it good?
? So you motherfuckers?
? Don't tell me
what I should do.?
Take your little
motherfucking face, Tex,
and ram it up your butt
is what I'm going to do.
It's an eye for an eye,
it's a tooth for a tooth,
it's a hand for a hand,
and an arm for an arm.
What you got in here,
Santa Claus?
I see something.
You betcha.
Somebody's little puppy dog,
aren't you, motherfucker?
Sweet.
You just tell him
what to do he does it.
Little Alfredo does this,
he does that.
'Cause Alfredo's
a stupid motherfucker, huh?
Yeah, well
fuck you!
He cleans,
and he does housework.
Here we got
a little pretty one, yeah.
I liked you a long time ago,
you know that.
Hey, pretty one.
We had some good times,
didn't we?
We don't have
good times no more.
You remind me of my last girl,
down in Tupelo.
You're gonna go down below.
Is it soupy et?
Hey, Junior.
Got something special
for you.
Tink did it.
Chromes every damn thing.
You like it, don't you?
Well, looks like
you just got a pres ent
for a job
you didn't finish.
You lost the darky,
didn't you?
Well, didn't you?
Oh, fine.
Another toy.
Well, you got to learn.
I'll tell you one damn thing,
by God if...
Junior.
Junior,
haven't I told you...
Wait, Mama.
Wait.
Okay, okay!
It's okay, now.
It's okay.
Hey, now.
Hey!
Now, now,
don't you fret.
What do you think?
Do you want to go
for a head shot or what?
Huh?
Let me see a smile.
- Let's do it.
- All right.
Why don't you
go and do your lessons?
And get that thing off
my cutting board.
Who's been dinkin'
around in this thing?
Trap's sprung.
Somebody's on the loose.
That's for sure.
Shh!
This makes
a very loud bang
and an awfully
big hole.
Do I know you?
Shut up and move it!
Now I am very scared
of guns, mister,
so please do not
point that at my face.
- How many?
- How many what, O.J.?
How many bent, sick fucks
like you are there out here?
Hey, baby, I only got one thing to
say to you. You know what that is?
I don't like
the tone of your voice.
What the hell's
wrong with you?
What is this?
Booby traps,
camo netting...
What are you people
doing out here?
Big surprise.
Fuck you, mister!
One down.
Please choose
an activity.
What is it?
F- o-o-d.
No, try again.
What kind of
sick shit is this?
F- o-o-d.
No, try again.
Always had a problem with this
hit to the head business...
till Tink here
genius ed up a new way.
No! Please don't!
Not again!
You promised.
The next one was mine!
Let me do it!
I don't see why not.
No!
All right, darling.
Go ahead.
Hell, she's old enough.
You ready, honey?
Hold Sally.
Okay.
Remember what I told you.
Take this one here.
You have to count
one, two...
three.
All right.
I will.
Grab on.
When I tell you.
You ready?
One...
two...
three!
Good shot!
Good shot.
Go get it.
Look here, Mama.
Colored drawers.
California.
Honey, you go get
washed up for supper now.
We get this 'un skinned,
dress ed out,
we'll have enough
sowbelly for a while.
Yeah, I guess
that's right, huh?
All we need now is
a good mess of greens.
Appears we get
to wait a spell on you.
Maybe we could, uh...
Let Junior play some.
He does make the sweetest
damn babies, you know.
Junior likes them
private parts.
We knows what to do
with them parts.
You got that right, Mama.
Cut my own out
years back.
I did.
Took care
of Papa's, too.
It'll be your turn soon,
little gal.
Hey, Tex, come help me
skin this 'un.
All righty.
Junior.
Go, Junior!
Motherfucker!
Get down!
Mama!
Aah!
Tink!
Yeah!
Get the bitch!
She stuck me!
Bitch!
Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey!
H e y, it's me!
It's me!
- Let's go!
- Run, run!
Go!
Shit!
Now what?
Great!
Go towards the trees.
Towards the trees! Go!
Okay, come on.
Shit!
Okay. All right.
You and me then, huh?
You sick... fucker!
Come on!
Fuck the flesh!
Give me steel!
Now damn it, boy...
go get the meat!
Get out
the big skillet.
I'll be in hell
for breakfast.
Son of a bi... tch.
Woo-eee!
Motherfucker!
Come on, sweetheart.
Let's see
what you got.
What the fuck is wrong
with you people?
Why don't you
leave us alone?
- We're hungry.
- You ever heard of pizza?!
I like liver.
And onions.
And pain!
- Come on!
- Whack, whack.
Time for dinner!
You're toast, fuck!
Yeah.
You son of a bitch.
Aah!
Fuck! Come on.
Benny!
Get him!
Get him, Benny!
Benny!
Yeah!
Here, take it!
Yes!
Go, Benny!
Benny!
Aah!
No!
Sorry...
little... guy.
little...
guy!
Sorry...
little...
guy!
No.
No, no...
Hey, hey, it's me!
It's me. It's Benny.
Let's get out of here.
You...
You made it!
Of course I made it.
Hey, we made it.
We made it!
Come on, let's get
out of here.
Come on.
Okay.
It's knock-knock time
in Lubbock, and I'm back!
You steal Daddy's car,
then you steal my car.
I'm gonna get ya, cut ya up.
You cheated on me.
Had to go out
with four-eyes, huh?!
Old four-eyes, eh?
You're two little
heifer-butts, huh?
Where are you?
Huh? Huh? Where are you?!
- No!
- Face it...
You flirtin' more
and you enjoyin' it less.
That's what they do
in California.
I never been with
a California girl.
I like that skin
of yours.
- Get away!
- Hey, hey!
Hey, you fuck!
I hate when this
happens, you know.
Okay, okay, now.
I guess this kills our chance
for dinner on Saturday night?
Shut up.
What are the chances
of a brainless bitch like you
knowing how to use
that thing, hmm?
Pretty goddamn good,
you backwoods motherfucker!
There's road kill
all over Texas.
You got that right.
Ha
Headin' for the southland
Down Texas way
Ready for the lightnin'
With a chainsaw blade
Here's your invitation
To come join Leatherface
It's his addiction
To keep you face to face
Screamin' in the darkness
As they nail you down
Swingin' the hammer
No one hears a sound
Here's your invitation
To come join Leatherface
It's his addiction
To keep you face to face
You're just a prisoner
In his game of chance
Another referee
For the devil's dance
Huh!
Come across the cosmos
Chainsaw running wild
Come into the heavens
For the final time
Here's your invitation
- To come join Leatherface
- Leatherface
It's his addiction
- To keep you face to face
- Face to Face
Here's your invitation
- To come join Leatherface
- Leatherface
It's his addiction
To keep you
Face to face
Leatherface
Leatherface.