"Welcome to Inveree"
Fuck!
Oh fuck, shit!
From the car off!
No, No, no, no, damn it,
Please not another,
Where did he go?
Who then?
The man you've just run over,
But apparently I did not,
And so there is no reason,
arrest me,
This is probably my lucky night,
-Meinst You?
Listen, I'm damn rights,
Not so hard! Tell Just,
that you would like to dominate,
then we take a room,
You know, handcuffs are at
the police here rather unusual,
Oh really? As a girl, I
a soft spot for wristbands,
"Missing"
Sergeant MacReady '?
They come with gifts?
Yes, My mother taught me,
never show up empty-handed,
Well that's all well before going on,
The young Caesar is one of our
Regular customers, do not you, boy?
Yes, but this is bullshit, Jim,
I did not do anything, I swear,
For you, Sergeant MacReady, boy,
And I am the way,
Constable Rachel Heggie,
But of course, They seem
yes to be quite eagerly,
The only question is, why you
are then stranded here?
We all have to start somewhere,
-Yes, And believe me,
from here it can only go up,
I have told you before,
Pass on what you say,
-Large God!
Also for you, do not take that tone, Thank You,
There are a few croutons for you here,
-Okay,
Then we want you times
message in the guestbook,
Yes!
Fuck! -I Am coming!
Still -Wait, I also equal!
Oh Man ,,,
I swear,
My Joanne was never so tight
even before she got the kids,
-The Makes the pelvic floor muscles, sweetheart,
Ready for another round? '
Oh fuck, give me a minute,
Lightweight,
Bitch,
How did you just call me?
-You Heard,
Bitch,
Mother's again,
So then:Francis Sargison,
also known as Caesar,
Again a joyride, yes?
-But This time without fun,
And your driver's license?
He almost killed someone,
Ah, no, I have not,
Where is the victim?
-Good That you ask, Caesar,
That's what I'll find out
while you strip,
Hop hop!
Mundie ,,, come on down!
I think we'd better back,
Come on,
You animal!
Ah, it goes straight to the point,
Let the prelude from simple?
This will now be under profiling, Sarge,
I'm prejudiced here,
If you were part of a minority,
Who would you maybe interested in,
Here is the squad leader,
Are you there, people?
Warnock? Mundie?
Present, Sarge, Loud and clear,
Here someone wants to say "hello",
Hi folks, here speaks
Constable Rachel Heggie,
Please keep your eyes open
for a man - White,
1 meter 80, beard and
likely to be injured, Thank you!
We should also contact the local
Hospitals check,
"Prisoner file"
"Date of Birth:05/10/1957
Occupation:Teacher "
"Chronicle:Domestic violence currently
Domestic violence - 07,14,2014 "
Sir?
Sergeant MacReady '?
Seriously, Constable, you are sure
They form is not an all?
There was blood on the headlights, sir,
Well no,
I would like to have the car checked,
if we had a victim, Is that so?
I set up shop under control,
In most cases, it is quiet here,
What do you mean?
-How They say:
Without victim no crime,
I told you,
I've told you,
Oh God,
Sorry, what was that? '
Sierra One, what exactly do you mean by
"White"? Shall we now have a
Search fucking snowman?
Flap! Makes your job and find him,
Yes, sir, Sarge, We keep our eyes open,
It's just ,,,
sounds as fun to
can be as suspect their testimony,
That's enough!
Please bring us even with a coffee,
We sit on dry land,
Do you want anything?
Except that confidential documents
be treated as such?
No,
Yeah, good luck with that,
Even at the local nail salon
hear less gossip than here,
Hello?
Can I smoke a lot
before I get involved?
Here's smoking ban,
-Is This a joke?
Your room, sir,
Have fun with the free
Skid marks on the pillow,
I had half a box
Cigarettes when I came here,
That was all counted accurately,
-Now Tell me you suspect
that we steal your butts,
He assumed it,
He will be assumed
you steal his butts,
A spokesman assumed
a listener suspected,
The one place where it is felt
To be sure - and there he is,
Something you have to swallow, Caesar,
Is nice if you have more time than
than at school want to spend,
We thought we doing you a favor
and bring the school to you,
Why is he here?
Because he just like his women
likes his whiskey - 12 Years Old?
Constable Heggie, Mr, Beswick,
You complain yet
constantly about class sizes,
This is our way to help
with some private lessons,
That's it, right? He is a fanatic,
I knew it, Dirty pervert,
Go back, away from the door,
-How's It twice with "please", bitch?
What the hell? That's assault,
Man, fuck brutality!
Just do it,
what is said to you, bitch,
Okay, all right,
You saw that, right?
You are my witness,
She was trying to break my arm,
-I Have not seen anything,
Oh come on, wake up!
If we approach this correctly,
we are still before the last
Round out here,
You simply have to say,
what you have seen,
I'll sue you, and this
Be photographed scratches,
Sometimes, Francis,
need to be disciplined people,
This preserves the natural order,
Is that what you did? '
I have read the file,
Pretty dirty,
how to maintain order, right?
Well, every story has two sides,
-sure, Of course,
Yours is certainly true maudlin,
So one, my boy, is commonly
known as a wire brush,
The salvage people do not respond,
I need to call a tow truck later,
Provoke getting your prisoner?
In fact, I do not even smoke,
Types such as Caesar come with
Authority not well understood,
So I use a number
different methods,
And cell 4?
He seems pretty convinced of
Ralph?
This man needs a sandbag,
His wife is for all
certainly not suitable,
He is also a regular guest here?
-You Can set the clock after,
And I guarantee that it tomorrow
early the charges will drop,
Unfortunately, a widespread problem,
If there is abuse in relationships,
Oh, that's so, Constable?
The little girl,
the back, came here,
The world is full of evil,
That goes double for police stations,
Hey, hey, calm, buddy, This way,
Hey, Sarge? We found him,
Ah, you must be the new one,
Mundie,
We've known,
I ,,, just kidding, you know?
Good work, Mundie,
Heggie? Warnock,
Is that him? 1 meter 80, beard,
pretty spaced out,
Yes, he is,
They are straight before
run a car, what?
He has a blow off in any case,
When we found him, he wandered around,
He was right in front of us,
and then just go away,
Probably due to the adrenaline,
-Yes, But adrenaline decreases,
Better call to Dr, Hume,
His number is on the wall,
What is your name, sir?
Cosy chat is
not with him, Sarge,
Hi, I'm calling from the police station,
We have an injured person here
the medical needs help,
Your name, my friend?
Honestly, I think,
from having a bit of a wheel, boss,
It looks like a
From concussion,
Thank You,
-What's Your name?
And the first in your day,
I tell you so that uniform does it,
It thus seems women
Uniform to like what?
Looks like,
To me it's better if they only
Handcuffs and the hat wearing,
but anyway ,,,
Do I have to tie you about?
Space, boy,
Now let us all Medical Play, yes?
Where is he?
To the patient, please click here along, Doctor,
Its injuries seem
just to be on the outside,
No evidence of toxicity,
So he has a clear head?
He definitely has something about him,
So I would say "yes",
His silence could be voluntary,
Then he comes over night in a cell,
Why that? His refusal to talk about?
Well then we just vagrancy,
In addition, he is tonight
went before a car, right?
Until you his identity
have found
it is probably best if he stays here,
Have you found a name, Constable?
No, No wallet, no ID,
no phone, no key,
Only this book, which is full of names,
Just what is his?
If any, Maybe he just
only the phonebook depreciated,
There is something compulsive,
There are small icons, small characters,
It must have a meaning for him,
I told you so,
the guy has a Hau away,
Since you can sometimes nice
determine Heggie, right?
Find out! Try it
times during the pat mills,
Maybe even a missing security wing
his diarist,
So I got him safely
never seen before,
What is unusual,
in such a small town here,
And damn lifeless it is,
I beg your pardon? What did he just say?
Doctor Hume?
He knows it,
-What Does he know?
Everything,
What does he know, Duncan?
What does he know?
So, so, Doctor Hume,
He's here to view our
To cure diseases,
What is it, Doctor? Are you here,
to investigate my wrist?
Go back cushion Hume,
-From Moral superiority
You are here below all
far away, Doctor,
But we all make mistakes, right?
Take care of your stuff, Beswick,
-Oh, I will, if he does it well,
But if I can not stand one
then a hypocrite,
How do you explain your
Presence tonight?
An whopping Swatter for Mr, Beswick!
-And What brings you this? '
I could watch,
And now have a cool little
Story for all my friends,
Threaten you about me, Francis?
-I Name is Caesar,
And no, I open
only the discussion,
what my silence you and the
good doctor could be whom,
You know, maybe I am
not literate,
Mr, Beswick, but I ,,,
-You Are not smart, Caesar,
You're an idiot,
So just sit back,
Keep your mouth shut
and listen to flush out the wildlife,
She used it for a can of cider and
made a thumb in the ass with everyone,
The evolutionary ladder climbs up
not saying anything, boy?
Small, sticky fingers,
So, according to our records
and your fingerprints
Are you Alexander Monroe from Port Glasgow,
And you are died in 1983,
In a fire
at the age of 79 years,
I must say you look healthy from, Al,
The advantage of a clear conscience,
And this
is applied modern policing,
Technology, completely unreliable,
But tonight we
proceed according to the old school,
Keep it up, then make
we really "perhaps,
Okay,
Let's forget for a minute
who you are, and ask why,
For example, why did you
Doctor Hume attacked?
Because the clock is ticking and midnight approaches,
He said, "you know it,"
What exactly do you know?
That the price of our
Sins are paid for with blood,
And I ,,,
"That I must be unsteady on earth,"
"And that slay me,
whoever finds me, "
I meant,
One common feature,
We are both Christians,
-Only That you have more to
Old Testament tend, right?
The blood and vengeance,
The sweat
and the sperm,
I can smell it,
I must say that I know
not from the Sunday School,
I just do not - but I
am also exited,
So do not believe in God?
-That I did not say that,
But I would like damn
some say talk to him,
It is not for us,
after asking why,
No! Because we can do here
what we want, right?
Create it away,
Get him down!
Coffins, I do not think so ,,,
Right Away!
Oh wonderful! I just wanted to
ask up to a round of tea,
Can it be that I'm above a
Pack of chocolate biscuits've seen?
Listen, should tomorrow morning
You have to be out here, okay?
Mundie?
You damned ,,,
Good God, are you okay?
So who's the first?
Hey, Hey, are you okay?
-Let It!
It was nothing, Leave me alone!
This "we have two girls
hold together number you can bend,
You and I are not friends,
We are nothing,
Still busy with Mrs, Hume, Sarge,
Sarge?
It is now more than
an hour on the phone,
The whole world could
Expert ability of these women testify,
Driving times out and take with Jen,
"Her husband is in prison"
is personally getting better,
I think it is better,
if you do tell her, Sarge,
I need to do some research here,
Let's see if I can not figure out
who our top crafty friend really is,
Rachel,
You stay here and make
for us patrols,
Drink tea,
answer the phone,
bake a cake,
Make just stay out of trouble, okay?
-Sir, Do you really think it's smart,
a single police officer with four
To let prisoners alone?
As long as you do not all
for a finger food buffet
and a few rounds Bridge let out,
I mean even know this was possible,
I am aware that you think, we live
here all in a fucking cookie jar,
But the fact is that you made me a
very good reason have been allocated,
I say this only once
for the cheap seats:
If you want to survive the probationary period,
you will learn to sit still,
To curb your temper
and to keep your damn mouth,
Got it?
25  years, I have never seen such a
blatant insubordination experienced,
"Missing"
We find that here is very convenient -
curb to the temperament,
Hilarious,
The Sarge has been right,
You have at your social
Skills to work,
I will definitely
take with you lessons,
Just call your friend on,
Thank you, I can do without it,
Okay, well then have fun
with the crossword puzzle,
On the one bites from the teeth,
Night,
I am very sure that you
provide a few more eggs,
I do not want my French
Waive toast, not because of you,
Who knows, maybe we are
tomorrow morning no longer here,
Sure, of course, Have a
Escape plan or something?
I thought you were the one
digging the tunnel,
I decorate just my cell, man,
Maybe you should learn first time,
how do you spell that, Francis,
But that would mean that I time
spend in school - with you,
And yet we're stuck here together firmly,
in the midst of offenders,
Right there you are also out -
Mr, Beswick,
How do you know my name?
What do you think?
"David Brundridge (the acid bath killer):
deceased "
"Bryan Heffington (the whale):
Wait until morning,
Wait until you forgive you again,
But no, that's not get it,
Not this time,
All the things you do, your punches,
The uterus, the
You have chosen,
the loss you have caused,
They think it's about control?
Do not talk to me,
That's not true,
There is a lack of control,
So much Situated Stautes, So much anger ,,,,
Why should not I be angry?
-just Why?
Who is it? To whom are
You really angry?
I know of no beating husband,
who does not actually
want to beat yourself,
Or was it your unborn child?
"Rodhe Kilpatrick (fishing home):
deceased "
"Deceased - dead - died"
Exactly,
think about it,
Think about it,
what you have done,
Because ,,, who is she?
Who is your wife?
-My Better half,
The only thing that builds me
which can withstand me that ,,,
loves me in spite of what I am,
Good Boy,
But who is it?
Who is it?
Who do I hate?
What the hell have I done?
It is you,
All her little ass holes,
Granted, you do not often right, but
here you are again wrong,
Mr, Beswick must try harder!
I stand there every day
and humiliate me for you,
and you did not even have enough
Emerge decency,
Well, as you want,
Sierra One of operational control, over,
I hear,
Here's Warnock,
We are the house of Hume,
burns No light, no one is home,
but the front door is open,
Okay, so a break?
We go inside and check it once,
Okay, Thank you for having me
keep up to date,
You're new, but we already know,
how pedantic you are with the protocol,
What's this?
-Seid You okay? ' What is what?
Shit, damn it, man! Help!
Holy Shit! Go ,,, go back!
Come on! Please, please, please help!
Come on, please!
Fuck!
,to Hell is going on here?
-Damn Again you can see him in!
For God's sake,
No, no, no, do not open,
he deceives only before!
Caesar, shut up!
No, no, shit!
I swear, he's trying to kill me!
Fuck,
Let me out!
Hello? Mrs, Hume?
This is the police,
Mission Control, over,
No Reply,
-Let The damn channel open,
I do not like that,
real funny here,
Hello
Hello? Someone at home?
I can help him,
Oh, what ,,,
Do you smell that?
Oh my god!
Do you really want for the death
be a man responsible?
If he still lives, I can save him,
But you need to let me out,
They behave,
or I will destroy them,
Fuck! Oh God, damn it! What the hell?
I know it,
I've seen who you are,
So there is a in each class,
I assume he means troublemaker,
You guys can not let him lie,
This is not that you can not do that!
Here's Sergeant Jim MacReady,
Please record your message after ,,,
Fuck!
We do not,
Take his legs!
Who is he? You can tell me,
How does he know it? '