We should have talked to the boatyard.
You don't wanna talk here.
I'm not falling over
to talk about it much anywhere, jack.
How much do you know?
- Not much.
The Birmingham one
was in the papers over a month ago,
and Atlanta was all over TV.
Did you think about giving me a call?
- No. - why not?
I quit, remember?
You look alright now.
I am alright.
If you can't look anymore,
I understand.
Don't play games with me!
If I really didn't need you,
I wouldn't ask.
This guy's on a lunar cycle.
I have three weeks till full moon.
We have a better chance
if you help me.
I'll think about it.
Stay and eat.
Think it'll keep them out, dad?
- Yep.
How many turtle's eggs are in here?
- In this hatchery?
40 or 50 of 'em.
Crabs get most of them, huh?
- Yeah, but not now.
These are all gonna make it.
What about the dogs?
No. That's why
we buried the wire down in the sand.
I need more staples, pal.
You're supposed to be his friend.
Why didn't you leave him alone?
If he decides to do it, molly,
I’ll keep him
as far away from it as I can.
We've got it pretty good.
- More than good.
All that happened before
lets you know that.
If I went back,
I’d only look at the evidence.
I wouldn't get involved.
He'd never even see me.
If they find him,
they'll have to take him down.
What do you think?
You've already decided
and you're not really asking.
If I were asking?
Stay here with me.
Me and Kevin.
That's selfish and I know it.
I'll come inside with you
and show you around.
Mr. Crawford said maybe you want
to be alone. - That's right.
There's a VCR in your hotel room.
There's home movies
of both families on half inch VHS.
Thanks.
Intruder entered through kitchen door.
Used a glass cutter on a suction cup.
Entry was skilful.
All prints are smooth gloves.
Blond hair, strong.
Size 12 shoe imprint.
Blood ab positive, from saliva
on glass from the suction cup.
Why did he leave saliva on the glass?
It was hot that night,
so it must have felt
cool in the house.
Intruder cut Charles Leeds’s throat
then shot Mrs. Leeds.
Bullet lodged in her lumbar spine,
but she died of strangulation.
Moderate elevation of serotonin and
an increase in histamine indicate she
lived for 5 minutes after the shot.
All other injuries are post-mortem.
Direction of the
blood stains on the wall
indicate arterial spray.
Leeds tried to fight because intruder
moved towards the children's room.
Blood stains on west wall
in master bedroom and sliding marks
on hall carpet remain unexplained,
as does superficial ligature mark
around Mr. Leeds' chest.
Also believed post-mortem.
What did the killer
do with them after they were dead?
Hi. This is Valerie Leeds.
I can't speak right now,
but if you leave a message after the
beep, I’ll get right back.
290th floor.
Going up.
When they were dead,
he smashed the mirrors and
selected pieces for use on Mrs. Leeds.
Killing Mr. Leeds and the children
would take less than a minute.
Mrs. Leeds' injuries were
post-mortem 4 or 5 minutes later.
What did he do in the interval?
He smeared blood stains on the wall.
Hello?
- Molly?
Will, is that you?
- Yeah, honey.
Look, I’ll call you tomorrow.
Go back to sleep.
I love you.
- I love you too, baby.
What are you dreaming?
That's something you can't afford
for me to know about.
God, she's lovely, isn't she?
It was maddening to touch her
with rubber gloves on, wasn't it?
They found talcum powder on her leg,
but there wasn't any in the bathroom.
It came out of a rubber glove
as you pulled it off to touch her.
You took off your gloves
to touch her, didn't you?
You touched her with your bare hands
and then you put your gloves back on!
But while your gloves were off,
did you open all their eyes
so they could see you?
Hallo?
- Jack, this is graham.
Is price still in latent prints?
- Yeah, the single print index.
What have you got?
- Get him to Atlanta.
Atlanta p. D. Dusted everything and
they're good. - Not as good as price.
I'll send him tomorrow.
What do you want him to do?
Dust Mrs. Leeds' finger and toenails
and the corneas of all their eyes.
I think he took off his gloves.
The subject's teeth look like this.
These were reconstructed
from the bite mark impressions we took
from Mrs. Leeds and the jacobi woman.
He has pegged lateral incisors,
that's these teeth here and here.
Vice and narcotics, you take the
k-y cowboys and the leather bars.
Marcus, Whitman heads up at the
funeral. The rest, see the sheet.
One more thing.
I've heard officers call
this killer the 'tooth fairy'.
Well, I don't wanna hear that
in public or see it in memoranda!
That's it.
I know a burglar's gonna fence
what he stole for cash money.
I know his motive,
so I go to work on fences.
This guy, we don't have a motive.
None of us have shit and we know it.
It's in his dreams.
His motive?
- Yeah.
His act fuels his fantasy.
Which is?
- I don't know.
Commissioner says you're the one
who got Garrett Jacob Hobbes
and then dr. Lecktor 3 years ago?
- Lecktor killed 90 people, didn't he?
Nine that we know of.
Two didn't die.
I heard he cut you pretty good.
What about the dog?
It's at the vet's.
It has puncture wound.
The Jacobis had a cat.
That's right.
We found the litter box,
but not the cat.
Give Birmingham p. D. A methane probe
out of Washington.
Have them cover the backyard.
Maybe the cat's buried there.
Yeah?
- This is Jimmie price, fbi.
Let me put you on the speaker.
- Who am I talking to?
Jack Crawford
and will graham.
I got a partial print,
probably a thumb.
And a fragment of a palm off the
nail of Mrs. Leeds' left big toe.
Thumb print came off
the oldest kid's left eye.
Can we make an identification off it?
- Maybe if he's in my index.
Wanna work on these in the dark room.
I'll fax the prints this afternoon.
- Thanks.
If we get lucky with that print...
if Jimmie can find him in the index.
- Hey, graham!
Whatta you say?
It's me, Lounds, from the "tattler".
I did the Lecktor paperback.
When did they call you in?
I'm buying lunch, alright?
- Give it a rest!
I'm doing my job.
How does he compare to Lecktor?
What does he do to them?
How does he do 'em, will?
Keep the fuck away from me!
- Will, will!
Son-of-a-bitch snuck into the hospital
while I was sedated and took pictures.
I know.
- Don't expect too much from me.
We only got three weeks left.
- You think I’m just gonna see him?
That's Houdini!
The tooth fairy's gonna go on till
we get smart or lucky. He won't stop.
Why?
He's got a taste for it.
- You do know something about him.
Not enough.
I'll go see Lecktor tomorrow.
Why?
Recover the mind set.
That's the same atrocious aftershave
you wore in court 3 years ago.
I keep getting it for Christmas.
Did you get my card?
- I got it, thank you.
How is officer Stuart?
Fine.
- Emotional problems, I hear.
Do you have any problems, will?
- No.
No, of course you don't.
I'm glad you came.
My callers are usually psychologists
from cornfield universities.
Second-raters, the lot.
Dr. Bloom showed me your article
on surgical addiction. - And?
Very interesting, even to a layman.
I want you to help me, dr. Lecktor.
- I thought so.
It's about Atlanta and Birmingham.
- Yes? - you read about it?
In the papers.
I don't tear out the articles.
I wouldn't want them to think
I was dwelling on anything morbid.
You want to know
how he's choosing them.
Any ideas?
- Why should I tell you?
You get to see the file.
There's another reason. - Pray tell.
You might be curious to see
if you're smarter.
Smarter than you,
since you caught me?
I know I’m not smart.
- Then how did you catch me?
Your disadvantages.
- What disadvantages?
You're insane.
You're very tanned, will.
Your hands are rough.
Not cop's hands any more.
And that shaving lotion
is from a child?
With a ship on the bottle?
Don't think appeals to my
intellectual vanity will work.
I don't think that.
You'll do it or you won't.
Dr. Bloom's working on it.
He's the best.
Have you got the file?
- Yes. - pictures? - yes.
Let me have them and I’ll consider it.
- No.
Dream much, will?
Goodbye, dr. Lecktor.
You haven't threatened
to take away my books yet.
Let me have the file
and I’ll tell you what I think.
This is a very shy boy.
What were the yards like?
- Big, fences, hedges. Why?
Because,
if he imagines he has a relationship
with the moon, he'll go look outside.
Ever seen blood in the moonlight?
It appears quite black.
If one were nude,
it would be better to have privacy.
Interesting.
No. You thought of it before.
- I considered it.
You wanted to look at me.
To get the scent back.
- I want your opinion.
I don't have one now.
- When you do, I want to hear it.
Can I keep this?
- Haven't decided. - I’ll study them.
Also any other files.
You can call me.
For calls to my lawyer I get a phone.
Will you leave me your home number?
No.
Do you know how you caught me?
There's a number on the file.
- Do you know how you caught me?
You caught me, will,
because we're just alike.
You want the scent,
smell yourself!
Gotcha!
Get up and face the wall.
Don't turn around,
or I’ll mace you in the face.
Thank you so much.
I'll call when I’m finished.
You ready for your call?
- Yes, thank you.
Paltrow, Christiansen and Golub,
law offices.
I'm sorry, I misdialed.
Thank you for using AT&T.
This is operator 24.
Operator,
I don't have the use of my arms.
Would you dial a number for me?
- Certainly. What's the number?
Area code 3-0-1.
5-5-5-6-6-2-4.
University of Chicago, department of
psychiatry. - Dr. Bloom, please.
I'll connect you with his office.
What's his secretary's name?
- Martha king. Just a moment.
Martha king's desk.
- Hi, Martha.
Martha doesn't come in nights.
Maybe you can help me.
This is Bob Greer.
Dr. Bloom asked me to send
a paper to someone,
but I never got the address or number.
- She'll be in in the morning.
I've got to catch the federal express.
Could you pull it out of her rolodex?
I don't see a rolodex.
- I bet she has a call caddy.
Yeah.
- Well point right on down to g.
Alright.
- The last name is graham.
The man the book is for.
Mr. Will graham.
Federal bureau of investigation,
10th and Pennsylvania, Washington d. C.
I bet his home address is there too.
3680 Desoto highway, Captiva, Florida.
Thank you very much.
Finished!
Mommy!
- Oh my gosh! Lt's ok. Stewardess?
There's a couple down from Duluth,
we were talking about mortgages.
And...
I figure,
you're gonna unload this turkey.
Well,
then the squad car rolls up,
they start asking questions,
the whole grand tour:
Who was lying where and what.
Terrific.
So they get in their sedan
and get the hell out of here.
Any single men ask to see the house?
No-one asked me.
You cut the branch so you could see.
Then you passed the time whittling
and dreaming.
When night came,
you saw them behind bright windows.
You watched the shades go down,
saw the lights go out one by one.
Then you went in to 'em,
Didn’t ya?
Didn't you, son-of-a-bitch?
You watched them all day long!
That's why houses with big yards.
I need the firearms and toolmarks
section on the severed branch.
I need bowman to fall on this carving.
- Is it weird?
The mark? Yeah.
If documents can't do it, Langley can.
- Did price get an identification?
No, not yet.
It's a hand search.
Have you seen the "tattler"?
It's not on my reading list.
- Yeah, well,
you're all over the front page.
Who the hell was it, Lounds?
- Who else?
Goddammit, jack!
I promised molly.
Come in!
- Dr. Chilton? - yes?
On cleaning out dr. Lecktor's cell,
he hid something in a book.
We dug around.
- Is that it? Put it down.
Has anyone seen this except you?
- No.
Crawford's office.
- This is Chilton. Mr. Graham please!
He's not here. Mr. Crawford
is on the line with him now.
Will you tell him this is very, very
urgent. I’ll hold on.
Dr. Chilton, it's Crawford.
Graham is on the line, too.
I have two pieces of a note
that appears to be from
the murderer in Atlanta.
Where did you get it?
- Hidden in a book in Lecktor’s cell.
Don't touch the note. Read it to us!
- It's on toilet tissue.
"Dear dr. Lecktor,
I am delighted that
you've taken an interest in me.
You alone can understand
what I am becoming.
You know the people I used to help me
are only elements undergoing change
to fuel the radiance
of what I am becoming. Just
as the source of light is burning.
My collection of your press clippings
is as absurd as are mine.
The "tooth fairy".
What could be more inappropriate?
Investigator graham interests me.
Very purposeful-looking.
I hope we can correspond."
There's a piece missing.
I'll read the bottom part.
"After I hear from you,
I might send you something wet."
Signed: "avid fan."
There are teeth marks at the bottom.
Order a chopper. Don't care whose.
2. call Alabama air national guard,
get graham back here right now.
Call documents and scramble a team.
I want everybody movin'.
The documents team is underway
to pick up the note.
Listen, I wanna replace the note.
I don't want Lecktor to know.
He might try to warn the killer.
Where's Lecktor? - Holding cell.
How long can you keep him in there?
- Three, four hours.
We have a note coming in,
possibly from the tooth fairy.
No. 1 priority.
Has to go to hair and fiber.
One hair.
Maybe half an inch.
Couple of blue grains.
- Work the hair.
What do you have as a negative
comparison? - Lecktor's comb.
Whiskers from a razor,
hair from the security guard.
How many handled this without gloves?
Guard, cleanup man, Lecktor.
- The cleanup man scrubbing sinks
probably had the oil
washed off his fingers.
But the others... one smudge.
No ridges,
it's just the texture of the paper.
I can fume it but I can't say the
iodine stains will fade. - Ninhydrin?
Boosted with heat?
- No. You couldn't wash it out.
I can't get a print in the time.
How long?
- 20 minutes max.
Main thing is,
how was Lecktor supposed to reply?
It's probably in the missing section.
'I hope we can correspond'.
Then comes the gap.
This note was written in ballpoint.
But it looks like Lecktor went over
this area with a felt-tip pen
and tore it away.
You're so sly,
but so am I.
The aniline dyes in the felt-tip pens,
like Lecktor used,
are transparent to infrared.
The tooth fairy's ballpoint isn't.
This looks like the tip of a t.
This one could be
the top of an r.
- Three t's and an r in "tattler".
The article about me and Lecktor.
No-one else carried that.
Personal ads.
The tooth fairy told Lecktor
to reply through the personal ads
in the "tattler". Chicago is running
through them right now.
Here is a line of communication
between the tooth fairy and Lecktor.
If we find Lecktor’s answer,
we'll replace it with our own.
This is what he'll read:
"Dear avid fan: Inherit my mantle
and surpass my achievements.
Mementos for you at Baltimore central.
Left luggage.
Ticket 7-2-6-8-3."
It's a letter drop.
We stake it out and grab him.
Anything from Chicago? - Not yet.
- When do they go to press?
In 35 minutes. - Christ!
- Let's get to the physical.
There was no print.
- The core size of the hair
matches the blond hair found in the
Jacobi's. Your man wrote the note.
Three blue grains
went to Brians's end.
Commercial granulated cleanser
from the cleaning man.
Particles of dried blood,
but not enough to type.
This is Chester, who's there?
- Will graham, jack Crawford.
Got a personal ad with "avid fan"
in it. - Read it!
"Dear avid fan,
you honor me. You're very beautiful.
One hundred prayers for your safety.
Find help in Galatians 6, 11 and 15,2.
Acts 3,3; revelations 18,7.
Jonah 6,8; john 6,22; Luke 1,7.
Thanks.
Jimmie,
get anywhere with the Leeds print?
- Not yet.
Cryptography at Langley?
- They're working on the telex now.
No.
Our ad has to go out
in the same book code, or he'll know.
Book code?
"100 prayers" could be a page number
and the paired numbers lines.
Galatians only has six chapters.
Same with Jonah, it only has four.
Lecktor was not using the bible.
The tooth fairy probably named
the book in the part torn out.
What about sweatin' Lecktor?
We tried sodium amytal 3 years ago,
and he gave 'em a recipe for
a chip dip. - Wonderful.
The tooth fairy knows which book.
He'd know from articles about Lecktor.
Willingham took polaroids
of Lecktor’s cell.
Have him meet me.
- Where? - library of congress.
25 minutes. He won't make it.
Lecktor's ad runs as is,
or we pull it
and run our own ad next week.
- We got 17 days left till full moon!
I don't like Lecktor’s ad running
without knowing what it says.
It's your call, will.
Run it.
And what if it encourages the
tooth fairy to do something else?
Then we'll all feel sick.
And if bowman can't figure it out?
Then we'll bait him with something
else in the "tattler". - What?
Me.
That's not a very good idea.
Why not? Won't it provoke him?
- Maybe.
I was thinking about you.
You're getting in deeper and deeper.
Sidney?
The last time
you pushed yourself all outta shape.
Try it on again,
or if you go through some trauma,
you could relapse.
Sidney, don't worry about me.
I'm workin' the evidence,
makin' moves, that's all.
I'm fine.
Bowman says
it is not books in Lecktor’s cell.
Price?
- It's a bust out.
The Leeds' print will
get us a conviction.
He must never have been printed,
because he is not in our index.
We are not gonna
identify him off the print.
I'll use Lounds.
What for?
Our boy doesn't read the times.
He reads Lounds in the "tattler".
What else should we cover? - He put
the shorts on Leeds after he was dead,
so we wouldn't think he was gay.
He molested all his male victims
and may be impotent with women.
Our forensic psychologists
have projected
that he may have had
sexual relations with his mother.
How long will you stay in Washington?
- Till we've got the tooth fairy.
Will the "tattler" get the stuff?
How's your sex life been affected?
Mine? Lt doesn't.
It affects yours! Fuck yourself!
Look, pal, you're news!
- You shot the pictures.
Alright. I’m in the shots with graham.
- What? - yeah. Come on!
You want this to look real?
Make sure the theater sign
is just out of focus.
We want him to read it.
- And make sure I look excellent!
Shoot it!
One more.
- That's enough.
Ok, graham. Always nice, huh?
Let's have lunch, call my service.
Crawford, always a thrill.
Dr. Bloom. L need them
on my desk in 2 hours. - Ok.
Did bowman break the code yet?
- No.
They say the cutting tool
was a common bolt cutter.
I got a call
from Asian studies in Langley.
The mark on the tree is a Chinese
lucky sign in gambling.
The same character appears in
mah-jongg. Lt means red dragon.
Mean anything to you?
No.
If he shows and he's smart,
he'll approach from the front,
pass, turn and try and take you from
behind. How's your hearing? - Good.
You'll wear a wire, one way.
We'll hear you, but you won't hear us.
Checked out a 44 special bulldog?
Load these in it.
You ever fire 'em?
- Glaser safety slugs?
Opens up on impact.
Guaranteed one shot stop.
You got body armor?
- Kevlar second chance.
Hope you get one.
- 'Cause he goes for the head shot?
Let's walk the route.
United flight 8490 to Newark
now boarding at gate 7.
Can you get to a phone?
So where are things?
Got nine days left.
We're working on it.
You don't wanna talk
about what you're doing, do you?
Hotel rooms...
an illicit romance...
we have to stop meeting like this.
Remember the first time we met?
Yeah.
We were alone together in that room.
Though I’d never seen you before,
we were sitting there,
speaking. A shadow flickered across
your face. L said, "what's that?"
Remember what you said?
I said:
"This is too good to believe."
Time is luck, will.
You know the value of every day.
Someone's coming.
Go!
Don't!
Don't move!
Take the money!
Don't shoot!
Clear!
Quicker, man!
I'm being mugged!
Do you know who I am?
- I don't wanna know who you are.
You said I’m a sexual pervert.
'An animal' you said.
Do you know who I am now?
Yes.
Do you feel privileged?
I'm very scared.
Open your eyes!
Mr. Lounds, you're a reporter.
That's why you're here.
Open your eyes or I’ll staple
your eyelids to your forehead.
Well, here I...
am.