I'm not going to biteyou.
I'm sorry, sir.
You gave me a fright.
You're up very early.
I'm generally up by 5:00, sir.
Otherwise I get behind.
I used to be able to stay up all night
and suffer no ill effects whatsoever.
Oh, well.
Those scars.
Would you mind
ifI examine them?
It's a purely
professional curiosity.
I don't really like to talk about them,
sir, ifit's all the same toyou.
There are some
on your neck as well.
They look almost
like teeth marks.
Yes, sir,
that's what they are.
Mary, you'll find an eel
in the fish pantry.
Fetch it in for me,
will you?
It's alive!
Warmth ofyour hands,
that'll be, revived him.
Put him here.
Difficult buggers
to kill, is eels.
Now, keep hold ofits tail.
Go on. Don't be soft.
Fetch the skinners.
- What's the matterwith you?
- I'm all right.
- You're as white as a sheet.
- Sorry.
Well, fetch us that
big saucepan offthe range.
What's he do out there
on his own all those hours?
He's after something.
I don't know.
Lastyear he used to give weekly
lectures in that operating theater.
He had patients,
like a regular doctor.
- And hejust stopped?
-Just like that.
From one day to the next.
Perhaps he's looking
for a cure for something.
Yes. Forwhat ails him,
ifhe's got any sense.
Shall I leave the candle a while,
or doyou want to sleep?
I always want to sleep.
I can't understand why it takes
so much effort to look after one man.
I don't mind hard work.
I do.
I've been in service since I was 1 2,
and this is the best place I've had.
He's a kind man, the doctor.
Anyone can see that.
Ifhe was that kind,
he'd let me sleep until 6:00.
Good night, then.
I feel safe here, is all.
Good morning, sir.
Mary, this is most welcome.
I'm ravenous.
I'm pleased, sir.
- I wasn't sure I should wakeyou.
- Why?
You can't have had much sleep, sir.
I heard you come in not three hours ago.
Last night I came to the end
ofa very longjourney.
For months now
I have been engaged...
in the driest kind ofstudy.
But last night
all the barriers fell before me.
I have made a great breakthrough.
I'm very happy to hear it, sir.
Yesterday as I was passing,
I looked into the library...
and thereyou were
with your nose in a book.
I had no idea
you were able to read.
I'm very sorry, sir.
You are most welcome to borrow
any book ofmine that takes your fancy.
No. I wouldn't want the other servants
to think I was getting above myself.
No. I can't eat any ofthis.
-I'll ask Mrs. Kent to coddle some eggs.
-No, that's all right.
Areyou quite sureyou don't want
to tell me howyou got those scars?
I'm sorry. I won't askyou again.
Leave the tray.
Would you ask Poole...
to organize the removal ofthat
to my cabinet?
Yes, sir.
I hopeyou haven't been making
a nuisance ofyourself, Mary.
No, sir. The doctor
wasjust telling me...
he wants his mirror
moved to his cabinet.
Can you account
forwhy the master...
chose to issue these
instructions through you?
No, sir. Except I told him
I'd heard him coming in late last night.
You did what?
You were in the master's bedroom
some considerable time.
What else did he say toyou?
We talked about doing something
with the garden.
The garden?
It's gloomy out there.
I thought we could plant a flower bed.
Who's going to do all this?
I would. I don't mind.
Aren't we finding
enough work foryou?
I could do it
on my afternoons off.
My last place in the country--
We're familiarwith your
reminiscences, Mrs. Kent.
The master used to send for one
ofthe housemaids every morning, 9:00...
regular as clockwork.
In the end,
she fell in the familyway...
and was dismissed
without a reference.
I often wonder
what become ofher.
I expect now she entertains gentlemen
all hours ofthe day.
- Bradshaw.
- Yes, Mr. Poole?
Saveyour breath
to cool your porridge.
Yes, Mr. Poole.
What areyou doing?
Mr. Poole doesn't allow me
in the theater, sir.
- Does he not?
- Mirror's in place, sir.
Thankyou.
Mary tells us you've been holding
a discussion with her about the garden.
Remind me what conclusion
we arrived at, Mary.
Flower beds there...
and at the corners...
and a herb garden
here by the kitchen.
The very thing.
Just what we need.
Oh, Poole, would you gather the staff
in the dining room at about 6:00?
- I have an announcement to make.
- Sir.
As I'm sureyou're all aware...
the pressure ofmywork has
increased considerably oflate.
Consequently, I have decided
to take on an assistant.
His name is Mr. Edward Hyde...
and I intend to give him
the run ofthe house.
Ofcourse, as a rule,
he will come and go...
by the side door
ofmy laboratory.
But when he does have
the occasion to step over here...
I trustyou will treat him with the same
respect thatyou've always shown me.
You may rely on it.
Will the gentleman
be taking his meals here, sir?
Not as a rule, no.
There really is
no cause for concern.
He is a quite remarkable
young man.
He's a solitary one,
isn't he, the doctor?
Ayear or two back
he used to have dinner parties.
- Then hejust stopped.
- Shame.
Oh, no.
Best thing ever happened.
Think ofthe washing up.
And he's never had any sort of...
a lady friend?
Never a woman stepped
in the front door.
Not since I've been here.
- Strange.
- Bradshaw says he goes to houses.
What?
Bradshaw says
he goes to houses.
What doyou mean?
You know.
Houses.
I can't believe that.
You best get offifyou're going.
I'll finish up here.
Thanks.
Sir?
Yes?
It was very good ofyou, sir,
to back me up about the garden.
Yes, I think I did ratherwell.
Mr. Poole questioned me
so closely about...
why I was so long
with you this morning.
It was the only excuse
I could think of.
So, thankyou.
Areyou sure he's not out on the landing
right now, the virtuous Poole?
No, sir.
He's gone to bed.
I thought, ifyou would like
to examine these scars--
Come here.
Raiseyour sleeve.
These go very deep.
Did they never affect
the use ofyour fingers?
I couldn't move my thumb for a while,
but it gradually came back to working.
Does it still
causeyou any pain?
Gives me a bit ofgyp when the weather's
damp. Otherwise it's right as rain.
What did this?
Come.
Sit down.
- No, sir.
- I insist.
- Something to drink, perhaps?
- No, sir.
So, how did it happen?
It was a punishment, sir.
You done that on purpose,
didn'tyou?
No, sir.
What doyou think?
I'm made ofmoney?
You careless little bitch.
I'm going out now, Mary,
to see what I can find.
He was gone some time.
He had a strange way ofwalking,
not exactly a limp.
Buthis footsteps--
Well, Ialways
knewit washim.
It was like...
everystep was calling myname.
Areyou still there, Mary?
I found you something
to keepyou company.
We wouldn't wantyou
getting lonely now, would we?
Was it a rat?
Yes, sir.
He knew the way
I felt about them.
HeknewIcouldn'tabide
even theidea ofthem.
And he knew,
sooner or later, it was--
Going to bite its way through.
Bite its way through.
Where was your mother
all this time?
She was working.
Shenevergothome tilllate.
She tookmeaway
that verynight...
triedto decide
what to do forthebest...
and thought I'd be safest
ifshe put me into service.
What happened to him?
I never seen him again
from that day to this.
It is a terrible story, Mary.
I can see whyyou were
so reluctant to tell it to me.
Thankyou for...
being so candid.
I shan't forget it.
I must go to my laboratory.
There's something I need to do.
You're up early
this morning, sir.
As a matter offact, I didn't
go to bed at all last night.
- You've been out, by seeing your shoes.
- Yes. I needed some fresh air.
I was thinking a great deal about
the storyyou told me last night.
You must have really
hated your father.
I don't know, sir.
Surely he was a monster.
When I was little and he was in work,
he wasn't so bad then.
It was the drinking
that did it.
You think
it was only the drink?
The drink turned him
into a different man.
A different man?
He even looked different.
What doyou mean?
It was like he carried
another person inside him...
and the drinking
brought him out.
Or maybe set him free.
I'd likeyou to do something for me
in strictest confidence.
I wantyou to deliver
this letter.
I expectyou know
where that is.
There'll be no reply
other than a yes or a no.
- Very good, sir.
- You'll do it then?
Ifyou want me to, sir.
Thankyou, Mary.
Haven'tyou everwished for
a completely new life, Mary?
No, sir.
What good would that do?
Supposeyou were able to do
absolutelywhateveryou wanted...
with no consequences
and no regrets.
Then what?
I don't believe there is such a thing
as actions without consequences.
Strictly speaking,
I've no vacancies at the moment.
We might be able to come
to some particular arrangement.
- Areyou Mrs. Farraday?
- Who wants to know?
I have a letter
from Dr.Jekyll.
- HarryJekyll, eh?
- Areyou--
Yes, I'm Farraday.
Keepyourwool on. Come inside.
Dear old Harry.
Ever the good Samaritan.
Not required in
the House ofCommons, Sir Danvers?
I imagine they can rub along
without me this once, Mrs. Farraday.
And vice versa,
I shouldn't wonder.
Sir Danvers is one ofour most
prominent spokesmen on foreign affairs.
- Aren'tyou, Sir Danvers?
- You're too kind, Mrs. Farraday.
Got any questions
on any sort ofexotic customs...
Sir Danvers is your man.
Well, perhaps
I've been a bit hasty.
No, no. She's not even
an apprentice. Notyet.
Oh, pity.
- Mary!
- Yes?
I look forward to meeting you
in due course.
You rub along for as long
as you like, Sir Danvers.
Or as long as you can manage.
I'll say this for HarryJekyll:
He may ask for a few special services...
but he doesn't mind
paying top whack.
So I'm to say
your answer is yes?
My answer's always yes.
I have my obligations, tell him.
It'll take me a week to clear out
the present tenant, then anotherweek...
to make these alterations
he's asking for.
Then his assistant
can move in.
Can't say I've ever noticed him
in need ofany assistant.
Well?
She said yes, but she said
she needs two weeks to get it ready.
Hard on myyoung man.
No hardship to stay away
from that place.
He's robust enough, and he needs to live
within easy reach ofthe hospital.
- Where is he living at the moment?
- Why doyou ask?
No one in the house
has seen him.
He comes and goes during the night.
Now I think that will be all.
- I've seen him!
- Yes, hejust crossed the bridge.
But I couldn't really
make him out.
What was he like?
He moves funny.
Not so much a limp.
More ofa shuffle.
And he's sort ofstooped.
- Did you see his face?
- No.
Just his eyes.
He came outofthe dark...
likehe wasmade ofit.
- What's this, the mother's meeting?
- No, Mr. Poole.
Come here.
Closer.
What am I going to do with you?
You should have no trouble
cashing this.
I thinkwe've had enough
excitement for one evening.
Close the door behind you.
My lord, sir,
what haveyou done?
- It's all right.
- Is it broken?
No, it's only a sprain.
I shall need helping into the house.
Shall I fetch
your assistant?
What? I'm sor--
What did you say?
I thought I heard him...
moving around
the house last night.
Ifhe were there, doyou suppose he'd
leave me to crawl out here on my own?
I'm sorry, sir.
Ifyou'll allow me
to lean on you...
I'm sure the thing
can be accomplished.
You've been working too hard, sir.
I'm not surprised you had an accident.
- What's going on?
- The master's had an accident.
Why didn'tyou come for me?
Hold your tongue. Go upstairs
and light the bedroom fire. Bradshaw.
I was out late last night.
I must have...
somehow put myweight on it.
Dr.Jekyll is all too
benevolent an employer.
So it falls to me
to draw attention to occasions...
when I feel members ofthe household
are failing in their duties.
It is also my task,
may I remind you...
to dismiss those staffwho
persistently overstep the mark.
Yes, sir.
Haveyou any idea
to what I may be referring?
It was not my place
to advise the master not to work.
Quite so. Now help me on
with my Ulster.
The master requires certain
supplies from the chemist.
Naturally, we're all concerned
when Dr.Jekyll is unwell.
We are hardly likely
to improve his condition...
by drawing attention to our own
entirely insignificant opinions.
You must be aware there are
a great manyyoung women...
in straitened circumstances
who could fill your position...
and observe a few
elementary regulations.
Remember that.
- Mary.
- Yes, sir?
When we had our talk, you refused
to sayyou hated your father.
I don't.
Why not?
He put a dark place in me,
and I can't forgive him for that.
But it's part ofme now,
and how can I regret what I am?
Though it often makes me sad.
Oh, well, sadness, yes.
That can't be helped.
That comes in like the tide.
I knowyou're afraid ofrats.
You told me.
But what else
areyou afraid of?
I don't know, sir.
Bad dreams.
- I see.
- Confined spaces.
Yes, ofcourse.
But whatyou're saying is,
you're never afraid ofyourself.
I didn't say that.
You are afraid ofyourself?
Yes.
I thought so.
God, Mary.
I'm so cold.
My hands are frozen through.
Take some broth, sir.
I don't know, Mary.
Why is ityou strike me
as you do?
Get some warmth intoyou, sir.
I'm very tired.
Will you get dressed? There's something
I need you urgently to do for me.
What's all this about?
How should I know? You'll have to do
the blackleading for me this morning.
I'm afraid this won't be
a very pleasant errand.
- Is it to Mrs. Farraday?
- It is.
And I can't tell you
how important it may be.
Come in here!
He won't slip out ofthis one
with a few quid and a smarmy letter.
All the same,
you'd better read it.
He ought to have the courage
to come here hisself...
and clean up after
that mad dog ofhis.
- He said there might be a reply.
- And so there might.
Come with me.
In you go.
Don't even ask.
What shall I tell him?
Tell him no need to panic.
I'll do anything he wants.
And you take this home
with you to HarryJekyll.
What am I supposed--
Ah, yes, it takes all sorts.
You tell HarryJekyll
this is such linen...
as even his old friend Mrs. Farraday
can't clean for him!
You've taken your time. The master's
waiting foryou, in the laboratory.
Go there directly.
The rule is relaxed.
And shiftyourself!.
What did she say?
She said she'll do
everything you want her to.
But she said this is such linen
as even she cannot clean.
She has always been prone
to exaggeration.
I saw the room.
There was blood on the ceiling.
And did Mrs. Farraday explain?
No, sir. But I felt sure someone
had been torn to death in that room.
No.
- She said you should've goneyourself.
- I couldn't.
I'm sureyou understand.
A place like that.
I sent my assistant, Mr. Hyde.
She called him a mad dog.
On those rare occasions...
when a woman like Mrs. Farraday
is not at fault herself...
she is liable to experience
a rush ofrighteous indignation.
I happen to know that Mr. Hyde...
did everything that he could.
The girl had already
lost too much blood.
These amateur operations,
as I'm sureyou--
Well, let's not
discuss the details.
Just rest assured
that I shall continue...
to look into the matter.
I suppose it would have been too much
to expect a bit ofgratitude.
I'm sorry I doubted you, sir.
I'm going to lock my door
and work.
Tell Poole he may close up
as he pleases.
I may not go back
into the house tonight.
Mary Reilly.
Doyou know who I am?
You're Mr. Hyde,
the master's assistant.
You may say so.
What doyou think?
I always had
an artistic temperament.
I know I owe my existence
to science, but...
I've never been able to whip up
much enthusiasm for it.
Strange...
the thoughts that come unbidden,
don'tyou find?
Ifyou mean we're not always
in control ofour ideas--
Why should we want to be?
That's the question.
I've never been
in favor ofcontrol.
By all accounts, your fatherwas
no paragon at controlling himself.
Men will chatter
amongst themselves in a--
What I wasn't able to find out
was how far it might have gone...
between your father
and yourself.
Didn'tyou look forward
to them sometimes...
those evenings when
your motherwas out working?
Still, wouldn'tyou like
to come in town with me tonight?
Good morning, Mary.
- Morning.
- What's the matter?
I thought, sir, when we
spoke ofprivate matters...
those were confidences
you would never repeat.
I'm afraid you've been
upset by my assistant.
No, sir. I was more upset byyou
thatyou told him.
As a doctor, I've always
been in the habit...
oftaking notes after
any kind ofconsultation.
I'm afraid myyoung man is less
scrupulous than he should be.
He read my notebook.
I see, sir.
Well, in that case--
I can't deny that his manners are rough,
but I've learned to look beyond that.
I know he likes you very much.
I see no reason whyyou shouldn't
become the best offriends.
As a matter offact, I was hoping
you would accompany him...
this afternoon
on a scientific errand.
I thought it might make a break
from this perpetual housework.
Ofcourse, I'll send Bradshaw
ifyou prefer.
And now, to where they
butcher human meat.
This hospital and the slaughterhouse
share the same gutters.
Most convenient.
Youjust can't say no
to our employer, can you?
And you believe
everyword he says?
The doctor's been
very kind to me.
He's much too old foryou,
ofcourse.
I don't know whatyou mean.
I keep telling him
he works too hard.
Areyou aware, when you're with him,
ofhow much he longs to touch you?
Ofcourse not.
He conceals it that well,
does he?
I don't want to talk about this.
Whateveryou say.
It is difficult to understand someone
who is entirely incapable...
ofsimply asking forwhat he most wants
in the world, don'tyou agree?
How can you presume to know
what goes on in the doctor's mind?
Inspired guesswork.
Instinct. Fellow feeling.
- What does he want them for?
- I've never bothered to ask.
I just supply the organs
as required.
You've no idea
how strange and twisting...
are the ways ofscience.
Wait there.
Afternoon, Doctor.
Visit from the butcher.
What's that?
He can't tell why, Mary,
but the doctor feels a bit hungry.
Tea and sandwiches, perhaps.
For two, sir?
Why not?
Dr.Jekyll and Mr. Hyde
would like some tea.
How doyou get on
with that Mr. Hyde then?
He manage to keep
his hands to hisself?
You shouldn'tjudge everyone
byyour own standards, Mr. Bradshaw.
Well, I hope Hyde was politer toyou
than he was to old Poole.
-What doyou mean?
-Beforeyou went off, he sent for Poole.
He tells him to get on the train...
go offto some chemist
way out in the country.
And when Poole says, ''Is there
anything else I can do foryou, sir?''
He says, ''Yes. Mind your own business,''
and slams the door in his face.
Mr. Poole was that upset.
I wouldn't cross him
in the next day or two ifI was you.
He said to me,
'' No matter how well he speaks...
Mr. Hyde could never be
mistaken for a gentleman.''
Who is he then?
You ask me, he's got one over on the
doctor. You know, a spot ofblackmail.
Or, tell you what,
maybe he's a souvenir...
from the doctor's student days,
sort ofa grown-up wild oat.
Now they do look a bit alike.
Mary don't like to think the doctor's
ever had any fun in his life.
Mary, you go.
Oh, it's you, is it?
Butler's night off, is it?
- What doyou want?
- A word with the gentleman.
- Which one?
- HarryJekyll, ofcourse.
IfI never saw that other devil again
in my life, it'd be too soon for me.
- They're both in the laboratory.
- That'll do as well as anywhere.
As a rule, the doctor doesn't
admit visitors when he's working.
Oh, I think he'll admit me.
Very likely he'll admit both ofus
ifyou playyour cards right.
Wait here.
What is it?
Mrs. Farraday is here
to seeyou, sir.
- Who?
- Mrs. Farraday.
- What doyou want?
-Just a word.
Thought we might have a chat about
improving our financial arrangements.
Staywhereyou are.
I'll be with you in a moment.
There's something
I have to do first.
Don't be too long.
It ain't very festive down here.
- I'll bring the tea in a minute, sir.
- What?
- Mr. Hyde ordered tea and sandwiches.
- Cancel the tea.
Hold your horses.
I'm parched.
I'm sureyou'd prefer
something stronger.
It won't take me
a moment to prepare it.
Have ityour own way.
Doctor?
I'm very sorry to disappointyou,
but it isn't the doctor.
He chivalrously insisted on seeing
Mrs. Farraday all the way home.
He told me he couldn't go
to that house.
She's moved.
- Will there be anything else, sir?
- Yes. There will be.
Come here.
There has been something
I've been trying to say toyou...
ever since our first conversation
in the library.
Yes, sir?
I--
I want to apologize
for some ofthe things I said.
Why?
Because...
I was unnecessarily...
offensive.
Now lookwhat
you've made me do.
Don'tyou know who I am?
Mary Reilly.
Sorry. Must be
some misunderstanding.
I thoughtyou
invited me here.
I did.
What's the matterwith you?
I'm sorry. Bad dream.
Didn't sound too bad.
Yes?
Mrs. Kent tells me
that while I was awayyesterday...
you had some dealings
with the master's assistant.
Yes, sir.
Did you hold much
conversation with him?
No, sir.
But I understand
a cup was broken.
That's right.
How did that happen?
- I dropped it, sir.
- You dropped it?
- On the carpet?
- No, sir.
- It landed on the fender, sir.
- I see.
- It should be stopped from yourwages.
- Yes, sir.
I'll discuss it with the master.
You may go.
Poole tells meyou've confessed
to breaking a cup.
Yes, sir. I'm sorry.
After the storyyou told me
aboutyour father, I can't understand...
howyou could ever bring yourself
to sayyou've broken a cup.
Especiallywhen
you didn't do it.
Yes, sir.
I can't rightly understand it myself.
I'm sorryyou don't
care for Mr. Hyde.
- Who told you that, sir?
- Well, you don't, doyou?
He troubles me, sir.
Leave me.
- May I open it, Mr. Poole?
- Verywell. Be quick about it.
What is it, Mary?
Is it bad news?
My mum's passed away.
Mary, you come
and sit down a minute.
We'll makeyou
a nice cup oftea.
This is from her landlord.
Says she owes him money for the rent.
Now, don'tyou worry. Mr. Poole
will speak to the master, won'tyou?
Yes. I'll take up
the breakfast today.
Yes. And then you can see
to things yourself.
I've got my savings.
Nearly eight pounds.
Would that be enough to pay
for a proper funeral?
Why isn't she in her room?
Well, you see,
I've a heavy demand for my rooms.
Long waiting list.
- Where haveyou put her?
- She's quite comfortable.
Very snug really.
Now, the parish will provide
the expenses ofthe burial.
No. I want her to have
a proper funeral. I can pay.
Then let me takeyou to a first-class
undertaker ofmy acquaintance.
Thankyou. I prefer
to make my own arrangements.
And did you say
you were also owed money?
I took the liberty
ofselling off...
her few bits offurniture
and crockery and clothes...
which, I'm very pleased to say,
cleared offher debt completely.
And, let me see...
yes, a shilling over.
A poorwage
for a lifetime's drudgery.
Very true, miss.
This is a vale oftears.
What haveyou done?
You have a wonderful knack for being
in the right place at the right time.
Why areyou about
at this hour ofthe night?
- My mother died.
- Oh, yes, I heard.
Oh, well.
She's not the only one.
Now I'm afraid I must
make good my escape.
I supposeyou'll
never see me again.
- Areyou the housemaid, Mary Reilly?
- Yes.
This way.
- Mary Reilly?
- Yes, sir.
Where haveyou been?
My mother's died, sir.
I had some arrangements to make.
And when did you last see the doctor's
assistant, Mr. Edward Hyde?
Some time ago, sir.
Not in the last 24 hours?
No, sir.
Another question.
Areyou acquainted
with a friend ofthe doctor's...
a member of Parliament,
Sir Danvers Carew?
What areyou up to?
I don't believe so, sir.
But I understand he was a regular
dinner guest here at the house.
Reilly is the most recently
engaged member ofthe domestic staff.
I don't believe Sir Danvers
has dined here since her arrival.
I see.
Ifyou'll oblige us,
Mr. Poole...
we'd like to search
the doctor's laboratory.
I don't believe there's
anyone out there, sir.
Will you not interfere in matters
which do not concern you?
You'd best ask
the doctoryourself.
May I be ofsome
assistance, gentlemen?
IfI had anywhere else to go,
you wouldn't see me for dust.
The police found nothing here
or in the laboratory.
This place is
goin' to the dogs.
Murder now, ifyou please.
He always gave me the creeps,
that Hyde.
What's to stop him coming back here
and skewering us when we're in our beds?
He won't do that.
You know him well, doyou?
Come on to bed.
Still feel safe here?
I don't know
what I feel anymore.
Well, I'd watch me back
ifI was you.
- Mary?
- Yes, sir?
Would you step in here a moment.
I want to speak toyou.
- Mr. Poole--
- Never mind Mr. Poole.
Put those down.
- You saw him yesterday.
- I did, sir.
- You told the policeyou had not. Why?
- I don't really know, sir.
Doyou know that whatyou've done
has madeyou an accessory to murder?
Not telling the police everything
you know is a criminal offense.
I know that, sir.
My God.
I was at school with him.
He was corrupt and frivolous,
but he didn't deserve that.
And he is an important man,
not easily swept under the carpet.
Not like the others.
What others, sir?
- What others?
- There were others.
Where is he?
Last night he walked in on me
as bold as brass.
He wanted money
to make good his escape.
I made him promise to disappear
and never show his face again.
What is it
you owe this man?
Why areyou prepared to risk everything
trying to protect him?
It's myselfI'm trying to protect.
And as far as what I owe him,
as strange as it may sound...
Edward Hyde has liberated me.
I no longer care
what the world may think ofme.
It is marvelous
how much he loves his life.
And his victims, sir.
Did they not love theirs?
Not as he does.
Not so ravenously.
Sir?
I trustyou
as I trust no one, Mary.
My life would be
a sad thing ifI--
What is it?
He is impatient.
Therefore, do we
now commit the body...
ofour departed sister
to the ground.
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
I wanted to make
a contribution...
towards the expense
ofthe funeral.
Lookin' well.
And settled in service
in a big house.
- So I've been told.
- Who told you?
- Your mother.
- When?
Oh, I've seen a bit ofher
the past couple ofyears.
She wasn't one
to bear a grudge.
I wasjust thinking...
ifyou and I couldn't get
together again sometime?
The doctor tells me I'm not
likely to live through the winter.
Here. This must've costyou
six months' wages.
You keep it.
Why not? My money's
as good as anyone's.
Haveyou no heart at all?
I'm your father.
Haveyou no feelings for me?
We had our good times,
didn't we?
Wehadsomegoodtimes.
Youremember?
Mustremember.
Did you miss me?
You promised the master
you'd go away.
Easier said than done,
as it turns out.
- What did you do to him?
- Betteryou askwhat he has done to me.
The truth is,
I am your master.
- What doyou mean?
- I mean I am the bandit.
He is merely the cave
in which I shelter.
- Where areyou going?
- To raise the alarm.
Last week, you saved my life.
Nowyou want to send me
to the gallows?
Can you explain?
Can you?
I feel differentlywith you.
Why should that be?
You still the rage.
Where does it come from, sir?
This rage.
How should I know?
It comes in like the tide.
Now areyou beginning
to understand?
Foryears now the doctor has been
suffering from a strange malady.
He experimented with manyways
to keep it at bay.
But it would always return
more acute than ever.
Finally, he distilled two drugs...
tested them, and understood
that he had found the cure...
which took an unexpected form.
What form?
Me.
I was the cure.
The first formula
transformed him into me.
The second formula--
which he always refers to...
rather insultingly,
I can't help feeling, as the antidote--
transforms me
back into him.
Lately, I've found a way
to slip his leash.
To become myselfwithout
having to wait for the injection.
How?
Presumably, because
I am the stronger.
Is evil stronger than good?
You tell me.
Please let me go.
I am sorry. I thought
you were planning to stay a while.
But perhaps my sense
ofsmell deceives me.
Where areyou going, Mary?
The master's asked me to bring him
something from the laboratory.
I'll take care ofthat.
- He particularly asked I do it myself.
- I will do it!
You don't know what he wants.
Please don't interfere.
And he's not to be disturbed
for the rest ofthe morning.
- Mary?
- Yes, Mr. Poole?
I wantyou to go
and wait in my parlor.
I have something to say toyou.
Yes, Mr. Poole.
- Poole. Thereyou are.
- Yes, sir, I--
I wantyou to payvery close
attention to what I say.
You must make anothervisit
to Finlay and Sons.
I'm very much afraid
theywon't be--
Will you listen to what I'm saying
beforeyou start raising objections?
Three or four months ago
they prepared this at my instruction.
There must have been some impurity
in the compound because since then...
neither they nor any ofthe other
chemists has been able to reproduce it.
You must ask them
to analyze this precisely...
and then wait on the premises...
until they succeed
in reconstituting it.
Tell them that this is a matter
ofthe greatest urgency.
Life and death.
I will, sir.
Mary, will you come with me?
At least there is someone
in this house I can rely on.
I didn't know ifI could believe
what he was saying.
But it's true, isn't it?
I kept thinking you must know
we were the same man.
How could anyone know such a thing?
How could anyone possibly guess?
I wantyou to do
something for me.
I wantyou to go now
to my laboratory...
and make up a bed.
That is where I'll need to spend
most ofmy time from now on.
- Shall I take this with me?
- No!
Sir?
He said you have an illness.
What kind ofan illness?
You might call it
a fracture in my soul.
Something which...
left me with a taste
for oblivion.
You should've seen him.
Shuffling across the courtyard.
Hanging onto that drawer like he thought
someone wanted to take it offhim.
Poor Mr. Poole,
run offhis feet.
And he's not looking
verywell on it either.
I'm afraid the master's
been put out ofpatience.
As I feared, his new consignment
ofmedicine is not at all satisfactory.
There are a number ofbroken bottles
in the operating theater.
I'll go and clear it up,
Mr. Poole.
Never mind.
Leave it till the morning.
Best to get it done now.
Doctor?
Is thatyou?
Who is that?
What stops me from killing you?
I always knewyou'd be
the death ofus.
He took pity on me.
Seems he took pity
on me as well.
He mixed something
with the antidote.
A poison.
Another cruel trick to take his life
and leaveyou behind to suffer.
It was the onlyway
he could devise to setyou free.
It was inevitable
from the moment...
I found how to achieve
what I'd always wanted;
to be the knife
as well as the wound.
Would you have
ever forgiven me?
I wanted the night, you see.
And here it is.
You said...
you didn't care what
the world thought ofyou.
Norwill I.