[Boat Whistle Blowing]
Honey?
Come on over here, sugar buns
[Man]
This machine just called me an asshole!
(music)[Rock]
(music)
[Male Singers]
(music) The video game says "Play me'"
(music)Face it on a level
but it takes you every time on a one on one
(music)Feeling running down
your spine
(music)Nothing gonna save your one last dime
'cause it owns you
(music) Through and through
(music) Who made who
Who made you
Ain't nobody told you
(music) Who made who
Who made you
(music)lf you made them
and they made you
(music) Who picked up the bill
and who made who
(music) Who made who
(music)[Continues Indistinct]
[Man]
I knock
- Huh?
- Jesus Christ!
Do you know how to play this game?
- Sure
- Then why don't you make your last draw?
(music)Satellites send me pictures
(music) Get it in the eye
(music) Take it to the world
Spinning like a dynamo
(music)Feel it going
round and round
(music)Running out of chips
You got no line in an eight-bit town
[Motors Whirring]
(music)So don't look down, no
(music) Who made who
[Loud Whirring]
- [Woman] The bridge is going up!
- [Man] It can't be
Stop the car!
What the fuck?
[Man]
Look out!
[Screaming]
What the hell?
Wow! Far out!
[Man Screaming]
- [Screaming]
- [Brakes Squealing]
[Screaming]
- What is this shit?
- [Man] That's impossible!
- The light's green
The crossbars never went down!
- Huh?
Shut up, you goddamn
stupid asshole!
Can't you see we got
a situation here?
[Man #1] Did you get Mickey Mantle
over to the baseball game?
You go on and joke
all you want
But he hit three balls over the fence,
and one must've gone 250 feet
- [Man #1] Holy God! Look at that thing
- [Man #2] I'll get it
- Handy, you son of a bitch
I thought you was in Texas
- No, that was last week
You like that, huh?
Yeah, that's some rig,
all right
Give her a big drink
I gotta have some coffee
Right
- Hey, man
- Handy!
- This damn thing!
- What's the matter, hon?
This thing was working just fine
a few minutes ago
Now I can't get pea-turkey on it
You wanna bring me a light coffee
when you get done jerking on that thing?
[Man]
Robinson?
- Robinson, get in here, boy!
- I got eggs on
I don't give a lady bug
I want you in here now
Wanda June, shut off that radio,
mind them eggs for Billy
[Games Beeping]
Your mama!
[Hose Clicks Off]
[Screaming]
Steve Gayton, Mr. Hendershot
Duncan Keller's had an accident
[Hendershot]
Oh, "shitsky"! What happened to him?
He got diesel in his eyes
I'll be damned if I know how
Is that all?
Flush his eyes Leave me alone
Got some talkin'to do
in here
I gotta wipe everybody's ass
around here
Shitty job, but I reckon somebody's gotta do it
Ain't that right, bubba?
No, no Let me
get this straight now
You want me to work for nine hours,
and only clock in for eight?
I know you been to college, boy
Uh-uh, screw that
Not this kid
You know what that star means, don't you?
You ain't that obtuse, are you?
On parole, boy
Either your ass belongs to me
or it belongs to the state of North Carolina
You got one hell of a racket goin',
don't you?
Here Put that back in the rack
for me on your way by, would you?
Thank you, bubba
[Laughing]
Oh, shit!
[Man] Wanda June, honey, you want me
to get that cup of coffee myself?
Bill?
Billy, gettin'
out of hand in here
[Man]
You ain't talkin'about me, are you, honey?
Jesus Christ!
[Knife Whirring]
[Man]
Hey, those eggs comin'Pony Express or what?
Just a minute, sir
[Screaming]
It's biting me! Make it stop biting me!
- What is?
- The knife! The knife!
Quick, a rag!
Somebody get me a rag!
That knife go rabid on you,
sweet thing?
Well, it turned itself on,
and it bit me
- Short circuit, maybe
- [Wanda] There it goes again!
[Man]
It's on again
It's still goin'. Look at that sucker
Nail it!
[Games Beeping]
[Beeping Continues]
- [Gasps]
- Now what?
[Loud Beeping,
Whirring Noises]
[Crowd Cheering]
Come on!
Safe!
Come on Sodas
I'm buyin'
[Boy]
You guys gonna help me pick this stuff up?
Uh-oh, no sodas
- [Rumbling]
- Huh?
[Groans]
- [Boys Laughing]
- [Groans]
- [Rumbling]
What the hell?
[Boys Screaming]
[Rumbling]
- [Rumbling]
- Oh, shit!
Coach? Coach?
You okay?
Come on, Coach
Bobby, look out!
[Screams]
[Man]
(music) One step at a time, sweet Jesus (music)
(music) That's all
I'm asking you (music)
(music) One step at a time
sweet Jesus (music)
(music) That's all
I'm asking... (music)
Might as well give up
on that, sugar pie
I ain't been able to get diddly-squat
out of it past half hour
Must have a broke antennae
or somethin'
[Radio]
Our firsthand information...
So, how far are you goin'
up the road, sugar pie?
Depends on how long you can keep
your hands to yourself
What's that, sweet thing?
I didn't quite catch it
I said,
I don't really know
Just driftin', huh?
[Laughing]
- Yeah, I know what it's like
Been drifting for ten years
- As far as we can tell...
When I started this business
about eight years ago...
Shh, shh
I got somethin'
[Radio]
Before our microwave facilities broke down
Reports of strange occurrences
are pouring in over the wire services
We will have further bulletins as they come
in, but let me repeat this urgent message
If you are on or near a major highway,
get away at once
Get away at...
[Static]
- Shit!
- Whoa! What's wrong, sweet thing?
Pull in there, and if you don't
get your hand off my leg
you're gonna be wiping your ass with a hook
next time you take a dump
I never heard no talk
like that when I was a boy
What the hell you doin', girl?
What's the matter with you?
Lordy! Lordy, girl!
You gone crazy or somethin'?
Did you hear anything
that man said?
Are you...
are you on somethin'?
Jesus!
Wait a minute Wait a minute
Wait a minute!
Don't you go walking
away from me like that!
You come back here, girl!
You come back here! You listen to me!
Eat my shorts
Sometimes I think this world forgot
what good manners is
I give you a ride in my brand-new car,
and look at the garbage
comin' out of your mouth
- [Engine Revs]
- And you know what I think?
It's that damn TV
Look at what that stuff does
You're losing your immortal soul!
- [Engine Revs]
- Whole goddamn civilization...
[Continues Indistinct]
It ain't newspapers
gonna save this world
It ain't TV
I'm tellin' you here and now
- far as all that's holy, holy...
- [Engine Revs]
It ain't full yet!
[Man]
What is wrong with this?
"The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want"
- Jesus Christ, what the hell happened here?
- I don't know
What in the Dickens
is goin' on around here?
[Billy]
That's a damn good question
- [Man] That was your rig, wasn't it, Handy?
- Yeah
- [Man] Then who was driving it?
- I don't know
But he must've been
a hot-wire champion
[Man]
Hell's bells
- We gotta get some gas
- That's good, 'cause I got to go to the ladies'
- Can I come in and watch?
- No, you cannot come in and watch!
Ouch Shoot
- Did you see...
- What, honey?
Never mind
- Oh, Jesus!
- [Screams]
- [Fly Buzzing]
- Curt?
Curtis?
Is he dead?
Great God!
[Engine Revving]
[Revving Continues]
Hey! Hey!
I need some...
I need some help ov...
Hey!
Curtis, I don't like this!
Shit!
Curtis!
Are you dead?
Shit
[Coughs]
- [Engine Revving]
- [Screaming]
Curtis!
Get in!
Get in right now!
[Engine Revving]
Go! Go! Go!
[Screams]
[Curt]
No! The other way! The other way!
[Connie]
Oh!
[Curt]
Jesus Christ, honey!
You stop that yelling!
You know I can't drive when you shout at me!
[Engine Revs]
[Hendershot]
Boy, ain't this a ton of shit!
You do what I said
with his body?
Got him downstairs, sure Pretty crispy,
Mr. Hendershot What happened?
Fucked if I know, bubba
Fucked if I know
(music)[Musical Note]
(music) [Musical Note]
Yo!
Vroom-vroom
[Woman]
So, anybody in there?
Nope, not now
You're cute
[Laughing]
Yeah? Am I?
Not that cute
Well, maybe I'll grow
on you
[Woman]
Look at that There's nothin'.
You ever see that much nothing
at 10:15 in the morning, hero?
- Name's Bill
- Hi, Bill Brett
[Radio Indistinct]
Although our microwave relay
was knocked out at 9:00 this morning
this frightening mechanical revolt
appears to be occurring everywhere
New York, London,
New Delhi, Moscow, Peking
The reports we have
are all the same
Machines apparently operating
by themselves
or under the direction
of some agency we don't understand
are going on
a homicidal rampage
Whatever is happening...
[Continues Indistinct]
[Siren Wailing]
[Wailing Continues]
[Radio] Some cities are waking up
more slowly than others
Only one thing is completely
certain this morning
and that is no machine
is to be trusted
Unplug all
electrical appliances
If you have a truck
or car...
(music)[Ice Cream Truck Jingle]
(music)
(music) [Ice Cream Truck jingle
Continues]
[Motor Revs]
Let me tell you right now,
boy and girl
this beautiful American Truth Way bible
with gilt edges and color pictures
can be yours
for just $995
Wait, before you say anything,
let me tell you something
This bible has everything
in it
from the creation of this beautiful world
of ours to the fall of mankind
Look, Duncan, just hang out
a little longer, all right?
I gotta find my boy
Christ knows what's goin' on out there
Look, man,
you can't even see!
I can see just fine
I don't wanna pop you one
You keep yappin' at me, I'm gonna
- [Billy] Duncan? Duncan?
- [Man] What's he doin'?
- You really goin' after Deke, man?
- Yeah
How many fingers do you see?
Eight, twelve?
So I got a little double vision,
but it's clearin' up
I gotta find my boy!
I gotta!
Anything could be goin' on out there
Christ's sakes!
You leave without punching out
and you ain't never gonna
have to punch out again, bubba
Good
You leave me alone,
you fat fuck!
Yo!
Leave him alone
Or what?
Or I'll knock
your teeth in bubba
[Engine Revs]
[Billy]
Duncan, look out!
My God!
- [Engine Revving]
- It'll give you protection in time of danger
It'll give you health
in time of sickness
It'll give you Leviticus...
Oh, sucker!
Son of a bitch!
Outta my way!
[Muttering]
I'm gonna tear 'em up,
boy!
Where the hell are you goin',
you truck son of a bitch?
Get back inside,
you idiot!
Goddamn it, you snotbag!
Come on!
[Man] You scumball!
You wanna rock and roll with me, puss bag?
Right here, you prick!
You lowdown scumball!
I got...
- Get outta the way, you asshole!
- [Shouts]
This is Bubba Hendershot at the Dixie Boy
Anybody read me? Come in
Come on in, Rusty!
No one
No one in the cab of that motherfucker
Horse pucky!
What are we gonna
do now, huh?
I don't know
This is Bubba Hendershot
at the Dixie Boy
Goddamn it, Rusty,
come on in, boy!
Spread it on the ground
next to him
Hurry up, man,
he's startin' to draw flies
What the hell
you doin' in there?
Changing
That salesman had his hands all over me
And he's dead now
I don't like the smell of him on me
I don't like it
[Chuckling]
Jesus
For Christ's sake, don't just stand there
He's dripping over my floor
- Get him outta here
- Come on, man
What the hell are you guys lookin' at?
- Nothin'
- That's right Nothin'
Then go look at it
somewhere else
[Chuckles]
Okay
[Engine Revs]
[Engines Revving]
[Truck Horns Honking]
[Honking Continues]
Most of them goddamn things
got no right to be runnin' through this depot
[Connie]
Where are they going, Curtis?
I don't know
Greensboro, maybe
Maybe Charlotte
Why?
Don't know
Try the radio again
[Radio Static]
[Radio Off]
- Look out!
- [Brakes Squealing]
I think I just loaded
my pants
Curtis? Curtis!
It's comin'after us!
Get going, Curtis!
It's gonna bump us!
[Connie]
Why is this happening?
Hang on!
[Screaming]
Curtis, I never should've
let you drive again!
[Connie]
Curtis!
Make him stop bumping us!
[Brakes Squeal]
- Curtis, what is going on?
- I don't know!
But I know we can call the police
from that truck stop up there
Oh, my God!
When we get to that truck stop,
everything will be all right
Oh, yes!
[Laughing]
- [Shifts Gears]
- What are you doing?
You see that gap?
The next time it comes around,
I'm gonna shoot right through it
No, you don't!
They'll gang up on us and squash us!
- I can do it!
- So we can be inside where they are?
What do you think's gonna happen to us
if we stay out here?
I'm scared
Me too
Billy, come here
and look at these fools
- [Man] Now what?
- They're dead
- Maybe not
- Hey, don't go out there
- Don't, Joe
- Eat this
Hang on tight
[Truck Horns Honking]
[Connie]
Curtis, I'm scrunched up!
Where are you going? Will you get me
outta here? I'm caught in this seat belt!
I'm stuck!
[Shouting Continues]
I told you a thousand times,
"Watch out! '"
Curtis, will you help me?
Watch that thing, will you? That thing
looks sharp Will you watch that thing?
He's not my Curtis
Where is my Curtis?
Shit! I'm sick of this shit!
You goddamn asshole!
Curtis, will you help me?
Help me!
[Connie Screaming]
All right, bubba!
Stick this one up your home sick
[Hendershot]
Fuckin'truck's to be dee-po'ed
That one's dee-po'ed
for sure
[Hendershot]
Reload me, Joey Reload me, boy
[Hendershot Laughing]
I want that shit, bubba!
- Connie, run!
- [Screaming]
Oh, honey, you're bleedin'
like a stuck pig
- Where'd you get that stuff?
- We got a whole bunch...
- Shut up, Joey
Found it in my Christmas stocking, bubba
Get inside
Come on, let's get inside
[Gasps]
[Crying]
How are the lovebirds?
Heart rates are slowin' down
a little, I think
That's good
Mother's helper?
A girl hitchin' her way to Florida
needs some protection
Yeah?
That's what you're doin'?
Yeah
That's what I was doin' before every machine
went into maximum overdrive
[Crying]
I'm scared
If I put my arm
around you
would you stick me
with that thing?
You don't stick a person
with a straight razor
It's more like...
And I wouldn't
- Okay?
- Mmm
Holy crow!
Joey?
Yeah
Get up here
Tell me, man,
does he really got a lot of firepower
down in the cellar?
You heard him tell me
to shut up, didn't ya?
Come on,
this is serious
He's got a lot
- Grenades?
- Well...
Flame throwers?
Rifles? What?
You're gonna get us
in an awful lot of trouble
In case you didn't realize it, buddy,
we're already in trouble
Talk to me, Joey
Everything
He's got everything
Now leave me alone, Billy!
Holy shit!
- You think he stole all this?
- No, I think he bought it
- That's what a guy like him does
- Buys things
Buy cheap and sell dear
It's the American way
[Screams]
[Hendershot]
Jesus Christ palomino This is cute, isn't it?
You find any money on him, bubba?
I don't know what to make of you, boy
You're bright I know you are
You keep on being obtuse
We don't wanna steal anything
We just wanna get outta here alive
You messin', bubba,
where you hadn't ought to be messin'
Sometimes even college boys don't learn
their lessons till they had their chops busted
You know what's goin' on outside, huh?
You blind?
You tell little road twitch
about your illustrious career?
He's a bloodthirsty criminal
A regular John Dillinger
Goddamn you
Couple of Charlotte cops caught him
in this little bitty grocery store
Sack of money in his hand
Thumb up his ass Big grin on his face
- You wanna get outta here,
one call, I get you out
- Who you gonna call?
The North Carolina
state police?
I don't wanna play any goddamn games
with you I just wanna get the hell outta here
I'm warnin' you, boy
No, I'm warning you
This thing's over,
your ass is grass
Grass, you hear me?
Joey?
Goddamn you, Joey!
I told you to keep an eye on them keys!
I owed a guy some money
I was about 20 at the time
Not real bright
about most things
- Hey, it's all right
- No, it's not
You know what gets to me?
Is the stupidity
Cops put that spotlight on me,
and I just froze like a rabbit
Hey! Hey!
It's all right
[Truck Engines Revving]
[Giggling]
- [Brett] I'll tell you one thing
- [Billy] What's that?
You sure make love
like a hero
Wow
Look at that light
- [Brett] You know what I think?
- What?
I think it's the comet
We've been in its tail
for almost 12 hours
If it is that comet
that's making everything go crazy
then all we gotta do is stay alive
for the next seven days
No problem
[Sighs]
- I got an idea
- Hmm?
- Can you sail?
- A little Hobie cats and things like that
Mm-hmm, good deal
I used to crew the big ones
Sailboats No motors
- No motors?
- Uh-uh
- Where would we go?
- I've been thinkin' about
this place called Haven
It's an island about,
about six miles off the coast
There aren't any motor vehicles allowed
None whatsoever
- None?
- Uh-uh
You know
you are not only a hero
you are a genius
(music)[Rock]
(music)
[Rumbling]
The whole goddamn world's
goin' tits up
They can't
We made them!
Look, you've gone and hurt yourself
Come on, sweet thing
Don't you "sweet thing" me!
- Wanda June baby...
- They can't!
We made them
You can't!
We made you!
Where's your sense of loyalty?
You pukey thing!
We made you!
- We made them! We made them!
- Hey! Hey!
[Truck Horns Honking]
Oh, God, not the dark!
Please, God, don't...
Oh, I'm scared
Please don't leave us
in the dark
[Spoons Tapping Cup]
[Man]
Man, stop with them damn spoons
It's safer
than the jukebox
I like spoons
Man, this is one piece of shit!
Shit
Damn trucks ain't never
gonna let us out of here
[Giggling]
- [Dishes Rattle]
- Ahh! [Giggling]
- Place your bets
- I don't usually play for peanuts
- Come on
- Hmm
- I gotta eat
- Deal, woman
Hit me
There's lots less
of'em
[Billy]
Yeah Looks like they're runnin'dry
I think they're
pushin' 'em in back
Maybe tomorrow
it'll be our world again
I don't know
Was it ever?
I hate those
fuckin' trucks
I never did like trucks
anyway!
- [Groaning Sound]
- Holy shit!
- [Groaning Continues]
- [Curt] What was that?
[Brett] Oh, God!
That's that bible salesman I rode in with
There's some guy
out there?
[Bible Salesman]
Sweet Jesus, help me!
Help! Help me!
[Groaning Continues]
[Gasps]
- Let's go get him
- No, you don't!
You let those other big, strong men
go out and get him
[Trucker]
I didn't sign on here to be no hero
Yeah
Wait a second, man
Wait up!
It's like the old joke
You can't get there from here
We gonna stand around
and listen to him do that?
There might be a way
to get to him
[Trucks Rumbling Overhead]
[Rumbling Continues]
Now, that shower drain runs
into the ditch where that guy is
- Will we fit?
- One way to find out
- You boys are crazy
- [Connie] Curt!
Curtis! Curtis!
- What are you doin'?
- I'll be right back
- You ain't goin'!
- There's a man layin' hurt out there
There's gonna be a man layin' hurt in here
if you don't quit this foolishness
- If it was your man out there,
you'd want someone to go
- Well, it ain't
- You're not going
- I'm going
- Don't make me a widow
on my weddin' day, Curtis
- Okay
No reason why
we can't scoot across
- Pick up your feet and try not to shuffle
- I can handle it
[Hendershot] You boys are just crazy
as a couple of rats in a plugged-up shithouse!
And you, sir,
are without a doubt
one of the biggest fuck heads
I've ever met in my life
Wish me luck
You ready? Let's do it
Good thing that one
was out of gas
What makes you so sure
that it was?
I don't think we need to worry
about that right now
Man, you ready?
One, two, three
Bombs away!
- Think it'll hold?
- Fucked if I know
- You okay?
- Yeah
- Wanna grab that bag?
- Thanks
Jeez, this sucker
weighs a ton
Oh, boy!
Great smell, huh?
You okay?
Yeah, uh-huh
Wonder how many people
have peed in this
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay
How's it taste?
[Laughs]
Oh, shit
Hey, I'm sending you a friend
Oh, shit!
Get out of here!
Mister?
[Screams]
- Help me!
- How?
Pull me Pull me!
I can't
You're too heavy
Get me out of this ditch,
or by Jesus
I'll kill you
Ahh! Shit!
What a great time!
Wish I could do that every day What a blast
[Deke]
Bill! Bill! Help me, Bill!
- Jesus Christ, that's Deke
- Who?
Help me
- Come on
- Please, help me!
- Stop! Stop pulling me
- He's dead
- [Deke] No, he isn't!
- He's dead!
He's dead!
I'm going, I'm going!
- Bill, you okay, bud?
- Yeah, I'm okay
Move your ass, for Christ sake
Okay
All right
Let's go
Bill?
Bill, is my dad okay?
Come on
Let's go, partner
[Connie]
I think that truck got 'em That's what I think
I think they're dead
No, they're all right
- Then where are they?
- There they are!
They just came out
[Hendershot]
That ain't no salesman That's Duncan's kid
- [Truck Engine Revving]
- Go! Go!
Yeah!
[Laughing]
Yee-haw!
- [Man] Way to go, Billy!
- Attaboy!
You ain't gonna be satisfied until
you get 'em right in here with us, are you?
Cigar, Joey
[Joe] Mr. Hendershot,
did you see how he nailed that big sucker?
You okay?
How'd you find the kid?
Bill, where's my dad?
Dunc got scrubbed
by one of them big boys out there
- Tough break, kid
- You unbelievable shithead!
Is it true?
Yeah, it's true
No No
Hey, hey, hey
No, no, no, no
Hang on
Hang on, Deke
Mr. Hendershot?
Just a little lesson in manners
from the road twitch
- [Sobbing]
- Hold on, Deke
[Snoring]
- [Knocking]
- Bill! Bill!
Bill, you gotta wake up
There's something out there
Come on, Bill, wake up There's something
out there You gotta see this
Come on, wake up
Come on
It's right up here
What the fuck
is goin' on here?
Now what?
Holy God!
[Hendershot]
All right!
All right, Goddamn it!
You want a war
- you got one!
- I wouldn't do that
- Shut up, bubba
- Shit! Down, down!
How do you like that chickenshit?
[Laughing]
- [Machine Gun Firing]
- Keep your heads down!
[Growling Sound]
- What the shit's goin' on, man?
- It stopped, man
You sons of bitches!
- [Steve] Wanda, no!
- Sons of bitches!
Wanda, no!
Let go of me!
- We made you! Can't you understand?
- [Steve] Wanda, no!
You can't do this!
We made you!
- [Machine Gun Fire]
- Wanda!
Wanda! Wanda!
That's Wanda June out there!
That's Wanda June!
- Deke, Goddamn it,
you're gonna get killed Stay down
- It's right there
- If it wants to waste us, it will
- [Honking]
[Honking Continues]
Now what is it doing?
It's Morse
- Bullshit
- No, really
I should know
I got a merit badge in it this spring
What's it sayin', kid?
[Honking Continues]
Gimme a pen
I can't keep up with it
[Honking]
[Brett]
Incredible
- They want us to feed 'em
- Feed 'em?
Fuck 'em Let 'em starve
Half of'em's out of gas already
Let 'em starve
It won't take long
[Honking Continues]
Can't fill 'em anyway
We ain't got no power
- Aw, shit!
- There's your power
How'd they do that?
I'll be damned
I'm gonna turn on the pumps
I hope none of them left home
without their American Express cards
[Brett]
Bill, wait
Wait
You can't do this
It's not a good idea It's like
Neville Chamberlain giving in to the Nazis
I gotta show you something
Come here
Okay, now you see
that one?
- Yes, I do
- Now, look, here's the way I figure it
The big guys,
they're heavyweights
They crash in here, they're gonna break
through the floor and end up in the cellar
But that bastard,
ain't no reason
why he couldn't call in a truck full of Napalm
and hose this place down
- just take care of yourself, okay?
- What are they gonna do?
Run me down?
That'd be like a junkie
trying to run down his connection
[Sighs]
All right, you bastard
Tell all your friends
the main line's open
I got the best shit on the east coast,
practically uncut
You got that,
fuck face?
[Engine Revs]
[Bell Ringing]
[Bell Ringing Continues]
This could be
a very long day
[Male Singer]
(music)I'm a rolling thunder, a pouring rain
- (music)I'm comin'on like a hurricane
- All set, big guy
(music)My lightning's flashing
across the sky
(music) You're only young
but you're gonna die
(music)I won't take no prisoners
Won't spare no lives
(music)Nobody's putting up a fight
(music)I got my bell
I'm gonna take you to hell
(music)I'm gonna get you
Satan get you
(music)Hells bells
(music) Yeah, hells bells
(music) You got me ringing
hells bells
- [Truck Horn Honking]
- (music)My temperature's high, hells bells
Shut up, already!
You ain't doin' so bad here
There!
Suck on that!
I'll take over now
Thanks
I hope they choke on it
(music)Hells bells
Satan's comin'to you
He's ringin'them now
(music)Hells bells
The temperature's high
across the sky
(music)Hells bells
They're takin'you down
They're draggin'you around
(music)Hells bells
gonna split the night
There's no way to fight
[Bell Ringing]
Sorry, guys
If was fun while it lasted,
but we're all out
[Trucks Honking]
[All Trucks Honking]
What?
What do you want?
- [Honks]
- What?
- What's it doing?
- I don't know
Hey, Billy
Hey Billy!
Come on
I'll take over here
He's all done, man
- They don't understand
- What's that, Billy?
How it is
to get tired
How a man gets tired
Why should they?
Come on
If you need any help,
you call me
I will
Come on, man, let's go
We've been puttin' stuff
down in the cellar
The kid said there's
a big sewer pipe down there
He couldn't get in because of the wire
and shit, but we can use it to get out
[Engine Revving]
[Handy]
Looks like the coffee break's over
His master's voice
- Go on, Billy Go on in and lay down now
- All right
It isn't the comet, you know
It's a broom
- What?
- Broom
Imagine you're a,
you're a race of aliens, right?
And you're looking for
a new place to live
Say you're looking
for a planet
Like you and I, you know?
Like we looked for a new place to live?
A new house or something
So here's Earth
Only it's like
this big ol' house
and it's kind of polluted
Dirty and smoky
Grease on the walls
Soot in the chimney
- And they send in
- Shh
Their interstellar
housecleaners
Send in their broom
sweep us all up
That's what it is
It's a broom
using our own machines
to sweep us right off
Hey, mister!
Mister!
Come over here
- How ya doin'?
- I'm tired and I'm scared
I got us a plan
- [Curt] Come on with that thing
- Son of a bitch!
We ain't never gonna get out of here,
are we, really?
Whoa!
Cool it, champ
Little peep business
to take care of
Something you wouldn't understand
Now, when I say "run,"
you run, okay?
- What you gonna do?
- Don't worry about it just run, okay?
What you gonna do?
- Run!
- [Machine Gun Fire]
[Brett Laughing]
I ain't never seen a hero
with his ass in the air like that
- Hi, babe
- [Bullets Ricocheting]
I bet there's spiders down there
I hate anything with more than four legs
I can't do this!
Oh, don't drop me now!
I'm delicate
I'm just gonna keep...
[Connie Chattering Indistinct]
Oh, my God
Look at me I am a mess!
[Connie]
Dang! I wish we could get out of here!
Holy shit!
- Stay down
- Oh, my Lordy
Jesus is coming
and He is pissed
- Can we get outta here?
- Yeah, I think it's time to get out of here
Let's go, gang
Oh, my God
That son of a bitch is goin' up, isn't it?
- God almighty!
- Come on, let's go
Come on, go, go, go!
[Truck Engine Revving]
- How far, Bill?
- To the marina?
We're close
About a half a mile
[Voice Over Speaker]
Humans here Humans here
Humans here
This is for my dad,
you loudmouthed son of a bitch
I don't want this
anymore
(music) [Ice Cream Truck]
- [Curt] I got him
- Curt!
[Connie]
Curtis!
(music) [Ice Cream Truck]
Hurry Come on,
get in the boat
That's it right there
That's the one I was thinking about
[Curt]
We better hurry up It's getting light
Come on,
hustle, hustle!
[Brett]
Bill, where's Brad?
[Engine Revving]
[Screaming]
Adios, motherfucker!
[Cheering]
Brett, mother's helper
[Deke] Come here!
Somebody help me with this thing!
(music) Who made who
Who made you
(music)lf you made them
and they made you
(music) Who picked up the bill
and who made who
(music)[Continues Indistinct]
[Deke]
You think we're gonna be all right?
[Billy]
Deke, I know everything's gonna be all right
(music) Who made who
Who
(music) Yeah you
(music)Ain't nobody told you
(music) Who made who
[Connie] Curtis, when do we get
off this boat? You know I get seasick!
I think I'm gonna whoops my cookies
[Groans]
(music)
(music)She was a fast machine
She kept her motor clean
(music)She was the best damn woman
that I'd ever seen
(music)She had the sightless eyes
telling me no lies
(music)Knocking me out
with those American thighs
(music) Taking more than her share
Had me fighting for air
(music)She told me to come
but I was already there
(music) 'Cause the walls start shakin'
The earth was quakin'
(music)My mind was achin'
We were making it and you
(music)Shook me all night long
(music) Yeah, you
shook me all night long
(music)And knock me out
and then you
(music)Shook me all night long
(music) You had me shakin'and you
shook me all night long
(music) Yeah you shook me
(music) Well you took me
(music) You really took me
oh, you
(music)Shook me all night long
(music) Ohh you
shook me all night long
(music) Yeah, yeah, you
(music) You really took me, you
shook me all night long
- (music)All night long
- (music) Yeah you shook me
}}