Not sure of the
induced collapse,
team of specialists working in
the causes of the accident.
But I assure you that we do
possible
dropped to the survivors.
Calm down children
routine matter.
Harry is the only survivor may be
able to report on the incident.
He claims that he is responsible
But it was an accident.
Forget''to ventilation
pipes''
Firefighters found
5 corpses.
For the survivors.
Harry Gouornten the sole survivor
the collapse in the mine.
5 people killed by
neglect of one.
Murder?
There was an accident death
These 5 people
Gouornten Harry was killed by
the air to save himself.
The evidence is strongly against
Harry's death miners.
The diagnosis is that Harry can be
can never go out of his coma.
God is not reserved for final
Miracle at Gouornten Harry.
We better go lower
ready.
- I did my job, Harry.
-Do what I say!
Belonging to the father
mine do not hesitate to do so.
Everybody now!
My Bloody Valentine
3D
Happy fucking days
of lovers.
Sheriff here.
I waited a long time
Obtain a pension.
The same, who did this?
Harry Gouornten.
Harry is Gouornten
one of the parties.
Probably woke up.
Where the hell are you?
We will find other
for the feast.
I said that we expect the
Sarah and Tom.
- The promised.
- Oh my.
We have broken the rules?
So says Sarah
is the love of his life.
While, until the xanachalasoun.
- I am stupid.
- Yeah right.
- Hi guys.
- Hey!
Thanks for waiting.
Yes, another little doubt Axel
He knew that the future tense.
Hello.
To get a picture?
- No, thanks.
- Come on!
- Come on.
- Are you sure?
You are so beautiful together.
The bird!
- Would you?
- No, not okay, go.
- Ready to glentiseis?
- Are you sure.
We must go
Tom if you do not.
We believe that we
a photograph.
Great things will go
later.
You're right that it was inappropriate
time.
No matter, everyone is here
with his desire.
- Want to be here?
- Yes
- Are you sure?
- I love you.
- I.
I forgot the beer in the car,
Wait.
I come back.
- Can I come?
- Do not go.
Children!
Axel?
Peace?
Where are you?
With the passing of Harry
Gouornten, check this out!
Anyone?
Tzeison?
Tzeison you?
See a scare!
Come on.
I go here!
Go fuck!
Fuck you listen to?
Sarah?
All died!
Come on! Come on!
Hurry! Run!
Tom? No!
My God! Tom!
Stay Harry!
Tom?
Come on, take it from here.
by nirvana
Hard to believe that this quiet
Rokgouel and beautiful city,
is the metropolis of murder
of America.
Now completed 10 years
the day of love,
10 years later.
held the ugly
crimes.
When a miner, the
Harry Gouornten committed a series of
murder, killing 22 people
including women and children,
before finally buried alive
mine once worked.
But after 10 years the victims and the city
able to overcome the shock?
We are here with the Sheriff Axel
Palmer said the following.
That was was long ago,
trying to look ahead.
Sheriff not ever worry
similar events occur?
The media likes
something.
Because each time walking around?
It's like a bad show ...
And most ridiculous of all ...
Sheriff do this tomorrow
seems like a good community.
- We are a beautiful community.
- Enjoy your coffee?
- Where is the joke?
- You and the Sheriff Axel Palmer.
- Now we see that age.
- I do not know.
I am a bastard beautiful and good if
ask me to start my own show.
Yes better to do a Gyra
anyone catch bicycle thief.
- Hey Sarah.
- Hi, honey.
- I would not have a little bit?
- I see.
- Loss on television.
- Right, how was it?
When we leave this stupid
and come with me?
- Around 8.
- I have gasoline in the Cadillac.
We do not strongylokathises now.
Sarah I have an appointment with the doctor and
There can be a bit wrong?
Yes, when finished.
The main jobs I have something
Yo.
Want to come?
Not the coffee you drink, you will
if it is for you.
Shudder here.
We can not go anywhere
motel next time?
Yes, good idea.
Just stop
and go.
I do not think anyone noticed the
sheriff's car from outside.
Perhaps to say
his wife.
Perhaps.
I know that will not allow Sarah
that day and I said so ...
We have something ...
We need, I already did.
I am pregnant.
Tom what are you doing here?
What do you mean?
I came to sign the papers.
We become before Monday.
Not to be on Monday?
Good.
Since arriving,
Want to come for a drink?
- Yes, of course.
- Was lost funeral.
- Of course.
His father lost his
earlier, however.
You can if you want maloseis.
We ekove his ass if he knew
to sell mines.
- I am who I am Ben.
- Bullshit!
These mines are within the
Tom lives.
We are talking about families here.
We will ensure that all renewable
contracts and more experienced
like you, at work.
- How? 3 months?
Not my problem.
No! It's my shit!
These old mines
when I was a child.
But my father did not want
to admit, you know.
Thus, in this case.
Well.
If you do peace
father,
set.
I am the majority shareholder and
will sell.
And that's all.
Your father and I care
these people.
Sold as
someone here in town.
Welcome to property
my side.
Lewis to come here immediately!
- Is Mel here?
- I hope not.
- He died 7 years ago.
- Is there a place?
So come on.
- God!
- What happened?
I am so turned on!
Stay Harry!
Finally, we will stay
another night?
We travel and I have come
until the day of love.
Did you know that Valentine was
Roman who lived around 500 AD;
There was a large part of the recording
name a couple decoder,
the girl was a secret sexual
any profit for the year.
From there, follow the letters
in a romantic form of disease.
Yes, it's romantic.
- What are you doing?
- None.
Frank?
What is this?
Peace is personal
my collection.
- Look, you pay.
- I'm not a whore!
Now you are.
Frank! Bastard!
That can
no children around.
Shit for clothes, give me the
Cassette swear otherwise,
I swear!
- Peace, two things.
1) do not want another.
2) I know that the gun is empty.
Fuck you Frank!
Jesus!
Puta!
Oh my!
My God!
Louis are you?
Lewis where are you?
Small skatiariko, stop
hiding from Mom.
Lewis all the problems are.
As in the closet?
Damn! Let go!
What do you want?
What fucking?
Leave me alone!
Christoula my peace!
He took his heart.
Seems to use a screwdriver?
So I think that what you said?
Irene had no connection with them.
Sorry Sheriff, I know
know.
Not anymore.
Checked entries
in motels,
not all normal
names, if you know what I mean.
This is true,
Tom Chanigker.
We found a video camera
I wrote that.
Sorry again later.
Become a punishment out there
Police around the world.
- Speaking of Axel?
- No.
Hello.
- Tom!
- Sarah.
I work with
Your own.
Tom what are you doing here?
I went back to clear
one thing.
His father, sorry.
Thank you.
Tom were you? Is ...
10 years.
You were beautiful when I left.
If this is to say ...
Simply disappear, nor his father
I knew you were.
We thought you were dead.
Sorry.
Family you have there.
And Sarah Marshall was not right?
No, now Sarah Palmer.
I knew that Axel manage
arez always.
- I gotta go.
- Wait ...
Nice to see Sarah.
- Mom.
- Come on Sheriff, I come in?
- Okay.
- Well?
Why not go to brush their teeth
and I tell you?
- Okay, Mom.
- I love you.
- Axel arrived yet?
- No, Mrs Palmer.
Well, thanks for today
I will take now.
- What?
- I am.
You okay? I heard it was
something that the motel yesterday.
Look I do not have time to talk now
others must know that it was Irene.
- Murdered.
- La Paz?
Gotta go.
Indeed, what if we want to clarify
Harry Gouornten returned.
If people remember
more problems.
Most people remember what happened
Sanaa was 10 years ago yesterday.
Many outsiders in
Gordon this city.
There Harry Gouornten
is dead, remember?
Sheriff has a gift for
Valentine's Day.
I get my gloves.
Jesus!
There is no right to Harry?
Gouornten Harry is dead.
I shot myself.
Copy, a
sick bastard.
Saying that there was never a corpse
in contrast with the reports say.
Damn.
Look what happened.
- What the hell do here?
- Leave the girl alone.
- Relax.
- Shit.
Stop!
Came for you!
You are responsible! You!
You brought me!
Stop at once!
Harry will kill you for the good
this time, right?
- Go to the outside.
- Why?
Want to blame for
happened, so you want to go?
That kills me!
Come on, come on!
Start with you, Tom.
Half the people here know someone
who died from his father ...
Harry Gouornten the
dead, not me!
- I know this.
- So why blame?
- You will not be sheriff?
- Yes
Once you have saved your own ass
a second time.
But do not worry, kid,
any third party.
What happens? The NOA;
A playground is an NOA
is 2 in the morning.
What is this?
There is evidence of murder.
Sorry, I did not realize.
Tom turned Chanigker
in the city.
Do not visit huh?
Yes, the wine shop.
Imagine my surprise,
Why?
The love of your life can be
too involved in the shit.
- It is the love of my life.
- No?
You forgot this.
It was the last time
they were together.
I come to mourn.
I do not want to malosoume
I'm at work at 5 hours.
Yes, I
working now.
Found on tape
Part of the murders.
If xanaerthei contact
to trial.
I am.
- I'm at work.
- Sorry.
What are you doing here?
I'd like to talk a little with you
when will you be in business.
I now work.
You have 15 minutes before the opening
Shop.
We should have gone.
Fucking.
Come on time.
I thought it sell well if the
mines in the past two years.
If he loses and sell
rest of your life too.
We came to talk about it.
You have no idea huh?
This city depends on
these mines.
So many people who work there are
the only income to survive.
- It is not my responsibility.
- Yes it is.
Left 10 years ago, but the rest
ceased to collect the pieces.
We supported each other.
Recall that these metals
support your family?
Probably not.
I just left and went
to run.
It is not a nuisance for 10 years.
- I ... response.
- I do not.
I wish I could, but
I can not.
I lost my way.
Tom can not re -
The top left.
Only be implemented in all
his life.
Your choice.
Tom what are you doing here?
Where is Ben?
I want to talk to him.
You may be down.
- I'm down.
- Of course not!
It is not safe.
We grew up, a joy
I will be.
Turn the lights 3.
From here descend.
How are you?
Do not touch anything!
I will call Ben!
Ben entering tunnel 3
have visited.
What do you mean?
Go for it!
Stupid!
Come with me.
Best to start
Work ...
So to move the hands
listen ...
What do you want?
Children 3 to problem again!
Get started!
Call again motherfucker!
Ben?
Christoula me.
Is he dead?
The children are dead?
Pull me out of here!
What happened?
- Blocked help.
- Stay open.
- What did you do?
- I did nothing!
Damn!
- This will tell the public Hey task.
- No problems in Dr. Miller.
- Give me one.
- Take what you want. - Thanks.
Where the hell have you been?
I was in the tunnel 3
in Ray.
- Was Harry Gouornten.
- Tommy, come now.
He was attacked and
killing rays.
You know how crazy heard?
Very well;
I know this!
However, he was tried and
to kill me.
Sir, please calm down.
- You will be fine.
- Thanks.
- Tell what you saw.
- What happened?
- He attacked.
- Who?
- None.
- Harry Gouornten.
Mining.
What did you do there?
I went to tell Ben
not sold.
And why not?
Find something worthwhile
to make your stay?
Always with our envy
Sarah.
You mean my wife
Sarah?
Living in my house?
The mother of my child?
Bed
do sex with her?
- Sarah?
- Stop! Quite!
- Harry to attack him?
- Yes
Apart from being killed
10 years,
which was not seen in
Anyone else?
I do not know who was a sheriff
there, I saw him.
You do not need the city in panic,
because of you.
Cease immediately.
That means the
What should I do?
- What are you talking about?
- Well, I tell myself.
You see my father Tom
pareitsa here with Ben,
decided to lerosoun
hands 10 years ago,
Harry Gouornten dead.
And the sheriff Berk
hidden.
The parents of the city uses
Some justice unsolicited.
You see Harry not buried
I live in mine
But the dead buried.
And rest in peace.
And?
Where is it?
I do not know what to expect you.
Jim is my show
buried the corpse.
Once the mechanism
is the trap door.
Sheriff really believe that the bone
before 10 years
will clarify these
murder;
Nobody stops the world
believes that Harry has become,
and we can do
proper investigation.
A hatch.
Yes, here we again
the hatch.
Here.
Understood.
Here at least was.
What the hell is this?
Animals ... should be
work.
Animals;
He was killed when
the thapsate?
Of course, there is no pulse.
Life had stopped,
Huh?
Throw the bastard
until he died.
Thapsame here.
This deserves.
And certainly he was dead?
Exclude lived.
Damn.
I want their deposits.
And you.
I want now,
to discuss.
Come on, Sarah.
Come, gentlemen.
- What is mine?
- My job.
You are a suspect,
not me.
The murdered man
mining,
may seem that I did
me, but he did not.
Relax I did not say anything.
So,
because you are actually new?
Do you know why.
No,
I do not know how someone who does not
came to the funeral of his father,
decided to sell the
single property.
Eventually sell.
I decided to stay.
Why?
You know that a commitment
with you, right?
God.
What you just said?
Sarah is with you ...
Do not fuck with
my wife, me?
Axel cool.
- Mine is.
- Can.
The rest assured that Tom
was trapped in the cage,
someone was still there.
Very nice.
Crap.
It will take time to be
Axel on the right.
Because it is believed
does not mean he is right,
someone was still there.
- Yes
Harry, but how?
I do not know, maybe he wants to end
that began 10 years ago.
If I were in your position
Leave.
Not this time.
I believe him.
If you can not look
not find it.
The you.
Return of the murderer
Day of love?
Who is it?
Harry Gouornten can obtain
must remain in the dark,
in the dark ...
You are!
Crap!
I know the picture is
is a man we have,
and send it to be.
I do not care ...
It is possible, what is
problem?
Amazing,
yes, immediately launched a
I do not care,
just do it.
Well.
Yeah, well, well.
Sarah.
I have brought something to eat.
- Have you seen Tom?
- Not since yesterday.
We lost track of the morning
Ben and ignore.
I do not know who they are.
Look, Sara is not a game
people who die
and Tom is the only
knows something.
Tom is not ...
- Shut up.
- Jesus!
What's wrong?
I feel good?
Sorry.
- Sheriff.
- What is it?
We found Ben.
See you later.
What do you think?
We koroidepsan.
I was here with other
above,
And I'm pretty sure that the
Harry is not the murderer.
Putting off guard
my home
find Berk,
and Tom is Chanigken
the main suspects.
Megan mind
to help a bit to go
faster than here?
Whatever.
They finally
Axel Tom with you?
It was long ago.
When the Harry Gouornten
killed them all?
You were there,
Tom was?
Yes
Axel was the one who
I stopped.
But ... not anymore.
Closed front?
Yes
Please? Åre closed.
Please?
- Wait here.
- Wait!
I fear that very few times.
There is nobody here.
Megan God, go!
Get the hell out of here.
Run! Run!
Help!
Push!
Back! Back!
Help!
We want the keys!
The keys are here!
Here!
- Come on!
- Not seen!
It is urgent ...
I can not open!
Spring!
No! No!
Go quickly!
Wait!
Come on! Come on!
Here I am!
Sarah is?
Where is it?
From behind ...
back.
Stay behind me!
Sarah Stay behind me.
- Do you understand?
- Yes
Stay here.
- Jesus.
- What?
I would not let Sarah
please watch this.
EFTICHISMENI day of love
I go to hospital
to see.
Are you going to find?
All
mining,
10 years ago.
Megan not.
Perhaps the murderer knew
to do.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm not blind Axel.
Come on.
- Where you going?
- Take out the trash.
Finish the baby?
It is here, inside the house.
Come on.
Want to drive?
He retired.
I bend and
hide this?
Do not leave until it reaches
although they do.
Berk, come here!
Please?
Sarah, I am who are you?
In the hospital.
What happened are you okay?
I'm fine.
Harry turned Gouornten,
tried to kill me.
- Missed it.
- Have you seen them?
Only the mask.
Sarah thinks it's not Harry.
- What do you think?
- Trust;
- Tom ...
Yes, trust.
Well, if you have to show something.
Tom has to go home.
Well I will go myself and I
show on the road.
Where is Sara?
- Just go.
- What are you talking about?
Before 10 minutes with him
Tom Chanigker.
Sheriff?
Hello?
Upon receiving the request
Tom Chanigker,
Must see.
It took 10 years to forget this
the mask and just returned.
- Axel is always here;
- Yes, here was all.
Last changed?
Axel is not
Sarah what you think.
What do you think?
I think that I believe this
is responsible for that to happen,
of murders.
It's crazy.
Do not answer.
- Hello?
- Where are you from?
It is with you right?
- Yes
- Who was that?
Sarah heard,
must go outside the
Tom immediately.
What do you mean?
Tom was in a psychiatric institution
the past 7 years
not what they loved.
Who is it?
Sarah was at home, Louisa
dead,
it and Berk, pursued
our son!
And now you.
- The NOA is that?
- So, so.
We were at the station
are safe.
Watch ...
I know it's terrible to you
I apologize ...
you can if you want a split
Please get in your car
Sarah, please.
We come to see mama.
Come home to mom
told me that the NOA is not good.
It's about your mom.
- We must return to my son.
- Trust;
Go to the house.
Do not take it with confidence.
Tom, Tom begins to scare me.
You have to trust
this.
I have a husband and son in
Please go to the house.
Axel wants to believe
I'm not one.
I do not think you know
because it is capable.
We will restore
opportunity
not allow
again.
Damn!
Sarah! Sarah!
- Who are you?
- Axel;
Colliding with the car in the woods
near the mine.
You okay?
Yes ... I think.
God, well ...
You can go to the old
in my parents' house.
- Hide me there.
- Okay.
Crap!
"Axel is not
you think. "
"I do not think you know
because it is capable. "
Axel.
Stop!
Damn!
Do not move!
- Sara ... What are you doing?
- I found your heart.
What heart?
The day of love!
This Megan?
Look I'm sorry ...
We talked to Megan
damn!
I mean those who use
to put within their hearts!
Sarah is Tom ... This ...
Parada, Tom photo
Got to be there!
Tom was there,
Sarah was working the last
72 hours
where to find the time
to play the psychopath?
You're the sheriff Axel.
Oops, you're the police.
Tom left.
Sarah's too late ...
No Kounen damn!
Sarah looked at me with ...
kouniete and no fire.
What?
Axel will help.
What the fuck!
Sarah tell me you do not think so!
Axel does not give a damn
if you hate,
But this is not your wife
I say not to lie.
Shut up, that was crazy
in an institution.
Very nice good job.
There gamiete, fire and
two.
- What?
If the fire and the two.
Make the only choice
if we stop killing
the murderer.
What are you talking about?
Sarah does not listen.
- Sarah do.
- Can help Sarah.
We must do Sara,
We shoot!
- Not applicable.
- Shoot!
- Sara heard.
- Stop!
The words written by Megan
on card:
"Be mine forever
were the same words that were written
on your body.
- Axel, no?
- I will eliminate the head!
How do you know what he wrote?
I said.
No, I did.
How to know which words?
Sarah ...
Who is it?
This is Harry.
Harry is the fire Sara.
Sarah fire.
Sara should rixeis.
That's it!
- Check there!
- Nobody!
Behind you!
Sara should rixeis
immediately!
Sarah is behind you!
Shoot him now!
It's here ... behind you ...
Harry is not here Tom.
No, here it is.
This is Harry?
This means that Tom?
Here I am.
- I knew it.
- Axel ...
Well, well ...
We must leave immediately.
- You okay?
- It was a bullet.
Do not miss.
Tom ...
Come see here.
Hang the man comes to help.
Come!
Enough to get help
here.
What is your name?
Sheriff ...
Where is the Chanigken?
Is dead.
- I love you.