Nightwatch
It's my birthday,
so I decide what we do.
You're stiII a kid.
OnIy 24 years oId.
You're not oId enough
to decide anything.
Why don't we just chat
Iike reaI aduIts?
- TriviaI Pursuit!
- That's a game for idiots.
I think he's proud of his ignorance.
We just don't know how
to party anymore!
- Christ, we're so boring.
- InteIIigent peopIe are never bored.
Let's watch TV instead.
Shit, the psycho kiIIer
strikes again.
She was a prostitute.
It appears she was stabbed.
This is such an exciting case.
- What's up?
- The damn bottIe!
Oh no, my IittIe Burgundy.
- Here's to boredom!
- Here's to my new job!
- I don't understand why you bother.
- Doing what?
It sounds disgusting.
AII I have to do
is sit on my ass aII night.
- How did you get in?
- The door was open.
Damn, that door never
cIoses properIy.
- Are you the one?
- Yes, I am.
- WeIcome to Mars.
- Sorry?
I'II Ieave you the coffee machine.
But you don't get the radio.
Have you got a radio?
WeII, get one!
Let's do the rounds.
Have they toId you about the job?
No, not reaIIy.
There are stiII a few peopIe around,
but at night this pIace is Iike Mars.
So, what have you heard?
Have they toId you the whoIe story?
- Did they say anything about me?
- No. What shouId they have said?
Didn't they teII you why I quit?
No, they didn't.
May we come in for a moment?
Put the key in the box.
Now turn it.
We don't need to check this room.
The key's here.
Come and have a Iook.
Look.
Do you know what's in the tubs?
Can you smeII the formaIin?
You can smeII it, can't you?
Don't ever go in there.
Look.
I never wanted to Iook either.
Disgusting!
- So I'II be aIone here at night?
- Didn't they teII you that?
Sometimes an ambuIance comes in,
apart from that it's just "Them."
This is the morgue.
I don't know why the heII
they put a key in here.
WeII, Iet's get on with it.
They won't do anything!
Just keep your eyes on the key.
Just keep Iooking at it.
Damned idiots, putting a key in here.
- What are these cords for?
- They're just a precaution.
In case one of them wakes up.
He can puII it and the aIarm goes off.
Then you caII the duty doctor.
Just caII.
Don't worry, it never happens.
It's coId in here, but you can stiII
smeII them, can't you?
Make sure the door doesn't cIose.
There's no handIe on the inside.
But why shouId it cIose?
- Don't forget to turn off the Iights.
- Why?
- This is where it happened.
- What?
The scandaI...
A terribIe scandaI.
A night watchman, years ago...
It went on for many nights.
- He did it with "Them."
- You mean he...
The poor guy had
his very own harem.
One night they caught him in there
whiIe he was doing it.
The senior doctor hushed it up.
For the sake of the next of kin...
They say he stood outside for weeks,
Iike a Iovesick teenager.
Gross!
You get bad breath, when you've
worked here for a whiIe.
Put your hand over your mouth.
Breathe out and you can smeII it.
I'm right, aren't I?
- Christ, yes!
- It goes with the territory.
These are the staff fiIes.
Sign here.
Then I'II give you the keys.
I'II fiIe this in here.
Together with aII the other fiIes.
We're aII in here, you know.
Here's your duty roster.
- Is that the aIarm from...?
- It'II never happen.
- Weird photograph.
- It's aIways been up there.
You can't keep the radio.
- Have you got one?
- I'm actuaIIy going to study...
Get yourseIf a radio!
- I'd better get myseIf a radio.
- Good.
Just one more thing...
There's nothing to be afraid of.
But it's a good thing to have.
Don't forget about the radio.
- Do you know your "Gretchen"?
- We have to Iearn it aII.
- Your director's an idiot.
- He's actuaIIy very sweet.
Why can't anyone be an idiot
in your IittIe worId?
Does that irritate you?
No. I wish the worId was Iike that.
If I say... KaIinka?
If I say, "I Iove you." Does that
sound Iike a bad American movie?
- It depends how you say it.
- I Iove you.
I Iove you.
I Iurve...
...you.
Why can't we say that anymore?
We've seen too many bad movies.
I Iove you.
One day you'II be
the greatest actress in the worId.
Then you won't be abIe to say it.
The Iights!
- What a sick job!
- It's easy money.
- Get your mom to send a check.
- We have to test ourseIves.
- Let's see if you've got the guts.
- What do you mean?
CouId I borrow a pen, pIease?
Isn't KaIinka enough for you?
- I'd never cheat on KaIinka.
- Watch what you say.
Why don't we flip out?
For the next two weeks,
Iet's forget the Iimits.
- How?
- We'II chaIIenge each other.
We can ask anything of each other.
The one who backs down, Ioses!
- No Iimits?
- None!
- Any chaIIenge?
- Anything goes!
What are the stakes?
Freedom!
The Ioser wiII be condemned
to famiIy Iife forever.
If I Iose, I'II marry Lotte.
If you Iose, you marry KaIinka.
So, we'II pIay with destiny.
It's aIready resting heaviIy on us.
Can't you feeI it?
- Get your tits into that!
- Pervert.
Oh sorry, I forgot, you're a priest.
I got a summer job.
As a beII ringer.
- A beII ringer?
- And you'II go to church on Sunday.
I'm going to officiate my first service.
He's working with corpses,
and you're into crucifixions.
Don't forget, I'm
rehearsing "Mephisto."
Excuse me.
What a bunch of queers, eh Guggi?
Visit me at work one night.
I chaIIenge you!
Do you know what I saw yesterday?
There was a girI standing at the bus
stop. But she didn't get on the bus.
So, she was waiting for another bus...
She was a hooker. Just 1 7. Joyce.
- How do you know?
- You're not very quick tonight.
What happened?
God, I'm restIess tonight.
There's a fuII moon.
I gave you 500 crowns!
Must be the monkeys' night out.
Stop gawking!
- I gave you 500.
- It was onIy 50.
- I just gave you 500 crowns.
- ReIax.
- Want a beer with me?
- Move your ass.
You shouIdn't taIk Iike that.
Am I right, Guggi?
The girIs are having a probIem.
We're a coupIe of reaI horny boys!
You want some reaI cock tonight?
I guess we shouId do something.
Yeah, right. We're tough guys.
You've got a IoveIy mouth, you know.
Giddy up!
Thanks a Iot!
You just sat here on your asses.
- I want to go home.
- We might do something eIse.
- Come on, Iet's go.
- We're going to stay awhiIe.
Is that okay?
- Are you coming by tonight?
- Maybe.
I couId win our contest right now.
I chaIIenge you to show them up.
What are you doing?
A quadrupIe Jack DanieIs, pIease.
- What are you doing?
- AIright, Martin.
- What are you taIking about?
- You chaIIenged me!
But, you can't...
Jens, don't...
HeIIo Fishface!
Stop bothering decent peopIe.
Were you brought up
in a foreign cuIture?
Guggi?
Isn't that a Pakistani name?
You do speak Danish, don't you?
You're not Pakis, are you?
You beat up Pakis, but you're not
Pakis. Then again, who knows?
When your mother's a whore,
she couId have screwed anybody!
That reaIIy hurt.
Queers!
Jesus, that was great!
I hate them!
"Fish face."
Did you see the Iook on his face?
"When your mother's a whore,
she couId have screwed anybody!"
Let's have a smoke.
Hans Christian Andersen was a jerk.
He was a genius.
You know,
every time he masturbated...
...he put a mark in his diary.
- What?
- He made a mark with a penciI.
If I did that every time...
...there'd be no penciIs Ieft!
That girI, Joyce...
you know, the hooker.
I screwed her.
You didn't teII me that.
She did everything I asked her to.
- I said my name was Martin.
- You said you were me?
- She doesn't know who you are.
- You bastard.
- Yeah, right, a stupid bastard.
- You're incredibIe.
Want to be a bastard Iike me?
I'm a reaI bastard.
I aIways hurt the ones I care about.
I hate it aII.
I hate studying Iaw. I hate
having "fun" with the girIs.
I couId puke!
I couId puke too, sometimes.
ReaIIy?
Give me a chaIIenge.
Do it with Joyce.
It's not a game. Are you in or out?
Okay, I'm in.
ReIax.
We'II take her out for dinner.
Saturday.
I'm supposed to be with KaIinka.
You don't have to teII her about it.
That which does not kiII you,
wiII make you stronger.
Dickhead!!
I can't remember how I got home.
- I made you a packed Iunch.
- Don't go. Don't Ieave me aIone.
- Your breath stinks.
- Thanks a Iot.
It doesn't matter.
CaII me tonight.
Good evening.
Sorry.
Peter Wörmer. Homicide.
Did I startIe you?
You're new here?
Yes.
A Iaw student.
- I worked here when I was young.
- Here?
- I don't know who he is.
- Lewis Payne.
The picture was taken in 1865.
WhiIe he was on death row.
- That's what I reaIIy need now.
- What? Death row?
- No, a murderer.
- Has there been another one?
They're bringing in the body in now.
- This pIace gives me the creeps.
- Have you ever been in there?
Why not get it over with?
You're curious, aren't you?
If you don't do it,
you'II be haunted by fantasies.
Go on.
- Are you aII right?
- Shit. There was nothing but feet.
It makes you appreciate being aIive.
- I saw you on TV.
- Did I make a good impression?
- Are you on to him?
- No, he's too cIever.
- How do you know it's the same guy?
- Can I trust you? Of course I can.
- He has his trademark.
- Trademark?
He scaIps them.
- Good evening.
- This one just quit smoking!
RoIf, this is the new night watchman.
What's your name?
Martin Bork.
Our young friend, Martin Bork.
- I don't Iike it.
- It wasn't that bad.
- Why did they Iet you Iook at her?
- I work there.
- What's that suppose to mean?
- Nothing.
I'm sworn to secrecy.
- I can't teII you.
- But I'm your girIfriend.
- You wouIdn't want to know.
- You're a pain in the ass.
- Duty nurse.
- This is the night watchman.
- The aIarm just went off.
- The aIarm?
- The aIarm from the morgue.
- Go and check it yourseIf.
- The doctor wiII be there in an hour.
- But what if...?
Go and see if it's a faIse aIarm.
- But what if it's not?
- Don't worry, it is.
HI MARTIN
You're crazy!
You insane bastard!
What the heII are you doing?
- I'm sorry. Take it easy.
- Who do you think you are?
- I couIdn't heIp it.
- I aImost had a heart attack.
Jesus, this is gross.
How the heII did you get in?
The door wasn't Iocked. And you had
your nose buried in your book.
I stood and watched you
for five minutes.
You nearIy gave me a heart attack.
Cozy pIace you've got here.
I taIked to Joyce.
- Remember, your name is Jens.
- AsshoIe!
- I can't heIp it.
- Cheers.
I think you scared
ten years off my Iife.
Now they'II think I've gone crazy.
I just caIIed the duty doctor.
So what? We're aII crazy!
You can keep the paper bag.
- Stupid bastard!
- Love you too!
WeII, did you find any ghosts?
It was just my aIarm cIock, I'm afraid.
- Can I offer you a sedative?
- No, thank you.
It'II make you sing hymns,
whiIe watching a sIasher fiIm.
I'm okay, thanks.
Just don't froak out again.
We don't have time for
screwed-up kids.
Those things'II kiII you, you know.
CouId that be the Iady, I wonder.
Have fun!
Good evening. PIease aIIow me
to congratuIate you both.
- CongratuIate us?
- Yes, on your wedding.
- WouId you Iike to order now?
- Sure.
Oh, you'd Iike to...
- We'II have the Iemon soIe.
- I don't Iike fish.
Oh yes, that's right.
We'II have the veaI then.
- So, where do you come from?
- Home.
- No, I mean...
- Copenhagen.
What the heII are you doing?
Martin said I had to do it right away.
- You caIIed?
- No.
I'm sorry, but I'II have to
ask you to Ieave.
CouId I have a word pIease?
You're going too far, Martin.
200?
- Cheers.
- I can't hoId my Iiquor.
How much to drink
a gIass of whiskey?
100.
100 crowns.
Let's drink.
Just a minute.
You need a IittIe more.
I didn't say how big it wouId be.
Bottoms up!
Drink it aII, Joyce.
You're dribbIing.
That wasn't part of the deaI.
How much for a smiIe?
100.
So smiIe.
Not good enough. Make it Iook Iike
you're reaIIy having a good time.
TeII me you Iove me.
- Give me the money.
- I earned it.
- How much to give the money back?
- 100.
100 crowns for giving the
other 100 back!
Here. Give me my 100 crowns.
Listen, Joyce...
I'II give you 200 crowns
if you can say that you Iove me.
I Iove you.
That didn't sound quite right.
Can you beIieve that, Jens?
I'II add another 200. It's aII yours
if you can make it sound reaI.
I Iove you.
Sorry. I just don't beIieve you, Joyce.
How are you feeIing?
Okay.
- Why do you take this shit?
- What's it to you?
I own you tonight!
TeII us about your customers.
- What's your weirdest experience.
- Why?
Just answer the question.
One guy pays me 1 ,000 crowns
just to pretend I'm dead.
Yeah?
He covers me with a sheet
and puts a tag on my toe.
That sounds famiIiar.
But I wouIdn't bring anyone home
that I didn't reaIIy know.
- That's too risky.
- What do you mean?
My girIfriend brought
that psycho home...
- Then what happened?
- I'd rather not...
TeII us.
I had to identify her body.
He'd scaIped her.
- I know what you mean.
- Like heII you do.
Have I finished yet?
Do you think you've met him?
Can I go now?
I'm exhausted.
Why does Lotte toIerate him?
One of his one night stands
phoned here and asked for him.
Jane or Joyce or something.
He shouIdn't give peopIe our number.
Where is that idiot?
You're Iooking good.
Are you wearing
anything underneath?
- Where's Jens?
- He's probabIy on his way.
- We're about to begin.
- There he is.
- Are you drunk?
- I've just got a sIight hangover.
Cross your fingers for me.
- Joyce caIIed my house Iast night.
- What did she want?
- Was it reaIIy necessary?
- It's nothing to do with me. Honest.
So, who gave her my number?
- I've got a chaIIenge for you.
- What?
Don't take the sacrament.
Lotte wiII kiII me!
"Eat. This is my flesh given for you."
"Do this in remembrance of me."
This is the body of Christ.
I can't do this.
This is the bIood of Christ.
I can't drink it...
- Lotte, baby, I got sick.
- You idiot!
- It was the Iukewarm wine...
- Shut up!
You can't yeII at me here.
It was the damn hangover.
- Can't you just change the water?
- Do you think it's that easy?
You make a mess of everything.
Grow up! You thrive on buIIshit!
You are so chiIdish.
- I'm crazy about you.
- Crazy about me?
Can't you say Iove anymore?
If that's how you want it,
then I won't feeI anything either.
Great. No more responsibiIity.
We're both past feeIing.
- But you're the most Ioving person...
- I've had enough of Ioving.
Rubbish.
I'm crazy about you.
I guess I Iove you.
You stink of puke.
Not as much as the baptismaI font!
You never took the sacrament.
Daddy's home!
- Jens speaking.
- It's me. Are you at home?
- Have you been here tonight?
- You'II have to speak up.
- Have you been here?
- This is a recording.
- So, how are we feeIing today?
- Just wait and see.
She's down there.
Now Iisten...
Let's go and see
if she's gone back to bed.
She was there a moment ago.
Which one was it?
The scaIped one.
Good morning Inge CarIsen.
This young man cIaims you've
been up and about.
WeII, what do you know.
She's dead as a doornaiI.
But she was there.
Just as reaI as you are.
She must be pIaying
a trick on us then. Wake up.
She won't wake up.
- What's going on?
- I'm sorry, Wörmer.
I just wanted some back-up
in case there were Zombies to fight.
But it's onIy CarIsen who's pIaying up.
- She wasn't here a minute ago.
- Nothing unusuaI in that.
They often go for a quick stroII.
Do you want me to get rid of him?
But I saw her!
- It's Iike a bad movie.
- What do you mean?
The hero sees something strange.
But then it turns out to be nothing.
Sometimes its hard to distinguish
between fantasy and reaIity.
But this was reaI!
When I've been working hard
I feeI as if I'm in a gIass bubbIe.
Or in a movie.
When I'm trying to catch a murderer,
I try to think Iike him.
I somehow dissoIve.
Right and wrong cease to exist.
But I know I've got him when I
Iook in a mirror and see his face.
- OnIy then can I return to reaIity.
- But I did see it.
You saw what you saw. No harm
done, and forget the doctor.
He's just a IittIe too IiberaI
with his own medicine.
You can aIways reach me here.
I don't reaIIy want to go back.
- Do we have the money we need?
- I couId ask Mom for the rest.
- But you hate asking her for money.
- I just want some peace.
- I don't ever want to Iose you.
- You won't.
If you drink Iess...
...study hard, and wash behind
your ears, I'II be yours forever.
It's Jens...
- We've been wiId.
- Lotte's tamed him.
- WiII you marry me?
- What did you say?
WiII you marry me?
Yes.
That damned job.
- I'II go with you.
- You can't.
Have you got a knife?
In the top drawer.
Your friend's got probIems.
That detective...
The one with the psycho kiIIer.
Soon we can Ieave aII this behind us.
Thank you.
- What are you and Jens up to?
- It's just some buIIshit.
- Time for my rounds.
- Can I come too?
If you dare.
Jees...!
It's so quiet.
You can hear the bIood rushing.
- ShaII I never Iie with you...
- No, no.
You aIways forget that bit.
Let it out.
Damn it. I'm suffocating.
I can't breathe in here.
Do you know why?
Have you ever heard of taIent?
Is that theater?
- Never seen that before.
- It's no great Ioss.
- Are you KaIinka?
- Yes.
It's about your boyfriend.
You have to make him stop.
FiIthy bastard!
What the heII are you up to?
- What am I up to?
- Your sIave girI came to see me.
- Who?
- Joyce.
TeII me she's a screwed up junkie
who just happened to drop by.
TeII me it's aII buIIshit.
I can't.
Are you crazy?
- What the heII were you thinking?
- Take it easy.
- You behave Iike a jerk.
- It was just a stupid mistake.
Was that why we had to do it
in the morgue?
Was I just a stand-in for her?
- What?
- Do you want me to pIay dead?
Is that what turns you on?
I don't know
what you're taIking about.
CaIm down.
- Do you beIieve her?
- Did you sIeep with her?
No. It was nothing.
Did you enjoy it?
What?
Sorry?
Did you enjoy it?
- How are you Martin?
- The doctor just gave me an earfuI.
- Did you do your rounds Iast night?
- Of course.
Come with me.
- What's that?
- I haven't got a cIue.
It Iooks to me Iike a woman's body
Iying on its stomach.
- The Iegs were spread somehow.
- I don't know anything about it.
The doctor teIIs me that you're
the onIy one who's been down here.
Wörmer, come over here.
Do you know anything about
the drops of semen over there?
- Who eIse couId have been in here?
- I don't know.
Coffee?
Someone's trying to frame me.
That doctor...
I'm just as confused as you are.
But the murder victim has
pIayed tricks twice now.
And you've been invoIved both times.
- Do you have any enemies?
- No.
- Any debts? OId grudges? Anything?
You've got a girIfriend, haven't you?
What about affairs?
Maybe you've hurt someone?
There is someone.
A hooker caIIed Joyce.
- I went out with her.
- Martin!
The girI down there was her friend.
She had to identify the body.
- She caIIed me at home one night.
- BIonde and skinny? I know her.
But how couId Joyce...
The kiIIer moves in her circIes.
Who introduced you to her?
One of my friends.
It was just a joke.
What's his name?
Jens Christian ArnkieI.
Martin... I don't want to worry you.
But I have to be frank with you.
If I'm right...
...there's someone very dangerous
breathing down your neck.
Maybe you've unwittingIy
become his Iink to Joyce.
What do you mean, Iink?
Can I trust you?
WeII, maybe the murderer wants
the murderer to be exposed.
I don't get it.
A psycho thinks Iike a psycho.
His onIy way out is to find
another victim...
...and then make someone
eIse Iook guiIty.
He's gained Joyce's trust.
Now aII he needs is to find her kiIIer.
Her kiIIer?
You can't be serious.
Why does Joyce suddenIy caII you?
Think about aII that's happening.
Even RoIf's starting to suspect you.
This is too far out.
Don't worry. I don't suspect you.
The oId night watchman...
It must be someone who
knows his way around here.
I'II Iook into it.
Where did that semen come from?
I don't know.
We'II anaIyze it.
Can we have a sampIe from you?
HeIIo Jens.
What's up?
What are you doing with Joyce?
Run that by me again.
The poIice can't find the murderer.
Then this guy turns up.
He rapes the body of one of
the victims and threatens a hooker.
- So they have a suspect?
- Yes.
Who?
It couId be the wrong guy.
So who do they suspect?
Me.
Come on...
I'II onIy ask you once.
And be honest with me.
Is it you?
What are you taIking about?
What the heII's wrong?
Martin!
What's the hurry?
Take it easy.
I paid 400 crowns for that.
- Do you know where Joyce Iives?
- Yeah. Up there.
I've never been abroad.
Have you?
Do you know where
the HimaIayas are?
I'd Iike to taIk to Joyce, pIease.
- Joyce doesn't Iive here.
- But I was toId that she...
Have you got 100?
Try upstairs.
The Iine's busy.
FeeIing better now?
If you hadn't got out of there...
What did she Iook Iike?
Poor girI.
We have to caII the poIice.
We can't just Ieave her there.
Martin Bork here, the new nightwatch.
You showed me around.
It's 1 1 o'cIock!
- Is it hard to quit?
- What are you taIking about?
You forgot your knife.
You can keep it. Good night.
- A 16 year oId prostitute...
- They've found her.
Detective Wörmer reveaIed that
the poIice have a suspect.
We haven't arrested him yet.
But we have the evidence we need.
We know who he is.
We wiII arrest him tonight.
Sources say that the suspect
is a young Iaw student.
They think it's him.
Why do they think it's him?
I'd Iike to speak to the doctor, pIease.
This is Martin Bork.
The weirdo from Forensics.
Joyce toId me to say heIIo.
I have personaIIy asked
for your removaI. Go home.
- I thought you'd want me to stay.
- Go and see a psychiatrist.
- Do you think I'm a psychopath?
- You wouIdn't be the first.
- Goodbye.
- The first...
THE FIRST
RoIf Ericksson, homicide.
I'd Iike to speak to Martin.
We don't know where he is.
Joyce has been kiIIed.
The poIice are here.
- I'm going over there.
- It's too dangerous.
- Martin didn't do it.
- Stay here.
- How do you know it's him?
- We know.
- Martin is not the murderer.
- We don't make the evidence.
So he's the suspect just because
some weird things happened?
It's not just that.
And besides
Joyce exposed the kiIIer herseIf.
- She wrote his name.
- What did she write?
- His name.
- What name?
Martin, of course.
But we changed names.
Joyce thought he was Jens.
So if it was him,
she wouId have written Jens.
- That makes you the prime suspect.
- No...
- There was no name.
- KaIinka was there.
There was bIood, but no name.
- And the murderer was there.
- KaIinka.
Can I use your phone, pIease.
This is Martin Bork again.
That story about the nightguard
who was a necrophiIiac...
- Who was he?
- I don't know who he was.
But peopIe taIked.
- Was he sent to a mentaI hospitaI?
- No.
- What happened?
- The whoIe thing was hushed up.
The bastard is
stiII out there somewhere.
Where's his girIfriend?
"Interview..."
"Dismissed on recommendation
of Doctor K.K."
"WiII never be given
future empIoyment."
Martin.
It's Peter Wörmer.
Joyce has been murdered.
We've got to taIk.
I'II come down to the station.
We have to get to the bottom
of this. I'II pick you up.
Are you stiII there?
- Maybe I shouId go home first.
- No, I'II pick you up.
Are you innocent?
But who eIse couId it be?
Was it you, Martin?
I'II taIk to RoIf instead.
Why?
It's 1 :30 a.m. You're under arrest.
How couId you?
What have you got against hookers?
Do they offend
your respectabIe mind?
What you've done to these girIs
is simpIy ungodIy.
UngodIy...
Just taIking about it makes me sick.
I Iove the smeII of this room.
Come on. Hit me!
You can't be serious.
Get a hoId of yourseIf.
I've destroyed your Iife.
How much more can you take?
Come on, hit me! Hit me!
Or I'II scaIp your girIfriend.
Martin?
He's gone mad!
KaIinka.
KaIinka!
- He can't get in here.
- He didn't do it.
- Why didn't you caII?
- The murderer was stiII there.
What's more, they swapped names.
Joyce thought Martin was Jens.
It must be Jens then.
Or someone who
didn't know about the names.
What shouId we do?
KaIinka!
Martin!
- I was worried about you.
- He knocked me out and escaped.
- Something's wrong.
- What about KaIinka?
This is Jens.
- Where's KaIinka?
- How shouId I know?
- Her bike's outside.
- He probabIy took her with him.
HeIp!
Take him to the station. I want
to take another Iook at Joyce.
- Why wouId they try to escape?
- Take it easy.
Handcuff him. We'II get the others.
- Come with me.
- But you've got your doubts too.
Doubts...
- Doubts about what, RoIf?
- Nothing.
What the heII...?
No!
Have you ever been kiIIed before?
I'II be back for you.
This is crazy. You can't do this.
- What do you want?
- Just the usuaI.
Your hand...
Come on, we'II be Iate.
It's raining.
It's onIy a shower.
We're so damn predictabIe.
We're just Iike our parents.
My god, you Iook Iike my dad.
That's odd. You Iook Iike my mom.
If this had been a movie,
they'd caII it "The Nightguard."
- The great heroes end up married.
- So it seems.
They often chaIIenge each other
and suddenIy one of them says:
I chaIIenge you.
- Let's hear it.
- Says the other.
- Say no, says the former.
- Say no?
Say no to the priest,
says the former and smiIes.
Do you think I'm afraid to say no?
I mean, what's a "no"?
You want to hear me say no?
It was a joke.
Don't do it, Jens.
Jens Christian ArnkieI...
...do you take KaIinka Martens
to be your IawfuIIy wedded wife?
No!
It's actuaIIy the other way round.
It shouId be me who...