DON'T LOOK BACK
Let's go, Jeanne.
Robert...
Come on, have a seat.
All right...
Why do you insist?
Why are you so set
on writing fiction?
You didn't like it?
No.
Forgive me but I'd rather be frank.
It doesn't work. Drop it.
I want to write this story.
Your thing, Jeanne,
isn't stories or novels.
You write remarkable biographies.
Intrusive historical studies.
Even your guides are original.
That's not writing,
that's journalism.
Really? And?
I'm sick of it.
I want to change. As a little girl...
That was ages ago.
You need a subject
you can get a hold on.
Why do you insist
on writing about childhood?
But... That's what inspires me.
The trouble is, it doesn't.
There's stuff here.
But only isolated images.
The heroine observes
but has no flesh or emotions.
It's too detailed for a story
that doesn't hold water.
All the details are important.
I want the descriptions
to be precise.
I know, Jeanne, but it's so cold.
You don't draw enough
on your own memories.
I have no memories.
Nothing before I turned 8.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Your mother never said.
You neither.
But...
Never mind!
We have objects, photos.
My mother told me things...
Memory isn't information.
It's feelings, emotions...
It eludes me
so it interests me.
I need to write this.
I need to find my childhood.
My life lacks something.
Thanks for your time.
Jeanne...
Are you ok?
Yes...
How many?
1.
3 for me.
Nadia, your call.
1,000--
I'll see you.
A thousand in.
Raise by 3.
Fold.
All right.
Raise you 1,000--
I'll stake the pot.
Come on, children.
Drawings and coats. Let's go.
Jeanne...
Nadia, play.
Just a second, dear!
Count me out.
He's not interested?
No.
Why not?
Too descriptive, factual, detailed...
Too cerebral.
Detailed?
Forget it.
Let me read it and see.
No, not yet.
Maybe autobiography
isn't right for you.
I read them "Jeanne's Stories".
It's 30 years old!
Was that your dad?
Was he your brother?
Were they nice?
Don't worry, sweetheart.
Don't worry, my kitten.
Nadia, are you coming?
Have dinner at the club.
I hate seeing you play.
I hate their mugs.
Somewhere else...
No, I'm tired.
You'd look better
without those highlights.
Bye, you darlings!
Bye, Grandma.
I'll call you later.
Just a second!
Robert's a jerk.
Your book's great!
I cancelled my dinner.
I'll stay in.
No, I hate that!
Just for us. The kids love it.
Go on then...
Come on, smile.
Shit!
One boy's scared of apples.
Weird!
Enough. Let's eat!
Revisiting your works?
No, it's nothing.
I had more imagination then.
It's old.
Use what inspires you now.
Mum said that too.
Maybe it's a bad idea then.
Look at me.
Talk. It's recording.
You'll be slaves to this thing.
He's a pain!
I won't stay.
Let go of her.
- Leave me alone!
Mind the table.
Stop, I don't like that.
Again? Stop it!
Fascinating.
Who does the dishes?
Am I tired or something?
It looks like the table's parallel
to the window.
Yes, like usual.
You moved it.
Why did you move the table?
It's been there since we moved in.
I don't mind as long
as you put things back.
Léa...
What is this crap?
What are those movements
and looks about?
Maybe the tape skipped.
You're so childish!
Is this for me?
No.
Was your film good?
Stop, I hate that.
I let you work. I deserve a reward.
I'll make hot chocolate.
Morning.
I couldn't wake you.
The table's still there?
What? Don't start that again.
I have a say
in the kitchen layout too, you know.
Where's the honey?
Just put everything back.
I hope you remember because I do.
I can't spend my time looking for stuff.
No one touched a thing.
What's up with you?
Want to check my cock too?
It was to the right before and...
Very funny.
Jeremie! Hands on the table!
Eat up.
Léa, sit down too!
What's on the 27th?
Who are you signalling to?
Someone opposite?
Are you crazy?
Of course. I'm crazy!
Move this damn table!
Calm down.
No!
That's boiling!
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
I'll do it!
Ok, it's no big deal.
I'm tired.
I'm just tired, ok.
Let's do your hair.
Stop it!
No! Leave me alone, Dad!
It wasn't a bad birthday party.
Sit still or I'll hurt you.
I like other people's homes.
They're weird.
I don't like his mum.
She flattens my hair
and she smells of eggs.
Raw eggs or cooked?
Ham, rather.
No way, but go ahead.
Misconduct.
I'll invent something.
Totally fake, I don't care!
Enough to fire him.
I'm losing time, customers,
my sanity...
He's not just plain incompetent,
he's after us. And he'll find us!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Off you go.
See you.
The trainee's pissing me off.
I'll end up punching him.
Do... do you want a drink?
Little bird...
Come to my hand...
Léa?
You scared my bird away!
Get your pyjamas on.
Grandma won't be long.
Which poster is best
for our Woody Allen day?
I prefer that one.
What's all this?
You've gone off the apartment?
No, they're just doodles.
You're obsessed with that table.
Any idea where my Bulgarian necklace is?
Jeanne, answer me.
I see changes everywhere.
The table and all the rest.
Even your faces, your eyes.
What do you mean?
This apartment is totally unfamiliar.
I recognize things, the furniture...
But it's not us.
And in the photos and videos,
I don't recognize anyone at all.
It's another family.
Outside, I'm ok.
But here...
You can't be serious?
Not recognizing things is bad.
It's a brain problem.
A lesion, maybe a tumour.
A tumour?
You're freaking me out!
I recognize you.
You said you didn't.
I do, I recognize lots of things.
I don't have a tumour!
Maybe it's your eyes.
See the optometrist.
Call Feldmann.
I'm scared...
Maybe it's nothing.
But you need to check.
Everything's ok.
We'll relax tonight.
No talking about books.
Good evening.
Hello, Teo.
Are you well?
Very. The kids have eaten.
Jeanne's in our room.
I'll go in.
A drink?
You don't return my calls?
I haven't had time.
It stresses me when you worry.
Thank you.
No...
I won't insist.
I don't understand but...
Never mind.
There's food in the fridge.
Thanks for the shawl.
Basically, a woman witnesses a crime.
She hears a shot go off near her.
Everyone around her
tries to play down the trauma.
But, soon after, she goes deaf.
I'm lost.
That's not what happens.
Shut up!
She links it to the detonation.
But her husband doesn't remember,
even though he was there.
It's like he's erased it.
So she starts suspecting him,
suspecting the people around her
because they act weird with her.
And...
She spies on others, searches...
You're scared she could get killed.
But she realizes she already
got killed at the start.
It sounds great.
That's bullshit!
Have you forgotten your Italian?
I remember it perfectly.
Ok, ok...
Is that enough or shall I go on?
Anyway, that's not the story.
A woman sees an accident
and realizes it's a crime.
The police won't listen
and you realize it's a conspiracy.
It doesn't make much sense.
We'll see and decide.
What are you doing?
Nothing. I don't know...
Why are you crying?
What?
I'm not crying.
I don't understand.
I'm not sad.
I didn't even realize.
Are you hiding something?
The novel, your eyes...
You're miles away.
You're never with us.
Even the kids have noticed.
They said so?
Has the book put you in this state
or is it something else?
I don't know...
I don't know.
I don't understand.
I'll make an effort.
Right...
Come to bed, it's 3 a.m.
Are you crazy?
Watch where you're going!
This can't be real...
Here you go.
Thank you.
Forgetting is normal.
You never call your own number.
What happened?
She's all on edge.
I had a memory lapse but I'm ok now.
Come on, the kids are alone.
See you tomorrow.
What's happening tomorrow?
The same as usual.
Want to turn vegetarian?
Hurry up!
Come on in.
Jeremie! Léa!
Children!
We're in our room!
Jeremie!
Mum!
I'm hot, I'm sweating.
I'll go and change.
Let's choose cartoons.
Yeah!
Jeanne?
What's wrong?
You see?
Yes, your face is really red.
Is that all?
What do you mean?
I don't get it.
What's going on?
What's wrong?
Sit down.
I'm burning up...
What did Feldmann find?
Nothing.
Well, he did...
Some ocular pressure.
It could be that.
What else could it be?
Nothing. I don't know...
You got a prescription?
Yes.
You don't seem sure.
Let's call him and ask.
No, not now, please.
Tomorrow, ok?
You feel hot?
Yes.
Hot how?
Stop, your hands are cold!
They'll cool you.
Stop it!
Stop!
Let's go away
after the Woody Allen day.
It'll do us good.
Why not the Hotel Borgne?
You liked it.
Borgne?
Yes.
Never been there.
It wasn't me.
You sang "I Was a Fireman"
in the harbour karaoke bar.
That was definitely you.
That was there?
How do you know?
I mean, you remember?
Teo...
I miss you.
I can't help this.
It'll get better soon.
Relax.
Relax...
Teo?
No!
Get off me, you bastard!
Get off me!
I'm sorry.
No, it was good.
The look of disgust,
"Get off me, you bastard"...
I love it.
I didn't dare ask
but calling me "piece of shit"
would be even better!
Dad, the movie's over
Mum will wash you.
I'm going out for some air.
No...
Get me to hospital.
Jeanne has always been fragile.
She had an accident at the age of 8
that left her with amnesia.
Maybe it's important.
These changes you see...
What has changed exactly?
Everything.
Colours, objects,
other people...
Me...
You? What are you like?
I'm...
I've always had brown hair
and pale green eyes.
And how do you see your husband?
Fine. Fine...
Handsome.
Well, fairly handsome.
I see him with short, brown hair,
fairly dishevelled,
dark blue eyes,
a small scar on his forehead,
broad shoulders,
a slight stoop,
fairly tall, a dark complexion...
But you don't have to agree.
No, I see him the way you do.
But, before...
He had brown eyes...
a light complexion,
very dark, wavy hair...
He was bigger, heavier...
He was the man I'd always lived with.
Sorry, but he's not the same man.
This is incredible!
Mr. Garsch,
let's try to understand this.
Could you leave us together?
Yes.
Thank you.
Yes? I'm listening.
Nothing, that's all.
There were those changes,
those signs...
They were like...
signs addressed to someone,
sly expressions.
But they've vanished.
It was like a secret between them,
unrelated moments...
A dream?
No, not at all.
Does the idea of change alarm you?
Not to this extent.
This seems staged.
My husband and children
seem to be manipulating me.
You said you'd changed too.
So, you think the problem lies with you.
There's something else.
It can't be me alone.
It's all so otherwise.
When you say "otherwise".
You could be saying, "the other lies".
You think I'm lying?
I said "the other".
What other?
Just an idea...
This concern about manipulation,
hidden reality...
It's just what I hear.
Perception is shaped
by what we believe or know.
It's like a drawing that has
a second one hidden within it.
I just drew
plans of my apartment to...
That's not what I meant.
It was a metaphor.
I don't know.
Lies...
I don't know...
I think she needs therapy
but it's her decision.
Putting her under observation
could complicate things.
There's no neurological trouble,
so see how it develops.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
I want to go to my mother's
to take a break.
You used to need me, not your mother.
Will you drop me off?
Careful, you're driving too fast.
Please don't be angry with me.
Call me tomorrow?
Yes.
Mum?
Sweetheart?
Just a second.
Mum...
I feel so weird.
Take me home with you.
Give me 10 minutes, ok?
Why not now?
How long have you been here?
I can't right now!
In 10 minutes.
10 or 15, I don't know.
Have a drink.
Madam?
Something to drink?
Nothing. Thank you.
Ace.
1,000--
Your call, sir.
3 queens win.