[Woman Screaming]
[Woman Gasping]
[Screams]
[Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
[Panting]
[Sighs]
Well, hi.
Hi.
You okay?
Yeah. Sorry.
- Want something to eat?
- No.
- You know what?
- Hmm?
[Sighs] We should get
out of Calgary for a few days.
- You know, just take off.
- Anyplace special?
Somewhere where we
can be alone together.
More alone than this?
[Laughs]
Yeah. And no work.
No, no telephone calls.
- No bad dreams.
Mmm.
[Sighs]
Decker's been calling again.
When?
- All last week, every day.
- What does he want?
I don't know. I haven't talked to him.
I haven't called him back.
Well, if he can help.
I'm just...
I'm just frustrated.
- Spend all that time
working with somebody...
- Now, go see him.
Tell him it's all gone
except the bad dreams.
The dreams aren't
even that bad anymore.
I'm actually beginning
to like them.
[Chuckles] That does
sound crazy, now doesn't it?
[Dog Barking]
[Grunts, Laughing]
But I like being fat,
because it's comfortable.
And I like myself fat.
I like you fat too.
Ooh, you'll wake the munchkins.
[Child]
Mommy.
Sweetie, you're supposed
to be beddy-byes.
- I heard something.
- What did you hear, honey?
- A bad man.
- Oh, everything's all right.
You go back to bed, munchkin, and I'll
come and see you a bit later, okay?
Okay.
[Toy Squeaking]
[Dog Continues Barking]
[Gasps, Whimpering]
[Gasping, Choking]
[Sportscaster On TV]
Looking very aggressive.
There's the steal
by Roberts. All alone!
Oh, what a save!
[Siren Wailing]
You know, most of my colleagues would
have walked away from a case like yours.
But I found you intriguing.
All that talk about monsters
in Midian.
Only I didn't create 'em.
I heard about 'em' from other people.
Yeah, but you incorporated it
into your private mythology.
I guess I did.
[Phone Ringing]
I needed a place to escape to.
- A place where all your sins
would be forgiven.
- Yeah.
- Do you remember what sins?
- What do you mean?
Well, when you imagined
yourself being taken away...
to this invented city,
to Midian,
what sins were you
gonna be forgiven?
Are we back in therapy, Doctor?
They were just dreams.
Midian doesn't exist.
Monsters don't exist.
But murder does, Aaron.
Murder is very, very real.
It might start in the mind,
but then it changes
to flesh and blood.
Two days ago, the police
brought me some photographs.
They wanted to know
if any of my patients...
was capable of doing
what's in those photographs.
I'm gonna show them to you.
- Why?
- Because when you talked
about murder on the tapes,
I assumed
it was just hallucinations.
That's what I assumed.
What you described
on those tapes, Aaron,
was very detailed, very specifiic.
- Houses, faces.
- [Helicopter Hovering]
These houses, these faces.
No, l...
I don't remember.
- Would you like to hear?
- No!
- So you think I did this?
- Six families killed
in ten months, Aaron.
Oh, God.
[Sighing]
So what am I gonna do?
You're gonna take these.
They'll help you.
You've got 24 hours to go to the police
and tell them the truth.
And that's all I can give you.
Boone?
[Dial Tone, Touch Tones]
[Line Ringing]
[Answering Machine]
This is Boone. You know what to do.
Adios.
[Machine Beeps]
[Woman On Machine]
Yeah. Hi, it's me.
I'm at my place. I thought
you were gonna be here.
So, um, so come over as soon
as you get this, okay?
I love you. Bye.
[Truck Horn Honking]
[Brakes Screeching]
- Take it easy. Take it easy.
- [Woman On P.A., Indistinct]
- What have you been taking?
- Lithium.
Lucky you're in one piece,
fellow.
- This is not Lithium, friend.
- What was I taking?
It looks like it could be some kind
of lab quality hallucinogen.
- [Phone Ringing]
- You're on what we used to call
a bad trip, old buddy.
[Dr. Decker's Voice] Six families
killed in ten months, Aaron.
Six families killed
in ten month, Aaron.
[Voice Fading] Six families
killed in ten months, Aaron.
[Man]
Take me to Midian.
[Continues, Indistinct]
I'll do anything for you.
Have I missed you?
Have I missed you? No.
Please. Please come.
Please come. Take me.
Take me to Midian.
Please take me.
Take me to Midian!
Please. I beg you.
I'll do anything.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Gasps]
Why won't you come?
What did you say?
I said shut up!
They won't come when you're here.
They won't show themselves
to the likes of you.
- What did you just say?
- "What'd you just say?"
- You said "Midian."
- Did I? Maybe.
What do you know about it?
It's where the monsters go.
It takes away the pain.
[Thunder Continues]
Hey, wait a minute.
[Shuddering]
What do you know about it?
- They forgive you there.
- See, they only take you
if you're worthy.
Know what they do
to those that aren't worthy?
Kkkkk!
[Laughs]
So you know where it is?
You and I could go there.
- They sent you.
- What?
They sent you to take me.
- Yes. Yeah.
- [Whimpering]
But I need to know
where it is.
It's a test.
Yes. Yes.
North of Athabasca.
East of Peace River.
North of Dwyer.
You'll take me?
I'm worthy. You ask anyone.
I knew you'd come.
I was waiting!
Good.
I know, I know, I know.
I know. I know.
First I have to show you.
That's how it works.
- Show me what?
- My true face.
That's what these are for.
I'm an actor, see?
There's a face
beneath this face.
- No!
- You have to see me!
First I'll show you, then you'll
take me with you. [Screams]
Juvenile delinquency,
periodically institutionalized.
Some violent episodes.
No criminal charges.
- And he's been in my care...
- [Woman Screaming]
Ahhhhhh!
- What the hell have you done?
- Nothing.
[Crying]
In there!
They need help!
What's he saying?
He's not making
a whole lot of sense.
Something about a place
called Midian.
He's dying.
I think he wants to die.
Inspector, I know Boone.
I know how he talks.
I know how he manipulates.
Now, maybe, if the right words
are said to this man,
they'll trigger something.
Go ahead.
I'll do what I can.
But I'll have to have privacy.
[Dog Slobbering]
- [Gasps, Grunts]
- [Dog Whimpering]
[Bird Squawking]
[Distant Laughter]
Move, and I'll
slit your throat.
- [Monster] You got him?
- I got him.
[Aaron]
Holy shit!
Are you from Midian?
- We shall take him below.
- He's not Nightbreed.
- He's Natural.
- No. I've killed people!
I'm like you.
That's why I'm here.
Shut the fuck up.
You're meat.
If we eat him,
we break the law.
That's true?
Everything's true.
God's an astronaut.
Oz is over the rainbow.
And Midian is
where the monsters live.
And you came to die.
I didn't come to die.
I came to be with you.
No. Sorry.
I can smell innocence...
[Sniffs]
From 50 yards.
I've killed people.
I've killed 15 people!
- Who told you that?
- What do you mean?
He lied, asshole.
He lied.
You're Natural.
[Shudders]
And that means...
you're meat...
for the beast.
[Snarling, Roaring]
[Wailing]
We mustn't!
It's the law!
Fuck the law.
I want meat.
No!
[Groaning, Grunting]
Let him go!
Women Wailing]
[Drumming]
[Indistinct Shouting]
Peloquin, no!
He's meat! He's meat!
[Laughter, Wailing]
[Fingernails Scraping]
[Indistinct Voice]
[Laughter Continues]
He's after you. Quickly, that way!
The gate's that way!
Run while you've
still got legs!
He's gone! Enough!
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Laughing]
What?
Something Natural.
Freeze! Aaron Boone,
you're under arrest!
Boone, listen to him.
It's no use.
Stay back!
Inspector, I know
how to talk to him.
Boone, it's gonna be okay.
They know everything now.
I've explained
everything to them.
They're not gonna hurt you.
I didn't do it.
I didn't hurt anyone!
- Of course you didn't.
- Then you believe me?
I believe you.
- He's got a gun!
- [Gunshots]
No! Hold your fire!
Hold your goddamn fire!
Where's the gun?
He reached into his jacket.
Miss Winston, can you identify this
as the body of Aaron Boone?
You know, you meant
the world to Aaron.
He used to talk about you
all the time.
He talked a lot about you too.
- We don't have to do this now.
- I'd rather get it over with.
What was your relationship
with the deceased?
We were lovers.
[Coroner] Deceased is male
white Caucasian, late 20's.
Possible cause of death:
Multiple gunshot wounds...
to the thoracic cavity
and the extremities.
Unspecified animal bite adjacent
bullet wound upper left shoulder.
Bullet wound number one,
upper left shoulder.
Second bullet wound
above left nipple.
Third bullet wound
below costal margin to the left.
Jesus! They weren't
taking any chances!
He never raised a hand to me.
He never hurt anyone in his life.
Miss Winston,
everybody has a secret face.
Coffee break.
Sweet dreams.
Where did he die?
What was the name of that town?
It was a place called Midian.
[Window Shatters]
[Decker On Tape]
Is it always the same dream, then?
[Boone On Tape]
Oh, no, it's... Sometimes it's...
It's like I'm... I don't know.
It's like I'm underground.
Maybe Midian,
a place full of monsters
I told you about.
[Decker]
Are you buried alive?
[Boone]
No, not alive.
[Decker]
But you're conscious?
[Boone] Yeah, but not alive.
I'm dead, but I'm still functioning.
[Decker]
Death is the end.
[Boone]
Not in Midian it isn't.
In Midian, I live forever.
[Grunts]
[Boone] So maybe death
isn't the end, huh, Doc? Huh?
- [Chattering]
- [Man] Good morning, Torrez.
- What'll it be, darling?
- Yeah, um, draft.
A draft comin' up.
I'm looking for a place
called Midian.
You're not the only one.
A bunch ofTV news folk
passing through.
Ever since they nailed
that baby slasher up there.
- Baby slasher?
- Been a hell of a week for us.
Took 30 shots
to bag that sucker.
What is it?
Men or money?
Whenever I cry,
it's usually men or money.
[Crying]
A man.
What'd he do? Leave?
Not exactly.
He didn't come back,
did he? That's even worse.
Some loser
gets a crush on you,
you could throw him in the river
tied to a piano,
he'd come back faster
than a dog with a bone.
Oh! Why I bother
to look so good...
when there's on one here
to admire the end product is beyond me.
- Know what I mean?
- Yeah, I can't argue with that.
Do you want a drink?
I want a drink.
[Indistinct Howling]
[Indistinct Chattering]
You'll enjoy this.
No, really!
You hit me again,
I'm gonna rip your face off.
It's just a way to say
welcome to the club.
I'm not so sure
I want to be in the club.
You found your way back here
for the same reason I did.
We belong here. There's no place else
on earth would take us in.
Go on in.
They're waiting for you.
That's Lylesberg, the boss.
Who's that girl?
Shunma Sassi. Why?
I dreamt about her.
I dreamt him.
- Who is your advocate?
- I am.
- Have you tutored him in the law?
- Yes, he has.
Let the advocate answer.
[Advocate]
Yes, I have.
You understand what you do,
joining us here tonight?
You leave the natural
world behind.
The life you lived
will be a dream.
I know.
The blood of Baphomet
knows all truth.
Are you prepared
to be judged by the gods?
Yes, I am.
Aaron Boone...
the tribes of the moon
embrace you.
[Whistles]
[Indistinct Congratulations]
You were wonderful.
[Indistinct Howling]
Music. Music. [Country]
Bon appetit.
Hi.
How's your head?
Please.
But it was worth it.
Lori, my grandmother
always used to say,
"Sheryl Ann, there's
a man walking around out there
with your name on his mind.
All you gotta do
is run into him."
Of course, he happened to be checked
in here at the crossroads of the world?
He's fabulous.
His name is Curtis,
and he's a banker.
He's just moved to Edmonton
since he got his divorce.
And best of all...
he thinks I'm wonderful.
Sheryl, are you sure
you want to come along?
Oh, yeah.
I wouldn't miss it.
Beside, Curtis has
some business to do today.
But we're meeting tonight,
so that's okay.
- My God!
- Looks like the gold rush is over.
- Why the hell
would Boone come out here?
- To get away from it all?
Shut up, Sheryl Ann.
Look, you go do
whatever it is you have to do.
I'll stay here and,
uh, do something else.
All right.
I'll see you later.
[Bird Squawks]
So this is Midian.
[Radio Tuning]
Music. This is someone else's soul music.
Music. Someone that I never knew music.
Music. This is someone else's body music.
- Curtis.
- music. Am I getting through to you music.
What are you doin' here?
- music. Lf you feel the way we all do music. Music.
- Hello, Sheryl.
[Indistinct Moaning]
[Moaning Continues]
Bring her.
Please bring her.
Don't be frightened.
All right.
Pick her up.
O-Okay... hold still.
Come on.
Come on. No, it's okay.
It's all right.
Hurry, please. Bring her.
Please bring her to me.
Pay no attention.
Just give her to me.
Babette, no!
What's happening?
- [Gasping]
- What? Is it sick?
- What's happening to it?
- Mommy, help me.
Jesus!
What the hell is this?
She likes to play outside.
I tell her the sun will hurt her.
She's just a child.
She doesn't understand.
She likes to play outside?
You saved her.
I owe you something.
Listen, I know
why you've come.
Is Boone here?
Did somebody bring him here?
Rachel, you have said
too much already.
But, Lylesberg,
she saved Babette.
We know.
But you cannot help her.
Look... I don't know
who you people are,
but I saved the child's
life, didn't I?
So don't I deserve
something for that?
The child has no life to save.
But what it has is yours,
if you want it.
That is the law.
Do you want her?
No! No, thanks.
No, I just want some answers.
But to speak of this to anyone
would bring dire consequences.
- What is that? A threat?
- Not to you. To us.
What's below... remains below.
This is the law.
Boone. Aaron Boone.
Just tell me, is he here?
You took him.
You took his body, didn't you?
I need to know. Didn't you!
I'm sorry.
Please don't go.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute!
Where'd they go?
[Shrieking]
[Screaming]
She's mine!
[Screaming Continues]
Y'all come back now, ya hear?
[Laughs]
Sheryl, we're goin'.
I saw...
Something's kinda come up,
and, um, l...
music. Music. [Radio: Country]
Sheryl?
[Bird Squawking]
[Insects Buzzing]
Oh, my God.
- Lori.
- How do you know my name?
Oh, that's a good question.
Here's the answer.
Oh, no.
Boone's alive, Lori.
Nd you're death is gonna
bring him out of hiding.
Somebody help me!
[Rumbling]
Oh!
[Whimpering]
I'm not gonna let her die!
You made an oath
to obey the law.
I'm not gonna let him
butcher her.
[Screaming]
Bitch!
- I love her.
- But she's a Natural.
- She can't love you. Not now.
- I don't care.
[Grunting]
Boone! Boone!
Lie still.
It's quicker that way.
Decker!
You're here.
Isn't this where the dead
are supposed to go?
- But you're not dead.
- Oh, you're wrong, Decker.
We're both dead.
- Boone.
- [Grunting]
Don't you get it?
Blades are no better than bullets.
I'm dead.
I'm the walking dead.
Are you gonna kill him or not?
Only I want his balls.
And his eyes. Unless,
of course, you want them.
I think I'll pass.
Remember me, Doctor?
I was dying when you
had your way with me.
- [Grunting]
- You made me give up my secrets...
when I was feeling
particularly vulnerable.
- Now!
- No!
[Grunts]
He's mine!
Pretty sweet.
[Screaming]
[Growling]
I wasn't gonna hurt her.
I only wanted to keep her warm.
She's not gonna like
the way you look.
You've put us all in danger
for your love of this woman.
- Decker won't tell anyone.
- He can still lead our enemies here!
If he does, and Midian is unearthed,
you are responsible.
I'll make amends.
Just take the girl!
Go on your way amongst the Naturals!
That is the law.
We got visitors, boy.
- Can I use your phone?
- Yeah.
Don't know if it works.
Broke down, did you?
You ain't gonna get nobody
to come out here.
- Nobody never comes out here.
- Get me InspectorJoyce.
Dr. Phillip Decker.
You been up to Midian?
[Chuckles]
Kind of smelt like you had.
Where exactly
is the town of Midian?
It ain't no town.
Just a cemetery.
Joyce? Decker. Listen,
I found out where Boone is.
- Where are the nearest police?
- Shere Neck.
Shere Neck. Yes.
I'll meet you in Shere Neck.
- Who's buried in Midian.
- Dead folk.
Prospectors come from all over
and got buried up there.
- But there's something else.
- Ain't nothin' but dead folk.
Thanks.
[Dogs Barking]
[Groans]
Had to happen sooner or later.
They couldn't hide forever.
[Barking Continues]
It's all right, boy.
It's all right.
Everything's gonna be all right.
- [Man Screams]
- [Cat Meows]
[Mutters]
What the hell is this?
It was Boone up there.
- Yes.
- But Boone's dead.
- I saw him in the morgue.
- You still don't understand.
You're below now,
with the Nightbreed.
The last survivors
of the great tribes.
- Okay, tribes of what?
- We're shape-shifters. Freaks.
Remains of races that your tribe
have all but driven to extinction.
- So you're not immortal?
- Far from it.
The sun can kill some of us,
like Babette.
Some of us can be shot down.
Others can survive that because
they've gone beyond death.
This is too weird.
To be able to fly?
To be smoke?
Or a wolf?
To know the night and live
in it forever. That's not so bad.
You call us monsters.
But when you dream,
you dream of flying
and changing...
and living without death.
You envy us,
and what you envy...
We destroy.
Babette, show her.
Show her the past.
[Woman Wailing]
[Wailing Continues]
[Shudders, Gasps]
We are all that remain.
So you're saying, you're saying
that Boone's like you?
Yes. He's Nightbreed.
No, that's not possible.
- I gotta find him.
- He's beyond your help.
Where did he go?
Down to the tabernacle.
To Baphomet.
- Who's that?
- The baptizer.
Who made Midian. Who called us here
and saved us from our enemies.
- Okay, take me there.
- It's forbidden.
We'll see about that.
I told you everything I know.
- No, no. The monsters.
- N-Nightbreed?
- Can they die?
- What harm they ever done to you?
Can they die!
- Yeah.
- How?
Well, there are
all kinds of Breed...
and all kinds of ways
to kill them.
Uhh... bullets for some
and f-fire for others.
Why is it that you know
so much about them?
L-I wanted to be one of'em.
They...
Did they kick you out?
Is that why you
hate 'em so much?
[Laughs]
I'm not one of them.
I'm here to destroy them.
You see, I've cleaned up
a lot of breeders.
Families like cesspools.
Filth making filth making filth.
And I did it over and over
and over again,
but it was all
leading me here.
I was born to destroy
the whole Nightbreed together.
Y-You're crazy.
No, I'm death.
Plain and simple.
Say it!
[Screaming]
[Scoffs]
Then don't say it.
[Indistinct Chattering]
[Indistinct Snorting]
[Chattering Continues]
[Bird Squawking]
[Belching]
[Shrieking]
Ahhhhh!
[Indistinct Wailing]
There goes the neighborhood.
Boone?
Looking for Boone?
[Gurgling]
Boone?
Boone!
Damn it, Boone.
No one here by that name.
- [Gasps]
- Told you.
I know you.
He's talked about you...
Lori.
Pretty little butterfly.
Nice.
You're still a Natural.
- Want to join the family?
- No!
You will.
Sooner or later,
you'll want to live forever.
- No!
- [Laughs]
- Okay, Decker, what do you got?
- I found Boone.
Somebody stole the corpse,
brought it down here?
There is not corpse.
He's not dead.
He was shot, pumped full
of bullets. I saw it.
I saw it too,
but he's alive.
- He's killed again.
- In Shere Neck?
No. No, up in Midian.
Gentlemen.
Captain Eigerman.
InspectorJoyce,
Calgary Police Department.
This is Dr. Decker.
And this is Shere Neck.
Midian is my jurisdiction.
Boone was my prisoner.
We can work together.
No, we can't.
I'll bring him in myself.
- But he's not alone anymore.
- I've heard that talk.
- It's nuthouse talk.
- What talk?
Midian. Something is breeding there,
underneath the cemetery.
- Bullshit.
- You believe that?
Yes, I do. If somebody doesn't stop
them, there's gonna be more bloodshed.
I promise.
[Narcisse]
Hey, you're really light on your feet.
You may not be gorgeous,
but you'll do for me.
[Chuckles]
Up and about already?
- Just stay away from me.
- Hey, I'm sorry about upstairs.
But I see a pretty face,
and I just had to kiss it.
[Kisses, Laughs]
- Hey, you can't go down there!
- Why not?
Isn't this a great place?
Shangri-la on dope.
We love it!
- What's that smell?
- [Sniffs]
Not me.
- [Screams]
- The Berserkers are down there.
Mad bastards.
They'll rip off your head
and shit down your neck.
- Did Boone go down there?
- And he won't be coming back.
- He's not dead.
- He's more than that.
If you don't believe me,
just wait till he comes to...
[Sniffs]
Sniff a little blood.
That'll bring out
the beast in him!
You can't go down there!
You need some beauty sleep.
Hey, love those tattoos!
Sailors.
[Creature Shrieks]
Help me!
[Growling]
Come back here!
Come back!
Hey! Shine!
- [Screams]
- Slaughter! You missed.
Where's Boone?
This way.
[Creatures Shrieking]
[Thunder Rumbling]
Boone! Boone!
Don't look!
Come on!
Well, well.
Guess he can't take the heat.
[Gasps]
[Grunts]
Thank God. Let's go.
I can't go out there.
I belong here!
Now listen to me.
You belong with me.
That's why you lived.
That's why we both survived...
because we belong together.
Don't you see
they don't need you?
Nobody needs you but me.
- Okay.
- Okay?
I love you.
Come on.
[Bird Squawking]
[Woman]
There's no answer from the room.
I tried twice.
Huh? Oh.
Yeah, the key's still here.
I don't know.
I haven't seen them.
Arnie! Hey, Arnie!
Where the fuck is he?
Arnie!
Listen, I'm gonna have to
get someone back to you on that.
Okay? Yeah.
Oh, shit.
Oh, God. What a mess.
Gross me out.
- Arnie?
- [Thud]
[Screaming]
Okay. I'll get my stuff
in two minutes.
[Car Door Closes]
- What's wrong?
- Why is it so empty?
Must be the rodeo.
- [Sniffs]
- I smell blood.
It's okay.
[Woman On C.B. Radio]
Shere Neck Police.
Boone! Next door.
It was Decker.
Decker did this.
Boone, what's wrong?
What is it?
I don't want you to see!
- Get out!
- I'm not gonna leave you!
- [Growls]
- [Screams]
In! Go! Go!
[Guns Cocking]
[Lori]
They're coming!
[Grunting]
Go!
[Offiicer]
Freeze!
Up, up, up, up!
Get him up!
Christ, he stinks!
[Guard]
What are you looking at?
Move!
[Guard]
Captain.
[Yells]
You are a freak and a cannibal,
and you've come to the wrong town.
Get the door. I'm gonna give you
something to remember me by.
- [Thudding]
- [Door Slams]
- [Grunting]
- [Guards Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
Fuckin' cannibal.
Creep!
[Men Arguing]
- Put him in my custody now!
- Still here, huh?
- I'm gonna go back to Midian with you.
- [Phone Ringing]
Yeah?
I'll be right there.
I'm not going anywhere with you.
I got a press conference to deal with.
- Now you tell him
I've got Boone under control.
- Don't trust him.
- He changes.
- Sure he does.
Eigerman,
he was right about the motel.
- So what?
- So maybe there are others.
- What are you talking about?
Monsters?
- Aliens, a cult.
- I don't know. We should check it out.
- You wanna go out there?
- Yeah.
- Okay, we'll go out there. Pettine.
- Yo, Chief.
- You and some of the boys take
InspectorJoyce out to Midian.
Look around that graveyard.
If you see anything with more
than two eyes, give me a holler.
In the meantime,
I got a press conference. Good-bye.
Hey, the doctor's here
to examine you, freak,
just so no one can say
we laid one finger on you.
[Laughing]
He looks okay to me.
What do you think, Doc?
- No pulse.
- [Laughs] What's that?
The man is dead.
- [Gun Cocks]
- [Train Whistle Blowing In Distance]
What the hell are you
trying to do to me?
I don't understand what the hell
is going on around here!
Now, how many bullets did they pull out
of that geek up in Midian?
- Why?
- Why? You tell him why!
- I can't get a pulse on him.
- Jesus Christ!
- Are you saying he's dead?
- Not lying-down dead, my friend.
Walkin' around
in my fuckin' cell dead.
Now, what have you got
to say about that?
Can you hear me?
They'll find a way to kill you, Boone.
You know that?
Are you listening?
You're an abomination, Boone.
You have to die.
You hear me?
There's people down there.
I can feel it.
If there is,
we call for backup.
- Oh, shit.
- Was that something?
I don't know.
Maybe we're just all spooked.
Hell, who'd want
to live in a graveyard?
What do you say, Inspector?
- Let's just call it a day.
- [Dog Growls]
- [Dog Barking]
- No, no, no, no!
[Yelling]
No!
[Screaming]
Do you want me
to interrogate it, Inspector?
- Give him some air.
- What the hell for?
- Can't you see there's
something wrong with him?
- [Screaming Continues]
God, get him off me!
Damn it, get him off me!
- [Whimpers]
- [Coughing]
Jesus Christ on a crutch.
He was just dust?
It was the sun.
The sun did it.
We got the perfect weapon
right over our heads.
Yeah, just
until it goes down.
- [Coughing]
- [Explosion]
[Car Horn Honking]
Oh, no, shit!
Pettine!
Goddamn it, get out here!
- Who did it?
- [Laughing]
[Narcisse] Why do we
have to get him back?
Maybe Baphomet
told him something...
something
that could save Midian.
- Pettine, what's your status?
- They torched our car. Lousy freaks!
King, get in here.
- Yes, sir?
- I think it's about time
we go out there, don't you?
Reverend Ashberry,
your services are required.
- He looks like a drunk.
- He is a drunk.
Lost his brain. Now you wouldn't want
to miss theJudgement Day, would you?
The apocalypse?
It's here?
Well, they're warming up for it
over in Midian.
I want you to go to your church
and get crosses...
and prayer books and Bibles and
whatever the hell else you people use.
'Cause we're goin' out there
with God on our side.
[Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
Whether it's Commies, freaks or
Third-World Y-chromosome mutants,
we are there.
Sons of the Free.
- Come on, guys! Let's get 'em!
- [Indistinct Shouting]
Hey, freak-face, we found your pals.
They're gonna fry just like you.
Hey, Constable Labowitz,
something to blow your brains?
- Beauteous.
- All right.
- Suck on that.
- [Laughs]
Hey, who's there?
What's the problem?
No problem!
Shit!
- [Grunting]
- Hold him!
[Grunting Continues]
- [Alarm Ringing]
- You all right, Coback?
Where is he?
Where's Boone?
Cell three, through the door.
I love a coward.
[Laughing]
Don't think you're getting broke free!
No way they get through that door!
It's solid steel!
Do you hear me, freak?
Jesus Christ!
Oh, fuck me.
[Grunts]
I do not want to hurt you.
[Blows Kiss]
Naughty, naughty.
- I want you to wait out here.
- Brave girl.
I'm not afraid of you.
[Whispering]
I don't wanna be dust.
I want us flesh and blood.
[Boone Grunting]
No time for hoochie-coochie.
Are we going?
[Snickering]
Did you ever perform
an exorcism, preacher?
- No.
- I suggest you start rehearsing.
- Better take one of these.
- I wouldn't know what to do with it.
"So Moses spoke to the people, saying,
"'Arm yourselves for war and go
and take vengeance for the Lord...
"on Midian.'
"And so they burned with fire
all the cities where they dwelt...
and killed the kings of Midian,
both man and beast. "
Ooh, Doc, it sounds like we're goin'
head-to-head with the Devil himself.
- I don't believe in the Devil.
- Oh, but you will.
Hot damn!
[Shouting, Cheering]
[Gunshots, Cheering]
All right, let's move in.
It's only a mile or two more.
- There's a shortcut near here.
- [Boone] Where?
Now!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move it!
Move it, move it!
What are you doing here,
Decker?
You'll miss all the fun.
I just found something in there I really
think you ought to take a look at.
What the hell is this,
Decker?
T minus ten seconds.
Five, four, three,
two, one.
We are too late.
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
Looks like the millennium
just ended.
[Yelling]
[Growling]
Stand up, fucker!
[Tires Screeching]
[Man Screaming]
Bastards.
- [Lori] Rachel! Rachel!
- Babette!
Babette, no!
[Screaming]
[Lylesberg]
Stay down! This is our home!
We belong here!
Stay where you are!
- They're waiting for us above!
- No!
Don't listen to him!
We'll all be slaughtered!
If you want to live, it won't be here,
and it won't be by your laws.
Now if we want to survive,
we can't hide.
Brothers and sisters,
it is time to fight!
Outstanding.
[Screaming Continues]
[Whimpers]
Come on! Don't look down!
Hurry, hurry!
Women and children upstairs!
- You heard what he said.
- What chance have we got?
- They're armed.
- So am I.
Come to Daddy.
[Shouting Continues]
[Gunfire Continues]
Babette! Come on.
- Come on.
- [Man] Hey!
It's my lucky day!
- [Gun Cocks]
- But she's just a kid.
[Grunting]
[Screaming]
You found her.
[Screaming, Gunfire Continue]
Come on!
Hey, look what we got here.
- [Screaming]
- Say good night.
[Grunting]
Don't be afraid.
It's all right.
Which way is safe?
- You've got to stop.
- [Man Yells]
There are children
down there.
You're killing children!
Go ahead, faggot.
Don't!
- Sorry, padre.
- Eigerman!
[Grunts]
- Hey, papa.
- [Whimpers]
We don't like priests here.
[Screaming]
[Whimpering]
- [Laughing]
- Ow!
Je...
What the fuck is this?
[Moaning]
[Moaning Continues]
I don't feel so good.
Kane!
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Laughing]
What the hell are you doing down here?
Your people need you.
Baphomet is going to destroy us all...
the Naturals, the Breed, Midian,
everything!
- How do you know?
- Take a look for yourself.
- The whole place is gonna blow?
- It's Baphomet's will!
Look, we can make it out!
But we need fighters.
- We're not warriors.
- What about the Berserkers?
Madness.
They're uncontrollable.
Better yet!
Let them out.
We are the tribes of the moon.
You said so.
The tribes of the moon.
I'll release them.
[Grunting]
- What's the plan?
- The usual.
You take the big guy.
- Sucker.
- [Shouting]
You don't want to do that.
Give me a good reason why not.
I'll give you two.
[Laughing]
- [Giggling]
- Ugh, what a mess!
My God.
[Screaming]
[Ashberry]
What have you done?
[Yells]
[Man]
Yo, Moses!
Watch the pretty light.
Wait for it.
- Here it comes!
- [Gunshot]
[Grunting]
[Screeching]
- [Screeching Continues]
- [Pounding On Door]
- [Pounding Continues]
- [Berserkers Grunting]
Shit!
Go get 'em, boys!
[Screaming]
[Roaring, Growling]
[Roaring, Growling Continue]
[Moaning]
[Whimpering]
[Screaming]
- Come on! Let's go!
- [Indistinct Shouting]
Cut it out!
Stop!
You goddamn cowards!
I'll kill you all!
Dennis, give me a weapon!
- [Roaring]
- [Yells]
[Groans]
Lori.
I didn't believe
in the prophesies.
It's all over.
What prophesies?
You want to see?
[Laughs]
- That's Boone.
- Yes, it's him!
All these years
waiting for a savior.
He hasn't saved us.
He's destroyed us.
I made him!
The bite... was mine.
The bite that mocks death.
- That doesn't make him yours.
- [Crashing]
[Gunfire Continues]
Quite a dance, huh? Death everywhere,
and you and me in the middle.
[Knife Clangs]
[Both Yelling]
[Grunting]
[Grunting Continues]
Come on!
[Grunting, Shouting Continue]
Boone!
Not yet!
One last dance?
Boone!
Oh, my God.
- Oh.
- Decker's dead.
[Sighs]
Pull the knife out.
[Screaming]
[Baphomet]
Boone!
Don't go.
I have to.
I'm responsible.
You have destroyed our refuge.
This was inevitable.
No home is forever.
You must rebuild
what you've destroyed.
You must find me.
Heal me.
Save me from my enemies.
You are no longer Boone.
You are Cabal.
Save me from my enemies.
Night-night, sweetheart.
Where will I find you
when I need you?
You'll find me.
And you'll need me.
I never touched
a legend before.
[Laughing]
I saw their god, Master.
He burned me.
I want to burn him back!
[Screams]
Hallelujah! Hallelujah!
Music. Music. [Choir]
Music. Music. [Country]
Music. This is someone else's soul music.
Music. Someone that I never knew music.
Music. This is someone else's body music.
Music. Am I getting through to you music.
Music. Lf you peel away the orange music.
Music. There's something underneath music.
Music. Lf you look below
for hidden treasures music.
Music. Underneath another layer music.
Music. Are you hiding underneath the sea music. Music.