SUBTITLES BY LUIS-SUBS
[UPBEAT ROCK PLAYING]
Rockin'.
[BELCHES] Trick or treat!
[LAUGHS]
You're just disgusting.
And turn that noise down!
Don't you dare, bitch,
get off that!
- Hey, Stooge.
- What?
Check out the old fart.
All right, dude!
Stooge is hellin' him.
Make yourself useful, okay?
Take the wheel.
Ahh!
[HONKING]
Hey, Grandpa, look in the mirror!
You stupid bastards!
Damn you all to hell!
Happy Halloween, asshole.
[LAUGHING]
Damn kids.
[DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE]
There's no fool like an old fool.
You son of a bitch!
Hey, hey, cool it, pops.
You want to blow
your pacemaker or somethin'?
[GIGGLING]
[SQUEAKING]
[GROANS IN FEAR]
Gee, mister, I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to scare you.
Get your hands off of me!
- Hey, calm down.
- Get away from me!
I... I was just trying to help.
I don't need your help,
you damn little whore!
Well fine, I wouldn't want to help
an old creep like you anyway.
Damn rotten kids.
They'll get what they deserve.
Yes, they'll get what
they deserve tonight.
- Judy.
- Sorry, Mom, I'm in a hurry.
Has Jay Jansen called?
Jay, no.
Oh, but that boy Sal, he stopped by
to see if your were home.
- Sal?
- Uh-huh.
[PHONE RINGING]
I'll get it.
Hello, Jay?
Hey, Judy, you almost ready to go?
Um, not quite.
I got stuck after school
helping Mrs. Evans out
with that drive for the homeless.
I told you that was a scam.
Well, someone has to do it.
Well, listen, there's been
a slight change of plan for tonight.
Wh... what do you mean?
I've got a better party to go to.
Does this mean I should find
another date for the dance?
[SCOFFS]
Of course not.
Hey, I thought you'd be happy
to go to a real party.
That school dance is for nerds.
Oh, okay, sure, why not?
Who's giving it?
I don't know if you know her,
her name's Angela.
Angela?
No, the only Angela I know is that
weird girl in history class.
Well, as a matter of fact...
Jay, you've gotta be kidding.
Angela is such a weirdo.
Frannie says she's into witchcraft
and all sorts of creepy stuff.
Come on, you don't believe
all that, do you?
It's a bunch of crap.
Just a lonely old misfit trying
to get some attention
by acting weird, that's all.
So, why in the world would
you want to go to her party then?
Because it's Halloween.
Who do you know
that'll give a better party?
It's like Christmas to her.
Do we have to?
Come on, Max and Frannie are going.
It'll be fun.
Oh, all right, I guess so.
[SCOFFS]
I can't wait to meet her family.
She probably lives in a belfry.
Well, it's...
it's not at her house.
It's at Hull House.
Hull House?
Jay.
Pick you up in 20.
[DIAL TONE]
- [ROARS]
- [SHRIEKS]
Wow, bodacious boobies, sis.
You keep growin' you'll have to hire
someone just to tie your shoes.
Ooh, out!
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
I'll get it
Uh!
[OWL HOOTS IN DISTANCE]
[CREAKING]
[DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE]
Boo!
[LAUGHS]
I wish I had a camera.
You looked like
you dropped a load, Junior.
Hey-hey, cool it, squirt.
Who do you think you are,
Rocky Balboa?
Let me go, creep!
Sure.
Now go tell that pretty little piece
you call your sister
that handsome hunk Sal is here.
And tell her I brung my pet
snake for her to play with.
Judy's gettin' ready
for a date, butt hole.
If I were you, I'd get outta here
before he shows up
and turns your ugly face
into a punching bag.
Don't give me that shit, punk.
Go get your sister
before I lose my cool.
What's the matter,
you didn't hear what I said, bozo?
Let me go or I'll yell for my mom.
Aww, go on, baby.
What's the matter,
you can't take a joke?
Now, go get your sister.
Judy's gettin' dressed.
She's goin' to a party.
Party, what party?
Wouldn't you like to know.
Oh, you little asshole.
Oh, Mother!
Hey, hey. hey, hey.
Come on spill the beans, ace.
Here, here's a nice chunk of change
to loosen your lips a little.
Are you kidding, betray my beloved
sister for a measly quarter?
What do you think this is,
some kind of depression
or something?
Oh, that does it.
[FEMALE]
Billy, did you call me?
Hey, hey, hey,
this is my final offer, kid.
Now take it and sing.
Where's the friggin' party?
Sure, you'll be too chicken
to crash it anyway.
Hey, try me.
- It's at Hull House.
- Hull House?
Huh!
What are trying to pull, Shorty?
Your sister wouldn't be caught dead
in a dump like that.
What do you think I am,
some kind of idiot or what?
What I think is besides the point.
Hull House tonight.
Better be straight, Billy boy.
Or I swear I'm gonna come back here
and kick your little ass.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, my mask.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
[WHISPERS]
Fag.
[VIDEO GAME BEEPING]
[WHISTLING]
[VIDEO GAME BEEPING CONTINUES]
Do you guys have sour balls?
Why, sure we do.
Too bad, I bet you don't get
many blowjobs.
[DING]
[LAUGHING]
You think you got enough stuff?
Come on, we don't want to be late
to our own party.
Come on, your face looks fine.
I've never seen anybody spend
more time in a mirror.
Relax, I just want
to look good for the boys.
You did remember to invite some cute
boys to the party I hope.
Of course I did.
And we're gonna scare
the shit out of 'em.
[RAPPING]
[BILLY] Cutie, Prince
Charming's here.
[SCREAMING ON TV]
Well, you must be
Judy's little brother, huh?
Huh, that's pretty lucky.
She's, uh, she's a real nice girl.
Yeah, are you dating her
for her personality
or because she has big cha chas?
Well, hello there.
- You must be Jay.
- Yeah.
Would you like a fudge log?
Oh, gee...
Hey, I'd love to, but I'm trying
to watch my weight.
Oh, your weight...
you must be kidding.
You're skinny as a rail.
Oh, come on, Jay, don't be shy.
Have one... I just took 'em
out of the oven.
No thanks, Mrs. Cassidy, really.
- You're sure.
- Yeah.
Of course, he's sure, Ma.
Why would he want one?
They look like
sun-dried poodle turds.
Billy.
Why me?
Hey, you look great.
You're the best bride
of Frankenstein I ever saw.
Jay, I thought you were gonna
wear a costume.
Well, I was, but I...
He is, he's the boogeyman.
Can't you tell?
He's the pick of the litter.
Billy, please.
Happy Halloween, sweetheart.
Um, we better hurry.
Uh, yeah, Max and
Frannie are waiting.
Good night, girls,
have a nice time.
Enjoy the dance.
God, I'm so embarrassed.
My mom and her cereal box recipes.
Hey, forget it.
Come here.
Jay, slow down, okay?
Yeah, right, sure,
we've got all night.
Come on.
Whoever drew up this map
must have been half blind
and half retarded.
Sounds like Angela.
Dizzy fuckin' bitch, man.
Stooge, did you become an asshole
of your own free will
or were you born that way?
- [LAUGHS]
- Did you hear somethin' funny?
I don't know why I'm hangin' out
with you two wipes.
- Give me that damn map!
- Hey!
Great, Stooge,
now look what you've done.
- Typical.
- Typical!
Shut up and drive, bitch!
Look here...
turn here!
Well, if the party's a real drag,
we can always come back
to my house.
Here they come.
Well, thank God you two have
the Halloween spirit.
At least I won't be
the only one wearing a costume.
Oh, you didn't really expect
to see Jay in a costume.
Jay's way too cool for that.
- [GIRL GIGGLING]
- [JAY] Just get in the car, Max.
[CAR STARTS]
Great.
Just great.
You know, I always wondered why
they called you Stooge.
Hey, look, I said I
always carry a spare.
I never promised you a tire iron.
You know, we really must have taken
a wrong turn somewhere.
No one would give a party out here.
Look, we definitely did not take
any wrong turns, okay?
I know where Hull House is.
It ain't far from here.
So, shut up and start walkin'!
- Great.
- Walk?
Are you fat and dumb?
Hey, here comes a car.
Must be my good karma.
- [HONKS]
- [STOOGE] All right, Jay buddy!
You got here just in time, dude.
You guys need a hand?
We sure do.
See ya.
I'm so glad I let you guys
talk me into this.
Shouldn't we at least
help them change their tire?
For Chrissakes, Judy,
it's only a flat tire.
I think even Stooge
can figure that one out.
Hey, there it is, stop the car.
[FRANNIE] This place was once
a funeral parlor, wasn't it?
[MAX] Yeah, biggest one
in four counties.
A funeral parlor, way out here?
Sure, it's nice and cozy,
right next to the old cemetery.
And rumor has it, old man Hull
really loved his clientele...
I mean, in the carnal sense.
Yeah, that doesn't surprise me.
I once saw a portrait of Mrs. Hull.
[FRANNIE] I've heard stories about this
place ever since I was a kid.
The Hull family met a pretty
gruesome end, didn't they?
They sure did.
As a matter of fact,
it was on Halloween night.
One of them went crazy
and slaughtered the entire family,
then committed suicide.
They could never figure
out who did it.
Too much blood and guts.
I can't believe
we're gonna party here.
[SIGHS]
Neither can I.
[BIRD CAWING]
[JAY] Hell, that was easy.
Didn't even lock the gate.
[MAX] Yeah, the county used to keep
this place locked up all the time.
Only the locks kept disappearing.
I guess they finally gave up.
[FANNIE] Well, it doesn't look like
much of a party happening here.
[JUDY] Maybe we could still
make the dance.
Max, what are you doing?
I'm just checkin' out
an old legend about this place.
Come here.
Judy, come here, will ya?
Come here, listen.
- Water.
- Yeah, an underground stream.
According to legend,
it completely surrounds the property.
This wall was built
right on top of it.
A brick wall on top
of an underground stream?
Now, there's a stroke
of engineering genius.
Well, the wall was built
to mark the stream.
Uh, supposedly the evil spirits
that haunt the land
can't cross over running water
or something.
Hey, can we go in now?
It's getting kind of chilly
out here.
Shh... listen.
What?
I don't hear anything.
That's what I mean.
Isn't it quiet?
Not even the crickets
will come to this property. [LAUGHS]
[JAY] Yeah, right, Max.
[RAPPING]
[COUGHING]
Oh, geez.
[FRANNIE] Somebody fire the maid.
[MAX] Yeah, somebody did.
The Hull family maid was killed
along with the rest of them.
Someone managed to roast her.
[JAY] Great, barbecue maid.
No wonder she didn't keep
the place clean.
[JUDY] Can we go home now?
I guess not.
[JAY] Hey, you guys,
check this out.
Oh, my God.
This must have been left here
by previous tenants.
[HONKING]
Okay, everybody hide... quick.
Get rid of your light.
Jay.
Come on, this is gonna be great,
just relax.
Arrgh!
- You dirt bag.
- Jay, no!
Hey, who's side are you on?
Who's side am I on?
You're acting like an idiot.
You were just about to climb in there
and scare somebody else.
Now are you going to punch out Sal
just because he beat you to it?
Yeah, yeah, lighten up, Jay-bo.
It's Halloween.
[AS DRACULA] Good evening,
allow me to introduce myself.
Yeah, Count Dingleberry,
the flaming asshole of Transylvania.
Aw, what's the matter, Maxie baby,
you pissed because I made you
lose your brewski?
Hey, Angela didn't tell me
this asshole was invited.
[FEMALE] He wasn't.
[CHUCKLES]
All right, dudes!
And dudesses.
[CHUCKLES]
Let's party!
[METAL ELECTRIC GUITAR RIFF]
[UPBEAT ROCK PLAYING]
Hey, Sal, where do you want this?
Hello, Sal, come in, Sal.
Earth to Sal.
Hey, yo.
Where are we gonna
put this thing, man?
It weighs a fucking ton.
[UPBEAT ROCK PLAYING]
[CRASHING]
Thanks.
Oh, I wouldn't do that,
if I were you.
Huh?
I wouldn't leave
that lighter lying there.
We wouldn't want the spirits
to see you littering up their place.
Would we now?
I'm sure they'll make
a federal case out of it.
Oh, have it your way.
Oh, this feels great, really.
- Uhh.
- Just what the doctor ordered.
What'd the wicked witch
of the West want?
- She tryin' to scare ya?
- Of course.
So, did she do it?
Are you kidding?
I'm not a baby.
That's the spirit.
Here, Max, this ought
to cool you down a little.
Thanks, babe.
Oh, how sweet.
- Far fucking out!
- All right! Whew!
I found it in my mother's closet.
She used to be an acid head.
Whoa!
Now we're cooking it up.
[MUSIC DISTORTS]
[GRUMBLING]
Holy shit.
Haven't you idiots ever
heard of Duracell?
Hey, look, don't blame me, man.
I just put batteries
in the damn thing this morning.
[SOBS] I can't live
without my music.
Forget it, there's plenty of time
for dancing later.
Now it's time for party games.
Yeah, we can play post orifice
and you can be the stamp.
[MAKES SLURPING SOUND]
Please don't make me ill.
I was thinking of something a
bit more in tune with the holiday.
Like what, bobbing for apples
with razor blades in 'em?
No, I was thinking more
along the lines of a séance.
A séance?
Isn't that a little chancy?
I mean, this is Halloween...
the night when all the creepy things
are supposed to stalk the Earth.
I mean, there's no telling
what we'll dredge up,
especially in this old place.
Hey you guys, how about
a past life séance?
A what?
A past life séance.
You know, we all sit around,
look in a mirror,
and see our past lives.
What kind of drugs
are we gonna need for this?
[LAUGHING]
Cool, will this do?
I'm afraid not, Suzanne, we need one
we can all look into at once.
[EERIE VOICE-LIKE SOUND]
What the hell was that?
I don't know, buddy,
let's go check it out.
Hey, hey, Stooge,
hey man, cut it out now.
[STOOGE] Oh, come on, Rodg,
now don't be afraid.
[CLAMORING]
Come on, Rodg, be a man.
- No, Stooge!
- Yes, Rodg!
[SCREAMING]
Are you okay?
What's the matter, Rodg,
you're white as a ghost.
Hey kids, you're not going to
believe what I found in here.
Oh, it's perfect.
I can't believe our luck.
[JUDY] Maybe this isn't such
a good idea after all.
Well, don't tell me
you're afraid too.
[STOOGE GROWLS]
Come on, it's just a mirror,
what harm can it do?
It's really very simple.
You just keep staring
at my reflection in the mirror
until the glass clouds
up all black.
When it clears, we'll see what
I looked like in a past life.
Sounds easy enough to me.
Yeah, right, and if you buy that,
I got this real nifty
bridge to sell ya.
[ANGELA] Everybody shut up.
Now, concentrate on my
reflection in the mirror.
[LAUGHING]
Concentrate.
I'm trying to, Ang, but I can't
get past that zit on your chin.
[LAUGHING]
Shut the fuck up, asshole.
If you're not going to help
us along, then get lost.
Okay, now concentrate.
Concentrate.
Holy shit.
You idiot, it was just
starting to work.
It was, I swear I saw
the mirror turning black.
Hey, I saw it too.
[SCREAMING]
[CRASHING]
- Jeez.
- Why the hell did you do that?
What is wrong with her?
Festerin' fuckwads, uh!
You cannot take
this bitch anywhere, man!
[WHIMPERS]
What happened, Helen,
what's the matter?
[WHIMPERING]
I saw something in the mirror.
Saw what in the mirror?
Oh, jeez, this bitch has flipped.
Shut up, Stooge,
you're not helping matters!
- [WHIMPERING]
- What?
[HYSTERICAL CRYING]
Probably saw Sal
in that stupid mask.
I wasn't wearing my mask.
Oh, God, that's even worse.
It doesn't matter
what she saw, does it?
If she saw anything.
It looks like our
little game is over.
Yeah, I just hope Helen didn't
piss off the owner of the mirror.
Ow.
I was only kidding.
[POUNDING IN THE DISTANCE]
Oh, no, here we go again.
Relax, it's probably just
someone arriving late.
You guys did invite some
other people to this party?
Angela?
Some cute boys, I hope.
[RUSTLING]
It sounds like it's coming
from the basement.
[RUSTLING LOUDER]
[GROWLING]
[GROWLING, BREATHING]
God, it's freezing in here.
Never mind the draft, man,
who cut the cheese?
Oh, P.U., that is rank.
Stooge must be wearing
his mom's dirty panties again.
Hey, man, as least
my old lady wears panties.
His just wears a coin
changer for sailors.
Your mom couldn't give it away.
God, man, it smells like
somebody died in here.
[ANGELA] I don't like what's
happening here.
[FEMALE] What do you mean?
[MALE]
I know what she means.
Like, come on, this ain't exactly
the most happenin' party
I ever been to, okay?
What do you mean, Angela?
Those noises that we heard,
there were three of them.
And that awful stink
and then the chill.
[FRANNIE] It's not cold now.
Must have been a draft.
Well, maybe somebody did come in.
[FEMALE]
The odor's gone too.
But we all experienced them...
the noise, the stink,
and the chill.
They're all signs of
demonic infestation.
Demonic what?
Demonic whatchamacallit.
I mean, come on!
Little Ang here is just trying to
put the old woo on us, okay?
Yeah, Ang, I'm sure
you're right, okay?
Or could it be that Rodg here
just had too much cold beer
and blew us a cool, stiff breeze
right out of his butt hole?
- [FARTING NOISE]
- [LAUGHING]
I don't care what you all think.
My daddy was a preacher.
And I know better than to be in here
fooling with this stuff.
This is a house of the dead.
And I'm gettin' out now
before it's too late.
Wow, hey, take a look at that.
What is that?
It smells like roses.
Hey, you know, I think we're
smelling multiple ghosts here.
I've read about things like this.
[FLAPPING]
[FARTING NOISE]
That is something, Max...
I never knew you could read.
No, really, Stooge,
I'm not kiddin'.
I read all the time.
Would you listen to me?
They're not ghosts.
This house is not haunted,
it's possessed.
[STOOGE LAUGHING]
Possessed, man, haunted... come on!
Who gives a shit!
What's the difference between
possessed and haunted?
A haunted house is a house
with ghosts in it...
the spirits of people who've died.
But the spirits living
in a house possessed
have never existed in human form.
They've only existed
in spirit form.
They're pure evil.
They're demons.
[LAUGHING]
Kids, come on,
you can't really believe
this place is possessed?
Nah, just repossessed.
[LAUGHING]
[MASCULINE VOICE]
For tonight anyway.
Maybe Rodger's right.
Maybe we should leave.
Aw, come on, let's hang out.
Yeah, eat a bowl of fuck!
- [LAUGHING]
- I am here to party.
- [CHEERING]
- Me too.
Just because one lame
wuss wants to bail,
doesn't mean we ace this party.
I want to go too.
We'll need a ride.
[CHUCKLING]
Hey, don't look at me, pal,
my cruiser's sittin' in a ditch
two miles from here, huh?
Hey, you know, you could spend
the night in it, though,
if you wanted to.
Oooh. [CHUCKLES]
Here, Rodg, take Angie's car.
Hey, what the fuck
do you think you're do...
Chill out, hon.
It's your party,
you ain't goin' anywhere.
Thanks Suzanne.
Don't mention it.
I don't care
if you're a chicken shit.
Just remember to open the gate
before you drive through it.
[LAUGHING]
[MALE] Bye Rodg.
Drive carefully, you guys.
Let's party.
- [HOOTS]
- Yeah.
Yeah, well you guys
can count us out.
Judy and I have some
exploring to do.
[MAX] Yeah, great idea.
Let's see what kind of action
we can dig up
in this glorious old dump,
huh, cutie?
I don't know, Jay.
Oh, come on, Judy.
Who knows, maybe we'll be able
to find a little privacy.
Hey, we'll check you guys out later.
Don't do anything stupid
while we're gone, huh?
Yeah, right, you all say hi
to Casper for me. [CHUCKLES]
Well, this party's gettin'
down to the cream now.
I think I'm gonna go
find the bathroom.
Mm, good idea,
I'll go too to protect ya.
Oh, no thanks,
I'd rather take Stooge.
Stooge?
Hey, you heard the lady, man.
She wants a real man
guardin' her charms.
Stooge is a fat pig.
Maybe I'm in the mood
for pork tonight.
[SHORTS]
[CREAKING]
I'm into all sorts
of things tonight.
I'll tell you what, babe,
I'll hold yours, if you hold mine.
I don't fuckin' believe this.
[DOOR CREAKS]
[FRANNIE LAUGHS]
Jeez.
Hey, you know what?
This reminds me of a great story.
You know, I think we've heard
enough stories for one night.
No, come on, let's hear it.
All right, but only
because you asked.
[SCOFFS]
Oh, God, this one better be it
or I'm gonna water the hallway.
- No, try this one.
- What?
Well, all right, Suzie-Q!
How did you know this?
Ladies before germs.
No, wait, um...
I thought... well, I thought maybe
we might could go in there together?
Huh?
Fuckin' party.
Whoa, Jesus!
Fuck!
Shit! Shit!
Yeah, but even before the first
white settlers colonized this area,
this strip of land already
had a bad rep.
Sure, Max.
Mm-mm... For centuries,
the ancient Indian tribes
that used to live around this
area would never set foot
on this side of the
underground creek.
Even back then, they said
the land was unclean.
Right, Max.
And I suppose the ghost
of an ancient Indian told you that.
No, Mrs. Porter down at the library
gave me a book that one
of the earlier settlers wrote.
I mean, you cannot believe all the cool
shit that used to go down here.
Yeah, especially since they didn't have
any indoor plumbing, right?
No, really.
A young brave got lost
and settled here
with his family by mistake.
Anyway, they found him
three weeks later
sitting under a tepee he made
out of his squaw's intestines
and chewing on the leg
of his papoose.
Oh, gross.
I've never heard so many
disgusting stories in all my life.
Oh, um, you know, I think it's time
that, you know, Frannie and I
did some exploring on our own.
Happy Halloween.
Happy hunting.
Yeah, this place is big enough.
I'm sure we'll find somethin'
interesting to do, right?
[SQUEALS]
[LAUGHING]
Well, Alice, looks like
we're all alone in Wonderland.
Well, what gives?
Not here, Jay.
What do you mean, "not here?"
This place, it's...
it's too creepy.
Well, that's the whole idea.
You're supposed to be
jumping into my arms.
Just hold me.
[SIGHS]
Where the fuck is
the God damn gate?
We came in through
a gate, didn't we?
This just doesn't make sense.
Give up already.
Give up?
Now, what kind of talk is that?
There was a gate here.
And if we just keep following
this damn wall,
we're bound to find it.
Look, we've already
been around it twice.
Don't you understand, Rodg?
We're dead.
We've all died and gone to hell.
What are you talking about?
Are you goin' crazy on me, girl?
Look, if that's all
that's on your mind,
you just better shut
that mouth of yours.
Shit!
Hell, my ass!
There is a gate here.
There is!
Oh, sweet mother.
Helen?
Helen!
This isn't funny, girl.
Helen?
Where the hell did she go?
[EERIE VOICE] Rodger.
Rodg.
Oh, heaven help me.
[GRUFF MALE VOICE] Rodger!
Jay, hold it.
Judy, come on.
Quit the act, I know
you've done this before.
What?
I saw the way
you jumped to Sal's aid.
Jay, what are you getting at?
I know all about you two.
Oh, really.
What do you know?
Nothing.
I just know that you used
to date Sal, that's all.
Date him?
I went out with him once.
Once is all it takes.
I don't understand why
you're acting like this.
Half the school knows
about you and Sal,
so what's the big deal?
Oh, so you think I slept with Sal
just because I went out with him.
Didn't you?
You know,
that's none of your business.
[SIGHS]
So, that's why you wanted
to go out with me?
Oh, come on, I thought you wanted it
just as much as I did.
[GRUNTS]
Jesus.
Fine, have it your way.
I'm outta here.
Jay, wait.
Come on, Jay.
[STOMPS]
Jay.
Come on, Jay!
Damn it, bitch, come on.
[STOOGE] What'd you do, flush yourself
down the fuckin' toilet, or what?
Open the damn door already!
[CRASHING]
Suzanne.
What the fuck?
[DRIPPING]
[DOOR SLAMS]
Jesus!
Suzanne?
Dizzy bitch.
[DOOR SHUTS]
Hey, Ang, what the fuck are
you doin' over there?
[WIND HOWLING]
Blessed be the sinners,
for the day of atonement
is at hand.
Say what?
[PANTING]
[UPBEAT MUSIC SWITCHES ON]
[BAUHAUS PLAYING "STIGMATA MARTYR"]
[CLICKING]
Whoa, Sal, easy man.
A little jumpy, huh?
Yeah.
Well, all right,
now the party's back.
And so is Stoogie.
Hey, careful, man,
she's actin' really fuckin' weird.
Don't worry, Sal,
it ain't the weird ones
you gotta watch out for.
God, didn't your mom teach
you nothin' about women?
Oh...
[MUSIC STOPS]
So, Ang, ya come here often?
[CHUCKLES]
[ANG LAUGHS]
You know, Stooge, I never
realized how sexy you are.
Kiss me.
Oh.
[CHUCKLES]
[STOOGE GAGGING]
[YELLING]
[BUZZING]
[DRIPPING]
Suzanne, lights.
I'm fixing my face.
Aw, shit, not you too?
What, is everybody here
on drugs or somethin'?
You know, you're a sweet
lookin' babe, Suzanne,
but you and your friend, Ang,
are just a little too weirdo for me.
I can't seem to get it right.
No thanks, honey,
I'm not that type of guy.
Good night, now, I'm going home.
You are home, Sal.
Un-uh, this dirty dive
don't spell home to me.
I live in a nice house, you know,
with plastic slip covers
on the furniture.
Enjoy your lipstick, dollface.
Good night.
My word, I can't believe
all this stuff is still here.
It's creepy in here.
Don't worry, I'll protect ya.
And who's gonna protect you?
[MAX CHUCKLES]
You know, I've never made it
in a coffin before.
Me neither.
So, what are we waitin' for?
[CHUCKLES]
[MALE] Suzanne?
What are you doing?
Now, that's not a bad paint job.
But I think that it needs
a little touching up.
Hey, when did the lights go on?
Okay, forget the lights.
Hey, Ang, I'm splittin'.
Oh, there you are.
I was just warming
my hands in the fire.
Holy shit!
Leaving so soon?
[KNOCKING, CREAKING]
Jeez, what an asshole.
Stooge, I know that's you, man.
Only a fat slob like you
could shake this car so much.
[SCREAMING]
[HUMMING]
Yeah.
All right.
Look at you.
Come here.
What are you looking at?
What?
Is my makeup okay?
Are you crazy, what are
you talkin' about?
Stop staring at me.
Damn it, Suzanne,
your makeup is fine.
Come on, what are
you worried about?
Uh!
Jesus Christ!
Stop looking at me!
Uh!
God damn it!
[YELLING]
[WHIMPERS]
What was that?
Uh, it's more party games.
Ow, Max, I don't bend that way.
Uh, shit.
Damn it, this is worse
than my brother's VDub.
Hey, man, get the fuck outta here!
- [GRAMS]
- [SCREAMING]
No!
No, Stooge!
No, Stooge, no!
Not... no!
No, please.
[YELLING]
[ANGELA]
Welcome back, Rodger.
Uh!
Sal, move!
Something...
It's Angela, man!
- She's... she's...
- Hey, I know, I know...
I know there's some really weird shit
going on around here.
Something happened to Helen.
What do you mean?
[SOBBING]
I don't know, man, I don't know.
Hey, hey, it's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay, man.
We're gonna get outta here, man.
We're gonna get outta here.
[HEAVY BREATHING]
Jay?
Jay, is that you?
Let me outta here.
[SAL] This way, come on,
follow me.
Jay.
Come on.
I knew we shouldn't have come here.
We're never gonna
get outta here, man.
Shut up, Rodg, shut up,
I swear I'm gonna slug you!
- [KNOCKING]
- What's that?
[JUDY] Help!
Somebody get me outta here.
Hold it!
How do we know it's really her?
Come on... Judy?
Get me out, Sal.
Please get me outta here.
Sure thing, Judy, stand back.
Wait!
What if it's not her?
Come on, Rodg,
who else could it be?
[HEAVY BREATHING]
[GROANING]
- Come on, get up, Judy!
- I can't!
I can't!
Yes, you can!
Come on!
Hey, there's no boards on it.
[BUZZING]
[SCREAMS]
Hey, how 'bout an orgy?
I'm sure if we try,
we can get Jay hard again.
Run, Judy!
Run, Judy, run!
[ROARS]
[SCREAMING]
Run, Judy, run.
See Judy run.
[CREAKING]
[SLAMS]
[WHIMPERS]
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
An air shaft?
No wonder why there weren't
any boards on the window.
Can't get the fuck outta here.
Thank heaven for water pipes.
[CREAKING]
Rodger.
[ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
Judy!
Judy.
Shh.
Judy, look out!
[GRUFF MALE VOICE]
Enjoying the view?
Judy!
[SCREAMING]
[YELLING]
[THUNK]
[JUDY WHIMPERING]
Oh, God, please don't let me fall!
Judy, work your way over this way.
Come on, Judy.
Yeah, come on,
just a little further.
[CRYING, WHIMPERING]
I can't do it!
Yes, you can!
Come on, woman, do it!
Don't look down, girl.
[SOBBING] Oh, Sal!
Come on.
You're almost home.
God... Judy, hurry up!
[SCREAMING]
You all right?
Yeah, I think so.
[GROWLING]
[SCREAMING]
Oh, don't tell me you're leaving?
Sal wanted to go,
but he decided to stick around.
[CHUCKLES]
[GROWLING]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[RODGER] Oh, God.
[RODGER SOBBING]
Shh, Rodg, come on,
it'll be all right.
Please don't cry.
We're gonna make it.
I know we're gonna make it.
You really think so?
You already saved
my life once tonight, didn't you?
That had to be for something,
right, Rodg?
I guess so.
[JUDY] There's a door.
Look, Rodg.
Maybe we can get out.
A door?
Yeah, look.
Judy, wait, don't!
We can't wait, Rodg.
We gotta try.
There's no other way out.
First, let's pray.
My daddy, he told me how
to pray real good.
Come on.
I've been praying all night, Rodg.
We gotta go now.
[CLUNK]
My God, what is this?
There's all this pipe running
along the wall.
It's weird.
- [WHIMPERS]
- What, what's wrong?
It's an oven.
A what?
It's an oven, Rodg.
This is a crematorium.
[BANGING]
[GROWLING]
[GRUFF MALE VOICE]
Open the door, Rodg.
We don't want you,
we want the bitch.
You know we'd never hurt
a nice little boy like you.
Go to hell, you dirty bastards!
Well, not tonight, my boy.
Oh, no, not tonight.
Rest assured we've got something
wonderful planned for you.
So much pain.
So much sorrow.
Did you hear what they said, Rodg?
Not tonight.
They won't go
to hell tonight because...
because it's Halloween, right?
That's why they won't go
to hell tonight, right?
Because it's the one night
of the year they don't have to.
Remember what Helen said, Rodg?
Didn't she say that tonight's
a special night of evil?
Remember?
Didn't she say that tonight's
the one night of the year
when all things unclean are free
to roam among us?
Remember?
That's what she said,
Rodg, right?
I think if we just
hang out here until... till dawn,
we'll be all right.
Yeah... yeah.
I bet you're right.
[CLICK]
[FEMALE] Judy?
[CLINK]
Oh, dear God, no.
I warned you this house
was possessed.
Didn't I?
We can't let them get us, Rodg.
We can't give up, Rodg.
[CLINK]
We've gotta find a weapon.
A Pipe.
[GROANING]
[HISSING]
Gas.
[YELLING]
I can't stop it, Rodg, help me!
Please come and help me!
Find the valve, Rodg, the valve.
[YELLS]
Rodger, wait.
[CLUNK]
[DOORS CLOSING CONTINUES]
Rodger.
We can't get out.
- Judy.
- Oh, Jay, no.
Why hast thou forsaken me?
[GRUFF MALE VOICE]
What's the matter, Judy?
Don't you like your blind date?
[CRIES OUT]
You won't get me!
Rodger!
I'm alive.
Hey, we're out.
No, Rodg, we have
to get past the wall.
We have to cross over
the underground stream.
- Where are you going?
- We have to get to the gate!
- There is no gate.
- The gate's over here, Rodg!
There is no gate, come on!
[JUDY] Ow!
Ow!
[GRUFF VOICE]
Rodger!
[RODGER GROANING]
Judy, give me your hand.
Come on.
[CRIES OUT]
[GROWLING]
Help me, Rodger!
[SCREAMING]
Judy, Rodger, where you going?
The party's just begun.
[SCREAMING]
Rodger!
Help, Rodger, help!
Rodger, help!
Climb, girl, climb!
[WIND BLOWING]
[GROWLING]
[YELLING]
Rotten pig trash.
Been out all night, huh?
[CHUCKLES]
Eh, they'll all rot in hell.
Huh, kids.
Good morning, dear.
Yeah, what's so good about it?
Better drink your coffee
before it gets cold.
Eh.
Is it good, dear?
Nah, it's okay.
Just okay?
You used to love my homemade pies.
Homemade?
When did you make this?
I've been up for hours, sleepyhead.
I made it while you were getting
your beauty rest.
Last night?
There weren't as many
trick-or-treaters last night.
Not like the good old days.
I had to do something
with all those leftover apples.
I still can't understand why
you buy so many.
Uh!
[GROANING]
Happy Halloween, dear.