Lucy, calm down.
I... I see something horrible happening.
You're just having another nightmare.
I'm scared.
Relax... It's only a bad dream.
Jonathan. You're working too hard.
It's not good for you.
I'm worried about you.
Good morning.
Ah, Harker, please come up here.
Yes, Mr. Renfield.
I have a very important job for you.
And I don't trust anyone else
to do it, but you.
You're very kind, Mr. Renfield.
Count Dracula...
...he sent me a letter from Transylvania.
He wants to buy a house around here.
I'm aware that it's a long trip to
go there.
Where is that?
Somewhere over the
Carpathian mountains, isn't it?
Yes...
...and there will be a large commission.
Oh, then I could get
a larger house for Lucy.
She deserves a nicer house.
Well, this won't be easy.
It'll take you a long time...
...you'll sweat a lot...
...and perhaps you'll also...
...spill some blood.
It'll be good for me
to get out of the city...
...get away from these canals...
...which go nowhere.
Transylvania...
...there it is, beyond the forest.
It's a wonderful place.
A little gloomy, maybe, but very exciting.
The Count is looking
for a beautiful old house.
I'm going to show him the big house,
near your place.
But it's been abandoned for years.
It looks like a haunted house.
I'm sure he'll feel
very comfortable there.
Anyway, we'll offer it to him.
I'd like you to leave soon.
Soon? You mean, today?
Absolutely. I even prepared the papers.
It's bad business to let him wait.
Very well.
If you insist, I shall leave today.
Today? Are you serious?
Yes, to a castle in Transylvania.
I hear it's a strange place infested with
wolves and people who see ghosts.
Jonathan, it scares me...
I don't want you to go.
I'll be fine.
You'll be in danger.
Don't go.
Wolves. Bandits. And ghosts.
Don't go. I won't allow it.
Let's go to the ocean, now.
To the place where we fell in love.
Lucy...
...I don't know.
Sometimes I feel so ignorant.
Jonathan, I really have to say this...
...even if you think it comes from...
...the weak heart of a woman...
...your wife.
Yes?
It really comes from the strength
of my heart.
I feel a kind of...
...dark force...
...like a nameless deadly fear.
Lucy is the dearest thing in the world
to me...
...take care of her.
Mina, treat her as a sister.
Yes.
Innkeeper! Quick, my supper. I must go
to the castle of Count Dracula tonight.
Are you really going there?
Yes. Why?
It's not a safe place.
Why do you want to go there?
At midnight evil spirits come out.
And people disappear without a trace.
Oh, come on, that's all superstition.
Not at all.
Bad things will happen to you if you
go there.
Besides, no coachman will dare
take you there...
...your horse needs a rest
for several days.
I'll find another horse.
Don't go, sir.
I know a few gypsies...
...who have been on the other side...
...and they can tell you.
He also says you shouldn't go there,
young man.
He says there's a great chasm on the
way that swallows the unwary.
If that doesn't get you,
he says the towering crags will.
And in the Borgo pass...
...the light suddenly divides and...
...the land begins to rise
towards the heavens...
...and then it drops. No one has ever
returned from that place.
The gypsies say that
no such castle exists there...
...except maybe in the imagination
of man.
There used to be a castle there. But
now it is a ghost castle. It's only a ruin.
And whoever enters into that land of
phantoms is lost...
...and never returns.
Of vampires and bloodsuckers.
Of corpses which devour their own flesh.
Of incubuses and succubuses.
Of the living dead who follow strangers
in the night...
...and attack them.
Hmm...
Transylvania... Nosferatu,
beyond death...
...a curse that will last till the end of time.
The curse of Nosferatu.
Coachman, could you take me to
the Borgo pass?
I'll pay you well.
There is no road to the Borgo pass.
But it's right there.
I need your coach.
I haven't got a coach.
Then I'll take one of your horses.
I'll double the price.
Sorry, sir, but I don't have any
horses. Don't you see?
Well...
I guess I'll have to walk there.
Count Dracula?!
I am Count Dracula.
Welcome to my castle.
You must be Jonathan Harker.
Yes.
Come in.
The night is cold and you must be
tired and hungry.
I've got the papers here.
This is the layout of the house...
...which I'm sure you'd like to see.
Yes, yes.
Please, help yourself.
Please, I'm afraid
you must dine alone.
It's nearly midnight and I
partake of nothing at this hour.
Unfortunately, the servants
are not at our disposal.
So allow me to see
to your comfort.
Listen.
The Children of the Night
make their music.
Ah, young man...
...you're like the villagers who cannot
place themselves in the soul of the hunter.
The knife is old and could be dirty.
It could give you blood poisoning.
Please let me do it. It's the oldest
remedy in the world.
Oh, forget it. It's hardly worth
mentioning. Just a little cut.
You... you know...
...it's only for the best.
Let's sit down for a while.
It's still many hours till dawn.
And during the daytime
I am always away.
Lucy, my love...
...there is no postal service
from here...
...but I shall write a diary, preserving all
my thoughts and feelings for you.
Last night after a tiresome journey,
I finally reached my destination...
...the castle of Count Dracula.
I had a bad dream,
but I hope it will pass.
This castle is so strange.
At times I wonder if it isn't
part of that dream.
Everything about
it looks so unreal.
I don't attach importance to the
sunshine anymore...
...or to glittering fountains,
which youth is so fond of.
I love the darkness
and the shadows.
Where I can be alone
with my thoughts.
I am the descendent
of an old family.
Time is an abyss, profound as
a thousand nights.
Centuries come and go...
...to be unable to grow old is terrible.
That is not the worst. There are
things more horrible than that.
Can you imagine enduring centuries...
...experiencing the same futility
each day?
I'm glad you found such a large
old house for me.
Very near your lodging,
I understand.
Yes, it's just around the corner.
Ah...
...may I have a look
at the contract?
What?...
What a lovely throat.
It's my wife, Lucy.
Your hand.
Your hand is so cold.
The document... the contract for
the house, I must sign it immediately.
Yes, but we haven't
settled on a price.
It doesn't matter
between gentlemen...
...I accept whatever
you find just.
How long did it take you
to get here from Wismar?
Four weeks.
I...
...it takes a while
to travel on land.
From the seed of Belial is the
vampire born.
He who feeds on the
blood of mankind...
...who, unredeemed, taketh
his refuge in caves, tombs...
...coffins filled with the
unblessed soil of cemeteries...
...wherein the black death
has reaped its harvest...
...the plague.
Jonathan!
She has a sudden fever.
Her pulse is too fast.
She needs to rest.
Call me if you think
it is necessary...
...but I don't think
it's something serious.