But this isn't a
time of endings. No.
This is a time of new beginnings,
a time of transformation, change.
I know change isn't always easy
but change
is what's going to allow us to grow as
individuals and embrace our destiny.
To become the persons that
we were meant to become.
HECTOR: (WHISPERING) Hey, Jesse
One of my personal favorites,
William Arthur Ward...
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CHUCKLING)
OSCAR: "...a blessing
or a curse,
"a dawn or a dusk."
(SHUSHES)
It's time for us to embrace the
next chapter of our lives.
And I know we're ready.
Thank you, class of 2012.
Thank you.
(APPLAUSE)
(ALL CHEERING)
HECTOR: So, 5 bucks,
your brother fell asleep.
My brother did fall asleep,
I bet with the babas. Exactly. Yes.
'Cause that principal was drunk.
ALL: Jesse! Jesse!
(ALL CHEERING)
(EVETTE CHUCKLING)
Congratulations, brother.
What are you wearing?
Shut up.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Show the love.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
EVETTE: Hey, look at here.
My number one right here.
CESAR: Get a picture.
HECTOR: You two.
Get a picture, Hector.
Show the diploma.
HECTOR: Two, three...
Take one real quick.
All the best friends?
All the players.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
MARCOS: Oh, oh...
EVETTE: Ah.
Look good, fools.
Hey, what's up, Oscar?
You good?
Yeah, congratulations.
JESSE: Great speech, man.
This is my mom
and he's my brother, Arturo.
Hola.
You guys have a nice summer,
all right. Take care.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What? That's his brother?
(ANSWERING IN SPANISH)
Man, this camera's nice.
(MARCOS SPEAKING SPANISH)
Si. How much is it?
It was about $300.
You think I could like,
you know, record and stuff,
mess around with it?
I won't drop it.
JESSE: I like this camera, Dad. I'm serious.
All right. Just be careful with it.
JESSE: Hey, Chavo!
You hear that?
Daddy graduated.
Yeah, barely.
JESSE: Don't hate, appreciate.
Hmm.
Seriously, though...
JESSE: What?
Mom would have been really
proud to see you graduate.
I wish she would've been here.
Oh.
Thank you. That's like the
nicest thing you've ever said.
Oh, do not get used to it.
You actually got a turnout.
JESSE: Right? People actually
care about me. Hey, Marisol!
Hey! How are you?
Where were you today?
I told you I couldn't
get off of work.
But I made you some salsa.
Hey...
JESSE: Thank you.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
How does it feel?
I feel like a man now.
(ALL CHEERING)
Hey, give me the camera, dude.
Did you see that?
(ALL CHEERING)
Chug it!
(TRADITIONAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah, Grandma!
RAMON: Newspaper all over the window?
HECTOR: That's weirdass Ana.
JESSE: Yeah, my crazy neighbor Ana lives
there. She lives right under me.
And so, in my dad's room, there's
a vent that connects to her room.
And sometimes in the
middle of the night...
I'm talking about like,
weird sounds, dude.
I hear like, wailing, moaning.
HECTOR: Jess!
Jesse! Listen!
We got to go, man!
Come on.
(HECTOR CHUCKLING)
Nice! All right!
All right, let's go.
Yeah, that's nice.
It is high definition.
How much is it then?
Uh...
Two-fifty.
Two-fifty?
Two hundred, that's it.
That's it, 200.
I'll just go somewhere else then.
PAWN SHOP OWNER:
I think 250 for that is cheap.
I can knock it down.
So, 200, it's the most I can...
One-fifty?
You know what? What about...
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Come!
So you're not gonna
give it to me for 150?
(STAMMERING) No, no.
I'll give you for 200. But,
I'll give you this for free.
JESSE: Welcome to
my neighborhood.
That's my mansion, right there.
It's actually a cochinero, but...
Fuck it.
What's up, little man?
Hola.
Right up there, to
the top on the left.
That's my best friend, Hector.
He lives right there.
And then, straight to the back...
Fuck, where's the zoom, man?
Shit, it's good.
That's crazy Ana's apartment.
She lives right under me.
She covers her windows so
nobody sees what she's doing.
I'm gonna take you up
to my pad right now.
Oh, shit!
Who's that sexy man?
Sexy... Oh, fuck!
My hair's crazy right now.
This is the pad, right here.
Anybody... Hey, Chavo!
Hey, boy!
Look at you!
Papa!
CESAR: What?
You in here?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
This is my room, right here.
Oh, you gotta check this out.
This is what you call ghetto.
Bam! That's my side
of the room, right here.
The other side's where my dad lives.
What's that?
It's cool, right?
I just got it.
I just got it at the pawn shop.
The pawn shop?
Look for a job.
I will.
I'll see you. Bye.
All right.
Love you.
Come here, Chavo. Hey,
let's go look for Grandma.
(IRMA PRAYING IN SPANISH)
Oh, I can hear her.
Probably doing her prayers.
(CONTINUES PRAYING IN SPANISH)
What the fuck is that?
Este es el Chake Weight.
Mm-kay.
Chake Weight.
Oh, Shake Weight.
Shake Weight.
Feels like a Shake Dick
or something.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(LAUGHS)
Nada. Ten.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Nada.
Es Chake Weight.
(LAUGHING) Okay.
Chavo. Did you hear that one?
Shake Weight.
JESSE: Got you.
Look at this dumbass.
What the fuck is he doing?
Oh, shake it, shake it.
Oh, man, I would not
let this guy work for me.
(INAUDIBLE)
JESSE: What's up?
JESSE: What?
JESSE: Yeah, yeah.
I'll go over there.
I finally got this shit, dawg!
It looks ill, right?
Yeah, that's dope.
JESSE: Don't drop my shit.
I'm not gonna drop it.
Sick, man.
JESSE: You'll get fired.
I bet I can work better
than your dumb ass anyways.
HECTOR: Dude,
look at this zoom, man!
This zooms in hella deep.
JESSE: Come check this out!
HECTOR: Oh, shit!
What the fuck are you doing?
HECTOR: Oh, fuck. Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
What the fuck are you guys doing?
JESSE: Nothing, man.
Nothing, nothing, nothing.
What do you mean nothing?
You got a fucking camera!
JESSE: It's not even
recording, man, I swear.
SANTO: Bullshit!
It's not even on, huh?
Fuck you!
JESSE: Hey, come on!
SANTO: Give me
the fucking camera!
HECTOR: Fuck! Go!
JESSE: Fucking idiot, man!
HECTOR: Go! Run, run, run!
HECTOR: Yo, what is that?
JESSE: It's a GoPro.
I got it with my camera.
HECTOR:
What the fuck are you doing?
JESSE: (CHUCKLES)
It's gonna be dope. Watch. All right.
Look, this is the way
you move it.
Oh. Hell, no. You won't...
I'm not getting in that shit.
I'm not eating all your food,
I'm eating a fucking tortilla right now
'cause you didn't have chips or anything!
(JESSE CHUCKLES)
I'm not getting in that shit.
I'm not getting in...
JESSE: Go for it!
Man... Shut up, man.
Get your ass up here, then.
JESSE: Fuck, no.
I ain't going up there.
I don't even got insurance.
You're gonna pay for...
JESSE: Stop being a pussy!
Three... Two...
One... Go!
Shit!
(EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
Ah! Fuck!
(GROANS) Shit!
Ah... Fell on my nuts!
Oh, my God, my dick, man!
JESSE: My God, dude, like, I can't believe
you actually went through with it!
Man, you get your ass
up there and do it!
JESSE: I'm not gonna do...
I'm not the stupid one.
That was high, dude.
Holy shit.
That's not cool, man.
You're always making me
do dumb shit.
JESSE: Hey, when you were going
down, like, how did it feel?
(PEOPLE ARGUING)
What the fuck is this?
JESSE: Yo, is that coming
from Ana's apartment?
(ANA SHOUTING)
JESSE: Yeah, dude,
that's Ana.
JESSE: Holy shit!
Dude, that's Oscar.
Yo! Oscar!
Hi, Jesse.
JESSE: What are you
doing here, man?
Yo! What the fuck?
That's the dude from your school?
JESSE: Yeah, man.
Arturo's brother?
That's the same dude?
JESSE: Yeah.
What the hell was he doing here?
HECTOR: What the fuck was
he doing in Ana's apartment?
JESSE: Yo, that lady's
fucking weird, dude.
I don't know what he was doing here.
So, how does he know Ana?
What you cooking?
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
No cooking.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Irm, want some tequila?
I got a surprise for you.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What are you talking about?
Oh! You don't?
JESSE: Only half.
You'll get a good night's sleep.
JESSE: Whoa!
Fucking...
JESSE: Look at that!
(EXCLAIMING IN SURPRISE)
Look at that!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
For your grandma Irma.
JESSE: Yeah!
(TOASTING IN SPANISH)
Ah!
(JESSE SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(EXCLAIMS LOUDLY)
JESSE: Whoa!
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, yeah! One more round.
Come on. Please.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
(THUDDING)
(JESSE SHUSHING)
JESSE: Wait up.
Did you guys hear that?
(JESSE SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WOMAN MOANING IN DISTANCE)
(SCOFFS)
(WHISPERING) What is that?
(MOANING CONTINUES)
Someone's getting fucked.
(WOMAN SHRIEKING)
Oh, fuck!
JESSE: What the fuck?
(WAILING)
What the fuck is that?
HECTOR: I don't know.
Didn't sound good though.
JESSE: (WHISPERING) I wish
we could just see down there.
(STAMMERING) Get your
little GoPro thingy.
We'll just tie it down,
and we'll put it down there.
JESSE: With what?
(DOOR CLOSES)
HECTOR: Yo.
You got it?
Yeah, dude, I found
these little ropes.
You just tie this shit on there.
Holy shit.
And I got the Hedmi cables
that my uncle got.
Fool, it's an HDMI cable.
Got it! Got it! Got it!
Check it out.
Come on!
Go check over there.
All right.
HECTOR: Keep going.
It's still dark.
It's still going down the vent.
Oh, shit.
Hey! Holy shit!
No, no, no, yeah...
Wait, wait, that's it.
(STAMMERING) I see something.
I just saw something.
Half of some shit.
(EXCLAIMING IN SHOCK)
Oh, shit!
There's a fucking...
There's a naked girl!
Look at her!
She's fucking fine!
JESSE: Are you serious?
(HECTOR EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
No, no, no, stay right there!
Stay right there! Oh, fuck.
JESSE: I want to see.
Turn the TV.
HECTOR: Dude, she got bigass
titties. Oh, shit.
Come get this shit.
No, just stay there!
HECTOR: No. This is
the best day of my life.
You should fucking stay in there.
You shut the door.
JESSE: Turn the TV.
You stay there.
What... All right.
All right, hold on.
Dude, she's buck naked!
(DOOR OPENING)
HECTOR: Oh, fuck! Oh, shit!
(HECTOR STAMMERING)
HECTOR: No, no, no, it's okay!
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
HECTOR: You can do
your laundry later!
JESSE: Lock the door, idiot!
HECTOR: Shit!
What the fuck, dude?
She's just standing there, man.
JESSE: She look good?
HECTOR: Yeah, hell,
yeah, she looks good.
Oh... Fuck!
JESSE: She got good titties or what?
HECTOR: Oh, shit!
JESSE: What?
She got a dick?
HECTOR: Dude. Fucking... No!
(STAMMERING) There's...
Ana... Ana's fucking...
Ah, dude!
JESSE:
What do you mean, "Ana"?
HECTOR: She's fucking naked,
man! What the fuck?
Holy shit, dude!
I just lost my boner, man.
My dick's...
...soft, like, forever. What
the fuck, dude? (STAMMERING)
JESSE: Turn the TV.
I can't see shit.
HECTOR: What is she doing?
No, she's...
She's, like, fingerpainting on the...
JESSE: What?
She's fingerpainting her?
HECTOR: (STAMMERING)
Painting with her fingers.
She's painting some red circle
shit on that girl's stomach.
JESSE: Turn the fucking TV.
I can't see shit.
HECTOR: Dude, I... I...
Oh, fuck, dude,
pull it up, pull it up!
(WHISPERING) I think
she heard you, so shut up,
don't say anything.
Pull it up.
Did she hear me?
HECTOR: Shut up.
Hold on.
HECTOR: Dude...
What the fuck was that?
(CHUCKLES) That was pretty fucking funny.
HECTOR: Dude, no, but...
Maybe your grandma's right, dude.
Maybe that bitch is abruja.
(JESSE VOCALIZING)
Well, hello, ladies.
(BOTH VOCALIZING)
(BOTH BEATBOXING)
HECTOR: Oh, man... (STAMMERING)
Let's stop messing with Chavo.
JESSE: You're scaring him! He
doesn't like your Spanish music.
JESSE: ...drawing some symbol
right on the girl.
Yeah.
JESSE: With blood, I think.
It was like some red shit. We don't
know if it was blood or anything.
It looked like a ritual
or something.
And the girl was... I'm talking
about... She was gone.
She's probably a pimp.
Like, you know, she's
running a whorehouse.
How's she gonna run a whorehouse?
What about that one girl...
MARISOL: That sounds stupid.
...who was, like, nine months
pregnant? She was about to pop.
Well, eventually, if you
work at a whorehouse,
you will eventually get pregnant!
JESSE: You know what everybody
says around the hood, like,
that she's some bruja
or witch or whatever.
I mean, I believe it now.
And tell her about Oscar. Remember how he...
JESSE: Oh, yeah, yeah...
How does he know Ana?
JESSE: I don't know.
That's what's weird to me.
JESSE: Eber!
(SPEAKS SPANISH) Come here.
Hey, listen, you want to
do us a favor?
You know Ana, right?
This is gonna be priceless.
JESSE: Hey, Eber.
(HECTOR SHUSHING)
JESSE:
Knock on her door loud.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
JESSE: Call her name.
Scream her name.
Bruja!
(JESSE AND HECTOR CHUCKLING)
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
(HECTOR CHUCKLING)
HECTOR: Oh, my God.
What the fuck!
JESSE: She said we don't know
what's gonna happen to me.
(CHUCKLING)
JESSE: Hey, where'd you get the
firecracker from, anyways?
From my uncle, when he goes to
Mexico, he gets them in TJ.
JESSE: That shit looks dope.
(JESSE SPEAKS IN SPANISH)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING FRANTICALLY)
HECTOR: Back up
a little bit more.
JESSE:
That shit's about to pop.
(HECTOR CLICKS TONGUE)
JESSE: Or not.
HECTOR: Did that shit go out?
JESSE: Boom!
What the fuck!
Don't do that shit, man!
It's just not funny, man! What
if that shit would've...
What the fuck?
JESSE: Shit!
(DOG BARKING)
Holy shit!
Dude, that was Oscar!
Whoa... Whoa!
(CAR ALARMS BLARING) Holy shit!
Oh, shit, look!
JESSE: Oh, fuck!
(CAR HONKING)
HECTOR: Oh, shit.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
HECTOR: Look at all those
people, man.
POLICEMAN: Please get back
to your apartments.
You two, please.
Inside, now.
JESSE: Holy shit, dude.
POLICEMAN: Come on, guys.
Everyone upstairs.
Get that camera out.
(JESSE GRUNTS)
HECTOR: Did someone die?
JESSE: It's crazy.
HECTOR: I don't know...
I don't know what happened.
DIEGO: Hide the shit.
EVETTE: Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
JESSE: Yo, Hector!
HECTOR: Yo!
JESSE: Yo! I think he jumped
from Ana's apartment.
HECTOR: What?
Look. They're taking
the body out! Look.
HECTOR: Goddamn!
JESSE: Holy shit!
That's Ana's body.
(SHUSHES) Be quiet.
That's so messed up.
I can't believe that's Ana.
MARISOL: They still
haven't caught him?
JESSE: I guess not.
MARISOL: That's so scary.
JESSE: I just don't get
why Oscar would kill her.
I mean, he just
graduated valedictorian.
You guys talk to the cops?
No.
HECTOR: I ain't talking to the cops.
Why would we talk to the cops?
And plus, his brother is,
like, the main head of 805.
I'm not messing with
that gang stuff.
HECTOR:
Snitches get stitches.
I don't even think he knew
the camera was there.
That's how fast it was.
You don't know that.
You can't even tell it's him.
You guys better erase it.
You saw him coming out
of her apartment!
Stop tripping!
He didn't see the camera!
HECTOR: We're not
gonna be showing people.
We haven't even shown anyone.
We're not gonna show people.
You better hope that I'm tripping.
You're so stupid, dude.
HECTOR: What?
HECTOR: Blow it out, fool.
Dude, blow that shit out!
(COUGHS)
Stop fucking spraying me!
That was crazy. Someone died
right underneath you, man.
Don't think about it.
She probably sleeps,
like, right under me.
Exactly!
So we're like this.
(COUGHING)
JESSE: Come on.
Don't choke.
(IN JAMAICAN ACCENT)
Blaze one for the nation.
JESSE: Rasta!
(CHUCKLES) Rastafari!
Dude, man, I'm still tripping
about fucking Oscar.
Tell me about it.
Whatever the hell
was going on down there,
I wish I knew, dude.
She was probably doing
weirdass shit down there.
Hey.
I had an idea.
Let's go check
that shit out, man.
What, the...
Downstairs. Ana.
For real?
(SHUSHES) Yeah, man.
Dude, I bet you could find,
like, clues and shit.
What do you think you are?
Sherlock Holmes?
What the fuck?
Sherlock Homes!
You're Sherlock Homes!
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
JESSE: (WHISPERS)
Here, let me try to open the door.
HECTOR: Oh, it's sealed.
JESSE: Hold it open.
HECTOR: Probably
it's gonna be locked.
See, what did I tell you?
It won't open.
JESSE: I got an idea.
(SHUSHES)
Don't make noise!
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
JESSE: (WHISPERING)
Hand me the camera.
HECTOR: Oh, it's fuckin' open, man.
Oh, shit.
Give it to me, hurry up.
Here, give me your hand.
Give me your hand.
Watch your step.
Turn on the light for me.
All right.
Oh, shit.
(POTS BANGING)
Shut the fuck up!
I know. My bad.
Why would she lock her fridge?
HECTOR: Fuck, what is this?
I don't know.
For old people peeing?
Hector, stop touching everything.
Hmm. It's garlic.
(IMITATING PIG)
Stop touching everything.
What is this thing?
Okay, don't listen.
Hey, look.
There's Chavo with a grenade
in his mouth.
It's corn.
Yo.
I think that shit just moved.
Go check it out.
No, man. You go.
Just go check it out.
Dude, just fuck...
What is it?
Dude!
(GROANING)
Stop being such a dick, dawg.
(LAUGHING)
Fuck.
She never took
a shower either, fuck.
Oh, there's a spider right there.
(BABY CRYING)
Baby, it's all right.
What the fuck?
You hear that shit?
Yeah, be quiet.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Oh, shit.
HECTOR: Did she have
a baby?
No.
I don't think so.
Here, Hector.
Get your phone.
Oh, fuck!
Scared the shit out of me.
What the fuck?
All that shit?
Don't touch it, fool.
JESSE: Why?
HECTOR: Just don't touch it, man.
You don't know the shit she...
JESSE:
A bunch of old-school tapes.
See this? Dude.
HECTOR:
"Katie and Kristi, 1988."
JESSE: Let's just go
check out that last room.
(SNIFFING)
Dude, it fucking stinks.
HECTOR: Oh, fuck!
JESSE: Oh, shit, dude.
What is that?
Is that blood?
Yes, "vive."
Check this shit...
Don't get close to that shit.
Holy fuck!
There's blood everywhere.
JESSE: Hold on.
HECTOR: What is it?
JESSE: Some type of
journal or something.
HECTOR: Come on, dude,
let's just fucking go already.
JESSE: All right,
let's go.
JESSE: Holy shit!
HECTOR: Oh, fuck! (GASPING)
What you guys doing here?
You heard that he did this shit.
That wasn't my little brother.
What about that bitch that used to
stay right here? You know about her?
HECTOR: Honestly,
we don't know shit, man.
JESSE: We don't
know anything.
Get the fuck out of here.
JESSE: Oh, fuck.
HECTOR: Come on.
MARISOL: I can't believe you
guys stole this from her house.
Look, she has
a whole bunch of pictures.
MARISOL: What's that?
This looks dope.
HECTOR: What language is that?
They're basically saying
that if you build this door,
it's like, you could
travel through time.
HECTOR: Man, if she could
travel through time,
why the hell is she staying
in this shitty-ass apartment?
I'd timeportal my ass to
the Bahamas or something.
No, it says destinos profanos.
Like, you could only go to
unholy places through this door.
HECTOR: Unholy places.
Oh, shit.
What's an unholy place?
How am I supposed to know?
I'm trying to get up into Marisol's
friend Espi's unholy place.
Oh, you're so nasty, man.
Dude, that's her cousin.
Look at this.
Can I see it?
MARISOL: Looks like some
medieval looking type of shit.
What is that?
It's a map.
Scavenger hunt.
HECTOR: This is like what Ana was
painting on that naked chick.
JESSE: That is.
MARISOL: Oh, shit.
Maybe this is the ritual
she was doing to her.
"Levantese, incubo.
"Lo convoco."
(SCOFFS)
HECTOR: What's theincubo?
It's like a demon.
A demon?
(GROWLS)
HECTOR: Why couldn't we
just buy a black mirror?
Where the hell can you
buy a black mirror at?
That doesn't even make any sense.
JESSE: That's my boy.
Man, shut up.
It's supposed to be
like a doorway.
Like a portal.
Like a port?
Yeah, to the spirit world.
I better not fall off this shit.
The spirit world, what...
Yeah.
How do you even know this shit?
I looked it up, fool.
Grandma said we shouldn't
be fucking with that shit.
Don't even worry about that.
Oh, my gosh!
Just let it go.
We're just gonna fuck around
and then, you know...
Nothing's gonna happen.
Don't trip.
You tie your shoes?
Why can't we just do this
at your apartment?
If myabuelita saw this shit...
She would flip out. You know
how superstitious she is.
Here, go in fast, but be quiet.
MARISOL: Are you sure nobody's
gonna catch us in here?
Yeah, I'm sure. Go through
this door right here.
Fuck!
See the chandelier?
That is dope. It looks
crazy in the dark.
MARISOL: It's so quiet.
Let's do it right here.
Okay, I'm gonna put this down.
Did you hear that?
No.
I swear to God.
You're tripping.
So what are we supposed to do?
Make a triangle. I'm gonna
make it right here.
And then put a circle in the
middle and put the mirror...
Damn, that looks good.
Yeah?
It looks just like the drawing.
Over here.
After we say the spell,
then the portal's
supposed to open up.
(LAUGHING)
I don't know.
Is something supposed
to come through?
I don't know.
Is it gonna be floating around and shit?
Yo, that's gonna be dope.
Let's just do it...
(RECITING SPELL IN SPANISH)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL CHANTING IN SPANISH)
Pshoo.
Pshh.
I'm gonna go, man.
Nothing's happening.
Why?
You're not giving it enough time.
Just sit back down.
Man, I'm hungry, man.
You guys have been...
You've been here forever.
You're being serious right now?
HECTOR: Totally. Later.
(IMITATING HECTOR)
I'm leaving.
You'll never guess.
I'm never gonna guess?
No.
Lemme see.
I promise you there's
no point of, like, going on.
Like, you're not gonna guess who.
Why do you say that?
I'm just sayin'.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You think it's Hector?
I don't know.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Be quiet. Be quiet.
Where do you think he went?
(DOOR CLOSING)
I don't know.
Hey, Hector.
We know you're here.
Come out.
(RUMBLING)
What the fuck was that?
Come on.
Here.
Hello?
Anybody in here?
Oh, shit.
Hello?
Anyone there?
Here, come here, come here.
Give me the light.
There's no one in there.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(LOUD BANGING ON DOOR)
(SCREAMS)
Go, go, go.
Go!
Wait, wait, wait.
What?
We're really just gonna
leave our stuff there?
Fuck that. I'm not going back in there.
That was fucking crazy.
My heart is beating so fast.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, shit.
Get up, fool.
It's noon!
(GROANING)
I'm too tired.
Get your lazy ass up.
Come on. You gotta go
show the world your face.
(SIGHS)
(LAUGHS)
What?
Dude, I had the craziest
fucking dream last night.
I was at some farm with,
like, all these women.
Sounds like a good dream.
(LAUGHS)
No, but they were old.
Like real old.
I don't know.
It's just weird though.
Oh, dude... Hey. You bleeding?
What the...
What?
Hey, did you get your period last night?
What are you talking...
There's blood on your bed, fool.
Look.
Oh, what is that?
It looks like a...
Like a bite or something.
Did you bite yourself?
Why the fuck would I bite myself?
(GROWLING)
Dude, what's wrong
with Chavo, man?
He's growling at you.
He don't like you anymore, man.
Are you kidding? He loves me.
Huh, Chavo? You
love daddy.
Whoa!
What the...
(LAUGHS)
What was that, man?
I don't know.
Chavo!
He ain't feelin' you today, man.
They're hiring at my job
if you want to apply.
I'm not gonna
flip signs like you.
Why not, man?
It takes skill, man!
I've been practicing this whole time.
Skill.
I've been getting better.
(CHUCKLES)
What?
(LAUGHING)
I'm hungry.
You have a dick
on your face, fool.
What?
(HECTOR LAUGHING)
You have a dick on your cheek.
(LAUGHING)
Saw how I drew pubes
and everything?
You're nasty...
Hector, you asshole!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
How long you guys had this?
(BEEPS)
JESSE: I don't know.
Since, like, I was a little kid.
This is older...
This is ancient.
MARISOL: Watch a pro
do it now.
I'm like the master of this game.
All right. Here we go.
HECTOR: Turn it on.
It is on.
Hello!
(GROANS)
Are you gonna work or not?
(BEEPS)
Oh. There you go!
HECTOR: Oh, there you go!
HECTOR: (CHUCKLES)
That was funny, you said,
"Are you gonna work or not?"
And it went "toot."
Man, you broke it, Hector.
I really think, like, it thought you
were so stupid that it stopped working.
HECTOR: Aw, shut up, man.
Do you think Hector is stupid? (CHUCKLES)
Oh, do you think Hector is stupid?
(BEEPS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Wait a sec. Is that a yes?
I think that's a yes.
It's not broken.
Now it's my turn.
HECTOR: It's probably just
coming on every 30 seconds.
(STAMMERING)
I'm gonna speak in the third person.
Is Jesse handsome?
(BEEPS)
(LAUGHING)
Ask it something that
you know it'll say "no,"
to see if it
only does green or what.
Okay. Um...
I can't believe we're actually
like, talking to this thing.
Is Hector black?
(LAUGHING)
(BEEPS)
HECTOR: What?
(ALL LAUGHING)
This is crazy!
(WHISPERS) Now, watch it.
Am I holding the ace of hearts?
(BEEPS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
Holy shit!
HECTOR: That's great!
I could make money with this.
Do something else.
HECTOR: Show your grandma.
You think it understands
Spanish? No.
Okay. Um...
(MURMURING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BEEPS)
Oh, shit.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
HECTOR: Dude,
why did she trip?
JESSE: She thinks it's
bad or something.
(INDISTINCT PURRING)
JESSE: What the hell?
What's going on, Chavo?
Hello!
(DOORKNOB TURNING)
Oh, shit.
(JESSE GASPS)
Jesse, take that off.
Dad?
Yes, take the chain off.
What's going on?
Were you here just like a minute ago?
No. How could I get in when you
have the chain on the door?
Getting home from work right now.
You sure?
Yes!
Put that away. I don't
want you waking up abuela.
Come on. You know the bet.
Shut up, man.
MARISOL: You are not
seriously gonna eat that.
It's not even that bad.
That's so nasty.
No, not those.
You gotta put the habanero.
(MARISOL GROANING)
How does it taste?
He's loving...
I told you. A bet's a bet.
For real?
Wait for it.
There it is. There it is.
(MARISOL LAUGHS)
(SCREAMING)
Agua!
Do you have water?
No agua?
Why are you talking like that?
Shut up, dick. It burns.
That's why. It burns my tongue.
Here you go.
Two? Where's the
rest of the money?
I said two. I didn't say 20.
What?
So, I walked over and then he was
staring right out the front door.
And it was wide open.
The front door to the apartment?
Yeah. And everybody was asleep.
And my dad was at work, too.
Maybe it was Oscar.
Would you stop saying that?
Yeah, he's still out there.
No, don't say that, man.
What if he saw you guys tape him
and he's coming back for it?
Or trying to look for it
or something?
But it didn't feel like
it could have been Oscar.
It feels like something's around me.
Like something's in my house.
Like el cucuy?
El cucuy?
No, I'm serious.
(MARISOL AND HECTOR LAUGHING)
Is el cucuy there?
(LAUGHS)
Like, have you ever felt like
something was watching you?
(HECTOR FARTS)
Yeah.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, shit.
Please tell me that was not real.
That is so...
Oh, my God. Oh, fuck.
What?
Oh, shit.
Oh! Are you serious?
Are you serious?
I think I sharted. I swear
to God. I think I just sharted.
MARISOL: No!
Oh, my God.
Go, cochino!
Get away from me.
Wait, did it go through?
Oh, I think I can see it.
Fuck.
Mirasol, come.
Help me.
No! What do you want me to do?
I have to clean laundry.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What?
Is this all over the house?
JESSE: Yeah.
Oh, man.
She's trying to
protect the house.
It smells really bad, though.
Dad!
What?
She's getting it all over my room, too.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
There is no bad spirit.
What did she do in your room?
She put all the vinegar
all over the bureau.
And you're encouraging her.
JESSE: I'm not
encouraging anything.
You're following her, filming
her doing everything.
JESSE: Just let her do her thing.
Just let her do it.
Ooh.
(JESSE VOCALIZING)
Right here, about to play
some basketball.
I'm gonna show you
how I ball 'em up.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
HECTOR: See how my knee
locked up?
Stop making excuses.
I'm not. This shit
locks up, man.
It affects my jump shot
'cause there's a whole flow.
How you like losing, again?
HECTOR: Man, shut up!
I'm just tired 'cause I haven't
eaten since, like, lunchtime.
And it's not even fair, dawg.
You know I have scoliosis.
(BLOWING RASPBERRIES)
Scoliosis?
HECTOR: You got change?
Oh, I think I left it.
Yo. You have money on you?
No, fool. I'm not gonna
give you shit, either.
You still owe me 6 bucks from
when I bought you tacos.
JESSE: Just, like, give me $2.
HECTOR: Hey. Oh, shit, dude.
Let's go. Hurry up, dude.
JESSE: Stop tripping.
HECTOR: Let's just go.
Oh, fuck.
Careful. Don't point
the camera at them.
What's up?
JESSE: What's up, man?
You guys want to run twos?
Uh...
No, we were just leaving.
What you got in the backpack?
What?
Nothing, man.
I don't have anything.
HECTOR: Come on. Just chill, dawg.
Just chill, man.
Let me check the backpack.
I don't have anything, man.
Can you just leave us alone?
Give me the backpack!
Hey!
Hey, man.
Give me my backpack!
HECTOR: Dude, leave him alone!
What the fuck, man?
Shit! Hey!
(JESSE GROANING)
HECTOR: Stop! Get the fuck
off him, man! Stop it!
Oh, shit! Oh, fuck!
(HECTOR GASPING)
Jesse! Jesse! Come on!
Get up, Jesse!
Get up, dawg!
What the shit?
What the fuck?
Dude, let's go! Let's get
the fuck out of here, man.
Jesse! Come on, dude,
let's fucking go!
(PANTING)
JESSE: Hey, the bike!
HECTOR: What?
Fuck the bike, dude!
Hurry up, man!
You all right, dude?
What happened?
Dude, let's fucking go. Shit!
What the fuck was that, man?
How the hell did you do that?
I don't know.
I mean, I barely touched him.
What happened?
Man, what are you talking about?
They flew through the air!
That was crazy.
They flew, dawg.
It wasn't even a knockout.
They fuckin' flew...
Yeah, but I just don't remember.
Ask it.
Hello?
Anybody there?
Anybody?
(BEEPING)
Oh, shit!
HECTOR: Oh, shit. Did you mess
those guys up at the park?
(BEEPING)
(HECTOR GASPING)
That's crazy!
HECTOR: Oh, shit!
Are you my guardian angel?
(BEEPING)
Are you good?
(PANTING)
JESSE: Dude! All right.
Here. Just get the camera!
HECTOR: All right, fool.
Hold on.
Are you ready?
All right, watch this shit.
Just watch!
Here. You got me?
Yeah, I got you. What...
(EXHALING SHARPLY)
What are you doing?
What...
(CHUCKLES) What the fuck?
Oh, shit! What the fuck?
Do it again! Do it again!
Check this shit out.
Go, go, go.
HECTOR: (LAUGHING) Oh, shit!
Fucking shit! That is fucking...
Dawg, are you sure
you want to do this, man?
(HECTOR LAUGHING)
Oh, my God!
Fuck, dude!
My turn, my turn!
JESSE: One...
All right, wait.
Just do it! Two...
Three! Go!
(THUDDING)
(JESSE GASPS)
BOTH: Fuck!
Yo, you okay?
Shit!
You all right?
Oh, no. Not cool, man.
Want me to lift you up?
Why the fuck didn't it catch me?
All right, watch.
HECTOR: Oh, shit, dude.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
That was incredible!
Oh, my God!
That was amazing!
You flew over me, dawg!
How did you do that?
You see how much air I got?
One, two, three.
(BLOWING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
HECTOR: Oh, shit!
What the fuck?
You got to breathe in
and breathe out.
What? That's insane, Jesse!
Oh, shit! Oh, my God!
We almost got 400 views.
Let me see.
Look, people are
commenting on it.
"Oh, so fake."
Man, what the...
"Wow, this looks totally real.
"Good job, dude.
What effects program..."
All the people who leave comments are
always so negative on this shit.
"This is just an illusion by someone
obviously seeking attention."
Stupid. This is stupid, man.
They just sit in their basements
jacking off to R. Kelly videos all day.
I feel like, right now, if I want
to go do something, I can do it.
Yeah...
Like, do you get me?
Yeah, it's all adrenaline.
You saw how badass that was.
How I just fell and, like...
I know, man.
Okay, but that's what I'm saying.
I don't even know...
I don't even know, dude.
I just feel like I could
do anything right now.
JESSE: Why do you have
a bat in the backseat?
Dude, in this hood,
you never know, man.
Remember, I told you about that
crazy-ass bum at the gas station?
JESSE: So you're gonna
carry a bat on you?
Oh, hey, check it out.
What?
JESSE: Back up. Back up. Back up.
What, the car?
Yes, the car, dude! What else?
Dude, we're definitely going inside.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
Hell, yeah. Here.
JESSE: Take my camera.
Just follow me.
HECTOR: They're gonna know we're not invited.
You can't just walk up to...
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
HECTOR: I'm serious, man. Some of these
fools look like criminals and shit...
What?
HECTOR: Not you, man.
JESSE: Look at those girls.
HECTOR: Damn, she got
a Kim Kardashian ass.
I just wanna ask you if I could
have a kiss on my cheek.
I made a bet with my friend, so...
A kiss on your cheek?
(LAUGHING)
You mother...
HECTOR: Can I get
a kiss on the cheek
if I make you laugh?
No.
The thing is, my cheek is
right above my testicles.
Oh, my God!
Leave some for me!
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
We're taking them home!
Home, to my mom's!
My mom don't get back... My mom
falls asleep at 10 p.m., for real.
(PENELOPE GIGGLES)
Hey, whoa, whoa.
This is my building.
Let's go.
Are you insane?
I need my purse!
JESSE: Hey, right here, you
have to be quiet, please.
(PENELOPE SHUSHING)
JESSE: Oh, shit.
Okay, be quiet.
NATALIA: Oh, she's so cute!
JESSE: Hey, why don't we
just go to your spot?
Hell, no, man. There's like 50
people that live up in there.
JESSE: Are you serious?
Yeah.
Oh, she's sleeping, dude.
Can't we just...
JESSE: Oh, I got an idea.
Take them to the courtyard.
Yes! Just take them
to the courtyard.
What are we waiting for?
JESSE: (WHISPERING) Come.
HECTOR: What?
(GIGGLING)
HECTOR: Jesse. Dude,
are you serious right now?
Are you sure we can be here?
HECTOR: We're good.
The lady moved out.
The lady that used to live
here, she got murdered.
Shut up.
Right here. I swear to God.
Come here, come here...
NATALIA: No, don't take
the light away!
HECTOR: Just chill.
All right, dude.
(LAUGHING)
(HECTOR SHUSHING)
Listen. I want to take
Penelope and I want to...
What am I gonna do
with the other one?
The other one's not into me.
She is.
Dude, at the party, she kept
staring at you. I swear.
She's trying to get away from me.
(CHUCKLES)
It's all right, dude. Fuck.
Just do me a favor.
What?
I don't know.
Take her somewhere.
JESSE: Just give it to me.
HECTOR: Okay, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna take it... I'm hot.
Are you serious?
What are you wearing?
I was hot.
JESSE: He's trying to get sexy for you.
(LAUGHING)
JESSE: Penelope.
Okay, goodbye. Mmm-hmm.
You want to come?
JESSE: Yes, okay,
she's leading it.
You see what I'm talking about?
NATALIA: Have fun!
JESSE: Bye-bye.
NATALIA: Slut!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
JESSE: Penelope?
Penelope?
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, my God.
I want you to fuck
the shit out of me, okay?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm serious.
You're serious?
Yes!
Okay.
I'm serious. I want you to
fuck me really, really hard.
All right.
You have a condom, right?
Uh...
Yeah. I'll be right back.
What do you mean, you'll be...
It's upstairs.
Don't worry. I'll be back.
(DOOR OPENING)
(SIGHS)
(THUDDING)
(SCRATCHING)
(LOUD THUDDING)
(SCREAMING)
(PENELOPE SCREAMING)
What the fuck
is she talking about?
JESSE: Hello?
Hector, stop messing around, man.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
She put it inside me.
That's why I killed Ana.
She changed me.
And it's inside you, too,
isn't it, Jesse?
You have the same mark.
The only way to stop it
is to kill yourself.
Kill yourself before
you hurt someone, Jesse.
IRMA: Jesse!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(DOG BARKING)
(JESSE SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Oh, Jesse, he is here!
JESSE: Oh, shit.
(PANTING)
HECTOR: What's going on?
JESSE: Where are the girls?
HECTOR: They're inside.
JESSE: Call 911!
(JESSE PANTING)
Where the fuck are you?
HECTOR: What the fuck's
going on?
JESSE: He was in Ana's!
HECTOR: Who?
JESSE: Oscar!
Oh, my God!
Oh, fuck! Fuck!
HECTOR: Holy shit!
JESSE: Oh, my God!
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
You don't see his eyes? Look.
Yeah.
Go back.
His eyes look all...
Look at his eyes. They're
all cracked out looking.
He died last night, man.
Ana got killed in there.
I'm not gonna go
down there anymore.
Okay, well, he had the
same mark that I do.
He said whatever happened
to him is happening to me.
(SHUSHES)
JESSE: It's right there, you can see it.
I got it. Watch out.
Oh, shit.
Follow me.
I'm gonna go in.
JESSE: Watch your step.
HECTOR: I can't see shit.
JESSE: Close the door.
HECTOR: Why?
JESSE: We're not supposed to
be down here. Just close it.
(HECTOR STRAINING)
(WHISPERING)
I can't see shit.
Here. Give me your phone.
JESSE: Flashlight.
Come on. Follow me.
MARISOL: What is this place?
JESSE: I don't know.
Check it out.
MARISOL: Jesse.
What?
This is you.
JESSE: What the fuck?
MARISOL:
She had pictures of you.
This is me when I was a baby.
MARISOL: Oh, my God.
My dad's been looking
all over the place for this.
This is my mom.
MARISOL: What?
This is when she was
pregnant with me.
MARISOL: Shut up. That's Ana!
No, it's not.
Yes, that is. That's Ana!
Who's this white lady?
"Lois. November 3rd, 1994."
Oh, my God.
What's my mom doing with Ana?
MARISOL: Shit.
HECTOR: And Oscar, too?
This shit's crazy!
Dude, what is all this?
(DOOR OPENING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
MARISOL: There's somebody in here.
(JESSE SHUSHING)
MARISOL: They're in here.
JESSE: Look at me.
(FOOTSTEPS)
I'm scared.
(SHUSHING)
MARISOL: Do you think they know
we're down here?
(SHUSHES)
Quiet.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
JESSE: Come on.
(DOOR BANGING)
JESSE: Back up,
back up.
(FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS)
(FOOTSTEPS ABOVE)
MARISOL: Hector.
Hector.
(DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING)
I think they're gone.
Yeah, okay.
MARISOL: Let's go.
Yeah, come on.
Go ahead, Hector.
JESSE: What do you see?
She's still here?
Yeah.
It's a lady.
What?
It's a lady?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What is she doing here?
I don't know.
HECTOR: (WHISPERING) Oh, shit.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
JESSE: You think she's gone?
HECTOR: I think she left.
She's gone?
You sure she's gone?
Yeah, she just closed the door.
MARISOL: What did she look like?
HECTOR: She was dressed in black,
and she was like this
tall, just a white lady.
Is this Ana with Mom?
JESSE: Yeah.
Where did you get this?
It doesn't matter.
I just wanna how Ana knew Mom.
Check out the picture. Mom was
pregnant there, with me.
I mean, I heard stuff from
people saying that, like,
Ana, like, she was doing
all this weird witch stuff,
like, rituals on
pregnant women and stuff.
How did Mom die?
Having me, right?
So what if Ana did
something to Mom?
You're tripping, dude.
Are you serious right now?
Do you hear yourself?
You're just rambling on.
You don't sleep, you don't eat.
I hear you get up at night.
What are you talking about?
Mijo, I'm worried about you.
What is that?
(WINCES)
(SHUDDERING)
What the fuck?
What the hell?
(HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL)
(GASPS)
What the fuck?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(JESSE GASPS)
CESAR: Jesse. You okay,mijo?
JESSE: (CLEARING THROAT)
Yeah, Dad. I'm fine.
What the hell is happening to me?
Arturo's a serious gangster.
What is he gonna do?
HECTOR: He's gotta
know something.
It's Oscar's brother.
MARISOL: Why is he taking so long?
HECTOR: Oh, shit, is that him?
He's calling us.
Don't touch nothing when
you get in there, all right?
JESSE: Okay.
Mom's having a hard time
dealing with all this shit.
She doesn't want nobody
moving his stuff.
I noticed Oscar started acting
different about a month ago.
He got real quiet.
Stayed in his room all night.
Then he started even
acting crazy with my mom,
started breaking
shit in the house.
Then I found this.
MARISOL: Oh, shit.
HECTOR: Oh, fuck.
Can we take a look at this?
ARTURO: The last time
I seen my brother,
he said there was
others like him.
He said they were all marked.
He said these witches were trying
to build an army or some shit.
MARISOL: An army for what?
These are all in
different languages.
ARTURO:
From all over the world.
HECTOR: It's all little kids?
ARTURO: All little boys.
First-born boys.
JESSE: Like you.
ARTURO: I'm the first-born.
JESSE: That's why...
But Oscar was adopted.
So what happened with his mom?
She died at birth.
My mom and dad took him.
HECTOR: That's like
your mom, Jesse.
Your mom?
Yeah... (STUTTERS)
His mom died
while she was giving...
Who's this girl?
All these are boys,
and then there's this...
Isn't Carlsbad near here?
HECTOR:
Yes, it's pretty close.
"Ali Rey was..."
Wait, that's her!
HECTOR: What is?
That's her. It's Ali Rey.
It says "Ali Rey" in the article.
Was he talking to her?
Do you know her?
ARTURO: I have no idea.
Thanks. We appreciate it, man.
We got to go.
HECTOR: What are you doing?
We should check this stuff out, man.
Come on. Let's just go.
Thanks.
MARISOL: Jesse, what's wrong?
HECTOR: Jesse...
ARTURO:
What's up with your boy, man?
No, he's just going
through a lot right now.
JESSE: Yo! Let's roll.
HECTOR: Yeah. Sure.
HECTOR: So what's up, dude?
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, man.
What do you mean, nothing?
Why'd you take off like that?
I said, nothing, man.
I'm fine.
Was it the thing about the mom?
Dude, Jesse, all that shit's exactly
what's been happening to you.
All that stuff that
Oscar was saying.
No, it's not.
Then how do you explain
all the crazy shit
that's been happening?
Just back up, Hector.
Please.
No shit, man. You're the one
who told us to go to Arturo's.
You don't want to
talk about it now?
What's wrong?
Jesse.
Dude, Jesse.
Is this guy bothering you?
What? No. This is Pablo.
Oh, is this your boyfriend?
He's a friend from high school.
No.
Jesse, what's up?
Jesse, what's wrong with you?
Yeah, what's...
What's your problem, man?
HECTOR: Jesse.
Jesse, calm down.
Just chill out.
HECTOR: Dude, calm down.
Did you not fucking hear me?
I said get out of here!
Dude, Jesse.
What the fuck, dude?
He's not doing anything to me.
Just calm down.
What the fuck you looking at
me like that for, huh?
HECTOR: Jesse, dude... Hey!
Jesse, don't...
Dude, calm the fuck down.
Are you serious right now?
Yeah, I'm serious. Do I look
like I'm fuckin' playing?
Jesse, dude, let's fucking go.
What are you doing, man?
Hey, Jesse, what the fuck, dude?
Just leave him alone!
JESSE: Back up, all right?
SHOPKEEPER: You, get out of here!
What are you doing?
What are you gonna do, huh?
HECTOR: You all right, man?
Hey, Jesse, what the fuck?
Get out of here, now!
What the fuck are
you gonna do, huh?
HECTOR: Jesse!
Back up, I said!
Why don't you fucking hit me right
here if you're gonna fucking hit me?
(SHOUTING) Leave, now!
HECTOR:
Marisol, what the fuck's he doing?
Hey!
Jesse, stop it!
Come on, let's go! He's got a bat!
HECTOR: Jesse!
Come on, man! Jesse!
Jesse! What the fuck!
What are you doing? Jesse!
Hey, man! What the
fuck's wrong with you?
Come out, motherfucker!
MARISOL: Let's go home!
Why don't you come out?
HECTOR: Jesse! Jesse!
He's gonna call
the fucking cops! Go!
Yeah, I'm getting the cops!
MARISOL: Jesse, let's go.
Come on.
HECTOR: I've been texting you
all morning, man. What's up?
MARISOL: You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Like last night.
I couldn't control myself.
And a lot of times I feel like
I'm losing time. I can't...
I don't know what I'm doing.
All the stuff before, man...
It was fun, you know?
I felt like maybe I was
special or something.
But not anymore.
I'm telling you,
it's not gonna work again.
You can just try it.
Ask it something.
It worked last time, right?
HECTOR: Yeah.
What makes you think
it's gonna work twice?
(CLICKS)
Are you there?
I said, are you there?
I told you.
HECTOR: Dude, try something else, man.
Is there something you want from me?
(BEEPING)
I want you to leave me alone!
I said, leave me alone!
(BEEPING)
Just leave me alone! Now!
(BUZZING)
You think it's gone?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING ON T.V.)
JESSE: Chavo?
(CHAVO BARKING)
What the hell?
Chavo!
Chavo?
(CHAVO BARKING)
Chavo!
(CHAVO WHINING)
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit.
(CHAVO SQUEALING)
Okay, Chavo, I'm coming.
I better turn on my light.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Okay.
Chavo?
Chavo!
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Oh, fuck!
Help!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(CONTINUES POUNDING
ON DOOR)
Help!
Oh, shit!
GIRL: He's ready for you.
(GIRL CRYING)
(RUSTLING)
(THUMPING)
(GROWLING)
(JESSE SCREAMING)
HECTOR: What the fuck is that?
What the fuck?
(THUDDING)
Jesse.
What's wrong with you? And what
the fuck is that on your wall?
Dude, Jesse, why are
you ignoring me, man?
You're my best friend.
(SCOFFS)
We're not best friends.
Okay? Do you get it?
Give me my camera.
Dude...
Just give me my camera.
What's wrong with you?
What are you doing, man?
Just stop, dude.
Say something interesting.
Get this shit out of my face.
What, you don't like this?
Stop, man.
What the fuck's wrong?
I don't need that anyway.
Maybe that could be
your best friend.
HECTOR: What did he
tell you when you saw him?
I told you, he didn't
say anything.
He didn't even act like I was there.
He just walked out and left.
HECTOR: I don't know.
I'm worried about him.
MARISOL: Who are you calling?
You took this?
What are you gonna say?
(SHUSHING) Hello?
HECTOR: You think that's her?
I don't know.
Ali?
Hi! Nice to meet you.
Hey! I'm Hector.
ALI: Do you guys
recognize that?
MARISOL: Yeah, that was in Oscar's room.
That's the sign of The Midwives.
They're a coven.
HECTOR: What?
MARISOL: A coven?
Yeah.
Like of...
Witches.
That mark right there...
HECTOR: Mmm-hmm.
The Midwives will mark
an unborn male in utero.
And then they wait
for the baby to mature
until he's ready to be possessed.
But why now?
Like, if Jesse, our friend,
was marked at birth,
why would the demon come now
and try to possess him?
Okay, you ready? Your friend,
Jesse, I'm assuming he's 18?
BOTH: Yeah.
And the other kid?
Your friend?
Oscar? I think so.
Add them up.
This transformation, it's like...
It's like when you have
an infection in your body.
So he's fighting it off.
They'll perform a final ritual,
and then he'll go back to normal.
But he won't...
He won't be Jesse anymore.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
HECTOR: Uh-huh.
What? Slow down.
I don't understand you.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING SPANISH)
What?
(JESSE LAUGHING)
HECTOR: Dude? Jesse!
Jesse?
(LAUGHS)
What are you doing, man?
(WHIMPERING)
What the... Jesse!
Jesse, stop! Jesse! Stop!
Put him down, man!
You're gonna hurt him!
(JESSE LAUGHS)
Dude, what the fuck
are you doing?
Let him go, Jesse! Stop!
Shit, you're hurting him, man!
What the fuck you doing?
Jesse! Stop it, man!
(IRMA SPEAKING SPANISH)
HECTOR: She's telling him?
She's talking about Jesse.
That he has a bad spirit in him.
And she needs his help.
(IRMA SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
What'd he say?
He said, "Cleansing."
HECTOR: Should we...
Let's go. Come.
Dude, this place is a trip.
(SHUSHING)
HECTOR: Jesus Christ.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(PRAYING IN SPANISH)
IRMA: Jesse.
(IRMA SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WHISPERING)
Eggs are supposed to help him.
(IRMA SPEAKING SPANISH)
(PRAYING IN SPANISH)
HECTOR: Jesse!
What the fuck? Shit!
What the fuck? Jesse!
(JESSE WAILS)
What's wrong, Jesse?
Are you okay?
HECTOR: Jesse, what the
fuck is happening, man?
Fucking shit! What the fuck?
(JESSE GROANING)
MARISOL:
Jesse, are you all right?
HECTOR: Damn it!
Stand back! Get back!
MARISOL: What happened to the lights?
HECTOR: Just shut up! (SHUSHING)
(MARISOL AND IRMA WHIMPERING)
I can't see anything.
HECTOR: Just stay
back, all right?
Just stay right there.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
MARISOL: Oh, shit!
Oh, my God, what happened?
What was that?
HECTOR: I don't know. Fuck.
Jesus Christ. Oh, shit.
(HECTOR BREATHING HEAVILY)
Fuck. What the fuck was that?
Just hold on.
Just stay right there.
Jesse?
(JESSE GRUNTS)
Is he okay?
HECTOR: Yeah.
(PRAYING IN SPANISH)
(HECTOR SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
HECTOR: What happened?
I thought it worked.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
HECTOR: He's gonna be
okay, though, right?
(PRAYING IN SPANISH)
Hey, I think your grandma's
running the tub, man.
I think she's gonna put you in there.
It'll cool you down, all right?
(MUTTERS)
All right, don't worry about it.
Everything's gonna be cool.
(CRASHING)
Irma?
(GASPS)
(THUDDING)
Oh, shit.
(GASPS) Oh, fuck!
Jesse?
Irma?
(WATER RUNNING)
Jesse?
What the fuck?
Jesse.
Oh, Jesse.
Jesse, you all right, man?
Jess...
(GASPS)
Oh, fuck! Irma! Irma!
Irma!
Someone call 911! Call 911!
Where did he go?
HECTOR: I don't know.
I went to go call 911,
and when I came back,
he was gone.
He didn't call or text you?
No, I've been looking
everywhere. He's gone.
They just moved her to the ICU.
So I'm gonna go to the
hospital to be with my dad.
Uh-huh.
Okay, but...
I don't know.
He just disappeared.
What?
She said this is where Jesse is.
HECTOR: What?
Ali said this is a house
where they do a final ritual,
and that's where he's gonna be.
HECTOR: Is she sure?
We should call the cops.
Call the cops and tell
them what, Hector?
They're not gonna believe us.
We can't just fucking show
up at this house, Marisol!
We're gonna go walk in? These people
are dangerous. They kill people.
We'll get help or something!
We can't just leave him there!
We can't just leave our
friend, Hector! We have to go!
Stop. All right, look. We're going
to the hospital, all right?
I'm gonna tell his dad everything.
I'm gonna show him the footage.
MARISOL: So are we not
gonna talk about this?
What's there to talk about, Marisol?
MARISOL: What are we gonna do?
I'm gonna...
I'm telling his dad.
What is his dad gonna do?
Well, what are we doing? We don't
even know what the fuck we're doing.
(CAR STALLING)
MARISOL: I'm just saying...
What the fuck
is wrong with the car?
Are you fucking kidding me?
(MARISOL SIGHS)
Are you serious?
I just fixed this.
What's wrong with it?
I just got this shit fixed.
Fuck!
(MARISOL SIGHS) Goddamn.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(RADIO PLAYING STATIC
AT HIGH VOLUME)
Ow! What the fuck! Turn that
thing off! Turn it off.
Jesus Christ, Hector!
What the fuck was that?
I don't know! It just
turned on by itself!
(SIGHS) What the fuck, Hector?
The fuck?
(BOTTLE CLATTERING)
MARISOL: Oh, my God.
HECTOR: Is that Jesse?
MARISOL: Now start the car.
(CAR SPUTTERING)
MARISOL: Fuck!
Shit, he's coming this way.
Oh, shit.
Come on, let's just get out.
Let's just get out.
The door is stuck.
What's this guy doing?
MARISOL: What the fuck...
What the fuck is happening?
HECTOR: Shit!
Oh, this is insane!
(BOTH GASPING)
MARISOL: Where the fuck...
Where the fuck did he go?
(CLANGING)
MARISOL: Oh, shit.
(CAR SPUTTERING)
HECTOR: Oh, shit.
MARISOL: Where'd he go?
(THUDDING ON CAR ROOF)
(BOTH GASPING)
MARISOL: Where'd he go?
Hector! Hector! Oh, my God!
(HECTOR SCREAMING)
MARISOL: Stop, Jesse!
(HECTOR AND MARISOL SCREAMING)
MARISOL: No, Jesse, stop it!
(HECTOR CHOKING)
HECTOR: Stop!
MARISOL: Oh, my God!
He's not moving, Hector!
He's not moving!
Stop yelling right now!
What are we gonna do?
No, he's fine. He'll be fine.
MARISOL:
His eyes were all black and shit!
I don't know if he's breathing!
Hector, what the fuck
are we gonna do?
He's not moving! (SCREAMS)
(HECTOR GRUNTS)
Oh, my God.
(HECTOR GROANING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
MARISOL: Oh, my God.
HECTOR: You okay?
MARISOL: Oh, my God! Oh, shit!
HECTOR: What?
MARISOL: They took him!
They took him!
HECTOR: Jesse!
MARISOL: Hector,
they took Jesse!
They took Jesse and they're
gone! They took Jesse!
Get in the car!
HECTOR: Shit!
HECTOR: Oh, fuck.
(STARTS ENGINE)
Fuck.
(BANGING)
Arturo! Arturo!
HECTOR: Are they home?
Hey, is Arturo here?
MAN: Hey, what the fuck...
We need to talk to him.
HECTOR: Tell him
it's an emergency.
We need your help, man.
What do you mean?
They took Jesse!
Jesse... Jesse... What do
you mean, they took him?
They took Jesse!
The women! They took him!
HECTOR: This is a bad idea.
I can't believe we're doing this.
MARISOL: Slow down.
I think this is it.
ARTURO:
You sure this is the place?
MARISOL: Yeah.
Yeah. This is it.
Let's go smoke these bitches.
ARTURO:
Crack that shit open, Santo.
Where the fuck we at?
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
What?
That was me. That was me.
(RUSTLING)
(MARISOL GASPS)
HECTOR: What was that?
MARISOL: What?
HECTOR: I thought
I just saw something.
ARTURO: It's locked.
MARISOL: It's locked?
Yeah.
This way.
ARTURO: Down this side, something.
SANTO: All right.
HECTOR: Think anyone's here?
ARTURO: You see anything?
SANTO: Nah.
(ARTURO SHUSHING)
This shit's locked, too.
Let me try this shit, homes.
Just give me a minute.
(WIND CHIME TINKLING)
(WATER FLOWING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
HECTOR: Shit.
Oh, fuck.
(HECTOR GASPING)
Do you see anything?
HECTOR: No.
ARTURO: Santo. Santo.
SANTO: I almost got it.
ARTURO: Let's go.
What the fuck?
HECTOR: What is it?
ARTURO: Looks like
some food or something.
HECTOR: Are they cooking shit?
HECTOR: Think there's,
like, squatters in there?
ARTURO: I don't know.
You see anything?
(SIGHS)
I don't think anybody's here.
You have to help me!
MARISOL: (GASPS) Holy shit!
Help me, please!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(MARISOL SCREAMING)
HECTOR: Fuck! Oh, shit!
HECTOR: Watch out!
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
HECTOR: Oh, my God!
ARTURO: Get the fuck
out of here! Go! Go!
Get out of here! Run!
MARISOL: Oh, shit!
HECTOR: Run! Go, go, go!
Go, go, go! Shit!
Holy shit, Santo!
(BOTH PANTING)
MARISOL: Help me move him!
Help me move him!
HECTOR:
Go! Close the door! Go!
(BOTH PANTING)
(SOBBING)
HECTOR:
Come on! Come on! Come on!
(HYPERVENTILATING)
HECTOR: They're fucking
everywhere! Oh, shit!
What the fuck is that?
MARISOL: What?
HECTOR:
Just stay there, all right?
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
(GASPS)
Oh, God!
Marisol?
Marisol!
(GASPING)
MYSTERIOUS VOICE: Hector.
Hector. Right here.
Help me.
HECTOR: Is that Arturo?
What the fuck is that?
(THUD)
(HECTOR EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
(GASPING)
Oh, God! Fuck, fuck!
Marisol! Where are you?
(WHIMPERING)
Where the fuck are you?
Marisol?
Fuck.
Marisol.
Oh, shit!
Where the fuck are you?
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPING)
(HECTOR SCREAMING)
Marisol! Oh, my God!
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(HECTOR WHIMPERING)
(LOUD BANGING ON DOOR)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(SHUDDERING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(GASPING)
(ROARING)
HECTOR: (SCREAMING)
Oh, oh, shit!
Oh, God!
(EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
Oh, fuck! Shit!
(GASPING)
Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck!
What the fuck?
What the fuck is that?
JESSE: Hector?
Hector, please open the door.
HECTOR: Go away!
Get the fuck out of here!
JESSE: Hector, I'm scared, man.
Please open the door.
HECTOR: Fuck you!
I'm not opening this door!
(HECTOR SCREAMING)
Jesse! Stop! Jesse!
(DISTORTED SCREAMING)
Where the fuck am I?
Oh, shit.
(SHUDDERING)
Hello?
(STAMMERING)
Excuse me.
(CONTINUES STAMMERING)
Hello?
(DRAWER OPENING)
Excuse me.
Excuse me, lady, please.
I don't know where I am.
Please!
Excuse me.
I need your help, please.
Micah! Micah!
(SCREAMING)
What's the matter?
Where are you?
What the fuck?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(HECTOR GASPING)
(GROWLS)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(CLATTERING)