Bye, old Shep.
See you in heaven. Yeah?
This is where my kitty lays.
No more he screams
and hollers.
He lived for
5 and 20 days.
He cost me $50.
Spot--a good fella.
We love you.
We're finally here.
Yeah.
Yay!
So?
What do you think?
It's gorgeous.
Decided to wake up
and see what home
looks like, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Uh-huh. Come here.
Mommy! Daddy!
I see a path.
Ellie, be careful.
Ellie!
Listen to your moth--
Mommy! Daddy!
It hurts!
Mommy! Daddy! It hurts!
Honey, are you ok?
It hurts.
Get rid of this.
I got it.
You OK?
No. It hurts.
Anyone screaming that loud
doesn't need
intensive care.
Hi, Church.
Church.
She just skinned
her knee.
[horn honks]
[honk]
I don't want
the stingy stuff, Daddy.
Where's Gage?
Gage!
No, you don't, my friend.
Not in that road.
Gage!
I corralled him
for you, Missus.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
I'm Louis Creed.
Jud Crandall.
I live just
across the road.
You want to watch out
for that road.
Them damn trucks
go back and forth
all day and night.
And, uh, who might
you be, little miss?
I'm Ellen Creed.
Your dad's going to be
the new Doctor
up at the college.
I think you'll be
happy as a clam here.
Are clams
really happy?
Mr. Crandall,
there's a path over there.
Do you know
where it goes?
Oh.
Ayuh, that's
a good story.
A good walk.
I'll take you
up there sometime.
Tell you
the story, too,
after you get
settled in.
Great.
Uh, excuse me,
I've got to get
this kid changed.
Nice to meet you.
Same here.
Come on, Ellie.
House has stood empty
too long.
It's damn good
to see people in it again.
[meow]
Aah! Church!
You scared the life
out of me, Church.
[meow]
Come here.
Is that you, Doc?
Yeah, it's me.
Come and have a beer.
Need a glass?
Not at all.
Good for you.
Jesus.
Ayuh.
That's one
mean road, all right.
You know that path
your wife commented on?
That road
and those Orinco trucks
are the two main reasons
it's there.
Well, where
does it lead?
Pet cemetery.
Ha. Pet cemetery.
It's that damn road.
It uses up
a lot of animals.
Dogs and cats mostly.
My little girl's got a cat.
Winston Churchill.
We call him Church for short.
I'd get him fixed if I were you.
Fixed cat
don't tend to wander.
If it's always
crossing that road,
its luck will run out.
I'll take it
under advisement.
Meantime, Doc,
here's to your bones.
And your bones.
Uh-oh.
I'll be going now, Dr. Creed.
All right, Missy. Thanks.
Hi, Missy.
I'll do these up,
bring them back next time.
Great. Can you come
on Monday, Missy?
Always thought it would be lucky
to marry a Doctor.
Wish I had a Doctor around
with my stomach pains.
Guess I'll never be lucky.
Hell, I ain't married
to anyone.
Bye, Missy.
Mommy, Daddy,
come on, let's go!
We're coming.
All set?
Let's get on with it.
Yay!
There's the place.
What's it say, Mommy?
It says "Pet Sematary,"
honey.
It's misspelled,
but that's what it says.
Ellie, wait a minute!
I told you it was
a bad road.
It's made a lot
of kids unhappy.
At least something good
come of it. This place.
Couldn't plant nothing
but corpses here anyway.
How can you
call it a good thing?
A graveyard for pets
killed in the road,
built by
brokenhearted children.
They have to learn
about death somehow.
Why?
Can I have the baby?
Yeah.
Daddy, look,
this one's a gold fishy.
That's right, Ellie.
They wasn't all killed
by the road,
especially the ones
back from my childhood.
They get older as you go
towards the middle.
Harder to read.
Missy Ellen, come
over here just a minute.
That's where I buried
my dog Spot
when he died in 1924.
Ellie...do you know
what a graveyard
really is?
Well, I guess not.
It's a place
where the dead speak.
No, not right out loud.
Their stones speak
or their markers.
This ain't
a scary place, Ellie.
It's a place of rest
and speaking.
Can you remember that?
Yes, sir.
Shh.
Hi, babe.
Daddy, what if
Church dies?
What if he dies and has to go
to the pet cemetery?
Honey, Church
will be fine.
No, he won't.
Not in the end.
In the end
he's going to croak.
Lovey, Church
might still be alive
when you're
in high school,
and that's
a very long time.
It doesn't
seem long to me.
It seems short.
I'd let Church
live to be 100,
but I don't
make the rules.
Well, who does?
God, I suppose.
He's not God's cat,
he's my cat.
Let God get His own
if He wants one.
Not mine.
Not mine!
[meow]
Yecchh!
Gross!
Uh-oh!
I'm scared.
What if school here
isn't like in Chicago?
I'm scared.
I want to go home.
You'll be
all right, Ellie.
I don't want Church to get
his nuts cut, Daddy.
Good God, where
did you hear that?
Missy Dandridge.
She says
it's an operation.
Well, the road
is a lot more dangerous
than any operation.
Church will be
just the same.
Well, almost the same,
and we won't
have to worry
about him getting run over
by trucks.
He'll be all right.
You promise, Daddy?
Don't shilly-shally,
Louis.
Give the little girl
a promise.
Church will be fine.
I promise.
Yay!
Thank you.
Oh, you're very welcome.
But if anything does happen
while he's under the gas--
now, it's a 1 in a 1,000 shot,
but it does happen--
you explain it to her.
[yeow]
Church!
Got to go.
Going to get his--
Nuts cut. Yes.
Thank you, Missy, for introducing
that colorful phrase
into my daughter's
vocabulary.
Don't mention it.
How's that bellyache
of yours?
No better. No worse.
I can take a look
at that.
It'll pass.
They always do.
Missy.
Ma'am.
Still friends, Doc?
I kissed you.
Have a great first day
at school, Doc.
Bye-bye.
What happened?
He got hit by a truck.
Oh, God, his head.
Hold him gently.
Didn't even stop.
There's so much blood!
What's going on?
Get Dr. Creed!
What's happened?
He got hit by a truck.
Dr. Creed!
Get them all out of here.
Easy. Easy.
All right.
Everyone out, please.
Let the Doctors
do their work.
Let's clear
the room here.
Just clear out!
Ambu bag.
Start a cardiac monitor.
Yes, sir.
Need large bores.
Get an ambulance here.
He's going to EMC.
It won't do any good.
I know, but let's
follow the rules. Move!
Mark, who is it?
It's Pascow.
I told Rachel not so much
as a sprain today, my friend.
Aah!
The soil...
of a man's heart...
is stonier...
Louis.
How did you know
my name?
I'll come to you.
How did you know
my name?
[crash]
Come on, Doc.
We've got places
to go.
Come on, Doc.
Don't make me
tell you twice.
Hey, why are you here?
I want to help you
because--
Louis?
Because you tried
to help me.
Jeez.
Let's go, Doc.
I don't like this dream.
Who said
you were dreaming?
This is the place
where the dead speak.
I want to wake up.
Don't go on, Doc.
No matter how much
you may feel you have to,
do not go on
to the place
where the dead...
walk.
Please.
I just want to
wake up, that's all.
The barrier was not
meant to be crossed.
It's not my fault
you died.
You were
as good as dead
when they
brought you in.
The ground beyond...
is sour.
[birds chirping]
[children laughing]
You up, Doc?
Getting there.
Thanks, nurse.
Louis, it's not right.
I don't like
to think of you
rattling around the house
on Thanksgiving.
That's supposed to be
a family holiday.
That's why you're going
with the kids and without me.
As far as
your dad's concerned,
- I'll never be a member of the family.
- But I want you around.
I'll be around plenty
when you get back.
[telephone rings]
Hello.
Afraid you may have a spot
Of trouble here.
Jud? What trouble?
There's a dead cat
on the edge of my lawn.
It might be
your daughter's.
Yup. That's Church
all right.
I'm sorry.
At least it don't
look like he suffered.
Well,
Ellie will suffer.
She'll suffer plenty.
Here. Give me that.
[crackle[
What are you going
to do with it?
Put him
in the garage.
I'll bury him
in the morning.
You going
to tell Ellie?
I have to mull that
over for a while.
Maybe I'll
just tell her
I haven't seen
the damn cat around.
I don't want to spoil her holiday,
and Rachel's.
Maybe...there's
a better way.
Do we plant him
on the outside
of the circle
or start a new one?
The place we're going
is on the other side
of that.
We can't climb
over that.
We'll break our necks.
No, we won't.
I've climbed it
a time or two before.
I know where to step.
Just follow me.
Move easy.
Don't look down...
and don't stop.
If you stop,
you'll crash through
for sure.
Just don't stop, and...
Whoa!
And don't look down.
Right.
Louis, you all right?
Yeah.
I just lost my happy thoughts there
for a second.
Whoo!
Not much farther now.
[loon cries]
[rumbling]
Jud, what's that?
Shh!
[rumbling]
[loon cries[
Just a loon, that's all.
Here we go.
Won't be
much longer now.
Just down here
a little ways.
Almost there, Louis.
You keep saying that.
This time I mean it.
What is this place?
This was
their burial ground.
Whose burial ground?
Micmac Indians.
I brought you here
to bury Ellen's cat.
Why, for God's sake?
I said why, Jud?
I had my reasons.
The soil's thin,
but you'll manage.
I'm going to sit
over yonder
and have a smoke.
I'd help you,
but you got
to do it yourself.
Each buries his own.
Uhh!
[telephone rings]
[ring]
Shit.
Louis?
Yeah.
When you talk
to them,
not one word
about what we done tonight.
What did we do
tonight, Jud?
What we did, Louis,
was a...
secret thing.
Women are supposed
to be the ones
who are good
at keeping secrets.
Any woman who knows anything
will tell you
she's never seen
into a man's heart.
The soil of a man's
heart, Louis,
is stonier,
like the soil
up there
in the old Micmac
burying ground.
Goldman residence.
Hi, Dory.
It's, uh, Louis.
You want to talk
to your daughter?
Yeah. That would
be real fine.
Hi, Daddy.
Hi, baby.
How's everything
in Chicagoland?
Grandma and Grandpa
gave me lots of neat things.
How's Church, Daddy?
Does he miss me?
Well...
I--I guess
he's just fine.
I haven't seen him
this evening.
Make sure you put him
in the cellar
so he won't run out
in the road.
Kiss him good night
for me.
Yuck.
Kiss your own cat.
Want to talk to Gage?
Yeah.
Hi, Daddy.
I love you.
Aah!
Jesus.
Church.
[tapping bowl]
Food, Church.
[meow]
[tapping bowl]
Food.
Come on, Church.
Chow down.
[meow]
Christ.
I don't believe this.
[meow]
You stink, Church.
Hold on a second.
God, he chewed
his way out.
Jesus, boy.
Christ.
Damn it.
I tried to tell myself
that I buried him
alive.
I'm not a vet.
It was dark.
Sure, it was dark.
But his head swiveled
on his neck
like it was full
of ball bearings.
When you moved him,
he pulled out of the frost.
Sounded like a piece of tape
coming off a letter.
Live things
don't do that.
You stop melting the frost
under where you're laying
when you're dead.
Well, I feel like
I'm going crazy.
It was the ragman that told me
about the place.
He was half Micmac.
He knew how I felt
about my dog Spot.
Spot had got caught in barbed wire
that infected.
When he died,
I thought I was going to die.
Ragman did for me
what I did for you last night.
Only I wasn't alone
when Spot came back.
My mother was with me.
You could still see
the barbed wire marks on him.
[grrr]
Jud, come and get
Your dog!
He stinks of the ground
you buried him in!
Jud!
[barking]
Spot came back,
all right.
Spot!
He wasn't quite
the same dog I knew.
Spot.
When he died
that second time,
I buried him there
in the pet cemetery
where his bones
still lie.
A man doesn't always
know why he does things.
I think I did it
'cause your daughter
ain't ready
for her favorite pet
to die.
Maybe with more time,
she'll learn what death really is,
which is where
the pain stops
and the good memories
begin.
Has anyone ever buried a person
up there?
Christ
on His throne, no.
And who ever would?
Oh!
[grrr]
Shit.
How the hell
did you get in here?
Out!
Uh! Ow!
Bye-bye, Ellie.
Watch your step now.
Daddy!
Hi, sugar!
Come here.
Mmm.
Hi, Daddy.
Daddy, is Church
all right?
Yes.
I guess so.
He was asleep on the porch
when I left.
There you go.
I dreamed he got
hit by a car,
and you and Mr. Crandall buried him
in the pet cemetery.
That was a silly dream,
wasn't it?
Is he really all right?
Yes.
Hi, honey.
You want to take
your son, Doc?
Oh.
Hey.
[meow]
Phew. You smell bad.
Can cats have shampoos?
You have to take them
to someone
who grooms animals,
and it's pretty expensive.
I'll save my allowance
and pay for it.
Church smells bad.
I'll cough up
the money, Ellen.
I hate that smell.
Yes.
I hate it, too.
May the Lord
bless you and keep you.
May the Lord make His face
to shine upon you
and comfort you
and lift you up
and give you peace.
Amen.
- Amen.
Rachel not feeling well?
Just a touch of the flu.
She's been throwing up
ever since
Mrs. Rogers called
and said
Mrs. Dandridge--
That's enough, Ellen.
Poor Missy.
I don't know why God
takes someone like her,
who should still
have a bunch of years,
and lets an old fart
like me go on and on.
My father used
to have a saying, Jud.
God sees the truth...
but waits.
Ayuh.
How's your cat, Louis?
It's Ellie's cat.
No.
It's your cat now.
Possibly more dolphins
have beached
or stranded themselves
along the eastern
Maine coast,
and scientists
don't know why.
[meow]
What's up, sugar?
Daddy,
did Missy Dandridge
go to heaven?
Do you want
to talk about it?
Is Missy in heaven,
do you think?
I don't know, honey.
Different people believe
all sorts of different things.
Some believe
in heaven or hell.
Some think we come back
as little children,
and some think
we just wink out,
like a candle flame when
the wind blows hard.
Do you believe that?
No.
I think we go on.
Yeah.
I have faith in that.
You believe in it.
Give me a kiss.
What do you want
to watch?
I heard you
and Ellie tonight.
I thought
you might have.
I know you don't
approve of the subject.
I just get scared.
And you know me.
When I get scared,
I get defensive.
Scared of what?
Dying?
My sister Zelda--
I know. She died.
spinal meningitis.
She was in the back bedroom
like a dirty secret.
My sister died
in the back bedroom,
and that's
what she was...
a dirty secret.
I had to...
I had to feed her
sometimes.
I hated it,
but I did it.
We wanted her to die.
We wished...
for her to be dead.
It wasn't just so
she wouldn't feel pain.
It was so we wouldn't
feel any more pain.
She started to look
like this monster.
Even now, I wake up
and I think,
is Zelda dead yet?
Is she?
My parents were gone
when she died.
Rachel...
Ha ha ha.
She started to...
She started
to convulse...
and I thought...
I thought...
Oh, my God,
she's choking.
Zelda's choking.
And they'll come home,
and they'll say I
murdered her by choking.
They'll say,
"You hated her, Rachel,"
and that was true.
They'll say,
"You wanted her to be dead."
That was true, too.
And then she died.
And I started to scream.
I ran from
the house screaming,
"Zelda's dead! Zelda's dead!
Zelda's dead!"
And the neighbors
came out
and they--they looked.
They thought
I was crying.
But you know something?
I think maybe...
I was laughing.
If you were,
I salute you for it.
If I needed
another reason
not to like
your parents,
I have one now.
You should never have been
left alone with her, Rachel.
Never.
Where was a nurse?
They actually went out
and left
an 8-year-old kid
in charge
of her dying sister
who was
probably insane.
Where are you going?
To get you a Valium.
You know I don't take--
Tonight you do.
Well, in my heart
I could be ready to go
Get ready to go now
Let's go,
let's go, go
Look!
He pulled.
Daddy's flying a kite.
Mommy, look!
Watch it!
There it goes.
That's it, Louis.
Go, Daddy.
Higher.
We want it higher.
Let Gage do it.
Here, buddy.
God, she's so young
Sheena is
a punk rocker
Sheena is a punk rocker
Sheena is
a punk rocker
Now
Sheena is-- 떰
You're flying it.
There's the kite!
You got it.
Gage is flying it.
Can I fly it now?
Let Gage
finish his turn.
We gotted it.
We got it.
The kite goes.
Go ahead.
Run, buddy. Run.
Gage is flying it.
I'm flying it.
That kite
is getting up there.
Uh-oh.
It got away
from him, that numb shit.
Ellen...Creed!
Oh. I dropped it.
Daddy, can I fly it now?
OK. In just a minute.
I want to fly it.
Daddy, Daddy,
it's my turn now.
All right.
Just a minute.
Don't let him go
in the road, Louis!
Get him, Louis!
Get the baby!
Gage!
No!
Sedative
finally took hold.
Rachel's asleep.
I want to go back
to my own room.
I can't sleep with Mommy.
She keeps
stealing the covers.
Ellie, what
you got there?
Hmm?
What you got there?
Let me see.
Can I see?
Oh. Ain't that real nice?
You pulling him
in the wagon.
Bet he liked that,
didn't he?
I'm going to carry
this picture
until God lets Gage
come back.
Ellie...
God doesn't do
things like that.
He can
if He wants to.
I have to keep his things
waiting for him.
That's what I think.
I've got his picture.
I'll sit in his chair--
Ellie.
Louis.
Take care
Of your little girl.
She needs you.
I knew something
like this would happen.
I told her
when you married,
you'll have all
the grief you can stand.
Now, look at this.
I hope you rot in hell!
Where were you
while he played?
You stinking shit!
You killer of children!
Daddy!
Ellie!
Stop it!
You son of a bitch!
No!
You had no right!
What's wrong with you?
It's your son's funeral.
Get a hold of yourself.
Good night, Ellie.
Good night, Daddy.
Daddy?
God could take it back
if He wanted to,
couldn't He?
If He really,
really wanted to.
Can I have faith in that?
Yes.
I suppose you can.
Good night, Ellie.
[rowr]
Fuck off, hairball.
Mmm.
[rowr]
Jud, I buried
my son today.
I'm very tired.
I wonder
If we could just--
You're thinking thoughts
best not thought of.
I was thinking
about going to bed.
I'm responsible for
more pain in your heart
than you should have
tonight.
For all I know,
I may even
be responsible
for the death
of your son.
What?
Jud, you're talking crazy.
You are thinking of
putting him up there.
Don't deny the thought
hadn't crossed
your mind, Louis.
Louis...
You asked me if anyone
had ever buried a person
up there in
the Micmac grounds.
I lied to you
when I said no.
It's been done.
What you've been thinking of
has been done.
He was a local boy.
It was towards the end
Of the Second World War.
His name
was Timmy Baterman.
He was killed
on his way home
from
the Second World War.
His father Bill
was so grief-struck
he buried his son
up there
before he had the chance
to get to the bottom
of the truth.
I'll bite, Jud.
What's the bottom
Of the truth?
Well, that sometimes
dead is better.
The person
you put up there
ain't the person
that comes back.
It may look
like that person,
but it ain't
that person.
'cause...
whatever lives
in the ground
beyond the pet cemetery
ain't human at all.
Ha ha ha!
It was four or five days
after Timmy's funeral
that Margie Washburn
seen Timmy
walking up the road
towards Yorkie's Livery.
As time went by...
Aah!
lots of folks saw Timmy
walking back and forth.
But it was Margie
who finally came
to us men folks
and said it had
to be stopped.
She knew it was
an abomination.
So us men sat down
and talked it out.
We got in my car
and went to Baterman's
to take care of it,
one way or another.
There's no other way.
He's got to burn!
You're wrecking my house!
Stop it!
Timmy, stop it!
Daddy.
The place's going up!
Go away!
Get out
While you still can, Bill!
Bring out the cans.
Igot them.
Wait!
He's a monster, Bill.
Leave us alone!
He's my son!
Come, Timmy.
Let's get out.
No, Dad.
Hate living.
Come on, son!
Timmy!
Aah! Timmy!
No, Dad!
Hate living.
Louis, sometimes
dead is better.
The Indians knew that.
They stopped using
that burial ground
when the ground
went sour.
Don't think
about doing it.
The place gets holier,
but the place...
is evil.
Sometimes,
dead is better.
You see, Louis, what
I'm getting at here?
You understand?
You're telling me
that place knew
Gage was going
to die?
I'm saying...
that place might
have made Gage die
because I introduced you
to the power.
I may have murdered
your son, Louis.
This could
be the beginning
of patching things up
with your folks.
If something good doesn't
come from Gage's death,
I think...
I don't want to go
to Chicago, Grandma Dory.
Why not, darling?
I had a bad dream
last night.
About what?
About Daddy...
and Gage...
and someone named Pax-cow.
You guys
better get going.
You're going
to miss the boat.
Louis.
I am sorry.
What can I say?
I lost my mind.
We all lost our minds.
You take care
Of your mother.
Come with us, please.
I'll be there in three days,
four at the most.
Please, Daddy.
I'm scared.
Everything's going
to be all right, Ellie.
Do you swear?
I swear.
Come on, Ellie.
Let's go.
It's wrong.
What happened
to you is wrong.
Remember, Doc.
The barrier was not meant
to be crossed.
The ground is sour.
If it doesn't work...
if he comes back...
and he's like Jud said
Timmy Baterman was,
well, I'll just put him
back to sleep.
They don't have to know.
Rachel and Ellie don't--
don't ever have to know.
[Ellie crying]
Mommy.
Mo-Mommy.
Ohh, Mommy!
Mommy.
Mommy!
Mom-Mommy!
You had a bad dream.
That's all.
You know that,
don't you?
It wasn't a dream.
It was Pax-cow.
Pax-cow says Daddy will
do something really bad.
Who is Pax-cow?
Is he like
the bogeyman?
He's a ghost.
He's a good ghost.
He says he's sent
to warn us.
He says he was near Daddy
because they were together
when his soul was...
dis-- dis--
I can't remember.
Shh. Listen to me.
There are
no ghosts, Ellie.
There are no ghosts.
Now sleep and forget
this nonsense.
Do you hear me?
Would you at least call
and make sure Daddy's OK?
Of course I will.
Pax-cow? Where do
I know that name?
Pascow.
Pascow?
Was she saying Pascow?
[Ellie]
He was trying to help me
because Daddy
was helping him
when his soul dis-dis...
Discorporated.
I'm going
to bust you out, son.
[telephone rings]
[ring]
He's not home.
Probably went out
for a hamburger
or a chicken dinner.
You know how men are
when they're alone.
[ring]
Hello?
Hello, Jud.
It's Rachel.
I'm calling
from Chicago.
Chicago?
Is Louis with you?
No. We're going
to be here a while.
He needed a few days
to close things up
back there.
I just wondered
if he was with you.
No.
But if he drops by,
I'll tell him
to call you.
Don't bother.
I'm coming home.
Rachel, no.
You don't want to do that.
I have to do it, Jud.
Good-bye.
[dial tone]
Rachel! Rachel!
You've done it,
you stupid old man.
Now you got to undo it.
Oh, Gage.
It's going
to be all right.
I swear it's going
I'm coming
for you, Rachel.
And this time...
I'll get you.
Gage and I will get you
for letting us die.
Good evening again,
ladies and gentlemen.
We've had
a strong tailwind,
and we expect to arrive
at Boston's Logan Airport
almost on time.
Thank God.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Don't do that, babe.
- Make it wait.
- I can't.
All right.
I'll call the pilot.
I'm not going to stop,
Gage.
I'm not
going to look down.
I'm sorry.
It's been busy.
I don't have anything.
What about the Aries K
with the scratched side?
I do have an Aries K,
but it came in
beat up
with a long scrape.
I'll take it.
OK. Major credit card
and a license.
Louis.
See?
Just imagination.
Aah!
Now what?
It's trying
to stop you.
Do you hear me?
It's trying
to stop you.
Is anyone there?
Come back to me, Gage.
Come back to us.
[honk]
[honk honk]
Hey!
Hey, stop!
Hop in, babe.
Oh, thanky ou.
Oh, my.
Hee hee hee hee!
Hee hee hee hee hee!
Who's there?
Hee hee hee!
Let's play
hide-and-go-seek.
Gage?
You the one
playing games?
Ha ha ha ha!
Gage?
Come on out.
I brought you something.
Hee hee hee hee!
[rowr]
Where did you come--
Thank you so much.
Think nothing of it.
Well, I didn't get
a ticket, lady,
so you're welcome.
Whatever your problems are,
I hope they work out.
It's the end of the line for me, too.
I'm not allowed any further.
I'm sure things
will be fine.
I'm not.
[Zelda]
Rachel!
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
[rowr]
Church?
Jud?
Are you up there?
[Zelda]
Rachel.
Rachel?
Is that you?
I finally came back
for you, Rachel.
I'm going to twist
your back like mine
so you'll never
get out of bed again.
Never get
out of bed again.
Never get out of bed again!
Never get out
of bed again!
Ha ha ha ha!
[Gage[
Hee ha ha ha!
Hee hee.
Oh, Gage.
I brought you
something, Mommy.
Gage.
I brought you
something, Mommy.
Oh, Gage.
Gage.
I brought you
something, Mommy.
Aah!
Ohh!
Gee.
Oh, Christ.
Oh.
Gage.
Oh, my God.
Ha ha ha ha!
Gage?
[telephone rings]
Hello.
Hello, Louis.
It's Irwin.
I just wanted
to be sure
Rachel got back
all right.
Louis?
Are you there?
Yes, I'm here.
Did she get back
all right?
Yes. She's fine.
Put her on
at that end.
I'll put Ellie
on this one.
Ellie's very worried
about her mother.
She's almost
in hysterics.
She's...
Rachel's asleep.
I suggest
you wake her up.
Ellie had a dream
her mother was dead.
Irwin, I can't
talk to you right now.
[telephone rings]
Irwin,
I can't talk now.
[Gage]
I'm at Jud's, Daddy.
Will you come over
and play with me?
First I played
With Jud.
Then Mommy came,
and I played with Mommy.
We played, Daddy.
We had
an awful good time.
Now I want
to play with you.
What did you do?
Hee hee hee
hee hee hee hee!
What did you do?
Ha ha ha ha!
Hi, Church.
Want some grub,
Church?
Church!
Don't mind me.
Eat it
while you can.
That's right.
Today...
is Thanksgiving Day
for cats.
But only...
if they came back
from the dead.
Go on.
Lie down.
Play dead.
Be dead!
Gage?
Gage,
what have you done?
Rachel!
Scared you, didn't l?
Gage?
Hi, Daddy.
Now I want
to play with you.
Ha ha ha!
All right, Gage.
Let's play.
Hee hee ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Aah!
Ah ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Aah!
Daddy.
Come here.
Ha ha ha ha!
No fair.
No fair, no fair.
Rrarr.
I'm sorry, Louis.
I'm so sorry.
But don't
make it worse.
Don't.
I waited too long
with Gage.
With Rachel,
it will work
this time,
because
she just died.
She just died
a little while ago.
Louis...don't.
Please.
Louis.
No!
It will be
all right, Rachel.
I promise.
[Jud]
The soil of a man's heart
is stonier, Louis.
A man grows
what he can,
and then he tends it.
Because what you buy
is what you own.
And what you own...
always comes home to you.
[bong]
[ring]
Darling.
Aah!
Under the arc
of a weather-stained bone
Ancient goblins
amble alone
Come out of the ground
not making a sound
The smell of death
is all around
And at night when
the cold wind blows
No one cares,
nobody knows
I don't want
to be buried
In a pet sematary
I don't want
to live my life again
to be buried
In a pet sematary
I don't want
to live my life again
Fallen victim
to the sacred place
Just seen a grin
I can't escape
Old empty things,
the clicking of bones
Spirits moaning
among the tombstones
And at night
when the moon is bright
Someone cries,
something ain't right
I don't want
to be buried
In a pet sematary
I don't want
to live my life again
to be buried
In a pet sematary
I don't want
to live my life again
The moon is full,
the air is still
All of a sudden,
I feel a chill
Victorious grinning
faces writhing away
Skeleton dance,
I curse these days
And at night
when the wolves cry out
Listen close, then
you can hear me shout
I don't want
to be buried
In a pet sematary
I don't want
to live my life again
to be buried
In a pet sematary
I don't want
to live my life again
Oh, no
I don't want to live my life
not again