[Discordant beeping sounds]
[Spaceship engine humming]
[Electronic signal beeping]
ARE YOU ABLE TO SEE
ANYTHING AT ALL, BURT?
NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
ONLY A SURFACE OF CLOUDS.
THIS PLANET SEEMS
TO BE MADE OF FOG.
NOT EVEN INFRARED
RAYS GET THROUGH.
WELL, KEEP TRYING.
I'VE GOT THE LASER
ON INFRARED,
IT MAY PENETRATE.
[Electronic signal beeping]
THERE, THE STRANGE
SIGNALS ARE CONTINUING.
NOW THE LOCALIZATION
IS SHARPER.
15 DEGREES, FELCAR
COAXIAL ALFA VACUUM..
RIGHT.
THIS IS OUR SIXTH ORBIT
AROUND THIS PLANET,
AND THAT SIGNAL ALWAYS
COMES FROM THE SAME POINT.
IF A MAN-MADE
TRANSMITTER DOES EXIST,
THAT'S THE SPOT,
ALL RIGHT.
[Swoosh]
[Mark] 2 MORE METEORS.
YES, SIR. I'LL CHECK
ON THE TOTAL.
ELDON, TIONA, KELL, WE JUST
REJECTED 2 MORE METEORS.
WHAT'S OUR TOTAL NOW?
999, WESS.
1 MORE AND I'LL BAKE YOU
A LITTLE BIRTHDAY CAKE
WITH 1,000 CANDLES.
WITHOUT THIS REJECTOR,
WE'D LOOK LIKE A PIECE
OF SWISS CHEESE.
OUR SHIP WOULD BE DOWN
IN LESS THAN A MINUTE.
LET'S PREPARE FOR
A LANDING, BRAD.
OKAY.
ATTENTION. ATTENTION, ALL CREW
MEMBERS, PREPARE FOR LANDING.
IN 60 FRACTIONS OF MEGON, WE'LL
START THE LANDING MANEUVER.
THE INTENSITY OF THE
GRAVITATIONAL FIELD
WILL BE MAINTAINED
AT THE WAVE
MOMENT OF FORCE G 7.
SYNCHRONIZE THE
METEOR REJECTOR
ON THE ELECTRO-MAGNETIC
CONTROL DEVICE.
APPLY NEURO-VASCULAR TENSION.
SUPPRESS CORTICAL
AREAS X, Y, Z.
INSERT THE AUTOMATIC CONTROLS.
WE WILL KEEP A DISTANCE
OF 2 PARSECS
FROM OUR SISTER
SHIP GALLIOT.
RESPOND WHEN COMMAND RECEIVED.
[Radio beeping]
COMMAND RECEIVED.
SANYA, GET ME THE CAPTAIN
OF THE OTHER SHIP.
SPACESHIP ARGOS CALLING
SPACESHIP GALLIOT.
SPACESHIP GALLIOT,
WE'RE RECEIVING.
CAPTAIN SALAS IS WANTED
ON THE IONOSCOPE, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, MARK,
HE'S STANDING BY.
YOU WERE RIGHT, MARK.
IT'S NOT COSMIC RADIATION.
IT'S A REALITY,
A REALITY THAT WE'LL
SEE AT FIRST HAND.
GLAD TO HEAR YOU ADMIT IT,
SALAS. IT'S NEVER TOO LATE.
WE WERE NEVER AS CRAZY
AS YOU SEEMED TO THINK.
YOU CERTAINLY HAD
US WORRIED, THOUGH.
OH, YOU'VE PUT A SPY
ON BOARD? HUH, HUH.
ANYWAY, YOU'LL HAVE TO AGREE
IT WAS JUST LUCK.
YOU CAN'T CHASE AFTER ALL
THE SOUNDS IN THE UNIVERSE.
ALL RIGHT, SO IT'S NOT
A COSMIC CLOUD.
BUT WHAT ABOUT LIFE?
WHO CAN SAY YET THAT
THERE'S ANY LIFE ON AURA?
WHO CAN ASSURE US THAT IT'S NOT
A NATURAL SOURCE OF EMISSION?
WE'LL FIND OUT SOON ENOUGH.
RIGHT NOW, GET READY TO LAND.
SYNCHRONIZE ON GRAVITATIONAL
WAVE MOMENT OF FORCE G 7.
SHALL I PUT US ON
THE AUTOMATIC CONTROL?
YES. WHEN YOU'RE
2 PARSECS FROM US.
1 MINUTE.
MARK, WAIT.
YOUR YOUNGER
BROTHER IS HERE
AND HE HAS SOMETHING
ELSE TO TELL YOU.
MARK, I WANT
TO WARN YOU.
THIS WILL BE THE
FIRST AND ONLY TRIP...
WE'VE LOST IT.
SANYA, THE RESERVE CHANNEL.
[Flat beep]
ZINEX IMPULSE,
QUICKLY.
HELLO. HELLO, GALLIOT.
HELLO, GALLIOT?
HELLO! CONTACT'S
BEEN BROKEN, MARK.
THE ZINEX IMPULSE CHANNEL,
THROW IT ON.
THE SIGNAL'S BEEN
INTERRUPTED, MARK.
THE PLANET STOPPED
TRANSMITTING.
[Sanya] GALLIOT.
SANYA, WHAT ABOUT
THE GALLIOT?
[Sanya] GALLIOT, HELLO!
I'M NOT GETTING
ANYTHING, MARK.
THE ZINEX IMPULSE
CHANNEL, TRY IT AGAIN.
HELLO, HELLO. HELLO!
THERE'S NOTHING, MARK.
THE RADIO COMMUNICATIONS
ARE BLOCKED.
TRY IT AGAIN,
SANYA.
HELLO.
HELLO, GALLIOT!
[Rumbling]
[Mark] THE AUTOMATIC ALARM.
[Alarm sounding]
[Mark]
EMERGENCY! EMERGENCY!
THE GRAVITATIONAL FORCE
IS INCREASING RAPIDLY.
[Buzzing]
[Rumbling]
WESS, WHERE ARE WE AT?
GIVE ME A READING.
[Gasping]
20, MARK. 20 G.
SEAL BULKHEADS. GOT
TO ACTIVATE THEM NOW.
[Gasping]
[Alarm continues]
[Gasping and groaning]
BRAD, THE AUTOMATIC
CONTROL, DISENGAGE IT.
I'M SWITCHING TO MANUAL.
[Gasping]
[Humming]
[Metallic clanking]
[High-pitched clanking]
[Gasping]
[Hissing]
[Machines beeping]
[Grunting]
WHAT HAPPENED? WHY DID SHE
ATTACK YOU? IS SHE CRAZY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
DON'T YOU REMEMBER?
WESS!
[Grunting]
[Burt] MARK. TRY TO
GET HOLD OF HIM.
[Gasping]
MARK!
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR MINDS?
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH EVERYONE?
WHERE ARE YOU
GOING? MARK!
[Meteor rejector sounding]
[Mark] TIONA.
TIONA!
[Tiona gasping]
[Wess] STOP!
DR. KARAN! STOP!
CARTER. CARTER!
MARK, WHAT WAS
I TRYING TO DO?
MARK--
[Wess]
IN HERE, MARK!
MARK, NOW KARAN'S
GONE CRAZY.
I WAS JUST COMING TO
WHEN HE ATTACKED BRAD.
I RUSHED HIM, BUT HE
ESCAPED THROUGH THERE.
BURT, YOU STAY HERE.
WESS, COME WITH ME.
HE'S ACTIVATED
THE SECURITY LOCK.
[Groans]
THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO.
THEY OPEN ONLY WHEN THE
SENSORS TOUCH THE GROUND.
[Panting]
THE HELMETS! WE'D
BETTER GET THE HELMETS.
[Clicking]
[Clank]
[Groans]
[Coughing]
WHAT HAPPENED? HOW DID
I GET OUT OF THE SHIP?
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING
AT ME LIKE THAT FOR?
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED, KARAN.
ONLY SOME OF US HAVE BEEN
BEHAVING STRANGELY
WITH NO MEMORY
OF IT AFTERWARD.
DO YOU FEEL
ALL RIGHT NOW?
I GUESS SO.
YOU'RE SURE?
YES, YES,
I'M SURE.
ALL RIGHT,
GO INSIDE.
SOME OF THE MEN SEEM
TO BE HURT, DOCTOR.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THEM.
HE DOESN'T REMEMBER
ANYTHING EITHER.
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I WISH I KNEW.
[Mark] I CAN'T SEE
ANYTHING.
NOT A SIGN OF
THE GALLIOT.
YET WE DON'T SEEM
TO BE DAMAGED AT ALL.
COME ON, LET'S
GET IN THE SHIP.
I CAN'T SEE A SCRATCH ON
THE RADAR GUIDANCE ARMS.
LET'S CHECK
THE UNDERSIDE.
THERE'S NO DAMAGE.
IT'S AS IF WE MADE
A PRACTICE LANDING
AT THE SPACE
ACADEMY.
COME ON
LET'S GET IN.
[Hissing]
ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
QUIET DOWN.
STAY CALM.
LET'S ALL TRY
TO STAY CALM
AND FIGURE OUT
WHAT HAPPENED.
NOW, THE AUTOMATIC CONTROLS
WENT COMPLETELY HAYWIRE.
MAYBE WE CAN
FIND OUT WHY
AFTER WESS HAS HAD A CHANCE
TO CHECK OVER HIS RECORDINGS.
WITHOUT WARNING, THE FORCE OF
GRAVITY INCREASED LIKE MAD.
AND IT WENT
UP TO 40 G.
A FORCE WHICH
ONLY A PLANET
WITH A MASS 1,000 TIMES
SUPERIOR TO OURS
COULD'VE PUT OUT.
THAT'S NOT ALL.
WHILE YOU WERE
ALL UNCONSCIOUS
AND I WAS EXPECTING THE SHIP
TO CRASH HEAD-ON,
THE FORCE SUDDENLY STOPPED
AND WE SET DOWN GENTLY.
AND THEN...
YOU ALL WENT CRAZY.
[Brad] AND IF YOU
HADN'T HELD OUT,
I HATE TO THINK OF WHAT
WOULD'VE HAPPENED.
YES, IT IS PRETTY
PUZZLING.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
PROFESSOR KARAN?
I DON'T KNOW. I DON'T
KNOW WHAT TO THINK.
I'VE ALWAYS KNOWN THAT ANY
FORCE GREATER THAN 25 G'S
KILLS EVERY LIVING THING
IN A FEW SECONDS.
[Salas on radio]
URGENT. URGENT.
EMERGENCY!
BE QUIET.
CONDITIONS DESPERATE.
LITTLE CHANCE OF
SURVIVAL. HELP US.
WE CAN'T HOLD OUT
MUCH LONGER.
REPEAT.
CONDITIONS DESPERATE.
SOUNDS LIKE
CAPT. SALAS.
THEY MUST BE IN TROUBLE.
SANYA, KEEP TRYING.
BURT, TAKE A LOOK
ON THE INFRA-RAY,
SEE IF YOU CAN SPOT ANYTHING.
THEY MUST BE FAIRLY CLOSE.
URGENT. URGENT.
HELP US.
HELLO. HELLO. ARGOS
CALLING GALLIOT.
ARGOS CALLING
GALLIOT.
WE'RE RECEIVING YOU.
CONTINUE ON THIS FREQUENCY.
WE'LL TRY TO GET A FIX ON YOU.
WHAT IS YOUR POSITION?
ARGOS CALLING GALLIOT.
ARGOS CALLING GALLIOT!
MARK, LOOK!
WHAT HAVE
YOU GOT?
THE GALLIOT.
[Mark] THE RED'S CUT THROUGH.
CAN'T TELL HOW FAR IT IS.
GET ME A FIX ON
THIS RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL DO A LOW-ALTITUDE
TAKEOFF AND SEARCH.
THEY CAN'T BE
TOO FAR AWAY.
WESS, BRAD,
CONTROL.
[Rhythmic whooshing]
[Bubbling sounds]
[Hissing]
ALL OUR SOLAR BATTERIES
HAVE BEEN SHORT-CIRCUITED.
ANY VISIBLE REASON?
ANOTHER MYSTERY?
WESS, WHAT CAN
WE DO ABOUT IT?
I CHECKED THE TEMPERATURE.
SECOND LAVIC STAGE.
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN THE TEMPERATURE.
CAN WE GET
ACROSS IT OR NOT?
WELL, IT'S PRETTY
DANGEROUS DOWN THERE.
THE ROCKS APPEAR TO BE FUSED
AND THEY'RE SOLID ENOUGH.
IF THEY CONTINUE
ACROSS THE MARSH,
AND IF WE'RE LUCKY...
LET'S TRY IT.
CLEAR.
IT'S OBVIOUS.
THEY FOUGHT.
THEY FOUGHT AND
KILLED EACH OTHER OFF.
JUST AS WE WERE
ABOUT TO DO.
NONE OF THIS--THIS MADNESS
THAT HAS TOUCHED SOME OF US,
NONE OF THIS
IS COINCIDENCE.
THIS WAS PLANNED.
BY WHOM?
BY WHAT?
AND WHAT ABOUT
THE OTHERS?
WE CAN LOOK
FOR THEM.
POOR TOBY, ON
HIS FIRST TRIP...
THE CHAMBER'S LOCKED
FROM THE INSIDE.
WE'LL NEED A TORCH
TO BREAK THROUGH.
I COUNTED 4, WHAT
ABOUT THE OTHERS?
THEY DON'T SEEM
TO BE INSIDE.
LET'S TAKE A
LOOK AROUND.
[Wess] THERE ISN'T ANYBODY
IN THE UPPER CHAMBERS.
[Mark] AND WHAT ABOUT
THE CONTROL ROOM?
IT'S EMPTY.
LOOK IN THE DOME'S
SECONDARY CORRIDORS.
ALL RIGHT.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE'LL LOOK IN THE SECTIONS
OF THE AUTOMATIC CIRCUITS.
NOW, IN CASE OF
ANY EMERGENCY,
WE MEET IN THE ATOMIC
GENERATOR ROOM.
[Rumbling]
[Mark]
FIND ANYTHING?
[Wess] NO. THE ENERGY
SECTION IS DESERTED.
LET'S CONTINUE.
THE 3 THAT ARE MISSING CAN'T
DISAPPEAR INTO THIN AIR.
[Faint squeaking]
SHH.
LISTEN.
[Squeaking]
IT'S COMING FROM
THE GENERATOR ROOM.
TURRELL.
AND SALAS,
MARK?
THE METEOR REJECTOR
IS OUT OF COMMISSION.
IT CAN'T BE
REPAIRED, EITHER.
THE GALLIOT
WON'T FLY AGAIN.
NEITHER WILL
HER CREW.
[Squeaking]
WHAT ABOUT THIS BULKHEAD?
WE'VE GOT TO GET THROUGH.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF IT, MARK.
I'LL GET THE CUTTING
TORCH FROM THE ARGOS.
NO, YOU'D NEVER
MAKE IT ALONE.
NO. WE'LL BURY DEREK
AND THE OTHERS
AND THEN WE'LL LEAVE
YOU ON GUARD, ELDON.
WE'LL GO FOR THE
CUTTING TORCH
AND I PROMISE YOU, WE'LL GET
BACK JUST AS FAST AS WE CAN.
[Groaning and sobbing]
[Sobbing]
SANYA, I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL,
BUT DON'T GO TO PIECES NOW.
JUST BE THANKFUL
WE WERE SPARED.
COME ON. WE'VE GOT
TO KEEP MOVING.
WE'LL GET BACK AS FAST
AS WE CAN, ELDON.
KEEP A SHARP WATCH.
[Winds howling]
[Gun loading]
[Male voice]
ELDON...
[Mark] ELDON?
ELDON, WHERE ARE YOU?
ELDON?
ELDON!
MAYBE HE'S INSIDE THE SHIP.
TIONA, YOU STAY HERE.
IF ANYTHING MOVES, SHOOT FIRST,
ASK QUESTIONS LATER.
[Mark] IT'S WEIRD.
THERE'S NO ONE HERE.
[Wess] BUT WE LEFT
4 BODIES HERE.
HOW COULD THEY
HAVE DISAPPEARED?
ELDON?
ELDON!
KIR! SALAS!
WHERE ARE THEY?
THEY'RE GONE.
ALL OF THEM.
ELDON, TOO. I LEFT
HIM ON GUARD.
LISTEN, MARK,
MAYBE YOU IMAGINED IT.
MAYBE THE BODIES
REALLY WEREN'T IN HERE,
YOU JUST THOUGHT YOU
SAW THEM. HALLUCINATION.
I DON'T SUFFER FROM
HALLUCINATIONS, KARAN.
I SAW THE BODIES.
MAYBE OUR SENSES REACT IN
A STRANGE WAY ON THIS PLANET.
I SAW THE BODIES.
I SAW MY BROTHER, DEAD.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO ELDON, THEN?
HE WASN'T A GHOST,
A HALLUCINATION.
LET'S TAKE IT EASY.
THERE MUST BE SOME
LOGICAL EXPLANATION.
[Karan]
THAT'S RIGHT, MARK.
MARK.
WHAT IS IT, WESS?
WE WEREN'T
DREAMING.
THOSE BODIES
REALLY EXISTED.
LOOK, BLOOD!
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
WHAT HAPPENED?
TIONA, WHAT DID
YOU SEE? TELL US.
COME ON, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE. HURRY!
[Squeaking]
[Creaking]
THERE SEEMS TO BE
SEVERAL THINGS
COMPLETELY
UNEXPLAINABLE.
FOR 2 YEARS, WE HEARD
THE ELECTRONIC SIGNALS
COMING FROM
THIS PLANET.
NOW THAT WE'RE
HERE, NOTHING.
YES, BUT WE DID HEAR VOICES.
A STRANGE TONGUE, BUT VOICES.
THERE WERE INTELLIGENT
BEINGS HERE.
YOU COULD'VE FOOLED ME.
I NEVER FELT SO ALL ALONE.
MAYBE WE'RE
NOT ALONE.
SOMEBODY
OR SOMETHING
COULD BE WATCHING
US HERE, RIGHT NOW.
IF THERE ARE ANY INTELLIGENT
CREATURES ON THIS PLANET,
THEY'RE OUR ENEMIES.
WESS, YOU'VE BEEN TAKING
SIGHTINGS AND ADDING FIGURES,
WHAT DOES IT
COME OUT TO?
HOW LONG CAN
WE STAY HERE?
3 DAYS,
MARK.
ANOTHER 3 DAYS BEFORE
THIS PLANET'S ORBIT
WILL HAVE SWEPT
US SO FAR AWAY,
WE MAY NOT GET
BACK HOME AT ALL.
WHAT DO
YOU THINK?
CAN YOU BOOST THE SOLAR
BATTERIES BY THEN?
I'M TRYING TO HOOK UP SOME
OTHER WAY OF STARTING US.
WHAT ARE OUR
CHANCES?
WE HAVE 3 CHANCES
IN 10 TO MAKE IT,
OR BE BLOWN
TO SMITHEREENS.
ALL RIGHT, WESS, TOMORROW
MORNING, YOU GET TO WORK.
TAKE WHOEVER YOU
NEED TO HELP YOU.
RIGHT NOW, I THINK WE
SHOULD ALL GET SOME SLEEP.
I THINK WE
NEED IT.
[Clicking on dictaphone]
A CAPTAIN SHOULD
NOT BE AFRAID.
AND I CONFESS NOW,
TO WHOEVER MAY HEAR THIS,
THAT TODAY, NOW,
I AM EXPERIENCING FEAR.
I MUST NOT LET MY
CREW KNOW THIS,
I MUST KEEP THEM BUSY.
I MUST NOT LET THEM KNOW
THAT THE SITUATION
APPEARS MORE HOPELESS
WITH EACH PASSING DAY.
DICTATED BY CAPT. MARK MARKARY,
OF THE SPACESHIP ARGOS
ON THE PLANET AURA--
[Thud]
[Meteor rejector sounding]
WESS!
MORE TROUBLE?
HE WAS TRYING TO DISCONNECT
THE METEOR REJECTOR.
DISCONNECT THE
METEOR REJECTOR?
I DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
I ASSURE YOU, I DON'T
UNDERSTAND IT EITHER.
WESS, YOU KNEW WHAT
YOU WERE DOING.
YES, I KNEW.
I WAS FULLY AWARE,
ALL THE TIME.
WHAT?
I COULDN'T HELP MYSELF.
I FOUGHT IT WITH ALL MY POWER.
BUT, IT WAS
NO USE.
I HAD TO DISCONNECT
THE METEOR REJECTOR.
BUT WHY,
WESS, WHY?
I DON'T KNOW!
IT WAS LIKE...
LIKE ANOTHER WILL
FIGHTING MY OWN,
IN MY MIND.
TRYING TO TAKE
OVER CONTROL.
DR. KARAN, HAVE YOU GOT
ANY THOUGHTS ON THIS?
THE ONLY CONCLUSION
I CAN MAKE
IS THAT EACH ONE OF US
IS HIS OWN WORST ENEMY.
BUT HOW?
WHY?
I'M AFRAID
I KNOW.
WHATEVER UNSEEN
BEINGS ARE OUT THERE,
THEY APPARENTLY
HAVE THE POWER
TO INFLUENCE OUR MINDS
WHEN WE'RE UNCONSCIOUS.
THEY TRIED IT DURING
THE LANDING
AND JUST NOW WHEN
WE WERE SLEEPING.
IF WHAT YOU SAY
IS TRUE, KARAN,
WE MUSTN'T GIVE THEM
ANY MORE CHANCES.
FROM NOW ON, WE'LL PUT A GUARD
ON ANYONE WHO'S SLEEPING.
[Light thud]
[Gasps]
WHO'S THERE?
BURT!
WHAT'S UP?
I...I DON'T KNOW.
I THOUGHT I HEARD
SOMETHING.
DID YOU SEE
ANYTHING?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I SAW.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW IF
I SAW ANYTHING AT ALL.
MARK SAID TO SING OUT
IF WE SAW ANYTHING
NOT IN THE BOOK.
IF WE SAW ANY THING AT ALL.
I'M GOING TO REPORT.
EMERGENCY. GUARD POST 3.
EMERGENCY.
WESS, YOU COME WITH ME.
THE REST OF YOU, BE CAREFUL.
WHAT IS IT?
I THOUGHT I SAW
SOMETHING.
WHAT?
OUT THERE.
WELL, LIKE
LUMINOUS GLOBES.
I SAW THEM OUT OF
THE CORNER OF MY EYE.
BUT WHEN I LOOKED,
THEY WERE GONE.
WHERE'S BURT?
HE'S GONE BACK
TO POST NUMBER 2.
KEEP YOUR EYES OPEN,
BUT DON'T GET CARRIED AWAY.
[Buzzing]
WHO'S OUT THERE?
HOLD IT!
[Screaming]
BURT, WHAT HAPPENED?
TELL ME, WHO DID IT?
IT WAS...CAPTAIN,
CAPTAIN SALAS.
[Groans]
WHAT'S OUT THERE, MARK?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE TO FIND
OUT BEFORE THEY KILL US ALL.
COME ON, LET'S GET HIM INTO
THE SHIP. GIVE ME A HAND.
[Machine humming]
1 ENTIRE CREW LOST AND 2
OF OUR OWN CREWMEN GONE.
BURT DEAD,
ELDON DISAPPEARED.
AND THIS UNKNOWN ENEMY
KEEPS GETTING CLOSER.
[Karan] THE ENEMY IS ALSO
BECOMING VISIBLE.
WHAT DO YOU
MEAN BY THAT?
WELL, YOU SAW
SOMETHING.
SOMETHING NOT
QUITE IDENTIFIABLE,
OUT OF THE CORNER
OF YOUR EYE.
AS IF IT WERE COMPOSED
OF LITTLE GLOBES OF LIGHT,
SOMETHING FLEETING,
NOTHING DEFINITE.
THE MINUTE I LOOKED AT
THE THINGS DIRECTLY,
THEY WERE GONE.
[Sanya] HOW CAN
YOU EXPLAIN IT?
[Mark]
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S POSSIBLE THEY'RE
AN ALIEN FORM OF LIFE.
[Dr. Karan] THAT'S TRUE. THEIR
FORM HERE COULD BE BASED ON
A DIFFERENT PLANE
OF VIBRATIONS.
FLESH-AND-BLOOD
MEN CAN'T SEE THEM,
EXCEPT OBLIQUELY,
AS YOU DID, MARK.
[Wess] THOSE STRANGE WAILS
WE HEARD COULD BE THEIR VOICES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL, WE'LL BURY
BURT TOMORROW.
ANOTHER TOMB WE HAVE TO LEAVE
ON THIS DANGEROUS PLANET.
SANYA?
I'LL BE RIGHT
WITH YOU, MARK.
FIRST, I WANT TO REMOVE
BURT'S NAMEPLATE.
SANYA.
SANYA, COME ON.
THEY NEED YOU.
OH, I STILL HAVE
BURT'S NAMEPLATE.
GIVE IT TO ME.
I'LL FINISH THE RECORDS.
YOU'VE DONE ENOUGH TODAY.
THANK YOU.
AAH!
[Crash]
[Sobbing]
[Winds howling]
REST WELL, BURT.
I'M SORRY WE WEREN'T
AROUND TO HELP YOU.
I PROMISE WE'LL TRY TO SEE
THAT YOU DIDN'T DIE IN VAIN.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S NOT
STAND AROUND,
WE'VE GOT
WORK TO DO.
FEELING BETTER,
TIONA?
BETTER,
MARK.
I SWEAR IT, MARK.
I DIDN'T IMAGINE IT.
WESS?
I THINK WE'LL
MAKE IT, MARK.
I'M BEGINNING TO GET ENERGY
TRACES ACROSS THE INDUCTORS.
HOW MUCH LONGER?
WE MIGHT BE READY
BY TONIGHT.
GOOD. WE'RE MAKING
A LITTLE TOUR OF INSPECTION.
CARTER SAYS HE SAW
SOMETHING IN THE VALLEY,
SOMETHING SHINING.
LET'S GO
TAKE A LOOK.
[Carter] MARK!
COME HERE.
LOOK DOWN THERE.
THAT'S WHAT
I SAW SHINING.
[Mark]
FINALLY, SOMETHING TANGIBLE.
THAT DOESN'T DISAPPEAR
WHEN I LOOK STRAIGHT AT IT.
[Sanya] LOOKS LIKE IT'S BEEN
HERE FOR A LONG TIME.
LOOK HOW PITTED AND
SCARRED THE HULL IS.
[Marc] DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
ANY SHIP I'VE EVER SEEN.
[Sanya] DO YOU THINK
IT BELONGS TO THE AUREANS?
[Carter] I DOUBT THEY EVER
BUILT ANY SPACESHIPS.
IF THEY HAD,
WE WOULD'VE...
[Gasps]
LOOK, MARK.
[Mark] IT'S 3 TIMES
THE SIZE OF US,
AND JUDGING BY
THE DETERIORATION
OF THE CALCIUM,
IT MUST'VE BEEN
HERE A LONG TIME.
PROBABLY BELONGED TO
AN ANCIENT CIVILIZATION.
CARTER, YOU STAY HERE.
KEEP YOUR EYES AND EARS OPEN.
RIGHT.
SANYA AND I WILL TAKE A LOOK
AROUND INSIDE THIS THING.
OH, UH, IF HE MOVES,
JUST CALL OUT.
RIGHT.
[Booming sounds]
[High-pitched buzzing,
Sanya gasps]
SANYA,
WHAT IS IT?
OH, I...
I GOT A SHOCK.
HOW?
TOUCHING THAT.
[High-pitched buzzing]
OUCH!
THAT MUST BE
OVER 200 VOLTS.
I WONDER WHAT
THEY USED IT FOR.
POSSIBLY IT'S AN
ELECTRIC TORCH. THEY...
HELD IT IN THEIR HANDS
AND IT BECAME LUMINOUS.
BEINGS AS BIG AS THEY SEEM
TO HAVE BEEN COULD HAVE HELD IT
WITHOUT FEELING
ANY KIND OF SHOCK.
[Click]
[Machine growling]
[Clicking]
[Door slamming]
CARTER.
CARTER!
[Growling continues]
CAR...TER!
[Clicking]
[Crashing]
[Growling stops]
MARK, LOOK
WHAT I FOUND.
WHAT IS IT?
LOOKS LIKE A
TUNING FORK.
[Buzzing]
WHY DIDN'T WE THINK
OF THAT BEFORE?
OF WHAT?
THE LOCKING DEVICE
COULD BE A SONIC ONE,
A LOCK DESIGNED
TO OPEN ONLY
TO A CERTAIN SOUND, TO A
CERTAIN FREQUENCY ONLY.
[Buzzing]
MARK, IT'S STRANGE
IN HERE. I CAN'T BREATHE.
[Gasping]
SOMETHING'S DRAWING THE
AIR OUT THROUGH THIS VENT.
[Sanya gasping]
WE'VE GOT TO FIND A WAY
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
IF ONLY WE COULD FIND
THE SECRET OF THAT LOCK.
[Buzzing]
OOH!
[Rapid beeping]
QUICK,
GET OUT!
CARTER!
CARTER, WHERE
ARE YOU?
MAYBE HE'S GONE BACK
TO THE ARGOS FOR HELP.
YES, YOU COULD
BE RIGHT. COME ON.
LET'S GO.
LET'S GET BACK.
CARTER?
YES.
NO, MARK. HE'S
NOT WITH US.
HE WAS WITH YOU,
WASN'T HE?
HAS HE DISAPPEARED
AS WELL?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT
HAPPENED LATER.
MARK?
TIONA, SHE'S
IN SHOCK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
SHE WAS
STANDING GUARD
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN
I HEARD HER SCREAM.
WHEN I REACHED HER,
SHE COULD ONLY
POINT AND WHISPER,
"DANNY, TOBY."
THERE WAS NOTHING, MARK.
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
SHE SIMPLY
BROKE DOWN.
WE'D BETTER
TALK TO HER.
I SAW THEM, AAH.
I SAW THEM, AAH...
[Gasping]
I SAW THEM.
I LOOKED RIGHT
AT THEM.
WHO DID YOU SEE,
TIONA? WHO?
THEY WERE THERE,
IN THE FOG.
ALL MUTILATED
AND BLOODY.
WHO, TIONA, WHO?
TELL ME.
I LOOKED RIGHT
AT THEM.
THEY DIDN'T GO AWAY.
THEY WERE HUMANS,
NOT GHOSTS.
WHO, TIONA, WHO? TELL ME,
WHO DID YOU SEE, TIONA?
EMPTY FACES.
DEAD FACES.
[Sobbing]
[Winds howling]
POST NUMBER 1.
REPLY TO CALL.
POST NUMBER 2,
POST NUMBER 2.
CALL RECEIVED. ALL OK.
HERE'S POST
NUMBER 3.
POST NUMBER 3.
EVERYTHING FINE
HERE TOO.
I'M PASSING BACK
TO NUMBER 1.
MACHINERY ROOM.
THIS IS POST
NUMBER 1. WESS?
I'M ANXIOUS TO KNOW
HOW YOU'RE DOING.
STANDING GUARD
HERE MAKES ONE
EVEN MORE IMPATIENT
FOR THE BLAST-OFF.
IS THERE MUCH
MORE TO DO
BEFORE THE BATTERIES
WILL BE READY? WELL?
I UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE WORRIED.
BUT I DON'T THINK IT'LL
BE TOO MUCH LONGER.
WE'RE PRACTICALLY
THERE, MARK.
ANOTHER 8 CIRCUITS
TO GO AND THEN...
AND THEN WE EITHER
TAKE OFF OR WE...
OR WE BLOW UP.
RIGHT NOW, I'D
WELCOME EITHER ONE.
POST NUMBER 3 ALARM!
WHO'S THERE?
WHO'S OUT THERE?
NO! DON'T FIRE.
SALAS.
KIR.
YES, MARK.
IT'S US.
WE'RE SO EXHAUSTED
IT'S HARD TO CONCENTRATE.
WE REMEMBER DESCENDING
FOR A LANDING
WITH ALL CONDITIONS
PERFECT.
THEN NOTHING.
UNTIL WE FOUND
OURSELVES
FIGHTING OUR WAY
OUT OF UNCONSCIOUSNESS
SOMEWHERE OUT THERE.
WELL?
THAT'S ABOUT
IT, MARK.
GO ON.
WE WALKED
AROUND SOME,
LOOKING FOR
THE GALLIOT.
BUT WE DIDN'T
FIND HER.
IT WAS A MIRACLE
THAT YOU FOUND US.
ALL RIGHT. I'M GLAD YOU
MADE IT. I SURE CAN USE YOU.
NOW, GO AND
GET SOME SLEEP.
THANKS, MARK.
I FORGOT. IF ONE OF YOU SLEEPS,
THE OTHER MUST STAND GUARD.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
I'LL EXPLAIN IT LATER.
VERY WELL,
MARK.
WHAT DO YOU
MAKE OF IT?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
TO THINK, MARK.
SHOCK? TEMPORARY
OR PARTIAL AMNESIA?
BY NOW, NOTHING
SHOULD SURPRISE US.
ANYWAY, YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
THE FACT THAT THEY'RE HERE.
AND VERY
MUCH ALIVE.
OR SO IT SEEMS.
[Tiona]
MARK.
YOU SAID "SEEMS", MARK.
HOW MANY STRANGE
THINGS SEEM
AND THEN ARE EVER SINCE
WE GOT ON THIS PLANET?
I REALLY SAW THEM,
THE 3 WE BURIED YESTERDAY.
I KNOW THEY'RE DEAD.
AND I SAW
ANOTHER ONE, MARK.
WHO, TIONA?
BURT.
BURT?
EVEN THOUGH WE
BURIED HIM YESTERDAY.
I SAW HIM, MARK.
I SAW HIM.
I SAW HIM, MARK!
IF ONLY I COULD BE CERTAIN
OF WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
THERE'S A WAY
TO BE CERTAIN.
YOU SEE?
IT'S INTACT.
[Tiona]
OPEN IT, MARK.
AH!
[Meteor rejector sounding]
[Door clanks shut]
WESS!
DR. KARAN!
SALAS AND KIR ARE
NOT IN THEIR BUNKS.
HAVE YOU
SEEN THEM?
NO.
HAVE YOU?
SALAS!
NO, IT'S NOT SALAS.
JUST HIS BODY.
I INHABIT THE BODY
OF YOUR LATE CAPTAIN.
AND I'M JUST ONE OF MANY
BEINGS ON THIS PLANET.
MANY BEINGS WHO
ARE DESPERATE.
WE'VE BEEN IN TROUBLE
MANY YEARS NOW,
AND WE'RE FIGHTING
TO SURVIVE.
WE ARRANGED FOR SEVERAL
OF YOU TO KILL EACH OTHER
SO THAT WE COULD
TAKE OVER YOUR BODIES.
YOU ARE OUR LAST CHANCE.
IT'S IMPERATIVE THAT OUR
RACE CONTINUE TO EXIST.
AT OUR EXPENSE?
IF YOU WERE IN OUR PLACE,
YOU WOULD UNDERSTAND.
ON YOUR PLANET,
I KNOW YOU HUMANS HAVE FOUGHT
AND KILLED FOR CENTURIES.
DO YOU REALLY EXPECT US
TO BE ANY DIFFERENT?
WE CANNOT BE WIPED OUT.
WE'LL STOP AT NOTHING.
WE MUST FIGHT, NO MATTER HOW.
WE ARE A RACE
THAT EXISTS ON
A VIBRATORY PLANE
DIFFERENT FROM YOURS.
OUR LIMITATIONS ARE
ENTIRELY DIFFERENT.
OUR TECHNOLOGY,
WE CANNOT BUILD ANYTHING,
SPACESHIPS LIKE THIS.
WE NEED SHIPS TO GET AWAY.
PERHAPS OUR SURVIVAL IS
POSSIBLE SOMEWHERE ELSE.
OUR SUN'S BEEN DYING,
AS YOU CAN SEE.
AND THAT MEANS THE END
OF OUR SPECIES AS WELL.
WE HAVE BEEN ATTEMPTING TO
SUMMON YOU HERE FOR CENTURIES.
JUST AS OUR SUN HAD
NO MORE ENERGY,
YOU HEARD OUR MESSAGE.
WE NEVER EXPECTED YOU
TO ACTUALLY RESPOND.
YOU MEAN, IT WAS
NOTHING BUT A LURE.
YOU WANTED US HERE.
THAT'S WHY YOU
SENT THAT MESSAGE.
HAVE YOU TRIED
THIS TRICK BEFORE?
YES.
THE STRANGE SHIP
FROM ANOTHER SYSTEM.
AND I SUPPOSE YOU
NEED OUR DEAD BODIES?
NO. THEY MUST BE
WILLING ONLY TO SUBMIT.
LOSE THEIR BODIES AS WELL
AS LOSE THEIR WILL.
WE'LL NEVER SUBMIT TO
A BREED OF PARASITES.
OUR RELATIONSHIP
WOULD BE SYMBIOTIC.
IN EFFECT, WE
WOULD BE 1 BODY.
IT WOULD IN NO
SENSE BE PARASITICAL.
YOU'VE GOT NO CHOICE.
EITHER ALL OF US
GO BACK TOGETHER
OR NONE OF YOU,
NOBODY WILL GO BACK.
YOU WILL NEVER GET THERE.
YOU'LL SEE. WE WILL
GET THERE, MARK.
A CERTAIN REJECTOR,
VITAL TO YOU,
HAS BEEN TAKEN AWAY.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE
WITHOUT IT.
WE'LL RETURN IT TO YOU,
ONLY IF YOU AGREE TO
TAKE US BACK WITH YOU.
ALL RIGHT, YOU'VE
HEARD ALL OF THE FACTS.
AND YOU'LL COOPERATE.
NO, NEVER.
WE'LL GIVE UP OUR LIVES
TO SAVE OUR OWN RACE.
QUICK, THE GENERATOR ROOM!
WESS, YOU HAVE THE RED KEY
TO THE ATOMIC DETONATORS.
HERE'S THE
GREEN ONE.
I WANT 3 POUNDS
OF PLUTONIUM.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO, MARK?
THE GALLIOT'S GOING
TO BE BLOWN UP
WITH ITS ENTIRE CARGO
OF LIVING DEAD.
BUT FIRST, I'VE GOT TO GET
BACK THE METEOR REJECTOR.
WESS, HOW LONG WILL IT
TAKE YOU TO GET READY?
I HAVE TO FINISH THE
PHOTONIC IGNITION.
THE REST IS ALL SET.
GOOD. I WANT YOU TO STAY HERE.
YOU 2 COME WITH ME.
WESS, AS SOON AS WE'RE OUT,
CLOSE THE DOORS
AND THE BULKHEADS, BUT
KEEP THE SCREENS TURNED ON.
AS SOON AS YOU SEE
US COMING BACK,
TURN ON
THE IGNITION.
WE'LL WORRY ABOUT
REPLACING THE REJECTOR
AFTER WE'RE
OUT IN SPACE.
THAT'S TAKING
A TERRIBLE RISK.
YES. I WISH IT WERE
THE ONLY RISK
WE'D HAVE TO RUN
BEFORE TAKING OFF.
BUT THERE'S NO OTHER SOLUTION.
GO ON, GET THE DETONATORS.
TIONA, YOU STAY HERE.
COVER OUR RETREAT.
DON'T MOVE FOR
ANY REASON.
AND REMEMBER, THE DANGER
IS NOT ONLY IN FRONT OF YOU.
15 SECONDS AFTER
THE GALLIOT EXPLODES,
IF WE HAVEN'T
COME BACK,
YOU RUN TO THE ARGOS
AND TAKE OFF, UNDERSTAND?
MARK, I CAN'T LET--
THAT'S AN
ORDER, KARAN.
LET'S GO.
[Gasping]
[Winds howling]
[Loud hissing]
THERE'S NOBODY HERE.
NOW, I WANT YOU 2
TO STAY RIGHT HERE.
NO, MARK. YOU
WON'T GO ALONE.
LISTEN, BRAD, I'M NOT
TRYING TO BE A HERO.
WE EACH HAVE
1 CHARGE.
IF I DON'T MAKE IT,
IT'LL BE YOUR TURN.
IF HE FAILS,
YOU TRY IT NEXT.
YOU STAY HERE,
BRAD. COVER US.
MY BROTHER.
HE'S TURNED
INTO 1 OF THEM.
TAKE THE COUNT.
READY? NOW.
GO AHEAD.
1...2...3.
[Clicking]
[Loud humming]
QUICK, IN THE
GENERATOR ROOM.
[Meteor rejector sounding]
SANYA, GIVE ME
THE COUNTDOWN.
29...28...27...
26...25...
[Toby]
ALL RIGHT, YOU CAN STOP NOW.
20--
THROW AWAY YOUR GUN.
LEAVE THE METEOR REJECTOR.
YOU'D BETTER GET USED
TO THE IDEA, MARK.
YOU'VE REACHED THE END.
YOU HAVE LOST.
TOBY, IF YOU HAVE ANYTHING
LEFT IN YOU OF WHAT YOU WERE,
LET ME GO ON.
FORTUNATELY, THERE'S
NOTHING OF WHAT I WAS LEFT.
ONLY THE BODY'S
THE SAME AND NOW...
[Sanya grunts]
NO USE, MARK. YOU CAN'T
HARM ME WITH VIOLENCE.
SORRY, TOBY,
BUT THIS IS THE ONLY WAY I CAN
PREVENT YOU FROM STOPPING ME.
AH!
[Meteor rejector stops]
TIME'S RUNNING
OUT. HURRY.
[Sighs]
[Grunting and groaning]
AH!
[High-pitched beeping]
[Rumbling]
AH!
[Bubbling]
THERE THEY ARE.
THEY'RE BEING FOLLOWED.
WE'D BETTER
HELP THEM.
[Screaming]
[Groan]
KARAN, BRAD, TIONA:
DEAD.
DEAD?
I'D BETTER REPLACE THE
METEOR REJECTOR RIGHT AWAY.
SANYA, YOU TAKE THE CONTROLS
UNTIL WE COME BACK.
IT'S SAD, MARK.
OUT OF 18 PEOPLE, THERE
ARE ONLY 3 OF US LEFT.
I'M ASHAMED
TO BE ALIVE.
THEY DIED TO
SAVE OUR PLANET.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
OUR WORLD INVADED BY THOSE
HORRIBLE CREATURES?
JUST THINKING ABOUT IT,
SEEMS A NIGHTMARE.
MARK.
YES, IT IS
SAD, WESS.
BUT IT WAS ONLY LUCK
THAT BROUGHT US HERE.
WESS, YOU NEED
SOME SLEEP.
YOU HAVEN'T SLEPT
FOR 2 NIGHTS.
YES.
SANYA AND I WILL
KEEP WATCH.
I NEED
SOME SLEEP.
[Footsteps approaching]
[Door screeching]
WHO'S THERE?
MARK, IS IT YOU?
SANYA?
IF I WASN'T SO WIDE AWAKE,
I'D SWEAR I WAS DREAMING.
WHAT HAPPENED, WESS?
I WAS ABOUT
TO FALL ASLEEP,
WHEN I HEARD FOOTSTEPS
OUT IN THE PASSAGEWAY.
THEY APPROACHED
MY CABIN.
THEN WHAT
HAPPENED?
THEN, THE DOOR
OPENED, SLOWLY.
AS IF SOMEONE WERE DEBATING
WHETHER OR NOT TO COME IN.
AND DID THEY?
NO, SANYA.
THEN YOU DIDN'T
SEE ANYTHING.
YES, I DID.
HE WAS HOLDING HIS
FIELD RAY GUN.
HE WAS MIRRORED
ON THE METAL WALL.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU SAW HIM?
I KNOW YOU WON'T
BELIEVE ME, SANYA.
I CERTAINLY WISH I
WAS WRONG, MYSELF.
BUT IT WAS REALLY
HIM. MARK!
IT WAS MARK, SANYA.
WHY DID HE
COME TO ME SO...
FURTIVELY?
MAYBE HE WANTED
TO KILL ME.
WELL, THEN WHAT ARE YOUR
CONCLUSIONS, WESS?
UNFORTUNATELY, THERE'S
ONLY 1 CONCLUSION.
EVEN MARK IS CONTROLLED
BY ONE OF THEM.
OH, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
LET'S GO SEE.
WESS?
WAIT A MINUTE.
MARK.
WESS HAS FOUND
OUT ABOUT US.
DON'T BE
AFRAID, WESS.
NOBODY WANTS
TO HARM YOU.
TO KILL YOU.
YOU...
YOU'RE ONE
OF THEM.
AND YOU
TOO, SANYA.
IT'S HORRIBLE.
YOU.
BOTH OF YOU.
YOU MUST BECOME
ONE OF US.
ALL YOU HAVE TO
DO IS WANT IT.
JUST LET ONE
OF US JOIN YOU.
IT'LL GIVE YOU THIS
WONDERFUL NEW COMPLEXITY.
NO. NO!
OUR WORLD WILL NEVER
FALL INTO YOUR HANDS!
MAYBE NOT, BUT YOU WON'T
BE THE ONE TO STOP US.
YES, I WILL!
[Meteor rejector sounding]
AH!
[Groaning]
SANYA, WITHOUT THE
METEOR REJECTOR,
WE'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO REACH HOME.
WHAT DO WE DO?
WE'LL HAVE TO LAND NOW,
ON THAT PLANET.
I'VE DONE AN ANALYSIS
WITH A SPECIAL PROBE.
WE CAN EXIST IN
THE ATMOSPHERE.
IT'S THE THIRD PLANET
OF THE STAR WE CALL SOL.
IT'S SO SMALL, IT'S
NOT EVEN MARKED
ON THE ASTRONAVIGATION
CHARTS.
BUT WILL IT BE POSSIBLE
TO LIVE THERE,
FOR US AND THOSE
WHO FOLLOW US?
IT'S MOST LIKELY A YOUNG,
PRIMITIVE WORLD.
BUT I THINK IT'LL BE
ALL RIGHT FOR US.
[Sanya] I'LL ACTIVATE THE
LONG-RANGE TELESCOPIC LENS.
[Chuckles]
YES, I WAS RIGHT.
IT IS A PUNY CIVILIZATION.
THEIR BUILDINGS ARE STILL
MADE OF STONE AND IRON.
HOW WILL THEY
ACCEPT US?
I HOPE, WELL.
FOR THEM.