["THE STAR-SPANGLED BANNER"
PLAYING ON TV]
Hello.
What do you look like?
Talk louder. I can't hear you.
Hey, hello, hello!
I can't hear you!
Five.
Yes.
I don't know.
[PANTING]
Whoa. Aah! Whoa! Ow!
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
Get her in focus, boys.
Here I come!
Open up! Aw, shit!
-I'm sorry. Shit!
-Jesus H. Christ! What are you...?
What happened?
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
ANNOUNCER [ON TV]: He's had all the time
in the world to throw it and he hasn't.
Now he's got pressure!
He has a receiver, Jim Youngblood!
[CHEERING]
[SINGING]
[CLANK]
Damn it!
Tweety?
Ohh.
Oh, shit. Tweety, couldn't you have
waited for a school day?
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[MISTER ROGERS SINGING ON TV]
Who the hell is this guy?
What the hell is going on?
STEVEN: All right!
MAN: Steven, what's going on?
Freeling, what's going on here?
I apologize.
My neighbor's on the same remote.
[MEN GROANING AND SHOUTING]
-I bet my life on this game!
-We're missing the game!
Hi, Ben.
We got a good football game
going on here.
My kids want to watch Mister Rogers.
I don't care what you're watching.
Just show a little mercy with that thing!
Steve, look at this guy!
Move your set.
Move yours.
There it is. Okay, don't move.
That's perfect.
[GASPS]
Tweety doesn't like that smell.
DIANE:
Sweetheart, Tweety can't smell a thing.
Put a flower with him.
A flower?
Okay.
For when he's hungry.
For when he's lonely.
And when it's nighttime.
[CAROL ANNE SNIFFLING]
Oh, it's okay. Shh.
Now I lay me down to sleep...
...l pray the Lord my soul to keep.
Oh, brother.
DIANE:
Stifle it.
If I should die before I wake...
DANA [WHISPERS]:
It did.
...l pray the Lord my soul to take.
That was lovely. Lovely, honey.
Mom, when it rots,
can we dig it up and see the bones?
Robbie! Will you come on down out
of the tree, please?
E. Buzz!
Can I get a goldfish now?
Come and get it.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
DIANE:
Honey, you're overfeeding them.
Tweety Two and Tweety Three
want seconds.
DIANE: You know what happens
when you overfeed goldfish?
They grow up to be...
...sharks!
[MAKES GOBBLING SOUNDS]
Good night.
Mom, there's a big storm
headed this way.
DIANE: You'll be asleep by the time
it gets here, if you hurry.
Come on. In you go.
-Good night.
ROBBIE: Good night.
Okay, lights out.
Closet light! Closet light!
My fault, my fault.
CAROL ANNE:
Turn it on, Mommy!
That enough?
-Okay?
-Good night, Ma.
Night, Mommy.
DIANE [WHISPERS]:
Good night.
Either I'm dead or I'm crazy.
Well, you're not crazy, Pete.
-You mean I'm dead?
-Yes.
I'm....
You mean I....
This is for good?
DIANE:
Sleepwalking.
Nocturnal somnambulism.
You know what?
I will bet you anything it's genetic.
[DIANE INHALING]
I mean, Carol Anne last night,
and all last week, you know.
And me when I was 10.
-Would you deal with this for me?
-Sure.
[BOTH GROAN]
You know....
[STEVEN SIGHS]
You know,
once I slept-walked four blocks.
And I fell asleep in the back
of this guy's car.
He drove all the way to work
before discovering me.
God, I woke up, I started screaming.
People came running from everywhere.
They called the cops. The cops came.
They took this poor dude downtown.
-My father...
-Big....
-...Ed.
-Mm-hm.
Big Ed has me examined for bruises
and hickeys. You name it.
God, I was so embarrassed.
[DIANE LAUGHING]
Oh, shit, Steven.
What if we dig the pool
and Carol Anne sleepwalks...
...and she falls into it
before there's any water?
Oh, honey, no.
Have you ever dove off
a three-meter board, sweetheart?
-What's three meters?
-It's about 10 feet.
Let's just dig the pool
closer to the house...
...and let the kids jump off the roof.
STEVEN:
No, honey, honey, honey.
Honey, a three-meter board,
it's like an air pocket, sweetheart.
When you dive off,
it's like free-falling, okay?
[DIANE GIGGLING]
You got to get your position now.
These feet are positioning.
-Honey?
-Three meters.
Your diving days are over.
We're talking Olympics, Diane. Okay?
-And then I can--
-Let me see your tuck position. Ha-ha-ha!
Then we can jackknife into the swan.
[DIANE LAUGHING]
You twist, turn and...
...splash!
Honey, it's right to the Nautilus machine.
Look at this, honey.
Before, after. Before, after. Before, after.
[IMITATES GUNSHOT]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
Don't. I'm telling you.
[IMITATING DONALD DUCK]
I love you. I love you!
You fool.
[STEVEN QUACKING]
[DIANE LAUGHING]
No, no!
Oh, God, I love it when you talk dirty.
The storm's coming closer.
Hey, partner.
Hi, honey.
Is everything okay?
It's thundering.
Come on. Come on. Hop up.
I'm the wind and you're the feather.
-Say good night to Mom.
-Good night.
DIANE:
Good night, sweetheart.
Here we go.
I don't like the tree, Dad.
It's an old tree.
It's been around here a long time.
It was here before my company
built the neighborhood.
I don't like its arms.
[WHISPERS]
It knows I live here, doesn't it?
It knows everything about us.
That's why I built the house next to it.
So it could protect us.
You and Carol Anne and Dana
and your mom and me.
It's a very wise old tree.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
It looks at me. It knows I live here.
I think the storm's gonna pass us.
How do you know?
Because I can count.
You know what you do?
When you see the lightning...
...you count till you hear the thunder.
If you can count higher each time...
...that means the storm's moving away
from us.
Want to try it? Okay.
Get some lightning.
Wait, it's coming.
Wow.
-Okay. One...
-One...
-...two, three.
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
Okay, but I bet next time you'll be able
to count to at least four or five.
[TOY PHONE RINGS]
-Betcha.
-Daddy, it's for you.
You tell them to take a message,
sweetpea.
My dad wants to take a message.
Good night.
It's too hot.
Okay.
Good night, angel.
Happy dreams, okay?
CAROL ANNE:
Good night, Daddy.
ROBBIE:
One, two...
...three, four.
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
DANA:
Did not!
Come on.
-Good night, Dana.
-Good night, Dad.
-Get off the phone, Dana.
-Okay.
Mm-hm.
One, two....
Three, four....
Five....
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
["THE STAR-SPANGLED BANNER"
PLAYING ON TV]
[VOICES WHISPERING]
[WHOOSHING]
[RUMBLING]
They're here.
STEVEN: Now listen to me, Jeff. No.
No, I'm not kidding.
I know, how could anybody
sleep through a 6.5?
There was damage.
The bedroom.
There's stuff in pieces all over.
ROBBIE:
Stop it! This is war!
STEVEN: We've been listening to the radio.
There's nothing on the radio.
DANA:
Don't touch me.
STEVEN:
It was two years after the Sylmar quake.
You are so obnoxious! You drive me nuts!
You're obnoxious.
-Force shields.
DANA: You are so obnoxious.
That was a good one.
This means war, and I mean it!
CAROL ANNE: Hey, watch out!
-Chew your food 10 times, okay?
You're a big barf bag!
You're a doggy bag.
That's a good one. I'm not gonna eat it.
DIANE:
There you go, Rob.
Sweetheart, last night when you said,
"They're here"--
Can I take my goldfish to school?
Maybe the fault line runs
just directly under our house.
Wouldn't that be a scream?
The ceiling got crumbs on my bed.
DANA: Who cares?
-Remember last night?
Do you remember when you woke up
and you said, "They're here?"
CAROL ANNE:
Uh-huh.
Who did you mean? Who's here?
The TV people.
ROBBIE: She's stoned.
DANA: What do you know?
More than you! Ask Dad.
-Ask Dad.
DIANE: Shh!
Ask Dad. Ask Dad.
Hey!
It's not my mess.
Uch! Thanks a lot, jerko.
I've got class in 20 minutes.
ROBBIE: Mom! It's not my fault.
-Give me this before you cut yourself.
The earth moved for you?
It wasn't quite the same thing
for us, Jeff.
Okay. I'll talk-- Yeah, right. Okay.
Give me that before you cut yourself.
ROBBIE: It's not my fault.
STEVEN: Bye, sweetpea.
-I'm out of here.
-Bye, honey.
ROBBIE: I'm out of here.
DIANE: Ah-ah!
You, I can handle.
-Got school.
-Yeah, well, breakfast first.
All right. I'll just flunk.
[WORKERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
WORKER 1: Don't take it so serious.
WORKER 2: I told the son of a bitch to put--
-It happens on every job.
-Well, l--
WORKER 1:
Hey! Look at this!
I love that swing.
I love you! I love you!
I love you!
I love it!
[WORKERS LAUGHING]
No!
E. Buzz, no. Get down.
Robbie! Carol Anne!
I've told you guys to push your chairs in
when you're done at the table.
Honey, you're gonna ruin your eyes.
This is not good for you.
[GUNSHOTS AND EXPLOSIONS
ON TV]
[MAN SCREAMS ON TV]
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
What's the matter, E. Buzz?
What are you doing?
[BARKING]
-How is it?
-Great, Mrs. Freeling.
Okay, Bluto. Give me my cup.
You sure make good coffee.
[DIANE YELPS]
Jesus! Don't do that, honey.
You want to see Mommy lying
in a cigar box covered with licorice?
-Uh-uh.
-Did you do this?
Uh-uh.
You guys.
I asked you not to pull the chairs out.
[DIANE YELPS]
TV people?
Uh-huh.
Do you see them?
Uh-uh.
Do you?
I tell you, I think you're really gonna
enjoy this kitchen.
This is our latest development.
We call this Phase 4.
Where do you live, Mr. Freeling?
Well, we were the first family to set up
housekeeping in Cuesta Verde Estates.
Phase 1.
We had to pass through my neighborhood
to get to this one.
Oh, that area with the lived-in look.
It has that, but I think in a few months...
...you won't be able to distinguish
Phase 1 from Phase 3 to Phase....
You know, we have a saying around here.
The grass grows greener on every side.
[COUPLE CHUCKLES]
That's the way I feel.
MAN:
I can't tell one house from the other.
You know something? I think you're right.
But I think our construction standards
are really very liberal.
I have this neighbor and he built a Jacuzzi
in his bedroom...
...and it has a running aqueduct connected
to a wading pool outside.
It's built half in and half out
of his living room.
That house was featured
in Town and Country.
Come on, I'll show you the den.
Honey! Come here! Quick!
-Hurry! Before it stops again.
-What about the cans?
DIANE: Leave this here.
-Right.
They don't make the pick-ups yet.
-Okay, just stand right here. Okay?
-Huh?
Listen, I kept Dana and Robbie out of this...
...but Carol Anne was here,
so she knows.
But Dana would blab, and Robbie,
he'd be up for three weeks...
-...sleeping on your side of the bed.
-You should sit down.
No, no, no.
Now just stand, okay?
-Now, just be calm.
-Okay.
Now reach back into our past
when you used to have an open mind.
-Remember that?
-Uh-huh.
Okay. Just try to use that
for the next couple of minutes.
-Okay?
-Yeah, okay.
Mother didn't cook any dinner.
We'll go to Pizza Hut, okay?
Okay, now....
Now just look.
Just look.
Just watch.
DIANE:
Woo-hoo!
[DIANE LAUGHING AND SHOUTING]
STEVEN:
Huh.
Come here, sweetheart.
Honey, could you move the chair
out of the way and just stay down there?
-Baby, let's show Daddy.
CAROL ANNE: I'm hungry!
Don't argue with Mommy. Come on.
Come on, let's just do this once.
Okay, here we go.
I want pepperoni pizza.
Mommy, that burns.
DIANE:
I'm sorry. The floor needs more wax.
-Steven, come on, you do it.
-No.
DIANE: Come on, honey, try.
STEVEN: Uh-uh.
It's like there's this tickling,
you know, right in here.
And it starts to pull you.
The tickling pulls you.
All of a sudden it's like there's no air,
except that you can breathe.
And you're getting pulled along and--
-Hi, Ben.
DIANE: Mr. Tuthill. Hi.
If you're having problems
with your set....
No, no, no.
It's nothing like that.
Diane and I were just wondering....
This will sound strange
coming from me....
Doubt that.
[DIANE GIGGLES]
[MOSQUITOES BUZZING]
-Those mosquitoes are something else.
-They're really chowing down.
I've never been bothered by them.
In fact, I don't think
I've ever been bitten by one.
As far as I know, nobody in my family's
ever been affected by them.
-A mosquito ever suck on you, son?
-I don't know, Dad.
He don't know.
DIANE:
Uh....
[STEVEN AND DIANE CHUCKLING]
Look, Mr. Tuthill....
Ben.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
-Ben.
-I'm really sorry.
DIANE:
Mr. Tuthill, look....
We were just....
What we were wondering is....
Look. Diane, my wife,
and I were wondering....
Ben, something funny
is going on here next door.
Something, uh....
We were wondering if maybe you had
experienced any disturbances lately.
What kind of disturbances?
Um....
Oh, you know, like...
...dishes or furniture moving around
by themselves.
Don't scratch them. You'll infect them.
-Just let me put this on.
-Okay.
Don't!
Boy, did I feel like a fool.
I'm sorry, but I had to say it.
We were losing pints of blood.
We'll keep this thing in the family.
-Don't scratch.
-Tomorrow, I'll call somebody in.
Yeah? Who, for instance?
I looked in the yellow pages.
Furniture movers, we got.
Strange phenomenon, no listing.
One one-thousand, two one-thousand,
three one-thousand...
...four one-thousand,
five one-thousand--
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
DIANE:
Honey, look....
I'm the one who lived
with this freaky thing all day...
...and nothing bad happened.
It's like another side of nature,
a side we're not qualified to understand.
When you overreact like this, it makes
what happened much too important.
No one's going in the kitchen
till I know what's happening.
One one-thousand, two one-thousand,
three one-thousand, four one-thousand....
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
One one-thousand,
two one-thousand, three one--
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
One one-thousand, two one-thousand--
[TREE GROWLS]
[ROBBIE SCREAMS]
[CAROL ANNE SCREAMING]
[TREE GROWLING]
DIANE: Robbie!
STEVEN: Robbie!
ROBBIE:
Mommy!
[VOICES WHISPERING]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
Mommy!
STEVEN:
Robbie!
DIANE:
Steven, hurry!
ROBBIE:
Dad!
Help me!
STEVEN:
Robbie!
ROBBIE:
Help me, Dad! Help me!
Honey, be careful!
Mom!
Mommy!
[CAROL ANNE SCREAMING]
Daddy!
Mom!
[ROBBIE SCREAMING]
Mom! Help me! Help me! Help me!
-Help me!
-He's coming!
Mom! It's taking me in!
-Robbie!
-It's hurting me!
Steven, hurry!
-Dad, help me! It's taking me in!
-Hold on!
Honey, hold on to him!
[CAROL ANNE SCREAMING]
No! No! No!
DIANE: Hold on to Daddy!
ROBBIE: Hold me, Daddy!
[DIANE SCREAMING]
It's got my leg!
Dad, my leg!
Dad! Help me, Dad! Help me!
DANA:
Look! Mom, Dad, it's a tornado!
DIANE:
It must have just skimmed us.
There wouldn't be a house left if....
STEVEN:
Carol Anne!
DANA:
I left her upstairs!
DIANE: Carol Anne!
STEVEN: Baby!
DIANE:
Baby, we're coming!
DANA:
Carol Anne!
[DIANE SOBBING]
[DIANE LAUGHING]
-I'll go check the kitchen.
-No! No, I'll do it.
I'll check the kitchen.
You check your room.
[ROBOT LAUGHING]
-Carol?
-Carol Anne?
Baby?
Carol Anne?
Carol Anne? Sweetheart?
STEVEN:
Carol Anne?
Baby?
STEVEN:
Carol Anne?
-Diane!
-Did you find her?
No. I've looked everywhere.
This is crazy!
Oh, my....
My God!
The swimming pool.
The swimming pool! The swimming pool!
Be careful, honey.
Steven!
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy!
Nothing. Nothing.
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy!
Mom? Mama?
ROBBIE:
Mom! Mom!
Thank God. Thank God.
Mom! Mom! Mom! Mom!
Mommy! Mommy! Mommy!
-Robbie! What's the matter?
CAROL ANNE: Mommy!
Carol Anne. Thank God. Baby.
Baby, where are you?
CAROL ANNE: Mommy!
-Carol Anne?
ROBBIE:
Mommy, come over here! Hurry!
-Mom! Mom!
-Robbie. What? What, baby?
Carol Anne! Carol Anne! Carol Anne!
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy! I can't see you, Mommy.
Where are you?
Mommy!
I can't see you, Mommy.
Where are you?
What members of the household
are involved...
...and what are their ages?
STEVEN:
There's Diane, my wife. She's 31.
Thirty-two. I'm sorry.
And my oldest daughter, Dana, she's 16.
My son, Robert, is 8.
-Carol Anne....
LESH: Hm.
Carol Anne, 5.
Has there been any publicity
about these events?
STEVEN:
No, absolutely nothing.
Can you be reasonably sure
of not letting any get started?
STEVEN:
That's the last thing in the world we want.
We haven't even gone to the police.
LESH:
Hm.
Would your family welcome a serious
investigation of these disturbances...
...by someone who can make
first-hand observations?
Look, Dr. Lesh,
we don't care about the disturbances...
...the pounding and the flashing...
...the screaming, the music.
We just want you to find our little girl.
I should warn you that we keep the room
locked off from the rest of the house.
Robbie's sleeping with us now
and Dana spends a lot of time with friends.
LESH: Well, how many disturbances
have you recorded in the room?
We don't go in the room anymore.
Mr. Freeling, we'll record
any psychotronic energy or event.
Yes, Ryan photographed an extraordinary
episode on a case in Redlands.
RYAN:
That's right.
It was a child's toy,
a very small Matchbox vehicle.
Just rolled seven feet across
a linoleum surface.
The duration of the event
was seven hours.
Seven hours for what?
For the vehicle to complete the distance.
Of course, this would never register
on the naked eye.
But I have it recorded
on time-lapse camera.
It's fantastic.
Mm-hm.
[WIND WHOOSHING]
[VOICES LAUGHING]
[TOYS SQUEAKING]
[HORSE NEIGHING]
[VOICE CACKLES]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DIANE: We've been trying to hold ourselves
together as a family.
Of course, no one's been sleeping much.
Steven has missed so much work.
But he's been wonderful,
really wonderful.
How long have you been investigating
haunted houses?
LESH: Well, Mrs. Freeling, l--
-Diane.
Diane, the determination as to whether
your home is haunted is not very easy.
I-- What I meant to say was, it might
very well be a poltergeist intrusion...
...instead of a classic haunting.
There's a difference?
Did you see that?
There'll be two more in a few seconds.
They always travel in pairs.
Dr. Casey.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
Gotta be quicker than that around here.
It's electrical. You can smell the charge.
You were saying about poltergeists?
Poltergeists are usually associated
with an individual.
Hauntings seem to be connected
with an area.
A house, usually.
Poltergeist disturbances
are of fairly short duration.
Perhaps a couple of months.
Hauntings can go on for years.
Are you telling me that all of this
could just suddenly end at any time?
Yes, it could.
Unless it's a haunting.
But hauntings don't usually revolve
around living people.
Then we don't have much time...
...because my daughter is alive
somewhere inside this house.
MAN [ON TV]: --while trying to escape
from an unknown assailant.
Marshall is listed as critical
and under intensive care.
DIANE: This is probably gonna seem
a little strange.
We hear better on this channel.
Don't ask me why.
Well, uh...
...l guess I'll call her.
Carol Anne?
Uh, it's Mommy, sweetheart.
Uh, we want to talk to you.
[WHISPERING]
Please answer me, baby.
Please answer me.
Please talk to me, bunny.
[E. BUZZ WHINING]
Look at the dog.
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
DIANE:
Are you with us now?
Can you say hello to Daddy?
[VOICES WHISPERING]
CAROL ANNE:
Hello, Daddy.
[E. BUZZ WHIMPERING]
Hello, sweetpea.
It's Mommy, sweetheart.
Hello, Mommy.
Hello, baby!
Can you see me?
Can you see Mommy?
Mommy?
Where are you? Where are you?
We're home, baby. We're home.
Can you find me?
Can you find a way home to us, baby?
Mommy, where are you?
I can't find you. I can't!
I'm afraid of the light, Mommy.
I'm afraid of the light!
Tell her to stay away from the light.
Maybe it's a way out!
It is a way out, but not for her.
Tell her quickly.
-Uh, Carol Anne--
-Tell her to stay away from the light!
STEVEN:
Tell her, Diane.
Sweetheart, stay away from the light.
The light is dangerous. Don't go near it.
-Don't even look at it.
MARTY: Dr. Lesh.
I don't believe it, but the voice could be
coming from a CB transmitter in the house.
LESH:
This isn't a hoax.
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
What the hell is this?
LESH:
Anything?
RYAN:
Nothing's registering.
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy, there's somebody here.
[VOICE WHISPERING]
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy, Mommy, is that you?
No, it's not Mommy. Who is it, Dr. Lesh?
-Who's with you, baby?
-Who's with you?
Mommy, somebody's coming.
Mommy, help me, please!
DIANE: God. My God. My baby.
-Mommy!
No.
You bastard! She's just a baby!
Help her! Can't you hear
what's happening? Help her!
[CAROL ANNE CRYING]
STEVEN: Listen! Listen!
CAROL ANNE: Help me! Get away from me!
Leave me alone!
Mommy, help me! Help me, Mommy!
[DIANE GASPS]
She just moved through me.
My God!
I felt her.
[LAUGHING]
I can smell her.
It's her.
Smell my clothes.
It's her. She's all over me.
-It's her. She's all over me.
-My God.
DIANE:
It's her. I felt her.
STEVEN: It is. It's her.
DIANE: It's her.
It is. It is. It's my baby.
It's my baby.
She went through my soul.
[DIANE LAUGHING AND CRYING]
[THUDDING]
[WHOOSHING]
ROBBIE:
Mommy!
[ROARING]
[ALL SCREAM]
DIANE:
Carol Anne?
I can't hear her anymore.
Carol Anne? Honey?
Where exactly do you suppose Carol Anne
was playing when she vanished from sight?
Diane?
Where was Carol Anne playing
when she disappeared?
Her bedroom closet.
Let's go up there.
-They won't let you in.
-We'll just see about that.
[MARTY GROANS]
LESH:
Whatever happened to you?
I was about to check out
the kid's bedroom when, I don't know...
...something took a bite out of me.
You got bit?
That or the worst muscle spasm
in the world.
Lift up your shirt. Let's have a look.
Wow!
We'll spend the night downstairs.
No. Wrong! Wrong, wrong, wrong.
Honey, I want you
to take Dana and Robbie...
...and spend tonight in town.
I am not leaving here
without Carol Anne.
DANA: I can't stay here.
I've gotta go to Lisa's place.
-No, you go, baby.
-I just don't want to stay here!
I'm not gonna leave anybody
in this house alone.
[WHISPERING]
Can we talk to you?
Let's go.
[WHISPERING]
Any movement out of them?
There's some ionization flux.
I'd like to see that they're not caused
by humidity from structure leakage...
...but I'm not going up there to find out.
We have got much more than
the paranormal episode taking place here.
There is a measurable physical science
in this house that goes beyond...
...any of the creaking doors
or cold spots I've experienced.
The voice on the television,
where is it coming from?
The absence of a signal on a channel that
is not receiving a broadcast means that...
...it's free to receive a lot of noise
from many things, like shortwaves.
Solar disturbances, car ignition sparkings.
Outer space.
Or inner space.
Yes. What if these people had an area
of bilocation in their own living room?
LESH: What do you mean?
RYAN: No, I mean it.
If that is the way out...
...then maybe somewhere in this house
there's a way in.
[WHISPERING]
No, please, leave it on.
Thanks.
You know, when it's quiet like now...
...l can imagine how all of this must look
from your side.
I'm really embarrassed.
Nonsense.
I'm the one who should be embarrassed,
being here with you nice people.
Parapsychology isn't something
you master in.
There are no certificates of graduation...
...no licenses to practice.
I am a professional psychologist...
...who spent most of my time engaged
in this ghostly hobby...
...which makes me, I suppose, the most
irresponsible woman of my age that I know.
Would you like a glass for that?
No, thank you.
You know, you were very funny.
Your hands were shaking
about a mile a minute.
[DIANE AND LESH CHUCKLE]
It isn't over.
I'm absolutely terrified.
It's all the things
that we don't understand.
I feel like the protohuman,
coming out of the forest primeval...
...and seeing the moon for the first time
and throwing rocks at it.
If I got killed, would I come back as a ghost
and get stuck in the house...
...like my sister?
Your sister isn't dead, Robbie.
If I got killed, could I visit her
and show her how to get back here?
You could tie a rope around me and hold it,
then somebody could come and get us...
...and we'd go live somewhere else.
Some people believe that when you die
your soul goes to heaven.
When Grandpa was dead, I looked at him
on the hospital bed, and I was watching...
...but I didn't see anything
go up out of him.
His soul was invisible, Robbie.
You couldn't see it.
But how come Grandpa isn't on television
with Carol Anne?
Shh.
LESH: Some people believe
that when people die...
...there's a wonderful light...
...as bright as the sun.
But it doesn't hurt to look into it.
All the answers to all the questions
that you ever want to know...
...are inside that light.
And when you walk to it,
you become a part of it forever.
And then...
...some people die,
but they don't know that they've gone.
They think they're still alive?
Yes.
Maybe they didn't want to die.
Maybe they weren't ready.
Maybe they hadn't lived fully yet
or they'd lived a long time...
...but they still wanted more life.
They resist going into that light...
...however hard the light wants them.
They just hang around...
...watch TV,
watch their friends grow up...
...feeling unhappy and jealous...
...and those feelings are bad.
They hurt.
And then...
...some people...
...just get lost on the way to the light.
And they need someone
to guide them to it.
So some people get angry and
throw things around, like in my bedroom?
Yes.
Just like in school.
Like some kids are nice to you,
some kids are mean.
I got beat up once by three kids.
They took my lunch money.
Maybe they got hit by a truck
and they're upstairs right now.
Listen, partner, maybe we ought
to get some shut-eye, okay?
Okay.
You know what?
When we called Grandma tonight,
she got really excited...
...that you're coming to stay with her...
...and she's planning all these neat things
for you guys to do.
-Can I take E. Buzz with me when we go?
-Sure, you can.
-Good night, Mom.
-Good night, sweetie.
Good night, lady.
Good night, Dad.
Good night, Rob.
I love you.
Good night, Carol Anne.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
ON HEADPHONES]
[WHISPERING]
I'm gonna go get something to eat.
-Okay.
-Thanks.
[SQUISHING]
[WHIMPERING]
[COUGHING]
[ELECTRICITY HUMMING]
[GROANING]
[GASPS]
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
ON HEADPHONES]
[DOOR CREAKING]
[EQUIPMENT BEEPING]
What is it? What is it?
[WIND HOWLING]
Roll it back!
RYAN:
I think we've got one. I think it recorded.
Yes, it recorded!
Look at all of them.
ROBBIE [WHISPERING]:
Is that our house?
Who are all those people?
They're so lonely.
So alone.
Where are they coming from?
I don't know.
Robbie?
Call me, okay?
This cameo is over 100 years old.
DIANE:
Yeah, some haul.
And this watch is only a few years old.
And it's not yours.
No.
Well, I'm off.
I'm taking these back to the lab
along with the tapes.
I'm gonna have to display these,
you know.
-Please, not on 60 Minutes.
-Or That's Incredible.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
I'll get it. Excuse me.
[LESH CHUCKLES]
LESH:
I'm leaving Ryan here with you.
Marty won't be coming back.
I am coming back.
[WHISPERING]
And I'll bring some help.
Try not to worry.
[WHISPERS]
Thank you.
We've missed you down at the office.
The boys have gotten worried...
...so I took it upon myself to--
Jesus, Steve, you look like shit.
Aren't you feeling any better?
I'm still weak. I've got the flu.
-I can't get up and l--
-Looks like you got some cable problems.
Yeah, well, move over here.
Cable's been off for a couple months.
We'll have to look into that.
The rest of the block dark too?
No, it's just us.
Got some electrical problems
as well here.
What have you got screwed in there?
A 300-watt bulb?
You afraid of burglars or you trying
to attract every insect in Cuesta Verde?
Steve, tell me something.
Are you happy here?
-Yes, I am.
-Forgive me for asking these questions...
...but we don't want to lose the best rep
we've ever had...
...to the flu or other opportunities.
Seeing all that software in your living room
makes me wonder if, well...
...maybe you got something on the side.
STEVEN: No, I just read Popular Mechanics.
I got hobbies.
Feel like going for a little ride?
I'd like to show you something.
Hello?
Carol Anne?
[VOICES SHRIEK]
[DIANE SCREAMS]
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
One of your children was born
in your house, huh?
Carol Anne.
I understand that she's missed
a lot of school.
One of Trask's daughters
is in the same nursery class.
She caught the flu as well?
Yeah, we've all got the same thing.
I'm sorry.
I didn't see her.
She's around.
Listen, I wonder if you'd mind
if I asked you a question.
Are you leaving Cuesta Verde?
STEVEN: It's hard to believe the day
could be this beautiful.
How could anyone in the world
have a problem on a day like this?
How's that spot for a bay window, huh?
It's pretty nice if you're living up here,
but not so great down there in the valley...
...looking at those homes
cutting into the hillside.
You don't have to live
in the Valley anymore.
What are you saying?
We're starting Phase 5 right here
where we're standing.
All of this can be
your master-bedroom suite.
That can be your view.
Interested?
Mr. Teague, that's a generous offer.
-I'm just not a developer.
-You're responsible for 42 percent of sales.
That's almost half of everything there.
Almost $70 million worth
of dwelling and properties.
Now, that's a whole generation
of security...
...that nobody can put a price tag on.
[STEVEN CHUCKLES]
Look, I know we should have made you
a full partner three years ago.
Well, I don't want to lose you now.
-Not much room for a pool, is there?
-We own all the land.
We've already made arrangements
for relocating the cemetery.
STEVEN:
Oh, you're kidding.
-Come on. That's sacrilegious, isn't it?
-Don't worry about it.
After all,
it's not ancient tribal burial ground.
It's just...
...people.
Besides, we've done it before.
-When?
-In '76.
Right down there.
-Cuesta Verde?
-All 300 acres.
And let me tell you, it was quite a deal.
STEVEN:
But I never heard anything about it.
It's not something one advertises
on a billboard...
...or on the side of a bus.
What's worrying you?
Friends and relatives can visit
their loved ones in Broxton Memorial Park.
It's only five minutes further,
for Christ's sake.
Yeah, well, five minutes.
You know, that's no great hardship.
I suppose that would be okay.
Okay with whom?
Whomever might complain.
Nobody's complained until now.
DIANE: We've had two experiences
in the kitchen.
Uh, this is the den.
Would y'all mind hanging back?
You're jamming my frequencies.
[TANGINA GASPS]
So, what side of the rainbow
are we working tonight, Dr. Lesh?
Is this your Knott's Berry Farm solution?
I know what you're thinking.
But you must take my word for it.
She's cleaned many houses.
Her gifts have been documented--
Look, we haven't heard Carol Anne
since last night.
TANGINA:
Why is this door locked, Mr. Freeling?
-Answer her, Steven.
-I am.
I am addressing the living.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
That's the room my son
and daughter used to occupy.
LESH:
We believe it's the heart of the house.
This house has many hearts.
[WHISPERS]
What is the matter?
What's the matter?
[STEVEN CHUCKLING]
[WHISPERING]
I was trying to answer her with my mind...
...and she couldn't hear me.
I thought you said Tangina Barrons
was an extraordinary clairvoyant?
TANGINA:
I am.
I just don't like trick answers.
Come here, honey...
...and give me your hand.
I'm not gonna bite you.
Come on down here. You're gonna give
me whiplash looking up at you.
Your daughter is alive and in this house.
[SIGHS]
Where was the last incident
of bilocation?
I get my strongest feeling...
...the point of origin is
in the child's closet upstairs.
Yes, I believe that too.
Now, honey, are you gonna be strong
for me and for your daughter?
I can do absolutely nothing
without your faith in this world...
...and your love for the children.
I will. Believe me, I will.
And will you do anything I ask...
...even if it comes contrary to your beliefs
as a human being and a Christian?
Yes, I promise. Please.
Would you all come on in?
Gather round.
There is no death.
It is only a transition...
...to a different sphere of consciousness.
Carol Anne is not like those she's with.
She is a living presence...
...in their spiritual, earthbound plane.
They're attracted to the one thing
about her...
...that is different from themselves:
her life force.
It is very strong.
It gives off its own illumination.
It is a light that implies life...
...and memory of love and home...
...and earthly pleasures...
...something they desperately desire...
...but can't have anymore.
Right now,
she's the closest thing to that...
...and that is a terrible distraction...
...from the real light...
...that has finally come for them.
Do you understand me?
These souls, who, for whatever reason...
...are not at rest...
...are also not aware
that they have passed on.
They're not part of consciousness
as we know it.
They linger in a perpetual dream state...
...a nightmare from which
they cannot awake.
Inside this spectral light...
...is salvation.
A window to the next plane.
They must pass through this membrane...
...where friends are waiting
to guide them to new destinies.
Carol Anne must help them cross over.
And she will only hear...
...her mother's voice.
Now...
...hold onto yourselves.
There's one more thing.
A terrible presence is in there with her.
So much rage, so much betrayal.
I've never sensed anything like it.
I don't know what hovers
over this house...
...but it was strong enough
to punch a hole into this world...
...and take your daughter away from you.
It keeps Carol Anne very close to it...
...and away from the spectral light.
It lies to her.
It says things
only a child can understand.
It has been using her
to restrain the others.
To her...
...it simply is another child.
To us...
...it is the beast.
Now let's go get your daughter.
TANGINA:
Red ribbons...
...handkerchiefs...
...tennis balls.
STEVEN:
Rope's right here.
TANGINA: Bath water?
-I shut it off. It's ready too.
All right.
Call to her.
Carol Anne?
Carol Anne, it's Mommy.
Can you hear me?
Carol Anne, please tell Mommy hello.
Try again.
Can you say hello to Daddy?
Daddy and I miss you so much.
So much. We love you so much.
Please just say hello.
She's under restraint.
What? Who's restraining her?
There are many arms about her.
She thinks it's safe. Quickly!
Who is she more threatened by,
you or your husband?
Neither! Steve decides the punishment.
The children know that.
-That's not fair. I've never hit her.
-Fight later!
Steven, make Carol Anne answer you!
-Carol Anne? It's Daddy.
TANGINA: Be cross with her.
Be angry with her,
or you'll never see her again.
Carol Anne, I want you to answer me!
Tell her if she doesn't answer you,
she'll get a spanking.
-Come on, I've never spanked the children.
-Honey, please, just tell her.
Carol Anne?
Answer your parents or you'll get
a real spanking from both of us!
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy, help me!
TANGINA: She's away from him.
DIANE: Away from whom? Is she all right?
Diane, ask about the light.
CAROL ANNE:
Mommy, help me, please.
Carol Anne?
-Honey, do you see a light?
-Help me, please!
Mommy! Mommy, help me!
Shh.
-Tell her to go to the light.
-No!
They'll follow her, they've followed her
for weeks. Now tell her!
-You must do what I say.
-It's all right. Tell her, Diane.
Mommy, I can't find you!
Run to the light, Carol Anne!
Run as fast as you can!
-Are you in the light?
-No.
TANGINA: Tell her you are.
-No! It's a lie!
You can't choose life or death when
we're dealing with what's in between.
Tell her before it's too late.
Run to the light, baby!
-Mommy's in the light!
-Tell her you're waiting for her.
Mommy is waiting for you in the light!
I hate you for this.
Now clear your minds.
It knows what scares you.
It has from the very beginning.
Don't give it any help.
It knows too much already.
Now, open the door.
Ryan!
Get downstairs and wait by the target!
Okay!
TANGINA:
Steven!
Give me the tennis ball
marked number one!
[WHOOSHING]
Dr. Lesh! It's my handwriting!
It came right out of thin air!
The ball came back! It's his handwriting.
[WHOOSHING]
Kiss my ass! Number two!
TANGINA:
Diane!
Give me your hand!
She's at the mouth of the corridor!
Tell her to stop!
Tell her not to go into the light!
Carol Anne? Listen to me!
Do not go into the light!
Stop where you are! Turn away from it!
Don't even look at it!
Hurry with the rope!
Throw it into the light!
[WHOOSHING]
Fantastic!
I got it!
Tell him to take up the slack gently.
Take up the slack!
Okay!
TANGINA:
Help me tie this around my waist!
What are you doing?
I'm going in after her!
She won't come to you! Let me go!
You've never done this before.
DIANE:
Neither have you!
You're right. You go.
-No! No! Let me!
-You can't!
Who's strong enough to stay up here
and hold the rope?
DIANE:
I love you!
TANGINA:
No!
No! Go downstairs and wait by Ryan...
...and pull only when I say so!
Only when I say!
Steven!
Don't let go!
Never!
[WHOOSHING]
RYAN:
It's coming.
How will we know she's got her?
When will we know?
Hey!
Cross over, children!
All are welcome!
All welcome.
Go into the light!
No! No! You said no!
There is peace and serenity in the light.
You said don't go into the light!
Diane!
Steven, not yet!
[ROARING]
[STEVEN SCREAMING]
LESH: They're here!
RYAN: They're back.
Diane! No, please, no!
Get them into the water!
LESH:
No, no, no. I'm helping you.
I'll get her something.... Don't worry.
Get her to the water. She's all right.
She's gonna be all right.
STEVEN:
Diane.
Come on. Come on, breathe now.
Come on, breathe.
Just take a breath.
Breathe, honey, breathe.
Breathe, damn it! Breathe!
Diane. Diane, breathe, breathe, breathe!
That's it. Come on, baby. Come on.
Come on, breathe! That's it, breathe.
[DIANE GASPS]
Baby.
Sweetheart.
Sweetpea, it's Daddy. Come on, honey.
Come on, pumpkin.
Hi, Daddy.
[DIANE SOBBING]
This house is clean.
DIANE:
Uh, be careful.
DANA: I'm going to dinner
with Janice and Brian.
-Is your room packed?
-Everything but the bed.
CAROL ANNE: Mom?
-Will we sleep here tonight?
Uh, I guess not.
So you better get Brian to bring you home
right after dinner.
Because Dad wants us to stay
at the Holiday Inn on I-74.
-Oh, yeah. I remember that place.
CAROL ANNE: Mom?
-You what?
-Are you gonna do anything about this?
-About what?
Your new gray.
Oh.
CAROL ANNE: Mom?
-You don't like it?
-You don't think it's kind of punk?
-Mom?
Bye, Mom.
Okay, Rob. That thing almost killed me.
DIANE: You okay? Don't hurt your back.
-Fine.
-How you feeling?
-I'm good.
I feel a little hung over,
like I've been asleep for a few days...
...but I feel good, Steven, I really do.
She doesn't seem to remember any of it.
Oh, what a day.
Smell that mimosa.
Cut yourself a bouquet to take with you,
because we're not staying.
I know.
We worked so hard for this.
-Many beautiful memories.
-I gotta go to the office...
...and pick up some stuff.
Clean up a few things.
DIANE: Okay.
-I'll be back early.
-So we're leaving tonight for sure?
-Yeah, we are.
I'll tell you what. If the kids get sleepy
just let them conk out till I get home.
How's Teague taking it?
He won't take "Go to hell"
for an answer.
-What are you gonna tell him?
-I'll give him directions.
[DIANE CHUCKLES]
[MOUTHS]
I love you.
DIANE: "Working from front to back, apply
mixture directly from applicator to hair.
-Gently work it--"
ROBBIE: Give me that.
CAROL ANNE: No! Give me this!
ROBBIE: Give me my truck back!
Stop!
Give me my truck.
CAROL ANNE:
Give me it!
"Gently work it through
to saturate every strand...
...then comb through
with a wide-tooth brush and a comb...
...to be sure that every hair is wet.
Do not lather."
-You! Give me this!
-Get out of the solar system!
Give me it!
-It's getting late, guys.
CAROL ANNE: Give me it!
-Give it back to me! Stop it.
-Give me it!
I'll be in the bathtub for a little while,
so could you please answer the phone?
Robbie! Could you answer
the phone for me, please? Okay?
And can you tuck yourselves in, please?
-No!
-No.
-Yes! We will.
-Thank you.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night.
-Good night, Robbie.
-Good night, Carol Anne.
[BELLS JINGLING]
[RUSTLING]
[GASPS]
[CLOWN CACKLING]
You're not real! Aah!
[ROBBIE YELLING]
Robbie!
[GROWLING]
[DIANE SCREAMS]
Help! Help me! Help me!
No!
-No!
-You're not real!
No! No!
No, let go!
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
Let me go!
[ROBBIE GRUNTING]
ROBBIE:
I hate you! I hate you!
I hate you! I hate you! I hate you!
DIANE:
Carol Anne! Robbie! Run!
Robbie!
ROBBIE:
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
[GROWLING]
ROBBIE:
Mom! Mom! Mom!
[ROARING]
Mom, open the door!
-Open the door!
DIANE: Carol Anne! Robbie! Run!
[SCREAMS]
No, don't touch my babies!
No!
[DIANE GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
Help me, somebody.
[SQUISHING AND DEEP GROANING]
No more.
DIANE:
Robbie!
Mr. Tuthill!
Ben! Ben! Help! Please help me!
Somebody, somebody! Please!
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
[RUMBLING]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
[ROBBIE AND CAROL ANNE SCREAM]
MRS. TUTHILL:
Your children!
-Listen!
ROBBIE: Help me!
-What sort of sound is that?
-I've got to get them! Come on!
BEN: What's going on?
MRS. TUTHILL: No, Ben, don't go!
-Please, Ben, please help me!
-No, don't go in there!
Help me!
Get away from my babies!
Get away!
[PANTING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
ROBBIE:
Help! Help!
[ROARING]
ROBBIE:
Help us! Help us!
-Mom!
DIANE: Grab me!
Robbie!
Give me your hand!
Mommy!
Mom! I can't reach you!
-Now grab your sister!
ROBBIE: Take my hand!
DIANE: Grab her!
-Take my hand!
DIANE:
Hold on!
-Robbie!
-God, help me!
[GROWLING]
[CAROL ANNE SCREAMING]
Diane!
STEVEN: Get out!
DIANE: Where?!
[ROBBIE SCREAMING]
Steven, help us!
[STEVEN YELLING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
ROBBIE:
Dad!
You son of a bitch, you moved the cemetery
but you left the bodies, didn't you?
You son of a bitch, you left the bodies
and you only moved the headstones!
You only moved the headstones!
Why?! Why?!
DIANE:
Steven!
ROBBIE:
Come on! Hurry, Dad, hurry!
Quick, come on!
-Dad, come on, hurry!
-Hurry, Come on!
Hurry, hurry!
-I can't....
-Go!
ROBBIE: Hurry, Dad!
DIANE: Come on, damn it!
Steven, hurry!
Come on! Come on!
[CAROL ANNE SCREAMING]
Hurry!
[ALL SCREAM]
[DANA WHIMPERING]
DANA:
What's happening?
What's happening?!
-What is it?!
-Dana, get in the car!
-Drive away! Daddy, drive away!
DANA: What is it?!
-Steven, hurry!
-Daddy!
The house is coming!
-Faster! Faster!
-Don't look back!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[EXPLOSIONS]
[HOUSE GROWLING AND GROANING]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
[WHOOSHING]
[WOOD CREAKING]
[CRASHING]
[SOFT HUMMING]
[CAROL ANNE WHIMPERING]
[ENGLISH SDH]