Oh! No!
No, no!
Mother! Oh, God, Mother!
Blood! Blood!
Are you stating, Counsel,
you're not gonna offer any
contradictory psychiatric testimony?
Yes, Your Honor.
On the basis
of this staff report,
Norman Bates is judged
restored to sanity
and is ordered released
forthwith.
What about his victims?
Don't they have any say?
Can you restore them?
Madam, please sit down.
This matter
is being represented
by the District Attorney.
Your Honor, my name
is Mrs. Lila Loomis.
I have a petition here
signed by 743 people
against Norman Bates' release,
including the relatives
of the seven people
he murdered.
Doesn't that give me
the right to speak out?
Has the District Attorney
advised Mrs. Loomis
about her rights
in this matter?
Yes, Your Honor.
I explained that her petition
had no effect
on these proceedings.
Did you explain to her
that this hearing...
Why are you people
just sitting here?
Don't you realize they're going
to release a homicidal maniac?
I must ask you to sit down
or I'll have the bailiff
remove you
from this courtroom.
If you've
any further questions,
please discuss them
with the District Attorney
after this hearing.
Why bother?
It's all too obvious,
our courts
protect the criminals,
not their victims.
Congratulations, Norman.
Turning now
to calendar number 71143.
Is that all there is
to it?
That's all there is
to it. Let's go.
Let the record reflect
that the defendant
is present with counsel.
Just like I said,
they let him go.
I'll call you later.
Are you satisfied,
Doctor?
Turning a murderer loose
on an innocent public?
Mrs. Loomis, Norman was
not convicted of murder.
He was found "not guilty"
by reason of insanity.
And since he is
no longer...
That is just
legal hocus-pocus
and when he
murders again,
you will be
directly responsible.
Well, this belongs
to Mr. Toomey
who runs the motel.
Want me to find him?
I'll introduce you.
No, no. It'll... lt'll wait.
What's the matter?
Uh, I saw someone.
Where?
L-ln that window.
They haven't had a tenant
in the house for years.
I guess
I'm just nervous.
Well, that's understandable
under the circumstances.
Yeah.
Well, this is it.
You don't have to
stay here, you know.
I could find you
a place in town.
No, no.
L... I want to stay here.
Then as long
as you realize
that the memories are
more likely to reoccur here...
But you know how to handle
that now, don't you?
Sure.
You start work at noon today.
Don't forget.
No, I won't.
I don't suppose you will.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing, really.
I just wish there hadn't been
all those cutbacks,
there'd be
a trained social worker
looking in on you
from time to time.
Well, I have you,
don't I?
Damn right you do.
I had the phone
reconnected.
Any trouble, use it.
Okay.
Thanks, Doctor,
for everything.
Mother?
Norman.
Norman, what did you put
in my tea?
I'm gonna get you
for this, Norman.
I'm gonna show you
what happens
to bad little boys
who poison their mothers.
I'm going to kill you!
Can I help you?
I'm Norman. Norman Bates.
The new cook's helper.
Oh, yes.
Doctor what's-his-name
called about you.
Raymond.
I'm the one
who urged Mr. Statler
to give you the job.
I think
it's very Christian
to forgive and forget,
don't you?
I sure do.
So do I. Myrna.
This is Norman Bates.
That's Myrna, Norman.
Come on, I'll introduce you
to Mr. Statler.
He's in the back.
Ralph, this is Norman Bates.
You have to tell me what.
Just give me...
Ralph, this is Norman Bates,
your new helper.
Hi. Get him an apron,
will you, Mrs. Spool?
Scott, we have to talk
about it sometime.
Step on it, would you, girl?
You're being paid to wait on
tables, not gab on the phone.
Look, I'll call you
back later. We'll talk then.
We're getting ready
for rush hour.
He's really very nice
once he catches his breath.
Hey, Queen for a Day,
wanna try being a waitress?
Mary, this is Norman.
He's gonna be working
back here.
Hi.
Boyfriend troubles,
poor child.
Heart of gold
but head of wood.
Let's get that apron
for you, shall we?
Here you go.
Jesus Christ, girl,
what have you broken
this time?
It wasn't her fault,
Mr. Statler.
It was me.
L... l... I did it.
Well, let her pick up
and you get back here
before you do
any more damage.
Thanks.
Here, Bates.
Here, put these up there under the
hot lights and read the orders off.
On the wheel. On the wheel.
Oh.
Uh, two meatloaf sandwiches and
one mashed potato with gravy.
And one baked potato.
Okay, go ahead, go ahead,
do it. See if I care.
No, no, Scott. I didn't
mean it. Listen to me.
Hello?
Bastard.
You all right?
Of course I'm all right.
Where you going?
Into town.
Will you
please leave me alone?
If you're going into town, you're
heading in the wrong direction.
Look, l... I don't know
what happened,
but, uh, why don't you
let me call you a cab?
Why?
Why? So you can
get home safely.
I don't have a home.
No home?
I've been living with my
boyfriend for over a year.
And all of a sudden,
he tells me we're through.
And then I just phoned him to ask
him why and he wouldn't tell me.
All he'd say is that I couldn't
come back to our apartment.
Well, what're you...
What... What're you gonna do?
Call a friend in town,
I guess.
See if somebody'll let me
crash with them for the night.
What about your parents?
Uh, couldn't you
stay with them?
They're in Portland.
And they don't care
what happens to me, anyway.
Oh, uh, I own a motel
not too far from here.
And you'd be welcome
to spend the night
in one of the empty rooms
if you'd like.
F-FOC, of course.
What?
Free of charge.
Oh.
But no, that's very nice of
you but I don't wanna impose.
You wouldn't be imposing.
Co-workers ought to help each
other out, don't you think?
You know what, you covered for me
today when I broke that pie plate.
Yeah.
I figured you'd get into more
trouble for it than I would.
You're not kidding.
I've been working there four days and
I've broken a dozen dishes already.
You sure it's all right
if I stay at your motel?
Absolutely.
Come on, let's get going.
It looks like rain.
Well, we almost made it.
You didn't get
too wet, did you?
No, I'm all right.
Oh.
Do you own all this?
Oh, yeah.
Well, it isn't much,
but I'll get it
fixed up eventually.
Well, let me
get you a room key.
Mr. Toomey.
Why don't you wait here
while I check the room?
Uh, just to make sure
the linen's fresh.
What you thinking about
stealing something?
There's no reason to be scared,
sweetheart. I manage this dump.
What do you want, a room?
Norman's already
getting me one, thank you.
You're with Bates?
Well, uh, you must be
Norman Bates.
I'm Warren Toomey.
Mary, why don't you
go up to the house?
The... The front door
is open.
Is something wrong
with the room?
No. Just... Just... Just... Just...
Just go up and wait for me, okay?
Look,
it doesn't matter...
Look, just do
as I say, okay?
She's pretty cute.
Where'd you find her?
What's this stuff?
I'd say it was drugs.
What about
the occupied cabins?
Is that what's going on
in there, too?
Yeah.
Boy, this town.
If it isn't the parents,
it's the kids.
I caught a couple of them
screwin' in the basement
of your house up there
last week.
Of course,
I threw them right out.
Can you believe that?
What kind of a motel
are you running here?
The kind that makes money.
People come here to party.
They stay a few hours
and then they leave.
What more can you ask from a motel
so far from the beaten track, huh?
You're fired.
Hey, you can't fire me.
I was hired by the hospital.
This State has no claim on me
or my property anymore.
And neither do you.
I want you
out of here tomorrow.
Yeah, well, why don't you try
putting me out, Mr. Whacko, hmm?
I'd like to see that.
I won't have to.
I'll just go to the police.
I'm sure they'd be very
interested in what's going on here,
especially the drugs.
Tomorrow, Mr. Toomey.
And don't rent out any more
rooms in this motel. No more.
At least my customers
have a good time.
What'd yours get,
Bates, huh?
Dead, that's what
they got!
Dead! Murdered by you,
you loony!
Hi!
What was all
the yelling about?
Oh.
My motel manager
and I just had a fight.
Wasn't because of me,
was it?
No.
Why are you sitting
in the dark?
I was just thinking
about Scott.
Maybe if I hadn't
blown up at him so quick,
we would've
worked things out.
Yeah, maybe.
L... I don't know.
Is that, uh, better?
Do you think I should call
him and talk to him again?
Oh, sure.
Hi, Scott?
Are you all right?
What were you talking about?
Listen, I didn't mean it.
Are you still
mad at me?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm at this motel.
No, I didn't get wet.
I got here just
before the storm started.
Look, I can take care
of myself.
No, of course not.
Look, I can't talk any longer.
I got to go.
Uh, oh.
How did it go?
Terrible. I found out why he
didn't want me to come home tonight.
Oh, well, why?
He's got somebody new.
He's moved her in
already.
Well, that's no good.
Oh, well.
Think how it would've been if
I'd married him and then found out
what sort of guy he was.
He asked me to, you know?
Sure. L... I mean,
I'm sure he did.
Oh, uh, have... have...
have you had dinner yet?
No.
Well, let... let's have it
together.
I was just about to
sit down.
It's just, uh,
sandwiches and milk,
but you're more than welcome to share it.
I really
don't think that...
No, no, no, do it. Do it... Do
it for my sake. Starving yourself
isn't going to make
anything any better, either.
All right.
But this is yours.
No, go ahead, you... you
have it. I'll make another.
Do you have a knife?
No, I'm afraid I don't.
L... I just moved back here
after being many years away.
I forgot to bring
any cu-cutlery.
That's odd.
People usually
leave something,
even if it is only
an old butter knife.
Oh, there.
Is something wrong, Norman?
Um,
aren't you going to eat?
No. L... l... l... I just
suddenly lost my appetite,
but you... you... you
go ahead.
Enjoy it.
I guess I'm like you. L... I
suddenly lost my appetite, too.
Oh, w-w-would you like
something else?
There're cookies for dessert.
Oh, no, no, th-thank you.
Uh, can I use
your phone again?
Sure.
Who you gonna call?
Um, I just remembered this
girlfriend I have in town.
L... I mean, she's kind of
a girlfriend, and, uh,
maybe she'd let me
spend the night with her.
Well, huh, I thought
you were gonna stay here.
There's a spare room
upstairs
and you're
more than welcome to it.
Uh, l... I don't think
that's such a good idea.
Why?
I don't mean to hurt
your feelings or anything,
but Myrna was talking about
you at the diner today.
Mrs. Spool kept on telling
her to shush but she wouldn't.
She said you'd been
locked up.
Did she say why?
Well, I'll tell you.
When I was 12,
my mother went mad,
so I put some poison
in her tea.
You know? Just...
I'm all right now.
You sure?
Sure.
Otherwise they wouldn't have given
me a job in a diner, would they?
I don't know.
It takes a nut to work there.
Oh, boy!
Look, I-I-I'm sorry,
but I don't want to...
What if I told you
that I needed you to stay?
Why would you need me?
Because this is
the first night
I've spent in this house
in years, much less alone.
A lot of my troubles
had to do
with this house.
So you see, I'm as scared as you
are, just for different reasons.
I-I'm sorry,
but l... l...
Please.
That bad, huh?
No. Not... Not... Not that one.
This one over there.
What's wrong
with this one?
Well, that, uh, used
to belong to my mother.
But she's dead,
isn't she?
Yeah.
Is this the room where
you had your troubles?
One of them, yeah.
Well, I don't know what
happened to you in the past,
but you're never gonna get
over it, not unless you face it.
See? No ghosts.
No.
I could sleep here.
No, I'd, uh...
Why not?
I'd just rather
you didn't.
What happened in here
that scared you so?
Let me show you the room
across the hall, okay?
You'll be, uh,
just fine in here.
Well, the, uh...
The bathroom?
L-ls, uh,
right over there.
Uh, well,
I guess it's time to, uh,
to go to sleep.
Okay.
Good night, Mary.
About time, girl.
Sorry.
Hi.
I'm sorry I missed you
this morning.
I got up early and went into
town to see my girlfriend.
You know, the one
I was telling you about.
Guess what?
What?
We're going to
room together.
Well, y-y-y-you... you're more than
welcome to stay with me, you know.
Thanks, but I'd really
rather live in town.
Oh, in town, yeah.
Uh, my... my place is
a lot closer to work.
No, l... I really don't think
that's a good idea.
Okay. Well,
if you change your mind.
Hey, girl, I gave you the
morning off, not the afternoon.
Hop to it.
Charming, isn't he?
Chop up some more lettuce,
will you, Norman?
Hey, Ralph, so, uh, how's
your new helper doing?
Hi, Warren.
Just fine, thanks.
Yeah, well, I hope he washes
dishes better than he runs a motel.
Hey, can I get a little service
around here or what, huh?
Okay.
Hey, cutie! Come here.
Oh, hello,
what would you like?
I'd like some of what
Norman got last night.
Pardon?
You heard me, sweetheart.
Why don't you look at a
menu and I'll be right back?
What happened between you
and that man last night?
I fired him.
Oh, great,
he's on my station.
What did he say?
Nothing nice and I
think he's been drinking.
He sure smells like it.
Hey, you do have
other tables, honey,
or do you want me to
wait on those, too?
Talk about the customers
being nasty.
Excuse me,
do you still work here?
Yeah.
Then can I please
have my orders?
What was it like?
What's what like?
Screwin' a psycho?
Would you mind
removing your foot?
Next.
Two turkey sandwiches
on whole wheat toast.
One BLT, hold the mayo.
I'll get the tomatoes,
Mr. Statler.
Hey, I suppose
you didn't spend last night
alone with him
in that house, huh?
You got strange tastes
in men, honey.
Just because two people
sleep under the same roof
doesn't necessarily mean
they've made love.
Since when, huh?
Or are you the kind that
doesn't, uh, kiss and tell?
You really want to know
what Norman's like?
Yeah.
Better than
you'll ever be, fat boy.
Cut it out, Toomey!
Norman?
Are you talkin'
to me, whacko?
Come on.
Come on. Come on! Huh?
What's wrong?
Oh. Oh, that's... that's beautiful.
Go on, psycho, pick it up.
Come on, pick it up!
What's the matter,
you lose your nerve, huh?
Or do you only
attack women, huh?
Go on, pick it up!
Show us what
you're really like.
Come... Come on, loony.
Oh, look, not only is he
crazy, he's chicken shit, too.
What's the trouble, Warren?
The trouble is
that psycho you hired.
This is the last time
I eat here.
You're sweating all over.
Can I get you
something?
A glass of water, maybe?
No.
What the hell did you
do out there?
That man, Mr. Toomey,
he was trying...
I'm not talkin'
to you, girl.
Well?
He was bothering Mary, and
then he slipped me a note.
What note?
It's there on the wheel.
There's nothing here.
Look, Norman, you're tired.
Why don't you take the
rest of the afternoon off?
I'm telling you,
it was right there.
Sure it was.
Don't humor me.
I'm telling you there
was a note on that wheel
from my dead mother.
Okay, everybody,
business as usual.
Hi.
Is that offer to room
with you still open?
Oh, sure.
Great.
Well, w-what happened?
Oh,
you know my girlfriend,
the one I told you about?
Yeah.
Well,
her boyfriend sleeps over
almost every night.
Do you know what it's like trying
to sleep in a one-room apartment
when a couple's making love
five feet from you?
Noisy?
You're not kidding.
Well, I thought you were
wonderful today.
Why?
The way you handled
that Toomey guy.
What an asshole.
I could've killed him
and you were so cool.
No, I don't kill
people anymore, remember?
Oh, here.
What's this?
Fudge.
My grandmother sent it to
me. She makes great fudge.
Well, thank you.
What about that note?
You figure out who sent it?
That was just
a practical joke.
Yeah, I guess so.
Oh, oh, oh, l-let me
take that.
No, no, no, that's all right. I can manage.
Uh...
Did you... Did you
have dinner yet?
Yes.
And I'm exhausted. I'm going to
bed right after I take a shower.
If that's all right
with you.
Oh, oh, sure.
Hey, wake up!
Hey, you nut guys there?
Hey!
Psycho!
Hey, hello, psycho!
I just want you to know
I'm moving out! Huh?
Hello?
W-What? Who is this?
My mother is dead.
Mr. Toomey, if this is you,
you're sicker than I ever was.
Bastard.
Bill!
Hi, Bill. I wasn't
expecting you till tomorrow.
Hi, Norman.
I got a call
from Mr. Statler.
He said you quit your job
at the diner.
Yeah. Well, I just figured I could
make more money with the motel.
You know, once I get... once I
get it back into condition that is.
What does Mr. Toomey think
about your plans?
Him? You know,
I fired him.
Y-Y-You know,
he was turning this place
into what I think
they call an "adult motel."
Oh, I see.
Well, there've been an awful lot of
changes in the week you've been back.
Yeah, yeah.
Any more notes
or phone calls?
Oh, no, no, no.
Who's that?
Where?
There, in the top window?
In the attic?
It looked like a woman.
Oh, oh, oh,
that must've been Mary.
Mary, who?
Oh, Mary. She works with me
at the diner.
She's been staying here, too.
Hmm?
Oh, it's nothing like that.
We're just, uh,
we're just friends.
Mary.
Hi, Mary. You look great.
Look, this is, uh,
this is Dr. Raymond.
He was my psychiatrist
in the institution.
Hello.
Hi.
Well, what do you think?
About what?
What Norman's doing. Has he
told you his plans for the place?
Some of them.
Well, I have to be going
to work.
Can I give you a lift?
Go ahead.
See you tonight.
So, what can I do
for you, Doctor?
Oh, thank you.
Are you familiar
with the Norman Bates case?
Very. I was deputy here
when Sheriff Chambers
arrested him years ago.
I re-read the file when I
found out he'd been released.
So, what's the trouble?
Bates dressing up
as his mother again?
No, nothing like that.
Although, Norman says that
somebody has been leaving notes
and making phone calls
claiming to be his mother.
Well, people. So, what do
you want me to do about it?
Put a tap on his phone.
Sorry, Doc,
I can't do that.
This is Fairvale, California,
not Washington, DC.
But I can check around and see who might
hate Norman enough to do something like that.
Anything else?
You could keep
an eye on Norman.
I have been.
All right, Sheriff,
here's my card,
in case you should need me.
Oh, there is
one other thing.
Why, of course, what?
He's got a girl
living with him.
Uh, Mary Samuels.
She works at the diner.
Then I'll check on her, too.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Any time.
Slut?
Are you sure
this is safe?
It always has been.
Come on.
Oh, I don't need
any more.
What's that?
What?
That sound
in the next room.
You're just stoned.
I'm not.
Jesus.
What is it?
Shh.
Let's get out of here.
Come on, hurry!
Come on!
Look out, behind you!
Norman?
Mary, up here.
What are you doing
up here?
L... I was locked in.
You couldn't have been.
There's no key in the lock.
Someone unlocked it
while I was asleep.
Who?
Whoever's been pretending
to be my mother.
Norman, what are you
talking about?
I saw her in the window.
And just look
in the room.
It's all been fixed up
and her stuff's inside.
There's another note, too.
I'm going to check
the back stairs,
maybe they went down
that way.
Norman?
What?
There's no note in there.
What do you mean
it's not there?
No, th-this isn't
how it was.
It was all fixed up.
It wasn't like this.
The... The note.
This...
The dresses are...
Who's that?
Norman, you better
answer the door.
Yeah.
Norman,
whatever you do, don't
tell them about the bedroom.
Hello, Norman,
Well?
I'm Sheriff Hunt.
How are you?
This is Deputy Pool.
Can we come in?
Sure, yes. Yes.
Uh, this is...
I know. Mary Samuels.
What can we do for you?
There hasn't been
any trouble, has there?
Yes, there has.
What sort?
The old sort.
There's a girl sitting down
in my squad car below.
Too scared to come
into this house.
Why?
She claims that
she saw her boyfriend
murdered in your
fruit cellar today
by a large woman
dressed in black.
That's just how
your mother used to look,
isn't it, Norman?
Well, what...
what were they doing
in the cellar, anyway?
Oh, what kids do today,
I guess.
Smoking dope,
messin' around.
Do you know anything
about that, Norman?
No.
Do you mind if we look
in the fruit cellar?
No.
Looks clean to me.
Yeah, doesn't it?
You've been straightening up
down here?
No, sir.
This is the first time
I've been inside this room
s-s-since I came home.
Then who did it?
I did.
Several days ago.
Hey, Norman?
I just hate a dirty house,
don't you?
Why is this open?
I don't know.
You better put a padlock
on it
before someone
robs you blind.
You know why Norman doesn't
come down here, don't you?
No, I don't.
He used to keep
his mother's corpse down here.
Stole it from the grave.
Talked to himself
in her voice,
answering in his own.
What do you think of that?
It's horrible.
That's right, it was.
Now, let me ask you again.
Are you positive
you cleaned up down here?
Yes.
All right.
Mike?
Yeah?
Let's go.
Are you sure
that neither one of you
heard anything this afternoon
between 4:00 and 5:00?
I don't know.
But I was...
He was with me
all afternoon.
We were walking
in the fields.
Goodbye.
Nice to see you again,
Norman.
Why did you do that?
Do what?
Lie to the Sheriff?
You weren't with me
this afternoon.
I had to do something.
He was going to arrest you.
Norman.
It's starting again.
Sheriff Hunt?
Yes.
I-I'm Lila Loomis.
I used to be Lila Crane.
Oh, yes, of course.
What a coincidence.
I was just thinkin'
about you and Sam.
How is he?
My husband is dead.
I'm sorry.
Well, what brings you
back to Fairvale
after all these years?
Norman Bates.
Where is he?
He's out at his motel,
I suppose.
Why haven't you
arrested him?
What for?
For murder.
It's all over town
what he did to that boy.
Mrs. Loomis, I can't arrest
a man without proof.
Especially one
with an alibi.
What alibi?
There's a girl staying
out there with him
and she says
that he was with her
at the time
the murder took place
if there was a murder.
Oh, well, what do you mean
"if there was a murder"?
Well, what I mean is
that I am not convinced
that anybody was killed.
There's no body.
No corpus delicti.
So let's just wait
and see
if the boy
comes home tonight.
Have you dragged
the swamp yet?
What?
The swamp?
That's where he dumped
his victims the last time.
Have you dragged it yet?
No, ma'am.
Well, then I suggest
you start,
before there
are more murders.
Unless, of course,
you want it
on your conscience.
What's her problem?
I don't know.
But if Norman Bates
is crazy,
there are a whole lot
of people around here
runnin' him
a close second.
Are you sure
you're all right?
Yeah. I'm fine.
What you need is one of
my special Irish coffees.
Is there any brandy
in the house?
I don't know.
My mother
doesn't allow liquor.
Mr. Toomey was a drinker,
wasn't he?
Did he leave a bottle
in the office?
I don't know.
I didn't look.
I'll be right back.
You rest here.
Hello?
Why did you lie
to the Sheriff
and say Bates was with you
this afternoon?
Mother. What are you
doing here?
Go back to the hotel
before you ruin everything.
Answer my question?
Why did you alibi Bates?
I didn't alibi him.
Don't lie to me.
I talked to the Sheriff.
Why did you do it?
Because Norman couldn't have
murdered that boy.
Why not?
He saw me in the window
like we planned,
then he went in to the room
and saw the stuff.
Then when he went
looking for her,
I locked the attic door
behind him.
He was trapped in there
for hours
while I took everything
down the back stairs.
So, you see,
he couldn't have done it.
What difference
does it make?
We want him re-committed.
This would have done it.
Mother, he's innocent.
Innocent? He killed
your aunt, didn't he?
Not to mention
the six other people.
Mother, that was 22 years ago.
Mary, people don't change.
He must have
gotten out somehow.
Mother, I was wrong.
I don't think
he drilled that hole
in the bathroom wall.
Of course he did.
Mother, listen to me.
I think there's someone else
in the house.
Don't be stupid.
It's just Bates
up to his old tricks again.
It can't be Norman.
He isn't like that anymore.
Maybe if you knew him now.
It's just that
he's trying so very hard
to do what's right
to keep his sanity.
And that hardly
seems fair for us
to be doing
what we're doing to him.
You're as crazy as he is.
We'll talk later.
Norman needs me.
Norman needs you?
A psychopath needs you?
Look, go back to your hotel.
We'll talk later.
He'll kill you.
You know that, don't you?
He'll murder you just like
he did all the others.
Mary!
My God, what happened?
I don't know.
Jesus. How did that
get in there?
After I killed that kid
in the cellar,
I used it
to clean up the mess
and then, then I flushed it
down there.
You didn't kill anybody.
You were locked in the attic.
It wasn't locked.
You said so yourself.
Norman,
stop talking nonsense.
I told you,
you didn't kill anybody.
Then how do you
explain this?
Well?
I can't.
Did you clean up the cellar
the way you told the Sheriff?
No.
Somebody did.
And with that towel,
after they killed that kid.
Norman,
it couldn't have been you.
How can you be so sure?
Even I don't know.
I always used black out
when l...
Because you couldn't.
You don't have it in you,
not anymore.
Norman, look,
why don't you go downstairs
and make us a drink, okay?
And I'll clean this up.
Norman.
Yes.
Uh, the tea kettle's boiling.
Oh.
Okay.
What happened?
Up there.
I saw someone staring at me.
There's no one there now.
Someone was watching me
through that hole.
They're in the house
right now.
Where'd you get
that thing?
L... I had it
in my purse.
My mother gave it me
when I was...
Oh.
Come on.
Uh...
You take the downstairs,
I'll check up here.
Well, shouldn't we
stick together?
Don't worry,
I've got this.
It's because of me, isn't it?
That's why you have it.
Of course not.
Hurry up,
they'll get away.
Mrs. Lila Loomis,
Room 15, please.
You're sure
she hasn't come back?
There'll be no message,
thank you.
Okay, Mother,
where are you?
Norman.
What is it?
It's my mother.
She's downstairs.
Did you see her?
You're sure you heard her?
Come on.
No.
She'll kill you.
I know she will.
Norman, your mother's dead.
You killed her.
You told me so yourself.
I was wrong.
She survived.
And now,
she's downstairs,
waiting for you.
Norman, it couldn't
be your mother.
No.
No, it... it had to be
someone else.
Whoever it is that's trying
to drive you crazy again.
Yeah?
Yes.
So, let's go downstairs
and find...
No!
It's too dangerous.
Let's wait till morning.
What are we gonna do
until then?
I'll protect you.
You'll be okay.
I'll... I'll be fine right here.
It was always safe here
at night.
Norman, listen...
No!
Okay.
We'll spend the night
in here.
You can
use the sleeping bag.
What are you doing, Norman?
Norman, put the knife down.
Nobody's gonna come
in the door.
They're not?
No.
Okay.
Mary.
Yes.
I'm becoming
confused again, aren't I?
Of course not.
Don't lie to me. Not you.
Yes, Norman, you are
becoming confused again.
Just
don't let them take me back
to the institution, all right?
Don't worry, Norman.
I won't.
You smell good.
I do?
Yeah.
What do I smell like?
You smell like, like the
toasted cheese sandwiches...
What?
...that my mother
used to bring me
when I was in bed
with a temperature.
She used to do lots
of nice things for me
before she went...
Before she became...
Shh.
Just remember the good things
she did for you.
Only the good things.
I can't.
They're not there anymore.
Of course they're there.
No, the doctors
took them all away.
Along with everything else.
Except,
except those sandwiches.
Shh.
Just sleep.
Oh, good morning, Doctor.
Good morning, Norman.
I called your office.
They said you were on your way
over here.
Where's Mary?
She's gone in to town.
Oh. What for?
I don't know.
She didn't tell me.
Some tea?
Coffee, if you have it.
Thank you.
Sure.
Norman.
Do you remember
Lila Loomis?
Yes.
She's staying in town.
She is?
She's Mary's mother.
That's why Mary went in
to town. To see her.
Do you realize
what this means, Norman?
What?
They're the ones
who've been leaving the notes
and making
the phone calls.
Why would they do that?
Because they hate you.
Mary, Mary doesn't hate me.
Come on, Norman.
Like mother
like daughter.
You know how Lila Loomis
feels about you.
She can't wait see you
re-institutionalized.
That's why all this
is happening to you.
They want to destabilize you,
undermine your sense
of reality.
They can't do that.
Good. Glad to hear you
say that.
But...
It isn't them, anyway.
It isn't?
Who is it?
It's my mother.
She's not dead.
How do you know that?
I've seen her,
up in the window.
You saw her, too.
That was Mary Loomis
or Lila Loomis dressed up
to look like your mother.
What about the phone calls?
Mary Loomis again.
But she's been with me
when the phone rang.
Then it was her mother.
My mother spoke to me.
Downstairs.
Norman.
Do you remember now our
discussions about your mother?
Once you accepted the fact
that you murdered her,
her memory would have
no hold over you.
Room 15, please.
I want you
to stop calling Norman.
What are you
doing here?
You heard me.
Stop calling Norman.
I haven't called him.
Don't lie to me.
You called him this morning.
For God's sake,
keep your voice down.
All right,
so what if I did call him?
He's slipping
into insanity again,
I can hear it in his voice.
There's nothing anyone
can do about it,
not even you.
You could stop stuffing
bloody towels down toilets
and peering through
peepholes in walls.
That would be a help.
What?
What are you talking about?
About what you're doing
to Norman.
You were in that house
last night.
I was not.
I came right back here
after I saw you.
Don't lie to me.
I'm not lying.
Why weren't you
in your room last night
when I called?
What, did you have me paged?
I was probably down here.
Mother, stop lying to me,
please.
What happened in that house
last night?
Goodbye, Mother.
He's about to go
over the edge, isn't he?
Listen. Now listen.
Just dress up
in his mother's clothes
one more time.
That's all it's going to take.
I'll have the police
and the doctor
before you are in danger.
Then they'll have to act
on our petition.
Mother, I signed
all your petitions.
I've been to
all your meetings,
done everything
you've asked for years.
But I am not going to
hurt Norman anymore.
Well, if you won't do it
for me,
at least do it
for your father.
I'm not living for dead people
anymore, Mother.
Not for your sister,
or my father,
not even for you.
I'm going.
Now, wait a minute.
Mother, let go,
you're hurting me.
Mom, don't.
No.
Listen to me! If you go near that
house, you're going to be sorry.
Yeah.
I don't see
what all the rush is for.
The Sheriff's concerned.
And he thought we might
bend the rules.
I don't like it.
You're supposed to have
an order from the coroner.
Now do you believe me?
Yes. She's dead.
Then she's not coming back
to life again, is she?
Back to life?
No.
Shall we go?
Mary.
Back here.
I was just about
to have some lunch.
You want some?
No.
Where have you been?
At the cemetery.
Dr. Raymond had them open up
my mother's coffin.
Oh.
Yes.
That proves that
she's not the one
who's been
torturing me.
Not unless
she's a ghost.
No.
No. He says,
he says it's you
and your mother.
He says your last name
is Loomis.
Is that true, Mary?
I wonder
who that could be.
I don't know.
Don't you?
Hello, Mrs. Loomis?
How are you this...
I'm... I'm sorry, Mother.
I didn't mean to insult you.
Norman, stop it.
This is not your mother.
Hello. Hello, Lila?
Lila, are you there?
There's no one on the line.
Hello?
Yes, Mother, I'm sorry
we were interrupted.
Norman, there's no one there.
Yes, Mother.
Hello?
Hello, Norman?
This is your mother.
It doesn't sound like her.
It is, Norman,
and I want you to hang up.
Do you understand? Hang up.
All right.
Do it, Norman, now.
Hang up.
I was so worried.
About what?
Well, that all the things
that have been happening to me
were because of you
and your mother.
When Dr. Raymond showed me
Mrs. Bates' corpse,
I knew she was dead for sure.
But now,
now I know it's somebody
completely different.
Who is it?
My real mother.
Who is your real mother,
Norman?
I don't know.
She won't tell me.
Your mother is dead.
Mrs. Bates
was your real mother
and she's dead.
Then who was that
on the phone?
My mother.
Dr. Raymond was right
about both of us.
Lila and I were trying
to drive you crazy again.
But then I stopped,
only she won't,
and she's the one
who's calling.
Well, why did you stop?
It wasn't fair for us
to be doing
what we were doing to you.
Is that the only reason?
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
Ma'am?
Norman?
The Sheriff would like
to see you out at the swamp.
Hey, Sam.
Yeah?
Scotch it is.
There you go.
All right.
Spread that line away.
We're gonna send the divers
down here in a minute.
Hello, Norman.
Hi, Sheriff.
What is... What is
going on here?
Have you
seen this before?
No. Did you... Did you find it
in the swamp?
Yes.
How about any of this stuff?
This is Mr. Toomey's.
Who?
Norman's motel manager,
before he fired him, that is.
Have you seen him since?
No, I told him
to get packing and he left.
That's all I know.
You sure?
Y-Yeah.
Well, that's about it then.
You can leave.
Just you, Norman,
not the young lady.
Okay. But shouldn't I wait?
Don't worry.
I'll have her
along presently.
Oh, forget the marker.
Get on in there.
Sheriff, I've been
wanting talk to you.
Yeah.
Someone has been
phoning Norman
claiming to be his mother.
And not the dead Mrs. Bates,
his real mother.
So?
So I've been wondering
if it's possible
that he was adopted?
Not that I've ever heard of,
and I've lived my entire life
here, Miss Loomis.
How did you find out
who I was?
We're a tad slow
around here, young lady,
but not incompetent.
Now,
I've got a question for you.
Either you or your mother
know anything about this?
No.
I don't see any point in
either of you stayin' around
Fairvale any longer, do you?
Have we broken some law?
None that are on the books,
but a whole hell
of a lot of them that aren't.
Like all the ones having to do
with right or wrong.
I'd say you and your mother
just about
broken every one of those,
wouldn't you?
I didn't mean to.
Well, that's what
Norman said 20 years ago.
Only he was crazy.
Now, what's your excuse?
I guess I don't have one.
Well, I'll just say goodbye
to you now then.
I expect it to be
for the last time.
Sheriff.
I said goodbye,
Miss Loomis.
Sheriff, there's a car
down here.
Anybody in it?
I can't tell.
It's stuck in the mud.
Well, get a winch line down
to it and get it out of there.
All right,
we found a car.
Doctor?
What are you doing here?
I followed Lila Loomis
from her hotel to your house.
She came down here.
Oh.
Where is she?
I don't know.
But she was here.
It proves she was the one
that was dressing up
as your mother.
How?
If she wasn't
gonna do it again,
why would she sneak
into your house?
But she wasn't the woman
I saw in the window.
She wasn't?
No.
Then who was?
That was my mother.
Norman, your mother's dead.
Remember the open coffin?
Mrs. Bates only
took care of me.
My real mother is somebody
completely different.
How do you
know this, Norman?
She told me on the phone.
Norman, I've already
proved to you
that Mary and Lila Loomis
were the ones
who were calling you.
Would you accept the fact
that you have no other mother
than Mrs. Bates?
Of course.
Then that's what I'll do.
It would be a great load
off my mind.
Okay, everybody stand back.
That's it.
Keep it comin'.
Looks like Toomey's car,
doesn't it?
That's it, a little more.
We'll check inside
before we open the trunk.
All right.
That's it.
Do you recognize it?
Okay, hold it right there.
Well?
Sheriff, it's empty.
Don't you have
some place else to go?
Open the trunk.
Watch out,
Mike.
Oh, Jesus.
Norman. Norman!
What is it?
They found a car
in the swamp.
Who? I don't know who it is.
They just found a car.
Isn't that enough? For what?
For them to arrest you!
I'll get your jacket!
Come on.
We're getting out of here.
How?
I don't know. We'll hitch
a ride until we get a car.
Where would we go?
Somewhere,
anywhere, Norman.
Please hurry.
They'd catch us.
You're right.
So what's the point
of going?
Because it's my fault.
If my mother and I
had left you alone,
you would've been fine.
Nobody'd be dead,
and I'd just be
a dumb psych student
with nothing on mind
but having a good time.
It's not your fault.
Then whose fault is it?
My mother's.
She's the one
who's been doing the killing
to protect me.
She told me so herself.
Oh, Norman.
You're mad,
don't you know that?
You're mad as a hatter.
Should I answer it?
Why bother?
It's only my mother,
poor thing.
She shouldn't be calling.
She should be sitting back
and gloating.
I better answer it.
Hello?
Norman, this is Dr. Raymond.
I just found Lila Loomis' car
parked down the road.
I'm calling you
from the motel parlor.
The calls that
you've been receiving
from your fictitious mother
have been placed
right here.
Lila Loomis has used
this phone to call your house.
Yes.
L... I understand.
Mother?
Norman,
this is Dr. Raymond.
I've been waiting
for your call, Mother.
Hello. Lila?
Lila...
She's hung up.
No, Mother.
Mary's still here with me.
I like her.
No.
No, of course not.
Not as much as you.
No, I...
I won't do that.
You can't make me
kill her.
Do I have to, Mother?
But why?
Why do I
have to kill her?
Oh, no, Mother, please.
Please don't make me...
Oh, Mother,
How can you even think
such a thing?
I can never do
anything like that.
I don't think you understand
about Mary, Mother.
She's really very kind.
I trust her.
She would never do anything
to hurt me.
Norman? Norman.
Do you recognize me?
It's me, your mother.
Yes, Mother.
And since I'm standing here
in front of you,
I can't very well be
on the phone, can I?
So hang up the phone,
Norman. Hang up.
Yes, Mother.
Norman, put the phone down
this instant!
Norman, this is your mother.
Norman, can you hear me?
Norman.
Norman, are you there?
Norman, please say something.
Norman.
Got you!
Norman!
Norman, I...
I didn't mean to do it. L... I...
I thought he was you.
It's all right, Mother.
Norman, I'm not your mother.
It's all right.
Norman, I am not your mother.
I am Mary.
How many times
have you killed?
have I told you...
Norman, look,
I am Mary.
They're gonna come for you,
Mother, just like they did before.
Stay away from me.
And I'll cover up for you.
Now give me the knife.
Stay away.
I always have,
because I'm your dutiful son.
Stay away.
And you're my loving mother.
So, please give me the knife.
It's time to go to the fruit
cellar now, Mother.
Norman, stay away.
Mother, I don't want to...
Norman, now, look.
I don't want
to hurt you, Mother.
You're coming.
In there, Mother, hurry.
Norman, please stop.
You... You need help.
You're losing blood.
You did it.
They're here.
Let me help you.
You killed them all.
Freeze!
The County Sheriff
and the DA
have come down
from Bakersfield
to confer with Sheriff Hunt.
Is that loud enough, guys?
Yeah, that... that's good.
Move over to your left.
I'll get the City Hall
in the background.
Okay, we'll go in
Five, four, three...
You want to read
through this
and make sure
it's exactly what you said.
Yeah, that's...
No, wait a minute.
She didn't say that.
She said
if she didn't stay away,
she'd be sorry.
Sorry.
Not that
she'd kill him?
Can I get a cup of coffee? In a minute.
Everybody's getting
coffee around here.
...the suspect,
uh, wielding a big knife...
...the victim.
I drew myself...
So, she and her mother
were trying to put Norman
back in the asylum.
Well, that much
we know for sure.
Then somethin' went wrong
between them.
What?
They had a fight.
She wanted Lila
to leave Norman alone,
but she wouldn't.
We have a witness
that heard the whole thing.
So she murdered
her own mother over Norman?
Looks like it.
What about the bodies
in the swamp?
The boy
and that motel manager?
Mary and Lila Loomis did it.
They tried to blame
the murders on Norman.
Or maybe only the daughter
did it.
She definitely
killed Dr. Raymond.
I'll tell you, If you had seen
Mary Loomis at the end,
you wouldn't
have questioned it.
She'd gone mad.
Dressed up in Norman's
mother's clothes and a wig,
trying to kill Norman,
and him hardly even able
to defend himself any longer.
Right till the end,
she kept saying
Norman was the one
who was crazy.
It was horrible.
What about it, Norman?
Are you ready to go home?
Lt'll all be in my report
tomorrow, gentlemen.
Uh, let's go out
the back.
Mrs. Spool.
Hello, Norman.
Come in.
I was just having
some supper.
Nothing much,
but would you like
to share my
toasted cheese sandwich?
Oh, no, thank you.
It's, uh,
Miss Spool, actually.
Oh.
You were expecting me.
Well, I was...
I was expecting someone.
I just wasn't sure of when.
Tea?
Please.
Milk and sugar?
That would be nice.
So,
are you really my mother?
The name Spool doesn't mean
anything to you?
No. Should it?
It was Norma Bates'
maiden name.
The woman you thought
was your mother was my sister.
I had you when I was
very young out of wedlock.
I couldn't handle
a brand-new baby,
especially, uh,
being by myself.
I had some trouble
and the State put me away
for a while.
That's when
Norma took you in.
You were less
than a year old.
Too young to remember me.
She never mentioned me,
did she?
No, she, uh,
she didn't.
I guess she didn't
want you to know
that you had a mother
who wasn't quite right.
But we know all about that,
don't we, Norman?
Mmm-hmm.
After I got out, you'd already
had your troubles
and been committed.
I decided to wait for you.
Then when I saw
what they were trying to do
to my poor little boy,
I couldn't stand it.
So I followed them,
and one by one...
After all,
you're all I have
in this world.
You're sure you won't
have a sandwich?
Pardon?
I know how it is, Mother.
You've had a long day.
You must be tired.
I'll just put you to bed
and tuck you in for the night.
I'll even say your prayers
for you.
Would you like that?
I'm not sleepy.
Put me in my chair.
Yes, Mother.
And now,
turn me to the window.
I want to keep my eyes
on you.
Make sure
you don't start playing
with filthy girls again.
Yes, Mother.
Good.
Well, what are you
gawking at?
Go downstairs
and open the motel.
What do you expect us
to live on, hope?
No, Mother.
Remember, Norman,
I'm the only who loves you.
Only your mother
truly loves you.