RABID
KELOID CLINIC
As far as I'm concerned these guys
are completely legit.
The bank is just as convinced as I am.
They wanna go all the way with us.
You know the idea of a franchise
operation for plastic surgery resorts is
one of those magnificent,
inevitable ideas.
Banks are always quick to say that
when everything's rolling easy.
But you can take it from me - first sign
of heat from the medical association,
first cries of professional outrage,
and the bank'll
call back its note and leave us
hanging by our thumbs.
It's not the financing that's
bothering you, Dan.
Your voice has that edge to it.
I've never denied it.
I sure as hell don't want to become
the Colonel Sanders of plastic surgery.
Why not? Sounds great to me.
- We passed it. - We didn't pass it.
I remember that farm.
We passed it. That farm comes
after concession road 12 and we were
supposed to turn at concession road 11.
I don't remember that farm, Dad.
We didn't pass it. I very distinctly
remember that farm.
If you would just stop this vehicle long
enough to look at this map I will...
All right!
You're both right and I'm all wrong.
We'll turn around and
go all the way back.
Goddamn thing!
Shoulda never sold
the goddamn station wagon.
Oh, Christ, Bob!
Huh? Oh, Christ!
Lloyd!
Lloyd! My God! I just saw a motorcycle
exploded in that field.
- I think there's somebody under it.
- I better tell the boys inside.
Is Dr. Keloid there? It's urgent.
Yeah, what is it, Steve?
There's been a motorcycle accident a
few minutes down the highway.
- Should I take an ambulance
and go get 'em? - Yeah, sure.
What am I suppossed to do?
Go back to the three of the
largest investment groups
of North America and say...
- Steve? You still there?
- Yes.
Hang on till I get there, OK? I'm coming
with you. Meet you at the front.
Oh, now, Dan. We've got
a lot of decisions to make...
You and Murray work it out, hon.
Just make the pill easy for me to
swallow, OK?
I don't know why you'd married him.
Bob, get back!
Be careful, Bob!
Get in back, hold him back there!
Get the car run, let's go!
They're over there, Doctor!
They were speeding!
Oh, my God.
- How is her breathing?
- Heavy.
The man's got a broken hand,
separated shoulder, concussion.
We can send him to the General.
But it's definitely major
surgery for her, and right now.
I know we're not, but
we've got no choice.
- How is her blood pressure?
- Steady.
I'd say she's got a half
hour to live and it's
three hours to the nearest
serious hospital.
It's us or nobody.
It must be bad.
Oh, my God.
Get it up!
The guy in the van has got a concussion,
separated shoulder, broken hand.
- Maybe some Demerol when
he becomes lucid. - OK, Dr. Keloid.
OK, boys. Take her into pre-op.
- Tell Dr. Karl to set her up for the
works. - Yes, doctor.
- What's that all about? - Somebody
said something about an accident.
Couldn't they throw a sheet over it
or something?
- I don't buy it, Dan.
- You haven't seen her.
I don't have to see her.
Neutral field grafts have never
been used internally.
We could end up with a terminal cancer
patient on our hands.
Aw, c'mon. We can monitor, Roxy.
She's got nothing to lose.
Literally.
So when do I get to see Rose?
Not for a while.
Why not?
Oh, Jesus.
I didn't kill her, did I?
She's not dead.
Now, I know everyone
here is familiar with
the standard techniques
of skin grafting,
but what we're going to do is
a little out of the ordinary.
I'll explain it as we go.
We're removing
full-thickness skin grafting
material from the
patient's thighs
as per normal graft
acquisition procedure.
However, before these grafts
are applied to the damaged areas
of the patient's breasts, abdomen,
and so on, they will be treated
so that they become
morphogenetically neutral.
They are then called
neutral field grafts.
Well, when the thigh skin tissue is
treated,
it'll lose its specificity as both
thigh tissue and skin tissue.
For example, if it were grafted
to a burned cheek,
it wouldn't just be thigh skin with the
color and texture of thigh skin
it would actually develop as facial
tissue.
In other words, neutral field
tissue has the same ability to form
any part of the human body that
the tissue of a human embryo has.
Let me add that there is always a
possibility that carcinomas will form
when neutral field grafts are
used internally.
In this case, we're using a radical
plastic-surgery technique
to compensate for our lack
of heavy medical hardware.
Can we treat the graft material here,
Dr. Keloid?
No, Dr. Karl. The
graft tissue will be
frozen and sent to the
Sperling Institute.
We'll have to keep the patient
in an operation-ready state
until it comes back to us.
That's going to be a bit trying for
all of us, but it can't be helped.
ONE MONTH LATER...
No. Her body is still in a state of
total shock.
She can't possibly be moved
to a city hospital yet.
Her grafts seem to be healing well.
We've been monitoring
the internal grafts electronically and
there is definitely new tissue growth
happening in the abdominal cavity.
Her helmet probably saved her
from brain damage,
but until she's fully conscious...
- You won't know that either. - Hart,
what can I tell you? There's no magic.
Look, I've done my best.
You're welcome to visit Rose
any time you want.
Please, believe me,
I will personally telephone
you the instant Rose shows
even the slightest signs of
regaining consciousness.
Jeez, when I saw that thing
burning, I never figured
I'd be standing here talking
to you a month later.
- How's your hand?
- Oh, it's ok, I think.
They're taking the
cage off later on this
afternoon. That's
when I'll find out.
The pin stays in my shoulder
for another month, though.
Doesn't seem to bother me except
when it gets damp.
Last time I've got my ears done I've
really felt when the weather changed.
- It's probably something you gonna
have to live with. - Yeah, I guess so.
- Hi Lloyd.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- Great, not too bad.
- Looks terrific.
- Good.
- C'mon, Hart. I got
a pack of hungry
investors waiting for me.
- Ok, Bye, bye.
I hope you've got some friends who'll
help you unload that pile of junk.
I've got a bad back. What're you going
to do with it? Use it for an ashtray?
Rose!
Rosie, sweetie, take it easy!
You need that juice, sweetie.
It's keeping you alive.
What are you doing, Hart?
Are we all right? Are we...
I'm not Hart, Rosie.
Hart's back in Montreal waiting for you.
I'm Lloyd. I'm a friend of yours.
- Hart?
- Back in Montreal. Waiting for you.
Oh. I... I guess I was dreaming.
I don't think you were just dreaming.
You and Hart were in a really
spectacular motorcycle crash.
- Crash?
- Yes.
You're bleeding right now.
I'd better get Dr. Keloid.
Oh. No! No. Don't go.
I'm all right.
But I'm freezing cold.
Oh, you're so warm.
- Look, I think I'd better...
- Hold me!
Please.
I'm dying of the cold.
Oh, God, that feels so good.
- Ah, look... you don't even know where
you are, do you? - Oh, good.
Look, this is really weird.
Are you sure you know
what you're... Ow!
Hey, I think I... I think
I cut myself.
I think I cut myself or something.
Yes.
Who is it?
Mr Walsh! What on earth
has happened to you?
I don't know.
I can't remember anything.
Were you sleepwalking?
Could you have fallen
against something outside
and then come back in
without waking up?
I doubt it. Never done
anything like that before.
Get me some stuffing, maybe a sponge
or two as well.
This wound isn't clotting at all.
I think we're going to have to shoot in
some coagulants to get a scab to form.
Right away.
Does this hurt?
Can't feel a thing.
You can't?
My whole right side has
no feeling in it.
Just this aching kind of tingling.
Dr. Keloid.
Maxim would like to see you.
- Right now? - He says it's very
important. He's waiting in the hall.
Ok.
Listen...
our friend here may have had a stroke.
The General's the best place for him.
But before you plug him
up I want 10 cc of blood
drawn directly from
that wound for tests.
Then get Steve to drive
him into the city in the
ambulance. Tell him to take
lots of plasma with him.
We're going to have to
forget about the coagulants
until the General has a
chance to do an ECG on him.
Will do, Doctor.
Yes Maxim, what's up?
You told me to check around
the grounds to see if I could find out
how Mr. Walsh got hurt? I couldn't find
nothing outside. No blood, nothing.
Then Nurse Rita call me.
Watch your feet, Doctor.
The police may want
to examine it exactly
the way we found it.
Why the police?
Mr. Walsh fellow attempted to molest the
poor girl while she was still in a coma.
I've seen things like that happen
before.
Maybe he was drunk.
Hm. Her grafts have taken amazing
well.
Judy Glasberg.
You back again?
Daddy didn't think the
new nose was different
enough, so I'm in for
more alterations.
I keep telling him it looks
just like his, and he
keeps saying, 'That's why
I want you to change it.'
- What's that? - I'm terrified
to find out what it all means.
All right, you! Hold it right there!
Oh. Whatta we got here?
Hello, sweet honey pie.
What're ya drinkin'?
You come in to get outta the cold?
I got something ya can take a drink
off of, an'it ain't no whisky, neither.
Honey pie.
You've got blood on your mouth.
Do you like me, ha?
I kin tell ya do.
Come on!
Hurry!
Lloyd, where are you going?
You can't leave yet.
They haven't figured out how come
you're bleeding all over the place.
Aw, it's slowed down to a trickle.
- No problem.
- No problem, ha?
- How's your arm?
- It's fine.
All right.
If the night nurse comes around, I'll
tell her you're in the can, how's that?
Terrific.
- Take care of yourself.
- You, too.
Take me to Camelford.
I'll tell you where to go from there.
Rose? I thought everyone was asleep.
Do you mind if I get in with you?
I've been lying in bed for such a
long time, my body aches all over.
I'm so glad I ran into you.
I think I'd better get out now.
I'm getting all wrinkly.
Oh, no. Not yet. You haven't
even told me your name.
Judy Glasberg.
Mondom neki: "Miért hagyod,
hogy a nejed dirigáljon neked?"
Mister, are you ok?
You look a little bit sick.
Do you mind if I pull over the side
of the road?
- Hello?
- Hart!
I'm in terrible trouble.
I want you to help me.
Rose? Is it really you?
Where are you? Are you all right?
- Hart, can you hear me?
- Yes, I can hear you.
Listen, you've got to come quick
and get me.
Rose!
Tell me what's wrong?
You all right, dear?
Rose, what's wrong?
Christ! What was the number of that
place?
Doctor, I think you'd better
come with me.
I think...
I'd like to talk to her alone first.
Ok.
Rose... I'm Dr. Keloid.
Dan Keloid.
I'm here to help you, sweetheart.
Oh, dear.
It's all right.
Rose, we won't talk about anything
right now except how you're feeling, OK?
Good.
First thing I want to do is to check out
some of the skin grafts we did for you.
What's the matter, Rose?
Are you in pain?
Talk to me, Rose.
It's the only way I can
understand what's bothering you.
I'm hideous, Doctor.
I'm crazy and I'm a monster.
C'mon, Rose.
There's just about nothing we can't fix
if we know what's wrong.
Now, I don't want any more games.
Do what I tell you.
That's enough.
Ok.
Look at Potato-man!
He is in love with Ketchup-women.
Not now.
Excuse me.
Who is this? What do you want?
Do you know what time it is?
Listen Murray, I hate like
hell having to bother you like this,
but I'm going out of my skull.
It's ok. I was up anyway with
the baby.
- What's the matter?
- I got this phone call from the clinic.
- And?
- From Rose.
- Who?
- From Rose!
She's supposed to be in a coma,
for God's sake.
She said she was in trouble.
She wants me to help her.
She wants me to come
and get her right now.
Look, Hart - she's confused and
she's scared.
Did you phone the clinic
back and try to talk to Danny?
I did. I got to talk to
a tape recorder.
I left a message.
Ok.
OK. I tell you what I'm going to do.
I'll phone Danny right now at his
private number, and I'll tell him
that your Rosie is making phone calls
in the middle of the night.
Then I'll pick you up
in an hour and we'll go
up to the clinic together.
How's that grab ya?
Ok, Murray.
- Thanks a hell of a lot.
- Yeah, Keep well. See you soon.
Does that hurt?
No, it doesn't hurt.
How long have you been conscious,
Rose? Do you know?
Couple of days.
Do you feel weak?
I feel strong. I feel very strong.
Rita tells me you refused
to let her attach you
to your intravenous
nutrient bottles. Why?
I don't need them.
They make me feel sick.
I don't understand.
- They've got to be your only
source of food. - They're not
They haven't been for
a couple of days.
- Not since that man...
- Man?
What are you talking about?
I'll show you.
- Half a BBQ chicken to go.
- Yes, sir.
Half a BBQ chicken to go.
And... will that be all?
Hey, Mister. Did you know
you're bleeding?
It's nothin'.
- Musta had a rough night, Buddy.
- I can't remember too good.
Here is your order, Sam.
Hey, Buddy. I think that one's mine.
I said... I think that one's mine,
Buddy.
I gotta eat. I gotta eat. I gotta
eat...
I don't hit nobody with glasses.
Now calm down!
You're sure you want to do this one,
Dan?
Louise and I could handle it
with no trouble.
I'll be fine.
You were pretty groggy this morning.
Cut yourself shaving?
I'll be fine.
Scalpel.
Sponge.
Do you want me to complete
the stitching, Dr. Keloid?
I need... I need something to cut
with, Dr. Rushton.
- You want the scissors now, Doctor?
- Yes. The scissors now.
Scissors.
Dan...!
Rita, Dr. Keloid's gone crazy.
He's killing everybody!
There's blood everywhere!
We've got to do something!
- Calm down.
- Come quickly.
The man, later identified as 43-year-old
Fred Atkins of Camelford,
went berserk this morning
during an argument over who was
to be served first, and bit
the counter girl on the arm.
The man was subdued by an unidentified
truck driver and the place's cook,
but died of unknown causes
before police arrived.
Local health authorities suspect
that rabies might be involved
and have vaccinated
everyone concerned.
And now, after a brief pause for station
identification, we'll...
The place they were talking about
on the radio.
Wanna stop off for a bite?
Not hungry, thanks.
- Hey, look. What's going on there?
- What?
The place is crawling with police.
You're right.
Oh, Christ, no!
- What's the matter?
- It's Rose. It's got to be.
- Something's happened to Rose!
- Take it easy, Hart.
They wouldn't need three cruisers
for that. It's something else for sure.
C'mon! C'mon!
Take it easy, will you?
Bill, what's going on?
- Where's Dr. Keloid?
- Murray, thank God you're here.
It's been a nightmare.
I'm trying to find my girlfriend.
She's a patient here.
She was here last night but nobody
seems to know where she is.
We got a young girl downstairs.
You wanna take a look at her?
- Is her name Rose? - We don't know.
We didn't ask her. C'mon.
Tell the chief I'm downstairs gettin'
an ID. Be back in a flash.
- So you are in fact Dr. Keloid's
business partner? - Yes, I am.
Come with me, please.
Excuse me.
- Bill?
- No, you go, Murray.
I can't. I've seen it.
Mr. Cypher, please!
Couple of my men got bitten.
Those rabies shots are killers.
Think I'd rather take my chances on
getting sick instead.
How is he, doc?
You said they've got bitten.
- Bitten? By what?
- By that.
- What?
- Go ahead, take a look.
Can you confirm the identification
of this man as Dr. Daniel Keloid?
C'mere. Can't see anything from there.
Is that Rose?
No.
No. No, that's not Rose.
Rose, would you like a bite?
Steak on a bun.
Real good.
Um... wouldn't mind just one bite.
Sure?
It's fabulous.
It's ok.
Last time I ever patronize that greasy
spoon, I can promise you that.
C'mon sweetheart. There's a girl.
Get it all out.
I'll lift you back in. We'll get you
some soup or something at the next stop.
Something wrong?
Hey, buddy!
What?
I musta dozed off.
Yeah, I was driving...
Well, that's good.
We find too many of you
boys taking pills to
keep yourselves going
all day and all night.
Thanks.
Next time, though, try to pick
a better spot to pull over.
This road's kind of narrow.
Oh, thanks. I will.
Sorry.
OK. Have a nice day.
Hi.
- Hi. where are you going?
- Montrea. Where are you going?
- Same place.
- Great.
I was beginning to think
I'd never get back home again.
Claude Lapointe, Quebec Bureau of
Health, official business.
Sorry, boys.
You can't go in unless you're
willing to stay.
The whole station's
under quarantine.
We think we've got an epidemic.
Hello, Mindy?
How are you?
Good.
Listen, I thought that Rose might try
to get in touch with you.
Yeah. She what? She called you?
She's on her way over?
That's incredible.
You wouldn't believe what's been
happening. It's crazy time.
Well, listen. When she gets there,
tell her
I'll be stuck in the Camelford cop shop
for at least forty-eight hours.
When she gets there
you'll keep here for me.
Ok, Mindy. Bye.
Hey, anybody here seen Eddy?
He's got the lead
truck and I can't find
the son of a bitch.
I think I've seeb him
in the back before.
He didn't look too good.
Whaddya mean he didn't look too good?
Smooth Eddy always looks good.
He looked sick.
Like, nauseous.
What the fuck we runnin' here,
a nursery?
Eddy!
Hey, Eddy, you in there?
God damn truck drivers,
you can't trust them...
...and health officials have said they
consider the outbreak
of the new strain of rabies as being
potentially 'the worst of this century.'
At the police station in Camelford,
Kathy Draper talked to
Quebec Bureau of Health official
Claude Lapointe.
This is not just a question of swine flu
or something like that.
We have already several deaths on
our hands in this one small area alone,
and the main problem is... we don't
know what we're up against.
Are you saying that this is not
an outbreak of rabies?
I'm not saying that. I'm not
saying that, exactly.
But it must be a new strain of rabies,
because there are symptoms involved
which we and even
the world health
community do not seem
to be familiar with.
What are these symptoms?
Well, the period of incubation of
this disease is very brief,
maybe six to eight hours at the most.
Now, that's quick, much quicker
than normal rabies.
Then the victim begins to sweat,
to shake, to foam at the mouth.
That's not so rare.
What is rare is that
the victim always with this new disease
becomes violent
and wants to bite somebody new.
And this crazy phase
is followed by a coma
and then, in every case
we know, by death.
It's very strange.
What advice would you give
to our viewers?
The disease spreads
through the saliva of the
victim... the saliva
is very contagious.
It dribbles into open wounds and cuts
and causes immediate infection.
So?
So... don't let anybody bite you.
And if somebody does,
find a doctor who can give you
rabies shots immediately.
I heard you mention the
Black Plague of London just
before we went on the air.
Is that what you mean by...?
Surprise. I'm amongst the living.
Got anything in there I might want
to read?
I'm starting to go stir crazy already.
It's actually pretty exciting stuff
if you know how to interpret it.
Really.
I can't see straight.
I'm just going on automatic pilot.
Oh, boy.
I just can't believe
they're all dead...
George, for God's sake! Can't you
understand what I'm saying?
Stay back!
Sit on the floor and put your
hands on your head.
Get into the cell.
Do what I tell you!
Gimme room. I'm coming in quick.
They gave him rabies shots.
He got bitten up at that facelift place
and they gave him his shots right away.
They didn't do him any damn good,
did they?
Where are you going?
I think I have to go out for a while.
Rosie, I feel so stupid.
I haven't been much of a hostess.
Why don't you stay here?
There must be
something in the fridge
I can tempt you with.
Thanks, Mindy, but it's not that.
I just have to get out
into the fresh air again.
It's a real experience for me
just to walk down a street.
- Let me come with you. - No. You
stay here and finish your laundry.
- I won't be gone too long.
- OK, Rosie.
If you get dizzy or anything,
call me.
Ok, I will. Don't worry.
'Scuse me. I didn't mean
to touch you.
Well, pardon me for existing.
I thought you did it on purpose.
No. Really. I was taking my jacket
off and it brushed against you.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
I like seeing these movies
but men are always bothering me.
I guess I'm a little paranoid.
Well, look.
If I come and sit beside
you everybody will think
we're together and you'll be
able to watch in peace.
All I ask is a couple
handfuls of popcorn.
Ok.
C'mon.
I'm going, Rosie.
I've left you some coffee on the stove.
Turn it off if you go out, OK?
OK. 'Bye.
Aren't you going to wish me luck?
Are you OK?
Brushing my teeth.
Bye.
Good luck.
Thanks.
See you later.
You'll pardon me, Mr. McLaren,
but I think
the mayor should be taking this
epidemic more seriously than he is.
A city is a complex
machine, Mr. Lapointe.
Needs constant attention.
The mayor will listen to you, but you're
not the only one. It takes time...
- Why have we stopped, Clark? - There
is no way to get around this truck.
Well, isn't there anyone around?
- Do we have to turn around?
- Oh, here is somebody, sir.
Clark... roll down your window and
ask them why the road is blocked.
- It may be strike trouble. Be careful.
- Yes, sir.
They've got the disease!
Look at their eyes!
...we spoke with a director
of the World Health
Organization who had just
arrived from England
to take charge of liaison with Health
Bureaus in Western European countries.
Dr. Gentry, do you honestly feel that
this is a time for martial law?
I don't think there's any question
that martial law is needed
in the city of Montreal
at this point in time.
It's a necessity.
It has already been established
that victims of the disease
- and it is not rabies, though it may be
related to the rabies virus -
victims of the disease are
beyond medical help
once it has established itself to
the degree of inducing violent behavior.
What you're saying, then, Dr. Gentry,
is that...
What I'm saying is very simple. It may
not be very palatable for your viewers.
Shooting down victims
of the disease is as
good a way of handling
them as we've got.
If we lock them up, they immediately go
into a coma and die shortly afterwards.
We've now got a vaccine that we think
will work in a preventative way,
but for those who are alread
incubating the disease...
- C'mon. Rose is waitin' for me.
- OK, kid. Let's go.
All those receiving
shots of the new
vaccine are being issued
plastic ID cards.
Viewers are urged not to leave their
homes unless absolutely necessary,
and are reminded
that if they do they
must carry their vaccine
cards with them.
Police, army, and militia officers
may demand to see them.
- Give me the keys.
- Here you are.
Remember to keep your
windows up and your
doors locked once you
get into the city.
Maybe the bug can't get
you now, but that...
...that won't protect
you from the crazies.
- Take care now.
- Thank you.
Bye.
Hi.
Mind if I sit down?
I don't mind.
Nothing like Christmas, huh?
Ah... you smoke?
You know... cigarettes?
Do you want a cigarette?
Have you got a light?
I lighter?
I'll ask that guy over
there for a light.
I'll be right back.
You gotta light, buddy?
Stop or I'll shot!
Stop!
Get out of the way!
Christ!
Rose, are you home?
You never guess what happened to me
on the subway today.
The whole city's gone crazy.
Have you been out?
Have you gotten your shot?
I can't go out.
What's been going on?
What's the matter with you?
Poor kid.
Well, don't worry.
I'm here and going to
take care of you.
...and the crisis has now
been officially granted
epidemic status by
officials of the WHO.
The Prime Minister was reluctant to
officially declare a state of emergency,
but as any citizen in
the streets can tell
you, martial law has
come to Montreal.
How long are wee gonna be stuck here?
I can't believe it.
It's like we were at war.
Listen, Hart. We're going
to my place first.
I'm not going to relax until
I know that everything there's OK.
Once we're there, I'll give you the keys
to the car and you can go get your girl.
OK. Thanks.
Listen,
- phone me when you get there.
- Yeah, I will.
Look, maybe you should bring Rose
back here with you
until this thing blows over.
Yeah, ok.
- Listen, Murray.
- Yeah?
Thanks for the car, right.
- Don't forget to lock the door.
- Yeah.
- I'll see you soon.
- I'll call you.
Cecile!
I'm home.
Honey.
Cecile? I'm home.
Cecile!
Hey sweetie!
Cecile?
Cecile!
Honey!
I'm home.
Cecile?
Honey?
Oh, God!
That's it, Rosie.
You just get as much sleep
as you need.
Don't think about anything.
Let your mind drift.
And so after using
some rather elaborate
tracking procedures and
applying them to a map
we find that the disease
does in fact seem
to have a very specific
place of origin.
Which is...?
Which is the Keloid Clinic
of Cosmetic Surgery,
a few miles outside the
town of Camelford.
You can see with your own eyes
how everything has spread out from there
in geometrically increasing proportions.
Now this pattern, in
conjunction with some
of our other statistics,
indicates that
hthere is a strong
possibility that there is a
special factor at work in
the spread of the disease.
You mean a carrier.
Well, at the risk of setting off
a futile witch hunt... Yes.
Someone like the infamous Typhoid
Mary who incubates the disease
and transmits it, but
is herself immune to it.
What were they doing at the Keloid
Clinic, Dr. Gentry?
Ok, Jack. I got another.
Oh, no!
Rose, you can't!
It's dangerous out there.
Mindy. I don't want it
to be you.
Of course it should be me.
Who else but your best friend, Rose?
I'll take care of you.
Oh, I ache all over.
I'm hurting from the inside out.
Well then, what you need is a nice,
deep, hot bath.
It'll seep in and relax you.
It won't ache anymore.
It's not my fault.
It's you.
- It's been you all along.
- What are you talking about?
You carry the plague. You've killed
hundreds of people.
No... no... you don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm still me.
- I'm still Rose.
- No, you are not Rose!
What did they do to you at the clinic?
What did they turn you into?
I have to have blood.
It's all I can eat.
And it's my fault.
It's your fault!
- It's all your fault.
- Stop!
There must be some way to fix this...
- We'll go to the police...
- No.
We'll go to the hospital...
No, we won't. Just leave me alone.
- Wait!
- No!
- Leave me alone! Let me go!
Rose, listen to me.
Listen to me, you're right.
We're in it together. We'll figure
it all out together...
Hi.
I've seen you around
before, haven't I?
I just moved out of this building.
They keep sending my mail here.
I... yes, I'm a friend of Mindy Kent.
I was supposed to meet her here,
but she must have gone out.
- Hello?
- Hart.
It's me.
I'm glad I managed to get you.
Rose, where are you?
Are you all right?
Did I hurt you?
We should be together.
Please, tell me where you are.
Well, what you said to me hurt me.
It scared me.
It scared me because I suddenly
knew you might be right.
And if you were right, about my being
a carrier, I mean...
I murdered Mindy.
I murdered a lot of people.
Rose!
So I decided to try a
little experiment to
prove that you were
wrong about all that.
You see? I'm being very positive,
aren't I?
So I found myself a partner
for my experiment,
a normal, healthy guy,
and I took a little of his blood...
just a bit...
and I've locked myself in with him.
I'm going to stay here with him until
I'm sure he's not going to get sick.
And then I'll know that I'm not
the one who started it all.
Rose, look. You gotta get out
of there, right away.
You're commiting suicide,
you know that?
Hart, I just want you to be with me
over the phone...
I mean just a few hours,
just until I find out.
I mean we can live together
over the phone, can't we?
Oh, please. Listen.
Please.
Rose! Get out of there!
Please, Rose, just drop the phone
and walk over to the door
and run outta that place
as fast as you can.
You're not giving us enough time...
No, Hart.
Listen...
Hart...
Get out of there!
- I'm afraid.
- Run!
Hart!
Subtitles: mitbrille
Karagarga@2014