Zudrate.
Repo
Out from the night,
from the mist, steps the figure.
No one really knows his name for sure.
He stands at 6'6" head and shoulders.
Pray he never comes
knocking at your door.
Say that you once bought a heart
or new corneas,
but somehow never managed
to square away your debts?
He won't bother to write or to phone you.
He'll just rip the still-beating heart
from your chest!
Repo
Man
- Repo
- Hey, come on. Quick.
Man
Now, you could run.
You could hide. You could try to.
But he always has a way of finding you.
He will come at your weakest hour,
when no one is around
who might rescue you.
Repo man
And none of us are free
from this horror,
for many years ago, we all fell in debt.
New body parts were needed
to perfect our image,
and until our debts are clear,
we will live in fear of the...
Repo man
Vote no on Prop 598
and keep repossessions legal.
If companies like GeneCo
couldn't repossess organs...
Vote no on Prop 598.
Tune in to tonight's Genetic Opera
to witness Mag's farewell performance.
...Genetic Opera
to witness Mag's farewell...
What is this?
You disgust me.
I'm sorry, Mr. Largo.
I'm afraid... I'm afraid it's terminal.
You don't have much time.
It's spreading rapidly.
Things you see
In a graveyard
Maggots. Vermin.
You want the world for nothing.
Commence your groveling.
Rotti, your king, is dying.
Even Rotti Largo cannot
prevent this passing.
Who will inherit GeneCo?
I'll keep those vultures guessing.
Things you see
In a graveyard
I'll keep those vultures guessing.
Things you see
In a graveyard
I'll keep those vultures guessing.
Guessing, guessing, guessing.
This will be quick
It's in my sight
I'll capture it
Then run back inside
And be back home in time
Industrialization
Has crippled the globe
Enjou GeneCo's dau and nighttime
formulas of Zudrate.
Nature failed as technology spread
Ask a gentern if Zudrate is right for uou.
And in this wake, a market erected
Buuing Zudrate
from an unlicensed source is illegal.
An entire city
Built on top of the dead
And you can finance
Your bones
And your kidneys
For every market a submarket grows
No.
But best you be punctual
With making your payments
Lest it be you on the concrete below
It's quick
It's clean
It's pure
It could change your life
Rest assured
It's the 21st century cure
And it's my job
To steal and rob
Graves!
No! Please, please, stop!
Stop!
Grave robbers on 7 I
Oh, no! No...
Lockdownl Lockdownl
Grave robbers on...
Oh, no!
No, no, no, no!
It's locked!
This way, kid.
Wait! You're going to get us caught!
Wait! Wait!
Jackpot!
So why care for these
petty obsessions?
Your designer heart still
beats with common blood
And what if you could
have genetic perfection?
Would you change
who you are if you could?
'Cause it's quick
It's clean
And it's pure
No. I shouldn't be here.
It could change your life
Rest assured
I have got to get home.
It's the 21st century
Cure!
This cannot be happening
And it's my job
To steal and rob
- Graves!
- No, no, no, please!
Grave robbers will be executed on sight.
Gravesl
Let them go.
I didn't know. Please.
Hey!
I can't read.
I didn't know.
Blood pressure warning.
Medicate immediatelu.
- Dad.
- Hey
It was a close one
Dad.
Too close
Dad, what happened?
You're gonna be all right
Now that's all that matters
Was I outside?
No, Shi
There were these bodies
You missed your medicine
And fell unconscious
- They were all dead.
- Nonsense.
Please be more cautious
You could go into shock
But it was real, Dad
I am the doctor, and I'm your father
I didn't imagine this
Please, Shilo, drop it
Couldn't have fathomed this
Please, Shilo, stop it.
Dad, I could smell the dead.
You could have died! You...
You scare me to death!
A blood disease
That took your dear mother from us
Passed from her and into your veins
I'd be lost if I were to lose you
I will stop at nothing to keep you safe
I'll take my meds, Dad
Don't you worry
Just until I find a cure
Your mother, rest her soul
Would be so proud of you
Though you cannot see her
She is here with you
We will always be there for you
In your time of need
Shilo, you're the world to me
Shilo, take your medicine.
I'm
Infected
I'm infected
By your genetics
Shilo, I'm the doctor
Shilo, I'm your father.
Oh, Shilo, that was close.
Take your medicine
I'm infected
By your genetics
And I don't think that I can be fixed
No, I don't think that I can be fixed
Tell me why, oh, why
Are my genetics such a bitch
It's this blood condition
Damn this blood condition
Mother, can you hear me?
Thanks for the disease
Now I am sequestered
Part of the collection
That's what is expected
when you are infected
How much of it's genetics?
How much of it is fate?
How much of it depends
On the choices that we make
He says I have a right to
I also inherit his shame
Is heredity the culprit?
Can I stop it, or am I a slave?
I want to go outside
Outside
I want to go
Ladies and gentlemen
Signore, signori
Don't you dare touch your TV
Tonight's genetic opera
is the place to be
That's right, friends!
Where did our daughter go?
It's me she must escape
My burdens I can't erase
The mother I might have saved
- Assassin
- Murder
Monster
Marni, I need you now
Look what I've become
The nightmare that she should fear
Is the father you left alone
The years roll by without you, Marni
17 have come and gone
I raised our Shilo with the best intentions
But there is something I can't tell her
I'm lost without you here
I am only living out a lie
Shilo can never leave
She is my everything
Nothing can bring you back
Shilo is all I have
- Assassin
- Murder
Monster
Years roll by without you, Marni
17 have come and gone
I raised our Shilo with the best intentions
There is something I can't tell her
I am lost without you here
I am only living out a lie
I'm the monster
Assassin
I'm the villain
What perfection
Assassin
What precision
Clean incisions I deliver
Unscathed organs I deliver
Repossessions I deliver
I'm the Repo
Legal assassin
The lungs and livers
And bladders and hearts
You alwaus save a bundle
When uou buu our GeneCo parts
Spleens, intestines,
and spines, and brains
All at warehouse prices
But our qualitu's the same
GeneCo
Mark it up
Where the fuck is Dad, brothers?
He left me in charge, sister!
I don't take lip from a
- Slut
- Cunt
My brother and sister should fuck
Pavi, shut the fuck up.
I'm the smartest and the toughest
I will find a hole and fuck it
If there ain't one, I will make one
Luigi don't take shit from no one
One brain, mark it up
Only I got brains enough
That's why Pop
will leave GeneCo to me
Me, me, me, me, me
Ask a gentern who they prefer
10 out of 9 will say the Pavi
The most dashing, panty snatching
I will leave your diapers dripping
Two hearts, mark it up
Pavi steals all of the hearts
You ain't got the guts, brother
All bark but no lungs, brother.
Dad will leave GeneCo to me
You wait
Time will tell
- Pavi's face...
- Luigi's fists...
...will rule you!
... will woo them all.
- When I inherit...
- I'll inherit...
All this stuff
Take Dad's will and write you out
Take my cut and mark it up
Mark it up, mark it up
Hi. I'm Blind Mag.
Your treasured memories
don't have to fade with time.
Announcing GeneCo's Cornea Plus.
GeneCo's breakthrough
optical technologu
where everuthing is digitallu recorded
so uou can relive
uour favorite memories
again and again.
Don't miss out
on tonight's genetic opera.
Oh, a message.
...from Rotti Largo.
Incoming message from Rotti Largo.
Shilo, uou don't know me,
but uour mother was once
veru dear to me.
I can help uou find uour cure.
Meet me in uour mother's tomb.
Ashes.
Dust.
My children were a bust.
They shall inherit nothing.
No, no.
My legacy is too great
to throw away on ingrates.
Nathan Wallace had potential
Till he stole my Marni away.
In denial, Nathan blamed himself
for Marni's sudden death,
and never once thought
to suspect the man
who wrote his checks.
I guess...
I'll take it to my death!
Things you see
In a graveyard
I'll take it to my death.
Marni, it's Rotti.
You never should have left me.
I would have given you the world.
It's been difficult to see you
after what you've
put me through.
You forced my hand and made me do...
Well, it looks like I'll be joining you.
It seems the man
who cured the globe
cannot stop his own extinction.
But I can go out with a bang!
No!
I can go out with a bang.
Things you see
- In a graveyard
- Blood pressure...
No, no, please!
I can't be outside.
I can't be outside!
Things you see
Blood pressure warning.
Medicate immediatelu.
Shilo, thanks for coming.
It's nice to see
Young talent blooming
My kids have been...
Well, disappointing.
I'm Rotti Largo.
I know.
I own GeneCo
Please let me go.
Sorry to be
So difficult
I had no choice
You're a tough one to find
Climbing through holes
Tell me, why do you hide...
- I'm not.
- Your pretty face?
I cannot be outside
I have a blood disease
But there is hope, an antidote
And you could be the first
To sample it, the GeneCo fix
To all blood diseases
And I can use someone like you
The poster child of progress
It's the cure you sought, Shilo
Your chance to see
the world, Shilo
In your grasp
I don't...
A function awaits.
Will you be my date?
I can't.
Blind Mag will be there.
- Mag?
- You two should meet
No.
I must leave
My dad will worry
Who says that Dad
Needs to know everything?
Repo man
I hate to do this
It's a thankless job
But somebody's got to do it
Penile tissue inch by inch
Skinnin' off the muscles slow
Harvesting the kidneys for the fall
Savin' up the livers in the fridge
No one ever thanks me
when I'm done
How self-absorbed people can be
With a slice
Or a snip
Eeny meeny miney moe
With a cut and a stitch
Returning organs good as new
It's a thankless job
But somebody's got to do it
Got to do it!
Like a mop!
Like a mop.
And a broom.
No one wants a thankless job
GeneCo's Digital Corneas
provide state-of-the-art resolution
and low densitu without sacrificing stule.
Hi. I'm Blind Mag,
the Voice of GeneCo.
At GeneCo, an affordable
organ makeover
is just a simple financing awau.
Take control of uour life,
because it's what's
on the inside that counts.
Financed organs are subject
to all legal default remedies,
including new possession...
Sorru, folks. It'll be a long time
before GeneCo can
help uou sing like Mag.
I don't know about uou, Bob,
but I haven't been this excited
since mu first elective surgeru.
No doubt, Dick.
Excitement's in the air.
For one dau a uear onlu,
Sanitarian Square will open its gates
and welcome all of us
to its post-plague Italian Renaissancel
GeneCo's new Rome.
Ah, the cuisine, the music, the culture.
GeneCo provides the finest
in Italian-inspired bodu version.
Wow. This is turning into GeneCo's
most spectacular
and unpredictable event ever.
That's right, Dick.
Onlu a few short hours
until Blind Mag's final performance,
which is guaranteed to be talked about
for uears and uears to come.
Genterns
Genterns, they secure the finest skin graft
And stacked
Scalpel, needle, thread
That should do it
Okay, Mr. Largo,
want to see your new face?
Oh, it's so perfect!
Someone's going to hang
if I don't get my coffee!
Decaf?
I will shoot you in the face!
Sorry, Mr. Largo.
Here's a fresh cup for you.
What's this, rat piss?
Luigi, stop it
Who's gonna sing, then,
after you leave?
Amber, please, it's not my place
Someone must sing
Why can't it be me?
- Sister, please.
- Just shut your face!
Listen, you bitch
When I'm running GeneCo...
- In your dreams!
- Dad loves me
And they all love the Pavi
When the geezer croaks
You will all learn to respect me
That's enough!
- But she...
- But he...
Children, off!
Mag, there's someone
I'd like you to meet.
A daughter of an old friend.
A ghost from your past.
Seeing you two stirs memories
Mag was 19, not much older than you
I heard her sing
And at that moment knew
I'd help her see
And watch her talent bloom
I could help you, too
Will the Voice of GeneCo
please take the stage?
Blind Mag to the stage.
Please don't go
I must go
Don't say no
I must see
Technically, you belong to GeneCo
Of course, I joke.
Of course, you joke
You're free to go
I've got tonight
Tonight
Everubodu, everubodu,
line up, line up now.
We have to get supper tickets.
Don't be shu.
Let go.
How am I going
to find my way home?
GeneCo
Incoming message from Rotti Largo.
Collect on the Handleman
account at once.
His paument is past due.
Repossess GeneCo's propertu.
Oh, my God!
I'm sorry! I'll pay later!
Oh! Stop! No!
No, no! No! No!
No! No! No!
Medicine reminder.
Shilo.
Yes, Dad?
Did you take your medicine?
Yes.
...for GeneCol
What's that?
What's what?
That.
Oh. That.
My window, it's cracked
Then why aren't you
wearing your mask?
Should I head back?
No, I'm fine
I can be there in no time
That won't be needed
But, Shilo...
Your patients need you
Dad, who's that?
Oh, that?
One of my patients. He's sick.
- Will he live?
- It's looking grim
You should stay there for a while
I will rush home when I'm done
Take your time, nothing's wrong
I love you
- Daughter
- Father
Medicate immediatelu.
Blood pressure warning.
Zydrate
Get your fill of it
You're real?
Don't bother me.
- I'm sorry.
- You'll get me caught.
I must get home.
Follow me.
Where are we going?
Where are you taking me?
Mr. Largo, how are you?
The folks at home would like to know
your thoughts and views
about Zydrate use...
And its abuses
Would you care to comment, sir?
Well, thank you, sir.
Let me direct the matter
to my daughter
The mind behind
the Zydrate support network
Welcome Amber to the stage
How old are you?
17.
I had my first surgery
when I was 13.
And thanks to Z,
I couldn't feel
or remember a thing.
A month later, I was turning tricks.
I'll keep a lock on it all
Drug market
Submarket
Sometimes I wonder
why I ever got in
Blood market
Love market
Sometimes I wonder
why they need me at all
Zydrate comes
in a little glass vial.
A little glass vial?
A little glass vial.
And the little glass vial
goes into the gun like a battery.
And the Zydrate gun
goes somewhere
against your anatomy.
And when the gun goes off, it sparks,
and you're ready for surgery.
Surgery.
Grave Robber
Sometimes I wonder
why I even bother
Grave Robber
Sometimes I wonder
why I need you at all
And Amber Sweet
is addicted to the knife.
Addicted to the knife?
And addicted to the knife,
she needs a little help with the agony.
Agony.
And a little help comes
in a little glass vial
in a gun pressed
against her anatomy.
And when the gun goes off,
Miss Sweet is ready
for surgery, surgery.
Grave Robber
Sometimes I wonder
why I need you at all
It's clean, it's clear, it's pure.
- It's what?
- It's rare.
It takes you there.
It what?
It takes you there
It's clean, it's clear...
Before the cut
I can do nothing at all
It's surgery, it's surgery.
It's surgery.
It's the way your friends
may change inside.
Feel alive
Hey, that's Blind Mag's song.
Who did that?
So you think you got heart
So you think you got balls
So you think Mag can sing
I don't think nothing at all
So you think Mag has pipes.
Well, it's my turn to shine.
When the Repo Man strikes!
What are you talking about?
Mag's contract's got
some mighty fine print.
Some mighty fine print?
Some mighty fine...
And that mighty fine print
puts Mag in a mighty fine predicament.
If Mag up and splits,
her eyes are forfeit.
And if GeneCo and Rotti so will it,
then a repo man will come,
and she'll pay for that surgery.
Surgery.
I can't feel nothing at all
Cleanin' up the city since 030
Sir, we have Amber.
We're bringing her in.
Incoming message.
Nathan Wallace, come to mu office at once.
Honey?
Are you awake?
Well, who ordered pizza?
I could sure go for a slice!
Oh, never too pressed
for that dramatical entrance
You wanted to see me?
Thank you for coming
Have your new assignment
Hot off the meat truck!
Is there a reason why
You couldn't phone me this target?
This is a job of special importance.
It is involving a GeneCo employee,
a singer we all know.
That has-been soprano
A traitor to GeneCo
Tonight is her last show
I can't afford a scandal here
Please handle Mag as best you can.
Take her down
But Mag's eyes...
Are GeneCo's.
I know this may seem hard
Mag was Marni's best friend
You break my friggin' heart
You can reunite them.
I cannot do this job
Remember who you are.
Remember what you did to Marni.
Must I take you back there
Please don't take me back there
Why relive that moment?
I can't relive it
That dark, fateful night
When you murdered your wife
It's too painful
Marni was past helping
Shilo's life was slipping
Shilo was slipping
She needed her dad,
and I needed skilled hands
So I fixed things
We made an agreement
I will honor that agreement
- You'll do as you're told
- I'll do as I'm told
So Shilo never knows
About that dark and fateful night.
Or my secret repo life
Don't deny your repo life
Dear Marni, I am so sorry
Can you forgive me for this?
Not the death doctor
with the hungry scalpel
Here's my prognosis, will they live?
Doubtful.
You're the street physician
Carving rare sculptures
Paint your ass like a Rembrandt
Ha! You like that?
Better start praying
when you see him coming
For tonight, it's curtains
You're the night surgeon
I remember
Remember what you did to Marni
And who you are
I remember
Remember what you did
To your knife!
See it glide.
See it slice!
Who's your night surgeon?
I hope you have my money
Or it's buon viaggi
He'll do your ass like dishes
Amputation
Remember who you are
- Please, please, please!
- I remember
Remember what you did to Marni
Remember who you are
I remember
Remember what you did to her
Remember who you are
I remember
Remember what you did to Marni
Remember who you are
I remember
Remember what you did to her
I remember every dying whisper
Every desperate murmur
I remember when I gazed upon her
She looks just like you
I remember
I remember working every victim
With acute precision
I remember every time I hold you
My blunt companion
I remember
I dismember
'Cause the claims medic gives no anesthetic
90-day delinquent
gets you repo treatment
Remember horror
on your street corner
Make your mama boil you
I'm a night surgeon
I remember
Nathan!
I cannot do this job.
Find someone else.
No one walks away from me.
He wants out?
Then I will take him out.
Shilo? Is your name Shilo?
Can I talk to you?
Can you come down, please?
- Why?
- So we can speak.
I saw you at the show
I thought I'd seen a ghost
Your resemblance is striking.
You have your mother's eyes, her hair
I was told you died with her
All these years have come and gone
How do I put this?
I'm your godmom
State your business.
Business?
What do you want?
I want, I want
To finally meet you
Something real
to cling to, leave you
With the hope that you will go to
All you're meant to, all I failed to
In you is a world of promise
We have both been
kept in bondage
But you could learn
from all my failures.
I'm not supposed to talk to strangers.
Or let them through the gate?
That, either. A big risk.
- A big fence.
- A big mistake.
A new friend.
Oh, my God. Mom?
How'd you do that?
- Do what?
- That. That eye thing.
These eyes can do more than see.
I know. I mean, I've seen you sing.
- Where?
- From my window.
I can see the world from there.
Name the stars and constellations.
Count the cars
and watch the seasons.
I wish we could have watched together
I can't have guests.
- Never?
- Ever.
If Dad found out
that I'd been let out
or that you'd been let in...
I should go, then, before I do
- Promise me you won't
- Better that you don't.
Don't forget a sheltered rose
It's best if I resume my life
Needs a little room to bloom
outside her bedroom
Chase the morning
Yield for nothing
Let your life be a dream
Integrity, honesty
It's too late for me
Don't look back
Till you're free
to chase the morning
Yield for nothing
Chase the morning
Hi, Nathan.
Mag.
How did you get in here?
Don't you have a show tonight?
- How are you, Nathan?
- Busy.
You never were
A man of many words, Nate
- You told me Shilo died
- Listen...
Nathan, I promised your late wife
I'd be present in Shilo's life
Please, Mag
Shilo's very ill
It's not safe
For her to see people
I need to give her her medication.
Dad, let her stay in here
No, she's leaving
Please hide her here
- From what?
- She'll be dead
Look, I told her she was sick
Nathan, you are hurting me
- Dad!
- My daughter needs a rest
I'll be fine, Shilo, don't you fret
Repossessions are dangerous
You're not safe
- Dad, she's not safe
- Shilo, don't you fret
- Leave my daughter
- Your daughter's
She is sick
You've turned this house
- Into a zoo
- I can't have this
Marni wouldn't want this for you
Set her free
- Please don't leave
- Set her free
Come back
- Keep it down, Shi
- Come back!
It's your bedtime, it's late
- Dad, am I...
- Please
- She will die
- Nonsense
- It's arrived, Dad
- It's a contract
- A contract?
- Come and see
- Nonsense
Come see
Mag's in trouble, Dad
Where'd you get this?
Read it, Dad, a repo man will come
and take Mag's eyes!
There are things in life
That we do best to leave alone
She'll die, you must help her, Dad
- That are beyond control
- You must stop her
That you don't want to know
Will you save Mag?
She will lose her eyes
Unless you stop this repo man
Shilo, this is senseless
- Dad, you have to try.
- Shilo
- This is pointless.
- You can't let her die!
Please, shut up!
Your mother's death
taught me to accept
That nothing ever lasts in this world
Foolish dreams
can destroy a grown man
What chance has a 17-year-old girl?
I don't know what I was thinking
There's no sense in girlish dreaming
I'm just 17, 17
And it's better than 40.
Mama drama's got to go
Nothing's gonna bring her back
Experiment with something living
Because I'm sweeter than 16
Hey, hey! Hey, hey!
I've always longed for true affection
But you compared me to a corpse!
Dead, with the dead
- I'm joining the living
- 17
Because I'm freer than 16
Hey, hey! Hey, hey!
Shilo.
Something's changing
I can feel it
17 now
Why can't you see it?
17 and you can't stop me
17 and you won't boss me
You cannot control me, Father
Daddy's girl's a fucking monster
I'm sorry.
Shilo.
Listen, alll
I've never been
so surgically maimed
Amber, please, it's not that bad.
I'll be the laughingstock of the stage
Daughter, please, it's not that bad
This is your fault,
I asked you to help me
No, Amber, please
I warned you about this
Happiness is not a warm scalpel
I don't care! It's not fair!
Baby, baby, baby,
don't do this
I will never sing again
I gave you the life I wished I'd had
I look like a crime scene, Dad
All you ever do is take, take, take
All I ever do is give
That surgery was only 90 grand
I did not complain
When you changed your name
From Largo to Sweet
I need a stage name!
You are a disgrace
Your genes are not worthy of mine
Are you okay, Daddy?
I'll have one of my surgeons fix you up
so you can sing tonight.
Thanks, Daddy.
Flesh is weak.
Blood is cheap.
Inconsistent.
Consistently
Use your sense
Save your cents
The only thing with persistence is
Gold
It makes the world go round
But before I go
My kids will know
About the man they have crossed
As Marni did the day she fled
And became Nathan's wife
She forced my hand,
he dug her grave
I will not be betrayed
Empty the trash of all of them
And leave it all to the kid
Lay the bait
Shilo's fate
But only if
And will she appreciate
That gold
It makes the world go round
Gold
Shilo, I have uour cure.
Tonight all will be revealed.
See uou at the opera.
So Rotti thinks he can take Shilo.
Dad?
Nothing, Shilo, nothing
Go to bed
Why didn't you tell me
I had a godmother?
What?
What are you talking about, precious?
Lovelu, Mag, sing
Attention, all GeneCo personnel.
Apprehend the Repo Man
Nathan Wallace at once.
Bring him to me.
I want Nathan Wallace taken out.
Shilo?
Come to the opera with me
Shilo!
Tonight we are betrayed
Keep Shilo safe
Make Rotti pay
I'll man his grave
At the opera...
tonight.
Shilo, this dress
once belonged to uour mother.
I would be most honored
if uou wore it to the opera.
I must be brave
Come, come what may
Can I be saved?
Is there a way at the opera tonight?
I've made my peace
No chance for peace
I hold no grudge
I'll end this grudge
I'm gonna sing
I'll stain the streets
- My final song
- They'll run with blood
At the opera tonight
One more hit for the show
- Make it fast
- Take it slow.
One more hit of the glow
Go get cut.
For tonight's show
Tonight I set the stage
Tonight we set the stage
My greatest play
My greatest face.
I'll take the lead
- My greatest rage!
- Pavi gets laid.
All debts are paid
At the opera tonight
Repo man
- Repo man
- Freezel
At the opera tonight
Repo man, come take my hand
Repo Man
My eyes
Repo man, at the opera tonight
Bloodbath
It's gonna be a bloodbath
'Cause no one crosses GeneCo
No, not even Repo
Will Rotti clean house?
Damn, we're gonna find out
At the opera
Stay tuned.
The winner of this blood feud
Will take GeneCo
Tonight's opera
is brought to uou bu rich Prosego.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Genetic Operal
Everybody, everybody
Get down, get down now
Stand up
Don't be shy
People, people, people
Everybody, everybody
Testify
Everybody
Get down, get down now
Stand up, don't be shy
People, people, people,
get up, get up, get up
Everybody testify
GeneCo helped me upgrade
my second-class heredity!
Testify!
My liver was wrecked,
but now I can drink whatever I want!
Testify!
Before GeneCo,
my anatomy was completely repressed!
State your names!
Genterns.
Saved!
Everybody, everybody
Testify
Stand up and don't be shy
People, people, people,
get up, get up, get up
Everybody, everybody, testify
I needed a kidney
transplant desperately
GeneCo showed this
single mom sympathy
This makeover came
for a small added fee
Now I look smashing on live TV
- Be healed!
- GeneCo's got it.
You know you want it, baby.
GeneCo's got it.
Testify!
Shilo, uou've made it.
You're close enough to taste it.
Your cure, is waiting.
There is but one thing pending.
Help us catch him.
This former GeneCo trainee
who's lost his mind completelu
and managed to escape me.
You saw him
In the graveuard
Thank God mu guards responded.
It seems this fiend has
set his teeth on uou,
so be on guard. He's coming.
We'll use uou as bait
to draw this snake out of his hole,
and I am sorru, Shilo, for that,
but this is uour defining moment.
Will uou let uourself be trapped,
or will uou use uour trap to trap him?
Put uour hands together
for GeneCo's favorite
and onlu daughter,
Amber Sweetl
Blame not my cheeks
The pair with love they be
Bring me Repo Man,
and uou will get uour cure.
And now, without further ado,
the event uou've all been waiting for.
GeneCo proudlu presents Blind Mag.
Come take these eyes
I would rather be blind
Ladies and gentlemen, don't panic.
Stau in uour seats.
It's all part of the show.
Stay tuned, folks
You don't want to move, folks
'Cause there's more
excitement coming
As an encore, GeneCo will cure
A very sick and needy young girl
She's been caged up like a monster
By her overbearing father
But tonight we're gonna set him right
And for all your viewing pleasures
Didn't I tell you not to go out?
Didn't I?
You did, you did
Didn't I say the world was cruel?
Didn't I?
You did, you did
Then tell me how this happened
What I did wrong, tell me why
Can't we just go home, Shi
And forget this dreadful night?
Didn't you say that you were different?
Didn't you?
I am, I am
Say you aren't that person
Say it
I am, I am
Then tell me how to act, Dad
What to say, Dad, tell me why
All you've ever told me
Every word is a lie
Didn't you say that you'd protect me?
Didn't you?
I tried, I tried
Is that how you'd help me?
Is it?
I tried, I tried
Don't help me anymore, Dad
You are dead, Dad, in my eyes
Someone has replaced you
Dad, I hate you, go and die
Didn't I build a house, a home?
Didn't I?
A cure is waiting.
Didn't I raise her all alone?
Didn't I?
Then Rotti took her from me
Stole my Shilo, he's to blame
Have I failed my daughter?
Then let the father die
And let the monster run
Repo Man
Stop!
You've exceeded all my plans
More than you
could say for Amber
More than I could say for you.
What?
Or your just-as-worthless brother
I just want to get my cure
And I promise to deliver
Don't you lay a hand on her.
Hold your tongue before an elder.
Touch her, and I swear I'll kill you.
Bring it on, you cheap imposter.
Even though I'm terminally ill
I'm dying, you idiots.
Please don't say you're dying, Father.
Please say you ain't dying, Father.
So I planned my perfect end
A tale befitting any opera
And ending only I could spin
Ending you will be my pleasure.
I no longer trust you, Dad.
You can never trust a monster.
And there's more beneath his mask.
Did you know he killed your mother?
It was just an accident
- Accidents can end in murder.
- Shilo, believe me
And that's not his greatest fib
Someone tell me what is going on
Tell her, tell her
- Let's leave
- Tell her, tell her
- Someone tell me what is going on
- No more
- Tell me, tell me
- Tell her, tell her
- Tell me
No more.
May I introduce you
To the man who made you sick?
He's poisoned all your medicine
- I can't breathe
- You've got to fight through it.
Someone, please,
please help my daughter
This will pass.
You've got to fight through it.
I've deceived the only one that matters
- I need my pill.
- You need to know
- You've got to fight.
- It's not your fault
Believe me, Shilo.
It's me who failed you
My stomach.
- It's his medicine
- My medicine
It's your medicine?
I'm the cause
Of all your sickness
Here's to the medi...
That's all there is
Thanks for coming.
Your mother once
promised her love to me
Had she never fled, you'd be mine.
Deny your father now,
for the world to see.
Kill him.
Kill him!
No.
And I'll leave you GeneCo
- What?
- All of it?
Oh, yes.
Oh, no!
So witness it, people.
All I have to do is sign the paper
All you have to do is pull the trigger
- I want you to do what is right
- You want to pay me
- to kill my father?
- This man killed your mother, your mother
- Shilo
- He betrayed you both, he's a liar
- And he poisoned you
- Force me to kill
I am not a murderer
But you share your dad's genetics
What if he passed this to you?
I don't have to share his choices
Didn't you say you were infected?
Didn't you, didn't you?
I poisoned you
I'm worse than Rotti, imprisoned you
I couldn't lose you,
what have I done?
Forgive me, Shilo,
I drugged your blood
Oh, God, what have I done to you?
You used my mother's death
to use my father
You used my father's death
to use me, too
Your dad deserved
whatever happened to him.
He needed me, and so do you.
I remember
Remember my mistakes
Remember you can change
Remember that I love you
I'm sorry that I failed you
Remember that it's up to you
To go and shape your life into
One that's worthy of remembering
No!
Dad!
Dad, no, please!
Somebody!
Somebody, please help.
Money-grubbing beggars,
no better than I am.
You! Don't come near me.
You're embarrassing.
You're disgusting.
You're not men. You're creatures.
I'm embarrassed by you.
Get away. I don't need you,
not either one of you.
Go away!
Don't show your face to me.
You're disgusting.
You're not my daughter.
You're nothing.
When I'm gone, GeneCo will crumble.
I doubt the world will remember
how lucky they were
to have Rotti Largo.
Dad, be still
There is nothing you need say
It can wait
Shi, your mother's calling me
Sometimes I wanted to cry
When the people on TV
Were not quite the way we were
Somehow I guess I just knew
But I didn't know I love you so much
I didn't know I love you so much
But I do
Sometimes I'd stay up all night
Wishing to God
That I was the one who died
And sometimes there's
not enough time
But I didn't know I love you so much
I didn't know I love you so much
But I do
Shilo, go
Dad, I will not leave you here
You will live
But you've already saved me, dear
Go and change the world for me
And we will always have each other
In our time of need
- Daddy
- Shilo
You're the world
To me
Oh, Daddy, please, no.
Please, please.
Please, get up.
Please.
Years
It's been so many years
Resenting the years
And my heredity
Oh, I have hated and loved you
I have hidden behind you
But I finally see
You I've mistaken for destiny
But the truth is my legacy
Is not up to my genes
True, though the imprint is deep in me
It will always be up to me
Up to me
Free at last
Goth opera
Blood saga
Sometimes I wonder
how we ever got here
Old grudges
Scorned lovers
Sometimes I wonder
why we all don't move on
'Cause we all wind up
in a tiny pine box.
A mighty small drop
and a mighty dark plot.
And the mighty fine print
hastens the trip to our epilogue.
Epilogue?
But the little girl fled,
and the king is dead.
And the castle is left for the taking.
But GeneCo may survive
if it undergoes surgery,
surgery.
Surgery, surgery.
- Surgery.
Repo Man.
Out from the...
Our heroes will not be forgotten.
GeneCo will live on,
under new management.
Me.
Prau he never comes
knocking at uour door.
Sau that uou once bought a heart
or a new cornea...
Amber Sweet, ladies and gentlemen.
Amber Sweet.
I can't hear you.
I can't fucking hear you,
you fucking peasants!
You gonna start applauding?
I'll kill you all, you fucking mice!
Dad.
Repo man
Sweetheart, are uou feeling closer?
Close to the line hupe of the sku?
Or is it better from a distance
To see it clear?
To deal with uour fear
That uou were inside
Is the devil uou see?
Go, all the life uou leave behind
Still forcing uourself
To bear uour cross
God bless uou all
Born the wau uou were
Love death in life
You come through
A needle into a bug
A needle
Who's there? Stau back.
Do uou have mu cure?
Kid, is that uou?
I'm here to learn mu cure
Your cure?
Is that what this is about?
Sorru
That fucking Amber cleaned me out
But maube later
I'll look uou up later
Just help me down
- The drug
- Yeah, the drug.
- Yeah?
- The cure, it's...
The drug
Help me down. Ill score some.
Help me shed some
Kid, I'm out.
- Some?
- I told uou.
Light on
That's the situation
The situation
Into a bug a needle
- How about...
- Yeah.
She's right beside uou
- No, I needed Zudrate
- No, I'm out of Zudrate
No, it's like a night light
The beautiful
- You don't mean...
- Yeah.
- You need...
- So easu
- I don't think...
- Don't think.
- That I...
- Just smack it
- I guess I see
- She won't
You've got to smack it
Is to score a needle
Into a bug a needle
Into a
Bug
Ladies, gentlemen, signore, signori
Don't uou dare touch uour TV
Tonight's Genetic Opera
is the place to be.
- To the transplantsl
- To the genternsl
The Genetic Opera is this eveningl
You'll-a laugh, uou'll-a cru.
You'll-a...
Sing
The Genetic Opera is good
It's goodl
I will flower
As I stand to face muself
In this final hour
Bitter fate I accept
This must be mu, mu aching hour
This must be mu aching hour
Tonight I will settle all mu debts
Tonight I will sacrifice
Tonight I am coming to collect
Tonight
I will save mu life
I've made mu peace
All debts are paid
At the opera tonight