25.000 English
RESURRECTION
by Russell Mulcahy
- Prudhomme.
- John, sorry to call you so early.
- I was up.
- We got a problem.
What time is it?
Is early.
Ok. I make you some breakfast.
I don't have time.
Go back to sleep.
Yeah. The old man says,
I get a hard-on once a week...
but I fart at least
ten times a day
- Good morning, John.
- Keep them away, Mac.
Ok. Stay back!
- You've been inside?
- No, I just got here.
Hey how does a blonde turn on
the lights after sex?
She opens the car door.
- I don't know why I'm wasting my good jokes on you?
- I don't know either.
Prudhomme. What are
you doing here?
- I got the call.
- Bullshit. We run at the scene first.
- I got the call!
- What's the deal, man?
You don't have enough cases
that you need more?
- Where's the body?
- I asked you a question.
Hey! He just doing what
they told him to do.
Hollinsworth, I'm not talking to you.
Oh, you're not talking to me, Scholfield.
Yeah, well... I'm talking to you.
So what is it?
Are you better than everybody else?
Nobody can do it as good as you do?
We're all idiots here?
I don't see the point
of this conversation.
The point is the reason why
nobody likes you.
I like you.
He's a little ripe, but a...
He's been dead for four days.
- Who is he?
- Peter Balcour. He owned the place.
Who found him?
Contractor who had
an appoinment with him.
It seems Balcour's old man was
a little bit reckless
Owned a large fleet of fishing boats...
He died a couple of months ago
and left everything to his son...
Balcour had an appointment
to the contractor...
...to fix the place up to sale it.
Any other family?
Contractor said the kid
was end of the line.
- Anything taken?
- You mean besides his arm?
No. We did find his wallet in his
jacket pocket with 112 dollars in.
Was he alive when
he lost the arm?
Yeah. If you check out
the blood splatter.
Take a look at this.
He has some kind of
strange burn effect here.
And the back of his
head is all singed.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
I have to verify all that
when I get him back to the shop.
Any more light in here?
No, that's it. I didn't wanna touch
anything so I left the curtains closed.
- Open them.
- Sure.
- Do you finished that report?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- OK.
Do you think this guy is
somewhere in New York city?
I'll get in touch with NYPD
and when they get him, I'll get his ass!
Hey Jack, can I get one
of those papers?
Prudhomme, Hollinsworth.
In my office.
Rousch and Scholfield were just in here
preaching about you stealing their case.
They can have it if they want it.
This is not a democracy, Prudhomme.
It's your case.
- I gave it to you.
- Then what's the problem?
The problem is you pissed 'em off.
Hollinsworth is the only one in the entire
department who wants to work with you.
I don't know how would it
like in New Orleans...
but since you came here you got
through one partner after another.
Did you bring me in here to talk
about my social skills?
Talking to you is like
pissing into the wind.
I bet you should know
better by now.
What do you got?
Peter Balcour, 33 year old, male.
Owner of a fleet of fishing boats.
And his right arm cut
off up his shoulder.
The killer, we presume,
took it with him when he left.
Took it where? Like a souvenir?
That's somethin' new.
Witnesses?
No, but the killer
left us a message...
...written in blood.
- Prints?
- Forensic is cheking.
- We won't find any prints.
- How the hell do you know that?
Because he doesn't want us to.
- And also there be more bodies.
- You don't know that.
- For all you know, this... What's his name?
- Balcour
Balcour sort out a customer
on a case of tuna.
The guy cut his arm off and pull
out this bullshit to throw us track.
The killer wrote "He is
coming on the window.
That signifies a future event
that isn't taking place yet.
This guy has something worked out
and today was just his first move.
If this is all planned,
what's the motive?
Whe already know the motive.
The killer wanted his arm.
That's a motive.
Would it be to much of asking to have
a cheeseburguer any once in a while?
Why do you think
he took the arm for?
Do we have to talk
about this over lunch?
I don't know. Obviously we're not dealing
with someone who is paying food back here.
God only knows what is doing.
Maybe we got another
Jeffrey Dhammer.
Why don't take the whole body?
Maybe he only wanted a snack.
Jenny call today.
She's coming to visit us.
Again?
Yes, again.
What? Is there a problem?
No but the last time she
came for a weekend...
...she stayed two weeks.
She's my best friend. What I'm supossed
to tell her? Stay in a hotel?
Hey, are you OK?
Yeah. Just... Thinking.
About that case?
I saw it on the news.
This world just keep getting sicker
and sicker everyday.
Why would someone do
such a thing?
I don't want to talk about it.
Well, I'm not asking details.
I'm just asking your opinion.
I said I don't want
to talk about it!
And the fat guy said: I though I was gonna
scream when I came out of the closet.
Prudhomme.
Do you know the exact cause of death?
Yeah. Exanguination. That means
he bleed to death.
He also has some burns on the right
side of his parietal region.
Looks like he was tortured with a
taser or some kind of cattle prod.
It didn't kill him but
probably knocked him out.
So he was unconcious when
his arm was taken?
No, unfortunaley he was.
His endorphine and adrenaline
were incredible high in his blood.
Which means he was
wide awake. He...
He experienced a severe
trauma just before he died.
You tell me that he waited for
him to wake up before cut his arm off?
- Yeah, that's what I'm telling you.
- How sick is that?
I can also tell you that
whoever this guy is...
...he knows what he is doing...
...because he removed that arm
with almost surgical precision.
This guy is no Jack the Ripper.
You might be interested in this.
- Roman numerals.
- What's that?
Oh, yeah. Is a keymark and
is tinted permanently.
Let me check the neck.
Bismark Locker Services.
Over there.
Bingo!
Can you identify it?
Brachiate Serafolios.
Is a flower from the Bonewood tree.
Where I can find it around here?
- You cant. Is indigenous to Australia.
- We're not in Australia.
I can see why they
made you detective.
- What about the Botanical Museum?
- I don't think so.
This flower was picked
only a few days ago.
There is one however
at the Botanical Gardens.
There's your flower.
- Billy?
- Got it.
Hey Prudhomme...
This whole area was being
cut out and made back in.
- Spread out.
- Why not?
Oh, my God...
Jesus!
Call Chibley and
call this place down.
How difficult could be for someone
afor get in here at night?
Not very difficult. All we have is
a wall around the property.
No security?
This isn't a bank.
All we have are plants here.
Prudhomme?
Andy...
His arm is been removed.
What's that?
This guy likes to play
with numbers. Doesn't he?
Prints identify him as
Matthew Leesan, age 33.
He works for the I.R.S.
It seems our killer's taste
in victims is improving.
To be exact he was killed before
Balcour and at different location.
The killer moved this
body to the Gardens.
Why go into all that trouble?
First being in scene.
What about the numbers
on the victims?
- Actually, they're numerals.
- What?
- They're roman numerals.
- And numerals aren't numbers?
All I'm saying is I think the killer
choose numerals for a reason.
119...
2427.
Numbers, numerals
So far, we're only found
what he wants us to find.
No prints. No trace evidence. Nothing.
What we got here is a
very clever serial killer.
Guys, the lab just called down.
The blood on the window
wasn't Balcour's.
- From whom it was, then? Killer's?
- It wasn't anybody's.
Lab says it wasn't human.
Says it was lamb's blood.
Do you wanna play?
That's it, my baby.
You wanna play?.
No!
- Who called it in?
- I did.
- Where is it?
- Over here.
Right down here, getleman.
Watch your steps is a
mess down here.
Transients, druggies, whatever...
All kinds of shit happens
to live down here.
Fuck! It stinks!
Yeah, is too easy to go outside
and relieved themselves.
- How do you come across in?
- One of the bodies slided down.
Lots of rats in this city!
Here is something you
don't see every day.
It's in there.
Oh my God!
What's this guy wanna find?
Is like a shopping list or somethin'?
Where's his head?
There's a guy sitting in front of me here.
Where's his head, John?
I'm sorry
Where is Chibley?
He's on his way.
One plastic comb, about
1,25 in change and pack of gum...
Oh yeah. And a wallet.
One James Ordway.
- You done?
- Yeah.
I got a pretty good
idea what killed him.
- Is this the scene?
- No.
The killer cut him in here...
strangle him up and let him
bleeding like a stuck pig.
Then he dragged him back in there,
cleaned him up...
...and sat him on the throne
for a dramatic effect.
- I gotta have some air.
- You welcome.
- Any witnesses?
- No.
What? No witnesses?
No witnesses?
- Are you kidding me?
- We talked to everyone in the building...
...no one saw anything.
No one heard anything.
Wait a minute! You kidding me.
A guy gets in here...
...cuts another guy's head off...
...walked out with it
and nobody sees anything?
No witnesses! Fuck!
I swear to God, man. I've
been on the job for 8 years...
...I never seen anythin'
like this. Never!
- He want to shock us.
- He's doin' a good job.
Let's go.
We found the victim's wallet.
Driver license id him as James Ordway.
Are we sure is him?
Yeah. We check the prints
against the license. It's him.
Leesan was killed 2 weeks ago,
Balcour one week ago...
- Ordway, last night.
- He's getting up to speed.
I have the lab download
his licence photo.
2427...
119...
Numbers...
1 plus 1 plus 9. 2.
2 plus 4...
4 plus 2 plus 7...
5... Doesn't make sense.
Doesn't make sense.
Peter, 119...
119...
Peter 1:19...
My God! Peter 1:19...
Mathew 24:27...
Peter, Matthew, James,
All names of apostles.
Peter was a fisherman. Balcour
owned a fishing fleet.
Mathew was a tax collector.
Leesan worked for the I.R.S.
So the guy is some kind
of a zealot?
The numbers he carved on the victims
are chapters and verses of the Bible.
Peter, chapter 1, verse 19.
119.
"But with precious blood
as of a lamb...
...unblemished and
unspotted. Christ...
...a message was written
in lamb's blood. "
Matthew, 24:27.
"For as the lightning cometh out of the
east, and shineth even unto the west.
so shall also the coming
of the Son of man. "
All the victims were 33 years old.
The same age as Christ...
...when he died.
All three died a week
apart of each other...
...on a friday, the same
day as Christ died.
The guy is been building
the body of Christ.
You said he's actually
rebuilding a body?
Yes. He's killing a person a week
for the last 3 weeks.
He's half way through.
If he stays right on his friday schedule,
that all take 3 more weeks.
- What's 3 weeks from now?
- Eastern.
The resurrection.
Scolfield, you and Rousch
contact...
...every seminar, school
and church in the area.
Check on zealots,
disturbed personalities...
Anyone who might fill the profile.
Moles, check the mental institutions...
- ... see if they ever treated anyone that could be our boy.
- Got it.
The rest can check the crime scenes again.
Somebody had to see somethin'!
Care for a beer later?
I can't, I promised Sara
go to the market...
...so the house is stuffed
when Jenny comes in.
What's the story with this Jenny?
Is she cute?
I guess so.
You guess so? She's cute.
She's cute, right?.
OK, what's the problem?
You know I'm cute.
Can we make a little connection here?
You'll hooked us up?
I don't know... Last all I need is for her start
liking you and I've to see her longer.
No, no. That's good.
She likes me, she can stay with me.
It's all good. We all win.
Are you really that desperate?
Yeah. I'm really am.
Father Rousell dropped by
to see how you're doing.
- Good to see you, John?
- What brings you by, Father?
Well, it's been 6 months
since you've been to church.
I just want to see how you doing.
I'm fine.
Will you sit down.
I just get's some coffee.
I'm just fine.
You shouldn't turn your
back on your faith.
God loves you, John.
His love can help you heal.
Oh, I've seen how he loves me.
My son was in a coma
for 5 days.
You know how many times I prayed?
Where was God when
I needed him?
- I'm sorry.
- It's alright... It's alright.
What the hell where
you thinking, Sara?
I can't reach you anymore.
I'm right here.
I'm worried about you.
I'm worried about us.
What do you want from me?
I want you to talk to me.
Will you please just
talk to me!
It's been 1 year
since Michael died...
...and you have not visited
his grave since the funeral.
You don't understand.
You are not the only
one who lost a child!
I'm sorry...
I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean that.
- Morning, John.
- Good morning.
So he says: we finally get back
together and she got hit by a bus..
This isn't a joke?
No. My cousin's girlfriend
got hit by a bus last night.
I'm sorry. How is she doing?
She's got a broken leg.
- Smooth, John, smooth.
- I though it was a joke.
What so funny?
- You have to be there.
- What do you got?
Since your press conference last night
we received about 50 calls...
...we've got people accusing everyone
from their mother in law to the mayor.
Well the mayor might not
a bad lead.
I got someone in my office you
guys should talk to.
- Who is he?
- FBI profiler.
- C'mon, Jack...
- OK, he's trying to help.
- Alright? This guy solved a lot of cases.
- What is he gonna tell me?
I'm looking for a white male...
- ... 25 to 45 years old?
- Just talk to him!
Prudhomme, Hollinsworth,
agent Wingate.
Nice to meet you.
I understand you might
have something for us.
Well, I though maybe
I can help...
...although I never come
across a serial killer which moved...
...in such accelerated paced.
How do you know what pace
he's moving at?
Your captain let me
look through your files.
Did he?
Based on what I've seen so far, you look
for someone above average intelligence.
White male, 25 to 45 years old...
Something funny?
- No, no. Go on.
- I'm sorry.
He'll be middle class,
a loner, not married.
Those who know him will
find him aloof but cordial.
Although he prefers isolation,
he has the ability to navigate...
...in social settings when he has to.
He will have strong moral
and religious convictions.
Obviously his moral convictions
don't include murder.
He doesn't view what he's
doing as murder.
To him, he's making
sacrifices to God.
What point is there in keeping his
victim concious when he mutilates them?
Christ suffers on the cross.
He wants his victims to suffer.
But leaving clues behind
put him at risk.
He want us to know what he's doin'.
True. But there's more
to him than that.
If he merely wants you
to know what he's doing...
...there're more direct ways to inform you.
The clues he leaves give
him a sense of power.
And show he's in control.
Prudhomme, this fax just came in for you.
I think you should take a look at it.
You've heard the voice of the prophet
as he prepares the throne of grace...
...and you've twisted his message.
Those who died, do so
for the glory of God.
Spread the true gospel
before the end...
of the Boanerges, or you should
be judge by me.
What makes you think this is him?
Read the bottom.
So you do not doubt... Inside
the third one was the key to the mount.
May I? Third one?
Ordway.
Ordway, John...
Come in.
where's Ordway's body?
I just finished the autopsy.
I'm making out the report now...
...you can have it in... You can
have it by this afternoon.
- Anything unusual?
- No. Not really.
Except that all he's been
eating was olives.
The stomach was full of them.
- Mount of olives.
- It's him.
See ya.
This guy is fucking with us.
He likes you to know his word
so you can publicises his work.
He knows you know what
he's doin'
You failure to aknowledge him
just anger him.
So he's going to kill again tomorrow
and there's nothin' we can do to stop him.
Can you run a search through
your database...
...and see if you have anything
similar on file?
No problem. This my direct
line at the Bureau...
...and my cell phone number
will be at the back.
Call is it anything I can do.
Thank you.
They already got a name for him.
It sells papers.
What do you think makes
a man this crazy?
Who knows.
Problems goin' up,
pressures grew...
One day it start to slip
through the cracks.
And there's no one there
to catch you.
Happens every day.
I tell you one thing for sure,
I feeling a hell of a lot better...
knowing that he's drooling out
himself in a petty cell somewhere.
You're assuming we're
gonna catch him?
What the hell that
supossed to mean?
Assuming we're
gonna catch him?
It means that either we catching or
hell finished what his doin'...
...and dissapear like Jack,
the Ripper and the Zodiac Killer.
Or, come Eastern, he realizes all
he has is a rottin' corpse in his garage...
So he figure fucked up
this little respite...
...and start all over
again for next year.
I don't know if he really believes
he's creating the second coming.
I think is more simbolic.
He's sending a message.
- Yeah? To whom?
- To us. The world.
The guy is a fucking nutcase!
All this religious mambo jumbo
is bullshit!
You don't think the guy is at home
right now, reading this headlines...
...and jerking himself off?
He loves the attention...
He wants the attention!
I'm not doubting he's insane.
But don't discount his intelligence.
You think you just go out
and you find a 33 year old guy...
...named Peter. Who happens
to be a fisherman?
Or someone named Matthew
who is a tax collector?
Don't you see planning
that's got into this? The time.
Stop admiring him. He kills people.
Let's hear what you say of that.
I admire the intellect,
not the action.
Do you know how difficult
it is to get away with murder?
There're over a 50 ways
to fuck up a crime.
And if you can think of 20
of 'em you're a genius.
So far, this guy is adding
a thousand.
...just to find thy words...
... the faith of the son of God...
Spread the true gospel before
the end of the... Boanerges...
You shall be judge by him.
Boanerges...
From the greek, sons of thunder...
...an epitet used by Jesus.
Sons of thunder...
Seems to be 2 people or more.
Who is it?
John Prudhomme!
- John, is very latee.
- I'm sorry, father.
I need to talk to you,
is important.
- Come in.
- Thanks.
Is everything alright?
Yeah. I need some information
on the... Bonaerges.
- The what?
- The Boa-ner-ges.
Oh, is pronounced Boa-ner-ges.
Yeah, whatever. I... I know it
means sons of thunder.
Who's sons?
- Zebedee.
- Who is he?
He's only mention in the Bible
in relation to his sons.
- Yeah, where in the Bible?
- You should know this...
listen father, I don't have time
for a Bible class right now.
well, come with me.
Here it is...
Mark, 3:17.
James sons of Zebedee
and John, the brother of James...
...and he surname them the Boanerges...
Which is the sons of thunder.
John, the brother of James?
Yes.
Thank you, father.
Ordway has a brother.
His name is John.
He's going to be the fourth victim.
I need an address, fast. Thanks.
John Ordway, fotographer
has a work studio...
- at 1432, Baker Street.
- Home address?
The Baker's studio is
his home address.
Ok, I'm ten minutes away...
Call him and tell him to lock himself in.
And wait for me.
I'll meet you there.
I talked to him and told
him to lock himself in.
Call for backup and
check the perimeter.
Detective Hollinsworth requesting
backup at 1432, Baker Street.
Hang on! Hang on!
Oh God! Hang on!
Hang on!
Oh my God!
God!
I think he's still here...
He's here! He's here!
- Are you ok?
- He fucking got by me!
Where did he go?
Let's split out.
- I want a 10 blocks perimeter set.
- I'm on it.
Close the roof!
You two take the alley,
We'll take the street!
Freeze!
Put your hands on your head!
He's got a gun!
Drop the weapon!
Drop the weapon, now!
Put it down!
Drop it and put up
your hands rigth now!
Don't shoot!
No! No! No!
Shit!
The gun was taped to his fucking hand!
No!
Get an ambulance!
Take it easy!
God!
No! Oh, no!
I can't... I can't feel my leg.
- I can't feel my leg!
- Can't you give him something?
- I did. It doesn't seem to work!
- I cam see my leg!
- Can you see my leg?
- Hold on!
We'll be at the hospital
in few minutes.
Andy, 2 boys are sharing
in a hospital room...
...so, one boy ask the other
why did he stayed for...
...so the boy says: circumcision..
The other boy says: Oh man,
I'd that done right after I was born...
...and I couldn't walk for a year.
It was... It was the fucking worst
joke I'd ever heard, John.
I know.
- Hello, Jack.
- Sara.
- How is he?
- We don't know yet.
Bone is completely shattered.
We stopped the bleeding,
but we'll have to ampute it.
It has to be something
else you can do.
If it was, detective,
I'll be doing it.
- Hey.
- How you doin'?
- I'm okay.
They wanna take my leg.
I know.
Don't let 'em take my leg.
Please, don't let 'em take my leg.
John, please, don't let them
take my leg!.
I'm scared. I'm scared.
I'm... I'm scared!
What the hell is he doing?
It's a... An old cajun superstition.
When someone suffer,
you put a knife under the bed...
It cuts the pain in half.
What are you doing here?
I'm working.
John, go home. Get some rest.
I'm not tired.
In my office.
John, I want you to
take a few days off.
We can't waste anymore time.
That's really how you see it?
Isn't it?
If you not here, the rest of us it
just ploughing alone in the dark.
- I dind't...
- You seeing those guys up there?
Those are detectives.
They do the same
job as you.
I know that.
I also know we
had him last night.
He was standing in the
same room with me. And got away.
Don't take me out of this, Jack.
Alright.
Thanks.
What do you think he's gonna do?
I mean, you interrupted him last night.
He didn't get what he came for.
If he wants to stay
on schedule for Eastern...
He's gonna have to
make up for lost time.
So do you.
John.
- We just want you to know that...
- Thanks guys.
Thank you.
There's a Dr. Nestler
on line one for you.
- Hi, doctor.
- We've a problem over here...
...that I think you
should know about it.
I though the operation
went fine.
It did.
I... I don't understand.
One of our ordelies was
found out unconcious down there.
Someone beat the hell out of him.
- I'll send an officer over.
- The police are already here.
Detective...
The orderly was carrying
an appendage dowstairs.
Somebody stole your partner's leg.
Can I see him?
He's still pretty grounded.
Try not to be long.
Thanks.
I wanted to stop by
and see how you were doing.
You need anything?
Yeah. A leg.
You got one?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Hey, you know... When I was
coming out of the alley...
I was... I was...
I can hear you screaming.
I just... I never imagined that
you were screaming at me.
I must being pretty out of it,
from the stunt gun.
I just get...
I just get moving towards
the sound of your voices.
I loved being a cop.
Is all I ever wanted to be.
For as far back I can remember.
A cop.
Helping people.
Righting wrongs.
You know what I mean?
That's the finest thing you can be.
Oh man... Oh man...
What I'm gonna do now, John?
What I'm gonna do now?
You can go, you know?
You can go.
I just want to be left
alone. Alright?
Go on. Go!
- Wingate.
- John Prudhomme.
Thank you.
You let him get inside your
head. You can't do that.
How am I do not that?.
You divorce yourself from
your emotions.
What?
Turn it off like a light switch?
Right now, there is a cop...
a friend...
Who will never be the same
because of me.
You're doing exactly
what he wants you to do.
You're concentrating in your guilt.
I got my fucking partner
shot last night!
What the fuck at you
looking at?
How can I help you,
Prudhomme?
I assumed there are others
you can talk to...
- Or you just wanted to vent.
- Sorry.
I think last night was my best shot
at catching this guy and I fucked it up.
I don't know where
to go from here.
If you can't go fowards,
go backwards.
Back up. Who is he?
What do you know about him?
He wants to kill?
I mean, he's insane.
I've spent years studying
these guys. Divulging their excuses...
Fathers who beat them,
mothers who raped them...
Voices tell them what to do...
The bottom line is,
except for a very small percentage...
...they all know
they commited murder.
He thinks he's rebuilding the body
of Christ. If that is not insane!
His actions don't define
his state of mind.
Look at Dhammer,
Casey, Bundy...
They all commited horrible
acts. But they were sane.
The fact that he's careful
not to leave any evidence behind...
.. shows he's aware the're
consequences to his actions.
Look...
I don't care if he's sane or not...
I just wanna catch him.
You couldn't catch a cold,
the way your thinking.
Thanks.
Stop focusing on
his state of mind.
Look for the pattern.
Whatever he thinks he's doing...
...or creating that's what
drives him to murder.
What is doing it doesn't as
much important as why is doing it.
If you can figure that out
it lead you to him.
- You really should eat.
- No, thanks.
This came for you
while you were out.
How is Hollinsworth doing?
- You didn't see him?
- Yeah, I'm saw him.
- Anything else?
- Nothing.
The computer give us a couple of names
that could be our boy, but...
...they're all in prison
or in the loony bin.
It would appear that I
underestimated you.
Sometimes, I'm too clever
for my own good.
It won't happen again.
You must admit there's a strange
irony in the last night events.
In the end,
I got what I wanted.
John would be better,
but Andrew was an apostle also.
I was hoping not to
make this personal...
I warned you that
you would be judged
...if you did not tell the
world of my work.
Your lack of contrition...
...leave me no choice
but to punish you.
Your penitency shall be remorse.
Remorse for the dead
of your wife.
There's a unit in the area!
Send them over, now!
Get out of the way!
- Sir, you have to stop right there!
- I live here!
- Believe me, you don't wanna go inside!
- Let me go!
John...
I'm taking care of this now.
You don't need to see this.
No. No. No!
John, c'mon. C'mon!
You don't need to be here.
Step outside.
No! No!
C'mon, John.
Step outside!
John, don't touch anything.
This is a crime scene.
Jenny!
Jenny.
I'm pulling you off this.
It's gone too far.
He came to my house...
To kill my wife.
Wich is why you're
off this thing.
It's personal, now.
You can't do this.
It's done. I'm giving it
to Rousch and Scolfield.
I'm went out to get
something special for dinner.
Jenny was tired for the trip.
We don't have to talk
about it now.
Why would someone do
such a thing?
It was him.
The guy who is killing
all these people.
He was trying to hurt me.
By killing Jenny?
Oh, my God!
He was trying to kill me!
I though I'd lost you.
I want you to go stay with
your mother until this is over.
But, John...
Sara, please...
Good evening...
As it has been, our top story
tonight continues to be...
...the ongoing search
for a serial killer.
Chicago Police Department has
released part of a tape...
...sent to them by
the "Numbers Killer".
"It would appeared
I under estimated you...
Sometimes I'm too clever
for my own good...
It won't happened again".
Anyone who recognizes
this voice...
...is asked to contact the
Homicide Division...
...of the Chicago Police
Department.
In other news tonight,
Chicago City officials has released...
...last year crime statistics...
What's up?
A woman just called
from the Beaumont Hotel...
Says she recognizes the
voice in the tape.
I'm gonna want to take
a couple of guys with me.
Take whoever you need.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
Scolfield.
Prudhomme...
He said whoever I need.
- I'm looking for Dolores Koons.
- Well, take a seat...?
Chief... This ain't
an interview, buddy.
4- D.
Nice smell in here.
It's like a goddammed letrine.
- Miss Koons?
- Yeah.
I'm Detective Rousch.
You called us?
Yeah. I sure did.
I was watching the news this
morning then I heard the tape.
I mean, as soon as I heard it
I thought to myself that's Mr. Bresler...
You know his first name?
Fisrt name? No.
I just always called
him Mr. Bresler.
He seems like a
very nice guy.
But I bet a lot of those serial
killers are like that. Huh?
You sure is his voice?
Yeah, enough to call.
Where we can find him?
Down the hall. 4-G
If is him? Do I like gain
anything?
Appreciation from the people
of Chicago.
Mr. Bresler, is the police.
Could you open the door, please.
Mr. Bresler, we'd like to talk to
you. Please, can we come in?
We're here because someone
thinks you might sent us a tape.
A tape...
Mr. Bresler, I'm gonna
read you a couple of sentences...
I apreciate if you repeat 'em
back to me.
It would appeared that I
under estimated you.
Sometimes I'm too clever
for my own good.
It would appeared that I
under estimated you.
Sometimes I'm too clever
for my own good.
It won't happened again.
You must admit there's a strange
irony in the last night events.
But in the end, I got
what I wanted it.
John would been better, but
Andrew was an apostle also.
Should I do the rest?
- He's not the guy.
- What? Did you hear his voice?
He made the tape...
...but he's not the guy
we're looking for.
His blind.
Mr. Bresler,
did you make the tape?
- Yes.
- Why?
- Someone paid me 50 dollars.
- Who? Do you know him?
Some guy I met
in the park.
Said he was working in
some kind of movie...
He was looking
for interesting voices.
I knew that was a lot
of bullshit...
But 50 bucks is 50 bucks.
Thanks.
He's smart. He talked to us
without using his voice...
The guy who made the tape
can't identify him.
I'm getting the feeling we
never gonna catch this guy.
They just found number 5.
- Hey, John?
- Yeah.
You got change for a dollar?
Come with me.
What are we looking for?
Peter Balcour had five
quarters in his pockets...
So did Leesan.
What about the others?
- James Ordway too.
- John Ordway also.
So did Wells. Five victims.
All with five quarters in their pockets.
No way that's a coincidence.
Wait...
To finish what he's doing
he needs six bodies.
Six bodies with five quarters
each is thirty quarters.
Thirty pieces of silver!
He thinks he's Judas?
No. He's letting un know
why he's doing this.
- He's atoning.
- John?
- Take a look at this.
- What is it?
Homicide report from Tennessee.
Two and a half years ago, a police
incursion found a 33 years old male...
...with his head cut off.
Victim's name was Phillip Weir.
- He was an apostle.
- Yeah.
How did you get this?
- FBI computer spilled it out.
- Just now?
What do you mean just now?
We call over Quantico
about three days ago.
But I asked Wingate
three weeks ago!
I'm detective Prudhomme.
I wanna see agent Wingate.
Agent Wingate is in
a meeting right now.
I don't care what he's doing.
I wanna see him now!
I think you better
get out here.
Hava a seat, please.
No, thank you.
I don't wanna sit down.
I wanna see Wingate.
Is there a problem here?
What the fuck?
Yes there is a problem!
I wanna see agent Wingate!
I'm agent Wingate.
Didn't anybody check his I.D.?
Yes sir, they said
they saw it.
But look at to him...
Somebody this clever wouldn't
have any problem getting a card.
A badge you can find anywhere.
What about the office
number they gave us?
It was a message center,
rented by mail with a money order.
- Cell phone number?
- Clone..
If we get a print and it's
on file, we'll id him.
We still have on thing
on our side.
He doesn't know we know it.
- Wingate.
- Prudhomme.
- How is it going?
- Good.
We may have find a few things
that might put us a little closer.
What things?
I want to run them by
you here, sometime.
- I'm kind of busy today...
- It only take about half hour.
I'll meet you in two hours
over that pizza place.
- Great, I apreciate it.
- no problem.
We got him.
- Are you guys ready?
- Ten-Four.
- Moltz?
- Roger.
He's here.
He's crossing the street.
Dark blue suit.
Got him.
- Take him!
- Freeze!
Put your hands over
your head. Now!
Put your hands on top
of your head!
Get down! Down!
Get on your fucking
knees, now!
Get on your knees. Now!
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be use
against you in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you can't afford one
it would be too fucking bad.
Let's get this prick
into the fucking car.
It just a matter of time that your
prints tell us who you are.
Only if I have a
criminal record in Illinois...
Which I do not.
I'd like to know
why I'm here.
Because you murdered five people.
Really?
What, may I ask, is the evidence you
using to support this claim?
Do you have any prints?
Any trace evidence? Physical evidence?
Witnesses? Motive?
Anything?
One thing that connects
me with these crimes?
You don't have to answer.
I already know. I've seen the files.
You think you really
clever, don't you?
Let's talk about the
clocksteel murder.
I'm afraid I don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh yes, you do.
You where there.
What was it a practice one?
Do you really think you're
doing God's work?
If God were to call
upon someone...
You really think he'd choose a
pathetic little whined like you?
Detective Prudhomme, I do believe
you're trying to provoke me.
- Listen to me...
- No! You listen to me.
I'm talking with you because it gives me
something to do before my attorney arrives.
The truth is I'll be out
of here in 48 hours.
You know it
and I know it...
Of course, you and your
partner will follow me...
Oh, I'm sorry. I forgot!
Your partner can't walk anymore...
- Since his leg was blown off.
- Shut up!
I'd imagine you carry a tremendous
amount of guilt for that.
Shut your mouth!
He trusted you, but when he
run towards you for safety...
Prudhomme, outside.
Now!
I enjoyed our little
chat, detective. I truly did.
He's a cocky little prick,
isn't he?
He knows we've nothing.
He also knows the law.
If we don't get something in 48 hours,
we got to cut him loose.
I'm sorry about last week.
It wasn't your fault.
You know that.
It's okay.
They said you got him.
Who is he?
We don't know. We plastered
his face all over the news.
Hundreds of people are calling.
We feed the names
into the computer and a...
...wait for a print match.
- But it's him?
- It's him.
You cant let this
fucker walk, John.
I won't.
Not guilty.
Bail?
Your honor, the State is
requesting the bail be denied.
On what grounds?
We do not know the
defender's true identity...
...therefore we cannot determine
his ties to the community.
We feel that the risk of
flight is great.
The fact that the police
cannot prove nor disprove...
...my client's identity is not
grounds to deny bail.
The truth is Mr. Wingate
has been held for nearly two days...
...on a probable cause
on another matter.
Is this true, Mr. Galloway?
Yes, your honor... he is
considered the prime suspect...
...in regards to recent murders.
I see no murder
charges before me...
...the only charge I see is
impersonating a federal officer.
Bail is set at twenty
thousand dollars.
We'll have a ten minutes recess.
Gentleman, will you aproach the bench, please.
Mr. Galloway, what exactly do you
think you're doing out there?
Just stop a murder for
going free.
Therer are procedures for that.
As a distric attorney, I should not
have to tell you this.
I will not have this
courtroom used...
...for your own personal
agenda, Mr. Galloway.
Judge, my client is
ready to post bail...
I like to request his
inmediate release.
I'm still have six hours
left to hold him.
And I'm intent to use them.
Six hours, Mr. Galloway...
You are to file murder charges
or you'll release him.
Janice, what the...
I sent photos of a man!
Sex change operation.
Ok, thank you very much.
When was the last
time you saw him?
- 40 years ago!
- I'll check on it. Thanks.
- The killings in Tennessee?
- Ask him how far is from Clarksdale.
Ma'am, how far are you
for Clarksdale?
- 20 miles.
- Ma'am I need you to...
Gerald Demus.
Pass it through...
FBI, Tenesse Police
and the DMV.
No, thank you.
I'll be going out for lunch today.
I just got out the phone
with the Social Service Department...
They have no record of
a Gerald Demus.
You try the neighbors in town?
We're on it now.
I'm here for Greg Wingate.
- Yeah?
- Delwey's here to pick up Wingate.
- What? Stall him!
- How?
I don't know!
Think on something.
We're having troubles
finding the paperwork.
- City Court.
- Judge Seers, please.
Prudhomme, what the
hell do you think you're doin'?
Wingate was supposed to
be released 15 minutes ago.
Re-cause him.
You got something you
can give right now?
- No.
- Then kick him loose.
I need a little more time.
We think we know who he is.
And if he is...
He lives 20 miles for
an identical murder 2 years ago!
We don't have any
more time.
I just got a
call from Judge Seers.
She issued the riff
for his inmediate release.
Thanks a lot.
You're out of here.
I want you on him
the minute he walks out the door.
If he takes a shit, I wanna know
how many times he wipe his ass.
- Sign here.
- Here?
Thanks.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Taxi.
He is in Sixth and Blanche.
He heads for the
train station.
Go.
Sheriff in Tennessee
says he arrested...
...Gerald Demus 5 years ago
for attacking a town minister.
- Prints are on their way over.
- Get that out.
- You think he's leaving?
- No.
He's not finished yet.
Yeah. Prints are in. Lab's working
on them now.
Can't you do this faster?
Yes. We got a match.
Take him.
Demus? This is the police.
Stand up and
open the door slowly.
Dot it now!
Shit!
Fuck!
What? Everyone moving.
I want this place closed down. Now!
- Seal the door.
- Got it.
Hold it, please. No one must
leave. This is a police emergency.
Shit!
Hey! Sorry.
Hey! Hey you!
Hey you, stop!
Get down! Get down!
Get down!
Get out of my way!
Freeze!
Demus!
Motherfucker!
Freeze!
Get out of the way!
I losted him.
Shit!
5 years ago, Demus attacks
the local minister in Windsfield.
The minister refuses to
press charges...
So they kick him loose.
But he's still arrested.
What else were his prints
in the system?
Woodsville is a small department.
They only came online with
the Tenesse database 3 years ago.
Even then, they only have
recent arrest into the system.
Hundreds of millions
of dollars in computers...
...and we id the guy
because some old lady...
...in Willingstone, Tenesse,
watched him on TV?
Incredible!
Two and a half years later,
Demus kills Phillip Weir.
Why'd he stopped?
Because 2 weeks after the murder
he was picked up in Tulsa.
Wandering the streets.
Talking to the pidgeons.
He spent the next 2 years
in the state mental hospital.
They just released him
6 months ago.
Why he didn't stay in Tulsa?
The media wants to
pass the status, ok?
Scolfield...
Wellcome.
Thomas Heckert, 33.
That's the boyfriend, works the
graveyard in the Memorial Medical Center.
Found him this morning
when he came from work.
- How long he's been dead?
- A few hours.
He took the torso.
Left the legs, the arms and the head.
You think this is
the end of it?
I hope so.
This thing have to happen.
All you had to do was
hold him a little longer.
Don't lay this at my door!
This man is still be alive
if your guys didn't loose him!
- Yeah, right.
- Fuck off!
You've seen this?
They running a pictorial
of the crime scenes.
Jesus! Next thing, they'll
be giving tours.
This isn't right.
- What isn't right?
- This photo.
When we sealed the crime scene,
all the windows and shutters were closed.
Look at the upstairs window.
It's open.
Where's the best place to hide?
Somewhere we already looked.
Go upstairs.
Go, go! Move.
Move! Go!
Clear!
Sweet mother of God!
Prudhomme?
You better get in here.
Shit!
Prudhomme,
check this out upstairs.
Behold the glory of God!
Sinners, take it!
Soon, the hand of judgement
shall be upon ye.
Motherfucker...
Alright. We leave a team here
in case he comes back.
He'll be back...
Twelve apostles
should be dead...
Look at the spreaders,
he used 'em to open the chest.
Don't even tell me that.
Yes. He's going after a heart.
Tomorrow is Easter...
We need to search every hospital...
We looking for a woman who gives
birth to his son after midnight.
- You know how many hospitals...
- Her name would be Mary.
I got a Mary at St. Paul.
She's in labor now.
Girl or boy?
I don't know. The parents didn't
want to know the results of the ultrasound.
You and Scolfield go
to see that one.
Thanks.
- I got it!
- What?
Oak Park Memorial
has Mary Dominguez...
- She just gave birth to a boy.
- Let's go!
God!
Hold it! C'mon!
- You're okay?
- Shit! Yeah. Go, go!
- Call for backup!
- Go, go, go!
It's over.
Give me the baby.
No! No!
It's called instinct.
For him to cry, isn't it?
Put down the gun.
Put it down!
Okay.
I'd imagine this is a painful situation,
you'd already loose one child.
It's over. We've been inside
the house and dump the body.
Sacrilege! It's a sacrilege!
You're nothing now.
Nothing but another lunatic.
One year form now, no one
will even remembered you name.
- If I'll drop this child they will.
- No!
It's my last offer.
No! No!
It's time for us to die.
Motherfucker!
- Here you are Mr. Prudhomme.
- Thank you.
- Are you alright?
- Yes
John, the baby's parents
would like to thank you.
- Thank you for the life of my son.
- I'm glad he's alright.
Please, take this.
Thank you.
I spoke to the doctor...
You're gonna be out of
the field for at least 3 months.
Its not important.
I need some time...
I need to pick up some
of the pieces in my life.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Hey man, come on in.
This is time for a test drive.
- You look good, Andy.
- You're mad? I'm terrible.
I met a guy who runs the Boston
marathon with one of this things.
When are you
coming back to work?
I'm coming back. Don't get
me worng, John. I'm comin' back.
I'm comin' back but no sit
around one damm desk, either.
Guys skiing with this things,
you know?
Fuck.
- Let me help.
- I'm ok, John.
Listen, seriously...
If this is gonna work for real,
you gotta gimme a chance, alright?
You gotta gimme
a chance to come back.
I'll be good as new.
But you gotta gimme a chance.
You may have to pickup
a fair share at the legwork.
But I will be back.
Whatever you say, partner.