In cooperation with
The Ring 2 Production Group
Asmik-Ace Entertainment
and OZ Production
Executive Producer
Masato Hara
Producers
Takashige Ichise, Makoto Ishihara
- The corpse found in the well...
- Yes, sir.
Mr Yamamura.
No, it's not necessary.
I haven't seen her
since she was a child, anyway.
The well was on the estate of
Dr Heihachiro lkuma.
The place was sold 30 years ago.
Since then no one
has opened the well.
It has been sealed.
Then there's no doubt.
It's Sadako.
But...
No 'Sadako' is registered in either
Dr lkuma's or her mother's records.
What's happened to Dr lkuma?
He died, soon after
the place was sold.
So I'm the only one left alive.
Please cremate her immediately.
It doesn't matter
which family she belongs to.
I'm afraid we can't do that.
This is a very strange case.
One of the people who found
her body is dead.
The other one is missing.
There's something else.
The estimated time of her death...
According to the autopsy,
she died only one or two years ago.
What?
It means she was alive.
In the well, all that time,
for 30 years.
RING 2
Starring
Miki Nakatani
Hitomi Sato
Kyoko Fukada
Nanako Matsushima
Hiroyuki Sanada
Based on the novel by
Kouji Suzuki
Screenplay
Hiroshi Takahashi
Directed by
Hideo Nakata
There's a story going around
about a cursed video.
What kind of video it is?
The version I've heard is,
a scary woman appears,
saying, "You'll die in one week."
That's what I've heard.
It interrupts late-night TV.
Then there's a telephone call.
The late-night programme
on which channel?
What I've heard is
some local channel in Izu.
- In Izu?
- Yes.
Is it really a good idea
to use this stuff?
Why not?
You'll die unless you make a copy
and show it to others...
Yes.
I have to confirm that story
with someone.
Have you heard from Ms Asakawa?
No.
The police called about her, too.
Yeah?
Excuse me...
Can I see Ms Reiko Asakawa?
Well...
She's not in at the moment.
There's a story going around
about a cursed video.
What kind of video it is?
The version I've heard is,
a scary woman appears,
saying 'You'll die in one week. "
That's what I've heard.
It interrupts late-night TV.
Wait!
Do you know anything about Asakawa?
We haven't been able to contact her.
A man named Ryuji T akayama is dead.
T akayama?
Ms Asakawa's ex.
The police came once.
She's been away for a while.
Did they go inside?
No, not at the time.
Go ahead.
Ms Takano.
What is this?
A video tape?
Dad,
forgive me.
This is to save Yoichi...
Are you OK?
Last time I saw her,
Ms Asakawa asked me about the video.
It was a human interest story.
They don't give a single mother
important reports.
Oh, yes, her boy.
I'll go ask the school.
Ms Asakawa?
She's not in.
This is the police.
Reiko Asakawa's father was
found dead this morning.
- Mr Kadokura?
- This way.
- Sir.
- Yes?
- I'm Omuta, from Shizuoka police.
- Thanks for coming.
Any luck finding the daughter?
None at all.
How about the body found in the well?
- We're rebuilding her face.
- Rebuild...
As soon as we have her model,
we'll take it
and ask around the area.
He found the body first.
Do you want to see it?
People don't normally die like this.
Was he making a copy?
Well...
We wonder if it has anything to do
with this note.
DEAR RElKO,
I GOT RlD OF THE VlDEO.
THERE lS NOTHlNG
TO WORRY ABOUT.
No good.
He's been absent
for more than 10 days.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Why are you looking for Ms Asakawa?
I want to know what happened
to Dr Takayama.
I'll check a bit more.
If I find anything, I'll call you.
See you.
Yes?
Police. Sorry for calling so late.
I'd like to ask
about Mr Ryuji Takayama.
Are you Mai T akano,
who found his body?
Yes.
May l...
Please.
Oh, I remember Mr T akayama.
He taught maths.
Are you...
I'm his assistant.
I see.
Ms Takano,
have you ever heard of
Sadako Yamamura?
No.
Shizuko Yamamura? Sadako's mother?
Heihachiro lkuma?
No.
Ryuji Takayama and Reiko Asakawa
were investigating something.
Is that right?
I don't know.
I see.
Today,
Reiko Asakawa's father
was found dead.
He died the same way
as Mr Takayama.
You know what I mean?
Please go.
They found the body in the well.
An unidentified woman, who died
one or two years ago.
But the well has been sealed
with concrete
for 30 years.
Can you believe it?
In the dark well, for 30 years.
Neither of her hands had nails.
They were all found in
the sides of the well.
Probably, she tried to climb out
so many times...
Please go!
Alright.
If you find out anything about
Reiko Asakawa,
call me at this number.
I'm sorry,
but this is such a strange case.
What's it all about, the video?
I don't know.
No...
Do you live around here?
I can concentrate better here
than in my room.
I see.
OK, it's rolling.
Let's continue.
Three seconds...
So, you have to copy it
and show it to someone else
within a week.
Otherwise, a week later,
at the same time...
So there's an original video
to make a copy from?
Yes.
Where does it come from?
I've heard that it's just there
in the room.
Everybody has some videos
they can't remember recording.
Among those tapes,
they find a strange one.
- How would you know that's the one?
- It's obvious if you see it.
- Has anyone seen it?
- I know someone who has it.
They're scared,
so show it to each other.
It's going around among friends.
Have you seen it?
Is it possible to get me a copy?
OK.
Excuse me.
Work out a price.
Probably, Ms Asakawa was
after these four.
A week after this date,
all of them died at the same time.
Hard to believe, isn't it?
This girl, Tomoko,
she was Ms Asakawa's niece.
A girl was with her
when she died.
Kurahashi...
Masami Kurahashi.
What happened to her?
She's in the hospital.
She can't speak.
The hospital belongs
to your university.
The doctor can't tell you anything
about patients' privacy.
The questions should be
on the area of his research.
Fine.
This way, please.
Ms Kurahashi!
How are you feeling?
Would you like to come out
to the balcony for a change?
Doctor wants you to
get some fresh air.
Are you still afraid of TV?
It's fine.
I'll bring a screen
so that you won't see it.
OK?
Doctor,
they're here.
Hello.
I'm Kawajiri.
Please.
Our medical files are
different from others,
because we attach photos.
Do you know why?
In case they run away?
That's right.
Illness can change the patient, even
their family can't recognise them.
So we always take photos
when they arrive.
But when we took photos
of this patient...
..with our usual camera here...
..a strange image came up.
It's called 'spirit photography'.
Something in a person's mind affects
the light and exposure.
There were similar cases in the past.
You mean, this photo was...
We also tried just
having her hold a film.
This shows a character clearly.
SADA
You may think I'm a strange doctor.
All of my colleagues do.
Do you know Ryuji Takayama?
That's odd.
He's the only one
who listened to me.
He was once in medical school,
before he went in for maths.
You know he died?
What a shame.
You didn't even come to his funeral.
OK? This way,
you don't have to see it.
No need to rush.
Nice and slow.
Take your time...
What's wrong?
Are you feeling bad?
Ms Kurahashi...
Take her to the treatment room.
Tomoko...
Help...
Help me...
Help her to get up!
Are you OK?
Help me!
They said it was the first time
she's spoken.
Are you going to continue
Ms Asakawa's report?
Yes.
You'd better stop.
Why?
Just stop it.
Did the patient tell you something?
Wait.
Excuse me.
You'd better not
tell anybody about it.
Such power you've got...
..it's no use to anyone.
Yoichi!
Are you Yoichi?
Where do you live?
You can't talk...
Go in there.
It's bare, isn't it?
Please.
I WANT TO GO TO SCHOOL.
I'M HUNGRY.
WHERE WERE YOU?
So, you need to talk?
Do you remember a girl called Masami?
She was with Tomoko when she died.
Yes.
When she went near the TV
in the hospital...
..a strange image came on.
What was it?
A well.
Only for an instant, though.
Was that all?
Yes.
You've seen it, haven't you?
It's fine,
if that's all you've watched.
But don't watch it again.
Masami...
She couldn't speak either.
What are you trying to say?
If Yoichi goes on like this...
What can we do, then?
Lock him up in the hospital?
It's none of your business.
I'm sorry.
Please go.
Can I come back again sometime
to see Yoichi?
...they can't remember recording.
Among those tapes,
they find a strange one.
How would you know...
Oh, hi.
This...
Oh...
So you got it.
20,000 yen, was it?
I...
..I watched it last night.
What?
Mr Okazaki...
you'll watch it, won't you?
Of course I will.
There's no point if I don't.
Will you promise?
Of course I will.
Trust me.
Hey,
the money.
Please keep the promise.
Nice catch.
Here it comes.
Here...
Oh...
you're learning that already.
Hey,
why were you
at the station the other day?
Was your mum angry?
Is anyone?
THE WOMAN WlTH LONG HAlR.
Dinner's ready.
Go and wash your hands.
I thought he won't speak
because he's blaming me.
Deep down in his mind.
That's not true.
When we came back
from my dad's,
the TV switched on automatically,
as Yoichi went near.
Could you talk to Dr Kawajiri
about it?
If Yoichi is...
really...
You've met Reiko Asakawa.
I didn't call him.
Okazaki, the assistant director,
told me about the patient.
He should be here any minute.
So...
We're going to try an experiment.
It may help the boy as well.
Come in.
This way.
What are you trying to do?
It's normal tap water.
The paper absorbs...
..well, about that much.
Do the same as before.
Concentrate on the water.
That's enough.
The water's changed.
Some kind of energy was transferred
from her to the water.
It also explains the film exposure.
It's all about energy transfer.
Eventually all the energy should be
transferred from her.
The experiment is to prove it.
Please.
- Are you trying to video it?
- Yes. You've seen it, right?
Don't do that!
- That image of a well...
- A well?
Everyone who sees it dies!
But you look perfectly fine.
Get ready.
Oh, Okazaki!
This is a brand new tape.
Could you set it up for me?
Masami...
this experiment is dangerous.
If people see it...
There's something in my head...
Set the tape, quick!
Even if there is such a video,
videos don't kill people.
Fear kills.
If I can prove this,
we can eliminate the energy of fear.
Free the fear.
Go out if you don't want to watch.
No.
Let's start.
Do the same as
with the photo film.
Relax and look at the camera.
What's that noise?
That woman...
Doctor!
Ms Furuhashi!
What are you doing?
There were a lot of calls.
"It's a week today", or something.
That girl with the video, isn't it?
I'll call her.
- Goodnight.
- See you.
Hello, this is Kawaguchi.
Hello, Kanae?
Yes.
It's Okazaki.
I watched the video.
Oh, I'm relieved.
I've been worrying.
You don't trust me.
Because it's almost the time.
Listen...
you know, that strange woman.
You mean, the one in the mirror?
Hello?
Um? Yes, that one.
Didn't it look like it changed to
a child for a second?
And the well at the end...
Where's the video now?
I threw it away.
Because it's really...
No one should watch it anymore.
But you can't stop it.
You'll show it to someone, won't you?
Mr Okazaki...
you have to show it.
I don't want you to die, Mr Okazaki.
I know.
- See you then...
- Yeah.
The woman in the mirror.
REPORTER DlES WlTNESSlNG
PSYCHlC TEST.
It's the public demonstration
by Dr Heihachiro lkuma.
He was fired
because of the demonstration.
THE FATAL EXPERlMENT
MS SHlZUKO YAMAMURA, RlGHT,
AND DR lKUMA
Shizuko...
Can you just will someone dead?
Dr lkuma talked about
intention as a living thing.
The energy of thought itself
can become substantial.
For example, to be on the video.
30 years in the well...
The concentrated thoughts
of 30 years.
Her fury.
We've all seen it.
Did they die just by watching
the video?
Takayama,
the father of Asakawa.
Why she involved her father...
The kid must have seen it.
Asakawa's kid.
He's probably
in the same condition as my patient.
In that case, we can't leave him.
Where is Asakawa?
Tell me!
Hello.
Sanae!
Come with me.
Please.
This is just a routine interview,
so please relax.
Oh, wait a moment.
Don't come.
Don't come. Run away!
Can't you hear me?
Go, run away!
What is it?
Mum!
Yoichi!
A monster.
A monster!
Murderer!
Monster!
Yoichi!
Dad?
Dad!
Didn't we save Yoichi?
The boy you're holding
is not Yoichi anymore.
Yoichi...
No...
Stop it!
Don't!
OK.
Why can't I erase it?
Where did that story come from?
When people worry,
rumours start flying.
In other words,
people hope things
will turn out like that.
Sir!
What's the matter?
Let's go.
Do you see any resemblance to her?
It looks like her.
Just as eerie.
We'll take some photos.
That's enough.
Sadako.
Why do you keep me alive?
I made you and
your mother into a freak show.
It was me.
Do you want me to return you
to the sea?
Is that what you want?
Do you know the Yamamura house?
There are a lot of Yamamuras.
The one where a woman named Shizuko
used to live.
Oh, that one.
THE YAMAMURA lNN
Hello.
This way, please.
Sorry. Did I wake you?
No.
Well...
Can you promise me something?
What?
No matter who comes to you,
don't do such a thing again.
That's terrible.
Are you on my side?
Yes, I am. Of course.
OK.
If you're looking for Sadako,
I've put her in the sea.
That was all I could do for her.
Come to think of it,
Shizuko used to say the same thing.
She went off to give birth to Sadako,
all on her own.
She came back after the birth,
saying she'd put the baby
away in the sea.
But the next day,
she had a baby in her arms.
That noise...
That's where Sadako was born.
This is called the Children's Limbo.
When the water is high,
it washes away all the unwanted.
Was Sadako's father...
Hello!
Yes?
Is Mai Takano staying here?
No.
At least you have a room, right?
Wait...
Sadako...
You are already dead.
Oh, I'm so relieved.
Do you remember
your dream last night?
In that case...
think about your mother.
That's good.
Can I have a word?
He is controlled by
anger.
His anger summons Sadako.
He can't control it.
My equipment should arrive today.
I'll try to eliminate
Sadako's energy.
"There's no such thing"
as ghosts or the other world.'
Takayama always criticised me.
But Yoichi isn't strong enough to...
What choice have we?
What happens if the police come?
He channels the energy.
A perfect medium.
I'll do it.
Do you have the same power
as Takayama?
Yes.
It doesn't mean you'll do better
as a medium than the boy.
What if I watch the video...
OK.
- Then all we need is water.
- Water?
Sea water doesn't permeate as well.
We need a lot of fresh water
to absorb Sadako's fury.
With this system,
you conduct the energy he generates
into water, where it dissolves.
Then Sadako will disappear.
- OK. Are we ready?
- Yes.
Take your place.
Come.
Remember, I'm on your side.
OK?
Let's start.
Close your eyes.
Remember what you saw.
What did you see?
Yes.
Both your father and mother died.
You are all on your own.
What did you see?
Shall I tell you?
Your mother died because of her.
She betrayed her.
Yes,
it was my fault.
It looks good.
Keep it up.
Dr Kawajiri, this is...
..it is connected
to the other world...
Sadako...
Take me...
..and kill me.
..and put an end to all this.
Are you OK?
Don't let go.
Let me fall, and you'll be safe.
"Frolic in brine, goblins be thine"
Hold on to the wall.
I can't support you by myself.
Mai...
It's enough, it's over.
Yoichi!
Yoichi?
Take him.
Sir...
Yoichi...
Give your fear to me.
Give it to me.
Give it to me!
Get away!
Take the rope.
Don't look back.
Help... help...
Help...
Why are you the only one saved?
You're not still scared, are you?
No. You?
Me?
I'm still scared, a bit.
So how's Okazaki?
Needs to be in hospital for a while.
Hospital?
Where's the key for this?
Key?
Is it this one?
Mr Okazaki,
I need to take photos for your file.
Look this way.
Mr Okazaki...
face this way.
Here you go.
Thank you.
CAST
Miki Nakatani
Hitomi Sato
Kyoko Fukada
Nanako Matsushima
Hiroyuki Sanada
Directed by
Hideo Nakata