In the Steven Spielberg movie "E.T.",
why's the alien brown?
No reason.
In "Love Story",
why did the two characters
fall madly in love with each other?
No reason.
In Oliver Stone's "JFK",
Why's the President suddenly
assassinated by some stranger?
No reason.
In the excellent "Chainsaw Massacre"
by Tobe Hooper,
why don't we ever see the characters
go to the bathroom...
or wash their hands,
like people doing in real life?
Absolutely no reason.
Worse, in "The Pianist" by Polanski,
how come this guy has to hide
and live like a bomb...
when he plays the piano so well?
Once again the answer is "no reason".
I could go on for hours
with more examples.
The list is endless.
You probably never gave it a thought.
But all great films,
without exception,
contain an important element--
a "no reason".
And you know why?
Because life itself...
is filled with "no reason".
Why can't we see the air all around us?
No reason.
Why're we always thinking?
Why do some people love sausages
and other people hate sausages?
No fuckin' reason.
Come on, don't waste your time
explaining that garbage. Let's go!
Just one minute. Let me finish.
Ladies, gentlemen,
the film you're about to see today
is an homage to the "no reason"--
that most powerful element...of style.
Why did they destroy all those chairs.
- Too sad on those.
- Yeah, it's really a pity.
Quiet, please.
Everybody turn around.
Good. Enjoy.
Excuse me, is it going to be in color
or black and white?
It's already boring.
Don't be so negative.
It's just the beginning.
It's going to pick up. Just be patient.
I hope that's not an old silent film.
I can't hear thing.
Yes, you can hear the wind a little.
If You listen.
Somebody see something?
I see a dump, there, straight ahead.
RUBBER
Amazing. He just blew up a bottle
without even touching it.
Really? Let me see.
That's odd.
It looks like he has telepathic power.
You mean Psychokinetic?
I don't care about the right word.
Has it just blown up
the bottle with its mind?
It is most likely. Yes.
That's awesome. I'm starting to like it.
I think the kid is right.
Psychokinetic powers.
Excuse me, but do you have to
comment everything aloud?
We are not commenting,
we are only trying to understand.
- What do you think of it?
- Nothing.
You know you're not allowed to film
the film. That is forbidden by law.
It is?
Yeah, they'll put you in jail for that.
Jail?
That's kidding me?
Yes, she's right, it is piracy.
I'll be careful if I were you.
My wife could not come.
I just wanna show her.
This's piracy anyway.
Thanks for that. I won't in the future.
Come on!
Starting again!
Wake up!
Let's go!
Jesus, I almost slept awake.
Fuckin' insects!
I was really cold myself.
Quiet!
Wake up!
Excuse me. Would it be possible
to have some coffee and toast?
Dad, I'm hungry.
Dad?
Where is he?
Straight ahead.
He just woke up.
Oh, thanks.
Anyone got any food?
Oh my god!
Not bad at all.
Well, let me see.
It is the first time in my life
I identify with a tire.
Stop that. Give me that!
Her ass is not that great,
but I understand.
You're hard to pleased.
It is fine with me.
Her ass isn't that great
but she has quite a wag on it.
You think the tire is gonna get laid?
I would like to see it!
What position do you think?
I think she'll start with
a good blowjob.
Oh yeah...
Jesus, you think you're
gonna shut up some time
and let's watch in
peace? I can't stand it.
Come on. Can't you take a little joke?
Yes, there is plenty of space. Go
somewhere else if we're bothering you.
You should be the ones to move if you
have to laugh so loud, don't you think?
No. Why don't you just do like that
cripple, and plug on your walkman
and listen to your music and
then no one bother you any more.
It's not a walkman
It's a medical gismo.
Come on, let's just forget it.
Brats.
Hi, brats.
Mom, it's me. I'm gonna spend the night
in a motel. I don't wanna try anymore.
See you tomorrow. I love you. Bye.
Anything interesting?
He just switched the channel.
Okay. Well...
wake us if we miss anything major.
Good night, everybody.
How long before humans start to
eat each other out of hunger?
Don't talk crap. Just sleep.
Are you rustlers?
You're gonna let us starve
without doing a thing?
I found the blown-off rabbit.
You are really so cruel!
- I think it's okay to eat, right?
- Idiot!
Can't you see it's fake?
Yes, master.
Very well, master.
Certainly.
I understand perfectly.
I am gonna do it
tomorrow morning without fail.
Yeah. First thing in the morning.
You can count on me.
Salutations, master.
Morning.
- Can I clean your room?
- Yeah.
Why not?
Food!
Animals.
Anybody there?
Excuse me,
you want me to come back later?
Fucking weirdoes!
I just saw a live tire.
You get nothing better to do than
come here to start talking rubbish?
I swear... it's true.
Look. He locked himself in room 16.
Did you get homework to do or something?
I am on holidays.
And you don't know what
to do with yourself.
Well you're bugging me.
You don't believe me.
You shut up!
Look, here.
Get on your bike,
and go get me a pizza, alright?
I give you ten minutes to kill.
You go have a look
in room 16 now. Please!
Would you get on your bike
and get  me a pizza?
Cut this bullshit out?
Do it!
And don't forget the double toppings!
Here's your double topping, dickhead.
And the tire's supposed to float?
An inner tube, yes. Not a tire.
Really? I'd rather bet
just the opposite.
Feeling any better, son?
It's burning hard.
Daddy, I beg you call a doctor.
Come on. Probably just ate too fast.
It's gonna be alright. Don't worry.
We all ate too fast.
It's hurting bad, I told you!
Does anybody know anything
about medicine?
No, sorry.
Well, do you happen to
know anything about physics?
Would a tire sink or float?
It would sink.
We just saw it a minute ago.
What is going on?
Oh, damnit! It's a hell.
Oh, help me!
What's happening to us?
We're poisoned.
The turkey was a trap.
A trap?
Oh! Is this how they
they treat the audience?
Don't worry ma'am.
They're not gonna get away with this.
I am still here.
And I want my show.
Sure I want my show.
Anybody there?
Tire?
...the pool there.
It is right here.
This tire is alive.
The tire story again?
It doesn't look very alive to me.
I saw the tire get into room 16.
He locked himself in.
You know what, I've heard
enough rubbish for the day.
Now get the dirty tire out of the pool,
or I'm gonna get really mad!
- Sorry, lieutenant.
- Nothing.
But tell me...
Don't you find it strange
we can't see the air around us?
Why do you say that?
Just like that.
No reason.
Okay, kid, listen to me.
Nothing to worry about.
It's a perfectly ordinary tire.
Yeah, same here.
You see it's not moving.
- Well, maybe it drowned.
- Would you stop with this crap, okay?
You're putting me ashamed in front of
- a police officer.
- Don't be rough.
- There is no need to do that.
- You know, someone died here, okay?
We don't joke about things like that.
Do you understand?
Yeah, that is true.
I'm not joking. I am sure
that this tire killed Martina.
Oh, that is enough! Alright?
I don't want to see you anymore. Okay?
We will settle this tonight. Now squirm!
You're getting on my nerves, go!
You're a little jumpy.
Not usually.
And take your fucking tire, would you?!
Sorry.
Mr. Hugues, can I ask you some
questions for the investigation?
Sure, go ahead.
How was your relationship with Martina?
We got along fine, you know,
employer, employee.
- You were satisfied with her work?
- Yeah.
Nothing in particular you'd mention
about her behaviour?
No.
Very good.
It's been 6 hours, the poison has
had time to take effect. We can stop.
- The poison?
- Yes, we poisoned the spectators.
And go home now, Mr. Huges.
We don't need you anymore.
- Thank you very much.
- I don't understand.
It was a pleasure working with you.
Everybody, listen!
I have something important to announce.
Pay attention, please.
You can all relax.
It's over. We're stopping now.
Thanks, and...
congratulations to all.
Great job.
What did you mean, Chad?
I meant exactly what I just said.
It's over.
You can go home with your families now.
It's been a pleasure working with you.
You're out of your mind?
Why do you want us to go home?
Come on.
Stop acting like this is real life.
I'm telling you we're done.
There's no one watching anymore, okay?
No use going on.
Stop.
Finish. We're packing in.
But... this is real life, Chad.
We have a dead body over here.
No.
Come on. It's not real life.
Look at you, you have a stuffed
toy alligator under your arm.
So?
Okay. I'm gonna show you something.
Denise, take your gun.
- Why?
- Take it, I tell you!
It's an order!
- Now point it to me and shoot.
- No way!
Doug, you do it.
Don't think. Just shoot.
Oh God!
You see?
I don't feel a thing.
No pain whatsoever.
It's not real.
You understand?
Everything is fake.
Shoot again.
Now you believe me?
This situation is not real.
Go home.
It's all over.
Thanks.
What about the cleaning lady?
She's really dead?
Open the bag. You might be surprised.
It is a regular corpse.
Give her a good slap, you'll see.
Stop your bullshit. She's got no head.
It's not funny.
Shake her up.
So? Nothing happened.
She is dead. The body is cold.
How cold?
One of the spectators
didn't eat the turkey.
He's alive
and watching as we speak.
Damn!
You sure this is true?
Master.
You have to go on.
Okay. Excuse me, please.
I made a little mistake.
Forget everything I just said.
I'm sorry.
I got a little out of myself.
We're not quite done.
How was your relationship with Martina?
- You're bleeding, lieutenant.
- Don't mind that.
It is nothing.
Let's proceed. Answer my question.
Ah, like I've said,
We got along fine, you know,
employee, employer.
You were happy with her work?
Like I said before, Yeah.
Nothing in particular you'd mention?
No.
Were you in contact with her family?
I met her brother once.
He was... ah... rather obese.
We really didn't talk.
Okay. Do you know if Martina was...
in good terms with her obese brother?
Maybe.
Do you think the obese brother...
could be directly or indirectly...
involved with Martina's death?
Mr. Huges?
"Oh God, the kid was right."
"The killer is a tire."
You killed Martina?
You're gonna be in trouble
with the police.
You know what the police are?
Do you talk? I mean...
Talk... Mm...
Me.
Human. Boy.
Answer me!
This is what our killer looks like.
A tire?
Exactly.
I give you an hour to find him.
It can't have run far.
If you have any questions,
It is now or never.
What brand of tire?
We don't know yet.
Probably brandless.
- Is it worn?
- Yes.
Is it black?
It escaped on the road. That way.
So...
What might you fancy?
Farm chicken?
Or maybe potato mashed with olive oil
and mushroom fricassee.
I'll be fine, thank you.
Wait until you see the rest.
Tuna Tartare on a bed of artichoke
with violet flavor and white asparagus.
It's tempting, isn't it?
Okay, you know, I'm not hungry.
So just forget it.
Dessert then, perhaps?
Chocolate eclairs.
It's... whoof... lovely. How could...
Hey, hey, I'm telling you
I'm not hungry, alright?
And you're wasting my time.
Just go away.
Come on. You gotta eat something.
It is unhealthy.
You can't go on like this.
You can't... You...
Have a yoghurt, at least.
Just do that for me.
I just want to watch the end in peace.
Wait all you want,
'cause there is no end.
Fine, I'll watch it anyway, alright?
I like it.
What's happening?
What's happening? He's rolling.
The cops are chasing him.
It's a pretty exciting scene.
Is that so?
Where? I can't see.
Right there. I see it.
- Where?
- Here.
Go on.
Then, one day,
My father wanna do something nice for us
and he took us on a vacation
to the mountain. But...
...because we had no money, we...
...couldn't take a skiing. So...
...along with my brother,
we started going on
these walks in the snow.
We didn't even have shoes.
It's funny...
And then...
my brother... climbs up a rock,
and slips, falls into a crack.
Dumb accident.
You surely don't wanna try the eclair?
It's amazing.
I'm fine, thanks.
where was I?
Ah yeah...
My brother falls into a crack.
and I don't know why,
but instead of offer help,
I take this some enormous rock
and I smash him into the face with it.
And then he stops screaming.
Damn.
You have something for stomache?
I ate too fast.
Oh, shit!
That stuff was supposed to be
for you to eat!
Oh God, it burns!
I don't want to die!
Help me!
Help me. Oh God, please!
Oh, it burns!
I'm going to die! I don't want to die!
Help me please. Help me...
You can't do that.
Really?
Well, you can if you want,
but it's against the rules.
So what... can I or can't I?
Unit 4 central. You receive?
We located the tire.
You receive?
I repeat. We located the tire
inside a house.
You're on.
We receive you, unit 4.
What did you mean by "located"?
We just saw him.
He's in a house on Belly Ball Road,
watching TV. What should we do?
Stay put. We're on our way.
You alright?
We're gonna neck him.
The door just opened. He's coming.
Alright, go ahead, read.
Come.
Closer.
Come on. Closer. I was expecting you.
Come on. Come here.
Articulate.
"Come here and kill me,
you son of a bitch."
Come closer and kill me,
you little jerk.
Stick to the text. Go on.
Son of a bitch.
Come on.
Closer.
That's good. He's biting.
Go on.
Come on.
You know I've been very naughty.
You have to punish me.
Come. Come punish me.
Who wrote this garbage?
Don't worry about that. Go on.
You like me?
You think I'm sexy?
Come on, be a good boy,
blow my head off, you big slut...
Sorry, I can't read that.
It is too aweful.
Get out of the way.
You're gonna ruin everything.
Blow my head off, you big slut.
You hear me?
I have a very...
I have been a very naughtly girl.
I need a good thrashing.
Come on, now! Go ahead.
Kill me! Go on!
I want to die.
Do it!
I think he suspects something.
I think we should stay
with the woman's voice.
Shit!
Take back the mic.
Come on. Go ahead! Go ahead! Come on!
Where are we?
I don't know. It doesn't matter.
Improvise. Quick!
Hey, blow my head off.
What're you wait for?
Very good. Go on.
Come on, I'm ready! Now!
Excuse me. Sorry to bother you, but...
The way I look at it,
this scene makes no sense at all.
And not that as great as we began
with, for at least I understood it.
Now, it's uh... it's totally confused.
That's why I took the trouble
to come over this way.
What do you mean?
What don't you understand?
What don't I understand is
the bait with the dummy.
It doesn't make sense. And what's
the point? What's the purpose?
Can't you see, it's a lure.
There's nothing confusing.
Yeah, I get the lure, okay?
I am not stupid.
What I don't get is why
it takes so many hours.
Why don't you just ice the bloody tire?
Now that he's...
He's standing in front of
the lure dummy,
with a Bazooka-
even better, no, no, listen, listen--
even better, you get one of
your guys with a flamethrower.
Just woo!
You gotta do something. I mean,
do something, anything.
No, no...
The idea was for him to blow up the
dummy himself instead of the dynamite.
That way, he will pop
himself off himself, so to speak.
That's brilliant. That's actually
brilliant. What I'm asking...
is speed up the action. That's all.
You know? Boom, boom!
Yeah. But then we wouldn't be here
if you've eaten the damn turkey.
That's true enough, but...
Listen, we like you told us.
We will try to speed things up now.
- You can go back to your place.
- Thank you.
Asshole.
Who's that guy?
Come on, let's get on with it.
I'm exhausted.
Read the last sentence there.
You're nothing but a rubber shit.
Once again.
Again.
You're nothing but a rubber shit.
damn, it didn't work.
May I ask what you intend to do?
I'm gonna blow up this
rubber shit myself. Be done with it.
No. You can't do that.
What about the dummy blow-up?
You promised man.
"The End". Bye.
That's it, ah?
That's all you got?
You can't stop here man.
Come on. What kind of racket you wanted?
Wait!
It is not the end.
It's been reincarnated in a tricycle.
Come back!
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm not a character. I'm just watching.
You just stay there.
Stay put.
No, stay put!
Good.
In the Steven Spielberg movie "E.T.",
why's the alien brown?
No reason.
In "Love Story",
why did the two characters
fall madly in love with each other?
No reason.
In Oliver Stone's "JFK",
Why's the President suddenly
assassinated by some stranger?
No reason.
In the excellent "Chainsaw Massacre"
by Tobe Hooper,
why don't we ever see the characters
go to the bathroom...
or wash their hands,
like people doing in real life?
Absolutely no reason.
Worse, in "The Pianist" by Polanski,
how come this guy has to hide
and live like a bomb...
when he plays the piano so well?
Once again the answer is...
"no reason".
I could go on for hours with
more examples. The list is endless.
You probably never gave it
a moment's thought.
But all great films, without exception,
contain an important element--
a "no reason".
And you know why?
Because life itself is made up
of tonnes...
of "no reason".
Why can't we see the air all around us?
No reason.
Why're we always thinking?
Why do some people love sausages
and other people hate sausages?
No fuckin' reason.
Come on, don't waste your time
explaining that garbage. Let's go!
Just one minute. Let me finish.