China-Hong Kong Border
Block 37? Down there
Thanks
Mrs. Lee, you're beautiful
They say your dumplings
are the most expensive
Of course; come in
You've come in the right time
The water is boiling, waiting for you
I know you
I watched you on TV;
when I first came to Hong Kong
You're a star!
I retired long ago
Please, sit
Guess how old I am
Sit here, please
Here
Guess, Mrs. Lee
Well...
You're in your thirties
I'm old; call me Aunt Mei
You don't have wrinkles
And I have good color
I'm my own best advertisement
Your skin is great
My dumplings are worth it
You get what you pay for
Mrs. Lee
Let me get you more cabbage
I bet you dislike chives with their strong flavor
This cabbage is great
I'll cut it smaller, squeeze it dry
I'll put more ginger in the filling
Up to you Okay
The Northerners always say...
Good feeling comes from a nap
Good taste comes from a dumpling
These have 1,400 years of history
But the Southerners still say
It's just meat-stuffed dough, nothing special
I use high-gluten flour
For texture and chewiness
I knead it fine
Until it is like a peeled egg
Smooth, translucent, and soft
There is a secret to keep the filling
from leaking out
So that the juicy flavor explodes in the mouth
Mrs. Lee
Eat while it's warm
Take your time
Behave, baby
I eat these often. They're nutritious
Sometimes in soup...
or minced and steamed with citrus peel
But the dumplings are best
They made me famous
Here, baby
It's shame to discard this
Wash it
Bury it with the flowers
They will bloom especially well
Let me tell you
Expensive cosmetics claim to contain...
bird's nest, longevity mushrooms
bee's pollen, pearls...
essence of hot springs
All lies!
For women to look younger,
you must start from inside...
for the best color
Only my secret formula can do this
Mrs. Lee...
think of the results, not what it was
Let me sing for you
After my customers eat...
I often sing songs from my youth...
for entertainment; listen:
Lake Hung waters are rough
At the shore is my home
At dawn, boats go out with nets
At dusk, they return loaded with fish
Wild ducks and lotus roots are here
Autumns are bountiful with rice
They say heaven is beautiful
How can it compare with Lake Hung?
The kitchen cabinets
will be delivered tomorrow
Bring soup the day after tomorrow
Excuse me, Mr. Lee, I have to go
deliver Mrs. Lee's soup now
Mr. Lee, you've stayed here for months
You don't want to leave
My home is being renovated
My dining set just arrived from Paris
It's too humid, my designer refuses to work
I'm fussy like him
If it doesn't feel good, I reject it
Please behave
Stop it...
I'll behave when I eat
You are naughty I can't break it
What is it?
Good for you
It looks horrible
Try some? No, thanks
Your soup, Madam
What did she say to Mr. Lee?
I don't know
Shenzhen, China
I went through so much to get these
It is hard to keep secret
I hear reporters want pictures
The problem is from Hong Kong
Don't come for the next two weeks
Even the locals can't get a hold of the stock
We'll see
This is for you Thank
You know him? Who?
S.N. Wang Oh, him
Why did you break up?
It was long ago
He disliked the one-child policy
But I was aborting over 10 fetuses a day...
or over 3,000 a year; over 30,000 for 10 years
Because I had done so many abortions
He was afraid we would be cursed
It was national policy Yes...
I was serving the people; Thanks
Thanks; bye
This way, Miss
China-Hong Kong Border
X-ray, please That one?
The lunchbox Okay
Open it
Ham and egg on rice?
Yes, lunch for my son:
Ham egg, plain rice
You may go Thanks
Thank you
I didn't lie to you, trust me
Stop it!
Anna!
Believe me, I didn't lie to you
Stop following me
You better stop or I'll beat you into pieces
I taped these for you
Enjoy!
Hello? Fung!
Yes
Is it raining in London?
Your mom said you maxed out your credit card
Who are you with? A girl?
Girlfriend?
You're dating?
Does your mom know?
And she tells me...
she hasn't seen your report card
You did well to choose me as your sponsor
I'll call you later
Okay? Bye!
Dating at thirteen!
Dating at thirteen?
Puppy love. Your son?
I look that old?
Do you have children?
We don't know whose fault it is
I'll bring back your youth...
and his heart
Do you have more potent stuff
for faster results?
It's best in the 5th or 6th month
Extract it by breaking the water sac
and slide it
It's covered by a layer of creamy fat
The colors are defined
and you can see the cranium
And the little hands and feet moving around
In the first trimester, they're this small
By the third trimester, they're too tough
The 5th month is perfect, kitten-like...
and most nutritious
Let me show you
Some say even if you're eighty
After eating them
You feel eighteen again
See
This is what I chopped up
You're still afraid?
I was a doctor
In China, only the best minds
could study medicine
My forte was surgery with no bleeding
Always bloodless
So you've saved many lives
Nothing is left after I'm done!
We must all face our fates
Our fates are all different
So we must treasure our time...
and live well
Honey?
I'm at your favorite bakery
Want some custard tarts?
I'm working Really?
I'm be home late
Remember your promise
Of course; our 15th anniversary
I'll keep you company tomorrow
Okay? Bye
You were just on a trip last week
You promised to be with me
I'm just going for a few days
I want to visit my nephew in London
Sure, if you like
And go shopping, too
So many zeroes?
You used to laugh a lot
Aren't you happy with all the zeroes?
Laughing doesn't equal happy
Plus, you're not coming
I'll be gone 4 or 5 days
And if not?
I'll write you another as a fine
Fines are for mistakes
Whatever
Hello? If you don't send that contract
I'll change my mind
Not more than 950 million
These are bland and crunchy
By the 2nd months
they have little hands and feet
And ears too! Those were bones?
Nah... their bones aren't hard
I'll chop them finer next time
Cook them in broth next time
It will enhance the flavor
Are you done?
This can't go on Why?
My skin is still flabby
It's much better!
I need your most potent stuff
I'll find it...
let me sing now
Sing as you wish, I must go
Bye, Mrs. Lee...
Mrs. Lee, this way please
I'll find it for you
Call me when you do Don't worry!
Aunt Mei?
You are...? Mrs. Kam recommended you
Come in; hello, Little girl
Beg Aunt Mei
Find someone else
Where? Mrs. Kam says you were
a great doctor in China
I believe her
It's too dangerous
Let me recommend a Shenzhen hospital
It's quite good, and it's legal
I know, but I can't afford the fees
Black market, then
You are the black market
No, I'm not!
Her feet are swollen
She's showing
I thought she gained weight
She's five months along
In the first trimester, I could scrape the vagina
But now it's all in place; I can't force it
The bones will pierce the vagina
It's too dangerous; no
I beg you; she's only fifteen
I'm retired, and it's illegal
How can she give birth to a baby?
She's too young to be a mother
Say something! Speak!
Speak up and beg Aunt Mei!
I must tell you
Her dad did it; we can't keep it
Please abort it for her
It's a monster
Once the baby is born...
Is it my child or grandchild?
Please
Quit your job today
Will you be my sugar daddy?
I can afford you
You don't eat that much
I do
You like to laugh, too
Your home is so grand!
What's the use? It's empty
It's a house, not a home
My husband is with some young girl
Did he notice the difference?
I can't wait, I need your best
For youth and beauty
Women must fight time
I used to always laugh
After high school, I went into a TV series
I became very popular
Mr. Lee was the sponsor of my show
I fell during a stunt
And he held me
So you married him?
I was just 20
Everyone wants to marry well
He was in his thirties, and he loved me
I thought it would be "happily ever after"
All men love 20-years-old gals
Yes, when they are in their thirties...
and in their 40's and 50's...
and in their 60's and 70's
I let it go
As long as he doesn't flaunt it
Men are all the same...
all they know is sex
What's so good about a 20-year-old?
And you?
So sad
I broke up with my first love...
and married an uncultured cook
a cook...
Times have changed
All Chinese wanted to come to HK at that time
Wanted a Hong Kong identity Card
And I...
After a hard struggle
I got mine and I grew up
But I also got divorced
I don't think you dare get a divorce
Women like you are everywhere
Be glad you know me
otherwise... Second Wife in 5 years...
Third Wife in 10 years...
and Fourth Wife in 15
and I am different from you
I rely on myself
You may be rich, but I am free
At the shore is my home
Mrs. Lee, go cast your net
Mrs. Lee!
Return loaded with fish
Thanks, Aunt Mei You're welcome; bye
Hello? Not yet, Mrs. Lee
Money can't buy it; just like love
The prime material is rare
All right; bye
What is this place?
Relax...
Almost done
relax
I'll be done soon
It's been eighteen hours
Relax
You must relax, too
Will she be all right?
Don't worry
Relax
The vagina is not fully dilated yet
She still has the body of girl
We women must defend ourselves...
or they will bully us
Take care of your daughter...
so it doesn't happen again
The water broke
It's fine Don't be nervous
I swear it will be over in ten seconds
Deep breath
Work with me, relax... Hold on
Relax! Cry if you want to
It's fully dilated, don't worry
One, two, three
The head is out... wait!
Where are my tongs?
Relax...
relax
Beautiful
Don't be sad
The baby has no more life
So fresh
Little girl
Little girl, you'll be fine
You'll be fine
It's over. Little girl
Lie down on my couch
Easy
Thanks Take my shoes
Let me sing for you
She's so heavy
I can't hold her much longer
Wait
Mrs. Lee, help yourself
I will make steamed dumplings
Have more wine
It was a boy
A boy?
See, look at that
So beautiful and rare
In China, people only abort girls
I didn't use drugs, just a catheter
Drugs make it inedible
They will damage its nervous system
It is also a first-born, even more nutritious
It's the most nutritious thing in the world
You saw the mother; nice girl
Young, still in high school
Healthy
Well, what are you waiting for?
What are you cooking today?
You'll feel like a new woman
My husband broke his leg
Now you need me
Normally you wouldn't care. Where I go
You smell nice...
Iook nice
You haven't held me in ages
Thirsty?
I'll get water
It's so hot
And we must go to Mongkok next
I forgot about that
With two cases
Woe is me And they're huge
Oh?
What is it..."blood"! What is it?
You're joking
Here's a tissue Whose is it, Driver?
Kay? How are you feeling?
Kay? Answer me
Kay? Are you all right?
I don't want to die
Don't die, Kay!
It's all my fault!
It's a reasonable amount
I'm busy; my assistant Emily will follow up
Don't worry; bye!
Sheep placentas or longevity mushrooms?
Otherwise, it must be the Snow Lotus
I say a major facelift
She's done something
Or eaten something
Mrs. Lee
You look great Thanks
Talking behind my back?
Of course not!
Just about how beautiful you look
Please wait for a moment
You're so late
Perhaps she finds herself a guru
I think "voodoo" is closer
What evil thoughts!
That's horrible
It is scary
Please sit; you're the host
You are the host
Please help yourselves Well
The food smells fishy
Is it the beef? The beef?
Fishy, I don't eat fish
Is it the fish?
I don't think so
There is a strange smell
I smell it, too What's wrong?
It's not the fish
But it really stinks
What's that?
It's coming from here
Excuse me
She's off again
Where is she going
The smell is gone You're right
Aunt Mei?
What is your "best stuff"
What did you feed me?
Was the fetus sick?
I smell fishy all over
What do you mean?
I've eaten so much and I'm fine
If anything happens to me
I hold you responsible!
I'll sue you!
You'll sue me?
You're the cannibal
Don't be silly, Mrs. Lee.
It smells because it works; you're too sensitive
Look at the mirror tomorrow, you'll be grateful
What do I do?
This baby was hard to find
It was a child of an incest
One in a million, you know
You mean a true bastard?
This is because of the incest?
Incest makes it extra potent
Hurry...
Turn your TV to Channel 2... it's your series
No Really?
The one you said looks like Alan
No way
Just admit it
No Really?
Sorry Never mind
Mrs. Lee, are you crying?
Don't cry; be strong
Have a good sleep
Take a hot bath
Sip some vinegar; you'll be fine
Good night, Mrs. Lee
Coming...
Aunt Mei?
Yes, Mr. Lee
You're breaking the law
How come?
This is just my dumpling shop
You advocate cannibalism
Does it really work?
Please sit
I will prove it to you
Please take a seat, Mr. Lee
We Chinese have had a long history
Who can tell if it is illegal to eat flesh?
About eating humans
Ancient medical texts say...
human flesh and organs...
can heal diseases
During famines
People could not bear to eat their own children
So they traded and ate other people's children
An ancient chef heard that...
...his Emperor wanted to taste human flesh
To please his Emperor...
...he cooked and served his own son
to the monarch
Tales abound of caring sons and daughters...
...cutting off flesh for their parents' medicines
In the Water Margin
Heroes ate human organs with their wine
One even opened a bun shop
using flesh as filling
The Japanese ate the Chinese
China had civil unrest and famines
Did they avoid human flesh?
We hate people "whole-heartedly"
A patriotic poem describes...
"eating barbarian flesh...
drinking their blood"
We love people "with all our hearts"
We want to take bites...
and swallow them
We are inside each other
You were 20 in 1960?
You're in your sixties now
Age is just a number
But you're an old lady
My body is what's real
Feel it, harder
Is it young enough?
You can be the same...
...stay young forever
Stay young forever by eating my dumplings
This is Mrs. Lee
Do you have any supply?
Money is not a problem
I need supplies...
Mr. Lee, will you return?
Yes, to eat your flesh
That's a promise I must go
Goodbye
I'll wait for you
Aunt Mei!
Aunt Mei, it's me
Dizzy? And rashes?
It's just nerves!
You'll be fine after you move back home...
You'll be fine
I'll give you drugs to ease the itch
Hotel living is not for you
Nurse?
Yes, Dr. Wong
Mrs. Lee's driver will pick up her medication
Yes, how many days' prescription?
Give her a week Okay
Mr. Lee's secretary called and asked
Why you skipped your ultrasound yesterday
I'm here now Here's your report
Call us if your morning sickness continues
Thank you
Goodbye Bye
Aunt Mei
You scared me!
I was rude...
But as a woman
you know what I was going through
I really need your help
I've retired
Money is not a problem
That "best stuff" was a dream
Mrs. Lee, don't try that
I beg you, I really need you
Please help
Mr. Lee, I am fixing my hair now
I've been waiting for your call
I want to see you soon, too!
Okay, Bye!
Don't move
Dispatch, we're at 2103
Victim is male, badly cut up...
We need an ambulance
We have the female under control
Tell them to hurry
Please tell the ambulance to hurry
What are these?
Must you scream? So much stuff left
He's back with me
I won't let go again
Give up
I've thought about it
But you're pregnant
He said he wanted a son
And if it's a girl?
Then I charge less
You're having the child?
I'm five months along
I'm almost due
I'm young; the time is nothing
I can live on Mr. Lee's cheque...
...at least for a while
I want your baby
Why? Inheritance issues?
I want your baby now
Now?
Abort it; You don't have to carry it
And I don't have to worry
I'll double your price
How's that?
Doctor, she's in her second trimester
Don't let her miscarry
Do not use drugs to induce birth
I don't want drugs in its system
Use a catheter...
...and adrenaline to stimulate the vagina
Then the fetus will be perfect
Using this method will take longer
And cause pain to the mother
The pain only lasts for a while
You want...
to keep this fetus?
Yes, and in its pure form
Why do you want it?
Trophy, a souvenir
It's the world's most expensive trophy
Hurry, then
I want to watch
Shenzhen, China
Put three wishes...
...in the music box
Your first wish?
A man to love me all my life
And then?
Happiness always
What's the third? Hurry
Youth and beauty
Of course, beauty Hurry, it's our turn
Your wish of marriage is granted
Wait, greet my guests for me
I left something Hurry, then