/ She's always In my halr//
/ [Funky Rock]
I hate scary movies. I should be
studying. You know I gota bio due.
Baby, did I mention that
these tickets were free?
- Free.
- Sandra Bullock Is playlng
rlght down the street.
Nobodywanna pay $7.50 to see
some Sandra Bullock shit...
unless she's naked.
Oh, butyou will sitthrough
a movie called Stab?
It's adrenaline, Maureen.
It's good to be scared.
It's primal.
You knowwhat I'm sayin'?
No, I'm gonna tellyou
what it is, okay?
It's a dumb-ass white movie
aboutsome dumb-ass white girls...
gettln'thelrwhlte asses
cut the fuck up, okay?
Yeah. I suppose Sandra Bullock
is Miss Ethnicity, right?
Well, no, all I'm saylng Is that
the horror genre Is hlstorlcal...
for excluding
the African-American element.
When the hellyou getyour Ph.D.
in Black Cinema, Sister Souljah?
Listen, I read my Entertalnment Weekly,
okay? I knowmy shit.
Yeah, Maureen.
I read my Black Beat, too, homey.
Tonightwe're going to have an
all-black movie, all-black cast,
all-black wardrobe, black eyes...
Everything.
Black-eyed peas. Black cats...
- Crazy.
- Thank you.
- Hi. Here you go.
- What's this?
Stab souvenirs.
The studio sentthem.
Hah! And it's white.
- [Laughs]
- Thanks.
Thank you.
// [Goth-Rock Playlng]
[Chattering, Screaming,
Laughing]
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Very romantic.
[Metallic Slicing Effect,
Explosion]
- // [Contlnues]
- [Chattering Continues]
Whoa!
[Audience Hooting]
[Hooting Continues]
[Thunder]
[Man In Audlence]
Whoo.! Take It off.!
Now, why has she got
to be naked?
What does that have to do with the plot
ofthe story, her being butt-ass naked?
I don't know aboutthe plot,
but I gota stiff one.
You better loosen up thatwrist.
[Telephone Rlngs]
[Audlence Groans]
[Screaming]
Hello?
[Distorted Voice]
Hello.
- Who is this?
- Guess.
- No, really. Who is this?
- Were you expectlng somebody?
- [Popcorn Popping]
- No.
Bitch, hang the phone up
and Star-69 his ass! Damn!
- [Audience Hushing]
- Shh!
- [Actress] Who Is thls?
- [Dlstorted Volce]
Who would you llke It to be?
I don't like games.
Who is this?
[Dlstorted Volce]
Look out back.
Do you see
your boyfrlend anywhere?
I don'teven have
a boyfriend right now.
Would you like one?
Damn itall. Can l... Give me some money.
I need to getsome popcorn.
- You gotmoney.
- I gotmy money. I asked foryourmoney.
[Dlstorted Volce]
What do you say?
Cheap ass.
- Thank you.
- Come on.
Cat gotyourtongue?
You know, I don'teven knowyou,
and I dislike you already.
[Audlence Hootlng, Whlstllng]
[Sighs]
[Audlence Screams]
[Giggling]
Come on!
- Hey, we're sold out.
- Oh, cool!
Hello.
Hi. Um, can I have a medium popcorn,
no butter, and a small diet Pepsi?
- You got it.
- Thanks.
That's it.
I am not going back in there.
Come on, you chickenshit.
It's justa movie.
No, it's not justa movie.
It's a true story.
All these kids got killed
a couple years ago in California.
- Here's the popcorn.
- Thanks.
[Laughing] I was so scared,
I almost had a heartattack.
Hah! Stab you, man!
[Laughing]
[Audlence Hootlng]
- Whoa!
- [Screams]
[Laughing]
- You ass!
- I'm sorry. I had to, baby.
- Whatare you playing?
- Would you relax?
God! What's wrong with you?
I don't like being scared.
I don't like that.
Baby, it's justa movie.
Besides, scary movies
are greatforeplay.
Excuse me?
Let's go see Sandra Bullock.
Oh, no. Sandra started already.
We can stay.
Juststop playin' so much.
All right.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
See ya Inslde.
[Audlence Hootlng]
[Audlence Squeals]
Sorry.
Hello?
[Hlgh-Pltched Volce]
I dldn't mean lt. I dldn't mean lt.
I swear. I swear.
I'll be good.
Please, don't, Mommy.
I'll tell you. Really.
I'll tell you, Mommy.
Really. I'll tell you
why I dld lt, Mommy.
Llsten, Mommy.
[Groans]
N-N-N-No! No, no, no, no, no, no!
Don't do that!
Move! Move! Go!
Run. Go!
Baby, give it up.
You came back just in time.
It looks like she's aboutto get it.
Wantsome popcorn?
Uh-uh. See, ifthatwas me,
I would be outofthere.
Oh! Here itcomes!
- [Audlence Screamlng]
- [Maureen] Here It comes.!
Here It comes.!
Oh, my God.!
[Screaming]
[Howling]
/ Whoa, oh, oh /
/ Thls could be your lucky day /
/ In hell /
- / Never knowwho It mlght be /
- [Phone Rlnglng]
/ Atyourdoorbell /
[Phone Contlnues Rlnglng]
/ Thls could be your lucky day /
/ In hell /
/ In hell //
[Ringing]
Hello?
- Hello?
- [Distorted Voice] Hello, Sidney.
- Yes?
- What's yourfavourite scary movie?
- Who is this?
- You tell me.
Cory Gillis, 555-0176.
- Oh, shit!
- Hotflash, Cory...
- Shit!
- Crank calls are a criminal offence...
prosecuted under penal code 653-M.
[Dial Tone]
Hope you enjoyed the movie.
Time to change numbers again?
No. It'll die off.
It's opening weekend.
We'll see how it goes.
Okay.
[Man On TV] You know, Ron,
uh, It's not an easy thlng...
to be accused ofa crlme
you dldn't commlt, partlcularly
one as helnous as murder.
But how do people treatyou
nowthat they knowthe truth
aboutyour Innocence?
Most people are cool.
There's some who still keep
a safe distance, which is odd forme,
'cause I've always been
sort of a people person.
Butyou were wrongly accused.!
You were fully exonerated.
Yeah, well, that and a nlckel
wlll getyou a cup ofcoffee.
- Even that's nottrue any more.
- [Audlence Laughs]
Certalnly, wlth Gale Weathers'book...
and nowthe movle...
It's set the record stralght
forCotton Weary.
One would thlnk.
But, uh, Gale's... Gale's been terrlfic.
Hey! Move your ass, okay?
You're late.
Don'tforgetaboutthatmartini mixer
tonightatthe Delta Lambda Zetas.
- I don'tthink I'm going
to be able to make it, Hal.
- What?
Don'teven try to bag, okay?
'Cause you promised me.
- Avague promise at best.
- Nobody's asking you to join, okay?
It's a party.
Free beer, meetthe girls.
Hallie, you knowme
and organized religion.
- It's a sorority.
- Worse.
Look, Sid, just lowerthe walls
forthe nextfew days.
This self-induced isolation
you got goin' is not healthy.
- I'm fine.
- "I'm fine."
Yes, I know. "I'm fine"
is stretched tightly across yourface.
Check outthe news.
[Man On TV] The two WlndsorCollege
students were murdered...
last nlght durlng a sneak prevlew
ofthe new movle Stab.
Police haven't released any information
exceptforthe victims' names,
but a press conference
Is scheduled for latertoday.
The vlctlms,
Maureen Evans and Phll Stevens,
were both Windsor seniors.
- Where's Randy?
- He's got Film Theory this morning.
...ended wlth the brutal murders
oftwo promlslng...
Sldney.! Sldney.!
Sidney, did you knowthe victims?
- Do you feel threatened by the murders?
- No comment.
- Do you think there'll be more murders?
- Sidney! Sidney!
- Whatcan you tell us aboutthe victims?
- How aboutthe police?
- We just need one statement.
- Please talk to us!
You could saywhat happened
in thattheatre is a direct
resultofthe movie itself.
That is so Moral Majority.
You can't blame real-life
violence on entertainment.
What? Waita second. Yes, you can.
Don'tyou even watch the news?
Yeah. Hello! The murderer
was wearing a ghostmask, okay?
Just like in the movie.
It's directly responsible.
No, it's not. Movies are not
responsible for our actions.
It's a classlc case ofllfe
lmltatlng art lmltatlng llfe.
Thls Is not a hypothetlcal.
It's not about art.
I had Biologywith that girl.
This is reality.
Thank you. I agree with you.
Letme tellyou about reality, Mickey.
I lived through this.
Okay?
Life is life.
It doesn't imitate anything.
Come on, Randy,
with all due respect,
the killer obviously patterned himself
aftertwo serial killers...
- who have been lmmortallzed on film.
- Thank you.
Are you suggesting thatsomeone's
trying to make a real-life sequel?
Stab 2? Who'd wantto do that?
Sequels suck.
- [Students Argulng]
- Oh, please. Please!
- By definition alone,
they're inferiorfilms.
- Bullshlt generallzatlon.
Many sequels have
surpassed their original.
- Oh, yeah?
- Name one.
Allens.
Far betterthan the first.
Yeah, well,
there's no accounting fortaste.
Thank you. Ridley Scott rules.
Name another.
No. Allens is a classic, okay?
"Getaway from her, you bitch!"
I believe the line is
"Stay away from her, you bitch."
It's film class, right?
[Students Laughlng]
- Yeah, whatever. You knowwhat I mean.
- Another.
- T2.
- Mmm.
You've gota hard-on for Cameron.
- Big one.
- Walt a second.
- The first Termlnator is historical.
- Yeah.
"Sarah Connor?" "Yes."
[Imitates Gunshot]
- [All Laughing]
- All right. All right, okay.
House II. :
The Second Story.
- What?
- The entire horror genre
was destroyed by sequels.
Hey, I got it, by the way.
I got it.
The Godfather Part II.
[General Agreement]
[Imitating Marlon Brando] Very good.
That's the Oscar-winning exception.
- [Laughter]
- All right, that's enough.
That'll be a wrap.
The sequel dlscusslon to be contlnued.
[Chattering]
So, Mr Originality,
howwould you make it different?
I'd letthe geek getthe girl.
Three hundred people watched.
Nobody did anything.
They thought itwas a publicity stunt,
for Christ's sakes.
[With Cockney Accent]
And itwould have been a good one too.
- It's starting again, Randy.
- It's not.
A lotof shit happens atthe movies.
People get robbed, shot,
maimed, murdered.
Multiplexes are a very dangerous place
to be these days.
Yeah, and you are
in extreme denial.
And you should be too.
This has nothing to do with us.
Randy, a guy in a ghostmask
hacked up two people...
in a movie theatre
telling our life story.
- Coincidence?
- You knowwhat happened
atWoodsboro, Randy.
- You can't ignore it.
- I know, Sid, but I don't
wantto go back there again.
Can'twe just go back to our
pseudo-quasi-happy existence?
- Hello, Derek. Howya doin'?
- Hey, Sid.
- I heard. You weren't in class.
- Yeah, I know.
I skipped. I couldn'ttake
all the "that's her" looks.
Is there anything I can do?
Well, you gotany tricks
for getting me back...
to a pseudo-quasi-happy existence?
- I might just have one forthat.
- Yeah?
Oh, yeah? What is it?
Thatwas pretty good.
Geta room.
[Woman] They're threatenlng to what?
Are you klddlng me?
They'd be stupid to pull this movie.
With all this free press, they're
gonna have huge numbers this weekend.
It'll break box office records.
- [Man On Phone, Indistinct]
- Consider it done.
Uh, Miss Weathers?
Hi. I'mJoel.
I'mJoel. The affiliate sentme.
I'm your new cameraman.
- Yeah. You gotexperience?
- Huh? Uh, yeah.
I mean, I'm local,
but I shotthe bingo finals.
- Great. Great.
- I almost gotan award forthat.
All right, listen, Joel.
This is how itworks.
I point, you shoot.
You stay focussed and faston yourfeet,
and we'll getalong fine.
You're playing with the big boys now,
you got it?
Got it! Gotyou covered.
I'm all over it.
Don'tworry abouta thing.
How hard can it be?
You pointand I shoot.
I'm there!
Excuse me, Miss Weathers?
Uh, could I have a minute?
- No.
- Justone second.
l-I knowyou probably
getthis all the time,
but ljustwanted to say
I am such a big fan of yourwork.
ljustfinished you book.
l-I couldn't put it down.
Insightful, probing...
ljust really, really loved your book.
- Thank you. Thanks.
- Sure.
I'm a writermyself.
I write forthe local paper,
forthe Post Telegram.
I'm Debbie Salt. I took your seminar
in Chicago lastyear.
I was the one in the front row
asking all the questions.
- Right. I thoughtyou looked familiar.
- Oh, thank you.
Um, can'twaitto see the movie.
You know, you must be getting
quite a lotofflak on that, right?
I mean, with all the
violence-in-cinema issues.
What is your position going to be?
- No comment.
- Miss Weathers, please... I would...
Itwould be such an honour
forme if I could just get
a quote from you formy story.
Okay. Begin quote:
- Great.
- "Yourflattering remarks
are both desperate and obvious."
- [Woman] Ouch.!
- End quote.
Gale, whatare you doing here?
Do you think these murders
are connected to Sidney Prescott?
Miss Weathers,
what's yourfeeling aboutthis?
[Man On P.A.]
May I have yourattentlon.
- My name is Chief Louis Hartley...
- Chlef Hartley.
Hi. Gale Weathers,
author of The Woodsboro Murders.
Do you think the killer
will strike again?
We have no evidence
thatthis is a serial killer.
- I'd llke to read from a prepared...
- Can you tell us of any precautions
thatyou're taking?
Well, firstof all,
we think it's justan isolated incident,
- and we wlll be...
- Ladies.
Oh, my God.
This is huge.
Do you have any suspects?
- Sidney, look. It's Gale Weathers.
- What?
Star ofthe Gale Weathers
press conference,
based on the book by Gale Weathers.
Soon to be a major motlon plcture
starrlng Gale Weathers.
- Be kind. She saved our lives.
- She had calf implants.
Chief Hartley, do you plan
on giving the town a curfew?
I'm gonna getcloser.
- So that's her?
- Yeah.
Hello, girls.
Enjoying yourselves?
- Hello, Sister Lois, Sister Murphy.
- Hello, pledge. Hi, Sidney.
- Hey.
- This must be flat-out hell foryou.
- How are you holding up?
- I manage.
It's reallyweird, isn't it? To think
this fuss is all because of you!
I mean, not dlrectly, but In some
slx-degrees-of-Kevln Bacon way.
[Woman] Now, Hallle, are you
gonna brlng yourfrlend to our
llttle martlnl mlxertonlght?
- I have a lotofwork to do.
- We'll be there.
Oh, good.
Because, Sid, we have our eyes on you.
You hang in there,
and ifthere's anything we can do...
The Delta Lambdas
are very sensitive to your plight.
- Yeah. Bye!
- Bye!
- You gonna start to dress
like thatonce you get in?
- That's not gonna happen.
The Delta Lambdas
are the biggest bunch offuckin'...
Hey! I'm pledging
Delta Lambda, thank you.
Oh, my God.
Who's that?
Dewey?
Hey! [Laughs]
- Whatare you doing here?
- Ah!
- Oh, I was worried aboutyou.
- Yeah?
I heard aboutwhat happened
and I was on the next plane.
- Oh.
- Can we talk?
Yeah. Yeah.
[Dewey]
Are you okay?
I'm fine, Dewey, or I was.
I mean, things were okay until now.
But, uh, theatre's going great.
I gotmy firststarring role.
We open in two days.
- That is great.
- Yeah. I'm loving it.
You know, and I've got
some greatfriends,
and, uh, I'm seeing someone.
Nice guy. Premed.
No apparent psychotic tendencies.
I was justworried.
Look, Sld, lfthere Is some
freaked-out psycho trylng to follow...
in Billy Loomis's footsteps,
you probably already know him.
Or her, orthem.
They're probably already In your llfe.
They getoff on that.
I justwantyou to be careful, Sld.
Oh, you...
You think I don't knowthat, Dewey?
[Sighs]
Butwhatam I supposed to do?
Justcuteverybody off?
Crawl under a rock? What?
[Sighs]
Justwatch out.
Keep an eye out.
I'm gonna talk to Chief Hartley
and the local police.
I'm gonna just hang around.
I wanna make sure you're safe,
ifthat's all rightwith you.
Yeah. I'd be honoured.
All right, Sid.
[Sighs]
Hey.
- You okay?
- Uh-huh.
- Who was that guy?
- An old friend.
Deputy Dewey, Woodsboro's finest.
What's he doing here?
He's worried.
Our surrogate big brother.
Nothing like a funeral
to bring a family together.
I'm gonna go say hi.
- Chief Hartley said the girl
was stabbed seven...
- [Derek] Drop lt.
Hello, Sldney.
- How are you?
- Hi. What do you want, Gale?
Well, I was hoping
I might get justa fewwords with you.
- Cotton.
- Hi, Sidney.
Here we are atWindsor College,
where Sidney Prescott...
has just been reunlted wlth Cotton Weary
forthe first tlme...
since she wrongly accused him
of murdering hermother.
- Whatthe hell are you doing?
- We wantto know howyou feel.
Tell us everything that's happened,
looking back on the lasttwo years.
Sidney, I'd just like to say
that I forgive and forget,
and just like you, I'd like
to get back on with my own life.
- [Weathers] Do you have any comments?
- You bitch!
- Ah-ah.
- Deep breaths. Lot ofdeep breaths.
Oh, Sidney, share with us, please!
- I'll share with you!
- Okay, okay, okay.
Did you getthaton film?
Yes, I gotthaton film.
Sid?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Where's she going, Gale?
Sidney?
Where's she golng?
Gale, l-I thoughtwe had
an official interview. What's going on?
- She didn't know?
- Man, thatwas cold.
Hey, you need to check your conscience
atthe door, sweetie.
I'm not here to be loved.
Gale, you promised me
ten minutes of national coverage.
You'll getyourten minutes
when I getmy goddam interview.
Don'twalk away from me, Gale.
I'm still...
Gale, I did my part!
Joel!
Dewey.
Whatare you doing here?
Why don'tyou just leave her alone?
Hasn'tshe been through enough?
And my name is Dwight.
I was just doing my job, Dwight.
No matterwho gets hurt
in the process?
Hey!
Who got punched here... again?
Well, I don'tcondone violence,
butmaybe you deserved it.
Page 32:
"Deputy Dewey filled the room...
with his Barney Fife-ish presence."
- You read my book.
- Oh, yes, I do read, Miss Weathers.
Oh, Dewey, don'ttake itso seriously.
It's a character in a book.
Page 41:
"Deputy Dewey oozed with inexperience."
Don'tyou think you're overreacting
justa little bit?
No. What I think is that
you're a money-hungry, fame-seeking
and, forgive me for saying,
mediocre writerwho's gota cold
storage shed where her heartshould be.
No offence intended.
Dewey, I nevermeantto imply...
How do you knowthatmy
dimwitted inexperience...
isn'tmerely
a subtle form of manipulation
used to lower people's expectations,
thereby enhancing my ability
to effectively manoeuvre
within any given situation?
I'm sorry.
I don't knowwhatelse to say...
except I'm sorry.
No. I'm the one that's sorry.
I misjudged you.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some oozing to do.
One more thing.
Nice streaks.
Well.
// [Pop-Rock Playlng]
Hey, I am nota sorority pusher.
ljustthink, despite its trivialities,
it is a life-affirming, mentally stable,
healthy environmentforyou.
I mean, look atthis place.
I think you're taking your psych major
a little too seriously, Hallie.
[Sniffs]
I'm fine.
Yeah? That's beginning
to become yourtheme song.
"I'm fine." Yeah... Fucked up,
insecure, neurotic and emotional.
Sidney, you made it!
Hi!
No, I really mean that.
- Hi.
Do you girls wanta drink?
Well, actually, yeah, butyou knowwhat?
We'll get itourselves.
[Woman On Phone] I love those guys.
Are they stlll together?
I haven'tseen It
In, llke, three weeks.
- No, they broke up again.
- Really?
Mm-hmm. Sarah found out
that Bailey sleptwith Gwen.
She dumped him,
like, two episodes ago.
I wish she'd get her shittogether.
- Hold on. Someone's calling.
- [Beeps]
Omega Beta Zeta.
[Distorted Voice]
Hello?
- Yes?
- Who is this?
- Cici. Who's this?
- Who do you think?
Ted? Where are you?
Are you drinking? Hold on.
Ted's on the other line.
He sounds drunk. I'll callyou back.
Thatshitonly calls you
when he's drunk.
- Don't go overthere, Cici.
- All right. I'll callyou back.
[Beeps]
Okay, Ted. You sound loaded.
What's up?
Who's Ted?
Oh, I'm sorry. My bad.
I thoughtyou were someone else.
That's okay.
I am.
Who are you calling for?
Nobody's here.
Where is everybody?
We're cosponsorlng the acld raln mlxer
at Phl Gamma Alpha tonlght.
- Why aren'tyou there?
- I'm "sober sister."
I need to be here in case a drunk sister
calls and needs a ride.
- That's too bad.
- "Drink with your brain."
That's ourmotto.
- Who are you calling for?
- What if I said you?
- What if I said goodbye?
- Whywould you wantto do that?
Why do you always answer
a question with a question?
I'm inquisitive.
Yeah, and I'm lmpatlent. Do you want
to leave a message forsomeone?
Do you wantto die tonight, Cici?
[Beeps]
Omega Beta Zeta.
[Woman]
So, was itTeddy?
No. Itwas some creep asshole
trying to scare me.
Thatmovie Stab
is bringing outthe crazies.
[Clatterlng]
- Shit.
- What is it?
- I heard a noise.
- Where?
Upstairs.
- [Clatterlng]
- Shit!
- Hello? Hello?
- Kill, kill, kill, kill, kill, kill.
- Die, die, die, die, die. [Laughs]
- Stop it!
I can't believe
you're alone in that house.
- I don'tthink I'm alone.
- [Clatterlng]
I'm outof here.
You're breaking up.
Where are you?
- Outside.
- Don't panic, Cici.
- Call campus securlty.
- [Clcl] Okay.
[Beeping, Ringing]
[Man, Through Static]
Campus Security.
- Hi. I'm calling from the Omega Beta...
- I can't hearyou. Hello?
Hello?
- Can you hearme now?
- Hello?
- [Dial Tone]
- Hello? Shit!
[Beeping, Ringing]
- [Breaking Up] Campus Security.
- Yes. I'm calling from...
I can't hearyou. Hello?
- I'm calling from
the Omega Beta Zeta house.
- [Static]
Look, someone is harassing me.
- Hello? Shit!
- [Dial Tone]
- Hey!
- [Gasps]
- Jesus, Dawnie, you scared me.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Did anyone call forme?
- Whatare you doing here?
- I live here, remember?
ljustthoughtyou were
going to the mixer.
Yeah, I am. I had to change,
so I'll be outof here now.
[Ringing]
Omega Beta Zeta.
- [Distorted Voice] Is Cici there?
- Mm-hmm. Who's calling?
- It's Ted.
- It's your ill-conceived boyfriend.
Okay, so, I'll see you later.
And don'tforgetto setthe alarm.
Bye.
Hello, Ted.
You wish itwas Ted.
Don'tforgetto setthe alarm.
[Phone Falls To Floor]
[Beeping]
- [Dog Barklng]
- [Gasps]
[Floorboards Creaklng]
[Dog Barks, Floorboards Creak]
[Phone Rlngs]
[Rlnglng Contlnues]
Hello?
[Screaming]
[Whimpering]
[Alarm Soundlng]
[Groans, Screams]
[Screaming]
No! Please, no!
- [Screaming] No!
- [Alarm Contlnues]
/ Neversald I was Innocent/
/ I wlll burn In hell
forthe thlngs I've done to you /
/ Neversald I was anythlng good //
/ [Contlnues, Indlstlnct]
Everyone thinks thatsororities
are justabout blow jobs.
- But it's nottrue.
- We only promote safe, condomed sex.
See, we're about love,
respectand responsibility.
Harmonica style is okay, right?
- Oh, yeah.
- Cocktail?
Whattook you so long?
And you know,
Derek is a Delta Lambda big brother.
And we like to keep it
all in the family.
Wow. You know, you girls have really
given me a lotto think about.
Thanks.
It's working. It's working.
- Hey, babe. You wanna dance?
- Oh, I'd love to...
with thattall,
wide-shouldered fraternity boy.
- Thlnk you can arrange that?
- [Mlckey] That hurts.
- Go away.
- The Emplre Strlkes Back.
- Better story, improved effects.
- Nota sequel.
Part of a trilogy.
Completely planned.
- I like those little furry things.
- They're Ewoks. They blow.
Hey.
- Howya doin'?
- Good.
- Twits being nice to you?
- Painfully nice.
I take ityou will not be
pledging Delta Lambda Zeta.
[Laughs]
I think not.
- I'm crushed.
- Hey, guys.
Something is up
at Omega Beta Zeta.
- Police are everywhere.
- Hurry!
[Man]
Come on, let's go.!
[Slrens Blarlng,
Students Clamourlng]
[Sirens Blaring, Tyres Squealing]
[Chattering]
- Way to break up the party!
- Shit!
I should have broughtmy drink.
[Salt] Death by blunt trauma,
and there's a double stabblng.
So it's definitely notsuicide.
Okay. Thank you.
Gale, hi. You're just getting here.
It's not good.
It's a single victim.
Sorority girl.
So... I gotta go.
I've got a deadllne.
- Joel, let's go.
- [Joel] In-ln a mlnute.
It's happening again, isn't it?
You'd love that, wouldn'tyou?
- [Man] Please, stay back.
- [Sighs]
Better hurry, Gale.
Might getscooped.
[Man] Come on, I'm just trylng
to get close enough to get a shot.
Move it, Joel.
Gale, I have to be honestwith you.
I'm notcutoutforthis.
I mean, I was brought here to do
an Intervlew, not Faces of Death 14.
Do notfuck with me.
[Indlstlnct Chatter]
Come on. Getyour jacket.
Let's getyou home.
Yeah.
[Telephone Rlnglng]
[Rlnglng Contlnues]
- You about ready?
- [Rlnglng Contlnues]
Almost.
- Hello?
- [Distorted Voice] Hello, Sidney.
Rememberme?
- What do you want?
- I wantyou. It's showtime.
Then why don'tyou showyourface,
you fucking coward.
- [Man's Volce] My pleasure.
- [Blade Unsheathlng]
Derek!
- [Siren Wailing]
- Sid? Sid?
[Sldney] Derek.!
- Sid?
- [Screaming]
- [Gasps]
- [Panting]
Sid!
- [Screams]
- It's me. It's me.
- You okay? You okay?
- [Sobbing] Yeah. Yeah.
No, Derek! Don't!
[Dewey] Sld.!
[Sld] Dewey.!
- The klller's In there. And Derek.
- [Glass Breaklng]
[Groanlng]
[Gasping]
- [Panting] You all right?
- He wentthatway.
Sidney, he's in here!
Is everything okay?
[Breathing Heavily]
He gotme. He gotme.
[Sniffles]
- Now, apply pressure to it.
- Don't do that...
[Groaning]
[Dewey]
The pollce are on thelrway.
[Woman On P.A., Indlstlnct]
Thanks foryour cooperation.
Hallie, I'll be with you
in a fewminutes, okay?
Uh, no problem.
That's the easiest interrogation
of my crime-filled life.
I'm gonna go geta quick cup of coffee.
You want?
No.
You wantsome, Sid?
Howyou doin'?
You all right?
Notatall.
[Sighs]
You know, I knewthis was coming.
- I knewthis wasn'tover.
- You are notalone, Sid.
Okay? We are all here foryou.
All right? Whateveryou need.
- That poor girl.
- I know.
[Mlckey]
It's crazy, but...
- Derek could've been killed, you know.
- But he wasn't.
He's fine.
He just needs to realize the '90s
is no time to play hero.
Whywould anyone go back
in that house anyway?
I went around to the back ofthe house
and ran Into Sld there.
That's when she told me the killer
was inside, so I went in to see.
- [Groans]
- You're lucky there's no nerve damage.
You're gonna have
to take iteasy though.
- [Hartley] So then you
went back Inslde the house?
- Yeah.
No struggle?
He justcutyou and ran away?
- You're lucky he didn't killyou.
- Yeah, it's awfully convenient.
- Saywhat?
- Nothing.
It's justa shame
he gotaway so easily.
you gotthere too late,
rightafter he disappeared.
Yeah, it is.
[Pollce Radlo, Indlstlnct]
[Hartley]
We got three vlctlms.
Maureen Evans, Phil Stevens...
and Cici Cooper.
- Is Cici the girl's real name?
- Oh, uh, no.
It's, uh, Casey.
Casey Cooper.
[Indlstlnct Chatter]
As in Casey Becker?
- [Hartley] Excuse me?
- She was a young victim in Woodsboro.
As well as her boyfriend, Steven Orth.
As in Phil Stevens.
Maureen Evans... Maureen Prescott.
That's Sidney's mother.
Do you think someone's
trying to duplicate Woodsboro?
It looks like it.
I think you have a copycat
on your hands, Chief.
[Hartley Slghs]
Jesus Chrlst.!
Whatare you doing
to keep Sidney safe?
I gotmy two best
detectives guarding her.
Do these guys have to follow
you around everywhere?
Oh. We're attached atthe hip.
- [Bells Chlmlng]
- How am I ever gonna getyou alone?
- [Laughs]
- You know, to be honest, Derek,
I think itwould probably be
in your best interestto...
stay as far away
from me as possible.
I hope thatwas an
off-the-cuff remark...
that holds no subtextwhatsoever.
No, actually. I mean it.
I mean, look atyou.
You already got hurt.
I don'twantto see that happen again.
I'll take my chances.
Derek, I'm serious.
This is serious.
You are concerned with my
personal well-being and...
notwith trusting me
or anything, right?
Like I said, ljust don'twant
to see you get hurt.
And I don'twant
Okay, Sid?
- Take care, Miss Weathers.
- All right.
- Dewey.
- Chief.
HI.
So, I'm heading overto admissions
to do some leg work. You game?
I'm not here to write a book,
Miss Weathers.
I'm here to help Sid.
I wantto help her, too.
And help myself, of course.
Come on, Dewey.
Smile justonce. Please?
I'll smile when I catch the killer.
Gale, hi.
So who do you think did it?
WhataboutSidney's father?
Has he been ruled outas a suspect?
Well, he's supposedly
outofthe country on business,
butthatsounds a little fishy,
don'tyou think?
- I'm not here to do your job, Miss Salt.
- Whataboutthis ex-cop, Dewey?
- Kind of strange that he showed up.
- Yeah, what's he dolng here?
Dewey's a good guy, unlike some of us.
Really?
[Sighs]
Well, it justseems that ifthe killer
is repeating what happened in Woodsboro,
it's quite possible thatthe killer
could be from Woodsboro, that's all.
Derek, you think Sid will letme
interview herformy documentary?
Oh, yeah. You know, she turned down
Prlmetlme Llve, 20/20 and Datellne.
- Butforyou, yeah.
- Drop it.
I've been thinking
aboutthis whole murderthing.
- Have they checked out Randy?
- What?
I know he's an innocentvictim the first
time around, but he's a little off.
- You knowwhat I'm saying?
- Come on. Randy? The guy's harmless.
- That's whatthey said about Dahmer.
- Guys, keep it down.
Come on. What's up, Sid?
- Hey, Sid.
- How's it goin'?
Where are the SecretService guys?
Uh, overthere.
And which one is Kevin Costner?
The one on the right
is Officer Richards.
He Is a Caprlcorn.
Dlvorced. Fatheroftwo.
The one on the left Is OfficerAndrews.
He Is a Gemlnl.
He's single, but I think he's gay.
- [Mouthing Words] Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Derek?
Penny foryourthoughts.
"This morning,
I woke up with this feeling...
I dldn't know howto deal wlth."
/ And so ljust decided to myself /
/ I'd hlde It to myself/
- What is he doing?
- // [Contlnues]
Uh, Tom Cruise, Top Gun, 1986.
- Derek, don't.
- / When you walked into the room /
- / I think I love you /
- Don't do this.
/ I thlnk I love you
Isn't thatwhat llfe Is made of/
/ And though ltworrles me to say /
/ I've neverfeltthis way
Hey /
/ I think I love you
So whatam I so afraid of /
/ I'm afrald that I'm notsure of
a love there Is no cure for/
[Gasps]
/ I think I love you
Isn'tthatwhat life is made of /
- / And though itworries me to say /
- [Crowd Cheerlng, Hootlng]
- [Laughing]
- / I've neverfeltthis way /
/ Believe me
You really don't have to worry /
/ I onlywanna make you happy /
/ And if you say "Hey, go away"
I will /
/ But I thlnk betterstlll /
/ I better stick around and love you /
/ Do you thlnk I have a case
Let me ask you to yourface /
/ Do you really love me
'Cause I thlnk /
/ I love you //
[Cheerlng, Applaudlng]
Let's show a little love, huh?
[Cheerlng Intenslfies]
Come on.
Come here, come here.
Don'tworry, Sid.
I knowthings are a little crazy.
Isn'tthata big fratfaux pas?
Oh, yeah.
That is a big no-no.
See, you're notsupposed to
give your Greek letters to your girl...
no shape, way orform.
The brothers are gonna kick his ass,
but it's tradition.
- It's tradition.
- It's good luck.
It'll protectyou.
[Crowd Hootlng, Cheerlng]
So, tell us aboutthis part
you're getting rave reviews for.
Well, I play this young girl,
Sidney Prescott,
who discovers that her boyfriend
is this crazy serial killer...
who also killed hermother
the year before that.
So what kind of research
did you do forthe part?
I don't get lt.
They get Torl Spelllng to play Sld,
and they castJoe Blow Nobody
to play me.
- [Torl Contlnues, Indlstlnct]
- At leastyou get David Schwimmer.
I getthe guywho drove
Jane Seymour's stagecoach...
for one episode of DoctorQulnn.
This is Tori Spelling
starring in the newfilm Stab.
[Panting]
[Gasps]
Billy, you scared me.
- Whatare you doing here?
- They letme go, Sid. I didn't do it.
- I'm innocent.
- I know.
- Please.
- Whywon'tyou letme touch you?
Look, I've been going through a lot
lately, Billy. And with my mom...
Sid, I think you need
to just deal with thatand move on.
I mean, when my mom leftmy dad,
I accepted it.
That's the way the cookie crumbles.
Moms leave.
Yeah, yourmom lefttown. She's not
buried in a cemetery somewhere.
My mom's dead, and she's
never coming back. Ever.
- Stupid.
- Ooh, I love scary movies.
I'll waitforvideo.
Okay, let's get down to business.
The way I see it,
someone's outto make a sequel.
You know, cash in on all
the movie murder hoopla.
So It's our job to observe
the rules ofthe sequel.
Number one:
the body count is always bigger.
Numbertwo: the death scenes are always
more elaborate... more blood, more gore.
Carnage candy.
Your core audience justexpects it.
Numberthree: if you wantyour sequel
to become a franchise, never ever...
How do we find the killer, Randy?
That's what I wanna know.
Oh.
Let's look atthe suspects.
There's Derek, the obvious boyfriend.
Hello, Billy Loomis.
The guy's premed,
and his pity-me surface wound...
conveniently missed
every majorvein and artery.
- So you think it's Derek?
- Notso fast.
Let's assume the killer, or'ers,
has a half a brain.
He's nota Nlck At Nlte
rerun type of guy.
He wants to break some new ground.
- Right? So forgetthe boyfriend.
- Right.
- It's tired. Who else do we got?
- There's...
Mickey, the freaky
Tarantino film student.
But if he's a suspect, so am I.
So, let's move on.
Whoa, waita...
Let's notmove on.
Maybe you are a suspect.
Well, if I'm a suspect,
you're a suspect.
You have a point.
- Okay, let's move on to...
- Hallie.
- Sid's roommate?
- Uh-huh.
Serial killers
are typicallywhite males.
That's why it's perfect. It's sort of
againstthe rules, but not really.
Mrs Voorhees was
a terrific serial killer.
And there's always room
for Candyman's daughter.
She's sweet. She's deadly.
She's bad foryourteeth.
Come on, Randy.
These kids are yourfriends.
Who do you think's the killer?
- How about Gale Weathers?
- Gale? A killer?
- Why not?
- Well, she is vicious enough.
- She's an opportunist.
- Yeah.
Isn't itconceivable
she's planning her next book?
That's what reporters do, Dewey.
They stage the news.
No. Gale's a lotofthings,
but Gale's nota killer.
- Just because you're sweeton her...
- No, I'm not.
Please, this is me talking.
Randy,
the unrequited love-slave
of Sidney Prescott.
I know all aboutobsession...
and pain.
- You've gotyour love scarto prove it.
- And so do you.
And what's with that limp anyway?
'Cause you were stabbed in the back.
Severed nerve.
Look, Gale's no killer.
Okay, okay.
Whateveryou say.
But if she's nota killer,
she's a target.
Joel, let's get
some establishing shots.
Um, Gale, can we talk for a sec?
- What is it?
- Look, I'm a little confused here.
I mean, with your given track record,
whywould you wanna be here
when the killer strikes again?
I mean, granted, I should've
read your book before I took this job.
But I'm reading it now,
and... Whoo!
I read what happened
to your lastcameraman.
The guy got gutted.
Now, me,
I'm gonna do whatany
rational human being would do,
which is getthe fuck outof here.
Firstof all, he wasn't gutted.
I made that up. His throatwas slashed.
Whatare you... Gale, gutted, slashed...
The guy ain't in the union no more.
It's a job, Joel.
And like every job,
there's a few drawbacks.
Butyou're a professional cameraman.
You've gotto act like one.
Yeah, but I wanna report the news.
I don'twanna be the news.
Besides, brothers don't last long
in situations like this.
This is national television.
Think about it.
This is a big chance foryou.
The story is monumental.
Don'tyou wanna be a part ofthat?
Come on.
I need you.
I cannot do this withoutyou.
Good. Come on.
- Let's getsome work done.
- Yeah, let's go get killed.
We've been through thls before.
You knowwhat I thlnk about
your potentlal as an actress.
I know. I know.
It-It's justthatwith,
um, the murders...
and the movie and my life...
I do know how difficult
it is foryou.
Gus, l-ljust...
I don'tthink I can do it.
The battle forthe soul is
fought in the forum of art.
You're a fighter, Sid. That's why you're
here. That's why this is yourmajor.
- Yeah, I'm a fighter.
- I didn't hearthat.
- I'm a fighter.
- I don't believe you.
I don't.
I'm a fighter.
Okay.
So, atthe risk of sounding
like a college drama teacher,
if you've got pain around
this kind of material, use it.
This is your role, Sid.
Cassandra is one ofthe great
tragic visionaries of literature.
She saw It all comlng. :
the wars,
the murder, the madness.
She knew she was cursed.
Itwas herfate,
and she embraced it.
None ofus can avold ourfate,
but as an artlst...
you can honestly face it...
and fight it.
- You're good.
- There's no understudy. I'm desperate.
[Sighs]
You can do this.
Okay, everybody. Gather around.
Third Act, one lasttime.
Cue the muslc.
- // [Dramatlc]
- [Thunderclaps]
[Crackling]
[Chorus] All, behold
the dreaded fate ofTroy...
that once stood proud and llght
upon the hllls ofSparta.!
Now shrouded in
the deathly smoke of ruin,
her royal children
pitched from herwalls,
her people driven through her ruins.
And now alone
in fate's cruel isolation...
stands Cassandra,
her kingdom, family and friends...
driven to the wind.
- [Thunderclap]
- No crime against gods orman...
have I committed,
save to speak the truth.
[All] And each hideous vision
born from my mind...
has come to pass.
Troy has fallen,
not by my hand orwish,
butas I foresaw.
So now, fate's vengeful eye...
is fixed...
on me.
[Chorus] Tell us, O Cassandra,
where has the sweetness...
of life gone?
Whatstays fate's hand
from striking now atthee?
Whatstays fate's hand from thee?
[Screaming]
[Dlrector]
All rlght, hold lt. Hold lt.!
Everyone, take five.
[Sniffling]
Sidney?
[Sldney Pantlng]
Sid. Your escort has arrived.
- Derek, how long have you been here?
- ljust got here.
- Is everything okay? What's goin' on?
- What happened to Mickey?
We swapped. He had to edit.
You getme instead. What happened?
Derek, don't.
Don't. l-ljust need to be alone
right now, okay?
Being alone is notthe answer, Sid.
Yeah, well, I think it is.
I need some distance.
Well, do I geta say in this?
No.
I guess I'm supposed to be...
understanding.
Yeah.
[Sniffles]
You got it.
All right. Let's justassume
the killer is repeating Woodsboro...
- [Phone Rlnglng]
- Yes?
- I have Bob calling.
- I'll have to callyou back.
[Dewey]
That doesn't explaln Sldney's attack.
Sldney wasn't kllled In Woodsboro.
Wasn'tfor a lack oftrying.
The killer's trying
to finish whatwas started.
- Sid's under protection, right?
- Yeah.
- [Phone Ringing]
- What?
- Bob really needs to talk to you...
- Tell Bob I'll call hlm back.
- When'd she startsmoking?
- Ever since those
nude pictures on the internet.
Itwas justmy head.
ItwasJennifer Aniston's body.
Anyway, you're forgettlng somethlng.
In Woodsboro, there were more victims
before the homestretch...
Tatum, my cameraman, Himbry...
Time out! I don't need to be hearing
about no dead cameramen, all right?
I'm warnlng you guys. I am a verb away
from vacatln'these premlses.
I'm gonna getme some coffee,
donuts, Prozac,
see If I can find some crack,
Speclal K..."X, "not Malcolm...
and I'll be back when you guys
start talking aboutsomething...
a little more Saved By The Bell-lsh,
all right?
- He seems a little shaky.
- Don'tworry about him.
lfthe killer is following a pattern,
maybe we can figure outwho's next.
I wouldn't follow a klller's pattern.
We were all Involved In Woodsboro.
Could be any one ofus.
So what do you wanna do, bonehead?
Sit here, waitand see who drops next?
- Well, I don't know. "Phonehead."
- [Phone Rlnglng]
- [Rlnglng Contlnues]
- Gale's not here!
[Distorted Voice]
I'm not interrupting anything, am I?
You three look deep in thought.
Have you everfelta knife cutthrough
human flesh and scrape the bone beneath?
- [Sinister Laughter]
- It's him.
- Who?
- The killer.
[Randy]
He can see us.
- Just keep him on the phone.
- What do you wantme to say?
l-I don't know. Just keep him talking.
Come on, Gale.
- Uh... Hi.
- [Gale] Whatare we doing?
[Dewey]
Look for somebodywith a cell phone.
- So what's yourfavourite scary movie?
- You'll neverfind me.
What do you care?
Let'em have theirfun.
So, uh... What's up?
[Volce]
What's your favourlte scary movle?
Showglrls. Absolutely frightening.
What's yours?
- [Girl Gasps] What's your problem?
- Sorry.
Wait. Letme guess.
The House On Sororlty Row?
Dorm That Drlpped Blood?
Splatter Unlverslty?
Graduatlon Day? Flnal Exam?
- Am I close?
- Closerthan you think.
Too slow, geek.
Do you wantto die?
Is thatthe bestyou can do? Because
Billy and Stu were much more original.
- Gimme that!
- Hey!
- Who's this?
- Who's thls?
- Gale Weathers,
author of The Woodsboro Murders.
- Who?
Come on.
Okay.
He's gotta be
around here someplace.
He's just playing with us.
White male suspect...
nine o'clock.
- My clock oryour clock?
- Your clock.
I'll go around the back.
Why are you even here, Randy?
You'll never be the leading man.
Fuck you!
No matter how hard you try,
you'll never be the hero,
and you'll never, ever get the glrl.
- Wait!
- Shit! Sorry.
- Hey, man...
- Wrong guy, dead boy.
Oh, yeah? Well, let's redirect
a moment, Mr I'm-So-Original.
- [Glrl] What's she dolng?
- [Boy] I don't know.
Hey! Ah!
- [Woman On Phone] What just happened?
- Whatthe hell are you doing?
- Acitizen's arrest...
- Can I help you?
- Hello? Hello?
- Sorry. Beg your pardon.
Where's your innovation? Why copycat
two high school loser-ass dickheads?
Stu was a pussy-ass wet rag.
And Billy Loomis...
Billy Loomis! Whatthe fuck!
Jesus! Whata rat-lookin',
homo-repressed mama's boy!
Why notsetyour goals higher, huh?
You wanna be one
ofthe big boys? Huh?
Manson, Bundy, O.J., Son...
// [Hip-Hop Playing On Boom Box]
- Where's Randy?
- I don't know. Thls guy just grabbed me.
- I'm okay, Mom.
- I don'tsee him.
Randy!
Ah!
What's goin' on?
Yo, man.
Who broke mywindow?
[Screaming]
[Bell Tolllng]
Did your computer justfreeze?
You have an Instant message, that's all.
Just hlt "alt-M. "
Yeah, but I'm notslgned on.
Someone here in the library.
All the terminals are connected.
- He's here.
- Shlt.
Get here away from the computer.
Sld, It's probably just a slck joke.
- May I see yourscreen, please.
- Wait right here.
Yeah.
- Psst! Sid, you okay?
- [Gasps]
- Cotton.
- Can we talk for a sec?
Um, this, this isn'ta good time.
[Scoffs] Come on, Sid.
You sentme to prison.
I did over a yearforyou.
You can give me two minutes.
Cotton, I'm sorry. Every day I'm sorry.
I don't know howto apologize any more.
Don't be sorry. Sorry-schmarry, Sid.
I have the solution to all our problems.
Whatare you talking about?
Firstof all, forget Gale Weathers.
She doesn't get it.
She doesn'tsee the story.
She wouldn'tsee the story if
itsmacked her in the side ofthe head.
I mean, have you read that book?
Which brings me to my point.
Who calls me outofthe blue,
but Diane Sawyer.
Believe me,
I was as shocked as you are.
She tells me that if you and I
go on the airtogether,
- she will give us the entire hour.
- What?
We're talking prime time, Sid.
You, me and Diane Sawyer.
- Cotton, I can't.
- No, no. Look, Sidney.
lfthis is aboutmoney,
it's not like we're not getting paid.
There's $10,000 each,
notto mention what I've got
going on the side with the 900 number.
- Cotton...
- I know, I know, I know.
You don't like the press.
I knowthat, and I respect it.
But-But, Sidney...
[Chuckling]
It's Diane Sawyer. Hello?
She's a class act. Sidney, this could
be some very, very heavy exposure.
I'm sorry.
[Chuckles]
Look, between the movie
and the book...
people knowthe truth.
Let's geton with our lives.
There's been enough exposure.
Whywould you wantany more?
Why? I don't know, Sidney.
I don't know.
Uh, maybe because I fucking deserve
a little exposure? [Laughs]
I mean, come on, Sidney.
You dragged my name through the mud.
Everybody thinks I'm
some kind of psycho killer,
and all I'm asking for
is one fucklng Diane Sawyer interview...
to maybe get my side
ofthe story straight.
Now, I don'tthink I'm being
unreasonable in that request.
Do you? Honestly?
I'm... sorry, Cotton, but no.
You're sorry.
Yeah, I betyou're real sorry,
Sidney.
Such a good angle, Sidney.
Loveable and fucked-up Sidney Prescott!
Everybody's favourite little victim!
- Ow! Whatare you doing?
- Relax!
- Putyour hands on top of your head!
- Shutthe fuck up!
Jesus! I'm not Billy Loomis!
You killed him! He's dead! Remember?
Run it by me one more time, willya?
- Why did you attack Sidney Prescott?
- I didn't... There was no attack.
We were talklng very heatedly.
Miss Prescottand I...
have a very complicated past.
I didn'tthink thatwas a crime.
- No, but homicide is.
- Okay then, book me. Book me.
Okay? Look.
[Chuckles]
I don't know about homlclde,
butyou've definltely...
gotme for raising my voice
in a public library.
We're deallng wlth four murders here.
You watch your mouth.
[Phone Rlnglng]
Thatshouldn't have been Randy.
- Itshould have been me.
- No.
I should call his mother.
Sid, I already made
that phone call.
Are you okay?
Stop treating me like glass, Dewey.
I'm not gonna break.
It's okay to break.
It's not gonna happen.
[Chlef] You better hope
yourallbl's alrtlght.
Could I please remind everyone here
that I'm an innocentman.
Don'tyou watch TV? Current Edition?
Thatwas a very Inslghtful programme...
on which itwas made abundantly clear
that I'm an innocentman.
So untilyou find me standing over
a dead bodywith a knife in my hand,
I thlnk you bettertreat me
wlth the rlghts and prlvlleges...
accorded to every innocentcitizen
in this country.
I don't... Is there... Is there
some problem with the word "innocent"?
I know. It's a big one.
Chief?
[DoorOpens, Closes]
- What's golng on?
- I have to let him go.
- Why?
- We don't have anythlng on hlm.
Sign here.
Gale.
Enjoying the show?
- Cops are funny.
- What do you think you're doing?
Waiting formy 15 minutes offame.
You can understand that,
can'tyou, Gale?
Don't do anything stupid, Cotton.
Gale, you were so instrumental
in my freedom.
You're not having
character doubts now, are you?
- Sidney, if you change yourmind...
- Come on. Take a hike.
Sorry aboutthat.
Whata creep.
They're gonna take you
somewhere safe, Sid.
Yeah? Where's that.
I don't know,
but I'll be there with you.
We should get going.
We'll take you by the dorm,
and you can pack some things.
We've issued a campus lock-in
this evening.
- No one's allowed outafter dark, okay?
- Yeah.
Who's doing this, Dewey?
I mean, if not Cotton, then who?
I don't know, Sid,
but I'll find him.
Any leads, Gale? Do you think
the killerwill come afteryou?
How does itfeel to be
on the other side ofthe news?
There's Cotton.
Cotton! Hey!
- Are you still a suspect?
- It's all been a huge misunderstanding.
- Have you been officially released?
- Gale! Hang on one second.
How abouta photo?
No? You look great.
How're you holding up, Gale?
Must be scary knowing
somebody's outthere waiting,
watching, enjoying all this.
- How does thatmake you feel?
- Look, local woman!
I knowthatyou hold me up
as your careertemplate...
and it gives you some sort of...
charge to challenge me.
But give ita rest!
You're right. I'm sorry.
It's my...
Itwas the wrong time.
I'm sorry.
- What's going on?
- Whoo, let's see.
For starters, they impounded my van.
It's now an official crime scene,
thanks to you.
Here's yourfootage. Enjoy.
See ya.
Wouldn'twanna be ya.
Joel, I need you!
No. No, you need to
have your head examined.
- I feel bad, Dewey.
- [Englne Startlng]
I feel really bad.
I never say that because...
I neverfeel bad aboutanything.
But I feel bad now.
Is this justanother...
brilliant Gale Weathers performance?
There are no cameras here.
ljustwanna find this fucker!
l... I really do.
Me too.
Could I give you a hand?
What's in here?
Justsome crowd footage thatJoel shot.
Hey, waita minute.
lfthe killer really is watching
and relishing every minute,
then he'd be here on these tapes,
right?
- Ateach crime scene.
- It's worth a look.
It's definitelyworth a look.
This way.
Dubbing room.
Editorial.
Video archive.
- It's locked.
- Can you pick it?
- Thatwould be breaking and entering.
- No shit.
There's gotta be a VCR
around here somewhere.
What's in there?
- Nowwe're gettin' somewhere.
- Perfect!
- Let's startwlth thls one.
- [Tape Clatters On Floor]
- Sorry. Oh!
- Oh!
- Ow.
- I'm sorry.
- Dld I hurtyou?
- No.
[Dewey On TV]
You're a money-hungry, fame-seeklng...
forgive me for saying...
mediocre writer...
who's got a cold storage shed
where her heartshould be.
- I didn'tmean to imply...
- Listen.
- You're cute when you're angry.
- [Mumbles] I was rude.
I was being rude.
[TVContlnues Indlstlnct]
Dewey, I'm sorry.
I nevermeantto hurtyou.
Hey.
Really.
I should be studying.
You know I gota Bio...
Dewey.
Dewey!
- Sorry.
- That's notmy footage.
Outside.
- Fuck you!
- No matter how hard you try,
you'll never be the hero,
and you'll never, ever getthe girl.
- Sorry.
- Wrong guy, dead boy.
- Stay here.
- Dewey, don't!
Dewey!
There's no one there.
[Gasping]
Fuck!
Gale!
Gale?
[No Audio]
No!
So.
Listen, Sid.
Hey, walt up.!
- She's... She's fine.
- I'm hertherapist.
Bye, Derek.
Bye.
We better get going.
When this is all over,
I'll still be here.
[Car Englne Startlng]
You.! Prepare to dle.
- You gave up your letters.
- Oh, man.
I'm not... Uh, guys...
- To Troy! We march!
- Whoo!
[Boys Laughing, Shouting]
This is so romantic.
- And so Greek!
- [Laughing]
/ I was in the wrong place
But itmust have been the righttime /
/ I was In the rlght place
But It must have been the wrong song /
/ I was In the rlghtveln
But ltseemed llke the wrong arm /
/ I was In the rlghtworld
But ltseemed llke the wrong
wrong, wrong /
- / Wrong song //
- Who do you love, baby?
- Sidney.
- Did you say
"my Omega Kappa Beta brothers"?
No, I said Sidney!
So, where are you taking us,
anyway?
lfwe tellyou,
we'll have to killyou.
Don'task; don'ttell.
Help me!
[Hallle Screamlng]
Oh, my God.!
Outta the car, you fucker!
Get down back there!
Pull over, you son-of-a-bitch!
I'll blowyourfuckin' head...
[Screaming]
[Coughing, Gasping]
- Is he dead?
- I don'tthink so.
- He's still breathing.
- Oh!
Oh, is he dead?
Oh, God.
I think so.
- How are you
supposed to getoutta here?
- We're not. It's a cop car.
- [Whining]
- Hallie, it's the onlyway out.
Help me out.
[Sldney]
Come on.
[Gasping]
We're jammed up agalnst a pole.
Oh, my God.
Oh. Oh, my God.
No, Sld.
Don't, Sld.!
[Horn Honks]
God, I hate this shit.
Oh, my God.
Don't do thatagain.
[Hallle]
Try the wlndow.
- Shit!
- Getme the fuck outta here, Sid.
I can't. The door's jammed.
You have to go through the front.
- Oh, no fuckin'way.
- Hallie, do it.
Go on. Hallie, go.
[Whispering]
Okay.
Okay, that's rlght.
Shh.
Okay.
Okay, that's good.
Oh, rightthrough his eye.
Come on.
That's good. Easy. Easy.
He's not gonna hurtyou.
Come on. Let's go.
Let's go.
- Hallie.
- What?
I wanna knowwho it is.
- Oh, no. Come on, Sid. Let's just go.
- I'm going back.
Look, look.
Stupid people go back.
Smart people run. We're smart people, so
we should just getthe fuck outta here.
Hallie, I'm sick of running.
- lfwe knowwho it is, then it's over.
- No, we can just getthe police.
And when we come back, he'll be gone.
It'll only take a minute.
- I have to do this.
- Sid. No, Sid. Come back!
Sld, come back.
Shlt.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
- He's gone!
- [Screaming]
- [Hallle] No.!
- [Screams]
- Gale.
- No, no. This isn'twhat it looks like.
- Getaway from me.
I found Dewey. I tried to help him.
l... No, no. Gale, wait.
Gale! Gale, wait! Gale!
Shit.
- You can't mlss the street...
- Help me!
...curfew in full effect.
- Give me the goddam phone!
- I was right in the middle of a story.
- I've gotyour goddam story!
- What's the matter?
- Operator, this is an emergency!
Getme the police!
- What's happening?
- The killer. It's Cotton-fucking-Weary!
Cotton Weary?
[DoorCloses]
[Footsteps]
// [Symphonic]
// [Contlnues]
Hello?
Gus?
// [Discontinued]
Hello?
Hello...
[Gasps]
[Screams]
Derek?
Oh, God.
Derek! Oh, God.
Thank you. Thank God, Sid. Thought I was
gonna be up there till opening night.
- Shit! Who tied these?
We gotta getoutta here.
- The brothers gotme, Sid.
- He's outthere. He killed Hallie.
- Whatare you talking about?
- The killer! He's here.
- Where?
[Dlstorted Volce]
Rlght here.
- You're fast, Sld.
- Getme down. Hurry!
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
You reallywanna trustyour boyfriend?
[Mickey's Voice]
Don'tyou know history repeats itself?
Hmm, Sld?
Mickey.
[Distorted Voice]
Surprise, Sidney.
- Whatthe fuck?
- Since Derek here disappeared on my ass,
I been on my own all fuckln'nlght.
- Thanks a lot, partner.
- You motherfucker!
[Derek] Sld, he's crazy.
You know me betterthan that.
Come on, Sld.
I gotta have a partner.
I couldn't have possibly
done this alone.
- God, Derek.
- Sid.
Oh, no, Sid. Sid.
No, no, no, no.
It's okay, Derek.
We got her.
You... Sld, he's lylng.!
Sld.! Sld.! Untle me.
- Sid, untie me.
- Hmm?
Boyfriend. Killer.
Sid, the man is lying!
Untie me. Sid.
Untie me. Untie me.
What do you think, Derek?
Sidney experiencing some deja vu?
No. No.
I am gonna fuckln'klll you.!
Fuckin' killyou!
You are dead! Dead!
- [Screaming] Derek!
- [Groaning]
- Sid. [Groaning]
- Derek.
I'm sorry.
I never...
would've... hurtyou.
Never.
No.
You should really deal
with yourtrust issues, Sid.
I mean, poor Derek. He's completely
innocent. And such a nice boy too.
He's brightand funny and handsome.
Decentsinging voice.
And he was gonna be a doctor.
This was justthe kind of boy
you'd like to take home to Mom.
- If you had a mom.
- Fuck you!
Oh! So vulgar.
Did Billy letyou talk to him this way?
Billywas a sick fuck, just like you.
No. Billywas a sick fuck
who tried to getawaywith it.
Mlckey is a sick fuck
who wants to getcaught. Yeah!
See, I've got my whole defence
planned out.
I'm gonna blame the movies.
Pretty cool, huh?
It hasn't been done before.
You see, this is justthe beginning,
a prelude to the trial.
That's where the real fun is 'cause
these days it's all aboutthe trial.
Can'tyou see it? The effects
of cinema violence on society.
I'll get Dershowltz
orCochran to represent me.
Bob Dole on the witness stand
in my defence.
Hell, the Christian Coalition'll
pay my legal fees.
It's airtight, Sid.
I'm an innocentvictim.
- You're a psychotic.
- Yeah, well. Shh.
[Whispers]
That'll be our little secret.
'Cause people love a good trlal.
It's llke theatre. They're dyln'for lt.
And I've worked hard
to give the audience whattheywant.
That's what Bllly was good at.
He knew... It's all about... executlon.
Yeah? Well, you're forgetting
one thing about Billy Loomis.
What's that?
I fucking killed him.
- [Grunts]
- You piece of shit!
[Cocks Gun]
Sld.
You gota Linda Hamilton thing going.
[Chuckles]
No, no. It's nice. I like it.
Now, who's doin'that?
Could that be... the mystery guest
waltlng In the wlngs?
Told ya I had a partner.
Surprise cameo justforyou.
Gale.
Mrs Loomis?
- What?
- Billy's mother!
Nlce twlst, huh?
Dldn'tsee It comln', dld ya?
Jesus.
Itcan't be. I've...
I've seen pictures of you.
This is 60 pounds
and a lotofwork later.
It's called a make-over.
You should try it.
Look a little tired
yourselfthere, Gale.
- So you two are in this together?
- Yeah, well.
Had to have financing.
Tuition's expensive.
Deb, there... my backer.
We met on the Internet.
Psycho Web slte.
Classlfieds.
There's only an estlmated
97 actlve serlal klllers In the country.
So Mlckey, here, was qulte a find.
Definltely one on the way up.
- All he needed was a little
guidance and nurturing.
- As only a mother can do.
Told you ltwas gonna work.
Walt tlll the trlal.!
It is gonna rock.!
Oh, Mickey.
There's not gonna be a trial.
- [Gunshot]
- Gale!
Two birds, one stone.
Oh, Mickeywas a good boy, but, my God,
thatwhole blame-the-movies motive.
Did you buy thatfor one second?
Poor boywas completely outof his mind.
- And you're not?
- No. I'm very sane.
My motive isn'tas '90s as Mickey's.
Mine is just
good, old-fashioned revenge.
You killed my son!
And now I klll you. And I can't thlnk
ofanythlng more ratlonal.
You're never gonna
getawaywith this.
Of course I will.
Everything's traceable back to Mickey.
Including the cop gun
he used to kill everybody.
But let's justsuppose thatyou...
had gotten hold ofthe other cop's gun.
And you chased Mickey. And there was
a big shoot-outand a big scuffle.
And you shot Mickey,
killed Mickey dead.
[Gun Clatters On Stage]
But not before he gotoff
one shotatyou.
Okay.
So, have I covered everythlng?
Are there any questions, any comments?
You knowwhat, though?
Who give a flyin'fuck anyway?
Let 'em try and track down
the second posslble klller.
Debble Salt doesn't exlst.
You're as crazy as your son was.
What did you justsay?
Was thata negative, disparaging remark
aboutmy son? Aboutmy Billy?
No, Billywas a good boy.
Billywas perfect.
You did a bang-up job, Mrs Loomis.
It's notwise to patronize
a woman with a gun, Sidney.
Randy spoke poorly of Billy,
and I gota little knife-happy.
I was a good mother.
You knowwhatmakes me sick?
I'm sick to death of people saying
that it's all the parents'fault.
That itall starts with the family.
You wanna blame someone?
Why don'tyou blame your mother?
She's the one who stole my husband
and broke up my family.
And then you took my son!
You don't knowwhat it is
to be a mother.
To raise a child and teach him...
and guide him...
And abandon him.
Isn't Mickey supposed to be dead?
[Gunshot]
Don'tyou fuckln' move!
- Goddam it!
- [Sid] Cotton.
Okay, okay, okay.
Everybody slow down.
I have had a very, very bad day,
and I would llke to know exactly
what the fuck Is golng on here.!
- Sldney?
- Cotton, meet Billy Loomis' mother.
She's the killer.
What?
- Then who's that?
- The other killer.
- Mlckey.
- [Scoffs] Okay.
- Look, Cotton...
- Shut up.
So. Hi.
You're, uh, not Debbie Salt, are you?
You're notwith the Post Telegraph.
No, but I can still help you, Cotton.
Ah-ah-ah!
You don't need her.
Letme kill her!
As long as she's allve,
you're never gonna be the lead story.
That's whatyou reallywant,
isn't it, Cotton?
lfyou really wanna be
In the spotllght,
just letme kill her... right now.
Then you're the only survivor.
You're the star!
She sentyou to prison for a year!
Personally,
I thlnk It's rather poetlc.
No. No, Cotton,
don'tyou listen to her.
Oh. [Chuckling]
Well...
It's, uh, quite a predicament
you're in, Sid.
- Cotton...
- I mean, she makes a good point.
Letme think aboutthis.
Maybe you should too.
Betcha that Diane Sawyer interview's
lookin' real good rightabout now.
Huh?
Consider it done.
[Coughing]
Wow.
That... was intense.
Hey, Sidney, uh...
Look, I wantyou to knowthat I would
never, ever do anything to hurtyou.
Cotton, give me the gun.
Yeah. Okay. Sure. Take it.
Hey, Sid, we should talk about
exactlywhat happened here.
You know... I mean, getour stories
straightforthe press statement.
- Oh, shit!
- [Gasping]
- Cotton.
- Could somebody getme outta here?
Gale!
Are you all right?
I been shot.
Of course not.
- Help.!
- Give me your hand, Gale.
- Ow.!
- Jesus, you scared the crap outta me.
- Isn'tanybody else down there,
is there?
- No.
[Cotton] So much for reportlng
from the trenches, huh?
- Shut up, Cotton.
- How bad Is lt?
Just bounced off my ribs.
Geez, Gale,
you gotmore lives than a cat.
Give me one ofthose.
[Gale]
Is she dead?
I don't know.
They always come back.
- [Screaming]
Whoa!
Just in case.
- Thataboutwraps it up, Chief.
- Okay, Frank.
[Man] Take It easy.
You got a couple broken rlbs.
- Greg, I'm okay.
- Sure.
Hey, Gale.
Are you all right?
- Joel.
- I'm... I'm back.
You know, I was thinking maybe we could
getthe scoop like in the old days.
You're Gale Weathers...
atWindsor College.
[Man Shoutlng]
We got a llve one here.!
- Move it!
- [Moaning, Coughing]
- Where's Gale?
- There room In that one overthere?
- Yeah! Watch your back!
- Dewey!
- Let's go!
- Oh, God.
I can't believe you're alive.
- Are you okay?
- Gale.
You hang in there.
- [Mumbling]
- Knlfe went Into some old scartlssue.
Saved hls llfe.
Bye-bye.
- I'm coming with you.
- [Dewey Mumbling]
[Engine Starting, Siren Wailing]
- Can you tell us whatyou saw?
- What happened in there?
Can you tell us how itfeels
to be a hero?
Talk to Cotton.
He's the man you wantto interview.
He's the hero.
- Cotton!
- [Reporters Shouting Questions]
- Whatwenton in there? What happened?
- Is ittrue you're a hero?
- Details, please!
- Look, guys,
no one wants to give you
the story more than I do.
Unfortunately,
there is a time and a place,
and indeed, a price for everything,
so feel free to call me.
[Joel] Come on, Cotton.
Tell us somethlng.
Well, uh, I'll tellyou one thing.
It'll make a hell of a movie.
Thank you.
/ Llfe's rlvershall rlse /
/ She sald /
/ And only the strong shall survlve
she sald /
/ But I'm feellng qulte weak
/ Wlll you comfortand forglve me
she sald /
/ She sald she's stlll searchlng /
/ Forsalvatlon's llght/
/ Yetshe wlshes all day /
/ And then she prays all nlght/
/ She sald she won'tspeak oflove /
/ 'Cause love she's never known /
/ Well, It's moments llke these /
/ When she hates to be alone /
/ Forglve me /
/ She sald //
/ I'm sleepln'and rlght
In the mlddle ofa good dream /
/ When all at once I wake up
from somethlng
that keeps knocklng at my braln /
/ Before I go Insane
I hold my plllowto my head /
/ And sprlng up In my bed
screamlng out the words I dread /
/ I thlnk I love you /
/ I thlnk I love you
So what am I so afrald of/
/ I'm afrald that I'm notsure of
a love there Is no cure for/
/ I thlnk I love you
Isn't thatwhat llfe Is made of/
/ Though ltworrles me to say
that I neverfelt thls way, yeah /
/ Belleve me, you really
don't have to worry /
/ I only wanna make you happy
And lfyou say hey, go away, I wlll /
/ But I thlnk betterstlll
I'd betterstay around and love you /
/ Do you thlnk I have a case
Let me ask you to yourface /
/ I thlnk I love you /
/ Yeah, I thlnk I love you
So what am I so afrald of/
/ I'm afrald that I'm notsure of
a love there Is no cure for/
/ I thlnk I love you
Isn't thatwhat llfe Is made of/
/ Though ltworrles me to say
that I neverfelt thls way, yeah /
/ I don't knowwhat I'm up agalnst
I don't knowwhat It's all about/
/ I gotso much to thlnk about
Yeah /
/ Yeah, I thlnk I love you
So what am I so afrald of/
/ I'm afrald that I'm notsure of
a love there Is no cure for/
/ Do you thlnk you love me /
/ I thlnk I love you /
/ I thlnk I love you //
/ Paln goes away
I dlg a hole /
/ When It goes away
I'll dlg a hole /
/ Runnln', goln'out at nlght/
/ Frlends, they push and pull you /
/ Burned out ground
Poorflowers /
/ Splnnlng, falllng outta tlme /
/ When It goes away
I'll dlg a hole /
/ La-la-la-la, ooh /
/ I'll dlg a hole /
/ When It goes away //
/ I'm remlnded /
/ Someone thought they knew me /
/ That I hadn't changed at all /
/ Wrapped up
In a plcture perfect package /
/ That juststands up way too tall /
/ Because they see my world /
/Ooh, through the eyes ofsand /
/ You walk In desert
Baby, you're a pollshed stone /
/Ooh, oh /
/ You don't know my world /
/ Ah-ah /
/ You walk In the desert/
/ And I walk In the desert/
/ Yeah, I walk In the desert//
Scream.!
[Indlstlnct Chatter]
- [Woman Screamlng]
- Could be your best frlend.
Could be yourenemy.
/ Scream
I hear hlm comlng /
/ I see hlm comlng
I hear hlm comlng, peace /
/ Y'all be trlppln'
Man, the ghetto got me, I know lt/
/ I be llke eyes open
turnln'wlth both ofmy toys on hlm /
/ These daydreams
sometlmes turn to nlghtmares /
/ I be trylng to shake It
but ltseem to be llke rlght there /
/ I know some homles who made deals
fora short tlme to llve good /
/ Butwhen lts all overyou should see
the data that'll put 'em out the hood /
/One, two, I'm comln'foryou /
/ Three, four
I'm klckln'up In yourdoor/
/ Thls whole llfe
ltseem to be a bad dream /
/ Scream as loud as you want but
aln't nobody gonna hearyourscream /
/ Scream
I hear hlm comlng /
/ I see hlm comlng
I hear hlm comlng //