Moving onto the Hollywood Freeway,
we have a multiple vehicle...
multiple injury accident.
An absolute mess
from VineStreet to the valley.
If you're in it,
expect a long commute.
If you're not,
seek alternate routes.
If Dan doesn 't want to do a daily rate,
we can talk about a weekly rate.
But I'm tellin' you right now,
I'm not goin' below a million.
I mean, think about it.
I'm risking my reputation...
as the host
of this country's number-one...
nationally syndicated talk show to do
a cameo in some cheap slasher flick.
I mean, why can't these guys write me
a fuckin' decent part?
You know?
I lived through the fuckin' thing.
By the way, did you talk to Cathy
about that Navy SEAL script?
Hang on a sec.
- Hello?
- Who's this?
- Who are you calling?
- Oh. You know what?
- I'm sorry. I have the wrong number.
- That's okay.
Wait a minute. I know your voice.
You sound a lot like that guy on TV.
Um, Cotton Weary.
- I do, huh?
- Yeah.
I think he's got
a really sexy voice.
- Well, thank you.
- Wait a minute.
You are Cotton, aren't you?
Oh, my God.
I am talking to Cotton Weary.
I can't believe this.
You got me. Look, I've--
I've got someone on the other line.
Can you hold on one second?
I'll be right back, I promise.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Andrea, uh, I gotta call you back.
Someone's on the other line.
So, uh, you a big 100% Cotton fan?
- Yeah! One hundred and ten percent.
- That's very good.
So, um, why don't you tell me
who you are?
Ooh! You're a naughty boy, Cotton.
Now, what would your girlfriend say?
What makes you think
I have a girlfriend?
I know you do.
- I'm right outside her bathroom door.
- Who is this?
She's in the shower.
She's got a nice little voice.
Let's come in for a closer look.
She's very pretty, Cotton.
A step up from
Maureen Prescott.
Speaking of which,
let's play a little game.
Answer right,
your girlfriend lives.
Answer wrong, she dies.
- Where's Maureen's daughter, Sidney?
- Who the fuck is this?
Somebody who'd kill to know
where Sidney Prescott is!
One chance, Cotton!
You've got connections. Where is she?
You listen to me, you fuckin' psycho.
You lay a finger on Christine...
- and I swear to God I'll kill you.
- Wrong answer!
No! Wait!
Hello? Shit!
- Hey!
- Get outta the way!
- You just hit me!
- Move!
Christine, if you're there,
pick up the phone!
Christine, pick up the phone!
Oh, shit!
You have reached 911.
Due to the volume of calls--
Someone pick up the goddam phone!
Move outta the way!
Shit! Shit!
Cotton, is that you?
Cotton?
Honey?
Okay, Cotton.
You know I don't like
your Stab games.
- Who is it? Who's there?
- Christine?
Hon, you all right?
- I'm home.
-Jesus! You scared the shit outta me.
- You're not gonna believe
what just happened to me.
- What are you talking about?
- Get the hell out of here!
- Okay. Okay, I'm sorry, babe.
I didn't mean to scare you that bad.
It's me. Come on, open the door.
- What are you doing?
- What?
- What the fuck are you doing?
I was-- I was just, you know, trying
to take the game to the next level.
- I'm sorry. Come on,
open the door, Chris.
- The game?
- Yeah, the game!
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about how much fun it's
gonna be to rip your insides out!
Now, open the fuckin' door, Christine!
- Oh, my God!
- Now you're fuckin' history, baby!
Christine?
Hon?
The recent epidemic of roadrage
in Los Angeles.
- Innocent commuters mercilessly
terrorized, even killed...
- Chris?
- by these madmen of the freeway.
- Don't mess around, okay?
We're gonna make them confront their
victims face-to-face, mano a mano...
right here on 100% Cotton.
There is carnage on our streets.
And remember, it could happen to you.
Tomorrow on 100% Cotton!
Roadrage.
L.A. drivers fight back.
The news is next on channel six with our
exclusive entertainment report live...
from tonight's celebrity
premiere in Hollywood...
followed by--
Oh, shit.
Chris?
Is that you, babe?
Chris, if you're in there,
open the door. Okay, honey?
Chris? Come on, baby.
Open the door.
Chris! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Jesus!
- It's me, Chris. What are you doin'?
- Stay back.
Stay back.
- Chris, what's goin' on, babe?
- You've gone crazy. That's what!
- Chris, was somebody in the house?
- No! Get back!
Okay, okay, okay.
Just calm down, okay?
- Why do you want to kill me?
- What are you talking about?
- Why do you wanna kill me?
- Gimme the club. All right, honey?
Gimme the club.
Gimme the club, please.
Christine, get outta the way!
Behind you!
Shit!
It was a simple game, Cotton.
You should've told me where Sidney was.
Now, you lose.
Come on.
Come on, Cherokee.
California Women's Crisis Counseling.
Hey, it's Laura from Monterrey reporting
to work. Can you patch me in?
- Sure. Thanks, Laura.
- Thank you.
California Women's Crisis Counseling.
How can I help you?
Hi. Um, do I have to say my name?
No, you don't have to say anything
you don't want to say.
- How can I help?
- Um--
I'm 18 years old,
and I have a boyfriend.
- Sometimes he hits me.
- It's okay.
- You can talk to me, all right?
- Thanks.
So, in closing, as
the future journalists of America...
there is one thing
that you need to remember.
Being the best means being willing
to do what the others would not.
Break the rules.
Stop at nothing.
Be willing to have the world hate you,
because that is the only way...
that you'll get the story,
the facts and the fame.
Thank you.
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Yes?
So you're saying that we should
be ready to go out...
and cut each other's throats
because that's what you did.
- Metaphorically, yes.
- Well, tell me, Miss Weathers.
- Was it worth it?
- I'm so sorry. We're out of time.
Gale Weathers, anchor woman for
Total Entertainment.
Thank you very much!
There is a young man outside
who wants to see you.
- He says he's with the police.
- The police?
- Detective Mark Kincaid, L.A.P.D.
- Hello.
- That's quite an impressive resume.
- Thank you.
I assume you're not here
for an autograph.
I'm here because
Cotton Weary's been murdered.
- Someone killed Cotton?
- And his girlfriend.
Someone who left something
he wanted us to see.
I'll show you this because
you're the Woodsboro authority
and because you knew him.
But I promise you,
if you share this with the world,
it's you I'll be arresting.
I swear on my Pulitzer Prize, which
I plan to win one day, Detective.
This was left on Cotton Weary's body.
You have any idea who the girl might be?
Oh, my God.
This is Maureen Prescott.
This is Sidney Prescott's mother.
Hollywood is reeling today
from news...
of the murder of controversial
talkshow host Cotton Weary.
Weary had only recently finished
shooting a cameo as himself...
in the film
Stab 3, Return to Woodsboro...
the third and final part
of the famous horror series...
based on the Woodsboro
and Windsor College murders.
Before his rise to television fame,
Cotton had been imprisoned...
and was later exonerated for the murder
of Maureen Prescott, his former lover--
Just yesterday, Cotton Weary was
shooting here at Sunrise Studios...
his first cameo
in a feature film, Stab 3.
Security here is tight, but we'll see
if we can get a statement. Excuse me.
Always a controversial man--
Channel Eight news.
We gotta get in. We gotta get in.
No press beyond this point.
Alone at night
he crosses flames
Ashe makes a fist
with his red right hand
Look, you're worried about the movie,
then protect the movie, okay?
Hire more security. Hire the National
Guard.Just don't kill the movie.
Violence in cinema
is a big deal right now, Roman.
This is not the kind of news
this studio is after.
So if we stop making
scary movies, what?
All the psychos in the world
will retire? Come on.
I've been makin' horror movies for
30 years, never had a psycho problem.
He was your goddamn idea, guys.
All right?
An ex-con with a trashy talk show?
He must've pissed people off every day.
Detectives, there's no reason
to presume that Cotton's death...
had anything to do
with this movie, is there?
He was making a movie called Stab.
He was stabbed.
Probably some psycho fan pissed off
they killed Randy in Stab 2.
Well, Tyson, that'd make you next,
wouldn't it?
I am not a Randy substitute.
I'm my own character.
Named Ricky,
who works at the video store.
It's an homage.
Hey! What if the killer's
Sidney Prescott?
I mean, what the hell ever happened to
her? She's probably off in the woods...
livin' like
the fuckin' Unabomber, man.
I'm starting to see why
Tori Spelling and David Schwimmer
didn't want to come back.
Guys, this was about Cotton.
We are not in any danger.
"We are not in any danger,"
says Candy, page 15.
I don't see you leavin'.
You think serious black actors
my age can just throw away jobs?
It's all a business now. They got
Usher doing Pinter off-Broadway.
L.L. Cool J's
Shakespearin' in the park.
- Yeah!
- Maybe it's not meant to be.
Not meant to be? You win that
talent search for the new Sidney.
50,000 girls and they pick you. You
gotta be praying this movie keeps going.
Of course I am, but not
at the expense of people's lives.
Oh. Cue the violins, right?
Jesus.
Deja voodoo.
We need this area cleared, please.
Clear it.
- Gale Weathers! Oh, my God!
- Shit.
I-- Listen,
I-I-- I know we've never met...
and I don't mind you never returning
my calls, but I have to tell you...
after two films,
I feel like I am in your mind.
Well, that would explain
my constant headaches.
You know, I'm sorry things didn't
work out on 60 Minutes II.
- But Total Entertainment,
that's a pretty good fallback.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry that things didn't
work out with Brad Pitt...
but being single,
that's a pretty good fallback.
Gives me more time
for my work.
After all, Gale Weathers,
you're such a complex character.
Oh, and to be played by an actress
with such depth and range.
Uh,Jennifer,
Nick said you wanted to--
Gale.
Dewey.
Well, surprise, surprise.
Someone dies and Gale comes running.
Gale, I think you'll really appreciate
my character work in this one.
- Someone's helped me
understand the real you.
- Someone?
Your ruthless ambition,
your private self-loathing...
and that lost and lonely
little girl inside.
Lost and lonely what?
You heard me.
Thanks, Dewey, I'll return it.
Lost and lonely what?
- Little girl inside.
- I thought you were
supposed to be in Woodsboro.
Well, I'm surprised
you thought about me at all.
Listen, I gotta get back to work.
I really don't have time for this.
- Wait a minute. You work here?
- Yeah.
The movie needed
a technical advisor.
Someone who went through the real
experience, knew the real people.
- Hey, Dewey.
- Hey, Tom.
Hey! It's the real Gale Weathers.
Real from top to bottom.
Tom Prinze.
Watch your show all the time.
You're so right. Pop culture
is the politics ofthe 21 st century.
- Thank you.
- And that story that you did...
last month on me crashing my car?
-Wow, was that ever powerful journalism.
-Right, uh--
I especially liked the way
you implied that it was caused
by drinking and drugs.
And that the tyre blowout was faked.
That was great.
Tom, sometimes in journalism
you have to--
Are you parked in the lot?
'Cause I should check to make sure...
that nobody's messed
with your brake line.
Who's he supposed to be?
He's playing you? Him?
What?
I did not come here
to fight with you, Dewey.
- Cotton's killer left a picture.
- Of Sid's mom.
- The detectives told me.
- Well, does Sidney know about it?
Listen, Sidney doesn't need
you and your camera in her life.
Do you see a camera?
Right. You bought me
this purse, didn't you?
- Yeah.
- Look, it's-it's a habit.
-I-I walk outta the house, I turn it on.
-What the hell is this?
- It's like perfume.
- Gale Weathers?
- Could I be more popular?
- No press.
Mo press on set.
Get that woman outta here.
- Yes, Mr Milton. Let's go.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Where is Detective Kincaid?
- I am working with Kincaid, Dewey.
- Come on. Move along, miss. Let's go.
Rules are rules, Gale.
But, really, it was great seeing you.
Stab 3 is a closed set. But just up
ahead is the old Seinfeld stage.
Now, does anybody
need a potty break?
- Oh, I do.
- Yeah, me too.
Okay, let go!
Thanks for your help, boys.
Holy shit, Silent Bob. It's that
TV news chick, Connie-fuckin'-Chung!
Hey, Connie, how's Maury?
Dude, I think she likes me.
See how she's lookin' at me?
It's happening again.
Cotton had a lot
of enemies, Sid.
The police aren't saying
it's related to us.
Do you ever think about her?
Your mom?
None of this would've
ever happened if she hadn't--
if she hadn't--
Why'd she have
so many secrets, Dad?
Listen, maybe it's time
you came home.
I'm worried about you, kid. Out here
by yourself. You never see anyone.
The only people you talk to
don't even know your real name.
It's as if you don't exist.
That's the idea. Psychos
can't kill what they can't find.
Sid, come here.
Mother needs to talk to you.
Everything you touch, Sid, dies!
You're poison.
You're just like me.
Oh, my God!
What have they done to me?
They'll do it to you.
- They'll do it to you, baby.
- Mom?
Roman?
Stab 3.
Jesus, I gotta get a new agent.
Roman?
Someone here?
Stan, my man.
He does good work, huh?
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Fuck you very much.
- Tyson, go to hell.
- Well, excuse us, Sarah. Makeup tests.
Yeah, makeup. You can use it.
Damn it, have you seen Roman?
Look, everyone in the office
has gone home already.
- He said it was important.
- Everything's important to Roman.
Oh, shit!
- Director's office.
- Sarah, it's Roman.
I'm sorry I'm running late. I'm still
on the 405. I'm about ten minutes away.
Oh, it's no problem. I'm just
lookin' at your music video awards.
Since I got you on thephone, let's--
let's talk about your character, okay?
What character? I'm Candy,
the chick who gets killed second.
- I'm only in two scenes.
- You're not happy with your part.
I'm not happy that I am
35 playing a 21-year-old.
I'm not happy
that I have to die naked.
And I'm not happy that my character is
too stupid to have a gun in the house...
after her boyfriend's
been cut into fish sticks.
Great, okay.
So let's--let's run the lines.
Fine.
Page28.
Candy's big moment.
Page 28.
Ring-ring.
Hello?
- Hello?
- Who's this?
- This is Candy.
Hang on.
Let me get some clothes.
See? I don't understand why I have
to start the scene in the shower.
The whole shower thing's been done.
Vertigo. Hello?
And I mean, my boyfriend just died.
Why am I showering?
Why don't we just read the scene?
Candy. Nice name. Is that like
Candy Cane or Candy Apple?
Whatever.
Come on.
Who is this?
I think you have
the wrong number.
- But you know my favourite name?
- I'm hanging up right now.
It's Sarah.
Roman, that's not the line.
It is in my script.
Has there been another goddam rewrite?
How the fuck...
are we supposed to learn our lines when
there's a new script every 15 minutes?
It's not just a new script.
It's a new movie.
- What? What movie?
- My movie.
And it's called Sarah Gets
Skewered Like a Fuckin' Pig!
Still in character, Sarah?
Shit.
Thank you for calling
Sunrise Picture Studios.
If you'd like today's
commissary menu, press one.
Mr Bridger?
If you'd like to hear previews of
upcoming Sunrise Pictures'releases...
press four.
If you'd like information about
Sunrise Pictures' merchandise...
- Come on. Come on.
- press five.
If you're trying to reach Lot Security
or you have an emergency, press six.
Shit!
Oh! Fuck!
Look, I wanna get something straight.
I only got into this because
the police asked for my help.
- Why would the police come to you?
- Well, I did write..
the definitive book
on the Woodsboro murders.
I'm sure you just can't wait
to write another one.
- What about you?
- What about me?
You said you'd never leave Woodsboro.
"It's the only place that's real."
But now you're here.
Not with me.
Dewey, I took care ofyou.
I waited until you were well,
but I couldn't stay there.
It was like dog years. One year in
Woodsboro is like seven anywhere else.
So it's off to Paris for a week?
New York for a month? L.A. forever?
It was fucking 60 Minutes II.
- I couldn't say no. I could've
been the next Diane Sawyer.
- Wait a minute.
What's wrong with just being
Gale Weathers? I liked her.
It didn't work, Dewey.
We tried. We're different.
You used to say
that was our strength.
- Well--
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Dewey, you're not just here because
of that second-rate K-Mart...
straight-to-video
version of me, are you?
Brace yourself, Gale.
All of this is actually not about you.
All of what, Dewey?
You do know something, don't you?
- Off the record?
- Always.
Two months ago, the Woodsboro police
got a call from a woman...
who said she was with Stab 3.
She wanted to see the file
on Sid, "for research."
- And?
- The boys said no.
And she wouldn't give her name.
A month later,
the station gets broken into.
- The file room gets ransacked.
- And someone stole Sid's file?
I already removed it.
I think someone on the film
is tryin' to find Sid.
- I'm sorry, this is incredible.
- I said, "off the record."
Right.
It's Jennifer.
She needs me.
-Jennifer?
- Gotta run.
- Wait! Dewey, where are you going?
- I'm on duty.
Stop following me.
I happen to be working
for the police, damn it!
- You're not a detective, Gale.
- Neither are you, Mr Incognito.
- Uh, you left your motor running.
- Damn it.
Fans, I can handle. Fans, they want
a picture, they want a conversation.
I can handle fans!
You see this, Dewey?
I haven't had one ofthese in a year and
a half. Someone's gonna pay for this.
-Jennifer, settle down. What happened?
- I'm with him.
- You.
Like I'm ever going
to win an award playing you.
- There's been a second murder.
- Who?
- Sarah Darling.
- Where?
-At the studio.
-Where? Nancy Drew
wants to know where.
Cotton Weary. Sarah Darling.
Don't you get it?
Someone's killing them in the order
they die in the movie.
- Dewey, who gets killed third?
- Who gets killed third?
You do.
I get killed in Stab 3?
I get killed?
- Yeah.
- Dewey, where are you going?
I have to get something
from my trailer.
Your--
You live here with her?
- Yeah.
- Oh, my God!
I needed a place to stay,
and she said she liked having me around.
- Why?
- She says I make her feel safe.
- She says I'm her rock.
- Her rock?
Yeah. If you weren't so concerned
with pretensions and appearances...
you'd be able to appreciate the
positivity and emotional centeredness...
I provide a woman.
Stone, I'm headed
to the crime scene.
You stay by Jennifer's side.
I suggest a search of the grounds.
Hey, Dewdrop.
Can I have a word?
Just so it can be straight. I'm
the professional celebrity guard here.
My resume lists Julia Roberts,
Salmon Rushdie, Posh Spice.
You are the Hollywood hanger-oner.
'Cause you're just no good
as a cop any more.
Your resume reads
like the obituaries.
So how about you take suggestions
from me? All right?
Whatever you say.
Hmm. Same deal?
Found with the body?
- Yeah, Maureen Prescott again.
- This is great.
Ten more murders
and we can publish a calendar.
The old "killer playing
with the cops" routine.
Very Hannibal Lecter.
Very Seven.
Doesn't the killer come after
the cops in those movies?
Usually one cop makes it.
- And?
- One cop doesn't.
- Usually.
- Detective Kincaid.
- What do we know? Same killer?
- Hey, hey.
Terminal Entertainment,
this is a crime scene, okay?
Wallace, Miss Weathers
is working with me now.
- Thank you, Detective.
- You're welcome.
Well, in that case, I'm gonna go dust
for fingerprints with Jane Pauley.
Uh, photos, Wallace, please?
Thank you.
New pictures, same person.
Anything turn up on your research yet?
- Nothing that will help with these.
- What about an increased
police presence around Jennifer?
- She's the next one
to get killed in the script.
- She has a bodyguard.
And besides, the producers told us
that there were three different
versions of the script.
Something about trying to keep
the ending off the Internet.
You should know that.
You're the technical advisor, right?
Three versions.
Three different characters die next.
And we don't know which one
the killer read.
Hey, hold up.
All I ever wanted to do
was make a real classic lovestory.
And the studio said they'd let me.
I just had to do
a scary movie for them first.
And now we're shut down,
and I am fucked!
God, it's not the end
of the world, Roman.
That is so easy foryou to say. You can
always go back to, to MustSee TV.
You know, I have no movie,
I'm about to turn 30, and it
looks like I'm now the next target.
- What?
- You? Why you?
Do you think this wasn't a message?
- Roman Bridger?
- What?
Mr Bridger,
you didn't tell us...
you spoke with Sarah Darling
before she was murdered.
Uh, spoke with her, uh, when?
The guard said she was here
for a meeting with you.
- What meeting? I don't--
- We talked with her roommate too.
Says you called Sarah,
told her to come down to the studio.
- Roommate answered the phone.
Says it was you.
- Wait a minute. No, no.
I-I never called her.
I never told her to go anywhere.
Roommate says she knows
your voice, Mr Bridger.
Well, she wasn't speaking with me! God!
Look, I did not call Sarah Darling.
- Sarah Darling said you did.
- Someone's trying to ruin my movie.
Someone wants to kill
my movie!
All right, we'll talk about
your movie down at the station.
- All right.
- This is the scene
where you come with us.
Dewey,Jennifer--
Wait a minute.
She wasn't talking with me
on the phone. I'm coming!
I'll call him in. Battery. Mr Riley,
do you have a cell phone I can borrow?
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- God. Roman.
Remind me not
to sleep with him again.
Come here, Cherokee.
California Women's Crisis Counseling.
My name is Laura. How can I help you?
Oh, Laura.
I do have a crisis.
Okay, well, whatever it is,
you can tell me.
Oh, my God.
I've killed someone, Laura.
- Are you sure ?
- Uh-huh, I'm sure.
I killed someone, I know it!
Oh, my God.
- Well, then, um--
- I did.
Then the people you need to call
are the police.
No, I need to call you!
Just you.
I'm sorry, your-your voice--
Don't you wanna know
how you can help, Laura?
Are you listening to me?
Huh?
- Who is this?
- It's Mother, Laura.
Now, be a good girl
and turn on the news.
Do as Mother tells you!
You're not my mother. How did you
get this number? Who is this?
You know your mother's voice
when you hear it!
Now, turn on the news!
And with a second cast member
murdered, Stab 3...
has been officially shut down,
prompting those involved...
to hope and pray that
these killings maybe over.
Just one question.
Do you think it's over, Sidney?
Do you?
The sky was dark this morning
Not a bird in a tree
Is this a wrap party
or is this a wrap party?
Scene 34.
"Maureen's Murder Flashback."
- I never liked that scene.
- That's 'cause you weren't in it.
Scenes 40 through 47.
- "The Prescott House Flashbacks."
- Tom, stop it.
You're scaring me.
Two people are dead.
Scaring you?
Give the sweet,
young ingenue act a rest.
- You're drunk.
- I'm coping.
I bet she fought and clawed
for that Sidney part.
I bet she stepped on any poor girl
that got in her way.
- So you asked her out and she said no?
- That has nothing to do with it.
Right.
Come on, Dewey.
Scene 50.
"Dewey Saves the Day."
She's so focused on success
that she never thinks...
about who she's hurting
to get it.
And you saved her life, like,
how many times?
Gale wants the whole world
to love her.
One person's never enough.
She's a dreamer.
-No, she's a narcissistic, psycho bitch.
-No, she's not.
She's got a good heart.
She does.
She just hides it away because
she thinks people see that as weak.
This is a good picture of you.
You look just like her.
God, Dewey.
You make it sound like
you're still in love with her.
And I left out the part
that she's cruel...
and selfish,
obsessive and annoying.
We have one Gale Weathers here.
We don't need two.
Hey, Dewdrop,
got your girlfriend out here.
Look who I found slinkin'
around the yard. The nightly news.
I wasn't slinking.
I was walking.
You were eaves dropping
at the bedroom window.
Yeah, a bedroom that
you seemed awfully at home in.
All right, let's talk.
Come on.
- What's this about, Gale?
- Did you know they released Roman?
Sarah's call didn't come
from his cell phone.
- Where did it come from then?
- A cloned cell phone. It's untraceable.
Well, thanks for the update, Gale.
Why don't you just go back home?
Dewey, wait a minute.
Just wait one second.
How old do you think
Maureen Prescott is in this picture?
- Nineteen, twenty.
- That's what I thought,
so I checked it out.
I cannot find any information about
her at this age. I mean, nothing.
She lived in Woodsboro her whole life.
Someone there must know something.
Almost her whole life.
Two years before...
she met Sidney's father,
she left Woodsboro.
No one has any idea
where she went or what she did.
I mean, it's-it's like she fell into
a black hole, Dewey! She vanished!
- So?
Why is the killer
leaving pictures of-of Maureen?
And why these pictures at-at--
at that point in her life?
I don't know! If I thought
like a homicidal maniac...
then I'd know how
a homicidal maniac thinks.
What?
-Jennifer.
-Jennifer?
Look at the buildings.
The second story. There and there.
It's the same!
It's the same street 28 years ago.
Oh, my God. Maureen Prescott was
at the back lot at Sunrise Studios!
- Oh, my God.
- I gotta make some calls.
Steven Stone
Protection Services.
Stone, where are you?
I'm just checking
your tin can, Dewdrop.
Well, come back inside
and stay with Jennifer.
Something's happened.
I have to go to the police.
Is that an order, Dewdrop? 'Cause
Steven Stone doesn't work for you.
Get back in the house, Stone.
Would I call you if it wasn 't important?
- What are you doing in there anyway?
- Me?
I'm just checking to make sure
there's no killer in here...
waitin' to off you
like he did your little sister.
What did you say?
I can't believe you said that.
That makes me...
angry!
Fucker!
Gotta call Kincaid.
Dewey, where is everybody?
- Oh, God.
-Jennifer?
Angelina?
Tom?
Oh, my God!
What happened?
Don't do that.
I'm overreacting.
Dewdrop?
- Stone?
- Oh, my God!
Oh, God, Stone!
Oh, God!
- Dewey, is he dead?
- Yeah.
Everyone back inside!
It's all right.
Don't panic.
Okay, outside. Everyone,
stay together and try to remain calm.
A phone!
- It's not mine.
Shit!
It's the fax.
"Interior, Jennifer's house. Living
room, night." It's a script page.
- W-W-What's it say?
- "With the bodyguard stabbed to death,
the five stand trapped.
- He's rewriting the movie.
- As the killer waits outside...
suddenly the fax machine
sends news of their fates."
It's a trick!
Everybody, outside!
- Outside where he can
pick us off one by one?
- Shut up!
"The killer prepares to grant
mercy to only one of them."
Don't you get it? The killer says he's
outside because he wants us here inside.
- Which one is it?
- Come on!
"Who will survive? Is it Jennifer?
Tom? Angelina? Dewey? Gale?
- The killer will give mercy to--"
- Everyone outside!
He grants mercy to who?
I wanna know what happens!
- I wanna know what happens!
- Wait for the fucking movie!
- I've gotta know! I'm goin' back in!
- No.
All right, everyone, back.
Stay together.
- What's it say?
- "And the...
killer will give mercy to...
- whoever--"
- Whoever?
Whoever?
Piece of shit.
"Whoever--
Whoever smells the--"
I can't stop
rolling down the hill!
Gale!Jennifer!
- Dewey!
Dewey, where are you?
Over here, Dewey!
- Dewey!
- Gale!
Gale, behind you!
Dewey!
Are you all right?
Yeah, never been better.
Yeah, I'm all right.
Where'd he go?
- He must've rolled under the car.
- All right, stay close.
Is he back there?
- No.
- No?
He's fast.
Could've sworn I hit him.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Thanks for saving me.
Ah, it's habit.
Oh, God.
What the fuck happened to you?
-Jennifer, wait a minute.
- Who gave you a place to stay?
-Who are you supposed to be protecting?
-Jennifer!
Hey!
My lawyer liked that.
Not as much as I did.
- Angelina?
- Tom was in the house.
- How'd you end up way over there?
- Oh, my God! Tom was in the house!
- Are we safe?
- Safe from who?
Wait a second!
Another picture.
Whoever it is is now taking credit
for Maureen Prescott's murder.
But we know who killed Maureen
Prescott. Billy Loomis and Stu Macher.
-I mean, they even told Sidney
how they did it.
- Yeah, but if I'm not mistaken...
you said in your book that
Sidney got it wrong once before.
She accused Cotton Weary
of murdering her mother.
And he was sent away for it.
Maybe there is a third killer.
Sidney might know something.
I told you.
I don't know where Sidney is.
And even if there was a third killer,
Sidney doesn't know about it.
That is for me to decide.
I need to talk to her, Mr. Riley.
She is a key element in this case.
I have a press conference in an hour.
I need to explain...
why there are three dead celebrities
and a bodyguard.
And a very angry mayor.
Okay, look, we all know this has
something to do with Stab 3.
But what we do not know is why
the killer keeps leaving pictures...
of Maureen Prescott
taken over 25 years ago.
And the photographs taken at the same
studio Stab 3 is shooting out of.
What does this
have to do with Sid?
Who knows more about Maureen
Prescott than her own daughter?
Well, Sid's dad couldn't help you,
and he was married to Maureen.
What's your problem?
Last night you were almost charcoal.
You gonna help us or what?
Do you wanna have this
conversation with a polygraph?
- Is that a threat, Detective?
- When it's a threat, you'll know it.
- Was that a threat?
- Boys, boys.
Why don't we compare
our gun calibres later?
- The issue is Maureen Prescott.
- Wrong. The issue is Sidney Prescott.
And either Mr Riley is going
to obstructjustice or he's going
to put me in touch with her.
So, where is she?
Hi, you've reached the machine.
You can leave a message.
Talk as long as you want.
Sid, it's me.
This is the fifth time I've called.
Please pick up.
I wanna make sure you're...
okay.
- Sid!
- Dewey!
What are you doing down here?
Actually, what was I doing up there?
-Jesus, Dewey. Are you okay?
- Oh, yeah, I'm all right.
- Is she all right?
- Hey, you know Gale.
It'd take a direct hit.
So the news said this was the precinct.
Who's this guy Kincaid?
Come here.
I told you to stay hidden.
- It's not safe for you to be here.
- The killer called me.
- What?
- Yeah, he found me.
I'm no more safe there than I am here,
and at least here I'm not alone.
Okay, come on.
- Detective Kincaid?
- Yeah.
There's someone here
who wants to help.
Oh, my God.
Sidney.
Is the man fast or what?
- Hi.
- Hi, Gale.
- I'm glad you're all right.
- Thank you.
- Sid, this is Detective Kincaid.
- Nice to finally meet you, Sidney.
- The killer called her.
- What? When?
- What did he say?
- Oh, you know, the usual small talk.
What's new? How you been?
How do you wanna die?
Sidney, do you have any idea
how he could've gotten your number?
He could have monitored her calls on a
scanner. Did you call her from the set?
- No.
- Do you have her number
stored in your memory?
- Phone memory!
- Oh. Yeah, guess I do.
- Has anyone else ever used your phone?
-Just Jennifer.
And you.
Hey, I'm the cop here.
You're in my office, Riley.
The killer leaves a photograph
after each murder, Sidney.
They were taken in Hollywood at the same
studio that they're shooting Stab 3.
Why didn't you tell me?
This is my mother, Dewey.
- Why didn't you say something?
- I was afraid they were bait.
Something to, you know,
trick you out of hiding.
Sidney, was she an actress or a model?
Because they look a lot
like publicity stills.
I, uh, don't know.
Detective, I wanna see
this place in the pictures.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.
- Slow it down.
- Sorry.
Watch the fuckin' aliens.
I'm gonna go talk to
the studio brass about those photos.
Yeah, right.
I know where you're goin'.
- Yeah, keep an eye on Sidney.
- I know where you're goin'.
You're gonna get her some flowers
and candy, huh? Huh?
- Gimme a break.
- Yeah, gimme a call.
Just keep your eye on her.
That stairwell over there, that's
where one of the pictures was taken.
God. I can't believe
she never mentioned any of this.
- She probably just--
- Dewey!
- Sorry.
- Martha!
- Oh, my God, Sid.
- Hey, hold it right there! Hey!
- Don't shoot!
- I'm only 17.
- It's okay. We know her.
We do?
Tell me that's his ex-girlfriend,
I'll shoot myself.
- It's Martha Meeks, Randy's sister.
- Randy's sister?
- Yeah, can't you tell?
- We miss you in Woodsboro, guys.
- Martha, what are you doing here?
- There's something you guys should see.
Told ya I'd make
a movie someday. Huh?
- Oh, my God.
- Well, if you're watching this tape...
it means, as I feared, I did not
survive these killings...
here at Windsor College,
and that giving up my virginity...
to Karen Kolchakat the video store
was probably not a good idea.
- Karen Kolchak?
- Yes, Karen Kolchak.
- "Creepy Karen"?
- Shut up! She's a sweet person, okay?
We were workin'late. We were puttin'
away some videos in the porno section...
and, you know, shit happens.
- Open the door, Randy!
- Fifteen minutes.
- It's my room too!
- Paul,15 minutes.
I'm leaving my legacy.
Fifteen minutes, Paul!
Damn! Anyway...
the reason I'm here is to help you so
that my death will not be in vain.
That my life's work will help save some
other poor soul from getting mutilated.
If this killer does come back
and he's for real...
there are a few things
that you gotta remember.
Is this simply another sequel?
Well, if it is, same rules apply.
But here's the critical thing.
If you find yourself dealing...
with an unexpected back-story
and ap reponderance...
of exposition,
then the sequel rules do not apply.
Because you're not dealing with
the sequel. You are dealing with...
the concluding chapter
of a trilogy.
- Trilogy.
- That's right. It's
a rarity in the horror field...
but it does exist, and it is
a force to be reckoned with.
Because true trilogies are all about
going back to the beginning...
and discovering something
that wasn 't true from the get-go.
Godfather, Jedi,
all revealed something...
that we thought was true
that wasn 't true.
So if it is a trilogy
you are dealing with...
here are some super
trilogy rules.
One: You've got a killer
who's gonna be superhuman.
Stabbing him won't work.
Shooting him won't work.
Basically, in the third one, you've
gotta cryogenically freeze his head...
decapitate him or blowhim up.
Number two: Anyone, including
the main character, can die.
This means you, Sid.
I'm sorry. It's the final chapter.
It could be fuckin' Reservoir Dogs
by the time this thing is through.
Number three: The past will
come back to bite you in the ass.
Whatever you think you know
about the past, forget it.
The past is not at rest!
Any sins you think...
were committed in the past are about
to break out and destroy you.
So in closing,
let me say...
goodluck, Godspeed...
and for some of you,
I'll see you soon.
'Cause the rules say some of you
ain't gonna make it. I didn't.
Not if you're watching this tape.
Thank you. And you be careful.
Say hi to your folks for me.
You be careful too, Sid.
- Bye, Dewey. Come visit us soon.
- I will, Martha.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
I've got an idea.
I'll hook up with you guys later.
- Do you want us to come with you?
- I work better alone.
Why don't you try to figure out where
those other pictures were taken.
- I can see nothing's changed.
- No.
Oh, shit.
Hello!
-Jeez.
- What the hell are you doing?
Being Gale Weathers.
What the hell are you doing?
- I am Gale Weathers.
- Here's how I see it.
I've got no house, no bodyguard,
no movie, and I'm being stalked.
Because someone wants to kill me?
No, because someone wants to kill you.
So now, starting now,
I go where you go.
That way, if someone wants
to kill me, I'll be with you.
And since they really want to kill you,
they won't kill me, they'll kill you.
- Make sense?
- None.
You know, in the movies,
I play you as being much smarter.
And as a sane person.
Foryou, that must be quite a stretch.
- That's funny.
- Ha!
- Need to get in that building?
- Yeah.
- Is there a story in that building?
- Maybe.
Gale Weathers would find a way.
Bitch. All right, wait.Just--
Don't tell me what to do.
Basements, wow.
Basements creep me out.
You'd make
a fascinating interview.
Hello?
Hi. Excuse me.
I am Gale Weathers...