Hey...
Are you all right?
Wait...
Christ!
What did they do to you?
My family...
They've got the remote...
The door...
- Family... must call them.
- Wait...
A cell phone, please!
A cell phone...
Please, a cell phone...
- Take it easy.
- Call this number...
- Snit...
- Snip...
46... 9... 90... 44...
44... 44...
Give it to me!
- Hello?
- Dani, love, listen.
Don't let anyone in,
stay inside, call the police.
Don't let anyone in
until the police arrive, OK?
Dad,
they're here.
They shot mom.
KIDNAPPED
Hey!
You can't park there.
Why not? I live here.
- Yeah, but the truck...
- How's it going?
Fine, we'll be finished
in a few hours.
- Forgive him, he's new.
- That's OK.
- You got the invoice?
- Yes, it's perfect.
Take the car keys
in case you have to move it.
Hello?
Hello!
- I'll stay tomorrow.
- You'll stay today.
Look, I'll help you tomorrow.
Mom, I can do it then.
Ma'am, where does this go?
- Mom, listen!
- Is a, please!
Excuse me. Leave it in the room
at the end of the hall, please.
- Is a...
- I'll stay tomorrow!
- No, today.
- Don't do this to me, mom!
It's bad enough that you've made me
come and live out here!
This place is like a graveyard!
And now you won't even let me go out!
Who won't let you go out?
- Tell me, who?
- You!
That's unfair.
I just want the three of us
to stay in tonight.
But I've arranged to go out.
- Well, UN-arrange it.
- I can't do that, mom.
It's a party, don't you understand?
Your father and I have said no,
and we mean no.
Mom, dad doesn't care.
He does care.
- He won't care, if you tell him.
- Don't start that.
You just want to fuck me up.
Is a, don’t talk to me like that!
And lower your voice.
I'll ask dad.
Leave your dad in peace.
If I say no, it's no.
No, mom, I'm going.
Don’t care what you say, I'm going.
- What do you mean?
- I'm going.
Keep on like that...
Ma'am,
where does this go?
- At the end of the hall.
- That's mine, come with me.
- Is a! We haven't finished.
- My mother's being hysterical.
Yeah, of course.
Why not? Of course I'm going.
If you come, even better.
Let's meet
at the entrance.
I don’t know, I'll text you later
and tell you, OK?
See you.
Put that over there.
- Are you guys exhausted?
- Yeah, but we're almost done.
How did you cut yourself?
An accident.
- Do you play golf?
- No, they're my father's.
At the far end?
Yeah.
- Shall I help you?
- No.
- Yes?
- Excuse me.
Where do I leave the bag?
Leave it in that room.
Marta.
Do you know where mom is?
In the sitting room, I think.
Lots of light, like you wanted.
Yeah.
I haven't stopped all day,
I need a shower.
Yes, with hot water,
but it gets cut off.
You can't turn on both taps.
Yes, it gets cutoff.
This is the fifth time
I've called you.
I see.
Just a moment.
- Yes, love?
- The box with the files?
In the study, on the shelf.
Thanks.
Look, let's see
if we can sort this out.
Hello?
He hung up on me.
Don't get angry, the-y'll fix it.
Yeah, tell me that
when you're having ice cold showers.
It won't be that bad.
In the summer,
this be great.
We might even
have settled in by then.
What about Internet?
Weren't you going to call them?
What? No, I'm sorry,
we agreed that you'd call.
We-'II have it by tomorrow.
Really...
Put it facing that way, please.
Careful.
Against the wall.
That's it.
There.
What are you doing?
Something's stuck
between my teeth.
- I told you to use different floss.
- Yeah, and I did.
There are toothpicks in the kitchen.
Shit
What?
I was hoping
it would get lost in the move.
We're stuck with that thing.
If it wasn't from your mother,
you wouldn't hate it so much.
- My mother never gave us that.
- No, of course not.
Yes?
Yes, speaking.
Yes, I've got broadband already.
No, I'm not interested.
And I'm very busy right now.
- Is that enough?
- Yes, thanks.
- Be careful, eh?
- Yes.
Yes?
Yes, speaking.
I just told you I'm not interested.
No, miss.
- The toothpicks?
- We weren't cut off. Coming!
I hung up.
What's that?
It's your father,
calling the gas people.
You look lovely!
- Was the water hot?
- More or less.
Here, put this in the fridge.
- You bought champagne?
- Yes, of course.
Tonight we have to celebrate.
- Now, the cheese...
- Mom...
Darling, get me...
Get me a knife for the cheese.
It's in that drawer.
- This one?
- Yes, that's it.
- I'm not staying for supper.
- Is a, let's not start that.
Dad said I could go.
- No, he didn't.
- Yes, he did.
- That's impossible.
- I'm going to change.
Is a, come here a minute!
Is a, I'm talking to you!
- What, mom?
- What do you mean, "What, mom?"
- We talked about this.
- Yeah, mom, we did.
- I told you I was seeing Cesar.
- Invite him here for supper.
How can I do that, mom?
You can open the champagne,
we'll have a toast and I'll leave.
- No, Is a, not like that.
- Dad let me go, talk to him!
- Mom, really!
- I want the three of us here.
- This is our first night...
- I'm getting changed.
Shit!
Jaime.
We have to call
the gas people again.
- What are you playing at?
- That was cold!
I'm sick of you not backing me up.
What have I done now?
It seems your daughter is going out.
- Yes, she said something.
- Yes.
A party with Cesar, or something.
- You like him, don't you?
- Yes, I do like him.
Well, then?
You knew I wanted the three of us
to be together tonight,
maybe see a movie after supper.
You and I can see it.
It's not that, Jaime.
We're a family.
Can't we have dinner together
on our first night here?
I was looking forward to it.
If she wants to go out with her
friends, let her. What do you care?
What do I care?
It's not that.
Where are my T-shirts?
I can't find them.
Everyone does their own thing here.
I'm always the last to find out.
Always.
This one.
And I've cooked for three.
Here.
I'm ravenous tonight,
I'll eat everything.
Yeah, you'll eat everything.
She's 18, Marta.
Let her enjoy herself.
Come on, loosen up a bit, please.
Don't tell me that.
Jaime, stop that.
Let go, please!
I'm being serious.
Why am I always the bad guy?
You're not,
and no one ever says you are.
I'm just saying
she's at a difficult age.
And we' re not?
I wonder what you were like at 18.
I bet you'd like that,
to see me at 18.
I clon't know if you're joking
or being serious.
Are you at that again?
What's wrong?
I think I've broken a tooth.
- Broken it?
- Or cracked it...
- Get it checked tomorrow.
- It's rubbing against my mouth.
I don't want another gumboil.
This is going
to be difficult for her.
- She won't get used to it overnight.
- I know that.
She's not the only one who moved.
I just want your support.
I want you to back me up.
What was that?
What...?
Is a, sweetheart...
Are you all right, love?
She's bleeding, Jaime.
- She's got a cut.
- She's bleeding...
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
I need a cloth,
something to stop the bleeding.
Please...
What's wrong, love?
Are you dizzy?
What's going on, dad?
- Calm down, love.
- What do they want?
Has the bleeding stopped?
Please, my daughter...
No! Please, don't hurt him!
Take whatever you want.
But don't hurt him, please.
Calm down, love.
What do you want?
Do you understand?
Take out the credit cards
and write down the numbers.
Give me your card.
- The code?
- 4474.
4474.
Where is it, love?
No, please!
No, please, clon't!
Please...
Here...
What's your code, love?
Your code, your number.
- The code for your card.
- The number, to get out money.
The number, love.
All right, all right.
- The code for the card...
- 2300.
2300.
That's good.
That's it.
Cell phones.
- Cell phones?
- Our cell phones.
Where's yours, darling?
In your purse?
Is it in your purse?
Here it is.
Here.
Where's yours?
I left if in the office.
I wanted to use it earlier
and couldn't find it.
Really?
I don't understand,
I looked for it and I couldn't...
Really, I was...
Please...
Please, don't touch her!
Leave her alone!
Please...
No, please, don't do that.
No, please, Jaime!
Please, don't!
Please, leave her alone!
Let her go!
She can't breathe!
Take the bag off her head!
If you lie to me again,
I'll kill your wife!
Take the bag off her head!
Can't you see she's suffocating?
She's suffocating.
Please, take it off!
What's the number for the safe?
Come on!
The number for the safe!
2366.
Don't touch my daughter!
She-'s got nothing to do with this!
- What's the number?
- 2366.
- 23...
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
No, no, no...
Dad! Dad!
Let my daughter go, please!
Don't do anything to her, please!
Let her go!
Let her go, please!
Tell him not to hurt her!
Please, tell him to let her go!
Behave, and your girls
will be all right.
If not, they die.
OK?
I'm going to take off my hood.
Wait a minute...
No, please.
Don't, we-'II do whatever you say.
- I don't care.
- It isn’t necessary.
I know you won't tell the police.
It isn't necessary.
Please, please.
I don't want to see your face.
All right.
I've put it on again.
Open your eyes.
I didn’t have time to see it.
I don't want to see your face.
We-'re going outside.
I can't wear the hood.
So I have to trust you.
All right, all right.
I won't say anything.
Please...
Let's go.
The car keys are upstairs.
Where are we going?
Drive.
Close the window.
Where are we going?
Don't hurt my family.
- Which way? Right, left...?
- Straight on.
That's not up to me.
Who is it up to?
You.
Stop here.
Come on.
Get the maximum amount
from every card.
Aren't you coming?
No, the ATM has security cameras.
But if you speak to anyone,
if you ask for help,
or do anything stupid,
I'll make a call.
Don't worry, I'll be right back.
Yes, I'm on my way.
Five minutes, I promise.
You're crazy!
OK, see you soon.
Don't move, please.
No! No!
Please, don’t turn round.
Take it easy.
You must help me.
Calm down.
I'm not going to hurt you.
You have to help me, OK?
Don’t hurt me.
Have you got a cell phone?
You have to call the police.
Do you understand?
Please, do you understand?
- Here, this is all I've got.
- No, no, no!
No, don't, wait a minute!
Please, don't call!
It was a misunderstanding!
Please, wait, wait!
I swear I did nothing! The woman
got scared when I walked up!
- She must have...
- Start the car!
Move, move!
Come on, move!
When I went up, she must have...
Faster.
Right.
OK.
Stop here.
- Yes...
- What are you doing?
Ifs me.
Do what you want with the mother.
- No! Wait, please!
- He didn't understand.
- Please, don't do that! I swear...
- No, he doe-sn't care.
He doesn't care.
Come here!
No, please, don't!
Tell them to stop.
Shut the fuck up!
Stop him!
Tell him to stop, please!
I think I'll give him
another chance.
What?
Like he!
No! Wait!
I'll give you another chance.
Start the car.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I didn’t...
it's shit!
It's fucking shit!
Stop it! Stop it!
No one tells me what to do!
Stop it now! Stop it now!
But it won't be with you.
Not with an old woman.
He told you not to!
Stop, for fuck's sake!
You can't.
Are you expecting anyone?
Are you?
Mom! Mom!
Help me, please!
Help me.
- You, come here.
- No, no!
Who is it?
- Who is it?
- I don’t know! I don’t know!
What?
Who is it?
A friend...
He shouldn't be here...
- Who the fuck was it?
- I don’t know.
- What? Who...?
- A boy.
- A boy?
- And he went away.
- What boy?
- He's gone now!
Cesar!
Shout again
and I'll kill your mother.
One sound
and I'll kill
your daughter.
Is a, it's me.
- What'll we do?
- Give me the keys!
Hello!
Is Is a there?
It's Cesar.
What the hell...?
Who are you?
I'm a friend of Is a.
Is there anyone else?
No...
- Why would there be?
- What?
What?
I'd arranged to meet her,
and as...
As she didn’t come,
I came here, I saw the light...
- What?
- I don't know anything!
- I don't know...!
Shut up! Shut up!
Come on, faggot!
Fuck!
You bitches!
Open the fucking door!
Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck!
Listen to me!
Open the door,
or it'll be worse!
It'll be worse!
Open the fucking door!
Help!
Help us!
They closed
the fucking door!
I won't say anything!
Fuck, I won't say anything!
Shut your mouth,
you little shit!
- Hey, you in there!
- There's no signal!
Lady,
we've got your daughter's boyfriend.
Open the door
or I'll kill him!
Listen, love!
Open the door, please!
Is a, do what they say, please!
You have to climb out
the window and call the police!
Is a, listen to me!
Is a, open the fucking door!
Open it, for fuck's sake!
I think she doe-sn't like you.
She must have
another boyfriend.
Climb up!
I can't, mom!
I can't.
No, please, don't!
Listen to me!
Take it easy.
- Climb up!
- I'll count to three!
No, please-...!
When I get to three,
I'll shoot him!
One!
No, please, don'tl
Please, please!
Climb up!
Two!
Mom, he's killed him!
He-'s killed him!
Please, Is a, please!
Listen to me, darling.
Listen to me.
You have to get help,
please!
The cell phone!
Is a, take the cell phone!
Run, run!
Put it away.
Why us?
What?
Nothing.
Why us?
- Why us?
- Keep going.
- I've used all my cards.
- Now your girls' cards.
74.
You won't hurt them, will you?
Look at the ATM.
Before, I didn't...
00.
I was nervous, but now I won't...
I won't...
Listen.
I'd just like to know that
when this is over you won't hurt us.
I'm sure we can come
to some kind of agreement.
You want it?
Take it.
Take it and fire.
I don't care.
No hard feelings.
I just want this to be over.
Very well.
I don't make deals.
I don't negotiate.
They're alive because ifs easy.
If it gets difficult,
their lives don't matter.
Alive or dead isn't important.
Easy or difficult is important.
I like things to be easy.
And you?
Easy.
What are you doing?
Aren't we going home?
You said that when we got
the money, we'd go back home.
Turn off the engine.
Hands on the wheel.
We-'II wait until
one minute after midnight
and then we-'II get
more money from the ATM.
Your family is at home.
Be quiet, please.
- We should've opened the door.
- Be quiet, Is a.
Be quiet, please.
Is a, please, be quiet.
- Cesar didn't do anything.
- Neither did we.
Calm down, sweetheart.
- They're going to kill us!
- They' re not going to kill us...
Word, word, word...
I'm going to start crying.
Move.
Come on.
She can't breathe.
She's choking.
Water, please.
For fuck's sake!
What?
How many boyfriends do you have?
- What?
- Take the girl.
Come on!
Get rid of him.
Or your daughter dies.
I'll kill her.
Understood?
OK.
Good evening.
Is anything wrong?
I'm sorry to bother you so late,
but the neighbors rang
to say they'd heard screams.
Yes.
It's just that
my husband puts
the TV on very loud.
I tell him not to,
but he always does.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
What?
Yes, why?
You don't look very well.
I'm a bit tired
because
I've just moved house
and I'm very tired.
Good night.
I'm sorry,
may I come in for a minute?
Why?
I've told you nothing's wrong.
It would just be a routine check.
It's very late,
and I'm very tired.
I'm sorry.
Good night.
I hate to insist,
but I have to do it.
- It's very late.
- Good evening.
Is there some problem?
No, I was explaining
to your wife that
we had complaints about the noise...
That was my fault.
Yes, it was...
Well...
Come in.
Please, come in.
It's cold tonight.
Come on.
Darling,
why don't you turn off the TV?
Go on.
I'm sorry I disturbed the neighbors.
It's just that...
This music equipment...
We didn’t have them in my country.
Where are you from?
Albania. Why?
You're our first Albanian neighbor.
You seem to be doing well.
I can't complain.
Well, how's your patrol?
- Is there much trouble?
- No, no.
It's a quiet night.
Well, sir, we can
offer you...
Would you like some coffee?
Yes, thank you.
Darling, why don't you
heat some milk?
Sugar?
Yes, please.
Well,
I'm sorry, but...
we've just moved, you know?
Don’t worry, some other day.
I'll finish my patrol.
Excuse me?
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Come out!
What did you do?
God!
You killed him!
- Why?
- He realized...
What the fuck happened in there?
I told you to take the bitch...
Get out of there!
What?
Now what do we do?
They've seen your fucking face,
you moron!
They won't be able to say anything!
You've fucked up from the start.
Ifs all your fault.
And what do you mean,
they won't say anything?
Shut up! Are you scared
that they saw my face?
You're crazy.
You're fucking insane.
Take the mother down
to where the boy is.
- Grab her!
- What are you going to do?
What...?
Take me.
- Instead of your daughter?
- Yes.
- Yes?
- Yes!
Yes, yes, yes!
Why should I? Why?
You're old and she's young.
I won't fight you, I swear.
Take me, please, take me.
I love it when they fight.
Please, no!
You want me to fuck you?
Mom! Mom! Mom!
Get up, get up.
Ifs all right.
Everything all right?
Keep going.
What's wrong?
Tell me, what's wrong?
Did you call my home and no one
answered? Is that it?
What's going on?
Jaime,
ifs your wife.
She wants to talk to you.
Let's go.
Let's go!
I didn’t want this to happen.
Selfish bitch...
You should have opened the door.
- You should have opened it.
- Shut up!
- Fucking selfish bitch!
Shut up or I'll kill you!
Shut up!
Do you like it? Do you?
Come on, say nice things.
Come on.
Like This? Like This?
Like this?
Stop it!
Stop it.
Wait your turn.
I said, stop it, you bastard!
Bastard!
Bitch!
Open the door!
Please!
Please, help me!
Help me, please!
Please, please!
Why?
Open the fucking door!
Come on!
Open the door, baby.
Now that we-'re near the house,
I'll tell you something.
I don't want you
to get upset in there.
What's happened?
The ATM wasn't enough.
We're going
to the bank tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- To get more money.
What can I do with
the shit you got tonight?
Don't worry.
Has anything happened yet?
Just a few more hours.
Then we'll leave you
in peace,
you, your wife,
your daughter, everyone.
Don't worry.
Stop, stop.
What are you doing?
Stop, stop!
Stop the car!
Stop the fucking car!
Come here, we're not done.
Get away from the door.
Get away from the door!
Drop it.
Calm down.
Put down the gun,
I'm not like them.
Put down the gun.
Put it clown.
Calm down, calm down.
Trust me.
What'll we do?
Dad!
Is there anyone left?
I saw one of them leaving.
Dad! Dad!
Daddy!
My baby...
Are you all right?
Whose blood is that?
Where-'s mom?
Where-'s mom, darling?
- Mom!
- Marta!
I'm here!
We have to get out of here.
We' re coming, Marta!
Down here!
They've gone.
- Jaime, down here!
- Mom!
Mom!
What did they do to you, my love?
Are you all right?
Jaime, please, get me out of here.
Where-'s the tool box?
The tool box, Marta!
- Are you OK, son?
- Yes.
I'll get help.
I've got a cell phone here.
In my pants.
There-'s no signal, Jaime.
There's no signal here!
Love, listen to me.
Is a, listen to me.
Take this, sweetheart.
Do you hear?
It's all over.
I won't be long.
Police.
This is an emergency.
Three men broke into my house.
35, Camino de Simancas.