That is the ugliest thing
l've ever seen in my whole life !
It certainly is. Who sent it ?
That's strange. It doesn't say.
Where could it have come from ?
I don't like it. It's staring at me.
It's probably
one of Uncle Arthur's little jokes.
I don't think it's funny at all.
Darling, l'm just going
to have a shower.
Be there in a minute.
Claudia, I told you
not to leave your toys lying about.
Good God ! You are hideous.
- Claudia.
- What ?
I have a bone to pick you with you,
young lady.
We had an agreement, didn't we ?
But, Daddy, I didn't leave it there.
In a civilized society,
our word is our bond.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Just because it's your birthday...
that doesn't mean
that you can relinquish all...
Richard, what was that ?
You killed my mommy and daddy.
And now you're pissing your pants
you're pissing your pants
Wake up ! You're pissing your pants !
And now, ladies and gentlemen...
what you've all been waiting for...
Shitface !
And the greatest ventriloquist
in all of England :
the psychotic Psychs !
This grotesque abomination...
He ain't even anatomically correct.
Don't laugh.
It's a serious condition.
Six years ago, I found it
in a cemetery back in the States.
Little fucker
tried to rip me throat out.
I was trying to give you a hug.
I don't know much about myself.
I know l'm an orphan.
I know l'm a freak.
And, of course,
I know that l'm Japanese.
But why do I have
such terrible nightmares ?
Filled with hate and blood and guts.
l'm not like that at all.
I wouldn't even hurt a fly.
There he goes, back to his family.
I envy him.
Sometimes I wonder
about my own parents.
Were they Zen masters ?
Did they serve the emperor ?
Sometimes I wonder what
my mom and dad were really like.
So, you don't believe
in Santa Claus ?
Trust me, honey, tonight
l'm going to make you believe.
You wait and see what Santa
is bringing you, you naughty girl.
No, I can hear you fine.
You're not breaking up.
Sheila, I just said
you're not breaking up.
You're breaking up with me ?
Wait, you're breaking up with me
on Christmas Eve ?
Sheila, you have got to be
fucking kidding me !
Well, that's just great.
God !
I knew it !
You're not real.
You were never real.
You know what
that kind of disappointment...
can do to somebody ?
Do you have any idea
how that can fuck with your mind ?
fuck with your mind !
Chucky is broke again.
This is bloody ridiculous.
Cut !
Kill the snow.
Get off me.
- Tony, what was that ?
- l'm sorry, it's...
This is unprofessional,
and I can't work like this !
No, Jason, l'm sorry. Please wait.
We're here in Hollywood,
where production is underway...
on the new horror flick,
Chucky Goes Psycho.
The film tells the urban legend
of Chucky and Tiffany...
two dolls supposedly possessed
by serial killers.
The dolls were found at the scene
of a string of real-life murders...
which remain unsolved to this day.
You guys, I think Tiffany's left arm
is loose again.
Yeah, l'm looking for Jennifer.
Does anyone have a 20 on Jennifer ?
Check the catering truck.
Jennifer. I got you a Skinny Quick.
Miss Tilly,
we're ready for you on set.
- Jennifer, I am so proud of you.
- For what ?
For sticking to your diet.
Thank you.
What's going on in the world today ?
Julia Roberts is getting $25 million
for her next film.
Julia Roberts. l'm so tired
of hearing about Julia Roberts.
You know, I should have played
Erin Brockovich.
I could have
done it without a Wonderbra.
Julia stole that part
right out from under me.
And you know how she did it ?
She slept with the director.
That's what I think.
Jennifer, you know that's not true.
How come I don't ever get
any of the good roles anymore ?
How come nobody takes me seriously ?
- Nice tits.
- Thank you.
Look at me. l'm an Oscar nominee,
for Christ's sake.
Now l'm fucking a puppet.
l've got no fan mail, no paparazzi,
no stalkers.
Well, there must be something
l'm right for ?
Let's see.
Hip-hop superstar
turned director, Redman...
is still looking
for the right actress...
to take the female lead
in his upcoming Bible epic.
That sounds good. What's the role ?
The Virgin Mary.
- What's so funny ?
- Nothing.
It's perfect.
It's just what I need
to reinvent myself.
The Virgin Mary. I always loved
the way she wore robes...
and her hair off her face,
kind of like this.
Joan, get Morty on the phone...
and tell him I need to take
a meeting with this Redman.
- Right away.
- Okay.
That's a wrap for Access Hollywood.
Reporting from Hollywood...
where, as you can see, Chucky
and Tiffany are alive and well.
You can catch their movie
in theaters next Halloween.
Thank you, Chucky.
Fuck you very much.
l'm no orphan after all !
Well, you were shit last night.
You are going to have
to be more scary.
Scary ?
Let's rehearse, shall we, all right ?
Hello.
Look, you got to learn
to tap into your killer instincts...
give in to your natural impulses.
Or else l'm going to have...
to fire you.
Hey !
Come here !
"Mary, you are truly a vision
of unsullied innocence...
"unique among all women...
"as pure as the virgin snow.
"But I ask, what is troubling you ?"
"Joseph, husband,
there has been a miracle.
"As I stand before you,
I must tell you...
"I am with child."
"But, Mary, how could this be ?
"In accordance with God's wishes...
"we have never lain together
as man and wife."
"Yes, it is true.
"And I beg you that you believe me
when I tell you...
"I have never lain
with any man at all.
"Do you believe me, Joseph ? Do you ?"
- Do you ?
- Yes, I do.
- You were great. You were super.
- Thank you, Mr. Man.
Can I call you Red ?
Listen, there's a whole lot
of different ways I could do it.
Not just the way you saw.
I could do it faster,
I could do it slower.
- I could do it as a rap.
- No.
You already showed me
a side of the character...
- that l've never seen before.
- Thank you.
But I think l'm going to have to go
with my first choice.
Thanks for coming by anyway.
I mean, really, l'm a huge fan.
I really want to work with you
one day. We should call...
Excuse me, I hope
you don't mind my asking...
- but who is your first choice ?
- Julia Roberts.
But thanks for coming by, anyway.
Listen, Red.
l've been giving
a lot of thought to this project...
and I have a lot
of interesting ideas...
about the character.
I was thinking...
maybe you would like to discuss it
in a more intimate setting.
Just the two of us.
I didn't know you were
that passionate about the role.
Oh, yes, l'm very passionate.
So, shall we say my place ?
8h00 ?
Pardon me, sir.
Sorry.
Sorry, sir.
Don't mind me.
Excuse me.
Oh, dear.
Mom ?
Dad ?
l've dreamed of this moment
all my life.
I know this must come
as quite a shock.
It's going to be an adjustment
for all of us.
Look, I still have the necklace
you left me.
l've always wanted to know,
what do these words mean ?
ls it our family motto ?
Please say something.
It's because of the way I look,
isn't it ?
For pity's sake, please wake up.
"Wake up" ?
ade due damballla...
"Awake."
- Tiff ?
- Chucky ?
- Who the hell are you ?
- Shitface.
Now, what kind of a name is that ?
Where are your mother and father ?
Judging from that face,
my guess is they're hiding.
Shut up, you asshole.
Well, come on. It looks like
the kid fell off the ugly tree...
and hit every branch
on the way down.
I mean, you got to feel bad
for the parents.
I wonder what they must look like.
Oh, my God.
What ? No.
You didn't... We didn't...
Sweetface, come to Mommy.
What's going on ?
- Where are we ?
- In Hollywood.
I saw you on the telly.
Chucky, wake up.
Look at us. We've had makeovers.
We're movie stars.
- Shit. Barbie mode.
- No, they're puppets.
They don't walk and talk
by themselves.
Listen, if you want them to work...
l'm going to have
to take them apart.
- ls Mommy ill ?
- The courts thought so.
Heads up !
They're stark raving mad !
Hey, you're pissing your pants.
Chucky, she just had an accident.
You mean, "he" had an accident.
Don't look at me.
See, what did I tell you ?
A beautiful little girl.
What ? Are you blind ? That's my boy.
He just hasn't had
his growth spurt, yet.
Don't worry about it, Son.
You're a late bloomer, that's all.
And it's high time
that you had a real name.
Let's see.
I think l'm going to call you...
Glen.
What kind of a name is that
for a girl ?
Don't listen to him, honey.
From now on, your name is...
Glenda.
Run, Glenda.
Jeez, what a mess.
There you are, Mr. Goodbar.
Jennifer Tilly.
Hello.
Oh, my God. You look so real.
You look so real.
You are cuter
than my last boyfriend.
I think we make a lovely couple.
Jennifer. Miss Tilly,
were you having an affair with him ?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Pete Peters, Celebrities Revealed.
Jennifer, what did you see ?
You want me to draw you a picture ?
Would you ?
Somebody give her a piece of paper.
Look, l'm not gonna
draw you a picture, okay ?
Don't feel bad.
You're an actress not an artist.
What were you doing
when you saw the body ?
No comment.
Jennifer, I love you.
Jennifer I love, you.
ls it true that you and Redman
are in talks...
about you starring in his new movie ?
Yes. As a matter of fact,
that is true. I have...
- Can I have your autograph ?
- Okay, sure.
Hold on, you forgot the head.
Excuse me.
Jennifer, how old are you really ?
Paparazzi scumbag !
What year were you born ?
Give us the exact date.
- I want to sit up front with you.
- Sure.
Hey, you okay ?
Yeah, I am now.
So, are you a pair
of ninja assassins ?
What ?
Are you hit men for the yakuza ?
We're not from Japan.
We're from Jersey.
Just think, Jennifer Tilly
is playing me in a movie.
It's absolutely perfect casting.
But that voice !
I know,
she sounds just like an angel.
Now, l've got it all figured out.
l'm going to transfer myself
into Jennifer...
and you're going to
transfer yourself into Redman.
l'm down with that.
We'Il ditch these plastic bodies
once and for all...
and we'Il be
Hollywood's hottest couple.
What about me ?
Don't worry, Glenda.
l've got that figured out, too.
You're going to be a real live girl.
- Boy.
- How ?
Well, l'm not getting pregnant
again, l'Il tell you that much.
My mother always told me :
"Once is a blessing.
Twice is a curse."
Well, that would explain
your sister.
The only sensible option
is a surrogate mother.
HEY !
Jennifer, I have something important to say...
Hold on a second, Sweetheart.
Hello ?
- What are you doing ?
- l'm busy.
I do have a life, you know.
Turn on the news.
Were you having an affair ?
The actress discovered
the victim's body.
As of yet,
there is no official confirmation...
as to whether or not
Miss Tilly is a suspect.
Jesus !
- Can you believe this ?
- Are you okay ?
l've had better days.
Listen, Joan, I need you
to do something for me.
I need you to get me a bottle of
champagne and bring it by my house.
What for ?
- l've got a big night tonight.
- Tonight ?
- With who ?
- Redman.
Jennifer, what are you up to ?
Thank you, Joan.
Come on, Stan, it's just business.
He'Il be out of there by midnight.
Oh, my God, she's a complete slut.
Nighty-night, Glenda. Sleep tight.
Leave it on.
Sweetie, there's nothing
to be scared of.
Your daddy and I will be right here.
Why do you kill people ?
- Excuse me ?
- Why do you kill ?
It's a hobby, really.
It helps us relax.
Am I going to be a killer ?
Of course. It's been
a family tradition for generations.
But violence is bad, isn't it ?
They said so on TV.
Not "violence."
"Violins." Violins are bad.
That screeching music's
gonna ruin the goddamn country.
Chucky, Glenda's right.
It's time we owned up to it.
We have a problem with killing.
I don't have "a problem"
with killing.
I like a little killing
now and then.
What's wrong with that ?
Killing is an addiction,
like any other drug.
But we're parents now.
We have to set a good example.
Let's quit, Chucky, right now.
Cold turkey.
You have got to be kidding.
Promise me, Chucky, no more killing.
No.
No more killing.
We can't do it anymore.
- A thousand times no.
- We have the future to think of.
- We have a child !
- Fine !
All right, already. I promise.
Thank you, doll baby.
You're a sweetheart.
Now we really will be
the perfect family.
Did you hear that ?
Maybe you should forget the director
and fuck the exterminator instead.
So, how do I look ?
- Never mind.
- Jennifer, this is beneath you.
Think about what you're doing.
What are people gonna say ?
Who cares what people say ?
- But don't you see how evil this is ?
- I don't wanna hear it.
You're prostituting yourself
so you can play the Virgin Mary.
Joan, I don't wanna hear it.
This is so evil.
- You're going to hell.
- No.
Hell would be ending up
on Celebrity Fear Factor...
in a worm-eating contest
with Anna Nicole Smith.
Which you'd win.
He's here.
Let yourself out the back.
And while you're at it, why don't
you leave your key on the counter ?
What are you saying ?
Well, you think l'm so disgusting.
You think l'm going to hell.
l'm only trying
to survive here, Joan.
God knows I wouldn't want
to drag you down with me.
l'm saying you're fired.
Now, in artificial insemination,
timing is everything.
So you'Il have to hurry.
That shouldn't be a problem for you.
Yeah, just don't let that player
get into her pants.
I don't want him
touching my woman...
- till l'm him and you're her.
- Right.
Aren't you going to give me
a hand here ?
Too tall.
Lezbos.
Done her.
Here we go.
Come to papa.
Cheers.
You know, I wasn't bullshitting
when I told you I was a fan.
That's so sweet, Redman.
Which of my films is your favorite ?
That movie when you and that chick
was making out.
Bound. Everybody likes that one.
You still in touch with homegirl ?
- Gina ?
- Yeah.
Yeah, sure, we're friends.
Close friends.
Very close friends.
Maybe, the three of us
could hang out together some time.
You know,
I would really like that a lot.
Okay. l'Il see
if I can make it happen.
- Bottoms up, baby.
- Skol.
I was wondering...
what's it gonna take
to make you see me as a virgin.
Well, you tell me.
A masturbating midget ?
Get it, mini-meat.
Sweet Jesus,
God bless the little people.
- I don't know if I can do this.
- Why not ?
- What will people say ?
- Man, fuck what people say.
Know what l'm saying ? This
was meant to be, baby, for real.
Know how I know ?
Because the man upstairs told me so.
- Really ?
- Hell, yeah.
Look, Mel Gibson ain't the only one
God's been talking to in Hollywood.
He personally told me
that you was my Virgin.
Well, I guess...
What the hell ?
Pig.
And you...
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Where's your self-respect ?
You know what my mother used to say
about dirty girls ?
She said,
"You can always smell it...
"on girls who sell it."
By the way, Miss Tilly,
can I have your autograph ?
l'm a big fan.
What am I supposed to do with this ?
Now, Miss Tilly,
I know you're frightened.
You're probably even wondering
if you've gone completely insane.
But I promise you,
tomorrow you're going to wake up...
and this will all seem
just like a bad dream.
In the meantime,
we can do this the easy way...
or the hard way.
It's really up to you.
No wonder her career's in trouble.
Check it out, Tiff.
Look at the size of his feet.
You know what they say.
Fuck, she's fat.
I can't believe it.
She's not even pregnant yet.
Paparazzi scumbag.
Looks like you've got
everything under control.
l'Il just leave you to it.
Motherhood is so beautiful.
No.
Sorry, just messing with you.
What time is it ?
Time to get dressed.
We are going to have our own
boys' night out, just you and me.
How does that sound ?
- Where are we going ?
- Hunting.
I can't see anything.
Maybe we should slow down ?
No ! You're doing great.
Son of a bitch !
Up yours, asshole !
- What ?
- Not you, Son. Come on, floor it !
Oops ! I did it again.
Jesus Christ !
No !
Attaboy !
- No, I didn't.
- And I thought you weren't ready.
Kid, you're a fucking natural !
But he hit the shelf.
And don't worry about your mother.
It will be our little secret.
Say "cheese."
Good morning.
Hi.
We must have really got wired
last night.
Yeah.
Redman, did we...
- You don't remember ?
- No. It's all a blur.
What about you ?
I kind of remember
you screaming a lot.
Yeah, I seem to remember that, too.
I tend to have that effect on women.
- Really ?
- Yeah.
Wait, I do remember...
I had the strangest dream.
I dreamt my guardian angel
came to me.
She had the sweetest voice
I have ever heard.
She told me to respect myself.
And then she asked for my autograph.
Let's see."Step Number One :
Admit I have an addiction."
Okay, check.
"Step Number Two :
"Give myself over
to a higher power."
Whatever.
Here we go."Step Number Nine :
"The recovering addict
must make amends...
"to anyone he or she has harmed."
- Hello ?
- Good morning.
- ls this Ruth Bailey ?
- Speaking.
- The widow of Robert Bailey ?
- Yes. Who is this ?
Mrs. Bailey, my name is Tiffany Ray.
You don't know me...
but a few years ago,
I killed your husband.
And I am so very, very sorry.
What is this,
some kind of sick joke ?
No, l'm completely serious.
But I want you to know
l'm in recovery now...
and I have put all of that
behind me.
I don't know who you are...
Thank you, Mrs. Bailey.
Have a nice day.
I feel better already.
Morning, Stan.
Wasn't there something important
you wanted to tell me ?
Well
The thing is, Jennifer...
l'm sorry.
I don't know what's gotten into me.
So you were saying...
- Forget it.
- Okay.
Now, let's see.
What should we do today ?
l'm pregnant.
Redman, I said l'm pregnant.
Congratulations.
Who is the baby's daddy ?
Don't even look at me.
I haven't slept with anyone else
to advance my career lately.
- Who are you kidding ?
- It's true, Redman. Look...
I know I come off all slutty, but
that's for my image. It's just...
Do you think anyone would cast me
in these sexpot roles...
if they knew I hadn't been laid
in a year ?
I haven't even slept
with my driver yet...
and I think he really likes me.
That's all very touching and shit.
But l'm telling you, it can't be me.
Why not ?
I had a vasectomy as soon as I got
to Hollywood. I ain't no idiot.
That is impossible
Hey Jennifer !
I hate to break it to you. But I
can't hire you if you're pregnant.
That is ridiculous.
The character is pregnant.
Yeah, I know...
but I have a very specific vision
of Mary.
And what can I say ?
She gots to be hot.
That pig !
- Recovery Hotline.
- Yes, l'm in recovery.
And l'm afraid
l'm going to have a slip.
- Can you get to a meeting ?
- No, it's really not an option.
I just freak everybody out.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
We're not here to judge you.
- What's your name ?
- Tiffany.
Listen to me, Tiffany. I know
exactly what you are going through.
- You do ?
- Yes, I do.
In fact, l'm gonna let you in
on a little secret.
Just last week, I had a slip.
- Really ?
- Yes.
And believe you me,
it was not pretty.
It never is, is it ?
In fact, it took me three hours
just to clean up the mess.
God, don't remind me.
But l'm not beating myself up
over it.
- You know why, Tiffany ?
- Why ?
Because Rome wasn't built in a day.
You're right.
You are absolutely right.
Hello ? Speaking.
When was this ?
All right, I know.
I understand who you are.
I just don't know
how you got my phone number.
Because it is
a private, unlisted phone number.
Pete Peters ?
Yeah, I saw him yesterday.
No, I don't have
any relationship with him.
He is a firking paparazzi that is
trying to get pictures of me...
in compromising positions.
Yeah, l'm with Redman.
Redman, he's a director.
Oh, yeah. Well, he's a rapper, too.
He is a rapper-director, okay ?
He's a hyphenate.
Bye-bye.
Jennifer...
Do you mind ? l'm on the phone.
There's been another murder.
What ? No, I told you where I was.
I was right here all night
with Redman.
What ? I don't...
You're not telling me l'm a suspect.
All right, l'Il be fine.
l'm on my way.
l'm leaving.
You can let yourself out.
By the way, Redman, drop dead.
Oh, Glenda.
Glenda, honey. Everything is okay.
It was just a little slip.
There's no need to tell your daddy.
It will be our little secret, okay ?
It's D-day here at San Quentin.
Who would have thought
it would ever come to this ?
They're executing Martha Stewart
this morning.
I don't think I can take nine months
of this shit.
Silly Chucky.
It is a voodoo pregnancy.
- It's accelerated.
- How accelerated ?
It is 102. 7, KIISFM,
LA's number one hit music station.
Ryan Seacrest in the morning.
Ellen K, I don't know
if I can take it. What's on the way ?
We have bad weather on the way in
LA, Hollywood, and surrounding area.
- Now, we're not used to bad weather.
- No, we're not.
l'm not quite sure how that's going
to affect my whole vibe.
- This is Joan.
- Joan.
l'm fat.
- You're not fat.
- No, I am fat. l'm huge !
For the love of Mary, l'm pregnant.
- My God.
- No, I should have listened to you.
You said it was evil
and I was going to hell.
You're right,
and now God is punishing me.
- Oh, God. ls it Redman's ?
- No, it's definitely not Redman's.
- What ?
It's definitely not Redman's.
What an asshole.
What makes you say that ?
- Say what ?
- That Redman is an asshole.
I didn't say it, you did.
- No, I didn't.
- So he's not an asshole ?
Yes, he is.
Joan, will you please
stop doing that ?
Doing what ?
Imitating me.
I do not sound like that.
Yes, you do. I do.
Joan, will you shut up ?
There's something
really wrong with me !
l'm pregnant. I don't...
Jennifer, what's wrong ?
Nothing, l'm fine.
I heard you scream.
I can still hear you screaming !
I mean, it's just...
Well, Bound is on cable.
Gina Gershon is fingering me.
I love this movie. Don't you ?
Yeah, that's really interesting,
but l've got to go. Bye.
- Too tight ?
- Yes.
Ain't no such thing.
What are you doing ? Stop it.
What the hell is going on in here ?
She came on to me.
- Help me ! Somebody help me !
- Shut her up, asshole.
What the hell is this ?
We had an agreement, Chucky.
We decided,
for the sake of our child...
we weren't going
to do this shit anymore !
No, you decided.
Just like you decided
our son was a girl.
- He is a girl !
- He is a boy, God damn it !
And he is the most promising killer
I have ever seen.
You should have been there, Tiff.
You would have been so proud of him.
- I want a girl !
- I want a boy !
You are tearing me apart !
What about what I want ?
- What ?
Doesn't what I want
mean anything at all ?
Okay, interesting. Tell us.
What do you want, Sweetface ?
I think I want to be a boy.
Yes ! In your face, lady !
But being a girl would be nice, too.
Well, which is it ?
l'm not sure.
Sometimes I feel like a boy.
Sometimes I feel like a girl.
Can't I be both ?
- Well, some people...
- No way.
But one thing I do know for sure.
I don't want to be a killer.
Glenda. Glen. Whatever.
l'm so proud of you.
No matter what happens...
we'Il deal with it together,
as a family.
Okay, Okasan.
Wait a minute.
l'm not going to let you
poison our son's mind...
with your touchy-feely,
1 2-step bullshit.
If you two don't want
to kill anymore, that's your loss.
But don't look down your noses
at me.
l'm not ashamed to be a killer.
l'm proud of it.
It is not an addiction.
It is a choice.
And it is not something that you
should have to hide in a closet !
- Oh, dear.
- Oh, God.
Well, well, well.
Looks like Miss High and Mighty...
ain't so perfect after all.
It was just a little slip.
Rome wasn't built in a day,
you know.
Besides, the fucker
really had it coming.
- Well, what about my body ?
- l'Il take care of it.
Jennifer, I love you.
I love you.
This is Stan.
Hello, it's Jennifer.
Stan, baby, I need your body.
l'Il be right there.
Jennifer, if anything happens to me,
I want you to know...
They really do make a cute couple,
don't you think ?
- It's like my mother always said...
- Christ !
Enough with your mother, already.
I killed that bitch 20 years ago
and she still won't shut up.
There, there. It won't be long now.
Who is it ?
It's that nosy bitch, Joan.
l'Il take care of her.
I wouldn't want you to violate
your delicate sensibilities.
Jennifer ?
Jennifer !
Jennifer.
Oh my God
Jennifer ?
Look out behind you !
Joan !
No !
Dang !
Look, l'm not going to
give you crap.
Nobody is perfect, Tiff.
I got a few skeletons
in the closet myself.
See ?
Come on, Tiff.
How long did it take
to build Rome, anyway ?
Glen ?
Guess again, Daddy.
Glenda ?
That's my name.
Don't you wear it out.
Shit.
What did I miss ?
Nothing much. I just fired Joan.
Looks like you win after all, Tiff.
Congratulations.
You both win.
l'm a real lady-killer...
if you catch my drift.
l'm a bona fide bonus baby.
Jesus Christ, Chucky,
what did you do to him ?
What did I do ?
At least I spent time with the kid.
Glen, wake up.
Stop it, Mommy.
You'Il wrinkle my dress.
And how do you like it ?
I made it myself.
Like mother, like daughter, right ?
Like mother, like daughter.
Get it ?"Mother and daughter."
I said, wake up ! Right now.
Mom ? Dad ?
What am I ?
Push, Miss Tilly. Push.
I am pushing,
you little star-fucker !
Pay no attention
to little Miss Potty Mouth.
She's hormonal.
My God. It's coming.
I can see its little head.
What is it ?
It's a boy.
- A boy.
- Thank God.
Give me my baby.
I want my baby.
Chucky, we're not done here yet.
- What ?
- Jennifer isn't done.
We've got another one here !
Push, Jennifer ! Push !
Push it out ! Push !
What's this one ?
- It's a girl.
- Groovy.
Chucky, it's time.
ade due damballla.
Give me the power, I beg of you.
Chucky, first he has to choose.
I beg your pardon.
Sorry. She has to choose.
- We don't have time for this shit !
- Wait, Chucky.
We have a son and a daughter.
Glen and Glenda.
Don't you get it ?
Maybe they don't have to choose.
Help !
Hurry, Chucky ! Do the chant.
- Do it now !
- Help us !
What are you standing there for ?
Do the chant !
What are you waiting for ? Do it !
Do it !
Everybody just shut up !
I have had it ! That's it !
There is a limit
to how much I can take.
What are you talking about ?
Look around you, Tiff. This is nuts.
And I have a very high tolerance
for nuts.
If this is what it takes
to be human...
then I would rather take my chances
as a supernaturally possessed doll.
It's less complicated.
- You can't be serious ?
- As a heart attack.
Think about it.
What is so great
about being human, anyway ?
You get sick. You get old.
You can't get it up anymore.
l'm not looking forward to that.
But I want to be Jennifer Tilly.
I want to be a star.
And I don't want to be
your chauffeur.
As a doll, l'm fucking infamous.
l'm one of the most
notorious slashers in history.
And I don't want to give that up.
I am Chucky, the killer doll !
And I dig it !
I have everything I want :
a beautiful wife...
a multi-talented kid.
This is who I am, Tiff.
This is me.
Chucky, I don't know
what the fuck you're talking about.
I don't know
who the fuck you are anymore.
But it's not enough for me.
I want more.
- What are you saying ?
- It's over.
You've got to
get out of here, Sweetface.
l'm leaving you, Chucky,
and l'm taking the kid.
Nobody leaves me. Nobody !
No !
Jennifer. I... love
I... love
Stan, tell me. Tell me.
- I love...
- What ?
Jesus.
Oh, my God.
My babies. Give me my babies.
I just want to know where they are.
They're fine.
They're in the maternity ward.
All right, was that so hard ?
The important thing to think
about now is getting well...
so you can get on
with your life and your career.
I don't care about my career.
I want my babies.
l'm working on it,
but you're not making it easy.
I already talked to the cops.
They cleared me.
They know you're not a killer.
They didn't say
you were mentally competent.
What do you expect,
after the story you told them ?
It's true.
Yeah, well, I suggest from now on
you keep that to yourself.
We'Il talk later.
Try to get some sleep.
Wish me luck, Sweetface.
Mommy is going to be a star.
I can't think of a thing to say.
Fuck it !
ade due damballla.
Give me the power, I beg of you.
Leveau mercier du bois chaloitte.
Sequoise entienne mais pois de morte.
Ade du damballa...
Switch ! Switch ! Switch ! Switch ! Switch...
Nobody leaves me. Nobody.
I want you to be a good girl...
or boy. Whatever.
Don't make the same mistakes
your mom and dad made.
Especially your dad.
Let's go.
Glenda ?
No, Dad ! It's me ! Your boy !
Your chip off the old block !
Are you proud of me now, Daddy ?
Are you ?
Attaboy, kid. Attaboy.
There, there.
It's all right.
It's going to be all right.
Yesterday, she gave Dana Shelton
a bloody nose...
and took pictures of it
for Show and Tell.
She called the cat the "C" word.
And l'm pretty sure she's been
taking money from my purse.
That's ridiculous.
Glen, he is an angel.
An absolute dream.
But Glenda...
she's a bad girl, Miss Tilly.
A very bad girl.
l'm not listening to this.
I hate that thing.
Some of the kids
really want to see her.
- Miss Tilly.
- What ?
- l'm afraid of her.
- Fulvia, it's only a doll.
I was talking about Glenda.
Just exactly
what are you trying to say ?
I can't work here anymore.
- What ?
- l'm sorry, I just can't.
If you only saw the way
she looks at me...
with such hate.
All right, Fulvia,
if that's what you want.
We'Il miss you.
Thank you, Miss Tilly. God bless.
Mom got her wish.
She's a bright shining star.
Now we're the perfect family.
l've learned a lot about myself.
I know l'm not alone.
I know l'm not a freak.
And even though
we had our differences...
I know my dad really loved me.
Glen, sweetheart, come over here.
Here, sweetheart, look.
Here's another one.
- Who is it from, Mommy ?
- I don't know.
Let's see. It doesn't say.
Strange. It doesn't say who it is.
Bye, sweetheart. Don't run so fast.
You're going to trip.
So anyway, he determined
that he was going to go off...
I just love this movie. Don't you ?
I can't think of a thing to say.
Fuck it !
Oh, God !