¶ Music
Toss'em and bag'em.
Enjoy.
It's good.
Not great.
But seeing that you are a
business man, Mr. Santiago.
Captain.
[Laughs] Captain.
My associates and I are willing
to negotiate, a reasonable price.
Let's say, 100,000.
[Laughs]
One million for the entire take,
Not a penny less.
A steep price for a small catch.
A pod of 20,000 sharks are
migrating in this direction.
When we're through with it,
One million will look like a bargain.
500.
If you're looking to negotiate, Mr.
Palmer, look for the insurance salesman.
I do believe we have a deal.
[Thunder]
All hands on deck.
Tie the sails!
Get the fins to the gally!
Captain there is a north wind
hitting us fast!
You need to get up here.
I think this is for you captain.
The deposit.
You'll receive the rest when we dock.
You know the most important
thing I learned out here?
We shouldn't be afraid of the sharks.
They should be the ones to be afraid of us.
Salud.
[Waves Crashing]
What the hell is that?
They're called waves. They do
that from time to time.
The storm is too strong. We are
going to have to go around it.
Make it happen. I'm going to
down below.
[Waves Crashing]
Captain!
[Screams]
[Gun Shot]
[Gun Shots]
Change of plans Captain. I'm
going to take the money, your
cargo, and what's left of the ship.
[Gun Shot] Aah!
[Screams]
I don't think so.
Crazy waves out there today.
Something unnatural about it.
There's nothing unnatural about
everything.
Lots of scenery today.
I'm gonna focus on the waves.
You better hurry mate. The
clouds are coming in.
Whoo! Reminds me of the
nationals back in 04. Remember?
You totally ripped that bugger. I thought
you were going to be rag dolled for sure.
You know we really don't talk
like that, right?
You doing a ride-out or not?
Sure. Thanks.
It's totally cooking out here mate.
You're not kidding. It's a Mexican
hurricane. Bad for them good for us.
Isn't that a drink?
Hit. Hit!
[Laughs] Whoo!
[Reporter] Good Morning California
this is Jonni Waves. That's Jonni with
with an "I". You may have noticed this
morning the unusul weather here in southern
California. The clouds coming n over the ocean
and the large waves are proving difficult
for surfers. I'm here in Santa Monica with
some breaking news about Hurricane David.
It's been pounding the west coast of Mexico.
Pushing it's way up to the coast to the
state of California. It seems o be
driving a very dangerous surf.
No kidding. Fin's out there.
Yeah but I won't worry about fin,
I mean he's the best surfer I've ever seen.
Except for me of course.
In my prime.
When was that George?
The civil war?
Eh, I'm not that old. You know I
got some movies babe...
Hey! What did I tell you? You can touch
everything at this bar except for me.
- Hey! Come on!
- Oopsies! Looks like you need another drink
Yeah I need one. One on the house.
One that doesn't coast me any money.
How come you never talk about that scar?
There's nothing to talk about.
I cut myself shaving.
4 bucks.
4 Bucks? I thought it was on the
house. You spilled the last one.
[Reporter] Perhaps the silver
lining in this is that the storm
driven away the inflex of
sharks out of the area...
Yeah I hope it does. Hope it does. I hope
the storm kills'em. I hope it kills them all.
[Sigh]
Me too. You have no idea.
[Waves crashing]
[Laughs]
Tired already?
What's the last time you short
boarded, old timer?
I never stopped. I just like
this one rides.
Yeah. Whatever.
Alright grandpa. Ima show you
how it's done.
Grandpa?
Show her how it's done, Grandpa!
[Splash]
Come on. Oh!
Deanna there's a shark!
[Screams]
Hey get outta the water!
[Screaming]
SHARKS!
Hey Get out of the water!
Sharks! They're coming in!
Get off the beach!
Get out of the water!
Sharks! Get out of the water!
[Scream]
[Coast Guard] SHARKS!
Everyone out of the water now!
[Coast Guard] Everyone out of
the water now! We're evacuating
the beach. Everybody off
the beach immediately.
Aaah!
[Screaming]
Come here you bloody shark! Come
here!
Aaah!
Baz!
Just hang on. I'll let you in.
[Screaming]
These sharks of your have no etiquette.
Etiquette?
I thought you were Australian not British.
Tasmanian buddy.
Just hang on, I'll get you in.
[Screaming]
What were you thinking? You
could have been killed.
I'm fine.
Aah!
We need a tourniquet.
Here use this.
It's just a - aah!
- Little nibble.
Aah!
Are you ok? Are you sure?
He must have wanted a snack.
[Laughs]
Sharks don't like vegemite.
It's not funny.
Aah.
Hey. You gonna be ok?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Hey can I get some of those
tasty nuts. Thank you.
And then. Are you listening? The shark opens it's mouth.
Goes to swallow fin whole but Fin
Looks at the shark - Do the
look.
No, do the look.
Oh my god.
Yeah that one. And the shark
goes, 'You know what?'
I'm pissing off. I'm not gonna
mess with the surf champion.
Surf legend. Finley the Fin Shepard.
Ain't that right?
On you mate.
I don't believe it. You guys are
nuts.
Look.
Do you see that?
- Oh yeah.
- It's a little nibble.
So he gives him a look and you
give him a nibble -
No, HE gave me a nibble.
I don't know. Are you guys going back
out there and do any swimming?
With the sharks?
It's a storm.
It's what's driven them all up north.
Eventually they'll go back from they came from.
I hope. But the were knocking.
Yeah knock knock knocking on your door.
And i have never seen so many and so bold.
It's just a storm. Just gotta stay out of
the water for a couple days that's all.
Just a storm?
Looks like a hurricane.
I'm just happy you're ok.
Hey hey, what are you doing?
What? Do you think you're too
old for me?
No, I'm your boss.
So?
So? Go get back to work.
Hey! I'm not too old for ya.
I don't think.
I'm not your boss.
Daddy issues. Hey! I'm not
judging you darlin'.
[Nova smacks him] George: Ouch!
I have daddy issues too.
- Here to issues.
- Yeah!
Who's is this?
[Reporter] Hurricane David is
poised to be the 1st hurricane to hit
the state of California. And it is now
barreling to the Santa Monica shorelines.
We have suffered tropical stors in the past but
we have never been hit by a storm quite like
this. Wide spread flooding is expected
and experts are saying global warming
is the reason for this
unprecedented event. We will
be back with more news as it develops.
[Phone Ringing]
Hello. Wexler residence.
April it's Fin.
Yeah Fin I know your voice. What
do you want?
Look I'm just calling to make sure-
When did you go back to using
Wexler again?
[Laughs]
cause that's my name.
Look Fin I'm really busy.
Just calling to make sure you
and Claudia are ok.
There's a bad hurricane rolling
in and I want-
Is this about money?
Because if this is about money
Fin, I told you already that-
It's the storm. I just want to
make sure guys are ok.
Of course we're ok. It's barely
even raining.
Look, it's really sweet that you are calling in to
check in on us but Collin already checked the
drains and, we're gonna be fine.
They're cleared out.
Well it's flooding here and not
the plumbing. The ocean.
I think you guys should get out of town.
What are you talking about? We
are 100 miles from the ocean.
You are exactly 6.6 miles from the ocean.
And on a day like today it's not far enough.
I'm gonna take you and Claudia
further inland.
And what about Collin?
You know you are not the only
one that can keep us safe.
We're not going anywhere.
Fine. Then let me just get Claudia.
We'll it my week for the month.
Is that what this is about?
No!
Look you are gonna see her on the 20th
like you always do. I gotta go ok. Bye Fin.
Who's that?
My wife.
That is his wife.
- Yeah his wife.
- Shut up Baz.
[Thunder]
Already everybody, listen up.
I'm closing the restaurant.
Storm is coming and it's coming
fast. Get home safe everybody.
Don't forget taco Tuesdays.
George, you got to get out of here.
What's going on?
If I don't secure the bar, I'm
going to loose everything.
Come on George, George wake up.
Oh! I hear an angel, I must be
in heaven.
George you better wake up or I'm
calling in your bar tab.
Oh, i'm up I'm up.
Hey hey, you need to go home.
I'm not going anywhere.
This is not your problem.
No! It is my problem. Because if this bar
get blown over then I'm out of a job too.
Yeah, and I'm not gonna have any
place to drink.
Can't argue with that one.
[Crash / window shatter]
[Screaming]
For an environmentalist you sure
do hate sharks.
I've got fire power behind the
bar. Come on come on!
Alright, grab a weapon. Grab anything
you can find to defend yourself.
Give me something dangerous.,
[George Slurring his words]
Can I get one for the road Fin?
[Mumbling]
Huh? What?
Come on let's go let's go let's go!
[Nova] George get your ass up!
Now!
Alright.
[Screaming]
Come on kid.
Don't you ever make fun of my
stool again.
Come on come on.
That's what you get for trying to eat me.
Come on come on guys let's go.
[Screaming]
We are here live at the Santa Monica Pier,
this is what remains after
the massive storm tore through the popular attraction.
The waves also brought in sharks
which have injured dozens and
killed several people.
[Sirens]
We'll rebuild mate.
Insurance will cover it.
L.A. wasn't built for all this water.
I'm really worried about Claudia and April.
I really gotta go check on them.
I'm coming with you.
April doesn't like you, remember?
Nah mate. She doesn't like you, remember?
She loves me. Where do you think Claudia came from?
Who's Claudia?
His daughter.
You have an ex-wife and a daughter?
I can drop you at home if you want?
I live on the beach it's obviously flooded.
No where else to go.
Looks like we're all refugees now.
[Sigh] I wanna go with you.
Make sure your family is ok.
[Raining]
Anybody seen George?
George?
Here he is.
Oh man. I'm glad you woke me up.
I was having the worst nightmare.
Gosh the water is raising.
Water is not going to be a problem.
All the electronics have been sealed with
silicone. We'll be fine.
I've driven this thing from here
to the beaches of Costa Rica.
Why is the car shaking.
What the hell. There are sharks
on the streets.
These fish surely have a hankering for me.
It's like one taste of Baz is
just isn't enough.
Hey whoa whoa whoa.
Hold up with the guns. We don't
need more blood in the water.
That's a tiger shark.
How do you know that?
Shark Week.
Were'd it go?
Where did it go?
Ah geez.
- [Grunt]
- Hey
It's under the car.
Well can I start shooting now?
Yea. Do it.
We got to get to higher ground.
Take the freeway. It's above street level.
You take the 10 to the 405. You're almost in
Bevelry Hills. And there is no way
the ocean has washed inland that far.
What makes you an expert on
Beverly Hills George?
That's where I live.
George if you live in Beverly Hills
why do you come all the way to the
coast to come and drink at my bar?
I don't know. I like the view,
you know.
There's the beach. There's all these scantily
glad women there that pretend to like me if
I buy them a drink. And there is my seat.
My chair. My chair is always there.
Plus you don't charge 15 dollars a plock.
[Laughs] Yeah.
Plus there is the beautiful Nova there
who I am planning to marry soon.
I sit around and think about it every
night and day. Everywhere I go. [Laughs]
[Screeching Tires]
Hey!
Bloody hell.
That's the 405.
I hate the 405.
Bloody hell. What are these
idiots doing?
Yeah I'll just go around them.
You need to back up. I need to
get out of here!
Get back in your car. It's not
safe out here.
It's just a little water.
Typical Californians are afraid of the rain.
Yeah.
Stop!
Watch it will ya.
Maybe they're not such idiots after all.
Oh my god.
It's like old faithful.
We're gonna need faith to get
through that.
The water is raising behind us.
What what what?
[Screaming]
Oh my god!
I just can't sit back and watch this.
- What?
- The sharks are swimming right at them.
They're not gonna make it.
Don't even think about it.
Fin! Where you going?
The sharks are falling from the freakin sky.
[Yells] Here we go again.
Nova!
There's sharks out there. You
don't have to go out there.
There's absolutely no reason to
go out there.
Everyone needs to get to higher ground!
Puppy!
Somebody help me! Help me get my
dog out!
Please help me! My dog is locked
inside.
This area is flooding.
Come on, get out!
Please!
[Barking]
Please help!
[Everyone yelling]
Somebody help!
Ok. You go!
Ok. I got you princess come on.
There you go.
[Barking]
Come on George.
George! Come on George!
[Rushing water]
Oh Crap!
Ouch! Get off of me!
[Screaming]
It's not gonna end.
The flood channels, the storm
drains, the sewers.
It's not gonna stop at the coast.
They're going to swim everywhere.
Come on get in the car.
We've got to go through this.
What?
You've got kangaroos loose in the
brain mate. We can't go through that.
The aerodynamics in this car
cannot match the waves.
The waves are only gonna get
bigger as the storm get closer.
Trust me, if there is one thing
I know, it's timing waves.
That's what I was afraid of.
They come in sets of 3.
One.
Two.
Three.
[Screeching Tires]
Whoo.
Are you ok?
I'm alright. 10 fingers. 10
Toes.
Uh, gotta love LA.
What are these people thinking?
Nothing.
Does April know you coming?
No.
But at least we'll be in the
hills away from the flooding.
Alright.
It's awfully nice of you to let her
new boyfriend stay in your house.
Don't remind me.
[Sirens]
Unbelievable.
We're almost at the house.
That's too bad. I was hoping it
was further up the hill.
April!
Hey let us in.
Whoa! What are you doing here?
And what happened to him?
Nothing. Your Fin save my
life.
He's not my Fin anymore.
And who is she?
It's Nova. She works at the bar.
Now will you let us in.
No! I told you not to come.
No! Just go away. Take your
stupid friend and Baz and leave.
[Sewer Erupts]
[Gun Shot]
Nice Shot.
By the way I'm not a stripper.
Claudia!
She doesn't want to talk to you.
Dad? What are you doing here?
There's a big storm coming in.
It's not safe here.
I'm not going anywhere with you.
Just leave.
I didn't come here to argue with you.
I came here to get you.
I don't care.
What is all the ruckus?
Awe Sheppard.
Should have figured it was you.
What are you doing here?
L.A. is drowning.
I'm going inland. I'm taking my
family with me.
Finley. April is mine.
Excuse me?
My girlfriend is not your responsibility.
And unless it's the 20th of the month,
which currently it's not. Neither is Claudia.
Collin, don't be rude. He's just
worried about us.
Every time it rains in L.A. everyone
swears it's the storm of the century.
And even if it is, Beverly Hills
emergency services a second to none.
[Chuckles]
We're safe here.
There are sharks flooding the streets.
And there is now one swimming in
your pool.
Are you kidding?
Shark in the swimming pool is impossible.
[Screams]
Collin!
Something is on my foot! I can't
move!
Finley Help me! Finley!
Watch out!
[Screaming]
Collin!
Help me! It's getting away!
I've got your back.
Get it's nose.
[Grunts]
Die already!
[Screaming]
It's coming back!
- No!
- Oh my gosh!
Fin!
Ready?
[Screaming]
Fin!
Where'd it go?
Where's it go?
- Go go go!
- Oh my gosh!
[Gun Shots]
Fin hurry up, Get over here.
Nice shot.
Thanks.
Looks like it's that time of the month.
Look!
We're out of Ammo.
The eye of the storm still
hasn't come to shore yet.
It's gonna get worse before it gets any better.
We got to get inland and we got to get
some place safe for all of us.
Where?
I'm thinking the desert.
No, we have to go to Van Nuys to get Matt.
Matt's in flight school there.
Matt's at flight school? I thought he was
vacationing at Tampa with his buddies.
When did this happen? I just
talked to him.
How come no body tells me these things.
I'm suppose to be included in these conversations.
He wanted to tell you but, Collin said
it was none of your business anymore.
Who's Matt?
My brother.
You have a son too?
Alright.
We got to get out of here quick.
How are we going to do that?
I'm going to push the shark out of here.
I'm gonna distract it.
When I do this, get to the car
as fast as you can.
[Splash]
Now!
He'll be ok.
Fin!
Come on, get in!
Move it! Move your ass!
[Glass Shatter]
[Screeching Tires] Go Go Go!
Easy come, easy go.
[Reporter on Portable TV] The eye of
hurricane David is continuing it's relentless
pounding through the streets of Los Angeles.
And more surprisingly and most shocking
reports have been pouring in from all over,
that sharks are washing ashore.
Live sharks. And not just from the coastal
flooding but they are coming up through the drais
Do you always have this much
ammo in your jeep?
Sepra Peratus.
Dad, are you really saying that
right now. Can you be serious?
It means?
Always be prepared.
Thank you.
I always thought it would be an earthquake
that would be the end of Los Angeles.
Or a meteor shower. Zombies
even.
Yeah.
Black Plague. Aliens.
But sharks? Come on.
Yeah.
Yeah. Go figure. My luck,
sharks.
Yeah your luck. Sharks.
Mine too.
[Sigh]
I'm not gonna lie. It's kinda
hot when you do that.
[Chuckles]
[Reporter] Again we will keep
yo updated n this storm.
This is Jonni Waves. That's
Jonni with an "I"-
Call Matt.
This is the emergency alert system.
National weather servie has issued a tornado warning
through Los Angeles County. Water spouts have
been detected in the coastal water from Orane
No kidding. You are a bit late
on that one.
We got to get out of here fast.
We got to go get Matt.
The freeways will be a nightmare.
But there's a short cut if you turn right up here.
That's how I always get around the Hollywood
traffic with my friends.
What are you doing in Hollywood?
Since when do you care?
Hold on.
The storm is dying down.
How can you tell?
Not as many sharks flying around.
Why you stopping. We have to go
get Matt.
Don't you see that? There could
be kids in there.
There's no one in there. And
your kid is right here.
We got to get her somewhere safe.
This is so typical of you Fin.
You care more about other people
then you do your own family.
Let's go!
Please.
I can't.
The water is raising. I'm going to go
up on the bridge and rappel down.
Fin this is crazy.
[Kids Screaming]
Calm down guys. Calm down ok.
There's other grown ups coming ok?
Uh uh, Police Department, Fire Department.
They're going to get us out of this.
As long as we stay in here we
are going to be fine, ok?
Trust me. We're gonna be just
fine.
[Kids Screaming]
Anybody in there?
Whoa! Whoa! Be careful.
Need a lift?
[Kids Cheering]
I'm glad to see you.
Send the rope.
I reached dispatch right before all the electronics
went out. They said someone from 911
is sending someone over.
Oh yeah? Want to wait for them?
Hell no!
I didn't think so. Who's first?
Ok, come over here honey.
Ok.
Alright Samantha you're going to
be alright.
Start pulling, they are ready.
Alright you ready? Just keep looking up.
It's gonna be fine Samantha.
Here we go.
Ok, Lift her up!
Alright here we go Samantha
you're going to be alright.
Go ahead.
It's gonna be just like flying.
Come on come on. Quicker, let's
go.
Yes!
Yes! Alright pull'em up!
You're doing already. You're
doing good. Don't be afraid.
Come on. Hold on tight.
He's up.
Alright.
Alright, who's next?
A bunch of little kids went up before me.
How hard can it be right?
Let's go.
Alright.
Go over there. Come on sweetheart.
Your dad is trying to do good here.
Give him a hand.
Are you sure this thing is
strong enough to hold me?
Nope I'm not.
Great.
I'm sure not looking forward
going in there after you.
Yeah.
I hate sharks. I'm from Wyoming.
You know- [Laughs]
I moved down here to be an actor. [Laughs]
Dad.
[Scream]
Screaming]
I got to go up right now!
Please!
Up up up!
Come on!
Oh god! 15 grand a year. No benefits.
Screaming kids. [Screams]
Call down. It's ok. Don't Panic.
I use to hate heights. Now I'm
away from sharks.
Ok let's do this now before I
become hot lunch.
Watch out fin!
[Screaming]
Watch out to the right. Watch
out!
[Screaming] Oh my gosh be careful.
Watch your foot.
Hurry, keep going faster.
[Screaming] Oh my gosh!
Be careful!
Be careful Fin!
Watch out!
Fin come on! Watch out Fin!
I had just about enough of you.
Be careful Fin!
[Grunts] Come on.
Your ok. Oh my gosh.
Finny, look at the sky.
The storm is clearing up. Maybe
it's done.
Good.
These guys are gonna get you home, ok?
Be safe.
[Wind]
Oh Crap.
What?
Claudia get in the Jeep!
I'm fine mom.
Get down! Get down!
[Screams]
You alright?
[Laughing]
You ok?
My mom always told me Hollywood
would kill me.
Start the engine.
Is that good?
Ok rev it. Rev it.
Guys it's flooding.
It's gonna be easier if we steal
another car.
Then steal another car.
There's a small gas leak but it
should run for now.
What is that?
It's a water spout.
Tornado over the ocean. Water
gets sucked up in the air...
Are those sharks?
Yeah. Come on. Come on.
Close her up. Let's go.
[Thunder]
Well, at least the rain is easing up a bit.
[Loud bang on car]
- What was that?
[Noise continues]
[Screaming]
Oh my god. Oh my god.
What the hell?
Kill it!
This is crazy!
Hit the breaks!
Get down Claudia!
[Screaming]
Bloody hell!
Why did we stop?
It must be flooded.
Well fix it!
Mate I smell gas.
I do too. Get out of the car!
Get out of the car!
Go go go!
The gun!
[Explosion]
Can I use you phone please?
It's been dead for hours.
Thanks.
No problem.
So what kinda name is Nova anyway?
That's the kinda name you give yourself
when you don't like the person you use to be.
Hey, uh. Look, I see the way you
took at my dad.
He's just gonna break your heart
just like he did to my mom and I.
It looks like the eye of the storm is over.
Or maybe not.
Hey make it quick. I don't want
to spend too much time here.
[Reporter] With these storms ravaging
the streets of Los Angeles, some religious
[Chuckles] Apocalypse my ass.
This isn't the end of the world. Gods not angry with us.
The Aliens are not coming down.
It's the government.
Ye-ah.
With the big capital G. They're
behind everything.
They know what we buy. They know what
we eat. Where we go to the bathroom.
Hurry. Hurry.
They know what kinda cheese I like.
Pepper Jack.
[Whispers] And the weather too.
I gotta hand it to the, Sharks.
I never saw that coming.
Y-eah.
[Reporter] Weather satellites
they're currently tracking 3 off shore
water spouts over the pacific ocean.
Experts are categorizing this as an EF4.
With a potential to becoming ad EF5 tornado
by the time it touches down on land.
I n the San Fernando Valley all
roads are blocked and movement-
Protein.
I know how we're going to get out of here.
You know we need a car first.
I've got it covered.
Oh nice!
You're gonna need stiches and antibiotics.
And you're gonna have a hell of a scar.
That's ok. Chicks dig scars,
right?
Why you driving so fast?
We got to get there fast before
they clear the accident.
What accident?
Something I saw on the news
Look out!
Whoa!
This is nuts.
Now we're never gonna get to Van Nuys.
- Baz, Drive around it.
- I can't. It's blocked in every direction.
We got to get Matt before the
storm picks up again.
I'm going for it.
- Are you crazy! Don't do it
- Go! Go! Go!
Whoo!
[Sirens]
[Police] Pull your car over.
Dad! The police are chasing us.
- Hey Baz.
- Yeah.
Stop your vehicle now!
Drive faster.
No worries mate.
Fast enough for ya?
Yeah.
[Police] Pull to the side of the road.
[Sirens]
[Police] Stop your vehicle now.
Hey Baz, is that nitrous button?
- It certainly is mate.
- What do yo say we hit that?
- Give it a go.
- Hold on folks.
[Sirens Continue]
Hold on to your panties ladies.
[Fin Laughing]
Oh man!
Whoo! Now this is fun.
I think we lost them.
Now we're talking.
Ok.
It should be smooth sailing from here.
Why is there a retirement home
next to an airport?
Because old people can't hear.
It doesn't look like they've left.
Their cars are still here.
I'm gonna go look upstairs.
Ok. I'll check these rooms.
Matt?
Has anybody seen anything?
[Wind]
It's time to leave Kansas mate.
There's no one up here.
Where is everyone?
Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa!
No no no. I'm looking for Matt.
Is there a Matt here?
Matt?
Uh, yeah yeah. I'm Matt. Who are
you?
Guys I found Matt com on.
Come here. He's in here.
Matt!
Dad? Mom?
What are you guys doing here?
We had to come inland to avoid the storm.
- We came in to get you.
- There's sharks everywhere.
Sharks?
Is this the best shelter you got?
Look, we don't exactly have a storm cellar.
We better find something to
protect ourselves and quick.
From what?
They couldn't possibly make it
all the way out here.
They can.
It's entirely possible. A hurricane can
pick up marine life out of the ocean
and drop it hundreds of miles away.
Hold this.
Yeah, he's right. It happened once near Alice Springs.
100s of perch fell from the sky.
Why not Sharks?
Look, what the hell is going on here?
[Loud Bang]
[Creaking]
[Screaming]
It's a Sharknado!
Let's get inside here. Get in
get in.
The news said that there is 3 tornadoes
in the area. We're not safe here.
What's the fastest way to get out of here?
Can that fly?
I don't know. Let me check.
Looks pretty beat up.
Hey you know what? She'll fly.
We're not all gonna fit in here.
We can't fly in these storms.
Then what are we gonna do?
We're gonna stand and fight?
We just wait and wait here for
sharks to rain down to us again.
We need to arm ourselves with
something more powerful then these.
What were you thinking?
That store, It's got everything
we need.
Sepra peratus.
[Chuckles]
They must have evacuated.
How are we getting in?
Guys stand back. I have the key.
[Gun Shot]
Dad, I'll be right back.
I have an idea. Come with me.
[Chuckles]
Oh nice! This is what I'm talking about.
[Talking Under Breath]
Hey, do you think you can make
this work?
Yeah. I'll make it work.
Good.
Bombs.
Bombs?
Instead of letting live sharks rain down on
people, we are going to get in that chopper
and throw bombs into the tornadoes.
Blasting those bastards to bits.
I like it, but how is that gonna
stop a tornado?
Tornadoes happen when cold and
warm air meet.
Now if you drop a bomb head, right in the
middle of it, You might just equalize it.
But if you miss, we're screwed.
Oh, hell no. You got a death
wish? No way!
Dad, I'm the only one that could do it.
Bobby and Noellen haven't even solo yet.
What's wrong?
Your son wants to go into a helicopter
and drop a bomb into the tornado.
No! It's too dangerous.
I'll watch his back. I'll be his
bombardier.
Then definitely not.
Dad, we have a chance to save
thousands of lives. Maybe more.
You always taught me to help
others. I'm going.
He's right April. We'll work it out together.
I won't let anything happen to him.
Don't you understand you can die Matt?
Mom, we don't have any other option.
And you are not gonna stop me.
He certainly is your son.
Shopping cart?
Yeah.
Claud?
Hey! Come on. What are you doing
down here? What's the problem?
You.
Your my problem.
Are we really gonna do that now?
Now?
Look, what are you and mom doing?
You guys can barely stand to be in a
room together for 5 minutes, and now
What? Cause you are saving Matt
you're best friends again?
He is my son.
I'm your daughter.
You guys are always there for him
and you're never there for me.
Hey get that one. No no the
other one.
You don't think I try?
Not hard enough.
I came for you first.
Try to remember that.
Come on. Come on.
Hey.
I fell off a slide when I was 2.
It hurt like hell.
Now people think it's cool.
No body thinks this is cool.
What happened?
I had a tattoo removed.
I don't like to talk about it.
[Sigh]
I was raised by my grandparents.
We I was 7 my grandpa took me fishing with
one of those day charter deals with his friends.
We end up hitting into a reef
and the boat went down.
My grandfather took me and put me
inside this little life- raft for safety.
Everyone else was kinda swimming around
trying to stay up and suddenly all these
sharks just started swarming and-
and then they...
tried to protect me but...
By morning they were all gone.
So I floated out there for 2 days
until one of those coast guard
helicopters finally spotted me.
I thought I was safe but suddenly
this shark leaped up and bit my leg.
6 people went into the water and
one little girl came out.
The sharks took the rest.
They took my grandfather.
So I really hate sharks.
Now I really hate sharks too.
[Chuckles]
Nice work kids.
But this, this is a bomb.
Dad, the tornado is coming.
Hey!
Hey what are you doing?
In case things don't work out,
We're going to move to plan B.
Baz builds a bigger bomb, and
drives this in into the storm.
That's not gonna work. It's a
one way trip.
Especially with that leg.
You want to see me try?
No!
Fin, look after your family.
They are a good bunch.
It's fine.
Alright, do what you gotta do.
Don't I always?
I will.
Watch our backs.
Be careful.
[Clears Throat]
Alright get ready.
Do we have enough bombs?
Sure hope so.
First time on a chopper?
Yeah.
Scared?
Hell No!
Oh Crap.
Look at all those sharks!
Look out! More Sharks!
[Heavy Breathing] What are we gonna do?
You got it dad.
Oh my god, there's just too many
of them!
We're gonna need a bigger chopper.
- I hope this bomb idea of yours works.
- Trust me. It will.
- We're getting close. Get Ready.
- Ready?
- Yeah. Bombs. Bombs.
- Bombs. Bombs Bombs Bombs.
Careful with those Robert.
Alright, here's how you do it.
Open the valve.
First tornado coming to the left here.
Push the button. Hold it for 3
seconds. We're gonna count.
Ok.
1. 2. 3.
Strike!
[Screams]
Whoo! Hahaha.
[Laughing]
- Whoo! I did it! - Told ya!
That worked!
Fin!
[Chainsaw reving]
How's the front end looking Bobby?
I'm not a captain yet sir.
Bobby look out!
[Screams]
- Get down!
[Grunts]
The tornado is coming this way.
Baz!
Second tornado! Second tornado!
The tornado is headed towards the airport.
We need to destroy it before it get to them.
[Grunts] Why!
Baz! Baz!
[Screaming]
Dad! You have to leave him!
It's getting closer. We have to
go now of we're dead.
OK, Tell me when.
Come on. Come on.
Let's go up there!
Ok people, everybody out of the pool.
Everybody needs to get out of the pool and inside.
Yes Carl that means you. Out now
please.
[Reporter] This is Jonni Waves
that's Joni with an "I" reporting live
as just one of these massive tornados
is about to tear through Hollywood
and it's headed on course through the
Valley and onto Van Nuys. It's about to tear
through the city of Los Aahh!
[Screams]
Getting close to the second tornado.
Already got another one.
Press the button down for 3 seconds.
We're gonna count together. - Ok ok ok.
Alright. 1.2.3.
Light it!
[Explosion]
Falling sharks!
[Screams]
Come on let's get them inside.
Oh my god. Run! Run!
- Run! Honey!
- I can't run, I can't even walk!
[Seniors chatter]
[Gasps/Chatter]
Alright. Third tornado.
Look at the size of that thing.
Just stay focused.
- It's showtime!
- I'm on it!
Go it!
Alright. Strike it!
[Scream]
Who is that up there?
That's my son.
You must be so proud.
Yeah. Yeah I am.
Its not working.
The bomb didn't land right.
- Hey!
- We're out of bombs. What do we do?
I'll head back to base.
Turbulence is picking up.
Oh my god!
The Shark! The Shark!
- Watch out! Watch out!
- Get off me get off me!
Die already! Why won't you die!
[Screams]
[Yells]
Ooh! Oh my god!
[Yells] No!
[Beeping from Helicopter panel]
[Screaming]
Help!
Matt!
Get everybody to safely.
Come on everybody! Let's get
away from the window.
Matt! Matt!
Come on! Come on! Get out of
here.
Come here. Come on.
[Grunts]
Are you alright?
Yeah. Yeah where is mom and
Claudia?
They're on the hill.
Where's Nova?
She - Didn't make it.
Go look after your mother and sister.
Where you going?
I'm going to finish this.
[Screaming]
[Explosion]
Move! Get out of the way!
Daddy!
Get out of there!
Get outta the way!
Claudia Move!
[Chainsaw Revving]
Fin!
Dad!
[Heavy Breathing] Dad!
Oh my god.
[Chainsaw Revving]
Dad?
[Yelling]
[Coughing]
Dad!
Nova!
Come on.
[Grunts]
- Dad are you ok?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Oh my god.
Breathe. Breathe!
Come on!
[Coughing]
[Laughs] Oh my god!
Oh my god!
[Heavy Breathing] I really hate sharks.
- Thank you! Thank you.
- You're Welcome.
[Chatter]
I never got your real name.
Jenny Lynn.
Nice to meet you... Jenny Lynn.
[Laughs]
Hell of a day.