The last full moon of that spring
came a little more than a month
before school let-out
for summer vacation.
Our town's long nightmare
began that night.
My beer is Rheingold,
the dry beer.
Think of Rheingold
whenever you buy beer.
It's not bitter, not sweet,
A real frosty treat,
won't you have,
won't you buy,
Rheingold beer...
Won't you try,
won't you buy,
Jesus, Arnie !
Fear the boogeyman?
Yard!
Noone ever been busted...
Gimme a hand.
Alright!
What is it that you want Arnie?
I want some Rheingold!
Rheingold beer.
Oh, shit!
The killing had begun,
but at first, no one knew it.
You see Arnie Westrum was
a chronic drunk,
and what happened
seemed like an accident.
The county coroner concluded that
Arnie had passed out on the tracks.
There wasn't enough evidence
to conclude anything else.
Yeah!
This is Tarkers Mills,
where I grew up...
And this is how it looked that spring
A town where people cared about each other
as much as they cared about themselves.
I was nearly 15 years old
and my brother Marty was 11.
We'd like to get things started now!
May I have your attention
please everybody?
We'd like to get things
started now, we could?
Lot chairs down here,
come on right down, sit down!
Alright without... further due
I'd like to turns things over
to our own Reverend Lester Lowe.
I'm gonna go, okay?
Alright. Stay close.
Thank you.
And make sure your
brother's allright
"Make sure  your brother's allright."
Marty's a bugger.
Marty was the cross I had to bear
- A real garden snake?
- Hell no.
- He wasn't so bad actually.
- Let me hold him!
He was just constantly thrown
in my face by my parents.
- I have an idea.
- What?
Oh you wouldn't.
Oh you would!
Only... That's not...
You know... ??? or anything.
For me?
And it never likes, it seems to me,
to be the very definition of community.
Marty!
Oh, Janey!
Goddammit!
Come on Jane,
it's just a garden snake.
Look at my hose!
I hate you!
Jane, I'm shocked at you!
Stop it Brady.
Attention!
Look at what!
Hey Jane!
Do you wet your pants?
Jane I'm sorry.
Oh yes sure!
I didn't mean to.
Oh, no! You never mean to!
I hate you, bugger!
Well. She looks like we got
her go that time, didn't we?
Shut up, Brady.
You're warped.
It will take a minute.
Come here for a minute,
I have to talk to you.
I told you babe.
It ain't my baby!
- Don't you ever drag me off like that!
- Please, don't say that...
you know it's your baby.
Look, we had this conversation
before, sorry babe.
I have to hear some else,
but I don't know what to do.
It's your oven, it ain't
my bun you're baking in there.
You have to help me!
Remember the good times.
I want you two to bury the hatchet.
You're being very silly, Jane.
Did you see my knee?
Did you see my outfit?
Marty has apologized.
And you know as well as I do he couldn't
climb that tree to stop Brady anyway.
You always take his side
because he's crippled!
But it's not my fault he's crippled!
You just want to be quiet or
I'm gonna smack you now I mean it!
Come on Jane. I'm sorry.
But Brady wouldn't stop.
Hey pumpkin! Don't forget to
help your brother.
Bob, I don't have my keys.
Just a minute, sweetheart.
Don't sweat the small stuff, Janey.
Honey, would you want this?
Come on. Hurry up.
Is uncle Red still coming to visit?
Mum told that uncle Red's
getting a divorce...
Another divorce.
And she said he was drunk.
That's your great uncle!
- A chronic drunk!
- He's not.
- He's so!
Janey? Jane you awake?
What's the money for?
A new pair of pantyhose.
Is it enough?
Jane, please take the money.
It was Brady's idea.
Honest-to-god.
I want to make up.
I can get a pair of legs down at
the pharmacy for a dollar forty-nine.
Here.
Is it true what you said
about uncle Red?
Yes.
I'm sorry I told you the way I did.
It was mean.
It's okay.
Never did much like Sheila anyway.
Maybe I like the next one better.
Suicides go to hell.
Especially if they're pregnant.
And I don't even care.
You have to understand it's not
a normal situation down here.
Alright! What you told me this morning?
Well I'm happy to hear that.
You think it would be sometime this week?
Well that's good.
When? And how many?
Hey! Fuck off!
What did he say Joe?
He said they be here by noon.
Maybe that wasn't such a good idea
telling that smokey bear from the
detective division to fuck off Joe.
Well I waited til he hung up.
Jesus Christ, what a mess.
Joe Haller couldn't find his own ass
if someone rammed it full of radium
and gave him a Geiger counter.
Could be I know a fella
who's still PO (pissed off) about
being fined a couple of hundred bucks
for that little fender bender
he had back on Ridge Road last year.
Could be I know a fat old fella
who ought to take care of his mouth
before someone comes along
and turns it inside out.
We pay our taxes to keep
this town safe,
and Joe Haller ain't doing it.
Last town report said you were
in arrears in your taxes, Andy.
Guess you caught up huh?
What are you? Trying to be smart?
Now you boys better turn down
your thermostats
or you gonna both get
the hell out of here.
You got me?
Now who's drinking?
Hey! It's my man Marty
in the "Silver Bullet"!
So Marty, glad to be out of jail?
No. I like school..
Bugger.
Be careful.
Not bad, huh?
Uncle Red took off the
regular muffler.
Put on a Cherry Bomb.
What's that?
Glasspack.
He said he is making me a new
wheelchair. A custom job.
But now I don't know,
He's getting a divorce and
he's in the doghouse with my mum.
For getting a divorce?
Well, it is his third.
Come on, Tammy.
Thanks for coming here with me,
Marty.
I was scared to pass
her house by myself.
Yeah... it is a little scary.
I mean, I saw her.
All the time.
Hey, take it easy.
I know how you feel.
There's something else scary.
What?
That.
I've been hearing noises out there.
Tammy!
Get on in here!
Help your mamma with the laundry!
Well. I would well take
a look myself but...
I think the Bullet would
get stuck in the mud.
You would, wouldn't you?
Yeah sure. No sweat.
Tammy!
I gotta go, Tammy.
Thanks again for coming home with me.
Damn cripple.
Always end up on welfare.
I'd electrocute 'em all.
Balance the goddamn budget.
Oh come on, baby.
Hey Mr. Cutts!
Well Marty!
I see you lucked out again!
Yup. The fill up, please.
Want me to check the oil?
Yeah sure!
Wipe the windshield and check
the driver's bullshit level?
There is a guy sitting in a bar.
A bartender. He says
Hey! Jackass, give me a drink!
So the bartender pours him a drink.
He drinks it.
Sits there for a while.
Hey! Jackass pour me another drink!
So he pours another drink.
The guy gets some loose.....
The guy sitting there says
Hey why do you let him call
you jackass all the time?
The bartender says
Oh... Eeyore eeyore
he always call me that.
Give up for a fall,
- because you don't stand a chance.
- Yeah
Uh, I'll see ya...
And I'll... raise you this.
You can't bet managers.
- You can't bet managers!
- Okay, okay.
I said time and time again.
You can't bet managers.
So ... the yankee.
Piss on the yankees!
Piss on the indians!
- Piss on the felix!
- Come on.
Piss on the ...
Mom! Coming
Wo, Nan.
Let him finish the game. Okay?
- Make it quick.
- Okay.
What did you say? Yankees?
See your yankee.
And I'll call you.
I got three kings.
Read'em and weep.
I got a straight to the queen.
- That's bullshit luck! Bullshit luck!
- That's enough!
That's enough!
Hey wait. Can I say...?
Can I at least say good night?
Good night!
See you later.
See you in the morning.
- I will see you in the morning.
- Okay.
- Wake me up.
- No I will wake you up.
- Okay.
Okay.
Honey ask your sister to help you.
I will be there in a minute.
I will...
Good night.
I don't want you
drinking around Marty.
Don't be telling me what to do.
You've been telling me what
to do all my life.
Red, I don't care how you live.
But he is a very
impressionnable little boy.
You know, you think your only
responsibility is getting his butt
out of the chair and into the tub
and out of the chair and onto the toilet.
And you won't realize there's more to
Marty than him not being able to walk.
- It's so easy for you, isn't it?
- Yeah it is!
You blow in here once a month
and you tell a few jokes
and you have a few beers
and then you wanna lecture me
about how to raise my son.
Well I'm the one who is responsible
for how he feels when
he sees you like this.
And how he feels when you leave.
Red. Marty has enough strikes
against him as it is.
He doesn't have strikes against him.
I'm scared to death that someday
he is just gonna give up.
He's not gonna give up!
Well he doesn't need you
showing about how to do it!
Another wonderful night here
at sister Nan's.
Come on, Rebel!
We gonna bust him up tonight.
We gonna kick some ass.
Ow!
Bust him up.
Bust his chops.
Oh yeah!
Oh yeah, Rebel. Airplane!
Oh! That's it.
Oh that hurts my parts.
God. Dig it.
I was gonna do something about this.
See if you want to come back
and bust up my pots after
I put these rocks up your ass!
Come around bust up my pots
I'll bust up your ass!
Bitches.
I hope you in there.
I hope you in there cos' I'm
gonna blow your ass off this salt.
Aint' that a hell of a note?
Did you hear something?
Haller!
Well! You got any leads?
I'm working on it Mayor.
Mayor.
David!
Come on, come on. Get inside.
- Brady I got it.
- Great.
Marty Coslaw,
you get down of that tree!
Supper was ready an hour ago, Dumbo.
- Oh, Jesus. I forgot. She mad?
- Yeah.
At me for not finding you sooner.
You help me with the Bullet, please.
I don't let you fall.
Come on.
Hey, Brady! You coming?
In a while!
Come on, Marty.
Marty, it's getting late.
We all make Joe Haller dog catch it,
you know, nothing big,
just a little pools.
Andy, Andy, lighten up.
Let Joe handle the investigation.
Investigation!
This whole investigation
has been about as efficient as
a submarine with screen doors.
I've heard enough out of you,
Andy Fairton.
It's not working.
If you don't shut your mouth,
I'm going to shut it for you.
What did you say?
You heard what I said, motormouth.
You wanna dance cowboy?
Come on.
Has anyone in here
seen my son Brady?
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb.
Holy Mary, mother of God...
pray for us sinners...
now and at the hour of our death.
Herb! Herb! Wait here Herb.
- Is it my boy?
- Don't go up there.
- Is it Brady?
- Don't go up there
Brady!
Mr. and Mrs. Kincaid have asked
that I say a word of comfort
to you, if I could.
If there is any word of comfort
I can give you, it's just this:
that the face of the beast
always becomes known.
And the time of the beast
always passes.
Nan! How about if
I take the boy home?
Red...
Okay.
Thank you.
Come Marty.
You are going with me.
Hi! Jane see you there.
Alright.
- How do you feel?
- How did you feel?
They better get that guy.
- Uncle Red?
- Yo.
What if it's not a guy?
What do you mean?
What if it's...
some kind of monster?
Yeah, what if it's some kind of monster?
You know.
Like a werewolf or something.
That's a good one. Yea.
Here we go.
You know, Tammy told me she'd been
hearing noises in the greenhouse.
Growling noises.
Her father was killed that night.
Listen Marty, you have got to
get this idea out of your head.
Psychotics are more active
when the moon is full.
And this guy's a psycho.
When they catch him we gonna find out,
he is just as human as you and me.
Okay. Okay.
You all know what groups you're in and
what areas you'll be covering, right?
Damn straight!
Groups one through four:
in the woods
north of the Sturmfuller place.
Five and six:
west of Carson Creek.
Now if he comes out in the
moonlight tonight for a stroll,
we're gonna get that sorry sucker.
I want you all people to go home!
I don't remember deputizing
a single one of you!
That's right, Joe!
The only deputy you got is
that fat shitbag beside you,
and neither one of you has done
anything about solving this case.
We'll catch him.
You couldn't catch a cold.
The law has a name for
what you people are planning.
It's called private justice.
And private justice is about
a step and a half away
from lynch mobs and hang ropes.
Now I may be no J. Edgar Hoover,
but I, am the law in Tarker's Mills.
I want all you people to go home.
Don't let this guy scare you!
What's he done since this whole
thing started but hang his face out?
He ain't got so much as a fingerprint!
Shut up, Andy.
Now don't tell me to shut up.
Yes.
Shut up.
I just came from my boy's funeral.
Herb.
Herb. I know how upset--
How grief-stricken you must be.
He was torn apart.
I know that...
Upset.
Grief-stricken.
You don't know
what those words mean.
My son was torn to pieces.
Pieces.
My son was torn to pieces!
You come in here and talk to
these men about private justice.
You dare to do that.
Why don't you go out to
Harmony Hill, Sheriff Haller?
and dig up what's left
of my boy Brady
and explain to him
about private justice.
Would you want to do that?
As for me...
I'm gonna to go out and hunt
up a little private justice.
You heard him.
Let's go.
Stop!
Andy! Andy! Please don't do this.
Joe!
Reverend. This is that community
spirit you were talking about.
Billy. Billy, this is a bad idea.
Don't. Don't do this....
Leave me be.
No... David No......
Please! Please!
Come on, it's frigging time!
They'll have his hide tacked
to somebody's barn door
before we get out there!
Over there.
It's over there.
Ok come on up here.
Alright. Alright.
Make the other way.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Jesus, that was close.
Come on. Be careful.
God! Help Me!
What is it?
My foot! My foot!
Get it off me!
I'm coming.
Sure...
Okay...
Yeah, over here.
Hold on. Hold on.
I'll get it.
Don't you turn your back, now.
Andy there's your yellow ???
Careful Maggie.
Damn... Alright...
You gonna go through here.
You follow me one at a time.
Right behind you.
It came from over there.
As far as I could tell,
it came back of us.
It ain't down there, Andy.
We'll spread out in a skirmish line.
If the son of bitch tries to
come around us, we'll get him.
Holy shit!
Come on.
I don't know.
My, Bobby, you gonna make
lemonade in your pants?
I ain't scared! Let's go!
Where's it coming from?
Over there?
No. It's behind us.
I told you you couldn't
trust this fog.
It's under the fog.
What you saying?
It's right here with us.
I can't move.
Start backing up, Andy.
Yeah.
My God.
Son of bitch....
It's hard at a time like this
to find the words
to offer you any comfort.
There is no comfort.
There is only private justice.
The Bible
tells us
not to fear the terror that
creepeth by night
or that which flieth by noonday.
And yet we do...
We do.
Because there is so much
we don't know,
and we feel very small.
Reverend! He was torn apart.
No! No!
No!
Let it end, dear Lord.
Let it end.
Oh they canceled the fireworks.
It's not fair.
Oh... Look out, world!
Marty the Great didn't
get something he wanted.
Stop it, Jane.
I don't see why everybody
nearly breaks down and cries
whenever Marty doesn't get
what he wants.
Pumpkin!
What did your mother say?
It's about time you backed off
young lady.
It's always my fault.
Jane! You won't let up.
Come on Nan. Let's get home.
I don't believe it.
...by observing the Sheriff's
curfew and not by leaving town.
...he said the time to be pulling
together, not to be bailing out.
Now let's hear from Sue Ann Akerksy...
I need a Philips screwdriver.
You know it's not enough that
the monster killed all those people.
He killed Brady.
Now he's got them to cancel the fair.
And the fireworks.
Yeah. And the fireworks.
That's another thing.
Where's your mom?
She and dad are out back
lighting the barbeque,
Jane's walking around in all these
new clothes showing off her tits,
acting like nobody ever
had tits before her.
Let me see if I got this right.
The guy killed your best friend.
Drove your best girl out of town.
And now he's responsible for
canceling the only carnival we got.
Am I lying?
No. You're not lying uncle Red.
Well... It's just so happens.
I've got something
that might cheer you up.
Oh! You mean I can see it.
Yeah. It's time.
- Now?
- Yeah. Now.
Cover your eyes.
Oh! Come on.
Jesus!
I'm bustin' my ass on this steel.
Tadaaa.
Wow.
It's a nice kick Red.
- Is that for me?
- Oh yes, it's for you.
Damn. Looks good.
Wow. It's beautiful.
Do you have a pilot's license?
Do I need one?
Red?
Hey!
Hey Red!
O... Okay. The coast is clear.
- Are you ready?
- O... Yeah.
I feel like a virgin on prom night.
Here is the engine start.
- Remember what I told you.
- Yeah.
- Now be damn careful!
- Okay.
Then you're started.
Push.
- Sounds good, does it?
- Yeah.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Shake!
Stop! Right.
Oh! Kid's dead meat.
Oh! Yes.
That was wicked.
Oh... I hope you're happy, because
you are looking at a dying man here.
This thing goes super super fast.
I know it goes super fast.
And you better watch it.
Because if your mother finds out
just how fast it goes,
I'm gonna end up singing soprano
in the Vienna Boys' Choir.
I don't get you.
I know you don't.
But listen to me.
I built that for you cos I love you.
Right from my heart.
And I want you to be careful on it.
Because if you got hurt on it.
It'd kill me.
Let's get to this barbeque, okay?
- One more piece of rhubarb pie.
- Are you sure about that?
Anybody else like a bite?
- Well go ahead.
- Listen. No. Put it down.
- I've got to go.
- Okay.
- I've had a wonderful time.
- So have I.
I wish it could always be like this.
Maybe it will if you keep inviting
me down when you cook these pork ribs.
Okay okay.
Nice to meet you.
I'll see you later Janey.
- Bob!
- Oh! My God.
Okay.
Marty want me to ran my car.
Want me to ran my car.
Stay out of trouble at least that long.
Thank you very much.
Go Go.
Now I said I had something for you,
as I believe you do recall.
Yeah! What is it?
You're gonna have the Fourth of July,
but you're gonna have it in September.
Now remember:
it isn't just the fireworks.
It's so no crazy shithead can stop
the good guys, if you can dig that.
Yeah.
Now stay near the house.
Yeah... sure.
Okay.
Save this for the last.
It's a rocket.
You'll like it.
Thanks a million, uncle Red.
You're welcome a million, Marty.
Stick 'em in the bushes
for right now. Okay.
Alright.
Now remember: stay near the house.
Okay?
Promise.
Okay.
Alright.
That's good.
I want you have a good time.
Thank's a lot uncle Red.
Watch out for the werewolves!
Bye!
This is for the good guys!
Oh!
Ya.
Oh shit.
Hello!
Uncle Red, this is Marty.
I saw the werewolf last night.
Oh Marty.
I saw the werewolf!
Hey buddy you had a bad dream.
It wasn't a dream Uncle Red.
I saw the werewolf at the fireworks.
It was there.
There are no such things as werewolves.
There is. I saw it.
Uncle Red it was a werewolf!
Have some pity on
your poor uncle, okay?
Jesus!
What?
What was that?
Obscene phone call.
Marty? You okay?
You've just been sitting
here all morning.
Where's mom?
Out shopping. Why?
Jane, I gotta talk to you.
About what?
Uncle Red won't believe me,
and if you don't help me...
What is it?
He told me something that
was clearly unbelievable...
and yet somehow,
I believed most of it.
And I understood one thing
with total clarity:
Marty himself believed it all.
Marty had seen where the rocket
had struck home, he said,
And I went out that day looking
for more than just cans and bottles.
Hi, Mr. Thayer.
I'm collecting returnable bottles
and cans for the Medcu Drive,
I was wondering if you had any.
I was looking for a man or
a woman with just one eye.
Hello, Jane.
Who is it?
It's Jane Coslaw.
Hello, Jane.
I know what you're after, Jane,
and you're out of luck.
Little Toby Whittislaw
coming here yesterday,
and I gave 'em all to him.
That's okay.
That you, Mr. Fairton?
Got any bottles or cans?
No.
- Bye, Mr. McClaren.
- Bye, Janey.
- Jesus!
Gentlemen.
I'm sorry to disturb you at lunch.
I'm collecting bottles
for the Medcu Drive,
I was just wondering if any of you
would have seen Mr. Robertson?
Oh! Hi Mr. Robertson!
I was wondering if you had any?
I guess not.
Thanks.
It's my own fault. Believing Marty.
Little ass hole.
Hi! Reverend Lowe.
I'm ready to turn my bottles in.
Hi! Janey. And how are you?
Alright I guess.
Oh! It's just my little brother
gets me so mad sometimes.
Well Jane, young brothers
sometimes do that.
Take your cart around to the garage.
Then bring me your tally sheet.
Having some trouble?
Jane! You're trembling!
I don't feel well, I think
maybe I got too much sun.
Would you like to come in the
parlor and lie down for a bit?
No!
I have a cold drink?
I have some soda-
I think I should get home
and help my mom with dinner.
- I'll give you a ride!
- No.
Give my best to your brother, Jane.
-I will.
Oh, Jeez! What did you do then?
I ran faster than I ever ran
in my life--what do you think?
By the time I got back here,
I really thought I was going to faint.
Marty, what are we going to do?
If we tell anyone -- grown-ups,
I mean -- they'd laugh.
What are we gonna do?
I think I know.
I mailed another letter for Marty the
next day... a third the day after that.
Then, on Saturday, we told
uncle Red what we'd been up to.
His reaction was less than serene.
Holy jumped-up bald-headed Jesus palomino!
- Uncle Red!
- From him I'd expect it.
Sometimes I think your common sense
got paralysed along with your legs.
But from you Jane?
You're miss Polly Practical!
You don't understand.
I understand that
my niece and my nephew
are sending little love notes
to the local minister suggesting
that he gargle with broken glass,
or eat a rat-poison omelette!
He came for me!
I shot it in the eye!
Now he's wearing an eye-patch!
I wish I had a tape recorder so
you can hear what you sound like.
What about the baseball bat
Jane saw in his shed?
What about it?
You know who used to have a
baseball bat like that?
Mr. Knopfler!
So?
It looked like Bigfoot had
used it for a toothpick!
You wanna know what I think?
No, we just called you out here
to admire your pretty little face.
You better watch your mouth right now,
you're on thin ice with me son.
I think he had a hallucination.
Probably a broomstick, or something.
It was not!
You want me to show it to you?
Come on, I'm not afraid!
I'll show it to you right now!
No no no no no....
I'm a little too old to be playing
"The Hardy Boys meet Reverend Werewolf"!
Jane! Forget it.
Jesus! Ya.
Forget it. Forget it.
Probably have gotten
rid of it by now anyway.
This is dumbest thing
I've ever heard.
Just forget it.
It's crazy.
Do you see your suspect yet, Marty?
Yes, I see him.
Are you trying to tell me
that a man who took a rocket
in the eye three nights ago
is out here painting at ...?
He'd either be in the hospital
or he would be dead.
I didn't shoot him
when he was a man.
I shot him when he was...
What, a werewolf? Oh Jesus.
Jane, you don't believe
this madness, do you?
I don't know exactly
what I believe.
But I know that what I saw was a
baseball bat and not a broomstick.
I know there was something strange about
the way the garage smelled that day.
It smelled like an animal's den.
And I believe in Marty.
You used to believe
in him too, uncle Red.
Kids!
Hey! Marty you wanna go
to Robertson's for a soda?
No thanks.
Think I'm gonna go home.
Okay, see ya!
Yeah... see ya.
Oh my God.
Come on... Please... Come on.
Marty...
I'm very sorry about this, Marty.
I don't know if you believe
that or not, but it's true.
I would never willingly hurt a child.
Please I won't tell any one.
You should have left me alone, Marty.
I can't kill myself.
Our religion teaches that suicide is the
greatest sin a man or a woman can commit.
Stella was going to commit suicide.
And if she had done so, she would
be burning in hell right now.
By killing her I took her physical
life but I saved her life eternal.
You see, how all things serve
the will and the mind of God?
You see, you meddling little shit!
You're gonna have a
terrible accident, Marty.
You're gonna fall into the river.
Mr. Zinneman! Help me!
Please help me!
Mr. Zinneman! Please.
Mr. Zinneman! I'm in the bridge.
Help me! Please.
Hey! You Marty?
Spooky in there, ain't it?
Well I'll tell you it's
a lot easier to swallow without
the foaming jaws
and the hair and the teeth.
Did you talk to the Sheriff?
Yes, after Marty's latest
thrilling tale of wonder.
But he's had no complaints
of poison-pen.
See, I told you!
Shut up, Marty.
Jane!
What color is Lowe's car?
Blue. This blue.
Jesus.
That's the craziest goddamn story
I have ever heard in my life.
I know.
Do you believe any of this?
You do, don't you?
Well let's just say I believe
Reverend Lowe oughta be checked out.
That can be arranged.
Thank you Joe.
Reverend Lowe?
Can I help you Joe?
I think you better come
along with me Reverend.
But it's not my fault.
Sheriff Haller said he'd
check him out, and guess what?
No one sees him again.
What do you suggest I do about it?
I want you to turn this
into a silver bullet.
You won't let go of it, will you?
I saw what I saw.
Marty, the moon wasn't even full!
In the made-up stories, the guy who's the
werewolf only changes when the moon is full.
Maybe he's like this almost all the time,
only as the moon gets fuller...
The guy gets wolfier.
Here. Take mine, too.
Why don't you guys tell me how
this guy Lowe became a werewolf?
I don't know.
Maybe he doesn't know either.
I think he's going to come after me.
Not just because I know who he is,
but because I hurt him.
But I think he'll wait till
the moon is all the way full.
When there's no Reverend Lowe at all.
Only the monster.
You have gone right
out of your mind.
Will you do it?
Oui.
Stay!
Hello!
My nephew has just discovered
the Lone Ranger.
And I wondered if
you could help me here.
You want a silver bullet yeah?
The man uncle Red had gone
to see was more than a gunsmith.
He was uncle Red said, an old-world
craftsman, a sort of wizard of weapons.
He confirmed the high-grade silver content
of my crucifix and Marty's medallion,
melted them down and molded
them into a silver bullet.
Marty had read all the
legends about werewolves.
And though they differed on
several minor points,
they all agreed on one.
It takes silver to kill a werewolf.
And we were taking no chances.
Here it is.
Nicest piece of work
I ever done, I think.
It's got a low-grain load
so it won't tumble.
Oughta be pretty accurate.
No, won't shoot it,
it's just a gag.
I mean what the heck you gonna
shoot a 44 bullet at anyway?
Made out of silver.
How about a werewolf?
The night of the next full
moon came on Halloween,
and a happy coincidence left us
in the sole care of uncle Red.
We are going to New York
for a week-end.
At least it seemed
like a coincidence.
Nan! I got the number.
Bye... Bye...
Bye honey.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Oh! What's this?
It's just my luck to win a romantic
trip for two after Sheila leave.
That's all this.
Do you got the ticket?
Yeah! Yeah!
Okay, now go and have fun.
Bye.
Have fun Bob.
You too Red. Don't let
those kids run your wagon.
No! Don't run those wagons.
Listen! Don't let any trickers
or treaters in, even if they come!
We won't!
Bye dad, bye mom.
Bye bye.
Have fun.
Oh! Listen you kids go to bed early!
You gonna hurt your head bumping,
going in and out like that.
Be good kids.
Yeah we will.
Can I tell you kids some?
Sure uncle Red.
Me and Nan were just like you
guys when we were younger.
The bitch of it is, we still are.
Did you really win a trip to New York
from a publisher's clearing house?
No.
But the moon is full.
And your parents are gone.
And I did when the subscription
to the party begins.
You'll burn yourself up sometime
doing that, uncle Red.
Not probably. Will.
If that'd gone off, that would have
been the end of our silver bullet.
This is too much.
You guys are going to bed.
But uncle Red! You said...
I know what I said,
but it's ten to three in the
morning and it's not coming.
The moon's not down yet.
Well it's damn near down.
I'm gonna sit up the rest of
the night with the stupid gun
in my lap because
I promised I'll do that.
But you are going to bed.
And so are you.
What happens if I say no?
Then I'm gonna kick your ass.
It's the werewolf!
I saw, it's the werewolf!
Wait... Wait.
What did you see?
The werewolf.
I was looking at you...
It's okay. And look.
That's all.
A very familiar feeling
is beginning to come over me.
What?
I began to feel like
a horse's ass. That's what.
He is out there. I saw him.
I know you did Janey.
Why don't you just go upstairs.
And don't panic.
He is here.
Marty, it could be just a fuse.
Shit.
Uncle Red! Watch out.
Jane. Get the gun!
Hurry! Marty!
Leave him alone.
I got you.
Don't worry. He's dead.
Marty, are you all alright?
All except my legs...
- What?
- I don't think I can walk.
I love you, Janey.
I love you too.
It wasn't always able to say that.
But I can say it now.
I love you too, Marty... Good night.