News of a bizarre,
chainsaw-wielding family...
...reports which were to ignite
the world's imagination...
...began to filter out
of central Texas.
Regrettably, not one of the family
members was ever apprehended...
...and for more than 10 years,
nothing further was heard.
Then over the next several years...
...at least two minor, yet apparently
related incidents, were reported.
Then again nothing.
It's not clear how the shooting spree
was motivated...
...although there has been
widespread speculation...
...it was in retaliation for the bomb
threats in Hebron.
A jury ruled guilty in the slaying
of abortion doctor Irwin Guthrie.
It took the 7-man,
5-woman jury just hours...
...to find Norris guilty...
Hey, I think you're chasing
the wrong tail.
Where have you been?!
The wedding's going on.
You go on the top tier.
Don't mind the footprints
in the icing.
They look good. It's like a vest
thing. I fucking hate kids.
Miss Abbott,
did Barry come through here?
Oh, Barry?
Didn't you break up?
No.
Well, never mind. I just thought...
Forget it.
She's doing it again.
Miss Abbott, she's...
She just does that to make trouble.
It is so obvious.
What are you talking about?
Don't listen to her.
She's trying to make trouble.
She's such a bitch.
Sean, hi.
Have you seen Barry?
Not in a while. Have you?
- She was completely naked.
- Bullshit.
She was spilling all over the place,
like a battleship.
- A battleship?
- Okay, like a dinghy.
Has anybody seen Barry?
You've seen Barry?
Oh, shit!
Don't worry. She'll be back.
If that's really what you want.
Stop!
Heather, stop the car!
Damn it!
You better fucking stop this car
right now!
We have a wreck, it'll be my ass!
- I don't care.
- Slow down.
I wasn't doing anything.
I saw you. You were kissing her.
Once! What's wrong with that?
I can't even talk to my friends.
You're so possessive.
That's why you were feeling her up.
Guys need sex. It's bad to be excited
and not get it.
You can get prostate cancer.
You want that?
That's a lie.
Look out!
Fuck!
What's the matter with you?
I'm so fucking dead right now!
Oh, man.
You can't get cancer
from not having sex.
Like you'd know. You never
had a date, you're so ugly.
She is not.
Shut up.
He wants you to think it's your fault.
My father's a doctor. I know what
I'm talking about, so fuck you.
It's true, it is my fault.
I won't have sex with him.
It doesn't make it your fault.
What if he gets cancer and his hair
falls out from the drugs? Could happen.
So just shut up, all right?
It's a line to get you
to have sex with him. Ask Sean.
She's right.
He's never had a hard-on.
- I know his lines. We were neighbours.
- Shut up.
We were friends before he got too cool.
So fucking annoying.
It's not my fault you turned out
to be a geek.
He used to come to my house and laugh
about the girls he felt up.
He told them his father was a doctor...
...and they'd get breast cancer
if they weren't felt up.
It's not my fault they're
stupid enough to believe it.
What a schmuck.
What's your problem?
Just because you hate guys.
He's just trying
to change the subject.
What are you afraid of?
That they might try to fuck you?
No.
It's no secret.
What?
Ask anybody.
You never go anywhere
unless you're with Sean.
Everybody knows he's a pothead
and you're only friends.
What if we crashed into a car in front
of us and we all died?
I dreamt about a weirdo following me
through the woods, and it's coming true.
I'm sorry, but we're all gonna die.
Some murderer...
...will kill us.
Now we can't see.
Someone is following me.
I can feel their eyes on me.
Bullshit!
They want us to wander around
in the dark.
We need an ambulance.
Piece of shit.
You might be, but my father's
still gonna kill me.
Call the police. There's been
an accident. A man's dying.
Prom night.
Somebody bring me a glass of water.
I think I'm gonna pass out.
Damn answering machine.
Don't worry, he'll pick up.
Vilmer, if you're there, babe,
pick up the phone.
Phony as 3-dollar bills.
Changed my life, though.
Goddamn it, button it up, babe.
- Glass of water?
- Stop it!
You know what?
The minute I showed up with these,
every farmer in the county...
...thought he was God's gift to women.
What the hell, doubled my commissions
in the first six months.
Goddamn, it's about time.
Vilmer, listen.
Some kids got in a wreck up the road.
One of them is hurt.
Wait a second.
Which way?
- Back that way.
- How far?
About a mile.
About a mile back up 709 from me.
Why do blonds stick their heads out
car windows?
Why?
To get a refill.
I don't get it.
Airheads?
We should get back there
and see if Sean's okay.
What was that?
Don't worry.
It's just some farmer's wife.
Like I'm even interested!
See them and weep!
Or some high-school boy.
They're always doing something
to get me to flash them.
What?
Is an ambulance coming?
This guy's hurt.
I think he's delirious.
Is he okay?
Boy's dead.
He's not. He's just passed out.
I said he's dead.
He was just talking in his sleep.
Is that right?
Well...
He's dead now.
Don't run off down that road.
- It won't do you any good.
- What'll you do?
First, I'm gonna kill you.
It ain't no fucking biggie.
Of course, it's different
for every individual.
Sorry I can't give you a ride.
The wrecker will be here soon.
- Thanks for calling for us.
- Yeah, thanks.
Don't worry about that boy that drives
the wrecker. He talks tough.
Tell him how the cows eat the cabbage
and you won't have any trouble.
Thanks a lot.
What about that service station?
Can someone there give us a ride?
That old man? He's liable to shoot
first and ask questions later.
We see you, you old fart!
Thanks. Bye.
You tired yet, boy?
- Please, you're scaring me.
- No shit.
What did I do?
Let's just say you're shit out of luck.
What can I do? Give me a chance.
We ain't even having fun yet, son.
Run, run, run!
Swing right.
Come back to Papa now!
All right, racing fans...
...here...
...we...
...go!
This is what I want
Still kicking?
That should've done it!
Yes, that should have done it.
There's somebody out there.
I mean it this time.
I'm not making it up. Stop.
- Listen.
- I don't hear anything.
Jenny, stop. My feet hurt.
Am I supposed to carry you?
Carry me piggyback.
Just for a while.
Lose 20 pounds.
Oh, man. All right.
This guy's a lifesaver.
All we need is a ride! We'll pay!
Wait! We could get arrested
for trespassing!
Please, come on.
If you guys can hear me, I'm gonna
go back and see if Sean's okay.
All right?
No, wait!
Okay, who's there?
Is there anybody there?
Wait.
Stop.
What if they want us to follow them...
...so they can hide and stab us?
There could be dead people
buried all around us.
They could tie us in a cellar.
No one'd hear us.
That's dumb. There are no cellars
in the houses around here.
That's it. Don't call me dumb.
I may not be the smartest person
in the world, but I'm not stupid.
I act that way sometimes
to get people to like me.
Yeah, right.
All those stories about murderers,
I know it's not true.
It's better than being bored.
What's stupid is what you said
about you and Brenda.
No one would believe that.
She started this whole thing.
It's her fault.
You'd like to think.
I'll tell you what it is.
I'm a bitch.
I'm just like my mother.
She can't stand my father...
...but she stays with him because
she wants a certain kind of life.
No matter what anybody thinks,
that's the way to get it.
What's wrong with that?
Forget it.
You should've said something.
It pisses me off
when you let me go on.
It's embarrassing.
I told you, I'm a bitch.
If I were braver, I'd be like Jenny.
No, you wouldn't.
You're probably right.
She's a dog.
You just don't know.
Everyone thinks she's such a wuss.
Her mother gets married
every 15 minutes.
Her husbands always hit on her.
That's why she's that way.
But I've had P.E. With her.
She's got a body to die for.
Really?
Great.
Tell them we'll give them
$50 for a ride.
Fifty bucks?
Don't give it to them.
Tell them to send us a bill.
If they get mad, give them 5 bucks.
Tell them we'll send the rest later.
It's no big deal.
It's just business.
My father does it all the time.
You are weird.
Hey, is anybody home?
Must be deaf.
Hey, is anybody in there?
Maybe they're out back.
Go check.
I have an idea.
Why don't I go check?
Bitch.
Damn it!
Hold it right there.
It's okay. We had a wreck.
All we want is a ride.
You better not shoot me.
A man shot a kid wrapping his house.
They got him for murder.
"I propose to fight it out on this line
if it takes all summer."
That's Ulysses S. Grant.
You didn't know that, did you?
Of course you didn't.
Because you're a bona fide moron.
Come nosing around here
where you don't belong.
It's okay. She's my girlfriend.
Don't trouble yourself.
No! God!
Please! Please!
If I go in there, it's kidnapping.
I know what I'm talking about.
"Among other evils that being unarmed
brings you...
...it causes you to be despised."
That's Niccolò Machiavelli.
Now get!
I need to use your bathroom.
Dumb ass!
Heather, you in here?
Damn it, I need to piss.
Where's the bathroom?
Heather, are you okay?
There's a crazy guy outside
with a shotgun.
Locked him out, though.
You should've seen me.
Fuck!
What's going on?
Who's out there?
You shouldn't walk these roads
at night. Get in.
Did you move the cars?
Do you want a ride or not?
It's up to you.
Where are you going?
Where's Sean?
Where do you want to go?
Your boyfriend?
The one who wasn't hurt.
Know where he is?
I know where he is. Get in.
- Well, where is he?
- Damn it, get in the truck.
Wait a second. Hang on.
You gotta watch it, getting
into strangers' cars.
I heard about an old man...
...picked up a girl on the road...
...cut her arms off, put her
in a culvert. Left her for dead.
God, I fucking hate that.
That son of a bitch didn't have shit
for an imagination.
How simple can you get?
- Stop. You're scaring me.
- Scaring you?
You're not scared.
You don't know shit
about being scared yet.
You want "scared"?
Have a look behind you. Look!
How about that? Look again, damn it!
Look again!
I think I want you to let me out.
You think? Or do you know?
- Have a look! Get a better look!
- No!
Don't want to look?
What's wrong?
Okay.
If you stop, I'll look.
- You wanted "stop."
- Stop it!
Come on, have a look at that.
Look at that.
Look at that. What is that?
What is that?
Oh, God!
You have to put in something extra...
...to show it ain't the cartoons.
What's gonna happen to me?
You think I give a goddamn
what happens to you?
Are you letting me go?
Figure it out. It's your life.
I don't understand.
Welcome to the real world.
You don't know what you're doing.
Where do you think you're going?
Okay...
...if that's what you want.
It's up to you.
Live and learn.
No, no, God, no!
Somebody!
Open this door!
Open this...!
Oh, God!
It's okay.
He's out there!
Sit down.
I'm gonna go see what's what.
The guy with the wrecker killed Sean.
Hell's bells, it's party time.
What about your friends?
They tried to get a ride.
What the hell is going on?
Where's Vilmer?
Now listen...
...don't you worry.
Vilmer does something,
there's a good reason.
Who's Vilmer?
Good question.
You know what? You look real pretty
with your glasses off.
What?
You should've brought a gunnysack
or something.
What's this look like to you?
Green eggs?
What the hell are you waiting for?
Tie her up!
Sit down, little lady.
I got enough trouble...
Look what you started.
Wait till Vilmer hears about this,
I swear to God.
Where's my gun?
It's easier to resist at the beginning
than at the end.
Be sure to tell Vilmer I'm going
to the pizza place to get some dinner.
Why are you doing this?
"Conversation's a game of circles."
That's Ralph Waldo Emerson.
What if I turned you loose?
What would you give me?
What about that?
- What do you want?
- I'll tell you what I want.
W.E., what the hell
are you doing back there?
Tell you what.
Grow up, will you?
Tell Vilmer our pizza will be ready
when I get there...
...and then I'm coming home.
One medium deluxe, one medium
pepperoni, one large vegetarian...
...and I'll get your drinks.
Lady...
...I think something's in your trunk.
That's just somebody I got tied up.
Really?
Really, what's back there?
You wanna come see?
Sure.
I better not, I might get in trouble.
All right.
Will you shut up
and quit kicking my car?
Okay, but I can't breathe.
Can I get your order?
What do you want? Black coffee?
Two black coffees.
Is that all?
If I poke a hole for you,
will you quit?
Well, somebody's gotta do it.
In your dreams.
If I hear any more kicking
or screaming...
...l'm gonna tape your mouth shut.
What you got in the car, honey?
Believe me, you don't wanna know.
Come on, I'm a nice guy.
Ma'am, your drinks are ready.
What are you doing out here
in the road?
Please...
...help me.
All right...
...but I have to run and get a blanket.
You stay right there.
Please don't hit me. Don't!
Don't hit me!
Stop!
Okay...
...but don't you go crawling off.
- I said get on out there. Move!
- Leave him alone.
You do whatever W.E. Tells you.
He even tries to hit you,
let me know...
...and I'll tell Vilmer.
"I have not yet begun to fight."
That's John Paul Jones.
You can scare him, but you so much
as lay a finger on me...
...you'll wish you'd never been born.
I almost forgot...
...one of them got away down the road.
Better get her too.
Come on. Bring her in.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not gonna hurt you. See?
See? I'm right here.
Not gonna hurt you.
Go on. Get in there.
Move!
Get!
Get, I said!
Hi, sweetie.
How was your day?
Sweetie, would you shut up?
What are you so pissed off about?
You having a bad day?
Why aren't my batteries charged?
Did W.E. Tell you?
That son of a bitch!
I told him to tell you
I was getting pizza.
He didn't, and I'm sick of it.
Look what your brother did.
Nobody gives a damn about that door.
I've had it with you.
I'm sick of you trying to make
trouble between me and Vilmer.
You're nothing but trouble.
I put things together here.
It was fine before you come.
Shut up.
Oh, my God.
What are you gonna...?
You don't believe this, do you?
What are you gonna do to me?
I asked you a goddamn question.
He asked you a goddamn...
Yes, I believe...
You don't think the FBI
has us under 24-hour surveillance?
And transmitters in all these walls?
I don't know.
Let me ask you a question.
- Are you having fun yet?
- Oh, God!
Because I promise you...
...you and I are gonna have some fun.
No more, please.
What's my fucking name?
- What's this?
- I don't know.
- What is this?
You don't know shit, do you?
Do you think all I wanna do
is kill you?
I don't know.
You're goddamn right, you don't.
Why don't you try to relax?
I know it's hard...
Why don't you mind your business?
Look at this fucking door.
What?
"The woman's a whore
and there's an end on it."
That's Samuel Johnson.
Oh, take it on out of here.
Now, now...
...don't let him get to you,
because that's what he wants.
Please tell me...
...what all this is for.
You'll have to ask Vilmer that.
If you ask me, I think the son of a
bitch is from outer space.
What are you gonna do?
No...
...what are you gonna do?
Don't hurt her.
- Give her a kiss.
- How could I hurt this pretty face?
But then...
...I am in the mood for love.
There now...
How's that? Feel better?
Look at you!
You're really pretty.
You know what?
I've got this dress
I've never even worn...
...and it would be perfect on you.
Oh, you're scared.
I just don't wanna die.
Well, of course you don't!
Will you help me?
Shut up in there.
You hush up yourself.
It's just girl talk.
He's not near as bad as he seems
once you get to know him.
It's just this job, you know,
all the stress.
It's his job to kill people?
Well...
...I shouldn't tell you this.
You know those stories you hear
of people who run everything...
...but nobody knows who they are?
Well, it's true. I didn't believe it,
but it's true.
Who do you think killed Kennedy?
Government?
That government stuff is bull crap.
It's these people.
They been doing this kind of thing for
1000 or 2000 years, I forget which.
And nobody, I mean nobody,
knows their names.
That's who Vilmer works for.
I told you... No!
Alone again, huh?
Little desert flower.
I've got a mind...
...to slit your goddamn throat.
Count of 10 to tell why I shouldn't.
Nine, eight...
...don't be late.
Seven, six,
better get it right.
Why you shouldn't kill me?
Five, four...
- Three, two!
- Because you want me alive!
You want me alive for some reason.
That's a good answer.
Smart girl.
We've got us a smart girl.
Kind of makes you think, doesn't it?
You're embarrassing me
in front of company!
Okay, stop!
Don't move or I'll shoot!
What'd she say?
"Nobody move or I'll shoot"?
My advice? Gut-shoot him.
Poison his insides,
or it won't do no good.
He's been shot before,
lots of times. Run over.
- It don't mean spit.
- Shut up, W.E.
- Nobody asked you.
- You shut up.
Everybody, shut up!
Why don't you shut up?
Get down on the floor.
Put your hands in front of you!
Get down!
Okay.
You get down too.
What are you gonna do...
...shoot me?
Yeah...
...if you try something.
What if I do this?
Goddamn it, that ain't funny!
Now we're going. What do you think?
One, two.
Take your fucking chances.
It's a damn trick.
Shut up, W.E.
Why don't you shut up?
Just forget it, hon.
If that shotgun was anywhere
you could get it...
...it's where he wanted it.
You stop. You get back down.
"Discretion is the better part
of valour."
Billy Shakespeare.
Get down, or I'll kill you.
Come on.
I'm sorry, sweetie.
I got a big mouth, what can I say?
Okay, maybe it's not loaded.
But maybe it is, so fuck you.
And if you try and come near,
I'm gonna blow your fucking head off!
- Come on.
- Let's not make this an all-nighter.
I hate to be a party pooper, but it's
late and the pizza's getting cold.
And nobody asked you!
Heather, get up.
Get up!
You have to!
Five more minutes.
Get up!
You're gonna kill her!
Come on, get up, get up.
I can't find my shoes.
It's okay. Get up.
No, you gotta get up.
We have to get out of here.
Stop it!
Pop goes the weasel.
Oh, my God!
What are you doing there?!
No, no, God!
What are you doing?!
Oh, God!
Damn shame about her face, Leather.
At least you can have her shoes.
We'll have to see that doesn't
happen again.
That'll settle her down for a while.
You better be nice to me.
'Cause I can always
go back to my husband.
Is that all you got?
You better come and eat...
...before it gets cold.
All right, all right, all right!
What took you so long?
Welcome...
...to my world!
I suppose we can forget about having
a quiet evening?
Go ahead and breathe into this bag.
Go ahead.
I told him a thousand times,
it's gonna end in tears.
Lie down with dogs, get up with fleas.
Any fool knows that.
"Common sense is not so common."
Henry Voltaire.
Are you gonna help me or not?
- Are you gonna help me or not?
- And don't tell me any more stories.
You just don't understand.
He doesn't work for anybody.
The only reason for this...
...is, he's a psycho
and gets off on it.
Get off.
Now listen.
I just can't.
He put this little thing in my head.
All he has to do is push one
little button and...
...blow my head clean off.
There's nothing in your head.
You just said a mouthful.
Get to running with the wrong crowd,
wind up in a reformatory.
No respect, no discipline.
That's the problem.
Family values have gone to hell.
Now for why we came!
My brother is tired of
what's-her-name's face...
...and he wants a new one.
It just happens to be
he wants this face right here.
Oh, no!
Don't touch me!
Don't you ever touch me!
If you're gonna kill me,
then do it!
I'm not putting up with any more crap!
It's bullshit.
Nobody believes it
except your idiot girlfriend!
It's fucking pathetic!
"There is nothing to fear
but fear itself."
Now, I'm gonna leave...
...and no one is gonna stop me.
You sit the fuck down!
And shut up!
Are we having a party or what?
Here we go!
Douse her down!
You can't do that!
She has nothing to do with this!
- That doesn't matter!
- I'm sorry! Please!
Fire in the hole!
Burn!
Watch her burn!
Go to hell!
Burn!
Why'd you do that? I can never
get that smell out of my clothes.
Well...
...what the hell do you want?
I assume that that is
a rhetorical question.
Assume whatever you please.
It ain't no skin off my ass.
Is that what you want me to think?
That you're a silly boy?
Oh, God, you have to help me.
They're crazy. Please, let's go.
- Let's go, please.
- It's all right.
That's better. Come on, now.
Come on. It's all right.
Just sit down. There you go.
There.
That's all right.
That's fine. You just stay there.
It'll be fine, okay?
Come on, now.
It's all right. All right.
Come on, there. There. See?
What is this?
No?
Can anybody else tell me?
Things are gonna change.
I can promise you that.
- Just sit there.
- No.
You just sit there.
You...
...fuck!
This... is... appalling.
You are here for one reason...
...and one reason only.
Do you understand that?
I want to hear you say
you understand that.
No?
It's very simple.
I want these people...
...to know the meaning of horror.
Horror.
Is that clear?
You don't want to be a silly boy.
Is... that... clear?
Fucking-A, it is.
What...?
What are you...?
What are you doing?
Why a woman like you
has anything to do with this...
...cripple...
...is a mystery to me.
You bastard.
You know exactly why I'm here.
What are you gonna do?
Oh, God, what are you doing?
What?
No! Don't! It's not your fault!
Stop that.
Get her, Leather! Get her, Leather!
We got some more fun today!
Get that bitch!
Thank you, Mrs. Spottis.
It's a beautiful morning.
- Stop!
- Don't stop, don't stop!
Stop! Please, stop! Oh, God!
Oh, God! Help!
There's a monster chasing her
with a chain saw!
Step on it, Mr. Spottis!
You have nothing to fear.
This...
...all of this...
...it's been an abomination.
Please accept my apologies.
It was supposed to be a spiritual
experience.
I can't tell you how...
...disappointed I am.
I suppose it's something
we all live with...
...people like us
who strive for something...
...a sense of harmony.
Perhaps it's disappointment
that keeps us going.
Unfortunately...
...it's never been easy for me.
One of my many failings.
Fuck you.
Do you want to go
to the local hospital...
...or to a police station?
This isn't the first time
something like this has happened.
Miss?
We'll find out what this is all about.
This isn't the end of it.
Miss?
Do you know who that is, miss?
What the hell's going on around here?