Subtitles by arunk1415
Proudly Presents
THE CLINIC
Done by arunk1415
Six years prior to the advent of DNA testing
Dear Mom,
Have a wonderful Christmas.
Hope wait.
Oh that is terrible.
I can't write that.
That is so bad.
We should've bought one of those cards
where you had something in it.
Can not you suggest anything?
- How about:
Dear Mom, Merry Christmas.
- Well that.
Maybe next year
you can visit us,
so that we don't have to travel across the country to see you.
Be nice.
She likes you.
- I know.
Jesus, this guy is really moving.
I need some inspiration.
It's desert.
I know.
Beth ...
- It does not write.
You might want to sit up. Now, Beth.
You okay?
You sure?
We're ok.
A fucking maniac.
He certainly had us trapped.
We should stop for the night.
Call your mom, tell her we'll be there tomorrow.
- No.
It's Christmas Eve, Cameron.
I do not want to "wake up one motel room.
Who said anything about 'n motel?
We'll pitch the Tent.
That is shorter.
- Okay.
That's actually really good news,
because we're almost out of gas.
Hey this place looks alright.
Maybe we should pitch the tent.
It's okay.
I'm gonna ask you master suite.
Good luck.
That's a nice car.
- Maybe that visitor's suite already been booked.
Hello?
Jesus Christ.
You scared the shit out of me.
Welcome to the Overlander.
Just passing through are you?
We are underway to spend Christmas
with my fiancee's mother.
Oh outstanding.
Is that your fiance i think?
That's it.
Well chosen.
Look at the fucking tits on her.
Outstanding.
Loss' r.
Lemonade?
No i'm good thanks.
How much is it?
- Around $ 105.
The sign on the front
is $ 35 per person.
And what about the little one?
What?
You mean the unborn baby?
- Sure.
You can't be serious?
You don't like it,
next hotel is two ounces west.
Honey honey
You hear that?
What are you doing?
Ow get off.
There are in there people.
I know,
Hi.
This is not exactly the Ritz.
They were friendly.
It's okay baby.
Just relax.
- Again the same dream came.
The baby away.
It's perfectly normal to have
strange dreams during pregnancy.
The only thing to remember ...
is that is just a dream.
Let's go inside.
Can get nice sleep.
It's gonna be okay.
How're you feeling?
- better.
Miscarriage is almost impossible.
The doctor said that less than
3% chance of recurrence.
I know.
I would not cope again.
Really.
You don't have to.
You're gonna give birth to a
perfect, healthy baby girl.
She is gonna be smart, beautiful.
Just like her mom.
Try to get some sleep.
We need early in the morning.
And you're gonna see the brigade of some
wonderful and very unusal looking...
CLOSED
Ok so nothing missing?
No.
- Right, You went to the Sky Dragon ...
came back and your fiance is gone?
The door was unlocked
but you can't remember know if he himself had closed?
I was half sleepy.
I'm almost positive I locked.
Hank,It's marvin.
you in there?
I'm coming.
Good evening.
This gentleman misplaced his fiancee.
It's what i'm gonna ask you couple of questions?
Have you seen her perhaps?
Or something unusual?
No, it was real quiet.
Just this fellow ...
and his fiancee in room 26.
All the guests have gone.
Got a good relationship with your fiance?
You quarrelled recently?
No, we 've a great relationship.
Any history of mental illness,
amnesia, currently using drugs of any kind?
It's standard questions.
- This is bullshit.
Beth is missing and she is pregnant.
And I want to find her.
Got a picture of her?
That's enough. He immediately began
About Beth when we arrived.
Easy with the accusations.
- I want you search the motel.
I'm afraid i can't do that.
Nothing's been stolen, no signs
of a struggle ...
I can't even report her missing
since she's be gone within 48 hours.
This is bullshit. He knows something.
- Do not cry.
Will you start to do something
to find my fiance.
I can resign at the reception ...
- Asshole.
Calm down.
- Tell me!
You're excited a scolding.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
Look at eleven.
How does she get in ten
with Christmas and stuff?
Take care of yourself.
They will come sooner or later show up.
Help.
Hello?
Hello Is anyone there?
She's still alive.
We have to leave.
She has lost blood.
Only us.
- I had a feeling anymore.
She's not moving.
The Roman numerals.
You're in a lot of trouble.
Assault.
Resisting arrest.
Some fellow struck a cab driver
by Bly County.
I have taken hold of him.
The bastard was 8 months.
Six without parole.
That's enough for even 's lawsuit.
The system works very slowly here.
Not like in the city.
It's allright.
I'm a doctor.
Veronica, we have to get out of here
While we still can.
How do we gonna get past the gate?
Maybe we could cut through?
With what?
- I don't know.
We have to try something.
We need to rest for.
- That's enough time later for it.
What is her name?
Allison, I think.
She hasn't said a word
since we found her.
How do you know her name when she doesn't?
- A pendant around her neck.
I have heard about places like this.
Why we still alive?
They just wanted our babies,
they'd be bleeding.
What else could it be?
I don't know.
Did you guys hear that?
Come sweety.
It comes from there.
She was not sewn back.
Yes, the wires are torn.
Has she done it herself?
No, otherwise her fingers
filled with blood.
She's alive. Pressure on the wound.
Take a link.
Fast.
If you can survive ...
Please make sure for my baby.
He is blue.
We can not just leave her.
Put aside.
- Take it easy.
Take it easy.
Get out of the car.
Get out of the car!
Uncuff me.
Make me damn loose.
Forward.
Do you realize what kind of crime you commit one?
- I'm not ready.
Put your arms around.
Imagine not so much, asshole.
She said her baby blue.
What would that mean?
The baby syndrome is a term for various
birth defects such as skin grafts to describe.
It's in the blood.
Health problems and stuff.
Or her baby could be cold.
It's damn shame.
We have to leave right now.
I do not know who or what her by the way,
but I do not want to stick around to find that.
Did you hear what she said?
Take care of my baby.
- She also said: If you survive.
Our children are gone.
not coming back.
- I'm not leaving without my baby.
Not only still a chance
she might be alive.
That makes two of us.
I dont care
If I have to search every room.
What do you think, Allison?
Three votes to one.
We are finding our children.
Come if you want.
Ivy and I'll search the ground floor.
Veronica and Allis on top.
I'll wait back here.
When Allison takes the lantern,
I go with her. Better company.
All right. Care for her.
You're coming?
We go.
What do you do?
Receptionist?
Topless dancer.
Nod if I'm not right.
Smile.
So people believe
this really happened.
Come on.
Is it what?
The bleeding has stopped.
Thanks.
You must know something about Ivy.
She told me she was raped.
What?
She was tossed
between a pregnancy or abortion.
I understand t.
She was determined relieved
when she woke up without a baby.
Someone else make a decision for her.
We are not the first women
this is happened to.
I found this.
What the hell happened there?
- I heard screaming ...
and i found her like here.
- You supposed to look after her Ivy.
What the fuck was I supposed to do?
What are you doing?
What is that?
No idea.
It's look like someone has tried to get it out.
Maybe Ivy equal
and we have to leave while you still can.
No, don't say that.
A woman did this to her.
Allison must have taken
before she died.
Wake up.
Motherfuckers ...
The hell?
Where's Beth?
- I said it before ...
I don't know.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Sometimes i got a call from this lady who I
asks whether pregnant women staying in the hotel.
Where has she taking?
- I don't know.
The old Abbott,
on the other side of town.
Just drive to the west
Exit at the Old Wagon Wheel.
I swear.
Do you think those women
killed in the locker room?
It would not surprise me
if she has something in her.
The Roman numerals.
Why not before I noticed it.
Look, there's a sequence.
This woman is 604.
Allison was 605.
Ivy is 606.
I 607, You 608.
Are you alright?
- I'm fine.
You look tired.
- Nothing.
Really.
What is it?
Bottles of baby food.
Draw.
Ready? Now.
Quiet.
We do them hurt.
How do I recognize mine?
How do I know which one's my baby?
They all look the same.
What is this?
They have labels.
They look the same.
This baby was Allison.
- What?
I'm sure we all
a different label in us.
The woman said in the locker room
that her baby was blue, right?
Her baby was not cold
and was not sad ...
but she saw the color of the label
inside her.
This baby was hers.
How she knew the color
as the label's Sat?
And the woman took it from her.
She knows of the labels.
She knows them that way
her child can identify with.
So she does not need to tear open.
We need to get them out as soon as possible.
It's different.
Now I see it.
I think I can get out tags out.
Where I woke up there was
a veterinary laboratory.
I saw medical tools,
asthetic ...
I can operate.
If we have the tags,
we can try to get in the cage.
Lead the way.
Which way?
- Straight ahead.
Sure?
We do not have time to run incorrectly.
- I'm sure.
We need to find another way.
Come on, get up.
Wake up.
You having a nightmare?
It's quite common to have strange
dreams during times of pregnancy.
You mean the stress.
I have that diagnosis before
let set.
It is bullshit.
Why you say that?
What if I told you that I
had see this place in my dream?
Like I said ...
- No, before i was here ...
before I knew it existed.
I have dreamed about it all.
Babies, roman numerals, all of it.
It's Impossible.
I know it is.
But i did.
Why did not you?
Three years ago ...
I had a miscarriage.
That's when the dreams come.
I'm sorry.
I suppose you
was struggling.
I'm going to try to climb out.
Help me up ok.
I can't.
I 've tried.
I can not put pressure on my leg.
Dislocated my knee.
Come on.
I can't.
Okay? I'll find something.
Fuck!
Who's there?
Veronica?
You're in Duncan's house.
Ladies not allowed in Duncan's house.
Mrs. Shepard is gonna be so mad.
Mrs.Shepard's gonna be mad at Duncan.
Shepard's gonna be..be..be so mad at Duncan.
No allowed of ladies in the house.
No allowed of guests
Mrs.Shepherd's gonna be so mad at Duncan.
No one's gonna be mad.
you like candy?
Come on. It's allright.
Come on. It's okay.
My name is Beth.
Who is Mrs. Shepard?
She is the woman in the photograph?
It is Duncan's mom,
but not allowed to call it.
Does she run this place?
Do you work for her?
Duncan cleaned the floor ...
than the wet floor,
bleeds the floor, then mop the floor.
What is this place, Duncan?
Tell me.
DCVIII ... DCV ...
DCV ... DCIV.
Do the keys in your belt
open the cage to the babies?
Duncan not allowed to talk about it.
- Why can't you talk about it?
Duncan Wait!
Wait.
One of the keys can
The cages with the babies open.
Ivy is dead.
Can you walk?
We've to find out.
To rest.
I can make you a splint.
I will not be long.
Sorry.
How does that feel?
- The need to rest above the joint
Fuck. Come on.
Go on.
Hurry.
Let's go.
We don't have much time.
Beth I need you in now.
Dep hence the blood.
Hurry.
- It is again torn.
Just keep going.
Come on.
I can't see.
Hold on. I'll look for light.
It's alright.
I got you.
You're okay.
She was yellow.
No ...
That is four.
Only one more.
No, please do not.
- Promise me something and I give you my tag.
I promise.
If my baby is still alive ...
promise me that you'll take her
with you.
Never let her know what happened here.
Promise me!
- I promise.
A woman showed me the room
with the baby.
And she said the only way ...
to find out which baby
was mine, was to kill...
five women.
And collect the tags
she had put inside.
I didn't believe her first ...
She gave me this.
I just wanted to know which baby was mine.
So badly.
I didn't know what else to do.
Please be aware my daughter.
Red and yellow.
And green.
Who's there?
You will see that everything is in order.
She is the strongest I have ever had.
Can not be stronger.
I was very lucky to find you, Beth.
Sometimes a mother survives
not a caesarean.
My client paid to select a child
to select from six different mothers.
I had to find the replacement
in the last minute.
You're the mother first substitute who ever win.
This is the only facility in the world
where she is the mother of their adopted baby ...
evaluate before they buy.
You can not get baby
an unknown whore.
You can pick from an infant
doctors, lawyers ...
lead athletes.
But buying a baby is not like
buying an appliance.
You can't return the goods
if they're faulty.
No, please.
He says that your daughter will have a
good life with him.
Let may God have mercy on your soul.
- No, please. I beg you.
Please.
Put the gun down, Duncan.
- Bam!
No, Duncan. Do not.
Do not listen to her.
I need your help.
This is all just a game.
We've been through this.
- Duncan no more bleaches the floor.
None of this is real.
- She's lying, Duncan.
They're hurting me.
How could you do that?
- Bam!
You got Duncan's keys.
You got it.
- I want you to shoot the woman Duncan.
No, do not, Duncan.
We are friends.
- Shoot them.
I gave you the candy. Remember?
- Shoot her.
Shoot her.
Do what you're told.
She has your eyes.
Don't you come in closer.
You've matured into a fine young woman.
Your parents must be very proud.
- Stay Back.
How's your father?
You and Roger must be
very close.
What did you just say?
Roger and Judy seem like
such a happy couple.
How do you know?
How do you know their names?
- I recognized your last name already
Church.
I have reviewed your file.
Born 12th of May, 1950.
Biological Mother: Lydia Hayes.
Adoptive parents:
Roger and Judy Church.
- No.
No, you're lying.
- Roger couldn't legally adopt children of his own...
because of his criminal record.
So he came to see me to fetch his child.
I can still remember the transaction.
He paid cash.
I don't believe you.
You can still remember
your biological mother Lydia?
They really tried not to cry
when Roger entered her life.
She was a strong woman,
harsh like yourself.
She wasn't a killer.
Revolutions, bitch.
How does that feel?
In Loving Memory of
LYDIA HAYES
Excuse me?
Hello.
- The man who just came through here ...
do you know him?
Yes, hard knowing but he came to myself
most of the time.
After what he has been through,
I don't blame him.
Why, wo what happened to him?
His wife went missing.
They never found her.
She was pregnant at that time.
You alright miss? You look a little pale.
Does he live likely?
- He lives on the other side of town.
I'm just bad done here.
You like a lift into town?
No, i think up I'll walk.
Thanks anyway.
- You take care.