THE UNINVITED
I love you.
And I have a condom.
I should not be here.
Come on.
No, really should not be here.
Come on!
I'm at a party ...
... but the only thing
want to be home.
Do not you're having fun?
Hey, where VAE?
¿Anna?
Do not go home.
Mom is in the house boat.
I'm going to find it.
When the ill ee
moving to the house of the boat.
It's where I wanted to be.
But she is alone.
Not supposed to be alone.
I run to the house to find Dad.
Something is not right.
Do not feel safe.
There is something ...
... evil in the house.
One way or another
these dreams are trying ...
... on escape
forest and return home.
Yes, and if illegal, it's like
Mom tried to tell me if anything.
But I can not understand what it is.
What we try to tell me.
Well, we have already discussed
the girl redhead ...
... and now there'sa new
detail. The shower.
Why do you think that the hold out?
I don 't know.
I do not really remember.
Perhaps trying to extinguish the fire.
When my mom got sick said ...
... always be there.
That if a cat Maull, or
that if the whispering wind ...
... it would be.
Always protected us, but ...
But the night of fire
I could not protect her.
Smart girl.
If I'm so smart, why not
I can remember what happened that night?
Okay, this is what you think.
Survived when
remember, but sometimes ...
... survive when we forget.
You lost your mother in that fire.
Your life was changed by what?
A gas leak? Maybe
forgetting is not so bad.
But what about sleep?
The dream? I already know.
Here's how it works.
It is a process, Anna.
They spent ten months and
and you left this house.
But you will not achieve
in a place like this.
Do you think I'm ready to go?
What else do you want from me?
Go home, kiss a
boy, get in trouble.
Finish what you started.
The beautiful Anna ...
... is going to house.
- I will be alone.
- I gotta go.
There was a lot of blood, is not it, Anna?
You think you fix it?
Come on, leave it in peace.
What I said about you
be here all the time?
I do not managed.
Who would count my stories?
I have a surprise for you.
It's in the glove box.
Tell me that is a hamburger.
Not exactly.
I finished!
Look inside.
To my daughters, Anna and Alex.
Thanks, Dad.
Plenty of nothing.
- Is it good?
- Don 't know, but I sure will tell me.
I know something good.
Ah, great. Thank you.
Rachel made them. She
to come today, but I told him ...
... I wanted to do alone.
It was very good, Anna, really.
I do not know what I would have done if ...
Dad, I'm glad that you've been.
Alex!
¡Anna!
Return.
They arrived early.
Hug you, but ...
Welcome home.
Great lights, lights ...
... so flaquita.
I think I could spend
time there.
So your father is
belly getting fat.
I think he goes first. Yes, I
make cookies all the time.
- What do? --
- V-Formula, my favorite.
So now the house
Ilene women, Mr. Writer.
Your father told you my idea?
No.
On the feast. Thought
in becoming a party ...
... welcome.
Yeah, okay. Maybe.
Everyone asked about you.
- But we have every summer, there's no hurry.
- No.
Okay, I will go to the lake.
The cagué.
As if nothing had happened, huh?
Alex!
You missed so much!
So what do you think?
You know you did that
work on weekends?
For completion
before they return.
Welcome to the real world.
Better food, more people mad.
When he moved?
Guess.
First was helping with the accent ...
... and then was
helping with the funeral.
Now, it is different.
Three times a night.
Whatever.
By the way, thank you very much.
About what?
I hurt.
Alex.
I was here with these two, while
you were looking for yourself internally.
Alex, you have no idea what
that was to be there.
¡She was my mother too!
You know what? At least you could
I have replied to Ilam.
What are you talking about?
The songs that you sent the letters.
Do not got nothing, Alex! I swear.
Perhaps Dr. Silverman
I did not want to see.
No.
Dr. Silverman was not.
It's so silly!
How could you not send my
letters? They were my letters, Dad!
What? Did you have fear that it will count ...
... your girlfriend?
Was it? What you
contara secrets?
It was a stupid back to this town ...
... in which everybody talks about us.
Ah, me das asco.
- Alex, what are you doing?
- As if anyone would care.
I was caught.
Come here.
Now you can hug. I am clean.
Listen, Anna, I know they are supposed
who hate the new girlfriend Dad.
But I really hope that
we can leave that aside ...
... and make this work.
Clear.
Yes
¿Something is different?
Yes, paint.
I like the roles of the house,
but needed to illuminate the kitchen.
- Missing something.
- Really?
- Yes, the blackboard.
- Ah, yes, the blackboard.
Must be in the attic
with everything else.
I thought you no longer need.
So what do you think? Want
help set the table?
No, okay. I am not a
waitress, anyway.
Alex?
What are you doing?
So that was you vomiting?
- Don 't know.
- Okay.
I'm drunk. I went to a
party and had many drinks.
- Where did you find that?
- Top.
- What the hell are you doing with that?
- I do not know, was in the attic.
Well this is where it belongs.
I hate that bell.
Why? Reminds me of Mom.
We need, Alex. That was like
We called for the help ...
... after he got sick.
Anna, wake up. Rachel
bought the bell.
What are you talking about?
Became a whore store
bought a fucking bell ...
... and hung around his neck mom.
And you know why? To
when mom came to hear ...
while ...
mounted a busy dad.
We're inventing.
- Okay, why do that?
- To avenge dad.
Believe me, Anna, I'm not interested
nothing to avenge dad.
You know what? Perhaps I am drunk ...
... but I know the truth.
Oh, here comes the funny.
Maybe you can knock the
windows when you're done.
Sorry.
No need to apologize.
Great. In fact, I think it is
Io that the kitchen needed.
Right? I leave here.
- Okay.
- You know, Anna?
I remember the first time
I came here to care for your mom.
When I taught the
home, Alex was doing ...
... their role in adolescent
Harassed by his father.
But you were different.
Friendly, polite. A lady.
I remember thinking:
... "The other is the classic and the ...
... is strong. "
When I was your age, it was like you.
And be tough.
I did not have to bother.
I am so glad
you're back.
Let's see if you can stay.
Thank you.
This treatment.
Did you see his face? It is as if a jaguar ...
... have come and
had destroyed his kitchen.
- It was so weird.
- You did very well.
It was our slate
has to be there.
Remember how Mom
We left messages there?
Ah, but his writing was so bad.
Ready?
- Am I very pale?
- Yes, quite.
Ah, your husband comes around.
- No, I'll stop here.
- What are the sisters?
Alex, do not you dare.
- Hey, Matt.
- Hello.
- How have you been?
- Okay.
I had wanted to visit,
but I did not leave.
Ah, you should see my mates.
Glad you're back.
Listen, that night on the beach ...
I was nervous. Had
drunk too much punch.
I do not think that was very clever ...
... so it was a stupid drunk.
But I am very concerned for you.
I came to you.
What do you mean?
We followed that night.
I was here I saw everything.
Minutes late, Matt.
Thanks, that's all I needed.
I'm glad you have seen.
Bye.
Matt reminds me of the
purchases from the people.
Come on, your father and unreadable.
- Your agent called today.
- Really?
- Yeah, I knew I had a house here.
- The purchase five years ago.
Pretend you like to fish.
I think it could review
the next book here.
- Really?
- Yes
So I invited him to dinner
on Friday night.
Really?
With some other people.
Why not? Never
No one comes to the house.
It will be fun.
- Please.
- Okay.
Well.
¿Anna?
What are you doing here?
Hey, you okay?
I saw Mom.
What?
I saw my mom!
What are you talking about?
¡Anna!
Try to tell me something.
What?
The fire was no accident.
It was she.
He said he had the night off.
Sure.
- Alex.
- No, now everything makes sense.
She was a mom.
It became one of those weird clothes
and went to the house of the boat.
Perhaps we
conclusions too lightly.
Sorry, but I was not that
saw our mother dead ...
pointing the finger ...
the new girlfriend Dad.
- I think it was just a dream.
- Anna, you were quite awake ...
... I saw you.
- Maybe it was all in my head.
- Maybe.
But that does not change what you both know.
We all knew what she warmed.
Mom killed and will not be with theirs.
Hello. Hi there.
- Do you hear?
- I do not know.
I go to town to buy
some things for the party.
Are we together? ¿Something therapy
mental, perhaps something to eat?
I have great hope that I resaca
much headache later.
But Anna wants to go.
What? No!
What about Matt? So you can
and get to see it tonight.
Tell me, Anna.
Come on, you can go so I can stay
between here and register your things.
Come on.
You know what? We
do it later.
No.
Down in a minute.
Look for something nice to wear.
Fucking bitch.
Your father hates it when I drive fast.
To be our little secret, OK?
Our little secret.
What happened to mom's car?
Well, I discussed and decided
that the family needed more ...
... fun.
Good jewelry.
- Where did you get those?
- Someone gave me a few years ago.
A boyfriend?
A former patient, actually.
Sounds like a good job.
Cleaned in the ass
seniors, Anna.
And I can guarantee that
not all were beautiful.
Like your mom.
I had to do things for people
they were very embarrassed ...
... or weak to make themselves.
You know what I thought to get out of that?
At times were good.
But ...
... no matter how
were condescending ...
Io or bad ... I tried.
I always told myself ...
... "Will be dead very soon."
You know, Anna? We all have
things in the past ...
... of us ashamed.
I think sometimes it is better
if only I let go.
¿Anna?
Anna, are you okay?
Yes Yes
It was nothing.
We have shopping to do, right?
Beautiful. From where is it?
It is French.
Clear.
- I'm going to get milk.
- Great, thanks.
Matt.
Anna.
What are you doing here?
Listen, I think I know what
wanted to tell me that yesterday.
The fire was no accident,
Huh? What did you see?
Matt, these berries are not
being cooler.
Yeah, yeah, I go.
- Will you help please?
- Okay, but not here.
- Will you go tonight?
- Matt!
Yes, at once, in the stone.
Okay.
- Can not find the milk?
- Yes
We gotta go.
Ah, Matt, you do not have to
Bear buying the house.
That will be my job from now on.
Was fun?
Yes, but should ask Anna.
Yes, thank you for lunch.
It was good. Was somewhat
in an embarrassing moment.
Alex?
By God, you scared me,
I thought that was it.
- I talk?
- Yes, we will be tonight.
Well.
Watch this.
Oops, did not know she was naked.
I know, is like a
Farewell to dignity.
By the way, check this out.
Come on.
Look what I found.
Meet the fat.
Ah, it's disgusting.
No, I will not touch that.
Wow.
Here is enough to
reassure a horse.
What do you mean?
Come on, come on.
Wait.
The party was over, Rachel.
Dale, go, arrive late.
¿Matt?
I have bad spine.
What if something happens?
Okay, Anna. Rioja
find out tomorrow.
Yes
- I'm going to my bed.
- No, please stay with me ...
... until I sleep.
If you give me ten U.S. dollars
for every time I hear that.
Thank you.
It's not as entertaining.
Matt.
Careful, do not want
wake your father.
Matt.
Where were you?
We hope in the rock, like you said.
- Yes, I know.
- What's wrong? You are soaked.
I think I fell or something.
Come and sit down.
I feel having such a late arrival.
It's just that ...
... I think you should know
truth of what he saw that night.
- Tell me.
- Okay.
You're shaking.
I can not feel anything.
- I'm afraid, Anna.
- Don 't have.
Matt, what happened to your back?
Your mother wanted to tell you ...
... but not heard.
¡Anna!
¡Aguántame! Please!
Anna, hi, I am the sheriff
Emery, I do not know if I remember.
Listen, we'll
investigation ...
... but must have been beaten with something.
He fell from the boat, his back is broken.
Was supposed to be seeing?
Listen, we all know
Io you past.
If you need anything, what it is,
Come and see me, you know?
Sorry.
It's terrible.
Will make you breakfast,
need to eat something.
David.
Dad, wait.
What?
Matt was not there
out last night for fun.
- Came to see me.
- Anna, what happened was not your fault.
Dad, that's not what you try to tell you.
Honey, can you help me?
- Dad.
- I'm going.
What?
I saw Matt in the village yesterday.
I said what I had
seen the night of the fire.
Rachel heard we did not want
speaking that followed.
I was not coming further.
Anna, why Rachel would do something like that?
- She ...
- What?
Is everything okay out there?
- I will.
- Okay.
Honey, I know this is difficult
for you. And for all of us.
But please, do not
this. Please do not do this.
- Come, let's have breakfast.
- Be there in a minute.
You okay?
No, I'm fine.
I'm not crazy, Alex.
Matt was here, and I thought
I was dreaming ...
... but not what it was.
- Anna, I know ...
- My mom said ...
... was trying to warn me.
- How can it be?
- I was holding.
- Anna, listen.
Look!
Well, now I'm afraid.
I am not crazy!
I will not go back there.
I am not afraid for you.
I'm scared for us.
Anna, what we are all that remains between
Rachel and what he really wants.
Come on.
The murderers did not arise in series
for overnight ...
... so we need to find out who
Miss Rachel is really Summers.
Yes, hello, I try to find information
about a girl from your agency.
His name is Summers. Rachel Summers.
Good, I get references
on one of his nurses, please.
I think it was in the
staff of the hospital ...
... between July and December 2005.
Hello, I try to search for information
about someone who worked for you ...
... some years ago.
Summers.
S-U-M-M ... Yes,
as "Mother."
... E-R-S.
As "Satan."
What?
No, this is impossible
No, no, okay.
Well, thank you very much. Bye.
We have it.
Driver's license
Anna.
Enter.
You have such beautiful lips.
But do not know what to do with them.
The men say they
love the eyes of women.
But it is a lie.
What we really want ...
... is a girl ...
... with a pretty mouth.
You seem very interested in them.
Want to use it tonight?
I think not.
Come on, be fun.
What 's your real name, Rachel?
Say what?
The partnership of carers are not
record any of Rachel Summers.
Your Social Security number
Rachel Summers is the ...
... but it was a masterpiece
School of New Orleans.
He died five years ago.
So who are you? Really.
You know, Anna?
I do not think this will work.
Where do you expect?
A talk with my father.
I really do not have to.
I already discussed with Dr. Silverman.
- Discuss what?
- On your behavior.
Anna is very concerned,
is beginning to believe ...
... that was a mistake to leave out.
I do not lose what I have.
Not allowed.
Now go, I have guests.
I can not believe you apart from dad.
Perhaps you can
do you, but I do not.
I will talk to Dad.
No! She convinced
that lie ...
... and that is my fault. Okay?
Hopefully tonight and
Tomorrow we will go to the police ...
... and told them what happened.
That would only worsen
things for me.
Fine, but this can
be a little heavy.
- Hey, look at you.
- What?
- You look fantastic.
- Thanks.
You've grown, right?
Hey, if you is of all
this is very rare for me too.
Presentations
books are forever ...
the door open for ...
that people come and judge.
Can I ask you a favor?
Could you get a
Rachel hand tonight?
To be honest, I do not think that
sit well with all this ...
... and people are here
are also the judging.
Clear.
What?
I just wanted to ask
if you need help.
Really?
Sure, you can open the kiln.
Well.
This is perfect.
We have to wait ten
minutes before cutting.
That's what it takes.
I'm going to mix.
Ah, could you take out the trash for me?
You are disgusting.
No, no ... What did you do?
What did you do?
Why am I doing this?
What happened?
Let her alone!
Go to your room.
There is a reason for Io
what happened tonight.
Rachel is not who you think it is.
Basta, Anna. What made this time?
- I lied.
- About what?
Above all. On their behalf.
- Do you know where is it?
- I will not dignify that with a ...
No, of course. Because
just look what you see.
What I am trying to do is
this family function.
You think you do that? She
you want for herself.
That is ridiculous.
What mom would say if you
seen putting on the side ...
... that bitch that
just want to separate us?
Rachel is not the one that is separating us.
Look, maybe we should talk
with Silverman about it.
- Sure, because I am I'm crazy.
- Nobody said that.
I know ...
Where is your ring?
Will you marry her?
Tell me!
Yes, we married.
In the fall.
We talked about going to another party
but I want to marry here.
For all of us.
I am not ashamed, Anna. I
ashamed of being happy again.
Bye, Daddy.
Today is the funeral of Matt.
Wear something decent.
I want this to look like a family.
I take refuge in the Lord.
How to use your shelter?
When the values are
being destroyed ...
... What can we expect?
The Lord is my salvation ...
... and not be afraid.
Wright kids.
Murder.
Children brutally murdered.
This is April 11, 1996.
The police found the bodies of
three children in a makeshift grave ...
... a forest in less than 50 yards
the residence of a prominent doctor ...
... Harrison Wright.
The experts stated that
Children were highly sedated ...
... before being stabbed
repeatedly.
Police said the arrest
of Mildred Kemp, aged 19 ...
... who served as the babysitter
children since last August.
Mildred Kemp, shit.
Listen to this, according to Kemp family
was romantically obsessed ...
... with Dr. Wright since the death
his wife last February.
Despite the efforts of police,
still was not able to find.
Wait, what?
See what people are using.
¡Pearls!
Rachel said it was a
gift from a former patient.
Put them around my neck ...
... as if he was proud of them.
Well, it seems that
is our only evidence.
Yes, if we can get your hands on it.
Do not worry about that.
This was just tonight.
Crap.
Mira.
Alex, what are you doing?
Find the keys.
- What you gonna do?
- Just looking for the keys.
What are you looking for, Anna?
Is this what you're looking for?
You can take them.
Please do not mean anything to me.
We know, Rachel.
We know everything.
They caught me.
Here.
Alex!
¡Anna!
I do not want to hurt you.
This is not what I want.
You can do this easily.
- Anna.
- Alex!
What happened?
I was drugged.
¡Anna opened the door!
Got beads?
I did. I have.
¡Anna, open the fucking door!
¡Anna!
You have to go now, okay?
No, no.
I can not leave.
Take this.
¡Anna!
I love you.
I'll come back for you, okay?
I promise.
¡Anna!
So, say that Miss Summers is
actually a woman named Mildred Kemp.
- Yes
- And she was responsible for the fire?
So it was. It was not an accident. Killed
our mother and is now behind us.
Listen, I know it sounds like ...
No!
Mildred Kemp, I remember.
Some years ago in Orange
County, a woman died.
Her husband hired a nanny,
who killed all the children.
True, but never caught.
Listen, Mrs. Wright had a
pearl necklace, three laps.
There are pictures of him in the
Internet if you want to see them.
And?
Rachel is Mildred Kemp.
Well? You are trying to kill ...
to marry ...
as he did with them.
Listen, I want you to feel. I
I will look for Summers in the system.
No, no time for
that. Go to my house.
Alex is still there and
I'm afraid that something will happen.
Nothing will happen to anyone, Anna.
Wait here.
Mom?
Mom.
Do not be afraid.
I am a nurse.
No, no, believe!
Do not believe!
We will kill you!
That's it. Thank you.
The memories.
It was a few years ago in Orange County.
The wife died and her husband hired
a babysitter who murdered all the children.
Rachel is Mildred Kemp.
The police sought the arrest
of Mildred Kemp, aged 19 ...
... who served as a babysitter
children since last August.
Revealed that the forensic
Children were highly sedated ...
... before being
repeatedly stabbed.
Despite the efforts of the
Police have been unable to find it.
Now you can sleep.
You know, Anna?
I'll never have children.
I can not.
However ...
... that has never prevented me
Imagine what it might have a daughter.
But now I've removed that.
With care.
You do not want to hurt you.
Anna.
We tried everything, Anna.
This was the only way.
What did you do?
I had to do, Anna. Or not?
I had to do.
Everything is fine. I'm here.
We're fine.
Look at me. Look at me!
Well, okay?
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
It was Rachel, Dad.
Rachel started the fire.
- What are you talking about?
- She killed mom.
Dad, I know that I never hear
but you have to make the case.
Wait until you leave ...
... and I was drugged and drugged to Alex.
What?
He tried to kill us.
Alex had to do,
dad. She saved us.
Alex. Alex, tell.
- Anna, what are you talking about?
- Do not listen to me, Anna.
Never does.
- Do not know what happened to your sister?
- Alex, tell.
- She died.
- Do not you think!
On fire! It was a year ago.
- Alex, tell!
- Alex is dead!
What have you done?
Alex!
Anna, what do you mean
the fire was no accident?
What happened that night?
Tell me what happened that night!
Let me go. Let go!
Hello? Dad?
Hey, girl.
There are guys out there ...
... and you return to our home.
It is no longer our home.
What are you doing?
Will burn in hell.
Anna. ¡Anna!
Anna, what happens?
Alex?
Coming, Mom.
Alex!
How could you not give him my letters, Dad?
Did you have to fear
contara your girlfriend?
Was it? What would you
contara secrets?
¿Anna? Listen, I
the people, want to go?
I tell you what
I saw that night. I saw everything.
- No, no.
- Aguántame!
You know, Anna?
I'll never have children.
I can not.
But I never stopped thinking ...
... would like to have a daughter.
And now I take that away.
Sorry, Mr. Roberts.
I noticed the name of the
Miss Summers in the passport ...
... is not the name of
driver's license.
The name was changed three years ago.
Her boyfriend used to beat her.
His real name was Rachel Rochester.
Her daughter had the idea that his fiancée
was a woman named Mildred Kemp.
Why is this inventory?
Security Area.
Hello, Anna.
You okay?
Why ask?
I wanted to know, Anna.
I finished what I started.
Welcome home.
Mildred Kemp
Subtitles by: Papade