Some murders take seconds...
Others take minutes...
Some murders take hours...
Now...
this murder...
takes YEARS!
It began as a nuisance
Ouch! What the...
It became a menace
Get out of my house!
What the f*ck is wrong with you!?
Now...
Forensic Pathologist Jack Cucchiaio
is running for his life...
Lunatic has been attacking me all night
He's just broken into my house and...
I need a squad car here right now!
Ok, this might sound
ridiculous, but he's got a
spoon but it hurts like hell!
And.. and I...
H... Hello? Hello?
If you'd like to make a call,
please hang up and try again.
F*ck!
The strange man has been
attacking me with a spoon...
He's haunting me like...
oh... everywhere...
and... and it... Baby...
Did you say spoon?
Oh I just want my life back!
You need professional help, Jack...
Get the hell out of here!
I'm sorry Jack, but
there's just no way to
determine that these wounds
aren't self-inflicted.
They are not self-inflicted!
You need the evidence, Jack...
Get away from me!
I've travelled 10.000 miles,
I'll pay any price!
Just tell me what this means?
The mark of a Genosage! Nothing
can stop the Genosage...
the Genosage will never stop...
until you are...
...DEAD!
It will follow you to
the ends of the earth!
What would you do?
You can't escape!
You can't stop it!
You can't kill it!
It will find you!
It will catch you!
It will hit you!
With a spoon!
Again, and again, and again...
and again, and again, and again...
and again,
and again, and again...
(oh so tired, lol)
The spoon thunders down with relentless
merciness, soul shattering fury
Pounding and bounding
and bounding, shuffle
soft spots into your
skull until it cracks!
I feel like I'm losing my mind!
Come on! Come on!
Come on mother f*cker!
Jack!
A major motion picture event...
over 12 years in the making...
filmed on 5 continents...
with a running time of over 9 hours!
Perhaps...
the most relentless murder
in the history... of cinema.
Chaotic Rampage American Pictures
(C.R.A.P) Proudly presents...
Can you endure 20.000
spoonfulls of terror?
Coming... slowly...
...to a theater near you!
_english subtitle by rast20_