In Nature's scheme of things, certain plants
are carnivorous, or "eating plants".
The Venus flytrap
is one of the best known of these plants.
A fly, drawn to the plant by a sweet syrup,
brushes against trigger bristles.
Just how these plants digest their prey
has yet to be explained.
There is much to learn
about these fascinating "eating plants".
This is a newcomer, Triffidus selectus,
brought to Earth on the meteorites
during The Day of the Triffids.
All reports confirm that the world is witnessing
an unprecedented shower of meteorites.
There is no record of a display such as this
in recorded history.
At observatories, astronomers are noting
this fantastic phenomenon...
.. and carefully calculating the effect
on our solar system.
The consensus of opinion is that the meteorites
burn up from the intense heat
before they reach the Earth.
The show of meteorites continues unabated.
This is a thrilling once-in-a-lifetime spectacle
that simply must be seen.
"Once-in-a-lifetime spectacle"!
Free tickets, take any seat in the house!
Here I am!
Dr Soames to see you, Mr Mason.
Doctor, why can't I look at what's going on?
The bandages come off tomorrow anyway.
I'm afraid not, Mr Mason. After an eye operation
like yours, it's best to wait the full 10 days.
- Eight o'clock tomorrow morning, Nurse.
- Yes, Doctor, eight o'clock.
- Goodnight, Mr Mason.
- Thank you. See you in the morning, I hope!
I hope so!
I'll have that cigarette.
- Open your mouth, please.
- Ahh.
Now, this should give you
a good night's rest.
Lie back. I'm going to put your bed down.
Miss Jameson, are you realy
as pretty as they say you are?
Tomorrow morning,
you can answer that question for yourself.
Hmm. Tomorrow morning.
Do you realy think I'll be able to see?
Tomorrow night you'll be in Southampton,
on board your ship and ready for duty.
Aye, Ma'am.
- Goodnight.
.. And we remind you
the spectacular display of meteorites
is turning the night sky
into a blazing display of fireworks.
All over the world at this moment...
I can't leave this specimen. Why don't you go up
the tower and have a look? It sounds spectacular.
Sure! The tobacco company probaby found
a way to light up the sky to sell more cigarettes.
- Where did you hide it this time?
- It's in the cupboard.
It's always in the same cupboard.
I was, er...
I was hoping we could get back
to dissecting that stingray this evening.
Here we go again!
The subject is Tom Goodwin,
brilliant marine biologist.
I'm bored with stingrays.
I realy don't care what a stingray stings.
What DO you care about, Tom?
Realy want me to tell you?
Sooner or later,
you're going to have to face the fact.
Day and night, drunk or sober,
in a lecture room or a lab
or a deserted lighthouse off the coast of Cornwall.
To hell with it! Meteors and all, who cares?
I care what happens to us.
Karen, you're... You're a nice girl.
At the most...
You talked yourself into marrying me.
All right... What do you want us to do?
I don't know what you want.
But I want to get away from this island.
- This pretence of doing important experiments.
- It was your idea.
- Six months away from university. Fieldwork...
- Let's clear out of here!
Let me go where I can buy
a bottle of scotch when I want,
not wait for a rotten boat
to bring me one bottle a week!
- What about the equipment?
- Leave it.
- What about the fish?
- Throw them back in the sea!
Fine. We'll leave the island tomorrow.
The boat's due in the morning.
We are awaiting word from Australia.
Reports will confirm we
are witnessing the most...
.. the most beautiful
display of meteorites...
The BBC will be on the air all night tonight
to keep you posted on this truly historic
and marvellous display of Nature at its best.
.. from time to time
with the latest reports.
Eight...
.. Nine.
Nine?
Miss Jameson!
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Miss Jameson?
Dr Soames?
Miss Jameson!
Can anybody hear me?
- Phew! Dr Soames.
- Bill Mason?
Sorry, I just couldn't wait
to get those bandages off.
- You can see, Mason?
- Yes.
But I can't believe what I see.
What's happened?
Would you please take me to my office?
Now try the other eye.
- Certain the beam's on the pupil?
- Yes, sir.
All right. That's enough.
- Is the blind drawn in here?
- Yes, sir.
Would you be kind enough to pull it up?
What is it, Dr Soames? What's happened?
The optic nerves have gone.
The glare of the meteorites last night.
You're probaby one of the few people
in London who can still see, Mason.
I don't envy you.
I wouldn't care to see
the things you're likey to see.
In the outer office, in my desk,
you'll find a black leather kit.
Would you get it for me?
Of course.
No, it's not there.
Ah, here it is.
- No sign of the boat?
- No sign of anything.
It should have been here hours ago.
Nothing on the radio, either.
I've been trying all morning.
I suppose you're losing
valuable drinking time.
I'm sorry.
.. look-out. Repeat..
the entire population of England
is afflicted with blindness
after watching the meteorite
shower last night.
This is the Royal Dockyard at Devonport.
A number of naval personnel
have escaped blindness.
We are trying to set up a rescue centre.
All those who are still able to see
are urged to make their way to the dockyard.
Urgent warning..
all of England appears to be infected with
a strange new plant that can inflict a fatal sting.
It is rumoured this plant
can uproot itself and move about.
If you are blind, stay indoors.
If you can see, keep a constant look-out.
We will return to the air
with further bulletins.
Stay tuned to this wavelength.
Blindness, men-killing plants...
I'm not drunk, am I?
I wish you were.
And how do we get off this island?
Where would we go?
We are still trying to reach the police.
Please remain calm. Do not move about.
The only danger is that you will injiure
yourselves or accidentally start fires.
Do not smoke, do not light matches.
Stay clear of all electrical equipment.
We are doing everything
possible to get help...
- Are any trains running?
- I don't know.
Suddeny it went dark and I can't see.
Can you help me, sir?
Please, can you help me?
Beg pardon, sir, can you help me?
- I couldn't help overhearing...
- Can you get me a taxi?
- If you could phone my wife...
- I'm happy to pay. Here's my purse.
I'm sorry. There are no taxis
and the phones don't work.
Peter, my little boy, where is he?
I must find my boy.
- What's your boy look like?
- You can see?
- Of course I can see. Why shouldn't I?
- Perhaps you can help me...
- Where's the one who can see?
- This little girl.
- Can you see, girlie?
- Yes.
- Come on!
- No, let me go! Let me go!
Let me go!
Out of my way! Go away, I tell you!
Drop that child!
Thief! You thief!
- Were you in that train by yourself?
- I was in the luggage van.
- What were you doing in there?
- I ran away from boarding school.
- Where are your parents?
- I haven't any.
- The bank in London takes care of me.
- Well, the banks are closed.
- Why is he barking?
- I don't know.
Come on, we'll find out.
Ah, it's nothing. Come on.
Stay here.
Come on, let's go down to my ship.
Wait here.
Let's see if we can find some rocks.
Susan!
- Susan!
- Arghhh!
Get in the car!
- I wish I could understand French.
- I can!
- What's he saying?
-.. catastrophe. Les services sont terminés.
All services stopped...
Will continue sending as long as he can.
That's a big help
.. approximately 400 miles east of New York.
All officers, crew and passengers
suddenly stricken blind.
If you read me, come in, please.
SS Midland calling. Mayday, mayday.
SS Midland calling. Mayday.
- Is the captain here?
- Yes, what is it?
The passengers are panicking, sir.
- Can't you contact the doctor?
- No, sir.
This is the captain speaking.
Attention, all passengers.
There is no one on board who can help you.
We're radioing for a rescue vessel.
The only immediate danger is that
you may injiure yourselves by moving around.
Everyone stay where you are.
And if there is anyone who can see,
even a child...
.. please, come up on the bridge.
.. Ici Paris. Tous les gouvernements sont priés
d'envoyer immédiatement leur représentants...
It's Paris. He says they're calling
a meeting, a disaster meeting...
.. at the Palais du Charot.
Ici Paris. Ici Paris...
There must be others who can see.
If we could make contact...
.. Flight 356 from Cape Town calling.
Request tower stand by
for emergency landing.
Please talk us down.
Please talk us down. Tower, can you read me?
Tower, can you read me? Mayday, mayday.
Tower, please come in.
Please talk us down. Please talk us down.
- Still no repy, sir.
- Keep trying.
- Flight 356 from Cape Town...
- Fuel's about gone, sir.
- How much longer?
- Any moment now, sir.
Please talk us down. Tower, can you read me?
Tower, can you read me?
Mayday, mayday! Tower, please come in...
I've got the passengers quiet again, sir,
but it won't last.
They want to know what's happening.
I have to tell them something.
Tell them... Tell them everything's
all right and not to worry.
Tell them to fasten their safety belts.
We're coming in to land.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen, please fasten
your safety belts, as we are about to land.
I assure you everything's all right.
Thank you.
Fasten your safety belts, please.
Fasten your safety belts,
and no smoking, please.
- Belt all right?
- The pilot, is he blind too?
- Blind? Blind?
- Don't be sily...
- Blind?
- Don't panic! Don't panic!
- We're going to crash!
- Please sit down!
Arghh!
Mayday, maydayI Tower, please come in.
Tom! Tom, there's one of those plants
growing out there!
- Where?
- On the ledge by the cove.
How about this?
I'm coming with you.
Keep behind me.
No sense in getting killed by a plant.
- I thought you didn't care what happened to you.
- I don't.
But I picked a much pleasanter way to die.
Tom... It was here.
I know it was here!
Come on. Let's get back inside.
Arghh!
It's all right. It's all right.
Ici Paris. Bulletin in English.
Because of worldwide disruption,
it is impossible for delegates to gather.
Paris, with its millions of helpless inhabitants,
has become dangerous.
This will be our last broadcast.
No one here can see.
There is no one left.
There's nothing, Bill.
We're lost, aren't we, Bill?
Let me see that map again.
Bill, look!
Thank goodness, Mr Coker!
- But you are not Mr Coker.
- You can see!
- You too!
- Do you live near here?
- Five kilometres.
- Show us the way.
- Miss Durant, thank heavens!
- Mr Coker, this is Mr Mason and Susan.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
- You've found some more!
- Miss Coker, Mr Mason and Susan.
- How do you do?
- They can see.
Oh, good. I hope you'll stay and help us.
- How many blind people do you have here?
- About 40.
But you must be very hungry.
My sister and I were touring France.
We collided with Miss Durant's car.
Both our cars were ruined.
No one was bady hurt.
But we were all three under
sedation that night.
Thanks to Miss Durant,
her chateau became a hospital.
Yes, a tragic irony. The sick stayed well
and the healthy became blind.
- Your daughter is very sleepy.
- Hmm?
Come along, my dear.
Good night... Daddy.
- How old is your daughter, Mr Mason?
- Susan is not my daughter.
We met in London
and we've sort of been stuck with each other.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
We're all friends here.
Bettina, I want you to meet Susan.
- She's an English girl who's just arrived.
- Hello, Susan.
Hello.
I brought her to you because she feels
strange here and you speak English.
I'll call by later and tuck you in.
But you can see!
- How can you tell?
- I'm finding I can tell many things.
I can tell the way people react
when you touch them.
- See if I can tell anything more about you.
- Can you tell how old I am?
- About 13.
- I'm ony 12.
- But you're a very grown-up 12!
- I think I am.
Cury... blonde hair, right?
Right.
- And brown eyes?
- That's right!
And a good sense of humour. You have
the nicest laugh lines round your mouth.
I'll tell you something else, too.
We're going to be good friends.
Until things get back to normal,
you're welcome to stay and help us.
In the past few days,
I've seen London, Paris and a lot in-between.
- Things will never be "normal".
- So I've tried to tell Miss Durant.
- I have faith, Mr Mason.
- Faith is fine, Miss Durant.
- But we need a lot more than that to survive.
- Why shouldn't we survive?
In France alone there are
over 50 million people, almost all blind.
There's going to be
starvation, fire, pestilence.
Anyone caught in the middle has no chance.
I think we should get out and go on to Spain.
- How do you know it's any better?
- I don't.
And even so,
how could we get all the people there?
- We couldn't.
- Mr Mason, you're just running away.
Miss Durant, I've told you
what things are like.
If you sit here with your eyes closed and let
this run over you, it's YOU that's running away.
Perhaps you'll change your mind. I hope you
and Susan will decide to stay and help us.
- Goodnight.
A warm, generous-hearted woman,
but I'm afraid very stubborn.
- The lights are on again!
- They've got the electricity going!
- Who turned all the lights on?
- It's happened! France is back to normal.
- Maybe I can reach someone on the phone.
- The lights are on?
Yes, isn't it wonderful?
Allô? Allô?
- You won't get an answer, Miss Durant.
- Why are you so sure?
I put some fuel in the auxiliary motor for
the generator. While it lasts, we have light.
But there's nothing I can
do about the phone.
Cortex of the root system.
It's good to see you working again, Tom.
I assure you it's not for the greater glory
of science. I just want us to survive.
- We will.
- Huh!
Damn it all, I'm not even a botanist!
- Is it a plant or an animal?
- Who knows?
Doesn't seem to have a
central nervous system.
- No circulation.
- Then, how does it move?
All plants move. But they don't usualy pull
themselves out of the ground and chase you!
If we could find out how
this thing functions...
.. we might figure out an
easier way of killing it.
Look, you must get some sleep.
- There's no time.
- Just an hour.
Then I'll wake you, I promise.
Tom...
You realy must get some sleep.
Sleep now. I'll wake you in an hour.
Arghh!
Tom...
It got out! It came to life and it got out!
They regenerate.
Like worms - cut them in half,
you can't kill them.
There's no telling how many are out there.
Get the hammer and nails.
It's like being nailed in your own coffin.
- Bettina, what are you doing out here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
- You shouldn't wander round by yourself.
- I had to talk to you.
Is it true you're going to
leave us to go to Spain?
- Yes.
- But what about the rest of us?
Bettina, the ony way I can help
is to try to find some real help.
- I can't do it by staying here.
- Then you're coming back?
Yes... if I can.
I hope you do come back.
Come on, I'd better get you back inside.
- A triffid.
- A what?
A triffid.
The original triffid,
the kind I saw in a greenhouse years ago,
was known to have come
to Earth on a meteorite.
This reappearance must have been caused
by the meteorite explosion the other night.
Why should they attack people?
Most plants thrive on animal waste. I'm afraid
this mutation has an appetite for the animal itself.
This must be how they propagate.
- There are millions of them.
- One light wind and they're everywhere.
- Susan, where's Miss Durant?
- In there.
- I've something to tell you.
- Wait a minute.
- Miss Durant.
- One moment. Please sit down.
Now, Miss Durant, whether you like it or not,
we have to pack up and leave.
- Did you bring some more supplies?
- You tell her.
Mason's right. In 24 hours
the vicinity will be swarming with triffids.
I cannot leave all these people here to die!
I grew up with them. They're my friends.
Listen!
Bill, it's that plane again! It flew over before.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
Come on, Coker!
He says Toulon, the naval base,
is a rescue centre.
Toulon. 'Course, the French base
in the Mediterranean near Marseilles.
He's dead.
Ahh!
Are you all right?
- What's the matter?
- My ankle, I can't go on.
I'll carry you.
Coker?
- Bill!
- What's going on?
- Shh!
- What is it?
Some men, convicts, I think. They've taken
the girls in there and made them dance.
- They brought food and whisky.
- How many?
- I don't know, a lot.
- They can see?
- Yes.
- Where's Miss Durant?
She's with them.
They said they'd kill anyone who...
No! No!
Stay here and lock the doors.
Don't open for anyone but me.
Go on. Susan's in the car.
You're not one of us!
Come on.
Susan, open up!
I can't open it!
Arghh!
Susan, get over the other side!
Arghhh!
The things I said to you back at the chateau,
I had no right to say them.
Well, if it makes you feel any better, I'd probaby
have said the same, under the circumstances.
Feel guilty, huh?
Maybe.
- You know why?
- Why?
Because you survived.
Bettina, Coker and all the rest dead.
And you're alive and you wonder why.
- That's exacty right.
- I know the feeling.
In the war, you get a ship
shot out from underneath you...
.. all your friends gone,
ony a handful left.
You ask yourself,
"Why me? Why not someone better?"
Where will we go in Spain?
There's a big American naval base
in southern Spain, at Cadiz.
They're equipped for disaster.
They've got supplies.
So were the French at Toulon.
Negative.
Five per cent nitric acid
solution: negative.
Not that I expected a miracle.
I didn't think we'd find a magic bullet.
But absolutey nothing
seems to affect this tissue.
They live, they grow, they take nourishment.
They have sensory response,
they absorb and expend energy.
No matter what they're made of,
something must interrupt their life cycle.
Fundamentaly, it's a simple problem,
like finding a weedkiller.
No help out there.
There's been nothing on the air for days.
Can't help thinking
about that last radio call from Devonport.
The way the place caught fire and blew up,
it was like listening to the end of the world.
Well, it's not the end of the world, not quite yet.
There's an answer here, there has to be!
- We'd better find the answer pretty soon.
- What are they doing out there?
Staring in at us
like guards outside a condemned cell.
- Let's get through this checklist again.
- Right.
Whoa.
You're a good horse. You must be tired.
I'm going to find you some fresh green grass.
- Bill, may I go and look at the fair?
- Yes, but don't wander off.
If we can find something,
we'll eat right away.
- Ooh!
- Sorry, did I burn you?
No, it's nothing.
Bill, do you think we have a chance?
Once you taste this coffee of mine,
you'll know nothing worse can happen!
Your coffee is very good.
In fact, you're a handy man in the kitchen.
I've been doing for myself a long time.
- You have never been married?
- No.
- Why?
- Never been around long enough to get caught.
Now you're saddled with a famiy.
It might have its points.
Susan!
Look what I've found!
We could use it. We'll take it.
We can't leave our horse!
- We'll leave him in a field. He'll be fine.
- We can't leave him! I won't go!
- Susan, be reasonable. We can't take him.
- Don't let him, Christine! It isn't fair!
- It's mean! He doesn't have any right!
- But it's not Bill's fault, Susan.
He's ony doing what's right for all of us.
He'll never hurt you, never, if he can help it.
- You know that.
- I know.
- Are we on the right road for Cadiz?
- I think so.
What's the matter?
Let's find out.
Hello? Is anybody here?
Please... Please come in, come in.
Oh, God. Teresa!
Teresa, ven pronto! Ha llegado gente.
Pueden ver. Nos ayuderán.
I knew it. That's my rope.
- Luís de la Vega.
- I'm Bill Mason. This is Susan and Miss Durant.
But, please... Teresa...
.. three guests!
- This is my wife, Teresa.
- Welcome.
We are not the ony two people
left in this part of the world.
I believed someone would arrive to help.
That's why I put up the rope.
We are expecting a baby
and need someone to help.
Perhaps the two ladies could...?
You can't see?
- You both seem so natural.
- My wife has been blind for many years.
Now she's teaching me to get around.
But you ladies will stay and help her?
- Of course.
- Please be seated. I'll go and get some food.
We'll help. Come along, Susan.
- We were trying to get to Cadiz.
- You don't know about that?
- Know what?
- They had to evacuate the naval base.
- They did? How?
- By submarine. I heard it on my radio.
Some submarines were submerged on the night
of the meteorites. The crews were all right.
I tried to contact them with my transmitter
but something went wrong.
I can neither transmit nor receive.
- Let's take a look. Maybe I can fix it.
- Oh, are you familiar?
Yes, as first mate,
I have to have a working knowledge of it.
.. from the Gibraltar Rescue Centre.
Final survivor pick-up
will be on Saturday at Alicante.
We repeat our warning.
Vast bands of triffids are roaming the area.
Do not travel at night. Barricade all doors.
We repeat our warning.
Final survivor pick-up
will be on Saturday at Alicante.
That's tomorrow!
We'll leave first thing in the morning.
I think that'll work.
When I tell you, turn that switch.
OK, Susan, turn it on.
Well, it works.
All right, Susan, you can turn it off now.
- Baby born?
- Yes, it's a boy.
- How is he?
- Fine.
- And the mother?
- She's weak, but that's to be expected.
- Hmm.
- Bill!
Susan!
Look!
Susan, go turn on the switch.
The current's weakening.
Susan, get back to the house!
We just don't have enough power!
Come on!
Keep the engine running.
- Why do they keep coming back?
- I don't know, Susan.
There must be some reason.
- Maybe they can hear us.
- Hmm?
Hey, maybe that's it.
Maybe it's sound that attracts them.
That generator... Come on, Susan.
You're right. It's sound that attracts them!
If sound leads them to us,
it can lead them away, too.
- Like the Pied Piper of Hamelin.
- Yeah!
Yeah, the Pied Piper.
Susan, you've hit it! Come on.
When it's dawn, open the gates and take off.
But until then, no noise at all. All right?
Come on.
- What about you?
- I'll see you in Alicante.
Windows up, hmm?
Time to get aboard, Miss. We're sailing.
Miss Durant, we have to go now.
The submarine will depart
in five minutes. Life rafts will search for survivors.
Hey!
Ahoy!
This is the Gibraltar Rescue Centre
for the Mediterranean area.
Our pick-up at Alicante
has been made on schedule.
This is the final rescue
operation for the present.
Stay tuned to this wavelength
for further bulletins.
Repeat.. stay tuned to this wavelength
- How far is Gibraltar?
- Too far to swim. Let's get back to work.
Get away from that window!
Stop staring at them!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Karen, they're dissolving!
The sea water's dissolving them!
- Tom!
- Get back!
Arghh!
Turn the pressure up!
Sea water!
Two-thirds of the Earth is covered with it.
You hunt and you search
and all the while the answer's right in front of you!
A simple method had been found
to destroy the triffids.
Sea water, from which life
on Earth had sprung,
became the means of
preserving life on Earth.
Mankind survived
and once again had reason to give thanks.