I try now "Happy New Year."
He must learn for tomorrow.
- Look, there it is.
- You sit in the road.
- I'm sorry, honey.
- It is not bad.
Why we live in a house
such as Aunt Chloe?
Someday maybe, baby.
We will see if he wants.
Aunt Chloe.
Paulie, come on.
- A drink would be heaven.
- Hey, buddy.
Happy New Year in Chinese.
Not bad, huh?
- Do you speak Chinese? Cool.
- Yes.
- Do never gone.
- I received an offer.
You look beautiful.
- I can not.
- Yes it is.
Chloe, hello.
Casey, I was the Man
from Uncle Chuck in Tomarno.
You change in a pop.
- Casey, look how big you are.
- Hi, Uncle Robbie.
Let the uncle but fall.
Come on, let's start this party.
- Say hello, dear.
- Who wants a Christmas?
Me.
- Who think this is the best New Year ever?
- I.
- View Leah go, it is even.
- Unbelievable, huh?
- She is her Inhalator off.
- That is fantastic.
Is not it great? The children
are as enthusiastic as we are.
Come here, sister.
- Hi, Casey.
- Hello.
Ruined the weekend, right?
There are also parties.
- It is not just one.
- You know I can not go.
- Because you are married to a fool.
- The only two days.
You get your way the rest of the year.
Perhaps a few hours?
You know how hard I am looking for.
Please?
- Mouse.
- Call me if not.
Please.
Paulie. It is in order.
- Baby anyway.
- Mommy.
I think you are car sick.
It is not bad.
Paulie and help this weekend, right?
Have you ever heard of contraception?
- Mama was invited for Christmas.
- Yes, euphemistically speaking.
Did she put out a cafe?
Daddy, look.
If you play with your gift?
Sorry,
Casey has chosen Christmas gifts.
Did you know that mama has called
at eleven o'clock in the evening,
she wanted the children speak.
Excuse me, I can not invite.
They are interfering too
much, you understand me?
Is that make-up?
This year we had a drunken Christmas.
I sent the kids to bed.
I had a special punch and then
we had a nude snowballs fight.
You should see the photos.
They are fantastic.
We were just different.
Granny fell off the toilet.
- Mommy.
- It's all right.
Let's drink.
Someone who thinks that attention...
Jonah.
- Normally he never rough.
- Come here, baby.
Not like his mama, then.
Really. I had to pretend to the Director
and teachers of Casey. Terrible.
- I think I did pee in my pants.
- We do much OJ.
I never talk with my mouth full.
- What is OJ?
- Potbelly buttercup.
Did you read the article, which I'll
have sent, on MMR jobs?
You are cleaning your teeth.
Forward.
Hey, Leah, Nicky. Bedtime.
Have fun with your nephews and nieces.
I love you.
What happened to that
web design thing happened?
That was a complete waste of time.
A lot of techies
the whole day playing Sim City.
Actually I have a much better idea.
I met these guys...
I get no reception.
That was outside. I show you.
You can use anything.
Casey should really talk to anybody.
Papa has given her house arrest.
House arrest? That sounds interesting.
Mama wants Jonah's
self-confidence upgrading,
so we try not to be disobedient.
Casey drink whiskey.
This is heaven.
Have you been told Elaine
that the children get home schools?
Are you qualified for it?
I mean, the school
is in the neighborhood, huh.
It is logical. Since the case sold,
we have the time.
At that age they are so plastic.
I really wish them the chance to...
I think it would be a good idea. I try
Miranda Mandarin words to learn.
Chinese, how many schools do that?
None. Why, certainly not us.
- Oddly, it's a world economy.
- Is this again a sect?
Now we do not chant?
And I show too thick in monk attire.
What is it, honey?
- Are you okay?
- Come here, baby. What is wrong?
I was afraid of Paulie.
Honey, it's Paulie it.
This morning he was still fun.
It is in order.
Miranda, Leah does
not bring you to the top?
No.
- Honey, do not start.
- Let her wait.
That is like Leah.
Right, honey?
Maybe you can
a gold star to give Miranda.
- Goodnight, Daddy.
- Goodnight, Princess.
- Ga me.
- Come here.
- Goodnight, lickspittle.
- Goodnight, Mommy.
Goodnight, Mommy.
Super Mama.
- Miranda?
- What?
You know how a real Liavor sounds?
Are you still in the school orchestra?
- Your dad said you played flute.
- I call him Dad.
I think you have certainly not called uncle.
Try here.
- Does it work?
- Yes.
- Good night.
- With Lisa. I'm busy or dead.
- Thanks to record.
You had better not deceased,
miss Demurray.
Is not this great. I think
that we still have to take ten children.
You look so tired and Lainy.
She is so bad.
You would also be tired,
with all those rough conditions.
Ecotourism. What a farce.
Take photographs of a gorilla that fleas
of his butt unplucked
and we burn you away atmosphere.
They have so much luck. They have
their five cases no two brain cells.
And that home schools. I thought Chloe's
capabilities in design-earth 'layers.
Now they
fundamentalist in Buddhism.
- Why did your book in Chinese medicine?
- I thought Robbie would have interest.
Why you insulting me, when I
China talking? Support me, right?
I said already.
It is a great idea.
Come on.
I thought you and I we would
fun this weekend.
Does your daughter understand that?
Goodnight, my angel.
Leah, Nicky. Come play with me.
From the road.
Since the children on sledges, Robbie.
Stay with one seat.
You're right. For the first time up.
First up, may not.
Leave it on, Paulie.
I've just had 24 hours nonversatie.
Just come.
Take me home.
Come to the exit. You have my card, huh?
Whatever you want.
- Have you seen Jinxie?
- A while ago in the forest.
- Where have you been?
- For you a question, for me to know.
- No adults in the tent.
- I think I now regret.
I must be the worst
vegetarian ever.
- I looked briefly in the oven and I...
- Me too.
- Is Robbie still to the city today?
- Occasionally. If you want his advice.
- Is he sleeping?
- Not much.
- But mostly he?
- What? Lainy, milk.
- That smells good.
- Where are you going?
I get a little ga.
You too.
Is it good?
Yes, great.
We will do more as a family.
These are my New Year plans.
- Casey helps much?
- She has the Christmas gifts purchased.
- Look how hard I was.
- Lainy, you were pregnant.
You were not really an example.
- I do my job is not bad, huh?
- No, Lainy.
Promise me that you kill
If I completely change mama.
I promise.
I've missed.
You must know everything
on Chinese medicine.
He does not know that the Internet
there is full of them.
You should be able
to help Elaine and Chloe.
And feminism, then?
Does that have anything to do
with selfish?
I ga you.
- Welcome to my office.
- Thanks.
I have spoken to those guys.
They import a lot through the internet.
Many ingredients come from China.
And you know, thank you...
There is already a big market.
We know that. Thank you, honey.
... viruses, I think,
each year are identified and...
... that is traditional Chinese medicine
and that is to explode.
It has serious side effects.
I get you.
It is finished.
Where's Paulie?
Jesus.
- Are you okay?
- It is.
- It is only a graze.
- Excuse me.
- It was an accident.
- Here we do not save children.
It is in order.
- Dad is very angry.
- It's okay. Who brought him?
- Where were you, Casey?
- What have I done?
It is in order. Do not cry.
He was not here.
Now it's just a quiet time,
while we prepare for the party.
You are the oldest.
You are the mommy.
I feel sick, Mommy.
Be a good boy
ga and lie down.
I mean, Mommy.
I do not.
If you help Leah
with them to dress for the party,
she maybe
another gold star.
Leah, come here.
Favorite.
Stop.
Can I what?
Come on.
Like I've never smoked.
Jim Morrison imitation.
And you would an expert be?
Jim Morrison lives on
in the lost centuries.
Miranda and Paulie are a nightmare.
They see how they can go
just like you.
What was that?
They do not know
So you can not tell you.
It is...
It is a baby.
Did you not?
I am the abortion that is escaped.
Time to work, huh?
- I was looking for Miranda.
- It is up to the other children.
Happy new New Year.
- Everyone starts it. Do not let it cool.
- Do I get the pepper?
Do you have meat?
For anyone peas.
Robbie is excited about
my new business project and...
... and it does so on the market.
It can be fun, it will be something
as a family.
- We discuss later on.
- Yes, but you see something in there, huh?
- Bon appetit, everyone.
- Enjoy.
We can something like a junior Thesium do
such as the immunity of children up
naturally.
Sit down, come.
Look, Jonah, I'm glad you think a
way to have a start
but I do not understand why you think
that we want them involved.
Legal import of rhino horn or
tiger balm to cure acne and impotence?
You still know what Chloe and I
Job did?
Is that a tattoo, Casey?
Remember that you always wanted one,
Lainy, but I forbade you?
Can I look?
That is beautiful.
Very seasonal.
It's actually a self portrait.
- I mean, what could have happened.
- I think it is cool.
I feel sick.
- Mommy, I feel sick.
- You're not sick, sweetheart.
You must not always imitate niece.
Besides Miranda has not yet eaten.
- Miranda, please eat something.
- Let her.
- That is enough.
- Jesus.
Not the rest of you.
What if
Miranda again I gave a gold star
... because they eat a few peas.
- It's okay. I can handle it.
It does nothing.
Come game time, we make a tent.
We are an indoor igloo. Come here.
- I am on the bad side.
- Okay, the bad side. Casey, help out.
- Everything is ruined.
- It's okay. Let me look.
Please, stop it.
What is wrong with you.
- Who is the Arthenon?
- I.
- Who is the Invectra?
Leah, come here.
Your coat is not properly closed.
- I'm glad you liked it.
- Let us hope that your mom that is.
I need to call.
I am so sorry.
Maybe she is sick. I thought yesterday
Paulie that car was sick,
but perhaps he was really sick.
Great.
You bring them here if they are sick.
You know how Leah is admissible.
They are children, Chloe.
Things go round, there it is.
Ga just sit.
My God.
What do you...
Please bring the children inside.
Bring the kids inside.
Please.
Come here.
Damn.
What the hell going on?
Listen to me.
Go sit down.
Paulie.
The ambulance and police
are about half hour.
Police?
If the roads were bad.
- God, what happened?
- Fucking Paulie, what do you think?
- Is he okay? Where is he going?
- It's my damn blood.
I get...
Casey, you...
Let him.
Where are the children?
Where are my babies?
- I think they started the forest.
- God.
Stay here.
- Quiet. I will search the woods.
- I want my babies.
I do not know what to do.
- Is he really dead?
- You have it so cold.
- Tell me then, dear.
- I do not know.
- But you were there.
- I think he was on the sled. He must...
- But you should still have seen...
- I have not seen. Okay?
But Robbie helped you with the children.
I was not there.
I went to the track to see Lisa.
She came to retrieve me for the party.
I am returned.
I would be Chloe.
Search for the children.
Leah, what is it?
I am.
Casey.
It is okay.
Princess?
Hello, Princess.
- Are you mad at me?
- Of course not. I would never be.
- What you are doing.
- Where is Uncle Robbie?
Come here. Sit down.
I have something to say.
- I love you.
- I love you, Daddy.
I am sorry that I was not at.
I was upset.
- Why were you upset?
- Casey.
It is okay.
Chloe, please come inside.
- No, I want him to leave.
- You'll freeze.
Casey is a moment
with the children. It is okay.
I want him to leave.
- You can not see me Robbie.
- She told him not to move.
Come on. Chloe, come inside.
Yes, I understand that.
But now it takes much longer.
- Help me. Mommy.
- Paulie.
It is okay.
Come here, baby.
Come on.
Mommy is here.
It is all right, Paulie.
No, Paulie. Wait.
It is okay. Take my hand.
Take my hand.
Yes, you're a good boy.
Not moving. Give me your hand.
It is okay. Not moving.
Come to me. Come on.
Mommy.
Excuse me.
Stop.
What is wrong with you?
- Tell it to the tent to go.
- I do not here with him.
Please, Casey.
Let her not enter.
Favorite.
It's Mommy.
Favorite?
My God.
Come out.
Paulie, baby.
My God, no.
It is good.
It is good. I got it.
Paulie, baby.
Paulie, come on. Look at me.
Papa.
It's good, baby. I do so. Ga in.
They can not see.
What have you done?
Paulie would be in my face
have been.
Mama had to keep him from me.
She had no choice.
Mama.
You have to say.
I do not know.
You guys are monsters.
How could you do that?
You were never a mother figure,
but even then.
You have your baby killed.
Jonah, what should we do now?
Maybe we should go to the police.
Nobody leaves here
my children are.
We can not help them.
They were stabbing you down in the tent.
- You've seen them.
- We must find them.
Get your hands on my body.
Excuse me.
Elaine, you stay here. Wait for the police.
The rest are looking into the children.
- I let Mommy alone.
- You do what I tell you.
It remains away from my family.
Mama.
I am. Mouse.
It was your fault.
They do not want to really.
I think they are sick.
There was vomit in the woods
and Paulie was sick yesterday, huh.
Even if you believe me not, stay
Please away from Leah and Nicky.
I think they are very sick.
They are here.
What have they done with my babies?
Open your eyes.
Jonah, it's Casey.
She was out with Robbie.
It was me.
And then she Lainy Paulie dead.
God. Look, Jonah, blood.
The blood of my children.
She is in my house.
What if they go home? It is there.
We must do something.
You must be the case in hands.
A policeman.
- You have to stay here...
- Your mom is upset.
She is hurt.
She must rest.
Mommy.
And Lisa?
I can call her.
They can come out.
- Search into the phone, lickspittle.
- I look at Mommy.
Whatever you do,
Please do not let them inside.
Mommy.
God, you so cold.
Are you sick?
You need it so cold.
Honey, where is your brother?
Where is it, baby?
Where is he?
My God, I love you.
- Mommy.
- My beautiful boy.
Mommy is here.
I leave you with nothing done.
Do not.
Get up. Open the door.
Come on.
Ga out.
Miranda, ga out.
Papa.
If its something you have done,
than you... I swear
Papa.
Let her mom not murder.
What is going on?
- Casey has hurt me.
- Jonah?
Stay here, honey.
You guys are fucking each other while.
Jonah, please.
- Bye, Mommy.
- What?
Be nice to Leah and Nicky.
I do, Dad.
It is okay, Princess.
Everything is fine.
Mama.
Please do not let them inside.
Mama, say something.
- Please tell me something.
- Casey, silent.
Mama.
It is okay, Leah.
It is Lainy.
God.
Stay.
Stay away from me.
Please.
I do not...
Please, Mommy.
Please.
Where is Mommy?
God.
Paulie.
Excuse me, Casey.
Excuse me.
Please.
Stupid idiot.
I am so sorry.
I told you already
that he was a fool.
It is okay. I ga do.
Okay, baby, okay.
- Is it okay?
- I gotta ask.
I go to my mother.