THE RETURNED
Dad!
Oh, no!
Daddy, Daddy!
Daddy?
-Shot.
Mom!
Please!
NO!
Mom!
Please!
NO!
No Mom!
Please!
-Relax, everything will be fine.
-We are here sky.
-You'll be fine.
- Okay buddy?.
-Quiet honey.
-Sure you will be fine, you'll see.
Wait, wait,
only nurse!
Only the nurse, sorry
but will have to wait here.
- Are you the mother?
-Si.
He'll be fine.
No, no, wait, we go with him.
- Mom?
Mom!
- What?
-Estate calm, calm down.
- What you got there?
-Look...
- Oh my God!
-Could dive right there.
'It's a huge house.
-'s Beautiful.
'Yes, and very expensive.
-Romantic...
-yet is so expensive...
-I know, I am the worst.
Remember, Jacob and Amber
come to dinner tomorrow.
Yes, I had not forgotten.
- Do you really want to tell?
'Yes.
This time looks seriously
and I'm sick to hide it.
's My best friend.
- Is that okay?
-You dedices.
Good morning .
- Did you cut your hair?
Yes, my wife, as always.
Good morning.
Thanks.
UNIT RETURNED
-Hey, how's it going?
'Hello Doctor.
-Hi.
- How are you?
Watch Me.
- So, is everything okay?
Yes, all right.
Hello, sir, you better see this morning.
'Yes, I slept well.
-Hey, how are you Paul?
-I'm fine.
'Well, I think he's going down, I think
is over fifty.
'Very well.
Good morning.
-I have a secret for you.
- What?
'I leave here.
- Really?
-'ve Come to get you.
- Yes!
- Are you happy?
I'm sad....
I'll miss you.
And you to me?
-Sure.
'Okay, is good.
Yes.
-Just have to be careful with blood,
if you are injured or damaged in some way, be sure to wear gloves
.
- Do we need to take any other precautions
special?
-
Same as with any other child his age.
- The same?
Ha injected with it every day of his life,
and if it does you can...
-must.
When they brought here last week,
would have been relieved with this result.
-Being a "Returned" is a privilege, not a curse
.
-Do not patronize me.
-I just try to help.
-Well, you can not help,
Okay?, Because you have no fucking idea what is
love someone with this.
- Is it true what they say doctor?
What almost no protein reserves
and can not make more?
'That's a ridiculous rumor.
His son was saved,
go home and enjoy it,
do not worry about this.
Thank you.
'Very well.
-Mark.
Come
-No, it's too hard for me, sir.
Is very complicated.
-I can do it, have faith, come here.
- No, seriously,
Look like one of the returnees,
every time I try my hands tremble
'Okay, well then over here, come.
-No, I just wanted...
- Out!
'Okay.
'Well, well, remember your pentatonic and
...
... good night to all,
pummeling.
"DEATH TO RETURNING"
Good night.
'Hello Kate.
-Hi.
-You know, I will not give you an increase by
you leave late Friday.
-Oh, I know.
-Johan says the boy's parents are very concerned
.
-Ya, is evident.
- You tell them not to worry?
- What else can I say?
-Ya.
'Well, take care Kate.
When did you eat something  last?
See us.
-Good weekend.
- How's it going out there?
-Another day, same shit.
Jesus...
-Forgiveness.
Thank you.
'Hello.
'Here .
Thanks, good weekend.
-Also, take care.
-The situation is complicated by the minute.
Previously demonstrations against returnees
be used in rehabilitation centers
now are being
direct attacks throughout the city.
The last one occurred in the
Castle Prank,
where the full light of day, a
returned was assaulted by two masked men.
No
is the first time that such incidents happen but...
-Oh my God, here
smells wonderful!
-I hope he's just as good.
-I have five more.
-Well.
-You smell good.
Can you guardarmelos?
They'll be here soon.
- What time come?
-In about ten minutes or so.
My God, it's great, I mean,
are just a couple of reviews so...
'Okay, okay, and we say,
're here all weekend.
'Okay, take care.
- What was that?
-Oh, my God.
- What have won the Pulitzer or what?
-This woman goes
national book tour.
Is what he said, was what we talked...
and have been out a couple of reviews,
- So? Are they good? Nena...-
My God.
-Well, come on toast.
-
Can not do this to us without telling us that's the book.
At least you tell us how many times
get the word "lust" in this,
Because we have done  bets.
-Yeah, very funny.
-Have bet money, come on.
'Actually, it's the story of a guy who finds
inconceivable death.
-'s Crazy, can not believe
that will happen,
and is sure that there must be some kind of exception
for him.
-Do not die.
-If, and when the time comes somehow escape
,
something happen and save.
-That is wishful thinking.
-I know.
Until one day, a routine checkup
,
you discover a tumor.
No doctor gives you more
than four months.
- Shit!
The guy is taking it personally, as if fate
insulted him.
So decide which will be making noise,
Murdering one person every day.
- It's amazing, right?
-It's sadistic.
'Okay, but why, why...
?
-Think contacting
indirectly with death deliberately
then be able to understand.
- And get get somewhere?
'Of course not, just like all buried.
Without actually understand.
'That's why I love my wife, I used to write romance novels
,
but it is actually the most dramatic
person on the face of the earth.
Congratulations darling, I love you.
-And I love you.
-'s An interesting story,
a little sadistic for my taste.
But somehow fits the
why I invited them for dinner tonight.
- Is there something wrong?
-Quiet  not I have a tumor.
'Well, thank God.
That his story becomes reality is the nightmare of any author.
Well, that depends on the story right?
- What is it?
-Walking down the street one day,
and that's when I saw her.
I never thought I would find that guitar, but it was there.
Was totamente sure it was my lucky day.
- Hello?
No one was behind the counter,
guess I should leave.
But I did not.
- Hello?
I saw the man.
Shit!
Hey, hey!
Dude, come on!
I thought I was under attack,
so I went down to try to help,
Grabbed my wallet and put it in your mouth for
not bitten tongue and...
I just brushed your teeth.
Just a scratch,
but sometimes the little things can grow
.
-Emergency, how I can help?
... Yes .. I do not know,
I think I could have it.
- What are the symptoms sir?
-Cold sweat, palpitations, shortness of breath
.
- Please, can I have your name, sir?
-Alex Green.
The military took me to one of these mobile hospitals
.
I saw bodies in the halls.
A few of them had been shot,
a blank in the head.
I guess I opened my eyes too soon.
few hours spent strapped to that gurney,
not know if you ever come out of that hole
.
- He said he woke up on the way here?
Forget what you have seen.
This tumbaría an elephant tranquilizer,
cause hallucinations in patients.
We have the results,
this shit is not going to kill him.
Do you know? every time
the first dose does not work, it kills me.
So congratulations son,
almost do not tell.
Then I transferred to a civilian hospital.
And that's where I met Kate.
So...
... six years ago,
I returned.
I want you to know because it might be true this time
stocks are completed.
I thought, should know.
Thank you.
-See you next month.
Let's get out of here!
Back here!
- Please do not hurt me!
I want to be normal!
Do not hurt me.
-If a returned no
is injected into a 36-hour period,
the spread of virus in the body becomes irreversible.
These statistics are irrefutable,
not a single case to prove the contrary.
And we all know the consequences that entails.
Well, do not have official figures
compared to the first outbreak.
But most of us have experienced at least one case
firsthand.
However, we believe that there were more
hundred million deaths worldwide.
The outbreak can not be compared with any other tragedy
known in modern history
Trauma  That is what pushed us
to start looking for a solution.
And ten years later, protein return
,
was the big prize which
humanity was rewarded.
And so, after the inevitable
second outbreak
we were able to save so many people.
A returnee is someone who has had the great misfortune
contracting the virus,
yet the vast fortune
has been treated in the early hours.
As everyone knows, the virus persists
.
We can not cure it.
Yet.
But now at least we can control if we arrived on time.
Return protein is like a barrier,
as a retaining wall.
Incuvado  The virus is still there, but the daily dose
keeps it at a safe distance.
The problem of lack of natural protein
,
end with the creation of a synthetic alternative.
This will
infected guaranteed lifelong treatment.
A cut in funding private
be a disaster, believe me.
For returnees, of course, but for what
society as a whole.
'Yes, but there are two things that omitted mention
.
'Please ilústrenos,
here everyone is free to express.
-Very friendly.
's People,
are time bombs.
Until we find the synthetic protein,
are a threat.
If a dose is skipped, one!,
No turning back.
-Precisely why we need to continue investigating.
And this is a very expensive treatment,
who keep all their lives.
'Yes, do not deny it, but
face another epidemic like 20 years ago...
-There are alternatives.
-... Would be much more expensive for everyone.
'Please share them with us.
He could make them live in special camps
,
outside cities,
away from children.
-O can remove them.
-I never said that.
'But you think.
For that matter, because
rid of smokers, diabetics,
and obese as we are.
I mean  besides
cost us a lot of money, it is also unpleasant view.
Well, that was... different.
- Too rude?
-No, no, no, you've just called
fat idiot.
-Was an idiot, which turned out to be fat,
and now seem to have
prejudice against fat people.
'Yes, among other things.
- Think you bring money?
- Who? Is the fat idiot? No.
Fuck you, everyone else bring something
because you were sensational, okay?.
-Correct me if I'm wrong but the
natural protein can be extracted only
spinal fluid of infected
those who have died.
Fortunately there are fewer returnees
But that also means there is less
sources from which to extract the protein.
Exactly,
-This is a vicious circle,
so unless returned reserves equals less protein.
This has led to restrictions enforced
in access to treatment,
the consequences of these restrictions,
is what worries the authorities,
especially after the tension of recent weeks.
Sixty-Put me please.
My father is in, it charges you.
-Sixty.
Yes, it is.
RETURNED
Thank you.
'All right, nice people, nice music
.
I have night shift, there
dinner in the oven. I love you.
-Damn, just spent half the night,
I am not able to get used to the shift.
'I is not much, are the three,
your turn is almost over.
Then I see.
-Are perfect.
I mean, I think Tristan and Josh
can go home early.
'I hope, Josh has been here a long time.
- Where the fuck are you going? put against the wall.
You! there. Come on, come on!
-Quiet and calladitas,
this has nothing to do with you.
'Here, take it.
- Have to have nerves of steel to take care of those
zombies is not it?
What should then
tears and shaking?
-There are zombies,
have been returned.
- What did you say?
Listen here bitch,
because it seems to speak my language.
Are zombies.
Is that clear?
-'re Not.
- Hell, what if they are!
Repeat!
-I'm telling you,
are not zombies.
And I am telling you they are.
Repeat bitch.
Come on, say it.
Okay, I'll get you
a bullet in the head bitch. I say it.
-'re Not.
- Forget them!
We have to get out of here!
-It's your lucky day.
Do not move a fucking muscle is that clear?
- Come out of here!
- Who's in charge?
-I.
God... we...
I've never seen anything like it.
-There's a first time for everything.
Unfortunately.
Let's see who are in the recordings.
-I already said, wearing balaclavas.
-Soon will come the vultures of the press.
There is nothing they like better than a good
piece of fresh meat.
Go home.
'Yes, thank you.
- What is it?
Baby, baby, okay, okay
honey, okay.
-Is multiplatform,
that's what we already know, and they lack leadership
however, many people would want them to be more emphatic
condemning these acts.
-Platform "non-return"
condemns the criminal acts like last night,
we have always done.
'Yes, but never before have we seen
an act of such magnitude.
What you think is the cause of increased
these attacks?
-Fear.
- And fear justifies such barbarism?
-Do not put words in my mouth.
True, the Health Service
controls most of the returnees,
but we also know that there are cracks in the system.
There are a fringe group outside the control
physician as homeless people for example.
-Y protein intolerant.
Yes, like that, exactly.
Do you remember what happened when that returned
stopped taking their daily dose without warning?
In less than 24 hours without treatment that
man attacked five people.
We had to kill them all.
-Psycho, psycho fucking suicidal.
- Do you think a person in a thousand justified...
-Jesus...
'All right, quiet.
'Well, how long a break?
-One month.
- A month?
Kate , I need you,
damn, you're my best doctor.
Please at least tell me you will not let
fundraising conferences okay?
Please.
'No, that will not quit.
Thank God.
- Are they kidding?
The girl clinic
wants to go to her home.
Says that there is safer.
But he lives miles away.
- Do you want to go with you?
-No, I think I better go alone.
-I do not want people to know about you,
and even less now.
'Hello, do you know where I can find the building manager
?
'Yes, climb the stairs apartment No. 4,
says "Administrator" on the door.
- Have you seen anyone enter?
-No.
I mean ,
do not know, I have not fixed.
'Well, please look
next time, just in case.
Okay?
After the attack the other day,
things have gotten much in the hospital.
So I no longer think it's a good site
for two classy women,
like us, do business.
- Is there nothing more?
I mean
money is no problem.
Lame-Ya but realize too
to take inventory.
Only I can catch a few at a time.
We have not received
heading lab this week.
- What?
-
Other hospitals also have received so ..
- How much is you booking?
'As for a month.
- Can you bring me next week
please?
I'll pay whatever.
Please.
'Okay, I can not guarantee it but I'll try
.
Will cost four times more this time.
-I told you money is not a problem.
'Okay, give me a few days.
Thank you.
- Is it for you?
Are you one of the returnees?
The fucking bastards not only killed,
also took records.
- With all patient records?
-Also took hard drives,
in them had addresses, phone numbers.
All you need to fuck them good.
So if you're one of them,
please be careful.
Thank you.
- Hey, buddy!
- What are you doing here?
-Hawkers.
- A coming glasses?
- You like?
'Yes, very sophisticated.
-Go does not want people to think I'm sophisticated
.
Anyway  false.
-Kidding me, have you
you become one of those guys?
'I am one of those.
Want a drink?
Always.
-Let's go to Spendler.
- Al Spendler, whatever?.
- How is Kate?
-More or less.
It has taken some time off work in
after what happened the other day
It's too hard.
But it
is stronger than it looks.
I am a lucky man.
-We both are.
'True, but you're a rich man
lucky.
What is this?
- What is that?
Do not know, you know,
you know  25 years
and told me that the other day
and did not give you a hug, so...
-Was not a shit
I have been able to tell before.
'Okay, I just want you to know...
... for me still the same.
Okay?
Still the same shit that got me
a pellet in the leg, makes a lot of years
-You deserved it.
-I know, but who cares.
Anyway, what I mean is that I do not care
,
I do not care what happened to you,
I do not care what this is,
always be there.
Thank you friend.
- Oh my God!
- Oh God, look!
Said, he must prove not why.
Are you okay?
Do not worry, you're done.
-Get rid of it.
'We should call the police.
We can not, are we okay,
will ask questions, they will pull the thread?.
-Being a returnee is not a fucking crime.
-Yeah, but can now be a problem.
Quit and kicks.
Come on!
"
Maximum interest of press around the upcoming...
... press conference health minister,
where suspected
made an official announcement of the temporary suspension
distribution return protein. "
"No reason to be alarmed
returnees, the suspension is temporary,
and all
State resources are working perfectly.
Our officers are specifically designed facilities,
for this kind of emergency
and ensure that all affected
receive the attention they deserve.
The announcement has shaken the people,
afraid that this situation will lead to a new
uncontrolled outbreak
what the Government has seriously
focus.
Thousands of people have taken to the streets to protest
in all major cities.
The looting and burning of several centers
protein supply by backflow groups
have caused the collapse of several
in the lower areas of the city.
Returnees have also been involved in the riots
,
tension exploded after news
lynching of some
Nearby Freddys Burg.
Seguirdad Forces of the State have been deployed
to disperse the concentrated mass
front of City Hall.
-'m Ready, how you going?
-Ending.
- Where are you going?
-I do not know, but tonight
go to the motel 28.
-No guys, that's ridiculous,
can not do that, they have to come with us.
-Come.
'No thanks brother, but not
, too.
-All will be well.
-Hundred and fourteen.
- You also tell him?
-And whisper them.
Caress And saying nice things.
But not multiply.
-Motherfuckers.
-Do not look like much, but it does its function
.
-It should not be legal.
-Treat is a sticky, sweet and greasy
, will, eat it.
-I have news.
-
Returnees Seven dead in St. John Hospital,
and twelve in the Central.
Attacked two places at once
around two in the morning.
-Awesome.
What did the police say?
-The shit.
That can not ensure that groups have been
backstop, but not good.
And that's not the worst of it.
They say it's only until the synthetic protein function
.
-No
let you go to one of those sites.
-Han given three days to spare.
-Plan to publish lists, Kate.
Any returned not delivered to a monitoring center will be arrested.
- Observation center?
So you're kidding Jacob?
Sound like them.
Look at that!
-Try to convince Alex.
Come to the house with us.
Is a safe place,
go talk to him, let him come.
Go talk to him, pick up his stuff and let's get out of here
once.
'm Your agent!
'm Your fucking agent!
Okay, you know what?
Now you're talking, talking, blah blah blah
not understand a word
what you're saying.
-Need more conflict.
-Okay, more conflict, more conflict
Here, okay?
Should not feel that way now, but
is forced feelings,
and I am forced to do this,
you get up the ass!
'Brother, I love when you are angry.
- Oh yeah?
-Si.
Alex is lucky to have you.
- Why do you say that?
-'m A writer,
I notice things in people.
- What do you notice?
-Do not leave to pity himself.
Do not treat me like a sick or an invalid.
'Because it is not.
-This is a little creepy.
- Have you inectado today?
-I want to eat your brains.
'Okay, start with your wife.
I do not want to eat hers.
-It's too brain.
"Military use force on citizens
"
Van-home people.
'I have done before.
'No, not this way.
-No taking people by force and against her will
as the gestapo bitch.
Therefore  I love Kate.
So I want to have her.
-You can not even shoot.
'Any idiot can fire a gun,
aim and pull the trigger.
-Let's not exaggerate.
Here we are safe.
No, we're not.
Are very close to the city.
And...
... is too risky for Jacob and Amber.
'But we are not gunmen,
for the love of God.
-Before we were not,
but I have no idea what we are now.
Everything has changed.
Got a better idea?
What to do?
- I do not know, whatever,
not want a gun in the house!
-Come on, we'll call the elevator, hurry.
Jesus!
-'m Detective Call,
this is Detective Anderson.
We're here to see Alex Green.
-Solo will be five minutes.
'Well, is not.
What the hell is this,
presented here unannounced,
With a warrant, and I teach my floor
. I'm late.
-Only orders we fulfill lady.
-This home is listed, the sooner we start before
ended.
'I went three weeks ago.
- It was three weeks ago?
-Or four.
The eleventh day.
- For some reason in particular?
'Not that I know of.
'You are men,
certainly know better than me
what goes through the head of a man
before leaving a woman.
-Need to see the rest of the apartment.
- This is really annoying!
The sound studio.
The -room.
- Do you have any idea where
have gone?
- I shot him in the head!
I shot him in the fucking head!
Oh my God!
He finished dosages.
- Why not take him
Observation Center?
I did not want to go.
- Why did not compel him?
-Because actually was right in not wanting to.
She had been monitored and controlled.
My God,
would let him die.
You know that those sites are.
Would have died surrounded by strangers.
Have I gotten into a mess, is not it?
Well, in theory yes.
- And in practice?
Our job is
-mark X on a list.
If what you are saying is true,
our work is done and we will remove
frankly a load off.
Need to see the body.
-Okay, but,
After it's over?
Will not there be questions?
-No questions asked.
-Right.
- Hello!
Hello?
'Okay.
Well, this thing very quickly decomposes
bodies.
What I can say is:
What is a male,
thirtysomething,
with a single shot to the head.
'All right, do not need to pick it out, call the
Rescue Unit.
We have enough on our own.
My companion take home.
Thank you.
-If it makes you feel better, I think
did the right thing.
In a few hours they will announce that no synthetic protein
when thought.
Not seem to work the way
when they said it would.
Things are complicated.
Thank you.
- You all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
-Kate spoke to Eve.
She is the woman who has been helping with
protein supply.
We have got sixty doses so...
- How?
'So we'll go
the morning to pick them up.
And then we'll go far away from here as possible.
- Sixty dose?
Well, that gives them some time.
-Si.
-If they do
by us is not necessary.
Did you know  true?
-Know.
They say that will fix
Alex within days.
O well, you know,
weeks at most, you will make that work.
'd Better get going.
's Too dangerous.
-
But thanks for all you've done.
The negative results of recent tests
made us delay our expectations
The synthetic protein has not been synthesized yet.
However
government laboratories continue to struggle to find a solution
Our hopes are still intact, since
everything can change in the coming weeks.
All sectors of the population should remain calm and
can be sure
we have
control and we will address this.
Thanks , there will be questions.
Good morning.
'Hello.
- Would you like a coffee?
-No thanks.
- Looking for this?
-Si, where was I?
-On the couch.
-You're up early.
'Yes, Amber,
got up early to go to visit his mother and woke me up.
'Well, do not wake Alex.
- It will not go with you?
-No, he thinks so, but it turned out the
alarm.
It is easier if you go alone, you know?
-He will be angry.
-Have a good...
- Kate Guess what?
I think it's admirable how calm you are.
-Y too.
-Bye.
-'m Eve, you know I do.
Hello?
? Eve?
'Hello, baby, tell me.
- Are Jacob and Amber at home?
- Why? What happens?
'Go to your room and check
injectables.
-No, I think they've gone.
- Go check injectables!
'Darling what is going on? Is something wrong?
- Go away dammit!
-Okay, okay, I'm coming.
SORRY
Oh my God.
-You know, what they have done is not unlike
what we have being doing us.
That nurse basically we sold doses
belonging to others.
-I have not killed anyone
to get them.
-Directly no.
I'm sorry, it was stupid, silly
I said, I did not say that.
Nena.
I wish -
corriese time and already out of date.
- Are you sure that you can see?
-I expected at nine.
I said it was important.
Be there.
- Are you going to tell?
'Yes, you may have the solution.
But to find out I'll have to tell the truth.
Okay?
'Okay.
Jacob!
Jacob! Thanks, thanks, thanks!
What the hell is going on?
-
Not have much time so let me talk okay?.
- You do not have much time?
Where the fuck are you?
-You know I can not tell Alex.
- Do not you? Where the fuck are you?
Have my fucking dose.
Alex  stop talking or I'll hang up, do you understand me
?
- Where are you?
- TALKING TO!
'Okay, okay, talking, TALKING!
-Amber is not in the room.
She did not want him to call.
And I promised I would not.
But I had to talk to you.
Had been for me,
never have done this.
But it has been for her.
I know it's a bitch.
- Bitch? Will I be kidding?
I get less than 24 hours,
you know what that means?
-Alex had not choice, it's the greatest shit
I could have done, I know, but I had no choice.
-You had no choice, had it,
Wait! Hear, hear!
I'm sorry, listen.
Give me  only six or seven doses okay?
Do not have to see us,
can leave them somewhere and I gather.
- How I can do that Alex?
Why your life is more valuable than
it, eh?
What makes you so special?
-Jacob, man...
- What?
-I do not even have to see me,
-I can not do it.
-It would pick them up right?
Six or seven doses,
that are six or seven doses of your life.
-Jacob, please man.
- What choice do I have? Tell me.
Dame just a few.
Not yet, not yet...
I have not yet fired from Kate,
I'm not ready, give me some,
is all I need, just a few
.
I can not.
-Jacob  please.
Please, I just need some.
Alex, sorry Alex.
Goodbye.
-I have been dismantled, and
have taken all the military hospitals.
And we have sent to each of us
to a different site.
I am on dialysis, Lucy in the ER,
and Mary is upstairs with the kids.
Is a disaster.
No you will convert.
David says you might want to change the appointment,
because it will take, surgery was complicated
-I'll be back in a minute.
- Will they get that work?
-Yeah, I'm sure.
The last few days have been working on the new antigens
trying to implant them in,
-David, do not tell me rolls, when?
-You should have told Kate.
- What fell in love with a returnee?
-No, you're so involved in all this
.
- I expedientasen Why?
For all cleaning including
bitch could gossip about me?.
What for?
-In order to save this disaster.
Now I can not help Kate.
'Well, I'll have to go to one of those military hospitals
.
-You arrested.
-I need injections.
-There are none.
And so will catch him.
- So what do you suggest I do?
Make it stop me seeing him die?
I'm sorry.
What you suggest I do?
Tell me.
'Come with me.
-Mother,
Fuck!
-There for fifty days
hope that this already long before this all figured out.
'I had no idea.
-
Each hospital decides where teachers save reagents,
most prefer that the government has, prevents them problems.
I have always preferred to stay out of it.
-Cameras have seen us enter.
-Yeah, I know.
I'll think of something.
Anyway I...
... I've been wanting to retire.
Thank you.
- I have them!
- Thank God!
-Fifty.
'Wait, wait, how many?
- I'm fifty dose!
'm Coming home, I will give the
you there in half an hour.
I love you.
-I love you.
Then see you, bye.
- Drop it!
- Oh my god!
Oh no, shit!
Oh God no.
Fuck...
I do not want you to look elsewhere
okay?
... I want you to go.
No, Kate.
-I have to try.
No time to talk.
I can hardly breathe.
-That still does not mean anything right?
-Kate, look at me...
can say goodbye now, because
do not have to go through this Kate.
'I will not leave you alone right?
I'm here.
'Then promise me one thing.
Before things get out of control and accelerate
, you will.
No mom, please!
I can not, please!
No!
I love Mum.
- KATE!
-Kate.
Okay.
-No, no, no...
-Okay, okay, calm.
-I love you so much...
-know.
No, no, no.
Kate!
- Thank God!
Not afraid to reach you all night,
what the hell's wrong with your phone?
-I lost it.
- Shit, I thought you had something happen.
- What is it?
- Do not you hear?
- Heard what?
- Are you serious?
With all the fireworks and the ruckus
mounted half the city?
And yet you have not heard?
-No, what about David?
-Kate works. -No...
-The synthetic protein functions.
- What?
'Yes, it works.
For hours have announced.
Indeed
and are distributed outside the centers.
We got  Kate,
go, look at those fireworks.
People are going crazy.
Kate?
What is it?
Kate!
Come on, Kate,
go, limping.
-There will have time, you'll see
.
-Guess where these boxes are.
- Oh, sorry, sorry!.
-Feel stairs.
'I'm used to.
Thanks.
- Is child?
-'s A boy.
'Congratulations.
Thanks.
-We're almost done.
-Okay.