Sub by: Sang Pangeran
Hey, you're supposed to be asleep. What's
the matter? / The wicked is gonna get me.
The wicked? / She's out there.
She eats children to stay young.
I think the older kid has been
teasing you, sweety. / I broke her window.
Her window?
If you threw a rock at the house, and break
one of her window, the wicked will get you.
So, you and Jenny went out with the older kids?
You were supposed to stay at her house.
It was just for a bit. Her sister had
a car and we drove.
And I didn't know it that far.
I'm sorry, Mommy.
Well, I remembered a story of the wicked
from when I was a little girl.
And I can tell you, we searched and searched
that old house in the woods...
And it was never a witch to be found.
It was just a silly story
to frighten little kids.
Here.
Now, I have to go concentrate on work.
I have a big case tomorrow.
So you, go to sleep.
Mommy, help me!
Mommy!
Mommy! /
Amanda, that's enough.
Amanda?
Amanda!
THE WICKED
MYSTEROUS FIRE BURNS TOWN
Locals Claim Witch Responsible
WHERE ARE THE CHILDREN?
FEARS RAISED OVER DEAD
PRAY FOR THE LOST
2 MORE MISSING!
STAY INDOORS!
TRAGEDY STRIKES AGAIN!
TOWN ON ALERT
AFTER SLAYING
TRAGEDY IN THE WOODS
"WITCH HUNTER" REVEALED
REWARD $200,000
OPEN HEARTH:
IS IT REALLY A WITCHES LAIR?
MISSING HIKERS
WICKED JUST A MYTH?
I wanna thank you all for coming.
I know my dad would really appreciate.
Quite a character, rather than miss him.
Especially his grandson.
You believe or not, I think you all are gonna miss
his magic. I've always been a victim from time to time.
Before he died, he said something that I think
he wanted me to pass on.
"God is the greatest magician of all."
"Family, friend, and the love that bind
some of us most in need. That lasts forever."
"That's not an illusion."
Told you what, man. When I go, I wanna be cremated.
Of course, no way I'm gonna stuck in the box.
What's the diffrence if you dead?
I'm just saying, I don't wanna bugs and shit
crawling over me chewing on my flesh.
Hey, guys.
That's cute. Hey, hello? Guys!
Excuse me.
Hey, Zack. What's going on? /
Well, my grandpa just died.
He was old, wasn't he? / Nice. /
Yeah. Sucks to get old I guess.
But we're still going tomorrow night, right? /
My dad has to work at hospital all night.
And? / I mean he has to babysit
his retarded brother.
Dad's freaked out about that girl
dragged aside from a window..
He thinks there's some child murders
creeping the neighborhood or something.
We go anyway. / Come on man, you know
my little brother. He's a dick in hotel.
If I got caught drinking or anything else,
..dad's not gonna pay for school.
I'll never get outta here.
Thanks for coming. Keep your food then
in kitchen, that'll be great.
How are you doing, kiddo? /
It's delusion, isn't it?
There's no up there. It makes you feel
better when someone died.
I don't know. I mean there's no
fluffy clouds or winged angels.
I think we go somewhere. I think
we go somewhere that not so far away...
...that we still a part of those
who still here.
Come on. Grab something
you can believe in.
You'll be okay.
Yeah..
Abra cadabra, Grandpa.
Oh, did you ever find out who
ratted  you out at the McDowel's party?
Who else? Deputy dickhead Carl.
Yeah. But you know the new girl, Julie? /
Oh yeah. / Yeah, who doesn't?
Dude, Jake was calling, said she
got kicked out of her old school...
..'cause she had sex with
her English teacher.
Oh yeah? I heard she was, uh..
doing coke in the bathroom.
Oh, whatever. Apparently she has noticed
you hot stuff, and she wants to come.
Where's that? / Open Hearth. She needs a big
strong guy like to keep her safe. / Open Hearth?
Really? / Dude, what it is, works it out./
You're not scared, are you?
Yeah, he is.
What the fuck! What are you doing,
shitbrain? / Trimming the hedges, screw you!
Hey, why don't you find your boy friend, then? /
He's not my boyfriend.
She's a dyke, remember? / You know, Tracy,
do you spoke your mind, you'd be speechless.
Give me, give me that. How long you've been, uh..
trimming the hedges? / I didn't hear anything.
Yeah? I'll give you third eye
If I ever found out what you did. Got it?
Come on, man. Let her go, dude.
What is she doing?
So disrecpectful..
** Local Historian Dies at Age 86 **
Leads are not apparent according to police.
What's with the flamethrower?
My grandpa's.
Gave me all his magic stuff.
What's this? /
A witch bottle. / A what?
It's supposed to ward off the witch's spell.
Careful with it. It's fragile.
Do you have any asshole bottles?
Might work on your brother.
Idiot! /
I'm sorry seriously.
Hey, wanna make a fun prank call? /
Fun when we were like what? 10? Grow up!
Look, I was forced to grow out when I was about 6.
So, I'm gonna be a kid for as long as I can, all right?
Any plans tomorrow night? /
My dad's working.
Yeah, so is your brother.
Working something, anyway.
If I say anything I'm dead. /
If you don't you're dead. / Okay. God.
He's going camping with Carter and Tracy
and some girl named Julie. Open Hearth.
Open Hearth? / I heard that girl that was
kidnapped the other night was up there.
She broke a window. /
It's just a myth for suckers.
Your grandpa believe in it. /
He had done a lot of things that weren't real.
"Season of the equinox,
the witch besets her kill."
"One less soul the town to know,
taken against their will."
Let's go up there. Take photos of your brother.
Something we can blackmail him.
He'll never bother you again, I promise.
They have cars, we have bikes. /
We cut through the woods.
I'm not interested. /
Whatever!
Why don't you go ask them if you can hang out? /
Please, a bunch of prissy snobs.
Tell me if they ever make fun of you. /
Thanks, Doctor Freud. (wrong pronunciation)
They think I'm a lesbian, just because I don't
wear prada or get a tit job.
Are you?
I'm not a lesbian, dick!
Sam!
By the way it's "Freud"! (correct pronunciation)
So Jake, you enjoy your last day at the mother nature?
You know you're missing Spring Equinox Festival.
Yeah, but you know me, Bob.
I'm not so good with people.
The town is buzzing about
that missing Drake kid.
Her mother claimed she was taken right
from a window. You know what that means?
You know, if they just tear down that stupid house,
this whole witch legend, will die with it.
Yeah, tell me about it. The police think
the estranged father took her for the weekend.
So listen... right in a couple of hours..
you'll have..
Bob?
Bob!
A piece of shit.
Who's out there?
Are you okay?
You need some help?
Jake?
Jake, are you there?
Yeah, Bob. I'm here. /
You all right, buddy?
I've been out here too long.
Way too long. I'm starting to hear things.
Jake? Jake? You still there?
There's steak for dinner in the freezer.
Listen, I want you both to stay in tonight.
Zack, anymore screw-ups, I'm not gonna pay
for your community college next year.
You with me?
Are we clear?
Dad, for the fourth time, we clear. /
I'll be back at noon tomorrow.
I love you guys. /
I love you too.
Keep the doors locked.
Why don't milk it a little bit more,
you pussy? / At least I care grandpa died.
I care, I just don't use it as
a crutch. / Fuck you!
You're supposed to stay home! /
That little bitch told you, didn't she?
Hey, let me tell you something.
You say anything to anybody,
..and I'll post that picture that I get you
jacking off in the bathroom. All over the internet.
What picture? / Are you not in the bathroom
a couple nights ago, just.. whacking it?
Like you don't do it. /
Yeah, it's better than you do.
Just inbreds like you with no friends.
Pretty worth of it, it's all on Facebook. Okay?
I wish it was you that died! /
Likewise.
Where'd you up to? /
Just coming home frome my shrink.
She said you can be a real asshole sometimes. /
A shrink said that? / Yup.
She's right.
It doesn't matter.
We have plans tonight.
Take your camera. I wanna blackmail
his ass. / Excellent.
My mom's been drunk since this morning.
So she won't even know.
We'll grab some sleeping bags. We camp.
Unless you're scared ./
Scared of what?
Hey, Samantha, how is it going? /
Hey, Carl.
Come here.
Roy Harlan said he saw you swiped a cigarette from
his shop yesterday. / It wasn't me. I don't smoke.
Other kids just got it somehow, right? /
Leave her alone.
Shut your smelly dickhole!
Your mother's a drunk. And nobody knows who
your father is. You know what that means, right?
It means when I finally nail your ass,
..they're gonna ship  you out to a foster home
just as far away from here as they can.
We haven't forgotten about all those
prank phone calls, shitsmirk.
Paybacks are coming.
Trust me.
You consider mouthwash, Carl? I don't know
what smells worse, your breath or your ass.
I'm sorry about your grandpa.
I liked him.
He didn't like you.
I got a picture you're smoking dope while on duty.
That'll got you fired you know.
That's bullshit. /
Isn't.
See you around, fuckers. /
Mahoney! Button up your shirt.
God, he's so weird. /
Let's get outta here.
Damn, nice house.
You thought I was kidding? /
Crazy.
Sweet.
I mean this just.. just like Bruce Wayne mansion. /
For real. Hopefully she shows us the "bat cave".
Really?
Grow up.
She's gorgeous and loaded.
Lucky ass. / Hey, how are you? / Good./
It's good to see you.
Zack, you know Julie, right? /
Uh, we're in trigon.
Are we?
I should tell you.
Hey, what's up? /
Thanks for inviting me.
Yeah, anything, just sure then.
Dude, her eyes are green. All right.
Come on, we gotta sort shit up./ Whatever.
Hey, hey, wanna switch girlfriend? /
I told you. / Come on.
Well, speak of the devil.
So, what's this "Open Hearth" thing anyway? /
Oh, it's the name of the witch's house.
Witch? / Yeah, it's used to be
thruth and dare.
The trick was you had to get close enough
to throw a rock at the house.
If you hit the house without breaking
any windows, then you would safe.
And if you break a window? /
Then the wicked will get you.
It's just bullshit, right?
You know legend has it, that the witch and her cavern
were burnt by with hunter back in the day...
..like, you know, a hundred years ago
or something.
Ladine Lorene. / Yeah, that's right.
Ladine Lorine. She survived.
You wanna know how? /
Yeah.
She eats kids. Yeah, she eats kids.
She tears the limbs off.
One by one. She start with their feet. And then
she rips off their legs. And she rips off their arms.
And she eats every part of the body. And she
eats the little ones, you know, to keep her young.
She eats the older ones to keep her strong.
Then she eats the pretty ones, just like you...
..to keep her beautiful. /
That's ridiculous.
"Season of the equinox the witch.." uh.. /
"Besets her kill." /
Terima kasih. /
"One less soul the town to know"..
.."taken against their will". /
Nice!
It is time. Let's go.
But, why doesn't it feel like a tradition?
I mean, why we're the only ones doing it?
Well, apparently 15 years ago some kid
broke her window, and was never heard from again.
Yeah, except he ran away to Florida or something. /
Dude, that's just what the cops want people to believe.
Okay? What about those kids
who were hiking from long way?
What, 4 years ago? Right?
No one found them.
Yeah, well. They did searched the entire house.
It was abandoned. So.. / That's all part of her magic.
Come on, man. Do you really believe that?
Listen, all I'm saying is, there is a reason
that we should stop doing this.
Whatever. Let's go.
Road trip!
Hey, what are you doing? / Taking a picture. I'm just
gonna put it on Facebook. / Are you retarded?
I'm not supposed to be up here! / Stop it, okay?
Don't post anything. I have a class to show up.
Oh, this is so freaking sad.
She's just like my little sister.
I heard that she ran up with a bunch of kid,
and someone hit the window.
You're freaking me out. / The cops went
to checked it out, it was empty.
Oh, don't listen to him. That house
has freaking awsome mirrors.
Oh my God, the creepiest thing, whenever
we tried to get back, those windows are fixed.
Have you ever done it? /
Oh, yeah. We were 12.
Zack backed out. /
I had excuses!
Holy shit. I forgot that one. Show her your hand.
Come on, don't be embarrassed about. Just show her.
I wanna see it.
Why is that? / Well, my grandpa crashing
the bowling ball trying to do some magic trick.
I became his favorite prop all over the show.
Great grandfather. /
Yeah. Right.
Sammy?
Sammy!
How much further? /
I think it's just ahead of us.
You mean we're lost? /
We're not lost.
We're in the middle of nowhere. /
You scared, aren't you? Come on.
Come on. / You wanna race? /
Come on.
Speeder Point.
Here it is.
What do you think? / There is no
road from here to Open Hearth. So...
Let's hike. It's just a few miles, right? /
You wanna hike tonight?
Yeah, what are you, nervous? / No. I just
got the things in the dark I'd rather do.
Oh, man. Check this out. Wow. /
Beautiful.
I have probation. Probation. /
Are you sure? / Yeah.
I think that's cool. /
What's cool?
I like a guy who doesn't fall for peer pressure.
Just character. Or, you're being a total score.
Come on. /
Try some.
Ladies. /
Don't run away.
So, what's up?  / So, are you
gonna sleep in the same tent?
You're telling secrets already? /
Oh, my God.
Okay, watch.
That was good.
Yeah, my grandpa was great at it. Everybody
was given out silver dires in Christmas.
You still have one. / Yeah.
He was really cool.
Do you really think there is anything
after we die? / It has to be.
You don't? / Biological.
It's like.. everything else.
And when we die... we just..
..just vapor. Energy.
Just like this flame.
And do you think trees are gonna have it? /
Only if they're good.
Otherwise, they're right to the chipper.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were lesbian. /
Shut up.
Have you ever done it? /
Done it, done it?
No. Have you? /
No.
Just the pine cone, all right?
You're scared of everything, aren't you?
Aren't we supposed to be friends? /
So?
I just don't wanna go all the way, for now.
Okay.
For now.
I'm not a lesbian.
You're kidding.
Open Hearth.
Did you hear that? /
Hear what?
That's what I mean. Quiet.
All the bugs.
All right. Let's get this over with.
I wanna go back. /
Oh, someone's scared.
I'm fucking scared shitless.
I don't.. / Just take it. /
I don't want it.
Come on, Tracy. We're all on this together. /
I don't want to.
You did not drive me here for nothing, did you? /
Yes. / Okay, ready? / Count it down. / Okay.
One, two, three!
Oh, shit!
Whose rock is that? /
We'll know soon enough.
There's nothing to worry about.
What? What the fuck! /
Guys! Guys!
Guys, it was just the shadow of a tree.
Yes, it was. / Dude, I was pissed my pants.
Jesus! Can we just go? / I think we probably
should. I think you're the one who broke the window.
Damn it, you're a dick, Carter!
We got a LOL. Ready? /
Yeah.
Okay. Here we go.
We're getting closer. /
Why do you say that?
Do you think anyone actually died there?  /
That's witch's stake. They burned her there.
Oh my God. They're gonna hear us.
Good.
Well, it must've been hard moving so far
before graduation. / Yeah, that is a thought.
Well, you could improve those here.
So, hey. Why did you get kicked out of school?
And you don't have to answer that.
So you heard all those rumors. /
Some of them, yes.
You wanna know what my big secret is?
Because nobody knowing out what happened.
But you have to promise to keep it
between us. 'Cause it's kinda embarrassing.
Okay. /
My big secret is...
..that I don't have one.
I would, I just moved. I mean...
the same thing that happened since 8th grade
when my dad got reassigning./ Seriously?
Of course. You didn't sleep
with your English teacher?
And I don't do coke, and then punch
my friend in the face.
I can't even remember the other one. /
Wow, how boring.
It is, isn't it? But, life is cute, isn't it,
'cause you joined the cold status.
Yeaah! Oh God! Oh God!  /
Oh God...
That's my boy.  /
It's fun to have it.
Don't do that. / You're gonna go in.
You're gonna go in. / Oh yeah?
Did you hear that? /
What?
You didn't hear that?
It's just umm...
It's something else.
It's just the wind .
That's not the witch, Zack.
Do you wanna go swimming?
I didn't bring a suite. So...
I mean, unless you really think you melt.
Julie? Julie!
Did I scare you? / Not cool. / I thought
it's pretty funny. / No, it's not.
Of course not, if we die.
It's close, right? /
Not as scary as everyone says.
I think they're here.
You're gonna do it? To hit the window? /
That's the point.
Beside, how cool it be
to see a witch.
You do it.
Crap.
See?
Total gip.
It's just the wind. /
What wind?
We have to leave. /
What's that? Let's go.
Oh, shit. Go, go!
What's wrong? /
I thought I heard something.
Amanda?
Zack! / I'm sorry. /
Look at this.
A teddy bear ? / Yeah. It wasn't here
before./ What are you talking about?
Carter! Tracy! /
What the fuck! / Wake up!
Look at this.
Look.
It's hers, I just found it.
Julie, this could be anybody's. / No, that's personalized
teddy bear. My little sister has the same one.
Pretty funny coincidence, don't you think? /
Where did you find it?
It was found it over there, but it wasn't there
before. / Well, obviously you just didn't see it.
Or maybe someone came through here
with that little girl.
Hey, what are you doing? /
I'm calling the police.
Look, I'm screwed if they came by
figured that we're up here. / Seriously?
That little girl is missing, and
you worried about getting into a trouble?
I had reception area, what the hell. /
Look guys, I don't want rumors going around.
My parents think that I'm staying
at Tanya's. / You guys are unbelievable!
That little girl could be out there somewhere,
so alive. We have to look./ In the middle of the night?
Maybe she's right. / What, really, lover boy?
Or it's just your dick talking?
Fuck you. / Guys, I don't think it's a good idea
to go marching up to the woods.
If you are right, that girl's kidnapper
could be out here.
Fine. Then I go by myself.
We're all go. Right?
Where is she? / I don't know.
Take out your camera.
Why? / To document it,
just in case.
That's a good idea.
You're on? / Yeah, yeah. Hurry up, it's gonna die./
Hi, I'm Max Reese at Open Hearth.
If you find this, burn that house down.
The wicked is real!
I broke a window. Then uh..
something came out of the house.
Hairstrap from the picture.
What was her name again? /
Amanda.
This is creepy.
Can we just go?
Julie! Go get her!
She's your date!
Julie, what are you doing? / It's empty./
No shit. Let's get outta here.
No. That teddy bear didn't just get up there
by itself. Someone kidnapped that girl.
That's what kidnappers do.
Listen you have to call the police.
I don't want to get any trouble.
Let's just get outta here. Come on.
Julie.
Did you hear that? /
No.
Well, it sounded like somebody's crying./
No, it didn't.
This is all a gag, isn't it? /
What?
Carter placed that teddy bear out there.
You guys are just messing with me. Right?
Very funny, Julie. You got me.
Let's go. Come on.
Probably just the pipes. /
Yeah, the pipes.
Julie.
We have to pin it and get down there.
Zack.
Zack, I found it.
You go look, Zack.
You go look. /
Seriously?
No, no. Okay. I'll go.
Just wait here.
Where did they go? /
Maybe they ran inside the house?
Oh, shit.
I think I heard something upstairs. / What? /
There's something in the house up there.
Are you serious? /
Yes.
Carter, look.
Hold this.
Okay. Somebody's down there.
Yes, yeah..
Flashlight. /
Here.
Oh my God! /
It's her.
I'll get her hold up.
Guess it'll be easy.
Good luck.
Okay. All right.
It's okay.
Okay. Get your feet up. No, no, no. It's okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you. Okay?
We'll get you outta here.
You ready to go?
Yeah? You're going to hold on this.
I'll carry you out. Okay? Come on now.
I'm right behind you. She's coming up.
She's almost there.
You got her?  You got her? /
I got her.
Okay.
It's okay.
No, no, no, no, no..
No...
Where are they?
Zack, get us outta here!
They're trying to get out. /
Wait, wait. It might not be them.
But what if it is? /
I'm not going near that goddamn house.
Fine. I am.
Zack! /
I know! I know!
Come on!
Wait! We're running in circles.
We need a plan.
It's her? What about the dude that took her?
He'll get coming after us.
It's not a him.
It's the witch.
What? /
It's not a ghost story, Carter.
Right over there is graveyard
of camping shit, back down that house.
Okay, she was in that cellar
wrapped in some cocoon or something.
It comes from the camp. /
Shit, my car!
Listen. I'll bring him back.
You're gonna stay with her. Keep her safe.
Dude, my car is gone. /
Dude, everything is gone.
You're just gonna leave us here?
Can we go to the truck, please?
There is no truck.
Somebody stole it.
She wants it. The girl. /
Are you believing this shit?
It's real, Carter. We need to keep going.
We need to get outta here.
How are we gonna do that, genius?
It's 10 miles to the nearest town.
What about that Ranger station? I mean,
the one we saw on the way down here.
I mean, they might have phone or something.
That's still 4 miles away. / You wanna wait here
for the witch to get you? Cause she's coming.
Carter, can we just go?
All right. Witch or not, whoever took her,
it is probably pissed off. So yeah, let's get outta here.
Hey, wait a second. / What? /
Well, look!
What is that? /
It's Max's bike.
I mean, he must just followed us up here. /
That little prick took the car!
Without the keys, Carter?
Max! Max! /
Shut up, dude.
What is it?
Look at this.
Look at that. / He's probably a half way home
with shit stain on underwear.
What if he were not?
I'm gonna back to the house and find him.
You could do it on your own. /
I'm not asking you, Carter. Am I?
Zack. You can't go back there.
Would you leave your little sister up here?
Listen, I can't just do that. Just call
the police and get her some help.
Fuck it!
Okay, can we just slow it down? /
Yeah, yeah. You do whatever you want.
You don't have to be such an ass, okay?
She's here. The wicked. /
Wait a minute. What? What did you say?
She's already here. / Who? Who's already
here? What are you talking about?
Shit.
Tracy? /
Julie?
What are you doing, Zack?
Calm, they're not here. Let's go back
and catch up with the others.
She got Max.
Where is he, Sammy? / She hides
him inside. Zack, we've gotta get him...
Listen to me. Hey, when we travel
back here, there's a county road nineteenth.
There's a ranger station about a half../
We've gotta save him.. / Sammy!
There's a phone there.
I need you to call for help.
Listen to me, shitbrain.
I'm gonna get Max. Trust me.
I need you to go.
Go, Sammy.
Go.
I'm coming, Max!
I want my mommy. / It's okay, we...
we have to keep going.
Come on. Come on.
Carl, you've gotta take a look at this. /
No, thanks. I don't feel like to throwing up today.
So the chinese call "The great wall of vagina".
Have you been to China? / That's the size
the point. Just take a look at it.
Is that legal? /
In what country?
You pig. Button up your shirt.
I'd like to "Mao Tse-Tongue" that.
Baker County Sheriff Department? / I, I need help.
All right. My friend.. my friend has been kidnapped.
Listen. There's this woman she's..
She has my friends and she's going to kill them.
Hey, Carl. Carl, this voice sounds
familiar to you?
She dragged him into the basement or something,
I don't know. He's alive. Please. You've gotta help us.
Samantha? Hey, great to hear from you.
Sorry about your problem.
We're gonna head over right now. Yeah, yeah.
We're on our way to.. That's a cop car. All right.
Red roger. Squad's ready to run.
Baker County Sheriff Department? /
Listen, don't hang up.
Listen to me, you little fuck. We don't have time for this.
You do realize, prank 911 phone call is federal offence.
Yes, you damn bitch. Which this time is not a joke. /
Yeah. Well, good bye! / Wait, Mahoney, wait!
You know who this is, right?
I admit to everything.
I'm the one who use to make
all these prank phone calls.
Tell Carl, if he'll come and arrest me.
Tell him, tell him..
I'm gonna post that picture from getting eyed
all over the internet. I swear to God I'll do it.
Hey, you little shit! Kid, listen. This is
all on tape. When you do show your face..
..you're going to juvenile halt.
Do you know what happens to deputy
to get cought doing drugs?
You're not gonna get a job working
security in a graveyard.
Too bad you didn't trace
this call, deputy dickhead.
Get her location. / Yo, Carl, she's fucking with you.
She's fucking with you. Just let it go. Just let it go.
Thank you, Debbie.
Come here. Come on.
Come on.
Zack...
Go!
Come on!
Hallway, let's go!
Hallway, go!
Max, let's go. Let's go!
She won't let us out.
There, upstairs. Come on.
Ready? Come on.
One, two, three.
That's her. / Go, go! /
One, two..
Look at there!
Come out here.
Somewhere outta here. / Who with? / A witch. /
Halloween's up another 5 months.
You don't understand, Carl.
They're going to die!
You don't understand. You have no idea
how badly I wanted to bring you back brute.
You're hurting me! / Just a little bruises
for a little girl who's very bad.
They're at Open Hearth, Carl. I'm serious! /
I'm not gonna like that, though.
And I'm gonna enjoy watching you rot
in juvenile halt.. / Carl, listen!
All those stories about
the wicked, they're all true.
The witch, she.. she's somewhere
out there. She's going to kill them!
You have the right to remain silent!
Find another way! Find another way!
God!
Zack. Zack!
Go, go, go, go!
Go, Max!
You all right in there?
Go, go, go, go!
She's coming, come on!
Zack! Zack!
Anyone there, help!
Come on! Help us!
Come on, what's wrong with you?
They did it. We're okay, Amanda.
What the hell happened down here?
You guys all right?
No! No! No! No! /
Max!
Max, Max. It's me,
Max! It's me. / Zack!
To the tree.
Come on.
We've gotta break her spells. /
How?
I don't know. /
Wait a second.
Grandpa always talked abouth witches and shit, right? /
Yeah./ I mean, I never believed in these, but you did.
Grandpa never said anything to you? /
Nothing ever help.
All right, listen to me. She can't move
in place at once, right?
I don't know, she can do fucking anything.
Listen to me. This is what we're gonna do.
When it's quiet, you follow that road to Speeder Point.
No, we've gotta to stay together. /
We can't stay together, Max. Listen to me.
We stay together, she's going to get us both.
I'm fucking afraid, Zack. / Listen, dont' be.
Grandpa's watching over us, right? Right?
He is, Max. And you should
believe that, Max.
That's all. Remember when
it gets quiet. Just go.
You can do this. You can do this,
we're almost home. We're almost home.
Zack! / Come on,
you stupid bitch! Come here!
Turn around, you dick! / Everything
you say can and will be used against you.
Just take a look, that's all I'm asking.
Just drive up there.
I'm not wasting my time.
So, shut your fucking mouth.
Unit 221, Base, over.  /
This is Carl, what is it?
You're not gonna believe this.
Julie Ramm found Amanda Drake, alive.
And on top of that, we got a dead ranger near Speeder
Point. He was found with his throat ripped open.
What am I gonna do, Carl?
Mahoney, I'll get it back to you.
I swear to God, it's not a joke, Carl. Please..
Mahoney, meet me at the Open Hearth.
Yo, Carl. What the hell is going on here? /
Stay here. Watch the truck.
Baker County Sheriff Department.
Anyone here?
Base, 221.
Investigating Open Hearth property about
a half miles south of Speeder Point. Stand by.
Stand forth, 221.
What is going on here? Why are we out here?
It is late and I wanna go home.
Mahoney.
Please, look.
Oh, fuck!
Carl, get your ass up here.
Mahoney?
Carl.
Dispatch 221. There is nothing here. /
Copy that.
That kid got me again.
Carl?
Max! Max, please. Get up. Get up.
Please... / I can't...
She poisoned me.
You have to. Come on.
Shit. Mahoney?
Mahoney?
Base, 221. Officer down.
Please respond immediately...
Come on, Max!
Just leave me. /
No way.
Zack!
Come on. Come on.
She's in the hallway.
We're never gonna get pass her.
Witch bottles? /
What?
Like the one grandpa gave me.
The only way to ward off the witch's spell.
What do you do with it? /
Put something of yourself in it.
Uh.. hair, nail clipping, blood,
anything. The repelling spell.
Then why would she had it? /
She's using them too.
That's how she stayed safe.
They protect her.
It's gonna be more powerful than hair, right?/ At this
point, I'll take a crap in it, if it worked. Just hurry!
Give me your hand.
It worked! / Come on! /
We've gotta stop her!
Let's go!
It's not working.
Max.. witch's burn.
Max.
Abra cadabra, you ugly bitch!
Zack? / Julie.
It's okay. It's all right.
Have you seen Carter?
And the witch, Zack?
Dad.
Dad...
This is Julie.
You guys absolutely sure
there's someone in that house?
Yeah. We set her on fire.
We trapped her in the cellar.
Well, there's no other bodies
in that house. There's nothing.
That means she got away. /
No, she didn't get away.
I have a 10 mile radius set-up
and block around here.
If there's anybody out there,
she won't get far. Trust me.
House and mirrors.
Even if the festival continued with a good news,
that 7 year old Amanda Drake is recovering..
...and has been upgraded
to fair condition,
..we are hearing that the suspect
has still not been found and remains at large.
The house where it all took place, of course,
has been a piece of local folklore for generations.
Bit local kids insisting the legend is true.
And that Ladine Lorene..
..is in fact, a witch.
And still very much alive.
It seems awhole new generations of children
are being frighten into believing,
..that the wicked is just
outside their window.
Sub by: Sang Pangeran