Hey.
Can I ask you a question?
Okay.
You know that
the distance between here and here
is the same distance
between here and here.
No I didn't know that.
Well now you know.
It's very smooth.
Who is that?
I don't know.
Ahhh.
No!
Ahhh!
Stop.
Hey!
Shh. It's gonna be okay.
Stay back here,
we'll tell you as soon as
we know something.
Guys,
please.
The assailant parked his car
approximately twelve feet behind
this car on the passenger side.
He then walked around to the driver's
side and fired several shots.
Girl got out her door
and started running.
Boy tried to go out the same way.
The assailant walked around the front
of the car, came around,
shot the head
in the head at point blank range.
He then turned,
fired six shots at the girl.
Five shots hit her in the back
in a tight cluster.
Only five? What happened to the sixth?
Or the first?
What?
Or the first.
The first?
Nobody could have hit her like that
if she was running.
There was probably a warning shot
to keep her from running away.
To bulls-eye five shots
in total darkness at that distance.
He was a lucky man
or he was a trained marksman.
You guys know how important
it is to catch this guy?
And catch him fast?
There hasn't been a killing like this
in this area in years.
Those vultures are gonna be all over
us until we put somebody in jail.
This is it son.
I'm putting this whole mess
in your hands.
Clean it up. Okay?
Yes sir.
Hey.
-Hi dad.
-You're not supposed to be here.
I know. I just wanted to...
Get up. Come on. Let's go.
Let's go.
What happened?
Do you know who did it?
Not yet.
Hey inspector. So who did this?
You have any suspects yet?
As you heard Chief Perkins say
earlier this morning,
we are pursuing several leads.
Will you excuse us please?
But inspector, you can't expect
the people of this city to...
Mr. Coverling, exucse us.
-Hi Mr. Perry.
-Hi Bobbie.
It's christmas vacation.
You should be asleep still.
Yes sir.
Go.
You alright?
Are you alright?
Yes.
Get going. Follow her home.
Don't say a word to your mother.
You were not here.
IT'S THE MOST WONDERFUL TIME
OF THE YEAR...
Hello?
Oh hey Jenna I was going to call you.
I wanted to see.
No why?
No, not since.
Oh my god.
No that's awful I...
This was last night?
Okay, bye.
Ahh, oh my god.
Are you okay?
You scared me.
Johnny in bed?
I heard you're in charge, Detective.
Big news travels fast in a small town.
You're dinner is in the oven.
So, does this mean we're going to have
to start locking the door?
Sure.
Coffee?
No? Alright then.
I know this isn't easy for you
and Mrs. Boucher.
I assure you, I wouldn't be asking these
questions if I didn't they could help.
Help? Do you have kids officer?
Yes, Ma'am.
How old?
I have a son and he's twelve.
She was so young.
Mrs. Boucher, help me. Help me help you.
What about the necklace
and the earrings?
Did your daughter wear this sort
of expensive jewelry all the time?
It was her first date.
She was so excited.
Have you ever been
to Lake Helena road... at night?
No.
Why? Have you?
Uh uh.
And that's all of them?
Yep, that's the last one I found.
They came in just to the left
of her vertebrae
but there's not exit wounds.
Probably just ricochetted inside.
As far as I can tell,
he never touched her.
Before or after.
Or the boy for that matter.
Look at that,
almost done Johnny.
It's loking good.
-Honey?
-Yeah?
-Have you seen this?
-What?
This. It's that.
It's everywhere I go.
It's at the market, the post office,
it's all anybody talks about.
People are asking me if I know anything.
People are scared Matt.
They are more scared than you know.
Things like this just don't happen
around here. Okay?
You think this guy came
in from the city.
I was reading in the paper that
they saw a car get...
I don't want to get into it Laura.
Jesus Christ. Please?
It's just that Lake Helena...
Drop it!
This is my problem, okay?
It isn't just your problem.
I'm sorry.
You alright?
Bye Johnny.
No that's what I'm telling you.
I'm at the station now
and they won't talk.
Yeah. No.
No I don't care what Perkins says.
It's not a robbery.
The fact is, they don't know shit.
They don't know anything more this week
than they did last week,
or the week before that.
Or the week before that.
They're not talking because
they don't know anything.
You know,
we use to play bridge
with the Boucher's.
Poor Diane is gonna be crying
her way all the way to Easter,
for god's sake.
Hey, you've got a family
so you understand the concern here.
Okay, tell me what we've got right now.
Tell me straight.
The truth is sir, not a lot.
No weapons, no witnesses,
no prints, no motive.
All you're telling me
is what we don't have.
All right. He must have some kind
of light attached to his weapon...
so he can aim it at her hand free
for target fire.
He's good with weapons,
there's no doubt about it.
He's driving along the outskirts of town
armed with a customized 22 Caliber
loaded with long rifle slugs.
Yeah for raccoon hunting.
He comes across a couple
in a dark remote spot
and attacks with hesitation.
The large number of rounds fired
and the patterns on the victims bodies
indicate he attacked
with intention of killing those kids.
Wait, wait, wait! Hold on there son.
See, I can see where you're going.
Between you and me, it's great,
it's fine
but our official take on this is that
it's a botched robbery and nothing else,
until we have clear evidence
to the contrary.
If it was robbery sir,
why didn't he rob them?
Is that what you want in the headlines?
I have not seen any evidence
on either side.
Sir, the killer did not take
the boy's wallet
and did not take the girl's earrings.
It wasn't robbery.
That is why
I want you to catch this guy.
Yes, sir.
Now's not a good time, kiddo.
-Well, can I just stay?
-Not today.
Not today.
Johnny, come here.
I'm sorry.
Oh, oh man I've got a lot of work to do.
It's all right, I'll just go.
Johnny.
Johnny. I'm gonna catch this guy.
I'm gonna get him, okay? I promise you.
This, Inspector Parish,
is your first day off in months.
You're supposed to be having fun.
Mom? Can I go?
Yeah, you be home by nine though.
-Alright, eleven, thanks.
-Come here, give me a kiss.
Ten, okay?
You be home by ten.
Alright. Love you, bye.
Be safe.
It's gonna be fine.
I know.
I'll be back in a minute.
Johnny, come on.
You get comfortable?
Yes.
So... Why'd you bring me here?
Well, I thought maybe we could talk.
Shit!
Do you know him?
I think it's the cops.
Hello? Police Department.
I want to report a double murder.
If you'll go one mile east
of Erikson Parkway to the public park,
you'll find kids in a red car.
They were shot
with a 9 millimeter Luger.
I also killed those kids last year.
Goodbye.
Call CHP, tell them we need help
with a road block, right now.
Did you see him? Do you know him?
Did you get a look at him?
What did his hair look like,
his clothes?
Short hair, brown I think. Dark clothes.
What about his car, did you see his car?
I think it was a Corvair.
We've gotta move.
I never saw it before.
You're gonna be okay.
Logan, I need you to ride with him.
If he remembers anything,
if he has any information,
any vital information,
contact me immediately.
You're gonna be okay. Try to remember.
Fucker called the station.
When?
Couple minutes ago, Price took the call.
Gary, it's Dale.
You ready to finally give me
an assignment?
No, bigger than that.
There's a god damned psychopath
on the loose in Vallejo.
He shot two more kids. Uh-huh.
No, we missed the morning edition.
It'll be in the afternoon's.
You want the story first?
You've gotta let me do it...
on the morning show.
That's right.
Yep.
Yeah, I'll be there. Alright.
In what appears to be the second
murderous assault on young lovers
in less than a year.
A Vallejo couple
was viciously attacked last night
and I'm saddened to report that one
of them has died.
While this small town has mourns
the death of twenty-two year old Gail...
the miracle survivor, Scott Walter,
recuperates here
at Sonoma County General Hospital.
You thought you were being followed?
Who do you think
was following you, Scott?
Did uh, did her husband know
you two were together?
Anything you can tell us, Scott.
Anything.
She dated a lot of guys.
So do you think, Scott,
that it might have been one
of her boyfriends?
She was acting strange just before.
Sort of felt like we were being watched.
Scott, is there anything else you can
tell us about his physical appearance?
He had the light in our eyes.
I thought it was a cop.
Say that again.
I'm afraid you gentlemen
are going to need to leave now.
He needs to rest.
Scott, listen.
If anything comes to mind,
you contact us.
Please.
Even at this moment,
Scott Walton may be providing police
with vital information
about the appearance of the deranged
killer who attacked him and Gail Lewis
at the Himut Valley golf course
on the fourth of July.
Perhaps an artists drawing
will finally help the police
make some progress in capturing
this elusive madman.
In his taunting phone
call to the police
the killer boasted of a double murder
but in fact he failed
to kill Scott Walton,
he failed to kill him.
Altitude now twenty-one thousand
feet still looking very good.
Velocity down not
to twelve hundred feet per second.
You're looking great there.
Give us a reading when
the 12-02 programs reading alarm.
Roger we're go on that alarm.
Good radar data.
We're now in the approach stage,
everything looking good.
Man, this bullshit theory about there
being a bloodthirsty killer on the loose
and we don't know this guy is
the same guy that killed the other kid.
So what if he makes a phone call?
What does that prove?
Proves he likes to brag,
the son of a bitch,
doesn't mean he really did it.
I still think it was one
of Gil's boyfriends.
Listen to you tow, boyfriends, husbands,
it could have been anybody.
That guy, he didn't kill out of passion,
he didn't kill out of anger,
he shot them at random
just because they were there.
Wrong place, wrong fucking time.
I think that he might
have had training as an officer.
Oh Matt, that's crazy, we don't,
we don't have any evidence.
Why? A guy pulls up right behind a car
at an angle, driver's side.
That's standard police procedure.
Walks up to the car,
approaches them with a flashlight,
shines them right
in the face so they can't see his.
That's another standard
police procedure,
it's obvious that this guy
is familiar with weapons.
Specifically handguns.
Probably years
of training with handguns.
This shit moves in
and out without leaving a clue,
a fucking clue.
Matt, where are you going with this?
No, no, no,
where are you going with this?
You think we should start looking
for cops in our own department?
All I'm saying,
all I'm fucking saying...
Mare IsIand.
Mare Island.
What if he was from the Naval base?
What the fuck are you two talking about?
It's Mare Island.
They've got a at least
four thousand stationed there.
Have any of us interviewed
any of these guys?
No.
I don't know, somebody who,
somebody who got discharged,
somebody who got into trouble
with the short patrol.
-Think about it!
-He's got a point.
Matt, you've got a point.
Okay, engine stopped,
we copy you down Eagle.
The eagle has landed.
I guess that means they did it.
Come on, it's the moon.
...That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
Dear Editor,
this is the murderer of the two
teenagers last Christmas at Lake Helena
and the girl on the Fourth of July
near the golf course in Vallejo.
To prove I killed them
I shall state some facts
which only I and the police know.
Christmas. One, brand name
of ammo was Super X.
Two, ten shots were fired.
Three, the boy was on his back
with feet to the car.
Four, the girl was on her right side,
feet to the west.
Fourth of July.
One, girl was wearing patterned slacks.
Two, the boy was also shot in the knee.
Brand name of ammo was Western.
Here is part of a cipher,
the other two parts of this cipher
are being mailed to
the editors of the San Francisco
Chronicle and San Francisco Examiner.
I want you to print the cipher
on the front page of your paper.
In the cipher is my identity.
If you do not print the cipher
by the afternoon of the first of August,
I will go on a kill
rampage Friday night.
I will cruise around all weekend
killing alone people in the night,
then move along to kill again
until I am done with a dozen people
over the weekend.
Fucking Shit!
Who the hell does this guy think he is?
What'd the lab say?
He used a blue tip pen,
nothing unique about it.
Could probably pick one up
at any drug store in the country.
Same goes for the paper.
Umm, he was probably wearing gloves
when he handled the letter.
Wearing gloves?
Print analysis
won't be back for at least,
what, a couple hours
but it doesn't look good.
Oh, according to the NSA guys,
he's right handed but could
have been writing with his left.
You see the way that
the k's and the t's slant.
Yeah, he's just trying to fool us.
what about all the misspelling?
Tell us anything about his background?
I...I don't know.
You got any word on cipher?
Well, it's a fairly elaborate
cryptogram or code,
similar to those used by military
intelligence in World War Two and Korea.
He wrote them in three parts.
If you put the three parts together,
there's a message but it's gonna
take a lot of time to decipher.
We don't have any time,
it says here he's gonna start
killing people tonight.
Yeah? Perkins here.
What about these symbols?
You recognize any of them?
No, random as far as I can tell.
This is bullshit, that's what...
Did the feds say how long
they thought it would take?
Yeah, they said it'd take about a week.
...Well? Why the hell not?
Twisted fuck.
God damn it! Well, they're gonna run it.
It's gonna hit
the stands tomorrow morning.
A killing rampage!
I mean this town is already
on the verge of panic.
What are these people going to think
when they find out that some guy wants
to kill twelve more of them?
I got an idea.
Your hair looks nice.
Hey why don't you relax,
move a little closer.
Maybe put your head on my shoulder.
What?
Here we go, here we go.
Freeze! Get your hands up!
Aww! What are you doing?
Do you guys know
what's going on right now?
Do you have any idea
Get outta here!
-I didn't touch her.
-Shut up!
Get outta here!
Be a gentleman and you take her home
right now and you stay home.
Get sticky at home, go!
We have no comment at this time!
Why do you think he hates
the police so much?
What about the cryptogram,
have you figured that out yet?
No! No we have not and as soon as we do,
we will get to you guys, okay?
Detective, come on, you've gotta
give us a comment about something.
Dale, give me a break! What?
Can I help you?
Yes, ma'am.
Uhh, could I have a word with you?
Sure I guess.
She always had a lot of boyfriends but,
but none of them are serious...
And Gail's husband, Randall,
he was okay with this?
Sure, it wasn't a big deal, alright?
She usually brought
the guys home to meet Randall.
She didn't want to hide anything
from anyone.
I know we've asked you this before Patsy,
but, can you think of anyone
that might have wanted to hurt Gail.
No, Gail would have told me.
Did she ever date anyone
from Mare Island?
No, sailor boys aren't her type.
There was this one guy, Sammy,
I think he worked at Mare Island
for a little while.
He had a couple of screws loose
so she finally told him to get lost.
That was months ago.
You got a last name?
Caruso I think or Carasko.
He was a mechanic, he um,
drove an old blue pickup.
Patsy,
did he look anything like that?
I don't know, I never met him.
Well, the special attention he's given
to the female victims
shows a pattern of sorts indicating
some sort of sexual disfunction.
He's obviously intimidated by the male
victime as he attacks them first,
facing and conquering
the immediate threat.
Why teenagers?
Well not just teenage victims,
but victims engaging in
intimate situations of
a potentially sexual nature.
Again, he's attacking what
I see as his own fears.
Most likely a victim himself.
Childhood abuse or trauma.
I suppose his anger towards women stems
from his relationship with his mother.
So uh, why the letters
and the phone calls?
This is a very disturbed individual.
I believe he wants to be caught.
He wants help and until he gets it,
his violent tendencies
will only become stronger.
Say you will hunt with me. Hunt men?
Say you will hunt with me!
No!
What do you think I am?
Thank you for coming.
After extensive study
by expert criminal investigators,
we have concluded that the author
of the letter and cryptogram
may not be the killer
that we are seeking.
If he really did kill Mary Boucher,
Michael Newman,
and Gale Lewinson
then he must provide
the police with more definite proof.
That's your new strategy
to become pen pals with the killer?
That's it.
This is the Zodiac speaking.
In answer to your asking
for more details about the good times
I have had in Vallejo,
I shall be very happy
to supply even more material.
By the way, have the police been having
a good time with the code?
If not, tell them to cheer up;
when they do crack it they will have me.
On the Fourth of July,
I did not open my car door.
The windows was rolled down already.
The boy was originally sitting
in the front seat when I began firing.
When I fired the first shot at his head,
he leapt backward at the same time,
thus spoiling my aim.
That's how I shot him in the knee.
The man who told the police my car
was brown was a negro about 40 or 45,
rather shabbily dressed.
I was in this phone booth having some
fun with the cops when he was walking by
Last Christmas, in that episode,
police were wondering as to how I could
shoot my victims in the dark.
What I did was tape a small pencil
flashlight to the barrel of my gun.
If you notice in the center
of the beam of light
if you aim it at a wall or ceiling
you will see a black, dark spot
in the center of the circle of
light about three to six inches across.
Taped to a gun barrel,
the bullet will strike right in the
center of the black dot in the light.
All I had to do was spray them.
Should I leave dad's place?
No.
What are you doing?
What's a aphelion?
Aphelion? Aphelion, it's when the earth,
the moon and the sun
are perfectly aligned. Why?
Well it says here that there was a um...
Aphelion?
Aphelion on July Fourth.
Here look at this.
You know what, honey it's late.
You should go to bed.
No. Give me a kiss.
Good night.
Parish.
Honey,
listen Johnny was going
through some of my old astrology books,
now it just...
I think he may be on to something.
According to this, the first attack was
on the night of the winter solatice
and the second attack was
on the night of...
I don't have time for this right now,
I have, I've gotta get back to work.
We'll talk about it when we get home.
Matt, the guy is obviously calling
himself the Zodiac for a reason.
What reason would that be, babe?
Listen,
I just have a feeling about this.
Laura, there is no god damned
astrological pattern to this guy, okay?
He's just trying to scare people,
that's all.
Well, it's working.
We'll talk about this when I get home.
Okay?
Fine, by the way, happy birthday.
What's the PD doing up this way?
Name's Parish.
Gray.
I'm looking for Sammy Karzoso,
he works here, doesn't he?
Not anymore,
he quit about two weeks ago
and I haven't seen him since.
Could you give me
a physical description on him?
Yeah, um...
Height?
Five-nine maybe, good sized belly,
brownish hair.
Did he look like that?
Yeah, something like that.
Hair might be a wee bit longer now.
Do you think you could give me anything
he might have written on?
A job application?
Sure, step into my office.
Always knew there was something wrong
with that SOB.
That's a nice Corvair, who's is it?
That little darling's mine,
you interested?
No, thank you.
Yeah, here it is.
Was he working July fourth?
I'm not sure, I went fishing that week.
You mind if I keep this?
Nah, go ahead. I hope you catch him.
He took some
of my tools when he cut out.
Thank you, buddy.
If you hear anything or see anything,
give me a call, okay?
You bet.
Great stuff isn't it? The Zodiac?
The Zodiac. The Zodiac. Ahem.
The Zodiac.
Much better than the cipher slayer.
It's got that like creepy magic feel.
Excuse me.
People can't get enough of it.
We're ready whenever you
are Mr. Coverling.
Alright, this is what I'd like.
I want a wide shot with as much
of the building as possible.
Get as much of me as you can, you know.
Get the uh, get the whole outfit.
How do I look?
Hey Johnny!
Bye!
Where you going?
Nowhere. What about you?
Nowhere. You want to walk home?
Film star, Sharon Tate,
another woman and three men
were found slain yesterday.
Their bodies scattered
around a Benedict Canyon estate
in what police say resembled
a ritualistic mass murder.
The victims were shot,
stabbed or throttled.
On the front door of the home written
in blood was one word.
Oh my god.
Isn't it weird,
seeing your dad's picture
in the paper all the time?
Yeah, I guess.
Well, The Zodiac's reading
those papers too.
He can probably find out
where you guys live.
I never saw him much.
He mostly kept to himself.
Come out to get his mail,
but that's about it.
It's right here.
I've got the forwarding
address downstairs.
I think it's somewhere on Sonoma street.
He has no reason to hide.
He can just go wherever he wants,
no one will notice.
He's not crazy,
nobody seems to get that.
It's like he has this plan
and he's following every detail.
Out of all the places in the world,
why did he come here?
Maybe he didn't come here,
maybe he grew up here.
Hello, this is the police.
No, no, I wasn't after you.
Shit!
Do you want to talk about it?
Landlord said she'd only lived there
a few months
and she'd never heard
of that Karzoso guy either.
It's a dead fucking end.
What the hell was she running for?
Who knows.
Evading a warrant,
possession of narcotics,
drug trafficking among other things.
Sad part about it is the girl's
probably never heard of the Zodiac.
Maybe the feds will find something.
The feds only have what we've given em
and we haven't given em shit!
The guy is a fuckin ghost.
Detective, this is compliments
of the gentleman at the end of the bar.
What?
To my friends in law enforcement.
Matt, let it go.
-Let it go.
-Yeah, yeah.
Jesus, god you scared me.
What's the door locked for?
Have you been drinking?
What's the door locked for, Laura?
What do you think?
He's still out there.
What's that supposed to mean, still?
Still.
Where's Johnny? Johnny?
Suddenly you want to talk to him?
You care?
I don't know, honey.
We're scared, okay?
I see you're scared,
you're scared John...
Are you even listening
to what I'm saying?
You know why you're scared?
You know why you make him scared?
Because you read these fucking papers!
You read all this fucking crap
in the papers,
all this gossip,
all these fucking rumors!
There's a guy out there
who probably knows where we live
and you want me to leave the door open
and wait for him?
Leave the fucking door unlocked!
How can you say that
when you're never here?
You stay put, you stop reading this shit
and nothing is going to happen!
I will take care of this!
How can you say that
when you're never home?
You're never home anymore!
I'm out there doing my job!
No, you're out there
getting fucking drunk!
-Do you fucking understand that?
-Stop it! Stop it!
Do you understand me?
Leave it unlocked!
Fuck!
This is Dale Coverling reporting live.
I'm here in the town of Salinas,
75 miles south of San Francisco outside
the home of two amateur detectives
who broke the code
of the Zodiac's cryptogram,
Fred and Sheila Morris.
They succeeded where the police and
the naval intelligence center failed.
The bizarre content of the Zodiac's
message proves beyond a doubt
that a cold blooded monster
is stocking the foothills of Vallejo.
The decoded message reads, and I quote,
''I like killing people because
it is so much fun,
it is more fun than killing wild game
in the forest.
Man is the most dangerous animal
of all to kill,
something that gives me
the most thrilling experience.
It is even better than getting
your rocks off with a girl.
I will not give you my name
because you will try to slow down
or stop my collection of slaves.
It's so beautifuI here.
Yeah, it wouIdn't be haIf
as beautifuI without you.
I wish you weren't going.
It's gonna be okay.
I mean, we're stiII gonna
see each other, right?
I know.
Hey, we're not aIone.
I don't see anybody.
There was a guy. He's right over there.
You think we shouId move?
I don't know.
Uh uh.
-Oh my god.
-It's cool,
what do you want my wallet
or something?
I don't understand,
what does he want Paul?
I don't know. Oh my god.
I'm sorry.
Shh. It's fine sweetheart,
just do what he says.
Oh god, please! No!
He will do it!...
Please! Please...
Hello, Napa Police Department.
I want to report a murder.
-Sir, where are you...
-No, a double murder.
They are two miles north
of park headquarters.
Okay, sir...
They are in a white
Volkswagen Karmann Ghia.
What part of area did you say? Sir?
Sir? Can you tell me
where you're calling from please?
I'm the one that did it.
Hey, Matt.
Didn't take them long to print it.
I didn't think it would.
Here's some old hospital records
on that Cordoza guy,
thought you'd want to see it.
Any photos?
No, but we found a current address.
2323 Sangragorio.
It's on the far east side of town,
right?
Yeah, it's out past Lake Helena.
What is it?
The profile matches perfectly,
we just need the go ahead.
Where did he get the car?
He had access to a Corvair.
I don't see a photograph.
No, not yet.
How about the handwriting analysis?
We've gotta do this now.
Listen, son,
I want this guy as bad as
you do but we have to play by the rules.
This is the guy, if we stop him now,
the whole thing is over.
Not without a positive ID.
What did he say?
Let's go.
The recent attack by the Zodiac killer
demonstrates that
this deranged murder is also willing
to seek victims outside
the Vallejo area.
Most shocking of all is
the bizarre costume the Zodiac wore
when he attacked
Gina Chambers and Paul Carmichael.
Miraculously, Carmichael survived
the attack
despite receiving seven
vicious knife wounds.
Gina Chambers was not so fortunate.
She was stabbed a total of thirteen
times and died almost immediately.
The police seem helpless to stop
the Zodiac from killing at will.
More on this story after
these commercial announcements.
Did you pack your bags yet?
I'm not going!
We're going, okay?
I don't wanna go.
Johnny, we're leaving.
Johnny?
Hands in the air! Don't move!
Man I didn't do anything!
Sammy Karzoso, you fucking say it!
You fucking say it!
I didn't do anything, I swear!
Yeah, I'm Sammy Karzoso
but I didn't do anything, man.
It's not him, Matt! It's not him!
I swear!
It's not him.
Take it easy.
Matt.
Your free?
Depends, where you going?
Washington and Maple.
In Presidio Heights?
Yes.
It's your lucky day,
I'm heading over there anyway. Climb in.
...You've embarrassed the department,
you've embarrassed yourself,
you've embarrassed your family.
I don't want to see
your fucking face anymore!
Get the hell out of here
and take the fucking files with you!
So here we are.
Go up to those steps.
Alright.
Alright, so you owe me four...
Ahhh, ugh!
Excuse me.
Did you see anybody walking away
from that taxicab?
What?
Have you seen an adult negro male
in the past few minutes?
Uhh, yes. I did.
He went that way.
Thanks, go home.
That way. That way.
This is the Zodiac speaking.
I'm the murderer of the taxi driver
over by Washington
and Maple street last night.
To prove this, here is a blood stained
piece of his shirt.
I'm the same man who did in the people
in the North Bay area.
School children make nice targets.
I think I shall wipe out
a school bus some morning.
Just shoot out the front tire
and pick off the kiddies
as they come bouncing out.
School children make nice targets.
I think I shall wipe out
a school bus some morning.
Just shoot out the front tire
and then pick off the kddies
as they come bouncing out.
That was the word of the Zodiac...
...in a scene that's being played out
in neighborhoods all over the Bay Area,
anxious parents are wondering
whether their children
will be safe from attack by the Zodiac.
In his newest letter which specifically
threatens to target school buses...
I'm waiting for a good movie about me.
Who will play me,
I am now in control of all things.