What's up, fellas?
Where were you?
I stopped by to give you a lift.
Had things to do. How's the party?
Don't know. Just got here.
Well, hell, boys...
...let's drop in.
Oh, shit, yeah.
Tyler!
Come on, Caleb.
It's not like it's gonna kill us...
...yet.
So give me the scoop. Who's here?
The first thing you have to know
is that Aaron Abbot is a prick.
- Treats girls like dirt.
- Okay.
- Who's that?
- The new guy.
He's looking over here.
Don't know much about him,
but I intend to find out.
He's cute.
- Hey, who's that chick with Kate?
- Sarah something.
She transferred in
from a Boston public.
She's kind of hot.
- Yo, Caleb.
- They're here.
- Who are they?
- The Sons of Ipswich.
- Hey, Kate.
- Caleb.
- Hi. You're late.
- I had a thing with the family.
- Who's this?
- My new roommate.
Sarah, this is Pogue Parry,
Tyler Simms...
...Reid...
- Garwin. Reid Garwin.
- Good evening.
You know,
Sarah's my grandmother's name.
- You kind of remind me of her.
- Caleb Danvers.
And you don't bring
my grandmother to mind in any way.
Good. Sarah.
- Hey, Caleb.
- Kira.
How was your summer?
- I'm Kira.
- Sarah.
Oh, right. From the Boston public.
Tell me, how does one go about
getting into Spenser from a public?
- Why don't you give it a rest, Kira?
- Why don't you give it a rest?
- I don't want any trouble, Aaron.
- I'm sure you don't.
You posers make me wanna puke.
- Is that right?
- Hey, let it go.
I think you owe Kira an apology.
Actually, I think
Kira owes Sarah the apology.
You were being kind of bitchy.
Disgusting! You idiot!
Guys, Dylan just called.
He said he saw three cop cars
headed this way on Old Dell Road.
- Hey, let's roll!
- Let's go.
- Let's go, boys.
- Let's go!
- You need a ride?
- No, Sarah drove us out here.
- Will I see you back at the dorms?
- It's getting late. I'm just gonna crash.
Call me in the morning?
- I could use a lift.
- No problem.
- Hey, nice going back there. Caleb.
- Chase.
Thought that guy and I
were about to go at it.
His friend's puking
sure came at an opportune time.
Didn't it, though?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Hop in my truck.
- Good night.
- I got room. Who needs a ride?
Hey, guys, let's go.
We gotta go before the cops come.
Sarah wants you, man.
- That's bullshit.
- Oh, now. Don't be jealous, Reid.
- My car won't start!
- Hop in with us.
- I can't just leave it here!
- I could fix it for you.
- Reid, don't.
- It's not over yet, boys.
Let it go. It's his life, man.
Try it again.
Thank you!
- Gotta bolt. Move over.
- It's my car.
Move over, baby boy. Now!
No sweat.
We gotta pull over.
You wanna stop?
That'll impress Harvard.
All right, what the hell?
Let's lose them.
Cut across Marblehead.
We might as well have some fun.
Lose them!
- Step on it. Go!
- Stupid kids.
All right, guys, you ready?
Come on, Caleb.
It's gonna take all of us.
Hey, they don't know.
Hit the horn. Hit the horn!
- Holy shit, they're going over.
- Harry Potter can kiss my ass!
Stop the car! Stop the car!
Son of a bitch.
We must be the last ones in.
Well, this is us.
- Just a sec.
- Oh, my God!
- Hate those things.
- And they're all over the place here.
Thank you.
See? Chivalry's not dead after all.
No, it just transferred in.
We're gonna go into town
tomorrow for some things.
- Do you need to pick up any stuff?
- Sure.
I'm in 311. Call me.
Okay.
- He's hot, huh?
- Listen to you.
- Thanks for the ride.
- All right. Take it easy.
- I'll see you later, man.
- Call me in the morning.
You're home early.
It's after midnight, Mother.
What are you still doing up?
Thinking about my baby
turning 18 this week.
God. You look so much
like him in this light.
You know, he was a year younger
than you when we met.
Did I ever tell you that?
Yeah. You've told me.
Now, let's get you up to bed.
So handsome.
He was the most beautiful man
I'd ever seen.
I'm so afraid I'll lose you
like I did him.
How many times do I need to tell you
that I'm not him?
That's the same thing
he said about his father.
You know, these powers...
...that you and your friends developed
when you were 13...
...are nothing compared with
what you'll get when you ascend.
They are 1000 times stronger.
Caleb.
They are so seductive.
You'll suddenly think...
...the world is yours for the taking.
And then you really start to use...
...and use...
...aging each time.
Taking bits of your life...
...until there is nothing left.
- I won't.
That's what he said.
I can't lose you both.
I won't survive it this time.
I won't.
So why do you call them
"the Sons of Ipswich"?
What are they? Like, a boy band?
You know what? I like you.
You're funny.
Not like all the other
stuck-up bitches.
No. They're supposedly descendants
of five families...
...that settled the Ipswich Colony
in the 1600s.
Old money.
Caleb and Reid were both
checking you out tonight.
If it were me, I'd go for Caleb.
Why?
He's just one of those
majorly good guys.
Well, how do you mean?
He could stay here
and party with the rest of us...
...but he stays at home
to take care of his mom.
What's wrong with her?
After Caleb's dad died,
she became a bit of an alcoholic.
So is he seeing anyone?
So we are interested.
- So who's the fifth?
- Fifth what?
Well, you said five families.
They say the fifth was killed
during the witch-hunt.
- What?
- Cool, huh?
Or creepy.
Couldn't see nothing but their taillights
in the damn fog.
But I swear to God...
...it sure seemed like
they went right off the damn cliffs.
What you were
probably looking at...
...were the aircraft warning lights
on the Marblehead lighthouse.
Captain, we have a suspect vehicle
with occupant back near the Dells.
Respond and advise.
We tried to wake him,
but he's passed out cold.
Doors are all locked.
Go ahead and call it in.
We're gonna need a tow.
Hey, kid!
Open up!
Give me your flashlight.
Break out the rear window.
Son.
Somebody there?
Hello?
- Oh, my God.
- Didn't mean to scare you.
- Just got back.
Sorry. I'm just a little freaked out.
It felt like someone was watching me
in the showers.
Let's take a look, shall we?
It's okay.
Don't see anyone.
- I'll catch you later, then.
- Yeah, see you.
- What makes you think it was Reid?
- It's always him.
I've never felt it when one of us
used The Power. Have you?
No. I don't know, maybe it's because
you're so close to ascending.
I don't know. Maybe.
I'm telling you, it was strong enough
to wake me out of a dead sleep.
He's only using his powers
to piss you off...
...because he's jealous
you're ascending first, man.
I'm telling you, just... Jesus!
Caleb?
What's going on, Caleb? Pick up.
Caleb, pick up the phone, man.
Caleb, what's going on?
I just saw a darkling.
It was in the form of that dead kid
they found at the Dells.
I saw his picture this morning
in the newspaper.
- But who'd send you a darkling?
- I have no idea.
Something's wrong. I can feel it.
We gotta talk to Reid tonight.
He'll probably be at Nicky's.
- We'll see him then.
- Definitely.
- Here you go, Caleb.
- Thanks.
Hey, Caleb.
- Oh, hey, Kate. What are you up to?
- I'm just stocking up our room.
- Did you hear about the dead kid?
- Yeah, I did.
Did you know him?
No. No, he just transferred in.
Yeah, I heard he lived on
Reid and Tyler's floor.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
You scared me.
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
I'm gonna see if Pogue wants to catch
that new Brad Pitt flick this afternoon.
- Who else wants to go?
- I will.
I gotta run some errands
for my mother.
I already saw it.
- Do you feel like running errands?
- Sure.
I wish I'd brought my camera.
This place is so beautiful.
That's the old Putnam barn.
What's left of it.
This whole place, for miles around,
was the original Ipswich Colony.
- So, what brought you to Spenser?
- A scholarship.
- But why Spenser?
- I want to go to Harvard.
- My father was class of '81.
- That's so cool.
- Kate told me he passed away.
- You and Kate talk about me?
Well, you know, just girl stuff.
It's our family's first colony house.
- Wait. Somebody lives here?
- Just our caretaker, Gorman.
Gorman! It's me! It's okay!
- He doesn't see that well anymore.
- You think?
- Who's with you?
- Just a friend.
- I'll be right back, okay?
- Okay.
Caleb.
- You should be more careful.
- I know, Gorman.
- Is there anything else he needs?
- No.
I'll see you next week, then.
- Okay?
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm okay.
So you wanna shower
or change first?
- For what?
- We're going to Nicky's.
What's Nicky's?
Hey. How are you?
Oh, hey, baby!
You missed a great movie.
Yeah, I had to get my bike fixed.
That's cool. Chase hung out
and kept me company.
I'll just bet he did.
- What's up, man?
- It's all good.
You want something to eat?
I'll just pick at
whatever you're having.
Can I get a burger, fries and a Coke?
- Corner pocket.
- Great shot.
Well, well, well...
- How long you guys been here?
- A bit.
Just been playing Aaron and Bordy,
and... Would you look at that?
- Blue, cotton.
- Pink, lace.
Boys, that girl hasn't worn panties
since she was 12.
Yeah. Thanks, boys.
Keep the change.
Next time.
You guys are real tight, huh?
Families are real close.
We kind of grew up together.
- We're kind of like brothers.
- That must have been nice.
- The best two out of three.
- Okay.
Hey, Chase.
Mind if I get in a game?
Yeah, yeah. Sure.
Reid and Tyler are here.
- Where?
- Pool tables. With Aaron and the boys.
Great. That's trouble.
So Caleb tells me
you guys are swimmers.
Spenser's best. State finals twice.
I swam for Hastings.
I was their freestyle man.
You won't be here.
That's Caleb's swim.
- Okay, what just happened?
- What?
We were sitting here together,
having fun...
...and now we're
watching them have fun.
That's what girls do.
You know boys and their toys.
- Give me a quarter.
- Why?
Just give me a quarter.
I'll show you what girls do.
Thank you.
Gentlemen, it was a pleasure.
What?
- Blow me!
- Let's take it outside. Come on.
Hey, it's Reid and Tyler.
Grab my jacket.
- You guys need help?
- Just stay with the girls.
Get him, Reid!
Let's go. Bring it on, man.
He made the shot, dickhead.
You bet him he couldn't and he did.
We ain't paying you shit,
so if you don't like it...
What's the problem?
He bet me I couldn't
make a combo shot, and I did.
- Everyone just forget about it, okay?
- Hey! Take it someplace else, ladies.
- Now.
- Whatever you say, Nicky.
- What were you thinking?
- We were just playing them.
Yeah, come on, Caleb.
They were suckers for it.
Why don't you quit
being such a pussy?
I'm not finished with you yet.
Reid, stop.
What will it take for you to get it?
It's addictive, you moron!
You've seen what it can do
if you abuse it.
You want that? That's your business.
But if you use in the open, like you
did tonight, you risk exposing us all.
And that I won't let happen.
- My power's greater than yours.
- Not until you ascend.
All right, go for it, tough guy.
- Stop it! This is crazy.
- It's for his own good!
Keep using like you did tonight
and last night...
...you'll be as good as dead.
So I fixed her car. Big deal!
Don't play me, Reid!
I'm talking later and you know it.
The hell I do!
I didn't use later.
It's not right
using on each other, Caleb.
Tell it to Reid.
Reid's lying.
It had to have been him.
How do you know?
Because it wasn't you. Tyler doesn't
have the balls to lie to me.
- Hey.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Let's go.
Yeah, let's get out of here.
Thanks again for a great day.
I had fun.
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
Listen, I'm sorry about Gorman.
He's just not used
to seeing me with anyone.
I think I'll survive.
Fact is, you're the only girl
I've ever taken out there.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- And why is that?
- I'm not sure just yet.
- Good night.
Kate, wake up! Kate, wake up!
Yeah.
I just saw the same darkling you saw
last night. That dead kid at the Dells.
What the hell is it?
I don't know.
It's starting to freak me out.
I'm telling you,
someone's using powers...
...and I mean bigtime.
And I intend to find out who.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Good morning.
Mr. Danvers...
...Provost Higgins requests the
pleasure of your company after class.
We're going to study four American
contemporary writers of fiction.
First is Cormac McCarthy,
then Tim O'Brien...
...Kent Haruf,
and last but not least...
...Stephen King.
- Yeah! Dreamcatcher was the shit!
Thank you, Mr. Garwin, but no.
My choice is The Shining.
This is not the kind of publicity
this institution is interested in.
You wouldn't know anything about it,
would you, Mr. Danvers?
No, sir.
But you would know about a fight
at a local bar last night.
- Sir, if I could...
- And if I'm correct...
...Chase Collins was with you?
Yes, sir.
Chase Collins comes to us
with a brilliant academic record...
...and his family trust has made
a generous endowment...
...to this institution.
I want to make sure he has
a positive experience at Spenser.
- Do I make myself clear?
- Yes, sir.
Good.
I understand you and Chase
have already bonded...
...and I would appreciate it
if you would continue...
...to take him under your wing, make
sure his stay here is a pleasant one.
- And, Caleb.
- Sir?
No more fights.
Yes, sir.
What is that?
Caleb's family history.
Did you know that the witchcraft thing
started here in Ipswich?
Every time I ask Pogue about it,
he just tells me it's all nonsense.
So, what did the provost want?
Someone told him about
the fight at Nicky's.
Feel like elaborating on that?
You got a piece of glass in your face.
Hold on.
- Say my name!
- Grow up, dude.
What are you looking at, fag?
That thing between your legs.
It's like a penis, only smaller.
Hey, let him go, Aaron!
Don't be so sensitive, Aaron.
Size isn't everything.
My man.
Up for some foosball?
I have dinner with Sarah,
but I think I can hang out for a while.
- What about you?
- No, man. I'm cool.
You're being ridiculous!
What is your problem?
- Chase is my problem.
- What, are you jealous?
- I don't want you hanging around him.
- Look, he is just a friend.
Yeah, right. I'm sure he's interested
in just being friends.
This is beyond idiotic.
Thanks for dinner.
- How about Saturday?
- What about Saturday?
- It's the Fall Fest.
- Oh, Fall Fest.
Just wondering if
you wanted to go with me.
And, also,
it happens to be my birthday.
I don't know.
I'd love to go with you.
- I should go.
- Yeah. Yeah, you should.
- No. I mean, back to the dorms.
- Yeah, I know what you mean.
I'm really gonna go.
This is me leaving.
- Good night.
Sleep tight.
I hate him when he's like this.
He's been jealous since the day
we met. It drives me crazy.
You don't hate Pogue.
You guys are perfect for each other.
Maybe not.
Maybe it's time
to check out something new.
And maybe that's what
Pogue's picking up on.
- This is the eighth time he's called.
- So talk to him.
No. Not until he stops
being an idiot.
I'll bet Caleb's not the jealous type.
Go for it!
Come on, man!
Come on, Pogue!
- He really is good.
- He's the best.
I hear you swim a mean freestyle.
- That's what they tell me.
- Let's see what you got.
Let's go!
Push off! Let's go!
You okay, man?
There you are.
Had us going there for a second.
Whacked your head pretty good.
Lucky for you, Chase was there
to get you out...
...before you sucked up the pool.
He also whipped your ass.
It became apparent
that the view of civil liberties...
...needing no special protection
was not widely shared.
Come in. Thank you.
Twelve amendments were suggested,
10 eventually ratified.
Called the what, Ms. Snider?
- The Bill of Rights.
- Right you are.
Arguably, the first being the most
important. Read it for us, Mr. Simms.
Mr. Collins, you're wanted
in the provost's office.
Mr. Simms.
"Congress shall make no law...
...respecting an establishment
of religion...
...or prohibiting
the free exercise thereof...
...or abridging the freedom of speech,
or of the press...
...or the right of the people
peaceably to assemble..."
- Provost Higgins. You wanted to...?
- Chase, come in.
You know one of our students
lost his life...
...a few nights back at the Dells.
Yes, I heard.
- Did you know him?
- No, sir. Why?
His car was returned to his parents.
His mother was kind enough
to send this back to us.
- My student ID. I lost it that night.
- It was in the back seat.
That's odd. I wonder how he got it.
- Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome.
I understand you've become close
with Caleb and his friends.
Yeah. They're great guys, sir.
I agree. You couldn't have
picked a better bunch.
I think so too.
- Am I gonna see you tonight?
- I hope so.
Listen, I have something to do first.
I'll give you a call later, okay?
- I'll be in my room.
- Okay.
What'd she say about Kate?
Why won't she call me back?
She's still pissed at you.
- Why are we doing this?
- I saw the darkling again.
Yeah, but why break into
the admissions office?
Because I wanna know more
about Chase Collins.
Look, I don't even like the guy.
Are you sure you're not
just imagining this?
I'm telling you, his eyes were
as black as night in the pool today.
All right.
Well, how sick is she?
She came in complaining
of chills and a headache.
Within an hour, she had
a 101-degree temperature.
- What could it be?
- The doctor's checking her now.
- We'll call you when we know more.
- It's okay. I'm coming over there.
They died in a car accident.
It says Chase's father
just lost control.
His real name was Pope.
Chase Goodwin Pope.
Born July 14th, 1988.
The Collins adopted him
after his mother died...
...when he was 2 years old.
- When did you say his birthday was?
- July 14th.
That's the same day
his adoptive parents died.
- What year was he born?
- 1988.
They died on his 18th birthday.
Why are you taking her to the hospital
at Gloucester?
Her temperature's jumped to 105...
...and she's showing symptoms
of anaphylactic shock.
- What does that mean?
- It's a severe allergic reaction.
- To what?
- We're not sure.
It's as if she'd been bitten
by hundreds of insects.
Like spiders.
Goodwin Pope. Goodwin Pope.
Goodwin, Goodwin. Goodwin Pope.
Agnes Goodwin Pope.
- That's where I've heard it before.
- What are you talking about?
The Book of Damnation.
They used to call her Goody Pope.
Do you remember her?
I haven't read the Book
since we were kids.
Just call Reid and Tyler.
I told them everything.
About the darkling,
what we found in his file...
It's a list of names...
...who brought charges against
John Putnam and his family...
...during the Salem hunt.
Pope was one of them.
Goody Pope.
Widow of Jacob, mother to Hagen.
So what?
So she claims that John Putnam came
to her as an incubus in her dreams...
...after she was widowed.
The Book also records births
and deaths during the damnation.
Goody Pope's husband, Jacob,
died June fourth, 1692.
Her son, Hagen,
was born April 11th, 1693.
That's 10 months and 24 days later.
If what you're saying is true...
...and Hagen Pope is the bastard son
of John Putnam...
...then the fifth bloodline
in the Covenant didn't end in Salem.
- And Chase is one of us.
- That's crazy.
He can't be.
The night after the party
at the Dells...
...someone was using.
The Power was strong enough
to wake me.
The next night, it happened again.
- I felt it then.
- See? I told you.
I felt it too.
When you said it wasn't you,
were you lying?
No.
- You swear?
- I swear.
Then it was him.
- Hey, could I call you...?
- Caleb, Kate's been attacked.
Wait, wait. What?
They say it's like
she's been bitten by spiders...
...and I had this terrible nightmare
about spiders.
I'm scared, Caleb.
Something weird is happening.
Okay, listen.
I want you to go back to your dorm...
...and wait for me there.
- I'll see you soon, okay?
- Okay.
He's put a spell on Kate.
What are you talking about?
What kind of spell?
Creation.
Spiders.
They're taking her to a hospital
in Gloucester.
Don't do anything
until we know what he wants.
We're talking about Kate!
Come to save Little Miss Muffet,
have we?
Well, you're too late.
A spider came
and sat down beside her...
...and frightened Miss Muffet away.
You hurt Kate, and I'll kill you.
Hurt her?
I only used her to get to you.
It's you that I'm gonna hurt.
And you're just my bait
to get to Caleb.
These are her things.
Why don't you go back to the dorm
and get some sleep?
If I hear anything, I'll call you.
Hey.
What's wrong?
Have you seen Pogue?
No, but I called him
and told him about Kate.
Well, how is she?
Not so good. But they said they'd call
if there are any changes.
Maybe this is him.
Pogue's been in an accident.
Stop right there.
Close the door.
Let's just keep this between
the Sons of Ipswich.
Don't hurt her.
She has nothing to do with this.
Whether she lives or dies
is entirely up to you, my friend.
You can't imagine what it was like
growing up not knowing what this was.
When I finally found my real father,
he filled in all the missing pieces.
But it was too late. I was hooked.
By then, he was
such a bitter old man...
Or I should say,
bitter, old, young man.
- that all he wanted to do
was end the suffering.
Like all our bloodline before us...
...he was more than willing
to break the laws...
...of your sacred little club.
So I got him to give me
his share of The Power.
And he died knowing that his son
was going to get revenge...
...on your Covenant.
You keep her in that spell,
and she'll die.
I know.
What is this all about?
I mean, what do you want?
Want?
I'm Chase Collins.
I have everything
I could possibly want.
It's what I need.
More power.
Tomorrow night, birthday boy...
...at the exact moment
when you ascend...
...be at Putnam Barn...
...where you will
will me your power.
Do that, and I'll let her live.
And Pogue, Kate, Reid and Tyler
and your mom...
...and what's left of the families.
And don't think I won't kill them.
It comes natural to me.
Just ask my adoptive parents.
You killed that kid at the Dells.
Well, he caught me
doing a little magic.
At first, he wasn't sure,
but then, well...
...he just wouldn't leave it alone.
So I caught a ride with him
over to the bonfire.
What are you doing?
Just making sure
I'm making my point.
Do you see my problem here?
I like to use. A lot.
Only...
...no one ever told me about...
...the effects and the damage.
The addiction.
And we both know
what happens, now, don't we?
So...
...the way I see it...
...I add your power
to what I already have.
It won't stop the aging.
Your father obviously found out
the hard way.
My father never had
this kind of power.
It doesn't work like that.
It's the body that wears down,
not the power.
Just think of yourself
as a sacrificial lamb.
Hell...
...you're already their golden boy.
Why not go out a real hero?
So tomorrow night, the barn.
Where it all started.
A birthday party. Just you and me.
It's either you...
...or them...
...brother.
Don't leave her like that. She'll die.
What happened?
- You passed out when I told you...
- What?
- Pogue's been in an accident.
- Is he okay?
Hey, hey, take it easy.
- What?
- Stay away.
He's more powerful...
...than you can imagine.
Hey, don't worry.
Don't worry about that.
We can't stop him.
- How is he?
- He's hurt pretty bad.
- Where's Sarah?
- Waiting room.
I say we all go after Chase.
Right now.
Listen, it may not be that easy.
You guys stay here with Pogue.
Call me if there's a change.
How's Pogue?
He's not good.
What about Kate?
Have you heard anything?
They stabilized her,
but she's still really sick.
Caleb, look me in the eye
and tell me the truth.
The spiders.
I read about them. They're one
of the charges against John Putnam.
They're some kind of spell,
aren't they?
I wanna show you something...
...and then I'll explain everything.
Don't be afraid.
What about your caretaker?
It'll be okay.
- What are you doing?
- It's all right.
- Caleb...
- This is important to me, Gorman.
It's okay.
This is William Danvers III,
my father.
He's 44 years old.
Every generation,
the bloodlines produce only one:
The eldest male.
And you've always had this power?
At 13, you get a taste of it.
It's a test, in a way.
At 18, we ascend,
and our powers fully mature...
...and it's seductive.
And some can handle it,
and others, like my father, couldn't.
Tonight, at 12 minutes past 11,
I'll ascend.
And what if you don't
will him your share?
He's already got his father's.
It makes him very powerful.
And what if someone wills you
their share?
It's against the Covenant laws.
If it weren't, I wouldn't let them.
- Why not?
- When one ascends...
...The Power becomes your life.
That's why it ages you.
Will it away, and you die.
Caleb, you cannot do this alone.
We have to go to the others.
We can't do that.
He'll kill us all, including you.
Pogue was the final warning.
- We have to go to your father.
- No.
I know what you're thinking, Mother,
and you know what'll happen.
But he loves you.
Well, then, he'll die with that secret.
- Where's Sarah?
- Upstairs, changing.
- You should never have involved her.
- You're right.
But I can't change the past...
...and he's using her against me,
all of you...
...and it's going to stop.
I want you to take Sarah
to the dance.
I'll meet you there. I don't think
he'll try anything in the open.
Would you just let us help you?
You know we've got your back.
I know you do.
But please, just once, do what I ask.
You look beautiful, my dear.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Why can't I go with you?
- I won't risk you.
- I'm scared.
Don't be.
- I'll see you soon.
- You better.
I promise.
Be careful. I'll call you.
- Hey, any sign of him?
- No.
Good. Listen, I'm on my way.
If he does show...
...please promise me you won't
do anything stupid.
- How's Sarah doing? Can I talk to her?
- Yeah, she's fine. Hang on.
- She was just here.
- Guys, what's going on?
Caleb? Caleb?
What's your plan?
You can't beat me, you know.
Something's happened.
You know...
...I'm just getting the feeling that...
...you're not gonna keep up
your end of the bargain...
...so I took out
a little insurance policy.
She does look quite stunning.
You touch her, and she dies.
In fact, time's running out for Sarah.
So why don't we
get down to business?
Witchy.
Oops, wait.
Did I just say, "witch"?
All right. Tell you what.
I'll make this easy for you.
How about an accident?
You lose control of your car
on the way to the pathetic little dance.
Trust me. I'm good at car accidents.
Everyone'll miss you.
They'll say great things about you.
Only the Covenant
will know the real truth.
But, to them,
you'll become a legend.
The one who gave his life for them.
How about you let her go,
and I let you live out your life?
How about I make you
my "weyotch"?
I'll never will you my power.
Then it looks like trouble for Sarah.
I'll never let that happen.
Fine. Let's do it your way.
Like taking candy from a baby.
Easy as pie.
- You find her?
- No.
Twelve minutes past 11.
Happy birthday, Caleb.
Are we ascending?
Finally!
Scary, huh, Caleb...
...this new power you get
when you ascend?
Frankly, I don't think
you're cut out for it.
So why don't we just call it a night?
Just say the words.
Okay, I'm a little impressed.
- Not bad.
- Thanks.
Trying to impress your date, huh?
You ready to say uncle?
I'm ready for you to go to hell.
Leave us, Gorman.
Just say the words.
Say the words, and it's all over.
Listen to me, William.
I need you to understand me.
Come on! Say it! Say the words!
"I..."
- I...
- "...will you..."
...will you...
...nothing.
He is your son.
For once in your life,
think of someone other than yourself.
I...
...will...
...you...
...my power.
We searched the entire area.
We didn't find anybody.
How can that be?
Where is he?
I don't know.