Get off the phone!
- Gina... McDonald.
- McVey.
Green Volvo.
Cherokee. Jeep.
Right.
- Who are these for?
- Dr. Waters.
- Interesting.
- What?
Well, do you notice anything?
They're back-to-front?
No, look.
Left and right tags.
The heart's on the
right side of the body?
Dextrocardia with situs inversus.
It's not uncommon, but it's pretty rare.
One in every thousand.
Hello?
- Hey, you.
- Hey.
Sounds loud over there.
You got some happy clients.
No, I'm trying to keep them away
until it looks in better shape.
I'm sure it's going to look great.
Listen, I'd better go before
one of these guys kills himself.
What time are we meeting tonight?
Seven. Don't be late.
I won't.
Bye.
Happy birthday.
Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Scared the crap out of me.
- Happy birthday, Dad.
- Thanks.
Happy birthday.
You didn't have to do this.
Please, you didn't have to do this.
- Should I take my teeth out?
- Yeah!
So, how old are you now, Dad?
Twenty-seven.
You were younger than that.
Well, two weeks, I retire.
You won't know what to do with yourself.
Bob said I should come by
the embassy twice a week
in an advisory capacity.
What is it that you do
at the American Embassy, John?
Pretty much everything
from lost passports to kidnappers.
The American tourists in this country
like to keep us busy.
Dad, tell Stephan the story about
the woman who's having an affair.
Go on. Come on.
I love this one.
All right. We had a case a few years ago
where this couple from America...
The husband came for business
twice a year to London,
and his wife always came with him.
- This is great. You're going to love it.
- Let him tell it.
Okay. So, the husband noticed
this lubricant in his wife's makeup kit.
And even though they weren't having sex,
the lubricant was still getting
lower and lower and lower.
Seemed a little suspicious,
so he started to snoop around,
and he found that his wife
was banging this English guy.
So, the next day, before he goes
to the business meeting,
he empties the lubricant
and he replaces it with superglue.
It took the surgeons
about eight hours to remove her
from the guy she was
having an affair with.
Get together, you two.
Tradition. After that story.
Yay!
You two. You two.
Come here, you.
- Well...
- Come here.
Beautiful.
God, you're so ugly.
Look at your face.
- Great. Thanks.
- You've got paint all over your face.
At least I have an excuse.
Look at the state of your face.
Look.
He's been working hard.
His first ever exhibition is on
in less than two months.
- Exactly.
- You happy with what you've done?
Yeah.
I think you're going to like it, Dad.
To my family.
Thank you for a lovely evening.
Happy birthday, Dad.
- Happy birthday, Dad.
- Thank you.
- Happy birthday.
- Cheers.
Jesus.
Having fun, Stephan?
Oh, yes.
I guess that's seven
years bad luck, then.
I thought it was seven years bad sex.
No, I've already had that.
Oi, I heard that.
Baby, that was before I met you.
Yeah, yeah.
Do you think we can fix it?
- Happy birthday, Dad.
- Thank you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Good to see you again, Stephan.
Yeah. Thank you.
You, too, John.
- Okay. Good night.
- Good night.
You're coming in?
No, I'm going to stay at mine tonight.
I've got some laundry to do.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm just running between yours
and mine and work, and, uh...
a girl's got to have clean underwear.
And I've been thinking.
Maybe you have a drawer
or something at mine.
You know, where you could
keep some stuff.
I don't know, Stephan.
A whole drawer...
It's... It's a big step.
Okay. Now you're just making fun of me.
Finishing the work in your flat
would be a start, though.
I'll have the builders
back in by next month.
I'll come over tomorrow night after work.
You can make dinner.
Oh, really?
Okay. Drive safe.
Bonsoir.
Bonsoir, madame.
Anthony?
- Forget something?
- What?
I just saw you leaving to go home.
Did you forget something?
No, I was here.
That's funny.
I could've sworn I saw you
leaving the building.
No.
Anyway, I'll see you tomorrow.
Hello. This is Stephan.
Leave a message after the beep.
Coming through.
Hi, Gina. My name's Lucy.
I'm one of the doctors here.
You're in hospital and you're safe, okay?
Gina, you all right?
Can you hear me?
Put out a trauma call.
We're just going to take you down
to the resusc room.
What's the story?
This is Gina McVey, 28-year-old female,
involved in an RTA.
Head-on collision.
She was driving.
Belted, airbag deployed.
Conscious at the scene.
On three. One, two, three.
- Glasgow Coma Scale?
- Thirteen.
- And respiratory rate?
- Twenty-five.
Okay, guys. Let's get the oxygen
connected up properly, Marie.
Can you get her on some monitors, Jess?
Her clothes off?
Lucy, can you start to conduct
a primary survey?
- Ziad, can you get two lines in, please?
- I'm just gonna have a listen to your chest.
Breathe normally for me.
- Pupils 4 and reacting.
- Good.
We're just going to do some tests, okay?
We've got to cut your clothes,
unfortunately, okay?
I just need you to stay nice and still.
Check the pelvis for me.
Yes, please, can you get
a liter of warm saline?
Gina, we're just poppin'
a needle into your arm, okay?
On the left side.
Sharp scratch coming up, okay?
Good air entry bilaterally.
- Okay.
- Pulse 120.
Just gonna have a little feel
of your stomach, okay?
Pass the monitor to engage it.
She has got a seatbelt mark, though.
Right. Ziad, you need to go
and get the radiography machine
so that we can do a trauma series
including a chest X-ray.
Just cover you up, Gina,
'cause it's a bit cold in here, okay?
Gina, we're just gonna
take some X-rays now.
We need to get the on-call radiographer,
and then we can logroll
after the pictures have been taken.
She's gonna be fine.
She was pretty dazed
when she first woke up.
Didn't even know her name.
She's a lot less disoriented now.
Her responses are slowly returning,
although she still has no memory
regarding the details of the crash.
She's a very lucky girl.
Telephone call for Dr. Kenric.
- I'll give you a moment alone.
- Thank you.
Hey, sweetheart.
How's my little girl?
I hope it doesn't look
as bad as it feels.
Just a few bruises.
And they'll fade.
It's funny.
The last time I sat
in a hospital room with you
was when you fell off a horse
and broke your arm.
You must have been about 13.
It was just a few months
after your mom died.
You sat there with...
the X-ray of the broken arm,
and announced that you wanted
to be a radiologist.
I left work with Stephan.
Daniel and Kate, they stayed
almost the entire night with you.
You're looking much better.
Apart from a slight concussion,
physically speaking
everything seems to be okay.
A few sprains and bruises,
but they'll soon heal.
We'll have you back
in the X-ray department in no time.
Regarding your memory of the crash...
Gina, I'd like you to meet
with a colleague of mine,
a Dr. Robert Zachman.
He works through the hospital
in a counseling capacity.
- A counselor?
- Yeah.
As I say, physically speaking,
I'm not worried.
It's the psychological scars
of an accident like this
that can cause problems.
Anxiety, panic attacks,
fear of driving, etcetera.
I just think it would be a good idea
to talk to someone about it.
Might help make things clearer for you.
At any rate, I'd like to keep you here
for at least one more day.
Get some rest.
I'll look in on you later.
Hi, Gina.
I'm Robert Zachman.
Dr. Kenric asked me
to stop by and say hello.
Oh, the, uh... the counselor.
Yeah.
I hear you're a lucky girl.
So they keep telling me.
You look all set to leave.
Yeah. Just waiting for my boyfriend.
I see.
Kenric told me that you don't
remember the crash at all.
Not really.
Just, um, fragments.
Well, fragments are good.
I can work with that.
Hey.
Hi. I'm Dr. Zachman.
Stephan Martin.
Tell you what. Here's my card.
Why don't you give me a call
when you feel up to it?
We can have a chat
about those fragments.
- Okay.
Nice to meet you.
How are you feeling?
Better.
What happened there?
I broke the mirror.
Well, I think I'll walk the dog.
What's wrong with him?
He can shit in his bed, for all I care.
Stephan?
What are you doing?
Jesus, you scared me.
I think you've got a leak.
I'll fix it tomorrow.
Shit.
So... how are those fragments doing?
Still fuzzy.
Well, fuzzy's not too bad.
Means you know it's there,
you just need to make it clear.
You still don't remember
anything from the accident?
No.
How are you sleeping?
Great, but I think maybe
it's the medication.
Your relationship. Steve, is it?
- Stephan.
Sorry about that.
What does he do?
He's an architect.
And you live together?
What are you holding back, Gina?
Tell me what's wrong.
I don't think Stephan is my boyfriend.
Well, we all have different relationships
until we find the one.
No, he looks like him, but he's not him.
Right. When did you
first notice this change?
After the accident?
Do you think, then,
that maybe he really is Stephan
and that you're just still confused
about the events surrounding the crash?
- Dr. Zachman...
- Robert, please.
Robert.
The man in the apartment
is not my boyfriend.
I'll just change that. Sorry.
Gina, have you ever heard
about Capgras Syndrome?
It's a rare disorder, in which a person
holds a belief that an acquaintance,
usually a close family
member or a spouse,
has been replaced
by an identical-looking imposter.
The condition in most cases
is a direct result of brain lesion.
With your permission, I would like
to readmit you to hospital
and get Dr. Kenric to
do some further tests.
Gina, it's difficult to determine
if what you're feeling
is a result of the bruising
found in the CT scan.
Capgras Syndrome is rare.
A hundred confirmed cases since 1923.
Eighty of those in the last 10 years.
The area of bruising is consistent
with those suffering from the disorder,
but it's hard to diagnose,
mainly because its symptoms
are so closely associated
with mental illness.
Your limited memory of the accident
is also a factor.
What do you think?
We need to run some more tests.
I don't want any more tests. Sorry.
Gina? Gina, I know how you must feel.
- Do you?
- Yeah.
I have photographs
I don't remember being taken.
All I have is my feet slamming
on the brakes of my car, and here I am.
Well, you sustained
a sizable knock to your head.
And what tends to happen
is that the brain will shut down
large chunks of memory.
But gradually, these chunks
of memory will come back
when your brain feels able to cope.
How does that explain
how I feel about Stephan?
Well, Dr. Myers thinks
that your fears towards Stephan
and your loss of memory are linked.
And that fear will go
when you get your memory back.
It's like losing your car keys.
You have to go back
to the last thing you remember.
You remember hitting the brakes, right?
Then go and see your car.
It might help prod those fragments.
Oh, wait.
One bill for you...
one love letter from
a secret admirer for me.
- Punk.
- Last one up fixes dinner.
Come on.
Is that the best you can do?
Let me help you with
these men overboard, Harry.
- You all right, Harry?
- It's my wife.
What's wrong?
She's...
Yes, darling?
I was told my car was brought here.
And what name is the car registered in?
McVey.
That red Jeep?
You won't be drivin' that
anywhere in a hurry, love.
I, uh... I just wanted to look at it.
- Was you in that car?
- Yeah.
Lot 36, love.
Oh, hi, Mary.
Here's the last of the ex-pat
documents you requested.
Thank you.
Is everything okay, Mr. McVey?
Yes. Why?
Oh, it's just that I...
I saw you on the street, at lunch time.
And you... you just ignored me.
Mary, I've been here all day.
I didn't go out for lunch.
I could have sworn I...
Well, I better carry on.
I've got Dr. Kenric on 2.
Thank you, Mary.
Hello?
Hi, Mr. McVey, sir.
How are you doing, Stan?
Not so horrible.
Hey, Stan, what happened to the mirror?
I came in this morning
and it was all over the floor.
Well, good night, Stan.
Same to you, Mr. McVey, sir.
Daniel?
No, no.
He's one.
Shit.
- Why don't you watch where you're going?
- Sorry.
Silly cunt.
Dr. Kenric called me today.
He's worried about you.
He told me that you believe Stephan
is somehow changed.
Is that true?
You really believe that?
I saw this woman.
Before the crash.
She looked like me.
Where was this?
She drove past me on the street.
Turned into a garage.
I followed her.
I followed her up to her flat.
It was like having
the longest case of déjà vu,
except there was a photo.
A photo of me and you.
Why would she have a photo of you?
Maybe it's not me.
Hello, this is Stephan.
I can't get to the phone right now,
so leave a message...
Stephan?
Hello?
Whoa, whoa, slow down, slow down.
Slow...
Okay, slow down.
Now what happened?
Where are you now?
I don't...
Gina, where are you now?
I'm in Stephan's apartment.
Okay. I'll call the police, okay?
Okay.
All right, now, Gina,
it's important that you listen to me.
Okay.
It's okay. Stay calm.
Gina? Gina.
Listen to me very carefully.
I want you to get out of the house now.
Don't wait.
I want you to get out now.
And I will meet you...
Dad?
Hello?
Daniel?
Gina, what's wrong?
Daniel, listen to me.
You're in danger.
Stephan, he, uh...
He's after me. He, um...
Well, slow down.
You're not making any sense.
It looked like him, but it wasn't him.
And now I think something's
happened to Dad.
What's happened to Dad?
Gina?
She's after me.
Who's after you?
The woman I saw before the crash.
You're really starting to scare me now.
What woman?
Look, I...
I saw this woman before the accident,
and she looks like me.
I followed her to Pembridge Road.
Pembridge Road?
Yeah.
- Pembridge House.
- Pembridge House?
But Gina...
that's where you live.
Hello?
Gina?
Kate?
I... I've lost my keys.
Don't worry, I'll get the spare set.
Will you need an extra
set of keys to be cut?
No, I've got a spare set somewhere.
Thanks.
I'm just going to go home
and grab some stuff,
and I'll see you later.
No. No.
Is that another case
of dextrocardia with situs inversus?
Yes.
Subtitles by LeapinLar