I'm Sergeant Joe Fink.
Working 24 hours in homicides.
? His is my area.
Everyone knows but no one wants to see.
Here? the crime rate is higher than anywhere else.
Skid Row, my route.
Little Shop of Horrors
The period m? S terror? Fico of this area.
Began? in the vase? to Mushnick's.
Buenos d? As, Ms. Shiva.
? C? Mo is? Today?
The nephew of my sister died? in Little Rock, Arkansas.
- What? occurred ??
- Explot ?. ? Qui? N know how?
? Want to get used flowers for a funeral?
Like you. It takes care of all my funeral ...
I could? To make a discount.
? Perhaps I am a lic? Ntropo?
As s? I sell cheap carnations.
? And you want a discount?
I can not even pay
The water for irrigation.
Silent ah? atr? s.
- Sorry, this Seymour ...
- He's a good guy.
? Why? do not let him sing?
We have a new client.
I can not even afford to fire that guy.
Mushnick's flowers, pleasures of spring.
? Qu? I can do for you., Dr. Farb?
I do not have much time.
Env? Eme two gladioli and ferns.
Perfect, two dozen gladioli and a fern in a pot.
No no no. Mushnick.
Two gladioli and ferns.
You want me to put two gladioli in the pot with fern?
No, a fern. There are three things separately.
They are waiting for.
- What ??
- The filling is gone.
All right. Har? a hole m? s great.
? S? It wants two crappy gladioli and ferns shit?
It is my weekly budget for flowers.
? Qui? N can be a dentist in Skid Row?
All right. Seymour command immediately.
I will not argue with science.
It is r? Ask.
Now he will have his due. Look.
Seymour Krelboin
Est? Bamos talking about flowers for the funeral.
- I called Mr. Mushnick?
- Do not.
Rockefeller called to borrow a Rolls Royce.
Listen Seymour.
Take two gladioli.
The short right.
And you take a fern and take him to Dr. Farb.
?All right? Come.
- What? I can do for you. It? or?
- I'm Purcell Fauch.
- I am Gravis Mushnick.
- Nice name.
-? N Who I am responsible for my roses?
- I ?, har Ms. Shiva..
? Want some Orchid? Ideas for a girl?
Do not.
I want two dozen carnations.
Carnations.
As you lose your, someone dies.
He has had very bad luck, Ms. Shiva.
If it had been given? Ado dir not you know? As the same.
? Qu? carnations tell me?
- He said he wanted to roses?
- S ?, Stanley.
Carnations.
Duty? To see what is? by Seymour.
Here? It has its carnations.
Is the wrap ?.
No, me eat? here? same.
? Why? do not?
Clear.
- Est n good?
- The best I've eaten.
? His is a small tent? A.
Large stores are expensive and pretty flowers.
The better you look, the worse the taste.
I like the little known sites.
Look to eat the flowers.
Do not say anything if you have not tried.
Look what happened.
This is what I refer? A.
Look at the quality of their work.
If you say goodbye,? D? Nde get? as good a job?
? It's going to fire me?
No, I will elect you President of the United States.
? S ?, is? S fired!
- Gravis, you can not do it.
- Why? do not?
- It's been unintentionally.
- As usual.
Like when you sent the bouquet wishing good health to the funeral.
... Or when you sent black lilies to the elderly in the hospital.
Tambi? N was unintentionally.
But this time I'm serious.
But I always try to do the right thing.
I love the flowers.
I like flowers almost as much as Audrey.
Very good. Est? S he fired.
- Why? You do not give him a chance?
- The chance to say goodbye.
I will not fire.
You are very brave.
Est? S he fired.
But it's not fair.
Do you know what I'm doing?
I'm working on a special plant.
It is a plant that has not seen jam? s.
I can not even sell the store.
- Out!
- Wait.
If a new plant has to see it.
I do not look at the flowers.
My ancestors s? They engaged in this, 200 years.
But I have a stinking Skid Row Store.
And do I like flowers.
Does not understand me.
I have eaten in vase? Ace worldwide.
And those plants m? Extra s? Ace earn m? S money.
? You see ?,? You see?
? Qu? This is it?
? A tango?
Very good. Tell me more.
I remember one with a wall covered with poison ivy.
People see? A very far to see it and buy it.
? And due? Or got rich?
No, it scratched? to death in a madhouse.
That was my cousin Harry.
According.
Come home and brings that plant.
Yes? L said to be a attraction? No, you keep your job.
If not, you take? both.
Do not worry, you like ?.
This has been more music to inv annelids.
We continue to serenade the asylum.
- Seymour, are you?
- S ?, mom ?.
- Come here? and m? rame language.
- I've already seen the language.
? Do you feel sorry for your poor mother?
Ri? Ndote when it has one foot in the grave.
I said unintentionally.
Always unintentionally. M? Rame language.
All languages ​​look alike to me.
You got the results of my an? Lysis?
S ?, the doctor says you have nothing.
Dr. Mallard thought always dec? Truth.
He says he could? As the Rams play.
I want to die.
Should be assistant medical examiner.
I think back to have mumps.
The notice each morning.
That's when you eat the grapes.
? Have a surprise for me ??
? Brelo.
The t? Nico Dr. Slurpsaddle.
For v? To internal or external pain ...
Neuritis, neuralgia, migra? A.
In case of violation, call Traumat? Logo.
Alcohol content? Lico 98%
This will do wonders.
I notice the heat and Cure? N
Down my body.
I'll take my floor.
? That nasty weed from the kitchen?
If you do not like Mr. Mushnick, fire me ?.
I think I'm deaf.
It looks like your job depends on that floor.
Est? worse than this morning.
Eyelet? know what? do.
I throw? To the trash.
I do not like rotten vegetables.
? I get you something?
S ?, the peri physician.
There is a SELF-contest? Stico.
The winner go? the cl? nica May.
Adi? S, Mom ?.
Adi? S.
You see? the pink sunset.
P? Ngalo in my account.
- What? you think?
- Of course it's different.
It looks delicious.
But, do not you est? withered?
He is not well.
It seems to have not spent a good d? A in his life.
I do not care. A m? I like.
- You like to pumpkins.
- S ?.
- What? kind of plant is it?
- I'm not sure.
Got was? the seeds of Japan? s.
They sent them to plant along with other ar? BLUEBERRIES.
You do not even know what? plant is.
- I've put a name.
- What? Name?
? This is a dirty name and now you averg? Enzas?
Audrey called J? Nior.
? You've put my name?
It is the best thing anyone has done for me ?.
I not think I should continue wasting ...
The ten-dollar of your paycheck.
But Gravis, has put my name.
And then the call? N
Mushnick madness ...
And I be? c in lockup by delinquent.
- Est s crazy?
- Qui n?
Your. It may be a plant? nica.
? You do not realize that if it heals ...
Will have? S here? people from all over the world?
- You think so, Fauch?
- What s ?, Mushnick, but I will.
My wife has gardenias for dinner.
- Adi s?.
- Adi s?. You see? morning.
I love flowers kosher.
He is a good man.
You may have reason? No you may not.
Dir you? I'm going to do.
T? and your idiot j? nior Qued you? is one week.
If he recovers, I pod? Is staying.
If not, you are? Is dismissed.
Thank you, Mr. Mushnick
There is? S sad, Seymour.
Do not waste your l? Stima me.
It is not worth it.
-? N Who says that?
- All the world.
S S ?, what ?, but I think you're a good boy.
And s? Audrey knows who you are
The man m? S sweet world.
I gave her all kinds of fertilizers ...
Fertilizers at nomic and distilled water.
But each time is? worse.
Do not worry.
Being? S another Luther Glendale.
- Pasadena.
- Burbank.
- Goodnight, Seymour.
- Good night, Audrey.
? I have not done everything possible?
? D? Nde I fail?
You're my first floor and if you die not s? what? har ?.
Do not die.
You give? water, okay?
As you've opened every evening.
Eyelet? know c? mo make you grow.
Remove? this so you can breathe.
? Qu? It happens?
? C? Mo you woke up?
? Blood?
Do you like the blood?
You must be kidding.
Look what I do for you.
? Qui? N what There would be said?
Contra tastes nothing written.
Fantasy see a new plant? Stica. Audrey J? Nior.
Seymour.
You are the person m? s magnetic? nima world.
M? Rale. Is not that lovely?
? Qu? such an increase of two-dollar?
- What? It happened to your fingers?
- Bee stings.
? Why? I am
Suddenly so wonderful?
Five bees. ? One for each finger?
Ten bees. ? He said an increase of 2-dollar?
Exactly, my good Seymour.
- Ten bees.
- What? I do now?
?you do not know? Look.
It has grown.
Measures almost 30cm.
It grows much as a sore.
Hello, girls,? What? I can do for you?
- We've seen the poster.
- Over Audrey Junior.
- And we have come to see her.
- Pass.
They have entered four to see.
? What? wonderful!
- What? kind of plant is it?
- It's an Audrey J nior?.
? C? Mo ten o'clock bees have stung you?
? Cient does not have a name? Fico?
S ?, but? You qui? N can pronounce it?
-? Quer is to buy something?
- we do not have money.
- The 2000 d S dollars?.
- But they are to flower.
We have m? S. It's a shame.
? Ten? Is 2,000-dollar to spend on flowers?
That's.
? Qui? N he is dead?
? C? Mara trade?
We are the Cucamonga Institute.
prepare a float for the Rose Parade.
- Made of flowers.
- Thousands of flowers.
- We are the committee ?.
- We chose the vase to?.
And we put the flowers.
That plant is amazing.
- S ?, Seymour invent?
- ?really?
girls, watch horticulturist.
? Why? not bought me? is
A m? those flowers?
They have something special.
- The what ??
- They are cheap.
If you have been invented Audrey Junior ...
Will have? N all we need.
We'll talk with the rest of the committee ?.
- We have to go. Adi? S.
- Adi s, Seymour?.
Adi? S, girls.
A son.
Look, Audrey, I have a son.
Mr. Mushnick go ...
Do not call me Mr. Mushnick. Ll? Mame pap ?.
- Okay, Dad ?.
- It is not that wonderful?
Seymour, come here? son m? o.
I want to talk to you
About the future.
Is Ahab? Skid Row. We'll be rich.
Construire a giant greenhouse to create impossible flowers ...
To sell? prices rid? ass in my giant new salon in Beverly Hills.
I see a big sign in the sky that says:
Gravis Mushnick, in French? S.
It is fant? stico.
We will have an orchestra next to the box.
And the lead Gravis ?.
Touching? N m? Music of Mendelssohn ...
And I wear? an expensive dress ...
Carnations 600-dollar a dozen ...
Two dozen per thousand.
?it is a bargain!
Stop screaming.
The brother of my t? O Moshel just died.
? A c? Mo carnations go today?
A 600-dollar La Doce ...
? Why? lets you out there? loose?
Sorry my son.
Take what you want, I give it.
- ?What you want?
- That's.
May be the register.
A few dozen carnations, cuts? A Mushnick ...
Mogul flowers.
That's my father.
Thank you.
? Why? est? so glad?
You have not s? Dead the brother of my t? O ...
At that dead plant
You will come? An good flowers.
- What? It happened to my plant, pap ??
- Who are you calling pap ??
And it was so beautiful a few seconds ago.
Just now I've given dozens of carnations.
Free.
It has been unintentionally.
? Have you any explanation? N?
I can not but think about it
In a minute.
We'll go to a nursing home.
I see a sign in the sky, he says:
Seymour Krelboin
Rest in peace, in? Rabe.
Give him another chance.
I promised? one week.
Happen? all night with the plant.
Be? cured by tomorrow.
I promise you.
Give me something to eat.
? Qui? N said that?
? T? you said that!
Give me something to eat.
? T? you said that! You can talk.
A talking plant.
- say it again.
- Give me something to eat.
I have not gone to college ...
But surely there is a talking plant.
I like? To help you, but I've used all my fingers.
Give me something to eat.
M? Rame.
I'm shattered.
But you may find a drop m? S.
It is all I can give you.
M? S, m? S.
But I'm an? Mico.
I m? S food.
You give? To anything, but I need some blood to m ?.
I'm going for a walk. You might think something.
Papi. Is anyone ah? out.
Give me something to eat.
D? Jame, eats food.
I have my own problems.
Give me something to eat.
I have no more blood.
P? Give it to another.
- I'm hungry.
- I do not care.
Do not you see I'm shattered?
I killed a man.
I am a murderer.
Do you think that's funny?
You think it's fun to go out there? with a sack full of ...
...food...
No, J? Nior.
? What? kind of man you think I am?
I'm starving.
Maybe a small or bite.
That is? well.
This is what I call a salad.
- HOW TO called this salad?
- Ces area?.
Before pr? Maximum plate, I smoke? pure.
You want a cigar?
T? do not smoke cigars.
? D? Nde est? N matches?
Well, looking for matches, I discovered I left my money in another jacket.
Here? It has its chicken thighs.
Does not have money.
- ?Do not tell me?
- I was wrong.
It can happen to anyone.
This and waiting for the joke.
Do not overdo list.
In the case of my shop I have the recaudaci? N today ...
M? S 9-dollar.
UD. bring the rest of the meal,
and I go? to the store and bring the money!
It breaks my heart? N.
Look, boss, one of you. Will the bot? N ...
While the other waits.
?Know what I mean?
In this disgusting restaurant have hostages!
- Exactly.
- Perfect.
Keep eating.
Back? right away with the money.
Adi? S, Gravis.
You have money, right?
Bring whiskey, wine, rum, gin, bourbon.
? What ??
Liquor, tequila, sake, Manischewitz ...
? It's against? I do the money?
Fuck the money.
I want a drink.
- What? happens?
- Do not s ?.
Bring whatever, whatever.
All you have,
- Gravis, what? He has passed?
- do not ask.
- It seems you've seen a ghost.
- That there will be a better state?.
- D melo?. Quiz? I can help.
- Help? You can not.
Eat something.
That will calm ?.
In my own shop.
Do not believe it? Ace.
- I hope you let go now.
- Dir you what ?. Morning.
After? S of cont? Rselo the policeman.
But Mushnick not avis? the cop.
If he had done There would be been the end of this sad story.
Hi, Gravis! 85-dollar and we have just opened.
? What? I told you?
? Will not want? S sell half the business?
- We have talked to the committee ?.
- And we will use your vase to?.
- And will Audrey J nior?.
- You imagine?
- People will want? com? rsela.
- People, com rsela?.
- And we open.
- For the queen to sit.
With crown and scepter.
- Be? so beautiful.
- Be? to com? rsela.
Girls eat.
I have a toothache.
Come with me.
I already told you I have a toothache.
Cu? Ntame.
My tooth hurts.
? Qu? Want to talk?
Plant.
It is a good topic.
The plant is? fant? acoustic.
It is four times m? s bigger than yesterday.
? C? Mo is that it has grown so much?
It s not ?.
But look at the people.
In half an hour we have made seventy-dollar.
85-dollar.
You put a nice name, Audrey J? Nior ...
? But as it is actually called?
It is a cross between a carnivore? vora this flytrap?
Eats insects three times in his life and reaches its size? Om? Maximum.
Perfect.
? And how many times have you eaten this?
Once or twice.
?you do not remember?
It is a rather special plant.
You may not eat jam again? s.
I do not think grow m? S.
Then, do not you need? S m? S flies?
S ?.
My tooth is me? killing.
Go to the dentist.
I'll take care of everything.
We have to ask m? S flowers. Tons.
We are making a lot of money.
Do not make me m? S da? O.
That'll teach? Ar? to pay your bills.
Dirty dog ​​flees, flees.
- Seymour, you have a toothache?
- No, they were cre services?.
Back here ?, miserable.
Sign ah ?.
T? You ruined my gladioli.
If? Ntate. Come on.
- You know what ??
- The wheel does not hurt anymore.
S ?, what s ?.
We'll see. Open the mouth.
- It hurt?
- S ?.
All right. Well, that still is not.
It is? st here ?.
? Qui? N is the dentist?
Look at that stalagmite.
Be? f? cyl.
Will put even? anesthesia.
He has put the mirror in the mouth.
Well tr? Gatelo, est? I ask.
We'll see...
You take? that ... And that ... And that ...
And that also? N ...
S? It is a tooth.
? Maybe you practice odontology
Unlicensed?
Let all ?.
Look at this.
She did not know you were an elf.
I have this mix instant? Nea ...
It does not last long,
But tastes good.
All right, Seymour.
Al? Jate m ?. You want to kill me.
A duel.
- It is the view of Dr. Farb?
- One second.
I see that s ?.
Pass.
- My name is Wilber Force.
- Wilber Force that?
S? What Wilber Force.
My name and my last name is Wilber Force.
? Have time?
No, but one of his patients
I spoke? Very good of you.
The Ms. Shiva.
I'll take care of the funeral
Their families.
I'm very busy now.
Will have? come back tomorrow.
?Oh no!
I have three or four p? Pustules ...
Some piorrea ...
Nine or ten cavities.
I lost a fang and it really hurts.
Today I can not do anything.
According.
Expect? out.
The patient arrived? a large
Hole in the abdomen ...
Produced by a poker ...
Almost had to completely bled ...
And he began to have gangrene.
She had other complications.
Ten? C? Cancer, tuberculosis, leprosy and some flu.
My patient is gone.
You can pass.
I have not seen him leave.
He went through the back door s.
People do not like going to the dentist, but I really enjoy.
It's a great sensation? n ...
When you enter this drill.
I'd rather go to the dentist to ning? N else.
- ?And you.?
- S ?.
No novoca? Na.
He feels that numbs.
This is going to hurt.
Oh, well, well, here? comes!
Oh, my god? Or, do not stop now.
I have made many holes and now I will cover them with this.
? I will not draw any? Come on.
In short, it is his mouth.
It was a great afternoon.
He had never enjoyed so much.
You recommend? to all my friends.
- Thanks, adi s?.
- Adi s?.
- Give me something to eat.
- Quiet, Dr cula?.
? What? you think I bring?
? Laundry?
- Food.
- I'm coming, I'm coming.
This duty? To be enough.
Food.
Adi? S Dr. Farb.
It was a bad dentist,
But he was a good guy.
I never wanted to kill anyone ...
And I've already killed two and two d? Ace.
If the dentist had not attacked me ...
Good trip, Dr. Farb.
You want something more? S?
You see? morning.
Forward.
It's me, Joe.
? C? Mo is? S, Frank?
- HOW TO est? your wife?
- Is not? evil.
- I'm glad. ? And the kids?
- Forgiveness? one yesterday.
- HOW TO occurred ??
- I was playing with matches.
- These things happen.
- I suppose.
I have one extra case? O.
The railways say they have lost one of their own.
Guarding a shipment of refrigerators.
- Thieves ice?
- That's.
? What? pas ??
No idea. Disappeared ?.
Blood in the v? As.
- Tracks?
- Any.
- M s something?
- Dentist, Farb.
-? S ??
- Disappeared.
- Tracks?
- Blood in office.
- Where'd?
- Skid Row.
- Ideas?
- any.
- We check what?
- S ?.
Now is? Bamos if Stooly Frank and me.
I am Fink.
Sergeant Joe Fink.
Buenos d? Ace.
Look at that.
Hello everyone. God m? O.
- It's monstrous.
- S ?.
And to think you did t ?.
Audrey, do not have to kiss me.
? You do not like to kiss you?
A m? s? but you do.
- Why? do not?
- Nobody ever kissed me.
- Well, m? I like.
-? S ?? ?Really?
- Do you like kissing?
- Clear.
- You kiss me again?
- Okay.
- You kiss very well, Audrey.
- I guess I'm good.
- I like to go out with me?
- Sure whenever you want.
- ?Tonight?
- Voucher.
Great.
The plant ...
We have the list of flowers ...
For the parade float rose.
Not now, girls.
Talking to Audrey.
We are ready for carriage.
Let's take a look.
- Hello Qu? is it?
- Look at my plant.
- It is huge.
- S ?.
Hello, Mrs. Shiva,? What? is new?
Something terrible.
My nephew Frankie has lost his ni? O.
I'm sorry. ? C? Mo been?
Playing with matches.
- You want to buy flowers?
- I spend? 50 cents.
Now I prepare something.
Look at my plant.
I am looking.
? Are you. Gravis Mushnick?
No, my name Gravis Mushnick.
- We want to ask you some questions.
- ?Some questions?
- I did not do it.
- He did what ??
What ever.
- You know this man?
- Male ... Know ...
- Why? est? so nervous?
- ?guilty feeling?
?Do not!
? Why? owe to?
- Has seen this man?
- S ?, pictured ... Dr. Farb ...
- As? you know him?
- It's my dentist.
- You done anything?
- Has disappeared.
- Blood in your query.
- The other man also n?.
Blood in the v? As and debris.
- Dr. Farb has been killed?
- Ah ?? s
? Qui? N you know?
I do not.
- T? what do you think?
- He knows nothing.
If you know some of these men, call our office.
Be? happy to cooperate with the cop.
- Hello, I t a?.
- It's too bad about your son.
These things happen.
Tell me if that plant has stopped growing.
Not grow? m? s.
-??? Ar s not deceive your father?
- My father has returned?
A m ?, idiot.
I do not want to that plant.
I est? throwing my store.
Not grow? m? s, I promise.
- HOW TO s is so sure?
- You've already eaten three times.
?here n...
What? He has eaten this time?
A mill? N of Japanese beetles.
- You do not eat? m? s?
- Est? full.
There is a woman of a committee ?.
- I think it's important.
- Great.
I think you're going out with
Audrey tonight.
I stay? to monitor the plant.
? D? Nde we going tonight?
I just remembered
I do not have money.
We can go for a walk along the beach.
We can have dinner at my house.
My mother is a good cook.
That is? well.
The call? dir and then what ?.
It's marvelous.
?likes?
Nor do I like or dislike me anything.
I am of the association? N of silent observers of flowers California.
? What? is that?
-? Qui n think this plant?
- It was me.
- ?And what's his name?
- Seymour Krelboin.
- Krelboim?
- Krelboin.
The cri? in a can of coffee ?.
? You yourself can plant m? S?
I do not think there m? S se? Ora ...
... Lawn fishtwanger ...
? Sta be? the? nica Ms. F ... Winger.
- Fishtwanger.
- Fishtwanger?
Surely not edible.
Mr. Krelboin,
He has been elected to ...
The prize of our society.
?A prize?
?I?
He deserves it.
? Cu? Ndo be opened? N
These buds m? S great?
Sec? N the book, to be opened last morning, at dusk.
Back? then to deliver the prize.
Extraordinary.
They're going to give a prize.
- I'm so proud of you, Seymour.
- An award for Audrey J nior?.
We'll put it in the hearse.
Rose Parade.
Do not look at me. I'm horrible.
I am a aut? Dispossession ntico.
He always says that.
I do not feel well? Lately.
Audrey,? His is my mother, Winifred.
Mam Foquart Audrey ?, is my girlfriend.
- Hello, Audrey, are you hungry?
- I eat a herd or?.
Sit down.
Go? to the starter.
If? Ntate here ?, Audrey.
? I have your your? Ter?
Try this.
- Looks like cough syrup.
- Dr. Phlegm syrup.
- ?A toast?
- By Audrey J nior?.
No, Senior Audrey.
Tu, gluttonous.
I'll watch.
Dont let? anyone near.
Here? est? Soup.
I'll get the seasoning.
Est? S very pretty in the light of the candle.
- Seriously, Seymour?
- S ?.
Here? You have.
pru? bullet now.
- Smells different.
- is different.
Some kind of oil, right?
Oil h? Gado cod.
Magn? Fico for the colon.
And that is above sulfonamide.
Give me something to eat.
I'm hungry.
Est? open.
Give me something to eat.
I have not or? Do.
- Give me something to eat.
- Or do I have?.
I want food.
We have a talking plant.
I'm hungry.
?Hungry?
? A little fish stock?
? Qu? you like? to eat tonight?
T? est? s quite chubby.
No s? The speech, but Adem? S is funny.
Esc? Chame, lazy bot? Nica.
Not getting? S food.
I'm starving.
Perfect.
Let? S Skid Row uninhabited.
Olv? Give it.
Not getting? S
Gravis Mushnick food.
Good evening
And to get there? your time.
I like these noodles.
If est? N is a bit bitter because they are Chinese herbs and sulfate.
No other cook like my mother.
That said your father before me.
If you're getting married,
You have to be a good cook.
You. I could? To teach? Ar.
- Are you going to marry?
- Even I would not have been asked.
- Qui n?
- Seymour.
Seymour's too young.
You have to go out and have fun.
Pas? Rselo big.
I do not want pas? Rmelo big,
I want to be with Audrey.
I promised you not married? As ...
Until I comprases
The Lung? N of steel.
But you take years breathing.
And it's not f? Easy, son.
It not f? cyl.
No one.
Black, Tuesday and thirteen cat.
Est? You ask superstitions.
Salt ah ?.
Do not fire.
I am old and sick.
Come to light where I can see him.
S? I am Gravis Mushnick.
? For me it's going to kill?
I will not kill you.
Unless you try something.
Jam? S tried anything.
? You want my money?
C? Pulled.
S? I want to steal from you.
I like their hospitality.
I feel that there is no m? S.
S? I am a poor florist.
Here? no 30-dollar.
?And the rest?
This afternoon had 30,000 people here ?.
No m? S money.
See, to watch an Audrey J? Nior plant.
Do not deceive me? E.
Many people do not see? To see a plant.
I have m? S money.
Let's try this.
One two three four...
I have m? S money, I swear.
We will do the rev? S.
Five, four, three, two ...
Very good very good.
- Where'd?
- in the plant.
?In the plant?
In the big plant, Audrey J? Nior.
- Within the large sheet?
- That is, inside.
- HOW TO opens?
- Just call.
Ah? inside?
- Inside. Deeply.
- I see nothing.
Bottom.
Right at the bottom.
What I have done.
I do not care if you have an appointment.
I do not keep this plant.
But you not have to stay with it.
It has grown at all.
? C? Mo know you will not have? m? s hungry?
- why...
- Tonight you stay.
Tomorrow get the prize and dispose of it.
? Get rid? ? Why ??
Do not ask.
Ahab is ?.
To litter.
? S ?, Ms. Shiva?
Seymour, your plant is wonderful.
Nothing happens.
Cultivate? others to? No better than? sta.
? Have you thought what? We do tonight?
We'll go to a place full of flowers.
- We have to stay here ??
- S ?.
We will make a picnic.
Be? like going to the field.
? Have the 3,000 pink azaleas to the network?
What about the 9,000 yellow chrysanthemums contour?
? And the roses to the front?
? And the back?
? What? is that of a picnic
With that Foquart?
- Not like Audrey, mam ??
-? S wants your money.
- I do not have money.
- It is very clever.
They stick? to you until you have and then, adi? s fortune.
Audrey is a decent girl.
Never f? Is a woman
Too healthy.
But he had a cold two weeks ago.
A sad cold.
B? Scate mononiscoliosis a woman with stones in the kidney or ?? n.
Can I catch something like that ?.
How ironic that is going to catch you.
And you get? in a madhouse.
A m? I leave? in the hands of Chiropractic? cticos and healers.
S? when you do not want me.
- Sorry, Mom ?.
- Do not sit by m ?.
Look for? an alley? n h? Mede and wait? to my time comes.
Do not die until you return.
I care? of you.
Adi? S.
He had never tasted as food ?.
It is a s? ndwich with peanut butter.
- And what? It is what heals?
- Nothing, s it is a meal.
? And to that point if you do not remove the grains or shrinks the nasal tissue?
Do not be silly.
- What? you want to be, Seymour?
- I want to plant things.
If I had money I go? To the South Seas ...
Where they grow plants m? S ex? Policies.
- That sounds exciting.
- S ?.
- I like to go to the South Seas?.
- Of course you could s go?.
? I bring? S you, Seymour?
There could? To go without you, Audrey.
- Why ??
- Because I love you, Audrey.
I also? N love you.
Give me something to eat.
- What? you said?
- It was a joke.
I'm hungry.
- Seymour.
- It's been unintentionally.
? Why? what did you say?
Food, food.
T? you did not say that.
S? I said, s? I said.
I was watching you.
- I'm a ventr locuo?.
- What ??
A ventr? Locuo.
Give me something to eat.
- Seymour, find yourself well?
- It s not ?, I'm not sure.
Stop fooling around and b? Same.
I'm starving.
If you're hungry, eat something.
But olv? Date of m ?.
Sorry, Audrey.
I want food.
If you can not control, I'm going home.
I need grub.
I have his stomach vac? O.
Audrey, wait, esc? Chame.
I've heard enough.
Est? S crazy.
You say you love me and act? As a fool.
Soon you could what? explain everything.
? Why? I do not explain it now?
Because there are many very important things.
I want to marry you, but I have to take care of mom ?.
That plant will make it? all reality.
Morning give me? N an award and be? famous.
Be? great botanist.
We can go to the South Seas.
? Qu? that got to do with what happened ah? inside?
When you recover the trial, talk? you.
Good evening.
I'm getting tired of you.
- I'm hungry.
- I do not care.
Look what you made me.
I'm a murderer and I have no girlfriend.
C? Shut up and tr? Eme food.
Do not tell me to shut up. C? Shut up you.
? Qui? N cri you? from seed?
? Qui? N gave you all kinds of fertilizers
And she spent the night with you?
Nobody There would be done that for you.
? You think anyone There would be against? Do
People to eat?
Anyone.
I helped you and t? You've helped me.
Shut your mouth and to sleep.
Krelboin!
Turn around.
Close your eyes.
You dream.
Open your eyes.
- Do what I say.
- S ?, master.
- Salt to find food.
Go away and do not waste time.
?Fool!
I Leonore Klide.
? C? Mo going?
My master is hungry.
? Hi!
I have to find food for my love.
To my love I have to find food.
Quiz? I can help.
-? N Who are you?
- I Leonore Klide.
Love you.
The master wants food.
Let the old goat wait.
The night is young and we also? N.
The master does not like the guy.
? What? food do you like?
That is? best. B? Same.
? Qu? happen to you? ?You do not like me?
Too bony.
? Bony? Nobody told me that before.
Beef is better than beef.
You are an idiot.
? Qu? This is it?
? H? Gado chopped?
The master likes to m? S fat.
Speak for yourself, John.
My name is Seymour.
I also? N as my name ?.
? Est? S interested or I est? S wasting my time?
Never thought? someone to offer? a volunteer.
- T? s ??
- Clear.
If est? S safe to volunteer.
- In my house or yours?
- I do not care.
- Flip a coin.
- I have no coins.
- For another thing.
- Ah? It is a stone.
- Wet or dry?
- Wet.
Whenever it est? Bamos m? S close and soon will have? Masters the murderer.
He had no masters m? S tracks, but you keep? Masters to say something to the boss.
She had the sensation? N that is? Bamos
Nearing the end of the mystery.
And He wanted to be close.
Outside worldwide.
Today is a special party for Seymour.
I want the whole world apart.
We want to Seymour.
This is worse than being the keeper of a revolving door.
- What? is this celebration? n?
- He was going to give my son a prize.
? Qu? has done?
? Run away from home?
Do not look as ?.
I want to talk to you.
Sorry Seymour.
I do not understand.
You explain it? all after? s ceremony.
? Qu? est? n doing here ??
O? Mos there was something here?
This afternoon.
We have come to have a look.
No need ning? N look.
Observers Society
Silent has arrived ...
And is? dusk.
Welcome.
It is an honor to have you here ?.
- We continue with the disappearances.
- We believe they were murdered.
Not yet
To talk about it.
Let me see your tongue.
- You know what you have?
- S what the facts are , now ? .
Tonsillitis .
I also ? N have.
- be? I might as well look .
- Whatever, Joe .
This dusk ? Create to open ? N these assholes ?
I hope so.
If not , we will deliver
the prize later.
It is ? N open .
The first was opened .
- Is...
- Cop train.
View the rest .
- T ? what do you think?
- Est n all ah ?.
It is true.
? C ? Mo explain this , Mr. Krelboin ?
It was an accident .
Has reason ? No , he would not kill them.
Seymour , you said to me explain ? Ace .
It escapes.
Let's go for him.
The coach be ? perfect .
No passing.
- Filthy floor , you ruined my life.
- Give me food!
I will feed you ...
Feed you , feed you like never before!
Be? better to call it quits .
We will not find tonight.
Look, the door is ? open .
It was such a good boy.
Seymour.
It was unintentionally.