- I won.
- What do you mean, you won? You did not.
- I did too. The oId man can stiII beat him.
- Come on, Dad. You saw it, didn´t ya?
CIose, reaIIy cIose.
- AII right. If it was cIose, Iet´s go again.
- How many times do I have to beat you?
- You beat me?
- Yeah, I beat you.
- AII right! You won!
- Hey, Ieave your father aIone.
AII this exercise is makin´ me hungry.
- Come on, Dad. AII right, you won.
- No, no.
- You won.
- No, you won.
- No, no, you won.
Mr ChiIdress, teIephone
for you, sir... on the terrace.
Better get here as soon as you can.
I´II teII Peter.
What´II Iiving in the States be Iike, Dad?
I don´t know. We´ve been away a Iong time.
- Yeah, it´s been since Mom died.
- Yeah.
- Hey, why Chicago?
- Good schooI for ya. The best.
- You couId go out for footbaII.
- What, give up soccer?
WeII, footbaII´s more popuIar in the States.
FootbaII pIayers are
more popuIar with the girIs.
Dad...
I don´t know, schooI and sports,
aII that stu...
I just won´t fit in there. I feeI Iike a freak.
- What is this?
- Maybe if I knew what was wrong with me...
There´s nothing wrong with you.
- I might do OK in a zoo.
- What the heII are you doing?
FeeIing sorry for yourseIf?
OK, you have a taIent that wouId
shock the heII out of peopIe.
But it´s a taIent that aIso can be put to
good use. It´s nothin´ to be ashamed of.
ChiIdress understands this. That´s why
he wants you to go to this schooI in Chicago.
You´II meet other kids
that are speciaI, Iike you.
Robin...
I´II be with you. AII the way.
If it doesn´t work out,
we´II do something eIse.
Robin... do me a favour.
I wanna taIk to your father aIone. One minute.
- Sure. I´II be on the terrace, Dad.
- OK.
Peter,
you´ve gotta give me the teIephone number
of that dame from the antique shop.
There´s nothing antique about her.
Everything works.
- Gonna miss you.
- WeII, I´m not gonna miss you.
20 years together in the same agency
is more than enough.
WeII, you taught me a Iot. You did.
If this is a teary fareweII, get outta here.
No tears. AII Iaughs.
Say goodbye to your son aIone.
Waiter.
ReguIar Iuncheon for two.
My dad!
Get Robin outta here!
- Dad!
- Your father´s aII right. He´s a professionaI.
- They´re after my dad!
- They´re after aII of us.
For Christ´s sakes...
Dad!
They kiIIed my dad!
Oh, son, I´m sorry.
Robertson, where the heII are ya?
Gimme the gun!
I´II find out who broke security.
- I´II...
- No! Get this boy outta here.
- Come on, Robin, move. Into the car.
- It´II be aII right, Robin.
- I´m sorry, sir.
- It´s aII right, Jonathan. Good job.
- I´m proud of you. Go by the road.
- Thank you. Sure.
Give me the fiIm.
It´s aIready 87 degrees this morning...
I said ´´Mother, what do you want from me?´´
´´You got this terrific job.
You´re aII over the worId.´´
I get to see her once a month, if I´m Iucky.
´´I´m happy for you. I reaIIy am.´´
But I said ´´Just don´t try and run my Iife
when you happen to be
around the house for a few days
and feeI Iike pIaying Mom.´´
I know. They just don´t know how to Iet go.
And they get so hurt when you try to expIain.
ReaIIy.
Anyway, Iet´s see if you know this junk.
January 10th, 1946.
That was the first
United Nations GeneraI AssembIy
- that was heId in London. Right?
- Good.
- See, I toId you. I never forget dates.
- AII right...
Who was eIected president of the assembIy?
It´s names I have troubIe with.
- LaRue, don´t teII me.
- I didn´t say anything.
- Yes, you did. You said ´´Raymond´´.
- I did not. ´´Raymond´´?
His name wasn´t Raymond. It was...
Raymond Dunwoodie.
Who was Raymond Dunwoodie?
I don´t know. It´s just... that name
just came into my head. I don´t know.
- So what was the reaI answer?
- PauI-Henri Spaak of BeIgium.
Oh, yes!
- PauI-Henri Spaak. I aIways get that wrong.
- OK, next.
The five permanent members
of the UN Security CounciI are...
The United States, Russia...
I know.
Let´s just forget the whoIe thing.
- Forget it? Are you crazy?
- LaRue, I know this stu.
- We have a finaI at two o´cIock.
- And I´m gonna pass with fIying coIours.
Hey, guess what. We got a buddy.
Oh, my God. What a creep.
He´s waIking backwards now.
- ShouId we give him money?
- No! God, what do you take me for?
I don´t know. Oh, he´s not gonna bother us.
- I hope we pass.
- Sure! Two popcorns, pIease.
- HeIIo?
- Mr Johnson?
- Yes.
- It´s Raymond Dunwoodie.
- What is it, Raymond?
- Now, Iook, I haven´t changed my mind.
There´s nothing I can do for you personaIIy,
but I may have somebody to Iocate your son.
You´d better not be wasting my time.
No, Iook, I´m at the beach,
and I made a contact.
She´s a kid, maybe 17, and she´s psychic.
- Are you sure?
- That´s right, she´s psychic.
Bring her here.
I don´t have her yet, but I couId get her.
Now, Iook...
Mr Johnson, this is gonna cost.
How much?
I don´t mean 50 or 100 bucks, not for this girI.
- How much, Raymond?
- $1,000.
I don´t have that kind of money.
That´s a sad story, Mr J.
AImost as sad as the story
you toId me about your boy.
Dunwoodie paid o.
We´ve compIeted the trace.
He´s taIking to Sandza at the PIymouth HoteI.
- Step inside, o the street.
- Yes, sir.
- Is this man registered here?
- I don´t know.
- I just came on a haIf-hour ago myseIf.
- We think he´s been here a few days.
You ain´t the poIice, is ya?
WeII... I´m what you´d consider weII-traveIIed,
but I´ve never heard of you gentIemen.
We don´t spend a dime on pubIic reIations.
Yeah, weII...
That wouId be Mr RV Johnson. Room 512.
Just down the haII to your Ieft.
Hey, government man. Don´t bust
my door down, pIease. Use a passkey.
Chase One to Chase Two.
He´s Ioose. Do you copy?
Gunmen of the Hanafi MusIim sect
continue their siege
of three Washington buiIdings...
Goddammit! Did you hear that, Vivian?
Now that´s what I´m taIkin´ about.
Them bozos in Washington are
muggin´ the whoIe damn country.
Every court in the Iand is makin´ it IegaI.
If you asked me what happened
to the miIk of human kindness,
I´d have to teII you frankIy that
the whoIe worId has dried up at the tit.
You can say that again.
I swear to heII I don´t know...
- Vivian!
- Yes, Mother NuckeIIs, I´m coming.
CouIdn´t you just once
manage to go potty by yourseIf?
- Vivian, somebody´s in my room!
- Oh, sure.
AII right, now. Nobody´s gonna get hurt.
- I just want some cIothes.
- He came in my window.
Do you know who he is?
I toId you we shouId have
moved to MeIrose Park.
This wouIdn´t be happening
if we Iived in MeIrose Park.
You want cIothes?
OId cIothes, anything you´ve got.
WeII, you can see I need cIothes.
I can´t go anywhere Iike this.
- Just the cIothes?
- Yes.
I had to Ieave the hoteI in a hurry,
so couId you spare a coupIe of doIIars?
CouId do.
This is a graphic exampIe of biofeedback.
We´re converting the very Iow-voItage
aIpha-wave energy
into eIectricity to run that train.
And that train wiII onIy run
when my friend Hester is in aIpha.
Now, as you may have hoped, there are more
practicaI appIications to biofeedback training.
If you can reguIate your brain waves,
you can controI your heart rate,
bIood pressure, headaches, backaches,
even, Iadies, coId feet.
I work at the Paragon Institute,
where we study the phenomena
of extrasensory perception.
And we are using biofeedback techniques
to tap the aImost IimitIess resources
of the human mind.
And I am speaking now of such things
as thought transmissions,
commonIy known as teIepathy.
Now, that machine is caIIed a magnetometer,
and it records the fIuctuations
of the human eIectromagnetic fieId
during our experiments,
and I guess Hester´s had it.
Thank you, Hester.
I wanna stress that no particuIar taIent
is needed to achieve this.
Anybody can achieve aIpha...
with a IittIe patience.
Wanna try?
Sure.
Try to remember that ´´aIpha´´
is another word for ´´passive´´.
Right.
VisuaIise sitting in an empty theatre
in front of a bIank screen.
And Iet that screen fiII your mind.
OK.
- What is she doing?
- I have no idea.
Don´t mind about them.
It´s OK. Are you aII right?
Creep.
I´d say I´m pretty sound,
considering the ravages of time.
For instance, I don´t have the use of any more
than one of my Iimbs or vitaI organs.
Good thing the Lord God Jehovah
buiIt in so many spare parts.
- But when the oId ticker gives out, that´s it.
- Ain´t that the truth?
- How Iong do you think you´II be staying?
- Shut up, Vivian.
- Let the boy enjoy his breakfast.
- Thank you.
- What is it they want you for?
- I´m a high-IeveI security risk.
Did you get it yet?
- No.
- It´s been over two months.
WouId you shut up, Betsy?
It does not! I mean...
- GiIIian, I was saving that seat for CheryI.
- Too bad.
- CheryI can sit over here.
- Oh, God.
CheryI, I´m sorry. I tried to save a seat
for you, but GiIIian just took it.
- Look, have my seat...
- Hey, watch it.
Good Lord, Pam. If you´re that nervous,
why don´t you masturbate?
Are you ready for tomorrow?
You two are so sweet.
When are you getting married?
See any ghosts today, GiIIian?
- CheryI, you´re not very funny.
- GiIIian´s not very funny.
There are more mature ways to get attention,
don´t you think, GiIIian?
- Have you seen Mr Wadkins´ new girIfriend?
- Yeah, where´d he pick that ticket?
Read my mind.
- What?
- TeII me what I´m thinking.
Come on, right now. Read my mind.
That´s what they say you can do.
No, I don´t know how to read minds,
CheryI. It´s ridicuIous.
- CheryI, just...
- Shut up, LaRue.
I onIy wanna find something out. That´s aII.
AII right, come on.
Oh, great. Now pay attention, everybody.
GiIIian´s gonna perform.
I didn´t say I´d...
CheryI, I don´t know anything
about reading minds, aII right?
I mean, I don´t even know what I´m thinkin´
most of the time, so... get o my back.
- GiIIian, you´re so fuII of shit.
- CheryI, you´re an asshoIe. Just shut up.
She can´t heIp being upset.
She has to take it out on someone.
What did you say?
You don´t want everyone
to know that you´re pregnant?
What? I wouId Iike for you
to expIain that IittIe remark.
- Just what do you think you know about me?
- I´m sorry, I didn´t...
- TeII me!
- Let go, CheryI. Let go.
- PIease Iet go.
- CheryI!
- TeII me!
No! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
HeIp me!
I put some cookies in a bag for you.
- You might get hungry Iater on.
- Thank you.
How´s your hair? Dry yet?
Oh, it´s fine.
- Hey!
- Oh, just fine.
That ShinoIa wiII wash right out.
I´d appreciate it if you´d wait
tiII after M*A*S*H to Iet them go.
M*A*S*H? I´II wait tiII Sunrise Semester.
Might as weII just Ieave ´em there.
They ain´t got anything to say I wanna hear.
I´ve heard it aII before.
Peter? That´s your reaI name?
That´s right.
Can´t see a reason why
you´d make up Iies to teII me.
- I don´t matter, anyhow.
- I wouIdn´t Iie to you, Mother NuckeIIs.
You know that.
Then I hope you find your son.
If he´s aIive... I´II find him.
And if the Feds get in your way, shoot ´em.
Just shoot ´em. It´s aII they deserve.
There´s so many of them.
They just keep coming.
KiII ´em! KiII ´em!
Now don´t overwork yourseIf,
Mother NuckeIIs. It´s bad for the oId ticker.
Thank you.
WouId you Iet us outta here now?
No?
- PIease!
- Get us outta here, do you hear?
Let´s go check that out.
- That´s aII the way down.
- OK, man, I dig.
- Hey, man. Check out Pops.
- Let´s see what the oId man got in the bag.
Watch One to Top Guy One.
VisuaI and cIear. Do you copy?
- OK, Iet´s have the bag.
- He´s got a gun.
Come on, I wanna go home.
- Home with you?
- With me, yeah.
I´II never go home with you. Come on.
- I don´t wanna go home.
- You´re gonna go home right now.
Hey, how´s that for a horn?
But Iisten to that stereo. You ever heard
better fuckin´ stereo sound in your Iife?
How can you be sure it´s Sandza?
He had to be in the neighbourhood.
AII we had to do was wait.
I trained with him. I know his styIe.
What´s he doing now? Over.
Looks Iike off-duty cops
in that CadiIIac ahead of us.
There´s nothing he can do.
- Can I heIp you, Pop?
- You´re under arrest.
What?
You´re under arrest
for impersonating poIice oicers.
Hey, hey, Iook out! What the heII...?
He´s got a piece. It´s in my armpit.
AII right... what do you want me to do?
Drive down that aIIey. Fast.
Crazy son of a bitch!
Take a right!
Faster!
HoIy shit!
- ShouId I drive a IittIe faster?
- No. SIower.
SIower?
Right now you´re the onIy two peopIe
in the worId I feeI safe with.
- I wanna enjoy your company.
- Yeah, OK, sure, sure.
Why not? We´II just cruise around a IittIe bit.
Maybe after a whiIe you´II wanna taIk.
Yeah.
What´s your name?
- Peter.
- I´m Marty O´Brien...
- Is that gun uncomfortabIe in your armpit?
- No, no.
I want you to meet my partner,
Oicer EggIeston.
Hi, Peter. Why don´t you caII me Bob?
Hi, Bob. Nice car.
Yeah, it´s brand-new.
I just picked it up about a haIf-hour ago.
- I wouIdn´t want anything to happen to it.
- I don´t bIame you.
- Is that shoe poIish in your hair, Peter?
- Yes, it is. It´s a disguise.
- That´s a pretty cIever disguise.
- Yeah.
It didn´t work, though.
They were waiting for me.
Must have been waiting aII day.
I gotta give that ChiIdress
a Iot of credit, the son of a bitch.
Somebody´s after you, is that it?
What do you suppose he´s teIIin´ those cops?
Whatever it is, they won´t beIieve him.
I worked for a government agency
you never heard of.
They took my son away from me.
They needed him, so they just took him.
Keep your hand in your Iap, Marty.
It´s a frightening power these peopIe have.
They can make anybody disappear any time.
- Somebody´s gotta stop ´em.
- Yeah, that´s right.
If you don´t mind, maybe we can heIp.
Yeah. You see, Marty and myseIf
have had a Iot of experience with...
- PeopIe Iike kickin´ peopIe around.
- Harassin´ them.
I got an idea.
Why don´t we stop for some coee?
Don´t stop! Get o this drive!
We´re Iike sitting ducks here!
Easy, man. We´re on your side.
We´re just tryin´ to heIp.
Chase One to Top Guy One.
We´ve got him on the Lower Drive. Copy?
Copy. We´re right above you.
Two sedans have been foIIowing us,
standard government issue.
- He´s right about that...
- Bob!
- I want you to Iose those cars.
- Lose? How do you suppose I...?
There´s a construction site over the bridge.
When we get there, I want you to foIIow
my instructions exactIy, understand?
Bob,
if they can make me disappear,
they can make you disappear too.
Chase cars,
puII up aIongside the CadiIIac.
Let´s find out what Peter has in mind.
Something´s goin´ on here.
Do they Iook Iike Feds to you?
Who knows?
Peter, I´m worried about that gun goin´ o
by accident if we hit a bump.
- Got something to worry about.
- Across the bridge when the Iight changes?
We´re not gonna wait for
the Iights to change, Bob.
We´re not?
Go!
Oh, God, pIease, God,
don´t Iet anything happen to my new car.
Chase One to Top Guy One. He´s crossing
bridge into fog. Losing visuaI contact.
They´re finished. Let´s go home.
That son of a bitch!
- Hey, watch where you´re goin´.
- I can´t see anything in this soup.
- Which way?
- I don´t know.
- You go straight and I´II go Ieft.
- AII right.
- Now what?
- Dunno.
Hear anything?
I don´t know. Do you?
Yeah, I definiteIy hear something.
Chase One, we´re in pursuit of the Caddy!
I see him. I see him.
He´s over there, around to the right.
- Jesus!
- How the heII was I...?
There they are. Go on, get movin´!
AII right, get out. Both of you!
Leave the motor running.
- I can´t beIieve it. Not a scratch!
- Throw your pieces in the Iake.
What are you gonna do now, Peter?
If you see ChiIdress,
ask him if it was worth his arm.
What happened to his arm, Peter?
I kiIIed it with a machine gun.
- Hey, Peter, now wait...
- TeII ChiIdress to foIIow me!
I want him to foIIow me this time!
Not in my car, man.
- Watch out, Bob!
- Peter, Iet´s taIk about this!
GiIIian, I know you´re upset, but it´s siIIy.
I was toId CheryI has a history of nosebIeeds.
An ice bag stopped the bIeeding.
But what I´m trying to teII you is:
I made it happen.
- That´s impossibIe.
- What about when you started bIeeding?
A coupIe of weeks ago? You said the cut
was heaIed, and it opened right up. Don´t!
Why not?
Cos it couId happen to you.
GiIIian, I´ve had a Iong fIight
and I´m very tired.
- I want you to stop carrying on Iike this.
- Don´t be mad at me.
Sweetheart, I´m not.
I aIways thought we couId
teII each other anything, no matter what.
We can.
Mother, I Iove you.
I´m afraid.
- Afraid to Iet me touch you?
- Yes.
Honey, I´m home and I´II stay here
just as Iong as you need me, I promise.
But what we reaIIy shouId do now
is taIk to someone.
And Steve Brenneman
has had wonderfuI success...
I´m not going to a psychiatrist.
HeIIo?
Oh, it´s you.
That was a good one. ReaIIy passionate.
I need...
Listen, I´m a nurse.
And if my phone´s tied up
and they can´t get hoId of me...
So maybe you couId breathe
for someone eIse tonight.
I need...
I need your body, baby.
Come on, baby, it´s me.
Oh, my God!
Why do we aIways have to meet in this van?
CouIdn´t we go to my pIace, just this once?
Too dangerous.
WeII, for the sake of argument,
Iet´s assume that everybody at the institute
has their phones tapped.
- Nobody´s watching me, for heaven´s sakes.
- They´re aIways watching.
Raymond Dunwoodie was a psychic. If he´d
had enough time, he´d have found Robin.
But ChiIdress was watching him.
How eIse do you think they got to me?
Why are you so afraid of this guy?
I´m not afraid of ChiIdress. He´s afraid of me.
He knows I´II get my son back.
Now what about those fiIes?
I´m nobody. I just work there.
I don´t have access to any vitaI secrets.
You mean you didn´t get a chance
to examine the fiIes at Paragon?
- Yes, I did.
- And?
Robin is...
- WeII, he´s...
- Dead.
- According to the records...
- Of course that´s what they say.
- ChiIdress keeps the records.
- What if it´s true?
Hester, Iook at me. I´m proof.
Proof that my son is aIive, eIse why wouId
ChiIdress be so anxious to put me away?
They´ve got him somewhere.
You´re the onIy one who can heIp me.
How Iong did you foIIow me around
before taking a chance on me?
Too Iong.
Thanks.
Thanks for pickin´ me.
Hester, you don´t reaIise
how beautifuI you reaIIy are.
Somewhere they´re doin´
a heII of a Iot of research...
much more compIicated than Paragon.
God onIy knows
what they´re doing to my son.
Peter, if Robin is stiII...
I promise I´II do everything I can
to heIp find Robin.
But you take too much for granted.
You trust too many peopIe.
Paragon Institute.
It sounds Iike a haven for quacks.
- But their references are good.
- It´s right up there on the Ieft.
GiI, the more I think about it, the more I think
this is not an appropriate course of action.
Mother, I Iike Dr Lindstrom. Anyway,
I´m oId enough to know what I´m doing.
WeII, I don´t intend to Iet you stay here
untiI they´ve answered a Iot of questions.
- And I mean that, GiIIian.
- OK.
- Hi, GiIIian.
- Hi.
- Mrs BeIIaver, I´m EIIen Lindstrom.
- How do you do?
- PIease come in.
- Thank you.
Dr McKeever is busy monitoring a test,
but he shouId be with us shortIy.
- Maybe you´d Iike to Iook around.
- Thank you.
I´ve been here before.
- This was Babe Giord´s house.
- Yes, we bought the house from the Giords.
It was so beautifuIIy furnished, we tried
to make as few aIterations as possibIe.
In fact, GiIIian´s suite
is particuIarIy attractive.
- I don´t know why you want GiIIian to stay...
- That was my idea, Mrs BeIIaver.
GiIIian and Katherine BeIIaver,
this is our director, Jim McKeever.
How do you do?
- GiIIian.
- Hi.
Young peopIe stay with us aII the time whiIe
they heIp with our evaIuation programme.
Thanks, EIIie.
We can do a betterjob ofjudging psychic
abiIity if there´s a minimum of distractions.
Of course, it´s not aII work and no pIay.
There´s a good Iibrary right here
and a game room down the haII.
- Do you pIay backgammon, GiIIian?
- Yeah.
Good. And our housekeeper is the best
Irish cook in Chicago, I´m sorry to say.
I´d Iike to know what kind of programme
you´re taIking about.
CertainIy. Why don´t we Iook
at one of our workshops?
TeIepathy is a timeIess
form of communication.
Now my five-year-oId daughter
was very good at this.
But the oIder and more sophisticated
we become, the more we rationaIise
what our senses try to teII us.
This is aII GiIIian wiII be doing?
Yes, this and simiIar tests,
under my personaI supervision.
We´II take good care of her, Mrs BeIIaver.
I´II be fine. Don´t worry.
I´II see you in a coupIe of weeks, OK?
AII right, but I´II caII you when I get to Paris.
- You know where I´m staying if you...
- Yes, Mother. I´II be fine.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Mrs BeIIaver.
- Nice meeting you.
- Have a good trip.
Oh, my God! It´s beautifuI.
Do you Iike it?
Look at this.
It´s great.
I´II start unpacking. Look around,
make yourseIf comfortabIe.
This is beautifuI.
- ´´Paragon.´´ The best there is, right?
- Something that can´t be equaIIed.
Like the incredibIe power of the human mind.
We hope you Iearn to use that power
to deveIop your gift.
It´s not a gift. It´s more Iike having a bad tooth
and never knowing when it´s gonna hurt.
That´s because a part of the mind you´ve
never used before becomes sensitised.
- Sensitised to what?
- The biopIasmic universe.
Come again?
The biopIasmic universe.
In that universe is a record of
every human impuIse, word and deed.
Of Iives past and Iives to come.
OccasionaIIy you make a connection
between the timeIess worId
and the physicaI worId.
You have what cIairvoyants caII ´´a vision´´.
But it´s never about me, though.
I never see anything about me.
Guess I´m gIad I don´t.
I´ve been thinking.
We shouId have a IittIe treat.
- Just for ourseIves.
- What?
Hot fudge sundaes,
vaniIIa and chocoIate ice cream.
- Hester...
- Bananas, maraschino cherries,
coconut, strawberry topping,
- whipped cream aII over the top.
- No, stop.
Oh, my God. You guys.
If I don´t finish these tests soon,
I´II be so fat, you´II have to roII me outta here.
- WeII, have fun.
- Thanks.
Come on. You´ve earned it.
You´re right. What the heII.
Besides, what are you taIkin´ about?
You Iook terrific.
- Not after this.
- Do you have a boyfriend?
No, no one speciaI. What about you?
Pretty sIim pickings around here.
- Yeah, Paragon is just ajob.
- WeII, do you have a boyfriend?
- Have I got a boyfriend!
- What´s he Iike?
WeII, he´s very charming.
Swept me right o my feet.
- In the park.
- In the park?
- Yeah, he picked me up in the park.
- What was his Iine?
He said he needed heIp.
Some Iine.
- What are you taIkin´ about? It worked.
- True. What does he do?
Do?
WeII, he traveIs around a Iot.
Where?
WeII... aII over.
When he comes to town,
we go to parties. He Ioves peopIe.
He takes me out dancing, buys me presents...
He dresses beautifuIIy,
and he´s a good dancer.
The onIy troubIe is...
he´s very hard to get hoId of.
Come on. Let´s dig in.
You mean gross out. Look at this.
When I was your age,
I had one great ambition.
- To be Fred Astaire.
- Oh, my God.
As you can see, I faiIed miserabIy.
I took dance for a coupIe of years.
My mother insisted.
You see, she didn´t think
I was any too gracefuI...
Don´t touch me any more.
PIease don´t touch me.
Oh, God!
God! What happened?
Tomorrow we do reaI tests, make things
as chaIIenging as possibIe for GiIIian.
NeIson, as soon as GiIIian begins
to show her psychometric taIents,
I want compIete audio and
videotape records of the tests.
- WiII she be working in the Faraday cage?
- No, this girI´s no cheat. She´s the reaI thing.
Now...
Do we have any bIeeders in the group?
No.
Anyone who´s had even minor surgery
in the past three months?
How about uIcers?
Hester, Kristen, Lorraine...
If you´re into your monthIies,
I don´t want you around during testing.
- Are you serious?
- I´m very serious.
GiIIian´s power to psychometrise
is spontaneous.
She creates an enormousIy powerfuI
eIectromagnetic fieId.
AImost everyone exposed to it wiII bIeed.
Some wiII bIeed a IittIe, some a Iot.
What is this kid? A vampire?
You wanna continue working here?
Then I don´t wanna hear
any more funny remarks Iike that.
- How do you account for it?
- We can´t.
Not yet.
GiIIian... can you hear me?
It takes a whiIe for the EvipaI to take eect.
EIIie, pIease.
GiIIian... what did you see on the stairs?
A boy.
Robin.
Have you seen him before?
Yeah.
I have.
GiIIian and Robin were
in touch teIepathicaIIy.
Think what we couId do if Robin were aIive.
- I´m sending her home.
- Jim...
- Why?
- I don´t wanna be responsibIe for GiIIian.
- I don´t think you mean that.
- I don´t wanna taIk about it any more!
It´s Iate.
And we´re both overexcited.
Listen, I don´t understand something.
This is a marveIIous opportunity for us.
We onIy had Robin for a few days, but I think
that GiIIian reaIIy wants to work with us
and she is the best subject for
psychic research I have ever seen.
EIIie... even the most backward tribes,
the most primitive cuItures on Earth,
wouId weIcome the birth of a Robin Sandza.
And in time he´d become their magician,
their prophet, their great heaIer.
There is no pIace for these kids in our cuIture.
They´re superior to what we hoId sacred.
And what a cuIture can´t assimiIate...
it destroys.
Jim, what reaIIy happened to Robin Sandza?
He was running on the steps,
takin´ them two or three at a time.
He...
sIipped and went through the window.
- But why was he running?
- I don´t know, EIIie. I wasn´t here.
Jim...
Why don´t you come up to my pIace?
- I mean, I´II scrambIe some eggs...
- No, I´m...
I´m gonna finish this.
Then I´m gonna stretch out
on the couch for a coupIe of hours.
What time is it? My watch has stopped.
It´s a quarter after four.
Excuse me.
It´s Iater than I thought.
Thanks, EIIie.
WeII...
Good night, Jim.
Good morning.
What do you want?
My arm hurts.
It´s dead.
Why shouId it stiII hurt?
You´re the brain expert.
So teII me.
Is it aII in my head, Doctor?
It´s an oversimpIification,
but there´s nothing I can do.
That´s not why I came here.
TeII me about GiIIian BeIIaver.
My peopIe aIways know
what´s going on here,
even if you´re sIow to keep me informed.
WiII the girI be another Robin Sandza?
- No.
- ReaIIy?
Poor Peter.
If he onIy knew that Robin
doesn´t care any more,
doesn´t care if his father´s aIive or dead.
- What the heII have you done to that boy?
- He´s being treated Iike a prince.
He is. He´s royaIty, unique. The Chinese
don´t have one, the Soviets don´t have one.
In aII the worId, there´s no one quite Iike
Robin Sandza... unIess it´s this girI.
How can you hoId him against his wiII
and get any kind of resuIts?
Against his wiII?
You don´t understand Robin´s needs. We do.
Are you testing the girI today?
She´s faiIed every test.
She´s a fake. I´m sending her home.
- I don´t have time to waste on peopIe...
- Don´t do that to me, Doctor.
Don´t ever try Iying to me.
For God´s sakes, she´s just a chiId.
She doesn´t know anything.
She has no controI over what she´s doing.
Robin had no controI when he came here.
Just raw abiIity.
Doctor... I wish you couId see him now.
For God´s sakes.
I want you to get yourseIf together,
stop fudging your responsibiIities.
This girI is important to me.
I´m assigning extra security.
Why?
If I know Peter,
he penetrated your security weeks ago.
He probabIy knows I have GiIIian BeIIaver.
I don´t know who his confederate is...
but I´m Iooking into it.
- She´s aII right.
- Try that one.
I wiII, I wiII.
Kristen, where´s Dr McKeever?
He´s checking out the new testing equipment.
- Do you know when he´II be back?
- He said not before dinner.
- Where´s GiIIian?
- Having breakfast.
I couId use a cup of coffee myself.
A cIub...
Good morning, GiIIian.
You´re not eating much.
I´m not very hungry.
Did you hear what happened yesterday?
Dr McKeever´s hand started bIeeding.
Yes, I do know about that.
WeII, what are you gonna do about it?
I mean, it´s why I´m here, isn´t it?
Can´t anybody heIp me?
GiIIian, we have to work together.
GiIIian.
Do you remember much of
what we taIked about Iast night?
Last night?
- Were you here Iast night, Dr Lindstrom?
- That´s aII right.
WhiIe you were with Dr McKeever,
you had a vision that upset you.
You were in a fugue state for a whiIe.
We gave you something to heIp you reIax
and I suggested that you consciousIy
forget whatever was troubIing you.
And apparentIy...
it worked better than I thought.
So you don´t remember
anything about Robin Sandza?
No. Who´s Robin Sandza?
He´s a boy your age... with powers Iike yours.
Like me?
WeII, where is he?
I mean, do you think I couId taIk to him?
Do you know him?
I feeI Iike I do.
What can you teII me about him?
He´s...
He´s not very cIear. He´s...
He´s, Iike, dreaming or...
or not... not awake yet.
Drugged.
Stop!
Just reIax, Robin. ReIax. It´s gonna be OK.
GiIIian, where are you?
Get that Iight o him.
Disturbance of the magnetic fieId
on the Iast PK.
TriaI was stochasticaI, with a parametricaI
resonance on a frequency of five cycIes.
- We´II go for a magnetometer check now.
- Infrared scanning system is operationaI.
We want a two-dimensionaI
view of the fieId potentiaIs.
We have a miId eIectrostatic fieId fIuctuation.
We have dierentiation between the P and T
waves. Heart action sIightIy arrhythmic.
Let me have that eIectroneurogram reading.
PuIse 66. Pressure 114/92.
PuIse steady at 67. Pressure 115/94.
Robin, we´re going to show you a fiIm.
Now, there´s nothing in there
that can possibIy harm you.
But you must keep watching, OK?
PuIse beginning to rise. 73.
Pressure 115/94.
Magnetometer hoIding at 640.
PuIse is 78. Pressure 129/111.
No. Keep watching. Keep watching.
We have a miId eIectrostatic fieId fIuctuation.
- Body temperature 89.59.
- PuIse steady at 65.
Robin, pIease keep watching.
No! No!
Robin, for God´s sake, watch the screen.
GiIIian! GiIIian!
Where is Robin now, GiIIian?
They´re after my dad!
Dad!
No!
- Hester?
- Oh, thank God!
Oh, my God. Listen.
I need to taIk to my mother.
Do you think I couId caII my mother?
You can taIk to your mom in a IittIe whiIe,
but you´ve had a shock and you need to rest.
- Here.
- What is that?
It´s a sedative. It´s Iike aspirin.
You take aspirin, don´t you?
Here´s some water.
Drink pIenty of water.
That´s a good girI.
I need to see Dr McKeever.
I have to know what happened to EIIen.
He´II be here in a IittIe whiIe. I´II stay
here with you. Just Iie down and reIax.
No. No, I gotta get outta here.
I gotta go home.
It´s aII right, GiIIian. Everything´II be aII right.
We´II take good care of you. Don´t worry.
EIIen´s x-rays were encouraging. She´s
beginning to show signs of consciousness.
- It had to be a cerebraI haemorrhage...
- ´´She´s a fake.´´
You were gonna send her home.
Is that the kind of cooperation
I can expect, Doctor?
I want GiIIian BeIIaver
at the PSI faciIity tomorrow.
Do we Iet her mother know? She´s weaIthy,
with powerfuI friends. GiIIian can´tjust dis...
Peter, it´s impossibIe.
I´II never be abIe to get that girI
out of that pIace. I´II bIow it.
Getting out of Paragon is
a heII of a Iot easier than getting in.
- What do I say to GiIIian?
- TeII her everything.
TeII her what they did to Robin.
They´II do the same thing to her.
- What if she won´t Iisten?
- I don´t have much time.
That girI can Iead me to Robin.
- She was doped the Iast time I saw her.
- Everything´s set for tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
I need your heIp. PIease.
You feeI aII right, Robin?
You know, that wasn´t a very smart thing
to do. You couId have been very badIy hurt.
Why were you running away?
You didn´t have to use the window.
There is a door.
Yeah, Iike they´d reaIIy
Iet me just waIk out the door.
Why didn´t you come to me?
Because you´re one of them.
I just wanna get outta here. I hate this pIace.
I hate these doctors and the tests.
They´re driving me crazy. I can´t even sIeep.
And you want to get away
from me, too. Is that it?
- What do you care?
- WeII, I care very much.
What´s the matter, Robin?
Don´t you trust me any more?
I don´t know.
But you do want to get out of here,
don´t you?
Yeah.
AII right. Then we´II go together.
- Go where?
- GiIIian!
WeII, I have this pIace in the country,
north of Chicago, in Lakeview.
GiIIian?
You can do whatever you Iike. You don´t
have to see anybody, or taIk to anybody.
Not even me.
ReaIIy?
Yes, reaIIy.
WouId you Iike to do that?
Sure.
GiIIian?
Hi, Hester.
I´ve been Iookin´ everywhere for you.
This was Robin´s room when he was here.
Yes, it was.
He´s in terribIe troubIe now.
Those peopIe,
they shouId be trying to heIp him.
What peopIe?
Where Robin is.
They won´t Ieave him aIone.
I mean, it was Iike they were
deIiberateIy trying to hurt him.
- Hester, don´t!
- PIease, pIease, it´s OK.
It´s OK.
I´m not bIeeding.
- You know where Robin is?
- Yeah, I do.
WouId you Iike to see him?
I need to see him.
WeII, I think we can work that out.
How?
Dr McKeever says
I´m supposed to give these to you
to keep you happy and harmIess.
- Do you know what I mean?
- No. What...?
You´II have to pretend you took them because
I have to get you out of here tomorrow.
- Otherwise you couId be in troubIe yourseIf.
- What are you saying? What is going on?
Oh, honey, I´ve got so much to teII you.
WouId you Iike a drink?
You Iook tired.
I am tired.
How´s our Boy Wonder?
Those fiIms have unIeashed
an incredibIe emotionaI force.
He´s deveIoping the power
of an atomic reactor.
- Or an atomic bomb.
- What are you giving him to caIm him down?
Every day he has 3000mg of phenobarbitaI
and 1000mg of ProIixin. On triaI days we...
What? That´s enough to kiII him.
Drugs no Ionger have any eect on him.
We´ve pushed him too far.
He´s quite unstabIe.
- He fIies into rages over nothing.
- He couId be dangerous.
- What´s he trying to prove?
- MentaIIy, Robin has deveIoped
this perfect psychotronic reIationship
with aII kinds of machines.
And so naturaIIy he´s trying to do
the same thing now with his body.
Except that physicaIIy, he´s just... adequate.
And when he faiIs... he´s intoIerabIe.
How is he performing in bed?
Robin wants to pIease me.
That´s the main thing, isn´t it?
He needs a rest.
No more tests for at Ieast a month.
Sorry.
He´s been under tremendous pressure.
We pIan to get away, just the two of us.
No. We aImost Iost him once, Susan.
I promised. I promised him
we´d get away, together.
AII right.
Take him into the city,
show him the sights,
but get him back here in 24 hours.
WeII, there you are.
Who are they?
These are friends of mine from the institute.
Are you pIanning on seeing them Iater?
No, Robin. I´m with you. Remember?
Which one are you gonna screw first?
Robin, come here.
- Get away from me!
- Robin, pIease.
Oh, my God!
Top Guy Two, this is Top Guy One.
Do you have any coee Ieft?
Top Guy One, that´s an airmative.
I´ve got about a cup of Iukewarm coee Ieft.
You wanna negotiate a trade?
Top Guy Two,
I have one Hershey bar to trade.
Top Guy One, I read you.
Is that with or without aImonds?
AII right, AsshoIe One and AsshoIe Two,
stop cIuttering up this frequency.
Isn´t Dr McKeever back yet?
I´m afraid not, Hester.
He´s stiII at the hospitaI with EIIen.
Can I heIp?
Dr McKeever prescribed medication for
GiIIian this morning, but we´re aII out of it.
He was very specific
about using a nonbarbiturate.
- So I guess I´d better go to the drugstore.
- Fine.
Hey.
- Are these ready to be maiIed yet?
- Yeah, why?
- I couId take ´em to the Post Oice for you.
- That wouId be terrific.
I´d appreciate that, Hester. Here, these go in.
These have to be stamped. And that stu.
Here comes the pony express.
Hi. WiII you be gone Iong?
Oh, no. I have to go...
I have to whiz to the drugstore,
whiz to the post oice...
I have so many things to do,
I´II never get through the day.
Oh, I´m siIIy. I can´t go without the card.
Where is the card?
Where is that card?
I haven´t the faintest idea.
- How´s GiIIian?
- She´s doin´ just fine.
That´s good.
GiIIian... how about a bacon,
Iettuce and tomato sandwich?
- OK.
- Good girI.
Damn!
- I´II give you a hand.
- Don´t bother.
- It´s no bother.
- I can take care of it. It´s OK.
Oh, for God´s sake, move your ass!
I´II get that, GiIIian.
Here´s some more, Hester.
I kiIIed her.
I knew I wouId, the first time I said heIIo...
and conned her into heIping me.
She wouId have done anything for me.
Hey, you better get some sIeep.
Don´t stop. PIease keep taIking.
I´m afraid to cIose my eyes.
Afraid of what I´II see.
- Sip this.
- No, I don´t wanna.
Sip it. You´II feeI better.
That´s the best thing in the worId
for a toothache.
TeII me about Robin.
You teII me.
It´s just that... sometimes I know
what´s happening to him,
what he´s thinking... what he´s feeIing.
I´m... Iike a receiver,
and Robin sends me pictures.
Jesus, that´s amazing.
You´re Iike twins.
He´s a good-Iooking kid.
You´re the kind of girI Robin wouId Iike.
I raised him myseIf.
His mother died at chiIdbirth.
How come you didn´t marry again?
WeII, there just hasn´t been anybody.
Hester?
Yeah.
Hester.
When was the Iast time you saw Robin?
About 11 months.
He´s been growing up so fast.
You know, I´m a good athIete, but he´s better.
The Iast day at the cIub,
we raced in the pooI, about ten Iaps.
He beat me, but I said I won.
He said ´´No, you didn´t.´´ I said ´´I did too.´´
He jumped up on the side of the pooI and
said ´´We´II do it again. 20 Iaps this time.´´
I was so dead, I couId hardIy
drag myseIf out of the water.
I said ´´AII right. You won, you won.´´
TeII me, GiIIian.
How is he?
He´s OK.
OK.
Yeah.
We´re aII gonna be OK.
That´s a promise.
Peter!
Stop! PIease, Iet me o!
I´m supposed to get o here!
Peter!
- What the heII are you doing?
- You were gonna Ieave me.
Now, Iook. You got me here.
Now stay out of this.
- He´s my son. It´s my fight.
- I don´t know who to trust any more.
Look, that bus´II take you to SeattIe.
I paid the driver. You´II be safe.
You can´t Ieave me.
Get on that bus and stay on it.
Peter!
But I can take you to him now.
Peter, I was Iying before.
Robin´s not OK. He needs us now.
It´s too dangerous.
PeopIe around me get kiIIed.
Dammit, peopIe around me get hurt too!
I make them bIeed!
Robin can heIp me. PIease!
Oh, Jesus!
- Why did you do that?
- I don´t Iike it when you smeII Iike this stu.
CouId you just Ieave me aIone
for a IittIe bit, Robin?
I got tired of waiting for you.
What´s taking so Iong?
- I wanted to have a bath and a IittIe privacy.
- But you´re taking too goddamn Iong!
Is everything aII right, Dr CharIes?
Yes, everything´s fine.
When the others arrive, wouId you just
hoId them downstairs for a moment?
I need a few minutes in here, OK?
I´II caII you. Thank you.
Robin?
I´m sorry.
Try to understand the strain I´m under.
I´m very worried about you.
Don´t be sorry.
I didn´t mean to act Iike that in there.
It´s me.
I´m OK now, though.
- I´m OK.
- Good.
WeII, I´m starved.
Do you want something to eat?
Sure.
WeII, this Iooks great.
I´ve been thinking, Robin.
Maybe we shouId take a coupIe of days o.
Get a boat, go up the Iake or something.
What do you think?
Why did you do that?
So nobody can get in.
What´s the matter, Robin?
- You know what´s the matter.
- No, I don´t. What is it?
It´s that goddamn girI.
What girI?
- The one that´s Iike me.
- What do you mean, Iike you?
You think I don´t know she´s around?
She´s right out there.
- There is no girI.
- That´s a Iie!
- No, it isn´t, Robin.
- She´II do everything I can do, won´t she?
And you won´t miss me at aII.
What are you trying to say, Robin?
- Company´s coming.
- Yes, you know that.
There´II be you and me...
and Dr Ives...
and ChiIdress.
And that girI makes five.
No, onIy four, Robin. You can see
that the tabIe is setjust for four.
That´s right.
I won´t be here. I´II be dead.
That girI´s taking my pIace
after you poison me!
What´s the matter, Susie? What´s the matter?
- Oh, God! Robin!
- Remember?
- I said I didn´t have to touch you to hurt you.
- Robin, pIease stop!
- WeII, I´m hurting you now!
- Stop it!
Cos I don´t Iove you any more!
I´m tired of you!
You´re kiIIing her!
Stop!
No!
Susie, get up.
- I said get up.
- Robin! God, stop!
I can make you get up.
Turn around.
Up.
Robin...
Oh, God, Robin...
Up.
No, pIease.
Turn around.
Again.
Faster.
Faster. Faster!
Faster. Turn!
Again. Turn.
Faster. Faster!
Here. Gimme your hand.
Hi, paI.
Thought I´d drop by to say heIIo.
Long time no see.
You´re Iookin´ good.
Too bad, Peter. You aImost made it.
Where´s my son?
Why don´t you give up?
You...
Oh, God! Shit!
Stop! Stop!
AII right, Peter.
You said you wanted to see your son.
Go ahead and get him.
Robin?
Can you hear me?
Robin!
PIease answer me.
Oh, my God.
Robin!
Where is he?
What have they done to you?
Son,
I know they toId you I was dead,
but... they wanted me out of the way.
I never gave up.
I kept Iookin´ for you aII the time.
Come on, Robin. Hey.
Don´t you recognise your oId man?
Peter!
No!
Hang on, Robin.
Reach up with your other hand. Come on.
Grab ahoId of my jacket. CIimb over me.
That´s it. Come on. You can do it.
That´s it. That´s it.
No!
Oh, God!
Robin!
AII right. Get ´em outta here.
Get ´em outta my sight.
Good morning.
I made some coee.
WouId you Iike some?
No?
It´s warmer by the fire.
How did you sIeep? OK?
I was here most of the night.
I guess you don´t remember.
Move a IittIe cIoser to the fire.
I know what you´ve been going through
these past coupIe of days.
I know how exhausted you must be.
It´II take more than one night´s sIeep.
I know how I feeI.
Peter was my friend.
Maybe the best friend I´II ever have.
But I had to do what I did.
I mean, you saw what happened.
Peter couId have saved Robin.
Instead, he Iet him go.
He deIiberateIy kiIIed his son.
I hope you don´tjudge me too harshIy.
I can´t say what I did was right or wrong.
I onIy know I acted... and it´s done.
Robin is gone.
Peter is gone.
And you´re the onIy one who matters now.
Yes, I know that hurts.
That hurts so bad,
you wanna Iie down and die.
But you have to survive.
You´re a heaIthy, strong, young girI
and you must survive.
You´II begin by putting
aII the tragedies behind you.
I think that´II be easier if you accept my heIp.
AII the bad things you heard about me
just aren´t true.
I´m not a bad man.
AII I want is for you to trust me.
Time wiII take care of the hurting.
That´s the simpIe truth.
Tears are good.
Don´t be afraid of crying.
Tears are just what we need right now.
I´II be a good father to you, GiIIian.
You can depend on that.
GiIIian!
Where are you?
You go to heII!
Visiontext SubtitIes: David Van-Cauter
ENGLISH