I read your article.
- Article?
More like a blurt if you ask me.
It was well written.
- Spare me your sympathy Marcus.
Come on Carmen.
How long you gonna be
bitter about your work.
its bullshit.
i write one Controversial article
and im pushed down to the bottom of the food chain.
you probably shoulda left it alone,
you knew it was gonna get you in trouble.
can we just stop talking about this please?
ok , well what do you want to talk about?
maybe the fact that half the time you spend with me,
your typing on the phone?
or that you break our plans after we make them?
cos im good with iether
wheres this coming from?
forget about it, im gonna get going.
no! Seriously, what is this
You think that this is fun for me?
it seems liek everytime we hang out,
your mind is somewhere else.
I am swamped with work right now marcus,
you know that.
yeah so am i, but i turn it off when im with you.
you gotta give a little.
- oh so now im selfish?
Yeah, kinda.
- ok, i think thats enough.
Yeah, I think it is, im outa here.
marcus..
Bees?
- Yeah, bees.
A farmer in orchid medow, Omaha caims that non of the bees
do not return to the hive
and only 20% of the
crop is being pollinated.
Why dont we try something else
ive got a lead on the Eric Taylor case.
look .. a young man goes back packing across Europe and
goes missing, it happens all the time.
its a dead case.
- No, there's more to it than that.
He was last seen leaving a motel in Kozki, Poland.
Sara and I have have been doing some research.
we found record of 5 tourists who have gone missing
during the last 50 years,
while travelling through the exact same area.
Carmen, how many times do i have to tell you?
Listen ok , the strange thing is that shortly
after they disappear ...
their luggage shows up at random cities
all over eastern Europe.
now i spoke to Laura Taylor,
Eric's mom ...
she recently received a call from prague airport
saying they had erics luggage.
theres no record of him ever entering the Czech Republic.
that doesn't sound like fresh concrete evidence to me.
Have you ever been
to an airport?
Luggage gets lost all the time.
Not interested.
And Carmen
I do not want you and sarah wasting company time,
with this misisng person stuff.
are we clear?
Hello.
- Hi mrs. Taylor.
I'm Carmen Berk.
- Carmen,its so  nice to finally meet
you,please, call me Laura.
This is Sara Titasal, she
is an intern at our company.
Hello Laura.
- its a pleasure,
please come in.
Eric had been planning
his trip for over a year.
He was.. never much into school.
He always just wanted to travel.
and where are the police with this now?
its an absolute joke.
i contacted theKoski police,
they say they found nothing.
I contacted the police here ...
and after waiting days for them to get back to me ...
they call and tell me that eric
is now officially on a missing persons list.
and that his case
has been moved to a different department.
You mentioned you've been contacted about erics luggage,
have you been able to claim it yet?
Yes, it's upstairs in his room.
All his clothes are there, his books,
his journal, his hotel receipts.
di you tell the police that?
i mean, there could be evidence.
yes Of course, I called them right away.
They told me that they were too backed up to come.
That they would get to it, when they could.
would it be ok if i take a look at erics luggage?
there may something there that may help us.
Yes, ofcourse, please.
will you forgive me if i dont escort u up
I find it difficult to be in that room.
- I understand.
thank you
It's upstairs on the right.
I'll make some tea.
- ill help you.
That was Eric and his cousin, when
they decided they wanted to get tattoos.
I told them they were
crazy, but ...
Eric really wanted one.
Is this your husband?
- Yeah, that's my Jim.
He passed away five years ago.
I'm sorry.
- it hurt eric alot.
Laura , can i borrow this for the time being?
its erics journal.
but id really love to spend some more time with it
I don't see why not.
I don't imagine the police will want it any time soon.
Thank you for your time.
The last journal entry..
Alvainia.
Leave me alone.
look I hate fighting with you.
well obviously were fighting for a reason.
- I know. And I agree.
my head hasn't been in this relationship lately.
But I want to fix that.
which is why i think you should come on this trip with me.
I appreciate that.
But if were going to take a trip together,
why dont we go to the Cayman Islands or something?
Because there is no story in the Cayman Islands.
right..right.
- Come on Marcus.
I think your a great photographer and
I want you to shoot this.
tell you what, Ill leave my
BlackBerry in the hotel.
I do not know, Carmen it sounds
a little dangerous.
could be.
- I'm not kidding.
im surprised that Dale would even allow this,
this sounds like a police matter.
Yeah, well the police aint doing shit.
I'm going no matter what.
i have to, ive already booked the tickets
just think about it alright.
I gotta get back.
heres the contact info for Carl Pierson,
hes the farmer with the dying crops.
theres another farm house just east of him with the same problem.
These bees are literaly just dying off.
Anyway.
He looks forward to meeting the two of you.
this should be a good experience for you Sarah.
are you excited?
Yeah..very excited.
Well. Keep up the good work girls. Rock and Roll.
- Rock and Roll.
marcus
Yeah? Okay, great.
Oh no, we should have everything prept soon.
No we'll break up the details later.
I'm really glad your doing this.
ok talk to you soon
bye.
Okay, were good to go.
Marcus is gonna shoot for us.
Listen, I want you to start checking out
motels in Poland
start with the one Eric was staying at in Kozki.
alright
I can not believe were doing this.
Were gonna have to start brushing up on our Polish.
- already a step ahead of you.
so, what else we know about this place.
Not much.
They make their own clothes,
they grow their own food.
apparently the lands known for growing mushroooms.
it doesnt look like eric was in  Alvainia for very long,
theres only a few journal entries.
Hey listen to this one.
theres something odd about this village,
the people seem very odd and distant.
There are no motels or hostels, so
im roughing it in an old barn.
ive noticed some kind of smoke looming
above the tree line on the outer edge of the village.
i thought it was a fire at first,
but it actually seems to be more like a fog,
just sitting there.
was this kid eating the mushrooms by any chance?
That must be the turn up ahead.
well.. i guess were here.
pull over here, well walk.
Eric wasn't kidding about this place.
Oh my God, thats sick.
Come on, hes just a farmer.
need i remind you where hot dogs come from?
You said they teach English i school here right?
- Yeah thats what i read.
Hi there. Those are beautiful.
Do you speak English?
Yes.. little.
My name is Carmen,
thats marcus, and sarah.
What's your name?
- Lidia.
Lidia, thats a very pretty name.
Thank you.
We are journalists from America.
Do you know America?
Yes, cheeseburgers.
Have you ever travelled outside
Alvainia, Lidia?
No, not allowed.
Thats too bad.
Do you like it here?
No? how come?
listen Lidia, we're looking for a young
man, his names Eric Taylor, have you seen him?
You have to go.
- Have you seen this man Lidia?
Let's keep moving.
Is this town Christian ?
I do not know, it
seems really strange tho.
look at that guy, there treating him like roaylty.
holy shit..
speaking of strange.
That's it, thats gotta be what
Eric was talking about.
well how can that be? its still here.
What the hell is it?
Im not sure,
but its the last thing he wrote about in his journal.
i say we check it out.
i dont understand how it can just be sitting there,
in that one part of the forest?
I can see why Eric was intrigued.
I'm sorry,do you speak English?
- You, go.
We are looking for someone,
maybe you can help us.
get your hands off me
hey!!
English yeah? You are English?
so go to England.
Go.
alright, were going.
Relax.
There is nothing for
you here English.
Pull over Marcus.
- What? Why?
just pull over for a minute
We have to go back.
- what, are you kidding me?
Those guys looked like they
wanted to kill us.
There hiding something up there in that forest.
No, they wanted us out of there the minute we got into town.
No, that guy followed us half way round the village
it wasnt till we started walking towards the fog
that he came after us.
that was the one place they wouldnt let us go
and the last place eric may have been.
you dont think thats a major coincidence?
Carmen , we cant.
We have to.
- Why?
because if we dont.. my career is done.
Dale does not even know we're here,
he thinks we are in Omaha
covering some bullshit story.
if i go back empty handed
im finished
Are you fuckin serious?
You never got a go ahead?
Wait ...
you didnt tell him?
hold on a sec.. you knew about this too?
look, there hiding something up there in those trees
and i want to find out what it is.
We came all this way, we cant just turn back now.
Please Marcus, I need this.
We check it out and thats it.
ok
You should have known better,
than to get her mixed up in this.
she wanted to be here here.
- She's not your kid.
It should be straight ahead from here,
im pretty sure the church is off that way.
Yeah this feels right.
This is so strange.
Hows it not moving?
It's so dense.
It's too dense.
- What do you mean.
I can take a photo of what ever this is from here,
but theres no way i can get a decent shot its so foggy
lets head in, check it out.
- What difference does it make carmen?
we cant shoot what we cant see.
we didnt come all the way up here
so we could take a picture of some cloud
sitting in a forrest marcus
not exactly the story im looking for.
yeah
well the story your looking for is gonna get us caught.
Oh my god ,
would you stop worrying,
no one even knows were here.
Yeah,
no one in the whole fuckin world knows were here.
Jesus Carmen.
Ok what the hell
where is she?
i dont know,
but we should definetly be getting the fuck out of here.
Were not just gonna leave her here Marcus.
- i didnt say that.
alright, wait here, Ill go see
what's going on.
hold on.ill go check it out
No Marcus
i brought us here.ill go
Be careful.
What happened?
Where is Carmen?
- She is looking for you.
Carmen, she's here.
carmen..are you alright
are you hurt?
hey..are you hurt?
No, im alright.
We should go.
What did you see?
I saw a statue.
Yeah, i saw it too.
lets talk about this on the way back to the car.
carmen, leave it alone
lets just go.
Lidia, what are you doing here?
I know where your friend is.
you know where Eric Taylor is?
yes - i show you you
Come, follow.
I really think that
we need to get out of here.
We going
come on.
In there.
in here.
Oh my God.
Jesus.
Ok guys, Eric has to be in one of these.
here gimme a hand.
its Eric.
yeah thats not coming off.
it feels like its attached in the centre somewhere
That symbol,
its the same one from the church
Lidia, what have they done
to him, whys he wearing...
She's gone.
She locked us in.
- What? Why would she do that?
Probably cos it was part of her fucking plan carmen
well Can you get us out?
There's somebody down here.
i got it, come on.
- Let's go.
We should go.
- yeah no shit,
but wheres the car from here?
lets head back this way.
hey,you ok?
yeah
there was a bit of path up here,
we just gotta find it.
Wait, stop.
oh fuck!..lets go.
come on
Wait..wait,
marcus hold on
we cant stop here.
where are we even going?
i dont know, but not here.
- Can you run?..in a sec
we cant stay out in the open
come on, go to that barn
come on!
Come on,get inside.
can You see them?
marcus?
no
just keep quiet
We never should have come here carmen.
this whole fucking thing was a mistake
I'm sorry.
This is all my fault,
I shouldnt have been so selfish
i just wanted a good story
Please Marcus
please,
im so sorry for everything.
Oh my God.
lets get out of here
go sarah..hurry
Come on.
Wait here.
Sara, Im right here.
What have you done?
Marcus Wait.
No,no,no
we have to keep moving
Do not touch me.
We need a car.
were gonna go to that farmhouse
were gonna get a vehicle
and where gonna get the hell out of here
you dont have to run any more ok?
lets go.
Come on.
i have to get the keys,
im gonna go inside.. you wait here
No, Im comin with you.
Stay behind me.
im not gonna hurt you
I need your truck, I need
the keys to the truck.
Calm down, we just
need your keys.
I dont wanna hurt anyone
you just give us the keys,
and we will leave
the keys, where are they?
relax.
Dont move.
Who else is in the house?
Shut up.
in the other room..now !!
English, you speak English?
He say you must leave.
Where are the keys to the truck?
- I do not know.
Ask your father where they are,
or im gonna pull this trigger.
he needs to tell me now
i am not fucking kidding
The kitchen, there in the kitchen.
Come, I'll show you.
alright,
lets go
I'm sorry, but i have to.
Please, the woman ,
she is evil, she has seen the statue
please
are you alright?
I have tasted the blood and flesh
of fallen angels.
There is no redemption.
Your men are weak.
Help me Marcus.
He will take you where you need to go
what is it up there? in the trees
this is curse
left here on our land from long ago
It can not be undone.
created by sub-stance
feel free to upload to any sites you wish