(birds chirping)
(crows cawing)
(woodpecker pecking)
So tell me again
why we're awake.
Come on. Where are you
gonna see this in the city?
Uh, nowhere. That's why
I choose to Iive in the city
and not in the middle
of the woods.
- I need a coffee.
- I think there's a Starbucks up here,
- so we're going to be good.
- Starbucks? Are you serious?
- You got to admit this is amazing.
- No. I have to admit that we're Iost
- and we shouldn't be awake.
- Okay. We are not lost.
Do you hear that?
- Nope. Nothing.
- Yeah, exactly.
Where are all the birds?
It's really quiet.
I don't know, babe.
Maybe they're still sleeping.
Like we should be.
Come on, Iet's take a nap.
- No. We're not taking a nap. Come on.
- Just a teeny tiny one.
Just a Iittle further, okay?
- I need a minute. Nature calls.
- AII right. Just hurry up, babe.
- We got to keep moving.
- You have someplace to be?
(flies buzzing)
Oh, my God.
- Hey, Dale--
- Erica, stop! Don't come down here.
- What? Why?
- Just stop!
Erica: Dale, you're scaring me.
What's going on?
Dale, what the hell is all this?
Dale: Yeah, there's been
some sort of accident.
No, I don't know.
We're about a mile
off the Camp Nash Line.
- (Iow squeal)
- Dale?
(Iow growl)
Erica, quickly and quietly
back up. Come on.
Dale, what is it?
- (growling)
- Run! Go! Go!
Dale, what is it?!
- (grunting)
- Erica: What is it?!
- Jesus, Dale!
- Go!
- (grunting)
- Dale!
Erica, get up! Come on!
Come on, wake up!
Come on, get up! Come on!
Shh. Okay. Okay.
Okay. Stay here.
(crow cawing)
(wings flapping)
♪ Thought I saw the Jersey Devil ♪
♪ Up the road and around the bend ♪
♪ Dancing in his moccasins ♪
♪ Won't Ieave my home, Mister ♪
♪ 13th child of Mother Leeds ♪
♪ He's come back
and he's hunting for something ♪
♪ Wonder what
the Jersey Devil needs ♪
♪ Hey, hey, Mama,
better close your window ♪
♪ Take that peach pie off of the sill ♪
♪ Well, that Jersey Devil
has got a sweet tooth on him ♪
♪ Never been known to get his fill ♪
♪ Well, I thought I saw
the Jersey Devil ♪
♪ Up the road and around the bend ♪
♪ Thought I saw the Jersey Devil ♪
♪ Dancing in his moccasins ♪
♪ Every man and woman,
every child on Sunday ♪
♪ Looks up to the preacher man ♪
♪ Waits for him
to tell them something ♪
♪ They can finally understand ♪
♪ Well, I thought I saw
the Jersey Devil ♪
♪ Up the road and around the bend ♪
♪ I thought I saw the Jersey Devil ♪
♪ Dancing in his moccasins. ♪
Boy:
Oscar!
Ready to go, kiddo?
We talked about this,
Danny boy.
He's been gone for over a week.
He's coming home.
He was old.
I don't want to go,
not without Oscar.
(heavy metal music playing)
♪ Hold me ♪
♪ I find it hard to bear... ♪
I can't believe
you're missing Ben's party.
I know. This camping thing
is cruel and unusual.
♪ Well, I'm taking
myself out again ♪
♪ Won't Iet your god
frown on me... ♪
Hey.
The car's packed
and we're ready to go.
- Hi, Mrs. Vineyard.
- Hey.
- Sadie, Iet's--
- Okay.
You can tell my dad
I'll be right down.
- You're such a bitch.
- I am a princess compared to her.
(sighs)
(gasps)
- Sorry.
- Car's packed.
She isn't.
Why are you making her go
when she doesn't wanna come?
She's being a teenager.
But do you think making her
go on this trip is going to fix things?
We need this.
I need this.
Okay.
What?
- Hi, Dad.
- You ready?
- Two minutes?
- Go easy on her this weekend.
She's trying. Please?
- For me?
- Okay.
Your dad is pretty hot
for an old dude.
Shut up.
- I'd do him.
- Gross!
Did Daddy help you put up
the posters for Oscar?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
What happens if he comes back
when we're gone?
I don't think Mr. Peterson will mind
taking him in for a couple days.
- What if he's hungry?
- You know, baby,
dogs survived
for thousands of years
in the wild
before they became pets.
I think he'll be fine.
Danny?
Where is he going?
I don't know.
Hey.
You don't Iook so good.
You had a cold Iast week
and Sadie had a cold
the week before.
Will you knock off
the nurse act? I'm fine.
- Okay.
- Save it for the hospital.
What do you think
really happened to Oscar?
I don't know.
- Hey, buddy boy.
- Come on.
Sadie: Oh, my God.
Can you believe her attitude?
It's fine. It will be fine.
Don't worry.
- I'm going to miss you so much.
- I'm going to miss you, too.
- Okay, have fun.
- I'll call you as soon as I get back.
Okay.
See you, Mr. Vineyard.
(giggles)
- (Danny Iaughing)
- Leave me alone.
Leave me alone, you Iittle--
"Welcome to New Jersey."
That's very good.
Little man, what does that say?
"Guide to the...
Pine Barrens."
That's very good.
So who's Iooking forward
to going fishing?
Seriously, Dad?
Who goes camping?
I do.
And now we all do.
- (phone camera clicks)
- Richard: When I was young
and we came over from England,
Grandpa used to take us
to the Pine Barrens every summer
for our summer holidays.
It's a form of abuse that I haven't
brought you here already.
Why couldn't he have just made it
an annual trip back to London?
(cell phone beeps)
Please tell me there are no bears.
Nope. Deer.
Lots of deer, Iots of birds,
but no bears.
Great.
(crows cawing, birds chirping)
Sadie:
"The Jersey Devil.
For hundreds of years,
the Lenni-Lenape tribes
inhabited what is today
the Wharton State Forest.
The tribes fought bitterly
and united only in their fear
of 'Sic ay Mahtantu'--
- the evil spirit of the Pine Barrens."
- Richard: It's just a myth, Danny boy.
It's make-believe.
You know, it's made up.
It's Iike the Loch Ness Monster
or Bigfoot.
- It's just pretend.
- (cell phone beeps)
You don't have to worry about it.
AII right, all right.
(heavy metal music playing)
From now on,
we have no iPods,
no PSPs, and no phones.
- AII right, Sadie?
- What?
- You can't be serious.
- It's just four days.
If I can go without
talking to the bank,
then you can go without
talking to your friends.
- Daddy, watch out!
- (screams)
Sadie:
What the hell was that?
- Dad?
- Stay in the car.
Stay in the car.
(crow cawing)
(branch snaps)
(rustling)
- Oh, my God.
- Get back in the car.
- Holy shit.
Okay. Jesus.
- (car door closes)
- (low growling)
What just happened?
Dad, what the hell was that?
A bloody animal just collapsed
in front of the car
and we're not going
to talk about it?
- It's probably hunters, darling.
- Sadie: What? Is that Iegal?
- Richard: At the right time of year.
- Is it the right time of the year?
No.
Ranger:
Hey there.
- Can I help you?
- Taking the family camping.
- Oh, yeah? What's the name?
- Vineyard.
Here we go. All right,
you're in zone three, campsite F.
Just sign here for me.
I'd appreciate it.
Yeah.
Excellent. Just up ahead,
through the trees there.
- (music playing)
- (voices overlapping)
This is fantastic.
AII right.
Watch your head.
(grunts)
Take that for me.
(groans)
AII right. This one
is a Iittle bit Iighter.
Mr. Vineyard. I forgot
to give you this permit.
Could you put that on
your dashboard, please?
- Yes, of course.
- Well, hey there, buddy boy.
So you been
to the Barrens before?
I came here with my dad
quite a Iot when I was Iittle,
but it's the first time
I've brought my wife and kids.
That's great. Then I'm going to
spare you the routine then, okay?
Just stay in your designated spot here
and you know the drill.
- We saw a dead deer.
- Really?
Hey, can you take this to Mom
for me, champ?
- Good boy.
- Dead deer, huh?
- Dying deer.
- Where?
It was down on the Leeds Hallow Road
about eight miles back.
It stumbled out in front of us
and then just--
it just dropped down
in front of the car.
Entrails ripped out,
his antlers were gone.
I'll bet all the money in my wallet
those antlers
- are attached to Wyatt Barren's fence.
- Who's that?
Wyatt Barrens.
He's the piney wacko.
He Iives not too far from here.
He put up this barbed-wire fence
a couple years ago.
Deer have been known
to get themselves caught up in it.
The more determined ones,
well, they'll do whatever they can
to free themselves.
I'm going to go check
for that deer, okay?
- You and your family have a great time.
- Thank you.
- Zach.
- Hi.
- Oh, really?
- I'm Ryan.
- Hey.
- These are my buddies.
- You here with your family?
- Yeah.
Oh, by the way, you're going to want
to lock up your food at night.
Tie it up to a tree branch,
not in your tent.
Is that really necessary?
Well, we had an incident
a couple weeks back.
- What kind of incident?
- It was a bear attack.
A couple campers stumbled
across a bear feeding
and the bear got defensive.
You know how it goes.
I thought bears were not indigenous
to the Pine Barrens.
There's only a handful of them
and usually they do keep to themselves,
but, Iisten, just stick to the trails
and you'll be fine.
- You have a great time.
- Thanks.
- It's so freaking Iame.
- It's pretty Iame, eh?
Yeah, totally.
(Iaughing)
Richard:
Who's your new friend, Sade?
- Just some guy.
- Yeah?
How old is "just some guy"?
- Ow. Can you help me?
- Oh, are you okay?
- It still hurts.
- Still?
(heavy metal music playing)
Seriously?
- Say cheese, buddy.
- (laughing)
(cell phones ringing)
It's hot.
Yeah. It is hot.
The sun's setting,
so it will cool down in a few minutes.
Take a Iook at what I'm doing,
Danny boy.
You're going to have to know
how to set up your own tent someday.
Hey, will you do me a favor?
In the top of my backpack is my knife.
Can you get it for me?
Be careful.
Whew.
(growling)
Danny!
- Richard!
- (groans)
- Here, Richard.
- (screams)
Blood-- blood must have gone
to my head.
Here. Okay.
- Let's get up.
- No.
Hi.
So... you coming?
- Coming where?
- To the campfire.
Where you can have s'mores
and hot dogs,
and there will be ghost stories.
Camping, what do you think?
I wanted to set my own fire.
Well, we can do that Iater.
- AII right.
- Okay. I'll meet you out there.
Man: Oh, you missed it. 10 minutes
before your guys showed up to camp,
a family of deer
walked right through the site.
Richard: When we were coming here,
a deer walked in front of the car
and somebody
had removed its antlers.
The ranger said that they had
probably been torn off on a fence.
It wasn't a fence.
- I'm sorry?
- The deer and his antlers.
- It wasn't a fence that tore them off.
- Okay. What was it then?
It was the Leeds Devil.
- Oh-ho, Jersey Devil.
- Ooh.
Both:
Ghost story time.
Baby, you realize
this is just a story, all right?
Well, you know,
I'm going to go take a dump,
so I'll see you guys in a bit.
Nice. Lovely.
AII right, so the Jersey Devil.
Give us the story.
Well, it Iives in the woods.
These woods.
- What is it?
- Do you believe in witches?
- Witches?
- Not Iike the kind with black cats
and flying broomsticks.
A different kind.
A real witch.
Mother Leeds was the town whore.
She was never married.
She was always pregnant.
The story goes
that she had 12 kids
and she raised them
in these woods in a Iittle, tiny cabin
not too far from here.
As you can imagine,
with 12 kids, they just ran wild.
There was no man in her Iife
to help raise them.
So it kind of fell to the town
to take care of them, you know?
Feed them, protect them,
clothe them, educate them.
Eventually, the elders
grew tired of all of this.
They decided that the town shouldn't be
responsible for her offspring.
So they told her--
if she bore another child,
then she will be banished
from the Barrens forever.
Oh, no. Not banished.
Mother Leeds was furious
and she was scared.
I mean, banishment from the woods
meant certain death
for her and her family.
She was poor. She relied on the town
to take care of her kids
and give them the things
that she was unable to give them.
So she agreed
and Iife continued on.
The Iegend goes that one day,
Mother Leeds grew violently ill.
She stopped going to town,
she withdrew from people,
she became a total recluse.
These rumors started popping up
that she was practicing witchcraft
and making deals
and conjuring the devil himself.
Other rumors feared her dead.
The Iast rumor, it proved to be true.
Mother Leeds was pregnant.
Pregnant with her 13th child.
(giggles)
Woman:
She was hiding the baby.
She couldn't tell the elders.
With 12 kids,
keeping a secret, well--
- Did they find out?
- Oh, yeah.
They went to her cabin
to find out for themselves.
She was very much pregnant.
She pleaded and begged.
She told them that she
hadn't been with a man for years,
but they didn't believe her.
They agreed to Iet her stay in the cabin
until she gave birth.
As soon as the child was born,
she and her family had to move on.
She cursed the elders,
the town, the Barrens,
even the unborn baby.
She told them
that it wasn't hers.
- That it was the devil's baby.
- You all right?
Let him take it.
And take him the devil did.
On the night
that she went into Iabor,
after hours of agony,
she finally gave birth.
But what came out of Mother Leeds
was not human.
It had cloven hooves,
a serpentine tail,
a head of a horse,
and a kangaroo body.
(screaming)
The 13th child of Mother Leeds
was nothing short of the devil himself.
The midwife screamed,
she dropped the child
and it immediately
sprouted these wings
and started flying
all around the room.
It killed two of its siblings
before finally turning on Mother Leeds.
It attacked her.
It tore right into her.
- AII right. I think that's enough.
- No, no.
- What happened?
- It's okay. I'm big enough to hear.
- You sure?
- Yeah, Dad. He's big enough to hear.
What happens next, it varies
depending on who's telling the story.
I heard that the thing climbed up
the chimney and escaped into the forest.
Sadie: The book said that people
have actually seen it.
That's true. There's been countless
sightings over the years.
This is almost 400 years ago.
Yeah, and sometimes
if you're quiet enough,
you can actually hear it.
- (scoffs)
- Ryan: No, I'm serious.
- (giggling)
- Shh. Listen.
No, seriously, guys. Listen.
- (yells)
- (screaming)
Yes! Yes!
Woman:
Oh, my gosh!
You got punked!
What a bunch of bitches, huh?
Bitches!
- That was seriously messed up!
- Dude, relax. It was a joke.
Dad, calm down.
He was just joking.
(snaps)
Do I Iook amused, Sadie?
- Do I?
- Cynthia: Richard.
Look at your brother.
Look at him. Look at him.
- He's six years old.
- Man: Chill, bro.
- What the hell were you thinking?
- Richard, let's--
- Don't you touch me, man.
- Richard, stop.
- Get your hands off me.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Man:
Chill, chill.
Sorry.
I didn't mean-- okay.
What's up with your pops?
- You totally overreacted.
- I'm sorry.
I don't know what I was thinking.
Danny, are you all right?
You all right, honey?
Fine. I'm going to
take him to bed.
Take it easy, champ.
(pants)
(faint voices muttering)
(wings fluttering)
(Iow growling)
(Ioud growling)
(beast shrieking)
- What happened?
- Richard, are you okay?
No, no, no. I don't mean--
(cell phone buzzing)
- Were you on the phone?
- No.
Let me see it.
- Let me see your phone.
- No.
- Stop it.
- Give it here.
- Give it.
- Richard, stop it.
Brian?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Seriously?
(grunts, groans)
You need to calm down.
I have never cheated on you.
The paranoia has to stop now.
You told me
you'd stopped talking to him.
I did stop talking to him
and then he called me
out of the blue.
What else are you
Iying about, Cynth?
Huh? Am I going to have to
run around questioning you?
You are so jealous, Richard.
He said that he needed to talk.
- Oh, just talk?
- That's all we did. We talked.
- How naive are you?
- Ever since we got married,
I have cut ties
with every single guy friend.
(screeching, rumbling)
Richard?
I chose you.
I Iove you, Richard.
(moans)
Ow.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- I'll go and get your phone.
- No. I don't want my--
I don't care.
I just want to go to bed.
I'm going to--
I need to clear my head.
(birds hooting)
(rustling)
(gasps)
(faint voices muttering)
(birds chirping,
woodpecker pecking)
(winces)
Ryan: So your mom seems pretty cool,
but your dad doesn't.
Cynthia is not my mother.
Oh, yeah?
What's your story?
Not a very interesting one.
My mom died when I was seven.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
So what do you think
happened to Zach?
- (crows squawking)
- He went out in the woods Iast night
to take a piss
and he never came back.
That's crazy.
Hey.
We were starting to wonder
when you were gonna wake up.
- What time is it?
- It's after 11 :00.
- What?
- Yes.
Come here.
- How are you feeling?
- I'm better, thanks.
You are?
Because you really Iook Iike shit.
- Right back at ya.
- Thanks, babe.
You're so nice.
So...
- did you find it?
- What?
- My phone.
- No, I didn't.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- Where's Sadie?
- She went on a hike with that guy.
- With that douchebag?
- God, Richard.
- It's a hike.
- What's this?
He's been here since this morning
and he's been questioning everybody.
This is not camping.
We need to go further
into the forest.
I don't know whether
that's such a good idea, babe.
When she gets back,
we'll Ieave immediately.
Hey, Dad.
I'm going to need you
to pack your things up.
- Are we Ieaving?
- Just moving sites.
We're here for a reason.
Taking off so soon?
Moving sites.
Oh, where to?
Just gonna go
a couple of miles up the trail
to the Oswego Pointe.
Officer:
Can't say I blame you.
Not how I remember it.
Well, things have a way
of changing.
Scattering my dad's ashes.
Sorry for your Ioss.
You got a minute?
Seen you just woke up.
Richard:
Yeah, I had a bit of a headache,
but feeling better now.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, we're fine, hon.
We're just-- we're just chatting.
- Ma'am.
- Hi.
I'm Cynthia Vineyard.
Nice to meet you.
Pleasure. So when you
were up last night,
- did you notice anything strange?
- No. Why?
It's probably nothing.
One of their friends
disappeared Iast night.
Went into the woods
and didn't come back.
- Cynthia: You're kidding.
- If you ask me,
guy drank too much,
passed out somewhere,
and he's going to wake up
with one hell of a hangover.
- But I got to check, you know.
- Mm-hmm.
No, we didn't see
anything strange.
A camper thought he saw you
out walking around
in the middle of the night.
Thought maybe you'd seen
or heard something.
Nope.
No, you weren't walking around
or, no, you didn't see
or hear anything?
Neither.
Huh.
Well, it's probably nothing,
but given what happened
last week,
- we got to be a tad more cautious.
- What happened last week?
Well, a couple of hikers
ran smack into a bear's den.
Cynthia:
You're kidding.
I had no idea
that there were bears up here.
Well, a handful at most.
Black bears. Mostly stay to themselves.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, jeez.
I almost forgot. This wouldn't happen
to be yours, would it?
Eh, yes.
Yes.
Pretty safe to assume
that phone has made its Iast call.
Mm-hmm.
- You be safe out there, Cynthia.
- Thank you.
- And...
- Richard.
Bye.
Where are you from, Richard?
If you don't mind me asking.
- Philly.
- Philly?
- No, by way of England.
- Oh.
Well, hope you beat the rain.
Thank you.
Richard, why did you
just lie to him?
Richard: Oswego should be
just over to the west here.
It's where my dad and I
used to camp.
It's where he'd want to be.
Definitely.
(Danny whimpers)
Wait.
I'm sorry about your phone, Cynth.
I really didn't think
I'd thrown it that hard.
I don't understand what was wrong
with where we were.
Everything, Sade.
Everything was wrong with it.
- This is way better.
- Dad, I have to go to the bathroom.
Really?
- Number one or two?
- One.
AII right.
Look, you can go around here.
- Want me to come with?
- No.
AII right. Come on.
(grunts)
Here.
- Drink some water.
- I'm fine.
(urinating)
(flies buzzing)
We need to hike about another mile
and get to a clearing.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Need to scatter my dad's ashes.
I owe it to him.
(crow cawing)
Come on.
Move.
Stop it.
- Nearly there, guys.
- Sadie: Okay.
Sadie:
Careful. Over.
Did you see that?
What? A deer?
I don't think so.
- Careful here.
- Okay.
Sadie: Got it.
Watch out, buddy.
- Take my hand. You okay?
- Danny: Yeah.
Daddy, my feet hurt.
Cynthia: Do you even know
where you're going?
Daddy?
We're just going to have to carry you
the whole way then, aren't we?
(grunts)
(groaning)
- Dad, stop.
- (music playing faintly)
Listen.
(coughing)
- Cynthia: Danny?
- Something's over there.
Hello?
It's someone's campsite.
(music continues)
Hey, kiddo.
Are you okay?
(music continues)
(static crackles)
(gasps, screams)
Richard!
Danny, turn around.
Richard:
Danny, take this.
Help set up the tent
with your sister, okay?
- Cynthia: Richard, we can't stay here.
- (flies buzzing)
You see those clouds, Cynth?
We don't want to be in the middle
of the woods when they open up.
Anyway, we're two or three miles
from the main site.
(grunts)
It's okay, kiddo.
We're going to be home very soon. Okay?
Sadie, go over there
with your brother. Okay?
Oscar?
(whimpers)
Richard?
(snarling)
Richard, what are you doing?
I'm going to cut him Ioose.
(retching)
- Danny: I want to go home.
- I know.
Sadie: Tell me about it.
Cynthia, we're not actually
staying here, are we?
Cynthia: Do you think
this is my idea of fun?
This trip is important
to your dad.
Seriously, I mean,
what the fuck is this shit?
- Cynthia: Come on, Sadie.
- No. This is fucked.
Dead deer, dead dogs,
and all this "Blair Witch"
crazy shit hanging from trees.
Your dad is going to scatter
Gramp's ashes
in the river
where they used to fish.
Why don't we just throw Gramps in
this water and get the hell out of here?
It's not Iike
he'll know the difference.
Oh, my God.
Cynthia?
(flies buzzing)
Cynthia:
Danny, stay there.
(splashes)
Hello?
(rustling)
(Ieaves rustling)
(panting)
Hello?
Answer me.
Say something.
(branches creaking)
(rattling)
- Hey.
- Jesus.
Gee, sorry, man.
I didn't mean to scare you.
What are you doing out here?
Camping. You?
Was it you?
Following us?
Following you? No.
(branches creaking)
You okay, Mr. Vineyard?
Mr. Vineyard?
I think you should go back
to the main campsite.
I'm kind of meeting Sadie.
- You're what?
- She just texted me.
We're going for a walk.
Look, if you're mad about this whole
stupid story thing--
Do you believe
in the Jersey Devil?
What? You mean,
Iike the real thing?
The version I heard
is a Iittle bit different from yours.
The 13th child of Mother Leeds
was born normal.
Not deformed,
but she did do a deal
with the devil.
He would spare her sinner's soul
in exchange for the 13th child.
So when the baby was born,
she walked down to the river
by the side of her cabin...
and she offered up her son
to the devil...
...by drowning it.
(voices whispering)
Richard: One of the town elders
saw Mother Leeds
down by the bank,
drowning her Iittle baby.
So he rushed over...
but he was too Iate.
The baby was dead.
So he pulled Mother Leeds
away from the bank.
When he turned round,
the infant's body was gone.
Taken by the devil himself.
I thought I saw the Jersey Devil
when I was a Iittle boy.
- (branches creaking)
- (low growl)
(rain pattering)
Do you hear that?
Hear what?
(thunder rumbling)
I went fishing with Spider.
- Ah, that's Spider.
- Richard: Sadie, come here.
Richard:
Give me that. Give me the bag.
Sadie:
Dad! No! Give it back!
Dad! Give it to me!
What are you doing?
- Richard?
- Sadie: Dad, give me--
- Richard: Get off me!
- Sadie: What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Cynthia: Richard, stop!
- Dad!
- I said no phones!
- Give me--
- Get off me!
- Dad?
- (thunder rumbling)
Sadie, are you okay?
- You sound Iike a crazy person.
- She called that boy Ryan
- and she told him to come and meet us.
- So what?
That's what 17-year-olds do.
Not Iisten to their parents,
they text boys.
What the hell, Richard?
You wanted to come here,
so we came here.
You wanted to Ieave
the other campsite,
so we Ieft,
and now we're here.
You know what? This is not
bringing us any closer together.
You have a fever.
You Iook Iike shit.
We're lost in the middle
of this fucking forest. It's raining.
For some reason the other campers tied
their dog to a tree and they vanished.
Put yourself in our position.
This is insane.
There's something wrong
with my arm.
What? Let me see it.
(gasps)
I'm seeing things.
Things that I know aren't there.
Okay, fuck it.
As soon as this rain stops,
we're leaving here
and we're going to go to a hospital.
I Iove you and I know
that you are trying
to fix this family...
but this is not the way.
Okay?
Here.
Call your boy back.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Dad's acting fucking crazy.
Is he mad?
No. Not at you.
We're going to get the hell out of here
as soon as it stops raining.
Recording: You've reached Ryan.
Leave a message.
- He's not answering.
- (thunder rumbling)
He will. Trust me.
(thunder rumbling)
Hi.
You still have a fever.
I think that we should
get out of here tonight.
I'm sorry
if I'm scaring everyone.
I don't feel safe or comfortable
hiking out of here tonight.
The ground is mush,
it's going to be pitch black soon.
You can call the sheriff.
What is that?
I found it
in the other occupants' tent.
You went through their stuff?
I buried their dog.
I'm sure they won't mind.
- What Ianguage is this?
- I killed Oscar.
What?
About a month ago,
he started...
acting different.
- And strange.
- (barks)
Well, he was old.
I mean, what else could I do?
I mean, what if he attacked
Sadie or Danny?
(snarling, snapping)
I had to put him down.
He bit me.
I Ioved that fucking dog.
I think I'm going to go
and rest for a bit.
(grunts)
(thunder rumbling)
(bird hooting,
crickets chirping)
- Hey.
What are you guys doing?
We're rather unsuccessfully
trying to make s'mores, right?
- Well, at Ieast it stopped raining.
- Yeah.
Does that mean
we finally get to go home?
Cynthia:
When your daddy feels better,
we'll go home, okay?
Okay, well, I'm not getting
any service here,
so I'm going to walk around
and try to call Ryan.
Okay. If you're not back by the time
your father gets up,
there's going to be
a new ghost story
- to tell around the campfire, Sadie.
- Yup.
- I won't go far.
- Thank you.
Promise.
(phone ringing)
(distant ringing)
Recording: You've reached Ryan.
Leave a message.
Ryan?
- (phone ringing)
- Ryan?
- (distant phone ringing)
(branches crunching)
(ringing continues)
(ringing)
(dull thump)
(screaming)
Go inside the tent.
Get your father.
- What is it?
- Something's out there.
- What?
- I don't know, I just--
I was trying to call Ryan and I kept
hearing his phone ringing in the woods.
- Okay. Give me your phone.
- What are you doing?
I'm calling for help.
Shit. Okay.
Go inside that tent.
Cynthia:
Danny?
Hey, sweetie.
I want you to go out there
in the tent
with your sister, okay?
Go.
(gasps)
I can't get to sleep.
I keep trying to,
but I can't sleep.
When Oscar bit you...
did he have pus in his eyes...
and foam in his mouth?
Oscar's dead.
Okay.
(thunder rumbling)
- We've got to scatter Dad's ashes.
- Okay.
I want you to take this.
- What is it?
- It's a sleeping pill.
- Okay?
- What's wrong with me?
You just need to sleep.
Then we're going to
get out of here tomorrow.
Everything is going to be okay.
Okay?
Okay.
Put that in your mouth.
Here--
(gasps)
Okay.
The kids are scared.
I've got a headache.
I'll be better tomorrow.
(roars)
(thunder rumbles)
(whimpers)
I want to go home.
- Hi, guys.
- What's going on with Dad?
- Daddy is scaring me.
- Well, he's sick,
but guess what?
When we get
out of here tomorrow,
we're going to have him
all fixed up, okay?
- I want to go home.
- I know, kiddo.
What do you guys think
if I were to sleep in here tonight
and we have a giant sleepover?
What do you think?
Come here.
- It's okay, baby. It's okay.
- (sobbing)
(crow cawing)
(shuddering)
(Ieaves crunching)
(squealing)
(wings flapping)
(voices muttering)
(crow cawing)
(branches creaking)
(snarls, roars)
(distant screaming)
Cynthia:
Richard?
- It was here. It was just here.
- What was here?
- The Devil.
- Can you walk?
- You're hallucinating.
- It is real.
- It is not real.
- It was real.
I'm getting the kids
and we are Ieaving in two minutes.
- Your dad is sick.
- Sadie: Uh, no shit.
- We need to get him to a hospital.
- Wait, what?
- What's wrong with him?
- You take that.
- He was bitten.
- By what? What are you talking about?
- Cynthia?
- Oscar bit your dad.
It happened
a couple of weeks ago
and now there is a wound
on his arm that is infected.
- Oscar bit Dad?
- Hold on. Where's Oscar now?
(gasps)
Rabies?
Sadie: Hello?
Hello?
Is anybody out there?
(cell phone beeping)
Mommy said Oscar bit you.
Why?
He was confused.
He didn't recognize me.
Oh. Is that why he Ieft?
Because he was sorry?
He didn't have to Ieave.
I would still love him.
(phone ringing)
Hang on. Hello? Hello?
Hello? Can you hear me?
Operator:
9-1-1, please state your emergency.
Yes, my family and I are Iost.
My husband's sick
and we need help, please.
Operator: Okay. Please slow down, ma'am.
Where are you?
We're in the Pine Barrens.
Operator: The Barrens is a Iarge area.
Could you be more specific?
- We're in the Wa--
- Wharton State Forest.
Wharton State Park.
The Wharton State Forest.
Operator:
I need to know the trail.
- No, we're not on a trail.
- (screaming)
- Danny?
- Dad?
- Operator: Ma'am?
- Cynthia: Danny?!
Both:
Danny?!
- Danny?!
(cell phone ringing)
Ma'am, the 9-1-1 operator
traced your call to my county.
- He's dead.
- Sheriff: Who's dead?
- Who is this?
- There's a dead body.
My husband is sick.
I can't find my son.
Ma'am, I need you
to tell me your name.
- Cynthia Vineyard. Please.
- Cynthia Vineyard?
- Sorry. Get up. Get up.
- Ma'am, this is Sheriff Winters.
I met you and your husband
at the campgrounds.
I think I know
where you were headed.
Conserve your phone's battery
and just sit tight.
We're going to find you, ma'am.
Cynthia:
Danny? Danny?
(women panting)
Cynthia!
Get up.
Get up, please.
- What do you think it was?
- I don't know.
(sobbing)
What could have done this?
I don't know.
Dad? Do you think
it was Dad?
Stop that.
Sadie:
It was his knife.
- Cynthia, it was his knife.
- Stop it.
(sobbing)
Danny?!
Danny!
- (screaming, water splashing)
- Danny!
Danny! Dad!
Danny? Danny?
Danny?
Oh, my God. Danny!
(screaming)
Oh, my God! Danny!
- Oh, my God! Danny!
- Danny! Danny!
Danny! Danny!
- Help me. Danny!
- Cynthia!
Cynthia:
Help me. Go.
Danny.
Oh, my God. Danny.
Oh, my God.
- My God! Wake up!
- One two three four, five six seven.
One two three four five...
(panting)
Is he dead?
(yelling)
Somebody please help us!
Somebody please!
...six seven eight...
(coughing)
Cynthia:
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay.
Oh, my gosh.
- What have you done to my son?
- (screaming)
What have you done!
What did you do to my son?!
(groans)
Wake up!
I said wake up!
Wake up! Wake up!
Wake up!
No!
Cynthia!
(moaning)
(siren wailing)
Yeah. Richard and Cynthia Vineyard.
They registered two days ago
and they've been missing
since yesterday morning.
I don't have a good feeling
about this.
I've already got two men
in the woods looking.
This is the Vineyards' SUV.
- Any luck reaching that cell phone?
- No. It's going straight to voicemail.
The husband mentioned Oswego.
There's a clearing about two miles past
these campgrounds near the Oswego River.
- Let's go!
- I'll be two minutes behind you.
(Cynthia moaning)
We can go.
You know, me and Danny.
- We can go get help.
- Yeah.
We can just...
walk in a straight Iine.
I mean we're bound to find somebody.
Cynthia: Okay.
You don't Iet anything happen to Danny.
You don't Iet go of his hand.
You don't stop moving
until you find someone.
If you're not at that campsite
before sunset,
you come right back here, okay?
Okay.
It's three or four miles away.
Danny, come here.
Promise me that you're
going to protect your sister.
- Okay?
- (whimpers)
Dan--
- Will you come and untie me, please?
- Danny.
Sadie?
Sadie, come over.
Help Daddy now.
Come on.
Come and help Daddy.
You just need to untie me.
No. I can't.
You run.
Danny boy.
Danny boy. Danny.
- Danny.
- No.
Hey, come and help Daddy.
Come over here
and help Daddy.
- Danny.
- Run! Go! Go!
- Come on!
- Danny, come back here!
It's not safe out there!
Richard:
Danny!
(dispatch chatter)
Cynthia?
(panting)
Hello?
Can anyone hear me?
Sadie, come back!
It's not safe out there!
(groans)
(whines)
I didn't mean--
I didn't mean to hurt you.
Danny said that something
pushed him into the water.
- What pushed him?
- I don't remember.
Who pushed him?
(sobbing)
I would--
I would never.
- I wouldn't--
- Ryan is dead.
- Who?
- Sadie's friend.
- The boy in the fucking woods.
- You need to untie me.
He's following us.
He's here. I've seen it.
- I need your help.
- You have rabies.
- What?
- You're having hallucinations.
You're hearing things--
hydrophobia.
You have extreme paranoia
and dementia.
There's no monster
out there, Richard.
The monster is you.
- Fucking untie me now!
- Did you do it?!
- Did you do it?! Answer me!
- No! I did not!
No!
- Untie me?
- No.
The Devil. It's out here.
I've seen it.
It's gonna get us.
I need you to untie me
so we can get out of here.
I am not going crazy!
- Officer: Over there.
- (police dispatch chatter)
Another bear attack?
(flies buzzing)
Not Iikely.
Sadie: Did Dad tell you
to go in the water?
Danny, did he push you
in the water?
Danny, I need you
to answer me.
He said something
was following us.
He was trying to find
a hiding place.
Dad did something bad,
didn't he?
Come here.
(Danny sobbing)
We just need to keep moving, okay?
We need to keep going.
It's going to be okay.
We need to keep going, okay?
(grunting)
(screams)
- Yeah, we got a body.
- Sheriff.
You need to see this.
There it is. There it is.
There it is.
It's right there.
(Ieaves rustling)
(Iow growl)
It's there. It's there.
Look through the trees.
Cynth, Cynth.
Look through the trees!
It's not the first time
I've seen it.
It's been after me
since I was a child.
(Ioud growl)
Cynth.
You've got to trust me.
I know--
I know I seem insane.
I just want to protect you.
Sadie:
Help!
Somebody, please!
Ouch! Shit.
- (groaning)
- Sadie!
I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Ah, shit...
Danny, come here.
Danny.
- (Iow growl)
- Sadie: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Sadie:
Danny, don't move.
- Don't move.
- (growls, Ioud gunshot)
- Man: It's okay.
- (Ioud ringing)
Where are your parents?
Come on.
Come on. Hurry up.
I want every campsite
in a 20-mile radius shut down.
(grunting)
(moans)
(Ieaves rustling)
Richard?
Richard? Richard...
(branches creaking)
(screaming)
Cynthia.
(Iow growl)
(snarls)
(coughing)
- Sadie: Dad.
- Sadie. Sadie.
- Dad! Dad!
- I Iove you, baby.
Where's Cynthia?
Where is she?!
I'm not sure.
- I'm so glad I found you.
- Where is she?
It's not safe.
(grunts)
(gasps, trigger clicks)
- Miss, step away from your dad, please.
- Sadie.
- What did you do?
- I'm not--
Danny:
Mommy!
- Miss, please step away.
- Sadie!
- Mom!
- Danny!
Hey!
No!
What did you do?
- Danny, run!
- Mrs. Vineyard?
(gunshot echoes)
- (groaning)
- Sadie: Get up!
(growling)
(screaming)
Sadie?
- (distant shrieking)
- Cynthia?
Richard:
Danny?
Sadie? Danny?
(coughing)
(coughing, hacking)
Cynthia?
(screams)
No! Cynthia, get up!
Get up!
Atlantic County
Sheriff's Department!
(woman screaming)
No! No! Get up!
Get up!
No! Cynthia! Get up!
- Danny: Mommy!
- Please!
Danny:
Mommy, get up!
(voices whispering)
Sadie: Cynthia, please get up.
Please, get up. Please, get up!
- Cynthia?
- Dad!
I'm so sorry.
Daddy, no! Daddy, no!
Put the gun down!
No! Daddy, please!
Put it down!
Put it down, please!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Please, don't shoot!
Please, please, don't!
Please!
(Iow growl)
(Ioud growl)
Sheriff:
Atlantic County Sheriff's Department!
Sadie:
Don't do this! Please!
Sheriff:
Drop the gun! Drop the gun!
- (growling)
- Sadie: Please, don't.
Put the gun down!
- Sadie: Please, put the gun down.
- Sheriff: Drop the gun!
- I said drop the fucking gun!
- No, no, no. Don't shoot!
Danny:
Dad!
(snarls)
Sic ay Mahtantu.
(rumbling)
Danny: Dad!
(growls)
(screaming)
I'm so proud of you.
- Danny: Daddy!
- I'm sorry.
(Jersey Devil shrieking)
(screaming)
(music playing)
♪ Pharaoh, my Pharaoh ♪
♪ My girlfriend is dead ♪
♪ She's in my Camaro ♪
♪ She's got a tear in her dress ♪
♪ Last night at the drive-in ♪
♪ She kicked off her heels ♪
♪ She said, "Boy, Iet me know ♪
♪ If the Devil is real" ♪
♪ Bonnie, that birthmark ♪
♪ At the base of your ass ♪
♪ Is shaped Iike the gallows ♪
♪ And the shadows they cast ♪
♪ Well, Pharaoh, that shadow ♪
♪ Is shaped Iike a cross ♪
♪ So swing, Bonnie, swing ♪
♪ Till you swing us across ♪
♪ Pharaoh, my Pharaoh ♪
♪ The devil is real ♪
♪ He's in my Camaro ♪
♪ He's got his teeth on the wheel ♪
♪ And mile after mile ♪
♪ Field after field ♪
♪ Skyline and silo ♪
♪ The Devil is real. ♪