... :: TRANSLATION, TIMING AND REVIEW :: ...
......... :::: :::: Lara Phoenix .........
- Come on!
- I'm going.
- Brett, how much longer?
- J? let's get on top.
I'm tired.
In here...
Little miss.
Wait at? you? see the view.
Up here.
My God, you? has
raz? o. ? beautiful here.
Duty? Masters have brought
a blanket.
Brett, I
said duty? masters ...
Brett?
Brett, for God's sake!
Brett, please
that do not? Funny? ado!
Brett!
THE DATE
- Luke.
- All right, Simon?
No it should be surprised
because it is you ?.
I say the same.
- Who found her?
- Two young people at the festival.
Ca? Ram a slit
I had in the ground.
The pol? Cia took almost
To find a one week? them.
What happened?
The boy died instantly,
the girl...
was 5 days in complete darkness the
with a cad? see.
But so he died
they found.
May God save.
Michael.
Michael!
Michael, stop!
Oh my.
My God!
Michael, get to ?.
No the move.
Oh my.
You? suffered an accident.
I will call a Humvee Ambulance? INSTANCE.
No the move.
No the move. No the move.
How is she ??
? of course I will do
more tests ...
but I do not think his car hit
with is? that imagine, Mrs. Kirkman.
Such that ? poss? vel?
I know I hit for? A.
But it s? He has a cut on his forehead
and some scratches es. Nothing serious.
- She is? unconscious.
- N o, is she? sleeping.
The results are? The good.
She is? a little
bewildered,? clear.
The mem? Recent ria
est? shaken.
But do not h? why
the mant? -la here.
- Go Deix -la go?
- I'll see you in my consult river?.
No I can simply abandon? -la.
Who will take care of it?
That ? Horror? vel,
I do not know her name.
? Cassie Grant.
Michael.
The figure of Christ is? in
back to church.
At the ? that?
Everything seems to be reversed.
? a discovery very
significant, Luke.
?, I know.
I'm surprised you?
have come to me.
The epis hatred San Severo happened
H? long, Simon.
Two years?
To be frank, you? It does not was
my first op ?? the.
The edif? Cio? stone brick.
Opus reticulatum. T? Roman cnica.
This church was
built? in the S? culo I.
And ret? Bulo altar?
Ah yes. The ret? Bulo was
carved in it? poca.
? unusual one being crucified ??
shown by tr? s cross.
I had never seen
that before.
- It will deteriorate.
- It's gonna take a while?
I need a system
monitors ?? the most r? fast poss? vel.
And when you can eat? Air?
Once I get
meet my group.
Professor Kirkman, I prefer
working alone at this stage.
We think the less
people outside the church ...
concerned about the work
?? retains the be? best.
While still under
our jurisdictions ?? the ...
want? masters do our
pr? would put an? lysis ...
calmly and quickly and
without estardalha? o.
And without journalists.
We will cooperate all
forms, teacher.
We will arrange everything
you need.
- You? are you sure?
-? the m? nimo I can do.
We have space? The left.
You can stay as long as is necessary? River.
No reminds him why he was
coming to Ashby Wake?
At the. I owe
meet somebody here.
I'm so sorry.
Est? all confused.
FAIR ASHBY WAKE
Dr Byworth said
would be a bit confusing at eat? the
Ashby? a small town.
Someone will recognize you?.
- Michael? silent.
-.
How do you know his name?
- He must have said.
-? of course.
We arrived.
That ? Emma.
Hi, Emma.
I'm Cassie.
Hi.
Wow!
This house? too much.
No j s to buy? a year.
Soon after they were married.
I am the stepmother them. Still h?
much to be done here.
There are so many beautiful things.
Work of Simon, my husband.
He ? the expert.
Well, stay? will.
- I'll make some tea ?.
- I'll -la Bailout?.
- Tell me about this girl.
- Cassie ?
No had nothing but
I could do.
My God, I thought
had killed her.
It must have been Horror? Vel.
I was petrified,
I thought she was dead.
N do not know the
I would have done.
Gra? The? God
we Bailout? -la.
She lost almost all
her things.
At least let's
bed for her.
Oh, of course. She said that Michael
est? in shock.
We have to be patient.
She said he could
take some rem? dios.
No the certainly do not.
That's what I thought.
He will speak when
are ready.
I have to go back
to work.
Est? good...
You? est? best?
- Ol?
- Good day.
- How do you feel today?
- Much better, thank you.
I hope you do not mind. The child? The
were hungry, then? the ...
I made the coffee? -of-morning ?.
- I showed where things were.
- No. should be doing this.
No it's okay.
Ms. Groves arrived?
I have a meeting? The
in Oxford.
I can take
the child? the school.
- At the ? accurate.
- Glad to.
- You? You do not know where?.
- Well, Emma can show me.
Michael, how you like your eggs?
Scrambled or fried with runny yolk?
He do not have spoken.
Or make strange things
here ... how to mix with gel? would?
Thanks.
- Hello ?!
- I'm sorry, with the licen?.
Damages were most
caused by these ...
salts transported by? water
inside of the edif? cio structure.
And this applies above all?
these figures? right.
H? Most in blisters and scabs
other but ...
s? Awesome, do not?
Why you? came back?
Jos? of Arimat? I was going
the crucified ?? e ...
He came to
England soon after.
With lan? That wounded
Christ on the Cross.
AND?
And he built a church
in Glastonbury.
A church
Roman S? Culo I.
Certainly that.
-? poss? vel.
-? prov? vel.
When looking at this ret? Bulo,
You know what we may be seeing?
The registration of ?? the Crucifixion of Christ,
done by somebody who was l ?.
Cassie, I did it
to you ?.
I saw two people in the city
They seemed familiar.
I think I
They recognized, but ...
I do not did id? ia
who they were.
It always happens to me.
- Pain of up to?
- At the.
- Est? sleeping well?
- I think so.
Anything else?
When I saw those
people know there? ...
It was all t? the stranger.
I do not believe
that should be reoccupy.
You? He has been shaken and it will take
a time to recover.
Est? good?
Yup.
Thanks.
Hi.
- Where you? He found it?
- This ? your? You? wrote?
- Yup.
- Forensic F ?.
-? about my work.
- N restores works of art ?!
I restore. And I find the origin
them and s? the aut? nticas or do not.
What causes
many problems.
- But I mant m busy?.
- Too busy.
Est? being one d? diva of God
t? -la here with us.
? ? thymus to be here,
with the child? the.
S? O one really loves.
- J? bab was ??
- No I remember?.
Remember something
your fam? read?
No the, still do not.
- Also m want to drink?.
- Excuse me.
- H? how long they live here?
- H? one year.
Emma was born in Ashby Wake.
She was 9 years old, when we came to c ?.
It seemed a? Great place to
a new beginning.
The child? Underwent the
moments dif? ficult.
Michael was only 4 years
when the m? and died.
- I'm so sorry.
- She was sick h? long time.
It was terr? Vel for Michael.
Fool.
It's all right?
I conhe? The ?, you do not ??
- You? do not you remember?
- Ninth. I remember.
- In front ? school.
- Exact.
I? Tima,? s? what a..
- There are people following me
- Who?
A biker, a man
thin and tr? s old ladies.
Tr? S old ladies?
It seems that do not have no one there? out,
except a cowboy and some old ladies.
- I'm Cassie Grant
- Dan Blakley.
That part of the
United States you? ??
Midwest.
I'm staying in the house
a fam? lia.
In fact, I was hit by
a car h? a few days.
- You were hit?
- Yup.
But I'm fine.
I had only a small concuss? O.
Wow, it must have been a
shock terr? vel.
- Est? hosted in Ashby Wake?
- In Lime Court, nearby.
- A large house, thousands?
- Yes that's right.
Because I have the sensation the ??
that j? the conhe? the?
Because j? we met.
In school?!
No it before that?
You? travel a lot?
I have to go.
I'll give you a ride.
Or rather go
with some old ladies?
- You? You live around here?
- Still No I decided?.
I mean, I love
West Country.
I'm taking care of
a property in Stukeley Hill.
The relat? River shows no? Ble low
? high acid and salt in the soil.
- What might be damaging the walls.
- I know, I wrote this relat river?.
The interesting?
the soil was brought here ...
1200 years after the
Church was built? In.
You? do not put it
in relat? river.
The Church was buried,
intentionally ...
By occasion? the
Black Death that? poca.
Listen, Luke, met
H? so long.
Because est? wanting to keep
this place a secret?
Listen, have things
we do not yet understand.
If the Church was
buried intentionally ...
You must have had a reason to.
Michael?
Was you ??
You? I was crying?
No to sleep?
It was cute the dog.
? equal to that late there?
out, do not ??
You? also? m heard.
And the child? The?
You? the also heard? m?
Est? all right.
No need to be afraid.
Mrs. Groves?
Do you know some
the neighbor who has a Pitbull?
- What kind of Pitbull?
- I do not know.
His color? caramel and
It has fit? the really big.
I saw him here,
near the house.
I do not see one as Pitbull
this one h? times.
Where's the the child? The?
Est? almost done.
- How was the m and the child???
- Caroline? She was ador? Vel.
An & quot; optimal m? E.
At the ? of mine
business, but ...
married soon after do not help
Professor Kirkman.
-, They should be moved.
- N as much as come to c ?.
No they should have purchased the est? House.
You can call the child? The.
Michael! Emma!
You? do not est?
holding right.
Michael, all right.
It's all right. Calm.
It's all right.
catch me!
Where is? going?
Wait for me!
Child? The, do not arrive
near the river.
- Here!
- I'm going
Michael, do not see? away.
Stay close to Emma.
Stay tranq? Ila, they're good.
- I'm worried about Michael.
- Because?
Look at him? He is? good!
And you? Cassie,
How are you??
Strange.
N do not know explain.
A journalist was
calling the Writers? River Bishop.
No one should speak
with the press.
At the. You? think
it was me?
- No. of course that paragraph?.
- Think, yes.
- Well, what was you ??
- At the.
You? still finds
I was right, do not ??
About San Severo.
S? What did I do
He was telling the truth.
? what do you? You think,
at the ??!
In fact, what he did was end
f? of thousands of people.
People who have been led to believe in
one chunk of the wood that was ...
A Rel? Quia Bible.
In a floating wooden S? C. XIX
It was a fragment of the Holy Cross.
They believed
be sacred.
I s? I'm interested
by facts.
I know.
No, thank you.
Well, what we have
in here ? aut? ntico.
And that deserves to be headline ...
must be the oldest
crucifies what ?? n? s have.
At the ? that.
Arist? Polus, Bishop of Bret? Es
He wrote a s? rie letters.
He was in Glastonbury,
at the ?? S? Culo I.
As ??
Arist? Polus mentioned a Church
founded by Jos? of Arimat? came and ...
in the same letter, h? a...
esp? cie p? s-written.
Which left many
puzzled scholars.
"They came s? To see.
They came from the east and west ...
The city and the plan? Cie.
They came, do not in sacred
review? INSTANCE God ...
but for pleasure. "
Its Latin? much better
that my.
"They came s? To see.
No in the sacred review? INSTANCE,
but for pleasure. "
I think ? that
showing the low relief.
Through? S sos? S glasses
there were always people ...
they wanted only
see SPECTACLES? culo.
People who were together
the guillotine in the French Revolucni ??.
Crowd? Es that would assist
hangings in prison? the Newgate.
People watching eletrocuss? Es
in pres? dios Americans.
But still remains
one crucifies the scene ??.
- It may be unorthodox, but ...
- Ninth ? s? Crucify the one ??.
At the ? about Christ, Simon.
But people who
They came to watch.
- There you go, Father.
- Thank you.
Good day.
Ms.
Ms?
Michael?
Darling?
It's all right. He do not will get you
hurt. He is?...
Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Look at my face.
Michael!
No the'll let anything happen to
you ?. T? good? I promise!
I am fine.
No'll let the
anything happen to you ?.
I promise.
I am fine.
Sorry, Dan.? I do not know
who else talk.
Cassie, what happened?
The? Last days
I have had a ...
I do not even know what to call.
Visions. Hallucinates ?? es.
I see a Horror? Ble things.
And then, I'm not even sure
s gone? imagine the ??.
Well, you? was
hit by a car.
But what I see
? t? the real.
I think I'm having
premoni ?? es.
Premoni ?? s?
About what ??
I do not know.
- You know what I mean?
- I do not know! I do not know, damn it!
I do not know what happened,
how can I know what will happen ?!
I will Bailout? -la.
I feel so alone.
You? at the
est? alone, Cassie.
No est? alone.
There was a guy with a dog
stuck in the truck.
Michael was scared.
A guy with a dog.
The dog...
? weird, because this dog came
? night and barked at the window.
No s saw.
As a matter of fact,
s? me and Michael.
Found want? Them.
- You? help me?
- To qu ??
I do not know. Maybe you pe? A to
he hold the dog.
You? He said he was driving
a pickup truck.
You saw the license plate?
At the.
He must repair the car.
S? H? a workshop in Ashby Wake.
We eat? Air for l ?.
You? go with me?
No want to stay
away from me.
Ali est ?.
The car ? that.
What are you? The making?
Can I help? Them?
Can you tell me who?
the car owner?
- Why do you want to know?
- I want to buy.
No est? ? sale. Belongs to
one of my mec? nicos.
- He is? in here?
- At the.
- Can you give me his number?
- No. I?.
- He has No phone.
- All right, then the address to his?.
S? Tine thio.
Longridge Road.
His name? Argyle.
Jesus!
Ent? O this? the dog?
Yup, ? this dog.
Cassie.
My God,
s look? for this.
? sad.
FISHERMAN WINS NATIONAL TOURNAMENT
My God.
I conhe? O these people.
Dan, I will conhe? O.
That ? the m? physician of the hospital.
Let's go.
That ? Lime Court.
OPENS UP FOR RESEARCH The ??
LIME IN COURT
In the 60 Lime Court was
a home for the child? the. Maintained by the Church.
The funcion? Rivers were accused
of molesting the child? the.
That do not? novelty. Cassie?
We'd better get out of here.
Oh my.
They were all involved.
LIME COURT FIVE acquitted
CHILD ABUSE? AS
FATHER ABSOLVED
? he in Lime Court.
My God!
Dan? Michael!
It has a photo
Michael.
Because he has
a picture of Michael?
I do not know. Let's go,
before it comes back.
Wait a sec.
My God, Dan.
You? He saw the house. ? ? obvious that
this guy ? crazy.
All I saw was a life
sad and disgrace? ada.
- Let's find the pol cia?.
- And say what?
- That he took pictures of Michael?
- That. And all those other pictures.
He v? Michael as
to you pr? prio as a child? a.
He wants to get rid of it.
Erase your past.
- In one of my ...
- Premoni ?? s?
?, in a
my premoni ?? es ...
I saw Michael with half
Outsider's face? alhado.
But you? at the
can say that the pol? cia.
No s have to do
something!
My God.
T? good.
Let's find something else.
Before taking any action.
... and all the happiness
soon disappear.
Jackie finished your last
journey pol? tica.
In Dallas, Texas. He
was received by Governor ...
Thank you.
Also? m was there? Vice President,
Mr. Lyndon Johnson, who? Texas.
In that state the
Democratic government do not? popular ...
but the charm of Kennedy
It was effective as ever. And as soon as ...
The motorcade was closed after
all the confusion? o.
It was abandoned.
Ent? O Ms. Kirkman to
He bought and renovated.
Mrs. I came here before?
He knew the Father of the Church?
Look, now do not matter, do not? same?
J? est? All over.
No one wants to be reminding
this all the time.
It seems that somebody knew
what was happening.
Cassie was never proved anything.
Yes, there were rumors.
It was terr? Vel. Dreadful.
But it's over.
... but the concept of
security? has changed in those days.
Controv? rsias on
precaution ?? s taken ...
We are uninhibited and freq? ciently
posed for the c? maras.
? imposs? vel say how many
They had this destination.
It? dangerous.
He ? one of the child? of the
old Lime Court.
It's him ? dangerous?
?. I know I do not have reason? The
to believe me.
I think he wants
revenge.
T ?, revenge. From who?
I do not know.
Who hurt him.
- Maybe the whole town.
- The whole town?
He ? obsessed with this boy
I am in charge, Michael.
Because he would want
to hurt him?
I do not know.
Because of inf? INSTANCE him,
the harm they have done to him.
Sure, I believe do not know
the name of the Lord.
Frederick Michael Argyle.
Fred?
No need to believe that the
worry about it.
Everyone knows Fred.
Do you think he? Funny? ado?
What h? with you s?
I fear that without Evid? INSTANCE
concrete very little can be done.
What? Thymus, thank you.
Thank you.
E S? C XIX
male figure? right.
The detail of his face.
The figure in low relief.
And in this picture we are looking at the image
the older woman in the background.
Here is the detail of her face.
And again, the face id? Ntico
sunken to.
We need soterr? -la.
That do not?
very dr? stico?
We need soterr? -la.
I'm glad you do not been disclosed.
I've been busy.
And I believe that we are all so ...
since it was made
discovery.
And sorry for
those two poor young people.
But these findings ...
n? s? the big surprise
for n? s scholars.
You? at the
? the first, Luke.
The recognition that these figures
appear repeatedly ...
in tragedy scene? human day.
It has been documented by certain
Church members.
And we must respect the fact that the Church
j? It has been buried once.
It's because?
S? we can assume ...
but I'm sure it was for
protect the community.
Bishop forgive me.
But demolishing the church,
brick by brick...
do not will prevent these
tragedy? days happen!? am.
In fact, do not go.
Nothing in this world can
prevent this.
But we can avoid
this place ...
will become a center
of ?? the superstition and fear.
If people
become obsessed ...
By evils
that could occur ...
They v? Neglects good
This I could do.
Can take care of this quest? O
with Professor Kirkman?
I can. I will talk to him
tomorrow? early.
?thymus.
May the Lord protect.
He protects all of us.
- Frederick Michael Argyle.
- Fred ?
Everyone knows Fred.
No it!
Please!
I'll give you a lesson ?? o, Argyle.
You? do not will run away again. I saw you!
<> Always wanting to cause
problems do not? even, Argyle?
Please! Let me go!
- I'm sorry. No it, please!
- Now you will catch up!
Michael!
Michael.
Breathe deeply. Ready.
- It's all right.
- I heard voices.
I know. Me too
I listen, honey.
What happened?
What was Michael?
- He had a nightmare.
- Est? all right.
V? lie down. Was s? a
storm. Est? all right.
- I'll take.
- All right, Michael.
V? with Marion.
T? good?!
Michael
He took these pictures?
Yup.
Simon, where s? O
these photos?
S? O my work.
To tell me where
s? the these pictures.
S? O a ret? Bulo. A low relief
I'm working on.
- I saw these people.
- WHA??
Ashby Wake.
No o, s? The pictures of a work of art.
? an ancient work
- I saw these people in the city.
- What are you? I am saying?
It is.
And this.
J? arrives.
Cassie, v? to sleep.
Please.
Oh my God!
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
the friend you just and Him:. Mayor
Did you mean that? a big
joy to be here and ...
that give me the great pleasure to announce the
that est? open to fair Ashby Wake.
- Wait for me.
- Run. Run.
I'll beat you ?.
Of course.
Yes sir.
Thank you.
Bye.
Luke Fraser died
a car accident.
Simon.
He was coming to
meet me.
The car overturned
and looks like he died instantly.
? I better go.
The Bishop wants to talk to me.
- You'll be here?
- I will.
I am grateful for promptness,
Professor Kirkman.
It was a terr? Vel blow.
Luke was an extraordinary? River man.
It was yes.
I would like
you? saw something.
Arist? Polus called him
"The date".
They were people who were for
to crucify ?? the do not to worship or ...
comfort,
but to watch.
?.
"From the east and west come, do not
in sacred review? INSTANCE, but for pleasure. "
? true.
It has always been the tradition in the Church consider ??
"The meeting" Amaldi? Oado.
Lan? Ado into outer darkness
and being members convicted ...
to be spectators of suffering
of humanity for eternity.
The First World War.
?? The detonates the
first bomb at? mica.
Lynching b? Rbaro
a poor man.
I shook his f ?,
professor?
No the, I do not have f ?.
Your f? at
cient rationality? is.
- Do you have a phone?
- I have.
I know where
est? the these people.
They're here now.
Cassie, look at me.
Look at my legs.
Look at me!
- Cassie, look.
- Let's go.
They're here.
Come on.
- Mrs. Groves.?
- Ol ?, Michael. Emma.
- Vo buy a bal the???
- Yes please.
Mrs. Groves can take care
them a little bit?
Well, I do not know.
Mrs. Groves,
? very important, please.
- Cassie, where are the the the child?
- East with Mrs. Groves?..
What are you? going on? Simon said
we are in danger.
You have to trust me.
You? You have to take the child? the here.
Behold, est? in here!
The D.Jo.
Very kind of you
appears, Freddy.
What do you? You have a ?, Freddy?
He walked shooting rabbits again?
Damn it!
Hey! You? S two!
Where you? You have been?
At the.
Listen...
Hi, gone.
Hi?
- Cassie.
- Stay away from me.
WHA??
- Who ? you ??
- What est? Speaking?
I'm talking about a sculpture
h made? two thousand years atr? s.
I saw pictures of her yesterday
? night. I saw you ?!
You? was them.
- Yup.
- Yup?
What does that mean?
Who ? you ??
No it should have gone to pol? Cia, Cassie.
I tried to warn you ?.
They could have intruded and I
do not could let that happen.
I had a policeman here.
Where is he ??
Atr? S you ?.
My God.
Oh my.
Hi.
Frederick, in the fair?
Everything begun I
H? two thousand years atr? s.
A crucify the ??
on a hill.
No s went to watch.
But we were punished.
In my view, unfairly.
? natural to be curious.
You? I knew about Argyle
all the time.
- You? also? m.
- Do you? est? Speaking?
No the'm going to hurt? -la, Cassie.
I would never do that.
You? You know what will happen some
thing. So it is still? in here.
You? ? a n's, Cassie.
Just forgot.
Many years atr? S ...
we were condemned to go back and watch.
And that's what we did.
But with the passing of time,
found that we can be? useful.
But ? pat? tico.
? obscene.
See people suffering.
Get excited about it.
Ninth ? ?? excites him.
No we can prevent
what will happen, Cassie.
Will screw you, Dan.
You? can not
do anything, Cassie.
Ladies and gentlemen, this place do not
? safe. Get out immediately.
At the ? safe!
I'm sorry for that.
I want to introduce Dr. Byworth,
which will deliver the pr? awards.
Applause for Dr. Byworth.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Can you help me? Please can
help me push?
- Of course.
- Att s, please?.
Est? good.
- Est? Ready?
- Yup.
The pr? Mio goes to
Miss Goldberg.
- Try starting.
- More r fast!
- Take the p? Clutch!
- You're going to hit the wall!
- Care!
- Turn to the right!
Will hit ...
- My God!
- Run! Flee!
- You? est? good?
- Run!
Run! Run!
Run! It has a bomb
in the car! Run!
No you, Fred. At the.
You? est? late.
Sorry, but I screwed
everything to you ?.
No the spoiled.
You? He saw Cassie.
You know what's? It is happening.
It will ticking the list.
It will kill Michael now.
Michael est?
on a train to London.
In fact Michael est? in
Lime Court with Emma.
- Cassie.
- No. touch me?.
No it will make
No difference? a.
Marion!
- Where is? Marion?
- Cassie? you ??
No with you talk to Simon.
The train was canceled.
I thought to be? Masters
safe here.
Marion.
At the!
Michael!
Michael.
Cassie, get Michael.
Marion!
My God.
Take Michael. V ?!
V ?!
Run!
Run! Come on!
My God.
For the cornfield.
You? We saw the Marion?
Damn it!
Stay here.
Come on.
Marion? My God.
- My God.
- The child the?.
- V? atr? s of the child? the.
- Oh my!
V? atr? s of the child? the.
In here.
Stay down.
Cassie!
Please.
Cassie.
Cassie!
I saw this man
shoot you ?.
Yes, you? saw.
But do not hurt me.
No one can hurt me.
No I am like you ?.
H? long, long time, a girl
I was walking in the countryside ...
the outskirts of town.
And I saw something ...
One thing terr? Vel.
Then? He stopped and stared.
She do not should have done that.
Why do not?
Because it was a thing
Horror much? vel.
She should have tried
prevent or help.
Or at least could
have rebelled against that, but ...
she do not do anything.
S? watched.
What happened to her?
He was wandering, lost,
for a long time.
And I was very unhappy.
But then? O, I learned
an important thing.
Everyone
You get a second chance.
S? ? I need to know avail.
- I should be asleep.
-. I n the sleep
And the voices?
They disappeared. At the
longer have to be afraid of them.
You? You will stay with me, Cassie?
At the.
You? at the
need me.
We are now free,
Michael.
You? est? good?
? bedtime.
And the bear?
Good evening.
... :: TRANS ?? O, TIMING AND REVIEW? The :: ...
......... :::: :::: Lara Phoenix .........