ALEX:
Every life is a riddle.
The answer to mine is a knowledge
born of darkness.
It wasn't always so.
In the beginning I still had questions.
In the beginning...
... my mystery still remained.
[BELLS JINGLING]
[VOICES WHISPERING]
EDEN:
Brother Dominic.
Scholar of the Catholic arcane.
Believer in the unsanitized Church.
A church that no Ionger
believes in itself.
The church of stigmata...
...and exorcism. Saints...
...and demons.
And me.
I believe in many things.
So do I.
And right now, I believe it's time.
Are you ready to make your confession?
Forgive me, Alex.
I have sinned against you.
[SCREAMING AND BANGING]
MAN:
There he is. That's Alex.
DRIVER: He's young.
-But an old soul, Clive. He's an old soul.
[ALEX SPEAKING IN LATIN]
I need to speak with you.
-Do you always say the Mass in Latin?
ALEX: It's how I was taught.
DRISCOLL:
It belies your age.
And with your back
to your audience, no less.
Six or 700 years ago, they
wouldn't have seen you at all...
...and you'd have sung the Mass
in Latin behind a huge choir screen...
...out of the sight of a congregation
that was only allowed to listen.
I think you would have liked the choir
screen, Alex, for a contradiction.
I'm stuck here because the Church
doesn't know what to do with me.
The Church doesn't know what
the hell to do with itself.
I won't pretend I don't know
you have certain qualifications...
...certain skills that set you apart
from other priests.
However, the diocese has certain
questions about your faith, AIex.
So, what do you want from me?
Well, I have sad news for you.
-Dominic, the head of your order--
-I know who he is.
He's dead.
Today. In Rome.
MAN:
Is this your mother?
Say goodbye, AIex.
It's time to say goodbye.
Goodbye.
Leave your tears here...
...and then forget them.
DRISCOLL:
Alex.
Alex?
How is it that a cardinal has enough
time to come and tell me this?
Because I loved him.
Because he was my mentor.
And because the circumstances
of his death are curious.
I need to go to Rome.
The diocese will arrange a flight.
In the name of God, in the name of
Jesus Christ, I order you back to hell.
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
In the name of God, in the name of
Jesus Christ, I order you back to hell.
[JINGLING]
MAN:
Fuck your God!
All mouth, no trousers.
[HONKING]
Your Church will be lost, priest.
The dark pope...
...rises.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
THOMAS:
Hello?
ALEX: I've been trying to reach you.
-Alex.
-How are you, spaghetti-o?.
-Yeah, listen to me.
Dominic died.
-Dominic?.
- Yeah.
Oh, no.
- When did it happen?
-Last night.
Where are you? In New York?
At St. Agnes?
Yeah. Listen, I'm going
to Rome, Thomas.
THOMAS: When?
-Tomorrow.
And guess what?
So are you.
[PHONE BEEPS RAPIDLY]
ALEX:
Just be there.
Hi.
When did they release you?
I was released today.
Years ago it was a dorm
for the priests.
Now it's empty.
You're here.
True.
[KNOCKING]
I'll wait.
We're Iooking for AIex Bernier.
-That's me, is there something wrong?
-Just a heads up, Father. You know a...
-...Mara Williams?.
-Yes.
She escaped from the mental health
facility...
...where she was remanded by the court.
Remanded.
And what does this have to do with me?
She was locked up for trying to kill you,
wasn't she?
That was the main reason, yes.
I just thought you'd Iike
to know she's...
...unaccounted for.
I can have a car drive by
once in a while.
No, I'm fine, thank you.
Well, Iike I said, heads up.
You know, it says here...
...I couldn't make it out in this copy.
She, uh....
She shot you at an exercise class?
No, at an exorcism.
Oh....
-Have a good night.
-You too, Father.
ALEX:
You lied, you said they released you.
MARA:
No, I didn't.
I didn't lie.
I said I was released,
I didn't say who did it.
Mara.
AIex.
You didn't say goodbye.
They said it'd be better if
I didn't see you for a while.
For a year?
I don't know.
I started painting again.
Did you?
Yeah.
Flowers, mostly.
I wanna paint sunflowers,
but I don't have the guts.
You think I'm crazy?
I know you're not.
Why'd you come here?
I heard you call me.
Mara, don't say that.
Okay.
I got a feeling that...
...I should be with you, in case...
...one of us has to say goodbye.
I've never been to Rome before.
Is it amazing?.
I bet it is.
It scares me.
Ever since I was a boy.
-And you're staying here.
-No, I'm not.
I can't stay here.
And you need me,
whether you know it or not.
-And....
-The nightingales are gone.
-Are they?
-Yeah.
They've been gone for about a year.
Same as you.
AIex, look at me.
It's you and me.
You and me till the wheels fall off.
Promise you won't try to kill me.
Cross my heart.
Hope to die.
ALEX:
It's up here.
[VOICES WHISPERING]
Hey.
Mara.
What are they?
Orphans.
But of what, I've no idea.
[VOICES WHISPERING]
[KEYS CLANGING]
I've been in worse places.
Just needs light, that's all.
What are those?
Aramaic. It's the language of Christ.
MARA:
What does it say?
ALEX:
"BIood in."
Down there, "blood out."
This must have been where
they found Dominic's body.
AIex, what are you thinking?
It was a ceremony.
The message I got said suicide.
ATTENDANT:
SIeeping pills, signore.
Is that him?
Yes, it's him.
Thank you.
I didn't pay to look at his face,
if you don't mind.
-What are these?
-Let's go, please, hurry up.
No, no, what are these?
Do you know what these are?
ATTENDANT: Maybe a birthmark.
I don't know, I'm not a doctor.
It's not a birthmark.
When's the body to be released
to the Church?
It isn't.
When we are done with it...
...it goes to the state,
for burial in the state cemetery.
Okay, please, Iet's go.
PIease, come with me.
OWNER:
It's always nice to see a priest.
And a Carolingian, no less.
You've seen others?
A Dominic Souza, perhaps?
OWNER:
Carolingians.
You surpass even the Jesuits in your
heretical search for knowledge.
It's important to stay inside the lines.
ALEX:
What lines?
OWNER:
This way.
ALEX:
Those were the marks.
Dominic, what were you doing?
"Bread and salt eaten off the body.
The sins of one man
consumed by the Other.
The Sin Eater."
If Hitler had had one in the bunker,
he'd be sitting on a cloud right now.
Of course, Sin Eaters haven't existed
for two centuries, have they?
-What did Dominic buy from you?
-Many things over the years.
Last time...
...a vellum parchment
written in Aramaic.
What did it say?
I'm not as clever as Dominic...
...scholar of mysteries.
He delved deep and dark...
...always after knowledge.
I think he'd have sold
his soul for knowledge.
Do you?
His heretic soul
or something precious to him.
Is there a price tag on your head?
What's that supposed to mean?
Sometimes it's better
for a priest not to know.
Knowledge is the enemy of faith.
And sometimes,
when you look into the abyss...
...the abyss looks back into you.
Look, his order meant everything to him.
Dominic should be buried with his order
in the Concezione Cemetery.
Your order is former order.
The Carolingians.
Not many of you left in the world.
We're a dying breed.
Look, and when they die,
it's the Concezione Cemetery.
Suicide is a cardinal sin.
Dominic didn't commit suicide.
It makes no difference.
He had been excommunicated, excluded
from our society and sacraments.
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
"There is no--"
ALEX: "No salvation outside
the Church." I know my Latin.
BISHOP: Unlike your manners.
Respect what you are.
Well, what I am
is my concern, thank you.
Listen.
I'm sorry, I am, I....
I need the Theosophic Council
to convene as soon as possible.
The council.
It hasn't convened in years.
For what purpose?
Tell them I found a Sin Eater.
A Sin Eater? Here?
At the start of the new millennium?
How many other impossible things
do you believe in?
It's not impossible, I've seen the marks
on Dominic's body myself.
Your mentor...
...was excommunicated
for rejection of articles of faith.
Heresy.
Accept it.
He took his own Iife because
he couldn't bear that.
[ALEX GRUNTING]
-Grazie, Franca.
FRANCA: Father Alex.
ALEX:
Ciao, Marie. Ciao.
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
Amen.
[TWIG BREAKS]
In the name of God...
...I command you to return
from whence you came!
[ALEX SCREAMS AND GRUNTS]
In the name of God...
...in the name of Jesus, God and the
Holy Virgin, I order you back to hell!
[ROARING]
THOMAS:
FIy off to hell yourself.
What kind of a greeting's that?
-You're late.
-It's never too late, Alex.
Witness the repentant thief,
crucified alongside our Lord Savior.
-A quick thinker, eh?
-How you doing?
Ah.... I'm grand.
-So did you bury him?
-Yeah.
A rogue priest reading rites
over an excommunicado.
Damn dirty job,
but someone's gotta do it.
Cheers.
To the last of the Carolingians.
You and me.
Cheers.
What just passed through here, AIex?
Demon spawn in the guise of children.
Nothing I couldn't handle.
-Who summoned those nasties up?.
-Dominic, I think.
They were camped
outside his apartment.
Speaking of the apartment,
I met your girlfriend.
-She's not my girlfriend.
-Well, she should be.
She said you'd be at the Concezione.
You told her it was a restaurant?
-She would have come otherwise.
-Women.
Can't live with them...
...can't live with them.
Come on.
"Sin Eater.
In absolution, the burden of guilt
would be transmuted to the Sin Eater...
...as would the knowledge
of the transgressions."
MARA: Wait, you mean he'd know
what your sins were?
Even the details?
THOMAS:
He'd know and feel the burden of them.
He'd spend sleepless nights
over things others had done.
He'd have the ascendancy
to free a man's soul.
MARA:
And damn his own.
THOMAS: We're Carolingians, Alex and I.
In a way, that makes us responsible.
They say the practice of sin eating began
with banished members of our order.
That's like saying sheep are responsible
for the sweaters made from their wool.
THOMAS:
Maybe they are, Mara, girl.
ALEX:
I found the vellum Dominic bought.
I'll translate it for you.
Okay.
"PIace the instrument
of delivery over the heart."
Must be some kind of weapon.
And then look.
[SPEAKING IN LATIN]
"BIood in, blood out...
...and drive into the heart."
The rest is missing.
Still, you get the idea.
-I'm not sure I do.
-Well, they're instructions.
On how to kill a Sin Eater.
Dominic trained us to deal with ghosts,
demons and all manner of undead...
-...but this Sin Eater, he's a living man.
-Whatever he is, he killed Dominic.
Maybe, maybe not.
I've seen another copy of this
somewhere.
[BANGING]
So we meet again.
Jeez, the fucking cavalry.
How are you finding our city
of emperors, our city of martyrs?
Would you care for a beer, Your
Eminence, or something a Iittle stronger?
And you are?
-He's Thomas.
-She's Mara.
We're the Catholic
Pete, Linc and Julie.
I am Michael, Cardinal Driscoll.
And among other things,
I'm head of the Theosophic Council.
A bit like the dead letter department
of the post office, I'm afraid.
I believe Michelangelo
went blind from candlelight.
Dominic didn't believe in electricity.
DRISCOLL: Sin Eater? You couldn't have
shocked the bishop more if you said...
...you'd been possessed by a Phoenician
demon and demanded an exorcism.
The exorcism was on Friday.
Well, today is Monday.
And yet, I think there may be credence
to what you say.
As a matter of fact,
I know there is.
Sin Eater.
A renegade providing a path to heaven
outside of the Church and our Savior.
If you believe this, he has the power
to grant redemption to the unrepentant.
Sort of a heretical wrench in the cogs
of our Catholic machinery.
You two were Dominic's chosen.
What do you know about
his excommunication?
-Nothing.
-He wouldn't speak of it.
Dominic believed this Other,
this man, was based right here in Rome.
Now, that's all I know,
because that's all he told me.
I assume that the two of you
plan to seek him out...
...otherwise I am just
spinning my wheels here.
Sadly, the Church no longer
has the will to dispatch.
Thank God we still have the tools.
The instrument of delivery, if you will.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
...there are more pressing matters
weighing on the Vatican tonight.
Signorina.
MARA: What could be
more important than this?
They say the pope is ill.
In fact, they say that he's dying.
And that man, Mara, girl,
that American is front-runner for the job.
That man that just asked you
to kill somebody.
Left it to our discretion, I'd say.
ALEX: When did you get that?
-Last year. Got drunk, woke up with it.
That's very strange.
Sailors get anchors, so I'm a priest.
Still strange, Tommy.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
I'm glad Dominic believed in bathrooms.
I usually just open the window
and lean out.
What's strange is that you're a priest
sleeping on the couch...
...instead of a man
sleeping in bed with her.
Thomas, two days ago
she was in a mental institution.
So she's crazy about you.
Can you look me in the eye
and tell me you still want to be a priest?
Can you?
There are other ways to serve.
To serve.
It's knowledge I'm after.
Knowledge. When I look under a rock,
my gut reacts to what I see.
I don't wonder how it got under
the rock to begin with.
-You guys tired?
ALEX: Hmm.
Go upstairs and get some sleep.
-Night.
ALEX: Night.
THOMAS: Sweet dreams, yeah.
MARA: You too.
I know who she is, but who is she?.
Tell me something about her.
ALEX:
Hmm....
She's a painter.
Really good too.
I don't know, there's something
about her that....
She sees things differently.
She feels things differently.
I wish, I wish I never saw her face.
AIex, you're a fool.
Same as you were, once.
THOMAS: Your head rules your heart.
ALEX: Oh, and what rules yours?
THOMAS:
Laughter, of course.
Hey. You laugh to keep from going mad,
you laugh to keep the wolves at bay.
It's still laughter. As for you,
spaghetti-o, choose life.
-Right.
-Let your heart wear the crown...
...not your head.
Here we are.
Time to see Sirach.
Who is he, anyways?
A rising darkness.
A rising darkness?
[TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS:
We're Iooking for Rosalinda.
Sure. She's over there.
THOMAS:
Girl with the faraway eyes.
We need you to take us to Sirach.
[MUMBLING]
[SHERECK SPEAKS IN LATIN]
Don't start your posturing,
you pagan-worshipping pig.
You owe me a debt.
My friend and I are looking
for the Other.
Thomas, what does he mean
by "the dying"?
[MUMBLING IN LATIN]
[GAGGING]
ALEX:
Oh....
Ask him.
Oh, shit.
Where can I find the Sin Eater?
MAN: The Other will find you
upon the stone...
...where all is built.
He brings you:
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
The keys to the kingdom of heaven.
[COUGHS]
MARA:
"Upon the stone where all is built."
Upon the stone where all is built.
Ah. I hate riddles.
THOMAS:
Petrus. Stone.
Petrum.
Peter is the stone upon which "all,"
right, the Church, is built.
St. Peter's.
Well, the Other will find me, then.
THOMAS: St. Peter's. Doesn't anyone
just meet for coffee anymore?
And he will bring you....
AIex!
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS AND COUGHS]
THOMAS:
Come on, Iet's get out of here.
[VOICE WHISPERING]
No point in hanging around.
WOMAN:
Thomas.
Tommy, love.
How long have you been a priest,
Thomas?
Certain pleasures are forever
out of reach. Denied.
ALEX: Thomas, Ieave it for a sunny day.
Come on.
-All mouth, no trousers.
WOMAN: Remember that girl in Dublin?
Meagan was her name.
Did you feel foolish, Tommy?
In love with a whore?
Thomas.
It's personal, ignore it.
-The first and only lesson, remember?
WOMAN: Tommy, love.
Oh, Tommy.
-I love you, Tommy.
-Come on, mate.
-Never give them an inch.
-Tommy?
-Not one fucking inch.
-Thomas.
Thomas! Thomas!
In the name of God, of Jesus Christ,
to hell with you!
[CREAKING]
I love you, Tommy.
I'll pray for you, Tommy.
[SCREAMS]
ALEX:
Thomas!
I said there was no point
in hanging around.
You never laugh, AIex.
It's not good for the soul.
[THOMAS SCREAMS]
-I thought you might be the nurse.
-Thomas, what happened?
-Where's AIex?
-He's searching for coffee.
As for me,
I was hoisted up by me own petard.
Mara...
...if I can ask...
...what happened
between you and AIex?
MARA:
It's okay.
If I was embarrassed,
I'd wear bracelets.
My Iittle brother was murdered
and they brought Alex in to consult.
The Fillmore murders.
Dominic sent Alex.
That was the first time on his own.
Mara...
...I hear confession all the time.
Nightingales.
What about them?
Those are the birds
that I'd hear singing...
...right before the headaches started.
These headaches,
they'd go on for weeks.
They were...
...blinding.
So I did this. Even that didn't help.
And Alex performed an exorcism.
Yeah.
AIex took away my pain...
...and I fell in love with a priest
who couldn't love me back.
Love?
You traded one pain for another.
Something terrible
is going to happen to Alex, Thomas.
I don't know what it is,
but I know that it's worse than death.
EDEN:
Am I the answer to your prayer?
My friends call me William.
William Eden.
I'm not your friend.
That remains to be seen.
I know what you're feeling, Alex.
And you're right.
God exists.
He just doesn't give a damn.
Magnificence.
FIesh rots. St. Peter's remains.
This impossible dome, Alex...
...it was raised by my brother
when I was still a boy.
BIood and sweat built this, not faith.
It was Michelangelo who drew the dome
on a piece of paper...
...but it was Ieft to my brother
to figure out a way to raise it...
...halfway to heaven.
And it was my honor each day
to bring him something to eat...
...and ask him of the world
outside of my own.
William, you brought some food.
Thank you.
Tell me a story, Phillip.
A story of Jerusalem.
Jerusalem?
[SCREAMS]
[PHILLIP GRUNTING]
PHILLIP: Ah!
-Phillip!
Phillip!
He's dying.
PRIEST:
I can give no absolution.
He was excommunicated
last year in Jerusalem.
Good enough to build God's house,
but not to let him enter his kingdom...
...is that it?
William, go.
Fetch the Sin Eater.
In Jerusalem my brother
gave a dying Arab a drink of water.
There was no well,
so he gave him holy water.
My brother gave the Church
his youth in Jerusalem...
...his blood at St. Peter's.
But when he lay dying...
...they deserted him.
When his soul stretched out,
caught between heaven and hell...
...it was the Other
who delivered him.
It was the Other who gave him peace.
I always loved my brother, Alex.
But the Church I grew to hate.
SIN EATER:
This...
...is the other way.
I can teach you...
...if you are willing.
I was willing...
...and so I was taught.
Did you kill Dominic Souza?
The Church killed him.
He died when he was excommunicated.
His body continued on a while,
but his spirit was dead.
-That's a lie.
-He was, Alex. He was ruined.
Broken, not plagued.
And don't talk to me of lies.
I lost it in 1602.
I had dinner with Caravaggio
and drank too much wine.
It's a means. An instrument for ridding
the world of the Other.
Answer my question.
Did you kill Dominic?
He killed himself, Alex...
...after the Church abandoned him.
After they took away his reason to live.
They did to him as they did
to my brother, Alex.
And you know what I did?
You know what I did for Dominic?
I gave him absolution.
I took on the burden of his sins
and I gave him peace.
Not the Church.
I.
So don't talk to me of lies, Alex.
Dominic was like a father to me.
I'm just trying to understand.
[THUNDERING]
Come with me.
Every fear hides a wish,
don't you think?
So, what is it to be a Sin Eater?
What is it not to be one?
I know of no other way to be.
It seems beyond a man's judgment.
Forgiveness is God's domain.
I'm just an instrument. Like any great
power, it depends on how it's used.
-And how do you use it?
-As I see fit.
I'm not a threat to the Church.
I'm an insult, an embarrassment.
Well, you're a Carolingian,
you know how it feels to be outside.
I serve the Church.
Serve yourself?
Get Alex some fresh clothes.
And a hot bath, if he would like.
Then take him someplace
quiet where he can sit.
If you'd like anything,
anything can be arranged.
How long have I been asleep for?
A few hours.
What is it you want, Alex?
-I want to learn the truth.
-Truth?
The terrible thing about searching for
the truth is that sometimes you find it.
Not to mention it makes you
very unwelcome at parties.
It makes you unwelcome anywhere...
...even in church.
Who are you?
I'm all that remains
when everything else turns to dust.
To put it simply, Alex,
I'm very, very tired.
Are you a man?
I shit, I fuck.
I shave.
Does that make me a man?
Can you die?
You tell me.
I Iaugh.
I cry.
Once, I loved.
Does that make me a man,
I don't know.
What about you, Alex?
Are you a man?
I'm a priest.
You understand the difference?
The truth of it? Good.
Do you remember what Keats
said about the truth?
[CLEARS THROAT]
"Beauty is truth, truth is beauty."
Keeping that in mind...
... my original question:
What is it you want? The truth?
Or something beautiful?
Something beautiful.
Beauty is truth, Alex.
Does your oasis have a name?
Mara.
-Her name is Mara.
-So say it.
Say what you want, Alex.
If it's a truth, then why be afraid?
Say it.
I want Mara.
Then you're a man...
...and not a priest.
And if Mara's what you want,
then you should go and get her.
Hey. Shh.... You'll wake her.
She might be dreaming.
[CLANGING]
How we run from the things we need.
-He's dying.
-That's why I'm here.
Rembrandt did some remarkable things.
This isn't one of them.
It's a de Gelder.
But only I'll know that.
Put it in the car.
-Your services don't come cheap.
EDEN: No, they don't.
What did Dominic give you?
I mean, he had nothing.
That's not true.
He gave me friendship once,
and I returned it.
[MACHINE BEEPING]
What do you think you can do for him
that I haven't?
I am the conductor of the night train.
The answer to your question
is infinite.
Science...
...medicine...
...they give people nothing to hold
except words they can't pronounce.
Cancers that act capriciously.
You measure life with a ruler...
...and a bathroom scale.
And you take away.
You kill the mystery
that makes life mean something.
And you pretend to understand it all.
When you understand nothing,
when you are nothing.
When your dust
has more value than you do.
Christ on the cross...
...he gave forgiveness to a thief
being crucified alongside him.
The Church would not have allowed it.
-But Christ did.
-I know this man.
It's Marcus Burnham.
I read about him.
The lost sheep.
A man full of regret and fear,
such fear.
They say he got away with murder.
That remains to be seen.
Blood in...
...blood out.
From Jerusalem.
My brother said it held a splinter
from the true cross.
But the world is rotten with lies.
Bread for the host...
...and salt for the blood.
Are you ready to make your confession?
Forgiveness for the unforgivable.
Breathtaking.
[SOBBING]
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
[BURNHAM WHIMPERING]
I forgive you.
[SCREAMING]
[MAN YELLING]
[BURNHAM GASPING]
I'm--
I'm free.
EDEN:
My cross.
Alex, get me my cross, please.
[EDEN GASPING]
So, what do you think of what I do?
It's not immortality, Alex.
You would grow weary...
...but 500 years, 1000...
...imagine what you could
accomplish, given that time.
Imagine the knowledge that waits.
What are you saying?
I'm used up.
My time is done.
But I believe in the legacy of it all.
I should not be the last of my kind.
There should be another Other.
But why me?
-In the end, Alex, like recognizes like.
-I'm not like you.
Alex, you buried an excommunicated
priest in consecrated ground...
...after the Church had forbidden it.
You went around their authority, Alex,
the same as I do.
You're exactly like me.
I hope you like sunflowers.
I love sunflowers, you know that.
Why?
Why do you love sunflowers?
Because I always thought that when
God was making beautiful things...
-... he messed up with sunflowers.
-How?
Well, because they look like....
I don't know, they look like crooked
teeth around a mouth that's too big...
...kind of.
Yeah.
But...
...just when he was about
to start over...
...he realized that's what
made them beautiful...
...and that they're a brilliant mistake.
Like you and me.
Where'd you go?
William Eden...
...offered me the world last night.
When I saw these I knew.
Knew what?
That all I want is you.
Tell me what it is.
It's you and me.
It's you and me till the wheels fall off.
Yeah.
That's right.
EDEN:
I hadn't expected you so soon.
-How are you feeling?
-Formal. The pain has passed.
All that remains is the knowledge gained.
I brought you this...
...because I believe it's yours...
...and I have an answer for you.
Haste. That doesn't bode well.
My answer to your offer is no.
I don't want to be your successor.
Was I that wrong about you?
ALEX: We have a Iot in common,
I'II give you that.
-Can I ask you a question?
-Of course. Go ahead.
ALEX: Yesterday you said you
once Ioved. Were you ever married?
I've had many wives over the years.
But my Iove...
...that was centuries ago.
They grow old and they die
and I remain.
Maybe you'll understand, then.
Mara...
...I love her.
Well, that's fine. Have it all, Mara too.
There's no need to choose.
You're not a priest anymore.
Don't you see? I don't want Mara
to grow old without me.
AIex, the greatest truth of all
is that love cannot last.
You'll grow tired of it, bored.
I'll still be here. And so will my offer.
Goodbye, William Eden.
If I've learned one thing, Alex...
...it's that only in death
do we ever really say goodbye.
THOMAS: Want to know what I think?
-Do I have a choice?
I think he's evil. I don't think you
should have given him the dagger...
...and mostly, I don't think he's gonna
take no for an answer.
It's the only answer I've got.
Dominic trained us for what?
-I'm not a priest anymore.
-For what?
To dispatch ghosts, demons
and all manner of undead.
-That's right.
-But you said Eden's a living man.
Well, I was wrong. As soon as
I can move, I'll see if Sirach...
...knows where we can find
the rest of this.
It's time to walk away, Thomas.
Let it go.
No walking away, Alex.
Take Mara and run.
Get as far away as you can.
Lose yourselves somewhere.
Thomas, please.
Please, get some sleep,
eat some JELL-O, do something.
I'm gonna go visit Mara. I'll be back.
-Alex, I'm serious.
-Yeah, and I'm starting to laugh.
Just like you told me to.
Get some sleep.
[WINGS FLAPPING]
EDEN:
Is it dark where you go, Mara?
Is your pain shapeless,
or does it take form?
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
I thought we should finally meet.
I've heard many confessions.
I've never made one.
Did you know Alex's mother
killed herself?
Has he ever told you that?
How do you know about his mom?
I was there.
His father died in a car accident.
I was there then too.
Like me, Alex was defined
by specific events in his youth.
In his case...
...they were too important
to be left to fate.
You killed them?
Dominic helped me mold him.
Dominic gave me Alex. That was his sin.
[MARA GRUNTS]
You still haven't answered
my question, Mara.
Is it dark where you go, Mara...
...when the nightingales sing?
Huh?
I brought them to you.
I placed you in Alex's path.
Your love is my creation.
Manufactured like an automobile.
You don't need to worry.
Alex will be fine, I'll see to it.
I'm sorry, girl...
...this world is too much with me.
I'll take you to a place
where it isn't dark anymore...
...where the sun shines all the time.
I'm sorry.
[DOOR OPENS]
Mara?
[GASPING]
Oh....
No.
Mara. Mara.
Baby, baby, baby.
Baby. Oh....
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
-I'm sorry.
-Huh....
I can't. I can't.
I'm not a priest anymore.
I can take you out. I--
Baby, hang on, okay?
Hold on, okay? PIease.
[GRUNTING]
Now.
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
[GROANING]
MAID:
Buongiorno, Mr. Alex.
Eden!
MAID:
He's not here.
Where is he?
MAID: We thought you would know.
ALEX: Eden!
He said to say goodbye.
He told me to tell you
that everything's in order.
Everything that once was his
is now yours.
What's going on here?
[GLASS SHATTERING]
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
And watch your Ianguage.
It's a setup.
DRISCOLL:
Now.
Kiss the ring...
...and I'll spare your life.
Blasphemer.
So...
...has the world gone mad?
No, it still makes deals.
Mine was with William Eden.
I opened the Vatican vaults
and retrieved the dagger...
...William Eden had lost 400 years ago.
In return he compromised certain votes
of certain cardinals.
For my deal with William Eden...
...I will become pope.
A warrior pope.
A pope of a church
that will reclaim its property...
...and its sanctity and its power.
Blasphemer.
Pagan-worshipping blasphemer.
[HITTING]
[MEN YELLING]
ALEX:
I need to speak with Eden.
You know, the Other.
No, I'm asking you.
-I seek the Other.
MAN: He ends where he began...
...in St. Peter's.
We hang priests here. The weak ones!
[GUNSHOTS]
[THOMAS GROANING]
Mara died.
Slit her wrist.
I gotta go.
Gotta go.
THOMAS:
Alex.
-Am I the answer to your prayer?
EDEN: You just might be.
I performed the ceremony.
I found Mara dying...
...and I did it to set her free.
How did it feel?
Like I was God.
What about her sins,
do you have knowledge of them too?
Yes.
-There weren't many.
-Hmm.
She was a good girl.
One thing about it troubles me, though.
Don't intellectualize
something so visceral.
It's just, in the Church, suicide is
a mortal sin and I didn't feel it at all.
Maybe the Church is wrong.
No.
She was murdered.
One day you'll realize, AIex...
...that because of what I did...
...in your heart, Mara, your love...
-...will live forever.
-No!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
Now you'll know what I know, Alex.
Time to look into the abyss.
There are wonders there.
[GROANING AND SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING]
I feel like I'm...
... 10 years old again.
I'm home.
I understand.
God save me, I understand.
The parchment...
...it's not how you kill the Other,
it's how you become the Other.
Sorry I found out too late.
I won't leave you like this, Alex.
There has to be another way.
When I learn what it is, I'll find you.
Even if it's to kill you.
ALEX:
Morning.
-I sent for the Sin Eater.
-I am the Sin Eater.
Huh....
So Eden gets what he asks for
and you and I are left behind.
What you told the Vatican
has ruined me. Did you know that?
Deposed and degraded.
It was you, wasn't it?
I learned a lot in a very short time.
And in the end, the only secret
people keep is immortality.
You ready?
It's the confession, not the priest,
that gives you absolution.
You understand?
DRISCOLL:
Yes.
Are you ready to make your confession?
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
She was like a sunflower.
God's beautiful mistake.
Choke on your own filth.
[SCREAMS]
[CRACKING]
ALEX:
And now it is I.
I have been blessed and cursed...
...for now I possess the keys
to the kingdom of heaven.
I will forgive those
who deserve freedom.
I will damn those
who've damned themselves.
I will learn to live after love has died.
I am the Sin Eater.