Feet off the seat.
You see, Joe?
lt's absolutely beautiful here.
What type of trees are those?
They look like they're the same
as the one that was in our yard.
Don't you think?
Mind the paint, dear.
-Hello.
-Heather?
We didn't see you there.
l'm sorry.
l'm Miss Traverse, headmistress.
Welcome to the Academy.
Heather is so excited to be here.
This is much nicer
than the boarding school l went to.
We're rather isolated here...
...so we try and supply the students
with plenty of stimulation.
Academic and otherwise.
Do you like athletics, Heather?
You look as though you might.
Oh, Heather needs to concentrate
on her studies...
...before she can worry about
playing games.
This way, please.
lt's been over a century
since the Academy...
...was originally founded
as a one-room schoolhouse.
We've grown quite nicely since then.
ln fact, all of the teachers
were once students at the school.
Miss Leland,
this is Dr. and Mrs. Fasulo.
You must be Heather.
Heather, would you like to join me?
We like to have a short interview
with each new student as she arrives.
Just so we know what sort of
young lady we're dealing with.
Miss Leland will sit down with you
to discuss tuition.
Follow me, Heather.
So you enjoy setting fires.
According to my papers,
the whole house almost went up...
...as a result of some sort of
disagreement with your mother.
This is not a school
for wayward girls, Heather.
This is not a juvenile hall.
We have a great tradition of graduating
only the finest young ladies.
So no fires?
Your mother has inquired
about financial aid.
Apparently, your father is not as well off
as he presents himself.
We do offer scholarships for students
we consider particularly gifted.
Has anyone ever thought
you might be?
Complete this within the time limit,
and we'll go from there.
So how did we do?
Don't let your nails
get out of control.
Miss Mackinaw?
Take care of this young lady,
won't you?
Are you hungry?
You must drink your milk, girls.
Where's Ann Whales been?
You didn't hear? lt was really bloody.
You'll have to pull your socks up.
Otherwise, it's a uniform demerit.
And then what? A spanking?
l'm Marcy Turner.
Heather.
You take the scholarship test?
Apparently, my father isn't as well off
as he presents himself.
Who is?
Hi, Marcy.
How are you?
-l'm well.
-Wow, that's super.
Have you all met Heather?
Hi there.
So you're Marcy's new friend?
Sure.
That's super keen.
Hey....
Samantha.
-Samantha.
-Yes, Heather?
Do me a favor: Point those torpedoes
south and start walking.
l'm trying to eat.
A bad girl.
Hey, is your pubic hair red, too?
Guess there's only one way
to find out:
Marcy,
does Heather have red pubes?
ls she a fire-crotch?
l'm kidding. Friends?
Oops.
Sorry about that.
-Good night, ladies.
-Good night, Miss Mackinaw.
Good night, Miss Mackinaw.
Good night, everyone.
Good night, Mary.
Good night, Lena.
Heather.
Free us.
Release us.
This is my bed.
lt's a nice bed.
Someone else
will have to sleep here.
Why are there twigs in my hair?
What?
-Hey, wait up.
-Okay, well hurry up...
-...we can't be late again.
-All right.
Hey, whose bed is that?
Ann Whales.
She's in the hospital now.
She had an accident.
What happened?
Tried to kill herself in chemistry class.
Couple weeks ago.
There was blood all over the place.
Let's go, ladies.
Have a good day.
Say it.
'' l'm a fire-crotch.''
-What?
-'' l am a fire-crotch.''
How many football players
put it in you...
...before your mom got sick of having
another tramp around the house?
Nice one.
lf you know what's good for you, you'll
run away and never, ever come back.
Got it, fire-crotch?
Miss Fasulo,
you are 20 minutes late.
Sorry.
You are disrupting
the other students' ability to learn.
-Sorry.
-More than three minutes tardy...
...equals a truancy.
Go to Miss Traverse's office
and inform her of your infraction.
-Come on.
-Don't you dare talk back to me!
You get out of my sight!
Get out of my class immediately!
And that's a demerit
for your un-tucked blouse.
Do not go to the headmistress' office
without tucking in your--
Don't tuck it in here!
What kind of a low-class so-and-so
reaches her hands into....
Go to the ladies' room,
and then go to Miss Traverse's office.
I was hoping you'd be here more than a
few days before being sent to see me.
l'm disappointed, Heather.
You know, you're right.
l'm just not up to the standards
of this fine institution.
Better let me call my parents.
Tell them to come get me.
Here.
-Yes?
-Mom?
Heather, I wasn't expecting
to hear from you.
It's just wonderful about the
scholarship, dear.
I told all the other ladies.
No, Mom. l-- l faked it. lt was--
Look, can l just talk to Dad?
Your father is entertaining
company, dear.
-Listen to me--
-Mrs. Richards...
... will you mind the carpet.
It's brand new.
l'm sorry that l got into trouble
all the time.
Oh, hi, Dorothy.
And that l fought with you.
-And the fire.
-I had to pull a lot of strings...
-... to get you into that school.
-Mom, l...
...l promise that l won't embarrass you
anymore, okay?
You think I sent you....
Heather, I am your mother.
Oh, for heaven's sak e. I have to go.
Mrs. Richards just spilled that drink.
Mom, l just wanna come home.
l miss my friends.
Heather, sweetheart...
...you don't have any friends.
You stop being such a weakling...
...and you work hard
and you mak e me proud.
l'll excuse the truancy.
You may return to class.
You shouldn't go into the woods.
lt's not safe.
lt's not so bad here.
Better than living at home.
Home would be fine
if my mom was dead.
You shouldn't say things like that.
Here.
We can listen together...
...if you want.
You first heard her
at the ripe age of 1 7...
... with her number-one hit
''It's My Party, '' here's Lesley Gore.
-Marcy.
-Jeez.
-Marcy looked like she was gonna cry.
-Sorry.
-Come on, Samantha. We're ready.
-Ready?
-Here!
-Barbecue, it's you!
-Come on, Heather.
-Shut up, Jen. lt's okay, Heather.
-Come on, Heather. Heather.
-Come on, Heather, get the ball, Heather.
Quit standing around
and bring back the ball.
-What are you doing?
-Bring the ball!
Set us free.
Help us.
Has anyone heard what's happened
to Ann Whales?
l haven't heard anything.
ls she still in the hospital?
You know, Marcy, you could be sitting
on a dead girl's bed.
Ann's not dead.
-Well, how do you know, Marcy?
-She probably killed her.
-Yeah, and you're next.
-Shut up, fire-crotch.
Can we get back
to the photosynthesis?
-Maybe it was Clara Thompson.
-Oh, God.
-Who's this?
-A stupid story they tell all the freshmen.
Don't go into the woods at night
or blah, blah, blah.
The story goes all the way back
to the old days.
-Tracy peed her pants when she heard it.
-Oh, shut up.
Clara Thompson and her sisters
were these three witches...
...that took over this school
almost 1 00 years ago.
They just walk ed
out of the woods one day.
No one knew where they came from.
l heard they were orphans.
l thought they just kind of
came out of nowhere.
Anyways, after they arrived
at the school...
-...strange things started to happen.
-We love you.
The sisters were just creepy.
They were always
looking off to the trees.
Hearing v oices
that no one else could hear.
One day, the students caught them
practicing a weird ritual.
-Right inside the school.
-Witch.
They were terrified
by what they saw.
They taunted the sisters.
They beat them.
I mean, it got really bad.
So, Clara called upon the woods
for revenge.
She offered them all the students'
souls in return.
We'll do anything!
A couple of days later, the girls
chased the sisters into the forest.
Out for blood.
But when they all got out there,
something happened.
Something bad.
-What?
-No one knows.
Accept these gifts...
...and let the primal song
free your restless souls.
But what we do know,
is that later that night...
...all the other girls came out of the
woods, led by Clara.
Lik e she had them under a spell.
Lik e they were possessed.
And they all watched
as Clara chopped up the headmistress...
...with an axe.
I am so proud of you, Clara.
Yeah, and then
all the other girls joined in...
...and they stabbed her
and smashed her head in with logs.
And when she was in this big,
mushy pile...
...of guts and bones and blood...
...they dumped it all down the well.
The very same one out in the rec yard.
And what l hear...
...is that Clara still roams
the woods at night...
...waiting for little girls
to wander too far out.
Waiting for fresh blood.
Yeah, real mature, Jen.
What do you think, Heather?
l heard you took a walk
in the woods not long ago.
You see any Clara Thompsons
out there?
You ever been out there, Barb?
Quit it, we haven't started yet.
Quit it!
l'm going.
Maybe this isn't such a good idea.
-Go.
-l am!
This is so s--
Trust us.
How are you today?
-l don't have my pencils and stuff.
-You won't need them.
This is the first
of your advanced courses.
lt's a condition
of your scholarship...
...to participate in this class
whenever told.
Heather...
...how did you come
to attend this school?
Well, l got into the car and then
my dad started the engine....
l won't ask again.
A woman came to my school
during conferences this summer...
...and convinced my mother
that this is where l should be going.
-And?
-And...
...my mom wanted me
out of the house.
Do you resent your mother
for leaving you here?
Sure.
You hate her?
-No.
-Does she hate you?
A loving mother never
abandons her child.
To be separated from her
is like an amputation.
lt doesn't matter what a child looks
like, if she's smart, if she's stupid...
...if she has no friends.
So why would your
mother leave you here?
That is none of your business.
She's afraid of you.
-Stop!
-Why is she afraid of you?
Kill her.
Are you a bad person?
Do you think bad thoughts?
-Stop!
-ls it the voices?
Pain.
-l don't--
-Destiny.
l don't....
What do they say?
Heather.
Heather, do you hear?
Kill your mother.
Teacher. Death.
Serve us.
We love you.
Kill her.
-What the hell was that?
-Watch your language.
lf l frightened you...
...l apologize.
How did you do in there?
Are you special enough
for a scholarship?
Everyone knows you're a fake.
You're not an egghead
like Marcy and Ann.
You're dumber than
a fucking tree stump.
l believe you're gonna cry, fire-crotch.
Heard you scream all
the way down the hall.
Traverse give you
a hard time in there?
Seriously.
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Or heard one.
Not so tough anymore, are we?
Samantha.
All right, ladies.
The Austrian War of Liberation.
Today's lesson.
ln April 1 809, Austria proclaimed
war of liberation on France.
France responded by
rapidly advancing....
Which, if you remember,
we occupied....
The Germans....
Balance.
Drink your milk.
What is it?
You'd think her parents
would take her home.
Can't.
They died.
Marcy...
...have you heard...
...or seen strange things
happen at this school?
Like what?
Heard you been saying stuff
behind my back, fire-crotch.
Now, Samantha, all l said
was your breath smells like...
...you've been drinking out of
Miss Mackinaw's douche bag, that's all.
l don't wanna kiss you, Samantha,
so please, don't ask.
Now, you listen
very closely, fire-crotch:
We have a certain way
of doing things around here...
...and you better figure out
what that way is...
...or there are going to be
serious consequences.
Fire-crotch! Fire-crotch! Fire-crotch!
Get off me!
Get away from me.
Why don't you let her go?
-What is this?
-Miss Fasulo attacked Miss Wise...
...in the dining hall.
-ls that so?
-l didn't attack anyone.
l was just trying to defend myself.
l'm sorry. l didn't mean to....
Now, listen: We have a certain way
of doing things around here...
...and you had better figure
out what that way is...
...or there are going to be
serious consequences.
Get to the bunkhouse
before lights out.
Ann?
That's your name, isn't it?
l'm Heather.
l know what you're here for.
-You're special too.
-What?
Like me. Like Marcy.
We have to do what they say
or they'll kill everyone.
l can't understand you.
l am so cold.
lt's too late. They're here for me.
What are you doing out of
your bunk, young lady?
Ann, what are you doing awake?
You lie down right now
and go to sleep.
Sit down and wait for the nurse.
What was that all about?
What happened last night?
No, later.
Just go ahead, l'll catch up.
So we had a little
accident last night?
Twisted your ankle?
Hey, Ann.
lt's breakfast.
l know.
What happened to you?
No doubt you have all heard
that one of our family...
Banged up my ankle.
Sorry about all the hollering last night.
...Ann Whales...
...went missing sometime last night.
Last night?
When?
Breakfast.
l just wanted to reassure all of you:
Nuts, we should go.
The authorities are searching for her
as we speak.
ln the meantime...
...the best way to deal with this
is go on with our work...
...and trust that all will
be resolved in time.
Dismissed.
That's all that's left of Ann.
Wake up, Miss Turner.
lt's time for your lesson.
For your throat.
The song must be perfect.
You must do it over and over
until there are no mistakes.
My guidance will assure that.
All right, now, Miss Turner,
we're going to try it again.
-And this time--
-Please, l've been doing this all day--
lt is tremendously
important that we do this.
-l am trying. l can't do it--
-l wouldn't want to have to--
You put your makeup on
upside down, silly.
Your girlfriend's got a real
pretty voice, fire-crotch.
Back off.
We need to have a little discussion.
Try it again!
The folks at the hospital
gave me this.
l guess Ann must have forgot it
after her accident.
Ann will appreciate this.
l'll give it to her this evening.
How is she?
Quiet, but we're keeping
an eye on her.
l don't suspect she'll
try anything rash again.
Good.
Well, thanks for signing this stuff.
l'll be sure to get it to Ann's
insurance company this week.
lt's no problem at all.
Okay.
Marcy, listen to me:
l just saw a cop
talking to Miss Traverse.
And she didn't tell them anything
about Ann. She totally lied.
l had a really tough session
today. My throat's sore.
Hey. Marcy.
There's no one out
there looking for Ann.
Ann's fine.
Everything's fine.
Hey, l really need to talk to you.
Leave me alone...
...fire-crotch.
Don't forget to drink your milk.
She's crazy.
-Fire-crotch.
-l hope she gets kicked out.
-This girl is nothing but trouble.
-l told you they were gay.
She's in trouble now.
She is so lucky.
She better watch out.
She'll get her later.
Lights out.
Everyone in bed. Now.
Sleep.
Want Marcy.
Release us, Heather.
l was asleep.
You were asleep?
Everybody was asleep?
You didn't see anything, either.
Breakfast.
Why is everyone standing around?
Good Lord.
Everyone, get ready for breakfast.
l'll inform Miss Traverse
of what's happened.
Get dressed, Miss Fasulo.
Don't worry. We'll find Marcy.
And Ann?
ln the process of metamorphosis,
there are four stages.
Could you tell me another
word for chrysalis?
-Pupa.
-Correct.
Marcy?
-Marcy?
-You're not gonna find her out there.
-Get away from me. Get--
-Shut up and just listen to me.
-Get off of me.
-l'm trying to help you.
l have to get Marcy.
l tried to warn you about Marcy,
but they're always watching.
We've gotta get you out of here.
l called your dad.
l told him you went nuts.
l just hope he gets here
before they take you too.
lt's the teachers.
They do tests.
Give out scholarships.
Clara Thompson
was just the beginning.
The woods possessed her.
Took over the school.
And there's more of them
waiting to be freed.
You think you're the only
one that hears the voices?
How do you think they found you?
The woods need more bodies.
They'll take every girl here,
and you're the key, Heather.
Just like Clara was.
You're the first
Miss Traverse has seen.
You're psycho.
Listen.
Very closely.
-We've got to find--
-Samantha.
You should be in class right now.
Yes, ma'am.
Come with me.
l believe you're tardy for
Miss Charevoix's class, Miss Fasulo.
Don't drink the milk.
Marcy.
Right now.
So Hannibal began his
trek across the Alps.
Who can tell me his
mode of transportation?
Miss Fasulo?
l'll give you a hint:
lt wasn't horses.
He needed a lot of peanuts.
What was that?
Come on, let's go. Hurry. Go.
-Just follow her.
-Oh, what's going on?
-Where are we going?
-l don't know.
Come on. Everyone out.
Come on.
l'm gonna miss you.
This is so horrible.
-What did you say to Samantha?
-Nothing.
The girl is dead. What did you say?
l know what you're doing.
-She told me everything.
-Told you what?
Which story?
That l kidnapped your friends--?
Yes.
Samantha was a good student, once.
But she was very angry
and very confused.
But l was charged
with looking after her.
Obviously, l failed to do that.
Where are Ann and Marcy?
They ran away.
lt happens.
You don't have to believe me.
This is one of the most distinguished
schools in the country.
We could not very well survive,
had we orchestrated the disappearance...
...of two of our best students...
...within weeks of each other.
Truth be told:
We may not survive
this, regardless.
l don't know what l'd do
if l lost this school.
lt's been a part of me for so long.
Be patient. Your friends
will come back. They always do.
ls there something else
you wish to ask?
The things that l've heard.
The things that l've seen.
-l'm not crazy.
-l know.
You're different.
All the signs are there, Heather.
You want me to call the parents?
l should be the one to tell them.
Robert, have you met
Heather Fasulo?
How are you?
Hey, how's the search for
Ann and Marcy going?
l just miss them so much.
Miss Fasulo is expected in chapel.
Two of the students...
...did, in fact, go missing
shortly after we found Samantha.
-Ann was one of them.
-And you weren't gonna tell me?
l didn't wanna cause you
any more trouble.
Well, that's really not up to you,
Miss Traverse.
One of the students saw them
run into the forest.
Miss Leland will show
you which direction.
Ann? Marcy?
Hello?
'' Miss Leland will show you
which direction.''
Come on, it's beyond your curfew.
Come on, girls.
Lucky rabbit, lucky rabbit. Okay.
Marcy?
Ann?
Samantha?
Are you special enough
for a scholarship?
You tak e the scholarship test?
We do offer scholarships for students
we consider particularly gifted.
Blood.
Ann?
Marcy?
-Dr. Fasulo--
-l'm sorry to waste your time.
Whatever you were told,
the damage was not that bad.
Somebody called and said
my daughter went on a rampage.
l don't know who made that call.
But we've been very attentive
to your daughter's needs.
-She just needs to settle in.
-l'm sorry to waste your time.
But this is all my fault.
l never should have left her here
in the first place.
-Joe, turn around.
-l can't understand it.
Go back and ask for directions.
lt's too late.
l'm positive we went out
the same way we came in.
-This is ridiculous.
-l think l saw a road a ways back.
You be quiet. We wouldn't be out here
to begin with if it wasn't for you.
-Alice.
-l don't know what l have to do...
-...to get you under control, Heather.
-Then stop trying.
You keep up the smart mouth,
young lady.
As soon as we get home,
we are finding another school.
A religious one. l'm talking nuns.
-Oh, Alice, we're not even Catholic.
-l don't care.
Joe, watch where you're going!
Dad!
Great. This is my life.
Me and my perfect family.
Could we please just drop it?
Maybe you're the one
that needs to go back to school.
You can't even find your way
down a simple road.
Now, you listen.
l've had just about enough--
Heather. Heather, are you all right?
l can't understand it.
The earth must have just given out.
Joe, help me.
Heather, sweetheart. Hang in there.
-What?
-Hang in there?
You be quiet.
Alice?
-Does that hurt?
-Yes.
She actually sustained that
before the accident.
l'll go see about some crutches.
The doctor thinks you have
a mild concussion, Heather.
No big deal.
Where's my parents?
Why don't l go tell Miss Traverse
you're awake?
Help me.
Where's Mom?
Come here, honey.
Where is she?
Oh, Heather.
-Here she is.
-Oh, you can't be in here.
-No!
-Just relax. Just-- lt'll be fine.
-Hey.
-Dad! No!
-What are you doing? Let go of her!
-Heather, it's gonna be all right.
-Bring her back!
-She's a witch!
Stop! What are you do--?
She'll kill you!
What are you doing?
Where are they taking her?
She's in shock.
-Stop.
-Good girl.
-Bring her back.
-Heather hasn't been fully examined.
She needs me
and she needs to be here with me.
The doctor says she may have
internal injuries.
We must give them a chance
to do their jobs.
l can't understand it.
l mean, one minute...
...we're sitting there
on the side of the road...
...and then the next minute
the car just....
Something took her.
ln the car, something....
Bring her back here.
Bring me my daughter.
l wanna see my mom! Where is she?
-No. No!
-l really can't bring Heather back to you.
-Please!
-Who the hell are you?
You do as l say, right--
l want my mom! Where is my mom?
Stop him! l wanna see my--
Heather.
Wak e up. It's time.
How are you feeling?
Dad?
Heather? Heather.
l'm afraid his condition
has worsened.
But the doctors say
it's only temporary.
-Ceremony.
-Heather.
I love you.
Balance the stones.
All the signs are there.
It's time.
Our wait is over. Free us.
Free us.
Drink it.
They moved you. You're over there.
This is my bed.
-Good night, ladies.
-Good night, Miss Traverse.
-Good night, Miss Mackinaw.
Good night, Miss Traverse.
You better watch out.
Something's going to happen.
You better be careful.
My family is large.
I cannot rest until I've freed them all.
What's happening?
If you struggle, it will only hurt more.
Where are we?
You don't know what it's lik e
to be trapped.
To be tied to the same place...
... for hundreds of years.
They're here to help you, Heather.
Don't be sad.
By leaving this world...
...you're giving others the opportunity
to fully enter it.
What's wrong with you? Let me go!
Ever since I came here with my sisters,
we have been waiting for you.
Hear our prayer, Mother.
Marcy, stop.
Accept these gifts...
...and let the primal song
free your restless souls.
Balance the stones, Heather.
-And there shall be an end to the pain.
-No.
Mom? Help me.
What do you think l've been trying
to do this whole time?
Now, you stop being such a weakling...
...and you work hard...
...and you make your mother proud.
l'm sorry.
Heather! Let me in!
Balance the stones, Heather.
You never listen.
Heather!
Open this door!
Somebody let me in!
l'm so proud of you, Heather.
Let the souls of the woods
enter these young vessels...
...and finally walk the earth.
-Heather!
-Dad?
Heather, get out!
You can't escape.
You can't stop the change.
Help me.
-Kill her.
Kill her.
So gifted.
I am everywhere.