Come on!
What?
What? Are you kidding?
Nice shot!
Oh, are you freaking blind?
What the hell, man. I was open.
Bullshit. You were both covered.
Thought I got the shot off on time.
Yeah, right.
Hey!
Come on. There's two seconds
left on the clock.
Scoreboard's broken.
We got the official time on the ice.
Game's over.
Prick.
Hi.
Hey, Jenny.
I was starting to get worried
you were never going
to come outside.
So was l.
I almost didn't.
Are you all right?
Yeah. Aside from the sudden desire
to slit my wrists,
I think I'll make it to Monday.
I'm sorry.
Mm, it's all right.
I'll be fine.
Hey.
Do you want a ride?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Okay.
What are you thinking about?
I'm just freakin' blowing it.
The last second.
Ian.
It's a game.
I know, it's a game.
But--
It's pointless. It's over with.
Come on. Talk about it.
You know how it is.
You ever have a day
where just everyth--
everything's going wrong?
Yeah, sometimes.
That's today.
That's this day.
What happened?
Well, you saw the scoreboard
stop, right?
Yeah. Everyone saw that.
That's what I'm saying.
That doesn't happen.
Uh, that's--
Today has just been--
Something's just been off.
It's not right all day.
Baby.
Baby, you sound a bit crazy.
I know. It's because I am crazy.
You know, I bet I can make you
forget all about it.
I'd better go.
Call me later, okay?
Hey, I'm crazy about you.
I've heard.
Good night.
Bye.
Hey!
Ah, come on.
No!
Hello.
Ian.
You manage to look
at those spreadsheets
that I sent down?
Spreadsheets.
Yeah.
I was actually just getting to those...
next.
Marcus wants the client bios
for the presentation by 6:00.
Thanks much.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. I'm s-- I'm sorry.
I'm just spacing. Hi.
Hi.
Back on the pipe again, huh?
No. No. I actually quit yesterday.
Good for you.
Baby steps.
Ready for some bad news?
Uh-uh.
Purchasing want reports
on each of these.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Do me a favor.
Anything.
Kill me now.
But then I wouldn't get
to pass this shit off on you
and generally make
your existence a living hell.
So that's
all I'm good for.
Well, I guess I'd miss
seeing your pretty
little face every day.
So you're still heading home
to your folks for the weekend?
Yep.
Well, you don't sound
so enthused.
Well, I could do without
my mum's yearly
"Why aren't you married with three kids
like your sisters?" lecture.
- Do me a favor.
- Anything.
Shoot me if I turn into my sisters.
Yeah, but, see, then I wouldn't get
to see your pretty little face.
Hey, have a good one, Carl.
Just try and keep yourself calm.
- He was just going crazy.
- Call in, then.
- Yeah, yeah, loosen his collar.
- Try and stay as still as you can.
All right. Stay with us. Try and breathe.
Does anyone know who he is?
He's getting worse.
Looks like he's having
a heart attack or something.
It's just me.
Sorry, Medea.
- Mmm, so tired.
- Yeah.
Mmm. I just came straight home
and went to sleep.
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
Did you remember my dry cleaning?
- Shit!
- Ian, I reminded you twice.
I know. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- Idiot.
And I bought you a present.
- Did you?
- Mm-hmm.
You don't deserve it.
Do you want it now?
Or later?
Let's go with later.
Later's good.
All right, then, you have
to promise me that you'll like it.
I cross my heart,
and I hope to die.
- Stick a needle in your eye.
- In my eye.
This thing is heavy.
How much did you spend on this?
- Only my life savings.
- Oh, good.
- Open it!
- Okay.
That's beautiful, babe.
You're always running late.
I thought you might like it.
I do. I love it. It's great.
It's got a timer on it and everything.
There are loads of other functions.
The woman in the shop said that.
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong. It's fine. I like it.
I...
I watched a man die today.
What?
On the way home from work,
right in front of me.
And I just shared an elevator
with the guy, you know?
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
And this other guy
was standing over him.
And at first it looked like
he was there to help, I thought.
But then, uh...
What?
I don't know.
I don't know. I guess
I don't know what I saw.
Weird part is,
the guy that was helping him
reminded me of this hockey ref
who used to hassle me.
You never told me
you played hockey.
Of course I did.
Club team in college.
I told you a million times.
No, you definitely didn't.
No, I definitely did.
I'll get my yearbook.
There you go. Number 17.
Yeah.
Number 17's very cute,
but it's not you.
Huh?
That should be me.
All right.
So I never played hockey.
Problem is, I'm remembering
something that never happened.
Maybe something's wrong
with me, you know?
I don't know. Do you think
something's wrong with you?
No. I mean, I feel fine.
But you gotta admit, having memories
of shit that never happened...
Come on. Doesn't that
strike you as bizarre?
Nothing bizarre
ever happens to you.
I'm serious, Medea.
You don't think this is a little nuts?
Ian, you're speaking to a girl whose
parents named her after a witch
- who killed her own children.
- That's right.
You'll forgive me if there are
few things that strike me
as being a little nuts.
Something's not right.
Ian, I'm going to bed.
You should come, too.
He knows.
It's too late.
Ian, you're gonna be late.
Son of a bitch!
One day, you might actually
try getting up on time.
And not risk getting fired?
How much fun would that be?
Stop! Stop the bus!
Stop the bus!
Stop the bus, please. Sorry.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- No, I need to talk to you.
- I don't have any money. I have none.
- Look-- Please, Ian-- Ian--
Please! If you don't listen
to me, you'll be killed.
Come on. We need to go
somewhere safe. Come on.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
Do l-- Do I know you?
Your watch stopped.
Your watch.
After you left for work this morning,
it stopped, didn't it?
Whenever a clock stops, they're coming.
Who?
You know.
I'm sorry. I don't know
what you're talking about.
Listen, you're a smart boy.
Don't let denial
get in the way of that.
- Who the hell are you?
- That's not important.
- No. You know what? That is important.
- They're hunting you, Ian.
Since yesterday afternoon at 5:00,
when you woke up and this life started.
- "When this life started." Okay.
- Yes. Yes.
They created it for you.
Yesterday, at 5:03,
you found yourself
a year out of university,
stuck in an office,
- trussed up in a jacket and tie you hate.
- Don't touch me!
Before that, you were a hockey player
in a small university.
Wait a minute. Hockey.
That happened?
Yes. And before that,
you were someone else.
No, no... Just listen to me.
If they kill you, this is
gonna happen all over again.
No, it won't. If they kill me,
I'll be dead.
You won't die.
They've been murdering you
every day.
Always at different times,
different places, different lives.
You never know when they're gonna
get you, but sooner or later, they do.
This is insane.
You have no idea
what you're dealing with here.
They can alter reality, control minds.
You only see what they want you to see.
What the hell are they?
"They"...
People have called them lots of things.
Ghosts, demons...
No, no, no. Don't give me
this voodoo bullshit.
They coexist with humans
but on anther plane,
and they can only be seen
when they want to be seen.
And they're coming after you
because they need to stop you.
- From doing what?
- Remembering.
Okay. Remembering what?
They're gonna keep killing you
until you do what they want.
Okay, but I don't know
what that is!
No! Just--
Just run!
Run!
Who you lookin' at?
Come on!
Shit!
Hey! Hey! Stop! Stop!
Fuck!
Hey!
- Ian, what are you doing home?
- They're trying to kill me!
- Who? What?
- I don't know. I don't know.
- Ian, calm down. Tell me...
- Shh!
Do you hear that?
Ian...
Medea...
what are you doing?
I'm sorry, Ian.
I'm so sorry.
I don't enjoy this, Ian,
but you leave me no choice.
No.
No!
Ohhh, Ian.
Ian.
You shouldn't have remembered.
It'll be all right.
I promise.
Watch out!
Christ!
Pull over and get some coffee
or something, will you?
I'm really sorry about that.
Getting the customer to their destination
alive usually makes for a better tip.
Yeah, I've-- I've heard.
So you were saying that you're heading home
to your folks for the weekend, huh?
- Yeah. Last minute.
- Yeah.
I missed my train.
You don't sound so enthused.
I could do without
my mum's yearly,
"Why aren't you married
with three kids like your sisters?"
Well, we'll have you home in a jiffy.
I thought my mum was the only one
who still said "jiffy."
Thank you.
No, no. Miss? Miss?
I can't-- I can't--
I mean,
I almost got you killed.
Well, you got me here alive
and are being tipped accordingly.
Thank you.
Why don't you come in for a sec?
You look like you
could use a coffee.
Uh, no.
I probably shouldn't. I mean--
'Cause then I'd interrupt
the party, and your mom
would think you're getting started
on those three kids with a cabdriver.
Probably have a heart attack.
Okay.
Well, why don't you wait here
while I go get you one?
- That I could do.
- Okay.
Two minutes.
All right.
You okay?
Yeah. I'm just
really late for a call, so--
Don't you want the coffee?
Coffee. Right. Thank you.
Okay.
Hello!
Ian.
I know you.
How do I know you?
You have to remember, Ian.
They're already coming.
But whatever you do,
don't let them find her.
If they find out, they could
do terrible things to her,
and that will be the end for you.
What did you just--
What the hell's happening to me?
Come on.
Yep, I promise.
I'll be home this weekend.
Uh, look, listen. Okay.
I've gotta go.
Yeah, I'll be there.
I love you, too.
Bye. Bye.
Sorry about that.
Ian,
did you look for work last week?
Yeah. I had three appointments,
and all three positions had been filled
by the time I got there.
And what happened
with Mr. Glenn?
He was an asshole, and I didn't
feel like spending all day
crammed in a truck with him.
Have the clocks stopped?
What?
The clocks. H-Have--
Have the clocks stopped?
Why would they stop?
Are you all right?
Yeah.
You're gonna think
I'm absolutely crazy,
but I keep waking up in different places,
and everything's changed,
except you, 'cause you're still here.
Ian,
I thought you said you cleaned up.
What?
No. No, no, no.
This has nothing to do with that.
You don't understand.
These people are trying to kill me.
Right.
I'm not crazy, all right?
- This is happening to me.
- Yes, okay.
- I understand.
- No, you don't understand.
All right? You don't believe me.
I'm sorry. You need
to calm down, okay?
I don't understand. You have to
explain it to me. I'm sorry.
Oh, my God.
It's happening again.
What's happening again?
Ian?
Shit!
Come on. Come on!
Hey! Excuse me.
- Ian! What the hell's the matter with you?
- Let me go.
- I've gotta--
- Ian! Ian! Hey!
Oh, my God. It's you.
- He told me not to let them find you.
- For Christ sake, Ian...
Jenny, listen to me!
You're not safe.
- Okay?
- What?
Ian, stop running.
Oh, my God.
Ian!
Jenny, don't follow me!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Bloody hell!
What's up with you, mate?
Just go! Go!
So, where to?
Stop! Let me out!
Oi! Oi!
We don't like doing this, Ian,
but we don't have much choice.
Do we?
Ian!
For fuck's sake, Ian! I can hear
that shit through my floor.
- Turn it down!
- Jenny.
I'm gonna call the landlord next time.
Jenny...
Jesus Christ, Ian.
Please wake up.
But I feel bad for him, you know?
He wasn't always...
Yeah, you're right.
I will call the landlord. I promise.
No, don't come over. I'll be fine.
Okay. I'll come to yours.
Because you've got a bigger TV.
Ian! What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Jenny...
Jenny, I need your help.
Look, just get the hell
out of my house.
I'm not gonna hurt you, all right?
I promise.
I'm warning you,
just stay away from me.
Jenny, you know me?
Of course I know you.
From the office.
What office?
Ian, do you need me
to call you an ambulance?
No.
What's wrong with you?
Okay, I'm gonna get some help.
Don't touch the door.
We know each other
a lot better than you think.
What do you mean?
You don't like going home
to your mother's
'cause she wishes
you were married with kids,
like your sisters.
Come on.
I need you to remember.
Get up.
Duck!
Oh, God!
Tell me why
you never learn.
Maybe you should stop this now,
because I can do this
forever.
Run!
Ian.
Okay.
What are those things?
I'm still working on that.
What about you--
back at the apartment?
What happened to you?
It's like something
was attacking me...
from the inside.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my God.
You look better now.
I don't feel better.
I hate seeing you like this.
Like what?
It's like how nervous you get
before a game.
In college, right?
Yeah.
You remember that?
Of course l...
- We were dating.
- That's right. For more than a year.
And you played hockey.
You were still living
with your parents.
No. No!
This is okay.
This is-- This is good.
- But it didn't happen.
- No, because this did happen.
Do you remember the office?
You remember that?
You remember the taxicab?
Yeah.
When did you start remembering?
When you said I should remember.
When you said those things
about me not wanting to go home.
Right.
You couldn't possibly know that.
And the rest of it,
it just started coming back.
Are they following us?
No, not yet.
Okay.
I say we stay on this train
and travel as far as it goes.
Put some distance
between you and those things.
You don't understand. No amount
of distance is gonna stop them.
Well, it's a chance.
Hopefully it will give us some time.
How much time?
Enough time
so we don't get killed?
I'm sorry, all right?
I mean, I don't understand
why I keep bringing you into this,
but you need to just get
as far away from me as possible.
Hey, I'm with you, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
You look awful.
I could say the same about you.
So you're one of them.
A harvester.
We don't die.
We just keep going, feeding off them.
Feeding?
How?
I'll show you.
So you let him see you?
We feed on their fear.
So, w-what are you, like vampires?
It sustains us.
But we corrupted ourselves.
We began feeding
on human pain as well,
searching for it everywhere.
It's almost like an addiction.
And the fear one of them experiences
the moment before a violent death
is the most potent.
Our...drug of choice.
Once you've tasted it,
you never want to stop.
You need it more and more.
And when you can't find it,
you have to kill for it.
That's what turned us
from parasites into predators.
And you just keep hunting,
waiting to feed again.
S-So, how many of them are there?
I don't know anymore.
Why the hell are these things
coming after me?
You hurt them.
You did something to them,
and they won't let you remember
until they can work out how
to bring you back into the fold...
or destroy you.
You were the most powerful one.
They can't kill you, but together,
they have the power to move you
from life to life every day.
Such a simple thing.
How another can change us
so completely.
What are you talking about?
You have to protect her.
She's the only chance you have.
They found you.
- Jenny. Jenny, wake up. Wake up.
- What's wrong?
We gotta go.
Gotta go. Gotta go.
Sorry.
Bloody idiot.
Hello. Well done, man.
Run!
Ian. Ian! Ian!
You're tired, Ian.
Ian! Ian!
Ian, Ian,
Ian.
Silly name, really.
We could've chosen a better one.
Ian, please, you have to stand up.
I can't. I can't.
You can sense it.
Can't you?
- What's happening to me?
- You remember.
Blood always remembers.
- Ian!
- This one.
Medea, don't.
Why, Ian?
Pity?
For this?
But then necessity always
leaves an emotion.
Doesn't it?
Aw, you can smell her fear.
Just like the rest of us.
Come back to us, Ian.
We can be together again.
Take her.
Ian...
Kill her, Ian.
I--
Ian!
Come on, Ian.
Kill her.
No!
Stop.
Kill her now!
I'm sorry.
Hello?
Hello!
Help!
God! Help me!
No! Help!
Nobody can hear you, Ian.
Help!
Feeling better? No?
It's really quite simple.
Unless you feed,
you starve.
You're very difficult.
No!
It takes everything we have
to control you.
Still, those old memories
keep seeping back,
even though we wear you down,
killing you again and again
and again
and again.
So now it's time for answers.
How did you do it? Hmm?
Still don't remember?
Let me refresh your memory.
You killed one of us!
One of your own!
You shouldn't be capable of that.
I want to know how.
That was a very nice try.
Really, we know you've had
a little helper.
Where is he?
Hmm? I just want to know.
Is he one of us?
Another one like you, perhaps?
We're ready.
You're in need of treatment.
So you see why
we can't just let you go.
You're far too much of a threat.
A harvester
who kills his own kind.
And while we may not
be able to kill you,
we can certainly hurt you.
You turned on your own
and abandoned us.
Why did you do that?
I don't know.
I think you do,
but you've hidden it away,
and it's in there somewhere.
We just need to pull it out.
No. Wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait...
You're getting weak, Ian.
But you won't die.
The pain'll only get worse,
and it will never end.
You need to feed!
I won't.
Really?
I think we can change your mind.
Cross my heart
and hope to die!
No! No! No!
I know you're hungry.
But don't worry.
We always take care of family.
Hi, Toby.
How are you feeling now?
Is it better?
What do you want?
You can smell his fear.
Try and get some sleep now.
I'll check on you later.
Don't fight what you are.
Oh, well.
Waste not, want not.
No. No. He's just a kid.
Get away from him.
No!
Toby, what's wrong?
What's wrong, dear?
Dr. Gilbert!
Don't look at them.
Toby, it's fine. Don't worry.
Toby-- Toby, listen!
You're all right.
Stay with us.
No!
I don't enjoy this, Ian,
but you leave me no choice.
If they kill you, this is gonna happen
all over again.
That was quite a trick--
pulling her from one life to the next.
She's the reason, isn't she?
You have to protect her.
She's the only chance you have.
You left us for this!
But you know what I think?
Once she's gone,
you'll come back to us.
No!
They can do terrible things to her,
and that will be the end for you.
I'm sorry, Ian.
I hoped you could keep going--
go on protecting her.
I tried.
You must stop them, Ian.
What you draw from her,
it's more powerful than fear.
It will give you the strength
to destroy harvesters,
but-- but also
the power to give life.
I can't.
Jenny.
Help her.
She changed you.
What am I supposed to do?
You don't understand.
You're not like the others.
Not anymore.
I killed so many, Ian.
When you begin your existence
in darkness,
it's all you know.
Everything you do is driven by it.
But I found one... like your Jenny.
She changed me, too.
How?
Fear and pain
were no longer my sustenance.
I found new life in her love.
It allowed me to fight back.
Until they took her.
So long as Jenny lives,
you have a choice.
You have a chance!
But you'll have to feed.
I can't.
You have to!
For Jenny.
I won't hurt anyone.
Not them.
You can help me go.
Please.
But you found love once.
You can find it again.
Don't you think I've been searching?
I'm tired, Ian.
It's my time.
Still a little afraid?
Find him.
- Good night.
Please...
Somebody help me!
Run!
Jenny!
Come get her, Ian.
Ian!
Meddy, I promise
this won't end well for you.
My, my, my.
Let her go!
The little angel
who saved your soul.
Where's the sparkle on this one?
Don't!
You disgust me!
You're not strong enough to stop me.
Others will come for you.
Maybe.
You're an infection.
This ends with you.
We've only just begun!
Is this what you want?
You want to go back
to playing house?
Or maybe you like it here.
I'll do it to your world, Ian.
You're mine.
You're always mine.
Now I'll have to start all over again.
What would you like
your next life to be?
One thing I can promise you,
it won't be pleasant,
and she will certainly
not be part of it.
Meddy...
You can stop this now.
No.
You can feel it, can't you?
This is why we have to feed.
You're right.
Such a simple thing.
It will give you the strength
to destroy harvesters
and the power to give life.
Shh. Look at me. I'm right here.
- I'm right here.
- Ian...
You're not gonna remember
any of this, all right?
Everything's gonna be all right now.
You have to trust me.
I love you.
Come on!
Whoo! Yeah!
Hey.
So, how does it feel to be the hero?
Oh, you're a goddess!
I think I could get used to this.
- Not such a bad life, isn't it?
- No, it's not.
And if I had to pick one,
it would definitely be this.
Me, too.
Is it my turn now?
Drunk bastard, get out of here.
Good job, Ian.
Thank you.
For what?
For making me human.
What does that mean?
Maybe someday I'll tell you.
You know what?
I need to go take care of something.
- You're leaving?
- I am. Just for five seconds.
- I just gotta go talk to somebody.
- Okay.
- And get back here fast.
- I will.
What's the matter?
Scared?
Subtitles extracted by LeapinLar