- What's up, Claire?
- Hey.
So this is it, huh?
Just you and me?
- End of days.
- Yeah.
Have you talked to Ron?
Really?
Ron is in Barbados snorkeling to the
ever-elusive double back sablefish.
And he left exposed instructions
not to be disturbed.
You know, well, If you own this place,
you'd be at the Barbados too.
Sure I would, especially if I had 2 sabs
back at home waiting to cover for me.
- Did you get your camera fixed?
- No. It's totaled.
I have to send it back
to Pentax's suck-ass.
I have my microphone, though. So we can
make do with the EVP investigations.
Okay.
Oh, hey.
That reminds me.
I have to show you something.
So, I was trolling around on some of the
paranormal forums last night.
And I came across something
pretty interesting.
You definitely gonna wanna see this.
What is it?
Hold on.
Just watch.
Look closely.
I missed it the first time.
It can blow your mind.
Really heavy.
You bastard!
So good.
Oh my God, every time.
Oh, my God.
What room did you take?
- 216.
- Of course.
Hey, I've been here since last night.
This is just the way it goes.
225 is taken.
All the rest is pretty much wide open.
Second floor only, I don't remember.
The third floor is already done.
Only one guest? Brutal.
It don't take a genius to get why
this place is going out of business.
Okay, I'll take room 214.
I figure we'll take 7 to 7 shifts,
something like that?
You're right. Sounds good.
I'll bring it back down.
Okay, If I could just
get you to sign that?
This is your room key.
Number 224.
You wanna head up to the top of
the stairs, and take a right,
and then another quick right,
so like a doubly,
and then you go about halfway down of the
hallway, and It's on your right-hand side.
You can't miss it.
Thank you.
Do you know who that is?
- It's Leanne Rease-Jones.
- Okay.
She was the mom on
"Like Mother, Like Son"?
- Dude, she is super famous.
- Okay, whatever.
Oh, man. Leanne Rease-Jones.
I wonder what she's doing here.
She's guest speaking at some
convention in Pots Town.
- How do you know that?
- She told me.
- What? What else did she tell you?
- Nothing. Why are you acting so weird?
- I'm not.
- Well, here is her autograph. Just relax.
Whatever.
Why are you being so grouchy today?
I'm not. I'm just stressed.
This site is killing me.
Let me see it.
Looks good.
I hate web design.
It looks really good.
I like the little ghost.
It's not the most professional,
but it's not bad.
There's a lot of money in this right now,
I just... I have to act fast.
Looks really good.
I like it.
And, you know,
once you get some proof on that,
it won't matter what it looks like.
Hey, so I was thinking...
It seems like, whenever something
really creepy happens,
nobody else is around, right?
Like every time you've seen stuff,
you were alone. So...
I was just thinking that since
the hotel is practically empty,
we might have a good chance
of making some real contact.
- Does that make sense?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
I think this weekend's gonna be it.
We're gonna get something good,
I can feel it.
- What?
Front desk.
Yes, Mrs. Rease-Jones.
Oh, sure, I'll send them
right up for you.
You're welcome.
- I forgot to stack the towels.
- I'll get them.
Good, save me the hassle
of that gale on 225,
she's driving me nuts and
I don't want her to see me.
Uh, that lady with the kid?
I know, what's her deal?
She was gonna give me total
aggro vibes upstairs.
She had a huge fight
with her husband
and she's staying here till Sunday
with her son as payback.
she's having a very hard time
and she wants him to realize
how hard his life is without her.
- How do you know all that?
- She told me.
Why do you always seem so surprised
that I talk to the guests?
Go on, superfan, don't keep
the towels waiting.
Mrs. Rease-Jones, I have your towels.
Mrs. Rease-Jones?
Be a lamb and hand me one of those?
Thank you.
You're welcome, Mrs. Rease-Jones.
- Call me Lee.
- Okay.
- What's your name, sweetheart?
- Claire.
You're a lifesaver, Claire.
Oh, no no no, I couldn't. I couldn't.
Come on, you're hurting
an old lady's feelings.
Thanks, Mrs... Lee.
I am a really big fan of yours.
"Like Mother, Like Son" was one
of my all time favorite shows.
And you were amazing in it.
And... And...
"The Waking Of Eleanor".
I love that film.
I used to watch it all the time.
Crying out with my mom.
I even styled my hair in
little braids like you did.
But they never looked good, though.
Well, thank you.
That's very nice of you to say.
- And what do you do, Claire?
- I work at the front desk. So...
If there is anything else that you need,
just let me know. I mean...
This is our last weekend open.
So Luke and I are the only
people on staff today.
We actually sleep in here instead
of going home, which is pretty crazy.
I meant in life.
Are you an aspiring actress?
Is that what makes you such
a stout fan of my work?
Me? No.
I just work at the hotel.
But... I'm... I'm just kinda like...
you know, between... stuff.
Okay.
Oh, Claire...
The towels.
Right. Of course. Yes.
There you go.
How'd it go?
You two gonna collaborate on something?
She got to make me feel
like an asshole.
Well, she is an actress.
What's that supposed to mean?
What do you know about
actresses, anyway?
I don't know a lot, but I do know a
little bit about a lot of things.
Why you have to be such a bummer?
And why you have to be so negative?
I'm not negative, I'm realistic.
There's a difference.
You're a pessimist.
Pessimism is just a higher form
of optimism.
If you expect nothing from people, then you
go through life being pleasantly surprised.
Yeah, but nobody loves an albatross.
- I need some coffee. You want anything?
- I do not.
Fine.
Hey, how's it going?
What can I get for you?
Uhm...
uh...
Tell you what.
You take your time,
if you have any questions,
just let me know.
Doesn't a Cyclops always has one eye?
What do you mean?
Never mind.
I will have a...
large soy mocha latte
with a pump of caramel.
Good choice.
So how are things going next door?
Fine.
Can I speak frankly with you?
I mean, I know we don't know each other
that well, but I see you all the time
and we are all girls here.
This Sunday my boyfriend is taking
me on a picnic to the bay.
And I'm really excited. I know
is gonna be super romantic...
and I think that I'm not letting
myself be fully excited
because there's something in our
relationship that's been bothering me...
which that we've been together
for almost a year...
and he still has not told me
that he loves me.
I just need to talk to somebody about it
because I don't wanna ask him to tell me.
And he said it on IM.
That's the thing. He said it on IM.
Which my friends say that it doesn't count.
It's like saying "I love you" during sex.
It doesn't count.
And so I wonder...
Where is your coffee?
They ran out.
Is that annoying girl still there?
Yes.
What a failbug.
Epic.
Do you ever think about when
you dropped out of the college
and wonder if you made
the right choice?
Every day.
Why do people have
such high expectations?
Everything happens
for a reason, Claire.
Nobody just ends up
at the Yankee Pedlar.
I guess.
- You know what really gets me though?
- Hold that on.
My eyes feel like they've been
doused with xxxxxxxx
I need to go upstairs.
What?
I'm sorry. I'm dead. We can talk about your
upcoming quarter life crisis tomorrow.
- I just need to tap out right now.
- Fine.
Leave your computer, though.
What? I'm not gonna hack the system.
I just want look for a pair of high tops.
And it gets really boring when
there's nobody else in the hotel.
And my book sucks.
Okay, just be careful with it.
Dah.
Oh, and if you get the itch
to do any recording,
the recorder is charging
in the back office.
Remember how to use it,
you just point the microphone in the...
I know how to do it.
I get it.
Jesus, I would hate to be
a ghost in this hotel.
- Goodnight, Claire.
- Goodnight, Luke.
Where is your website?
Well done. I might forget
to remind him about this.
Tragedy.
Creepy.
Shit.
I can't work this thing.
I don't wanna scare you,
but I stand right behind you. Sorry.
Fuck! What the fuck?!
Oh my God!
Jesus Christ, you scared
the shit out of me!
What are you doing over here, anyway?
- I thought I heard a noise, Luke.
- Like what?
Banging, like a banging, man!
- Okay, well...
- God!
I woke up and I couldn't get back to sleep.
So we can switch now, if you want.
Fuck. Okay. Dah! Dah!
Sorry.
Fuck you.
Do you know the story
of Madeline O'Malley?
She was the one that
died here in the hotel.
She hung herself after her fiance
stood her up on her wedding day.
The original owners of the hotel,
thought it would be bad press
and hurt the business.
So, they hid her dead body in
the wood cellar for three days.
Before they could smuggle
her out of the loading bay.
When the people of the town finally
figured out what had happened here...
they were outraged.
So, the owners had to close
the hotel down and were forced to sell it.
Nobody came through here
again until the '60s.
And ever since then, people have reported
seeing the ghost of Madeline O'Malley
roaming the hallways
waiting for her lover.
Some say, she's even looking
to take up a new one.
Excuse me?
What are you doing?
Mommy.
What's going on?
She said there's a ghost in that hotel.
She said it's coming to get me.
- I never said that.
- What's the matter with you?
He's just a child.
Sweetie? Sweetie.
It's okay.
It's not real.
It's just a story. Okay?
Right? Come here.
I don't need this.
I've enough going on in my life.
Yes, ma'am.
Are you okay?
And you.
We still need towels.
I'm tired of asking.
Don't make me the bad guy in this.
Alright.
- We're in the 225.
- Yeah, I know which room you're in.
I work in the hotel.
Come on, sweetie.
It's just a silly story, alright?
Okay?
I've bought the cheap bread.
I can taste it.
Never skimp on bread.
You'll always regret it.
So, why do you think she
sticks around here?
Beats me.
The rates aren't that cheap here.
"Courtyard by Marriott" on
the route 13 is much better.
No, not her. I mean Madeline.
- What do you think she wants?
- I don't know.
I don't spend my time trying to figure out
what women want. Specially dead ones.
Please.
Well, when you saw her,
what did she look like?
Like she was all dead looking?
The thing about physical encounters is that
you don't really remember the details.
It's weird, cause you think
you would, but, it's like...
she was there one minute,
then gone the next.
Almost like she was
never in there at all.
I know, it's kind of hard to explain,
you just have to be there.
I'm so jealous.
But if I saw her,
probably I'd freak out.
I can't believe that you
never had your camera with you.
I know. It kills me.
Looking down for some recording tonight?
Definitely.
We gotta find some proof that
Madeline O'Malley really exists
before this place closes down, we have to.
I mean, imagine how she feels,
being stuck here forever.
We gotta get something on tape.
It's like a moral imperative.
Oh my God.
Shit.
How did you get in there, bird?
Luke.
Luke, you are not going to believe
what just happened to me.
Luke?
What?
Never mind.
I'm a pumpkin.
I'm gonna kill this snake.
Don't forget to record.
I left a list for you on my desk.
Okay.
Enjoy your internet porn.
This is EVP recording
of the laundry room.
Luke, I'm skipping this one.
There's nothing in here.
This is the EVP recording
of the banquet room.
I'm trying to contact the
spirit of Madeline O'Malley.
Madeline, if you can hear me,
please give us a sign.
Damn it, Luke, you said that
this thing would have been set up.
Luke!
Luke, come here, wake up!
- Come on, wake up, wake up, wake up.
- Hold on, hold on.
Luke!
What the... f?
Claire, I still have
like two hours left, man.
Dude, you have to listen to this.
The piano is playing by itself.
I think it was her.
Come on, I'll be down at 7:00.
I'll listen to it then.
No, no, I'm scared.
Okay, come in.
Shit.
Actually... I'm...
...okay.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I think I just freaked out
for a minute but I'll...
I'll be fine.
Okay.
Well, I'll be down in
a few hours, alright?
Okay.
Do you mind keep it down?
Do I have to ask you again?
You know what?
Just back off!
Okay?
You're asking me "what I do"
the other day?
Well, I just recorded an...
unexplainable phenomenon!
There's a ghost in this hotel...
I got it on tape and it's a big deal!
So just... leave me alone!
Come with me for a moment.
Here, sit.
You need a drink.
Cheers.
Are you alright?
Tell me about what you saw.
- I...
- Look...
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I have a tendency not to be
a nice person, I know that.
Please don't take it personally.
I don't apologize more than once.
Look, I can help you with
what you're looking for,
I just need to know what it is
that you are looking for.
I'm sorry, help me with what?
Do you know what this is?
It's a pendulum.
It's used to answer life's more...
difficult questions.
Do you know why I'm here?
You're speaking at an acting
convention in Pots Town?
No, I'm not here for acting.
I am here as a guest...
at the Healers Gathering.
That's what I do now.
It's my true calling.
Claire, everything in this
world is connected.
Whether we understand that or not
depends on our sense of perception.
Our willingness to communicate.
Now if you wanna communicate
with the spirits in this hotel?
I can help you do that.
I just need to know what it is
that you want from them.
I don't know if they are real.
- The ghosts.
- Spirits.
There is no "real" in this world,
Claire, it's all a state of being.
There are no beginnings.
There are no ends.
There are no ghosts.
We're each divine beings that incorporate
one energy in the universe
like uh... droplets of water
in a vast ocean.
The universe has a plan for
each and every one of us.
Now, I want you to ignore what
your conscious mind tells you.
And open yourself up.
Okay?
What is it that you want
from these spirits?
I wanna know if it was Madeline O'Malley
playing the piano downstairs.
And if she really is the spirit
living in this hotel.
Ask again. This time close your
eyes and really concentrate.
Open yourself up.
Really ask and ask it directly.
Are you the spirit
of Madeline O'Malley?
Did you die in this hotel?
Was that you playing the piano?
They aren't able
to say who they are.
They?
There are three of them.
- What do they want?
- The same thing you do.
- What?
- To live.
But they are not alive.
There was a terrible
tragedy in this hotel.
Something about the basement.
A mistake.
It's her. It's Madeline.
That's where they hid her body.
You mustn't go down into the basement.
Why? Is where she's trapped?
Is her spirit trapped in there?
You can't save her.
They tried to warn her.
They tried to help her.
Who's they?
What do they want?
What happened?
I lost contact.
Luke... No towels.
Luke!
Okay.
That's it. I've had enough.
We're going back to dad. Okay?
Drink.
Don't worry about Gozer and her demon
seed leaving. You actually did us a favour.
Claire, you're really freaking me out.
You gotta pull it together,
you're way out into the weeds right now.
It happened to me when I first started
messing around with all this stuff.
You really gotta be careful
about what's going on up here.
You start thinking you're seeing things,
and it might never stop.
Okay, fine. The dream in one thing,
but... what about the piano?
- And what about everything Lee said?
- I listened to that piano tape...
and I don't know what to tell you.
Maybe it's explainable, maybe it isn't.
But it's not worth getting yourself
worked up over. None of this stuff is.
As for the cook upstairs...
Look, Claire...
How many times have you seen
someone on late night TV
talking of their psychic awareness to
an audience full of rubes? Tons, right?
And how many times have you seen
a psychic in the newspaper
solving crimes, or healing
someone without medicine,
or winning a lottery.
Almost never, right?
That's because is all bullshit.
It's Hocus Pocus.
That woman upstairs is just
an insecure old actress.
She's just trying to stay relevant.
It's pathetic.
Okay.
Don't you wanna try to figure out
what's going on here?
Why are you not intrigued by this?
I mean, this could be it.
This could be Madeline trying to make
contact and you just don't even care.
Isn't this supposed to be your deal?
I swear to God, if that bitch
is back with her kid...
Be cool.
Can I help you, sir?
Yes, I'd like a room for the night,
please.
- Okay, just one night?
- Yes.
I'd like room 353, please.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
That room is not available right now.
We only have rooms available
on the second floor...
because this will be
our last weekend open.
No...
I must have room
3... 5... 3.
- Yeah.
- Please.
This is very important to me.
I came a long way.
Sir, all the rooms on the third
floor have been stripped, so...
if you don't mind
putting up some sheets
and sleeping in a room without furniture,
then, I think we can help you out.
That would be fine.
Okay, well, if I could just get a
credit card for the reservation?
I'll pay cash.
Okay, but we usually need a credit
card in cases of any damages...
Take these, please.
Okay.
Let's... go get you some sheets.
Have a nice day.
That's very kind of you
helping me out back here.
Oh, It's no problem.
I mean, I figure...
pretty soon this whole place
will be a parking lot, anyway.
So, if somebody wants a certain room,
who am I to stop 'em?
It's really no big deal.
Sir?
Oh, thank you.
353 is where I spent my honeymoon.
This old place holds some
special memories for me.
And It's interesting,
come back to a place
feels like you never left.
Almost like you're right at home.
- Don't you think?
- I don't know.
Why don't we take them upstairs?
So, like we said, the rooms have all
been cleaned and stripped, and...
most of the furniture and
linen are in the storage.
But, lucky for you, the owner is
too cheap to hire real movers,
so all the beds are still here.
The room might not have quite
the same charm that you remember,
but at least
you wont be sleep on the floor.
That's alright.
I'm just here for one
last bit of nostalgia.
Okay. Well, here we are.
Room 353.
"Honeymoon Suite".
And, uh...
if you change your mind...
and decide that you wanna move
to a room with TV, just let us know.
That won't be necessary.
This is just what I came for.
- Thank you so much.
- Okay, well, enjoy your stay.
If I wanna stay up all night with you,
you gotta get drunk with me.
Cheers.
- How are you feeling?
- Better.
Good. Keep drinking.
That always helps.
- Hi, Lee.
- Hi.
- How was your seminar?
- Very good, thank you.
- How are you two doing?
- Not bad.
- Do you want a beer?
- No, thank you.
Really? I heard you're
a huge drinker.
Well, we all have our moments.
So, Lee, tell me,
how does it all work?
- How does what work?
- You know, being a psychic and all.
Well...
Have you ever been
somewhere new and sworn
- that you've been there before?
- Like a deja vu.
Exactly.
Well, if you've ever experienced
what you call a deja vu,
then you have the same
God-given ability I have.
In fact, we all do.
It's just that...
Sometimes my deja vu's happening
in another direction.
I can experience certain
feelings before they happen.
It's not always clear when or
where they come from.
So I have to be very careful in...
what I choose to share.
Okay.
I'm really tired, so I'm gonna go upstairs
and go to sleep. It's been a long day.
I'll come find you tomorrow
before you leave. Lee.
Don't let the spirits
keep you up all night.
Dude, you don't need to say that.
That was really mean.
Oh, whatever. You said it yourself.
She made you feel like an asshole.
Besides, everybody needs a taste of
their own medicine once in a while.
- Do you want another one?
- Yeah.
- Alright, are you ready?
Okay, this is Claire's haunted
re-enactment. Take one.
Interior. Yankee pedophile.
Was that the piano?
What?
Is it playing by itself?
It must be the ghost of Madeline O'Malley
trying to tell me something.
Show yourself, spirit.
I said, show yourself, spirit!
There she is.
Poor, poor, Madeline O'Malley.
Do you think she's prettier than me?
- Honestly?
- Yeah.
She's a little homely for my taste.
I think you're much prettier, Claire.
Thank you.
That's nice of you to say.
In fact, Claire, I think you are
one of the prettiest girls I know.
Who are the others?
My mother, my sister...
and that girl who works
at the Dirty Queen.
- The one with the lazy eye?
- I find laziness very attractive.
- I really like you, Claire.
- I really like you too.
No, I mean it. You're just like
the coolest person. I Just...
I Just really feel like we match.
You know, I'd love the fact that
you support me with the website and...
I just love the fact that
you take me seriously.
It means a lot.
You're great.
Do you think
I'm going a little bit crazy?
You're not going crazy.
You are great.
I would do anything for you.
- Really?
- Absolutely.
Just...
I like you so much.
Hey, I have an idea.
Me too. What's yours?
Let's go to the basement, and find out
what the fucking ghost problem is.
Okay.
That's a good omen.
Turn the recorder on.
What was that?
I tripped.
Sorry.
It's just the lighting.
- A spider web.
- Follow me.
I'm starting to think we should
have brought breadcrumbs.
Hang on.
Hear something.
It's weird. You're static.
- I heard that too the other night.
- Must be a bad cable.
No, it's her.
This way.
This is it.
This is where they hid her body.
Are you ready?
We wish to speak to the spirit
of Madeline O'Malley.
If you're here with us,
give us a sign.
Make noise if you can hear us.
Why do you stay here, Madeline?
Why did your spirit never rest?
Madeline, give us a sign.
Did you feel that?
It's her.
- That was the wind.
- No, she is with us right now.
Madeline, speak to us.
We wish you no harm.
Why do you stay here?
Why did your spirit never rest?
Wait, no. Madeline, we know that you are
here with us right now. Speak to us.
I can hear her.
Do you hear the whispering?
Madeline?
Holy shit.
What?
She's right behind you.
She's coming closer.
Luke!
- I gotta get out of here.
- What?
I don't wanna be here anymore.
I don't like this.
What are you talking about?
We just made a physical contact.
Why are you freaking out?
I just don't wanna be here anymore.
That's it.
Why? Was it different from the
other times that you saw her?
- There were no other times.
- What?
I made it up.
I never saw anything.
I made it all up. I don't want
anything to do with this anymore.
This is just too fucked up.
I gotta go.
Luke!
- Luke, don't go!
- I'm sorry, Claire.
- You can't leave me here.
- I'm really sorry.
What am I gonna do now?
Lee?
Lee!
Lee.
Lee! Lee.
Lee, wake up. I need your help.
Help me.
Lee!
What are you doing in my room?
- Get out of here.
- No. No, please. Plaese. Please.
No, I will not help you.
Please go away.
Come on.
Why should I help you?
So you can make fun of me some more?
You know, I believe in what I do.
And I don't believe in wasting my time
on lonely hotel employees and their
insulting ignorance.
Lee, I'm sorry, okay?
I should've defended you downstairs...
and I made a really big mistake,
okay?
But I have a problem.
I'm scared, I'm alone,
and Madeline made contact with me,
and I don't know what else to do, okay?
I don't know what else to do!
- Is there anymore vodka over there?
- I'll check.
Here, take this one.
Okay.
Take me to where it happened.
Wait here.
Lee! Was it Madeline?
Did you see her?
- Lee, what happened?
- We must get out of this hotel.
You're in great danger.
You can't stay here any longer.
- What?
- I have to go get dressed.
Go get your things.
Trust me.
Oh, no.
Lee! I forgot something.
I'll meet you in the lobby.
Sir?
Sir, I'm sorry that
I'm disturbing you, but...
there has been an emergency and I have
to leave the hotel for a little bit.
Sir, can you hear me in there?
MY DARLING, THIS IS WHERE OUR
LIFE BEGAN. NOW THAT YOU ARE GONE,
THIS IS WHERE I WANT MINE TO END.
Sir?
Holy shit!
- Luke? What are you doing here?
- I'm sorry.
I should have not left you like that.
- Please don't be mad at me.
- No no no, listen.
- We need to get out of here right now.
- No no no, Claire...
- I have to tell you something.
- No! Listen to me, okay?
- Remember that old man upstairs?
- Yeah!
- Yes, so what?
- He's dead. He killed himself. He's dead.
- What?
- Yeah, he's dead.
- Did you call the police?
- No, not yet.
Lee... Lee said that it's no safe
to be here anymore,
and we need to leave right now.
- And I saw Madeline...
- Okay, wait, wait, wait a second.
Hold on, hold on. Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
come here.
Jesus Christ.
Here, sit down.
It's alright.
His face...
There was blood everywhere.
It's okay.
Please, please, please,
just get me out of here.
I don't wanna be here anymore.
Please.
- Alright. Okay. Come on, let's go.
- Lee, she's still upstairs.
- Where is she?
- I don't know, she's getting her things.
Alright, I'll go get her, and
you just stay put for a second.
Are you gonna be alright
down here for a minute?
Yeah.
It's fine. It's gonna be okay.
Just hold on.
Claire.
Lee, is that you?
Lee?
I don't wanna go back down there.
Are you down there?
Please, somebody help me!
Luke!
Please!
Somebody help me!
Please, help me! Please!
Please, no! No, please!
Alright, guys, hold her up.
Hold her up.
Jesus.
Alright, get her out of here.
I was banging on the door
as hard as I could.
I could hear her screaming.
I was screaming for her
to open up, but she wouldn't.
She called my name, but I wasn't
strong enough to break it down.
This was at the bottom of the stairs.
Alright, listen to me.
I need you to come with us,
and answer some questions
about the gentleman upstairs.
And help getting contact with
her family. Can you do that?
- Yeah, I just gotta get my stuff.
- Okay.
You think you can tell the actress
to hurry up...
while you're in there?
We need her too.
Yeah.
Oh, listen...
Are you sure you gave me all the names
and numbers of the other guests?
Nobody I might be forgetting?
No, I gave you everything. There was
just the other woman with her kid and...
Ron the owner, but he doesn't get back
from Barbados till tomorrow.
Alright, thanks.
What are you doing in here?
They're looking for you downstairs,
I said I'd find you.
We have to go to the police station
and answer to some more questions.
Did you hear me?
I said we have to go.
You knew this was gonna
happen, didn't you?
You could've done something.
No. There's nothing anyone
could have done.
They're looking for you downstairs.