Please, don't leave me in here.
Jake, I promise I won't be long.
She'll kill me
before you get back.
You're very safe here.
All right? Nobody's gonna harm you.
We're only locking the door
because we're worried
you might try and leave again.
I left because she was in here.
Why? Why are you doing this to me?
I promise you, Jake,
I would never let
anything bad happen to you.
Jake, I'm not trying to punish you,
but I have to be sure that you're safe
while I tend to other patients.
You see that camera up there?
Someone will be watching you
the whole time.
That won't stop her.
You have got to get some rest.
She killed my whole family.
She's gonna kill me.
- She's gonna kill me.
- Hey, easy.
Please. Please don't leave.
I'm so sorry.
Nobody should have to go through
what you've been through.
It doesn't matter.
I'm already dead.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
No. No.
She's here.
No. She's here! Let me out! She's here!
Dr. Sullivan, you'd
better get down there.
Another nightmare?
Sorry to wake you.
It's that same dream again?
Go back to sleep.
It was left on my desk to shame me.
It never stops.
"BIZARRE DEATH FOR
AMERICAN TRAGEDY SURVIVOR"
We'll move.
We can leave Tokyo if you want.
It's not just about what happened today.
What makes you sure this is part of it?
If you follow it from the beginning,
it's all connected,
and now it's in Chicago.
This happened in Chicago?
Then it has nothing to do with us.
Yes, it does.
I can't hide from this anymore.
Naoko, you're upset. People are talking.
Let them talk.
I told you, it's not about
what happened at the office.
Naoko! Naoko!
I understand your feelings,
but it's out of your control.
People are dying.
There's nothing you can do about it.
There is. There is!
Wait, hey. What about me?
Watch out for the fire alarm.
There's a closet wall, too.
Where're your keys?
- How many have we done it in?
- A lot.
You do know the only
reason I'm dating you
is 'cause you have the keys
to a whole apartment building, right?
I don't have the keys to anything.
My brother does.
You know the only reason I'm dating you
is 'cause I need a fashion model
for my designs.
You know I'm cool with that.
You can dress me up.
I'm really happy we're
doing this together.
Yeah. New York's gonna be awesome.
They have no idea what's about to hit them.
- Wait till you see what's about to hit you.
- Nice.
What?
- Oh, my God.
- Shit.
What apartment is this?
Fuck, this is where that family...
- Come on. Let's go.
- Okay.
- Rose, why so many dolls?
- It's a going away party.
- For who?
- Lisa.
Rose?
- Is it time for your medicine?
- No, I'm okay.
I'm letting Lisa take two of my dolls
with her on the trip.
- Are you?
- They wanna see the world.
And what about you, Rose?
Do you want to see the world?
I'm gonna when Lisa gets famous.
Hey. Hey, just put it
out of your mind, Lis.
Okay? Forget about it.
We're out of here soon enough.
Yeah, but I knew them.
I know you did, but it's the past,
and the past can't hurt you.
Okay?
- I'll call you later.
- Okay.
There she is.
Lisa!
Hi, Rose.
- Hey, Gretchen. Where's Max?
- Right behind you.
- Thanks for watching her, Gretchen.
- Always a pleasure.
Rose is an angel.
How's the painting going?
Well, the arthritis makes it hard.
I use more ointment than paint these days.
- Bye, Rose.
- Bye.
- Have a good party.
- I will.
- Bye.
You're late.
I had to ask Gretchen to look after Rose.
I'm sorry. I lost track of time.
- What?
- Cough them up.
We just needed a little privacy.
You're leaving town with the guy.
Can't it wait?
Wait, where are you going?
Well, now that I've got the keys,
I can do some things that need to get done.
Okay.
Oh, no.
- What's with Max today?
- He doesn't like people moving.
He doesn't like people moving out.
- Do boys like Mr. Potato Head?
- I guess.
Come back in, Rose.
I left him a toy.
- Who?
- The boy.
- What boy?
- I think he's new.
No, there's no new boys here.
- Where are you going?
- Can't leave a toy in the hall, Rose.
- Max'll have a fit.
- It's for the boy.
Where did you put it?
A toy'll make him feel better.
Well, I guess these belong to you.
Yeah. I really wish
I could convince you guys to stay.
- We're gonna miss you around here.
- Well, it's best for Brenda.
She's been having a rough time
since that family died.
A change of scene might help.
Well, if there's ever anything I can do
to help out,
a landlord recommendation
or anything at all, you know who to call.
Tell Lisa and Rose we said bye.
Mr. Praski, I didn't know you were
coming by. I was just seeing...
Two more tenants off.
Yeah, they were good ones.
- Reporters still hassling you?
- No, sir. I've been keeping them out.
Good, good.
Max, there's something
we gotta talk about.
I've been riding the contractors
like you said. I'll push them harder.
I've been thinking. Maybe it's time
to bring in a management company.
Someone to help put things back on track.
It's nothing personal.
I've got some prospects lined up.
- And there's a woman coming by.
- Yeah?
Yeah, I mean,
she sounds really eager to rent.
Don't let her get away, Max.
We got money flowing
in the wrong direction.
"You are charming
and wise beyond your years."
That's a compliment, not a fortune.
What's yours say?
Tell you what, I'll set up your bed
while you take a bath.
How's that sound?
You used to love taking a bath.
Half the water ended up on the floor.
I'll get a towel.
God knows where the mover put the box.
Brenda!
- How do I look?
- Like a crazy guy.
Everything changes today, Rose.
I can feel it. Can you feel it?
I don't feel it.
Come on, don't say that.
You have to think positive.
Okay.
- What are you doing?
- Thinking.
Attagirl. Wish me luck.
Good luck!
- You must be Naoko.
- Naoko.
Naoko, sorry. I'm Max.
Glad you made it okay.
- I'm sorry if I kept you waiting.
- No.
- Good then. Shall we get started?
- Yes.
Okay.
There is an elevator right there,
but it's old and most tenants
just use the stairs.
More communal.
Yeah, sorry about the mess.
We're in a transitional phase,
as you can see. 303 is down here.
Now this'll all be fresh paint before
you know it. It should be really nice
before you know it.
Really nice. Sorry about the mess.
You know, you're lucky. This is the first
floor to get the makeover treatment.
The owner's sinking a lot
into restoration. Every detail.
Here we are.
Okay.
Now, as you can see,
sizeable living room,
bright open plan.
In here, we've got the dining room,
kitchen, and even a little sun room there.
- Do you live here, as well?
- Me and the girls. Two sisters.
So I'll be right downstairs
if you need anything.
- How many others in the building?
- It's a quiet building.
There's hardly a peep out of anyone.
Now, there are three bedrooms,
if you wanna follow me.
Hi.
- May I?
- No, you may not.
You need to learn to share.
Guys, this is Naoko, potential neighbor.
Just grabbing an application.
Welcome, potential neighbor.
I'm Lisa, and this is Rose.
Rose. Like the flower.
If you see stuff for Rose sitting
outside, bring it in, okay?
Okay, sorry.
- So, where are you moving from?
- I'm from Tokyo.
- Here you go.
- You have a lovely family.
Thanks.
- I need that?
- No, ma'am.
The doctor just wanted to make sure
I could read the instructions.
It's okay.
The kids wear these at the hospital
all the time.
Can I breathe underwater with that?
You need a scuba tank for that.
I could go in a shark cage.
You could, but I'd be careful.
Sharks have a taste for little girls.
Look, I'm just gonna put this in the closet,
and we're never gonna talk about it again.
Come here.
Things'll get better. I promise.
Not always.
- What do you mean?
- Things don't always get better.
Like for those people,
the ones that died.
That's different. Entirely different.
Do you miss them?
I miss every tenant that leaves.
We take care of everyone here
in our own way.
You take their money.
That's part of our way.
Come here, shark bait.
Showed Rose the oxygen thing.
She wanted to go scuba diving.
- You tell her it was just a precaution?
- Yeah.
- So, New York's a crazy place.
- Well, so is Chicago, right?
I just worry, you know.
I'm gonna be fine.
Yeah, but aren't there fashion jobs here?
It's not about the job.
It's the internship.
If I could swing a scholarship from this,
then we can use the rest of my college
fund to pay for Rose's medical bills.
- I don't know.
- I'm just trying to help.
Look, if you wanna help,
you could stay here.
Okay, put off the internship.
Go when things are stable.
Max, my being here
isn't gonna change anything.
We need you, Lisa.
Now is all that matters.
Rose is getting worse.
Okay, the building is going to hell.
I may lose my job.
Why didn't you tell me?
Would it have made a difference?
Aunt Diane's been floating the offer
for us to move in.
- With her five cats?
- It's more like eight.
And I know we joke, but it's now
becoming our only option here.
Rose hates it there.
I can't do this alone.
If things work out,
I could make us stable.
Rose has her checkup,
and then I'm taking her to the park
to feed the ducks.
You can meet us there later if you like.
Hello?
Hello.
We don't allow reporters in here.
I'm not a reporter.
I have permission from the manager.
The manager's my brother.
You must be Lisa. I'm Dr. Sullivan.
The boy who lived here
was a patient of mine.
Jake.
- How is he?
- I'm sorry, I thought...
Jake passed away.
What? How?
Actually, we're not quite sure,
to be honest with you.
He said a lot of things
about the night that his family died.
So I guess I just wanted
to come and see for myself.
Are there any other boys living
in this building?
No, Jake was it.
Why?
He talked about a boy, seeing a boy here.
He was terrified of him.
My sister saw a boy recently.
Here?
Maybe I could talk with her?
She isn't really a fan of doctors
to tell you the truth.
So, Jake...
How long ago?
Not long.
The service is tomorrow. At Lakemore.
Hey, there you are.
This was the last place
I thought you'd be.
Andy.
- How you doing?
- Andy.
This is Dr. Sullivan.
Hi.
Hey, if you're thinking of renting, this is a...
You know, it's a good place.
- Good people.
- She was Jake's doctor, Andy. He died.
Shit.
I'm sorry.
- I thought you were just here...
- It was nice meeting you.
Nice to meet you.
- You ass.
- How was I supposed to know?
Anyway, I thought that kid survived
that whole thing.
- What happened to him?
- She didn't say.
- I don't want to think about it.
- Wait, wait, wait.
I've got some time before work.
- You are unbelievable.
- What?
Not on this floor.
Then... Then where?
There's an empty on four,
but I'd have to go sneak the keys.
Okay, so grab the keys,
and I'll meet you on four.
Fine.
Okay.
Busted.
Rose, will you go to your room
for me, please?
Lisa, we talked about this.
I can't watch Rose and you.
- I don't need to be watched.
- Of course not.
Come on, Max, give me a break.
I'll give you a break
when you start acting like an adult.
Fine. Whatever.
I won't be your problem
much longer anyway.
Is that how you see it?
Or is it that we won't be your problem?
Oh, my God.
You scared the shit out of me.
What are you doing up there?
Hey, you coming up or what?
You could have come inside.
I didn't really feel comfortable.
Well, I've always found funerals
more for closure than comfort.
Hey, there's something
I wanted to ask you.
Yeah, sure, what is it?
The boy that Jake talked about.
- Did he ever describe him?
- Why? Did your sister see him again?
No. Actually, I think I might have.
Why was he so afraid of him?
I never fully understood.
The boy played a role
in the alternate theory Jake created
in order to deal with
the death of his family.
There's something at my office
that I'd like you to see.
It may help answer
questions for both of us.
And I can drive you
back home if you like.
- Okay.
- Okay, good. I'm just right here.
And now you can go around there.
There you go.
You shouldn't be up there.
You should be down here
doing your homework.
Max.
Rose?
Rose? Come here. It's all right.
Hang on.
Hang on, Rose.
Hang on. I got you. I got you, babe.
Okay, here we go. Come on.
The woman's name is Kayako Saeki,
and the father is Takeo,
and the boy is Toshio.
That's him. That's the boy.
Maybe they knew Jake from somewhere?
Did they say anything?
Did you talk to them?
They're dead.
Dead?
It happened in Japan.
Years ago.
Father murdered his wife and son
before hanging himself.
Did you know a girl named Allison Fleming
who lived in your building,
the one who went missing?
Not really.
She was always away at school.
Jake thought she brought
something back with her,
something dark that changed her.
Allison visited the house
where the Saeki family died.
I wanna show you something.
This is footage
from my very first session with Jake.
At the time,
his stepmother was the primary suspect.
My job was to evaluate
his mental condition.
I'm not making it up.
I don't believe you, Jake.
I'm not lying.
You see her when no
one else is around.
She's real.
Well, I don't see her.
- She's real.
- Describe her again.
She... She has black hair,
and it hangs over her face.
All over, on her body, there's...
There's blood.
There's blood all over her body?
And it's like she's dead.
I reasoned he'd witnessed his
stepmother kill his sister and father.
Unable to cope with what he saw,
he invented these gruesome ideations
of a boy and a woman
in order to disassociate himself
from the truth.
But I saw the boy myself.
Yeah, I was wrong.
Unimaginably wrong.
You never told me how he died.
Our surveillance system shows him
reacting to a hallucination.
Only somehow that hallucination
broke nearly every bone in his body.
Max?
- Where have you been?
- I was with Andy.
Rose was in the hospital.
What?
Oh, my God.
Why?
Doctor said she overexerted herself.
- Doing what?
- I don't know.
She was playing.
I told you she's getting worse.
Yeah, but I thought the new medicine
was supposed to help...
It's not enough.
She may have to start wearing
the oxygen thing.
I guess I'll keep you updated
when you're gone.
I'll be calling. Every day.
It's better than nothing.
Why don't you tuck her in?
Make the most of your last day?
Hey, Rose. How you doing?
- Don't stop.
- I know.
Until you're asleep.
I love you. You know that?
Rose? Rose, what's wrong?
- What is it, Rose?
- The boy, he's here.
- Where?
- In my room.
No.
There's nothing there.
You wanna sleep in my room tonight?
Okay.
Ben! Ben, open the door!
Ben, help me! Open the door, please!
Ben! Please, help me! Help me, Ben!
Can I go play in the snow
when we get there?
Sorry, the snow's all gone.
Let's get you buttoned up, though.
Let's go.
Hi. Naoko, right?
I was wondering if we could talk.
Yeah, we were just about to go
to the park if you want to come.
- Yes, I would like that.
- Okay.
It's easy sometimes to forget
how sick she is.
I understand.
On the outside, she is okay,
but on the inside,
things are getting worse.
It may sound strange
but a place can get sick the same way.
I don't follow.
I know what happened in your building.
Guess you changed your mind
about moving in?
No.
What happened in your building
is the reason I'm here.
Shit.
In Japan, there is another place,
sick because of what happened inside.
What happened?
A husband killed his wife and only child,
then himself.
An evil started with their deaths
but has spread.
Now it gathers here in your building.
- Can I go play on the swings?
- Yeah, go ahead.
Who are you?
The woman who was killed,
she was my sister, Kayako.
Kayako and I had a difficult life.
Our mother was an itako,
someone who can commune with the dead.
From the time we were very young,
our mother taught us the old ways.
For me it was frightening.
For my sister, it was a nightmare.
Those possessed came to my mother
to be healed.
My mother took the evil from them
and fed the spirits to Kayako.
It silenced them,
but my sister was changed forever.
Gretchen? Got a spill out here.
Gretchen?
When my sister was killed,
a ju-on was born.
In English, it is something like a curse.
- And now you think the curse is here?
- I am sure of it.
Well, then why would you come here?
- To put an end to it.
- How?
A simple ceremony in the place
where the curse was reborn.
The boy's home.
But I cannot do it alone. I need you.
You and Rose.
Okay, look, I'm really sorry
for what you've been through. I am.
And I believe that you want to help,
but this ceremony or whatever,
we can't be a part of it.
If the curse is not stopped,
more people will die.
- You must understand.
- I'm sorry.
Come on, Rose. Time to go. Let's go.
Let's go home now. Get some lunch, yeah?
- Max. Hey, we need to talk.
- Get Rose out of here.
- Why? What's going on?
- Just do it.
Okay.
What happened?
Max.
Are you okay?
Look, I think we might
need to get out of here.
I talked with Naoko today.
- Wait, you talked to Naoko?
- Yeah.
She thinks we might be in danger.
That's nice.
She doesn't have time
to sign her credit application
but she's got time to tell you
that we're in danger?
Are you even listening to me?
I'm saying that I'm worried.
What have you got to be worried about?
You're out of here soon.
It's not your problem now, is it?
Miss Saeki is not
answering in her room.
We'll leave a message for her
at the front desk.
- This is what you wanted.
- Yeah, I did. I do.
Do you want to tell me what changed?
- Andy...
- You said it yourself, Lisa.
If things work out in New York,
it's only gonna help Rose.
- It's just with...
- What? Gretchen dying?
Yeah.
- Yeah. She was a nice lady.
- You don't think it's strange?
What? All those people dying?
Yeah, it's a tragedy. But...
You can't let it stop you from living.
I mean, it's over.
- I'm not so sure that's true.
- Thanks.
Look, the thing with that kid,
it's creepy, yeah.
Scary? Okay, maybe.
- But real? No way.
- You don't know that.
You're just seeing connections
you want to see.
It all leads back to those murders
in Japan. It's all connected.
- Lisa, like, please.
- You're not even listening to me.
You know what?
You're just anxious about leaving.
All right? And I get that.
Hey, we're doing this together, though.
I'm not going to New York, Andy.
I'm sorry, but my family needs me.
- What? Just like that?
- Sorry.
Okay. Okay.
If you're not going, I'm not going.
There's no reason for you to stay.
How could you say that?
Lisa, the reason I'm staying is
the same reason why I was going.
You.
Where's Max?
- Rose, where is he?
- He said he had to work.
He left you here alone?
When is he coming back?
Have you eaten anything?
I'm gonna make you something to eat.
How does that sound?
Okay.
- Can you believe this?
- Do you want me to stay here?
I can just call in sick.
It's not like they're expecting
me to work on my last day anyway.
No, it's okay. You should go.
I mean, if we're not going to New York,
you might as well keep your job.
Anyway, I'm here.
I'm gonna make her some dinner.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I'll give you a call when I'm off work.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Bye.
See you.
Okay.
Hey.
Fuck.
You don't have to pick that stuff up
by yourself.
I'll get somebody in here to clean it out
when things get back to normal.
I've been over this,
trying to make it work,
but I gotta switch things up.
I'm going with
the management company option.
They start the first of the month.
You can stay, of course,
but you gotta pay rent
like everybody else.
Might be temporary. Who knows?
What am I supposed to do now, Mr. Praski?
- How am I gonna take care of my family?
- Listen, business is business, kid.
Then fuck business, and fuck you.
Look, you don't gotta like the news, kid,
you just gotta take it.
It didn't have to be like this.
Where were you last night?
Manual labor. It's a bitch.
You left Rose alone.
- She can't be alone ever.
- I know that.
But I don't have Gretchen
to count on anymore, now, do I?
Listen, things are happening
and I think we should leave.
You're always making plans now,
aren't you?
I don't understand.
People are dying and you're
acting like nothing is happening.
How do you want me to act, Lisa?
Gretchen was old. Old people die.
Is that what you said to Rose?
I have been saddled with Rose
since Mom and Dad died. Not you, me.
She is not your problem!
What is wrong with you?
Not a goddamn thing, that's what.
I'm young, healthy.
I got all the time in the world
since I was just fired.
Yeah, what, are you surprised?
Surprised that I couldn't manage
a full-time job
while raising a
chronically sick 8-year-old?
You should have said something.
Gee, I wish I had. Wait, I did,
but you were too busy fucking Andy all over
the goddamn building to listen to me.
Max, please, can we just all go?
I mean, if we don't have to be here.
We're not going anywhere, sis.
But you, maybe it's time you go.
Max, what are you talking about?
What are you doing?
Max!
Stop. Max! What are you doing?
Max! Stop! Let me in!
You can't lock me out!
No, Max. You can't lock me out. Stop.
- What's going on?
- Go to your room.
- Where's Lisa?
- Go to your fucking room.
- Cademan Clinic.
- Dr. Sullivan, please?
- She's not available.
- Can I leave a message for her?
I'm sorry, but there's been an
incident here at the clinic.
- Excuse me?
- Dr. Sullivan...
- Dr. Sullivan has passed away.
- What?
Dr. Sullivan is dead.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know where else to go.
We'll leave, then.
We'll leave. I'll go get Max and Rose
and we won't come back.
It's too late. It is a part of you now
and only a matter of time.
Before I die?
And Rose? Max?
Everyone.
Your sister, where is she?
She's with Max.
You said he was angry, aggressive.
He was. I mean, he is.
You cannot leave her with him.
Max would never hurt Rose.
A great fury is at work.
It has hold over your brother.
I don't believe that. He loves her.
Max may not be Max anymore.
I can help Rose but I
need her to be with us.
He'll never let that happen.
Then we cannot let that decision be his.
Okay.
All right, wait here.
Rose.
Rose. Come on.
Come.
Rose. Come.
Okay. Now what?
It's time.
No matter what you hear,
no matter what you see,
you must not interfere.
It's okay, Rose. It's like a prayer.
I'm right here.
What was that?
The blood of my sister.
- What are you doing?
- She needs to drink.
- Drink what?
- Please, it won't hurt.
- You didn't say anything about this.
- We are running out of time.
The curse must be contained.
Please, Rose, you can end it.
- You can make the bad go away.
- Come on, Rose. Let's go.
Come on.
Max.
Please, don't do this.
You have to understand.
There has been so much death.
Max, no.
Hurting me won't help.
I mean no harm to Rose.
The curse is doing this to you.
Leave us alone.
Come on, Rose. What is it?
No, no, no, no, no.
Rose.
Rose? Rose?
Oh, God, Rose, what did you do?
What did you do?
Okay, come on.
Max.
Oh, God.
No, Max.
Max.
Rose needs help, okay?
You have to help her, please.
Max!
Please. Max, please, we need you!
Come on, Rose. Help me out.
Stay with me, Rose.
Rose, stay with me. Please.
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe, Rose.
Are you okay?
Okay. Okay. All right.
It's gonna be okay now, all right?
It's gonna be okay.
What the...
No. No.
Max? Rose, I have to go.
Here, this is gonna be here
if you need it, all right?
But just rest. You're okay now.
Just rest, all right? I'll be back.
Max?
We're gonna ride together
in the ambulance. Okay?
- I'll be with you the whole time.
- I'm scared.
I'm not gonna leave you.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Nothing can hurt us anymore.
All right?
As long as we stay together,
everything will be all right.
Okay? We just gotta stick together.
Subtitles by LeapinLar