In October 13, 2008, Filmkameratene
AS got an anonymous package-
-With two hard drives that contained
283 minutes of filmed material.
This film is a rough cut version
of the material.
Everything is displayed in chronological order.
The pictures are not manipulated.
For over a year they sought to find out
on whether it is a scam-
Or if the material is genuine.
It was concluded that
the material is genuine.
Of course.
Turn on the radio.
-Johanna, do you have sound?
-Yes, yes.
It does not work.
Late last night,
bear tracks was found in Volda.
A hunting team came early today
to trap the bear.
The leader of the team said this
to NRK (Norwegian Broadcasting Corp.)
There is a bear
that we must quickly get a hold of.
But our major concerns is a
sniper who followed after us.
Only a slected few has a
Bear Hunting Licence
I know all bear hunters in Norway.
He, with the Land Rover,
is definitely not a bear hunter.
If he shoots the bear
He does something illegal.
-Have you seen him?
-We see him everywhere.
If I see him again
it will have consequences.
I think it is
a regular poacher.
-What would you tell him?
-To put the cards on the table.
Now!
-There are cars coming from all directions.
-We lost him!
Ready?
We only know that his name is Hans.
We do not know his last name.
You need to be more serious.
But what is he doing in Volda?
Who is man?
-Any sound?
-You have not inserted it...
You get no interview
with a fucking sniper.
I do not like that they are
making fun of him.
Great! Many thanks. Goodbye.
Thomas, he says the guy is
staying at the campsite!
I can not say that I know
him, but he lives here.
He lives over there.
Should I show you?
I do not know what stinks,
but it stinks of something awful.
-What is this?
-I do not know.
Thyme?
He drives off and is gone until the sun
goes up. Then he is back in place.
Is he out there all night?
-Yes. Always.
-In a good mood?
-Yes.
We do not know when he will
arrive if he does.
-There he is!
-The camera is rolling. Just ask him.
Hi, my name is Thomas.
We are from the college in Volda.
Can we ask some questions?
Get out of here.
Can we come back later...
-Did you get anything?
-Quiet, I hear something.
I'm on my way out now.
I expect to find it tonight.
All right. Goodbye.
-He is not here.
-He was just in front of us!
Yes, but...
-Damn!
-Good job, Thomas.
-Are you filming? Do you see anything?
-Yes.
Some fur stuff hanging from the ceiling.
And it is a shotgun there.
We are heading to a place where
this morning they found a shot bear.
Could it be him
who shot the bear?
Where it comes from,
I have no idea.
I have checked with all
registered bear hunters.
No one has shot the bear.
All bear management in Norway
is strictly controlled by the state.
It will be a bloody commotion
when a bear is shot like this.
Come here.
These tracks do not match
with the way a bear goes.
I think someone brought the bear
and placed it here.
-That is just weird.
-I agree.
You are from the Game Board?
You are Finn Haugan?
The hunters say they do not think
these are bear tracks.
Ridiculous.
What tracks are they then?
There is a bear laying there,
with bear tracks behind it.
-Why do you think they doubt?
-Ask them. Totally insane.
Now we have been waiting for hours on Hans.
He seems to have something going on.
We're pretty sure that
He is on the way somewhere.
Go!
He is going with the ferry.
How long do you think
we'll keep on with this?
Farewell, Volda City.
Do you see what it is?
He carries a car tire.
-What is he doing?
-He disappears down.
Three, two, one and...
Sogn og Fjordane!
(County border)
Okay, he's standing over there.
Hide.
We met earlier.
-Really?
-Thomas, from College of Volda.
-Is it...
-Are you following after me?
No. We just want
ask some questions.
No.
Are you ...
What did you do in Volda, anyway?
Was it you who shot the bear?
Stay away from me!
Stop filming. Leave me alone!
When we got what we need
we can go back.
It's going to be insanely good
if we get him to talk.
We have tried several times.
Do you think Michael Moore
gave up after the first attempt?
Left arm or right foot?
Kickfoot and...
Now we've been here
the whole afternoon.
He is still in the caravan.
I guess he is asleep.
We must be patient
and wait for something to happen.
Are you kidding? All right.
I need to bring
the sound equipment.
What is this?
"Road closed. Blasting in progress."
Did you see that? Was it a road?
Did you?
Really bad roads.
If there are any inbred pig farmers
there, your ass is first.
-I'm not...
-Stop complaining.
-May I not say what I think?
-Should we go back?
-We can sidestep the whole thing.
-No!
Wait!
Look.
I do not think he's in the car.
-Then we know that he is here.
-But what is he doing?
Here is a path.
-I hear something far away.
-What is that?
Troll!
Thomas!
Hurry!
I have the car here!
I was fucking bitten!
-Are you ok?
-Damn it hurts.
-Did you hear that he called "troll"?
-Shut up.
You need more.
-Should I do something?
-Get a swab.
-Do not do that...
-We have to lift a bit of this.
You look like hell, Thomas.
-What the fuck are you doing?
-Tetanus.
Hans, you shouted something in the woods,
right?
-You heard it, Johanna.
-What is this slime?
-What did he say?
-Kalle...
-More?
-I'm good.
-Can you drive us to our car?
-Get In.
It is not so smart
to follow me.
You shouted "troll"?
-Is it your car?
-What the hell is this?
-What happened?
-It's our car!
Somebody smashed the car.
It is toally destroyed.
Look here, Thomas.
-Hans, do you understand anything of this?
-Yes, I have some ideas.
That's no bear
who did this?
What do you think has happened?
Ask if it's trolls.
If you know what happened
with the car, tell us!
-You yelled "troll" in the woods.
-Forget about it!
What the hell do you want?
Would you film me
when I say there are trolls?
-Is it funny?
-You do not think that there are...?
I'm going now. If you want a lift
you have to come now.
What do we do?
Do you have the luggage?
Just so we understand you:
So you think that there are trolls?
Do you think
that it was a bear that bit you?
What's happening? Why are you stopping?
Thanks for the ride.
We would like to come with you
and film what you do.
We really want to.
You can film when I kill the thing that
nibbled on you, on one condition:
You must do as I say,
whatever I say. Okay?
Yes.
It feels like I'm bleeding everywhere.
-Admiring your wound?
-It looks a bit cool.
-You are sick in the head.
-I mean it.
-Why should we call them?
-To tell us where we are.
He is not so dangerous,
He is just strange.
Remember what he said.
He run the show. We do as he says.
So we get what we need.
Is there anyone here
who believe in God or Jesus?
No, none of us.
Do not look at me.
Seriously? They can smell the blood
of a christian man?
Is it okay?
Go and close the gate. Hang the sign
in the middle, so it is visible.
-Is this a land mine?
-Yes, but it is not loaded.
Am I sitting on a land mine?
Are you crazy?
Anyone who does not want to
go up in the woods?
Anyone who changed their mind?
Anyone who is afraid of troll?
-No.
-Good.
There is a creek there. Take of all
your clothing and wash yourselves properly.
-Especially the armpits and crotch.
-No!
-Why?
-To get rid of any smell.
Then anoint your whole body with
this. On the clothes too.
-What is it?
-Troll stench.
-Apply on the whole body.
-Are you kidding? It stinks!
You have to smell like troll,
otherwise they smell us and run off.
Damn!
-I said no!
-I do not want to, Thomas.
No, I said!
You were supposed to do exactly what I said.
Otherwise I go alone,
and you get to stay here.
Do you understand?
Are you ready?
Have you smeared it on?
You are very cute.
Here are flashlights.
-What is that?
-A big flash, really.
Hans? How do you use the weapon?
It shoots a
strong ultraviolet light.
UVB rays. Same as in the sun,
or in a tanning bed.
You know nothing, Thomas?
They are petrified by sunshine.
-Yes. Or they burst.
-Haven't you read anything?
Well, I heard the stories when I was
little, but... - Did you know, Kalle?
If a troll wants to have an
eating race with you then?
Eating race?
Asbjornsen and Moe's tales
does not mirror reality.
I think they fit pretty good.
Troll-Piss.
Oh, God!
It stinks all the way over here.
I'm chasing a Ringlefinch.
There is piss everywhere in the forest.
Seems as if he had been chased away.
He marks new territory.
He does not seem entirely healthy.
Would love to know what the problem is.
Blood sample from the troll?
I have no equipment for that.
You too. Goodbye.
I need help to find out what
the problem is.
But blood tests...
It will be difficult.
-Who did you talk to?
-A veterinarian.
Veterinary!
Wait here, I will find the troll
and chase it out.
Oh well. Did you expect this?
It certainly takes some time.
It is a bit sorry for him
if he truly believes in trolls.
He might film us.
-It's probably what he is doing.
-Sitting and laughing at us.
We are so stupid
that we sit up here and...
Lingonberry?
-We are in the woods.
-Yes, completely without food and drink.
-Cool!
-What?
It's this night vision.
Listen!
It is only he who...
One week,
or be bitten by a bear.
-That is a better story.
-You look pretty good.
-So I think I choose that.
-Be bitten by a bear?
Do you hear?
What strange sound.
What is that?
Seriously. There's something happening.
What is going on?
It's just a crap joke.
It's a bloody Tosserladd!
Move!
Run for fuck sake!
Quick!
Thomas! Thomas!
-Did you see it?
-Yes.
Where did it go?
Have you seen it?
Hey!
Hide behind the car!
No!
-Give me the camera!
-No!
Where's Johanna?
Johanna!
Thomas! Kalle!
-Johanna!
-It was real!
I saw it!
I knew it!
They are for real!
-Say something then.
-It's petrified!
We ran through the woods...
Why the hell did you say
that none of you were a Christian?
Did you see how the troll sniffed?
One of you believe in God.
I do not believe in God, but I was
in a Christian children's choir.
But it was my parents
who said I had to.
I do not believe in God.
Seriously.
-It's not her. I can tell.
-What do you mean?
Knock it off with the bullshit! It is
some gene manipulated fucked up shit.
-It's a troll.
-It's not a troll!
Why is there no one else
who knows about this?
Some people want it to be
a secret.
The state?
Does the State keep this secret?
Do you work for the State?
-Why would you show us this now?
-It is a fucking crappy job.
I have no safety.
I have no night-ons.
No overtime
and no additional pay.
Perhaps the time has come for
changes in  troll management.
-Maybe if you get it on TV...
-I think we can fix that.
Come on.
If you want to see more of these
animals it is okay with me.
I would watch out a bit
if I were you.
God Damn!
Here's dirt
if someone is filling a hole.
What the hell is that?
-Who is coming?
-Do not know.
Hello, hello.
The guy we were filming...
What are you doing, Hans?
Do you have a film crew here?
They wanted to see trolls,
so I show them some.
We have interviewed him before.
- Aren't you from the Game Board?
It was an exceptionally bad idea.
Turn off the camera.
I have enough problems.
Lots of dead cows in the valley.
We can not talk when they're shooting.
Turn off the camera. Now!
-Turn it off now.
-We have the right to film here.
-Are you starting to lose your grip?
-I have complete control.
As soon as they come up with the
scapegoat, I'll fix the rest.
Hello, Finn. How are you?
Are you good? Are you very good?
We have driven a long way.
-Are you filming? Are you filming?
-Yes.
Very good, very fresh!
-This is not a Scandinavian bear.
-No, it is from Croatia!
To the Scandinavian bear it's very close
No problem, Finn!
Hello!
It's very fresh.
We must break.
My back!
Put it over there.
It is very good.
35 000.
Bad bear, bad price.
The Riglefinch is still up in the woods.
Find it then!
A pair of German tourists
disappeared last night.
-Some more will probably follow.
-It's not my problem.
If you think you may keep
recordings...You are wrong!
He is best at finding bear.
This bear is from zoo.
Zoo you know?
-Why does Finn buy bears?
-I do not know!
In Poland, we don't ask.
Why create problems when
don't want to have problems?
-Bye!
-Bye.
It says "Pioters painting service."
Honestly, what is your job?
To kill all the trolls who gets
out from their territories.
And closer to people.
-How often does it happen?
Very rarely. Now it has emerged
a special situation.
Many trolls have broken out
and wander around the area.
Finn, he is a bureaucrat....
He leads the TSS.
He shall prevent-
-That people know
that there is trolls in the woods.
In a way, you are
one of Norway's greatest heroes.
No, you're wrong there.
There is no heroism in the job.
It is dirty rough work.
How is it
that no one knows about this?
We go to Oslo and sell the
recordings expensive to NRK.
It is not related yet.
We just have to follow him.
Finn is pissed off.
-Where are we going now?
-Now it's breakfast.
-You should get some food.
-I'm not that hungry.
I feel a little half ill.
How many kinds of trolls are there?
There are two main groups:
mountain trolls and woodland trolls.
Of the subgroups, there are
Ringlefinch, Tosserlad, Rimetosser.
And Dovrehubby.
-Harding is a kind from Western Norway.
-But the monster we saw...
-They all have three heads?
-No, it's different.
They develop heads
through their lifecycle.
They are not born with three heads.
They are usually born with one;
then others grow out.
They only have eyes in the middle
head. The original head.
The others are not really heads.
They are just formations
-Which resemble heads
to scare other trolls.
Or make an impression on female troll.
What is the schedule?
-TSS. What does it stand for?
-Troll Security Service.
Every time we followed a troll
we need to complete this.
Where it was, sex, if it bursted
or was petrified...
In Asbjornsen and Moe-tales
trolls have clothes on-
And they talk to people.
-They are like people.
-You can just forget about fairy tales.
Trolls are animals. Predators.
They eat, shit and mate.
They eat everything they come across.
-How old can they be?
-1000, 1200 years.
-How is the level of intelligence?
-Very low. They are stupid.
They manage to ingest food. But how
difficult it is when they eat stones?
I saw a troll
who tried to eat its tail.
Stood with his head between his legs,
and tried to swallow its own tail.
When he had pretty much swallowed it-
-He fell and rolled
down the mountain like a wheel.
-I was a commando.
-Is that how you got into this?
No, they were looking for a person
who could...
-Are you the only one in Norway?
-Yes.
Are we going?
-They eat all kind of crap.
-They eat people?
-Try it yourself.
-No, but they have been eating people?
-Is it troll tails?
-Yes. Some are skinned, others are whole.
-Why?
-To make it smell troll.
Why should it smell troll?
I must be getting close
troll without them noticing me.
Solarium-Lamp?
-Yes.
-You can get skin cancer.
-I use sunscreen.
I have problems sleeping
in the dark.
-We smeared ourselves with that?
-Yes.
-What is it?
Concentrated troll stench.
A mixture of all the crap
you can squeeze out of a troll.
We must find the Ringlefinch before
he eat his way through every barn here.
The German tourists were found north
of Kulpefjellet, taken by a bear.
Finn Haugan from Game Board
investigating-
-If it was the bear
which was found...
Do you know where the troll can be?
You got a track?
No.
What are you looking for?
Rockslides, trees knocked over
and stuff like that.
Do you see anything?
It's that bad?
-Yes.
Maybe we should check it out?
-Are you really ill?
-It goes up and down. Now it hurts.
-This does not feel so safe.
-They are just out a night.
Kalle, we can not...
The trap has not been triggered,
but some Moomins have taken the bait.
Concrete stone and charcoal
is an unbeatable combination.
-Do it now!
-Now?
Now, Hans found tracks of what
he believes is the Ringlefinch...
Now Hans found tracks of what
he believes is the Ringlefinch.
They have found pig carcasses
nearby.
Hans think it's connected.
Now we are going out...
Hurry!
Global warming
have affected our fauna-
-Our flora and our wildlife...
The tracks in this area
comes from a Russian Bear-
-Which probably migrated here
through Finland and Sweden.
Bear store their food under the bridge
here, where it is dark and cold.
It's not strange?
-Not for a Russian bear.
They are accustomed to long, harsh winters.
They gather, just like squirrels.
Aren't the bear tracks a bit strange?
That is the outer toe, so it's
left foot. This is the right foot.
Has the bear been walking like this?
-You've seen bear tracks in the past?
What about the tracks?
He has gnawed the bark of the tree.
A typical Riglefinch.
He'll come back tonight.
I have something to tempt him with.
-Are you going to kill him then?
-Yes.
But first I need to take blood samples.
Is that the syringe?
It is awful!
It is animal cruelty.
It is not animal cruelty.
They are just decoys.
It is too far away.
Should we go further?
No, I'm zooming.
We see it very well.
Strange work hours.
We have been here long. It's not
certain there will be a troll.
-We see it well from here.
-But we see a lot better there.
Let's go there.
It's here.
Can't you hear?
Run!
Damn, I hate this!
Keep your distance.
I'll pour some Christian blood.
Move!
Damn! Kalle! Thomas!
Move! Move!
Hans?
Are you okay? You...
Are you okay?
Help him up.
-Come on, Hans.
-Are you okay?
Be careful with the red button.
Give me the syringe.
Stay up there.
Then we know that trolls burst too.
-What about you?
-Well thank you.
No greater danger.
-I was just a little stiff.
-A little stiff?
It's sick!
I got the blood sample.
I'll be there in half an hour.
Goodbye.
You look like a baby!
There are some people who do some
filming. They want to ask some questions.
-Hi. Thomas.
-Hi.
Is that the blood?
-Yes.
-It was a bit hard to take the sample.
-I see it.
Look at you!
-Help yourselves.
-There is a toilet in there.
-What do you see?
-Too little red blood cells.
It may take me a couple of days.
Can we get a little interview?
If you just sit there.
-What should I tell?
-All of it.
-We are not allowed to...
-I take responsibility for it.
The problem for the trolls is that they
are not able to convert vitamin D
-From the sunlight, as we can,
to lime or calcium.
When exposed to sunlight
the body overreacts completely.
The stomach swells up.
Gas is forced out of the digestive system
and blood vessels with enormous pressure.
And then they burst?
-Yes.
-But some trolls calcify?
-Yes, the older trolls calcify.
The blood vessels are too narrow,
such expansion will occur in the bones.
In seconds, they turn to lime
and is completely petrified.
It would be good if they did not
experience this pain.
It is traumatic, even if it
only takes a few seconds.
We would like to give them
a syringe instead.
-I know the answer in a few days.
And then you call me?
-Have a good one.
-Shall we go?
-Yes.
-Why so many local papers?
-I collect information.
-About what?
-About trolls.
Accidents and stuff that happens
where trolls often is the cause.
-I have folders there.
-May I look?
"The road disappeared."
People always want to
find natural explanations.
If you know what you're looking for,
it is easy to see if it was troll.
The bridge is broken in half.
He stood in the fjord
and struck his head through the concrete.
Is there trolls this big?
Yes, a Jotun can be that large.
I'm the only one who has seen them.
There is a mountain troll territory
up in Finnmarksvidda.
And one of Hardangervidda.
In Jotunheimen are three.
And then you have Dovre.
In which territory is the problem?
Jotunheimen is the closest.
We go there and check first.
We are heading to the first turf
that Hans will check.
We are running in a circle
around the territory now.
The territory ends up here.
Since this tire is intact-
-Hans says that no troll has
been outside this territory.
If they were
they had chewed on the tire here.
Smile!
That's it. Shoot that...
Trolls love to chew on
old car tires.
Here they have tried to kick in,
but they did not pierce the container.
-How many trolls are there?
-Completely impossible to say.
Don't you have a certain overview?
The gestation period is 10-15 years.
And they usually only get one little.
-Are they mammals?
-Yes.
Let's see...
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
It looks perfect.
All rocks are where they should.
This is apparently a battle field.
Here, mountain trolls and
woodland trolls fight.
They throw stones at each other.
But it's a while ago
there was any activity here.
He who's in back pays.
Isn't that what they say?
Do you remember the drawing of the Jotun?
They are around here in Jotunheimen.
-Where?
-In the mountains.
-What are you going to do?
-Stay there.
I've eaten a whole bread.
Finn refuses to give up.
He claims that all the trolls who escaped
comes from Dovre-
-Just because he did not see any
on the satellite image.
But troll is not visible on satellite
images. It proves nothing!
We will go to the bottom of this.
We're going to a farm
that's been featured on local news.
He believes the incident
can be troll related.
Oh, look there!
Did you get it?
-What happened here?
-It was a tornado.
-Were you here when it happened?
-No.
Do you see how the trees are there?
If it was normal wind
all would bee in the same direction.
Who was here and showed you the map?
They did not introduce themselves
But they had nice weather maps
and satellite maps of the area.
And we could see something
that looked like tornados.
There are traces of at least three troll
which continued north.
That people don't notice
the big beasts-
-Which roared up here!
We'll come back tonight
and take a trip in the woods.
I'm getting a bit tired.
-I do not want to.
-We must stick together.
-Are you serious, Kalle?
-Yes.
Now we have to go.
What do we do now?
Hans?
There are trails in there.
Here is the track. They have been here.
-We can not stand here ourselves.
-This way!
Disused mine.
-They have been here.
-I won't fucking go in there!
There is no troll in there now.
Come on.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
No, there is no one home.
Hey, I need to have
that troll lump.
-Here.
-I take the camera.
Is it good?
This is not just for one troll
A whole damn pack.
-We can go.
-Come on! Hurry out!
We go. Come on!
Someone is coming!
Come right next to the rock wall!
Can't we go?
We go inside again!
Quick, in here!
Switch off the lights!
I have to get out of here.
-Do you have more troll lump?
-No, not here.
Try to relax. Breathe easy.
Calm down.
-Why are you so stressed?
-I am a Christian!
-We're going to die!
-Damn!
Don't you fucking start sweating!
Good God...
Shut up!
Run!
The sun!
It still works.
There are more left in there.
I have to take them later.
Dovrehubbies.
Why did he not tell us
that he was a Christian?
I have to go up on Dovre and
figure out why the beasts escape.
I can drop you off
down at the campsite.
-What are you doing in my caravan?
-Searching for the recordings.
Have you been snooping
around in my caravan?
-Are you filming now?
-No.
-It's chaos up there.
-Shouldn't you be there?
I do not go into the territory.
I don't do it.
-Turn off the camera.
-It is not on.
Why should people not
know about this?
-What is your job?
-It's classified.
Why should people not know
what happens? People are dying!
Why is it kept secret?
-People have the right to know.
-No, they do not.
-Do not touch the camera!
-Don't stick your nose in others business.
Well, this is my problem!
-Go away!
-This is not over.
I'll see what's going on.
Come and shoot if you want.
-We will.
-Are you ready for it?
-Yes.
-We continue to film.
We find a new camera.
Here comes the new
camera woman Malica.
-Malica.
-Thomas. You're not a Christian?
-Do you believe in Jesus or God?
-I am a Muslim.
That is good.
- Is it okay with Muslims?
I don't know.
We'll see what happens.
-It must be okay.
-We will shoot the musk ox?
No, we aren't.
-Let's go.
-Yes, we might as well.
We take it on the road.
-What have you worked with before?
-Mostly for NRK and the BBC.
-I have filmed lions in Tanzania.
-Lion, yeah...
The worst I've seen. Damn.
They have broken every damn tree here.
A Jotun has probably broken out here.
A giant of 170-330 feet who
penetrated into the Dovre-territory-
And frightened down Dovre-trolls here.
A Jotun on a long tour, it's not good.
Honestly. Do you all believe in trolls?
Do you think a squirrel plowed down here?
If they'd had it good in the territories...
But TSS is putting the lid on everything.
It may look like ordinary
high voltage lines-
-But they are electrified fences
that will keep the trolls in place.
I do not understand how they
came through here.
There are some sourpusses in Dombaes
who manage the power grid.
-Do they know about the trolls?
-No, no.
Have you had any problem with
the power lines at Dovre?
Problem, you can safely say.
Hang up your jackets.
Over here.
Several hundred feet of high voltage
cable went into the ground. 300 000 volts.
-When did that happen?
-Three weeks ago.
-Do you know how it happened?
-No, no one knows.
The cable went into the ground. It should
withstand hurricane. We have no idea.
-Is this a school assignment?
-Yes. Volda College.
-Are you a teacher?
-No.
Where is the power cables?
It is here, then north
and then down here.
-Is it in a circle?
-Yes, it goes in a circle.
Isn't that strange?
-Well, maybe a little.
-Yes, it is strange.
-The power goes nowhere.
Well, it goes around. And it's
in a nature preserved area.
If the Jotun went through the
high-voltage fence, something's wrong.
I have to get up on Dovre
to try and find the beast.
Up there is the territorial border.
It is difficult
putting up new towers.
Protests by farmers
and tourism.
I think the masts are beautiful.
They were put here so the trolls would
have access to food in the territory.
They go around the entire territory.
We have been in this area.
And here.
We have not seen a trace of troll.
I think we'll try to
come up in this area.
There is a TSS-house
where we can wait.
Some researchers believe that there's
natural explanations, others...
They has registered
more than 1000 quakes...
Now we are in a home range.
I got the impression that you
not want to go into these territories.
Is there any reason for that?
It was a mountain troll home range
up in Stryn Fjell.
In the 70's they decided
to build the tunnel-
-Right where it was filled
of mountain trolls.
I and TSS tried to protest,
to no avail.
My sour job was to go into
this territory and kill all the trolls.
Everyone who was there...
Pregnant females and young.
Newborns who could not even walk.
It was a bloody massacre.
Almost his whole life has
been about trolls.
Every day for him has been
a battle for and with trolls.
He is in many ways a superhero
here in Norway.
What could we have done without him?
It is therefore important
that we are making this movie.
-Thomas?
-We must cut.
It's the shoulder.
How is it?
What is that noise?
It's light in an hour.
Shall we follow?
He is a heavyweight,
but I have to give it a shot.
He seems to have become completely mad.
This can be a bit unpleasant.
Your phone is ringing, Hans.
-Where is it?
-It's on the seat.
It's Thomas. He is
a little busy now. Can I...?
Rabies?
-The Ringlefinch had rabies.
-Can I speak to Hilde.
Hey, Hilde. Are you sure?
Then I understand some more.
Take care you too. Goodbye.
Would not surprise me if all the trolls
we have met have been infected with rabies.
He there have spread the shit to both
Riglefinches and Dovrehubbys.
And even you, Thomas.
-Me? I do not have rabies.
Hey! Dogs have rabies.
If you have rabies,
you have to be taken to the hospital.
If you think he has rabies
he must be taken to the hospital!
-I do not have rabies.
-Hans!
You can't know that I have rabies!
If so have to get to the hospital immediately!
-Here that fucking animal comes.
-I don't give damn!
-We can not be here.
-Look!
Is it heading our way?
Are you going out? Are you crazy?
He's fleeing!
Stand still!
I'm trying to get him over here.
"We have a friend in Jesus..."
What is he doing?
The battery for the damn flash
died out.
Definitely rabies.
Can't we go to the hospital now?
-I have to give a few more doses.
-What are you talking about?
But first I need to tire him out.
He's getting closer!
-We are getting away from him!
That's good.
-People! There's people!
-Stop, Hans!
-Get in!
-Hurry up, damn it!
Go! Go!
-What are you doing?
-Stay here!
Hans! Get in the car again!
Get in the car!
-What are you doing here?
-I am a seismologist.
I have to pass him.
Watch out!
Is the camera on now?
Hans, what are you doing?
I have to give him the deathblow!
-With that thing?
-Yes.
I hope you have recorded what you need.
Follow the road down
and you'll get to the E6.
Now it's quiet!
Malica...
Don't fool around.
There is troll on the tape.
Here are the films.
Am I bleeding? What did you say?
-Are you okay?
-Yes, I'm okay.
Look!
Isn't that Finn and the others?
Damn, it's Finn.
Give me the camera!
Thomas, what are you doing?
Thomas! Stop!
Here, the recordings end.
No corpse was found in the mine-
And the youths who filmed
are lost without trace.
We urge anyone who knows anything
contact Filmkameratene AS
Or the nearest police station.
It has been impossible to confirm the
existence of Troll Security Service Service.
Prime Minister Jens Stoltenberg
however, gave an indirect confirmation
-On Hukodden in Oslo 25 June 2010.
The press did not do anything.
We want the least possible disruption
in Norwegian nature.
Nobody thinks the power lines are beautiful.
I don't think so.
But in Norway we are for electricity-
-But against power lines.
It does not work in the long run.
Norway has troll, so more power lines
in Norway are necessary.
-That's how it is.
-Let's wrap it up there!