Please.
You don't have to do this.
Oh, God!
Not like this.
No, you can't. Please!
No.
Please.
Por favor!
I am so sorry.
Oh, God, I wanna go home!
You having fun?
- Am I the only one having a problem with this?
- I guess they're used to it.
I just keep thinking about
how far we must be from a hospital.
You know, with doctors who operate
instead of amputate?
So dramatic.
- Would you slow the fuck down!
- Jesus Christ, relax! You're such a tourist.
Por favor!
Calm down. He drives through it every day.
I think he knows how to drive better than you do.
- He drives like a fucking lunatic.
- Well, we're fine, aren't we?
I can't believe I let you talk me into this.
- We're flying back.
- Okay, fine.
- And I'm picking the hotels from now on.
- You were right about that.
I'm sorry.
Check it out.
- That looks painful.
- Stop it!
What do you think it says?
It says,
"Welcome to Brazil. Now bend over."
- We have to remember that.
- He likes you.
Deus!
Jesus Christ! Stay on the road, you lunatic!
Go out the window!
Go! Go!
- Get out!
- Get out! Go, go, go!
Get out right now!
Everybody out!
- Whoa. Whoa.
- Go!
Go! Get off!
Jump! Get off!
Oh, my God.
Get off! Get off, get off!
Get off!
- Oh, shit!
- Did everyone get out of there?
- You still think flying
would've been a waste of money?
- Don't start.
- I told you this was-
- Don't!
- Fine.
Why is my luggage
always the last to come out?
Ale-Alex? Found it!
Great!
I'm impressed.
- Why?
- Bit like bringing sand to the beach though.
Bringing a couple of fit little birds
like that to Brazil?
- That's my sister.
- Splendid.
Just like to know me options.
It's not an option.
- Get everything?
- Yeah, I think so.
- Hi, I'm Finn. Nice to meet you.
- Bea. You too.
- Liam.
- Hi. How are you guys?
Good as gold.
Hi. I'm Finn.
- Amy. Nice to meet you.
- Liam.
Guess we're bonded for life now, eh?
Near-death experience.
- Great story to tell the grandkids.
- Yeah.
- You think they got a plan to get us out of here?
- I doubt it.
- Should find out, I suppose.
- I'll find out.
Oh, man.
"Bussie!"
You suck at driving buses!
You should do something else.
Pick bananas or something.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- I'm Alex.
- Pru.
Yes. Yes.
- You're, um, supposed to kiss back.
- Ah. Sorry.
Except you don't actually kiss.
You sort of kiss the air.
- Yeah. Start again.
- I'm Alex.
- Pru. Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- So, do you speak Spanish?
- It's Portuguese here.
- Right. So, any idea what
these guys are talking about?
- Another bus is on its way.
- It's gonna be about 10 hours.
- Ten hours?
- Yeah. And then it's another 18 to Recife.
- Wait, what did you just say?
- About what?
- About where we're headed.
Well, the way that guy was driving,
I'm not really sure.
- But you said Recife, right?
- Yeah.
- Which is north of Salvador.
- On most maps.
- Which means we've been
headed north this whole time.
- Idiots, the pair of us.
We got on the wrong fucking bus!
- The Rastafarian.
- I knew he was dodgy.
- Brilliant cunts we are.
- Wait. Where did you guys think you were going?
- To Floripa.
- Oh, you took the long way.
- Yeah. Where was this bus headed?
- Belém.
Don't suppose that Belém is famous
for having a 10-to-1 ratio of women to men...
where even the ugly girls
look like Giselle.
And they're all smart, fun,
alcoholic nymphomaniacs...
with a soft spot for charming
if slightly grubby foreign tourists?
Uh, not that I'm aware of, no.
- Too bad.
- 'Cause Floripa is.
Six- Six Sports Illustrated
swimsuit models are from Floripa.
- Do you understand how select
that gene pool must be?
- It's a tiny town.
- Leave it out.
- All right.
- Hey, are you getting anything?
- No. Nothing.
Do you think they know
something we don't?
I'm gonna walk around.
Bonita.
Meu nome é Bea.
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Photograph.
Photograph. It's a-
Hey, hey.
- Jesus! Calm down!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Calm down! I'm sorry!
- You're not to take pictures
of kids without permission.
- How am I supposed to know?
Hey. "No, senhorita"
would have been fine.
Or even "No, you stupid,
bloody gringo!"
Asshole! I can't hear ya!
Leave the girl alone. All right?
Prick.
Tabloids have been writing stories
about foreigners...
coming here to steal kids
to sell their organs for transplants.
It's created a lot of hostility
to tourists.
- Has that anything to do with
that couple that were missing?
- I don't think they're a couple.
- French couple, right?
- Oh, I thought you meant the kayakers.
Oi! We got no designs on your organs!
All right? Your kidneys are safe with us!
We're on holiday, for fuck's sake!
Hey, where'd you get those from?
- What did she say?
- She said there's a bar on the
beach and it's really close.
- We can walk.
- Is there a town?
- Don't you think we should wait for the next bus?
- They haven't made the next bus.
Let's go.
We'll come back later.
Let's do it.
So, how did you end up here?
I'm here with my little sister.
She's always wanted
to come to Brazil...
my mom didn't want her to go alone
and didn't trust her with Amy...
so I get to pretend to be the boyfriend
when creepy guys try to bother her.
What happens when
creepy girls bother you?
- So what about you? You traveling alone?
- Yeah.
- That's brave.
- Not really. I've been everywhere
they tell you not to go.
Colombia, Nigeria. Just spent
three months in a favela in Rocinha.
The only place I've ever had any problems
is in a small town in Australia.
- So, you're from Australia?
- Uh-huh.
Got a boyfriend in Australia?
No! You did not just say that!
- What?
- "So, you got a boyfriend in Australia?"
I just meant that if I had a girlfriend
or a little sister who was traveling alone...
I'd be a little worried, that's all.
Well, don't be.
I can take care of myself.
- So, did she say this was
a proper bar with real drinks?
I don't know.
She didn't say.
Christ, I'd do anything for a pint.
I'd lick the sweat
off a monkey's balls.
"I'd lick the sweat off a monkey's balls."
- Christ on a cracker.
- This is amazing!
Oh, yes! Check this out!
- Baby!
- Oh, yes!
Whoo! Who wants to go for a swim?
- Yeah, sure!
- Yes! This is what I was talking about.
- They got beer?
- Get your kit off, girls!
Come on!
Let's swim!
Shit.
I left my top in Rio.
Would you guys mind if I went topless?
- Are you serious? No. Keep your shirt on.
- Yeah. Why not?
Do you see what they're wearing, Alex?
We're not in America.
No one's gonna care if I go topless.
Yeah, but the idea is to tastefully reveal
as much as possible-
Oi, oi.
Get a load of that.
without actually
revealing so much...
that you can still get into heaven.
That was good.
Yes!
- That is a fantastic trick.
- Well, it's still a Catholic country.
- Well, we're Catholics.
- And we definitely don't mind.
No. In fact, I think I can speak for Liam when
I say we wouldn't be offended in the slightest.
In fact, let's all go topless,
boys and girls.
No, Amy-
Oh! Nice!
Put your shirt on.
She's a naughty girl.
- How about that? Is this better?
- Oh, no!
Come on.
Let's go.
All right, let's go get it wet.
- Come on, Alex!
- Whoo!
Let's get a drink.
- Alex, where are you going?
- Over here.
Whoo!
- Qual é seu nome?
- É camila.
Pru. Alex.
Nice to meet you.
- What do you want?
- Uh, Coke, please.
A Coke? You're 7,000 miles away
from home. Try something new.
- Like what?
- Have you ever had assai?
Uh, no.
It's, like, this amazing drink
from the Amazon. It's-
Just a Coke's fine.
Thank you. No ice.
My God, I love this country.
It's like we died on the bus and this is heaven.
It's heaven.
It's, uh, paraíso.
And you? Angel.
Wait.
You too!
Come on!
Ah!
- Don't want to-
- Por favor?
- No ice.
- No, no. It's, like, a hundred fucking degrees.
No, it's like ordering with dysentery
or without dysentery. No ice.
Dysentery.
This is unbelievable.
You think you've found
your own private Shangri-la.
Next thing you know, the place is crawling
with backpacking tourists wearing sandals.
Welcome to paradise.
I'm Svend.
- Pru, my sister Bea, Amy.
- Hi.
- Where are you from?
- London.
- London. We're from Sweden.
- Sweden! Nice!
We rode this beauty all the way from Mexico City
and stopped to have a drink three days ago.
Now we can't
find any reason to leave.
Yeah, and Brazilians
are the warmest and friendliest...
and most chill people
you're ever gonna meet.
The drinks are cheap, and Camila's cooking,
it's unbelievable.
And you even have a barrack you can sleep in
on the beach- only four bucks a night.
- Oh, my God.
- Go on!
About what?
Oh, no, no.
It's just an expression, like "no way."
- Oh. Yeah!
- I hate living up to the natives' stereotype, but-
and I think I speak for
my brother when I say this-
we're not leaving here...
- until either we run out of money-
- Or they run out of beer!
- Oh, my God.
- So, what do you think?
About getting on the bus?
Come on. Look where we are.
Well, how do we get back?
Hitchhike to a bigger town. We'll get on
a better bus, with air conditioning and brakes.
You in?
- Sure.
- Yeah! Let's do it!
All right, fuck the bus.
Yes!
Ow.
Camila.
- Da. Ciao.
- Ciao.
Whoo! Let's go!
Let's go, let's go!
- Amy! Amy!
- Come on! In the middle!
Ohh! Nice!
Why won't someone pass me the ball?
- Come on, come on!
- Think fast!
Oh!
We know how to play this game!
- Ohh!
- You okay?
- You suck, Amy.
- Let's go!
You're on our side, Alex!
Come on, Alex! Pass!
Yes! Whoo-hoo!
Come on, Liam! Run! Run!
- Hi.
I am study the English.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Uh, I-I think I make my "practions" on you.
- Sure. Yes.
- So, what's your name?
- Uh, Pru.
- Pru?
- Yes.
- And what is your name?
- My name is Kiko. Meu nome é Kiko.
- Nice to meet you.
Okay, Pru, how many
brothers and sisters are you havin'?
Uh, only child.
- Que?
- Sorry. Zero. Zero. None.
Zero?
- Right.
- Ah. Only child.
- Only child.
- Ah. Zero.
I'm havin' four brothers
and two sisters.
- Wow. Big family.
- Big family.
- Uma família grande.
- Família grande.
Hey, my man!
What's your name?
- Alex.
- Okay, Alex. I'm love you, America!
I love you, Brazil!
Yeah! How many brothers
and sisters are you having?
No, it's how many brothers and sisters
do you have?
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm havin' four brothers and two sisters.
How many brothers and sisters
are you having?
- Do you have- No- One.
- One?
One sister. Yeah.
Uh, Bea! Bea.
- This is my sister, Bea.
- Hi!
And this is her friend, Amy.
- Just beautiful.
- Kiko.
- Thank you.
- E-Easy, Kiko.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hi. How are you?
We're gonna go get a drink.
Yeah!
One more. Go!
Right!
Has everybody got one?
One! Two! Three! Cheers!
Yeah!
Oi!
Ugh!
Cachaça, baby!
Cheers!
Oh! That's disgusting! I love it!
Oh! Oh! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
My music!
You like dancing?
- Yeah.
- Come here, girl.
Come on, Amy!
Yeah!
What, dance?
No, no, no.
Go on. Dance with her.
No, no, I'm not dancing.
No, no, no, it's not you. It's just that I have
these very European hips.
- They have to stay parallel to the floor at all times.
- Huh?
Apart from when I'm naked.
I can't do that.
You're not gonna take no
for an answer, are you?
Go on!
Show her how it's done!
Look at him go!
Hi.
Yeah!
Hey. Where are you going?
Hey, my man!
My man!
- Olá.
Uh, que é seu nome?
- Arolea.
- Areola?
Arolea!
Aroayla.
A... ro... lea.
Arolea.
Yes!
I get a kiss just for
saying your name?
Arolea.
Mmm!
This song is so nasty.
What are they saying?
I'm not getting it all,
but basically...
it's a long list of explicit things
he likes to do in his car-
one being up the ass.
Mmm!
Do you wanna dance?
- Yes.
- Come on. Let's dance.
Oh, yes!
Oh, it's like that, is it? Oh!
- Yes. I want. Yeah. I like very much.
- Mmm.
Oh, God!
- Ah?
- Damn!
Yes. More.
All of it. All of it.
Oh! Yeah!
Take it all off. Yeah!
- Mais?
- Oh!
Please.
Mais! Mais!
Oh, my God.
Oh, God bless Brazil.
Come on.
Yeah!
I love Brazil!
God, you really are an angel.
Wanna come back with me to London?
Oh, w-wait. No!
It's not like that!
- É assim.
- But I thought you liked me. No?
No.
Hey, Svend!
What a night!
Hey! Dude!
Bloody lightweight.
Bea!
Bea, get up!
Come on, get up. Get up.
Bea.
Come on, come on.
- You okay?
- What?
- No. I feel sick.
What happened?
They robbed us.
- What?
- We got robbed.
- By who?
- I don't know.
- What did they take?
- Everything.
- What do you mean, everything?
- I mean everything.
Our money, our credit cards,
our phones, our backpacks...
our passports, everything.
- Nana's ring.
- Yes, everything.
My earrings are gone.
How did they take my fucking earrings?
I think that they drugged us. They must have
put something in our drinks last night.
Mom is gonna kill me. She told me not to
bring the ring, 'cause-
Bea.
That is a very small problem right now.
We have no money. We have no way out of here.
We'll be fine.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
'Cause I'm not so sure.
Come on.
Mm-mmm.
Hold on.
Hey!
No! No! No! No!
No.
What?
What did she say?
Oh, God. She's saying it's down here to the left.
The other guy said it's down here
to the right. So I have no idea.
Are you sure it's smart
going to the police?
- Aren't they supposed to be
worse than the criminals?
- Not all of them.
- Come on.
- Someone in this town
must know what's going on.
These kids are definitely in on it.
It's freaking me out.
- God.
- What did he say?
Let's, uh- Let's just try up here-
this little house or something.
- Are you sure we're going the right way?
- That's what he said.
I don't know.
Alex?
Where are you going?
Aah! Ow.
- What is it?
- The Swede's motorcycle.
Hello?
Olá!
Hey! Hey!
Whose motorcycle is this?
Ask him who got-
Where'd they get this motorcycle?
That's Alex's hat.
That kid has Alex's hat.
- Alex!
- Alex, he's got your hat.
Grab him! Quick!
- Wait up, Liam!
- Just wanna talk to you!
Where'd you get that hat?
Come back here!
Wait! Shit!
Oww! Aah!
- Where'd he go?
- Don't know.
Aah!
Come back here!
Now!
You wait till I fucking catch you.
Now I've got you, you little shit.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit. Is he all right?
What happened?
What'd you do?
- It was an accident.
- You threw a rock at him?
Didn't mean to hit his head.
- It was an accident.
- We got robbed!
He had our friend's cap!
It was an accident!
Hey! Don't touch me!
- Walk away.
- Let's just go. Let's just go.
Hey, come on. Just relax.
Just walk away.
Come on, come on, come on!
- Are they following us?
- No, I don't think so.
W-We were robbed.
R-Roubado. Roubado.
- I know.
- You know?
- Everybody knows.
- Who did it?
Who did it?
What police?
You crazy.
No police here. Okay?
What do you mean, there's no police here?
- Christ, dude, where are you going?
- Stay here.
Nice work.
- Leave him alone.
- It was a fucking accident.
- You don't throw a rock at a kid!
- Let it go!
- I'm sorry. Okay?
- Sorry, everybody.
- It's all right.
Let's go, guys.
- Damn!
- Come on!
Come on!
- Okay, man! Hold up!
- Where are we going?
- Is not good for you in town.
- Yeah, no kidding.
They are looking for the father
of this boy that you hurt.
Is bad man.
They find him, is very bad for you.
Okay?
Ask him where we're going, Pru.
There is-There is
a house of his uncle...
and he says that it's very safe
for us there.
No. We just want a ride.
Do you know anybody with a car?
No, no, no. No car.
There is-
The only car is of the guy
that robbed us.
- You'd better wait for the bus.
- There's a bus? When is there a bus?
Uh, qu-quando- At what time?
Uh... today?
- Today there's a bus?
- Yes.
- What time?
- Two day.
- Two days.
- Two days?
Why does everything take
so fucking long in this place?
- Two day-
- Okay, vamos. Vamos la. Vamos.
Fuck! These insects are eating me alive.
- Look at that. All over me legs.
- Leave it out.
There'd better be a big bag
of fucking weed at this house.
Kiko, can we just...
stop for a minute?
I'll be back in a minute.
- Where are you going?
- The men's room.
Whose idea was it to leave the bus?
- Whose idea was it to come to Brazil?
- It was yours!
- I wanted to go to Bali.
- You're missing the point.
The point is, if we dig deep enough
I'm sure we'll discover this is all your fault.
Oh, right. Yeah.
- Which'll make me feel a lot better.
- Right.
And you know what? I did want to
come to Brazil. Why? Because I like girls.
And I like beaches and drinking.
And when they say
"Come to Brazil," they say...
"Come to Brazil! We've got girls
and beaches and drinking!"
What they do not say,
what they completely neglect to mention...
is anything about being chased
into the jungle by an angry fuckin' mob...
which is not my idea
of a fun vacation at all!
Oi, Kiko!
How far is this house?
- Uh, uh, como far?
- Hey, man, not so bad.
What do you mean?
This is pretty fucking bad!
What about a road?
Is there a road we can walk on?
- No roads.
- What kind of house has no roads?
Fucking hell.
Come on! Almost there!
Kiko! Where are we going?
There is a place where we can rest.
This place is amazing.
Check it out!
Come on! I show you something.
- Wow.
- This is my secret place.
Kiko, can we swim here?
I show you some caves.
What caves? Where?
There are caves in the water.
We'll swim, then go to house.
- How close is the house?
- It's right on the river.
Ten minutes.
Hey, guys, watch me!
You're joking. You're never gonna jump off of this!
- Kiko, It's too dangerous.
- Go ahead!
- Stop encouraging him!
- I am diving all the time!
Less talking!
More action!
No, stop!
Don't do it! No!
Kiko! Whoa!
Crazy son of a bitch!
- You're gonna kill yourself!
- Come on!
Come on, come on! Come down!
Swim!
I show you caves!
- No way I'm doing that!
- Come on. Let's go see 'em.
- I'm staying here.
- You sure?
Come on! Come on!
- You can do it!
- Yeah, I'm gonna, uh, stay here too.
Right.
Behave yourself.
Here?
- The caves! Come on!
- Over there?
I can't.
No, no, I can't.
Follow me.
It's an easy swim.
You can do it.
- Come on. Let's do it.
- Okay.
- Hey, Bea, you okay?
- Yeah.
- Is this it?
- Come on. A little more far.
- Follow me.
- Kiko, where are we?
Where are we goin'?
Fuck! That was a bat!
Kiko.
Come on, guys.
Let's go.
- Kiko, what is this?
- We go under.
- No!
- No. No.
- There-There is a hole.
- No, no, no, no.
Hey, man, it's easy.
This is incredible.
Incredible!
- All right. Let's go. Fine. Fine.
- No. No.
- One, two, three.
- What?
Asshole!
What the fuck is this?
Oh, Jesus!
That was not easy.
It was scary.
And this is not incredible.
We go more.
Ow! Ow!
Jesus!
- Kiko!
- Fucking lunatic!
- Shit! The light!
Holy shit!
Wow, look at this place.
Bea, look at this.
Wow, this is amazing. What is this place?
Very nice, Kiko!
This water is so beautiful!
- This is incredible.
- Yes.
Is my secret place.
I-I never making friends
with the gringos before.
- No?
- No.
I never have, um, speak with one.
Really?
Well, hi there!
Oh, my God.
You okay?
What?
You-You feel okay?
- Yes, yes. I am okay.
- Okay.
Uh, maybe...
we go back to town.
- What?
- Aqui. Yes.
Is better we go back.
We just hiked 10 hours through the jungle.
How can you go back?
- Did you say go back?
- We're not going back. No way.
Yes.
I-I-I think is better.
- Why?
- Maybe I talk with these guys, okay?
Um, tell them you are okay.
Maybe find a ride for you.
But why are you saying this now?
- I don't know. It's just, um-
- It's just what?
No- No nothing.
Look, it's simple- 10 hours hike through
the jungle, or 10 minutes to the house.
I don't like hiking.
We go to the fucking house.
Is there a problem
with this house, Kiko?
No. No problem.
Then we go to the house.
Okay?
- Okay.
That's for almost killing us!
Come on, guys.
We walk back.
- Oh. Hey. What's going on?
- Oi, oi!
Hi. How was it?
- Awesome. Underwater caves. It was cool.
- There were bats.
Come on.
Let's go together.
Hey, Kiko, show me how you do that.
- I wanna do it. Show me. Yeah.
- Let's jump together.
One, two, three!
You guys should try it!
Dude, I wanna try.
Show me how you do it.
Okay, okay.
I go.
Whoo! Crazy!
Whoo! Oh!
- Shit! He's bleeding!
- Kiko!
- We're coming down!
- Stay up!
Jesus Christ!
- What happened?
- He must have hit his head on a rock below.
Keep his head above the water!
Is he conscious?
Oh, my God.
- Get him to the side.
- Come on, come on!
- Swim! Swim!
- Over here!
What are we gonna do?
Take him back to the village.
We'll never get back before dark.
We'll go to the house.
- We don't know where the house is!
- He said it was on the river.
Help me get him out. Grab my shirt.
We're gonna wrap his head.
Is he gonna die?
- No.
- How do you know?
Between rugby and bar fights, I've probably
had a concussion a year since I was nine.
- When did you play rugby?
- I played!
- We should have just gone back to the village.
- No way!
They'll fucking kill us!
What is this place doing here?
You okay?
He all right?
Hello!
Nearly there.
Whoa. This is crazy.
Almost there.
Hello?
This guy likes his privacy.
- Hey, look, there's a dip there.
- Hello!
Oi!
Anyone home?
Bea, get a chair.
Here we go.
Fuck!
- Oh, shit, that's deep.
- Jesus.
Keep pressure on that.
We need something to close this up.
Find, uh, superglue,
needle and thread, anything.
Check upstairs.
Olá?
Olá!
- Hold his head right here.
I gotta cut some of this out.
- Okay.
Oh. Sorry.
- Hold his fucking head up!
- I got it. I got it!
Vicodin, codeine, Demerol made out to
every imaginable name and nationality-
- Gustav Roth, Marco Terelli-
- Hold him.
What the hell is this place, some kind of
youth hostel for drug addicts?
- Gotta hold this shut.
- I got it!
- A stapler?
- No, no, no. You can't use that.
- It's fine.
- No!
It's what they used on me when I split
me head open. Hold it closed.
- Hold it shut.
- You got it.
- Oh, Jesus.
- More.
Oh, shit!
- Sorry, mate.
- Hold him.
- Okay?
- I got him. I got him.
Kiko, where you going? Are you okay?
- Kiko.
- Kiko, you okay?
Kiko.
Should we keep him awake?
I don't know.
He could have a concussion.
Clothes.
Mmm.
Smoked herring.
Let's see.
Mushrooms and cheese.
That's good.
Hey. Look. Look what I got.
Oh, you want some, don't you?
You want some.
Come here. Up here.
Yeah.
Nasty.
Here you go.
Ohh.
Yeah!
Hey.
- Anything good?
- I think our luck might be turning.
- Oh, yeah?
- Twenty-year-old single malt.
What the hell is this?
Who the hell are these people?
Hmm.
Thank you.
This house is so fucking creepy.
We'll just stay the night.
Then Kiko will show us the way out
in the morning.
- If he dies, how do we get back?
- He's not gonna die.
'Cause I don't wanna be here
if his uncle shows up and we're like...
"Hello, mate. Here's your dead nephew.
And you're out of scotch."
And why is there no road?
What kind of fucking hermit lives-
- Oi!
- Yeah, I know. Leave it out.
So, how does this rank
with your other trips?
After the last few days,
right at the bottom. You?
- Well, we had a pretty tough time in Cambodia.
- At least we had that hash.
Yeah, and those Dutch girls.
I just want to go home.
His uncle.
What's going on?
I'm not sure.
What is he saying?
Alex.
Kiko, what's-
Olá.
Hi.
- You guys American?
- Mm-hmm.
Cool. I've been one time
to New York.
Hmm.
Go. Run.
- What do you mean?
- Run right now.
This guy has plans for you
and your friends...
and his plans are pretty fucking elaborate
and pretty fucking fucked.
So if I were you, I'd just run.
Look, we didn't-
We're friends of Kiko.
He said- Hey! Shit!
No.
Kiko. Kiko!
Where the fuck did you take us?
Tell him we're your friends.
Where the fuck are you going?
- Kiko!
- Tell him we're your friends!
Where are you going?
- Alex, help me!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Get your fucking hands off me!
What's the matter with you?
Back off!
Oh, God!
Don't take this personal, okay?
If it makes you feel any better...
please know that I'm doing this...
for a good cause.
Please, don't.
Did you know that in America...
there is a seven-year wait...
for a healthy kidney?
And in Europe...
it's worse.
So...
if a rich gringo needs a kidney...
what does he do?
Wait and get sick and die
like the rest of us?
- Don't. Please.
- No.
He comes here to Brazil...
to take advantage of our bounty...
and of our poverty.
The whole history of our country...
is you taking from us...
and our land-
rubber, sugar, gold.
And from our bodies-
for slaves, for sex.
And now, for- for our insides.
But I...
have had...
enough.
Bea! Bea!
Take the knife!
Take it!
Take the knife.
Cut this rope off.
Cut this off my hands.
Cut.
Hurry.
Bea, hurry!
Attagirl. Attagirl.
Cut- Cut it.
Hurry!
It sickens my heart,
this combination-
- your greed-
- Oh, God, no.
and our weakness.
And so I am thinking:
Maybe there is something
I can do to even the scales just a little-
to help you find a way...
to give back.
Today I am to take
the organs of all of you...
and give them...
to the People's Hospital in Rio.
Counting down from right now,
I have-
I have about 12 hours...
to get your liver
and your kidneys...
and the liver and kidneys...
of all your fucking amiguinhos...
into that helicopter
and back to the city.
I'd take your hearts too,
your corneas-
even the skin from your lily-white asses.
But they don't travel too well.
You can only keep a heart
outside a body for six hours.
But I want that.
I want a heart-
a heart of some
arrogant fucking gringo tourist...
pumping life back into the veins...
of a little Brasileiro.
But that's gonna take more planning.
Your turn.
Come on. Let's go.
Come on, come on!
Kiko, grab the key!
Go, go!
- Come on, come on!
- Oh, oh!
Hurry up!
Come on, come on!
- Come on. Go to the waterfall.
We'll meet you there.
- No!
- Alex!
- Take her to the waterfall! Go!
- Alex, no!
- Come on. Let's get him out.
Please. Please, don't.
Please. Please.
Please don't. Please.
No. No.
No, please don't.
No, please!
Please, don't!
Shut up, you-
Come on!
Come on, come on!
Let's go!
Go, go, go, man! Go!
- Come on, come on.
- I'm not leaving Finn.
What the fuck you talkin' about?
Don't be stupid!
What the fuck is that?
Yo, go, man!
- Get the fuck away from me, Kiko!
- Ow!
Shh. Stay back.
Jesus, please!
Come on now. Go! Go, go!
Oh, fuck.
Come on. I'm gonna get you
out of here, bro.
You'll be all right, okay?
Help me get him out.
Fuck! Hurry up! Hurry up!
Come on! Come on!
Quick, quick!
Shh.
Shh. Keep quiet.
Shh!
Let's go. All right,
go, go, go, man, go!
Go! Go! Run! Run!
Hey!
Oh, my God. Come on! He's dead!
Let's go! Let's go!
Jesus! Come on!
You're crazy! You're crazy!
You stupid son of a bitch! What are you doin'?
Fuck you!
- Oh, goddamn it!
- Alex! Alex!
Hi.
- Amy-Amy's-
- No, no, she's gone.
I'm sorry.
Hey, man.
It's danger. Danger, okay?
Let's go.
All right.
Come on, Bea. Up, up.
- Let's go.
- Come on, come on. Let's go.
Hurry, Bea.
Come on, come on!
Hey, guys, come on!
You okay?
I've been here most of the night.
What about the others?
They're gone.
Come on. We gotta go.
Be quiet! Silence!
- Stop it!
- You crazy, man!
This is all your fault! You brought us here!
You knew this was gonna happen!
- He's risking his life!
- Fuck that!
Go, go, go! Get down! Dive!
Come with me.
- You okay?
- What are we gonna do?
We gotta find a way out of here.
- There's someone coming.
- What? Who?
I'll find another way out.
Follow me.
Turn off your light.
- He's coming! Let's go!
- No, I can't! I can't go!
Bea, you have to!
Come on!
- Where's Bea?
- I don't know.
Bea.
Bea!
You okay?
Never leave me again.
Over here. Just take my hand. Come on.
There's land.
We can get out here.
- There's an airway up here.
- That's great.
This might be the way out.
Let me see it.
It's fine.
Here, hold this.
It's fine. It's fine.
Let's just find our way out of here.
- We should just keep heading up.
- All right.
Let's go.
Alex, get down.
Turn off your light.
Shh, shh, shh. Don't fucking move.
Hey.
Alex! Alex, what are you doing?
Get off him!
Stop do-Alex!
What are you doing?
Oh! Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
What?
- This is stupid.
Why don't we just take the bus?
- The bus.
- We could take the bus.
Then we could see the country.
- The bus takes forever.
- I thought that's why we came
here, to experience new things.
- Yeah, I guess.
- Take the plane.
- What?
Take the plane.
- Thanks, man.
- De nada.