- I don't know.
- Seriously, I don't think...
This is stupid.
God, Grace.
Thank you, it's beautiful.
Thanks.
You look great.
How did Dawn take the news?
The break-up and all.
She'll get over it.
Don't you move. Be right back.
Time for the girls
to get a little shut-eye.
This one's for the hippie chick.
Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
Here you go.
Sorry. I was so thirsty.
Everyone is staring at us.
You are so much more beautiful
than you think you are.
You want to go someplace
more comfortable?
You want to go someplace?
I didn't even know the door
was there.
- All right, here we go.
- I don't feel well.
Let me go. Stop.
Mary, help.
What's going on?
Do you think he would
ever touch you?
No!
Willy!
- Get her! She's sober. She'll squeal.
- Willy, get up, man.
Come on, Mary!
Help!
Mary!
Mary! Mary!
Come on, Mary.
We're just having some fun.
- Let's just talk.
- Get away from me.
Hey.
Come on.
It's gonna be all right. Your friends
are okay. It's all right, it's okay.
It's just a little prank.
Come on.
Let's go check on your friends.
You stupid bitch!
Mary?
Mary.
Oh, shit.
I'm sorry.
There you are.
Where's the girl?
I don't know. I thought she
was in here, but she's not.
- Shit.
- She probably passed out somewhere.
Come on, we gotta find her.
That was over 30 years ago,
but her rotting body is still there...
...waiting to be discovered.
Bullshit.
No, it's true. I swear to God. My mom
told me in complete confidence.
Well, complete confidence...
...doesn't mean much when
you drink vodka like it's water.
Shut up.
- Stop it!
- So you don't think it's unhealthy...
...for them to stay home
on their own homecoming?
Not everybody wants to
be homecoming queen.
It didn't hurt me.
You're right.
- And I only wish I could've been there.
- No, you were too old and serious.
Thanks a lot.
That story doesn't make any sense.
I mean, why don't the girls stick
up for themselves? I don't get it.
Maybe if you weren't always speaking
out, like in the school newspaper...
...maybe we'd have dates
to the homecoming dance.
Okay, so you changed your mind.
You think it's fair football players
get academic credit...
...for going to practice?
You shouldn't have published
the picture with the article.
They took the picture as a joke. You
published it out of context, without...
Guys. I've got another ghost story.
That wasn't a ghost story, Mindy.
It's an urban legend.
An urban legend is a made-up story
people keep telling as if it was true.
Like the guy who eats Pop Rocks...
...drinks soda
and his stomach explodes.
Like that bullshit about Mindy's
brother's camp counselor...
...getting his arm stuck in a soda
machine, and it falls on top of him.
That wasn't bullshit.
And it was a candy machine.
- Oh, and like Bloody Mary.
- Who's that?
Supposedly, if you go into
the bathroom and turn off the lights...
...and chant "Bloody Mary" three times
into the mirror, she appears.
Her face is like a corpse.
And if you look at her, well...
...then you have to turn the lights
back on before she drags you in.
In where?
I don't know. In the mirror?
I heard she'll haunt you forever.
That's not even a real urban legend.
That's just like that movie Candyman.
- Well, my story was real.
- As real as your mother's new tits.
What's the first thing you'll do
when you're mayor?
- I haven't won yet.
- But you will.
A lot can happen, so...
But so far...
- What's going on in there?
- I don't know.
Well, the first thing I'm gonna do
is propose a 9 p.m. curfew...
...on all teenage girls.
I'll keep them off the streets,
keep them safe.
Keep them virgins.
I'm afraid that might be too late.
Bloody Mary.
Who is it?
David.
Asshole.
So, David, you're back early.
Shouldn't you be at the dance?
- I'm sure it's still going on.
- Oh, yeah. Well...
I was there long enough
not to see any of you.
We didn't want to go that
stupid popularity contest.
And why is that?
Oh, because you couldn't get dates?
Yep, that's exactly what happened.
Football team put us on the blacklist.
We could've gone.
We just preferred to stay here
and have some female bonding.
Hey, Mindy. Nice.
- Shut up.
- David!
Oh, and just so you guys
get it right...
...Candyman ripped off Bloody Mary
in the first place.
Not the other way around.
How long was your brother
outside listening to us?
- Long enough to masturbate.
- Not long at all, then.
David.
So how was it?
Just like yours, I'm sure.
You didn't wake up naked in Tijuana.
Just because there's a dead
Mexican hooker in my room...
...doesn't mean I went to Mexico.
Oh, Bill drank all my lemonade.
David, be nice. You know, and you
could call him "Dad" once in a while.
Never happen.
But I still call you "Mom."
Mom, I need 100 bucks.
Do me a favor.
Go wake up the girls.
All right. Just because you own me,
it doesn't mean I'm your slave.
- Go.
- Yeah.
They're already gone.
She's never done this before.
I mean, this is so unusual for her.
- I have to call Sheriff McKenna.
- Okay.
Yeah, Sheriff McKenna.
It's Bill Owens.
Any word, anything?
We're doing all we can.
You have to understand...
...they're not officially
missing for 24 hours.
- Yeah, but they are missing.
- Hello.
That's it, nothing? All right, well,
you just stay on top of this.
All right, look, when
do we call in the FBI?
Our hands are tied.
We'll do all we can locally.
- officially missing for 24 hours.
But they are missing.
Right this way, sheriff.
- Sheriff. Thanks for coming.
- Hi, Bill.
- I appreciate it.
- No problem.
The mountain gorilla.
An endangered species native
to Central Africa. Mountain gorillas...
...live in groups...
...ruled by a dominant male...
...which determines
the group's daily activities...
...and enforces
a very strict social order.
The silverback.
Do you think Samantha
and her friends are okay?
Yeah.
- and consume 20 times
their weight in food annually.
I just spoke to Sheriff McKenna,
and he's got all his men out searching.
- They're gonna find her.
- Sure, that's easy for you to say.
She's just your stepdaughter.
What...?
Sam.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
They all say the same thing.
They woke up in the basement...
...of the abandoned old mill
on the other side of the state park.
The door was locked.
Well, that's what they said.
What do you mean?
Well, we're gonna check it out.
They don't remember anything.
Other than that, they're fine. Weren't
harmed or mistreated, nothing.
We ran blood tests and found
traces of Rohypnol in their system.
It's a date-rape drug.
You don't have to worry about that.
We ran medical tests.
They were not abused in that way.
So, what do you think?
Well, it could be the girls' idea
of a practical joke.
You know, for attention.
What happened?
What happened? What's wrong?
What's wrong?
What happened to you?
My mom says that it's all a stunt.
That they did it to themselves.
Samantha will write a story
about it for the paper.
Some people have no boundaries.
Some people need to mind
their own fucking business.
The girls are back.
They were in science class.
Took them long enough.
You'd think twins would have
some kind of sixth sense...
...like I'd know what happened to you.
We're fraternal, not identical.
How you holding up?
It was Buck and his friends,
wasn't it?
He told us they just wanted to talk.
You are butt-white.
- Hey, Roger.
- What?
You need to spend some more time
at that tanning salon.
Hey, girls dig it, man.
He doesn't go to that salon
to go tanning.
He goes to hook up with that chick.
- The one with the big tits.
- Oh, yeah.
Buck.
- What's up?
- Come here. Come here, check it out.
What? Oh, yeah.
I know it was you. All of you.
I know it was all of you.
What did your sister...?
We don't know what
you're talking about.
We were at the dance all night.
Ask our dates.
- Get out of here, loser.
- You little punk.
- Yeah. Get out of here.
- Get out of here, man.
- Get lost.
- You're not gonna get away with this.
- Whatever.
- Oh, I'm scared.
- Come on, get out of here.
- That's what I thought.
- Bye-bye.
- See you.
- We got a problem.
- This is not a problem at all.
Those bitches,
they won't say anything.
Yeah. Take Buck's advice.
What did you get
on your SATs, Buck? Seven hundred?
Total.
What's that supposed to mean?
You're such an asshole.
She needs to relax.
See you later, mama's boy.
Shut up. Shut up.
No way. Shut up.
Yeah. Totally. Shut up.
She did not. No way.
Oh, my God. He's here.
I gotta let you go.
Hi, Roger.
Hi, Betsy. I hope it's okay
I just showed up.
Don't worry about it.
I'm, like, the only one here.
I just wanna catch some sun.
Lay on the bed a little bit,
get my groove on.
Then maybe I could get
some of your sunshine.
Okay.
How long do you want it?
Just leave it on low.
I'm gonna relax for a bit.
I'll get out when I'm done.
I'll be ready.
Totally. Like, yeah, I saw it.
He is so hot.
Yeah, totally. Most people go nude.
Totally.
Yeah. Totally.
No. Totally.
Yeah.
Totally.
Shut up.
Help! Betsy!
Yes way. My past.
I could be president.
What time is it?
Oh, shit. Roger!
Oh, shit.
Roger! Roger! Roger!
- Amen.
Peace be with you.
Thank you, Father.
Samantha?
- Hey.
I brought you homework you might
have missed when you were gone.
I saw how Buck was looking
at David at the funeral.
Heather, you know that David had
nothing to do with Roger's accident.
Yeah.
Listen...
...I know that things have
been difficult for us.
It was so much easier
when we were kids.
God, Sam, we were so close.
What happened to us?
It's funny you should say that.
Why?
Because it sounds like it came
from a TV movie, that's why.
Look, what happened to you was
just a little payback prank...
...and I had nothing to do with it.
The guys didn't mean
to go so far...
...but they were pissed off
you published that photo.
Just a prank?
They drugged us,
and who knows what they did to us...
...after they locked us up.
I sure as hell don't.
How hard was it
to crawl out the window?
That's not the point, Heather.
Look, Sam, there's more.
It's...
- This has all happened before.
- What do you mean?
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Make sure and do
your history homework.
I'm sorry.
She brought me my homework.
She felt bad. She was cool about it.
Damn it.
- You sure you don't want a ride?
- No, I'm good. Thanks.
Heather!
Oh, my God!
Unit 14, we have a 174...
What's going on?
What happened?
Sam, what...? Sam, talk to me.
What's going on?
Ashes to ashes...
...and dust to dust.
She was in bed. How could they
be crawling out of her face?
I think it's really sick, though.
They were coming out of her face.
Now, I'm sure you've all noticed the
new security precautions on campus.
Every effort is being made
to keep our students safe.
Now, Principal Rosetti
has asked me to remind everyone...
Samantha, dear.
Is something the matter?
No.
Well, as I was saying...
...students who need to speak to
a counselor should tell their advisor.
So how was school today, honey?
I saw a ghost in science class.
Do you really think
that he did it to himself?
Roger Dalton was dumb...
...but don't you think that he would
wake up before he cooked his ass?
What are you saying?
I'm asking if you really think there's
nothing more to our friends dying.
Heather dropped some acid and
just ripped her face off like a mask?
Of course not.
She didn't even drink,
let alone do drugs.
There's something wrong
in our little town, and it has a name.
- Owens.
- David?
Both of them.
They were there both times.
Jesus, Buck.
Murder?
So, what are we gonna do?
Your dad still have
those emergency gas cans?
Get them.
And meet me behind the park
at midnight.
I don't know about this, Buck.
Come on. Scaring the girls
is one thing, but...
Right.
Okay.
I'll be there in 15.
Holy shit, this guy's dick
is smoking. Hey, McKenna...
...better check your beer bottle tonight.
Did you ever hear the story about
a guy who was drinking a beer...
...and found a finger in the bottle?
Look at this.
Someone cut his ring finger off.
- Wild.
- Will you stop with that crap?
That finger is probably
some coyote's lunch.
Yeah, we got EMTs on the scene.
Worthington High School classes
have been cancelled today.
Another student from that school
was found dead.
Although drunk and driving...
...early reports suggest electrocution
as the cause of death.
Tom Higgins,
a varsity football player...
There's something else
going on here.
Heather left this in my
American history book the other night.
I think someone sent this
to Heather as a warning.
This is the same thing
that happened to you.
Only I'm still alive.
Here.
Read the other one.
"Professor at Alpine University kills
students using urban legends as m.o."
Wait, you think there's
a copycat killer...
...that's killing our friends.
No, I just think that Heather
was trying to tell me something.
I need your help to figure it out.
Well, it's about time you asked.
Mary Banner lived here in Utah.
She went to Worthington High.
It says the other two girls
returned home unharmed.
They should still be alive.
See if you can find it online.
Are you smoking crack? This is
dial-up. Let's use the school database.
- School's closed today.
- I have keys to the newspaper office.
Okay.
Let's just get down there
and finish this.
Wait, wait, go back.
- There.
- Wow, deja vu.
"The two girls,
seniors at Worthington High...
...refused to press charges
against unknown assailants."
Why no names?
Got them. Gina Lotnick, 17, Mary
Banner, 18, and Grace Taylor, 17.
Where are they now?
Oh, that's from '82.
"Local resident Gina Lotnick
died this morning...
...of a self-inflicted gunshot wound.
Miss Lotnick was one of the victims in
the homecoming kidnapping in 1969...
...of which there are no suspects.
Mary Banner, another victim, was
never found and presumed dead."
- Who was the other girl?
- Grace Taylor.
"The only remaining survivor
of that fateful night is Grace Taylor."
Hey, got it. It's not that far
from our house.