MONSTER: It is with considerable difficulty
that I remember the original era of my being.
Ail of the events of that period
appear confused and indistinct.
A strange multiplicity
of sensations seized me.
And I saw, felt, heard
and smelled at the same time.
And it was indeed a long time
before I learned to distinguish
between the operations
of my various senses.
I remember a stronger light
pressed upon my nerves
so that I was obliged to shut my eyes.
Darkness then came over me
and troubled me.
But hardly had I felt this when
by opening my eyes as I now supposed
the light poured in upon me again.
-(GASPING)
-(INSTRUMENTS BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
Okay. Hold on.
(GASPING)
(BEEPING STOPS)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(MUTTERING)
So beautiful.
You're a miracle.
(DOOR OPENS)
You're so beautiful.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
It's okay. Don't be scared.
I don't think you can see.
Unless it's very close,
it takes a newborn days to master that.
He's alive.
- He's conscious. He's conscious.
-(MONSTER WHIMPERING)
- Could this be muscle spasms?
- No, no.
Look at the way he looks at me, Victor.
- Look at the way he looks at me.
-(GULPING)
He needs water.
I'm going to get you a drink of water, yep.
Open.Ah...
-(COUGHING)
- Oh! (GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Such trauma.
(ELIZABETH SCREAMING)
(cousmus)
ELIZABETH: Get him up! Get him up!
- He's alive!
-(LAUGHING)
He's alive!
- Shh!
(MONSTER MUMBLING)
It's okay.
Shh...
What?
Let me try him.
Try. Here. (SHUSHING)
Be careful. Careful.
Trusting that he has the reflex of a newborn.
Yeah.
- Will you look at that.
- Wow!
Okay.
- Very strong.
-(MONSTER MUMBLING)
(CHUCKLING) He's very strong.
Okay.
- We're not going to hurt you.
- Here we go.
I can't...
-it's amazing. He won't let me.
- ELIZABETH: Okay.
Okay. (GRUNTING)
Hey, get up.
- Okay, okay.
- VICTOR: This is it.
Treat him like a mama. Like a mama.
- Yeah. Yeah.
-(SUCKLING)
ELIZABETH: Okay, you can do it.
Here we go.
(LAUGHING)
Good, good. Yeah.
Yeah.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
VICTOR: Oh, my God.
(LAUGHING)
Oh! Oh.
(WHEELS RATTLING)
DR. MARCUS: Yes, I know the mechanics.
That doesn't explain how you finally did it.
VICTOR: I don't know, Dr. Marcus.
Quite honestly, I'm quite overwhelmed
by the immensity of it all.
- Oh, come on, Victor. Don't be so coy.
- I'm not being coy.
I want to know what the breakthrough was.
Well, it must have been something
quite wonderful. Brilliant.
- But this is something far too important...
- VICTOR: Simple.
...for you not to share
with the whole team, Victor.
Now, I already noticed
that some applications are out of control.
And what I was thinking was that maybe...
VICTOR: So what?
It just means he'll heal faster.
DR. MARCUS: Not necessarily.
Uncontrolled cell division...
VICTOR: I'm not interested in your analysis.
He's going to be healthier, stronger,
far, far more resilient.
Okay.
(MONSTER SCREAMING)
VICTOR: Administer the sedative.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(GASPING AND SOBBING)
Yes.
(GRUNTS)
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
- ELIZABETH: Oh!
-(MUMBLING SLEEPILY)
Look at you.
Well.
It's okay.
(CHUCKLES)
There you go. Good.
Yeah?
That's good.
Very good.
Okay, so...
Mmm.Yum, yum.
Okay?
Open your mouth.
Like this. Ah...
Ah...
- Ah.
- Now.
Ah.
ELIZABETH: Okay.
Ah... Mmm.
Yum, yum.
Okay?
Ready? Ah...
Ah...
Good. That's it.
(SPITTING)
(WHIMPERING)
Okay.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you like that? You want it?
- Why don't you have that?
-(WHIMPERING)
Mama.
Mom.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
DR. MARCUS: Peekaboo.
Good.
And back.
Brilliant.
- Whoa!
- Oh! (CHUCKLING)
-(GASPS)
-(CHUCKLES)
- Good boy.
- That's a good catch.
- Oh! (GROANS)
-(LAUGHING)
- Fuck!
- DR. MARCUS: Here. You okay?
Yes.
It's okay. You didn't hurt me.
It's fine. It's okay.
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Okay. You can let go now.
(CHUCKLING) You can let go. Let go.
Let go. Good boy. Good boy.
(DR. MARCUS SIGHING)
Yeah, I can see that, too.
We're going to have to do a biopsy.
(MONSTER GRUNTING)
ELIZABETH: Okay.
Okay.
Ready?
That's it. That's it.
(MONSTER WHIMPERING)
I got it.
Yeah. Good.
Good. Good.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
(BEEPING)
Oh, no.
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
(GRUNTING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GROWLING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(BEEPING SLOWS DOWN)
I don't want to talk about it right now.
ELIZABETH: I'm sorry.
VICTOR: This is not what I intended.
He can hear you.
- He doesn't understand.
- Yes, he does.
Mom.
ELIZABETH: Look.
Dad.
They're just sounds. Crude sounds.
Babies make them
and we ascribe meaning into them.
ELIZABETH: Don't kid yourself.
- Dad.
-ELIZABETH: Don't justify.
He's a conscious entity.
We can't just put him down.
VICTOR: If we accept that he is conscious,
then the concept of
prolonging his agony is unacceptable.
We can't...
I can't have anything to do with this.
I can't. It's...
It'd be murder. I can't do it. I can't.
Murder?
Murder.
What was that?
He was never born. He does not exist.
Look at him, Victor.
Murder.
(ELIZABETH SHUSHING)
(MONSTER MOANS)
Do you think that he's in pain, Victor?
(CHUCKLES)
I don't know.
ELIZABETH: Are you in pain?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ELIZABETH GRUNTS)
(DOOR OPENING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
-(ELEVATOR WHIRRING)
-(GASPS)
Okay.
It's okay. You're going to go home now.
I can't find a goddamn vein.
The pain is going to go away.
(HUMMING)
- Come on, Dr. Marcus.
- Wait a second.
Now then, what have we got here?
- That's all right. Leave it.
- DR. MARCUS: All right.
ELIZABETH: You're doing really good.
Okay.
-(YELPING)
- ELIZABETH: It's okay. It's okay.
(SHUSHING) Did you get it?
DR. MARCUS: No, not yet.
- Now.
- ELIZABETH: Okay.
Come on, Dr. Marcus.
(MONSTER WHIMPERING)
- She is gonna fit.
- ELIZABETH: That's it.
- You did it.
- VICTOR: Okay.
You did it. This is good medicine.
Good. Good.
- Good.
- ELIZABETH: Rest, baby.
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
- Close your eyes. Just go to sleep.
- VICTOR: Start it.
ELIZABETH: Close your eyes.
-(BEEPING)
-(ELIZABETH SHUSHING)
(GASPING)
That's good medicine.
Just relax and go to sleep.
Go to sleep.
VICTOR: Very good.
And go.
U-ussnue)
(VICTOR EXHALES)
(sums)
You ready?
Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
- VICTOR: Go.
- One, two, three, four, five.
-(HISSING CONTINUES)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SHUDDERING)
- Oh, my God.
- I'll do the rest. Hang on.
ELIZABETH: Okay. Okay. Please!
DR. MARCUS: Clear out.
(SCREAMING)
(ELIZABETH GRUNTS)
ELIZABETH: Oh, my God.
(YELLING)
Okay.
ELIZABETH: (SOBBING) Please, stop.
-(SCREAMING)
- Stop! Do something!
DR. MARCUS: I'm trying.
(BANGING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Yeah, fine.
(GASPING)
DR. MARCUS: Wait, wait.
VICTOR: Wait.
That's it.
(SCREAMING)
(VICTOR GRUNTING)
(MONSTER CHOKING)
(EXHALES)
VICTOR: You checked his pulse?
DR. MARCUS: Yeah, he's good.
(WHEELS RATTLING)
DR. PRETORIOUS: Oh.
See? Victor fucked up.
I'll say.
DR. MARCUS: Yeah. You can see
the cell replication issues.
And I think the circuitry issues as well.
Maybe next time he'll listen.
DR. MARCUS: I want you there more.
Seriously.
You know I want to be there.
DR. MARCUS: Here we go. All right.
DR. PRETORIOUS: Hold on a second.
You got him?
(GRUNTING)
Hey, give me a scalpel.
There's something wonderful going on.
These eyes, look at them.
Each one took six months to print.
Billions of microlayers.
I'm keeping these. Give me the scalpel.
DR. PRETORIOUS: Scalpel.
(STAMMERS)
DR. PRETORIOUS: Wait, wait, wait.
Let me section the cranium.
That way you'll have
easier access to the eyeballs.
Good idea. Yes.
(SAW WHIRRING)
(DR. MARCUS GROANING)
(CHOKING)
DR. PRETORIOUS: Get the fuck off him!
Fuck off!
(MUMBLES)
(EXHALES)
Okay. All right.
No, no. That's dangerous.
- That's... It's not a toy.
-(SAW WHIRRING)
No, no, no.
No, no, no. Put it down. Put that down.
Put it down.
(MONSTER LAUGHS)
No, no. You don't want to do this.
No. I'm a doctor. I can help you. Trust me.
No, no. Stop! Help!
(SCREAMING)
Stop! Stop!
(MOANING)
(MUMBLES)
You...
You are magnificent.
You have the strength of 10 men.
You are the future, my child.
You're the future.
- Hmm?
-(CHUCKLING)
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Ah...
MAN: (ON PA) Dr. Marcus,
please report to Level 5 security. Thank you.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(MUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALARM BLARING)
GUARD: Hey!
Hey, you! Stop!
What the fuck is that?
Hey, stop! I said stop!
- Stop! You! Get down!
-(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
Get down! Get down!
Lie down! Lie down!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(BONES CRACKING)
Down.
Get down.
(GASPING)
(CHUCKLING)
-(GUN FIRING)
-(GASPING)
-(BULLETS RICOCHETING)
God damn it!
-(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
-(GASPING)
(ELEVATOR WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
GUARD: Hey, stop!
(suns FIRING)
(PANTING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(nos BARKING)
(PANTING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(GASPING)
MONSTER: Here! lay, resting from my fatigue.
Until I felt tormented by hunger and thirst.
This roused me
from my nearly dormant state.
I staked my thirst at the brook.
And then, lying down,
was overcome by sleep.
(OWL HOOTING)
It was dark when I awoke.
felt cold also.
And half frightened, as it were,
instinctively, finding myself so desolate.
I was a poor, helpless, miserable wretch.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
I began to distinguish my sensations
from each other.
I gradually saw plainly
the clear stream that supplied me with drink.
And the trees,
they shaded me with their foliage.
(RODENT SQUEAKING)
I began also to observe with greater
accuracy the forms that surrounded me.
And to perceive the boundaries
of the radiant roof of the light
which canopied me.
(TRAIN PASSING)
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(PANTING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(GASPING)
(BARKING)
-(EXHALES SHARPLY)
-(DOG GROWLING)
(wmmwc)
(PANTING)
(CHUCKLING)
(nos WHINES)
One day, when I was pressed by cold
I found a fire
which had been left by someone.
I was overcome with delight
at the warmth I experienced from it.
In my joy, [thrust my hand
into the live embers,
but quickly drew it out again
with a cry of pain.
How strange, I thought.
That the same cause
should produce such opposite effects.
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
Hey, Tom. You see that?
Oh, yeah. Oh.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
MOLLY: Come back.
Puppy, come here.
Down, boy.
Is this your dog, mister?
Can I pet him?
What's his name?
Are you hurt?
You should see a doctor.
Will you play sticks with me?
(nos PANTING)
Come on.
Puppy's so cute.
Do you know how to play?
Now grab your stick and throw it in
when I count to three.
One, two, three.
See, I win. Again.
Okay, throw it in.
Grab your stick and throw.
(GASPS) No.
(SCREAMS)
-(LAUGHING)
-(GIRL SCREAMING)
Help!
- Help!
-(DOG BARKING)
WOMAN: Just jump in there! Go get her!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
-(GIRL COUGHING)
-(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
OFFICER: (ON MEGAPHONE)
Get out of the water. Get out of the water now.
WOMAN: Hey, Officer. We saw it.
He throw her in there.
He's trying to drown her.
OFFICER: Sir, put the girl down.
Sir, I said put the girl down.
Stop right there and put the girl down, sir.
I'm not going to ask again.
- Hold it. Hold it, sir.
- Put the girl down.
- Sir!
- Step away with your hands up.
- Sir, is this your dog?
-(DOG BARKING)
Hang on. Hold.
- Sir, is this your dog? Call your dog.
-(BARKING CONTINUES)
Sir. Sir, control your dog.
Control your dog!
-(GUN FIRING)
400s YELPS)
POLICEMAN 1: All right,
let's take him in, okay.
(WHIMPERING)
POLICEMAN 2: Sir,
you're going to need to turn around
and put your hands behind your back.
- Easy does it. It's okay. That's it, that's it.
- POLICEMAN 1: Nice and easy.
- Nice and easy.
- Nice and calm. Here we go. Here we go.
(GRUNTING)
Jesus. Get off him.
(YELLING)
MOLLY: Stop it. You're hurting him.
POLICEMAN 2: Jesus, help me.
Mom, help me.
Mom.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mom. Mom.
(MONSTER WHIMPERING)
WOMAN: Come get it!
MAN: Fuck you!
WOMAN: Kill the guy.
MAN: Yeah.
(YELLING)
(MONSTER GROWLING)
WOMAN: Fucking monster!
You're a fucking monster!
(ENGINE RUNNING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
JOHNSON: Who are you?
L---
You must have a name.
Name.
RUBIN: Name. What's your name?
He seems to have
the mental capacity of a one-year-old.
Name.
RUBIN: What's your name?
(STAMMERS)
Monster.
Monster?
Your mom and dad call you monster?
Who is your mom?
We found this on you. Is this your mom?
E -Mom! - a sy... Hey, hey' hey
Okay.
MONSTER: Mom!
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Mmm.
(DOOR OPENS)
Mom!
Mom. Mom.
What's wrong with him?
Mom!
We'd rather hoped you'd tell us that.
I'm sorry. I'm not a medical doctor.
I'm a research scientist.
RUBIN: You've never seen this man before.
MONSTER: Mom! Mom! Mom!
It would be very hard to forget him.
Mom! Mom! Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Seriously, shut the fuck up.
Mom! Mom. Mom.
(WAILING)
LINCOLN: It's a fucking shame.
BANKS: Yeah, man.
Bob just bought a house in Calabasas.
LINCOLN: No shit.
Yo, what happens to the mortgage
in this kind of situation?
They give her
some sort of bereavement pay, right?
(SCOFFS) Yeah.
That ain't fucking shit, dude.
They act like they give a fuck about us.
They don't give a fuck.
You listening to this?
- Fucking animal.
-(GROANS)
Oh... Does that hurt?
You fucking piece of shit!
Fuck you, animal!
LINCOLN: Yo, take it easy, Lenny.
BANKS: Fuck off, man.
You know Bob's face
was completely fucking smashed in?
Nothing left, man.
His fucking missus had to go down there
and identify that.
What the fuck is wrong with this thing?
A fucking freak show.
LINCOLN: He's a fucking Mongoloid, man.
He's a freakin' Elephant Man.
But he doesn't know what's going on.
Fuck you!
God damn it. Would you relax?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Just take a fucking breath.
Just calm down. It's all...
Everything's gonna be all right.
All right.
Let's just get this done.
(TRAIN PASSING)
(GRUNTING)
LINCOLN: He's a heavy motherfucker.
BANKS: Put him on his knees.
LINCOLN: Why?
BANKS: I want him to see what's coming.
LINCOLN: Now, come on. Get up. Get up.
(GRUNTING)
Fuck you, you fucking scumbag.
Fuck you! Deserve to die.
Die.
BANKS: What'd you say? You want to die?
- Die.
- BANKS: You want to fucking die.
(CHUCKLING)
Shut the fuck up.
LINCOLN: Come here. Come on.
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Mom. Mom. Mom.
Mom? What the fuck are you saying?
Mom.
BANKS: (MOCKINGLY)
You want your mommy.
Oh.
Is that your mommy?
Is that your mommy? Is that what you want?
Here you go. Here you go.
There's your mommy. There's your mommy.
-(GUN COCKING)
- Fuck you, motherfucker.
(sun FIRING)
(MONSTER GRUNTS)
(STONES RATTLING)
(TRAIN PASSING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(HORN BLARING)
WOMAN: You wanna go out?
Do you wanna go out, honey?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
That's fucked up.
(SIREN WAILING)
(TRAIN PASSING)
(GUITAR BEING PLAYED)
EDDIE: (SINGING) Everything, everything
Everything gonna be all right
This morning
When I was a young boy
About the age of five
My mama told me
I was gonna be the greatest man alive
I guess I am
A child
That represents man
NoB
0 Child
(EDDIE VOCALIZING)
I need my soul
(TRAIN PASSING)
(YELLING)
(GASPS)
-(EDDIE EXCLAIMS)
-(GASPS)
(STRUMS)
Who that?
What's your name?
Huh?
Welcome, friend.
My name is Eddie.
- Eddie.
- Eddie Child.
Monster.
Well, it's nice to meet you there, Monster.
Yeah. Are you a friend?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hey, what is this? Oh, I see.
They done fitted you for one of them suits
down at the funny farm, huh?
-(LAUGHING)
- Help. Mom. Jesus.
No, no, no. Hey now.
I ain't none of those, okay?
I mean, it seems like I've been fitted for
one of those suits once or twice in my life.
Yeah.
Huh?
Free at last.
You new in town?
Huh?
You new to town?
Ah...Ah...
You can't talk.
Huh?
Oh, yo, I see. You can't... You can't talk.
Well, I can't see.
It don't matter.
It seemed to me that you needed a friend.
Friend.
You're a friend to me, my brother.
Yeah.
(PLAYING GUITAR)
(SINGING) A child
.
That means maker
No B-O child
(MONSTER MOANING)
Y
That represent mannish boy
(VOCALIZING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
MONSTER: I led a miserable life
in the strange place where I found myself.
Endeavoring to cure the wound
which I'd received.
A bullet had entered my head
and I knew not whether it had
remained there or passed through.
At any rate, I had no means of extracting it.
Monster. Monster.
Hey, hey. Is this red?
- Red.
- Red. It's yours.
Try it on.
Here we go.
Hey, hey, hey. Be careful. Be careful.
Okay, put it on.
Okay? Yeah. Huh?
You're not going to
scare away any customers, huh?
Yeah, a coat.
MONSTER: Coat.
Ah!
Shoes.
(GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING)
Music good, huh? Awesome.
(SINGING) I love the life
I love waking up
and smelling what I can't see
I can't see
How you feel about me?
I smell some perfume
so you must be going home soon
Let me know
when something pretty comes by.
Let me know when them tourists come by.
...in my mouth is ringing right back there
(INDISTINCT MUMBLING)
'Cause it's no joke to be a joke
Watch out for the scallywags.
Scallywags.
Scallywag.
Okay, are we okay?
I smell something. I smell something.
MONSTER: I improved rapidly
in the knowledge of language.
So that in a short while,
I began to comprehend most of the words
uttered by my protector.
Okay.
Check it, check, it, check it.
I smell a dumpster.
(SNIFFING)
I smell a dumpster. Food. Food.
I smell a dumpster.
(CHAINS RATTLING)
I smell it. I smell it.
Okay. Sometimes the restaurants, see,
they put out their leftovers and their waste.
- Dumpster.
- Dumpster. Dumpster.
Dumpster.
(FLIES BUZZING)
(SNIFFS)
Yeah. Get anything good?
Huh?
Anything good?
Look for a box of food.
What? Anything good? Huh?
What the fuck is that? What the fuck is that?
No. No. No. It's not good.
It's bad. It's very fucking bad.
-(PLUCKING GUITAR STRINGS)
- One more. Yeah, vibrate good. Come on.
(PLUCKING STRINGS)
Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
Ah!
Mmm.
(GRUNTS)
Now this is good.
- That's good.
- Good.
Good. (CHUCKLES)
(SPITTING)
(GRUNTING)
- MONSTER: Bad.
- You are the craziest motherfucker.
- Very fucking bad.
- Huh?
Hey, You smoke?
Smoke.
(GASPS)
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
It's a lighter for fire.
-(GASPS)
- Careful. Careful.
Fire.
(BURPS)
When I could see... (CHUCKLES)
I used to be...
I used to be, I used to be kind.
(INHALES)
And then I was blind.
Sleep.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(MAN CHUCKLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GRUNTING)
You want to go, motherfucker?
- You want to break, bitch?
-(GRUNTS)
MAN: That boy's fucked up.
- Oh, friend, friend.
-(WOMAN SHOUTING)
DISPATCH: (ON RADIO) I have available cars
near 219 to transfer to Highland.
(SIREN WAILING)
How's his state?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
PARAMEDIC: Stick an IV on him.
Yeah.
All right, what the fuck's going on here?
Looks like they were flung right across.
These aren't choirboys. Let's go.
MONSTER: The strange system
of human society was explained to me.
I saw the division of property.
of immense wealth and squalid poverty,
of rank, descent, and noble blood.
Hey, Monster.
MONSTER: A man might be respected
with only one of these advantages.
I hope you're checking out them ladies.
MONSTER: But without either, he was
considered as a Vagabond and a slave,
doomed to waste his powers
for the profits of the chosen few.
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
And what was I?
of my creation and creator,
I was absolutely ignorant.
But! knew that! possessed no money,
no friends, no kind of property.
I was, besides, endued with a figure
hideously deformed and loathsome.
WANDA: Hey, Eddie.
EDDIE: Hey, Wanda, Wanda, Wanda.
MONSTER: Was I then a monster?
A blot upon the Earth?
EDDIE: Hey, hey, hey. Monster? Monster?
Tell me the truth.
Is Wanda as fine as she sounds
or is she butt ugly like a dog?
WANDA: He's fucking with you.
We're old friends.
EDDIE: Yeah, but I ain't never had nobody
to ask before.
Monster, tell me the truth, Monster.
Is she pretty?
Huh?
MONSTER: Pretty.
EDDIE: Hey.
Hey, your friend has good taste, Eddie.
EDDIE: Yeah, but is she prettier
than that girl across the street?
-(FOOTSTEPS)
- Huh?
How do you know
there is a girl crossing the street, Eddie?
EDDIE: 'Cause I can hear her heels
clickety, click, click, click.
You know I'm prettier.
She's a nasty ass bitch.
Prettier.
- Prettier.
- Yeah.
I'm teaching him how to talk.
But he can't talk much. He's learning.
Really?
What's your name?
Monster.
WANDA: Monster? Why are you hiding
in that hoodie?
(WANDA CHUCKLES)
He's shy. I've seen some
scary-looking creeps around here.
You can't look worse than that.
Come on.
EDDIE: Oh, yeah, he does.
He certainly does.
(GUITAR PLAYING)
Honey...
Are you sick?
Is he contagious?
No, no, it ain't catching.
I've been hanging around him long enough.
Were you born that way?
Born?
Yeah. You know, when you were a baby.
Baby.
You know, like,
goo-goo, mama, itty-bitty baby shit.
- Mom?
- Yeah.
Monster, do you know
where babies come from?
Does he know anything?
He does. He does.
Monster.
Have you seen this shit before?
That's fucking.
Well, that's how babies are made.
MONSTER: All my past life was now a blot,
a blind vacancy
in which I distinguished nothing.
From my earliest remembrance
I had been as I then was
in height and proportion.
I don't think he's ever been with a woman.
Okay, well, I ain't giving no mercy fuck.
I mean, he's sweet and all
but he's got some serious problems.
MONSTER: What did this mean?
Who was I? What was I?
You don't have that kind of money, Eddie.
MONSTER: Whence did I come?
What was my destination?
Monster, is that shit all over your body?
When did you last take a bath?
Wanda, Wanda, all you got to do is take him
to a room and scrub him down.
WANDA: A room?
You got money for that, too?
- I'll tell you what. I've got $100.
-(WANDA SCOFFS)
And that includes room and everything.
Thank you.
EDDIE: All right.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
WANDA: Don't forget. Yeah.
EDDIE: Here you go.
Don't you worry about a thing, okay?
Wanda's going to walk you
through the ropes, up and down.
-It's all right. Monster.
- Come on.
Come on.
EDDIE: Take him by the hand, into the water.
WANDA: There you go.
EDDIE: Take him to the water.
Whoa!
What color dress you got there, Monster?
(CHUCKLING)
MONSTER: Red.
Monster, have fun.
(DOOR CLOSES)
What's this?
- Pretty.
- Yeah, she is.
Ugly.
You are. Yeah.
What?
Fucking.
Oh, honey, I'll fuck you.
Oh, you want to fuck her?
- Yes.
-(EXHALES)
Well, she ain't here and I am.
Well, she ain't putting out and I am,
so what do you say?
(MUTTERING)
Do you love her?
- Love?
- Yeah.
Like, do you think about her all the time?
You know, dream about her?
Dream.
Like, pictures in your head?
Like this. See?
Pictures in your head when you sleep.
Dream.
- Dream.
- Yeah.
(sum-nus)
Love.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
You're so sweet, Monster.
(LAUGHS)
Do you want me to Google her?
Is that her?
You know her?
(MONSTER BREATHING HEAVILY)
(sums)
Okay. No, no, no. Okay.
You are sweet and all,
but you really, really got to take a shower
before we can do anything, okay?
(MONSTER STOMPING)
Come on.
My...
Eddie doesn't know, does he?
He can't see how bad it is.
Bad.
Sorry, honey...
But I can't.
I knew you were a bum,
but I thought you were a man.
You don't even look human.
Love.
I will personally cover the hotel room.
I'll refund the money, okay?
Love.
Get the fuck off me! Stay away from me!
Get... Stop. Stop!
Get the fuck off me! Get the fuck off me!
(SCREAMING)
No!
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
-(SCREAMING)
-(BONES CRACKING)
(SOBBING)
No. No. No.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
EDDIE: What's going on in there?
Lay it off!
Hey, Wanda, are you all right?
- What's the problem?
-(NECK CRACKS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Monster?
Monster!
Hey, yo!
(BANGING CONTINUES)
Open up the damn door!
Damn it!
Wanda?
What's happening, huh?
Monster, how come
you didn't open the door?
(WHIMPERING)
I hear you. I hear you.
Wanda?
Eddie. Eddie.
EDDIE: What did you do?
Move. Move.
Are you fucking nuts?
You weren't supposed to do that to her.
(SOBBING)
- You weren't supposed to hurt her!
-(SCREAMS)
You weren't supposed to hurt her.
Mannish boy!
Are you a man or are you an animal?
You fucking animal!
(YELLING)
(BONE CRACKS)
MONSTER: Eddie.
- Eddie. Love.
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(GASPING)
(SOBBING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(SCREAMING) Eddie!
(SOBBING) Eddie!
Eddie!
Once I falsely hoped to meet with beings
who, pardoning my outward form,
would love me for the qualities in my heart.
I cannot believe that I'm the same creature
whose thoughts were once
filled with beauty and love.
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Starting route
to 26800 Mulholland Highway.
Tum left onto West 7th Street.
Hey!
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: In 400 feet,
turn left onto South Broadway.
Keep right to merge onto CA 110 North.
(BEEPING)
BANKS: Hey, you can't walk here. Stop.
(SIREN WAILS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
- Stop. Stop right there.
- AUTOMATED VOICE: In 500 feet,
keep right to merge onto CA 110 North.
BANKS: Stop. You can't walk here.
Stop right there.
Sir, stop! I said stop.
Stop.
(sun FIRING)
(SCREAMING)
-(GUN FIRING)
-(GROANS)
What the fuck?
(BANKS CHUCKLES)
How the fuck? What the fuck?
(LAUGHING)
Fuck you!
Fuck you, freak show! Fuck yourself!
Shoot! You don't even
have the balls to shoot me.
Shoot me!
(LAUGHING)
(sun FIRING)
MONSTER: The fallen angel
becomes a malignant devil.
Yet even that enemy of God and man had
friends and associates in his desolation.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Proceed to the route.
MONSTER: lam alone.
AUTOMATED VOICE: In 9.8 miles, keep right
to merge onto US 101 North
towards Ventura.
MONSTER: [will revenge my injuries.
If I cannot inspire love,
will cause fear.
AUTOMATED VOICE: In 19.6 miles,
take exit 32 onto Las Virgenes Road.
(TRAIN PASSING)
You have reached your destination.
(MONSTER GASPS)
(ELIZABETH HUMMING SOFTLY)
VICTOR: I don't know
what's wrong with that guy.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(VICTOR CHUCKLING)
Sit on the bed.
Now here comes Dr. Feelgood.
(ELIZABETH LAUGHING)
VICTOR: I love you so much.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SLOW FOOTSTEPS)
Oh, what's happened?
Don't hurt him.
VICTOR: No!
No! No!
(GRUNTING)
- Let him go. Let him go.
- MONSTER: Mine!
Why?
(GASPING)
(cousmus)
You said you did not know me.
I ugly-
VICTOR: Stop!
- No.
- VICTOR: Stop. Leave her.
ELIZABETH: No.
It's okay.
It's okay, Adam.
I'm sorry.
- Adam?
- ELIZABETH: Yes.
Your name is Adam.
(ELEVATOR WHIRRING)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
See? That's how we made you.
- And we'll make you again.
- No.
Oh, no, yes.
Yes.
And this time you'll be beautiful.
Beautiful.
Oh.
You make me
ugW-
Why?
I don't know. It was a mistake.
The cells didn't replicate correctly,
and God only knows
what turned you into such a vicious beast.
ELIZABETH: Victor.
He is not me.
Not me.
He is...
Other.
- He is exactly like you.
- No.
I am
I-
Yes.
And you will be you again.
My boy, I understand your unhappiness.
I understand your pain.
And I can make it go away.
You will close your eyes and you will sleep.
And when you wake up,
you'll be just fine.
He is dead?
He's nothing but clay.
But we can all breathe life into him.
You see, that is the secret
that God is so jealous of.
The formula for life.
And I, me, Dr. Frankenstein,
discovered it,
and I will do it again.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
MONSTER: No!
I am!
(PANTING)
lam.
I am.
I am. I am.
You.
You made me.
You hate me.
No.
I'm alone.
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
I'll decapitate him
and then incinerate his head.
- Get off.
- No.
- Move.
- I can't.
Don't be ridiculous.
(ELIZABETH GRUNTS)
(GURGLING)
(YELLING)
(GROANS)
No. Oh.
Oh, my God. Oh, no.
(MOANS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(VICTOR SOBS)
(ELEVATOR WHIRRING)
MONSTER: I shall collect my funeral pile
and consume to ashes this miserable frame.
That its remains may afford no light
to any curious and unhallowed wretch
who would create such another
as I have been.
She is dead, who called me into being.
When I shall be no more,
the very remembrance of us both
will speedily vanish.
will no longer see the sun nor stars,
or feel the winds play upon my cheeks.
I shall ascend my funeral pile triumphantly
and exalt in the agony
of the torturing flames.
The light of that conflagration
will fade away.
My ashes will be swept into the sea
by the winds.
My spirit will sleep in peace.
Or if it thinks, it will not surely think thus.
Farewell.
lam Adam!