Come on, Louis. Come on.
They should make heroin
look like something else.
Candy bars, maybe.
You're gonna have to hurry, Louis.
l'm gonna miss my plane.
Be careful, Lisa.
You too, Louis.
Taxi!
Air Canada...
...flight 7 60 dC-9 jetliner service...
...for New York's Kennedy
International Airport.
Hey, is this St. Luke's Place?
-You, number 98.
-Who, me?
-Where's St. Luke's Place?
-l don't know nothing. l'm a dropout.
l asked you a question, kid.
-Yeah, this is it.
-Thanks.
Big man on campus.
What did she say?
l told you, she just left a message.
-But she asked for me?
-That's right.
-Happy days are here again, huh?
-Well, we'll see.
-You sure this is right?
-Read it yourself.
Don't make waves.
l only asked a question.
Lisa?
-Lisa?
-What are you calling for?
She says she's not here.
-Lisa doesn't live here.
-Yeah, l know. lt's clean.
What's the matter?
Since when can Lisa type?
Since never. Come on.
You think the place is bugged?
-You want something?
-You, Mr. Talman.
And you too, Sgt. Carlino.
l want you too.
ln fact, l want both of you,
and l've come here to buy you.
Sgt. Carlino, if you'd
just shut that door, please.
Don't call me "sergeant."
Why? Are you a touchy man?
-Just don't call me "sergeant."
-No matter. Sit. Sit.
We'll have a little chat.
-We'll start with, who are you?
-l'm Harry Roat Jr. From Scarsdale.
Scarsdale?
Well, now, may we have
weapons on the table?
We'll have explanations first.
Well, this goes back a little.
-So go back a little.
-Alrighty.
Once upon a time...
...there was a fairy princess
named Lisa.
And she had two very good friends,
who shall remain nameless.
Now, these three were fond of performing
little dramas for select audiences.
Their most memorable performances
were that of outraged husband...
...and detective breaking in upon
guilty wife in the arms of her lover...
...or vice versa.
They were adaptable.
The detective, it's worth mentioning, was
particularly convincing in his performance...
...but then he had had the benefit
of previous on-the-job training.
-Man, you're a charmer.
-Thank you.
Things went trippingly
for our three heroes...
...until one day, a certain stockbroker,
a Charles F. Parker, wasn't it? Got nasty.
And then our poor heroes went to jail,
or two of them did.
Lisa, well....
Well, she....
She escaped.
What's the point?
Lisa would like to do something
for her two friends...
...now that they're back
in circulation again.
-What does she want?
-A doll...
...for which she will pay handsomely.
Now may we have weapons on the table?
-l'm clean.
-Scout's honor?
Lisa says you favor brass, sergeant.
That pocket looks a little lumpy.
l cannot negotiate in an atmosphere
of mistrust.
Why, you?
-And, you, what's your favorite toy?
-Geraldine.
What does she do?
-May we have Geraldine on the table too?
-No, we may not.
-Why the hell not?
-Because she's the referee.
Now, Lisa will pay you $2000 each
for a couple hours work.
lnterested?
What kind of work?
Finding Lisa's doll.
-Are you serious?
-l am.
-What kind of doll?
-An ordinary doll, a child's doll.
What's in it?
-Do we hurt anybody?
-Not a fly.
-Do you care?
-No.
-What do you think?
-What's to think? He's a creep.
Yeah, baby. Not like us, huh?
We want an advance.
250. Each.
Lisa and l thought more like 500 each.
Why so generous?
So you don't ask what's in the doll.
So now we know what's in the doll.
Well, win one, lose one.
lt's all straight.
What do we do?
What you always do, Mr. Talman,
lie and cheat and play-act.
-Go on.
-Lisa gave the doll to a man named Hendrix.
She met him on the plane from Montreal.
Lisa's friendly.
Why?
Somebody waiting for her,
she hadn't expected...
...so Hendrix brought it home here.
Hendrix? Who's he?
He's...nobody.
Mr. Clean. A photographer.
Looks like he has a wife. Where's she?
Out.
She goes to school.
Come on. This is a hell of a place
to be talking.
Don't panic, sergeant.
-Why not?
-Because it's arranged. lt's all arranged.
By you?
Photographer Hendrix is in his studio
waiting to photograph a certain Miss Lejiana.
But a little while ago,
her male secretary phoned...
...very efficient, very humble,
grovelingly polite...
...to say that she had been delayed.
-He's terrific.
-Last night, Lisa called up about the doll...
...but Mr. Hendrix couldn't find it.
He looked all over for it,
but he couldn't find it.
Doesn't that strike you odd?
lt strikes me odd too, Mr. Talman.
-Was he lying?
-l don't know, but we're gonna find out.
Now, look around.
Familiarize yourself with the place.
We're coming back here tomorrow.
And the doll is here, you're sure?
Lisa and l checked earlier.
We didn't see it. lt's here, though.
Did you look in here?
Well, anyway, we don't work safes.
l know, but you talk, and that's why
you've been invited to this party...
...to talk your way into that big,
black safe, sergeant.
-There's a locked closet in the bedroom.
-Not there. Just clothes.
-How do you know?
-l looked.
-You got the key?
-lt's on the ledge above the door.
No, it isn't.
They must have taken it with them.
Lock the closet when they
don't bolt the front door?
They're strange people.
They lose dolls.
l think you just made a mistake.
l'd like the key.
Well, if you--
All right, fat man, over there.
Both of you through the door, backwards.
lf you'd only said please.
And now l'd like the key.
Please?
Go look.
Well, she was trespassing, Mike...
...poaching...
...going into business for herself.
Bad news.
Things like that go on,
what do you have?
Anarchy.
No discipline, no sense of order.
Bad news.
Out!
-Haven't you forgotten something?
-We just earned the money.
l mean fingerprints.
You just signed your names
all over this place.
Even if you could remember, it'd
still take you hours to wipe them up.
lf not days.
As for me...
...well, l've only touched one thing
since l've been in here.
And now it's clean...
...like me. No police record,
no known associations with Lisa.
Nothing, in fact.
l could let you go and what would happen?
l'd evaporate.
But you? Bad news.
Don't forget this, sarge.
And the icebox, don't forget the icebox.
Carlino, knock it off!
We can prove where we were
when this happened.
Oh, and when did it happen?
-Just before you let me in?
-So?
So if you do exactly what l tell you...
...there will be no police,
there will be no problems.
Go on.
First, get her out of here.
Roll her up in this.
l got a van by the corner.
l'll bring it out front.
Why not the back, where
there's less publicity?
There's no back door.
We'll dump her where l found this.
Give me a hand.
-She'll be found.
-l hope so.
All she's got on her is a hotel key.
When they check...
...they'll see she's Mrs. Harry Roat Jr.
-From Scarsdale.
-Right.
This changes things a little, you know?
That's what l figured.
We'll talk about it later.
No, we'll talk about it now.
lt was 2000 each. Now it's 4.
Get behind the door, and, you, back there.
Stay dead still.
She's alone. Don't breathe.
Sam?
Sam, are you here?
No, Susy, l'm not here.
Gloria?
-Hendrix here.
-Hendrix here too.
l called to tell you l was the best
in blind school today.
-That's my girl.
-l really truly was, cross my heart.
And I believe you.
So can l tap my way over to your studio?
Not now.
Some female with the unlikely name
of Lejiana is due any minute for a sitting.
Well, l'll wait for you here, then.
Look, I'll tell you what. Since
this Lejiana character is already late...
...I'll just stick around
a few more minutes.
So can l come over and wait for you
in the coffee shop downstairs?
Sure.
Won't be hard to find me.
l'll be the one reading Peter Rabbit in Braille.
-Bye.
Damn it. You're supposed to be there.
Gloria, l know you're there.
Mr. Hendrix won't wait forever.
Shall we go to work, children?
Two plus two, 4000.
Two plus two, Mr. Talman.
Highly recommended.
Disposable, you buy them in enormous rolls...
...from Hammacher Schlemmer.
Spread out the rug.
Trouble.
-Hi, Susy. Hey.
-Hi, Shatner.
Let me help you with that mess.
Oh, you're a lovely cavalier,
only don't tell Sam you helped me.
l'm supposed to be learning
total self-sufficiency.
Why don't you come down
for a drink tonight?
l can't. l'm off to Vermont for
a couple of days of chasing stretch pants.
By the way, l haven't been able
to get in touch with our slumlord all day.
And my skylight's still broken.
-lf you see him--
-We never see him.
He's owed us a new refrigerator since we
moved in, so he doesn't come around.
Don't let it get you down.
Have a good weekend.
On Monday, we'll form a tenants committee
or something jazzy like that.
Some committee. Me, you, Sam,
Gloria and her mother.
Oh, well.
-Ciao.
-Susy?
-No, Batman.
-Safe to open the door?
-All right.
-You want to give me a hand, darling?
-Sure.
Who are you doing?
Gloria.
She's been after me for weeks
to take some pictures.
l promised l'd have these done.
l've got to go to Asbury Park--
-Asbury Park? l thought you--
-Sorry, l only found out this second.
That's all right. l was just
planning something silly.
-Will it hold till tomorrow?
-Sure.
Someone called from the chemical company.
They saw my Sunday Times spread.
They want me to make their new factory
look like the U.N.
Another night shot.
They're paying handsomely.
That's the last one.
-Can l go with you?
-Sure, but l'll--
Be home much quicker if you don't.
You know there was a murder
around here last night?
They found the body this morning.
A lady from Scarsdale.
l heard it on the radio.
So?
What if l get chopped up in little pieces
and dumped in the river?
Little tiny pieces that nobody
could ever recognize...
...as having been a poor,
defenseless, blind lady...
...whose husband was off in Asbury Park.
-You're not listening, Sammy.
-Sure l am.
Why don't we have some light
around here?
They're always finding bodies in New York.
Not in the parking lot
practically next door, they don't.
-You're making it up, Susy.
-No, l'm not. l promise.
l told you l heard it on the radio.
Really, l did.
Come on, Susy.
The police don't have
the first notion who did it.
Pretty spooky, don't you think, Sammy?
Tell you what l think.
l think it's a ploy to make me stay home.
Well, there was a murdered woman
found from Scarsdale...
...and that's a true fact.
And you're afraid for your life,
that's a true fact?
No, but it was worth a try.
Fourteen.
-You sure he'll go?
-Yeah.
-He'd better hurry or he'll miss the bus.
-He's got time.
This is some day for a schlep
out to Asbury Park.
-When does your bus leave?
-Five.
Time for another cup of coffee?
Maybe half a cup.
lf that doll woman calls,
tell her l haven't found it yet.
Let Gloria look around for it while she's
down here. lt must be somewhere.
l don't want Gloria today.
l don't need her.
-Yes, you do, for your shopping.
-No Gloria!
-Give me a hint?
-You can find it by yourself.
lf you couldn't, l'd tell you.
-What have you got against Gloria?
-A lot.
The problem is, she's in love with you,
which makes me the villain.
Susy, she's a kid.
More to your left, in front of you.
l'd rather have a dog.
Dogs can't shop at the supermarket.
They can't rearrange the furniture either
so l trip over it.
That's her latest hobby.
l nearly broke my leg last night.
She's been sneaking cigarettes too.
l smelled smoke when l came in yesterday.
Susy, give her a chance.
Her father's run off again. Her mother's
flitted out for a weekend uptown.
Poor old Gloria gets slammed around
like a Ping-Pong ball.
On top of that, she's wearing glasses.
Kids are giving her the treatment...
...calling her the "monster from outer space."
lcebox needs defrosting, darling,
only my way this time.
lt's more practical.
Use plenty of boiling water.
-What if l burn both my hands off your way?
-Don't.
The Unguentine's in the emergency drawer.
lf the weather's okay, try walking
to the studio and back.
No cheating.
Do l have to be the world's
champion blind lady?
Yes!
Then, l will be.
l'll be whatever
you want me to be.
Tell me what you want,
and that's what l'll be.
-Susy--
-l mean it.
l don't want you ever
to be anything but Susy...
...because that's the way l love you.
Do you? Do you?
What do you think?
-Do you want me to stay home?
-Yes.
But you can go to work anyway.
l'll clean up here...
...then when you get back,
l'll be all scrubbed and polished.
You sure it's okay?
Then, l got to rush.
Where does the icebox plug in?
You'll find it.
No fair asking Gloria either.
Sam.
Are you looking at me?
-Bye, dope.
Thanks for everything.
Okay, Mr. Talman,
it's time for your soft-shoe.
And remember, there's a nice, little, pink kid
running around the house.
And she wears glasses.
Sam.
Gloria!
Somebody!
Operator.
-Please....
-Fire department.
There's something burning.
l'm blind, and l can't locate it.
-lt's getting worse!
-Can I have your address?
27B--
Wait, l think somebody's here.
Come in!
The door's open.
-You all right?
-There's a fire. Can you see it?
-l'm blind, and l don't know where it is.
-Oh, yes, l've got it.
-Careful.
-l'm all right. Please find the fire.
lt's in the ashtray.
lt's only a cigarette butt.
A filter and a bit of paper
making all the smoke.
Where was it?
lt was on the--
What is this, a safe?
Against the wall? Yes.
l couldn't tell where it was coming from.
Smoke--
Smoke isn't my favorite thing.
-l don't know you, do l?
-No, Mrs. Hendrix.
My name's Mike Talman.
l used to know Sam.
l can't thank you enough
for being here.
And l'm sorry that Sam isn't here.
He won't be back until later tonight.
That was stupid of me.
l should've phoned...
...but l thought l'd take a chance
and maybe grab Sam for a quick beer.
Wait. Let me give you a hand with that.
-You got it.
-Thank you.
l haven't seen Sam for years,
but some people you don't forget.
Oh, Sam you don't forget.
l don't anyway.
He saved my life.
How do you mean that?
-l mean, he saved my life.
-That makes two of us.
That makes two of us, Mrs. Hendrix.
Susy.
Thank you.
You mean in the Army or something?
ln the Marines, yes.
The 3rd Battalion.
-Charlie Company.
-Right.
-Has he ever told you about that?
-No. Tell me.
No, you ask Sam.
Oh, please. He won't tell me.
You'd better ask Sam.
He likes to do things his own way.
-You're just as mean as he is.
-That's us.
-Mean Mike and Mean Sam.
-Well, you are.
Would you like a drink, Mike Talman?
No. No, thank you.
Are these Sam's, these pictures?
-Yes.
-Yeah, l thought so.
Hey, here's one of me.
l sure have put on a few pounds
since those days.
Tell me something,
did you know Sam then?
No, we only met a year ago,
not long after my accident.
You--?
You lost your sight in an accident?
Yes, in a car crash
or really the fire from the crash.
One day, l was practicing
crossing at the lights...
...and the cars were piling up
around me like mad, and...
...suddenly, a man named Sam
grabbed me.
And that was that.
Gloria?
-Who's that?
-A little girl.
Come in, Gloria.
She went out.
Well, l'm sorry to have missed Sam,
but l'm happy to have met you.
You're very lovely.
Sam's lucky.
So's Susy.
Goodbye.
Please tell Sam that l stopped by.
Next time l come in from Phoenix,
l'll drop a line first.
Thank you forever and ever for--
Oh, Lord! Hello? Are you still there?
I have to have your address.
Listen, l can't tell you how sorry l am
to have kept you.
You're wonderfully good
to have stuck around.
-did you find the fire?
-Yes, it's out.
-lt was just a cigarette.
-Okay, then, ma'am?
Yes, thank you.
Everything is now.
Goodbye.
How awful.
Mike?
Who's Mike?
Hello, Gloria.
-Who was that man?
-Friend of Sam's from the Marines.
You wouldn't know him, dear.
Oh, l see.
ls the grocery list ready?
The supermarket closes soon.
lt's on the typewriter with the $5.
Can you see it?
Oh, and, Gloria?
When you come back,
give me a hand with the icebox.
l've got to defrost it while Sam's away.
-What did you do then?
-Switched it to defrost, of course.
-That's not how it's done.
-lt is too.
l've done it for Mother
hundreds of times.
Your mother's refrigerator is modern.
This one's ancient.
We've got to do it Sam's way. We--
Okay, do it Sam's way, then.
l'll go to the A&P.
Did you close the door?
Yes.
-l didn't hear it shut.
-Okay, so it's open.
-Please shut the door.
-Close it yourself. You're nearer.
Gloria, close the door.
-No!
-Gloria!
No, l won't!
Listen, little monster,
l won't put up with this one more minute!
What's that?
What are you doing?
Stop it!
Stop it! Gloria, do you hear me?
You shouldn't have called me names.
l don't call you names.
l shouldn't say things like that.
lt was wrong of me.
-lt's okay.
-No, it isn't okay.
People shouldn't say that
to each other.
They're mean things,
and people shouldn't say mean things.
Guess l get terribly frightened sometimes.
l'm not a very good blind lady, Gloria,
and l'm still not used to all this...
...dark brown.
l get cranky and impatient and....
-l know l look dreadful half the time.
-Oh, no. You're gorgeous.
What a lovely thing to say.
Thank you, Gloria.
But l do wish l could do things.
You know, important things like...
...cook a soufflé or pick a necktie...
...or choose the wallpaper for the bedroom,
you know?
Sure. l know.
l want to be gorgeous.
Guess you can't have everything, huh?
l guess not.
l'm sorry, Susy, for being horrid.
And me for being an old crank.
-We break anything?
-Oh, no. l only threw unbreakables.
-That was crafty of you.
-l learned it from Daddy.
Okay, pumpkin, let's clean all this up,
and you can hop off to the supermarket.
Look out!
There's a knife there.
Thanks.
Run along. l'll put this away
so l know where to find it.
-Right. See you later.
-Okay.
Bye.
l should very much like to speak
with Mr. Sam Hunt, little girl.
Who's he?
Well, he doesn't live here.
-Leave, little girl.
-Susy!
-Leave, little girl. Go about your business.
-Gloria, what is it?
-l should like to see Mr. Sam Hunt...
...and tell Mrs. Roat that l should
also like to see her. Where are they?
-Who are you?
-lt's not right, you know, and it's not fair!
-Well, tell me what you--
-ln there!
What is it you want?
What are you doing?
You can't go in there.
Tell me who you are.
Here! l was right, you silly thing,
and now l've got the proof.
You tell Sam Hunt to leave her alone
or l'll fix him!
-Please--
-Good and proper!
Oh, yes, yes.
Don't touch me.
Susy, it's Mike Talman again.
l think l left a package.
Mike!
-Susy, what's wrong?
-Mike.
There was a man here.
He flew in like a black crow.
He's gone now. lt's all right.
-l'm scared.
-l'm here now. lt's all right.
You must be so bored with me.
Every time you come,
l'm in absolute panic.
No, no, no.
Bedroom's a mess.
He's dumped stuff all over the place.
l better call the police.
He might have stolen something.
Do you know the number?
279...
...0099.
That's the emergency number anyway.
That's good enough.
279...
...0...
-0.
-...0...
...9...
...9.
Don't worry.
l'll take a later flight to Phoenix...
-...and stay as long as you need me.
-Could you?
Of course.
Hello?
Police?
And the guy just busted in?
That right?
Yes, he was at the door
when the little girl went out.
Gloria from upstairs.
Yeah, l got that down.
-Then he pulled out the drawers.
-Sergeant, obviously the man's crazy.
Why don't you send a report
and have him picked up?
Just tell me the facts.
l'll decide what to do, if you don't mind.
Well, l do mind.
-You act as if nothing happened.
-We'd better let the sergeant do it his way.
Thank you, lady.
The important thing is, this guy
didn't steal anything, right?
No.
No, not as far as we know.
l think l'll help myself
to that drink now.
Sure.