Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Before the beginning of time,
Did God insufflate the life? universe.
Lumi?re were born the Angels.
Ground was born the Man.
Fire were born the Djinn,
condemned creatures? to live
the vacuum enters the worlds.
Who awakes a Djinn
will see three of these exaucés wishes.
The troisi?me exaucé wish,
impious legions of the Djinn
will break on the ground.
Only one fear exists ...
Fear of the Djinn.
Formulate your second wish.
Astonish Me, Djinn.
Show me wonders.
If such is your wish.
Help me, wizard!
Draw aside this curse.
Help us.
By all the names of God,
I did not want that!
Draw aside very from a wish.
Make the wish.
More wishes.
That Its Majesty is keep silent.
But my poor people ...
Wish-you It that
in the whole world?
More wishes.
I will have warned you, wizard.
Do not say any more.
ll awaits nothing any more but one wish.
3 granted wishes? who awoke,
he open the door between the worlds.
New wonders.
New splendours.
And of new and terrifying main.
In America, nowadays
And you?tes come in person,
Mr. Beaumont.
I awaited it 1 0 years.
Ancient sculpture,
2 ,45 m. of top.
Rule of pre-Islamic God
Ahura Mazda.
These gods were prohibited
under the Islamic law.
Its existence is a miracle.
What does it make?
Oh the moron!
Gently with this case!
Get stuffed !
I can help you?
Can -?tre.
I hold the pawnshop
on the 5?me.
The cesspool of the universe.
In short, one brought that to me this morning.
I gave a handsome price of them
and I would like to make it appraise.
Excellent initiative.
- Nick?
- Shannon?
That should interest Alex.
Mazette!
Which is its source?
Its history.
ll comes from O?
Of a type which held it
of its large-m?re.
I have déj? heard that.
I will put
my best expert above.
Shannon will give you a receipt.
Thank you to have chosen our house.
I believe that that is there.
I believe.
Beautiful match.
How is Rick ?
I know anything of it. I did not speak to him.
It is finished.
Does Ca make how much?
Six weeks and half?
Seven.
You count what?
One could ...
- What?
- One could leave.
One leaves all the time.
One leaves all the time,
but ' ' one does not leave together ' '.
Josh, you are my best friend.
It is hard to find one of them.
I do not want to waste that.
You will find somebody well.
I know the song.
You know why?
I am afraid to lose the little which I have.
Including you.
Restaurant and movies?
And hot dog and match?
One ensures, hein?
I will wet myself.
I will throw you a fate, Alex.
Ca will go can -?tre.
One sees oneself later.
I will be at the laboratory.
Thinks? what I said.
An opal of fire of this size.
It is splendid.
It be-?-statement?
Excellent translucidity.
No coloured trails.
It is single.
Which beautiful word.
I adore this word.
' ' Single ' '.
Ca must be worth its price.
I salivate.
You submit a report/ratio to me.
Nick? Goes you in.
What is it?
You awoke me.
What?
I did not hear you,
you frightened me.
Which is the verdict?
I believe
that there is something of odd.
Does Ca change the value?
I must make other analyses.
How, physics?
- Something? interior?
- Exact.
I am not a gemmologist.
I could analyze the spectrum
with the infra-reds.
Now?
Wait...
I have initially a connery? to make
for Pr Leiber.
I make it d?s that I can.
You remainders?
Not, I have the training of the girls.
It is significant.
Keep me informed.
You are the best.
I will revaudrai you that.
And our dinner?
Pauses.
You know why you did not mark?
Miss of calms.
You all can mark
if you have time,
if you aim.
But that goes quickly a match.
One wants to take the ball to you.
Therefore, you owe?tre calms.
No the body. Of spirit.
If a opportunity arises,
you forget the remainder.
Time, other players
do not exist any more.
Only you and the basket.
You see it, you find it.
You launch.
Laser places from there for analysis.
You pack it as you want.
It is what that?
You awoke me.
End of the scanning.
End of the scanning!
We transform lead into gold,
then leave a message.
Josh, it is Alex,
you are L?
Something of odd
has just arrived to me...
ll has somebody there?
Is the pain terrible?
I can help you.
And to relieve your sufferings.
You do not have qu '? to ask.
Do you want that your pain ceases?
If such is your wish.
Release me!
I am sorry.
lnspector Nathanson.
You?tes?
Alex Amberson.
You knew it... Josh?
It was my best friend.
I am sorry.
You want to sit down?
Not What did it occur?
Undoubtedly an accident
D? with the material.
ll worked on what?
ll analyzed
a gemmeous stone.
An opal.
For me.
Help a former child of chorus.
If you do not have a currency,
I accept the tickets.
I await you L?.
Still L?
Is not necessary to leave the customers alone.
Keep your councils for you,
salt tramp.
I m?ne the life that I want, salt idiot.
I will speak? who I want.
The pavement does not belong to you.
But it belongs to me this pavement.
Because I pay taxes.
I you emmerde!
Me, I you emmerde!
Cr?ve, bag? shit!
I esp?re that you go claquer
in the gutter
so that I piss you above.
Baboon bald person!
Dyed of piss
wire of partouzarde Chinese!
ldiot informed!
' ' the pavement belongs to me,
I pay taxes.''
You know O? you can put them
your taxes!
I esp?re that you will burst kidneys.
That you will rot in hell,
and that...
Who it is that?
A friend, can -?tre.
Say to me...
You think really all
these curses?
I want, ouais.
What you would make
so that they are carried out?
I have that a cig
and a handshake.
Not all? fact.
You have a heart.
I exchange it against a shower
and of the Daniels Jack.
The death of your enemy
is our market.
You?tes well f?lé.
But I love how you think.
Please to me this.
Of which mani?re?
Find an idea.
And it enjoys.
ll should have cancer.
To have cancer and to burst.
If such is your wish.
Ch?ques of allowances...
Does Eh, that go?
- does Ca go?
- I do not know.
Leave it.
Was Ca worth the sorrow of it?
Run, insect.
Run to tell what you want.
Say to them that something is released.
Something which nourishes wishes.
Say to them quickly.
As long as you have a heart.
If you do not like,
crush it.
I am sorry for Josh.
You were so close.
Not as close as he wanted.
And now...
Listen,
it is not your fault.
If, I believe.
What?
Something was odd
in this opal.
It is that which has D? to explode.
What I gave him killed.
You know what you say?
I know that it is nutcase,
it is that the probl?me.
You want that I recall
Dr. Montiglio?
I smell myself well.
I am just shaken.
Not, you imagine things
like the derni?re time.
Doesn't that have anything? to see.
Will lay down you instead of you to worry.
Arr?te the number of the older sister.
The fire, it is past.
And you saved me.
I did not save dad and mom.
Not.
You could not.
It is as for Josh,
it is not your fault.
Arr?te to make feel guilty
if not that will start again.
Therapy, nightmares,
all.
Not.
It is different.
ll occurs something.
Something of low register.
I will find what it is.
A part, Alex?
I feel your fear.
I seek certain Etchison.
- ll arrives.
- It is him?
Mr. Etchison?
Call me as you will want.
I do not have time to play.
It is idiot.
One could have fun.
Let us speak rather about the opal.
Invaluable stone.
I do not see.
Your friend Clegg, him,
tr?s saw well.
Do not know.
50 years,
it holds the pawnshop,
and will denounce you in the event of continuations.
It is what the probl?me?
You?tes cop?
lls will remain outwards
if you say all to me.
On the statue. Apr?s the accident.
You saw the infos.
- a type died.
- That of Beaumont?
Do I know?
The type
who bought was L?.
Clegg spun me 200 $.
I was made entuber?
Royally.
ACClDENT OF The DOCKS
FAlT A DEATH
Alexandra.
Which joy of re-examining you.
Which sad news, Mr. Beaumont.
lrremplaçable.
Single in its kind.
We speak about ED Finney,
your assistant?
Well s?r.
If you allow, I would like to pose to you
some questions.
All that you will want.
Is the press interested more? the accident,
the workman of the crane...
This drunk pig.
qu '? the statue it-m?me.
Was it encrusted with stones?
Without ornament.
Like Ahura Mazda.
It was made
apr?s conversion? the lslam.
I want to show you something.
That will interest you.
Jerk!
My room of the Lost Gods.
Formerly venerated, forgotten today.
Each culture of antiquity.
Look at,
the reserved place
for Ahura Mazda.
Who is exactly Ahura Mazda?
I collect
objects,
not theologies which they represent.
It was a divinity
religion zoroastrienne.
A beneficial god?
Undoubtedly.
Nevertheless the legend known as
that the opposite force was in fact
its own shade.
ll was thus to some extent
the source of the evil.
Contact somebody? the University.
A brilliant woman
who worked for me.
She can help you. With condition
that it is of good mood.
Who is the pet of the professor?
What do you make in the black?
Who ?tes you?
This would be something
what don't you wish to see?
Tr?s well.
My eyes!
I do not see anything.
Bastard.
Alex, that does occur?
Excuse me.
I do not know.
You lost consciousness.
You want to drink?
Water?
Ca goes.
Ca owes?tre the stress.
Ca goes, sinc?rement.
Sinc?rement?
I esp?re to see you restored
for my evening.
That planned for f?ter
my acquisition.
Your owner received the invitations.
You and your sister
?tes welcomes.
It would be with pleasure ...
but I will undoubtedly be occupied.
Still ...
Wait ...
Move back of a m?tre.
The red tape, one will see tomorrow.
I am occupied.
Yes Well.
You must make error.
I am Alex.
Did R. Beaumont warn you?
Which fieffé jerk that-L?.
It is not your probl?me.
Except if you work with him.
Or sleep with him.
Voil? who shows
that you have go?t good.
A little ... Not.
Ca does not go. At the bottom.
What can I for you?
Nothing if I do not have
all your attention.
I like you.
I am m?lée
? this coproduction.
The folklore it is my ray,
not the theatre.
D?s which Pr Benson is L?,
I run away myself.
One spoke about Pierre of Secret Fire
00 :37 :17,000 -- > 00:37:20,900
A wizard would have locked up
a spirit malefic? interior.
A spirit malefic?
A creature residing between the worlds.
A Djinn.
A genius?
Forget what one says of the Djinn.
Forget Robin Williams.
For former Arabic,
a Djinn was not nice nor funny.
It was other thing.
The face of the fear.
Does Ca give what?
Say it to me.
You approve.
You want to test another thing?
More adjusted?
I do not like?tre tight.
I had enough of it.
Tr?s well. Follow me.
With pleasure.
Esp?ces or chart, Mister ...?
Demarest. Nathaniel Demarest.
Call Me Nathaniel.
Nathaniel, esp?ces or chart?
What do you prefer?
Esp?ces.
It is done.
It is my first day
in your world.
I like that the beauty is inalterable.
You do not fear
what yours fades?
That your mirror tells you
a sad history?
I think... that it is the life.
It is our batch? all.
Not.
Ask.
And you will see.
Ask that cease the decline.
Known as: ' ' I want?tre beautiful? never.''
I want?tre beautiful? never.
Delighted by treat with you.
I will find you soon.
Do you want that that is given?
I am sorry.
I wanted just to show
my costume.
Ca makes sufficiently fear.
Will repeat.
Does Ca go?
The Djinn, singular and plural word,
were created apr?s the Angels,
but before the Man.
Magic and malefic.
Maléfiques?
Do the geniuses exaucent the wishes, not?
It is their duty. But their real goal
is to adapt the world.
Me was told...
fables.
The faith passed in the tales.
Our terrors are camouflaged
in history of magic lamps
to rock our children.
Old accounts
are darker.
Much more.
The Djinn represents all our fears.
A race of?tres inhuman
who wants us evil.
More powerful than we could
to imagine,
guided by an insatiable ill will.
lnspector Nathanson?
You?tes chargé d' affaires Aickman.
I was it.
The business is classified,
at least side homicide.
With less
of information.
It is you who will inform me.
- What do you want to know?
- Little thing.
The address of a certain Alexandra.
Why I would give it to you?
In what that does concern you?
What do you look at?
This type...
is guilty of all the sins.
7 times released.
Ca returns to me sick.
You know what I would like?
Say to me.
Just once,
I would like to wedge this jerk
for homicide,
in front of everyone.
Eh, you!
Pierre of Secret Fire
created to deliver the people perse
of the Djinn
is also a curse,
because it is a door between the worlds.
Grace? it, a Djinn can project
its race in our reality
and to dominate humanity.
The Djinn charges initially Pierre
human hearts
of which a wish...
ll activates it by finding the human one
who awoke,
by granting 3 wishes to him.
The capacity of the Djinn is limited
? the achievement of the wishes.
It is closed.
I seek an employee.
- ll has only the owner there.
- Perfect, I want to speak to him.
Later, appointments.
You become razor.
Open
the door.
OK. Goes you in.
Push yourself of L?.
R?ve, jerk.
It is frustrating
that an unlimited capacity serf
only when one larva
ask something.
I know anything of it
and I have anything of it? foutre.
Ask me a thing.
I want that you leave.
I must enter.
Would be necessary to pass to me? through.
And I would like to see that.
What do you make L?
The guard opened to me.
Could you help me?
I seek Alexandra Amberson.
It is its day of rest.
Who?tes you?
Somebody until it waits.
Could you give me his address.
If she knows you,
why you do not have it?
I said that it awaits me,
not that she knows me.
Then, made that by ' ' e-mail '',
because
I can nothing give you.
- You include/understand?
- Perfectly.
Would you know O? she is?
Yes.
- would you say it to Me?
- Not.
It is a pi?ce of value.
Really?
You would like that it is worth
1 00 times more?
If I want that it is worth
1 00 times more? Yes.
You?tes David Copperfield?
How do you make?
Secrecy of family.
O? is Alexandra?
I am sorry, that me g?ne
to say it to you.
What would help you?
Say it.
Which limit?
Your imagination.
I am not covetous.
A million dollars?
It is done.
Let us see that.
The recipient is not mentioned.
Which idiot.
It is my son, Nick.
ll directs prestigious
cabinet of expertise.
Good flight.
Hello, you.
What do you make?
I learn the r?gles from a play.
I return expr?s early
and you are not m?me not pr?te.
Tennis shoe.
I did not pay attention.
Give me one second.
Super!
5 minutes of pause.
Calms, Miss Amberson.
I made as you said.
Pass by again to me your portable.
Who is this woman, initially?
The responder!
Pr Derleth, it is still Alex.
I must absolutely speak to you.
Recall me.
Forgiveness.
Can I use your portable?
I will pay the call.
It is good.
Voil?. Like that
you will not fall.
Nobody.
Practical, isn't this?
I require what is D?.
lnspector Nathanson.
We must speak.
A type sought you.
You only
can put an end? their pain.
You only can release them.
Patience, my friends.
Patience.
I can enter?
Pierre is charged by the heart
people, by their fears.
The Djinn seeks me.
This is not a little incredible
with the 20?me si?cle?
Small glass, can -?tre?
Me, if.
Isn't movable beautiful?
Your owner would like.
I did not speak to you about him.
Not?
How I know it?
By Beaumont?
It is him.
I will say to you.
You?tes? the search for magic,
of charm
to disencumber you
of a hypothetical Djinn.
lls existed certainly.
- You are cold?
- Ca goes.
Heating?
Not Continue.
O? in was I?
Charms, wizard...
You?tes born in an age of reason.
The age of Science.
All the wizards died,
and all the charms are lost.
The Djinn...
If there existed,
would be what was.
lmaginez.
The only magic element
of a rationalist world.
A vulnerable world incrédule.
O? no Reason
would never save you.
Nor no Science.
ll would take good time, not?
It is not a joke.
It is not funny.
You are hungry?
I am not hungry, not thirst.
Why?tes you so attentive?
I am sorry.
I am tended a little.
I believe.
But that goes.
O? in were we?
No charms.
No the hope.
If there is no hope, charms,
I must count on me.
To face a creature
bottom of time.
To measure itself
with the Prince of the Empire of the Shade.
To measure your brain of the 20?me si?cle
? that which crossed space
between the worlds,
and pressed the wings of the Angels.
You make my joy, really.
I am delighted.
I wounded you.
I am sorry.
I will catch up with myself.
What can I make?
I go there.
Sit down!
Please.
You sit.
O? is Wendy?
In the room.
Avoid going there.
I needed his face.
You killed it.
I cannot kill anybody.
Except if it is what they want.
You owe the knowledge.
It did not want to die,
salt lying shit!
I showed him my true face.
It did not like.
It became hysterical.
I asked him
if she wanted?tre delivered
of its fear.
They is dangerous to know you.
Your enquiring friend.
Your owner.
The police officer. Wendy.
By the way,
O? is your delicious small sister
today?
You make him evil,
I kill to you.
Save to me, my child.
Here my true nature.
Ca is likely to hurt.
Let us stop.
Formulate your wishes.
Three wishes.
You are not intrigued?
All that you want.
- All?
- of me all Requires.
I will grant it to you.
A voyage on the moon,
in Egypt of the Pharaons.
If I want your death?
As it is original.
I will grant a free wish to you.
A sample.
For?tre in environment.
I want that you destroy yourselves.
Make you jump the brain.
Now.
Well.
What is eternal cannot die.
If that can comfort you,
that made an evil of dog.
Formulate your three wishes.
ll is always necessary to know
its adversary.
I will make a wish.
I would like...
to know what you?tes.
What do you make?
I exauce your wish.
You want to know what I am.
For you, I am that.
The cry of the abandoned child.
The rail of the whipped b?te.
The face which scans you
bottom of the shade.
The vacuum in the heart
of your hopes, Alexandra.
I am despair.
Do not make any wish.
Then, you like me?
I did not want that.
You owe?tre outside, not here.
I am dependent? what I bind.
Locked up in what I lock up.
I did not want that.
Formulate your wishes more prudently.
Leave your sister alone.
T'en do not make,
I will hold company to him.
Leave it.
ll is necessary it.
The pain of the liked?tres
is tr?s persuasive.
Ask me to return.
I would like?tre at home.
Without you!
Shannon, O? you are?
ll is necessary to leave from here.
I SUlS AT BEAUMONT.
REJOlNS Us. SHANNON.
You made two wishes.
We are now dependent.
O? what do you go, O? that you would be,
I will find you.
I you emmerde!
You go by L?
Forgiveness, you?tes invited?
Help me.
This type is dangerous,
it broke my windshield
and desired to kill me.
Forgiveness, Mister.
?tes you waited by Mr. Beaumont?
I asked you a question.
If I am awaited? Yes.
I owe it? Mr. Beaumont.
Tr?s well, but that does not have the air
of an invitation.
I make fun about it.
You push.
I go?tre tr?s clearly.
If you?tes not on the list,
you do not enter.
I know this kind-L?.
You?tes never fallen
on one of my kind.
I will enter.
And you will let me pass.
It is clear, gatekeeper?
Gatekeeper? I am called Valentine.
Johnny Valentine.
That which will make you
to lose an eye.
Forgive my ardour.
Haste to finish the play distorted
my judgement. Let us make a market.
I do not do anything.
What will you make, then?
This evening,
I transfer the jerks of the receptions.
And tomorrow?
You cannot do only that?
You did only that.
You wished another thing.
Tell me the truth. You will not be
ever tired of this work?
Escape towards another trade.
Which report/ratio that has with you?
Ca has one of them.
Seized your chance. Answer? my question.
Would you like to escape?
If such is your wish.
Houdini put 2' 30 ' '.
Forgiveness.
Afflicted.
What do you make?
- I want to leave you L?.
- I Releases.
One must leave.
Trust me.
Not. You did not see
the new friend of Beaumont.
You remember the type of the tennis shoe?
I was? reception of Cindy
when they announced their divorce.
One spoke about it during one year.
Really?
One spoke about that of a prince
during si?cles.
It entered the history?
I would like a reception like that.
If such is your wish.
You see? through me.
My God!
Not yet, human.
Soon ... I will be it soon.
Buckle the périm?tre!
ll remains us
a thing? to finish.
One will remain L about it?.
Listen to their cries, my child.
Listen to the melody of their torment.
Refuse!
You can save them, Alexandra.
If such is your wish.
I do not want. I cannot.
Is my patience? boils.
You will do what?
To kill me?
And the 3?me wish?
I do not require that you would have died,
only that you wish the?tre.
Run ...
- What does it occur?
- O? is Shannon?
You saw it?
Come.
One tries to control the situation.
Do not remain L?
ll arrives!
ll is not necessary to remain L?.
One will not leave oneself there !
More exits.
More folds. More excuses.
Say your wish.
I do not have any.
Really?
M?me by seeing ultimate the pi?ce
Beaumont collection?
Final bouquet.
One of my masterpieces.
lntitulé: ' ' My sister,
why did you give up me? ''
Rather resembling?
I like especially
this glance of b?te tracked.
Salt son of vicious whore!
You do not approve ?
Tr?s well. To release!
You am to me?
In the absence of victory, let us br?lons them.
A memory?
Say your wish.
I advise to you to make quickly.
Calm ...
I would like ...
Continue ...
Calm ...
I would like that Mickey Torelli
did not drink 2 days ago.
It is impossible!
Not by ...
you!
You badly fell.
You?tes come
in person
Mr. Beaumont.
All is in order.
I awaited it 1 0 years.
Mickey, pay to!
They is not coconuts,
it is an pre-Islamic trick!
Then, mollo!
Included/understood!
Ca will make a charming gift
engagement.
At least.
You are late.
I give you 2000 of them.
One does what this evening?
' ' On' '?
What is there, Josh?
You are afraid of the complications?
You know ...
that will help you, that.
Does Ca help you?
O? does one go this evening?
Restaurant and movies.
With me?
I had rather thought
hot dog and match.
You smell yourself well?
Adaptation: White Philippe
Subtitling: L.V.T. - Paris
Do not make any wish.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org