Ten, nine...
... eight, seven...
... six, five...
... four...
... three, two...
... one!
Here goes.
Bravo, Mr. Van der Veer!
- Yes, Mr. Van der Veer?
- We'll go to the penthouse.
Stop by Battery Park.
Roger, routing change.
Penthouse, ETA: 0615.
What will Van der Veer do
at the Battery at 6:00 a.m.?
- Visit his ancestors.
- Whatever he wants.
Roger, Manattan arrival.
All clear, Romulus.
You've got sector five read-out on three.
Chris?
Darling?
Chris!
You scared me!
Darling!
- Did you miss me?
- Yes.
Pauline!
Forget it, kid.
Oh, good. Put him on.
Good morning, it's Warren.
We got a problem.
- You're up early.
- Yeah.
Well, there's a nightmare
down in the Battery.
Three bodies.
Mutilation, possible sexual assault...
... some dismemberment.
Maybe even cannibalism.
I'd love to see it, but I've...
I'm late for Mass
and I got a heavy golf date.
Oh, you'll see it, Dewey.
It's very weird and it's very strange,
just like you. So, it's back to work.
- I'm leaving now. Are you in Staten Island?
- Yeah.
- Get your ass over there as fast as you can.
- How?
Fly!
- How are you?
- Fine.
Food.
- How can you eat that crap?
- It settles my stomach.
Well?
Nothing. I didn't find anything aft, either.
So?
So, what?
So, who got killed? The governor?
Somebody bigger.
Christopher Van der Veer.
Megabucks.
Heir to the fortune,
maybe even the presidency.
So much for heirs.
His bodyguard. His wife is over there.
- Witnesses?
- Lf seagulls could talk, sure.
- Kidnapping?
- No sign of a struggle.
Take a look around.
See if you can sniff out anything.
Does this mean I'm back on the job?
- You're a detective, aren't you?
- I'll try and remember that.
- It's a good thing to happen on a Sunday.
- How long...
Oh, Christ!
- Let me handle this.
- I always do.
Commissioner. Mr. Mayor.
You handled that nicely.
This is just wonderful!
God knows what's next.
- Where's the damn coroner?
- We haven't located him yet.
I want him here!
Van der Veer was my friend.
You've got your best man here already.
Any more film, John?
Warren, what the hell happened?
It wasrt robbery.
Their money and jewelry werert touched.
There was some cocaine.
Party favors. But more than that...
Two factors have the potential
to make this international, Mr. Mayor.
Executions and terrorism.
Makes a bombing seem like child's play.
Excuse me.
Dewey Wilson?
Homicide, kidnapping and results.
I'm sorry, I don't know you.
Jonathan Ross,
Bureau Chief of Executive Security.
His firm's responsible for some
of the top executives in the world.
They have resources we don't have.
No matter how sophisticated
technology gets, there's no guarantee.
God, it stinks down here.
Severely inflicted wounds...
Dew! The old jogging trip?
The six month's annual bionic,
shed-the-twenty-pounds marathon resolve.
Sound mind, sound body.
You got to get into chemicals.
They keep you going.
Your body'll malfunction on you
one way or another.
Yeah. Tell me about it.
Wanna peek?
Something to tell
your grandchildren about.
Took his brain. What the hell
do you suppose they did with it?
Maybe they dribbled it down Wall Street.
I got a hand in a baggie.
It belongs to that guy over there.
Had a gun in it.
SR says he didn't even get a shot off.
How's that for fast?
Fraternity ring?
Pentagram and a goat. Voodoo.
Yeah?
Now, ain't this a shame?
Bizarre, man. It almost severed her head.
- It was instantaneous?
- Instantaneous?
You seen a chicken run around
with its head cut off?
Hey, nobody ever thinks about the head.
During the French Revolution,
when they chopped heads off...
...they'd pick them out the basket
and look them in the face.
Most went out right away, in shock.
Every fifth head or so was alive.
Wide awake...
...eyes blinking,
mouth trying to say something.
Yeah, sure.
The brain can live without oxygen
for more than a minute.
That's a long time, buddy boy.
How'd you like to see your own body
and know you're dead?
Give me a nice death in bed.
Preferably with a partner.
You can take her away now.
Hey, careful with her...
...head.
Well, let's see what happened to my man.
Two bullet holes upside the head!
See! You shouldn't have been fucking
with that bitch.
You going to push, man?
I'm working by myself today, right?
Ain't nobody working but me. Shit!
- Another hot Saturday night.
- I heard that.
- What's today's special?
- Tennis shoes and jock straps.
A lot of joggers are going out of business.
You check out that dude yet?
Dew!
Weird shit happening here, man.
Give us a few more minutes.
How's it going, Captain?
Why do I always have to get
the hard ones?
There's nothing there.
There's nothing there!
Hey, Dew!
The Chief will tell him what we got.
Severance of the jugular and carotids...
...destruction of the esophagus.
Lethal trauma on the throats,
resulting in...
But what's really interesting
is what we haven't got.
There's not a trace of metal.
You know how every piece of metal,
no matter how sharp or smooth...
...will leave a residue when it cuts.
It could be as finite as dust.
Soft x-ray should pick it up.
Nothing!
And nothing softer could have ripped
and ravaged like this.
Some plastic weapon?
Synthetics.
I don't think there's any way
I could check that.
You know, Dew, you could use a haircut.
Want to lie down?
Not till it's my turn.
How's it going?
Identification?
- My face.
- I need credentials.
All that separates you from a guard dog
is a brain.
All right, Captain.
Good dog!
- Hey, Dewey. What's happening?
- Hi, Captain.
- What's this?
- ME's report.
Oh, yeah? What's with the morgue?
No answers to a lot of questions.
- Is that it?
- That's it.
What's the matter with you? You bored?
I'm thinking.
You're just not used to the expression.
Dungeman? Did you find out
what they were doing there?
Anniversary party
with 100 of their closest friends.
We know! We're checking the guest list.
Big party at the family compound.
It breaks up at 5:00 a.m.
They head back to their penthouse.
A little pearl gift...
...a little booze, a little drugs.
They decide to boogie.
They were married there.
- How do you know that?
- I asked.
- You really are thinking.
- It's better than the Sunday crossword.
Maybe.
- Any Jack the Rippers out there?
- No psychos missing from the loony bins.
If it is the Ripper,
the ME can't find a trace of any weapon.
What?
Who knows?
The Filipinos remove organs
with their hands.
- That driver was a Haitian, right?
- Yeah.
One tough son of a bitch.
Worth three normals.
Ex-Papa Doc Secret Police.
Ton Ton Macoute.
Van der Veer had
a big liquor import business in the islands.
How that Haitian gets jumped
beats the shit out of me.
You check the voodoo angle?
Voodoo? There's 80 goddamn sects
in Manattan alone.
Come here, I want to show you something.
The meat and potatoes.
- Business and political enemies.
- Fuchek, what do you got?
Business enemies he ain't got.
Just one big corporate family.
Political, well, there's the action.
The family's got interests
on every continent.
Funding a government overthrow.
Putting a mine in some holy ground.
Moving a town.
A real friend of the Third World.
International terrorism, huh?
- You got quadrant four secured already?
- Yes, I do.
- Punch me up 20 on this.
- Roger, 20.
Got a demo run faction.
File facts negative so far.
Unknown radical connections.
Wait, wait. Give me the stats on 20.
- Well, hello! That's Van der Veer's niece.
- Have the police pick her up.
Give me 20.
Somewhere in the world, every other day...
... a corporate executive is kidnapped
or assassinated...
... netting ransoms in excess of $1 billion...
... and forcing the expenditure of $50 million
in corporate security measures.
Transnational terrorism would rival
their victims in profit if you guys...
I want her.
... sophisticated Joseph Richmond, central
chemical plant manager in Columbia.
Yeah?
Good morning.
Hi! Good morning. Come in. Sit down.
I was reading the response you got
on that Psychology of Violence report.
- That must be very gratifying.
- Yes, it is.
Good.
I'm teaming you up with Dewey Wilson
on the Van der Veer case.
I didn't know he was back.
I thought he retired. Disabled. Mental?
He had a lot of family problems.
He started to drink a little too much. He...
Police work piled up on him.
He's a good man. You'll like him.
Okay, fine.
We also had a little break this morning.
Van der Veer's niece was picked up.
She's Weather underground.
I want you to chat her up.
Put her on your machine.
Maybe we'll get lucky.
So what's new on the international
mutilation front? Run down the list.
Well, kneecappings, Red Brigade, Italy.
Slashed Achilles tendons,
eyes gouged out, ears cut off...
...Red Army faction.
Let's see, PFLP, Carlos,
Baader, Tuperamos...
...Fifth Estate, a few decapitations.
The Uno Mondo.
They slash off the male genitalia.
The cock and balls.
They stuff them in their victim's mouth.
- You ever seen anybody killed?
- Pardon me?
Somebody's insides on a wall?
Hold your nose.
So, who collects brains?
It's probably a symbol.
Miss Rensselaer
probably went to Radcliffe...
...and took a course in symbolism.
- What is your full name?
- Cicely Marie Rensselaer.
- What city are we in?
- That's a good question.
- Well, what city?
- We're in New York, aren't we?
We're in New York.
What are you watching?
She is an urban guerrilla
fighting the just war...
...against all us fascist swine.
And she is a chain-jerked...
...pussy of an amoral society.
Well, that's what she's just been called.
What is this crap?
Am I on some kind of a lie detector?
You know that would be illegal.
Yeah, the whole room's a lie detector.
This is a high-end infrared imager.
Well, you were always a good kid...
The register's heat changes
in the 8 to 12 micron range.
Thermo-graphic systems equipment,
voice analyzers.
Computers and recorders are back there.
Micro-frequency levels
indicate psychological stress.
These things should be monitoring
Congress and the White House.
Country would grind to a halt.
This stuff's all remote. Covert.
You don't hook them up with...
...a bandage on the arm and a sweat meter.
One death is a tragedy. A million
is a statistic. You tell me about our wars.
Tell me about three deaths.
Three deaths?
Well?
She's hiding something.
Did you, or anyone you know, participate
in the murder of Christopher Van der Veer?
That's one startled kid.
Are you aware of any information...
...about the murder
of Christopher and Pauline Van der Veer?
It wasrt a murder, Rebecca.
- It wasrt a murder, Rebecca.
- It was an execution.
Jesus Christ!
It was an execution.
It wasrt a murder, Rebecca.
She's lying.
She knows nothing about the murders.
Got you. Urban guerilla.
Till your goddamn trust fund runs out.
- You're sure she's lying?
- Absolutely.
- Great! Now where does that leave us?
- Like this just didn't happen.
I got to get straight.
What'll you give me for it?
No Hustler pinups!
I don't think
this has anything to do with terrorism.
What does it have to do with?
- Paranoia.
- Paranoia?
Your people want it to be political.
It justifies your existence.
She was a logical suspect.
What weapon did that?
Why hasn't anybody called the press?
Especially for such a beautiful job.
They all don't right away.
You wanna a shot?
- Have you got any ice?
- Only in my heart.
"God, guns and guts...
"...made America. Let's keep all three."
Why are you a cop?
Oh, I like to kill. It's a habit
I picked up and it's...
It's hard to shake.
Killed anyone lately?
Well, I tried to kill a rabbit this morning,
but it went down a hole.
What do you make of that?
Well, something sexual, I suppose.
Good night, Dewey.
Good night, Rebecca.
- Where are you staying?
- A company apartment.
Got a ride?
- You asking?
- Yeah.
No.
You want one?
Not tonight.
Stop! Stop!
Jesus Christ!
Over here! Come over here!
- Come on, man, hurry!
- Come on, let's go take a look.
Cesspool! Look at this sewer!
Jesus Christ!
Didrt expect that kind of work in here.
How many houses
did the Van der Veers have?
Locust Valley, Long Island, the Bahamas...
...Johannesburg, Rome, San Francisco...
...and this little pied-à-terre.
Peter Van der Veer.
And old John Joachim, himself.
He even looks like God!
Except his hands are in his pockets.
They'd better be! He's got
about four dead presidents in them.
Mrs. Van der Veer painted this?
- It's such a disturbing picture!
- It sure disturbs me.
- She was asking for help.
- With her art lessons.
It's not me.
- Got a phone I could use?
- On the desk.
What's this?
Mr. Van der Veer's real estate project.
Ground breaking ceremony was Saturday.
- Whittington.
- Dew.
They found some body parts
in the South Bronx.
- What's the South Bronx got to do...
- This is hot, man! Meet me at Baldy's.
I'll be right there.
We've got hair files on every race running,
plus your basic sub-flavors.
Facial, axillary, chest, pubic.
They're all different. All identifiable.
The one on the left came off
the Bronx kidney.
The one on the right was found
on Pauline Van der Veer.
Identical.
A hair is like a fingerprint.
And those two
came from the same source.
What are they?
Captain, they don't match anything I have.
All I know is they ain't human.
And in New York?
South Bronx and Wall Street.
What's the connection?
They're both dead.
- Thanks, Baldy.
- Thank you.
- See you, Baldy.
- Keep combing it.
My God!
- I haven't been in a church in years.
- Lost your faith?
No. I got married in one.
Is he still around?
Not anymore.
I was an altar boy once.
An old nun ran the show.
Used to beat the shit out of me.
- Take a look inside?
- No, thanks.
- What was that?
- What?
That sound! Like a baby!
There! Inside!
"The devil on one shoulder,
an angel on the other."
- What?
- Let's get out of here!
Did you hear that?
Wind.
I haven't been to a place like this
since school.
You really know
how to treat a woman, Wilson.
This isn't a date, Neff.
What do you think it was?
Kids.
Junkies.
Hallucinations. I don't know.
Have you killed anyone?
Well, I wounded someone.
I shot a rookie in the leg, cleaning my gun
in the locker room second week in uniform.
Have you?
Why don't you ask how many?
Thank you.