[People Whooping]
- [ Man] Yeah!
- [Woman Shouts, lndistinct]
- [Woman Speaking, lndistinct]
- [ Man ] Go, Trey! Go!
- [Trey] Come on, man!
- [Woman ] You guys are slow!
- [ Man ] Don't get caught up in the rocks.
- [Woman Yelps ] Oh, my God!
[ Man ]
Come on. Keep it going north-south.
[ Trey Laughs ]
[Woman ]
Look out for that rock!
Look out!
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Woman Whoops ]
[ Chattering ]
Whoo! Whoo!
My turn.
[ Man ]
That's it.
[ Chattering ]
[ Shrieks ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Groans ]
Jesus, Alex. Anyone ever told you to go slow
when we first enter the chute?
Slow is for pussies.
[ Groans ]
Get in there.
[Alex]
Let's set up camp here for the night.
All right. Let's pull the boats in.
This place is perfect.
[ Breathing Heavily]
Hey. We're gonna go look
for some firewood.
You do that.
I'm gonna blow a stick.
- Don't hog all the kush.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Lighter Flicks ]
- [ Exhales ]
- Mmm.
[ Exhales ]
You are a total exhibitionist.
So what? The girls need to breathe.
- [ Laughs ]
- We're in the middle of the woods.
Who's gonna notice?
I don't know. Some banjo-playing freak.
- What?
- Forget it.
- [ Sighs ]
- Hey, where's Trey?
Oh, the Boy Scout's gathering
the right kindling up the river.
Like there's a wrong kind.
I'm gonna go look for him.
You guys, don't do anything
that will scare the animals.
- Okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Hey.
[ Exhales ] Alex thinks I'm a slut.
Do you think I'm a slut?
Yes. But that is what I love about you.
- I thought you loved my tits.
- I do. You have perfect tits.
I could hold them forever.
- [ Gasps, Screams ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Panting ]
Please help me!
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Cackles ]
- [ Gasping ]
[ Cackling ]
Oh!
[ Grunting]
- [ Clattering ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Cackling]
[ Cackling ]
[ Cackling Continues ]
[ Cackling]
[ Screams ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Cackling ]
- [Man ] Help!
- [ Shrieking ]
Please, help! Help!
[ Creaking, Rustling]
Ooh!
[ Inmates Chattering ]
[ Grunting ]
[Man ]
Hey, come on!
[Man Continues, lndistinct ]
Why don't you step off, skinhead?
You fight one bean,
you fight the whole burrito, huh?
¡Quita!
You got your shit set?
Just make sure your fucking taco jockeys
don't fuck it up.
Don't test me, cabron.
You know, normally,
I'd slit your throat for less.
But seeing as we're business partners,
I think I'll let it slide.
Just remember one thing.
You're not the only one
that's good at slitting throats.
Now, I paid you a lot of fucking money
to help put this together.
So the shit better come good
like clockwork next week.
Don't you worry, Chavez. I won't burn you.
Money is money.
It makes the world go round.
Oh.
I'm not worried...
but we all know
how you like to burn things.
Firebug.
[ Chuckles ]
- [Buzzer Buzzes ]
- [Man ]All right, keep moving.
[Man ]
Let's go, guys.
Man, he is an idiot.
I'm just telling you what he told me.
Hey. Late on your last day?
Farmer will probably
write your ass up for it too.
He can write all he wants.
Damn, Nate, those are some
expensive-looking threads.
You got to dress for success, Walter.
Nate, I was just telling Walter here
how Sergeant Farmer was saying...
you're probably just gonna flunk out
in your first semester anyway.
Oh! Nice. I really care what he thinks.
Ah, by the way, warden wants to see you.
He says we got a transfer tonight.
Oh, man, I just wanna have a peaceful shift
and go home, not go on a goddamn road trip.
- I'll see you out there, man.
- See ya.
[Man On P.A.]
Cell Block "A"-prisoners, clear the yard.
Clear the yard.
- You wanted to see me, Warden?
- Nate.
- You know Willy here, don't you?
- A prisoner from Cell Block 3.
Willy Juarez is actually U.S. Marshal
William Juarez. This is Marshal Davis.
They're gonna help us out
with the Hazelton transfer...
specifically with Carlo Chavez.
That transfer isn't
supposed to happen until next week.
Yeah, well, I pushed it to tonight.
Our friends here got word...
that Chavez's gang may attempt
to break him out during the transfer.
We put Juarez undercover to try and find out
who he's passing the information through.
You chain him up
next to Chavez on the bus.
Nate, only you will know
my real identity in case of an incident.
Now, for this to work,
Chavez has to trust me.
[ Warden ] As an added precaution,
I've altered your route.
Nobody knows it
but the people in this room.
I'm counting on you, Nate.
[ Door Opens ]
- Thanks, Ally.
- No problem, boss.
¶¶ [Radio: Country]
[Phone Rings ]
Sheriffs station. Deputy Lane speaking.
Yeah. When?
What type of vehicle were they driving?
Ye-Yeah. Where can we reach you?
Thanks. We'll get back to you.
Some college kids went missing.
They were river rafting and didn't come back.
- How long?
- A couple of days.
- Where?
- Bluefish River area.
They probably stayed over
so they could camp a little longer.
- I'll take a drive out there.
- I can do that, Sheriff. You don't have to.
No. It's fine.
I could use the fresh air.
- Come on, Leon!
- [Dog Barking]
[lnmate]
Hey, come on! Hey!
[Key Rattling]
[lnmates Speaking, lndistinct ]
- What the fuck do you want?
- We're going on a bus ride, Mr. Chavez.
- What, now?
- Yeah, now. You know the drill.
- Well, this shit ain't right.
Where are you taking me?
- Hazelton.
But they said I wasn't going
till next week.
I guess they couldn't wait to see you.
- What about my shit?
- We'll have it boxed up and shipped.
Let's move, Chavez.
Touch me again,
I'll break your fuckin' fingers.
Just move your ass
before I lose my patience.
Oh, no, you don't. No. You're not chaining
that murderer next to me.
Shut up, Crawford.
Let's get Chavez up front followed by
Juarez here and then the rest of 'em.
What's your problem?
My problem is I don't wanna be chained
to a whack job...
who went all post-traumatic stress
on some poor asshole in a bar.
I mean, what-what-what-You know,
couldn't hack the war, soldier boy? Huh?
- Can't handle your liquor?
- Listen. I pushed the guy. He fell.
And he hit his head. Okay? I'm innocent.
- Yeah. So am l.
- And so is everyone else in here.
Never trust a con, huh?
I'm not buying your bullshit,
soldier boy.
I heard you had your hands
all up in the cash register.
-Just leave me alone.
- Oh, now. Soldier boy wants to be left alone.
Oh! She had what?
You get a "Dear John" letter?
Yeah. Yeah, went psycho...
when you found out your wife was fucking
a real marine, you punk-ass bitch?
- That's enough. Shut up.
- Man, I'm just saying, I don't wanna be
chained to a murderer.
I mean, at least stealing cars,
that's an honorable trade.
Jesus Christ, Crawford. Floyd over here
killed three people that we know about.
- That-That's different, man. Floyd's my friend.
-Just get moving!
[Walter]
Keep it moving.
[ Nate ]
Get out of the way. Move. Watch your step.
Here are the transfers. Gas up here.
The sheriff will be told you're coming
20 minutes before you're scheduled to arrive.
- Stupid shit, making us go all night.
- [ Snoring ]
Fucking bullshit! Don't you think?
Shut the fuck up and don't talk.
- [ Grunts ]
- Floyd!
- What the hell?
- What you laughing at, bitch?
- Fuck you, Adolf.
- You're dead, wetback.
Enough!
It's not him you should be worrying about.
Right?
It's all right. I got the word out.
It better be all right, homes.
So...
what you gonna do
when you graduate law school?
Practice law.
- I know that, wiseass.
- [ Gear Shifts ]
- What kind of law?
- The kind that buys me a big townhouse...
on the Upper East Side of Manhattan.
- So it's all about money?
- I plan on doing some pro bono work.
But first I got to be successful.
Hmm. You got some pretty big expectations.
I put myself through school, and I'm gonna
put myself through law school.
And when I'm all done,
I wanna retire to, like, Miami.
South Beach. Live a nice,
comfortable life, you know.
[ Chuckling ]
Retire?
Man, you'll be too old to enjoy it.
Money isn't everything, my friend.
[ Exhales ]
- I gotta go.
-Just can't wait.
- Move.
- Oh, God.
- Walter, where's the fire?
- Man, I got to go.
[ Crawford ] Hey, hey, me too, man.
Can you hurry it up?
You will each have an opportunity
to use the restroom.
¶¶ [Radio: Country]
- [Sheriff] Keep moving.
- [ Whistles ] Hey, sweetie.
Nate? Nate Wilson?
- Well, I'll be damned.
- Hi, Sheriff.
- I haven't seen you since you were about 12.
- [Dog Whimpers]
Well, since your folks moved away.
- Is that Leon? Here, boy.
- [ Chuckling]
Sure is. Fourteen years old
and still acts like a knucklehead.
- How's your dad?
- Uh, Dad passed away a few years back.
- [ Toilet Flushes ]
- Mom's fine though.
- [ Sheriff] I'm sorry to hear that.
- Next.
He was a good man. He was a great help
when we had that trouble...
- at the old mill years ago.
- Mm-hmm.
[Sheriff]
I think it got to him.
[ Chuckling]
I can't believe how you’ve grown.
- Law enforcement to boot.
- Hmm.
- You two know each other?
- Sure thing. Nate was brought up around here.
[ Chuckles ]
Damn, Nate. I knew you were a hick.
- But, like, shit, this is the middle of nowhere.
- Yeah.
- Coffee?
- That'd be great.
Yeah.
That better be my name tag
you're staring at.
Are those guns standard issue, baby?
- [ Groaning ]
- What did you just say?
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Groans ] Easy there, honeypot.
Oh, you like the rough stuff, huh?
Hell, I can do that. Even all tied up,
I can show a girl a good time.
- You like being tied up?
- You mean all hog-tied, bound and gagged...
- to where I can't move a muscle?
- Aw, yeah. That's it, baby.
No. I don't like to be tied up.
Aw, now, don't be that way, sugar.
You, get moving.
[ Lips Smacking ]
Thanks.
So, uh...
why are you going through Greenbrier?
High-profile prisoner.
They wanted to keep the route confidential.
- You going by the old mill road?
- Yeah. That's the plan.
Until we hook up with the main highway
on the other side of the mountain.
[ Grunting ]
[ Cackling ]
[ Panting, Muttering ]
- It's good to see you, Nate. Safe trip.
-Thanks, Sheriff.
Hey, hey. Give us a call
when you get through the back country.
Or give me your cell, and I'll call you.
Maybe we can grab a beer on your way back.
Sounds good.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Exhales ]
I think it's a conspiracy.
I mean, the World Bank is owned
by 12 motherfuckers...
who run our lives.
[ Scoffs ]
And they decide
to put us into recession...
just when I'm about to buy a house.
[ Sighs ] You know, it's like
that old Michael Douglas movie.
You know, the one with the 12 judges...
that decide to hand out
the wrong form of justice?
- What was it again?
- The Star Chamber.
Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
Yeah, I mean, the World Bank
is the fucking Star Chamber.
- [ Sighs ]
- [Horn Honks ]
- Hello.
- What is it?
There's some asshole
blinking his high beam.
- [ Honking ]
- Go around, asshole!
[ Horn Blaring ]
- Now he's slowing down.
- [Honking]
- Make up your mind, prick.
-Just keep cool. Don't slow down.
- [ Sighs ]
- [Horn Blaring]
- [ Blaring Continues ]
- He just shut off his lights.
All right, we're in an emergency procedure.
Don't stop. This could be an escape attempt.
[ Shotgun Cocks ]
What the fuck is going on?
Get on the radio now.
Uh, Hazelton-
Uh, Hazelton, this is Custody Bus-
[Loud Thud]
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Screams ]
Holy shit!
Damn it.
[ lnmates Shouting ]
Uh, Hazelton, this is Custody Bus 2
from Grafton Penitentiary.
Come in. Over. Come in. Over!
- [Tire Bursts ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
[ All Yelling ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Laughs ]
[ lnmates Coughing, Groaning ]
[ Coughing, Groaning Continue ]
- Oh, fuck!
- [ Coughing ]
[ Chavez ]
Hey, guard! Come on!
Let us out! We're gonna fry!
Come on! Get up!
- [Floyd] Hey, don't let me burn!
- [Pounding]
- Please, I don't wanna burn!
- Of course.
Of course the fucking torch
doesn't wanna burn.
- Walter!
- [ Chavez] Come on, man!
Please get us out of here!
We're gonna burn!
Everybody move to the back of the bus.
Chavez, move.
We're getting out the back. Come on!
- [ Coughing ]
- Get up! Come on.
[ Clanking ]
[Flames Crackling]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Nate ] Get the fuck up.
Now, don't be a hero, and we'll be cool.
- All right?
- Let me get the other two out of the bus.
Shut the fuck up and hand me the keys.
They're in the bus. I dropped them.
Drop the gun,
or I'll blow your face off.
[ Shotgun Cocks ]
Maybe l should just save the state
the cost of room and board.
[ Grunts ]
You guys see that shit?
Right in the fucking neck.
Hey, guys, come on out!
Your idiots nearly killed us all.
- [Arrow Whooshing]
- What the fuck was that?
- [ Whooshing ]
- [Shouting, Chattering]
- Shoot the fucker! Come on!
- [Mutant Cackling]
- Who's out there?
- [ Cackling]
Let's move before the bus blows.
You, move.
- Walter's still on the bus.
- I don't give a shit. Move.
Now! Come on. Let's get out of here.
I know I'm a redneck, but a bow
and fucking arrow? Who the fuck does that?
I don't know, and I don't give a shit.
All I know is we're all getting
the fuck out of here.
You, get in that bus.
Get me the keys for these chains.
- [ Coughing]
- [ Coughing ]
Walter.
Come on. I'm gonna get you out of here.
Come on. I got you.
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Grunting ]
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
- [ Shotgun Cocks ]
- [ Coughs ]
Smart move.
[ Coughing ]
Now, get him up.
[ Mutters ]
- [ Grunting, Coughing ]
- Get going.
Okay, let's stop here
and get off these fucking leg irons.
[ Groans ]
Fuck. What's up with these keys?
There are three different sets of keys.
One for the cuffs, one for the cage
and one for the leg irons.
- So hand me the other ones.
- They were in the bus. I told you.
- This is the only set I found.
- Fucking liar. Kill him.
I say who lives and who dies.
The fuck you do, asshole.
Let's just find out exactly what's going on
around here. All right?
- When was Hazelton expecting us?
-Just before dawn.
All right. Now, that gives us
a five-hour head start.
Man, we ain't going anywhere in a hurry
all tethered together by the ankles like this.
You're right. We have to find a way
of getting out of these irons.
You. Sheriff said you grew up around here.
Which way do we go?
- It's been years. I don't know.
-Just kill the son of a bitch, man.
No, no, no, no.
Officer Wilson here's gonna be my compass.
You take me to a phone, you live.
You don't, you die.
- Do I make myself clear?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- What about whoever's out there?
They won't be coming back
if they know what's good for them.
Now, which way do we go?
There's an old forest ranger's fire watchtower
near the top of the mountain.
It should have communication equipment.
- A radio. Maybe a cell phone.
- Good.
So pick up your pig and lead the way.
[ Grunting ]
[ Walter Chuckling ] Miami. South Beach.
That's where I should be.
Retired and surrounded by pussy.
Sounds like a plan.
[ Chavez ]
Hurry it up.
You kill that motherfucker
first chance you get. You hear me?
I hear you, Walter. Save your energy.
There he is!
[ Screams ]
- [ Muttering ]
- Take it easy.
- Take it easy. Nobody wants to hurt you.
- Is that one of 'em?
- A fucking little bitch did all this?
- Don't be stupid.
She's not who I saw on the tow truck.
She's got nothing to do with this.
- Let's just cap the bitch and move on.
- You're gonna be fine.
[Floyd]
Maybe we should fuck her first.
I don't know about you,
but it's been a long time.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Just let me go before it finds me.
- Please.
-Just let her go. We don't need her.
-Just shut up, asshole.
- Nobody's going anywhere.
What happened to you?
My friends and I were rafting
on the Bluefish River...
two days ago.
We were having a good time.
We stopped for the night.
Then it happened.
- What?
- It killed my friends.
"lt"? I thought it was
just some hillbilly.
- It eats people.
- [ Laughing ]
No. You got to be out of your mind.
It's a fucking mutant! Deformed!
It's got, like, three fingers on one hand.
And it kills to feed.
I've seen it.
So then, why doesn't it eat
the animals in the woods?
Because there are none.
It's a cannibal. We're its food.
[Nate ]
We're gonna get you out of here.
Everything's gonna be okay.
What's your name?
- Alex.
- I'm Nate.
Looks like you're screwed too,
aren't you, Nate?
Did you just say rafts?
Yeah. Two of 'em.
Then that's our way out of here.
Down the river.
Now, you take us there, sugar tits,
and I'll make it worth your while.
I think I was better off with that freak.
Now move. Move!
Hey. How old do you think she is?
I don't know, man. Twenty maybe.
Goddamn it. I think I'm gonna
make that one sit and spin.
Man, not if l don't first.
Hey, baby. Baby.
Hey, you like-you like cars?
- I can jack you any car
your sweet little ass wants.
- [ Laughing ]
Huh? Aw.
Well, would you look at that.
[ Crawford] Hey, Floyd, check it out.
Is that an armored car?
[Nate ]
Which way?
I'm not sure.
[ Sighs ]
I thought it was this way.
But it doesn't look familiar.
- [ Nate ] Careful.
- [ Walter Groans ]
You. How old would you say
that thing is?
[ Nate ]
Late '50s maybe.
Let's go.
- [ Clanking ]
- [ Grunting ] Still locked.
- Climb in the cab and take a look around.
- We're wasting valuable time.
- Let's just go.
- He's right.
- Let's go.
- [ Shotgun Cocks ]
Shut the fuck up, bitch, and don't even
think about giving me an attitude.
'Cause I'll shoot you where you stand,
you hear?
You. I said climb in the fucking cab
and take a look around.
- Any dead bodies?
- No. They're gone.
They must have been ejected.
You guys have a look around for bones.
One of the guards must have had some keys.
I don't think you'll find anything.
[ Chavez]
Why?
Because somebody broke the windshield
from the outside to get inside.
All the glass is in here.
And judging from the amount
of dried blood, they died in the cab.
- You find anything else?
- No.
Then get out of there.
Found these.
This might just be our lucky day.
Well, I'll be damned.
[Floyd]
Sweet Mother of Jesus!
- We're fucking rich!
- Holy shit!
- How much money do you think's in there?
- [Brandon ] Who cares?
- lt'll just slow us down.
- Fine. We'll split your share.
- The fuck we will.
- It's equal shares all around.
Why would I give a little fucking beaner
like you anything?
[Blow Lands]
- He won't suspect you.
- [Blow Lands]
You fucking morons.
A little money,
and you all lose your mind?
This is how it's gonna work.
Each of you will carry two bags.
- You. Hand out the bags.
- I don't want the money.
I don't give a shit what you want.
You're carrying the cash. Got it?
[ Grunts ]
- You too.
- I have to help Walter. He can't walk on his own.
I don't give a shit what you got to do.
Pick up the bags.
Go on. Go on.
Now move. Move!
Go on.
[ Groaning ]
- Him too.
- He can't. He's too badly injured.
- I'll carry his bags.
- Or I will.
Everybody's got to carry their own weight.
- Now, pick 'em up.
- [Nate ] Please.
-Just let me carry the bags for Walter.
- Shut up!
I'm waiting.
You smiling bastard.
Pick 'em up.
Pick 'em up!
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Coughing, Laughing ]
You know what they say about money,
don't you, Chavez?
I don't know, Corrections Officer.
What do they say about money?
They say money's hard to spend-
- [ Panting ] when you're dead.
- [ Shouts ]
[ Gun Clicks ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Spitting ]
Now, that was a stupid thing to do,
now, wasn't it? Huh?
Now just pick up the bags.
Shove it up your ass.
Uh-huh. Mm-hmm. Okay.
You hear me?
Shove it up your ass, motherfucker.
[Alex Screams, Sobs ]
Oh, my God!
No! Walter! Walter!
Don't. Don't do it.
[ Quietly ] Not now.
You stubborn fuck.
- [ Creaking ]
- [ Crawford ] What the fuck?
[Alex Screams ]
[ Growls ]
[ Yells ]
Come here.
[ Shrieks ]
This is what's been fucking with us?
A mutant kid?
That's not him.
This thing was a full-grown man.
He was deformed like him.
Oh, would you look at that. It's got
three fucking toes. Probably his kid, huh?
Okay.
Now, let's send this
cocksucking hillbilly a message.
You. Hold it.
[ Whimpering ]
- Floyd.
- Yeah.
- Hold him down.
- Come here.
Hold him down.
- [ Knife Stabs ]
- [Screaming]
- Here's the rafts.
- [ Crawford ] What?
That's a two-man raft.
That's not gonna
hold all of us and the money.
- Huh? So what do we do know?
- It's just for the bags.
You can go fuck yourself
if you think you're taking it all.
- Let's worry about that
once we get these chains off.
- [Rock Striking Leg lrons ]
Man, that ain't gonna work.
- [Shotgun Cocks ]
- This might sting a little at first.
God... damn it! Fuck!
- [ Laughing ]
- What the fuck did you do that for?
Well, you said the rocks
weren't gonna work.
- So I thought that'll do the trick.
- Are you fucking crazy?
I don't know. Maybe I am.
How are we gonna deal with the boat?
Let's just get it in the river first...
and then we'll figure it all out,
all right?
- Uh, I don't think that's a good idea, man.
- Shut up, Crawford.
[ Hissing ]
- Now we're walking.
- You stupid son of a bitch!
- Oh, God!
- [ Groaning ]
Fuckin' asshole!
Why did you fuckin' do that? Huh?
Why did you fuckin' do that?
Tell me! Fuckin' tell me!
Stop it! Stop it!
You got something to say? Huh?
- You got something to fucking say?
- [ Coughing, Spits ]
Looks like you still need this mule
to carry your money.
That's right. Then I guess it's back to you,
Corrections Officer Wilson.
Now, you wanna live,
you get me the fuck out of here.
Now, lead on! Lead on!
Get up! Get up!
Give me that.
Now, move! Move!
Get a fucking move on.
[ Grunting ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Sobbing ]
[Sobbing Loudly]
[ Chuckling ]
Sounds like he's learned his lesson.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Either that, or we just pissed him off.
[Sobbing, Screaming
Loudly]
- [Newscaster On TV] Good evening.
- [Phone Ringing]
[Newscaster Continues ]
- Hello.
- [ Ally ] Hi, Sheriff. I just got a call
from a Cliff Moore.
He said he spotted a truck
up by the upper river inlet yesterday.
- Any sign of the kids?
- No.
If it's all the same to you, I thought
I'd drive out there and take a look.
- Any word from Nate Wilson
or the corrections office?
- No. Not a peep.
Why? Were you expecting a call?
No. I just got a bad feeling,
that's all.
I'll be there in a minute.
[Distant Hooting]
What is that?
It can't be,
but it looks like Preslow's keys.
Good. Now we can get
these fuckin' chains off.
Now!
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasps ]
- [ All Groaning ]
- [Mutant Cackling]
Come on, you motherfuckin' hillbilly!
Come get me!
You got a death wish?
Don't fuck with me again. Right?
[ Panting ]
Fuck.
What the hell is going on?
I'll tell you what's going on.
- He's gonna kill us all. That's what's going on.
- He's hunting us.
Well, he won't be the only one hunting us
in a couple of hours.
- So let's go.
- How are we supposed to do that?
[Fabric Rips ]
Here. Cut it at the knee joint.
You don't have to cut through any bone.
-Jesus fucking Christ.
Fucking pussy. Give me that.
- [ Vomiting ]
[Vomiting Continues ]
Fucking wetback.
[ Laughing ]
[ Crawford Coughing]
- At the knee joint. That's it.
- [ Laughing ]
Piece of shit.
Okay. Let's get out of here.
Come on. Get your bags.
Let's get out of here.
Take that. Come on! Move!
Why don't you call Hazelton?
And say what exactly?
That I got a bad feeling?
That Nate didn't answer his cell?
It just seems like
an awful lot of effort for a hunch.
Well, it's my hunch, so it's my effort.
You really think they staged a breakout?
I don't know what to think, Ally.
What about that truck up by the river?
- You follow it up.
- [Bag Zips ]
[ Floyd ]
What is this place?
[ Chavez ]
This doesn't look like the watchtower.
It's not. I've never seen
this place before.
There has to be some tools
that we can use on these chains.
- [ Chavez] And you better make it quick.
- Move.
- [ Clanking]
-Jackpot!
- Give me that.
- Wait your turn, asshole. [ Grunts ]
[ Metal Clanks ]
[Metal Clanking]
- How much farther?
- [ Panting ] I'm not sure.
- A couple of hours maybe.
- You better find it.
Oh-ho-ho, man. I got to go pinch a loaf.
- I say we split up.
- No.
- Maybe it's a good idea.
- You think this is a democracy?
- You wanna fuckin' debate me?
- What happens when we meet up with your men?
What are you gonna do then, Chavez?
What ever happened
to honor among thieves?
You're gonna kill us all, then you're
gonna take the cash for yourself.
- That's what you're gonna do.
- Yeah, you're right.
I probably will kill all of you.
- Then why shouldn't we kill you now, eh?
- Good luck.
And you better be quick,
or you're surely gonna be dead.
Then I'll kill all you motherfuckers.
But I don't think
that's in your best interest...
- compared to a compromise.
- [ Chuckling ] Hey. Hey.
I just wiped my ass with a $100 bill.
It's comin' out of your share, asshole.
Now, shut the fuck up.
- What do you propose?
- You got one gun. I got two.
These humps have none.
Now, I can't carry
all the bags of cash on my own.
And if you kill me,
that's one less pair of hands.
Plus I have something none of you do.
- Yeah? What's that?
- lnfrastructure.
What?
My men will find me.
And all of you can come with us
to a safe house and not be on the run.
And in exchange for that, you give me
one of the bags you're all carrying...
and you all get to keep the other one.
How can you trust him, Floyd?
We can't.
Deal.
Now get this bum up.
Sorry about your friends.
This isn't going to end well.
- I know that.
- Then why are you going along with them?
Up to now, being all chained together...
I really didn't have
much of a choice, did l?
So that's the fourth time we've passed
that tree in the last two hours.
What are you up to, Nate?
Bidin' my time.
Chavez catches on, man, he'll kill you.
He's right, Nate.
Even I noticed. You gotta be careful.
[ Nate ] You should go back to the road.
Turn yourself in when the police arrive.
I am not going back
through the woods alone, unarmed...
to get sliced up by that hillbilly freak.
I don't know who's worse- him or Chavez.
Listen.
I'll do what I can to help you
once we've reached the ranger station.
I appreciate that, but I think you should
look after yourself first.
Chavez isn't gonna bring anyone
along for the ride that he can't use.
You're damn right.
He'll kill us all for the money.
If that cannibal freak
doesn't beat him to it.
[ Exhales ]
It's ironic.
- What is?
- Money.
I struggled my whole life
to put myself through school...
- so I could get out of here and make good money.
- So?
Now I'm holding in my hands more money
than most people ever make in a lifetime...
and all I wanna do is get rid of it.
[ Panting ]
This is a logging access road.
Fire watchtower's on the other side...
- further along the mountain.
- Hang on. Hang on.
- Hang on. Hang on. Crawford.
- [Faint Howling]
Come here.
- Think you can jack that thing?
- Piece of cake, man.
Finally, a ride out of this shit-hole.
Wait a minute.
That's the tow truck that ran us off the road.
- That's why Crawford here
is gonna go get it for us.
- [ Grunts ]
- Right, Crawford?
- [ Grunts ] I don't know about that, man.
I mean-
It's a truck.
Just run over there and check it out.
Come on! We got the cash.
Now let's get the hell out of here!
No way, man! Send soldier boy, damn it!
I'm not the car thief. You are.
[ Scoffs ]
Could be a trap, man.
Get movin', asshole. Go on.
Damn it.
[ Sighs ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [Lift Whirring]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[Engine Starts ]
Help me! Please!
[ Screaming ]
Fuckin' hillbilly motherfucker!
- I'm gonna find you,
then I'm gonna fuckin' kill you!
- [ Screaming Continues ]
No!
[Screams ]
Let's backtrack and get as far away
from here as possible.
He's not gonna stop until we're all dead.
- Who the fuck is he? Tell me right now!
- [ Gasps ] I don't know!
The fuck you don't!
You grew up here! The sheriff said so!
[ Grunts ]
Now you better get us the fuck out of here
before that freak comes back.
Fuck him. We don't need him anymore.
You kill me,
and you're on your own- lost.
- Maybe I don't give a shit.
- He doesn't know anything! Can't you see that?
Whoa! Just wait a minute.
If you kill him now, we are fucked.
Okay? We have no idea where we're going...
with some crazy hick out there trying
to pick us all off one by one.
No.
[ Chavez]
Enough. Come on.
Now, you don't want to see me angry.
Now, you get me to that station-
and a phone, you hear?
[ Screaming ]
No!
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! God!
I need a rest.
Get the fuck up. We gotta keep moving.
Get up, both of you.
- It's the money that's slowing us down.
We gotta lose it.
- No way.
They'll be looking for us
in a couple of hours.
If we don't show up at Hazelton,
the F.B.I., U.S. Marshals...
and every law officer in West Virginia
is gonna be hunting you.
Brandon's right. If you want to get away,
you need to move quicker.
- Dump the money.
- Now you listen to me.
We move now with the cash,
or we all wait here and die.
- [Bag Drops On Ground]
- [Floyd]She's the one who's slowin' us down.
- [ Gasps ]
- Ah.
- [ Chavez] Be cool.
- [ Sniffs ]
Be cool.
She's a nice piece of ass though.
Let's just pass her around,
then pop her in the head...
and get the fuck out of-
[ Grunting ]
[ Groans ]
- I'm gonna kill you, you fuckin' bitch!
- [ Shotgun Cocks ]
- [ Panting ]
- Not just yet.
Now be cool. Stay calm.
I got this in hand.
Be cool. All right?
Now, you just chill the fuck out.
- You're dead, bitch.
- We're all dead, asshole!
Give me my gun back.
[ Panting ]
Looks like you got some
impulse-control issues there, Floyd.
I don't think so.
You having all three guns does us no good
if that freak comes after us again.
Then that's just a chance
I'm gonna have to take.
They're gonna start lookin' for us soon.
There'll be a full search by morning.
- lf we make it till then.
- We'll make it.
These guys don't look like
they're just gonna let you go.
Why haven't they killed you already?
- They need me.
- And what happens when
they don't need you anymore?
I'm not planning on finding out. There should be
a radio and cell phone at the watchtower.
I'll call for help once we get there.
- How do you plan on
keeping this lot under control?
- There's a ladder.
Only one person can climb up at a time.
It's 75 feet straight up
and through a trapdoor.
Each station has a gun hidden in it,
and I know where they keep it.
It's a tight space.
I can ambush Chavez when we're up there.
I just want to go home.
It'll be okay, Alex.
I'll get you out of this.
[Faint Shrieking]
[ Chavez ] Walkin' a little slow there,
aren't you, Floyd?
She hurt you that bad?
- Die, bitch!
- Wha-
[ Both Grunting ]
Come on.
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Yells ]
Sheriff Carver calling Deputy Lane.
Come in. Over.
- Ally, this is Calvin. Come in. Over.
- [ Radio Static ]
County Dispatch, this is Sheriff Carver.
- I want to report an emergency. Over.
- [ Man On Radio ] Go, Sheriff.
The custody bus
from Grafton Penitentiary has crashed...
off the old mill road near mile marker 37.
I'm goin' in to take a look around.
Carver out.
- Dispatch, this is Carver.
- [Man On Radio ] Come in, Sheriff.
[Sheriff] There is no one on board.
Gonna see if l can track them.
- Carver out.
- Roger that.
[ Grunts ]
Come on. Let's go.
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Fist Smacks ]
All right. Stop. He's had enough.
- I say when the Nazi bastard's had enough!
- [Floyd Groaning]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Groans ]
[ Spits ]
- Now, which way did they go?
- I don't know.
I didn't see 'em go.
Come on.
Well, what do we do with him?
Fuck him. Leave him.
Nate, l-
I can't run anymore.
I- I just need a minute.
We need to keep moving.
We just have to make it a few more hours,
and then we'll be fine.
The police are coming. You can do this.
Listen, Chavez.
You can't get out of here alone.
- You know that, right?
- I'll be fine.
- Well, I can get you out of these woods.
- So, what do you want?
A fair deal.
- How much?
- [ Scoffs ] No.
I don't want the money. I don't need it.
But you gotta promise me that
you'll let me go when your boys show up.
Fine.
And, uh, I also need one of those guns.
Why should I give you a gun?
Because whatever's hunting us is gonna
continue hunting us till we're both dead.
It's simple tactical strategy.
Two gunners are better than one.
- And why should I trust you?
- [ Scoffs ]
Why would I fuck you?
I helped you with Floyd, didn't l?
Well, I didn't run.
[ Groaning ]
[ Spits, Panting ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Chittering]
- [ Door Creaks ]
- [ Lock Clicks ]
- [ Muttering ]
- [ Chittering Continues ]
[ Muttering Continues ]
Ah.
[ Muttering ]
- [Engine Starts ]
- [ Groans ]
[ Barking ]
[Distant Whistle ]
[Distant Chittering]
[lnhales, Exhales ]
Where will you take them, Nate?
[ Breathing Heavily ]
I 'm too old for this shit.
Come on.
We gotta go. We're not far now.
- Psst!
- [Nate ] We gotta move.
We gotta keep moving.
- [Alex ] I can't go on anymore.
- [Nate ] Come on.
[ Whispers ]
Over there.
Okay. Let's leave the bags down over here.
Come on.
We'll come back for them later.
- [ Screams ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Fist Smacks ]
- [ Screams ]
You shouldn't have run.
Stop it! Stop it!
- [ Grunts, Sobs ]
- Shut the fuck up, puta!
This is all your fault!
- Maybe I should end you first!
- Wait. That's not gonna get us anywhere.
It gets the bitch out of the way though!
The watchtower's just right over the hill.
[ Grunts ]
You've been leading us
in circles all night.
Why should I believe you now?
It's just over the hill-
right there. I swear.
- lt'll take two minutes to find out. Please.
- Get this bitch out!
[ Grunting ]
Move.
[ Whimpers ]
[ Chavez ] This is it?
A bunch of fuckin' charcoal?
- It must've been burned down.
- No shit.
So now what?
I don't know. This is the only place
I knew of that had a radio.
You've been fuckin' with me
the whole time, haven't you?
- No.
- Fuck you. You're a liar!
He's not lying.
Nate thought the tower was gonna be here.
We were gonna barricade ourselves in
and call for help.
Well, let's just keep moving, all right?
It's gotta be at least 3:.00 or 4:.00 a.m. by now.
- We could go northeast.
- I've had enough of your bullshit.
Get on your fuckin' knees!
- Get on your fuckin' knees!
- There's a small town 10 miles past the river.
- I'll take you there.
- Fuck you. Say good-bye, asshole.
- Think about this, Chavez.
- He's out there.
What?
I can feel him.
He's been following us. He's close.
Shh.
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Gun Cocks ]
- I warned you.
- [ Growling ]
- [ Chavez Screaming ]
Get it off me!
Get this fucking dog off me!
Drop the gun! Down, boy!
- Get the dog off me!
- Take his guns, Nate.
Are you okay?
I'm fine, Sheriff.
Just really glad to see you.
When you didn't answer your cell, l-
I came looking.
- There are others out there.
- How many?
Don't know. At least one other prisoner
and some freak hillbilly local.
Hillbilly? That can't be.
Please. Let's just get out of here.
Okay. Come on. Let's move it up there.
Hey, you, come on.
Move your ass. Get up.
Come on! Move it!
Move it,
you son of a bitch! Move!
Come on, honey.
He's close. He's really close.
- Who is?
- He's a fucking monster.
Please. Please. I just want to get home.
Oh, all right. Just-
Just calm down, little lady.
[Cackling]
- [ Screams ]
[ Whimpering ]
- [Cackling]
- [ Gunshots ]
If you think you're
moving out of this forest...
without going back for the cash,
you're fuckin' wrong.
Now move. Move.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Laughs ]
Jackpot.
Chavez, you stupid son of a bitch.
[ Grunting, Panting ]
- [Police Radio Chatter]
- This is where the sheriff reported the bus crash.
On foot in this terrain,
they should be within this perimeter.
I want it approached from all sides,
and we'll work our way in.
When is the air support getting here?
They're in the air.
They should be here within the hour.
Gentleman, we have a man out there.
I want all precautions taken.
- Let's move.
- Yes, sir.
- Where's my bags?
- Are you sure this was the spot?
Yes, this was the spot.
Now where's my goddamn fuckin' money?
- Huh?
- It's Floyd.
I'm gonna kill that motherfucker.
No. I'm gonna skin him alive first...
then I'm gonna fucking kill him!
Shit!
[ Grunting, Panting ]
- [ Bone Crunches ]
- [Floyd Screaming]
You-You stay here and you guard them.
You hear?
You don't move! Don't move!
[ Panting ]
That'll teach that motherfucker!
[ Laughing ] Who's laughin' now,
you Mexican piece of shit?
[ Screaming ]
Let me go, Brandon.
I can't.
I'm sorry. If l do, he'll kill me.
- [Nate ] Then let her go.
- I'm not leaving you.
- [ Grunting ]
- [Chavez] l see you!
- You cocksucker! You're fuckin' dead!
- [Laughing]
[ Grunting]
Fuck you, Chavez!
You can pick it up!
You can pick it all up!
[ Laughing ]
- You're fuckin' dead!
- [ Cackles ]
- Dead!
- Fuck you!
[ Cackles ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
Come on.
- [Chavez] Come on out, you hick motherfucker!
- [ Screaming ]
I'll kill you with my bare fuckin' hands!
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Screams ]
Shit! My money!
[ Gasping ]
- [ Groans ]
- My God.
[ Brandon ]
What do we do now?
We die... if we don't start fighting back.
[ Gasps ]
Let's head towards that town!
Come on! Move! Let's go!
[Horn Honking]
[Honking Continues ]
[ Engine Rumbling ]
- It's gotta be a trap.
- Yeah, but why would he think it'd work?
What the fuck does he want?
You hear that? You hick-ass motherfucker!
What do you want? Huh?
Tell me, you son of a bitch.
Can't be the money.
You've already fuckin' burnt that!
Huh? What do you want?
[ Cackles ]
Okay. You want to fuck with me? Huh?
- Come here. Come here.
- What the hell are you doing?
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Shrieking ]
Come on, fuck-stick!
Huh? A head for a head!
There she is. Take hers.
Come on, you bastard!
It's what you want, isn't it?
- Take the bitch!
- [ Shotgun Cocks ]
Run.
- No!
- [ Screams ]
[ Cackles ]
- Alex!
- Nate! [ Screams ]
- [Nate ]Alex!
- Stop!
- No!
- Alex!
- [ Engine Revs ]
- [Alex Screaming]
Alex!
- You son of a bitch! We've got to go after her.
- No.
He's gone. She's gone.
We're moving on.
- I'm gonna leave her to him.
- I said, we're moving on.
Now lead us out of here.
No.
[ Shotgun Cocks ]
This is something
I should have a long time ago...
you stupid son of a bitch.
[ Grunts ]
Here. I'm sorry I let it go this far.
- What are you gonna do?
- [Gun Cocks ]
Try and reach that town.
Good luck.
Get her back, Nate.
Should we kill him?
I'm not a murderer,
Brandon, and neither are you.
[ Gun Clicks ]
[Alex Screams ]
Somebody!
[Screaming]
Help me!
[ Screaming, lndistinct ]
Please let me go!
[Screaming]
Help me!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Muttering, Cackling ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming, lndistinct ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Whimpering ]
[ Cackling ]
- [ Sobbing, Shouting, lndistinct]
- [ Panting ]
[ Shrieks ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Panting ]
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Screaming, Sobbing ]
- [ Grunting ]
- Nate! Nate!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Screams ] Help me!
- [ Cackles ]
- Please let me go!
[ Screaming, lndistinct]
[ Sobbing ]
Nate!
[ Screaming ]
Please, somebody!
[Sobbing]
Help me!
[Rustling]
- [ Barking ]
- Leon. Hey, boy.
Come here, boy. Come here.
[ Panting ]
- [ Growls ]
- Find her, Leon. Find Alex, okay?
- Go, boy.
- [ Barking ]
[ Whimpering ]
- [ Buzzing ]
- [ Gasping ] Help me.
[ Gasps ]
[ Weakly]
Help me.
[ Gurgling ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
- [ Gasps, Sobs ]
- [Door Opens]
[Screaming, Sobbing]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Groans ]
- [ Sobbing ]
- [ Cackling ]
[ Shouts, lndistinct ]
No!
- [ Muttering ]
- [ Screaming ] No!
No!
[Screaming]
[Helicopter Passing Overhead]
- [Helicopter Retreating]
- [ Gasping ]
[ Panting ]
[Helicopter Retreating]
[Helicopter Approaching]
[ Helicopter Retreating]
You made a bad choice, army boy.
[ Panting ]
Hey! Hey!
Here! I'm here!
Hey!
- [ Muttering ]
- [ Chavez] There you are.
I've been looking for you.
[Babbles ]
Bring it, you motherfucker!
What's the matter,
you cracker-ass fuckin' freak?
- Scared of losing your head?
- [ Growls ]
- [ Gasps, Groans ]
- [ Clicking ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Screams ]
[ Grunting ]
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Bones Snap ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
[ Cackles ]
[ Coughing ]
Is that it, huh?
That all you got?
[ Both Grunting ]
Now you're dead!
I'm gonna kill you now!
You're dead.
[ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
[ Groans ]
[ Winces, Groans ]
God!
Looks like we're even.
- [ Grunting ]
- Puto.
[ Coughs, Groaning ]
- Shit. [ Coughing ]
- [Groaning, Laughing]
[ Snickering ]
- [ Rapid Breathing ]
- Ain't so tough.
- [ Screams ]
- [ Flesh Ripping ]
[ Coughs, Groans ]
[ Screams ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Groaning Continues ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Flesh Rips ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Muttering ]
- [ Mutters ]
- [ Rapid Breathing ]
[ Coughing, Grunts ]
- [Bone Cracking]
- [ Muttering ]
[Cracking Continues ]
[ Muttering ]
[Knife Cutting]
Yeah. Good boy.
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps, Panting ]
[ Panting Continues ]
[ Creaking ]
- Where is he?
- I don't know. Just hurry.
[ Gasping, Sobs ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Groans ]
Nate, she's dead.
[Creaking]
[ Shrieks ]
[ Both Grunting ]
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Gasping ]
[ Cackling ]
[ Groans ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Growls ]
[ Barking, Snarling ]
[ Screaming ]
- [Blow Lands ]
- [Leon Whimpers ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [Mutant Cackling]
[ Mutters, Cackling ]
[ Rapid Breathing ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Growls ]
- No!
[ Groans ]
[ Panting ]
Is he dead?
Yeah.
[ Whimpers, Sniffs ]
Let's get out of here.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Alex Groans ]
- [ Groans, Panting ]
- [Siren Wailing In Distance ]
Look.
It's almost dawn.
We made it through the night.
Thank you, Nate...
for coming back for me.
[ Cackling]
[ Metal Clangs ]
[ Alex ]
Oh, my God!
[Screaming]
Oh, God, Nate!
[ Screaming, Shouting ]
[ Cackling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Shouting ]
- [ Screaming ]
- Oh, God.
[ Screams ]
- [ Cackling ]
- Get the shotgun!
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Screams ]
Nate!
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Cackling ]
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Clattering ]
[ Hissing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams, Groaning ]
[Flames Crackling]
[Nate Grunting]
Alex! Alex!
We gotta get out of here. Alex!
[ Screams ]
- It's me.
- Get Alex first.
[ Grunting ]
I got you.
[ Alex Groans ]
[ Grunting ]
My leg.
- [ Groans ]
- Give me your arm.
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Nate ]
It's okay. He's gone.
Funny-
All that money...
up in flames.
You really didn't kill that bartender,
did you?
No.
So, now what?
You didn't make it.
Nobody goes looking for a dead con.
You'd do that for me?
Just stay out of trouble.
I will.
Trust me.
[ Sobs ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Coughs, Muttering ]
[Sirens Wailing]
[ Officer]
Is it them?
[Police Radio Chatter]
[ Chattering ]
Miami, South Beach...
surrounded by pussy.
I'm gonna miss you, Walter.
- [Blow Lands ]
- [ Groans ]
[ Gasping ]
Like I said...
never trust a con.
[ Muttering ]
- [Blow Lands ]
- [Brandon Screams ]