The boat can leave now.
Tell the crew.
Chopper One to headquarters.
We got a sailboat on a collision course
with just about every boat in the harbor.
Where's it at, Chopper One?
Just off Staten Island.
It was almost run down by the ferry.
We can't raise anyone on board.
Okay, Chopper One.
We'll send out a patrol boat.
- That must be it, Bill.
- Okay.
We'll take a look at her.
Chopper One to headquarters.
The harbor patrol's coming
alongside the sailboat now.
Ahoy there!
This is the harbor patrol.
Anyone on board?
Hey, Sarge, that boats abandoned.
Yeah, she looks abandoned.
The only question is, why?.
Hey, if she is, Marty,
we stand to make a nice little bonus
when we bring her in.
Yeah. Let's get over there
and check
Bring her up alongside.
Chopper One to headquarters.
This is headquarters.
Come in, Chopper One.
The harbor patrol is about to
board now. Still no sign of life.
Skipper, that craft
must be a real turkey.
- Hey, watch out forthe sail!
- Huh?
What?.
What the hell's going on?
I'm sorry.
The winch is broken.
I'll fix the sail.
You go below and look around.
Okay.
Hey, grab that on top
and bring it over here.
Okay.
Don't move.
Stay where you are, mister.
Throw your hands on the deck
I told you not to move!
I mean it!
One more step,
and I'm going to blast you.
Don't move, I said!
Don't move!
Where did they find
this abandoned boat?.
I'll put someone on it.
The boys in blue been there yet?.
Thanks for your information.
You're a sweetheart.
Get West in here.
Peter, the chief wants you.
Right. Thanks. See you.
- What can I do for you, Chief?.
- Sit down.
- Are you busy now?.
- That depends.
I'm giving you an assignment.
What did she say?.
- Pier 15- there's a story there.
- Is it something big?
Boat without anyone on it,
cop killed.
Poke around a bit.
See what you can find.
Okay. I'll let you know.
West.
Keep the British out of
your prose, huh?
- Don't mention your uncle owns the paper.
- As if I would.
They're going over
the last details.
They are leaving now.
Do you see them?
Yes, they are bringing the body
to the coroners for an autopsy.
All right, back! Back!
You there, back overthere!
There's nothing to see.
Well, Miss Bowles, we're waitin'.
Yes, it's my father's boat.
Where's your father now?
I don't know.
I was hoping you could tell me.
I haven't heard from him in over a month.
I see.
And how long since you
last spoke to him?
Three months,
when he set sail for the Antilles
to join some friends.
The Antilles?
Will someone please tell me
what the hell's going on?
We already have.
Man hiding on his boat, which was adrift,
killed a member of the Coast Guard.
Yeah, but... my father-
Where is he?
I mean, what's happened to him?
That's just what we'd like
to know, Miss Bowles.
Sorry to get you down here
at this hour.
I can't understand
why they're in such a hurry.
I can't understand, myself.
The DA's office phoned twice
before you arrived, Doc.
Well, let's get it over with.
Have you already examined him?
Yeah.
I made one ortwo notes.
In my opinion, the death of the poor bastard
was caused by massive hemorrhage
due to a huge laceration
of the jugular.
Do you have a hypothesis
for the cause of this injury?.
Take a look at these edges.
To me it's quite obvious
what caused it.
There appear to be clear indications
of one or more bites.
Look carefully.
Pass me the scalpel.
I wouldn't be able to cut my way
through tissue paper with that,
let alone carry out an autopsy.
Take better care
of your instruments, James.
Don't scream.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
My name's Peter West,
and I'm a reporter.
I'm gonna take my hand away,
and you're not gonna scream, okay?.
Sorry if I frightened you,
but if I hadn't, you'd have screamed,
and our friend up there
would have been on to both of us.
Who are you, and what are you
doing on my father's boat?.
I've already told you.
My name's West, and I'm a reporter.
- I've been following you all aftemoon.
- Clever.
Professional curiosity?.
The police version doesn't convince me.
I guess it doesn't convince you either.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be here.
What were you looking for?
You got a hell of a nerve.
You know that?.
- You're not so bad yourself.
- Please.
Let me put it this way.
I've got some information,
you've got some information.
So why don't we throw it together
and see what we come up with?
I think I've already found
what you're looking for.
What do we do now?.
Well, I've got an idea,
but I'm gonna need your help,
unless you want to explain
to some judge
what you were doing on your
father's boat in the middle of the night.
Now, just do what I tell you, okay?.
- Okay.
- Good. Come on.
What the hell's-
Excuse me.
Don't give me the same old story.
- Well, actually, Officer-
- Same old story, huh?
This is all your fault.
You realize that, don't you?
- It was his idea, not mine.
- Listen to her, Miss Goody Two-shoes.
It wasn't her fault?.
It was all my idea?
Whose idea was it to have
a romantic setting down by the water?.
I'd have settled for an empty boxcar.
No, never again.
Not another boxcar.
She takes after her mother.
They're both bananas.
- You leave my mother out of this!
- She's crazy-
Enough of this!
Both of you, get out of here.
Anything you say.
Come on, sweetie pie.
Good night, Officer.
Yeah.
Out of my sight.
Good night.
"To my daughter Anne,
in case anything should happen to me.
Due to my morbid curiosity, I have
managed to contraot a strange disease.
They are taking care of me as
if I were some sort of guinea pig,
but I know I'll never leave
this island again,
at least not alive.
I haven't been a good father,
but I have always loved you.
One last kiss from Dad.
Matool. "
It's dated 15 September.
Listen, Chief. I'm sure there's some
connection that ties this all together.
Well, her father,
the disease he mentions,
the boat, and the guy
that got killed as well.
Yeah, well, it's her idea to go.
Okay, Chief, fine.
And, Chief, you'll fix
the tickets, okay?.
Thanks. You're beautiful.
- I think it's three hours.
- Yes.
If it's on schedule,
we should arrive in St. Thomas at-
- Flight 782 for St. Thomas-
- Was that us?
- Passengers, proceed to Gate 8.
- Let's go.
No, no, no. I'll do that.
Last call for TWA flight 682
to Saint Thomas.
All aboard, please.
This is your final call.
Do you want to check on the boat,
or should we go to the hotel?
I don't know.
Whatever you think
Señor, do you know anyone
who can rent us a boat?.
Boat, señor?.
I'm sorry.
Not easy here to find boat.
We want to go to Matool.
It's very important.
I'm willing to pay whatever it costs.
Just now I remember
something, señor.
What did I tell you.
This moming, friend of mine say
two Americans cruise the islands.
That's his boat.
Last one at edge of jetty.
Maybe they take you.
You ask
Thanks.
Pedro not help you good, señor?.
Surely, yes. Here you are.
Thanks again
and good luck
Extra water.
Store it in the galley.
Aye, aye, sir.
Ahoy there. Hi.
- Hi, yourself.
- How're you doing?
I am Peter West,
and this is Anne Bowles.
Susan Barrett.
And you're talking to Brian Hull.
You wouldn't be looking
for a boat ride?
We would. We hear you're
going on a tour of the islands.
Yeah, a little cruise. Two months
of fishing, bathing and sunshine.
Well, we have to go to Matool.
We're trying to locate Anne's father.
She hasn't heard from him for some time.
Matool.
That's not a cool place to hit.
The natives claim it's cursed.
They avoid it.
We have to go there, anyway.
And you want a ride from us?
If that's possible.
Any experience with boats?
Mm-hmm.
And the lady?.
I was bom on a boat.
Okay. We'll have to load more supplies.
You pay your share.
- Deal?
- A deal.
Step on board. Here.
I'll wam you right now.
Don't expect us to come sight seeing
once we get there.
I found that it never pays
to ignore native superstitions.
This is Matool calling
Guadalupa One.
Matool calling Guadalupa One.
Come in, Guadalupa.
This is Dr. Menard
calling Guadalupa One.
Menard calling Guadalupa One.
Come in, Guadalupa One.
Still no luck?.
No.
I'm afraid it's useless
to go on trying.
Then we're cut off
from the rest of the world.
Well, no, hardly.
No, I wouldn't say that.
I want to leave
this damn island right now.
Well, you can't right now.
The radio isn't working.
How convenient for you.
I wouldn't be surprised
if you broke it on purpose.
You're tired.
Go to hell!
David, are you going out?.
I have to go to the hospital.
Have they found another one?
They have, haven't they?.
- Tell the truth.
- Now, calm down.
- Where did they find it this time?
- You really mustn't drink so much.
I asked you a question.
They're on the other side of the island.
When will they reach this side?
Tell me.
I really think you ought to rest.
We'll talk about it later.
There's really no need
to agitate yourself so much.
I hate you.
No. You don't know
what you're saying.
How you'd like to be able
to pass me off as crazy.
The truth is I'm a danger for you.
Apart from a handful
of superstitious natives,
I'm the only one
who knows what you're doing.
And don't think I'm going
to keep my mouth shut.
I'm going to tell everyone
that you are the one who's crazy,
demented, cruel, evil-
I'll be at the hospital.
Hospital.
You still see yourself as
the scientist you once were, don't you?
Well, you're not. You're no better
than one of their witch doctors.
Just stop it!
- My research is-
- Research!
You call fooling around with superstitions
and voodoo rites research?
You know perfectly well that the work
I'm doing is very important.
- I wouldn't be here if it wasn't.
- I don't give a damn!
I don't want to stay on this island
one more hour.
You won't be happy
until I meet one of your zombies.
Now, look
As soon as I've understood
the phenomenon, we'll leave.
I don't believe you.
I don't believe anything you say anymore.
Miguel.
I have to go to the hospital.
Make sure nobody comes near the house.
Si, señor. Miguel guard.
Doctor no worry.
- Nobody.
- Si, señor.
Tell me the depth, Susan.
Will I hit?
Well?
Nine, eight.
You'll have to pass straight,
this way.
- We were lucky to find you two.
- You could say that.
We're sure not having the same luck
trying to find your island.
We should be somewhere
around here, right?.
More or less, yeah.
But, acoording to the map,
there are no islands forthe next 50 miles.
Not necessarily true.
So many islands around here,
a lot haven't been charted.
The last couple we saw aren't
on any chart. It's hit or miss.
- We could spend a month out here.
- Like looking for a needle in a haystack
- You don't want to go back, do you?
- No. We'll find Matool.
That's a promise.
Don't go counting on us forever.
Don't forget, we're on vacation.
Brian!
It's time to work
I want to take some shots.
Brian, quick,
turn off the motor.
Look! Overthere!
See?
That's another island.
Maybe we're in luck at last.
Who's to say that that isn't Matool?
Help!
There's a shark!
It's going to attack her.
Hurry!
I'm going back down!
- There was a man down there.
- What?.
- There was a man.
- A man?
He's over here, Doctor.
Don't think he'll last 'til the morning.
What shall I do?
Take him into the sacristy.
I don't want the others to see him.
There's no need to alarm them.
Tie him down securely.
Doctor! Doc!
Doctor, everybody leaving now.
Quiet, please.
Nurse, look after that patient.
Doctor, the natives leaving village.
Everybody go.
What do we do?
Talk about it outside.
- Well, what happened?
- Don't know.
Fear in village.
There's great trouble and commotion.
It's the juju man,
the new one.
It's big and plenty.
They seem possessed
by all the devils in hell.
How ridiculous.
The natives are going crazy.
They run all over village.
They pick up their possessions
and disappear.
Where did they go?
They going inland.
They're making voodoo, I think
Voodoo.
Voodoo won't solve anything.
Doctor, they're afraid.
Very much afraid, these people.
You too.
You're afraid, aren't you, Lucas?
This is all right.
Give her two orthree feet of slack,
and then tie her off.
Doctor.
Doctor Menard.
What?.
What's wrong?
Matthias.
Matthias?
Matthias what?.
He's-
Why don't you say it?.
Are you afraid to say it?
Huh?
It's not that.
I don't believe in voodoo.
I don't believe in voodoo either,
but the natives do.
So we investigate
the phenomena, right?.
I've seen them,
and you've seen them.
Now, Matthias,
he's one of them, is he?
Well, we have to help him.
We have to try to help him.
So we go to the hospital.
Come on.
The drive shafts cracked.
It must've been the shark when he hit us.
Is it serious?
Well, we have two possibilities:
Either we go ashore and walk around
until we come to the local repair shop,
- or-
- Or?.
Or we remain here, fire off some flares
and hope that somebody will help us.
We'll have a tough time making it to the next
island if we don't get that shaft fixed.
Poor Matthias.
Let's go.
- What is it, Lucas?
- Rockets.
There's somebody firing rockets.
- Rockets?
- I see them, man.
- You know where they come from?
- They coming from Catfish Bay.
I better go and investigate.
Take care of him for me.
Who is It?. The devil?
We'll know soon enough.
Let's get this over with.
Bury them now, Missey?.
No, not yet.
There are two more
who are going to die soon.
Dad! Where are you?
Why did you leave me alone to die?
I've seen you.
With my own eyes.
Come to me.
Father.
Don't leave me.
I buried you,
but I see you walking.
I met your father
about three years ago
when he first came out
to these islands.
Whenever he could, he would stay
for a few weeks here with me...
on Matool.
Then he...
became a victim of the disease.
He insisted upon staying
in spite of everything I said to him.
I insisted that he should leave,
but he wouldn't.
He felt that he could in some way
become a guinea pig,
that he could help in discovering
what was causing the horrors
that were destroying our island,
transforming it into
a wasteland of terror.
Extremely courageous man.
I remember the day
when my assistant came to tell me
that your father was dying.
Doctor!
Your friend. Quickly.
Get closer.
It's over for me.
I feel I'm about to die.
I've had a good life,
but I never thought
it would end this way.
I've got two things to ask
Listen carefully.
They're very important, my friend.
I have written to my dear child Anne.
The letter, see that it gets to her.
And make sure...
my soul rests
in everlasting peace.
I spent the day
watching over his body.
But I knew eventually
I would have to find the courage
to release him from the living dead.
The boat can leave now.
Tell the crew.
What exactly did my father die of?
- And what happened to the boats crew?.
- Yes, Doctor.
What is all this about the dead
coming back to life again
and having to be killed
a second time?
What the hell's going on here?
- You ever heard of voodoo?
- Voodoo?
Doctor, you gotta be joking.
That's kid stuff.
I mean, voodoo's just
plain superstitious horseshit.
Basically, it's a mixture
of two religions.
One- Catholicism, brought here
by the Spanish conquistadores.
And two- African tribal rites that
were brought here by the slave trade.
Well, whatever it is,
it makes the dead stand up and walk
- I've seen it with my own eyes.
- That's impossible.
I know it's impossible.
I've seen it.
The natives say it's...
something to do with voodoo.
Some evil witch doctor
creates these zombies,
but I'm sure there's
a natural explanation,
and I'm determined to find it.
Something's happened to Mr. Fritz.
What happened to him?
No one told me.
Take a look
Go inside.
Bad news?
Fritz, a friend of mine,
happens to be the only other
white man on the island.
He's had an accident.
We've got him at the hospital.
- I'm sure he'll be all right.
- Is there anything we can do?
No, no. Thank you.
As you wish.
Well, yes.
My wife's alone at the cottage.
Our manservant is looking after her.
I'd be very grateful
if you'd call on her.
It's only seven or eight miles up the trail.
You can't miss it.
Go on. I'll see you later.
Doctor, I thought it was
more advisable to bring him here.
You did right.
What happened to your arm, Fritz?.
I left the living dead.
Too late.
I saw it too late.
Where?
Where did you see this?
In the village.
I saw it.
I can't-
In this village?
Yeah.
- Tell Lucas to lock all the doors.
- It's no use.
It's a waste of time
to lock the doors.
They'll be here soon...
to destroy us all.
We must have driven
eight miles by now.
Yes, more than that.
Why don't we just sail to the nearest
place where we know there's a shipyard?
- After we've seen the doctor's wife.
- Look, Peter. Is that it?.
Nice layout.
This is the nicest place
on the island.
The doctor's doing all right,
by the look of it.
But there's something fishy
about him.
Mrs. Menard.
Mrs. Menard?
It doesn't seem like anybody's at home.
What do we do now?.
Might as well go inside.
Is there anybody here?
Come on.
Brian, you drive.
Quick, Brian! Hurry!
Get us out of here, please!
My God, did my father
become one of those?
No, he didn't.
You heard the doctor.
Let's find that hospital and get the
hell out of here as quickly as we can.
Look out!
Damn it.
The radiator's had it.
Well, I think my ankle's
gone the same way.
We're gonna have to walk now.
Think you can make It?.
- We don't have much choice, do we?
- Come on.
Let's get to that hospital before dark
Give him a hand.
Drums.
Getting closer.
I hate it!
Damn you, you bastards!
I can't take it.
Come on.
They're doing a little voodoo on us.
Yes, well, anyway, let's hurry up.
It's going to be dark soon.
Lucas?
You know what is the cause of all this?
- Is it voodoo?
- Lucas not know nothing, man.
The father of my father always say,
when the earth spit out the dead,
they will come back
to suck the blood from the living.
That's nonsense.
That's just a stupid superstition.
Yes, you are right, Doctor.
You know many more things than Lucas.
I don't believe that voodoo
can bring the dead back to life.
And Lucas not believe...
that the dead be dead.
No. It's no good.
I can't go any further.
Gotta rest up for a bit.
Okay, Peter.
We'll take a quick five here.
Gotta be close to that
damn hospital now.
Look. Why don't you two rest here.
And we'll take a look up ahead, right?
- What is it?
- It's a helmet.
Must be over 400 years old.
This must have been a cemetery
for the Spanish Conquistadores.
I'm sorry I dragged you into all this.
It's my father we came
looking for, isn't it?
You know,
when we get back to New York-
Uh-uh.
You don't have to say anything now.
It's just-
I'm so scared we're not
gonna make it off this island.
Susan.
Come on, let's go,
before it's too late.
We can't leave her here alone.
- She's dead.
- Brian, don't you understand? She's dead.
There's nothing that you can do here.
Come on, man. Let's go.
Brian!
- Leave me here.
- Come on, get up!
Is that a church?
We've done it.
He's fading rapidly.
Shall I continue with the transfusion?
It's useless.
He's gonna die anyway.
Doctor! Please! Open the door!
Come on, Doctor!
Open the door now!
Out there,
they're coming back to life.
They're everywhere.
What about my wife?
Thank you.
What the hell are they, Doctor?
I don't know.
It all started about
three months ago.
One of the fishermen
said he'd seen his wife
walking in the village at night,
only she'd been dead for two days.
Well, at the time,
nobody believed the story.
In these islands,
fantastic legends-
voodooism, zombies-
have been around for centuries.
As a man of science,
I don't believe in voodooism.
But the phenomenon
defies logical explanation.
I've attempted to apply
the disciplines of bacteriology,
virology,
even of radiology.
We've performed tests for epilepsy
and for catalepsy.
Nothing fits.
- Will that hold 'em?
- Not a chance.
- How can we stop them?
- Here, take this.
I've got another gun in my office.
There's two drums of kerosene
in the sacristy.
Right, Doc. You two stay where you are.
Watch those windows.
Nurse, come with me.
We've gotta get some empty bottles,
all you can find.
Dr. Menard.
No!
No! No!
You bring some too.
Come on.
Go get some more bottles.
Brian, two more.
Shoot her, West!
Shoot her!
Come on, Brian.
We have to get to the boat.
Can't we go any faster?
The drive shaft could go any second.
We'll make it to San Cristobal.
There's a yard there that can fix-
What is it?
I feel so cold. So cold.
I don't want to become like-
Take me home, Peter.
Save me.
I beg you.
He's dead.
What do we do now?
Lock him in the bilge,
take him back with us to the States.
Someone there might be able
to do something.
But... we can't risk it.
You know what he might turn into.
Well, I'll make sure that he's safe.
We've got to take him back with us.
He's the only proof we've got
that this all happened.
And we will need proof, unfortunately.
Otherwise, they'll just think
that we're crazy.
I don't care.
I feel dead myself.
Take the wheel.
Let's see if we can find something
more cheerful on the radio.
In the latest news,
the situation here in New York City
since the discovery of the first zombie
is getting worse by the hour.
There's chaos in the streets.
The National Guard
cannot control the situation.
In every borough of the city,
from Bronx to Brooklyn,
from Queens to Coney Island,
the zombies are everywhere.
The governor has declared
a state of national emergency
and has asked the president
for immediate assistance.
The zombies are everywhere.
There seems to be no way to stop them.
The city is at their mercy.
Barricades have been thrown up
throughout Manhattan.
General Stein of the National Guard said
that missiles will be used if necessary.
[CL]Shub-Niggurath
Viña del Mar - Chile