Previously on...
Suits
We just went
through a civil war,
and the world knows it.
You're using
privileged information
to target our clients.
Pearson Hardman
is falling apart.
I never thought
you'd betray your own firm.
I did nothing wrong.
Jesus!
You're the guy
that nobody wants
but we can't get rid of.
You order me to rescind
an offer
due to a firm-wide
hiring freeze.
Two minutes later,
you hire a fifth-year.
Katrina Bennett.
I need you to waive
my non-compete
so I can take a position
at another firm.
- You went to Louis?
- He didn't betray us, Harvey.
He found the problem.
You may have fended off
this attack,
but we're not
the only ones circling.
We fended you off,
we'll fend off the rest.
I want my name
on the door.
Nice!
- Ugh!
- H-o-r-s.
That means you get an "e,"
you lose.
- Thank you. I can spell.
- Too bad you can't shoot.
Crumpled paper.
Winners don't blame
the ball or the rim
or the wind speed
in a closed-off room.
The fan was on.
Excuses don't win
championships.
Oh, yeah? Did Michael Jordan
tell you that?
No.
I told him.
Come on.
All right.
That was going in.
We're in the middle of a game!
If you two
are playing horse,
then one of you needs
to thank me.
Thank you.
Pussies.
Out.
Would you like to finish
this game?
Winner gets to be
name partner.
See, that's funny because
you're already name partner--
Derek Portis died
this weekend.
What took him so long?
- Harvey.
- What?
He lived a long life.
He was an old man.
- He was 56.
- Didn't look a day under 70.
Man dies,
and the first thing you think
to say is that
he looked older than he was.
No. That's the first thing
I said.
The first thing
I thought to say was,
"dead or alive,
Derek is a dick."
A dick that convinced
Folsom Foods
to settle with us
for $10 million.
Well, we'll just have
to tell his replacement
the settlement needs
a signature.
- It's not gonna be that easy.
- Why? Who's replacing him?
I'm gonna have
the cornish hen,
and we're gonna start
with the foie gras special,
two of them.
You're gonna love it.
Just one.
I'm okay. Thank you.
Dad.
I'm watching
what I eat.
- On my birthday?
- [Chuckles]
I'm trying to be
disciplined.
Listen...
I'm taking a case
against Pearson Hardman.
It's Folsom Foods.
Do you know it?
Um, of course. It's
the gender-discrimination case.
Well, I wanted to give
a chance to get off it,
if you were on it.
Well, I'm not, but okay.
It's just that I know
you keep a low profile
at work.
That was supposed to be
between me and mom.
Well, I wish you could tell me
these things,
and I wish
that you didn't keep the fact
that I was your father
a secret.
It's not a secret.
I just don't broadcast it.
People treat me differently once
they find out you're my dad.
Are you worried
that they're judging you
for being a paralegal?
No, Dad.
Only you judge me
for being a paralegal.
- I do not judge you.
- It doesn't matter.
I'm not planning on being
a paralegal forever.
[Laughs]
I know.
Right there.
You can't even pretend
to believe
I have what it takes
to be a lawyer.
Rachel,
you are a beautiful woman,
and you can do whatever
you want.
Beautiful, not smart.
Honey, I am trying
to give you a heads-up.
And you're taking
the whole thing
as an indictment.
Do you believe I have
what it takes to be a lawyer?
It's been five years,
and...
It hasn't happened.
I just wonder
if you've considered
trying something else.
Of all days--
"Hey, Rachel,
how was your birthday?"
"Great. My dad told me
that I should aim lower."
Please, Rachel,
that is not what I meant.
Let's just have lunch.
No, Dad.
Really, I wouldn't want you
to overeat
on the day that you told me
that I won't amount to anything.
Rachel.
Hi.
Excuse me.
But I think you might be
in the wrong office.
Oh, I'm in the right office.
You're Katrina Bennett,
Harvey's mysterious new hire.
I'm afraid that puts me
at a disadvantage,
because I don't know
who you are.
That's our problem
right there.
- We have a problem?
- Oh, yeah, a big one.
You haven't come
to see me yet.
Again, I don't know
who you--
I oversee the first-
and second-year associates.
It's a responsibility
that I take as seriously
as holding the nuclear
launch codes in my hands.
Well, if you take it
so seriously,
then why are you in
a fifth-year associate's office,
trimming your fingernails
at her desk?
Trimming?
This is a gold-plated
nickel alloy cuticle sculptor
from the south of Denmark,
and I will sculpt
my nails
wherever I damn well please.
Why don't we see
what you're up to?
That's password-protected.
Please. Prosecutor99--
third try.
That's a violation
of my privacy.
Oh, yeah?
Who are you gonna tell?
[Keys clacking]
I see you're representing
Chad Ritter.
And this is your defense?
Wow, it's like you're a baboon.
I'm in full control of
Mr. Ritter's defense strategy.
It's not a strategy,
it's a prayer,
which is why I'm going
to be forced to supervise you.
I don't need
a babysitter.
You're not getting
You're getting Louis Litt.
This is unacceptable.
Be that as it may,
you can either welcome
my tutelage,
or you can crawl back
to the D.A.'s office
from whence you came.
Welcome to Pearson Hardman.
You got a minute?
Maybe.
It's not about us.
It's about work.
Oh.
Then, yeah.
Folsom Foods--
Missy Dietler's
your paralegal on it, right?
Yeah, when she's not texting
her boyfriend
every five seconds
or her roommate,
like,
every other five seconds.
Put me on instead.
[Chuckles]
No.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
The new opposing counsel
is my dad.
Your dad
is Robert Zane?
Is it so hard to believe
that my father's black?
Robert Zane is black?
You think
this is a year-round tan?
I know who you are,
but I can't believe
that your father is
the Robert Zane
and you never said
anything to me.
I don't like people
here knowing.
Oh, and I'm just "people"?
[Sighs]
I mean, before,
with the--okay.
Look, I'm offering
to help you kick his ass.
Are you gonna make room
for me or not?
Before I answer
that question,
do you really think
it's a good idea
for you and I
to work together?
Are you really asking me
what is or isn't a good idea?
Wow.
Look out, Robert Zane.
♪ See the money,
wanna stay for your meal ♪
♪ get another piece of pie
for your wife ♪
♪ everybody wanna know
how it feel ♪
♪ everybody wanna see
what it's like ♪
♪ living in a beehive
of your mind ♪
♪ me and missus
so busy, busy making money ♪
♪ all right
♪ all that time
imagine this ♪
♪ Suits 2x13 ♪
Zane vs. Zane
Original Air Date on January 31, 2013
♪ the greenback boogie
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
First of ala Robert, I'm sorry
to hear about Derek Portis.
Oh, I appreciate
your condolences, Harvey,
but the fact is,
Derek was a dick.
[Laughing]
That's what I said.
That's what everybody says.
In any case, you didn't need
to come all the way over here.
We could've faxed you
that settlement.
Here you go, sir.
You and I both know
I didn't come over here to sign.
I came to negotiate.
To renegotiate,
which is bad faith.
The fact is
you snookered Derek.
10 million is double
what any competent attorney
would've settled for.
Should have been 5.
I'll give you 2.
Great.
Let's settle for 2.
Then I'll get you the keys
to my condo,
and maybe you'll drop a deuce
on my pillow.
Does it have
a security code? Doorman?
[Laughter]
Okay,
you've had your fun.
But we're not taking
that offer.
Then when would you like
to schedule
Sloane Moseley's
deposition?
But you can't re-depose her,
Mr. Zane.
Yes, he can.
And you'll use
this opportunity
to show Sloane Moseley
what she's in for.
When I get done with her,
she's gonna jump
at the 2 million.
That's more than bad faith.
That's just cruel.
My offer stands.
Uh, it was nice
to meet you, sir.
What?
"Sir"?
"Mr. Zane"?
Why don't you just call him
"dad" and get it over with?
I was showing respect.
You're trying to get invited
to Thanksgiving dinner.
You think he'd let me have
one of the turkey legs?
I don't think that's what
you're wanting him
to let you have.
You think I didn't notice
that Rachel Zane
just became the paralegal?
She asked to be on it.
This better not end up
with you in bed with her
telling her your secret.
Not a problem.
We'll do it
on the couch.
Wow.
that was not respectful
to you, me, or her.
- Or her father.
- Or your couch.
Not my couch.
[Elevator bell dings]
- Donna.
- Katrina.
- You know who I am?
- I know who everybody is.
That's what I've heard.
Do you have a minute?
Well, eight days from now,
I think I got
a spare 45 seconds.
Well, if you get
a break...
You think I can be bought
with cookies?
Homemade,
chocolate chip.
- Dark chocolate?
- Semisweet.
- A dollop of peanut butter?
- Butterscotch.
- Walnuts?
- Please.
Pistachios.
The nut of royalty.
Who told you
my weak spot--Mike?
Bertha.
Big Bertha
from the D.A.'s office?
You're remembered
fondly there.
Aw, yeah.
I'm remembered fondly
everywhere.
[Sighs]
Okay, you got one minute.
Who the hell
is Louis Litt?
This might take
more than a minute.
How bad?
I'd like to throw him
through a plateglass window.
Not a totally
unprecedented reaction.
Harvey brought me in,
so I don't want to piss him off.
I just want to know
what the protocol is.
Harvey won't stand in
your way, but you listen to me.
You want to go toe-to-toe
with Louis,
you better be prepared
to go the distance.
- Jessica.
- Robert.
What can I do for you?
I just want to talk,
one name partner to another.
I want you to settle
Folsom Foods.
I thought we were
already settling Folsom Foods.
I proposed
a slightly different number.
Which Harvey already
said no to.
Well, you know me.
I don't go for that
gender-discrimination stuff,
but Harvey negotiates
like a girl.
[Laughs]
No, he doesn't.
But he does style his hair
like one.
[Laughs]
I know.
What the hell is that?
[Muttering]
I don't know.
What's your number?
2 million.
That's
an $8 million hit.
It's 8 million to your client,
and you need a win.
Do I?
Yeah, it's no secret
that Pearson Hardman's
been taking it on the chin
since Daniel left.
Well, that might mean
something if I had a glass jaw.
Partners have jumped ship,
associates were poached,
clients have bailed.
Partners were pushed,
associates were fired,
and clients were retained.
Well, you can spin it
all you want.
But a high-profile win--
that sure would look good.
If I lower my price.
A win's a win.
It doesn't matter how ugly.
Robert Zane poked his nose
into my office.
He try and hit on you?
I think he's always had a thing.
Who doesn't?
He thinks we're weak.
I know.
He pulled the settlement.
Not on the case--us.
Are you saying
he went over my head?
He heard about Allison Holt's
bullshit last week.
Let me guess.
He's pulling the same bullshit
right now.
Told me the world knows
we need a win,
tried to leverage that
to get me to settle.
Son of a bitch.
That's not bad faith.
That's below the belt.
You know what I do to someone
who hits me below the belt.
Cut 'em off at the knees.
[Juicer whirring]
Louis.
[Juicer continues whirring]
I just need--
I just--
[whirring slows]
[Juicer turns off]
Yeah.
Looks delicious.
What is that?
It's a spinach
and kale power smoothie.
I'm in the middle
of my quarterly cleanse.
What do you want?
To apologize...
for any misunderstanding
we might have had.
That you might have had.
I had.
And it was huge.
I looked up your record.
You're a white-collar genius.
Go on.
I don't just accept
your tutelage.
I'm begging for your help.
Well, beg away.
My motion to dismiss
is Wednesday
with Judge McIntyre.
I've never been able
to connect with him.
Yeah, that's 'cause you
don't understand him.
Well, all I know is
he's punitive.
No, he's a stickler.
Don't be late,
don't be sloppy,
don't be disrespectful,
and he'll love you,
just like he loves me.
Since you know him
so well,
would you do me
the honor of signing on
as first chair?
I can.
And I will.
You've forgiven me
with grace,
and now you're saving me
in my hour of need.
You're my knight
in shining armor.
Ah.
[Chuckles]
I will see-eth you
on Wednesday, milady.
[Laughs]
[Clears throat, sighs]
Um...
[Clears throat]
You wanted to see me?
Yes,
but usually that means
the person tells Donna
they're here.
Then Donna tells me.
That's how it works.
- Donna's not there.
- You think that's by accident?
Apparently not.
You know why you're here?
Because my last name
is Zane.
You know why Donna isn't?
Because you know
we're friends.
And you're about to ask me
to do something
that she would tell me
not to do.
And what exactly do I want
to ask you?
You want to know if I want
to be in on the deposition.
- You did ask on the case.
- Yes, I did.
And before you ask me
if I'm tough enough
to be in there,
I want you to know
that I am tough enough.
That's not
what I wanted to ask.
I want you to know if you think
it'll rattle your father.
Frankly,
I don't think he'd care.
Good.
Why good?
Because if that's
what you think about him,
then your relationship
is worse than you think,
and he cares about you more
than you know.
Is this a joke?
She doesn't need to be
in there.
Sloane Moseley?
You know
who I'm talking about.
You think having her
in the room
is gonna keep me
from doing my job?
The relevant question is,
what is she gonna think
about you
after you eviscerate
Sloane Moseley?
You accuse me of being cruel,
and you orchestrate this stunt.
We had a deal.
You pulled it.
Put the deal back
on the table,
this whole thing ends now.
Harvey,
what did you do?
My job.
Miss Moseley...
why did you choose
this particular field?
Because I have
a love of food.
Is it really a requirement
of excellence
in an executive
that one love food?
It's not a requirement,
but it's a food company,
and it's what I thought
made it a perfect fit.
Well, if it was such
a perfect fit,
why were you looking
for a job in another field?
Because I spent nine years
killing myself for your client
and got passed over
for promotion after promotion
in favor
of less-qualified men.
Okay, let me get
this straight.
So you hit a wall,
you blame my client,
and rather than figuring out
what it takes
to make it
in this perfect fit,
you give up and fold
like a house of cards.
I don't know what law school
you went to,
but I was always taught
that depositions
require questions.
I went to Harvard.
And here's your question.
After all these interviews
for all these jobs,
why didn't you just pursue
one of them
and switch careers?
It would require
a step backward.
Isn't it true it didn't
require a step backward?
But that's all
you could find,
cause no one thought
you were any good
at the job you had
in the first place.
You don't know that.
I have sworn testimony
from a headhunter
who said
nobody wanted you.
Okay,
you're badgering her.
Well, the truth is
you're untalented and pathetic
and blaming other people
because you don't have
the skills or the fortitude
or anything else to make it
in your chosen field.
And you don't even have
the courage
to try something else.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to make sure
that the court reporter
got all that.
Did you hear it down there?
We heard it.
Good.
I have a few more questions.
No.
This deposition is over.
This is the men's room.
You know that, right?
Don't do that
shit again.
Excuse me?
I don't need
your protection.
That's what my dad does.
Rachel,
the only thing
your father and I
have in common
is that you're angry
at both of us.
Well, all you did in there
was embarrass me.
Embarrass you?
I wasn't even watching you.
I was watching our client.
You're trying to say
you didn't call that off
because of him?
No, I'm trying to say I didn't
call it off because of you,
even though evidently
you went to Harvey
to ask in
to make it about you.
I didn't go to Harvey.
He came to me.
Look, Rachel, you might want
to make this Zane versus Zane,
but it's not.
It's Folsom Foods
versus our client.
But you're so eager to prove
how tough you are
that you seem
to have forgotten about her.
- How dare you?
- How dare I what?
I just got a $3,000 fine
from Judge McIntyre
for missing my own hearing.
I know.
I was wondering
what happened to you.
I thought maybe your horse
took fever, my liege.
Uhhuh.
You said it was Wednesday,
and you know it.
No.
I said Tuesday...
as is confirmed
in the documents I gave you.
This here is a fight
you don't want to have.
- I didn't pick it.
- Yeah, you did.
And now you're gonna pay
that fine,
and you're gonna write
a letter
expressing how sorry you are
to Judge McIntyre.
No. I'm not.
I'm gonna count to five.
You can count to 500.
The only thing I'm sorry for
is getting stuck with you.
You lied to me...
and you know it.
Oh, yeah?
Who you gonna tell?
Here it comes.
Speech number 162--
14 reasons
why I'm an asshole.
No, no.
This is gonna be 216.
That's uncharted territory.
And you're still
not gonna like it.
If it's coming from you,
that goes without saying.
Look, I'm just saying
that you went
out of your way to put Rachel
in that deposition.
You promised
uncharted territory.
We've been here before.
No, usually you're accusing me
of making things personal.
But this time
you're making things personal
for Robert Zane.
No.
He made it personal.
And how exactly did
he do that?
He threatened our firm.
And on top of that,
he tried to show Sloane Moseley
what she'd be in for her
if this goes to trial.
So I'm just returning
the favor.
Yeah, well, it didn't seem to
have much of an effect on him.
Trust me.
It will.
And did you think
about the effect
it'll have on Sloane Moseley,
not to mention his daughter?
Here we are,
right back to good old 162.
Did you misunderstand me
when I said
to cut Robert Zane
off at the knees?
You too?
Oh, don't tell me
you think I went too far.
I don't think
you went far enough.
- What?
- Your client just called.
She wants to take
Zane's bullshit settlement.
You're gonna want
to turn your hips
to transfer your weight
through the ball.
Nice job tracking me down.
You think
you're the only one
who knows
where Judge Benjamin plays?
No.
But I'm the only one here
he plays with.
Now, did you come here
to caddie for me?
I came here to negotiate.
Bullshit.
Your client caved
after that deposition,
because she knew she couldn't
make it through a trial.
So I'm gonna negotiate
for you.
The offer on the table
was 2 million.
It just went down to one.
Robert.
Now it's 500,000.
You're pretty good
at this.
Remind me to have you buy
my next car for me.
Now it's 100,000.
No, wait.
Here.
No one wins
if we go to war.
You don't have children,
do you?
You came to my house
and threatened my firm.
"Your house"?
You put my little girl
in that deposition
so she could see me
shred that woman,
which I did
because that's my job.
And I was trying to protect
that woman.
That was my job.
Well, your client is scared
shitless.
So I guess that means
that I did my job
a lot better
than you did yours.
The settlement is gone.
You want something...
you come take it at trial.
What do you need?
A napkin.
No
social security number,
date of birth,
favorite color,
allergy to nuts--
I don't know.
What's it gonna take?
I don't think
I need to steal
your father's identity
just yet.
Mike said he pulled
the settlement,
and we can't let that happen.
- "We"?
- Yes, "we."
I work here too.
- Now I get it.
- Get--
No, no, no. This isn't
about me and my father.
This is about the client.
No, I meant
why Donna likes you so much.
Oh.
Thank you.
I-I like her too.
You know what?
I was gonna give in
and drop this case.
But now that you accosted me
during my me time,
I'm gonna change my mind
and do what you say.
You were gonna continue
with it anyway.
- Yes.
- Right.
Would you like to eat
my bagel now too?
Oh, thank you. I...
[Laughs]
I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
I just came by to tell you
that you were right.
This is your case, not mine.
I'm no longer first chair.
Fine.
We're best friends.
Now please leave.
Okay, I came to give you
your files back.
All rise.
No way.
I wasn't born yesterday.
I've got my files
right here.
Okay, Katrina, I'm offering us
both a way out here.
You keep whatever's in those
files the hell away from me.
Okay.
You got me.
I'm not to be trusted.
All right, let's get to it.
Ms. Bennett, I believe
you have something for me.
Your Honor,
Mr. Gibbs charged my client
with securities fraud,
but he neglected
to disclose discrepancies
between the S.E.C.'S findings
and the IRS's.
I have with me an exhibit.
I'm sorry.
You must've accidentally
somehow gotten
the file of pictures of me
photoshopped
as various American presidents.
I actually like that one.
I look pretty sharp,
don't I?
What you're really looking
for was this...
[Patting folder]
like I offered.
But per your request,
I'm gonna keep it
the hell away from you.
Is this some sort of joke?
No.
Your Honor.
Bring that folder up here
right now.
And if they're not
legitimate court documents,
you are in for one hell
of a fine.
Uh...
What are you working on?
I'm going through the reviews
for every executive
promoted at Folsom Foods
for the last five years.
You?
Reviews of every executive
promoted at Folsom Foods
for the past five years.
[Both chuckles]
You were right.
This is not Zane versus Zane.
And I don't want to talk
about my dad anymore.
Good.
It's like
he was sitting me down
and looking me in the eye
and telling me...
What?
That I'm untalented
and pathetic
and don't have
the skills or the fortitude
or anything else it takes
to make it in my chosen field.
He was talking
to a client.
You got a 172.
You're going to law school.
He can't deny that.
Yeah.
He--he doesn't know that.
Rachel, you--
[sighs]
When I, um...
told him that I was
high-school salutatorian...
Guess what the first words
out of his mouth were.
He wanted to know
who the valedictorian was.
Nope.
He said...
"Number two ain't bad."
He thought
it was funny.
Everyone's always said
that my mom is beautiful
and that my dad is smart
and powerful.
And all I've ever wanted
is for him...
He's never gonna see
a different side of you
if you don't show him
a different side of you.
He knew I was sitting
right there.
You chose to be sitting
[Knock on door]
- Louis.
- Hi, Donna.
What can I do for you?
Not for me.
For Katrina.
- Which one's Katrina again?
- Okay, you know what?
You've had your fun.
Time to let it go.
Yeah, I'm afraid
I'm not gonna let anything go
until that woman kneels
before Zod.
First of all,
you know who Zod is?
And second of all,
you think you're Zod?
General Zod
was a visionary leader
who was underappreciated
by his entire planet.
Of course
I know who he is.
Okay, well,
Katrina isn't Superman,
so what the hell
do you want from her?
Okay.
I get it.
Harvey is Superman,
and he hired Katrina,
instead of you getting
your first-year.
Her name was Maria,
and this is not about that.
What this is about
is me getting respect
from a new employee, so...
You beat her.
You want her respect?
Make up with her
and leave her alone.
Oh, really, Donna?
Is that a sign of respect?
Leaving someone alone,
like you and Harvey
left me alone
since Daniel?
Louis, Harvey
welcomed you back.
"Welcomed"?
He ripped up
my letter of resignation,
and he didn't say a word.
- Louis.
- You know what?
Over the years,
all the ribbing
and all the practical jokes
between you and Harvey--
I found that to be
a sign of respect.
But you haven't had
one conversation with me
since you told me
you never wanted
to see my smug face again.
So you know what?
You go tell Katrina
that I'm not really
in a forgiving mood.
I had an idea
about Folsom Foods.
- You too?
- What?
You are not getting
my bagel.
Why would I want
your bagel?
Never mind.
What do you got?
I checked the review
of every promotion
from the last five years.
Every time
they don't promote a woman,
they use some combination
of the same 16 words.
- And the men?
- No.
What are the words?
"High-strung, sensitive,
aggressive, abrasive..."
Coded language.
They went out of their way
to shield themselves
from any one person bringing
a gender-discrimination suit,
which means they treated
all of them the same.
As a class.
Yeah.
And guess how many.
113 female employees
across all 22 divisions--
you know
what they have in common?
All denied promotions
due to the fact
that they're women,
not that they're untalented
or pathetic
or lack the fortitude
to excel in their chosen field.
This is a crock of shit.
You didn't want to settle
for 2 million.
You'll be lucky to settle
for 200 million.
Robert,
play all the golf you want.
Judge Benjamin isn't gonna
get you out of this one.
How we doing today, boys?
[Metal detector beeps]
Sir, need you to step
over here, please.
Easy, Batman.
I left my belt on.
Well, if it's okay
with you,
I'm gonna break out
my trusty bat metal detector.
[Metal detector beeps]
Sir, we need you to raise
your arms
above your head, please.
Okay, and I'm gonna need
your badge number.
How did those get there?
- Sir, this is a weapon.
- A weapon?
They're my nail scissors,
you asshole.
They're gold-plated.
They cost $2,000.
You're gonna bring a $2,000
weapon into my courthouse?
I'm just saying I don't know
even how they got there.
Oh, well, maybe the Riddler
put them there.
Okay, that's very funny.
I'm just saying--
maybe it was, like,
a big misunderstanding.
You say you don't know
whose those are?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Okay, let's just start over.
I'm just gonna need
them back.
Ow!
I'm placing you
under arrest
for carrying
a concealed weapon
into a courthouse
in the state of New York
and for assaulting
an officer of the court.
- What?
- Hey, Eddie.
Hey, Ms. Bennett.
Nice to see you again.
- How are Shelly and the kids?
- Oh, they're doing great.
You know, I mean--
you know, she's--
yeah. No, they're doing great.
Thanks for asking.
It was her!
You think
I don't know that?
I always loved
that picture.
Me too.
Tryouts
for the school play.
Minnie Mouse.
I want to talk
about the deposition.
Rachel, you and I cannot talk
about the case.
I said the deposition,
not the case.
I don't give a shit
about the case.
Then why did you take it?
Because you took me out
for my birthday
and told me you were picking
a fight with my family and said,
"Sit it out, little girl.
You can't handle this."
Do you know
why I love that picture?
Because I'm still
your little girl.
Because you were happy.
You remember what happened
at those tryouts?
Yeah.
I didn't get the part.
- And it killed you.
- I was a child.
And most children
let things go.
But you never tried out
for a play again.
I did other things.
But why aren't you doing
other things now?
I am watching you fail
and stall
and beat yourself up.
And it rips me up inside.
I took the LSATs.
I got a 172.
When?
Six weeks ago.
And you're just
telling me now.
[Scoffs] I didn't want to hear
some joke about your 177.
- Ah, but--
- When we were in that room,
I know you were talking
to her,
but it was like you were aiming
everything right at me.
And then I thought,
"you know what?
Maybe you look
at all of us that way."
- Rachel.
- Well, we're not all the same.
And you need to toughen up
because I am not
that little girl anymore.
So who's gonna kneel
before Zod now?
I'm not kneeling
before anybody,
let alone the person
who framed me
and put me
in this jail cell.
You humiliated me
with Judge McIntyre.
Oh, please.
You did the same thing.
Missing an appearance
is different
from looking
like a buffoon in open court.
I gave you a way out,
so don't come crying to me.
Rapist, murderer...
these are the kinds of people
I'm used to dealing with.
And you know
where they are?
Spending the rest
of their lives
realizing that I wasn't just
a pretty face.
Is that what you think
this is about?
You treated me like shit
because I'm a woman.
How dare you?
I worship women.
My mother, my grandmother--
God rest her soul--
Hillary Clinton,
Gwen Stefani.
Then what the hell
is your problem?
You took a job from somebody
who deserved it more.
I went to resubmit my motion
to dismiss.
Turns out judge McIntyre
already received it...
from me.
The client needed it,
and you wrote it.
For me to put my signature
on it would just be wrong.
Well, it worked.
Are you ready to call
a truce?
Are you gonna frame me
for murder if I say no?
Not as long
as you keep these
in your own office.
Robert.
What a coincidence seeing
you here.
- It's not a coincidence.
- I didn't think it was.
I got to give it
to your man Harvey.
He comes full throttle.
He has his pros and cons.
They all do.
Did you bring
your checkbook?
Thank you.
I brought this.
You're going to decertify
our class?
I'm gonna bust it
wide open.
You see, after you brought
my daughter to that deposition,
I realized not
all women are the same.
No way this gets
busted up into 113 cases.
I'd say a minimum of 45.
Some you may win,
some you may lose,
all of which are gonna drain
your resources.
You're threatening me again.
- I have another option.
- Which is what?
I told you--
not all women are the same.
[Laughs]
You got to be kidding me.
"Not all women are the same."
What the hell does that mean?
He wants to merge.
What?
Pearson Zane.
No. No way.
I'm not doing that.
Oh, excuse me?
We didn't fight off Hardman
to end up here.
Well, you went
after the man's daughter,
which is what put us here.
You told me to cut him off
at the knees.
If you're gonna go that low
to put someone down,
then you better make damn sure
that they don't get back up.
It doesn't matter
if it's Robert or not.
They're gonna keep coming.
Until I put your name
on the door.
That's not
what this is about.
We can only take these hits
for so long.
Death by a thousand cuts.
[Scoffs]
All right.
Well, if they're
gonna keep coming,
then we may as well
just make it one big brawl.
Jessica.
What a coincidence.
Skip it.
I'm guessing
by your tone
that our merger
is off the table?
It was never on the table.
- What's this?
- A press release.
"Female head
of major law firm
"is going to the ends
of the earth
to fight 45 cases
of gender discrimination."
This is bullshit.
Look at me.
You'll cripple your firm.
I would rather lose my firm
than get married staring down
the barrel of a shotgun.
You're not gonna be able
to have my daughter
in every deposition.
This is 45 cases.
And it will cost you
45 times the amount
that you could settle
for right here.
Yeah, I know you.
The chess master--
you think you're Bobby Fischer.
This isn't chess.
It's dominoes.
Now, the first case
might be tough.
But after that,
one by one...
And when it's all said
and done,
I'll be
the last one standing,
holding a big, fat check
in my hand.
Remind me
to get the papers ready
for, uh, the deposition
tomorrow, the 19th.
Uh, that would--
holy shit.
Who the hell did this?
All right, Norma, if you're
gonna keep letting people
into this office like this,
then what the hell
good are you?
Oh, yeah, wait.
And by the way, remind me
to buy socks for next week.
I'm running low.
I got to admit,
you do look
kind of hot as a bad boy.
You tell me right now
this was not Katrina Bennett,
'cause this is not a truce.
Oh, please.
Katrina had nothing to do
with this.
- Then this was you?
- No.
Harvey?
You're not lying.
Nope.
Does this mean
that you and I are good?
No.
Not yet.
Bye, Louis.
Wait, don't go.
We're back!
No, we're not.
Oh, shit.
[Knock on door]
- Hey.
I'm dropping the case.
Why?
Because I never should have
taken it in the first place.
- Dad.
- You said it yourself.
I picked a fight
with your family,
told you to sit it out,
and those aren't words a man
should ever hear from--
from his daughter.
You're not tough enough?
Not even close.
[Laughs]
Well, we never finished
our lunch.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
But we'll have to pick
a new place.
I already tried
that foie gras of yours.
- You did?
- Yep.
And?
It tasted like ass.
Come on.
[Laughs]
[Chuckles]
Looks like
you guys made up.
It's a start.
I didn't want
to interrupt,
and I know
I'm a few days late,
but...
Is that my--
Your LSAT score?
Yeah.
I figured...
You shouldn't keep things
like this a secret.
Thanks, Mike.
Happy Birthday.
How did you know
it was my birthday?
Oh, right.
I must have told you once.
You did, yeah.
I mean, I forgot.
Yeah, this is from Donna.
[Imitating Robert]
Come on.
That is exac--
- I just saw that.
- [Laughs]
Yeah, that's how fast I am.
You're impressed.
It's no big deal.
How did it go down?
Did you tell him if he puts
one of ours in the hospital,
we put one
of his in the morgue?
No, Harvey. I did not quote
The Untouchables to the man.
You should've,
you stinkin' Irish pig.
That's really funny,
you lying member
of a no-good--
Robert.
Oh, I hate to interrupt
in the middle
of a Untouchables
quote fest.
Two doors down,
they're doing Steel Magnolias.
You'd fit right in.
I'm more
of a Beaches man myself.
I assume you're here
to settle.
I'm afraid not.
I wanted to tell you
that my firm
has a conflict of interest,
so I decided to farm out
the case.
Whose ass
are we gonna kick now?
Actually,
an old classmate of mine.
Let me guess...
Daniel Hardman.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==