(cattle lowing)
ADAM:
Look over there.
BEN:
So that's what's been
happening to our cattle.
It is as I have promised,
O, Winnemucca.
The cattle are in
the small canyon.
Your people are grateful.
Take them quickly.
If the Cartwrights come...
BEN:
The Cartwrights
are here.
You know what happens
to cattle thieves.
Shoot, Ben Cartwright!
Shoot!
(theme song playing)
Tukwa, I trusted you.
I gave you a good life
on the Ponderosa.
Do you repay me by
stealing my cattle?
Do not blame my brother.
He but did the word
of his chief.
How long have the Paiutes
been cattle thieves?
Since the Washoe antelope
and deer are gone.
Since thepinon tree burns in
the fires of Sun Mountain.
Since our women and our children
and our braves sit hungry
in our tents, and
sicken without food.
What say you, Winnemucca?
The Washoe antelope herds
have fed the Paiute
since the long-ago dream time.
The diggers of Sun
Mountain eat antelope,
while the pots of
the Paiute are empty.
They are but three head, the
weakest of the Ponderosa herd.
Tukwa cannot see
his people starve.
What's the matter
with you, Tukwa?
Would the Cartwrights
let the Paiute starve?
Why didn't you ask us.
The Paiute is a man.
He does not beg.
Even now, Winnemucca
is called woman
by my young men around
the council fires.
Winnemucca is
no woman.
He thinks
of his people.
The ways of peace
are good ways,
but because the
Paiute loves peace
does not mean he
cannot make war.
War brings nothing but wailing
in tents and lodges, Winnemucca.
For the Paiute and
for the white man.
You and I understand
these things.
Does Ben Cartwright disregard
the voices of his sons?
Even so, Winnemucca hears
the words of his young men.
They speak for war.
They see as I see
that the Paiute walks
the same trail
as the antelope,
and the antelope is dead.
The men who dig
in the earth
are new to Washoe,
Winnemucca.
They do not know
the ways of the land.
My sons and I, we will
ride to them
and make them understand.
They will listen.
The Cartwrights
and the Paiutes
have long walked
the earth together,
but if there is war,
Ben Cartwright,
even the men of the
Ponderosa can die.
There will be no war.
And no more
antelope will die.
I will see to it.
Tukwa always speaks
the truth.
They must indeed be the
weakest cattle of our herd.
For our friendship, would you
drive them off the Ponderosa?
Help your people, Tukwa.
Pa, I don't like
all that war talk.
That new Virginia City
is full of fools.
You'd think even
fools would know
you can't push
Indians around.
All they were
thinking about was food.
Food is one thing.
Destroying the balance
of nature is another.
If they keep this up,
the whole of Washoe
will become a desert.
I saw it happen to
John Sutter's California.
All right, let's go.
Where, Pa?
Virginia City.
Come on!
Hey, hey!
(speaking Chinese)
Hey, Adam, you see that
little gal smile at me?
What makes you think it was
you she was smiling at?
You know, every time
I come in here,
I got to get used
to it all over again.
Remember when this was nothing
more than a jackrabbit run?
HOSS:
Yeah, I don't know but what
I liked the jackrabbits better,
Little Joe.
Whoa.
All right, you two country boys
get your fill of the city.
Adam and I will take
a little look around.
Let's go.
Hey, Hoss, did you ever
see anything like this
in your whole life?
Yep, I seen a
stampede last fall
up in Silver Meadow.
Only difference was
the stampede
made more sense.
Come on before
you take root.
Looks good, Ma.
Move over, boy.
Wish there was more.
Guess we've seen it all now.
The good and the bad.
Is this what they call
striking it rich?
Looks like all they've
struck so far is bad luck.
Pretty rough on
young ones like that.
Howdy.
That's not much of a meal
for growing boys.
That ain't much of
a meal for anybody,
but that's my
business, ain't it?
No offense
intended, Mister...?
Harris. Carl Harris.
This is my wife, my boys.
Hello.
Howdy.
You know, Mr. Harris, you could
be feeding those boys beef.
Yeah, if'n I had wings,
I could fly, too.
Mr. Harris, we're
the Cartwrights,
from the Ponderosa.
Now there's plenty of
beef in the valley.
I... I reckon so.
All I can do
to fork over $10 a pound
for that skinny antelope.
I couldn't afford beef.
You paid $10 a pound?
And lucky to get it.
A man come through
last week
selling salt pork
for $15 a pound.
Least this
meat is fresh.
We aren't
starving, Mister.
We take care of ourselves.
I'm sure you do, ma'am.
But you don't have
to pay those prices.
We market our steers over to
Placerville for $25 a head.
We'd be making money
selling them to you for $20.
Twenty dollars?
That's right.
Are you joking me, Mister?
They're yours
if you want them.
All you have to do
is come over to the Ponderosa
and drive them away.
Whoo!
(laughing)
I couldn't do much better
than that back home in Kaintuck.
Kentucky?
You're a long
way from home.
I got tired of seeing my family
starve on 40 acres of rock.
and I figured if we had to
starve, we might as well do it
somewhere where there's a
chance of striking it rich.
Nobody's going to starve
while we have cattle to sell.
Now get yourself
some men together,
and come over
to the Ponderosa.
Well, by golly,
we'll do it!
(laughing)
Did you hear that, woman?
We gonna eat
ourselves some beef.
Oh, here I am acting
like a Yankee.
Come on in, have
a cup of coffee.
Mr. Harris, you sure don't know
anything about us Yankees.
You're Yankees?
(laughing)
Oh, I didn't mean any...
Oh, it's all right.
It's all right.
Come on in,
have some coffee.
BEN:
Mighty kind of you.
(piano playing lively tune)
Hey, where'd you come from?
You're cute.
Hey, now wait
a minute.
Lady, you just mind
your own business.
Come on, Little Joe.
She isn't for you.
Stuff your eyes back
in your head.
They're about to pop out.
You know, Hoss, I could have
a good time if you weren't here.
Yeah, and get yourself
into a peck of trouble, too.
(people clamoring)
Hey, look at that, Little Joe.
Let's go!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Let's go!
Antelope meat,
$10 a pound.
Yeah. Looks like
we're raising
the wrong kind of
stock, don't it?
Well, come on.
Hurry up!
Let's go!
Come on now!
Here, let me try,
Little, Joe.
Excuse me, men.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
(clamoring)
All right, get back in line!
Get back...!
Stay outta my way!
Get back there!
Get back in line!
Pound and a half, $15.
They must be out
of their minds.
How so, friend?
Always like to hear the other
fella's side of things.
$10 a pound
for antelope meat--
that make
sense to you?
Depends on your
point of view.
You see, that happens
to be my antelope meat
they're buying.
The Paiutes might
argue with you about that.
(chuckles)
I haven't seen you boys around.
Are you staking out
in Virginia City?
Mark Burdette's the name.
Joe Cartwright.
This is my brother Hoss.
Pleased to meet you.
Say, he's a big fella,
isn't he?
Boys, do you have any
idea how many people
are heading toward
Virginia City right now?
Thousands.
Yes, sir, thousands.
And every blessed one of them
with a belly he's got to fill.
Going to be a bunch
of 'em, huh?
Ever since they found out about
that blue stuff being silver,
which assays at better
than $3,500 a ton,
they're heading here
from all over the world.
Silver!
All that time, Comstock
and those other fellas
were chucking it away,
thinking only about gold.
Gold? Virginia City's
going to be
a hundred times the strike
the mother lode ever was.
And let me tell
you something, boys,
there's more than one way
to strike it rich.
Man can live without
whiskey and women
and clothing,
even shelter,
but if he doesn't eat,
he dies.
Hey, Little Joe, what
are you doing here?
Pa. Pa, I'd like you
to meet Mark Burdette.
He owns this place.
Proud to meet you,
Mr. Cartwright.
Howdy.
This is my
brother Adam.
Adam.
Howdy.
You've got a good thing
here, haven't you?
Takes a businessman to know good
business, Mr. Cartwright.
Is that what
you call it?
I could think
of another name.
(chuckles):
Well...
you boys sound
as if you want to talk.
Well, one thing you'll
find out about me,
I'm always ready to oblige,
This way, gentlemen.
Here we are.
It's not very much,
but it's a beginning.
What I say is, let them
have their silver,
as long as I can sell
them their meat.
Your charging pretty
fancy prices for that meat.
It's the only meat
in town, Mr. Cartwright.
It costs me a
lot to get it.
It's liable to cost
you a lot more.
Mister, you went out and
butchered the meat supply
of the whole Paiute nation.
You're risking an Indian war.
Oh, come now, friend.
I've got nothing
against the Indians.
What I always say is
fair game is fair game.
Hey, Pa, why don't we sell
some of our stock
to Mr. Burdette here,
and the Paiutes can
have the antelope to
themselves again?
What stock you talking
about, son?
Don't you know
about the Ponderosa?
Joe!
We got more
prime cattle than...
You have?
Real prime beef
east of the Sierras?
I'll tell you what I'll do,
Mr. Cartwright.
I'll take all you've got.
You can name your own price.
If you charge ten dollars
a pound for antelope meat,
what will you be
charging for beef?
All I can get.
If you think
that's out of line,
take a look in the saloon,
see what rot-gut
whiskey's going for.
Or a bag of flour.
Or a pick and shovel.
I just sold last side
of antelope, Mr. Burdette.
We're out of business.
Not yet, Thorne.
These gentlemen are
the Cartwrights
from the Ponderosa ranch.
Prime beef cattle,
as much as you want.
My assistant, Early Thorne.
How are you, gents?
Well, do we do business?
Why not, Pa? We're in
the business to sell cattle.
Mr. Burdette, we have
our own way of doing business
on the Ponderosa.
We pay an honest day's wages
for an honest day's work,
and we expect the
same in return.
Nothing more,
nothing less.
You referring to us, mister?
It's all right, Thorne.
Let's be honest, friends.
I need your cattle.
I'm willing to pay you
the best price you'll ever get.
I have a cold storage
tunnel out there
full of ice from the Sierras.
It's the only ice in town.
If you're gonna sell
in Virginia City,
you'll have to sell
to me anyhow.
I say let's get together,
we'll both clean up.
We ain't hurting for customers,
Mr. Burdette.
Any miner in town can
come up to the Ponderosa
and buy all the meat
he needs.
And we don't intend
to profit from his hunger.
Profit from their hunger?
You think I was twisting
those fellows' arms
to get 'em in here?
Every minute they can spare
they use to dig for silver.
I'm doing them a service.
My son is right.
The Ponderosa is
a business,
but there's more involved
here than profits.
I'm sorry, Mr. Burdette,
no deal.
Why not?
I'm offering you
top dollar.
And charging top dollar
to people who can't
afford to pay.
Maybe you need taking
down a peg.
Thorne!
It would be
foolish, mister.
I've told you
about your temper!
I'm sorry about this, gentlemen.
But we can't let it interfere
with our negotiations.
Our negotiations are over.
I want to warn you again.
Stop slaughtering
the wild herds.
If you don't want a war
on your hands,
you'll follow this advice.
The Paiutes can be...
unpleasant.
Come on.
I'm gonna kill me one
of them Cartwrights!
Thorne, when are you
gonna learn
there's more than one way
of getting what you want?
Are you sure,
Mr. Burdette?
I'm sure.
They'll sell to me
before I'm through
or they'll never sell cattle
to anyone else.
CAROL: Whoa. Hi, there,
Mr. Cartwright.
What do you think
of Virginia City?
Sure is growin' up,
ain't she?
It sure is, Mr. Harris.
This place is busier
than a nest of hornets.
Where you fixin' to go?
Oh, I got a little diggin'
to do up Six Mile Canyon.
You know,
back in Kaintuck,
I never thought
that I'd be living on
a mountain of solid silver.
(chuckles)
Kind of takes a man's mind off
other things, though.
About them Cartwrights...
There they are.
Don't you let it take
your mind off those cattle.
You get some people
together and come on over
first thing in the morning,
and we'll fix you up.
By golly, I'll do that
first thing in the morning.
And I want
to thank you all.
That's a real neighborly
thing to do.
I'll bet them two boys
make mighty good help
when it comes to digging,
don't they, Mr. Harris?
We sure do.
Yeah, well,
they'll be even better
when we get a little beef
on their bones!
We'll see ya.
Bye, boys.
You heard what
they're fixin' to do?
Sure, the Cartwrights
are gonna sell beef
direct to the miners.
That'll wreck us,
Burdette.
It could if those cattle
reach Virginia City.
Want me to stop 'em?
Let's just say I don't
look with favor
upon any unnecessary
competition.
If anyone's looking
for me, Thorne,
tell 'em I'm investigating
the pleasures of
The Bucket of Blood.
Right.
You were just about
to buy me a drink,
weren't you?
Well... how did you guess?
I suppose I just have a knack
for certain things.
Uh-huh, I'm sure you have.
Oh, um, isn't there
some kind of a rule
about women frequenting saloons?
Didn't you know?
This is Virginia City.
Anything goes.
Exactly my sentiments.
After you.
Well, it isn't exactly the
Palace Hotel in San Francisco,
but it'll have to do.
The name is Glory DeLacey.
And it's all right,
I've been in here before.
Then you'll know the kind
of whisky to order.
It's all one kind:
rotgut.
Well, let's see
if you're right.
Bartender, a bottle
of your very finest.
Why is it that
a new mining camp
always has the worst
kind of whisky?
And the worst kind of women?
That wasn't what I was thinking.
What were you thinking?
That you are the only really
beautiful thing I've seen
in Virginia City.
Why haven't I
seen you before?
I just got in town
a few days ago.
Well, let's celebrate.
Thank you.
What's your name?
Burdette. Mark Burdette.
To Glory
of the Comstock Lode.
To the Comstock Lode.
They say it'll be the biggest
and richest strike in history.
A bonanza, a real bonanza.
And I'm gonna get
my share of it.
You're not exactly
dressed for the part.
Hmm? Oh, you don't think I mean
to dig for it
like those fellows over there?
No, there's more than one way
of panning for silver.
Yeah, I know.
I didn't mean it that way.
Why are you here?
The excitement of a new camp.
I don't know.
Maybe the hope
that this one'll be it.
Anyway, there's nothing left
in California.
This is gonna be the biggest
thing that ever happened.
Make California look sick,
I can feel it.
And this time,
I mean to get my share of it.
How come you never made it
in California,
a smart man like you?
Oh, maybe I wasn't smart enough.
Come to think of it,
I could ask you the same
question, couldn't I?
Don't.
To the future,
when we both have
what we want.
You care to drink
to it?
As long as you're buying
the drinks, Mr. Burdette,
I'll drink to anything.
I'm going to be rich.
The richest man
in town.
Here's wishing you luck.
What I mean to say is
that from now on.
I don't want anyone
else buying you drinks.
You mean you want to take care
of... everything?
I'm gonna take care
of everything.
$20, $40, $60,
$80, $100,
Mr. Cartwright.
And I sure want
to thank you.
You can have more cattle,
if you want.
That's pretty near
all we can afford right now,
but as soon as I get a dozen
more feet down in my diggings,
I'll come back and buy
your whole ranch!
(all laugh)
Hey, there comes ol' Tukwa.
I thought he was supposed to be
up on the rim.
LITTLE JOE: He's riding like
there's some trouble.
Anything wrong, Tukwa?
More new diggers,
Ben Cartwright. Too many.
Like the trees
of the forest.
He ain't a-fooling you there,
Mr. Cartwright.
I bet there ain't a hard-rock
man left in California,
unless'n he's too sick
to walk.
Men who chase
the mirage.
Maybe so, maybe not,
but somebody's gonna hit it
over there
to Virginia City, and
nobody knows who yet!
Well, my boys, we got 'em.
Thanks again.
And just wait till them women
see a square meal
walkin' in on the hoof.
(laughs)
Bye.
Go ahead!
CARL:
Hyah! Hyah!
What's the matter, Pa?
Those newcomers
from California.
Adam, you double the riders
on the rim.
We'll start losing cattle.
I go back, tell 'em?
No, you've
had a hard ride.
You go down to Steamboat Springs
camp for a while.
I'll put another man
up on the rim.
Pa, we could have got
a lot more
than $20 a head
for those cattle.
We made a fair profit.
That's all the Ponderosa asks.
Yeah? Well, what about
the other ranches?
Pa spoke to the
other settlers.
They won't boost
up their prices.
What do you want more money
for, anyhow, Little Joe?
You ain't going no place.
(chuckles)
We're eating steak
tonight.
Get ready.
Remember, I'll take care
of the one who's to be
left alive.
Get 'em!
(all whooping)
Don't shoot!
Hyah!
(all whooping, gunshots)
The-The, The kids...
What are we gonna
tell the kids?
It's all over
town, Thorne.
Fever's running high
against the Indians.
Did you have
to kill like that?
Them cattle didn't get
to Virginia City, did they?
All right, they didn't,
but you could have
stopped short of murder.
You know any other way,
Mr. Burdette?
The Cartwrights
would've come around;
I'd have upped the price
until they had no choice.
Someday, you're gonna learn
it takes more than money
to make a real killing.
Thorne... you're a monster.
I never should have
taken up with you again.
You need me, Burdette.
Remember, we have
a murder charge hanging over us
back in St. Louis.
Or did you forget about
that prison guard I killed
so you could get
to be a free man again?
There you are--
three kings.
All right, boys,
party's over.
We got some more
work to do.
I thought we done enough,
Thorne.
Our job's only
half-done.
There's still
the other half.
Yeah? What's that?
The town is plenty riled up
against the Indians
for killing them miners.
Well, they're getting the posse
together to go after 'em.
Yeah, I know.
That's why we gotta get
the Indians stirred up
against the miners.
That way, we put the Cartwrights
plumb in the middle.
What's on your mind?
Killing us some Paiutes...
for having massacred
those poor hardworking miners.
Why don't we let the posse
go after 'em?
Because the posse might stop
long enough to ask questions,
and I don't like questions.
You mean, like "Who really
killed those miners?"
What's the idea?
I told you I don't
like questions.
You really are smart,
aren't you, Thornton?
Smart enough to know
a dead man can't talk,
even to a posse.
What's the name of that Indian
that works for the Cartwrights?
Did you hear me?
Tukwa.
All right, boys,
let's get moving.
We got to get to him
before somebody else does.
Get your hat.
(gunshot)
(gunfire)
(men whistling,
shouting)
(gunfire continues
in distance)
It was the diggers
from Sun Mountain.
Some of my
people saw them
as they drove the cattle
toward the waters.
Are you sure,
Winnemucca?
The Paiute does not lie.
The diggers kill
the deer and the antelope.
They cut down the pinon tree,
and the Paiute has no bread.
And now he cuts down
my young men.
It's like California
all over again.
Whatever they
touch, they kill.
Why would anybody want
to kill Tukwa?
Vengeance-- some strange
notion of vengeance.
It just don't
make sense, Pa.
Them miners was all
killed with bullets.
Paiutes use arrows.
I guess he didn't have much
chance to tell then that.
What will my young men
say when I tell them
of their brother's murder?
You must keep them
in hand, Winnemucca.
Let the Ponderosa find
the men who did this.
I am an old man leading
a thousand stallions.
Today I can stop
my young braves.
I do not know if
I can tomorrow.
We will return for Tukwa.
Now let's find out
who did this.
I know who.
Who?
Mark Burdette.
LITTLE JOE:
Now wait a
minute, Adam.
Don't you think you're
pushing this a little bit?
I know you don't
like Burdette,
but you heard Winnemucca
say some miners did this.
Burdette's no miner.
At the moment he's the only man
who stands to make a profit
by starting trouble
between the ranchers
and the miners,
not to mention the Indians.
Pa, we've got
nothing to go on.
If we listen to Adam,
we may ride
into Virginia City
and hang an innocent man.
He has a point
there, Adam.
We have no proof.
You've met Burdette.
How much proof do you need?
Enough to know that
we've got the right man.
Look, why don't you let me
go into Virginia City
and snoop around--
see what I can pick up.
Alone?
Sure. If we all go in
together, everyone
will see us.
I go in by myself,
I won't be noticed.
It might not be
a bad idea, Pa.
Well, maybe.
Now you take care
of yourself, Little Joe.
Don't let Burdette sell you a
half-interest in his business.
Might not be
a bad investment.
Little Joe, maybe I ought
to ride in with you, huh?
Hoss, I'd be less noticed if
I rode down the main street
with a couple
of wild steers.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of myself.
How can anybody, even
a man like Mr. Burdette,
shoot down innocent men
just for a few dollars?
Not for just a few dollars,
Hoss-- a bonanza.
Joe Cartwright just
rode in alone.
He's taking quite
a chance, isn't he?
Riding into
Virginia City alone?
Especially if word
gets around
that the Cartwrights are
siding with the Paiutes.
What do you think would
happen to him, if it did?
Who knows?
Almost anything.
I wouldn't want
him hurt bad.
I have a feeling that
Joe Cartwright and I
are going to be friends.
Yeah, good friends.
Hey, kid.
You talking to me, mister?
Yeah, I'm talking to you,
you murdering little skunk.
(men shouting)
(all clamoring)
Come on.
Yeah, get up
and hit him.
Get him.
Get up!
Come on!
Yeah, get up.
Get up and hit him, boy!
Come on.
Get up!
Hit him.
You know who he is?
No.
He's one of them
Cartwrights.
And they're siding with those
murdering, thieving Paiutes.
Paiutes?
Somebody get a rope.
No, don't do it.
He didn't do anything.
Let him alone!
Let him go!
He didn't do anything!
Let's hang him.
Come on,
let's get him!
What is all this?
We're going to hang
ourselves an Injun lover.
Nobody's going to
hang this boy.
We've got three men dead
over those Paiutes.
That don't say Joe Cartwright
here's any part of it.
Who started this-- you?
Yeah, so what?
Thorne, you're fired.
I don't want to see you
around my place anymore.
Here we go.
Take him
into my office.
Open up. Let 'em through.
What is this?
Anybody want to argue
about anything?
(groans)
Did I hurt you?
Oh, I don't think
you could hurt me, ma'am.
(chuckles)
I don't understand-- those
miners out in the street--
they wanted to hang me.
Why?
You don't know?
Well, the miners sent
two groups out to buy cattle.
One of them went
down to your place.
Yeah, that's right. We sold them
about half-dozen head.
BURDETTE:
The other went from
Gold Hill down toward Carson.
They found both
groups murdered.
Cattle were gone.
What makes them think
it was the Paiutes?
One of the miners,
a man named Harris,
managed to stay alive.
He recognized one of the
Indians, a fella called Tukwa.
That's a lie.
Easy, Joe.
He said it, not me.
Anyway, that's why
this Tukwa is dead.
They would've
hung him anyway.
Tukwa's not that
kind of a man.
He'd never take a part
in anything like this.
Mr. Burdette, You helped
me out there in the street.
I-I kind of think
of us as friends.
You can believe
me about Tukwa.
No, I don't want
to believe it.
Drop it.
Drop it?
What do you mean?
What I said.
It's all over now.
This Indian, whatever
his name was...
His name was Tukwa.
All right, it's Tukwa.
Anyway, he's dead now,
and he deserved to die.
He took part in
that massacre.
But he didn't,
Mr. Burdette, not Tukwa.
I know.
How do you know?!
Young fool,
how do you know?
I told you, he
was identified.
LITTLE JOE:
Yeah, that's right,
you told me.
Thanks for the help.
A fella buy you a
drink someday, ma'am?
You know where
to find me.
I'll find you.
You were pretty
nice to that kid.
That's my job,
being nice to people.
To paying customers, you mean.
He wasn't a paying customer.
And you are,
aren't you, Mr. Burdette?
You bought me
three drinks.
Or was it four?
I didn't count.
Look, what's
bothering you?
You, if you want to know.
What about me?
I don't want you fooling around
with anyone else, do you hear?
I told you I'm going to be
the biggest man in this town.
(chuckles)
Then God have mercy
on this town.
I'm sorry, Glory.
I didn't mean that.
I'm glad you did it.
'Cause now I don't
owe you a thing
for those three drinks.
What's bothering you?
You act as though
I've done something wrong?
What have I done?
I'm not sure.
But if it's
what I'm thinking...
What are you thinking?
That maybe, just maybe it was
you who ordered that massacre.
No, that isn't true.
You heard about Harris
identifying Tukwa.
I heard you identify him,
Mr. Burdette.
I didn't hear anything else.
I didn't hear
Mr. Harris say anything.
Well, there he is now.
About time.
Where you been?
We were worried
about you.
Sit down and eat and tell
us what you found out.
Little Joe, what
they do to you, boy?
What happened
to your face?
Forget it.
Who did it?
Now hold still a minute.
Now who did it?
Some miners in
Virginia City.
I said forget it.
They beat you
like this?
They'd have hanged me
if Mark Burdette
hadn't have stopped them.
Hanged you?
For what?
For being a friend
of the Paiutes.
They saw Tukwa riding with the
men who staged that massacre.
That's a lie.
Yeah, that's what
I tried to tell them.
For what good it did me.
Who was the one
who identified Tukwa?
The only one that
came out of it alive.
That fella named Harris.
Adam, what are
you up to?
I'm going to have
a little talk
with our friend Harris.
No, wait, don't ride
in there alone;
we'll go with you.
Where've you been?
Staying away.
After all,
you fired me.
Don't be funny.
You look worried, Burdette.
Don't remember seeing
you look that way before.
You're seeing things.
There isn't anything
I can't handle.
Sure, sure.
Like that girl
I seen walk out of here.
That one named Glory?
Why do you mention her?
She doesn't have
anything to do with it.
She don't, huh?
Well, I'm real
glad to hear that.
Because I just seen her
going up to the Harris place.
The Harris place?
Suppose Harris tells
her the truth?
I thought you and me
came to Virginia City
to strike it rich,
not stretch a rope.
Well, hello, boys.
Ma'am.
Hello, ma'am.
You're pretty
busy, aren't you?
We are. We're panning
for gold, ma'am.
Gold? Does anybody
ever find it?
Michael...
You want anything here?
You're Mrs. Harris,
aren't you?
Yes, I'm Mrs. Harris.
I'm pleased to
know you, ma'am. I'm...
I know who you are.
What do you want here?
I'd like to see
your husband.
My husband?
You know my husband?
No, but I must
talk with him.
It's very important.
How is he?
Since he was hurt out there,
he does nothing
but stare at the ceiling.
Sometimes he talks,
but mostly he just stares.
Carl?
There's somebody here
wants to talk to you.
A woman.
Mr. Harris?
There's something I've got to
know about that Indian attack.
I thought
I was doing the best thing,
coming out west,
bettering myself.
We're worse off here
than we were back home.
Mr. Harris...
Mr. Harris, I've got to know
about that Indian attack.
What do you want to know?
That Indian, the one that
rode for the Cartwrights,
the one they called Tukwa.
Did you see him
during the attack?
I don't even know who he is.
Then you couldn't have
identified him, could you?
I couldn't identify anybody.
Thank you, Mr. Harris.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, ma'am.
I sure hope your luck
changes for the better soon.
Goodbye, boys; I sure
hope you find that gold.
We will.
We just got
to keep on digging, though.
She's pretty.
Hey, Mike, keep digging.
All right.
What are they doing to her?
I don't know.
We won't hurt you, Glory,
but you better go with us.
(yelping)
Why, you...
Thorne! Don't you
ever hit her again.
Who's going to stop
me, Burdette, you?
Get up there.
They're hurting her!
Ma! Ma!
Mark, why are you
doing this? Why?
Be quiet!
What is it, Michael?
They're hurting her.
Who?
The lady that just
left the house.
Carl, they've taken
that girl away.
I gotta get to town,
get help.
It was just a bare rock farm.
A man had to take a chance...
for his wife, his boys...
You boys stay here
in case your pa needs something.
Mrs. Harris, we'd like to have
a talk with your husband.
The girl!
They've taken the girl!
The girl?
What girl?
I don't know her name.
She works in the saloon.
You mean Glory?
You've got to help!
They'll kill her!
Now, Mrs. Harris, just
try to calm yourself
and tell us what happened.
It was that man named Thorne.
They were beating her.
They? Who?
Who was with Thorne?
The man he works for, the one
that wears the fancy clothes.
Two men beating up on a girl?
They rode out of town.
Thorne had the girl.
Adam, I was wrong
about him. I'm sorry.
Forget it, younger brother.
Now, what do we do
about the girl?
We find her.
Don't we, Pa?
Yeah, we find her.
Come on.
Think I can
run away out here?
Thanks.
Where's that line shack you
were talking about, Thorne?
Should be
just over that hill.
Hyah!
Whoa... Whoa.
I sure would like to get
my hands on that Thorne.
You'll get your chance as soon
as we find the girl.
Hoss, you think you can tell
which way they're heading?
Pa, if I read the signs right,
it looks to me like
they're trying to make
the other side of Devil's Gate.
You think so?
Just the hottest,
driest strip of desert
in the Nevada territory.
All right. Let's go.
Now, this is Devil's
Gate, isn't it, Thorne?
Yeah, it sure is.
Where's the shack?
Just over the ridge.
You sure?
It wouldn't make much
difference if I wasn't,
would it, Mr. Burdette?
Why don't you kill him,
Burdette?
Now, where did you get
that idea?
I thought you were the biggest
man in Virginia City.
All right, prove it.
Kill him.
Think you can do it,
Mr. Burdette?
You're right, Hoss.
They're headed
for Devil's Gate.
Wait a minute,
Little Joe.
They can't be too far ahead,
with one horse riding double.
Adam, you and Little Joe
cut around that hill.
Hoss and I will plug the gap
from this end.
Sounds good, Pa.
Come on!
You were lying, Thorne.
I should've known it.
Now, why would I do a thing
like that, eh? Come on.
There's no shack there.
There isn't anything there.
Well, there's plenty of space.
Long, dry, hot space.
Want a drink, miss?
Course, it ain't none
of that fancy whisky
like you're used to having.
I don't want anything
from you.
Good. 'Cause that's exactly
what you're going to get.
Is that what
you were planning, Thorne?
To turn her loose
in that desert, without water?
She's the only thing
between you and me making
a real killing, partner.
I'm going to kill you, Thorne.
And just how do you plan
to do that, Mr. Burdette?
(gunshot)
Take cover!
HOSS: Sounds like Adam
and Little Joe found them.
(gunfire in distance)
You've got a gun.
Why aren't you using it?
You look worried, Thorne.
I don't remember you
looking that way before.
They'll kill you, you fool.
You want to get killed?
Get her.
She got away.
No, she didn't.
Use that gun.
Use that gun, Burdette!
You knew about me
all along, didn't you?
I didn't fool you
for a minute.
Not very many men fool me, Mark.
I didn't, either.
That's what's important to me.
You saw what a fake I was
right from the start.
Not a fake.
Just a man reaching
for the moon...
or anything else
a million miles away.
A million miles...
a million dollars.
Same difference, isn't it?
You coward.
You fancy-pants coward, you!
(Glory shrieks)
He ain't good enough
to worry about; let him die.
I said let him die!
Let me go!
Come any nearer,
I'll shoot her in the back!
Why doesn't he shoot?
'Cause Thorne can
still kill the girl.
Now, you clear out of here.
Clear out of here!
(gagging, grunting)
Hoss... Hoss!
You all right?
(muttering):
Yeah...
Always said he had
a hard head, Pa.
He's dead.
He's dead, isn't he?
He came here to
strike it rich,
find a bonanza,
and now he's dead.
He found it.
He found his bonanza.
He found it
just as he died.
And that's better than never
finding it at all, isn't it?
Yes, Glory, it's better.
Much better.
BEN:
One place or another, there
will always be a Mark Burdette.
And, for everyone like him
who makes it,
a thousand will fail.
But then,
what are thousand-to-one odds
for a man who looks up
into the sky
and sees a bonanza?