ANNOUNCER:
The following program
is brought to you
in living color on NBC.
(fanfare plays)
- Thank you, Mrs. Brown.
- Howdy, Bert.
- Ben.
- Another hot day?
It sure is.
(sighs):
Eh.
Hello, Hoss.
(mouth full):
Hi, Bert. Good crackers.
They sure are.
I'll put 'em on your bill.
Bert, you put 'em
on Hoss's personal bill.
Say, I got a long list
of supplies here I'd like you
- to put together for us.
- MAN: Leave me alone!
I said leave me alone.
Some of that sweet wine, Bert.
Doctor said take a little
with my meals.
I'm out of the brand
you like, Luke.
Maybe later today
we'll have some in.
WOMAN:
Luke?
Honey, you heard what he said.
Look, you can come back later.
I don't want no woman
telling me what to do!
(panting)
Who do you think you're fooling?
You think I haven't
got any eyes?
I'll get it myself.
Oh, wait a minute, Luke,
you stay out of there.
BEN:
Luke.
Hoss and I are just going out
to have some breakfast.
Why don't you
come along with us?
Now, you Cartwrights
stay out of this.
I don't like you!
I never did!
I ain't gonna put up
with this, Luke!
You get out of here
and stay out of here!
Luke, honey, please stop.
I don't want you to get hurt!
No stinkin' storekeeper's
gonna tell me what to do.
You high and mighty Cartwrights!
You don't mean nothin' to me!
Luke, honey, please stop!
I've always wanted
to kill me a Cartwright.
(gunshots)
(grunts)
(drops gun)
(quietly):
Luke...
Luke?
Luke, honey?
(voice breaking):
Please, Luke...
Now, how'd this happen?
I'm afraid it's
too late for a doctor.
Luke's been drinking
for a week straight, Sheriff.
He plumb went out of his head.
There wasn't nothin'
Ben could do.
Luke Grayson's been heading
for this for a long time.
Yeah, maybe so.
Miserable end for a man
like Luke Grayson once was.
You had to do this,
didn't you, Ben Cartwright?
You had to kill him.
(theme song playing)
DRIVER:
Hyah!
Hyah...!
Hyah, hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Giddyap!
Well, Todd, this is the end
of our long journey.
Virginia City.
(scoffs)
Doesn't look like either of us
are gonna get much of a welcome.
But Pa must've got my letter.
I wrote him right after he sent
me the money for the fair.
Well, time's pretty valuable
to a man as rich and important
as you say your pa is.
He probably left word for you.
Let's ask around.
Well, if that's the thing to do,
I-I want to thank you anyway,
for looking out for me
the way you have.
Aw. Agent?
Yes, sir?
You know a man
called Luke Grayson?
Sure. Who don't?
Well, he was supposed
to meet this stage.
Well, now, he ain't gonna meet
this stage or any other.
You'll find him over yonder.
MAN:
You don't mean he's dead?
AGENT:
Well, now, Ab Jenkins
ain't buried
a live one recently.
However, I think the townspeople
would've been willing
to make an exception
in this case.
No...
No, he can't be dead.
He... can't be dead!
Ain't that terrible?
That boy came all the way
from Boston to see his father.
Father?!
Is that Luke's kid?
Are you sure there's nothing
more Hoss and I can do?
Appears to me you done
too much already.
I don't like the way
you said that, Mr. Jenkins.
Everybody knows
it was either Pa or Luke.
You know that
ain't what I mean, Hoss.
I was referring
to all the expense--
paying for the best funeral.
The sheriff has a special fund
to foot that kind of bill.
Yeah. The sheriff
didn't gun Luke down, I did.
We'll see you at the services.
Thank you.
Get out of my way.
Let me to him!
Is that Luke Grayson?
I'm afraid so.
Not the way I remember him.
That's not the way at all.
How did he die?
I'm afraid this ain't
the time or the place to...
Look mister,
I got a right to know.
He was my father.
Todd.
Todd Grayson.
I'd have known you anywhere.
It's all Luke talked about
the last few days.
If there's ever
anything I can do...
What do you know about him?
I'm Dianne Jordan.
Luke and I were...
your father and I...
Well, he must have
written you about me.
How did he die?
Now look, son, this is no time
to be talking
about things like this.
Isn't it?
Why isn't it?
He'll have to know the truth
sooner or later.
Your father was murdered.
Shot down in cold blood
by a man named Ben Cartwright.
Now, you know better
than that, Dianne.
Son...
this ain't the same
as back east.
When a man draws a gun
on another man...
Ben Cartwright.
Why did he want
to kill my father?
If you're Ben Cartwright,
you don't have to have
an excuse to kill a man.
Dianne, I won't have this talk.
Now, look...
Boy, you come with me a minute.
It's your father's gun.
Take a good look.
It'll show he fired twice.
There was no way back
after that.
He fired even before
Ben Cartwright drew.
My father's gun...
He wore it proudly.
It was a famous gun once.
Uh, son, the gun,
I think I ought
to turn that over
to the sheriff.
Why? It was Luke's gun,
wasn't it?
Well, yeah, sure, but...
Then it should go to the boy.
Everything Luke left
should go to the boy.
Your father left
some other things
over at my place, with me.
I know he'd want
you to have them.
...nor is it for us
to condemn the victor
even while we mourn the fallen.
We can only hope that the soul
of Luke Grayson shall achieve,
in the everlasting life beyond,
the forgiveness...
and peace
denied him on this earth.
Let us pray.
(cocks gun)
You better say one
for yourself, Mr. Cartwright,
'cause it's...
it's gonna be your last.
You murdered my father,
and now they're gonna
bury you along with him.
Don't be a fool, boy.
Put up your gun.
TODD:
When I'm finished with it!
Son, this is your last warning.
You might get off
the first shot,
- but I'll get off the second.
- Hold it, Sheriff.
He's just a scared kid now.
Sure, I'm scared,
but that's not gonna stop me.
Todd... for your own sake,
listen to me.
It was no murder.
Ben Cartwright did everything
he could to avoid bloodshed.
You keep out of this!
It isn't your fight!
It doesn't have to be
anybody's fight, son.
If I'd done what you think,
do you believe
I'd be a free man today?
Oh, I've heard
all about you Cartwrights.
You can even buy your way out
of murder, but not this time.
Let me... let me go!
(sobbing): I'll kill him!
I'll kill him!
I'll kill him...
Todd, it's all right.
It's all gonna be all right,
just the way
I promised your father.
I don't want
any favors from anyone.
That's all right, Todd.
Your father was that way, too.
He wasn't the sort of man to ask
anyone for a favor, either.
You put him there,
Ben Cartwright.
Think of that when
you try to sleep tonight.
Now, I've addressed
the complaint
to Judge Parker in Eureka.
He should be there
by the first of the month,
- and he can head straight back.
- Well, that's fine.
That should only take
about three weeks.
Now, what happens
to the boy till then?
Well, I reckon the taxpayers
can stand expense
of another boarder.
Hang it all, Roy, you can't
keep that boy behind bars!
He's not a criminal!
He's a 16-year-old kid!
With a 16-year-old gun.
Ben, do you realize
that if that kid
was just a split second sooner,
you wouldn't be around
to watch either one of them
grow any older?
That's right, Pa.
A sidewinder is just as
poisonous the day he's hatched
as he is when he's full grow'd.
Yeah, well, we're not
talking about sidewinders,
we're talking about a boy.
Besides, the fangs of this one
have already been pulled.
And I aim to see
that he don't get a chance
to grow another set.
Leastways,
until the circuit judge
decides what
happens to him next.
Well... a lot of things
can happen till then.
But not with the boy in here,
eating himself up
with grief and all.
It's just no good, Roy!
What do you want me to do,
take him by the hand
and tell him that nice
little boys just don't go out
a-murderin' their elders
and turn him loose?
(door opens)
I've come for the boy.
The boy?!
Hold on, Dianne.
He's my responsibility,
isn't he?
Who else is gonna
look after him?
He was Luke Grayson's son.
And I'm the only one around here
that cared anything
about Luke Grayson,
so that gives me
a right to the boy.
Dianne, it's not a matter
of who the boy's father is.
It's just that,
well, he's upset,
and he's kind of dangerous
when he feels this way.
Well, I could take care
of him, Sheriff.
I could give him a home.
Where?
In the saloon?
Roy, please.
You stay out of this,
Cartwright.
I don't care what you all
think about me,
but the boy has to have someone.
Don't you understand that?
He needs someone.
I'm sorry, Dianne, but I just
can't turn him over to you.
Well, could I see him?
Why, of course.
That's perfectly all right.
Right over here.
Todd?
What do you want?
Well, I-I brought you
these things.
They were your father's.
Gold watch and chain.
Remember this?
Three silver dollars.
That's all he had.
But there must have been more.
He wrote me.
Oh?
What exactly
did he tell you, Todd?
That when I got here,
he'd buy a horse for me, and...
and I'd help him build a house,
and-and together we'd...
we'd start a ranch.
Yes, I know.
How would you know?
He never would have showed you
any letters he wrote to me.
No, that's right, he wouldn't.
Besides...
he never would have sent for me
on a three-dollar promise.
He wasn't that kind of a man.
Well, he's gone now,
and, and it doesn't matter.
Well, it does to me!
And it would to you, too,
if you ever meant
anything at all to him.
Well, I don't know
what I meant to him...
...but I certainly know
what he meant to me.
Dianne...
is there something I could do
to help with the boy?
What's the matter, Cartwright?
Looking for something
to ease your conscience?
Aw, Dianne, you know
better than that.
Pa's just trying to...
I don't care
what he's trying to do.
How can he know
what I must feel?
How can any of you Cartwrights
know anything about feelings?
You've got everything you want.
Isn't any room in your life
for anything like feelings!
(door closes)
Sheriff, I'm not gonna leave
that boy in that jail cell.
Ben, now, I know what you're
thinking, but you're wrong.
You don't owe that kid
any favors.
What makes you so sure
the favor would be for him?
Roy, both of us, we've been
around a pretty long time,
but not so long that we can take
a man's life and just forget it,
whether the man
needed killing or not.
I know, Ben.
Now, I don't like
keeping that kid in jail
any more than you do, but what
do you expect me to do with him,
turn him over to Dianne?
No, no, turn him over to me.
To you?
Pa, you forgetting what that boy
tried to do to you
out at the cemetery?
Hoss, he's a scared little boy
who traveled 3,000 miles
for what?
For a funeral!
He's hurt, he's confused,
he's-he's alone.
If somebody doesn't
straighten him out now,
he'll wind up
like his father or worse.
Then somebody else
will have blood on his hands.
Pa, if-if we do take him,
what are we gonna do with him?
Take him out to the Ponderosa.
Show him what fresh air
feels like.
Give him a horse,
teach him how to ride.
Don't you think I know
what to do with boys?
Ah, sure you do, Pa, but...
but this boy wants to kill you.
He thinks he wants to kill me.
But if he stays locked up like
a criminal, he'll be sure of it.
Now, Roy, please believe me.
I know what's best.
Ben, I have all the respect
in the world for your judgment.
I think you're wrong.
But if I do turn him
over to you,
you're gonna have to be
responsible for him all the way.
I'm perfectly willing
to accept that.
Boy, he's gonna be
a mighty big handful.
Adam and Little Joe
both going out on a roundup.
Well, we'll be able
to manage him.
But it's only a parole,
nothing more.
And if he steps out of line
just one time,
you're duty-bound
to turn him back to me.
Now, you understand that?
I understand perfectly.
There'll be no trouble.
Pa, I sure hope you know
what you're doing.
So do I.
Mind if I join you?
Don't you believe in knocking?
Oh, that depends.
Your kind never does.
Now, just what is my kind?
I've seen you
in every mining camp
and every tank town honky-tonk
between here and Mexico.
Maybe not the same face
or the same fancy duds, but...
the same cold eyes,
same way of walking
and the same stink
of killing on you.
Well, now that
we understand each other,
I'll have that drink.
Nice place you've got here.
Fine taste in furniture.
Now, um, you didn't come here
just to talk about
my taste in furniture.
Now, don't be too sure
about that.
Let's just call this
a sort of, um, social visit.
(chuckles)
People like you and me--
we never get
enough chance to talk.
Nobody much cares
what we think or how we feel.
Feelings?
Can't afford 'em.
Not anymore.
No?
Then what's this
still around for?
Give it to me.
It's all I have left of him.
That and the boy.
He's on your mind
whether you like it or not.
He's nothing to me anymore.
Now that I know
he's in good hands.
The hands
that killed his father.
That kid's got spunk.
How long do you think he'll take
what Ben Cartwright dishes out?
Come on, admit it.
Sooner or later,
he'll make his play.
Then he'll get himself
killed then or hanged later.
What can I do about it?
He won't talk to me.
Maybe he doesn't have to.
Maybe he already has.
What do you mean by that?
I was at the funeral.
He tried to kill Ben Cartwright,
and you didn't try to stop him.
I'm not responsible
for what he tried to do.
Maybe not.
But you were hoping the boy
would pull the trigger.
Or weren't you?
Well, how do you
expect me to feel?
After all,
his father and I were--
Were in love?
That's very touching,
but a little out of my line.
I'm talking about
killing Ben Cartwright.
You'd kill Ben Cartwright?
For a price.
For a price,
I could kill most anybody.
What makes you think
I've got the money?
Well, not you, maybe.
I was thinking of the kid.
On the way out here,
he told me about his father.
That boy's gonna fall into
quite an inheritance.
I haven't sunk that low.
Anyway, even if I wanted
Ben Cartwright dead,
I'd never hire
a two-bit gun like you.
No, I guess you wouldn't.
You can let the boy
do it for you.
Wear something pretty when you
go out to prison to see him.
Think it over.
I'll be around if you need me.
Ain't that the prettiest bunch
of trees you ever seen, Todd?
You ever been to Boston?
No, can't say as I have.
How do you know they don't have
prettier trees there?
Well... you got something there.
Never thought of it, I reckon.
Guess there are lots of things
you never thought of.
Yeah.
Yep, I reckon
you're right at that, too.
What about that horse?
You think you can ride him?
What's so hard
about riding a horse?
Come on.
Yes, sir, there's a whole lot
more to being a cowboy
than just smelling like one
or wearing boots.
For instance, you always get up
on the left-hand side
of a horse.
And you walk up to him
real easy-like,
so's you don't spook him.
Go on, try it.
Go on.
- (neighing)
- Todd!
The left side.
Doggone it, boy.
When are you gonna
get it through
that ornery head of yours,
we're trying to help you?
Help me?
You-You think I want to ride
that sweaty old bag of bones?!
I don't give a hoot
whether you want to or not.
You're going to.
You think you can make me?!
You dad-gum tommy-tootin' I can.
Hey, hey, hey, what's going on?
Pa, I don't know.
I've tried my best
with this boy.
I can't seem to do
nothin' to please him.
Oh? What seems to be
the trouble, son?
Look, I came out here
because the sheriff made me.
That doesn't mean
I have to like it!
Now, look, Todd, when you're
here on the Ponderosa,
you're here as a guest,
not as a prisoner.
Will you try to remember that?
Howdy, Ben, Hoss.
Roy, it's good to see you.
How are things in town, Sheriff?
Fair to middling.
How you getting along
with young Todd here?
Oh, just fine, Roy, just fine.
Everything's going fine.
Gonna make a rancher
out of him yet, aren't we, Todd?
Ben, uh, I've been thinking.
Maybe I overstepped my bounds
in letting you take that boy.
Well, I-I said I'd assume
full responsibility.
Yeah, but just the same,
technically,
he's still in my custody.
Where are you figuring on
sleeping him?
Well, most of the hands are out
with Adam and Little Joe
on roundup.
I figured I'd give him
the foreman's room there,
so he could have
a place of his own.
Mm-hmm.
Seems solid enough, exceptin'
for that window in the back.
You can see that from
your room though, can't you?
Now, wait a minute, Roy.
This here's a boy's room,
it's not a jail cell.
Not as far as I'm concerned.
And, Ben...
put a lock on that door
after the kid goes to bed
tonight, you hear?
Well, I'll be heading
back to town.
Roy, we got supper
on the table in there.
Why don't you stay
and eat with us?
I wish I could, Hoss,
but I gotta get back.
I'm sorry we're late, Pa,
but Todd here couldn't quite
make up his mind whether
he wanted to eat or not.
Well, believe me, Todd, I never
had any trouble like that
with Hoss when he was your age.
Not since, either.
Mmm! You know something, Hoss?
This beef is about
the tastiest we've ever had.
Mmm! That gravy looks good, too.
Now, there's
no sense in this, boy.
I know you're hungry--
why don't you sit down and eat?
Do you think I'd eat
at the same table
with the man
that killed my father?
HOSS:
Todd, we're just trying
to help you--
can't you understand that, boy?
Don't do me any favors!
Now, look, I'm not afraid of you
or any other Cartwright.
And I'm not gonna take orders
from you, either.
Now I said I wasn't gonna eat
at this table, and I won't!
(door opens)
(door closes)
Don't let him
spoil your supper, Pa.
You done all you could.
That boy's been through
a pretty rough day, Hoss.
Probably hasn't eaten since
breakfast, maybe even longer.
Made up his mind to hate
everything about this place...
starting with us.
Well...
he didn't exactly
choose to come here.
Look at it another way.
Now, suppose I'd been the one
who'd been gunned down.
How would you feel
about breaking bread
with Luke Grayson?
Yeah.
I reckon I never looked
at it like that, Pa.
Hoss...
take the supper
out to the bunkhouse.
The boy's got to eat.
Yes, sir.
Don't be surprised if I
come back with a finger bit off.
Pa thought you might
change your mind about supper.
I brung you something to eat.
Well, you can take it
right back to him.
I said I don't want anything
from you Cartwrights.
Look, Todd...
I don't care how mad
a man gets about something,
his stomach goes right on
needing something to eat.
You think you
can make me eat that?
No. No, I can't.
And I wouldn't want
to make you eat it.
But if Pa thought
you was down here hungry
and there wasn't
no food here for you,
he'd feel real bad about it.
Your father doesn't care
anything about me.
Todd, what makes you say that?
What makes me say it?
Because it's the truth,
that's why!
Ben Cartwright's a liar!
- Now, you listen here, boy...
- No, you listen.
You must think I'm
two years old or something,
you and all your talk about,
'bout teaching me to ride.
Well, I don't want to ride, see?
And I've had just about enough
of your father's talk
about me being a guest here.
Todd, he meant that.
You are a guest here,
as far as we're concerned.
Oh, am I?
I suppose you put locks
on the doors of all your guests?
There's your supper!
You can take that back to him
and tell him I'm sick
of his kind of favors.
(plate shatters)
(door opens)
♪♪
(rattling)
(cocks gun)
(door opens)
♪♪
All right, Cartwright.
Todd, what... what is this?
I guess you know what it is.
Todd, listen to me.
Don't come any closer.
Don't come any closer!
- Don't come any closer!
- (gun clicks)
(gun clicking)
Todd, give me the gun.
No! No!
- (glass breaks)
- Todd!
Todd!
(door opens)
Hey, Pa...
what's all the racket?
What's the matter?
(gasping)
It's Todd.
He stole an empty... empty gun
out of the desk drawer.
Tried to kill me.
Tried to kill you?!
Well, the little varmint.
- Where is he?
- Outside somewhere.
Probably hiding
like a scared animal,
waiting for you and me
and a dozen other grown men
to come chasing after him.
Well, Pa, you ain't gonna
just let him go, are you?
No, I'm not gonna let him go.
I'm not gonna go
running after him, either.
- But, Pa, he tried to kill you.
- With an empty gun.
Yeah, but, Pa,
he didn't know it was empty.
Dad-burn it, how far does your
obligation go with this boy?
- Hoss, please!
- Please, nothing, Pa!
After all you done for that boy.
You gave him a home, you--
Least I could do
after what I did to him!
Sheriff Roy Coffey--
I have to think of his position.
Regardless of what I think,
I... I'm gonna have
to tell Roy what happened.
He probably stole
one of our horses and...
halfway to San Francisco by now.
How far do you think
he could get?
You saw the way he rode,
didn't you?
Yeah, but I got a sneaking hunch
he wasn't doing
his best, neither.
Well, he'll probably...
try to find his way
back to Virginia City.
If he did, we'll...
we'll find him there.
I'm not gonna run after him;
not tonight anyhow, I...
(Ben gasping)
Let's try to get some rest.
We'll go see the sheriff
first thing in the morning.
It's getting late, honey.
Why don't you go to bed?
Go to bed?
I haven't slept since he died.
You gotta go on living, kid.
Yeah.
That's just the trouble.
Living and...
thinking.
Looking at nothing but this
day and night.
You really loved him,
didn't you?
Sure.
Funny, isn't it, Charlie?
Me falling in love
with a guy like Luke Grayson.
He really wasn't much, huh?
Couldn't keep a job.
Always getting in fights.
Always getting drunk.
Half the time he didn't
even know I was alive.
Funny, isn't it, Charlie?
You're not laughing.
Nope. I ain't laughing.
You remember how he was?
When he'd walk down the street,
all the women'd get mad
that they'd met
their own husbands.
I was just like 'em.
My eyes would follow him
wherever he went.
He was so...
so tall and straight
and...
and that smile that...
He was like that to me
until the day he died.
You want another drink, kid?
Yeah, I guess so.
Better than trying
to get to sleep.
Thanks.
Are you open for business?
Sure, I'm open for business.
What can I do for you?
I want to buy a gun.
Guns cost money, boy.
I-I've got money.
It's not much,
it's three dollars,
but that ought to buy
a gun of some kind.
I don't have a gun
I can let go for three dollars.
Look, mister,
any gun, an old one.
M-Maybe you've got
something here
that somebody left on a bill
or something like that.
Son, you might as well know,
I wouldn't sell a gun
to Luke Grayson's boy
for $3.00 or $3,000.
And nobody else
in town would, either.
Now just run along
and forget it.
(grunts)
(hoofbeats clopping past)
♪♪
DIANNE: Well, good
night, Charlie.
Todd, what are you doing here?
Mind your own business.
Leave me alone.
Todd, you're in trouble.
What's happened?
I-I tried
to kill Ben Cartwright.
Well, Todd, they'll catch you.
They'll put you in jail.
I don't care what they do to me.
Well, we can't stand here
talking like this.
Someone will see us.
Here, come with me.
Ben, it's just bad seed.
I knew Luke Grayson
when he amounted to something,
but he still had
that bad streak in him.
The boy's got it now,
just as same as the old man had.
You got any idea
which way he headed?
Well, he came this way,
as close as we can figure.
Well, I'll get a couple
of deputies.
I'd like
to have you come along, Hoss.
Ben?
Yeah, might as well get started.
Good.
Bert...
what happened to you?
Uh, Luke Grayson's kid came in
the store
and wanted to buy a gun.
I refused to sell it to him.
When I turned around, he hit me
on the head with an ax handle.
Don't you think you better have
a doctor take a look at you?
Well, I don't know.
Kind of stunned me for a minute.
I kept seeing the kid
taking the gun,
and I couldn't make my legs work
quick enough to stop him.
He took a gun?
That's right.
Six-shooter and some shells.
He knew what he was doing.
Ben, you better
take him up to the doctor.
Hoss will go along with me.
BEN:
All right.
And Ben, it's not just
a 16-year-old boy
we're dealing with.
It's Luke Grayson's kid,
and he's got a loaded gun.
All right, Roy.
All right.
I asked you,
where did you get that gun?
I told you--
I just got it, that's all.
Now that you've got it,
what are you going
to do with it?
I'm going
to kill Ben Cartwright.
What do you think
I'm going to do with it?
Now listen to me--
I want him dead
just as much as you do,
but what chance do you think
a kid like you will have
against all those grown men?
All I need is just
one clear shot.
Don't you realize
that they'll cut you to ribbons
the minute
you walk outside this room?
Todd, what are you going to do?
I'm getting out of here.
No, Todd. Wait.
There's another way.
Wh-What are you talking about?
If I help you,
will you promise me
that you'll leave Virginia City
and never come back here again?
How can you help me?
This is a draft
on the First City Bank
of San Francisco-- $500.
If I sign it,
it'll be payable to bearer.
Five hundred dollars.
Then I was right.
Right about what?
This is my father's money.
You were holding out on me.
Holding out on you?
Todd, I'm just trying
to help you.
Look, if my father
gave you this, you keep it.
I don't even want
to hear about it.
(door opens)
Maybe you don't need it, kid...
but I do.
You won't need that gun.
I'm on your side.
Right, Dianne?
What are you doing here?
I told you
I'd be here when you needed me.
I think you do now.
And I know you stole that gun.
So does the sheriff,
and he's coming to get you.
I've got to get him out of here,
get him to San Francisco.
Do you think
you could you do it?
I can do it for $500.
You see, I was listening
outside your door.
Now that's not
socially correct maybe,
but it's a way
to find things out.
Now you just sign it, and
I'll get the kid out of town.
There's only one thing.
You mustn't cash it
until you get to San Francisco.
Sure. I'm in no hurry.
What are you doing?
I don't want anything from you!
Look, my father wouldn't have
anything to do
with a woman like you.
Now, look, boy,
you do as you're told,
or I'll let
the sheriff have you.
Cash that for me.
Five hundred dollars?!
That's a lot of money.
You've got that much
in the till.
Just go ahead and cash it.
I... I've never seen anything
quite like this before.
Mr. Cartwright?
Yes, Charlie?
Would you take a look
at this for me?
Yes. What is it?
It's a bank draft.
You know about these things.
- I wish you'd look it over.
- Fine.
He doesn't have to look it over.
It's good.
It's got Dianne Jordan's
signature on it.
Why did she give you this?
I don't think that's any
of your business, Cartwright.
This has something to do
with Todd, doesn't it?
What's the matter, Cartwright?
Can't you hear good?
Where's the boy?
You've got my money.
I said, where's the boy?
I don't like people touching me,
and I don't like 'em
grabbing my money.
If this is yours legitimately,
you'll get it back,
but not until I've talked
to Dianne about this.
Ben!
Here...
Go on, that way.
(knocking on door)
BEN:
Dianne?
Are you in there, Dianne?
It's Ben Cartwright.
The door's open.
I think this belongs to you.
Where did you get that?
From that two-bit gunman
who's been hanging around town.
He tried to cash it downstairs.
DIANNE:
He tried to cash it?
Well, what business
is it of yours?
Maybe I owed it to him.
Maybe he did me a favor once.
Well, did he?
Or was he about
to do you a favor...
like killing me.
It was Luke's money.
Luke owed it to Appling, and--
Dianne, Luke never had $50
as long as I knew him,
much less $500.
Get out of here.
I don't have to sit here
and listen
to you saying these things
about Luke.
You killed him.
Isn't that enough?
Don't you think
the whole town knows
it was you who supported Luke?
Don't you think they know
it was you who fed him,
who clothed him, who even
gave him his drinking money?
And all the time, he didn't
even know you were alive.
That's not true.
Luke was good to me.
He loved me.
Did he?
Do you think Luke was capable
of loving anyone,
or even of thinking of anyone
other than himself?
Stop that! I won't listen
to you saying such things.
I won't listen, do you hear?
I won't listen!
Dianne...
you know that
what I'm saying is the truth.
And one day you're gonna have
to face that truth.
Where's the boy?
(gun clicks)
- (Dianne gasps)
- Right here, Cartwright.
It's easy to lie about a man
when he's dead
and can't talk back, isn't it?
Todd, put away that gun.
I'll put it away
after I kill you.
And this time,
I'm not going to miss.
This time,
I got bullets in the gun.
Todd, don't. Wait!
Todd, stop!
He killed my father.
Are you forgetting that?
No, I'm not forgetting,
but everything he said
about your father was true.
No, it's a pack of lies.
No, it wasn't a pack of lies.
Look, I knew your father better
than anyone in the whole world.
He wasn't any good,
just like Ben Cartwright said.
He was no good.
No. You're lying.
He... He sent me money.
He wanted me to come out here
and live with him.
DIANNE:
He never sent you a dime.
Every honest dollar
that Luke got, he drank faster
than he could walk
to the post office.
That $500 that I gave
to Appling was mine.
The money--
the check that you got
every month
to keep you in school--
that was mine.
Even the money
that you were sent
to bring you back here
to Virginia City was mine.
See, I thought if he...
if he saw his own son, that that
would help him straighten out.
It couldn't be.
If he was so bad,
why would you...?
DIANNE:
Why did I stick to him?
Because I loved him.
(crying)
I loved him
from the first moment I saw him.
(sobbing)
(uncocks gun)
Give me the gun, boy.
I keep trying to remember him
the way I wanted him to be.
He was such a wonderful man.
Such a rotten, lousy,
stinkin'...
wonderful man.
Pa, you all right?
Charlie just told us
what happened.
Yeah, I'm all right, Hoss.
That boy-- he's going
to be all right now, too.
I'm still gonna have
to take him in, Ben.
He stole a gun.
Did he, Roy?
An empty gun.
Now, what do you think
that would be worth?
The lives of two people?
I guess
it ain't worth a thing, Ben.
Oh, Roy, uh, in case
you happen to think about it,
that, uh, horse of ours--
the boy didn't steal it.
I just gave it to him.
That right, Hoss?
Yes, sir, that-that's right.
Roy, you-you tell him
to ride him out
and pay us a visit.
BEN: And tell him
to bring his new ma.
ANNOUNCER: This has been
a color presentation
of the NBC Television Network.