You do realize why you're in this car,
do you not?
You've been tasked by Mr. Durant
to build a bridge.
Any man can lay track.
Am I correct?
Yes, ma'am.
Pretty near.
Then can you explain
why you've been spending
all your energy at rail's end
instead of at the bridge site?
That will be remedied, ma'am.
Thank you.
[Sighs]
You heard what the lady said.
This the part where I tell you the men
don't like taking orders from a woman.
They don't have to like it.
No, they don't.
But if you're looking to get back
in Mr. Durant's good graces,
then pissing off the man
might not be the best tact.
Doesn't matter,
as long as we get this rail road built.
[Chuckles] If you're not
careful, miss bell,
you're going to start sounding like a man.
Right.
[Men shouting]
[Train whistle blowing]
All right! Move your carcasses!
Step on it!
You lot, for the gorge,
make room for one more.
And as for the rest of you
jackanapes, I expect to be able
to walk a mile of rail
by the time I get back from me lunch break.
[Indistinct chatter]
Change the numbers all you want,
that ain't the problem.
56 men?
23.
And we've got another 46 coming in.
Another...
[Man screaming and sobbing]
[Screaming and sobbing continues]
That's got to be Fleming.
The sentry?
You need to do something.
[Screaming and sobbing continues]
[Gunfire]
[Sobbing continues]
Bring me the long rifle.
There's too many!
They got the high ground.
If you keep them occupied,
we can loop back and try and outflank 'em.
Damn it, I said bring me
the long rifle right now!
Get back.
[Sobbing continues]
[Gunshot]
[Sobbing stops]
Man: He shot Fleming!
[All murmuring]
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Look at me.
I see you.
[Both gasping and moaning]
Damn, woman.
[Laughs]
[Both laugh]
What's so funny?
Never thought I'd be glad
Mr. Toole made foreman.
Out early, home late.
Don't speak his name.
You know the rules.
Right.
'Cause you live by rules.
[Birds chirping]
I want you to feel something.
Damn, girl.
Give a man a minute to raise his spirit.
[Both laugh]
You feel that?
That little bump?
You and me made that.
How you know?
Because I know.
Say something.
Elam Ferguson, you look me in the eyes
and you tell me what you're thinkin'.
Don't you leave here
without saying something.
I can't.
See, I'm ask... asking you
to look... look inside your heart.
Inside your heart.
Sorry, Reverend.
I'm afraid it's empty.
Same as my wallet.
[Grunting]
Hey!
All right now?
Reverend.
Cullen!
Could you...
Could you spot a fellow traveler a drink?
Rye, barkeep.
- Be right with you.
- Carl.
Just the one.
You've got to read over a man today.
Oh, you have to ask
that harlot who threw me out.
You mean your daughter?
Yeah.
That sinning bitch
stole my church.
Yes, she's...
Your conduit to the Lord now.
You mind me asking
where you been bedding down?
I've been, uh,
been sleeping in the cemetery.
It's near freezing at night.
There's no cover.
Yeah, I find the dead a comfort.
[Train whistle blows]
What the hell?
You can bunk with me
until you get yourself settled.
Go on. Set him up.
Carl, set them... set them up.
[Men shouting]
Cullen:
What in the hell's going on?
Why aren't y'all men at work?
Turn around and get back on...
[Gunshot]
Mr. Toole.
You mind telling me
why these men ain't at work?
With all due respect,
we lost a man out there.
A mate.
Man: That's right!
Then you finish your day's work.
Then you come back in
and drink to his memory.
We parlayed.
We all agree.
It's not safe.
It's about to get unsafe around here
if you don't get your ass back to work.
I am afraid you'll just have to shoot us.
That's right!
If we route South,
then we can bridge the river here...
And avoid the entire issue of Sacred Land.
Yes.
At considerable expense.
Spend a few more pennies now
and keep your work force, Thomas.
Pennies.
We can't run from the Sioux.
If it ain't this gorge,
it'll be the next one.
- The men are afraid to work.
- Then we should find ones who ain't.
They believe that if the Sioux
won't kill them, perhaps you will.
Bullshit.
Of course. When logic isn't on
your side, resort to the profane.
All right, I'll give you facts.
Here, here, here.
May not be sacred,
but it's all Sioux territory.
We've already established what's
on this side of the gorge!
For once, let's be smart.
Reroute and show the men that we can
steer them out of harm's way.
The Indians' home's at stake, young lady.
They'll fight us all
the way to the Rockies.
- If that's true, then we're lost!
- We turn tail first sign of trouble,
yes, we are.
You don't...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is your plan, Mr. Bohannon?
Fight 'em here, fight 'em now.
With what? That rabble?
Them's the ones we got.
[Chuckles] They...
They won't even work for you.
You let me worry about that.
Just don't reroute this rail road.
Let me.
Thank you.
Your husband know about
what you told me earlier?
No.
Nobody knows but you and me.
Good.
I've spent my whole
life trying to get free.
Then here come a woman...
A white woman...
A married woman, spinning my head
saying she's got my baby.
I couldn't think of nothin' to do but run.
Then it set with me.
And?
Any harm come to you,
I go weak in the head.
You are weak in the head.
All the gold eagles in the world
ain't worth a pinch of coon shit
if you can't use it to help
the folk that you care about.
Elam...
[Sighs] What are you saying?
You saying you care about me?
I love you.
I love you, woman.
[Coins jingling]
I need you to take these double eagles
and get yourself taken care of.
Taken care of.
You can't have no black baby.
Your husband will kill
it or you or both of you.
Elam, I used to be a whore.
If I want to get rid of this child,
I got my ways.
And you don't need to fear
for your freedom on my account.
♪ A prouder man I'd walk the land ♪
♪ In health and peace of mind
♪ if I might toil and strive and moil ♪
♪ Nor cast one thought behind
♪ but what would be the world to me ♪
♪ Its wealth and rich array
♪ if memory I lost of thee
♪ my own dear galway...
I come to pay my respects
to Mr. Fleming.
He was a good man.
A poor end he was met with.
And he won't be the last, I'm afraid.
For Mr. Michael Fleming...
Um...
He didn't ask for what he got...
But he got it anyway.
[All murmuring]
Life ain't fair.
Ain't fair at all.
Hell, most of us here in this room
fought in a war one side or the other.
We all seen men fall.
We prayed over 'em, we drank over 'em.
But we did not quit.
The best way to honor
your friend is to carry on.
Finish this road.
[All murmuring]
Mr. Bohannon, Mr. Bohannon!
No disrespect intended,
but we won't die for your rail road.
Not on your life!
Your friend didn't have to die.
You best have a point.
We're all in the same position...
The Sioux don't look
at any of us any different.
They just aim to kill.
That doesn't explain why you're
interrupting a private wake.
We're willing to protect
the end of the rail
and the bridge site.
If the rail road give us guns,
we'll go out early and...
Give 'em guns?
[Loudly] Patrol for Sioux.
Mr. Durant ain't going
to arm no ex-slaves
and these men wouldn't
stand for it, neither.
Damn right.
Aye!
You best get yourself on out of here.
Then you ain't getting no work out of us.
That's not a stand you want to take.
We aren't working, neither.
Not until you protect us.
We won't be sitting ducks out there.
[All murmuring]
Dammit, y'all, listen to me.
That road's going to get
built with or without you.
If y'all don't go to work,
it's you who's going to lose.
Now trust me on this.
You'll lose and it'll get ugly.
I'm sorry for your loss.
♪ 'Tis far away I am today
♪ from scenes I roamed a boy ♪
♪ And long ago the hour
I know, I first saw Illinois ♪
♪ But time nor tide nor waters wide ♪
♪ Can wean my heart away
♪ forever true it flies to you ♪
♪ My dear old galway bay
Hang him!
They are burning me at the stake out there
and I had to come and find you?!
Thank you.
Yes, ma'am.
[Glass shatters]
What are they demanding?
They want protection.
Well, we can't guarantee their safety
against the Sioux.
It's a hazard of the job.
More beans.
And the freedmen?
They want to be armed.
Give rifles to an army of ex-slaves?
[Scoffs] No, no.
I won't allow it.
- That's what I told them.
- This is why we change the route.
Avoid sacred land.
Win the men back
by taking them out of harm's way.
You do that, you'll lose this rail road.
At least get the freedmen back out there.
They'll do what we tell them to do.
All evidence to the contrary.
Those Negroes...
Are the property of this rail road,
Mr. Bohannon.
Property?
Yes.
Most of the freedmen are criminals
that we bought their sentences
from the states where
they were serving time.
Bought them, bought me,
it's all beside the point.
They do not make demands.
I told you when you hired me,
this was a war.
Yes. And I expected you
to have a battle plan.
Well?!
Let me be clear.
I can't do anything
without your complete authority.
This is yours to deal with.
Then, yeah.
I've got a plan.
[All yelling]
Hear you're holding
that rail road hostage, huh?
He'll use you as a sacrificial
lamb for them Injuns.
You worry about your people.
And I'm going to worry about mine.
Boys get themself killed playing with guns.
They ain't never going to see us as equals
till we holding the weapons they got.
Ohh.
[All yelling]
I suppose everybody looks the same
once the maggots get to 'em.
Mm-hmm.
[Muffled shouting]
You'd be a vision even if your whole body
were covered in them things.
Your beauty could never
be hidden from my eyes.
Are you drunk, Mr. Toole?
How did you know?
You always wax poetic
when you got a noseful.
Chitterlings again?
Yeah.
I had a hanking for them.
Just can't seem to get enough.
They're fattening you up a bit.
I like me a woman with a bit of girth.
Oh, it's... it's strange
me wanting to eat so much
with me being so sick
in the mornings of late.
I'm sure it'll pass.
Give us a kiss, woman.
Mmm.
Mr. Toole...
I'm with child.
And it ain't yours.
I can't...
I can't lie to you.
You've been one of the most
halfway decent men I ever known,
but this... this child
belongs to another.
Does this mean you're leaving me?
[Clatter]
Seems you've got your work
cut out for you, boss man.
It ain't nothing I can't handle.
Can you send a message
to the council bluffs office?
"Labor negotiations stalled." Stop.
"Work halted." Stop.
"Send 200 replacement workers
on the next available train."
Stop.
Got that?
All right.
There's gonna be bloodshed.
What you care?
You ain't no Freedman.
You sure as hell ain't Irish or German.
I ain't cleaning up after your mess.
Nah. You'll just do whatever
Mr. Durant wants you to.
Won't you?
[Accordion plays]
There is a storm brewing in town.
Oh, that's... that's a labor dispute
it appears to me.
Oh, more blood.
More bodies.
More coffins.
Heh heh heh.
Our jobs have never
been more secure. Hmm?
[Hiccup]
Can I tell you a...
A secret, Reverend?
War is coming.
Yet again.
And not this business of
workers sitting down on the job.
A real war.
Ahh!
Now is the time...
To see things clear.
We must decide...
Which side we are on.
Hmm?
[Dogs bark in distance]
[Indistinct chatter]
Where do you think you're going?
Out of me way.
I'm gonna tell you this once.
You lay a hand on her,
I'm gonna kill you.
Oh, you can thrash me?
Fine.
You're not a real man.
Just so we're clear.
Puffed up. Big gun.
You can go to hell.
What kind of man are you?
Most of us would give
our life to be a father,
but look at you, huh?
You didn't even stay by her side before.
And where are you now?
In the middle of town flexing
your damn trigger finger.
[Spits]
You're no father.
You're just a coward.
Good night, then, yellow belly.
Reverend?
You... you got any socks you want done?
[Train whistle blows]
Why don't you go to the starlight, huh?
Get us a bottle.
What's a train doing here so late at night?
Steel workers.
Coming in to take over for
thems who won't go out.
You're replacing the men?
Laying rail ain't no scholarly business.
If the men don't want to work,
there's hundreds more where they came from.
Now, you get us a bottle.
Whatever's left, you keep.
[Train whistle blows]
Elam:
You enjoying your view?
Matter of fact, I ain't.
[Men shouting]
Let's go!
The men think they stepping off that train
and get jobs.
If they can fight,
they might just have them.
[Indistinct yelling]
[All shouting]
Boys are getting their ass kicked.
Let's get them, boys!
[All shout]
Don't do it.
[Shouting continues]
[Train whistle blows]
You tell anybody else trying
to come out here what happened.
You hear me?
[Cheering]
Get out of here!
Go! Go!
Go back where you came from!
[Men cheering, train whistle blowing]
Woman: Let me see.
Man: What you got?
[Indistinct chatter]
We're willing to go back to work,
under one condition.
Maybe you don't understand.
I could have another trainload
of workers here tomorrow.
We understand.
If the Negroes are
willing to put themselves
between us and the Sioux,
we're OK with them having guns.
Hmm.
Go get yourself some rest, Mr. Toole.
Proud of yourself?
Pride ain't got nothing to do with it.
So that was the plan?
Now everybody's supposed to
get along happy ever after?
Not quite yet.
Now you need to get your
people back to work.
Ain't no sense having a horse
unless it's broke enough
so you can ride it.
Except we ain't talking about horses.
We talking about men.
Same principle.
You work for Mr. Durant now.
Same as me.
That means we're the ones doing the riding.
Y'all got a choice.
You either get back to work...
Or go back to prison.
Says who?
Boss man.
Then we need to hear it from the boss man.
You're hearing it just as good from me.
I ain't hearing nothing but some noise...
Coming from the boss man's flunky.
Look at you.
What you've become.
Get your ass up, boy!
[Men shouting]
Get him, son.
Get him!
♪
Aah!
Don't know if you're black,
don't know if you're white.
You're nothing.
You hear me?
[Grunts]
[Chicken clucks]
[Groaning]
You ain't nothing.
Get your ass up.
Get your ass up, boy.
Aah!
You bit me!
[Grunts]
[Groans]
You're still my nigger.
[Grunts]
[Men cheering]
[Chickens clucking]
Strike's over.
[Door closes]
They gave in?
If the freedmen agree
to go back out, no conditions,
when the men sober up,
we'll give the Negroes rifles
and send everybody back out to the cut.
But you said yourself
we can't capitulate to their demands.
Point is, we ain't.
I am not arming the freedmen.
You want this rail road built,
somebody's got to patrol that land.
Now, you gonna let me do this or not?
[Sighs]
Well, if they want to be Cannon fodder,
hmm, so be it.
But we have lost two days and 5 Miles.
Those men fought to
the death for their jobs.
We'll make up those 5 Miles in no times.
So that's it.
We move forward.
At what cost?
You're the one said building this rail road
is the only thing that matters.
Being smart and rerouting
is not the same as being weak.
You and me's gonna have to
agree to disagree.
Yes. Because clearly it always
has to be on your terms,
doesn't it?
It don't work...
If there's any question about that.
Got yourself a real workforce now.
[Door closes]
[Footsteps]
Mrs. Toole,
your husband has returned home.
Reverend, you leaving me?
Well, I see you've
bent the men to your will.
I suppose I played a part in that.
Yeah.
Is it true?
I mean, do you believe
you're at war with the Sioux?
Yes, sir, I do.
And now you have the men to do the job.
I can't stay with you.
I respect that.
Rifle in your left hand,
cartridge in your right.
Join the line.
Arms distance, please.
You think this is unwise?
Probably.
But this is...
Barrels down, gentlemen.
But a necessary evil, Mr. Toole.
You're speaking of
yourself then, Mr. Bohannon.
[Scoffs]
[Grunting]
Rifle in your left hand.
Cartridges in your right.
Congratulations.
All right, gentlemen.
The rest of y'all,
rifles in your left hand,
barrels facing the sky.
Finger off the trigger.
Take one cartridge in your right hand.
Sharp end is the business end.
Load that cartridge into the cartridge port
on the side of your rifle,
business end first.
Now, on the order to make ready,
rack that lever all the way forward
and all the way back,
loading the round into the chamber.
And... make ready!
[Guns click]
You dropped your round.
[Laughter] Pick it up.
Start again.
And... make ready!
[Gun click]
[Horse neighs]
Boss man coming through.
Hold your fire.
Boss man coming through!
Anything moves...
Shoot the shit out of it.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com