Previously on AMC’s Hell on Wheels…
Governor, my men are going back to work.
I want your guarantee they'll be left alone.
Sidney Snow, did you get him?
It's a fire!
It was him. It was Sidney Snow.
- Ezra hasn't come back.
- Under the floor.
[screams]
- You and me got unfinished business.
- Drop that gun.
♪ There's a land that ♪
♪ is fairer than day ♪
♪ and by faith we can see it afar ♪
♪ for the father waits over the way ♪
♪ to prepare us a dwelling place there ♪
♪ in the sweet by and by ♪
♪ by and by ♪
♪ we shall meet on
♪that beautiful shore ♪
♪ in the sweet ♪
♪ by and by we shall meet... ♪
Whoa, whoa.
♪ In the sweet by and by ♪
- [Woman screams]
- Stay where you are!
Ahh!
What are you doing here?
Daniel, help!
I've done nothing wrong!
Thomas, run!
♪ And our spirits shall sorrow ♪
Don't you hurt my kids!
♪ No more ♪
♪ not a sigh ♪
♪ for the blessing of rest ♪
[Grunting]
Reverend Cole.
Please.
Time's come, Henry...
For the sins of slavery to be
washed away from this land.
Purged by blood from your hands
as foreordained by God himself.
Lord.
Have mercy.
For as long as there are those in bonds,
I am bound with them.
Leave this place!
You are free!
No, they're... they're mine!
I have broken no law.
Law?
I acknowledge no master in
human form, nor should they.
But if I be asked to forfeit my life
in furtherance of justice for them,
I will gladly mingle my blood
with that which I spill...
Tonight!
No!
Pa!
- Let it be done!
- No!
♪ In the sweet by and by ♪
♪ we shall meet on
that beautiful shore ♪
Ruth?
What'd you do?
Oh, she did plenty. [Groaning]
Ugh.
Will you tend to her?
- Of course.
- Take her.
She shot a man.
- You're the law.
-  I'll handle it.
That's not good enough.
Those church ladies sure can shoot.
Shut up. I need help with this man.
Let him die.
Psalms? Delaney? Come on.
Get him up. Ahh!
Leave him. He don't deserve to live.
Ugh!
He dies, Ruth's a murderer.
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
Clear off that back table!
Breakfast is over, folks.
Easy, easy, easy.
Ahh! I said easy!
Ugh...
What you need, Mr. Bohannon?
We got Eva here.
Get on back to work.
Delaney? Need that steam shovel built.
Psalms.
Bullet went clear through.
This one's still in him.
Well, I know you ain't going fishing.
You don't know shit.
- Ahh!
- He's bleeding out.
We don't get that bullet out, he gonna die.
I need some coffee grounds.
Much as you got.
He needs a doctor.
Well, he's got us.
Here.
- Hold him still.
- Son of a... ahh!
If you ain't got a doctor,
you might as well find me a priest!
Ahh!
Closest thing we got put this bullet in ya.
The Lord Giveth and the Lord Taketh away!
Ruth.
Do you know what happened?
Do you know where you are?
Ezra's in the ground...
And I'm in the newspaper office.
That gunpowder will wash right off.
I have my father's hands.
Look.
Here.
I'll get you a wet cloth.
- Here.
- It won't help.
Sidney's bleeding out.
Needs a doctor.
He needs to be put down.
You that far gone?
It's what's best.
For everybody but Ruth.
[Groans]
Damn it, Bohannon.
[Groans] Hey.
Hey.
Hey, you ever been to Mexico?
Huh?
I got $5 in my boots.
I need a gun and a horse.
Maybe two horses.
Oh!
I don't care if you've got $5,000.
You're gonna die in this town,
by bullet or by rope.
Hard to get. I like that.
How is he?
He ain't dead yet.
Oh, come on.
I need a doctor, not some pencil dick.
Listen to me, you little pissant.
I am your only hope of
surviving past sundown,
so my advice is: Don't piss me off.
Good God.
Is that coffee?
We used it in the war to slow the bleeding.
Ah.
No wonder you lost.
Ahh!
How bad?
Bullet's lodged in the lower abdomen.
[Rapid breathing and coughing]
- It's nicked the celiac artery.
- Oh!
If I don't sew it up...
- Ahh!
- Stop the bleeding...
He won't need my help to die.
All right, fix it.
I'm not a magician.
Let's get started, then.
I told you I wasn't gonna make it.
Oh, hell, Sid. You've been shot before.
Plenty a times, so you told it.
I lied.
I ain't never been shot.
Yeah.
- Ahh! Ahh!
- Hold him!
I'm trying.
[Agonized groaning]
Hurry... hurry up.
I got it.
Okay, get it out. Get it out.
Eva, get me a pan.
He dead?
Not yet.
[Gasps]
What did you see, Ruth?
Tell me!
I'm sorry, Papa!
I am sorry! [Crying]
I won't strike you again.
Tell me what you saw.
I... I saw what happened...
To those men...
What you did.
It's God's will, Ruth...
'Cause those men were sinners.
Slavers.
Practicing that wickedness here in Kansas.
God exacts judgment against
such men through me,
the instrument of His hand.
It's God's will.
God's will?
What is it?
God's will.
That's right.
Good girl.
She's not herself.
I'm sure you've seen this in the war.
Water...
Won't chase the metal from your mouth.
It's from your heart racing.
It's what happens when you shoot a man.
And your hands get cold.
It'll pass.
I killed that man.
You ain't killed nobody.
Durant dug the bullet out of Sidney.
He's sewing him up now.
He'll hang for what he done.
We will have due process, Mr. Bohannon.
And by your hand, per that badge
on your chest, as we agreed.
She ain't done nothing.
You or I would have done if
circumstances were similar.
I want her jailed and
arraigned before the court.
Sidney snow needs to be jailed.
Soon as he's able,
he'll stand trial for murder,
be convicted, hanged, and forgotten.
In the event he dies first,
it must be seen that she's held accountable.
You arrest the church lady
for shooting Sidney Snow,
that might be your last act
as provisional anything.
She means that much to you?
Whole town.
Post a guard 'til we see
what Providence brings.
End of the line folks! Cheyenne!
Last stop! End of the line!
If it's trouble you bring,
you best keep walking.
We got our fill within.
Trouble's what I seek, madam...
In the form of Michael McGinnes.
Would you happen to know
where I might encounter him?
I heard he left town.
Well, now...
Suppose it's his dear ol'
cousin who'd be asking.
Would you have seen him then?
I don't care if it's Christ himself asking.
I haven't seen McGinnes
and I don't expect to.
You're a fine bit of stuff, aren't ya?
The brothel, then.
[Laughing]
Well, if it isn't the ugliest mug
west of the bleeding channel.
- Johnny!
- Michael!
- How the hell are ya?
-  Oh!
Hungry, horny, itching to fight.
You haven't changed a bit.
Beginning to wonder you wouldn't show.
Ah, Miles of cathouses and saloons
between New York and here, Michael.
But none as fine as this establishment, boy.
Ladies! This is me cousin,
"Dandy" Johnny Shea,
and this pack of rare
Bulgarians are the dead rabbits.
Welcome, lads.
Welcome. Tell you what.
Why don't you take them upstairs
and welcome them to Cheyenne properly.
- Let's go.
- Yes, sir.
Go on, get up. I'll speak to me cousin.
Hell yeah.
So, uh, Michael.
Remind me now why I left me
Dan and wife in the five points
to come out to this...
Rotten stink hole.
We're gonna extort some people,
bash some heads,
and strong-arm the governor.
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
It's grand to see ya, Michael.
It's great to see ya, boyo.
Tell me he ain't gonna die.
I've stemmed the bleeding.
He's stable.
I gave you ten, senorita.
You 'member that.
Drop the gun, Sid.
Adios, Bohannon.
You know me better than that.
Here, get him up. Oh...
The artery's shredded.
I can't fix that and I
can't stop the bleeding.
You ain't gonna let me die, doc.
We come too far now.
There's nothing more to be done, it's over.
Shit!
All right, saw it off.
Right above the wound and sew it there.
You can't be serious.
Hell no, you ain't gonna take my leg off!
Can't let you die, Sid.
Leg's coming off.
Bohannon!
Now you're just being cruel,
Bohannon, let him die.
He does, Campbell hangs Ruth.
Don't be absurd. He can't hang a woman.
It's been done.
There's not a jury in the
land who'll convict her.
Yeah, well I ain't taking that chance.
Got an amputation blade?
No.
And I have never amputated a leg, either.
I'll get you through it.
You best be building a birdhouse.
You want to die?
If I do, it's gonna be with two legs on.
Well, you lost that choice
when you threw them lanterns.
Hold him down.
Hey, hey, hey. No, no, no, hey!
You come anywhere near me
with that knife, I swear it God,
it's gonna be the last thing you do!
Ah! No! No no!
Look! Hey, Bohannon! Bohannon!
Look at me! Look at me!
Just let it loose and let me go!
Just put me on a horse!
Put me on a horse and I-I'll go!
I don't never come back!
You ain't never gonna see me again!
Come on! Come on!
Look! Just don't take my leg!
Just put me on a horse,
I'll go, I'll never come back,
you never gonna see me again,
I swear to God!
Don't take my leg!
[Groaning and choking]
[Screams]
I take no pleasure
in the prospect of sending the
church lady to the Gallows.
But that is the task laid before us,
be swift about it.
Your friend, miss Ellison,
will need to be managed.
She's widely read
and has been critical of our policies here.
The rule of the law applies
to everyone, Judge.
Task of enforcing it is
not a pleasant burden.
I'm not entirely unsympathetic.
Couched in the right language.
I'll handle miss Ellison.
Campbell!
You'll give me your ears before
you bend them elbows again.
This is here "Dandy" Johnny Shea.
He's a hard man.
A bruiser.
And a cousin on me mother's side.
And from this day forward,
he is the new proprietor
of this establishment
and any man who takes issue with that
can take it up with meself,
can take it up with Johnny,
or with one of our good friends here.
Is this the coward who beat
ya when your hands were tied,
Michael?
It is.
You want to, uh,
you want to dance with me, boyo?
He can't save you now.
Casino is yours, Mr. McGinnes.
Ugh!
Ahh!
Mr. McGinnes, we conceded the casino.
Johnny, that's enough.
Ahh!
I'll scoop the shite
clean out of your skull!
Mr. McGinnes, control your man!
- Ahh!
- Johnny!
I said stop, let go of him.
I heard ya, Mick!
Thing is, I love ya,
but I don't work for ya!
[Screaming]
A madman.
That's what they called my father.
Who? The newspapers?
I used to hate reporters.
I still do...
Sometimes.
When he left home to speak for
the Indians once and for good,
I read every article on his exploits.
And they called him a martyr.
I'm not a martyr.
How do you see yourself?
I'm a mother.
This is going to hurt like hell.
No no no no! No!
Wait wait wait wait wait wait!
Ahh!
[Screaming]
Now, Bohannon.
- Come on, man.
- Hold still.
It'll go faster.
Don't cut it off.
[Groaning]
My condolences, miss Ruth.
Over Ezra passing.
Thank you, Psalms.
What you need?
I'll get it for you.
No, I need to pass.
I-I'm here to see you stay put.
Mr. Bohannon's orders.
Well, can you tell me what's
happening with Mr. Snow?
I hear Mr. Bohannon doing
everything he can to save him.
Save him?
Why?
To save you, miss Ruth.
I think it's best you go back inside, now.
If I'm ever on that table, want you there.
If you're ever on that table,
I hope I'm the one puts you there.
It wasn't Elam in that box.
You said so yourself.
Elam wanted me.
He would have left quiet with me.
And you took that from us.
Eva...
It was for your own protection.
No one asked you for it.
Congratulations.
You ain't dead.
All this to see me hang?
Nope.
First you gonna save the church lady.
One good act ain't gonna wash
away all the bad I've done.
What becomes of men like us, Bohannon?
Where do you suppose we end up?
Nowheres good.
That bastard gonna live?
Eh,
took off his damn leg.
He gonna be meaner than before.
Not for much longer.
You posted a guard.
We took the leg off.
He'll live.
He will answer for Ezra, Ruth.
But will I answer for him?
You'll be free.
We'll rebuild your church.
You can't rebuilt what I lost.
You're a better surgeon than I was a farmer.
Well, from what little I know of you,
that's not saying a lot.
[Chuckles]
I wanted to be an eye doctor.
Studied ophthalmology.
But I never finished medical school.
Did you know that?
'Doc' is an affectation a...
An honorific title
I adopted to help me in the
business of railroading.
[Laughs] You're shitting me.
I am not.
Damn.
What you think is gonna...
Happen to men like us?
After she's built.
Well, I will be remembered
as the man who built the
Transcontinental Railroad.
You will not be remembered at all.
Not even by me.
Thanks for sugarcoating it.
[Laughs] It's the truth.
You live long enough,
you'll see I was right.
Yep.
Mm.
[Groaning]
I thought I'd see the world
one last time before I die.
Won't get far.
God.
I saw this Union boy once,
crawl a half-mile.
Nothing from the waist down.
He couldn't have been more than 17.
It's a hell of a sight to see.
A man with no legs, pulling himself along.
I chased him...
'Til he couldn't go no more
and I pinned him with my foot.
Said, "What's your hurry, boy?"
He started looking through
his jacket right about then,
for a photograph.
See, he wanted to see
his momma one last time,
before he died.
I remember he dug all through that coat.
He looked real hard.
Kept begging me to help him find it.
I said, "Well, hell, boy.
That picture's probably
in your pants pocket."
I had a good laugh.
We all got moments.
Every man I ever killed got one someplace.
Damn, Sid!
I need to tell that church lady...
I never meant to hurt her boy.
Shut up! [Groans]
I know it happens to men like us, Bohannon.
We end up far from home...
Covered in blood...
And shit.
We die alone.
I said shut your damn mouth.
"Shut your damn mouth."
That's funny.
Sid?
This pleases me much.
There's a... it is a blessing to have...
To have a child who cherishes God's word.
You are my good...
Good and beloved daughter.
"Thou shalt not kill."
Those men last night...
God sent me to them to, uh...
To avenge their sins.
"'Vengeance is mine.
I will repay, ' saith the lord."
Yeah. Paul to the romans.
Satan himself does
sometimes quote scripture.
It's one of his foulest tricks.
"Avenge not yourselves,
but rather give place unto wrath."
Enough!
[Laughs]
What does it mean, Papa?
When you're older the...
The truth meanings will stand revealed.
That is why the Lord
puts our elders above us.
Ruth?
God doesn't avenge sins
through his creations.
He doesn't move men to kill.
I've met plenty of men who would
have you believe differently.
You don't rely on God...
Do you, miss Ellison?
No.
Why?
I've seen far too much of
what men do in his name...
To believe that he would
ever be there for me.
Miss Ellison.
You sure you want to do that?
Are you sure you want
to prosecute Ruth Cole?
The world is a better place
without men like Sidney Snow,
and better with women of high
moral standards like miss Cole.
And yourself.
John, that's not an answer.
That's a public position.
I'm not a fool, Louise,
but I am the Governor and all that implies.
Can I quote you on that?
No, you cannot.
In fact...
I would suggest that until
this matter resolves,
you keep it out of the newspaper.
Is that a request...
Or a threat?
Public hysteria will not
help miss Cole's cause.
Nor yours.
Hmm.
He's better off.
A man like that...
Men like us...
We still got a job to do.
You know what yours is.
I'll bring the muck wagon around.
That's not what I meant.
I know what you meant.
He's dead, isn't he?
["Where we'll never grow old"  playing]
♪ I have heard of a land ♪
♪ on the far away strand ♪
♪ 'tis a beautiful home of the soul ♪
♪ built by Jesus on high ♪
♪ where we never shall die ♪
♪ 'tis a land where we never ♪
♪ grow old ♪
♪ never grow old ♪
♪ 'tis a land where we never ♪
♪ grow old ♪
♪ oh, never grow old ♪
♪ never grow old ♪
♪ 'tis a land where we never ♪
♪ grow old ♪
♪ in that beautiful home ♪
♪ where we'll never more roam ♪
♪ we shall meet in the sweet ♪
♪ by and by ♪
♪ happy praise to the king ♪
♪ through eternity sing ♪
♪ 'tis a land where we'll never grow old ♪
I'm sorry, Ruth.
It wasn't your fault.
Or God's will.
I'll figure a way out.
I'm fine, Mr. Bohannon.
The only thing more satisfying
than shooting Mr. Snow,
was the moment you told me he was dead.
♪ 'Tis a land where we'll never grow old ♪