[Grunts]
This infernal machine!
I appreciate your spending
your Sunday fixing it.
Better than another
Sunday in an empty house.
You know me circumstance.
Ain't going to lie to you.
What would you do
if you were married to a woman
whose heart was for another?
It's a big world,
Mr. Toole.
Ah, Eva's me wife.
I'm making me stand.
Hold on.
Thanks.
Mr. Durant is
returning.
Yeah.
His train is at council bluffs.
He could be here as soon as tonight.
More reason to get this
machine fixed by tomorrow
so we can finish the bridge.
Show how valuable you
are to the railroad.
He's going to know you had a hand
in raising this bridge, too.
I'm not so sure.
Shall I see you later?
When I fix the engine.
Right.
Durant's on his way back.
[Grunts]
I can finish up here if you
want to get back to town.
That's what I'd do.
You ain't me.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Man don't know nothing
about building no house.
Foundation first, then chimney.
Any fool know that.
Ain't you got somewhere to be?
Not on the lord's day.
Lord want me here, watch that
chimney fall on your head.
[Laughter]
Yeah, you funny.
Mm-hmm.
Building a house for, anyhow, huh?
Only folks stay behind
on the railroad is
them scrawny-ass
clodhoppers with
them saggy-titted wives
and squawking-ass babies.
That what you want to be?
Yeah.
Something like that.
[Chuckles]
Y'all go on ahead.
Hell, you gonna do it, do it right.
You got to lay in
a second wall of rock,
lest the whole thing fall
down on your head, huh?
[Whistle blows]
I'll take 3, too.
Let's hope it's a good time for you.
One...
[Laughs]
Ohh.
Come on. Get up.
What?
Let's go.
[Sighs]
Oi. I'm out.
[Indistinct]
Don't go too far.
We love taking your money.
Yeah. Just don't give up me seat. Oh.
That bast-- that bastard
Durant is back.
He'll be looking for the
payment for his land parcels.
Durant? Really?
So, pay him.
Back to me game.
I need my cut from this place.
Well, I'm sorry.
I'm a bit short.
Bad run of luck.
[Chuckles]
And drinking up the rest, no doubt.
Ma was right.
You're a shambles,
just like dad.
I'm the proprietor here.
This is my place of business.
Our place of business.
I stuck my neck out
floating a land parcel
for Mr. Ferguson for it.
Come on. I know
you have money.
What do you got on you?
No, Sean. You're embarrassing me.
Stop it.
I'll do worse than that if
you're holding out on me.
We'll see.
[Indistinct talking]
Damn it.
[Groans]
Oh, and thank you for...
[Grunts] All you've
done these past weeks.
Now, it's time to go take care
of that husband of yours.
At least let me
walk you to the office.
I should be seen making my way to
the office under my own steam.
Oh, uh...
Please, take it.
And...
If you ever need anything for
yourself or your child...
Thank you,
Mr. Durant.
Good-bye.
[Door opens and shuts]
[Sighs]
[Groans]
Mr. Gunderson,
that is Mr. Durant's desk.
And those are his personal ledgers.
Yes, Mrs. Bell.
That is true.
I was gathering them
under direct orders.
Direct o--
from Mr. Durant?
Woman:
No. From me.
I'm Hannah Durant,
Mr. Durant's wife.
Hello.
[Breathing heavily]
Mr. Durant!
How wonderful that you're back.
Ahh.
What are you up to, McGinnes?
Nothing at all, sir.
I...
Whatever happened to
the magic lantern show?
Oh, well, my brother and I
manage the pleasure house now.
And we're partners in the saloon.
I took in a...
Magic lantern show in
Chicago. [Chuckles]
Two men caught a tiger under a barrel.
Great story.
The two young men were
devoured by the tiger.
Think about it.
Sir, I will.
[Exhales]
[Indistinct talking]
[Grunts]
[Door opens]
Well, then. I'll be seeing
you for dinner later.
Of course.
[Doors shut]
[Indistinct talking]
Mr. Bohannon.
You're back early.
Damn miracle I got back here at all.
Yeah.
How you maintaining?
Is my bridge built?
Almost.
About wore out that damn steam engine.
So, no bridge.
All right.
For your sins, you will
come to dinner tonight
with me and my wife.
Your wife?
Don't look so horrified.
Oh, and wear a clean shirt.
Yes, sir.
And...Mrs. Bell
will be your escort.
Understood?
Yeah. Understood.
Why you looking so down, hmm?
Look how good this hearth draw, huh?
All you need now is
some walls, windows,
door, roof.
Practically done.
Toole going to kill Eva and the baby,
if the baby come out like me.
Look here. That ain't going to happen.
Hear me?
Who going to stop it?
Every damn body, you hear me?
That's who.
You'll be the best
father for that baby,
far as I can tell.
How you mean?
He'll be mixed.
Mulatto.
Whatever you wanna say.
He'll be like you, right?
Yeah, I suppose.
Who be better for him, hmm,
than somebody just like him?
I ain't never thought
about it like that.
See, you'd be his father.
And I'd be his uncle Psalms.
[Laughs]
I'll teach him all the
things you ought not to.
Hey, there, rascal, you pull
that girl's skirt back down.
[Laughter]
In Chicago,
you ain't never seen nothing
like them buildings.
Some of them are,
like, 6 stories tall.
You should see the buildings
in New York--twice that.
Me brother lives in a
building 10 stories tall.
Would you take me to New York?
Of course.
Well, depending on...
You know.
What?
The baby.
You mean, when the
baby's fit to travel?
Just say what you're thinking.
If the baby's born white, Eva,
then we can meet me family.
Well, see, I thought...
You said that you'd put
that aside, Mr. Toole.
Me brother wouldn't.
In the saloon, the men are wagering
whether the baby will be
born white or...
Something else.
Shall we leave this place?
Maybe.
It's a big world, after all, isn't it?
[Indistinct talking]
All right.
You ready?
[Grunts]
Oh, it's going to be
a wonderful evening.
I'm sure you'll adore them.
As for your flaxen-haired
maiden of the west...
Fair-haired
maiden of the west.
Just like most of your enthusiasms.
I understand. She's
attractive and capable.
And very smart.
And that makes her very dangerous.
Do you think she may have
deciphered our mileage from--
They--
here they are.
Here you are.
Come in. Come in.
Ahh. Mr. Bohannon. Pleased
to make your acquaintance.
Same here, ma'am.
Now, you'll come right over here
and sit on my right.
[Clears throat]
Lily,
forgive me, I--
Mrs. Bell.
Mrs. Bell,
please.
Andrew.
Yes?
Close those shades and shut the door
and see that we're not disturbed.
Yes, ma'am.
[Distant animal cries]
Thank you, Andrew.
Well, bon appetit.
So...
Tell me where you're
from, Mr. Bohannon.
Meridian, Mississippi.
Oh. Is yours
a cotton family?
Was.
Ain't nothing left.
Of course.
Thomas, didn't we know someone
with the railroad in meridian?
Is there a railroad
there, Mr. Bohannon?
Yes, ma'am, mobile and Ohio had a
railhead there before it burned.
Leonidas Tate.
Yes, Leo Tate.
He had shares in credit
mobilier, didn't he?
We used to summer with
the Tates in New York,
on long island sound.
I doubt Mr. Bohannon
is interested in our, uh,
sailing stories with
the Tates. [Chuckles]
Matter of fact,
I married Mr. Tate's
youngest daughter Mary.
It was there at Christ church.
Well, small world.
Well, tell us, how is she?
She's dead.
The war took her.
Oh.
Did your family know
Richard McLemore, then?
He and my grandfather laid
the very first spur line
in Lauderdale county.
God, Bohannon,
I just might send you to
New York one of these days
to deal with the board
on my behalf. Ha!
Unless memories of the
city would be too painful.
Well, my eyes are set west
to the future, Mr. Durant.
I think you know that about me, too.
[Grunts]
Well said, Mr. Bohannon.
Well, this has been lovely,
but I must go.
I'm so sorry.
All this talk of the railroad
must have been so boring for you.
Not at all. After all, my future
is bound to the railroad also.
Of course. It's very tragic,
what happened to your husband.
Well, it's just good
we could provide you
with some employment, in the meantime.
In the meantime.
Until you decide
where you're going to
reestablish yourself,
someplace more conducive.
Of course.
Thank you.
I'll walk you to your car.
There's no need,
really. Good night.
Good night.
Good night--Mrs. Bell.
I'll accept that offer,
Mr. Bohannon,
seeing as though my husband
is still enjoying his brandy,
aren't you, dear?
Yes, of course.
[Chuckles]
You should know that
Mrs. Bell has been
very important to the railroad.
She's done a lot to get us this far.
Does that include
sleeping with my husband?
I--
I ain't around much.
You ain't.
Why do you hide your
breeding, Mr. Bohannon?
Oh, I guess I just got used to
traveling low to the ground.
[Laughs]
Regarding Mrs. Bell,
my husband is making some changes.
Is Mr. Durant
firing her?
Be careful with whom
you align yourself.
My husband believes you have
a future on the railroad,
and I do, too.
Yeah?
You hardly know me.
Hmm.
Yes, but my instincts...
Are always right.
Good night,
Mr. Bohannon.
Good night.
[Indistinct talking]
Lily...
Mr. Bohannon.
[Grunts]
We need to dis--
we need to discuss your
progress on my bridge.
Mrs. Bell has an estimate. I
think we should ask her opinion.
I'm asking yours.
Two weeks.
If the weather holds
and we work Sundays.
Not good enough.
One week.
We're dangerously behind schedule.
Whose schedule would that be?
Yours, Mr. Bohannon.
It was on your advice
that we decided to bridge
the gorge at this point.
Yes, sir. And we made
good time, considering.
Considering what,
Mr. Bohannon?
Indians. Strike.
Wash-out.
All I need is a structure
that will support a locomotive
from one side of
the gorge to the other.
Understand?
I'll, um...
I'll drive it across
the bridge myself.
How about that?
[Water pours]
Can we speak in private?
Yes.
Got something for you.
It's a Claddagh ring.
From home.
You're offering it to me?
I mean, I'm a successful businessman,
and you're starting
in your church--
I thought when you gave me
the land for the church,
it came with no strings attached.
These aren't strings, Ruth.
It's a token of my affection.
Proposing marriage, Sean?
It's how
you wear it. Um...
On your right hand,
pointed toward your wrist means...
Your heart is captured.
I would like you to
wear it like that for me.
Ahh...
It's a bit small.
But I'll keep it, Sean.
And you will think about it?
I just need a little time.
This is all so fast.
Of course.
With your father's death,
and then, your church...
Take your time.
I'll find a ring that fits better.
Good-bye.
[Indistinct shouts]
Hey!
Let's get into position like
we went over this morning.
Man: Aye!
Check the corner braces
and line her up.
Hold tight,
Mr. Toole.
[Men grunting]
Man: All right, together!
She's lifting up. You lay
them braces, all right?
Aye, we will!
Give it speed,
Mr. Toole.
[Creaking]
[Men shouting]
Easy on the lift, Toole.
Damn it.
Watch your foot.
Keep that rope in line.
The valve's stuck!
[Steam hisses]
Ahh!
Mother of God, Jesus!
Get back!
[Steam hisses]
[Groans]
Cullen, look out!
Man: Look out!
[Men screaming]
[Screaming continues]
Man: Get it off of me!
Get it off!
Help! Help!
Second man:
Somebody!
Third man: Can somebody help us?
[Train whistle blows, bell dings]
Toole: Hurry up, get these
men to the infirmary.
Toole.
Man: I need help
getting him off.
I want you to tear that damn
thing apart right there
and tell me why she blew.
Overworked and overloaded,
Mr. Bohannon.
Do it.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Toole.
[Sighs]
I thought maybe you
would have been glad
that I had been flattened.
No. I was worried
about you.
Did--did you get hurt?
No, just bit by a bit of steam is all.
[Indistinct shouts]
What in God's name has happened now?
Steam engine blew.
Well, you should have
been more careful, then.
I ain't the one that wanted
to cross the gorge in a week.
Don't blame me for
your failures, Bohannon.
It's not my fault you blew the engine.
And it ain't my fault that
you oversold our mileage
to the board back east.
Mr. Bohannon.
You are out of your depth.
Thomas, let's get you back inside.
Ahh.
You need to fix this.
[Clatters]
[Sighs]
[Exhales]
[Indistinct chatter]
Joseph, where did--
I was worried you weren't
being provided for.
Where did you go?
Into the long country.
I prayed and fasted.
I realized I am, and always
will be, a Cheyenne.
No, you are a baptized Christian.
Ruth, after I became a Christian,
I killed my brother, and
I killed your father.
I broke my father's heart,
just like you broke mine.
I'm sorry, Joseph.
I didn't come here for your pity.
I came here to bring you food,
to tell you while I was hunting,
I saw the white spirit.
I don't believe in ghosts, Joseph.
Your father was right.
This is a bad place.
You should leave.
I've just started a new church.
I can't leave.
Then you will die.
Tell me you found the problem.
I pulled the whole bloody thing apart.
There's something keeping the
presser--the pressure valve's stuck.
Pressure valve.
Let me see it.
Ohh.
It's an ore coin.
A Norwegian penny.
Mr. Swede.
Put this back together
double-time.
We got a bridge to build.
I reckon I don't understand.
It's like he wanted us to know.
It's exactly
like that, Mr. Toole.
[Door closes]
Good morning.
I'm going to work.
You can't just push me out.
I'm trying to run a railroad.
So am I.
Thomas, you made me a promise.
I did?
Yes.
I have done the work.
I've been by your side
when you needed me,
and I've kept thing going
when you were at death's door.
You're not naive, lily.
Pretending to be only diminishes you.
Naive?
We've shared so much.
How can you deny that?
[Chuckles] Yes.
You seem quite fond of sharing.
How does Bohannon know about the
mileage shortfall on this railroad?
Um.
Did you lay with him?
Did you lay with him?!
Thomas, I've given everything
of myself for this railroad.
Yes, you certainly have.
If you'll excuse me,
I have work to do.
If I take the two
cards and not--
I have no idea what an
inside straight is.
Excuse me.
You've had your time.
Durant wants to see me.
Yeah, I got your money.
I'm not giving it to you.
I want my share, Mick.
You owe me.
Oh, that's right.
Ha ha ha.
For the paper you floated on the
negro's sorry scrap of mud bank.
Hmm. Yeah.
Yeah.
[Grunts]
That should cover it.
Now, bugger off.
I want my fair share, Mick.
I'm in a jam.
This was your plan, huh?
To palm the deeds and hope
that Mr. Durant died,
and that no one would find out?
And they call me the family idiot.
I want my money.
I'm not giving it to you.
I will not be party
to you paying the debts
of some church whore
across the street.
Watch your mouth.
Aye, it's an Indian-laying
church whore, by the way.
[Grunts]
Aye!
[Indistinct shouts]
[Horse whinnies]
[Both grunting]
Man: Get out!
Come here!
Will you listen to me?
Just--aah!
[Crowd cheering]
Just listen!
Get back!
Listen to me!
Son of a bitch.
Aah!
Get...
No. No!
Just stay there.
Stay there.
Take back--
take back what you said.
Jesus, Sean. Everybody in town knows.
It's not true.
It is.
I just saw them together.
Ask her yourself.
I'm your brother, Sean.
I'm not the problem, she is.
Let me go.
I tasked you with being
my eyes and ears
on this railroad.
I don't work for the railroad no more.
Really?
No, sir. Got me a place
down by the river.
Settled down.
[Sighs]
Now, you listen to me.
I own every piece of land
between here and council bluffs
and as far as you can see
in either direction.
Mr. McGinnes and me,
we have an arrangement.
There are only two ways
to leave this railroad.
You die in my employ,
or you walk back
through Indian territory.
[Groans]
Back to whatever squalid slave
shack from which you came.
This ain't right.
It ain't right.
[Sighs]
If the sun rises on your
sorry ass in the morning,
I will have you shot for trespassing.
Is that what you want?
What you just tore up,
that's what I want.
I want to build me a house
down by that river,
where I can lock
my damn door at night.
Know that that's my damn house.
And my damn property.
And I can shoot any damn man
that comes through that door
and tell me it ain't mine.
I ain't afraid to work,
Mr. Durant,
but I ain't gonna be your
damn nigger no more.
What I want is some respect.
And if I got to take it
out of your damn hide,
or anybody else's, I will.
Mr. Ferguson.
Have a seat.
Please.
[Knock on door]
Oh. Did I come
at a bad time?
No, I--I was just
resting.
Thomas told me you had words.
He did?
There are no secrets between us.
You were not a surprise to me.
I see.
I told him that I thought he was wrong
to speak to you in that way.
You've been very instrumental
in the building of the railroad.
And if it wasn't for you,
we wouldn't have stayed afloat
during Thomas' recovery.
Thank you.
That's why what I am going to ask you
is so difficult.
In light of Thomas' injuries
and his nightly discomfort,
well, it's just not possible
for us to share a bed.
[Sighs]
You want me to leave my train car.
I need suitable accommodations.
I'm sure you understand.
I have nowhere else to go.
You're a smart girl.
You seem to know your way around.
I'm sure you'll find something.
[Sighs]
[Lily sighs]
You don't have to leave.
I've seen how you fare in the tents.
Can't build another floorboard.
That's not funny.
I know it ain't.
You know, you could stay.
Thomas already knows.
No, he only thinks he does.
Yeah, well, he's right.
Lily...
You shouldn't test a man
who's jealous or afraid
for his livelihood.
Especially not when he's both.
Hey.
Don't want to test a man.
[Owl hooting]
[Door opens]
Sean:
Is it true?
[Breathing heavily]
Sean, you can't be here.
I need to know if it's true.
You've been drinking.
Did you?
Sean, you're scaring me.
Joseph.
Did you and he...
Don't.
People say you had relations.
People lie.
Mickey saw you together.
What do you want from me?
I want the truth.
Get out.
I want the truth!
And I thought it was me you wanted.
You have to go.
Please go.
[Door closes]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Glass breaking]
This ain't no boarding house.
From the looks of it,
it ain't even a house.
What happened, Durant kicked you
out of your fancy railroad car?
Something like that.
[Scoffs]
What about you?
You get tired of building
your dream house?
Something like that.
Might as well.
You ought to know, Mr. Durant
offered me a new job.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
He want me to do something
I'm sure you ain't gonna like at all.
What's that?
[Laughs]
What'd you tell him?
Told him I'd think about it.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com