Previously on AMC's Hell on Wheels.
AH-TAO: You choose to let
the murderers go free?
CHANG: The white man can
kill a Chinese man.
CULLEN: Get your people back to work.
CHANG: After you address
a list of our demands.
STROBRIDGE: I could settle this by
noon with a dozen men with ax handles.
CHANG: Your railroad will
not move another inch.
CULLEN: This cargo is impounded
by the Central Pacific.
CHANG: You think you can starve us out?
STROBRIDGE: Nothing a man respects
more than an emptstomach.
AH-TAO: Mr. Chang is arming
men to come get the food.
CHANG: Release my shipments.
There will be no blood shed.
STROBRIDGE: Come closer, Chang.
(COCKS GUN)
(WAVES LAPPING)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
Fifty men, ready to work.
- Same stock as Chang's?
- They'll need to be taught.
Uh, you're the man for the job.
After you, Mr. Tao.
MAN: All aboard!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
We are not in Truckee, Mr. Bohannon.
Merely passengers on a train.
A small alcove of civilization.
Surely, we can put our differences
aside and enjoy the ride together.
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
- Mmm-hmm.
Tin Hau Don,
the Heavenly Empress Festival, is upon us.
Each year I throw a celebration
because my men, though far from home,
long for China and its traditions.
A shopping expedition to San Francisco
seems a small pric to pay
to bring it to them.
Don't you think?
I think San Francisco's a long way
to go for fireworks, Mr. Chang.
I never was much for tradition.
(SCOFFS)
Such a western notion that
the past does not matter.
That the past can be forgotten.
What's your business with Thor Gundersen?
I didn't realize you made it your business
to keep an eye on my customers.
Just the bloodthirsty crazy ones.
(INHALES)
I sell him rice to feed his men.
Nothing more.
If you're smart, you'd make Thor
Gundersen part of your past.
Forget him.
Perhaps it is you, Mr. Bohannon,
who needs to put Thor Gundersen behind him.
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
(BELL TOLLING)
All right.
Teepee wagons out and over there.
Railroad's handling payroll now.
Why wasn't I informed?
You just were.
Mr. Huntington approved this?
Huntington ain't in
charge of payroll, I am.
Mr. Tao, make sure them gold eagles
is distributed by day's end.
Yes, bossman.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
MICKEY: Welcome to Laramie, lads!
Right this way.
Welcome. How you been?
Brian Lynch.
You wily bastard.
- Jesus, how was the trip out?
- I'm all twisted up inside.
Haven't had me a decent crap for a week.
Couple hours on the cut
will get you uncorked.
Good man.
Mrs. Palmer!
Never imagined seeing you here in Laramie.
- Hmm.
- You look lovely.
And you look like hell, McGinnes.
Just like this sewer pit of a town.
Mr. Delaney!
I need you to confirm that Samuel
Ammerman is on the UP payroll.
I'm the chief engineer, Miss Ellison.
I don't know the names
of everyone our employ.
So you're not denying anything.
I know he's not a surveyor.
He came from Truckee with maps.
I have my sources.
You th...
You think we employ spies?
I know you do, Marty, so don't play dumb.
Oh, Durant didn't tell you, did he?
I'm sorry.
Off the cut, out of the loop.
Tasked with fool's errands!
Well, at least the trite little bridges
I worked on in Connecticut got built!
But,
a bridge 12 miles long
across a lake of brimstone?
- Talk about a boondoggle!
- What bridge?
- Never mind.
- What lake are we talking about, Marty?
We're not... We're not talking, Louise.
I'm sorry.
MICKEY: You've all traveled
across the country, exhausted.
You'll be excited for what lies in store.
Now, gentlemen,
if you're at all like me,
there's nothing better after a long journey
than the companionship of a fine woman.
(MEN LAUGH)
A lady who's smooth as cream gravy.
A woman who's well-versed in
the art of pleasing a man.
And these women will leave no
stones unturned until they do.
(MEN CHEERING)
Now, after you've had your fill...
Or the ladies have had theirs.
My saloon is right down the street.
And I'll make you'll a promise right now...
It will not be all play,
but for every day ye lay
five miles of track,
the drinks will be on the house.
(CHEERING)
So welcome to Laramie, boys.
Wet your willie or your gullet,
whatever your pleasure may be.
For tomorrow, it'll be out
on the cut at daybreak.
- And don't you dare let me down.
- All right.
Gentlemen, enjoy!
(GROANS)
- What...
- Cut the shit!
(SIGHS)
Look, I'm the one spreading
my legs all day,
and you get all the money. It ain't fair!
No. It ain't.
Now, go use that mouth of yours
for something other than smartin' off.
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
come peruse the greatest collection
of potions, pomades, and perfumes
this side of the Mississippi!
The solution to whatever ails you
lies just inside my prodigious portmanteau.
The name's Bartholomew T. Gibbons.
Now, I'm no snake oil salesman peddling
piss in a bottle and I'll prove it.
If I could just have a volunteer. Anyone.
You, sir.
Mr. Young.
Sir? Excuse me, sir?
Sir... Sir, may I ask your name?
Uh, (STUTTERS) I'm Thor Gundersen.
Mr. Gundersen...
How much would you pay for a tonic
that prolongs health and well-being
beyond all bonds of expectation?
An Elixir of Life that protects
against the ravages of time,
guaranteeing you the joys of an extended,
vibrant and disease-free life?
- (STUTTERS)
- How much would you pay for that, sir?
- Would you pay $10?
- Yeah, uh...
- Would you pay $5?
- Well...
What would you say, sir, if
I were tell you right now
that future could be yours for only $2?
What would you say if I told
you eternal life is free?
Costs you nothing whatsoever?
I'd say, "Tell me where to sign up, sir."
(LAUGHING)
Salvation
through The Church of Jesus
Christ of Latter-day Saints.
We meet on Sundays.
(SCOFFS)
All are welcome.
Oslo, come.
(CHUCKLES)
CULLEN: You boys got everything
you need on them mountains?
We were well attended to.
Thanks to Brother Gundersen.
Thanks to his dealings
with Chang, you mean.
Brother Gundersen procures food
and sundries from the Chinese.
What we don't get from Zion...
Or you.
And you've seen these sundries yourself?
(SIGHS)
You're not the first person to
buy Swede's stock, Mr. Young.
Brother Gundersen is Norwegian.
He's fooled a lot of folks.
Most of 'em dead now.
He told me you'd say as much.
Don't confuse a confession
for prediction, son.
Thor Gundersen's a liar.
And a murderer.
He told me your father's a false prophet.
He told me you abandoned
your wife and child.
Whatever his dealings with
Chang, it won't end well.
You best cut bait and be done with him.
Brother Gundersen is a loyal Saint, Mr.
Bohannon.
Our progress on the grade, under his
direction, has been rapid and sure.
Now, if there are no other complaints...
Good day.
(CHANG CHUCKLES)
So...
The price of rice has not changed,
Mr. Gundersen.
But circumstances have.
Oh. If you're short on funds...
Uh, your circumstances,
if I'm not mistaken...
Uh, the recent labor strike
has cut into your profits,
and now,
with the payroll no longer
passing through your hands...
Well, perhaps, your need for gold
is greater than my need for...
Rice.
Now we share a common enemy, Mr. Chang.
I, too, have been diminished
by Mr. Cullen Bohannon.
Uh, sooner or later, the
devil makes us all pay.
This time...
He has chosen you.
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah. It's on.
Yeah, come, come.
Hey, come, come, come.
Up, up, up, up, up.
Yeah, good boy.
Yeah, sit, sit.
(GRUNTS)
- (HORSE WHINNIES)
- (THE SWEDE CLICKS TONGUE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING IN CANTONESE)
(SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
_
Bossman.
PHINEAS: Why are we here, Brother Thor?
THE SWEDE: I have had a vision, my son.
The Angel Moroni come to me.
Same as he'd come to Joseph Smith
himself to reveal the truth.
What truth?
There it was,
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
written upon a golden plate,
the proclamation from Heavenly
Father that you, Phineas,
are to be our new prophet.
Me?
I must see this plate, Brother.
As is with the Angel Moroni, the plate
is for mine eyes, and mine alone to see.
Your acceptance of his message, Brother,
is the test that will prove you
worthy of this new, exalted role.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Now, I...
Oh, I must show you something.
(CRATE RATTLING)
Guns?
For what purpose, Brother?
Some in Salt Lake City will
accept this revelation.
Some...
Will not.
DURANT: What is the one thing
there will never be more of?
The one thing you will never lose money on?
BUDILL: Land.
DURANT: Yes. Land!
Ah!
I can't tell you what a delight it is
to be finally speaking to an informed man.
You... You have no idea
how many imbeciles
do not know the answer to
that most basic of questions.
You know, when Laramie becomes the new hub
of the Union Pacific Railroad,
land bought today will be worth...
Ten times the price tomorrow.
Mrs. Palmer!
What a delightful and unexpected surprise.
I hope you're not too fond
of that shirt, friend,
because you're about to lose it.
Mr. Durant, who is this woman?
- Maggie, listen to me...
- Hmm...
He told you Laramie would be the...
The hub of the Union Pacific, did he?
- He did.
- Ha!
Well, see, yesterday, it was Cheyenne.
Tomorrow, it'll be Rock Springs.
The day after that, who knows?
He is as crooked as a Virginia fence,
and you're a fool to buy what he's selling.
That's a little harsh.
Now, you're not trying to pull the
wool over my eyes, are you, Durant?
Mr. Budill. A woman scorned...
Thank you for your time, Mr. Durant.
(DURANT SIGHS)
Ma'am.
What, my good woman, was that about?
What do you think?
My hotel is empty!
My property in Cheyenne, worthless!
Your lies and your schemes are about
to send me to the poor house!
Trust me, I have your
best interests at heart.
That would require you having one!
Maggie, at least let me try to explain.
(STUTTERING) Over dinner, this evening.
Did...
(GRUNTING)
- (GRUNTS)
- Oh! (GASPS)
(MAGGIE SIGHS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I can't do it like this.
Come with me.
Shut the door.
How far along?
Three months... About.
I think.
I'll get you through this.
Thank you.
(COUPLE CHUCKLING IN NEXT ROOM)
- (THUNDER CRASHING)
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Chang ain't gonna take this lying down.
Taking over payroll, bringing in workers.
TAO: He steals my money, I'll make more.
He beats me, I stand up.
He beats me again, I stand up again.
Them white men,
the ones trying to hang Chang.
Their coach never made it to Cisco.
He's capable.
He could not win in China.
He will not win here.
I'm not afraid of Chang.
Yeah, maybe you ought to be.
Tonight is Tin Hau Don.
Big celebration.
Please, be our guest.
Yeah.
I'll be honored.
Come.
Fong.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Your hair's all wet.
CULLEN: Yep.
Now...
I was hoping...
You'd look after this for me.
My daddy said not to touch
his special bottles
or I can't play outside for a week.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
This ain't like your daddy's bottle.
Smell that, go on.
That right there, that's the Pacific Ocean.
- The ocean?
- Mmm-hmm.
You weren't there.
Now, would I lie about a thing like that?
Was it pretty?
It's like a dream you
don't wanna wake up from.
Anyhow...
You take real good care of this.
And keep it safe till I need it.
You think you can you do that?
Good. Go and put it away.
(CHUCKLES)
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
_
(APPLAUDING)
What's Chang talking about?
Thank my father for end strike.
_
I was told that, in America,
to embrace the future, one
needs to forget the past.
(SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
So, I say, let old grudges and rivalries
melt away with the winter snow,
and allow new flowers to
blossom in their place.
(SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
(SLURPING)
_
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SIGHS)
This will help with the pain.
Mmm.
This here is called slippery elm.
I use it on my girls.
Goes up inside you, swells up real big.
Causes bleeding, fever.
Goes right, in a couple days, you'll
be in the family way no more.
I'm gonna start now.
(STUTTERS) Do it.
Focus on the stones.
(GASPS) Mmm.
(GRUNTS)
DURANT: Mr. Psalms.
Psalms' my given name, Mr. Durant.
Jackson, my Christian name.
Mr. Jackson, then.
Uh, any issues on the cut, can be
taken up with Mr. Delaney. Thank you.
Ain't no problem on the cut, Mr. Durant.
Here to buy some of that
Laramie property you selling.
Oh, Mr. Jackson...
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm not sure that you are the, uh...
Type of person to buy land in Laramie.
Ain't just me.
Some of the other freedmen, we
put all our money together.
Count it, it's good.
All the same. (SIGHS)
My advice would be to
hold on to your money.
Mr. Durant, I've been working for
you goin' on four years now.
Hear what you tellin' folk.
Land bought today be worth 10
time what it cost tomorrow.
Only right that the men would make it
worth somethin' in the first place,
make some money off it, same as you.
Now, you ain't gonna sell it to us,
better be a reason other than
the one I'm thinking you got.
There is nothing I can say to you
that would prevent me from selling
you land that you wish to buy.
PSALMS: I've got it, boys. I've got it!
(MEN CHEERING)
- MAN: Oh, yeah!
- PSALMS: We got that land! Yeah!
- Yeah.
- MAN: Whoo!
MICKEY: Eva!
Eva!
Eva, where the hell are you?
Hey! Close the door.
Eva! Where the hell are ya?
For Christ's sake, there's a
line of johns at the door.
Can't you see I'm working?
My cousin been mixing it
up with the whores again?
No, it wasn't Shea. But not
all gentlemen are gentle.
And how I take care of my girls
ain't your business, Mick.
(WHISPERS) It's all my business.
Now, get this place in order
or I'll put Shea back in
just as quick as I took him out.
You hear me?
All right, boys, how about
I measure you firm.
Biggest and smallest get a free poke
with the girl of their choosing.
(MEN CHEERING)
All right, what have we got here?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHUCKLING)
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
(SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
Will you come see?
(BOTH SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
- Nice celebration.
- Mmm-hmm.
You know, back in Taishan,
I dreamed of the day my
wife would give me a son.
Three girls later... (LAUGHS)
I always say daughters is a blessing.
Mei Fong was a blessing.
A special blessing.
(CHANG CLEARING THROAT)
She's all I have left, Mr. Bohannon.
She's my son, my daughter,
she is everything to me.
I see what is happening.
How you look at her.
If I can see, Chang can see...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Uh-uh.
Ain't like that.
Mei can never be a woman,
do you understand?
Never.
(CHEERING)
- Oh, Mr. Bohannon.
- Evening.
What a spectacle!
It is that. Where's Jim?
I sent him to sleep up on the roof.
A little too much to drink
from his special bottle.
(CHUCKLING)
- Come here.
- What?
(WHISPERING) Don't worry, I hid
yours where he won't find it.
Oh... Thank you.
Janie, I'm sure Mr. Bohannon has better
things to do than to babysit us.
Come now, Janie, keep
your hands off the man.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, Mr. Bohannon.
Mrs. Strobridge.
Little troublemaker.
Come on, now.
Come on, children.
Mr. Chang want you come.
Most urgent.
(CHANG SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
I have something to show you.
(CRATE CLATTERING)
A wise man suggested I put my business
(EXHALES) with Thor Gundersen behind me.
Rice?
- How many?
- Enough for an army.
Why you telling me this now?
In the hope that we might put our
past behind us, Mr. Bohannon.
And embrace the future together.
Mmm-hmm.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(PLATE CLATTERS)
Have land values really dropped
so precipitously in Cheyenne
since I set out and moved
the hub to Laramie?
Dog cheap with no bottom in sight.
Good.
- (SCOFFS)
- Start buyin' them up.
What with... With all the free
money my vacant hotel affords me?
I will supply whatever cash you need.
What are you up to, New York?
Laramie is not going to be the hub
of the Union Pacific, Maggie.
Cheyenne is.
Every newspaper article I have read
lately quotes you saying otherwise.
(LAUGHS) Yes, and for once
they've got it right.
News of the hub moving
has sent property prices skyrocketing here.
As they do, we'll sell.
And as they plummet in Cheyenne, we'll buy.
Once we've squeezed the
pig for all its fat,
I will announce I've changed my mind.
Cheyenne will remain as the
hub of the Union Pacific
and you, my dear, will
profit astronomically.
Though hand-in-hand with me.
- Why risk it?
- (LAUGHING)
It's bacon over butter.
You already own all you could ever desire.
I am beginning to think that
you want to get caught.
Oh, hardly.
Almost caught.
You wanna taste death
without swallowing it.
(UTENSILS CLATTER) Can I just say...
You are ruining this steak for me.
You and I, we are insatiable.
We...
We thrive on the hunt. It feeds us!
Us?
From the moment I laid eyes on you,
I knew you were a woman of appetite.
Oh, don't deny it.
(CHUCKLING)
Eat.
(GUN COCKS)
A church is no place for a gun, Mr.
Bohannon.
Turn around.
Take me to the rest of 'em.
On Heavenly Father's name, I do not know...
(THE SWEDE GRUNTS)
Mm. She pulls to the left.
You don't want to test your luck
again, you best get to walkin'.
(SCOFFS) And... Yeah?
You're missing the show, Mr. Bohannon.
- Show me what's in them rice crates.
- Hmm?
Open 'em.
CULLEN: Slow.
Steady now.
- Go there.
- Hmm?
Against that post.
Put your hands on it.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MAN SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
- Where are they?
- Where are what, Mr. Boha...
Give me 'em guns, you son
of a bitch before...
(GUN COCKING)
Back up.
(CHANG SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
Can I help you, sir?
Ah-Tao?
Put the gun on the ground.
There is no need for bloodshed, brothers.
I want them rifles, Swede.
There are no rifles, Mr. Bohannon.
- Chang told me his self.
- Chang is a liar.
Swede is.
I've never lied to you, Mr. Bohannon.
Why would you trust a Chinaman over me?
A Chinaman whom you have humiliated.
Whose business you have disrupted.
Perhaps the boy is right.
Mr. Chang has you chasing wild geese.
(GUN CLICKS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (THE SWEDE EXCLAIMS)
My friends call me Ah-Tao. How may I...
(SPEAKING IN CANTONESE)
(SOBBING)
CULLEN: Move!
You did this.
The assassin was a white man, Mr. Bohannon.
Ask anyone.
Pity the only witnesses were Chinese.
(MEI CRYING)
(MUTTERING IN CANTONESE)
www.addic7ed.com