[Flies buzzing]
[Horse whinnies]
Mr. Durant.
What the hell is he doing here?
Are you
the "Chicago Tribune" reporter?
Yes.
Did you photograph this body?
Yes, sir, Mr. Durant.
But just the one body.
What is wrong with you, man?
I'm sorry.
I thought...
Well, just the one won't do.
Get those bodies back off the wagons.
Come on, snap to, boys.
I want this scene photographed
exactly as you found it.
I want an unblinking look
at the horror perpetrated here.
More arrows.
We need more arrows.
[Grunting]
He can't feel anything.
He's dead, for God's sake.
The maps.
Did you find them?
No, sir. Nothing anywhere.
Keep looking.
Man: Mr. Durant, over here.
Robert.
Pack up everything.
Bring it all back to Hell on Wheels.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Yah! Yah!
They found Johnson's body.
Everybody back at the
camp talkin' about it.
Get the hell back to that cut.
Cullen Bohannon?
Did you hear about
Daniel Johnson's murder?
Who wants to know?
Why you so spooked, son?
I guess I still ain't quite cottoned
to the sight of union
blue riding up on me.
Well, you ought to
be happy to see us.
Yeah, why is that?
The boss wants to talk to you
about taking Johnson's job.
[Train whistle blowing]
I thank thee, lord,
for is bounty you
have placed before me.
Sit down.
Horse thief.
Thor gunderson.
Head of security
for Mr. Thomas Durant.
They call me the Swede.
I'm Norwegian.
No matter. We are all Americans now.
Even you rebels, yes?
Hmm.
Daniel Johnson told me that the two
of you was cut from the same cloth.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Why is that?
Did you not like him?
He's my boss.
That's about all there was to it.
And drinking companion, yes?
We tore it up some.
I understand thewo of
you was tearing it up
some on the night he was murdered.
In fact, you were seen
leaving the saloon with him.
Hmm?
Yeah.
I'm not here to talk
about Johnson's job, am I?
Is that what they told you?
[Chuckles]
You a law man, Mr. Swede?
Hmm?
Because I don't see no badge.
Hmm, no.
There's no official law out here yet.
Then what auority you got
to be interrogating me?
Mr. Durant has appointed me to bring
some order to the chaos out here.
When was the last time you
took a look outside, Mr. Swede?
Looks to me like chaos is winning.
Ah, when whorlets and
dipsomaniacs are killed,
I lose not a minute's sleep,
but Daniel Johnson...
Was a valuable asset to Mr. Durant.
Daniel Johnson was hated by just
about every man who worked for him.
Ah. Any with a reason to kill him?
Perhaps one of the negroes?
I heard he had some
trouble with them. Hmm?
Yeah, I don't
know nothin' about that.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
[Train whistle blows]
Well, that leaves only you then.
You know what?
I'm done here.
This ain't no court.
[Grunting]
This here's beauty.
She's an old piece,
but she still shoots true.
[Grunting]
I'm gonna give you a chance
to confess to this crime.
[Grunting]
[Train whistle blowing]
Where is she?
Hello, little brother.
What are you doing way out here?
Where's the woman?
I don't have her...
Yet.
You kill white men, it's one thing,
but you take one of their women,
you'll have every damn one
of them hunting you down.
Good.
I'll count coup and get more scalps.
I hope it was worth it.
What about all the scalps you took?
You act so pure now,
but I remember there was a time
when you loved the taste of blood.
Jesus has forgiven me for that.
Jesus may have forgiven you,
but do you think your
white friends would?
You better find her before I do.
[Grunts]
[Indistinct chatter]
Hey.
Hey!
You'd be surprised how fast you get
used to the feel of them things.
What the hell are you doing here?
Want to know if you fixin'
to be testifying on me.
I don't know, ain't decided yet.
I know 'bout that sergeant.
Heard Johnson say some
other things, too.
Things 'bout men gettin'
killed in churches and such.
Yeah, what's your point?
Point is, if I be
hangin' for Johnson,
then you gonna drop down right beside
me for them folks you done killed.
Tell you what.
You tell your story
and then I'll tell mine.
We'll see who they believe.
Yeah.
Who will believe some n
slave over a white man?
Relax, son.
Ain't nobody hangin' nobody.
I ain't your damn son.
Well, I'll be out
of here by tomorrow.
I imagine that's what
that horse thief done said.
[Indistinct chatter]
Thanks.
Thank you.
Thanks so much.
See you again.
Good luck.
Cheers.
[Chuckles]
Did you enjoy the show, sir?
Very moving images of home, boys.
But you don't sound Irish.
I ain't, but my heart
was moved nonetheless.
We're all yearning for our homeland
out here in this strange place.
Excuse me, sir, have we met?
We have not.
Folks around here call me the Swede.
You got yourself
a prime location here, boys.
Yes, siree, right between
the whores and liquor.
Picked it out meself.
What is it you want, Mr. Swede?
I like that, right to the point.
And the point is,
a nice location like this got
a nice price attached to it.
I should have realized
there was a reason
this spot wasn't taken.
I shoulda seen this comin'.
I take it then, you're the smart one.
Aye. Aye.
So, how much do you want, Mr. Swede?
Oh, once again, right to the point.
Uh, $2.00 a week.
The first payment due this Friday.
But that's half our flippin' take.
For this $2.00,
you shall have my protection
against all the villains that
surround you in this wicked place.
And what if we don't pay?
You can always move down
to the slaughterhouse.
And what if we refuse to move?
And I thought you was the smart one.
[Rooster crowing]
You know I used to be a bookkeeper.
You look like a bookkeeper.
Hmm. I was always more comfortable
around numbers than people.
I could control numbers.
The war put a stop
to that, didn't it?
You're suffering from the
soldier's heart, Mr. Swede.
I can see it in your eyes.
You're still fighting them battles.
I saw no battles.
I was a quartermaster.
More numbers.
Hmm. I never even saw the enemy
until our supply train
was captured and...
I become prisoner of war.
Andersonville?
That's right.
Way down in the great
state of Georgia.
Total chaos ruled.
30,000 prisoners, 14,000 dead.
I weighed 200 pounds when I
went in and 86 when I come out.
I just couldn't
make them numbers add up.
I woke one night to one of my own men
trying to eat the flesh from my arm.
He thought I was dead.
I realized that night
I had to control people
like I controlled numbers
and I learned to practice
a sort of immoral mathematics.
I did some...
[Mutters]
Not so good things in
Andersonville, Mr. Bohannon.
In the end I found I was able
to make them numbers add up.
Mmm.
So, have you thought
about that confession?
Well, I figured by your math,
you're gonna hang me either way.
Yeah.
You know why that man didn't
finish eating your sorry ass?
Mm-mmm. Hmm?
'Cause you Yankees
all taste like trash.
Ah!
Get right with
your maker, Mr. Bohannon.
Soon as we cut down
the horse thief...
You're gonna hang.
[Grunting]
Write this down.
Outnumbered five to one,
eight white Christian souls
were brutally slaughtered
by the marauding, bloodthirsty
war party of merciless savages.
Outnumbered five to one?
Make it ten to one.
Amongst the murdered
were Robert bell,
visionary surveyor of
the union pacific railroad...
His beautiful wife lily,
the fair haired maiden of the west,
was sullied by the savage pack,
then carried off into slavery
in their filthy camp...
What--what does sullied mean again?
It will mean whatever
the reader wants it to mean.
My road will bring civilization
to these untamed Western lands.
And the fair-haired
maiden of the west
represents nothing less
than civilization itself.
You see--you see this as
sort of a rallying cry?
Yes.
Now you're getting it.
Save her at all costs.
Well, yes, of course, save her,
but I also want the federal
troops brought in here
to clear every single last
savage from the path of my road.
[Breathing heavily]
[Grunting]
[Train whistle blowing]
Welcome, brother.
You must be that feller they're...
They're looking to hang.
You know, Saint Peter himself
was...Chained like this
and condemned to die.
And he was freed by an angel.
I ain't no Saint Peter, sir.
Yeah, and I ain't no angel.
Peace be with you, sir.
I'm with you, reverend.
I'm with you.
I hear your prisoner escaped.
Oh, we'll find him.
It's just a matter of time.
I'll be sure to keep
an eye out for him.
You be careful.
He's a dangerous man.
Brother...
We need to talk.
I thought you were gonna turn me in.
No. The lord instructs me to give
sanctuary even to the condemned.
Yeah?
What does he say about cutting
off a pair of cuffs, huh?
You're on your own there.
You know...
You'd best set things straight
in your heart before you
go a-swingin', son.
They ain't gonna hang me.
Well, nevertheless, ha ha.
One day your name will be called.
And on that day, you must answer.
I know it.
Yeah, and what are you gonna say?
I did the best I could in a bad time.
Yeah, see, I understand
that better than you know,
but it won't be good enough for him.
So, all you got to do is
get down on your knees...
Yeah. I seen plenty of men
get down on their knees
and call out his name
in terrible times.
I seen their prayers answered
with a bullet more often than not.
It's hard to comprehend
I...Son, I know.
It's impossible sometimes, but...
But he is here...And his
mercy knows no bounds.
Just bend them knees
and ask for forgiveness.
No, sir.
I won't do it.
Because the war took your faith?
Because I don't deserve forgiveness.
Oy.
We can't use that.
Ma would understand.
And what about next week
and the week after?
This ain't gonna stop.
There's nothing we can
do about this bastard.
That's what you said in Boston.
I thought you said we were
never to speak of that.
I got us out of that,
I'll get us out of this.
But how?
I don't know yet.
I'll figure somethin'.
One day we'll send this to ma...
And it'll be as thick as a brick.
My hand to God.
I had some Jack rabbit in me, too.
Master gave me a nice pair
of bracelets to sleep in.
Somebody put you in chains,
the natural thing
to do is try to escape.
Ain't I right?
Yeah.
You're right.
This way, let's go.
They're comin'.
You gonna make a run for it?
I ain't leaving.
They'll find you.
Not where I'm going.
So, it's true.
Mm-hmm.
All of them?
Everyone but the woman.
Them injuns get her?
I don't know.
Put the word out,
$100 reward for anyone who finds her,
but, uh...Not a word about the maps.
Yeah.
[Horse neighs]
Mr. Durant?
Who the hell are you?
Cullen Bohannon...The man
they're looking to hang.
For killing Johnson?
I suppose you're here to
tell me you're innocent?
No, sir.
I'm here to ask for his job.
How do you put your trousers on, son?
Sir?
Over those big balls of yours?
2 minutes.
That's all I ask.
[Ticking]
Did you fight in the war, Mr. Durant?
I served my country in other ways.
Oh.
Building this railroad ain't
much different than the war.
You got an army out there
and they need a leader.
I take it you fought for
the South, Mr. Bohannon.
Yes, sir.
And that's exactly why
you need to hire me.
You're going to have
to explain that to me.
I can't remember a time
I wasn't outgunned,
outmanned, or out supplied
fighting you Yankees.
But I damn sure whooped
your asses more often than not.
Is that so?
Yes, sir. My men rode to hell
and back for me, Mr. Durant.
That's why you need me out here.
What do you know about
building railroads?
Well, I had to learn
how they was built
so I could figure out
bestow to blow them up.
You remember the Baltimore
and Ohio bridge over
the monacacy river?
I built that bridge before the war.
I blew the whole thing up
using half a keg of black powder...
But I'm done
destroying things, Mr. Durant.
I want to help you
build this railroad.
Why should I trust
my railroad to a gray back?
You didn't have too much trouble
trusting gray backs
when you was smuggling cotton out of
Mississippi during the war, now did ya?
You walk a fine line, son.
40 Miles, Mr. Durant.
Ain't no secret you got to lay
40 Miles of usable track
before your government
money kicks in.
Now, you and I both know
that you ain't gonna get
there going at this rate.
You don't get that $16,000 a mile,
this whole thing goes belly-up.
You're fighting a war, Mr. Durant.
No doubt about it.
You need me to help you win it.
Son of a bitch.
What the hell are you doing, man?
He's the son of a bitch
who killed Johnson.
We gonna hang him.
Nonsense.
This is my new foreman.
Find me someone else to hang.
You're the new foreman?
Yeah.
Johnson's things still in there?
Yes, sir.
You want me to clear it out?
Leave it.
Yes, sir.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com