Previously on AMC's Hell On Wheels.
I'm coming back for you and the baby.
Don't say it.
I will.
We share a common enemy,
Mr. Cullen Bohannon.
You better shoot to kill.
I'm coming back to finish
this once and for all.
To be tested by you is
the making of my soul.
(BOHANNON) Tell me where my family is.
(CHUCKLING, BABY CHATTERING)
Naomi!
I look forward to this next test...
Devil.
♪ The camptown ladies sing this song ♪
♪ Doo-dah, doo-dah ♪
♪ Camptown race track five miles long ♪
♪ Oh! Doo-dah day ♪
♪ Going round like a railroad car ♪
♪ Doo-dah, doo-dah ♪
♪ Looks just like a shooting star ♪
I'm gonna teach you a new song.
♪ Old cow come up the track ♪
♪ Doo-dah, doo-dah ♪
♪ Bobby threw her on his back ♪
♪ Oh! Doo-dah day ♪
♪ Going to run all night ♪
♪ Going to run all day ♪
♪ I'll bet my money
on the bob-tail nag ♪
And I keep it on my back in
an old sack or something!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Another one, for God sakes!
Something we can drink to.
All right, this one I... I... I played
for a rosy-cheeked lady named Elsa.
ALL: To Elsa!
Uh-uh-uh... To Thor Gundersen!
ALL: To Thor Gundersen!
(PLAYING)
(CLAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
- (GUNSHOT)
- (HORSES NEIGHING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (GROANING)
(INDISTINCT SCREAMING)
- (CLATTERING)
- (SOLDIER GRUNTING OUTSIDE)
(WHIMPERING) Please...
(STUTTERING) I am only a quartermaster.
(HAMMER FALLS ON EMPTY CHAMBER)
(GRUNTS, THUD)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(THE SWEDE COUGHING)
(WHIMPERING)
GOODWIN: Don't. (HEAVY BREATHING)
(PLAYING)
GUARD: That sound you, shithead, hmm?
- GOODWIN: No. (WHIMPERING)
- His name is...
Is Private James Goodwin.
Oh, when you address me, it's sir,
you goddamn Swedish bastard.
Norwegian, sir.
Goddamn Norwegian bastard, sir.
The Swede's got jokes.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Ah...
Jokes and contraband.
Maybe the Swede should play me a song.
Mmm-hmm.
I said play me a song, Swede.
My name is Thor Gundersen from Norway.
- (GRUNTS)
- (SCREAMS)
(PLAYING HARMONICA OFF KEY)
(SOBBING)
(PANTING, WHIMPERING)
GUARD: Well, here we go, boys.
Here you go, stumpy.
Here you go, Swede.
Come and get it.
All right, one at a time. One at...
Back up, back up or nothing.
Here we go.
Swede, I'm the one
that feeds him, Swede.
I'm the one that feeds him.
- (WHIPPING)
- (YELLING) I'm the one.
I'm the one that feeds him.
Do you hear me, Swede?
I'm the one.
(GOODWIN CHEWING SLOPPILY)
(WHIMPERING, MOANING)
(CRYING)
- (GRUNTING)
- James, look at me, James.
Look at me.
I am your friend, Thor Gundersen.
(YELLING, GRUNTING)
It is me.
- It is... It is me!
- (GROWLING)
- Look at me, James.
- (GRUNTING)
It is me. I am your friend.
- I am your friend.
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
It is me.
Thor Gundersen.
I am your friend.
(VERY SOFTLY) It is me.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
You are my friend.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
(CHOPPING)
NAOMI: ♪ Sleepyhead, close your eyes ♪
♪ Mama's right here beside you ♪
♪ I'll protect you from harm ♪
(CHOPPING CONTINUES)
♪ You will wake in my arms ♪
(HUMMING)
(CHOPPING STOPS)
Hmm. Where'd he go, hmm?
Isaac?
Have you seen Isaac, sister?
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Sara?
Sara, what's wrong?
- Oh!
- (CLATTERING)
- (CHOKING)
- (GASPS)
(MUTTERING) Sara...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
(COCKS GUN)
Isaac?
Get William!
Papa?
- (RETCHING)
- Papa!
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Papa... (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Run!
- (SCREAMS) Papa!
(GRUNTS, SOBS)
- (POUNDING ON DOOR)
- (BABY WAILING)
- (CLATTERING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (COCKS GUN)
- (GUNSHOT)
- (GUNSHOTS)
THE SWEDE: Naomi,
I'm coming to get you.
- (HAMMER FALLS ON EMPTY CHAMBER)
- (HEAVY BREATHING)
You best run.
(LOADING BULLETS)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(YELLING) Naomi!
(COCKS GUN)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(GRUNTS)
(BABY WAILING)
(BABY WAILING IN THE DISTANCE)
(YELLING) Naomi!
I'm coming.
(SHUSHING)
(SNAPS)
(BABY COOS)
(BABY COOING)
(SHUSHING)
(TWIG SNAPPING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(COOING)
- CULLEN: Naomi?
- Cullen.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (CHOKES)
(SPLASH)
- (BABY CRIES)
- (NAOMI GASPS)
(GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING, SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHING)
(MOANING)
(COCKS GUN)
You move and I'll shoot you.
(WHIMPERS)
These stitches won't hold.
- This thread ain't the right kind of...
- I'll be fine.
You need a doctor.
I'll send Isaac for a doctor.
(SNIFFLES)
(STRAINING) Camp Douglas has a doctor.
You won't make it half way.
He won't let you.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
He will hang.
Then why go?
End it here.
(GRUNTG)
THE SWEDE: Tell me where...
Where are we headed, huh?
If you wanted to kill
me you would have...
You would have done
it down in the creek.
Uh, perhaps a slow death, eh?
Torture.
Mmm, the leg in that condition...
No man tortures his enemy if he must
torture himself in the process.
Camp Douglas, huh?
Some 60 miles west of Gobbler's Knob,
with jurisdiction over all crimes
committed in the Utah Territory.
You want this to end in the way
you believe it should have ended a long
time ago upon that trestle bridge.
Uh, Heavenly Father has
spared my neck twice now.
He can manage a third, hmm?
THE SWEDE: My friend took a
ball to the leg during the war.
Same place as you. You would
not believe how he suffered.
CULLEN: I don't believe
you had a friend.
THE SWEDE: Uh, uh, Confederate
soldiers took us captive,
forced us to ride two days,
about the same distance
we are traveling, yeah?
By the time we arrived at
the Georgia state line,
gangrene had set in.
A river of shit ran through
the center of Andersonville,
and I tell you the stench of
Goodwin's wound overpowered it.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
The rot did not take his leg.
Uh, the rebels did. And
with it, his dignity.
Imagine saving a man's life
only to watch his slow death.
What breed of monster is
capable of such inhumanity?
I can think of one.
Oh, as can I.
(CULLEN GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(STUTTERING) Untie me, Mr. Bohannon.
I can help you.
Devil!
- Mr. Bohannon...
- (GROANS)
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
What, huh?
It's just a snake.
(WHIMPERING)
(SHUDDERING)
(GRUNTS)
Trapper once told me
that squirming is a...
It's a soul's way of leaving the body.
Said it could last for minutes.
Huh...
Guess it depends on the soul.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Sure you don't want none?
(GROANS)
You could be sharing a hot
meal with your wife and child.
Instead you are out in the cold,
with a festering wound.
It's interesting you
would rather be here,
offering me sustenance,
instead of your family.
I'd rather keep 'em far away from you.
If protecting them was your only motive,
you would have been safer to kill me.
And you fear killing me.
Why?
- I fear...
- Hmm.
I fear it would bring you peace.
Son of a bitch.
And I will see you hang.
If your misguided see of justice
requires that I hang for my crimes,
surely you can understand that
you must hang there beside me...
For yours.
And, the bodies you have piled up
do not disappear when
you bury them away,
out of sight.
And you bring death everywhere.
You scared?
Oh... (SIGHS)
You need your rest, Mr. Bohannon, hmm?
Hmm,
I'll rest soon enough.
Well, I certainly hope
you do not mind if I do.
We have a long journey ahead.
(SPITS)
(BIRDS TRILLING)
(WHIMPERS, GROANS)
(PANTING)
Shit.
Ah, I warned you, hmm?
(TSKING)
(YAWNING)
(GRUNTS)
Mmm, wasting precious
resources could prove fatal.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- Yeah, I got plenty of water.
- I was referring to the bullets.
(RELOADS GUN)
(BREATHING SHARPLY)
(SCREAMING IN AGONY)
(GROANING)
(MOANING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Down into the desert, then?
(CULLEN BREATHING SHARPLY)
(CULLEN GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(COUGHING)
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTING)
Right there is Camp Douglas.
- Hmm?
- (GRUNTS)
Exactly 40 miles
west of Gobbler's Knob.
Ride.
Move.
I said ride.
Get back up on that horse.
We were not meant to settle
this inside a courtroom.
We will settle this as God...
As God planned.
Here in the desert.
I said get back up on the horse.
You want final judgment upon me,
you will have to hand it down yourself,
as I most certainly intend to do.
- I ain't your judge.
- Yes, you are.
You are the only one who knows
me, same as I know you!
Do you think the world stops
when you leave it behind?
Does it stop for...
For Mary and... And Joshua
when you left for war?
Does it stop for Naomi
when you abandoned her...
- And William?
- Get on the horse.
You cannot see it, can you?
It is right there in front of you
but your myopic single-mindedness
on prosecuting me
has blinded you to the simple facts!
- I ain't asking you again.
- You like this!
You would rather be on death's door
than with Naomi and William.
No, death and killing have
been your only wives.
Your only family.
- (GROANS)
- (HORSE WHINNYING)
(GAGGING)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
- (GRUNTING)
- (GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTING)
- (GROANING)
(COUGHING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(MOANING)
(SCREAMING)
Prisoner...
I got...
(GRUNTING) I got a...
I got a prisoner.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(COCKS GUN)
(GUNSHOT)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
Prisoner...
(THE SWEDE GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(STRAINING)
Thank you, devil.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GUNS COCKING)
(SNIPPING)
(TEARING)
(SQUELCHING)
(DRIPPING)
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(METAL CLINKS)
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(METAL CLINKS)
(INHALES THROUGH TEETH)
I thought you gave up the ghost.
(GROANING)
You'll be all right.
That bullet shattered.
(SIGHS) Shrapnel all through your thigh.
Extracted a few fragments, but
there's still some deep inside.
Here you go.
I want it out.
All of it.
It's part of you now. You'll be carrying
it around for the rest of your life.
Hmm. How long I been here?
Four days.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
The man I brought in here. Gundersen?
Yeah.
Captain sent a few riders out to
that homestead you told us about.
(SIGHS)
Circuit judge come out from Salt Lake.
We had us a trial yesterday.
He hand down a judgment?
He did.
(HARMONICA PLAYING)
(SHUDDERS)
(GASPS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Excuse me.
(GRUNTS)
Private, what...
What is that...
What is that you're playing?
(GRUNTS)
It got no name far as I know.
Just a melody I keep hearing in my head.
It is not "just a melody"
rattling around in your head, you.
It is, unless I misheard, Two Soldiers,
and you...
You almost have it,
but for blowing a note or two,
you should be drawing.
A more intimate instrument
does not exist.
You...
You give to it the most
cherished gift a man has...
His breath, hmm?
You release into it your...
Your very soul.
The best players,
for a moment, they touch God.
I can show you.
Eat your food.
I am...
I was a musician.
That's your last food.
(STUTTERING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(GRUNTS)
(MUTTERING)
(GRUNTING IN PAIN)
Thank you, thee, oh, Lord,
for this bounty you have
placed before me...
Hmm.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(HEAVY BREATHING, GRUNTING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(CULLEN GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Mother gave me a harmonica
on my tenth birthday.
"A man who can make music will
never be lonely," she said.
Hanged by the neck until dead.
You...
You are a merciful man,
Mr. Bohannon.
Thought I was the devil.
I was wrong.
You are just a man.
Just a man. A man of war.
War made both of us, after all.
Ain't no way out of this one, Swede.
No. The way out is...
Is by your... Your hand.
One act of forgiveness
is... Is all I ask.
One act of mercy.
(STUTTERS) I do not want to hang.
I ain't your maker.
(WHIMPERING, STUTTERING)
Forgive me, Cullen.
(STUTTERING) Forgive me.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Forgive yourself, huh?
- PRIVATE: It's time.
- (THE SWEDE GASPING)
Oh! (HEAVY BREATHING)
God have mercy upon your soul.
(THE SWEDE GRUNTS)
(FLAG FLUTTERING)
"Thor Gundersen, late of Salt Lake City,
not having the fear of
God before your eyes,
but being moved and seduced by
the instigation of the devil,
have been found guilty of
feloniously and willfully
with malice aforethought
of depriving Aaron Hatch
and Sara Hatch of life
so that they then and
there instantly died.
The sentence is death.
You shall be hanged by
the neck until dead."
(PAPER RUSTLING)
May the Lord have mercy upon your soul.
(EXHALING HEAVILY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Uh, no, not this. Please, not this...
I ca... Please, please.
CAPTAIN PAULSON:
Have you any last words?
(HEAVY BREATHING)
I am Thor Gundersen.
From Norway.
Hmm.
- (CREAKING)
- (THE SWEDE GASPING)
(GAGGING)
(COUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GAGGING)
(GRUNTS)
(THE SWEDE GASPS)
- (CREAKING)
- (URINATING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He's dead.
(GRUNTS)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com