Previously on Longmire...
2x09 - Tuscan Red
Walt: Well, it looks pretty big.
Should be able to get enough
timber to do my cabin steps.
It's a sign
that you are a lucky man.
Good timing. The
election is a week away.
One day, you're standing tall.
Next day, people are
walking all over you.
A lot can change in a week.
[ thud ]
[ grunts ]
Ignore the polls.
I do. But there are some
things I can't ignore.
You still haven't told me
about your chat with Detective Fales.
You know the police.
He asked questions, and I answered.
Worry not ... in one week,
you will be re-elected
- and life will get back to normal.
- We'll see.
That answer verged on
optimism, almost excitement.
- You want this job.
- Let's just finish this one.
You want Branch to win?
- No.
- So you want this job.
Knock it off.
[ chain saw revs ]
You've never said you
want anything. Just say it.
Come on. Say you want to be
Sheriff and you want to win.
[ chainsaw stops ]
Okay.
I want to win.
[ explosion ]
[ birds squawking ]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~
[ radar beeping ]
Branch: No, no, no.
Don't put words in my mouth.
Walt Longmire's done a fine job.
All I'm saying
is Absaroka County
deserves more than fine.
We need to look forward, not backward.
[ radar beeping ]
I'll call you back.
[ engine revs, tires squeal ]
[ siren wails ]
[ siren chirps ]
Return to your vehicle, ma'am.
You know how fast you were going?
- 80 in a 55.
- 81.
I'm gonna ask you again...
return to your vehicle.
- We need to talk.
- Here?
Yeah. Um, I didn't ass-dial
you the other night.
I called you and
pretended I ass-dialed you.
I mean, I have ass-dialed
you, but not that time.
That time, I wanted to
see you, and I can't.
My head's not in the right
place for a relationship.
I wanted to call you
and tell you all of this,
but I'm sick of the phone,
and I'm not gonna text,
so I wanted to say
it face-to-face.
Well... we could have met for
coffee or at the monkey bars.
No, I didn't want anyone to
see us and get the wrong idea
and start gossiping.
I mean, you know this town.
[ horn honks ]
Right? So...
Now it just looks like
you're giving me a ticket.
Yeah. Great.
Now it just looks
like candidate Connally
is harassing the competition's daughter.
Don't bring politics into this.
We're friends, right?
But that's it.
That I can do ...
nothing more. I'm done.
You want to say something?
Fine.
Cady... we're not done here.
Did you not understand what I just said?
- Barely.
- Okay.
[ car door slams ]
[ engine turns over ]
- I want to see you again, too.
- Not gonna happen.
I think it will.
[ paper rustling ]
See you in court.
[ dog barking ]
- Do you see anyone?
- No.
All right, let's let it cool down.
Sheriff Longmire, the fire
department can handle this.
It's a volunteer fire department.
Today, we volunteered.
Geez, relax, Mathias.
He saw the smoke and came running.
Yeah, to a nice photo op.
- This is not about the campaign.
- Well, that's funny
coming from Walt Longmire's
campaign chairman.
What the hell happened here?
- I don't know.
- I do.
This house belongs to Dolan Lone Elk.
He's been protesting a fracking
operation just outside the res.
Now his house blows up
from methane seeping
into his water supply.
- It's ironic, isn't it?
- Vic: What's the name of the company
- that's been doing the fracking?
- Newett Energy.
You know, Mathias,
the link between fracking
and water contamination
hasn't totally been proven.
There's some methane
that naturally occurs in sediment.
Henry! Toss me your lighter!
Walt, we just put this fire out.
I rest my case.
Both spouts are open.
Water was running.
Which means the gas was leaking.
Someone was definitely home.
[ birds squawking ]
All the windows are closed.
This one's locked.
Build up enough methane pressure in
an enclosed space, you get all this.
Mathias: Dolan told me the
methane levels made him afraid
to even take a shower without
opening the windows first.
[ Walt grunts ]
Why didn't Dolan do it this time?
I got it.
Are you taking the
body to Doc Bloomfield?
- Is this suddenly my case?
- Ours.
My people, your energy company.
Accident or not, blood
is on their hands.
Okay, boys.
The sooner we get the autopsy done,
the faster we find out
what actually happened.
Ever heard of a burn
victim leaking blood?
I don't think it's blood.
- What is it?
- Paint.
- What the hell's going on here?
- Please, brother. Keep back.
I have a right to see that body.
Sir, you can't come
in here. Hey, hey, hey.
Mathias: It's okay, Philly.
It's his house.
That's Dolan Lone Elk.
If you're Dolan Lone
Elk, then who's this?
Ethan.
It's my brother, Ethan.
Take a seat.
Any idea why Ethan was at your home?
He's family. He doesn't
need a reason to be there.
- Vic: And where were you?
- I was at a sweat.
- For what?
- For strength to fight Newett Energy.
Idle no more is planning
a protest here today.
- They can't silence us.
- You think this explosion
was someone trying to silence you?
Ever since I blew the
whistle on Newett Energy
and started telling people
what this company is doing
to our land and our water,
they've been trying their
damndest to intimidate me.
My brother's murder
will just make our voices
stronger and stronger.
Okay. So, if it wasn't an accident,
why would someone kill Ethan?
Because they thought he was me.
I guess all Cheyenne
look the same to everybody at Newett.
- Was Ethan part of idle no more?
- No.
After he graduated high school,
he left the res for college.
He just moved back a few months ago
and accepted a management
position at Nighthorse casino.
I guess he figured that white
presidents on green paper
would cure all that ills us.
Maybe he just didn't know
about the methane problem.
Oh, Ethan knew. All
Cheyenne know about it.
We got to open windows and
doors just to wash our hands.
We have to sleep with windows
cracked and one eye open.
We need to notify Ethan's wife.
Sometimes, this kind of news
is better coming from family.
Her name is Lauryn.
She works at the casino, too,
and I'd prefer it if you informed her.
So, if you two don't mind,
I've got to get back to my people.
I'll see myself out.
[ door opens ]
Ruby: Doctor Bloomfield called.
He wants you to come over right away,
said he needed to talk to you in person.
Damn it, I really wanted to meet him.
So what is Doc Bloomfield like, anyway?
Ruggedly handsome with a somewhat
irresistible air of mystery.
Hey, Doc. This is Deputy Moretti.
My mother's Japanese,
father's Scots-jewish.
Thought I'd be Korean, right?
[ chuckles ]
We didn't come here
for your genealogy, Doc.
You said you needed to talk in person.
The, uh, Mayor asked me to
personally oversee the autopsy
and inform you of any results.
- Why?
- Well, apparently, Newett Energy's C.E.O.
called the Mayor's office this morning,
wanted to make sure no
details were overlooked.
Also wanted to make sure
no law-enforcement officials
jump to any costly
conclusions about liability.
I assume that means me.
Well, you do got a reputation
of being a Cheyenne advocate,
and you never really learned
how to properly oil
the haunches of power.
- What did you find?
- So far, nothing but trouble. [ spits ]
First of all, Ethan Lone Elk had
been painted red from head to toe.
Now, the paint fueled the fire
on his front, as you can see,
but his back was preserved,
most likely 'cause
he was lying down when
the blast occurred.
I took a sample of the
paint ... red, oil-based.
Here.
I cut a swatch from his shirt.
And I hate racial stereotypes
as much as the next guy,
but it looks like he
was one drunk indian.
I swabbed inside his cheek.
Hardly seems official.
You can't actually get a tox
screen back in 24 hours, can you?
We don't have the luxury of time,
given all the givens, darling.
So, Deputy Moretti,
please do me a favor.
I want you to hold this mouthpiece
over Ethan's mouth just like so.
Ah. Grazie.
Walt, I want you to stand there.
Now, on the count of three,
I want you to press down on
the victim's chest. Ready?
One, two, three.
[ air hisses ]
[ beep ]
[ whistles ]
He just blew a 0.34.
[ inhales sharply ]
That's a hell of a
lot of beer, eh, Walt?
We didn't find any empty
beer bottles or cans,
- anything at his house.
- So, Ethan was drinking.
This doesn't explain
why he was painted red
before a house went up in flames.
[ door opens ]
- Hey, Ruby.
- Where are you going?
Uh, to my desk.
Nope. Walt wants us to go out.
Why?
Paint shopping ... we
need to match this color.
Where's this from?
Off a gentleman from the
res ... Ethan Lone Elk.
I just don't get people sometimes.
They painted his entire body red.
It's horrible.
Let's go, hot shot.
[ door opens ]
Jacob: Full-time jobs
and medical benefits
for 42 Cheyenne, 14 Arapaho,
6 Lakota, and 3 Crow.
Now remind me ... how
again is this casino
a negative influence for the res?
I'm not here to debate with you, Jacob.
I need to talk to one of your employees.
News travels faster than you, Sheriff.
This about the explosion?
- No comment.
- I didn't tell his wife.
I didn't think it was my place.
That's your job ... for now, anyway.
Lauryn Lone Elk ...
she's training, third table in.
Face of steel, eyes of steel ...
you control the table.
Don't show them a thing.
Lauryn Lone Elk?
I'm Lauryn.
How can I help you?
Mrs. Lone Elk, can you take a break?
You have five minutes,
not a moment more.
I'm very sorry to tell you
there was an explosion
on the reservation today,
and your husband, Ethan ...
he was killed.
Can we not do this here?
Did your husband tell you he
was going to his brother's house?
- He never does.
- Why?
Ethan's family is a difficult issue.
My husband and I have
learned not to discuss it.
I don't exactly fit the
Lone Elk family's image
of an ideal squaw.
He said he stopped visiting them,
but I know he was still going.
Did Ethan always go to Dolan's house,
or did they ever go anywhere for a beer?
Ethan didn't drink.
Though he should have with
the pressures of his job.
I understand he worked
at the casino, too.
Ethan ran human resources,
drug-testing potential employees.
He decided who got
the job and who didn't.
That can't have been
easy. He get any threats?
For not hiring someone
or for marrying me?
- Both.
- Sure.
Anonymous phone calls,
hang-ups.
S.U.V.s rolling by our house.
I couldn't tell you if that
was because of me or the job.
[ voice breaking ]
But that's our life.
And we refused to live in fear.
[ sighs ]
I need to get back to work.
[ cellphone rings, beeps ]
Jacob: Deputy Connally,
I suggest you steer clear
- of this Ethan Lone Elk situation.
- Sounds like an opportunity.
However it shakes out,
people are gonna get angry,
and you don't want to
alienate any voting blocs.
Let Walt fall on it.
It's a political grenade.
- I disagree.
- Listen, you jump in,
you're either gonna piss off
big business or the Cheyenne.
You can't afford to lose either group
one week away from the election.
I got to go.
[ cellphone beeps ]
I need Ethan's list of job applicants,
especially ones that
didn't make the cut.
So, you've dismissed the
energy company already
And want to look for a killer
among my hardworking employees.
Why not look under the ground, man?
That's where the stench is coming from.
You say you want to help the Cheyenne.
You get me that list, or you give
it to Mathias ... I don't care.
Your employee was killed.
The person that did it
might be on that list.
Well, if I did have such a list,
it would be quite confidential.
Then I'll get quite the subpoena.
Let's go.
[ inhales sharply ]
[ crowd chanting ]
[ cellphone rings ]
[ cellphone beeps ]
Hi.
- Victoria.
- Can I call you back later?
No. I-I kind of need to
talk to you right now.
Okay, but make it quick.
The shit has totally hit the fan today.
I know.
Hey, you!
Yeah, you! Look at me!
Look at me!
You killed my brother!
How does it feel to work
for a bunch of murderers?!
[ chanting continues ]
That's Sean's truck.
- What are you doing here?
- Watching. Not them ... them.
It's energy company security guards ...
they've already taken out one of us.
I'm not letting them get another.
Keep your head, Mathias.
I'll take care of it.
Idle no more is a peaceful group.
this looks like something
completely different.
I don't think some of these
people are even in the group.
Maybe Henry will be able to
talk some sense into them.
- I was called.
- By who?
- His people.
- Great. So, what do we do now?
[ chanting continues ]
Sir, step out of the car, please.
You're under arrest for inciting a riot.
Walk out in cuffs if you want
to get out of here. Come on.
[ cheers and applause ]
That's for Ethan!
Don't make me come back for you!
Newett Energy is poisoning
our land and our people!
They killed my brother!
[ crowd boos ]
Walt: They also own that truck!
Get down!
[ booing continues ]
They will not break us!
They're trespassing on our land,
and they need to be sent
back to where they came from!
[ crowd cheers ]
[ crowd chanting ]
[ crowd boos ]
Come here!
[ handcuffs click ]
Who's gonna be next?
I am.
Is this your idea of justice, Sheriff?
Newett Energy poisons our water
and murders my brother,
and you put us behind bars,
while he sits there
like an honored guest?
He's simply filling out
a formal damage report ...
thanks to you.
He'll be gone when he's finished.
His arrest was fake.
Ours was real.
You know, there was a time
when you people at least tried
to disguise your double standard.
Just how much money is
Newett Energy donating
towards your re-election
campaign anyway, Sheriff?
- Not a cent.
- Prove it.
- Ask my campaign manager.
- It is true. They are not donors.
Walt, we need to talk...
you and me in private.
I just received the official
tox-screen report on Ethan Lone Elk.
It appears the explosion
didn't kill him.
He was already dead.
- How did he die?
- Acute alcohol poisoning.
- At 0.34?
- That came from his lungs.
but his blood test came back at 0.92 ...
more than 10 times the legal limit.
I actually called to chew out the lab.
I thought the number was a typo.
No one can drink that
much without passing out.
Someone was force-feeding
him the alcohol.
Any signs of bruising from
a fight, being tied up?
The burning and bubbling of the skin
would have covered all that up.
This man was painted red
and forced to ingest alcohol
until his body shut down.
Pretty brutal death.
We might be looking at a hate
crime ... emphasis on hate.
You gonna tell the Mayor?
Not until I get all the facts.
Politicians like
solutions, not problems.
- You get anywhere on our red paint?
- Got one of my deputies on it.
[ music ]
How many drinks has she had?
- Five.
- Better bring me four more.
Victoria, what they're
saying about us isn't true.
- You mean Newett?
- Yeah.
- [ inhales deeply ] So, ready to go home?
- I don't think I can yet.
I think it's gonna be a long night.
Oh. I get it.
Vic... I'd give you a kiss,
but I don't want to incite another riot.
- Come on. I'll walk you out.
- Sheriff.
[ door opens ]
[ door closes ]
Ethan was dead before
the house exploded.
- You sure?
- Unfortunately so.
Dolan, who wanted him dead?
Ethan mention anyone to you?
This is insane.
You already know what happened.
Newett Energy has been
targeting me for months.
Ethan died in a methane explosion
in my house because
they thought he was me.
Ethan was the target, not you.
How do you know that?
Blood tests suggest alcohol
poisoning, and Ethan didn't drink.
[ inhales deeply ]
A cynical man would accuse you
of trying to shift blame away
from the energy company.
Why should we expect
anything else, standing bear?
The Sheriff's department is
in bed with the energy company.
I'm not helping you pin
the blame on someone else.
Walt: Then enjoy your stay.
[ music ]
- [ chuckles ] Taxi!
- Uh...
I've got a better idea.
[ dialing ]
[ laughs ]
- I appreciate the ride...
- Mm-hmm.
...your open-mindedness,
and discretion.
- As well as your pepperoni.
- Oh, my god. [ laughs ]
Oh, you have to eat the crust.
You eat your half. I'll eat mine.
[ mumbles mockingly ]
[ mumbling ] Yeah.
[ both laugh ]
[ laughs ]
What are you looking at?
Are you gonna throw up?
Where did you get those eyes?
[ belches ]
[ laughs ]
I'm surprised to see you packing.
- I thought you didn't live in fear.
- I said, "we."
- Ethan's gone and his dream with it.
- Tell me that dream.
To move back to the res,
to create jobs.
You know, he even wanted
us to move to the res,
but that's where I put my foot down.
I mean, I wouldn't have
dragged him to the West
Memphis project to put up
with everything I escaped.
Ethan moved back to help the res,
and the res killed him.
The res didn't kill him.
A person did.
Your husband's death wasn't an accident.
He may have been murdered
before that house exploded.
You said Ethan didn't drink.
His blood-alcohol level was 0.92.
That's enough to kill him.
He was painted red.
Someone targeted him.
They painted him red
because he wasn't red enough,
because he wasn't Indian enough,
because he chose a black woman.
Was anyone particularly
angry about that?
Ethan's family. Even
now they won't let up.
You know his dad called me
an hour ago?
Not to give me sympathy
but to inform me
that the tribe did not
recognize me as Ethan's wife
and that I had no right
to Ethan's body.
Do you think they might have
turned that anger on Ethan?
Do you really think his family
could have done this because of me?
There's also a possibility
that someone may have been
angry with Ethan 'cause he
turned them down for a job.
Your husband ever talk about
the people that failed his drug test?
That was confidential information.
Ethan was very by-the-book.
But he wasn't much with passwords.
[ beeping ]
[ laughs ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ dog barking in distance ]
Cady?
Aah!
[ laughing ]
- Look at you!
- Stop.
- You are drunk!
- Stop. [ laughs ]
Hey!
Hey, hey. No.
No! [ laughs ]
Whoo! Look at me!
[ laughing ]
Bravo.
No! [ laughing ]
[ both laughing ]
No!
You sure you want to be friends?
Things have calmed down.
And I release you both.
Before I do, Dolan,
I want you to look at
a name on this list for me.
This is a list of
casino job applicants ...
people your brother
drug-tested and disqualified.
My brother was just doing his job.
I imagine there's some hard feelings
if people blamed Ethan
for taking jobs away, so...
One name on that list stands
out ... Mancell Lone Elk.
He a relation of yours?
You said these are the people
that failed the drug test?
- You know this man?
- He's my father,
but he's been clean
and sober for 11 years.
Not according to your brother.
I'm here to take a Dolan
Lone Elk into federal custody.
Oh, sorry ... my manners.
I am Lawrence Ward,
Federal Bureau of
Investigation, Casper office.
Sheriff, I'd like to thank you
- for your cooperation in this.
- What cooperation?
Well, for arresting Mr. Lone Elk here.
- I'm releasing him.
- I'll take him.
Disruption of international business,
destruction of private property ...
oh, and a politically motivated murder.
You think I killed my brother?
Oh, Dolan, now, I imagine
you probably thought
blowing up your own house
would result in some publicity
for your cause. It has.
- What are you implying?
- What I'm saying is,
is that Mr. Lone Elk
here has hit the big-time.
He's now a domestic terrorist.
[ sizzling ]
[ chuckles ]
Well, in the realm of drunken
mistakes, that was not so bad.
Maybe that should be my
new campaign slogan ...
"Branch Connally, not so bad."
- Good. Hair of the dog?
- Duty calls. Got to work.
Oh. Oh.
[ tab pops ]
Ahh. [ clears throat ]
Cady, it's 6:30 in the morning.
I made coffee.
What's going on?
I'm a single, highly educated woman
in the middle of Wyoming
with absolutely no career to speak of.
And my dad and my ex-boyfriend
are in the middle of
a nasty campaign fight.
And recently, I just found
out that my mother ...
Your mother what?
- Is this about Denver?
- No.
- You should go.
- I should be right here.
This is where I should be.
My mom didn't die of cancer.
[ dogs barking ]
Thanks for meeting me, Mathias.
What do you want with
Mancell Lone Elk?
Same as you. Answers.
Ethan's dead.
His brother's been labeled a terrorist.
Now you want to harass his father?
Hasn't the family suffered enough, Walt?
I appreciate your concern, Mathias,
- but the Sheriff's just doing his job.
- Probably not for long.
Mr. Lone Elk,
it must have been a difficult job
for your son Ethan to tell people he'd
known his entire life they're not
getting these high-paying casino jobs.
It was not easy on him,
but I taught my sons never
to choose the easy path.
And you did a fine job with them.
It must have been
even harder on Ethan
when he disqualified you
for failing the drug test.
This is a tribal elder
you're speaking to, Walt.
How hard was that on you, Mancell?
Rejection...
stirs hard feelings in the soul.
When I failed that test,
I was angry and I was ashamed.
What I should have been was proud.
I'd raised my two sons to follow truth
so they could not be corrupted.
Where were you two nights
ago when your son was killed?
He was leading an N.A.
meeting at the res center ...
the one my sister attends.
I was clean since
Ethan gave me that test.
I wanted to show him that I was worthy
of calling myself his father again.
You have no issue with
your son failing you?
Ethan didn't fail me. I failed him.
But you do have some
issues with his wife.
I choose not to recognize
that woman as Ethan's spouse!
- Because she's black.
- Because she's not Cheyenne.
When a child chooses to be with
someone you don't approve of,
it feels like rejection,
makes you angry,
and anger leads to bad decisions.
How could I do that to
my own son ... my own son?
Who knows what you would
do if you were high on this.
- Is this meth?
- That's not mine.
I took it off one of our
members at the N.A. meeting.
You are an elder.
You said you were clean.
Lying is the easy path.
When I heard about Ethan,
I bought a 1/4 ounce.
Without his expectations to live up to,
you tell me ... why
the hell bother, huh?
[ voice breaking ]
Why the hell bother?
So, who's gonna cuff him,
Sheriff? You or me?
[ indistinct shouting ]
Sean: You really think
you should go in today?
- Vic: I have to go in.
- Well, I'm walking you to the door.
No. No. That would
just make things worse.
They know we're married.
"Newett Energy and
the Sheriff'department
are in bed together."
Wait.
Who said that? Walt?
No. Dolan Lone Elk, right
before the FBI grabbed him.
So now you're letting yourself
be influenced by a terrorist?
Why would you just
call him a terrorist?
Because that's basically what he is.
Babe, look what he's done to durant.
Look what he did at our
headquarters the other day.
Sean, please tell me you
didn't call the FBI on him.
Because right now the
heat is off your company.
The whistle-blower
is in federal custody,
and you're using the
same language as the FBI.
Victoria, the FBI debriefed
my boss on the situation.
I was forwarded a memo.
They referred to him as a terrorist.
That's it.
- I'd like to see that memo.
- Just what kind of man do you think I am?
[ indistinct shouting ]
- Where's Mancell Lone Elk?
- Thought he'd be safer with Mathias.
[ shouting continues ]
Free Dolan!
- Free Dolan!
- I'm going to work.
Get out of my way!
All of you, move back!
[ shouting continues ]
Ruby! Stay back!
Is she all right?
She got a bit roughed up.
She's fine.
They seem pretty upset.
Why don't you go down
there and ask them to leave?
You might have to introduce yourself.
You haven't been around much.
Don't you want to know about the paint?
I found the shade of red
painted on Ethan Lone Elk.
Tuscan red.
None of the chain stores
could recall any buyers,
but I did get about 20 names
by hitting all the mom-and-pop
stores in the county.
Mancell's name on that list?
Why don't you read it and find out.
Branch got a match on the
paint and a list of buyers.
Mancell's not on that list,
but that doesn't mean he
didn't already have the paint.
We need to cross-check
the buyers' names
with the list of everyone else
that failed Ethan's drug tests.
We should probably cross-check
with the employees of
Newett Energy, as well.
Walt: You do that.
Meantime, I need to
talk to Dolan Lone Elk.
He may be a little more forthcoming
now he's the FBI's number-one suspect.
Dolan's in FBI custody.
How are you gonna talk to him?
Ask nicely.
- Where did everybody go?
- Everybody went home.
Nobody left to supervise their training.
After Walt questioned her,
Lauryn Lone Elk quit.
On the bright side,
the man is suffering the worst
political week of his term.
The two biggest job creators
in the area are reeling,
half the county thinks
walt's coddling the natives,
other half thinks he's
in Newett Energy's pocket.
With all due respect to Ethan Lone Elk,
he couldn't have picked
a better time to die.
Yeah, well, I still have a job to do.
- I can't keep my hands clean forever.
- No, you certainly can't,
especially if you actually
want to win this thing.
Even with all of Walt's
sudden political radioactivity,
the election's gonna be close.
There's got to be a better way
to tip this thing in my favor.
You know what would help?
Dirt on Walt or his family.
If you've got any
juicy Longmire secrets,
now would the time to spill them.
This is a closed crime scene, Sheriff.
- I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
- Dolan's still in your custody?
Mr. Lone Elk is
answering some questions.
- I have a few of my own I'd
like to ask him.  - Such as?
I'd like to ask him about
some folks on this list ...
people his brother
denied casino jobs to.
See if he knows of anyone
making threats against Ethan.
So, you want to ask the murder suspect
if he thinks you should
pin this on someone else?
I'll tell you what. Why don't
you just let me have that list.
I'd be happy to ask Dolan myself.
No, I'll hold onto this.
If I can't talk to Dolan,
I'll just run these names
by some of the neighbors.
- Did you get kicked out?
- Yeah. What are you doing here?
Following up on Mancell Lone Elk.
I searched his house ... no red paint.
So, now I'm hoping to talk
to Dolan about his father.
Hope you have more luck than I did.
Who lives over there?
That's Grady Littlefoot
and his brothers.
Here we go.
You here to punish us
for exercising our right to free speech?
It's a free country.
I hear there's another
protest at a fracking rig
going on right now.
Why aren't you there?
You have a change of heart?
Can't protest every dumb
thing the white man does.
We wouldn't have time for
our better home and gardening.
[ chuckles ]
You looking to sell?
We were. Then the gas started
leaking out of the faucets.
Then the neighbor's house blows up.
Right now, we could turn this place
into the Taj Mahal and
nobody would buy it.
That's a tough break,
especially since you all just
got turned down for a job.
Names are right here
on this list of folks
that didn't pass the casino drug test.
Must have gotten under your skin.
Yeah, we don't snort coke
or do meth.
- But you did fail the drug test.
- Yeah, for peyote ... that's no drug.
- That's our heritage.
- So, Ethan Lone Elk
wouldn't cut you any slack for
observing sacred religious rituals?
Ethan was a self-righteous prick.
He came back here after 20 years,
started driving his whitman's car,
waving his white man's diploma,
showing off his black man's wife.
It was like suddenly, he
thought he was someone.
He'd pull up over to Dolan's place,
and we'd call him over,
invite him to a drink,
and he would just stand
there like he was afraid.
So you weren't too heartbroken
about what happened to Ethan.
Eh, he deserved what happened.
White man's company blows up
the whitest indian I ever seen.
What do you call that?
Poetic justice.
I'd call that something else.
See, Ethan was dead
before that house ignited,
and his body was covered in paint.
Tuscan red ... it matches
the stripes on your car.
What, are you trying to
accuse us of something?
I'm still working on it.
[ grunts ]
Here's what I got so far.
I think you asked
Ethan over for a drink.
But this time, you didn't
take "no" for an answer.
I think you grabbed Ethan
and dragged him over here,
held him down, and forced
booze down his throat
and painted him Tuscan
red just so he'd remember
no matter how many diplomas he had,
Ethan would always be
a red-skinned drunk.
After you forced him to
drink himself to death,
you took him to his brother's house.
You opened the taps,
closed the doors,
and blew the place to bits
to cover up what you'd done ...
all because Ethan had
made himself into somebody.
And you...
...were still just you.
[ gun cocks ]
Unless you want to see if
your blood is Tuscan red,
I'd think twice about that.
[ dog barking in distance ]
You know, I heard that
information I gave you
about the shade of house
paint actually came in handy.
Sorry, I forgot to
bring you your trophy.
Should I step out so you
can measure the blinds?
- So, Walt, how's Cady?
- Cady's fine.
That's funny, 'cause...
I don't think she is.
I think she's feeling lost and alone.
And I think deep down, she's angry
because she put her entire life on
hold for you when you needed her.
And now that the tables have
turned and she needs you,
you're too busy being
Sheriff to even notice.
Not only do you think you'd
be a better Sheriff than me,
you think you can walk in here
and tell me how to be a father?
Walt, I know what happened in Denver.
No, you don't.
If this was just about you and me, you'd
be reading it in the
paper tomorrow morning.
But this isn't just about you and me.
So, word of your wife's murder
won't leave this room.
I can promise you that.
But I think you should
consider the idea that right now...
your daughter might need you
more than the county does.
[ music ]
[ door closes ]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~