Previously on Longmire.
Ed Gorski is stalking me.
Broke into my car.
My house.
There's no greater enemy,
than the mortal enemy of a friend.
I lifted a fingerprint of the car.
Cady was driving.
I did find an interesting detail.
You've found that David
works for me.
Would you mind telling me why
you were in Denver?
He's expecting to speak with me,
the slightest contradiction in our stories
and he will notice.
Ma'am.
Cady: [ Chuckles ] [
Telephone rings ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Telephone beeps ]
Longmire residence.
Ferg: Cady?
Morning, Ferg. What's up?
I didn't expect you
to be there.
Uh, how are you...
how are you going?
A-are you feeling any better?
I am. Thanks.
Is the Sheriff around?
Yeah.
Dad! It's Ferg!
Hold on.
We got a call because a guy
was beaten up
pretty badly last night,
and, um...
Walt, there's something
a little...
[Sighs] I don't know...
delicate about this situation.
What is it?
Well, I guess this guy's been
staying here for a while.
And he's from Philadelphia.
So...
I was looking at his phone...
Ferg, spit it out.
He called the same number
30 times in the last few days.
That number...
Is Vic's.
I'm sure you know that...
Vic's marriage
is a little... rocky.
Don't jump
to conclusions, Ferg.
Well, I'm not, but I-if this is
what it looks like
and Vic is having an affair...
you know, her husband found out,
beats this guy up...
I mean, she could be
in some real trouble.
Walt: What's the Victim's name?
Ed Gorski.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.Addic7ed.com
[ breathing heavily ]
Ed: Hey... Sheriff.
Come to finish the job?
What did you get yourself
into here, Ed?
[ Chuckles ]
You tell me, Sheriff.
Well, it says here you got
a busted rib, missing tooth,
and you took a pretty good blow
to the back of your head.
You get a good look
at your attacker, Ed?
No, I didn't.
You made sure of that
when you snuck up behind me
and hit me in the head.
I didn't do this, Ed.
Even though a few days ago,
you said you would do
exactly this
if I didn't leave your county?
Doesn't matter
what I said or didn't say.
I didn't do it.
How long you been
sleeping with Vic?
[ Scoffs ]
I'd think by now you'd learn
to watch what you say.
No. Now I got nothing to lose.
The people of your county are
gonna be surprised to discover
that their Sheriff goes around
beating up strangers.
Well, I think
the pain medication
is clouding your mind, Ed.
[ Door opens ] Vic: [ Sighs ]
You wanted to see me?
Ed Gorski was, um...
Beaten to within an inch
of his life last night.
I can't say
I'm sorry to hear that.
Ruby: Got Sergeant Haynes,
Highway Patrol.
What's that all about?
Vic, um...
I need to know
the precise nature
of your relationship with Ed.
Was he just an angry ex-cop
who lost a partner,
or is there...
More to this situation?
How is that
any concern of yours?
Because I am involved in this.
No. This is my problem.
And I will handle it.
Yeah.
Um...
I kind of made it my problem.
A couple of nights ago,
I went to see Ed,
and I told him to leave town.
One could characterize
what I said as a threat.
Now that the man's
been beaten up,
Ed thinks it was me.
I never asked you to do that.
I know. I know.
Now, I need to know that
this man was threatening you
and not that you two
had some kind of...
romantic relationship.
[ Clears throat ]
There was...
Kind of, sort of something
between Ed and I years ago
before I was even married.
"Kind of, sort of something"?
It lasted a few months,
but he was married,
so... I ended it.
And then I met Sean.
Look, Walt, I-I promise
I never meant for you
to get roped up in this.
[ Sighs ]
Just let me go talk to Ed.
I think I can get him
to drop the charges.
How?
Just trust me.
[ Knock on door ]
Walt...
Mathias is on the phone,
and... surprise, surprise...
he's not happy.
[ Police radio chatter ]
He didn't want me
to call his daddy.
Why is my Deputy in the back
of your vehicle, Mathias?
Neighbor called in
some suspicious activity.
Saw Deputy Connally driving
around the neighborhood,
peeking in windows.
It's a bit over the top
to cuff him.
Well, he didn't have permission
to operate on the res.
Oh.
And he just started
using these on the back door
when I pulled up.
May I have a few words
with my Deputy... alone?
You can have him,
but not his car.
I towed it.
[ Sighs ]
[ Keys jingle ]
[ Handcuffs click ] He can
retrieve it from impound later
after he pays the fine.
You know Mathias
could've locked you up.
What were you doing on the res
without his permission?
Come on, Walt.
You sneak around
behind his back all the time.
That's true.
I always feel bad about it.
And I always have
a good reason.
What's your reason?
The house I was looking into
belongs to a guy
named David Ridges.
I'm pretty sure he was involved
in causing Cady's car accident.
I found proof that someone
intentionally caused
that flat tire
that she was fixing.
I also found David's
fingerprints on the car.
[ Engine revs ]
[ Insects buzzing ]
[ Breathes deeply ]
Battery's dead.
What the hell happened in here?
Maybe this will tell us.
If I die, I will not travel
the road to the star nation.
I only know one way
to set things right.
I'm going back in time
to be the man I was.
I need to leave
this body behind
and save me from myself.
I'm going to take with me
everything that is bad
and return with
the true strength and honor
of The Crazy Dogs.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Thud ]
[ Sighs ]
That's quite a suicide note.
Yeah.
But what happened to the body?
Should we call Mathias?
Get him involved.
Walt: And say what?
That we snuck back
onto the res,
illegally broke into a house?
With probable cause.
We discovered a suicide,
but we don't have a body.
Also, there's no drag marks
or any sign of blood
on the floor.
I don't know much about
native American spirituality,
but is that time-travel stuff
normal,
or a sign that
the guy's a little nuts?
Yep.
I mean,
where in the hell is he?
He didn't just [Scoffs]
disappear, did he?
That's a good question, Branch.
And who is he? [ Sighs ]
Why was he trying
to hurt my daughter?
I've never seen this guy
in my life.
Yes, you have.
I think I'd remember it.
Apparently...
He was pouring drinks for you
the night before the election.
I found this at Cady's house.
This don't make any sense.
There's one more detail
about this guy
that might factor in.
David Ridges worked
for Jacob Nighthorse.
I think Nighthorse had David...
Sabotage Cady's car to...
Keep your voters
away from the polls.
Last week, I confronted
Nighthorse about it.
And Nighthorse denied it.
Pretty much.
[ Sighs ]
You think Nighthorse told Ridges
that you were onto him,
Ridges killed himself?
It occurred to me.
It also occurred to me that...
Nighthorse knew I was onto him,
and he killed Ridges,
and did a pretty convincing job
of making it
look like a suicide.
[ Woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A. System ]
No flowers?
I thought at least a balloon.
Cut the shit, Ed.
Language, Vicky.
I might have to wash
your mouth out with soap.
Is that how you talk to
your Sheriff boyfriend?
He had nothing to do with this.
He seems a little old
for you, Vic.
What's that about?
Daddy issues?
What do you want from me, Ed?
I want you to feel
the consequence of your actions.
Isn't it enough
that I had to leave town...
Leave my family...
The only home
that I have ever known?
[ Sighs ]
You don't think that
I felt those consequences?
No, I don't.
[ Scoffs ] I think you
had a change of scenery.
You haven't really felt
what I've felt.
You haven't had
your whole life unravel.
You've been out
in big sky country
with your chicken-shit husband
without a thought in the world
for the lives you've ruined.
[ Grunts ]
You want me to feel bad?
I feel bad.
[ Grunts ]
I want you
to feel what it's like
to have everything
you care about taken away.
I want you to hurt, Vic.
[ Sighs ]
[ Sniffles ]
I can arrange that.
David: I'm going to take with
me everything that is bad
and return with
the true strength and honor
of The Crazy Dogs.
[ Sighs ]
It all makes sense to me.
He's calling on The Crazy Dogs,
what the blackfoot call
their dog soldiers.
[ Sighs ]
Again with the dog soldiers.
Show me what else you found
in his house.
Yeah.
This is negative medicine.
It is used by someone
who is on the dark side.
It represents lost spirits
that are desperately looking
to find their way
back to the light.
I hope he finds the light after
what he did to my goddaughter.
He needs to go back.
So [Clears throat]
You believe
he actually time-traveled?
A lot of my people
have a different idea
about the nature of time
than you.
Perhaps he will return
in a few months or years.
You can ask him then.
I don't have years.
I need to know how this man
is connected to Cady's accident.
Well, if I were you,
I would proceed with caution.
All this... Bad medicine,
whether you believe in it
or not,
tends to attract
some dangerous types.
Like Nighthorse.
What does Jacob Nighthorse
have to do with this?
I'm not sure.
I think we should go have
a chat with him and find out.
[ Sighs ]
Hey, Walt,
I need to talk to you.
I can go alone.
Okay, sure.
But don't go in hot.
Cool as a cucumber.
So... [ Keys jingle ]
What's up?
Ed Gorski's gonna
fill out a crime report,
but he won't be naming you.
[ Sighs ]
So, who's Ed naming
as his assailant?
Me.
'Cause I did it.
I didn't want your life
getting tangled up in this mess,
so I decided,
before he came after me,
I was gonna go after him.
You beat him up?
Show me your hands.
[ Sighs ]
Based on the way Ed looked,
I'd expect to see
a cut or a bruise or...
I didn't use my hands.
I used a baseball bat.
You didn't hire Hector?
No.
And Ed's gonna
fill out a crime report
based on what I told him,
so I just thought
you should know.
And I should probably, uh...
Put myself on suspension
until the dust settles.
Vic, if he files that report,
you're not gonna be able
to work here...
anywhere, really.
I guess I should have
thought of that before.
Branch: Got a few more questions
about David Ridges.
Why? David is dead.
How do you know that?
Because I found the body.
When?
Two days ago.
I was worried about him.
He started talking about...
Killing himself.
Though he never put it
quite like that.
He talk about
going back in time?
Yes, that's exactly
how he put it.
How did you know about
the time-travel thing?
Did you talk to David
about the flat tire?
No, I didn't. Hmm.
You were the only one
I talked to about that.
Then I guess he'd heard about
your suspicions through me.
I don't think
I'd be betraying him now
by telling you that your
suspicions were well-founded.
Did he tell you
something about it?
He told me everything about it.
He thought that by disabling
that car Cady Longmire
was driving,
he'd be helping me...
and, of course, you.
He never meant
for anybody to get hurt.
So, he confessed to you
and then killed himself.
If all that's true,
then where's the body?
Hopefully with his ancestors.
I'm gonna need you
to be a little more specific.
A little less spiritual,
you mean?
I burned it...
As per David's wishes.
Show me where.
Hello, lawman.
How'd you find me?
Hector, I've got friends
in the Cheyenne nation.
You're not supposed to be
on the res.
off it.
I go where the wind tells me.
Justice has no borders.
But you should know
an injustice is about to occur.
Must be Tuesday.
Someone's about to go to jail
for what you did to Ed Gorski.
Who is Ed Gorski?
The white guy from the motel.
He's laid up in a hospital now
with a missing tooth.
Kind of your calling card,
if I remember correctly.
If you don't come back
to the station with me,
someone else is gonna
confess to that beating.
If she does,
she'll likely lose her job.
She should not confess
if she did not do it.
I know that.
But she's going to.
Now, an assault charge for you
might mean a little jail time
or a fine.
It's not gonna ruin your life
or end your career.
Some might say it'd
enhance your reputation.
I do not care
about my reputation.
But you do care
about right and wrong.
[ Police radio chatter ]
[ Knock on door ]
Longmire residence?
Cady: Yeah.
Excuse me.
Sorry, you can't just
come in here like this.
Detective Fales,
what is going on here?
Is your father at home?
No.
What is this?
It's a search warrant.
For what?
Honestly, I don't really know.
We're serving it on behalf
of another police department.
You think my dad
had something to do with
killing that meth head
in Denver?
What'd you do, standing bear?
Nothing.
Fales: If you really think
about your father
and how much
he loved your mother,
is it really so hard to believe
he would want to kill the man
that took her away?
So when I came to Denver,
you were already
investigating my dad?
You weren't helping me.
You were just digging
for information.
Mathias: I'm gonna need you
to close down.
Fales:
You almost done in there?
Almost.
Don't touch that.
Don't! You can take
anything you want, okay?
It doesn't matter because
my dad is not a killer,
but you cannot take this!
Open it.
Go to hell.
Cady, I have a warrant.
Now open it.
[ Crying ]
She can... she can
keep the tea box.
[ Police radio chatter ]
Officer: Don't forget
the cabinets over there.
Ruby: Those are
very important documents.
I'm gonna need those.
Hey, who are you?
What's going on?
They showed up an hour ago
with a search warrant.
Why didn't you call me?
He wouldn't let me
use the radio.
Who?
Fales: Hello, Sheriff.
Who's your friend?
Ferg.
Lock him up.
Officer: See this one?
Officer ♪2: Yeah, I saw that.
There should be
a file cabinet over here.
You mind telling me
what's going on in here?
I found a witness connecting you
to the Miller Beck case.
Who's Miller Beck?
The man who stabbed your wife.
Never knew his name.
Not even when you attacked him
in a meth house
in Denver last year?
You're tearing up my office
on the word of a drug dealer?
Oh, no, no, no.
He told
a very compelling story.
This witness remembers being
approached by a big cowboy
that had all kinds of questions
about Miller.
The witness told the cowboy
that Miller
had showed up recently
with $700 in cash
he had taken off some lady
in a purse-snatching.
The cowboy asked him
to describe the purse.
Then, he paid the witness
a few bucks and went on his way.
Cowboy in Denver...
what are the odds?
Well, a few hours later,
that same cowboy
busted into their house
with a gun.
He attacked Miller,
but Miller's friends
were all cranked up on meth,
and they kicked his ass.
When I showed the witness
some photos,
he identified the cowboy...
as you.
That's quite a story...
And one decidedly
lacking in evidence.
Why do you think
I'm serving search warrants?
Jacob: I brought David's body
out here to honor him.
And because a man tortured
by as much dark medicine
as David Ridges
needed all the spiritual help
he could get.
I wanted to set him
on the right path
into the next world.
You didn't think to call us?
Or Mathias?
Why?
No crime was committed.
Troubled young man
took his own life.
He has no family.
No one wished him ill.
Except you, I guess.
I did not wish him ill.
I was just trying to find out
what his fingerprints were doing
all around the flat tire that
almost killed Cady Longmire.
Obviously, I'll need
more than your word
to confirm that this is him.
It was him.
Then you don't mind
if I take a sample for DNA.
No. You will not.
This might not
look like much to you,
but it's sacred ground.
David is with
The Crazy Dogs now,
and you will let him be.
I need to do my job.
You set foot
on this land again...
The force of the Cheyenne nation
will come down upon you
for disturbing a holy place.
Henry?
Fales is here
searching my office.
I just wanted to warn you.
Too late.
[ Police radio chatter ]
They are here.
They gonna find anything?
Nothing I cannot explain.
So, what are you going to do?
At the moment,
there's not much I can do.
Fales has pretty much
taken over the office.
Couldn't come at a worse time.
I got, uh, someone in custody
who doesn't need
the extra scrutiny right now.
Who?
Hector.
[ Sighs ]
Walt, I told you
about Vic hiring Hector
so that if there was a beating,
you would not arrest him.
After all, he was doing
something for your friend.
Things have gotten
more complicated.
[ Police radio chatter ]
You have no idea.
[ Door opens ]
[ Sighs ] Hey.
[ Chuckling ] Hey.
[ Kettle whistling ]
What are you doing here?
Get used to it.
Yeah? What... what's that
supposed to mean?
It means that I might be
out of a job soon.
What?
[ Clears throat ]
There's, uh...
[Sighs]
Some stuff that's been going on
that I haven't told you about.
Uh-oh. That doesn't sound good.
It's not great. [ Scoffs ]
Do you, um...
do you remember those flowers?
Somebody from Philly
showed up here in durant,
and he's been...
[Sighs] Threatening me.
[ Groans ]
This Bobby donolato thing.
When are they gonna
let this go?
You didn't do anything wrong.
Cops aren't supposed to
rat on other cops.
You know that.
You did the right thing.
They were breaking the law.
Why didn't you tell me
this was going on?
[ Sighs ]
Because I don't
want to worry you.
It wasn't Gorski, was it?
[ Sighs ]
Well, now I know why
you didn't want to say anything.
Where is he?
I'm gonna kick his ass.
Somebody already has.
That's why I might be
out of job.
[ Cellphone ringing ]
Well, answer it.
Maybe it's another ex-boyfriend
looking to get back in the game.
Sean.
Fales: You going somewhere?
You got your job to do.
I still got mine.
I have to move this prisoner.
Well, can't you find
someone else to do that?
I may still have
a few questions to ask you.
Ferg, let me borrow
your cellphone.
Uh, okay.
You got any questions,
you can give me a call.
Hector:
Where are you taking me?
There's too much activity
in my station.
I'm friends with the Sheriff
in Cumberland County.
I think he'll take you in.
You mean jail.
For a little bit.
You in some type
of trouble, lawman?
I don't know, Hector.
Maybe.
Then why don't you
just keep driving?
I can't.
[ Horse whinnies ]
What are you doing out here?
Looking for you.
Ruby said you two were on
your way to Cumberland County.
And the horse?
It is for Hector.
You are going to put him on it
and tell him to disappear.
Told you before, Henry...
I can't just let him go.
You can, and you will,
because you owe him.
I owe him?
Never done anything for me.
[ Sighs ]
Actually, that is not
entirely accurate.
He killed a man for you.
When I saw what happened to you
in Denver last year...
I realized that there were
only two ways
the situation
was going to end...
with you dead
or with you in jail.
Neither of those two
seemed right to me.
So, while you were recovering,
I took the photograph
and address out of your pocket,
and I went back to Denver.
[ Gasps ]
It is time to get
your spiritual affairs in order.
What's going on here?
Who are you?
I am the judge and the jury,
and I am here
to pronounce your sentence.
Are you ready to hear it?
Get out of my way.
[ Grunts ]
Death... within the next
24 hours, you will die.
Do you know why?
Because you are a murderer,
and you do not deserve to live.
Think about that
in the hours you have left.
Walt: So, what does any of this
have to do with Hector?
I did what my people often do
when your justice system fails.
I called in Hector.
You pronounced his sentence,
and Hector went there
and killed him?
Yes. Hector: No.
I told you before, lawman...
I'm not a killer.
Hector, you told me
that you did it.
You told me that man
hurt the lawman's wife,
so I hurt him.
But I'm not a killer.
Hector, someone broke his neck
and buried him
in a shallow grave.
I believe you.
But it wasn't me.
I beat him like
I've never beaten anyone,
and I gave you his teeth,
but I didn't kill him.
If I did, he would have
stopped feeling pain.
Death is release.
Pain is forever.
[ Sighs ]
I assumed that you killed him.
I think choosing
who lives and dies
is up to the great spirit,
not me.
I'm just a man.
[ Sighs ]
So, what are you
going to do now?
Well, if he had killed that guy,
I'd probably release him.
But now, 'cause of
this Ed Gorski thing,
I don't think I can.
Ironic... Hector was
the only one of us
who did not have murder
in his heart.
So, if it wasn't you,
and it wasn't him...
who killed that meth head?
Where'd you move Ed Gorski?
He called me to come down.
Excuse me? Ed Gorski.
I was just in his room.
He's not there.
[ Sighs ] He checked
himself out an hour ago.
Shit.
Are you Deputy Moretti? Yeah.
Mr. Gorski left this for you.
[ Woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A. System ]
[ Crying ]
I'm sorry, dad.
What for?
[ Sniffles ]
I didn't know
that when I went to Denver
I was helping Detective Fales.
He tricked me,
and I should have known better.
It's okay, pumpkin.
You didn't do anything wrong.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Sighs ]
But I did.
After your mother died...
dad...
Did you kill him?
No.
But I wanted to.
And I tried to.
Did Henry?
No.
So, what does Fales have
that makes him think you did?
A witness.
Someone I talked to last year.
A friend of the murderer.
He told me that...
The guy was bragging
about mugging your mom.
He even described
your mom's purse,
the one you picked out for her
when you were 9.
Remember that purse?
Of course.
Well, I went
to the guy's house,
and...
That purse
was in the garbage can.
I still can't believe mom died
for what she had in her purse.
I mean, mom, of all people.
You know, she always taught me,
"you put $50 in your purse
and the rest..."
"The rest in your boot."
"...ln your boot."
[ Laughs ]
Fales told me
the guy that killed your mom
got $700 out of her purse.
Walt I'm patching in Vic for you.
Walt: Vic, what's up?
I wanted to let you know
that, uh, Ed Gorski left town.
He's not gonna
press any charges.
That's good news.
So, Ferg told me
that you arrested Hector.
You know, you didn't
have to do that.
You can't protect
everybody, Walt.
Well, it's sort of
my job to try.
[ Chuckles ]
So, anyway, I guess I can
come back to work now?
You want me to drive over
to Cumberland County,
get Hector released?
No, I'll take care of that.
You've already had
one heck of a week.
Why don't you take, uh,
a vacation day?
Really?
A vacation day.
Paid?
Don't make me
rethink the offer.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
[ Sighs ]
How'd it go with Nighthorse?
He said he found David Ridge's
body and burned it.
You believe him?
I'm heading out
to the burial site now
to see if I can get
a DNA sample.
You want to come?
Where is it?
It's on the res,
right on the other side
of the powder river.
Might be better
than going in there.
I can't.
I have to go in.
I got called in
to my own office.
Fales: I was beginning to worry
you weren't coming,
thought maybe
you were going to flee.
Are you here to arrest me?
[ Laughs ]
I'm still thinking about it.
Been wondering something
about you, Detective.
[ Door closes ]
Fales: What's that?
Why are you working so hard
to find Miller Beck's killer...
When your department
could hardly be bothered
to find my wife's killer?
Town I grew up in
was a small town,
like this one.
And our Sheriff
was a lot like you.
You don't know what I'm like.
I do.
You wear the hat and the badge.
Far as you're concerned,
you're the most important person
for miles around.
And you think you can do
whatever you want
without anyone checking on you.
You know, I saw Sheriffs
in the South
who literally
got away with murder.
And I saw that corruption
trickle down to the deputies.
I grew up around
too many badges
who'd arrest a man
they didn't like,
beat a man who
didn't respect them,
kill a man who hurt them.
I got my badge
for a different purpose.
I want to protect people
from guys like you.
So this is about you
settling some old beef,
with me standing in
for some some corrupt Sheriff
from where you grew up?
I have motive
and plenty of evidence.
What would you do?
Not ignore the one detail
about this case
that doesn't make any sense.
And what's that?
My wife's purse.
My wife...
Never carried more
than $50 in her purse.
Your witness said Miller Beck
took $700 off her.
If he didn't get
that $700 from my wife,
where did he get it?
From another purse?
No. I think someone paid
Miller Beck to stab my wife.
And I think
the same person killed him
to shut him up after
I started asking questions.
Who do you think would have
wanted your wife dead?
Someone that didn't like her,
or someone that didn't like me.
I got a few ideas.
That's a very good theory,
Walt,
but I'd rather stick
with my evidence.
We turned up this medicine bag
in your friend Henry's office.
Mathias said his people
often keep special items
in those bags.
I know what a medicine bag is.
Do you know
what was in Henry's?
Teeth.
And they match Miller Beck's
dental records.
I've got the dead man's teeth
from your friend's office
and proof that he was
in Denver last year.
You may be innocent,
but your friend Henry is not.
You arrested Henry?
The tribal police did.
Then I'll have him
extradited to Denver.
But don't you worry.
I'll make sure he gets
his one phone call.
[ Shelf clatters ]
Damn!
Aaah!
[ Telephone ringing ]
Henry, is that you?
Branch: Walt.
Help me, Walt.
[ Engine revving ]
Who shot you?
Who shot you, Branch?
A dead man.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.Addic7ed.com