[ Bell jingles ]
[ Voice breaking ]
Please help me! They're coming!
O-okay. Calm down, miss.
Tell me what's wrong.
[ Sobs ]
They're...
they're gonna find me.
I-I know
because they're following me!
Uh, uh...
[ Cries ]
Who's "they"?
Do you have a gun?
Um...
Uh, I-I'm gonna
get you some hp.
[ Dialing ]
[ Sobs ]
Hi.
This is Ellis Hinkley
out in cedar pass.
I've got a distraught young lady
in my station.
I'm gonna need Walt
or a deputy to come by.
[ Sobs ]
Oh, how much is the milk?
[ Tires screech ]
[ Bell jingles ]
[ Paper tears ]
Ellis?
Anybody here?
[ Gun cocks ]
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Oh, no.
Sync and correcting by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
[ police radio chatter ]
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
[ Car door closes ]
[ Sobbing ]
I'm so sorry.
Is he over there
behind those tires?
Ruby.
[ Sobbing ]
Ruby, Ruby. I-I had no
idea he was in danger.
Ruby...
Take a breath.
You're the closest thing we have
to an eyewitness.
Just tell me as best
as you can what you remember.
Ellis said there was
a distraught young lady,
and he asked me
to send you out.
Nothing else?
Well... I might have
heard her talk once.
She asked him
the price of milk.
Poor Ellis.
Now, why don't you head on back?
Ellis was a good man.
I'm sorry, Walt.
You have nothing
to be sorry for, okay?
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
[ Bell jingles ]
I swabbed some blood
for the kit.
I figure
that it's the girl's.
If it was Ellis',
prints would have led
right up to his body
whoever it is,
they weren't wearing shoes.
Those smudges
are from bare feet, so...
[ Sighs ]
[ Bell jingles ]
Didn't find any casings
near Ellis.
Somebody knew
to pick them up.
We got 10s, 20s, 5s,
even some 50s.
So much
for the robbery motive.
Unless it was botched.
Maybe someone came along
in the midst of a hold-up,
robbers took off.
If someone
interrupted a robbery,
don't you think
they'd have called it in?
People don't like
to get involved.
Vic:
Is that a camera?
This girl
is crazy town.
I can take a screen grab
of that woman
and get it
on the local news.
That's our best shot
at I.D'ing her quickly.
What did she just see?
So, Ellis
wrote something down.
He took the sheet
of paper with him.
Wasn't on his body.
So, the killer
takes the casings and a note?
The pad is still here.
17-78. What is that,
a phone number?
No.
It's part
of a license-plate number.
17...
that's Cumberland county.
Wyoming plates all start
with a number
that identifies the county.
No shit.
Ellis must have seen
a car drive up.
Something
must have concerned him.
Find out how many plates
in Cumberland county
start with 17-78.
Jealous boyfriend
or husband?
Ellis gets all chivalrous,
tries to intervene
in a domestic dispute.
Or it could be related
to that thing in South Dakota.
What thing? Oh, right. You
don't read the paper.
There's been a string
of gas-station robberies
by a young couple... kind of
a Bonnie-and-Clyde thing.
Call your contacts at the
South Dakota state police.
See what kind of car
this couple is driving.
Meantime, let's try
and find this girl
from the video right now.
She's the only lead
we got.
You alright?
Looks like you're
trying to hang yourself.
Jimmy's microphone
keeps cutting out
during the middle
of his songs.
I need to find
a different cable.
Take your time.
Crowd's never seemed happier.
[ Chuckles ]
When's the last time
you played, Walt?
[ Sighs ]
Last time I felt like it.
Besides, I've got
other priorities now, so...
Such as?
When's the last time
you tracked someone?
[ Sighs ]
Who would I be tracking
this time?
Possible murder suspect.
Young woman, early 20s.
She's the last person
to enter Ellis Hinkley's
service station
in cedar pass
before he was shot dead.
What do you know?
I think she left in a car.
Arrived by foot.
I'd like to know
where she came from.
She's unstable,
maybe armed.
I'll send a deputy
along with you.
I work alone.
Not this time.
Walt,
how does this sound?
"Ellis Hinkley,
beloved local businessman
"and good samaritan,
passed away before his time
of wounds suffered at the hands
of an unknown assailant."
You writing the police blotter
for the paper?
I'm trying
to write Ellis' obituary.
Usually, that job
falls to the family.
I know,
but he didn't have any.
That's a good start,
Ruby.
I'll start over.
[ Door opens, closes ]
Can I help you folks
with something?
Sheriff Longmire.
Hi. My name is Johnson Mace.
This is my wife, Maureen.
Pleased to meet you.
Our daughter, Evelyn,
disappeared
21/2 years ago.
We thought
that she was dead.
But apparently, you have
evidence that she's alive.
Evelyn disappeared
over two years ago.
The police couldn't find
any sign of her.
We put up a reward.
We even hired a private
investigator to find her.
Nothing... Until now.
You're from Portland,
right?
Yeah.
Then how did you see her picture
on the local news?
Our friends did.
They live in Jackson Hole.
They called, said they saw
a picture of Evelyn on TV,
so I booked a jet
immediately.
So, please tell us,
what do you know?
I want to be honest
with you.
Evelyn's a person of interest
in a homicide case.
What?
Does Evelyn have a history
of mental illness or drug use?
No. She was just
a normal girl.
Has she ever
been arrested?
Yes, once.
Shoplifting.
But that was
wiped from her record.
Johnson: There was also
a check-forging charge.
She was on bail,
awaiting a trial,
when she disappeared.
Our daughter is...
was aimless.
She was just trying
to find herself.
But she would never,
ever harm another person.
Did she
have a boyfriend?
Teddy brown.
We didn't approve of him.
But it's impossible
that she ran off with him.
Why's that? He still
lives in Portland.
We see him
from time to time.
Usually
coming out of a bar.
Ferg: I mean,
I went on outward bound.
You know,
I'm a little rusty.
But I learned survival skills,
rock climbing, orienteering.
Ferg, you realize that
tracking's a solitary journey?
Oh, sorry. Oh.
Yeah,
my pod leader...
he said it was a conversation
between man and nature.
A conversation
that you are interrupting.
This is a toe print pointing
right toward the front door.
The girl came
from that direction.
No one else
has come forward
with information
about this woman.
How about a cash reward?
The Maces could afford it.
That's asking the parents
to put up a bounty
on their own daughter.
They want to find her.
They may not
want to send her to prison.
Vic: I have been on the phone
with the D.M.V. All morning.
It's my favorite branch of the
state government. Any luck?
Out of the four license plates
that start with 17-78,
only one could have possibly been
in Ellis' gas station yesterday.
It's a late-model Chrysler
leased to Newett
Energy & Exploration, LLC.
Isn't that
your husband's company?
It is, and he got us a sit-down
with the supervisor.
Pulling some strings.
Nice work, Vic.
Got to watch out
for you.
Tell your husband
thanks from me.
Actually,
I don't think I will.
I had to promise that you wouldn't
be involved so he'd agree to help.
Walt: We're interested
in a vehicle
connected to your company.
We know a vehicle with the
beginnings of that plate number
was near the scene of a homicide.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Did you say the beginnings
of the plate number?
We're gonna need a list
of everyone who's driven
that car in the last three days.
Uh,
pardon me for asking,
but, uh, aren't you the sheriff
of Absaroka county?
That's right.
Since we happen to be standing
here in Cumberland county,
shouldn't sheriff Wilkins
be the one asking the questions?
I'd feel a lot better
if he were here.
This is a very simple request,
Mr. Vaughn.
I'm afraid our company
privacy policy's
also very simple,
sheriff Longmire.
Any requests for personal
information on employees
requires a subpoena.
Mr. Vaughn, do you happen
to know Randy Cahill?
I can't say I know him.
Wait, isn't he the editor
of the Durant Courant?
That's him.
Hmm.
He's always bugging me
for scoops.
I bet he'd be interested to know
that your company
is stonewalling
a homicide investigation.
Huh.
So, Mr. Vaughn here
has to decide
whose privacy
is more important...
that of a single employee
or the huge corporation
that pays his salary.
I'll take a look at those
numbers one more time.
I used to do some work
down in South America.
I thought I'd left behind
the corruption
and the blackmailing
from the local police force.
The vehicle with those plates
is... it's a company car.
It's used by Leland Townes.
He's not really an employee,
technically.
So,
who is Leland Townes?
He owns this property.
We lease his mineral rights
so we can drill here.
Henry, look at this.
Ferg, we are not
collecting rocks.
No, this is herderite.
Okay.
Herderite doesn't occur
naturally in Wyoming.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Most herderite
comes from Brazil or Africa.
I collect minerals.
[ Chuckles ]
You're full of surprises.
Why do you think
it's here?
It is a bread crumb.
Leland:
I inherited the place
about five years ago
from my dad,
but I'm a terrible rancher.
The land went to hay
a few years later,
so I decided to
lease some of it to Newett.
And they promised
that they'd clean it up
after they were done drilling.
It sure is nice
to get a paycheck every month.
We got your name
and address from Newett.
They apparently lease a car
for you. Is that right?
Yeah,
and it's a nice one, too.
Anyone besides you
use that car?
No.
Do you recognize this guy?
Yeah.
From... Somewhere.
I...
Oh, wait.
He's the,
uh... the cashier
at the gas station
at state road 27.
You, uh, been
to that station recently?
Oh,
I know what this is about.
This is about the crazy woman,
isn't it?
Crazy woman?
Yeah.
I mean, I pulled in there
yesterday to get some gas,
and this young lady...
homeless, I guess...
she nearly
jumped on my hood,
and she started screaming
about "they" coming to get her.
Is this her?
Yeah, that's her.
She seemed unhinged.
She kind of scared me,
so I just... I drove off.
Didn't want to get involved,
if you know what I mean.
The station owner
was shot.
Oh, no.
Is he gonna make it?
No.
[ Dog barking in distance ]
I feel awful.
I should have called 911.
Do you remember seeing any
other people at that station...
any other vehicles?
Yeah, actually.
There was a black S.U.V.
Pulled in,
and, um,
I don't know the make.
They all
look the same to me.
Did you see anyone get out of it?
No.
But, uh, the license plate
had an evergreen tree
in the middle
between the numbers.
Oregon plates.
Evelyn's boyfriend,
Teddy Brown...
find out what kind
of vehicle he drives.
The D.M.V. Again.
What am I,
being punished for something?
Character building.
[ Laughs ]
[ Telephone rings ]
Library's
down the street, Jim.
I can't
take anything out there.
I'm not a resident
of Absaroka.
And you're not the sheriff
of Cumberland county.
You upset
about something, Jim?
I got a nasty phone call from
the C.E.O. Of Newett energy.
They were upset
about getting the third degree.
You threatened to go
to the media?
Oh.
You know
how these corporate types are.
They can't see the upside
of a thing
till you point out
the downsides.
Those guys at Newett, they write
campaign checks... big ones.
That doesn't give them the right
to break the law,
but it does entitle them
to a little respect.
And by the way,
I feel like I've earned
a little respect, too.
I got a homicide case,
Jim.
I didn't have time
to check in.
I get that.
But you were on my turf.
It ain't much,
but it's mine, okay?
Mea culpa.
I'll... I'll check in
on any future visits.
Thanks, Walt.
Hey, branch.
Nice campaign signs.
Better keep an eye
on this one, Walt.
Every day.
[ Laughs ]
Better you than me!
[ Clears throat ]
So...
Talked to South Dakota.
Not a lot of info
on this Bonnie-and-Clyde couple,
but part of their m.O.
Is not using their own vehicles.
They steal a different car
for each hold-up.
I suppose you've already
got a list
of all reported auto thefts.
I did.
But, Walt, given our
limited resources,
we're dealing with a
needle/haystack situation here.
I really think we've got to let
the Maces offer their reward.
Putting money on the table
is gonna triple the number
of haystacks.
Just wait till you see
the garbage leads
they're gonna try
and sell us.
[ Sighs ]
But...
Given the circumstances...
I think you're right.
[ Gun cocks ]
I...
I took him by the hospital,
and... they examined him
he was a little dehydrated,
but he's in good shape.
Good.
You talk
to children's services?
Yeah.
Because a crime
was involved,
I convinced them
to grant us custody
until a social worker
can come and take over.
They're gonna
send me the paperwork.
Oh, this was in the
baby's swaddling blanket.
"I love you."
Do you think Evelyn
was the mother?
[ Sighs ]
Cady: What kind of mom
puts her baby
in a rabbit hutch?
I think that she was
trying to protect him.
Or hide him.
We don't even know for sure
the baby's hers.
Maybe she just
abandoned him.
You know, that happens
more than you think.
I-I don't think so.
She left these crystals
along her path,
like bread crumbs,
to mark the way back.
That's what
the milk was about.
What?
Ruby said the girl
asked Ellis about milk,
so maybe she hid her baby,
went outside to go to the store,
planned to go back to him,
but something stopped her.
Where did you say
you found him, Ferg?
Uh, right... Here.
Right there.
You two stay here.
Look after him.
Evelyn was trying
to hide this child.
Maybe someone's
looking for him.
Walt:
You looking for something?
[ Groans ]
Hi.
You're a good boy.
Yes, you are.
Who's next?
Branch: Thank you
for coming forward,
but our missing girl
is not a redhead.
You sure?
Does this mean
I don't get the $100,000?
[ Telephone rings ]
Moretti.
Walt: Can you bring me the photo
of Evelyn Mace?
Walt,
where the hell are you?
My office.
I found Evelyn's boyfriend,
Teddy Brown.
I got him
on the phone.
He said he'd been
in Portland the whole time.
I haven't been able
to confirm his alibi.
Who is this?
This is October.
I found her at the shed
where Henry and Ferg
discovered the baby.
She's looking for him.
That's what you say.
I say
I was just out for a walk.
Wearing a babybjorn.
Do you know this woman?
Hmm.
What a nice picture.
Of course I know April.
That isn't her name.
She doesn't
go by Evelyn anymore.
Are you looking
for Evelyn's baby?
The boy
is not April's baby.
He's our baby.
April stole him.
What do you mean
by "our"?
He belongs
to our family.
That's how we live,
as it was meant to be...
a loving community
of brothers and sisters
in harmony with the earth
and each other.
It's an incredibly
beautiful thing.
Okay.
Where's April?
Even if I knew where April was,
I couldn't tell you.
Why don't you tell us
about your family, then?
You wouldn't get it.
How many members are there
in your family? 12.
It's the golden number.
Does your cult
have a name?
Why is there so much ignorance
in the world?
You live your lives divorced
from the land and its bounty.
You fill your bodies with
chemicals and poisons each day.
You worship a Messiah
who vanished 2,000 years ago.
Maybe you're the cult.
I think I'll go now.
No, you won't.
You're the only person that's seen
Evelyn in the last two years.
Until you tell us
where she's been,
you're not leaving here.
[ Groans ]
You cannot detain me
for walking in the woods
with a babybjorn,
sheriff,
so I'm gonna go.
That's assault.
Shall I press charges?
Walt:
Vic... Let her go.
I get it.
Let them go, catch them later.
Clearly, she's not gonna
tell us anything.
Maybe
she'll lead us somewhere.
Ferg, there's a water glass
in my office.
Pull her prints
off that glass,
see if she turns up
in the system somewhere.
[ Dog barks in distance ]
You lost, Kemosabe?
No, I would be Tonto,
and you would be Kemosabe.
You're trespassing.
Raise your hands.
[ Gun cocks ]
How.
Vic, you're supposed to be
following October.
I am. Look.
She hasn't moved
since she left.
It's like some
creepy little vigil.
Don't let her
out of your sight.
Walt, this gentleman
insists he has valuable
information about Evelyn Mace,
but he will not talk
to anybody but you.
[ Door closes ]
My wife
is a nurse and midwife.
She delivered a baby
for that girl.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
When was that?
Maybe two months back.
Where's your wife?
Where's my check?
I've got a man dead,
and this girl could be
the key to finding the killer.
You realize that?
I do.
So, where's my check?
[ Chickens clucking ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
Please let me out.
Please let me out!
[ Cries ]
I want my baby!
Please let me...
[ Sobbing ] Let me out.
I'm looking to speak to a nurse
named Catherine holt.
Woman: Let me see
if I can find her, sheriff.
Ferg wants to
talk to you.
You know,
it'd be a lot easier
if you got a cellphone
of your own.
I don't need one.
What's up, Ferg?
Ferg: I got a hit
on October's prints.
Her legal name
is Fiona Hines.
H-I-n-e-s.
She's 27, and guess what...
she also went missing
but five years ago
in Madison, Wisconsin.
Last seen
at a greyhound station.
She still sitting outside?
Yeah.
She hasn't moved for hours.
Honestly, sheriff,
she's starting to freak me out.
You're all right, Ferg.
You wanted to see me?
Did you deliver
this young lady's baby
about two months ago?
Dr. Forest, dial 118, please.
I'm sorry I didn't come forward,
but these people are scary.
Which people?
Those girls
from the farmers market...
the ones that sell organic milk
and eggs and jam.
A couple of months back,
one of them came
pounding on my door at 3:00 A.M.
And said her sister
was having a baby
and there were
complications.
I guess they knew
I was a midwife.
They offered me
$2,000.
We need the money,
but I had no idea
what I was getting into.
They blindfolded me,
then we drove
for like 40 minutes.
No one spoke
the entire time.
Did you have any idea
where you were driving?
Could you hear
or see anything?
No, not really.
I tried to count the turns,
but I got confused.
I think we
crossed railway tracks
just before
we got there.
Got where?
When they
took the blindfold off,
I was in this weird room
with a mural.
The pregnant girl
was in bad shape.
The baby was breech.
I got him turned around,
and after about another hour
of pushing, she delivered.
None of these women
spoke to you at all?
[ Sobs ]
On the way home,
one of them whispered,
"if you tell anybody
about this,
"I will wake you in your bed
one night
and stick a knife
into your belly."
[ Sobs ]
You hear any rumors
about cults in the area?
You know, you hear about
survivalists up in the woods,
but that's dudes with beards
and guns and tins of food.
This sounds different.
More like Waco
or that Heaven's gate thing.
Who's leading it?
Where are they?
[ Cellphone rings ]
Hey.
Yeah.
Of course.
Ruby wants to patch in a call
to you...
On my cellphone.
Walt:
This is sheriff Longmire.
Jim: Hey, Walt.
I guess you figured if
you weren't snooping yourself,
it'd be okay
to send your Indian.
I thought we were clear on this.
Henry's there?
He is.
And he was trespassing
on Newett energy property.
Put him on.
What happened?
I followed
the yellow brick road.
It ended here, near the grille
of a black S.U.V.
You didn't happen
to see a license plate.
No.
I was a little distracted.
Sit tight, Henry.
Branch, you head back.
I've got to go get Henry
and find a judge.
This is like the world's longest
staring contest.
Ferg, come on.
I've worked with Monica
for years.
She's been in children's
services for like a decade.
You can't be too careful.
All right?
She checks out.
Thanks.
Thank you
for your patience.
Here he is.
Did you park nearby?
Oh, yeah.
Just around the corner.
Okay.
I'll walk you to your car.
[ Baby coos ]
Branch: Okay, then.
Bye-bye.
Cady:
Where are you parked?
Monica: Oh, I'm just right
around the corner there.
So, Cady.
Branch, don't.
Don't what?
Don't walk you
to this nice woman's car?
You need
to stop calling me.
Maybe if you
answered your phone...
[ Horn honks ]
Oh!
[ Screams ]
Give me that!
Oh!
[ Grunts ]
Branch:
Cady, are you okay?
Hey!
[ Horn honks ]
Go! Go, go, go!
[ Chuckles ]
Walt, you want me
to give you a warrant
to search the entire property
of Newett energy
based on a hunch?
It's more than a hunch, Gil.
Right.
There's those
vague recollections
by a blindfolded woman.
Judge Mayhew,
I tracked that girl
back from the scene
of the crime to their property.
And you and the eagle scout
found some crystals.
Herderite.
It is non-native.
Your honor,
Henry's a skilled tracker.
He's also
a trespasser.
Walt,
without some real evidence,
I'm not signing that.
Vic: 17-78-611.
17-78-611.
Holy shit.
That's October.
Vic.
What's up, Vic?
Vic: October stabbed the social
worker. I got hit by a car.
Wait, what?
It doesn't matter.
The plate number of the car
that tried to flatten me...
it's registered to October under
her legal name, Fiona hines.
Guess where the address is.
A cult?
Walt, I had no idea anything
like this was going on here.
I thought he
and these girls
were a bunch of hippie
organic-farmer types, you know?
Walt:
It didn't strike you as odd
that this man
was living with 12 young women
out in the middle of nowhere?
I didn't think it was
any of my business.
Leland
and the energy company
are funding
your campaign, right?
I'm not
in anybody's pocket, Walt.
I can trust you to back me up
when I go through that door?
You know you can.
[ Sighs ]
Looks like the cult
hit the road.
Vic:
Their cars are here.
They've got to
be here somewhere.
Over there.
[ Gun cocks ]
Put your hands up,
Mr. Townes.
Do as he says,
Leland.
[ Police radio chatter ]
Leland:
That's the gun.
You can check the ballistics.
Put your hands up.
An object in motion
stays in motion.
It's the law of the universe.
I did not want to kill
that old man at the gas station,
but he was gonna
take April from us.
And it was ordained.
Nothing shall interfere
with the plan.
You don't need this.
I've already escaped.
Where's Evelyn?
You mean April.
She's with January
and February and march...
May, June, July, August,
September, October,
November,
and December.
Walt:
Where are the girls, Leland?
What's this plan
you're talking about?
Leland: What was it
Louis Armstrong said?
If you have to ask,
you'll never know.
We're all just points
in the universe,
converging on the infinite.
Whoa. Whoa.
Hey. Whoa.
What the hell?
Must have taken something.
He's poisoned himself.
Get some water! Must have
been something in the tea.
Ferg:
What should we do?
Should we call an ambulance?
No time.
[ Gurgling ]
[ Coughing ]
Welcome back.
I'm not gonna let you die,
Leland.
You might as well tell me
where Evelyn and the girls are.
I've found that those
who fight hardest against death
are the ones most tempted
by its salvation.
They're lost.
April was lost
before she came to me.
What did you provide her
that she didn't have before?
Context.
I made her realize
that we're all just
individual points...
Converging on infinity.
[ Train bell clanging ]
Right.
I showed her.
We're all just part
of this earth,
here for a short time.
Need to step aside,
make room for new people.
April was trying
to avoid her destiny.
I couldn't
let that happen.
So, you found her
at the gas station.
All that business
about the black S.U.V.
From Oregon... you made that up.
Time to move on
to the next stage.
The next stage is death.
[ Laughs ]
No, you silly little man.
The next stage... rebirth.
Death... just a door.
Why now, Leland?
Why try
and kill yourself now?
It was ordained.
The boy's birth
was the sign.
Evelyn's baby.
April's and my son.
When he arrived,
it was clear
we'd all served our purpose.
You know, sheriff, you served
your purpose, as well.
I know...
you're not happy.
Why not just let go?
Why not drive
around those gates,
kill the pain,
become immortal?
Let's walk
through the door together.
Points converging
on the infinite.
Yes.
[ Tires squeal ]
Got a train heading west
near postal road.
Do whatever it takes
to stop it.
[ Siren wails ]
[ Train horn blares ]
[ Siren wailing ]
Come on!
[ October groans ]
They're still breathing.
Get them up!
[ Train horn blares ]
Help!
Where's my baby?
Is he okay?
He's fine.
We'll get you
out of here.
[ Siren wails ]
[ Brakes hiss ]
[ Train horn blares ]
Branch:
He's hit the brakes,
but that thing's gonna take
a mile to stop.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Screams ]
[ Train horn blares ]
Come on.
Get up! Get up!
Don't move.
I got you.
[ Wheels squeak ]
[ Music ]
Ruby: "Ellis Hinkley, long-time
resident of Absaroka county",
"passed away on Friday.
"A valued member
of the community,
"Ellis leaves behind no family.
"But his kindness, his decency,
and his courage
"will be remembered
by everyone who knew him.
He will be missed."
Sounds about right.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com