Previously on Longmire...
***
I promised Henry I'd go get
Cady...
***
Is it because of me?
Hey, Walt. You won.
- What?
- The election.
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Exhales deeply ]
Cady is awake.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Monitor beeping ]
Dad.
You look like hell.
You scared me, punk.
[ Sighs ]
Ah, so, any news?
Actually, uh...
yeah.
Looks like my daughter's
out of the woods.
Well, that's great.
Yeah.
Uh, sorry, um,
I don't think you guys have met.
Troy, this is Sheriff Longmire.
You're number 44.
They still have your jersey
in a trophy case at school.
Thing's almost an antique.
Your dad tells me
you're a pretty good player.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm a running back.
And hopefully, we'll have him
on the field soon.
Doctors have finally
figured out that
Troy has some kind of
degenerative muscle disease.
Wasting sickness, they call it.
Not the best of diagnosis,
but it's a step
in the right direction.
At least we know now
what to fight.
Nurse: Sheriff?
There's a phone call for you.
Excuse me.
Sure.
Hello?
Vic: Hey, Walt.
Ruby told me that Cady's awake.
I'm so glad.
Thanks, Vic. Uh, yeah,
she's doing better.
Is that why you called?
[ Sighs ]
It's not the only reason,
but, uh, I shouldn't have
bothered you.
What is it, Vic?
It's nothing.
Uh, you should
stay there with Cady.
She's resting. And besides,
I've been here for hours.
She could use a break
from her dad hanging around.
Ruby can stay with her a while.
What's up?
This is Connor Redding.
28 years old.
He's a game warden.
This entire area
was part of his patrol.
He was found by bird watchers.
Hey, sheriff.
I gave fish and game
the heads up.
This is Devin Gaines.
Appreciate you
coming down so fast.
I gather
you worked with the victim.
Yeah, I, uh, hired him.
Connor and I were pretty close.
He came out here from Alaska
about a year ago with his wife.
They've got a baby girl.
She's only 2.
Looks like he took
two stab wounds to the chest.
Deep cuts. Probably from
a hunting knife.
What about our other victim?
The elk?
Elk season's a month off.
Means this is also a murder.
Considering all the hunting
we got out here,
it's pretty easy for game
wardens to make enemies fast.
Most hunters
respect what we do,
but there are always
a few idiots
who don't like
having to abide by rules.
Anyone in particular you know?
I spent a month trying to catch
this one poacher.
He's been killing a lot of elk
out of season
and taking their heads
as some kind of trophy.
This looks like his handiwork.
I've searched the area.
Guy's got serious skills.
Knows where to go,
how to cover his tracks.
Looks like Connor probably, uh,
caught him in the act, so...
Wait, so, a guy gets caught
killing elk out of season
and resorts to murder?
It just seems like
a lot of risk
to put a head on a wall.
If the killer was looking
to mount the elk head,
he'd need to do it quickly.
[ Air hissing ]
Nice job.
Oh, hey. Yeah.
You'd never know
they weren't swimming.
I got more for sale
if you're looking to buy.
Actually, I'm more interested
in elk today.
Anyone come in recently
to have a head mounted?
Well, they'd have to be
pretty dumb to do so.
I keep a close eye
on the calendar.
Anybody comes in with an elk
even a day before
the season opens,
I put in a call
to fish and game.
You could risk losing your whole
business working with poachers.
I'm sure there are some
taxidermists who don't mind,
if they're
offered enough money.
All the other shops
are closed till the fall,
when elk and deer season's
opened.
That's when we make most of
our money mounting heads.
You mind if we
finish this outside?
I want to let this guy dry
out in the open air.
That works.
Summers are tough.
Not a huge market for 13-inch
rainbows, as you can see.
But I got a firewood business
that lets me stay open
year-round.
Well, keep an eye out
for me, Lee.
Anyone brings in an elk head,
you give me a call.
Yeah, will do, sheriff.
Oh, hey.
I've got a broken deer head
back at the station,
and I'm not sure
it can be fixed,
but I'd appreciate it
if you'd take a look for me.
Oh, I'd be happy to.
Hey, Lee.
Hey, I just picked up
a big load of scrap wood.
Figured you might be able to
sell some of it for kindling.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, Cady.
Do I know you?
I'm sorry.
I've had a head injury. I don't
remember certain people.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm sorry.
Ow.
I'm sorry, it was too good.
[ Laughs ]
I like to think
I'm kind of hard to forget.
Oh.
How you feeling?
Okay.
But they have me
doped up to the gills,
and I really haven't
tried moving around yet, so...
Do you, uh,
remember
anything about the accident?
You know how you got
that flat tire?
Honestly, I-I don't remember
anything from that day.
It's a total blank.
[ Sniffs ]
Um, is your, uh...
is your dad around?
No. He got called into work,
thank God.
He's been great --
it's just hard to rest
when someone is staring at you.
Oh, he got called into work,
which means that he won.
It was close.
Really?
[ Both chuckle ]
Mm-hmm. Really close.
You're not wearing
your uniform.
Does that mean you were fired?
He hasn't asked me to leave,
if that's
what you're wondering.
Have you asked him to stay?
[ Sighs ]
Did you dress your wounds?
Yeah, I used some of that
men-wake you gave me.
Thanks. I'm fine.
It will leave a mark.
Mm. Yeah,
I figured it might.
Henry.
Walt.
Whoa.
You go surfing?
Very funny.
Uh, you heard stories about
anyone poaching any elk lately?
Well, if I had,
you'd have heard about it.
Of course, if I had it my way,
they'd be shot on sight.
Poachers are
the lowest of the low.
They got no regard
for natural law.
There's a time to kill things
and a time to let them thrive.
Thank goodness
you have appointed yourself
the protector of natural law.
Natural law isn't my usual
jurisdiction, but, uh...
this poacher
didn't stop with the elk.
He also killed a game warden.
Which one?
Connor Redding.
Aw, shoot.
Young kid. Good guy.
What was this poacher
after? Meat?
Don't think so.
Head was gone,
body was left behind.
Looks like whoever it was
was after a trophy.
Not much of a trophy.
This time of year, the antlers
are barely starting to grow.
No. Most head hunters
wouldn't even bother.
Most poachers don't partially
gut the animal, either,
unless they were after
something else.
You mind if I
take a look at this elk?
Yeah.
Yeah, just as I suspected.
Pancreas is missing.
That would also explain
why the poacher took the head.
He wanted antler velvet.
Not following you, Omar.
You ever hear of elk velvetine?
I've heard of antler velvet,
but not velvetine.
It's one of those new-age
Chinese supplements.
Elk pancreas and antler velvet
are the two main ingredients
you need to make the stuff.
You saying this hunter
was killing elk
for its medicinal properties?
Well, there's a big, big market
in herbal medicines
if you can find
the raw materials.
These Chinese companies
hire a few hunters to --
well, kind of like
medical mercenaries.
These guys go all over the world
killing animals
just so these companies
can make their remedies.
Mm.
How do these Chinese companies
find their poachers?
Wait a minute.
I know how one guy tried.
About a month ago,
I had a Chinese guy
on one of my trips --
Mr. Chen.
Couldn't shoot worth a damn,
but he sure seemed keen on
killing an elk.
Even offered me some cash
to do it for him.
What did you tell him?
No, of course.
Well, looks like
someone said yes.
Hey, punk.
How you feeling?
Cady: The same as I was
a few hours ago.
I'm fine, dad.
Well, uh,
Henry gave me his cellphone,
so I thought
I'd give you a call,
see if you needed anything.
Don't worry about me.
You have plenty on your plate.
Ruby stopped by earlier
and told me everything.
Sounds crazy.
Okay, uh, I'll call you later,
or you can call me 'cause, um,
I got a cellphone now.
Uh, okay, you get some rest.
Okay, I will.
I love you. Bye.
Bye.
[ Phone slams ]
What?
You had to
give him your cellphone?
Ruby.
Ruby: Hi, Walt.
Lee.
I didn't think there was
much hope left for him.
Oh, I think there's
a little life left in him.
Try and take it easy on him, though.
Yeah. Thanks.
Show me the bill
when you get a chance.
Yeah, no problem.
Want me to
hang him back up for you?
Sure. Thanks.
This name that Omar
gave you -- Mr. Chen.
It's got to be an alias.
This guy's a ghost.
Paid Omar in cash, so there's
no way to trace his receipts.
And the address
and the phone number
that he listed
on the registry --
they're fakes, as well.
Omar give you
a physical description?
Yeah, mm-hmm.
It was useless.
And politically incorrect.
Walt!
I found some information
on elk velvetine.
Check in with the other
hunting outfitters in town,
see if Chen
booked any trips with them
or if he's got any
updated contact information.
Also, question as many
of the guides as you can.
If Chen hired any of them
to poach for him,
that might be our killer.
All right, Ruby.
Shoot.
Well, according to
these articles,
the nearest place
you can buy velvetine is China.
Now, you can get
a little bit online
from those shady
Canadian pharmacies.
But look --
a tiny little bottle
is more expensive
than my car payments.
So, if Mr. Chen found
a way to produce it in the U.S.,
he could make a lot of money.
Man, they use this stuff
for everything.
Cancer patients
use it to re-grow muscle,
eases arthritis in old people.
They claim pro football players
are taking it
instead of steroids.
But there are other side effects.
Huh.
Arrhythmia, severe cramping,
increase of something called
wasting sickness,
and high blood pressure.
Huh.
Thank you.
[ Sighs ]
Get some rest.
Thought you guys could use
some new reading material.
Already read through it twice.
Well, thanks. That's --
that's awful nice.
Uh, I'll give Troy first dibs.
I was just
heading to the cafeteria.
Why don't you stay
and talk some football?
Phil Steele's
College Football Preview.
Troy: Thank you.
So, what schools
are you thinking about?
I wanted to go to Oregon.
I still do
if I ever get out of here.
They even had scouts
looking at me last year.
Oh.
All that attention
from top programs,
you probably put
a lot of pressure on yourself.
Do what you got to do.
Lot of boys in your position
tend to go the extra mile
to impress the scouts.
Extra workouts, protein diets.
Some of them
even try supplements.
You ever heard of
something called velvetine?
Yeah. I heard, uh, pro and
college players use it, right?
Yeah.
How about you?
No.
Troy, the way I see things,
your chances of
playing college ball
are pretty slim if you don't
get out of this bed.
Now, the wasting sickness
you have,
velvetine can cause that.
If you used it,
you should tell the doctors.
They may be able to
help you play again.
I just need to know
where you got it.
There's at least 20
hunting guides in this town
that need to be questioned.
Don't you have to give, like,
two weeks' notice or something
if you're quitting?
Branch: I don't know
what I'm doing yet.
There's stuff
I need to figure out.
So, while you're out
soul searching,
I'm on my own?
What can I say?
You should've voted for me.
Yeah, whatever.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Hey. I'm, uh, looking for
the owner -- Rosco Wilkes.
You found her.
My dad wanted a boy.
How can I help you?
Uh...
How many hunting guides
do you have on staff?
High season, six,
but this time of year, ain't
that much hunting to guide,
so I only got one --
Keith Dixon.
He's up in the big horns.
Left two days ago to scout
fishing holes for a client.
He got a cellphone up there?
He's got a radio in his truck.
Checks in at night.
Is there some kind of trouble?
[ Chuckles ]
I'm gonna need some information
about a possible client.
Did a Mr. Chen book
a hunting trip with you guys?
Name doesn't sound familiar.
Oh, is he one of these guys?
You know, it would help
if I knew what he looked like.
I could check the registry,
see if we got any record of him.
That'd be great.
Thanks.
[ Whistle blows ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Hargis: It's a shame about Troy.
Kid with natural talent
like that,
as a coach,
you're lucky if you see that
four, maybe five times
in your career.
Could've played
Division-I ball.
He could've taken you with him.
A lot of high-school coaches
like a shot at a college job.
If a player under you
is recruited
into a
Division-I school,
it stands out on your résumé.
Troy said the scouts were
coming to take a look at him.
You needed him to make
a good impression.
So, what are you getting at,
sheriff?
Troy's sickness is caused by
a performance supplement --
stuff called velvetine.
He said you were the one
that gave it to him.
I'll have you know I run
a clean program, sheriff.
I won't deny that
I'd like a college job,
but I'm not risking
the one that I got.
Doping players -- that's grounds
for immediate dismissal.
I'm not trying to
get you fired, coach.
I'm just looking for a man
that's connected
to the velvetine.
Do you know someone
named Mr. Chen?
Never heard of him.
I care about Troy.
I wouldn't push
any kind of supplement on him.
Why did Troy
say it was you, then?
[ Sighs ]
Maybe he was trying to
protect his father.
Grant's a sideline dad.
Sits in the stands
every practice, yelling.
I had to ask him to leave
a few times.
Grant would do anything
to make sure that Troy succeeds.
Hey.
So, it turns out
Mr. Chen booked trips
with five different hunting
outfitters over the last few months.
I talked to as many of
the guides as I could locate.
A few of them admit that he asked
them to shoot elk out of season,
but they all claim
they turned him down.
What are the photos for?
I'm at a dead end
trying to find this guy.
He paid cash
to all the outfitters,
listed the same
useless contact information.
So, I called Omar
to see if maybe he had
a picture of Chen
from one of their
hunting trips.
It would help us
to know what he looked like.
Ah. And there he is.
Top left.
I know him.
Mr. Chen?
No.
But I know Grant Thayer.
[ Sighs ]
So.
[ Clears throat ]
I heard that the doctors
have a plan of attack
for treating Troy...
now that they know
he was taking velvetine.
Troy told me he got it from
Coach Hargis.
I spoke to Hargis.
He said it wasn't him.
He thinks
it was someone else --
someone close to Troy.
You just want the best
for your kids.
Want to give them
every advantage.
I thought the stuff
was all-natural.
I had no idea
it could have
side effects like this.
Where did you get
the velvetine?
I learned about it from
some guy on a hunting trip.
This man?
Mr. Chen.
[ Sighs ]
He was going on
and on about it.
When I heard the scouts
were coming,
I-I called Chen
and bought as much of the stuff
as he would sell me.
Troy wanted this
more than anything...
and I just wanted to help him.
So, you have a way of
contacting Mr. Chen, then?
You looking for Grant Thayer?
Yes.
Means you're Mr. Chen.
You're a hard man to find.
Now I know why.
Jonathan Ling.
You're a scientist?
Engineer, actually.
Coalage hired me
for a special project --
converting coal to liquid gas,
which we sell to China.
How's your company feel
about your side business?
Jonathan: I'm not sure
I know what you mean.
Selling velvetine.
Why should they care?
I've done nothing illegal.
I make many trips to China.
Velvetine is made and sold
legally there.
And I bring back small amounts
that the custom laws allow.
I might charge my customers
a little bit extra for it here,
but I'm simply obeying
the laws of supply and demand.
I guess that high demand
is the reason
you started
harvesting ingredients here --
making velvetine yourself,
which is illegal.
You went on hunting trips
over several months.
A few of the outfitters said
you offered them money
to kill elk out of season,
and the trips stopped.
Which probably means you found
someone
willing to hunt for you.
Or it could simply mean that
my workload got a little hectic
and I no longer have time
to take vacations.
So, it's just
a coincidence that, uh,
around the time
you stopped taking vacations,
a hunter started slaying elk
and taking the exact parts
you need to make velvetine.
You have actual proof
that I hired this hunter?
Not yet.
Looks like this hunter
also killed
a young man
named Connor Redding.
He's a game warden
who stumbled on the operation.
And when I find this hunter,
it's only a matter of time
before he tells me about
your involvement,
and you'll be implicated
in first-degree murder.
I'm sorry I can't be of help,
sheriff.
I have no operation.
I'm just an engineer who,
on occasion,
legally imports a product
for a few select clients.
[ Music ]
3:00 on a Tuesday
and you are not at work?
Looking to drown your sorrows?
[ Sighs ] Work is
sort of why I'm here.
I need your advice
about something.
You have got to be kidding me.
Given everything that's happened
with the election,
I'm in kind of a tough spot.
I cannot pretend
to feel sorry for you.
So, I never came up
with a backup plan
in case I lost the election.
Why not work for your father?
Not an option.
You want to work for Walt?
I don't know if it matters
what I want.
So, what advice
do you need from me?
You've known him the longest.
Is Walt the kind of man
who holds a grudge?
The first time I met Walt,
we were in sixth grade.
I was ahead of him in line
for the drinking fountain.
When I took a drink,
my lips touched the faucet.
Walt called me out,
told me not to do that.
I reacted as any
rational Indian kid would.
I turned around
and punched him.
After the principal
pulled us apart,
he asked why we were fighting.
I told him
it was a matter of honor.
Walt did not want to
share the drinking fountain
with a dirty Indian.
But then Walt explained
he was simply
trying to warn me.
People have germs,
and putting my lips on a faucet
is a good way to get sick.
What's your point?
I challenged Walt
without provocation.
He could've hated me for it.
Instead, we have been friends
for 38 years.
If nothing else,
Walt believes in second chances.
Hey.
Taxidermist -- Lee Rosky --
just called.
A guy named Keith Dixon came in and
asked him to mount an elk head.
Turns out that Keith Dixon is one of the
guys that Chen booked a hunting trip with,
only I didn't get to talk to him because
his boss said he was up in the mountains.
He still at Lee's now?
No.
Lee refused to stuff the head,
so the guy bolted.
But I did get an address
from his boss.
Check the back of the house.
Open up!
Sheriff's department!
[ Sniffing ]
[ Sniffs, sighs ]
Vic: Walt!
Velvet's been scraped off.
It looks like the head
that goes to our elk body.
It's got to be the same one.
I'll call the judge,
get a warrant.
We don't need a warrant.
Guy's got
a lot of animal parts,
but they're all on the wall.
[ Thud ]
[ Doorknob clatters ]
[ Sighs ]
Antler velvet.
Is this what I think it is?
Pancreas.
Well, we found Keith's stash.
Now we just have to
go find Keith.
[ Sighs ]
Why couldn't Vic come?
Lighten the mood in here a bit.
If I recall,
last time Vic
went hunting with you, Omar,
she got shot.
[ Chuckles ]
And why did we have to
bring him?
Walt: Well, he's
the best tracker I know.
I'll be the judge of that.
Okay, so you said Keith
was heading to piedmont falls?
According to his boss,
he was scouting fishing holes.
Destination --
Piedmont Falls, Wyoming.
[ GPS beeps ]
He probably entered in
right there.
Though there's
no fishing worth a damn
anywhere near here.
But it is near
an elk migration route.
Looks like we found our man.
Or at least his truck.
Walt: You said
Keith worked for you?
Omar: Yeah.
Till I had to fire him.
Henry: Why?
Found out
he took a few guys out
on a special
hunting expedition.
They offered him money
to shoot a bald eagle,
and he took it.
Killing animals for money
is one thing.
Stabbing a man to death's
another story.
You think Keith could've
killed Connor Redding?
Yeah, I do.
Elk tracks.
Look at this.
Salt lick.
Think fishing and game
could've put this out here?
No.
But it sounds like Keith.
Some guys track.
Keith was always
a shortcut artist.
He puts out salt licks
to attract the elk,
then hunkers down somewhere
and waits for his prey
to come to him.
That tree line's the best
vantage point for a hunter.
Keith's probably
hiding in there right now.
We need to get moving.
Easy, Omar.
I am easy.
Till I find Keith.
Do not be in such a hurry!
[ Screams ]
Henry?! Henry!
[ Screams, groans ]
[ Groans ]
O.I.T.
What the hell's --
Old Indian Trick.
[ Sighs ]
But you are an Indian.
I am Cheyenne.
This is an Apache death trap,
and if you were not distracting
me, my leg would not be
stuck in a hole
with sharp wooden stakes!
The animal's leg
goes in easy enough.
Yes, but you try to pull it out,
it messes you up.
[ Grunts ]
Give me a hand here, Omar.
Before guns, the hunters
used these traps
to bring down big game...
[ Grunts ]
...Easy.
Well, that sounds like Keith.
[ Grunts ]
He's probably nearby.
Jeff: We ran that print you sent
us through the DCI computer.
Got a hit right away.
Guy's name is David Ridges.
He got any kind of record?
Yeah, at least five
prior arrests
in Montana and Wyoming,
mostly assaults.
I got his last-known address
here if you want it.
I do.
Can you e-mail it to me?
Sure thing.
[ Elk calling ]
[ Calling continues ]
[ Leaves rustle ]
[ Elk call sounds ]
What the...
[ Gun cocks ]
Don't move, Keith.
Oh, come on, Walt.
Let him run.
I love a moving target.
[ Door opens ]
Vic, get Devin Gaines
on the phone.
Tell him we got Keith Dixon
in custody.
[ Clears throat ]
Mm-hmm.
I'll get, uh, Mr. Dixon
settled into your office.
Hey, Walt.
Does this mean
you still work here?
I guess it does.
Okay, then.
You want to try and slap some
poaching charges on me,
be my guest.
You can't ever prove that
I set any of those traps.
Walt: No need.
Considering all the, uh,
antler velvet and pancreas
we've already taken
from your house,
I say we'd got more than enough
evidence to charge you.
You guys went to my house?
All those body parts.
Devin Gaines said that's
at least 15 years in prison.
I wasn't killing those elk
for me, all right?
I was hunting for someone else,
and he was using those parts
to make medicine or something.
Was this the someone else?
He either goes by the name
Mr. Chen or Jonathan Ling.
You ease up on my charges,
and I'll write a novel
about the guy.
Huh. Okay.
May be able to cut some years
off your poaching sentence,
but you're still
looking at a life term
for killing Connor Redding.
Connor Redding? What are you --
what are you talking --
He's the game warden
we found stabbed...
next to a beheaded elk.
Now, whoever killed Connor
also killed that elk
and took its head.
We found that head
in your dumpster.
Whoa, okay.
Hold on a second here.
Okay?
The first thing you learn
is never dump illegal parts
where anyone can find them,
and I definitely wouldn't
leave a rotting head
outside my own house --
I mean, come on, guys.
Really, how stupid
do you think I am?
Stupid enough
to ask a taxidermist
to stuff it for you.
[ Scoffs ] Come on.
Okay, y'all were
at my house, right?
You saw the 10-point buck
on the wall.
That's a head worth mounting,
okay?
Why would I waste money
stuffing a puny head like this?
Huh?
And who told you that I brought
that head to the taxidermist?
Sheriff's department!
[ Knock on door ]
Lee. We need to talk.
Sorry. Couldn't
get to the door quick enough.
I don't move as fast
as I used to.
I'm sorry.
I was looking for Lee.
He left about an hour ago to
make some firewood deliveries.
I'm his wife, Bonnie.
[ Tea kettle whistles ]
I was just
making myself some tea.
Lee should be home shortly.
Come have a cup while you wait.
[ Whistling continues ]
Please, um,
let me get that for you.
Oh, thank you.
The tea's already in the pot,
and there's another cup
on the counter there.
[ Whistling stops ]
You take a seat.
Allow me.
Okeydokey.
[ Water pouring ]
There you go.
I was so sorry to hear about
your wife's passing.
You two knew one another?
A little.
We were chemo buddies.
She never mentioned you.
It was a group of us.
We kind of
formed a private club.
Martha would always say,
"Admission is free
'cause we've all
paid our dues."
[ Chuckles ]
I was surprised
she was taken so quickly.
Considering what I'm going
through at this stage,
I'm grateful she was spared
this kind of pain.
What kind of treatment do they have you on?
None.
The last round of radiation
almost did me in.
It's funny.
You take medicine
trying to kill a disease,
and it almost kills you.
I told Lee, I said, no more.
No more doctors, no more
hospitals, no more medicine.
So, uh...
what's all this, then?
Just herbal remedies.
You familiar with a supplement
called velvetine?
Yeah, Lee got it for me
after he read about it
on the Internet.
Supposed to be
some kind of miracle cure.
I don't know if it's
making me any better,
but it makes him feel better
when I take it.
Do you know
where he gets it from?
[ Grunts ]
[ Dishes clatter ]
[ Screams ]
Lee!
One man's already dead,
Lee! [ Grunts ]
Lee! Stop this!
You listen to her.
Stop.
[ Whimpers ]
Lee, what is going on here?
Please tell me.
He was trying to save you.
What?
[ Sighs ]
I was just trying to
get your medicine for you.
The velvetine.
Keith Dixon came by my shop
with a sample of the velvetine,
and it worked.
I could see the change in you
right away.
But when we ran out, I...
I couldn't afford it.
I looked everywhere,
tried everything.
And you couldn't stand by,
let that disease win --
you had to fight it.
So you decided to
make your own velvetine.
But that game warden caught me.
He was gonna take me in,
and that would've meant jail.
So we fought.
And I stabbed him.
[ Sobs ]
I couldn't let him
take me away --
not -- not with Bonnie
in her condition.
It was either him or your wife.
[ Voice breaking ] Yes.
Lee, baby.
I am not getting better.
You have to let me go.
You have to.
[ Crying ]
No. No. I never will.
Hey.
I was beginning to
wonder about you.
You disappeared for a bit.
Been a little preoccupied.
Did you know Cady Longmire
was in a car accident?
She okay?
She will be.
But I've been looking into the
circumstances of the accident,
and I found some odd things.
First...I found
a round puncture in the
side wall of a brand-new tire
on the station wagon
that Cady was driving.
Not the tread,
but the side wall,
meaning someone
flattened that tire on purpose.
Also lifted a fingerprint
off the car
right above the rear-back
flat tire.
Belongs to a guy named
David Ridges.
Tried to visit him at home,
he wasn't there,
but I did find an interesting
detail on his résumé.
You found...
that David works for me.
Normally, I wouldn't
blink at that.
You have a lot of employees,
but then I remembered
what you said
about retail politics.
Getting more of
our own voters to the polls,
keeping more of
the other guy's voters away.
You didn't have anything to do
with Cady's accident, did you?
You know, my people have had
a bad couple of centuries.
Some of us have learned that
to get by in the present,
you need to let go of the past.
In fact, I'd imagine that
I have already forgotten more
than most people
will ever experience
in their lives.
My advice to you
would be to do the same.
Don't look back.
Could lead to real pain.
It's better to keep your eyes
down the road, my man,
on your very bright future.
Not really an answer, Jacob.
I'll see you around.
Favorite from the Busy Bee.
Biscuits and gravy.
Thank you.
Have you gotten any sleep
in the last few days?
I plan to.
Things are starting to
settle down.
Got a full team back
at the station again, so...
decided to
keep your boyfriend on.
He's not my boyfriend.
I'm...
not sure what he is.
Well, whatever.
"Whatever"?
[ Chuckles ]
I don't think I've ever heard you
say that word my entire life.
I know I had some issues
with branch in the past, but...
I got to let that go.
I got to
let a lot of things go.
Maybe I'm just
starting to mellow.
I should
get hit by a car more often.
No.
Once was enough.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com