_
(man) The Alamo's fallen!
Santa Anna has taken the Alamo!
♪ ♪
Santa Anna took no prisoners.
Sam, what would your personal compunctions
lead you to do?
Let Santa Anna get drunk on
an abundance of confidence,
and then we attack with a vengeance.
Sergeant Knowles?
What the hell?
Last we heard, youse was deserting.
Now, just... easy.
General Houston wants us
to track down Santa Anna.
Come here. [crying]
As long as you don't get,
you and your men are
gonna be overrun and die.
I've ordered Colonel Fannin
to retreat from Goliad.
This is the very kind of deliberation
that lost the lives of our compatriots
at the Alamo!
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(Burns) Mexicans, right over the hill!
(Fincham) Mexicans back yonder!
- Close the gate!
- Right behind us!
(Burns) Urrea's whole army back yonder!
Close the damned gate!
(Fincham) General Urrea's
army right over the hill!
(Samuel Wallace) Whoa, our scouts
said Urrea's army wasn't
due for a few days, boys.
(Burns) Well, I reckon you got
some pretty lousy scouts, then.
Mexicans close by. There's hundreds of 'em.
Colonel, you want that I
should go ride for help?
We're moving out. Pack it up.
(Burns) We ought to
make a stand right here.
Yeah, the boy's right.
I don't want another Alamo on my hands.
Yeah, we go out there,
it's gonna be a slaughter.
Not if we make it out in time.
(Fannin) Let's go! Let's
go! Prepare to march!
- Pack all the essentials!
- You ain't listening, Colonel.
They're here! Listen to us.
- They're here. We seen 'em.
- Get on your horse!
(Fannin) Let's go, boys! Move! Let's go.
Take all the essentials.
Come on, let's go. Let's go.
Let's go! Let's go!
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
_
Your Excellency, pardon the intrusion.
Our sentries captured a
prisoner riding from the north,
but the rebel army is in Kent.
Clearly, she belongs to
someone of importance.
- No sign of a whip.
- I ain't common or a slave.
Long ago I was contracted
as an indentured servant,
but I was freed.
Remove your hands from her.
What is your name, Señorita?
Emily West... native New Orleans.
You may go with Colonel
Almonte to answer his questions,
or you may remain here and answer mine.
Well, I believe I'd like to get to know
His Excellency better.
And so you will.
I'll send for you.
Of all the settlers in the Union,
there ain't nobody left to fight for.
God damned Fannin.
He's a crow's egg in an eagle's nest.
(man) Watch out!
[crash]
(Houston) What's the hold up there?
(man) Yah, yah! Come on.
Push!
God damned wagon.
(woman) Keep pushing!
God damned Fannin. God damned every...
God damned patriot.
He thinks he can win this war on his own.
[coughing]
(Houston) Deaf, what's the
doc say about your condition?
Ain't nothing changed since
he gave me the long face.
Don't you never mind.
(man) Sam?
Hope Miss Emily's feeling better.
Sorry to hear she gone off.
That Tejano Ranger, Flores...
He's sweeping for stragglers with Anderson.
Summon him up for me.
My suspicion is that you
are running away from a man.
Now, why do you suspect that?
I just do.
Well, I like to think I
might be running to something.
(Almonte) General...
I'm in the middle of lunch.
I'm sorry.
It's important, Your Excellency.
[whispering]
Your vigilance is commendable,
but I will handle the interrogation.
Yes, Your Excellency.
My man discovered an interesting monogram
on your saddle.
"S.H."
S.H.:
could that stand for Samuel Houston?
Hmm?
This is the man you are running from?
He wasn't the man I thought he was.
And why is that?
I saw the look of defeat on his face
when he heard what happened at the Alamo.
Well, now you are here.
What do you want?
I want a warm bath
with you in it.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
_
[men clicking tongues and whistling]
♪ ♪
We get past this ridge,
men, and we're safe!
On the double! Let's go!
♪ ♪
[men shouting]
Fall back! Fall back!
Move! Move! Move!
[bugle calling]
♪ ♪
Ah!
(Fannin) Defend your positions!
Defend your positions!
Fire!
[screaming]
Colonel's shot! Yance, give me a hand!
Hang on, Colonel!
We got you! Hang on!
My leg! My leg!
Wallace, send scouts to Houston!
(Wallace) [shouts]
Houston ain't sending no
one! He's done warned you!
(Fannin) You must go!
Defend your positions! Spread out!
Spread 'em!
Boy, come here! My leg!
♪ ♪
General Urrea...
Tell Santa Anna we have
surrounded the rebels.
His Excellency will not accept surrender.
You must finish them.
I am not a butcher.
I will deliver your message.
(Burns) Come on! This
way, Truett! Over here!
How the hell did Fannin become Colonel?
Must have married well.
[bugle calling]
What's that sound?
The hell's that?
[drum and bugle corps playing]
♪ ♪
They're messing with us.
[pleasant folk music playing]
♪ ♪
[all singing in Spanish]
[cheers and applause]
Tonight, my countrymen,
we not only celebrate
our successes in battle,
but the total victory to come.
You stand in San Durant.
[cheers and applause]
Chupaldo, where are you? I don't see you.
[all exclaiming]
I'll give you the great
honor to dispatch this message
on the flag of truce to General Houston.
This message says,
"There will be no refuge, no escape,
"no surrender, no mercy.
"You will be hunted down, butchered,
"and fed to my pigs!
And then, in turn, we will
feast on you in celebration."
[cheers and applause]
Compañeros!
(woman) Vamonos!
Tomorrow, they might take our lives,
but never our spirit...
the Mexican spirit!
[cheers and applause]
Musica!
♪ ♪
[fireworks whizzing and crackling]
The men need that kind of thing.
(man) Señor Presidente,
General Urrea has Fannin trapped.
By morning, he will have the
surrender of over 300 prisoners.
Prisoners?
Those men are fighting
under no recognized flag.
The rules of war do not apply.
Don Antonio,
it's the Easter celebration.
Perhaps mercy would be
the Christian thing to do.
Christian?
They are from the devil, not Jesus,
and there will be no resurrection.
[bugle calling]
[crickets chirping]
(Burns) Fannin should've
listened to Houston.
(Fincham) You think we'll
get out of here alive?
I wonder what Sarah's doing right now.
Don't you be thinking about my gal.
No.
(Samuel Wallace) Get some sleep, boys.
Urrea won't try another
attack till morning.
[sighs]
Got no need to hurry.
Feel like I've been ate by a wolf.
Yeah, and shit off a cliff.
You boys brothers?
Nah, he's too ugly to be relation.
Yeah, well, he's too stupid.
I got a brother.
We call him Bigfoot
on account of he once killed
an Injun with big feet.
Our pap...
he's a Virginia blacksmith.
He made us these matching
wrist cuffs to bond us.
I hope like hell to see him again.
[soft music]
♪ ♪
- General?
- Come in.
If those Ranger boys don't
come back with Fannin,
I'm cutting him loose.
Captains... misters Truett and Yancey,
are due to report back tomorrow.
Have a seat.
Sir.
Would you like a cigar?
Sir, thank you.
[spits]
Señor Flores,
I need a volunteer to
infiltrate Santa Anna's camp;
assess the size and
readiness of his troops.
What say you?
I'd be awake, beast to hand, if I could.
Very good.
Yes, sir.
I want you to find out
if Emily West is there.
If she's in trouble, I
need you to get her out.
She can be high-strung,
but you strike me as a man who
can handle a spirited woman.
(Santa Anna) Very clever of
Houston to send you to spy on me.
(West) He tried to stop me.
I came on my own.
He tried to stop you?
I thought he barely noticed you were gone.
Well, we had a fiery affair.
It was a blaze so scorching,
it consumed itself,
then he grew cold to the touch.
I am cold.
Well, then, I must make certain
that you stay very, very warm.
Opium.
Romulo, bring the pipe.
"I have no fear of an army of lions
"led by your sheep,
but I do have fear of an army
of sheep led by your lion."
Alexander the Great.
Which one is he... a sheep or lion?
Well, is it me you want
or General Houston?
I have you.
Ah!
But do not think I am fooled.
I know that a sweet-scented yellow rose
like you has sharp thorns.
Perhaps on occasion,
but tonight...
I'm the one who's gonna be pricked.
[moans]
[drum and bugle corps playing]
♪ ♪
(man) Over there!
(man) I see 'em! We'll lead the line!
(Samuel Wallace) Wake up, boys. Wake up.
Wake up. Wake up.
We can hear 'em clicking and signaling.
It's time to get ready to
fight. Wake up. Wake up, boys.
- I hate this damned music.
- That's what they want.
[whistles]
[bullets whizzing]
[moaning]
Yance! Yance, I... I can't see!
- Help!
- I can't see!
- Somebody, we need bandages!
Help! Come on, buddy. Come on.
Am I gonna die?
No, no, no, no, you're not gonna die.
Come on. Come on, buddy.
- Am I gonna die?
- Come on, buddy.
- You're not gonna die!
No. You ain't!
[both shouting]
Come on!
Help me! Help!
Come on, partner.
We supposed to be heroes.
(Samuel Wallace) Come on, son.
- It ain't over yet.
- You're all right.
You've got yourself to look out for.
- Come on.
- I'll make it count.
Deaf and the Rangers
will get us out of this.
No, you stay with me. You'll die out there.
Rangers don't take no
orders from the damn army!
[boom]
I'm going for help! I'm... I'm going for...
It's all right. It's all
right. It's all right.
We're going, girl.
We're going. Come on, girl.
All right...
We're going to get Houston!
We're going to get General Houston!
♪ ♪
Pull the cannon. Advance the cannons!
[men shouting]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
(man) Nice shootin'.
♪ ♪
[jubilant music]
_
(man) Break camp.
Today's detail.
We sweep these valleys for
any wayward homesteaders.
That means you, Gator.
What do we do with him?
Nothing. He's being executed.
I reckon he can wait here shackled
till the firing squad come.
We ain't gonna wait.
He already run off when he
weren't gonna be executed.
No, no, no, no, gentlemen,
gentlemen, please.
I will wait for 'em. I will.
I will wait like you never
seen no one wait before.
Please, just carry on
with your duties and chores
and you can trust I ain't gonna do nothing
but stay right here, on my honor.
Let's shoot him.
Whoa, it's a damned shame
to kill a man for pilfering.
Man's got to eat, right?
Are we supposed to execute him?
Not a Ranger's job.
The army convicted him.
They shoot him.
May I just suggest...
I suggest you shut your hole.
(Knowles) I'm only saying
why not just take me with you?
Take me; make me do what-some-ever
you might need me to do.
I could... well... I
could carry your saddlebag.
- I could...
- That's enough.
[gunshot]
(Anderson) Rangers are not
executioners, you reprobate.
This man is right, if I may say so.
Making sure people's safe from Mexicans...
that's a whole hell of a lot more important
than shooting some no-account deserter
like myself.
I ain't worth it.
I ain't nowhere near worth it.
That's for damned sure.
Hell, you ain't even
worth the shot and powder.
You know what? You're
clearly a very smart man.
That's right. I am.
Still say we shoot him.
Well, well...
You agree not to rabbit off...
lend us a hand while we help
get these settlers to safety?
Course... innocent settler...
that was what I was doing before.
(Anderson) You do not
charge for your services.
- Right.
- No tricks.
No.
Or I will let Vern shoot you.
Yes, sir. I swear.
I swear.
But if I may just one...
make one last suggestion,
I still don't quite understand
how we can do something
and then not getting
anywhere near paid for it.
Just saying.
♪ ♪
You dug up the chest?
You and the little one are gonna need money
when you go to Victoria.
I'm not going anywhere without you.
Yes, you is.
Them Mexicans bastards are coming.
Deaf, I'm Mexican.
And so was I.
And now we's Texian.
Damn it.
[goats bleating]
Lupe...
[sighs]
You're right. I'm sorry.
That was very...
it was a poor choice of words.
But you ain't seen what I seen.
This ain't about us.
It's about a tyrant we can't abide by.
You know that.
Lupe.
I ain't seen Half Breed.
He comes and goes; got a mind of his own.
He's a smart dog...
knows when to get,
which is what you got to
do till we whoop Santa Anna.
And if you don't?
Well, then, it ain't gonna matter, Lupe.
We'll all be dead.
(Anderson) Shrewsbury, we are the Rangers!
We're here to help!
By order of the Texian government,
you must evacuate to safety.
Shrewsbury!
We gonna take a gander inside?
Let's send this hear wormy feller in.
It's high time he learned a
thing or two about rangering.
[laughter]
(Knowles) Wormy...
that's good. That's good.
I see what you're doing,
but the thing is, gentlemen.
I just ain't dumb,
so it ain't hard for me to see
there is no reason whatsoever
for me to go in there.
Ain't scared, is you?
Ho!
- You saying I's yellow?
- Yep.
- Youse born yellow.
- You saying I's...
Yellow as your damned shirt.
- Get on in there.
- Is that a fact?
All right, well...
I... y'all at least gonna give
me a damned pistol or something?
(Anderson) We got you covered.
(Knowles) All right.
Ah!
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
[door creaks]
"Gone for licker."
[clattering]
Who's that in there?
You best answer me!
The Rangers come to help!
♪ ♪
[pig squealing]
[gunshots]
Whoo-hoo! Whoo!
Damned pig 'bout broke my damned leg.
Whoa.
(Anderson) Is there anyone home?
You done good, Knowles.
Then again, it is starting to look a lot
like bacon and ham hocks for supper.
[laughs]
(man) Whoa.
- We got pork for supper.
- Whoo!
(Knowles) We gonna be
eating fine tonight. Hoo-hoo!
Truett and Yancey report in yet?
They haven't. I hadn't seen hide or hair.
We best report back to Houston.
Let's go.
♪ ♪
[ominous music]
Don't be too hard on 'em, Colonel.
They got their pride too.
I cannot offer you terms.
You must surrender at discretion.
If you won't grant their lives,
my men will keep killing Mexicans
until their last breath.
Surrender, Colonel.
I will see that your men are
fed and taken back to Goliad
as prisoners.
If you give me your assurance
that my men will be treated
under the rules of war.
I will appeal on your
behalf to General Santa Anna.
I suppose that's the best I can do.
I rely on your honest effort!
(Flores) Come on, Señor Beans.
[speaking Spanish]
(Gator) I think it's about time
to cut that up there, Beans.
We all might hungry over here.
Hey, I'm so starved I
could eat the south end
of a northbound goat, but it ain't ready.
Get your damned hand out of there.
Why don't you just hush
up? All of y'all hush up.
The only one that's gonna
be carving that porker
right there will be none other
than this gentleman right here.
Why? 'Cause who's the
one who flushed him out?
Who's the one who flushed him out?
Now, what I remember is this
little piggy flushing you out.
[laughter]
(Knowles) I can see you gentlemen
are doing your damnedest
to overlook the fact that I
risked me my damned behind.
That pretty little Señorita
that Truett and Yancey
are sweet on...
she must need comforting
with them boys gone.
Watch yourself, Vern.
You know that's Doc Ewing's daughter.
He married a Mexican?
Tejana.
Doc won't ever talk about it,
but she's not around no more.
Poor thing; no mama.
Don't pester that girl, Vern,
or her father will
shoot you where it hurts.
♪ ♪
Buenos tardes.
[chuckles]
That's all right. I got it.
You ought never to have
to work a day in your life.
Allow me.
This is how they do in the islands,
only they don't use no hands.
All right, just give me my basket.
And they dance the live long day.
Please, give me my basket now!
(Doc Ewing) Sarah!
Get your basket, Sarah, and get on inside.
Doc.
[whistling]
[indistinct chatter]
♪ My faith looks up to thee ♪
(all) ♪ Thou lamb of Calvary ♪
♪ Savior divine ♪
(man) General Portilla,
where are you taking my men?
I should be with them!
(Portilla) You couldn't keep up.
You will have to be shot like a lame horse.
General Urrea promised...
promised!
He does not speak for General Santa Anna.
He does not tolerate traitors.
If I am to be executed, I
will be shot in the chest
and buried like a Christian
in a box with a marker.
And I request that you
send this watch to my family
in Marion, Georgia.
If you were a soldier...
but you are a stinking wetback.
You swam across the Sabine River,
and you are here illegally
in my country.
[indistinct chatter]
(man) Keep walking.
♪ ♪
(man) General Urrea's
army is approaching Goliad.
(Houston) We got to get 'em out.
[drum and bugle corps playing]
♪ ♪
Any news from your boys at Goliad?
General, what are your orders?
We must do what's prudent;
not what emotion dictates.
Our enemy wants to
catch us out in the open,
where numbers count.
I can't risk us getting pincered
between Santa Anna's armies.
The order stands.
We will continue to withdraw east...
stretch out their supply
lines... pick our ground.
Withdraw, sir? The men
are already talking mutiny.
Let 'em talk while they retreat.
Yeah, but what about the dissidents
like Baker and Sherman?
- What should I tell them?
- Tell 'em to follow orders!
These boys have maybe...
maybe one battle in 'em.
If it comes at the wrong time,
we all die.
You men are in charge while I'm gone.
You're leaving, sir?
- Where to?
- Goliad.
I can't afford to lose those men.
- But, General...
- Drill the volunteers.
Discipline 'em. Make 'em an army.
That is all. Rally the Rangers.
I am personally pulling Fannin's head
out of his puckered West Point ass.
You heard the man.
Let's make an army.
[indistinct chatter]
♪ ♪
They said they were putting
us on a boat to Matamoros.
This road's to Victoria.
I don't think they're
taking us to either place.
(man) Take water.
♪ ♪
(man) Water!
[indistinct chatter]
(man) Drink up. Drink up.
All right.
Orderly, men.
Orderly.
Single file line;
we will all get our water.
We're not animals.
(Wallace) Come get your water.
Water, men... single file line.
[bugle playing]
[indistinct chatter]
What is going on?
Fellas, kneel!
People won't forget what you're doing here.
Aim!
They're gonna remember this,
and they're gonna remember the Alamo.
Remember the Alamo.
(all) Remember the Alamo!
Remember the Alamo!
Fire!
[gunfire]
[man groaning]
left, right, left, right, left, right...
(man) Houston needs to cease wasting time
with these exercises
and march us to Goliad,
otherwise we'll have a repetition of Alamo.
I do believe if President
Burnet knew of our situation,
it'd be a different story.
- Mm-hmm.
- Again, Sergeant. Again.
Mosley Baker... suggestion?
(Lamar) Sir!
Private Lamar...
I volunteered to fight for Texas,
not march in a damned Easter parade.
Is that right?
Private Lamar, report here now!
We will not tolerate insolent behavior!
This is Mirabeau Lamar.
He's secretly circulating a
petition to remove Houston.
Sir?
Private Lamar... please.
You may sit.
Private Lamar, we had a crisis
with our gutless commander,
and we understand you are of a like mind.
We need to get a urgent message
to Secretary of War Rusk.
Can you do that?
They may not know how to march,
but trust me, they know how to argue.
Colonel Seguin, despite
our poor marching abilities,
take comfort in knowing that
the men's hatred for Santa Anna
binds us together.
And so does their hatred for Sam Houston.
(man) The horses are tuckered.
There's a water hole
right around that bend.
♪ ♪
Charmaine could use a nice
drink and a good graze,
couldn't you, old girl?
Captain, it seems like you love that horse
more than you do your wife.
Hey, Deaf, who's a better mount:
your wife or your horse?
A horse.
He sure does love that horse.
I see; you're having a nice jest
at the expense of my impairment.
The good thing is I don't need
to hear no disparaging nonsense
from the likes of you.
You have something to say that matters,
you best say to my fast.
That's all right, Captain.
No sense in getting all hot and bothered.
Hey, I'm just wondering who bucks harder.
[laughter]
- What'd he say?
- Nothing.
[indistinct chatter]
(Baker) The Union's impositions
have negative repercussions
for the individuals of Texas.
Texas must be a sovereign nation.
President Jackson
supports western expansion
all the way to the coast.
Then why doesn't he send his troops?
Because this way,
Jackson is free to let
Texas into the Union,
and lead a clear, militaristic path
all the way to California.
Your blind ignorance
never ceases to amaze me.
Old Hickory is bound by treaty.
He can't just invade Mexico
and invite the likes of
the Spaniards and the French
and the crusty Brits to intervene.
This is different, gentlemen.
This is Texas.
- Hey, Texas is part of Mexico.
- Yeah.
What do you think we're fighting for, huh?
Yeah, but this is where
you're wrong, Colonel Seguin.
With Houston as our general,
we don't do much fighting.
(Houston) Robert Knowles,
you're not hiding from
your general, are you?
(Knowles) [laughs]
No, no, sir, I was just...
Yes, sir, I was trying to hide
from you, General Houston, sir.
I... yes.
I have my eye on you.
You rangering now?
He prefers it to the firing squad.
How's he doing?
Passable.
Ain't tried to run off.
I'm with Vern.
I say we shoot him.
- I tried, General.
- He did.
Be happy to try again.
[laughter]
We let him ride with us.
We didn't know what else to do with him.
(Houston) Robert, what qualities
do you possess to commend
you for a pardon?
He don't got no good qualities.
Hell no.
Qualities, sir... qualities.
Well, I like this part of
the country a whole lot.
I like the air around here.
I like... I do.
I like breathing it in, and then,
I like sleeping under the stars as well.
And, oh, I like breathing the
air while I'm sleeping under...
Knowles,
can't you think of anything
good to say about yourself?
No.
Damn it, I promise you, General Houston,
I do not care about nobody but myself.
I am bull-headed, and
I'm ornery as a snake.
Ornery?
Ornery's good.
Yep.
Ornery's not bad for rangering company.
- Ornery!
- Ornery.
Right? Let's ride out, boys.
Vern's the orneriest son of a bitch I know.
Yes, he is.
Ornery.
♪ ♪
Whoo!
_
You gonna cook them taters
or make a necklace out of
'em to wear with your skirt?
I bet you dyspepsia is not unknown to you.
Can't say I know him.
Oh.
You know what, Hays?
You remind me of my big brother Samuel.
I'm chagrined by the
notion of any resemblance
to myself and any pack
member of the Wallace species.
Well, don't get the big head on me.
You don't look more alike
than me and a mule's ass.
Well, dead ringers, then...
uncanny.
Sammy's got a way about him.
Horse sense, I guess you'd call it.
I see a lot of him in you.
This can stand to stew a bit yet.
When we was growing up,
Sammy saved my sorry butt more than once.
Ward off the bullies, did he?
Oh, hell no... made me whoop 'em.
If I hadn't, he'da whooped me worse.
I sense our kinship.
Hey, you sass me all you want
with that highbrow blather,
but I am paying you one
hell of a compliment.
If your brother's half the man you are,
we're gonna be good friends.
[laughs]
Taters could've used another five minutes
on the coals.
[birds squawking]
[foreboding music]
♪ ♪
Ah!
[indistinct chatter]
_
(man) Careful with that.
Those are the president's belongings.
Hurry up. No time to waste.
President Burnet?
President Burnet is busy.
I need to see the president.
Santanistas just burned Bellville.
(man) Señor, I said you can't come in.
(Lamar) Mr. President,
I'm here under urgent dispatch
of Colonel Mosley Baker.
It is my duty to present this petition
- from your rank and file.
- And you would be?
Private Mirabeau Bonaparte
Lamar... Fairfield, Georgia, sir.
Spit it out, boy.
We got to go before Santa Anna gets here.
Houston will not engage.
Rusk, why won't your men meet the enemy?
- 'Cause he's a damned coward.
- Houston may be many things,
but a coward he is not.
Then what in the name of
God is that man's soul?
I presume General Houston
is picking his ground, sir.
Forgive me Mister
Secretary, Mister President.
I desperately insist you come to the front.
I feel we face a mass desertion.
Look around you, son.
The Santanistas are half
a day's ride from here.
We've abandoned the capitol,
and I'm on the run again.
Now, if I am captured or killed,
this rebellion is finished.
Francisco, we're on our way
to New Orleans to set up
a provisional government.
Now, Rusk, you go tell
Houston that both his troops
and the enemy are laughing him to scorn.
He must fight, or I'll
find someone who will.
Yes, sir.
- Francisco, let's go!
- Yes, sir.
(Burnet) Get everyone out
before the Mexicans get here!
(Rusk) All right, young man,
I want to hear every detail.
(Lamar) A petition signed by each
and every man under General Houston
to relieve him of his command...
♪ ♪
[goat bleats]
(Lorca) Lucifer himself is
risen from the bowels of Hades
to tear the turgid flesh
off the bones of all Mexicans...
pluck their eyes and eat their livers,
till their wretched screams
for the angel of death
deafen this godforsaken Earth!
Who are you?
(Lorca) I am the punishment,
here to spite every jumping bean lubricano,
man, woman, and child
from the Texas plains!
This is war, not a crusade.
Had you witnessed the
abominations at the Alamo
and Goliad, you'd think differently.
Goliad?
Damned crazy bastard, speak plain.
They're all dead... murdered.
300 slain... slaughtered after surrender.
So much blood the air
turned to a crimson mist.
Two of my Rangers boys were there.
One had red hair.
The other one rode a big black gelding.
What of them?
Got ambushed.
Shot by so many bullets, shred the skin
clean off their bodies...
splintered their skulls beyond recognition.
All the bodies lay as they fell,
left to rot for the
buzzards and the maggots!
By what right do you have to do this?
I claim the ancient right
by my own death denied
and my brethren butchered!
Your account of Goliad...
I'll need more than a lunatic's word.
I answer to neither man nor God.
There's Chupaldo, Santa Anna's courier.
Why don't you ask him for his account?
Best make haste... fresh
dispatch from Santa Anna himself.
I am a servant to Lucifer!
Death to all brown-skinned Mexican demons!
[flies buzzing]
_
[indistinct chatter]
[woman crying]
Don Antonio, Burnet has just
escaped with his hand rush.
We were only moments too late.
The bite of the flames,
the sting of the smoke...
don't you feel it?
Feel what, sir?
Death.
Are you hot, Almonte?
Aye.
The flesh of victory
and the cries of the dying...
does it not excite you?
What an ordinary man
feels as pain or revulsion
a real soldier must
learn to feel as pleasure.
This is war,
and the truth is, we enjoy it.
[people screaming]
Our enemies are rabble.
The public's gratitude is uncertain.
The politicians: fickle at best.
A moment like this one...
victory gives purpose
to all our sacrifices...
our suffering.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[woman screams]
Jose.
Madam, come with me. Come.
Come. Come. Come. Come. Come.
(Karnes) There is little
more I can add, Mrs. Fincham,
excepting that Truett and
Yancey accounted for themselves
in this campaign with...
what's the fancy word for cojones?
I reckon "valor" is pretty good.
With valor.
You ought to be proud of your son,
as the Rangers hold them in highest regard.
Sincerely, H. Barns.
They was good boys.
Now, read that all back
to me from the start.
It ought to be suitable.
Youse hungry, ain't you?
So hungry my belly button's
gnawing on my backbone.
Go ahead.
(man) That crazy old coot.
I ain't seen nothing like him in
the good lord's Christian world.
Did you see his eyes?
- His... they were dead.
- Oh, yeah.
Just dead... like chunks of black coal.
I don't recall the bible talking
about a demon of his ilk.
Lorca.
- What?
- Lorca.
Lorca?
What is that, some
Injun name for Beelzebub?
(Anderson) It's Cayuga legend.
In ancient times, there
was an Atikapan warrior
who was killed in battle without honor,
and when his spirit rose,
it peeled off the skin
of his barbarian enemies,
and the sun burned them until...
their insides were crisp.
Sweet Jesus, that's what he did.
All right, just so you fellows know,
we chance on his like again,
I will likely soil myself straight away.
Oh, that's more than likely in your case.
I'm not at all sure this
rangering business suits me.
If'n these jackasses won't say it, I will.
That lickspittle Knowles was right.
Our cause is lost, damn it.
The onliest thing we're gonna
find in Texas is our graves.
Turn and run, huh? Is that it, Vern?
Hell no. Turn, run, and fornicate.
Texas is fine country, but Texican women...
they're so ugly they'd back
a buzzard off a gut wagon.
I'd sooner service a sow.
I'd best get back to Paris.
Ooh, Paris, huh? Paris.
In Paris, the missies paint their faces
like dolls, wear bodices,
make their teats spill out,
and the clincer is, they perfume their quim
to smell just like lilac.
You are a sinner, Vern,
marked by a terrible stain.
- Now, your British wench...
- Mm-hmm?
She kind of fleshy...
stinks a little when she sweats,
and she gonna sweat
plenty when I'm riding her.
Course, your best poke, now, in my opinion,
is ports of call of Spain.
Spain?
You been to Spain too, huh?
Don't interrupt.
All right. Continue.
Them skinny little dark-eyed gypsy girls
twirl around on your
pecker like a butter churn.
Yeah, well, you come near my sisters,
and I will shoot your
lecherous ass graveyard-dead.
And you best not so much
as glance at Rebecca,
that sweet young thing
we rescued at Gonzales.
I don't care one stringy
bean for that 7x9 gal.
Come with me, kid.
We'll catch a schooner out of New Orleans
with some of my old swabbies.
We ain't gonna do nothing
here but die young.
[soft music]
♪ ♪
[people shouting]
[lively music playing]
♪ ♪
[cheers and applause]
[gunshot]
Sir, it now seems unlikely
the Texans will prevail,
_
especially since Houston's at
odds with his officer corps.
Damned Texans.
Been at odds with them myself.
So Mister President, should we advise
the Texans to relieve
General Houston of Command?
As long as I've lived,
I've been a keen judge of horse flesh.
What clenches it for me is
just staring in the horse's eyes
and letting him tell me who he is.
I first looked into Sam Houston's eyes
at the Battle of Horseshoe.
He was 19 years old...
first on the line, first on the assault,
first to be marked for death.
I did not propose to understand him,
but if there's a way to defeat Santa Anna,
the only man capable of
doing so is Sam Houston,
except for me, of course.
All right there, Charmaine.
Good night, girl.
[coughing]
God knows I wanted to
be wrong about Fannin.
Goldarn it.
Deaf...
I'm hungry for counsel.
I'd welcome yours.
Well, one thing Santa Anna's done...
he's let every Texian know
that to surrender means death.
Don't run from him no more.
Fight him like Comanches.
You stay close... so close
he can feel your breath.
You let him know you're always
there and he can't touch you.
Sooner or later, he's gonna
show you his tender underbelly,
and when he does,
you take that sword of yours
and you sink it to the hilt.
You slit him through and through.
Well, that's all well and good.
What about his other
generals and their armies?
Cut the head off the snake, the body dies.
[chuckles]
(man) How do you know this, Francisco?
(Francisco) I heard it from
President Burnet's own mouth.
He's fleeing to New Orleans
by way of Galveston Bay.
(Santa Anna) And Houston...
What is his position?
Somewhere west of the
Sabine River below Gonzales.
Rumors say that he's crazy
and his troops are mutinous.
Burnet ordered Houston
to meet you on the field.
(Santa Anna) That's
exactly where I want him.
We will divide the army
into multiple divisions
to pursue and destroy what's
left of the rebel army.
(Almonte) General,
if you will indulge me...
our many great victories
have been because we maintain
an overwhelming force.
His Excellency's strategy is brilliant.
Ha.
(Almonte) What about President Jackson?
How can we be certain
that he will not intervene?
(Santa Anna) Almonte, Old
Hickory hides behind treaties...
moves in shadows.
His stole Florida from
Spain and claims Texas
was part of the Louisiana Purchase.
Texas is the pathway to the Pacific.
Jackson wants it all...
all the way to California.
Francisco, I reward results.
Bring me news.
Yes, Your Excellency.
(Santa Anna) Get back to your president!
[gasps]
♪ ♪
[laughter]
[mysterious music]
♪ ♪
A woman with full, meaty arms.
I like that! [laughs]
Be careful, my friend.
She's the Presidente General's property.
Hey, I know you.
You are Manuel Flores.
It is me, Hector Ribaldo.
We played cards. Remember? I won.
I was proud to take your money
'cause you joined the filthy rebels.
You mistake me for someone else.
No. I am quite certain.
You are a traitorous spy.
[grunts]
Meet me back here tonight at
the changing of the night guard.
- Yes.
- I have vital news.
- Yes. All right.
- Go.
(man) For Mexico!
(man) Presidente...
[indistinct chatter]
[laughs]
Everybody pays Francisco.
[clucking]
You pay me.
The rebel Presidente Burnet pays me.
[laughs]
Even His Excellency Santa Anna himself.
Everyone pays me.
Soon, that pirate Houston will pay me too.
Whoa!
I almost pissed myself.
[laughs]
♪ ♪
Francisco.
Who's that?
[groans]
This is how Houston pays spies.
[birds chirping]
[man snoring]
[dramatic guitar flourish]
♪ ♪
Oh!
Come on. [shushes]
Howdy.
♪ ♪
Come on, Ruthie! Let's get!
Got me a wrist cuff! Whoo-hoo!
(man) Mount up, you dang slowpoke!
Oh... oh, shit!
Forget the damned horse. We got to get!
My horse! They stole my horse.
[grunts]
(Wallace) It's a long walk to Goliad.
(Flores) Go. Go. Go.
Go east to Houston's army.
God bless you.
Look out for Comanches.
[indistinct chatter]
[men singing in Spanish]
Flores.
- We have no time.
- We go now.
I'd be better use to Texas staying here.
Hey, you're coming with me...
General Houston's orders.
I don't answer to him.
If you want to kill Santa
Anna, you will need this.
You may lose your life.
What life?
I'm a Negro born out of
punishment to my mammy,
growed up to be a whore.
Tell the general Santa Anna's
pursuing him personally.
It's an obsession.
Give him these.
He'll know. Be vigilant.
Be safe. Hurry.
(Flores) Get back before Santa Anna wakes.
(Wallace) Sticks in my craw... them
trash got off with my wrist cuff.
You're out a trinket.
I'm on foot. All right.
That was a blooded thoroughbred
those wastrels took.
Raised him from a colt, I did.
That's why you got your mind
set on walking all the way to Goliad?
Do I have a choice?
And that was no trinket, hard case.
It was a precious family
heirloom made by my pa
for me and my brother.
[soft music]
♪ ♪
Still damp.
She's bleeding out.
Pissant she-devil bitch...
I hope so.
♪ ♪
[flies buzzing]
Psst! Psst! Psst!
Come on!
(Hays) You got your wish.
(Wallace) She wearing my wrist cuff?
No.
Pissant bitch.
You sure you don't want a ride?
I told you; two grown
men can't ride double.
It ain't dignified.
Oh, you want dignity or blisters?
Come on. Yah.
_
[dramatic music]
[all shouting]
Comanches! Comanches!
My rifle!
[all shouting]
(Houston) Hold your fire!
Hold your fire.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I'm gonna be massacred by Comanches.
Shit, they ain't gonna take me alive.
Son of a bitch, let's open up on 'em!
(Houston) You'll follow orders!
[all shouting]
[speaking native language]
(Anderson) [speaking native language]
Fire on me if we fall dead.
Anderson talks Injun?
You just figured that out?
I thought he was kidnapped
by 'em when he was a boy.
You can smell the stinking savage on him.
Steady.
Tell him I'm a chieftain.
- He's aware.
- Good.
Tell him to kill me.
I don't think that's a good idea
with me standing next to you and all.
Go ahead.
Kill me,
if you want war the likes
the Comanches have never seen.
My death brings Yankee
soldiers like buffalo herds.
The croaking raven doth bellow for revenge.
Shakespeare does not
translate into Comanche.
[grunts]
[speaking native language]
He said that the Cherokee
call you the Raven,
but the Comanche call you Wild Turkey
because you drape
yourself in foolish colors
and you lose your head
when the coyote come.
What the hell they saying?
You'd prefer not knowing.
I would.
[shrieks]
[all shrieking]
[speaking native language]
If the Mexicans don't kill you, he will.
[shrieks]
[all shrieking]
Huh!
He's hardly 16 and he's already
got two scalps on his lance.
Friend of yours?
His name's Yellow Knife.
He's my son.
First wagon sets that side of the line!
Single file all the way to Nueces River!
[indistinct chatter]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
(man) Make sure of your spokes.
Make sure your water
barrels is full to the hilt!
We pull out for the [inaudible] in an hour!
You ain't ready, you're on your own!
(man) The Santanistas are killing everyone!
Flee for your lives!
Make that a 1/2 hour!
Let's go! Come on! Come on!
Go! Go!
Go!
They're coming!
Yah! Yah!
[horses whinny]
♪ ♪
(Pauline Wykoff) Everyone's skidaddling.
We're a long cry from Saint Louis.
(James Wykoff) Took everything
we had to get us this far.
Whoa.
There ain't nothing for us back home.
I told you the day we left,
I'd follow you to the ends of the Earth.
Well, this just might be it.
(Pauline Wykoff) Should
we turn and head back?
(man) No refunds!
Yes, sir; I'm a tracking
impresario Buckley.
And you're tracking me.
What can I do for you?
No refunds... as I've stated.
Yes, sir.
I'm looking to...
interested in a land grant.
With everyone leaving, why are you here?
- You running from the law?
- No, sir.
I'm interested in making a fresh start,
and getting some good land,
and now, I understand that the Mexican army
is driving all the Americans out.
Honest settlers have nothing to fear.
President Santa Anna
protects all legal landowners.
It's the thieving squatters
and revolutionaries that get shot.
I see.
Do you sweat allegiance
to the Republic of Mexico?
Yes, sir. For 6¢ an acre, I surely do.
I can grant 170 acres for farming,
but no whiskey brewing, gun
running, tobacco smuggling,
or frontier riff-raffing.
Oh, no, sir. I mean, yes, sir.
By law, improvements must be made timely,
but you've been shot in
the flanks with good luck.
There's a property
cleared with a sturdy cabin
on it ready to farm.
I can let you have it for 7 1/2¢ an acre.
You can pay on time, cash or trade.
Course, I favor cash.
Well, I was hoping to pay a
percentage of my crop yield.
That your big slave yonder?
Yep.
Mm, that Sambo's half the
down payment right here.
Oh, well, I'm gonna need Nate
to help me plough the field,
I mean, so's I can pay you.
But I was hoping to pay you
10% of my first year's yield,
then 20% every year thereafter.
I'll make an exception.
But don't tell nobody...
special circumstance, 'cause
I tend to favor a family man.
But at the very least, I'll need you to put
the negro up as collateral.
I can also allocate another
440 acres for ranching.
Ranching?
Comes from the Spaniards.
Cattle roam free, proliferate,
then sold on the hoof.
Mexicans been doing it for near 100 years.
No, I mean, farmland...
that's what I'm after.
Name?
Wykoff... James Wykoff.
Wykoff. What's your religion?
Well, now, my wife is
a hard-shelled Baptist.
Mexico only recognizes
those of Catholic faith.
Being a Catholic's not too bad;
you know, a priest instead of a preacher.
Well, then, we'll do right by him, Mister.
Signature.
- It's, uh...
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Welcome to Mexico.
- Thank you.
- [laughs]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[flies buzzing]
(Wallace) My God, Jack.
Oh no.
♪ ♪
[thunder rumbles in distance]
[mouthing]
Where you planning on heading now?
With you, I reckon.
Join up with the Texian army.
I figure it's what your brother
Samuel would want us to do.
[soft, pleasant music]
♪ ♪
(Wallace) I must say you're
looking mighty dignified.
Yeah, well, I'd sooner ride
on a burro than with an ass.
Smells a lot better too.
I will rectify the stink upon arrival
to Buckley's way station.
I can only hope, but I fear
that the ass will linger.
♪ ♪
[laughing]
(Wallace) You're riding
that thing pretty well.
(Baker) Remember that
the author of all this woe
is tyrant Santa Anna,
and Sam Houston does nothing.
(man) I know your families are suffering.
I know that I brought you here not to run,
but to fight...
to stand and fight!
(all) Stand and fight!
Stand and fight!
Stand and fight! Stand and fight!
(Baker) Now is the time to avenge
the blood of our fallen heroes!
Remember to nerve yourselves for battle
knowing that our cause is just,
and that our code words will be,
"Remember the Alamo!"
(all) Stand and fight!
Stand and fight! Stand and fight!
Patriots. Patriots, listen!
We must stand by General Houston.
General Houston needs to
stand his ground and fight!
He needs to stand and fight!
(all) Stand and fight!
Stand and fight! Stand and fight!
Stand and fight!
(man) I order you men to disperse now!
(all) Stand and fight! Stand and fight!
(man) Disperse!
Disperse now!
(all) Stand and fight!
(man) Now!
(Baker) Remember the next time
Sam Houston orders a grave dug...
- Make way.
- It will be his very own.
(Houston) Cold water
will cool that hot head.
Have you no shame, sir?
You can beat us, but you cannot silence us.
Stand and fight.
(all) Stand and fight!
Stand and fight! Stand and fight!
[gunshot]
Y'all need to cool down,
'cause we's all that's left.
Colonel Fannin and his men are gone.
God damn it to hell.
Goliad is no more.
Fannin disobeyed ordered.
His army did not survive because of it.
Should we do the same...
fight each other,
disobey our General?
And you, General,
will you lead your men?
I feel your scorn,
and I know I'm the reason for your dissent
when our cause can least afford it.
I was broken when I came to Texas.
I failed at my marriage
and turned my back on
the people of Tennessee.
I took refuge among the Cherokee
and failed them too.
I disappointed my family...
tarnished their good name.
I will atone for all
that when my time comes,
but I am no longer that man,
and the reason is Texas.
My heart beats strong again.
My head is clear. I see
a future beckoning us.
I did not ask to be your general.
I was asked by our government to lead you.
Now, I ask you to follow me east
where I believe victory awaits us,
for God has willed that
no tyrant will ever rule.
Follow me a little longer
down this twisted, bloody road,
and I will prove it to you.
By God, I'll prove it.
[crying]
[somber music]
♪ ♪
Holy Father, please watch
over Truett and Yancey.
I miss them.
♪ ♪
[cries softly]
Come to relieve me, Tom?
It has been discussed.
Before we are outnumbered
why don't we attack?
Your insubordination
could have cost us dearly.
Death before betrayal.
The worst we must do lies yet
ahead, judge me as you will.
What do you need this for?
Let me introduce Daphne
and her equally pretty sister Penelope.
Alright then let's see how fast we can get
one of them sisters ready.
[BOOM]
There was a shooting.
And you gonna tell me you are
all just innocent bystanders?
Necessity requires your help.
Comanches.
We end it all now.
Shoot me first.
You don't think I will?
Tomorrow we march!
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -