[MAN WHOOPING]
[WHOOPING]
Hyah!
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[BRAKES SQUEALING]
Whoa!
Heard your paper was running
an honest race.
You heard right,
Mr. Gebhardt.
Who in the hell handicapped
this owl-head as a favorite?
- The smart money.
- That's what we come to get.
Deal.
[WHINNIES]
[COYOTE BARKING]
[COYOTE HOWLING]
[SHOUTS]
[HORSE GROANS]
[COYOTE HOWLING]
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, boy. Whoa.
Whoa. You're all right.
Yeah. She's all finished, boy.
Yeah, she's all finished.
Whoa.
[COYOTE HOWLING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[CROSSING BELL CLANGING]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
Just--
Must be the dude from London.
How's he gonna win a 700-mile
race sitting on a postage stamp?
- He won't win.
- Wonderful journey. Wonderful.
Miss Jones? Reporter
for the Western Press.
You the one said
I wouldn't show up?
In this case,
I'm pleased to be wrong.
In that case,
pleased to meet you.
[TRAIN ENGINE CHUGGING]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING IN DISTANCE]
Don't never touch me.
Never.
Morning.
How much?
Civil War? South?
Yeah.
These days, medals from
losers is worth nothing.
No offense, mister. Giddyap!
[CLICKS TONGUE]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
Three's bet.
Check.
Two-fifty?
Call
Two pair.
You drew to an inside straight?
Go ahead and take yours.
I think it's rather sporting.
[LAUGHS]
I hope your horse
doesn't run as lucky.
My horse is the luckiest horse
in the West,
but he never plays
cards for money.
We've had more than 60 letters to the
editor asking why is a woman in the race.
Written by men?
Mostly women. They figure you
must have a special reason.
Two thousand reasons.
REPORTER:
How about you, Mr. Carbo?
Can your horse stand up
against thoroughbreds?
My bronco only has to be
half as good as them hotbloods...
'cause I'm twice as good
as these old-bloods.
I've never been committed
to defeat quite so tactfully.
This race will be won
by a horse, not a mouth.
Won by a bronco.
No thoroughbred has the speed,
wind or bottom of a mustang.
Not for 700 miles...
and that includes your Arabian.
Five thousand dollars.
My horse against the field.
- Even money?
GEBHARDT: How much?
Three thousand.
I'll cover the rest.
There's plenty more if you're game.
One game at a time,
Mr. Parker.
Where is this great horse
of his anyway?
Coming aboard next stop.
Good to have you with us.
Thank you.
- Mr. Parker-
- Where the hell is my horse?
Mr. Parker, meet-
You. You seen my horse?
Was she here?
Supposed to be.
Was I supposed to see her?
You can't miss her.
She's got champion
written all over her.
Oh, I see.
That explains everything.
I don't read.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Hold your damn horses!
[WHISTLE CONTINUES]
We're running late.
You're not leaving
without my horse.
You know the rules,
Mr. Parker.
The hell with your rules.
[MOOING]
Afternoon. Can you spare some
milk for a hungry orphan?
Yeah, here you go.
He don't know anything but his ma's tit.
[HORSE WHINNIES IN DISTANCE]
You like horses?
You got one of your own?
You want one?
You got one then.
Don't I gotta pay somethin'?
Yep.
Don't ever treat him bad.
You're in the big time.
I'm in the shithouse.
♪ [FANFARE]
[RINGING]
[SCATTERED GUNFIRE]
[CHEERING]
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
Out.
For what?
Hustling. That's a crime?
They're all hustlers.
They work for me. You don't.
That makes it a crime.
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
Hyah! Hyah!
[ENGINE REVVING]
Ride 'im, cowboy! Ride 'im, cowboy!
Ride 'im!
[MAN SHOUTING, INDISTINCT]
[WHOOPING]
Whoo! Whiskey for me and
a beer for my horse.
Hey, Slim, how ya doin'?
Cowboy always tends
to his horse first.
Mwah!
Telegraph Chicago. You're covered,
$15,000 at seven-to-five.
Twelve thousand
in Kansas City, even money.
Call of fall bets. Can't be done, baby.
It's play or pay.
Get through to my son.
On his way, Mr. Parker.
He'll be here before dark.
Mr. Parker, your father
left about an hour ago.
What about Tripoli? Did he show yet?
No, sir.
Damn stupid, $40,000 bet on a missing
horse in the hands of a damn fool.
Two important regulations.
[MEN SHOUTING]
Win!
Rule one-
Rule one,
each horse must carry...
no less than 160 pounds,
including rider, saddle
and extras.
Rule two, you'll be issued
a compass and a map...
for every leg of the race.
On it, you'll find
the safest route.
You don't have to take it.
You do have to
make every checkpoint.
Miss one, you're disqualified
Out of the race.
Any questions?
Jump-off time,
6:00 in the morning.
[MAN WHOOPING]
Hey, British.
- Drink to the winner.
- Thank you.
I haven't really won
the race yet, however-
Damn fine shooting, sir.
- The best, right?
- If you say so.
What do you say, Pop?
Never saw a man yet that could
hold his liquor like a bottle.
Hey, you.
What's your name?
What do you say?
[HORSESHOE SPLASHES, SIZZLES]
You're pretty good
calling a poker hand.
You care to call this hand?
You gonna pass?
Nobody wants to play.
Yo, Tex?
Yo?
Fetch a jackass.
Anybody killed?
just a quart.
Ya done right.
A boy lookin' for a reputation
is the most dangerous thing alive.
It certainly wasn't
worth dying for.
What is?
Even if you do it,
what's it going to prove?
Proves I can do it.
That's what it proves.
Ha-ha!
MAN: Ya-hoo!
- [LAUGHING]
- All right!
That yer jackass?
Nope.
Well, it ain't
your business-
You never heard
of Sam Clayton.
Champion of dumb animals, ladies in
distress, lost kids and lost causes
How ya been?
Fine till you come along.
You want it sudden?
Drag it out.
Palm Sunday.
Goddamn.
Matthew.
Chapter five, verse 44.
[GROANS]
[BOTH PANTING]
Just like old times.
Yeah. You start trouble
and I start bleeding.
- Get up, damn it!
- Palm Sunday's over.
Hurts, don't it?
Something personal?
Mm-hmm.
My eyes ain't
as good as his'n.
I might miss
and then you'd be dead,
and I'd be out of the race
for abusin' a dumb animal.
Bad for you, worse for me.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
Okay, Pop.
You look like
a man of property.
Well, when I shook you,
my luck changed.
Yeah, big things, huh?
New things.
Easy livin'?
Right.
Well, who wants easy living?
I do.
You- You're fired.
Your job was to get J.B.'s
horse on that train.
That was your job!
Much obliged.
You gave all the others
a 70-mile advantage!
She was handled real easy, Mr:
Parker: Perfect condition.
Then she'll win.
If she coulda won before
today, she'll still win.
Except for one thing-
Me.
And me.
Me too.
You'll need movin' money.
Who said I'm movin'?
Stayin' takes even more money.
I got a month's pay comin'.
A hot bath costs five dollars.
Yeah?
I guess I just won't bathe.
Takes $15 just to get drunk.
I'm gonna stay sober.
Thirty dollars
for an all-night woman.
Seventy miles
in six hours, eh?
Could he go 100 miles
every day for a week?
Uh-huh. That might be
enough to win this race.
I came 5,000 miles to try it.
Why?
To beat the best.
[CHUCKLES] Mister, you must
be either rich or crazy.
[LAUGHING] A little
of both, I'm afraid.
I came 3,000 miles
for the Kentucky Derby.
Another 2,000 to see Joe
Gans box Battling Nelson.
Forty-two fantastic rounds.
It was bloody marvelous!
You know who won?
I'm not interested.
Not interested who won?
That's not only unbelievable,
it's positively un-American.
What does interest you?
Right now?
just a jo
What did Parker pay you?
Fifty dollars a month? Sixty?
You win this race and you'll
get three years' pay.
What's the horse
get out of it?
Colic? Cracked bones?
Did you ever see a horse run himself
dead just to please the man on his back?
What for? Get his
picture in the paper?
For glory?
Some men live for it.
Horse don't give a damn
who wins the race.
Me neither.
[BELL CLANGING]
In the interest of the West's
greatest horse, the bronco,
and myself, who grows 'em,
I'm putting up an extra $1,000
to the bronco rider who wins!
[MEN CHEERING, CLAPPING]
¿Señor dentista?
Matthews,
I'd like a chance...
to win back some
of my dad's money.
I figured you would.
Well, how do you like the joint?
It ain't Kansas City.
Would you believe so many chumps
in the middle of Nowhere, U.S.A.?
Like shooting fish
in a barrel.
Nice, fat suckerfish.
All you need is the right bait, Rosie.
Well, it takes more than a deck
of cards and a pair of knockers.
Horse race pulled 'em in. This
crowd, their hustle's the fast buck.
What's yours?
Same.
And if you don't win,
which you won't,
I'll lend you the 2,000.
You can work it off
in Kansas City.
Bang, bang,
you're in the chips.
At $20 a bang, out of which you get half,
that's one hell of a lot of bangin'.
It's a hell of a lot easier on your
ass than 700 miles in a saddle.
The money's for Steve.
He won't care
how you got it.
Rosie, how many times
you been married?
Eleven. Ten without
a preacher or license.
Well, did you love any of 'em?
Oh, all of 'em.
Every one of 'em.
The good and the bad.
It's a shame to waste all that prime beef
on a guy servin' three-to-five in a prison.
You two keep in touch?
Uh, he's kind of
a lousy letter writer.
Lousy bank robber too.
Yeah.
[LAUGHING]
Thank you.
Tengo un dolor muy fuerte aquí.
You have anything
for a toothache?
Latest thing in miracles.
Heroin.
One of these painkillers
with a chaser of whiskey,
four hours of joy-house.
Have you tried
this heroin yourself?
Mister, I tried everything
except confession.
Even God wouldn't believe it.
Hey, miss? Beer.
Una píldora
cada cuatro horas...
con whiskey.
Salud.
Salud
Rosie?
Oh, ha, ha!
Rosie!
Oh, oh.
I've forgotten how good
a bad woman feels.
Oh, flattery and money
will get you anything!
Two of the best
for two of the best.
¿Como está?
Truly... a wonderment.
Maravilla.
[LAUGHS]
Here, have a little touch.
Whiskey.
You drink with greasers?
Only senoritas.
My grandpa was Mexican.
Yeah, I bathed that old man
every day till he died.
It's a funny thing though. I never
did find a greasy spot on him.
Pure Mex ain't bad.
Breed- you can smell it.
Well, that must be why I can't smell it.
I'm half Cherokee.
OLD COWBOY:
I'm a squaw man myself
Anybody pays, gets drinks. Anybody
don't like it, throw 'em out.
Mr. Matthews?
Business.
Hey, miss-
I'll miss your company.
♪ ♪ ["YANKEE DOODLE "]
[TAPPING]
Ninth and final entry:
Clayton, riding a coldblood
Attention!
For all contestants,
everything is on the house,
except booze, betting and bawds.
♪ [RESUMES]
[CHUCKLING]
What else is there?
Ahh!
We've got a problem.
We both can't win.
No, that's not
the problem.
The problem is
I can't afford to lose.
Who won the Gans-Nelson fight?
Gans, on a foul
in the 42nd round.
It was the greatest fight I ever
saw in my life. Black or white.
Won me $300, which I ran into $2,000-
most of it old Parker's money.
[CHUCKLING]
Anyway-
You know- You know
I'm un-American?
What's that?
Well, I don't know exactly.
Except if you're not the best,
or the first and the greatest,
if you don't win,
then you're not American.
Which brings us
to the problem.
You know, I didn't even know
that Joe Gans was a black man.
I just bet everything on this race.
I got seven-to-one.
You bet two-goddamn-thousand
dollars-
[CHUCKLING]
On yourself?
Well, who else?
Well, that's not so serious.
[CHUCKLES]
All you got to do is just beat J.B.
Parker's champion horse...
and J.B. Parker's
champion rider...
and J.B. Parker's champion
disposition, that's all.
You know that ain't all.
My bet says no other rider
in the race will beat mine.
That's in writing,
and that's a problem.
Miss-
Well, you got nothing
to worry about.
You admit that you can out-
[LAUGHING]
Drink, outfight,
outshoot, outjump,
outluck, outride any man
born o' woman, don't ya?
Except you. I never said
I could outride you.
Do we eat now
or after?
Just so it's not during.
Class.
For a natural-born loser, you
certainly got lots of class.
You just be at that finish
line with that $16,000.
He expects to win.
You saying this race
is fixed?
[SCOFFS] All I know is
no matter what the game-
Cards, craps, racing,
boxing, whatever-
If you can bet on it,
it can be fixed
Can be.
And that's all I know.
Well, all I know is I'm winning this race.
So don't crowd me.
Mister? How do
you like it, mister?
Without conversation.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
♪ ♪ [MARCHING]
Move! Move!
Come on now!
♪ ♪ [CONTINUES]
Whoa.
Don't forget my bed. Get all the tables.
Don't forget the booze.
Strip the joint.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
[GUNSHOT]
♪ [“THE CAISSON SONG"]
♪ ♪ [CONTINUES]
[BELL CLANGING]
MAN: Hey! Get a hose!
[WHINNIES]
Maybe- Maybe that'll
save a couple miles.
Go!
All right.
Hyah!
- Is he all right?
- Sple- Splendid. Fine.
Oh- Oh, boy.
What did I do to you?
It was damn stupid of me,
wasn't it?
MAN:
A little over eight hours.
They oughta be strung out
from here...
to about here.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Hyah!
Whoa.
[PANTING]
How far we come?
Oh, about halfway,
I think.
- Halfway?
- To the first checkpoint.
[PILLS RATTLING]
Milagro.
Gracias.
- Mucho caballo.
- Sí
The father of your father?
He was a true mexicano?
- [CHUCKLING]
- But you are simpatico?
I had a toothache once.
I've had it.
Good luck.
So long.
Good luck!
♪ [FLAMENCO]
♪ [CONTINUES]
Ya-hoo! Olé!
Ya-hoo!
Whee! Whee! Whee!
Whoo! Whoo!
[MUSIC OFF]
What happened to
the “miracle" painkiller?
Took six pills in one hour,
instead of one every four hours.
Killed the pain all right,
but he almost died.
I made him throw up the pills,
and now his toothache is back.
Siéntate.
Can you get a dentist on that thing?
Even if he could- which he can't-
the dentist comes, which he won't-
By the time he gets here,
we'll be gone.
Nearest town's a hundred miles
in any direction.
¿Comprendes?
Sí, sáquenla.
He wants it pulled.
Who by?
CLAYTON: By us.
- He's crazy.
- He's got a lot of faith.
That proves he's crazy.
MAN:
Checkin' out!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
- Christie just rode out.
- So did I.
[SPANISH, INDISTINCT]
Hold this, will you?
[GROANS]
Perdone, the tooth's chipped.
Well, that nerve is open.
Cover the tooth
and the pulling can wait.
What about the poison?
That goes first.
Do I cut it from the inside
or from the outside?
I'll do it.
Okay.
What caliber's that tooth?
Huh?
The bullet size. Use the
casing to cover the tooth.
Smaller.
Smaller. Okay.
¿Listo?
Checkin' out.
Hyah!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Crank out a round
for me, will you?
After you doctor him up?
Suppose he goes out and wins.
Then what'll you say?
I'd have to say, uh,
you're out $2,000.
Checkin' out.
Losin' time.
Right.
You won't think
it's unsporting?
Oh, hell. Racing for money
ain't sport. it's war.
This liniment's
gonna burn for a week.
Put a little right there.
[GRUNTING]
[LAUGHING]
Careful of my vitals.
Seems you're not
too worried about this race.
Yeah, seems like it.
You know, missing that train
like you did yesterday,
that's- that's just
not like your kind of man.
You- You must have had a good reason.
Must have had.
Well, I don't give a damn
about the reason.
I was out of hand. I just
wanted you to know that.
What's on your mind,
Mr. Parker?
I want you to come back
on our team.
You get a bonus, a raise.
Deal?
You just take the rest
of the week off with pay.
How about it?
I'll look you up
after the race, Mr. Parker.
Bite.
[GRUNTS]
Uh, thanks.
Get any sleep?
Not much.
They gone?
Yeah.
Long?
Three, four hours.
We'll catch 'em before dark.
[COUGHING]
Whoa.
[WHINNIES]
Drop it!
- Hog-tie her.
- Turn around.
Turn around.
[GROANS]
[GUNSHOT ECHOING]
[LAUGHING]
[STRAINING]
[HORSE WHINNYING]
[LAUGHS]
[GROANS]
[GUNSHOT]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[THUDDING]
Mornin', neighbor.
Fixin' to stay?
No,just passing through.
Then you ain't my neighbor.
Been here long?
Ever since I come.
This trail here,
where does it go?
Ain't goin' nowhere that I know of.
Always been there.
Well, how far is it
to town?
Don't know.
Never measured it.
Well, you don't seem to know much.
Huh?
I say you don't seem
to know much.
Mister, I don't know
a damn thing about nothing.
But I ain't the one
who's lost.
Much obliged.
[SPANISH, INDISTINCT]
[SHOUTING]
- [SNORTS]
- [GROWLING]
[WHINNYING]
[RATTLING SOUND]
Jesus.
He is generous today.
Well, one of us
better know the way.
[HORSE WHINNYING]
Whoa!
Son of a bitch!
[WHINNYING CONTINUES]
Whoa, now, whoa! Whoa!
Hold him, damn it!
Muzzle that stump-suckin' bastard!
I ought to bust your ass
wide open. Lousy whore.
- Shut up! Goddamn it!
- You ain't nothin' but a lousy whore.
Get back to that rope!
Whoa now! Whoa, whoa.
[WHINNYING CONTINUES]
Whoa. Whoa. Easy.
Don't say it.
[GASPING]
Whoa, whoa. Don't! What he said
don't bother me. Now, quit!
[GASPING]
Nothin' to do with you.
I know you can pull this over here, but
how in the hell do I pull you over there?
♪ Rode to Montana ♪
♪ For to throw o'er the early hand ♪
♪ They're freein' the coolies ♪
♪ There's water in the draw ♪
♪ Their tails are all matted ♪
♪ Their backs are all raw ♪
♪ Ride around- ♪ ♪
Good evening.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Good evening, gentlemen.
Evening.
Miss Jones.
¿Café?
- ¿Café, señor?
- Sí por favor
Ah, gracias.
Es un placer
Oh, mil gracias
And, uh, how was
the shorter road?
[CHUCKLES]
A little longer.
MAN:
Come away.
Hasta después
Adiós.
[WHINNIES]
Whoa. Whoa.
I'll go have a look.
Uh, watch the sport.
Miss Jones,
gonna need a blanket.
He's crazy.
He's gotta be crazy.
- That so?
- Tried to kill me.
Oh, he couldn't
have tried very hard.
Son of a bitch
tried to kill me!
Now, why don't you
tell me the...
story of your life?
Just skip everything
but the last few minutes.
What the hell
you doin' down here?
By God, I'm a-shiverin'.
Come on. Get up.
Ow!
Is it busted?
What's busted
is my pump.
How you know?
Army doc
couple of years back.
He said when that pain hits your
arm, that's the alarm bell.
It hits your pump
right after.
That's it.
Can you make it
to the checkpoint?
No.
Come on. it's only a couple of hours.
Easy ride.
[LAUGHS] All right.
Let's try it.
All right. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Hold on to me.
You certainly have a knack of
provoking a man to violence.
All I said was she was a- it must
have been the way you said it.
Like an insult. Hell, yeah,
when a woman does it for money-
A man always gets
the best of the bargain.
Before you take her to bed
she's a thing of beauty.
In bed,
an angel of mercy.
And afterwards, she's a-
Whore.
A pillow of peace.
A whore.
That's what Clay married.
In the war, Cuba, '98'.
She's the only woman Clay
ever loved How about you?
I was never that lucky.
Let go.
I don't want them to know.
I ain't run out my string yet.
Evenin'
Thank ya. Hey, old man, thought
sure you'd cashed it in.
Not till I'm back
in Oklahoma.
I'd rather be in hell
than Oklahoma.
Every man
to his own country.
Thanks.
Why didn't you take the barge across?
Against your religion?
You know injun ponies.
He said if he couldn't go on a canoe
he'd rather swim.
Well, I saved ya some supper.
That's good.
I want it served by one of them nice
ladies, wearin' nothin' but a big smile.
Done.
[GROANS]
Thanks.
Why?
Why in the damn-it would a sick old man
like you get tangled up in all this-
Why in the name
of sweet Jesus, huh?
What is so important about this
gut-twistin', back-bustin',
man-killin' goddamn race, huh?
The money?
The prize.
Ah!
The prize is the money.
The prize is winnin'.
Lose, you're nothin'.
Who remembers a loser
or even cares?
Win, you're somebody.
What ya done, it's printed.
It's in a newspaper.
And when it's printed,
it ain't brag. It's real.
Suddenly everybody
knows ya or wants to.
Strangers
shakin' your hand.
“Pleased to know ya.
Have a drink.
Have a cigar.
Meet the wife."
Everybody's friendly
and welcome.
And I got a lifetime hunger
for bein' welcome.
No family?
Him.
Oh, you know saddle tramps.
They sign on, drive the beef a
thousand miles, make your mark,
draw your pay
and move on to the next ranch.
Another roundup,
another drive.
Hired, fired and move on.
Well, never
bothered me none.
No, me neither
when I was 30 years lighter.
Ever prospected?
[CHUCKLES]
Ever hit pay dirt?
I've dug for gold,
silver, lead, mercury.
I've dug more holes than a
whole regiment of gophers.
Ain't never dug out a decent
day's wage yet. [CHUCKLES]
God what ain't I tried?
Pony Express rider,
Overland Stage driver,
lawman, gambler,
river man, rancher,
rodeo hand, barman,
spittoon man, old man.
Nothin' much to remember.
Of course, ain't nothin' much
to forget neither.
Nobody's got much use
for an old man.
Can't blame 'em much.
That's why I'm gonna win me
this here newspaper race.
When I cross that finish line,
I get to be a big man,
top man,
a man to remember.
I didn't even know
your name, mister.
Couple miles out from here,
47 miles of desert.
Nothin' but sand,
an ocean of it.
By night, cold, hostile,
but easier going.
By day a blazing hellhole.
Halfway across, water stop,
the only one.
Miss that water,
you're in trouble.
If you're lucky, eight hours
in the devil's own frying pan.
Railroad.
We'll wait here till noon.
Time.
Can you beat the desert before sunup?
Nope.
How's it shape up?
Tight.
You're not worried?
[CHUCKLES]
Who by?
An old man, girl, punk kid.
Where's the class?
Kids and old men don't respect class.
Don't sell the girl short. If she'd
ever cut that brute of hers loose-
Why would she hold back?
Probably too green to know better.
But the Mexican's not,
and he's tough.
Anytime we can't beat
a Mexican- Horseshit.
And that stubborn Englishman.
He'll never keep up the lick.
Tell that to him. I lose him.
I look around.
He's bitin' my ass.
Sand dunes will finish him. Tougher
it gets, the better he likes it.
Same goes for Matthews.
What he hasn't got in horse,
he makes up for in brass.
Cuts every corner,
takes a lot of chances...
and he's lucky.
- That cowboy you fired?
- So far, he's showed nothin'.
So far,
maybe he ain't tried.
His bronc's a real stayer.
Tough hide.
He's got the heart.
Cowboy's got the know-how.
He's the sleeper,
the one to beat.
- We'll beat 'im.
- Yeah!
News! We're big news everywhere.
“Chicago. Adding $250 to purse and will
headline winner in my Wild West Show.
Signed, Buffalo Bill Cody."
Wasn't he the fastest gun in the West?
Only in bed, kiddo.
“London. To Sir Harry
Norfolk-" Our Englishman.
“Up the British.
Signed, Prince of Wales."
Invitations to the winner from Rome,
Paris, Moscow. All expenses paid.
And get this, from the president
of the United States himself-
"To all the intrepid contestants,
bully for you.
To the two rough riders, Clayton and
Matthews, who served with me in Cuba,
remember San Juan Hill.
Charge, boys, charge!"
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
Look him over fast!
What happened to the old man?
He's dead.
Get movin'!
I'm goin' out.
This horse is runnin'
a temperature.
It's nothin' that'll bother 'im!
Come on! Hyah!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
I'll be fine.
[WHINNIES]
Come on!
[NICKERS]
Son of a bitch.
I'm gonna catch me
that "champeen" cock.
Yes, sir, I'm gonna catch him
before this day is done.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Whoa!
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Come on! Get up! Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Come on!
Come on now! Get on!
[PANTING, GASPING]
Salt.
Could I ask you somethin'?
Your wife?
Where is she?
I was wonderin'
how you met.
I worked for Rosie...
off and on about a year.
I guess that don't
surprise you none.
The only thing that surprises me
is the people some people marry.
Because she was a whore?
A Cuban.
Paula was
a Cuban insurrecto-
Guerrillas fightin' the Spanish,
just like we was.
That's where we met-
on the battlefield.
That was our weddin' bed...
till that day.
We came out of the jungle and
there it was- San Juan Hill.
Spanish guns lookin'
right down our throat...
and sharpshooters
pickin' us off.
Wejust charged right up that hill.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
That's not the way
it happened at all.
Wasn't anything like it was in San
Antone where we did our trainin'.
That's where I ran into Luke...
and a lot of other men
from every other country...
that wanted to be Rough Riders.
Bakers and barbers
and congressmen, cattlemen,
ballplayers, farmers, reporters,
cowboys.
No, we didn't rough-ride up that hill,
'cause we didn't
have any horses.
We didn't charge
up there either.
We crawled up there
on our scared bellies.
There was only one horse
and one rider.
That was Colonel Teddy.
He went chargin' up that damn hill,
and they shot his glasses off.
He put on another pair.
They nicked him in the elbow.
He said, “Follow me!"
And we did because we was
too damn ashamed not to.
After the hill came the church.
There was
a French .75 out front,
and every window
had a rifle sticking out of it,
and there was a Gatling gun
in the bell tower.
We could have called the artillery
boys in to blow it to pieces,
but... outside along the walls,
they'd tied all these people up,
and they'd roped them together.
Hog-tied 'em.
Looked like
a bunch of sandbags.
Women and children
and nuns and prisoners and...
my Paula among 'em.
Neither me nor Luke
nor anybody else knew what to do.
Inside the church
they knew what to do.
They opened up on us
and we fell back.
All of a sudden
I heard Paula scream out,
"Asalto, cubanos, asalto.
Asalto."
Then a Spanish bullet-
Then the rest of the women-
they took up the cry.
"Attack, Cubans, attack
Attack."
Her own band of guerrillas
led the way.
The people some people marry.
I wasn't worth her spit.
Hyah! Come on! Hyah!
[HEART BEATING]
[WHINNYING]
[WHINNYING CONTINUES]
[WHINNIES]
[HORSE GASPING]
[GASPING CONTINUES]
[GROANING]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
[GROANS]
[MOTORCYCLE APPROACHING]
Bury him.
What with?
Your goddamn hands.
See he does it.
You see to it.
What he said-
is it that important?
Must be.
He said it twice.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
[WHISTLE CONTINUES]
Whoo-hoo!
It was Gans!
In the 42nd round!
- [LAUGHS]
- [SHOUTS]
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[WHINNIES]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[THUNDERCLAP]
[NICKERING]
[SOBBING]
[NICKERS]
¿Gustas tomar?
Ah, sí gracias.
¿Cómo estuvo tu día?
Así, así
¿Puedo hacer
algo mas por ti?
No. No, gracias.
Bueno.
Anyway, he's walkin' in
from a couple of miles back.
Didn't want me to
carry the extra weight.
Said it wasn't sporting
Hey, kid.
Yes, sir.
I'm gonna lay a chore on ya.
Take the old-timer's
horse here.
We got a problem
with those prisoners.
They're all maximum security.
Our plan still holds.
Look for this mark
on the left front hoof.
No horse passes through
without this mark.
List of riders.
[STEAM HISSES]
To you this race
is worth 2,000, $3,000.
To me it's worth 14,000.
Now, say it's you and me in front,
comin' down the stretch.
Got the picture?
Mm-hmm.
You hold back.
Make it look good, of course.
I win. I collect my bet, turn the prize
money over to you. Nobody gets hurt.
Except old Parker who's out
$14,000, which is only justice.
Huh? [LAUGHS]
[LAUGHS]
Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
I could never do that
to my... best friend.
Only friend.
So we split 50-50.
Deal? No deal.
You want more than me?
What I want is, uh-
Name it.
What I'm gonna do
is win this race.
[SIGHS]
That is the greediest,
most... selfish thing that-
You realize
you're betraying a friend?
If it ain't by a friend,
it ain't betrayal.
Thank you.
[LAUGHS]
She, uh- Hmm?
Hey.
Got it.
Not hungry?
Miss?
I'm sorry about
all those things I said.
All this hardware- I ain't
never been in a gunfight.
Killin' a man
don't prove you're a man.
I ain't never been a cowboy
either like I said.
[LAUGHS]
I know.
I been around a lot of cowhands,
one way or another.
[LAUGHS]
Cowboy dresses
from the top down.
First thing on is his hat, and
he undresses from his boots up.
Last thing off, hat.
Uh, another thing,
to be a cowpuncher-
That don't mean you got to go
around punchin' them, you know.
Yes. ma'am.
Laudanum.
Yeah.
Supposed to
make you sexy sleepy.
Oh.
Well, I got
no such problems.
I gotta get me some sleep.
I can't sleep.
Guilty conscience.
[GRUNTS]
Why, 'cause
I won't throw the race?
Nothin' so hard on a man
as virtue.
How could you know?
According to the gospel
of old Luke Matthews,
virtue is
its own punishment.
You might say
this is our last supper.
Beyond that next mountain,
it's all downhill to the finish line.
You, Mr. Norfolk- Will you
be with us at the finish?
- I wouldn't miss it.
- To the West.
Awesome, but inspiring.
What the hell is inspiring
about a flash flood or a blizzard...
or a landslide or a sandstorm
or dust storm or...
any sudden disaster,
personal or financial?
Today the desert
broiled you raw.
Tomorrow the mountain
will freeze you stiff.
That's your West.
Violent, treacherous.
Where every prairie-dog hole
is a gold mine,
every molehill is a mountain.
every creek is a river,
and everybody you meet is a liar.
When you call me that,
smile, stranger.
Ah, yes. The Virginian.
Owen Mister Another liar
For a family who don't know a jackass from a
mule, you sure know a lot about the West.
We don't have to know about it.
We own it.
[SCREAMING]
[HORSE WHINNYING]
[GROANING]
What's the matter?
Bastard. Ya poisoned him!
Come on.
Wait. Wait.
Wait, Miss Rosie-
Who paid ya?
Him?
Nobody.
Bitch!
Where'd ya get this?
Couple of days ago. For me!
For when I can't sleep!
Neither could he! Ask him!
No, she's right!
Come on.
It's just supposed to make you sleepy.
That's all.
Get him.
[SOBBING]
You mix it with booze,
you get one hell of a Mickey Finn!
[SCREAMING]
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[NICKERING]
No me desampares
ni de noche ni de día.
Jesucristo me defienda-
[WHINNIES]
[GROANS]
Compadre.
Adiós.
See ya.
You bet your ass.
[WHISPERS]
Whoa. Whoa.
[GROANS]
Whoa.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[METAL CLANGING]
Mornin'.
Your name?
Jones.
Stretch. Face down.
Steve.
Kate, rifle.
[GROANS]
[GROANING]
[HOOF BEATS APPROACHING]
Kate, darlin'-
What about those two?
Where the hell do they fit in?
I need 'em.
They're comin' with us.
How?
No!
¡Vete!
Name?
Matthews.
You're not takin' his horse!
His and two more.
That's the plan.
The plan was us,
nobody else.
You and me outta here
on my horse!
Will you for Christ's sake
shut up!
[SHOUTING]
[GUNSHOT]
[WHINNIES]
Dirty business.
Hey, you never think maybe
to win this damn race?
They hurt you?
I have seen many bullets.
Too many.
But this one-
Truly, did you
ever know a bullet...
that is good
for the health?
The key! The key!
[GUNSHOT]
[WHINNIES]
Get on your horse.
Let's go. Come on.
Hyah!
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
¿Qué pasa aquí?
La señorita Jones...
estaba en la carrera
sólo por-
[TRAIN APPROACHING]
Librar a su amante,
un prisionero aquí
¿Bien?
Más o menos.
Yeah ?
Apoye la buena.
[TRAIN APPROACHING]
[LAUGHS]
Es lo que voy a hacer
Horse stolen!
Go on!
How do you start it?
How do you make it go?
And how do you stop it?
[MOTORCYCLE MOTOR REVVING]
Take your hand
off the clutch!
That's it!
I'd like to go with 'em.
This horse stays here.
That makes it
a one-horse race.
That's not the kind of race
I wanted to win.
Set a reasonable time for them
to get back with their horses.
If they get back.
[WHINNIES]
Whoa.
Hey!
Come on. Come on!
Whoa.
If he gets into those woods-
Hey, kid!
The horse!
Hyah! Come on!
Get! Come on!
[SHOUTS]
Come on!
Come on. Get.
[GUNSHOT]
[HORSE GROANS]
[HORSE PANTING]
[GROANING]
[MOTOR IDLING]
[HORSE SNORTS]
[GROANS]
[COCKS]
[UNCOCKS]
[CLICKS TONGUE]
[MOTORCYCLE APPROACHING]
[HAND SLAPS HORSE]
[WHINNIES]
Asalto.
Asalto. Asalto.
Miss Jones.
The people
some people marry.
[MOTORCYCLE MOTOR REVVING]
Whoa.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Get up there.
[SHOUTS]
[Shouts]
♪ ♪ [BAND]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Hyah!
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING]
[HORSE PANTING]
[WHINNIES]
[CROWD QUIETS]
[PANTING]
[CHEERING]
[NICKERING]