(birds chirping)
Man:
"Dear Ryan,
I reckon you're feeling lonely
now that your mother is gone.
You're too young
for something like this.
I know she must've
told you about me,
and I for one never stopped
thinking about you.
Even though
I've never seen you,
I bet my best memories
I'd recognize you in the blackest night.
These past years
have been hard on us all.
Very few of us
are still around.
The land where I live now
is a good one...
quiet people,
peaceful for the most part.
But it's not home.
That's why it's time for me
to come back.
Burn this letter
after you read it,
like your mother
would've done,
and wait for me.
Much love, your uncle."
(giggling)
(man shouting)
(speaking Spanish)
I can't come tomorrow.
We need you to pay us
for this week's work.
And for the seeds too.
You never paid for them.
You know where the money is.
Just take it.
No.
You're the boss.
You have to give it to me.
I can't take it.
That would be wrong.
I'm not your wife.
Sure.
You're right, Yana.
You're right.
(thunder rumbling)
I have rain gear.
Mr. James, you're going away,
aren't you?
My mother says all gringos leave
once they have enough money.
You're a gringo,
but you don't have that much money.
I'll have enough
after selling the horses.
Take care, Yana.
I'll see you
when I'm back from Potosi.
Then I'll leave for good.
♪ Ain't no grave ♪
♪ Can hold my body down ♪
♪ There ain't no grave ♪
♪ When I hear
that trumpet sound ♪
♪ I'm gonna rise
right out of the ground ♪
♪ Ain't no grave ♪
♪ Can hold my body down ♪
♪ When I look
way down the river ♪
♪ What do you think I see? ♪
♪ I see me
a band of angels ♪
♪ They're coming after me ♪
♪ Ain't no grave ♪
♪ Can hold my body down ♪
♪ Well, look down yonder, Gabriel ♪
♪ Put your feet
on the land and sea ♪
♪ But, Gabriel,
don't you blow your horn ♪
♪ Until you hear from me ♪
♪ There ain't no grave ♪
♪ Can hold my body down ♪
♪ Ain't no grave ♪
♪ Can hold my body down. ♪
- (newsboy shouting)
- (church bell ringing)
Take care of him.
(car horn honks)
I'm withdrawing all my money.
In dollars, please.
Mr. Blackthorn,
have we done anything
to upset you?
Well, you know,
there is just one thing.
I can't remember ever being
so well received at a bank before.
Buenos dias.
(piano music playing)
Your whisky, sir.
American.
Here. Thanks.
Americans are
creatures of habit.
They have excellent
scotch here, French cognac,
but Mr. Blackthorn here
likes to stick to his
old gringo whisky.
Yeah, it just seems
to haunt me, you know.
To a fine sale.
Gracias.
You have quite a talent
for breeding horses.
Those horses will be the envy
of many men around here.
But you'd think
that here in Bolivia,
with so many bloody Indians,
it would be simple
to find good horses.
Indians got nothing
to do with it.
The terrain's too rugged here
for good horses, too high.
I was wondering if maybe
you all would like to play
a few rounds of cards.
What do you think?
Yes, we're in.
You know, I miss
a good game of cards
out on the ranch.
Ain't nothing but a goddamn bunch
of Indians out there, you know.
There's no civilized folk
like yourselves.
(whistles)
(flies buzzing)
- (gunshot)
- (horse neighs)
Easy.
Don't leave me now, Cinco.
(snorts)
Whoa.
Easy, buddy.
Oh, easy, buddy.
(man speaking Spanish)
Don't move!
- (gunshot)
- (horse neighs)
- Come here, horse.
- (cocks gun)
That's it.
Man: Hiya!
- (horse neighs)
- (man grunting)
No. (whistles)
Cinco!
(whistles) Hey!
Whoa! Cinco!
God damn it!
- I'm out of bullets.
- Get up.
(grunts)
Please.
I'm freezing.
Are you Chilean?
Spanish.
Conquistador!
I just came here to work.
Are you going to kill me?
Oh, so you speak English.
You got any idea
where in the world we are?
Huh? We're in the middle
of nowhere.
My entire future ran off
with that horse,
everything I've got...
$6000 to get me back home.
The horse alone's worth $500.
Now I've got your miserable
life on my hands.
Ain't worth a nickel.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were after me.
Please, I just want
to live a little longer.
You do, huh?
Be my guest.
Man: Eat.
Eat, you
flea-ridden coward.
It was just a little jump.
(grunts)
"The best horses."
Filthy hag.
(grunts)
I'll run you all the way
from here to El Paso.
Oh shit.
Come on.
(gunshots)
What the hell
are you doing, Butch?
Not the best place to rest.
- It has a nice view.
- (chuckles)
(gunshots)
Oh, she's handy.
You teach her?
I don't think anybody
ever taught her anything.
And it's about time
you learned her name.
Kid, I think it's time
for us to go.
Don't worry.
Those were the last.
You're not listening.
I mean go as in leave,
go to South America now.
Butch wants to leave,
go to South America.
And he wants me
to go with him.
Why are you telling me?
I think it might be
a good idea...
the three of us...
that's all.
It's a great idea.
(cocks gun)
You're pushing
your luck, son.
Please.
They have been
following me for days.
I need your help.
All right, now you
can be on your way.
Taypi is only about 15 miles
down the tracks here.
You just follow it.
Even if I make it,
they'll catch me
and they'll kill me.
Well, good for them,
whoever they are.
- (gunshot)
- I'm not gonna repeat myself,
you son of a bitch.
Get up and get down the tracks.
Please.
Have pity and help me.
I can give you
your money back.
I have the money,
but it's hidden.
That's why they're after me.
You'd better not be
playing me, you bastard.
Man: It's two or three days
on horseback from here...
an abandoned mine.
I'm an engineer.
I work at the tin mines.
That's why I came over
from Spain.
When we get there,
I'll give you
your money back.
I promise.
That's not good enough.
I stole from the mine
I was working at in Oruro.
Those mines are well-guarded.
Patiño owns all that.
Yeah.
You stole from Simon Patiño?
You're plowing
in high cotton, boy.
Can I have a drink?
Patiño, huh?
Yes.
I robbed the Suyana Mine.
Patiño... you know him?
I know snakes,
no matter what hole
they crawl out of.
- How many's following you?
- I don't know.
A dozen maybe.
I'm not sure.
How far back are they?
A day or two.
Not anymore.
Who are you?
My name is Eduardo.
How much money
did you steal, Eduardo?
Not much.
Just enough to...
Nobody steals not much
from the richest man on the continent.
Now how much
did you steal?
£10,000 sterling.
$50,000 American,
more or less.
Yeah, well, that's
$25,000 for me then.
But you said $6,000.
Look, the only reason
that you're alive
is that you might have
some money.
Now you owe me half.
You owe me for every step
I take without a horse,
every hour I go without water.
And you also owe me
for not shooting your sorry ass
the first time I saw you.
- Do you understand?
- Yeah.
Now shut the fuck up
and just follow me.
(Eduardo speaking Spanish)
Fuck!
Four days without a hat.
This plateau sun is killing me.
James:
Meet me at the cantina.
(door closes)
Keeper.
We only have chicha.
No. I want a pitcher of water.
There's only chicha.
Yeah...
Two Bolivianos.
(chuckles)
(speaks Aymara)
(speaking Spanish)
Gimme a drink.
And I want
two boxes of ammunition too.
The same as yours.
- I only have one.
- Okay.
Thanks.
I bought us
a couple of mules.
That's all there is
around here.
At least buy me a drink.
You'll soon be rich.
Nice pistol.
I should thank you.
I could have died.
The plateau is like hell.
You got no business
judging this land.
And I'm not
helping you either.
I'm just trying
to get back what's mine.
Okay.
So what do we do now?
Drink.
Okay, we agree on something.
In silence.
James:
Will you get your ass up?
I've got a couple
of mules here.
Let's get mounted.
Come on.
I'm ready when you are.
Hey.
Thank you.
You know, if that money
doesn't exist,
I'm going to kill you.
I'll take my sweet time doing it too.
(mule braying)
Eduardo:
Shouldn't we move faster?
James: Last time you moved faster
you killed your horse.
Don't you remember that?
I wouldn't say
I killed my horse.
You wouldn't, huh?
What would you say?
Hey, who do you
think you are?
We could get shot
any minute now
- and you acting like nothing...
- What? Come on.
Enough already!
Go to hell, man!
Go to fucking hell!
(horses approaching)
Eduardo: The last miner left
eight years ago.
There were 10,000 people
living here at one point.
Patiño was convinced
he could bleed a little more out of it.
So when I came over
from Spain,
he sent me here
and had me searching
six months for nothing.
I know this mine
like I dug it myself.
You'd better.
Are you going to kill me
when you get the money?
(chuckles) Come on,
let's get this over with.
Wait.
I have no reason
to trust you either.
There is a lot of money
at stake.
Where did you get
that antique?
I'm not so bad
with Bolivian women.
So you're going to
shoot me now?
Huh?
No, I don't want to.
We've been together for days
and I don't even
know your name.
I can't trust someone
with no name.
Well, you ought to trust me.
I saved your life a couple
of times, didn't I?
Besides, I'm not your problem.
That's your problem
over there.
What?
That dust.
Those could be several of your friends
at a full gallop.
(cocks gun)
You're empty, son.
You son of a bitch.
(chuckles)
Yeah.
You should've heard
what they called me back in Wyoming.
Eduardo:
We are close.
Next gallery to the left.
Watch your head.
When did you find out
I had the other revolver?
About 10 minutes ago.
Giddyup, son.
Bring the light.
I'm not a goddamn mole.
It's all here.
I'm willing to split it now.
- What's to split?
- Sorry?
There's nothing to split.
It's useless in here.
I mean, if you make it out of here
alive, it might be worth something,
but right now all you got
is your stupid gun and your lamp.
Now how the hell
do we get out of here?
- Just follow me.
- Yeah, that's what I've been doing.
Come on. The mine has lots of ways
out of the mountain.
(voices whispering)
Now what, Mr. Engineer?
Shoot the lights.
Leave them blind.
Okay, here's your gun back.
- Ready?
- Ready.
- (gunshots)
- (people chattering)
Goddamn Spaniard!
You call this a way out?
I could find my way out of hell
easier than this.
Thanks to this way out,
it'll be impossible for them
to pick up our trail
again, old man.
Where the hell are we?
- We are safe.
- Safe?
You stole $50,000.
You ain't gonna be safe for long.
Well, I guess I'll have
to live with that.
But I feel good.
I feel better than ever.
The name's James Blackthorn,
Utah, United States.
Eduardo Apodaca
from Madrid, Spain.
Rosario is not too far
from here.
We can buy cheap horses
over there.
I got me a little ranch
somewhere around here.
We can get some rest
up there.
Sometimes it's beautiful.
It is that.
You kept me waiting
for an hour for that?
You in a hurry?
Sometimes this is like having
a little friend along with you,
- maybe even better.
- Yeah.
♪ Well, my name,
it is Sam Hall ♪
♪ Sam Hall ♪
♪ My name,
it is Sam Hall ♪
♪ Sam Hall ♪
♪ My name,
it is Sam Hall ♪
♪ And I hate you,
one and all ♪
♪ I hate you, one and all ♪
♪ Damn your eyes ♪
♪ To the gallows I must go,
I must go... ♪
Get him!
♪ To the gallows I must go,
I must go ♪
♪ To the gallows I must go ♪
♪ While you critters
down below ♪
♪ Yell out,
"Sam, I told you so" ♪
♪ Well, damn your eyes ♪
♪ Now the preacher,
he did come ♪
♪ He did come ♪
♪ Now the preacher,
he did come ♪
♪ He did come ♪
Both:
♪ Now the preacher, he did come ♪
♪ And he preached
till kingdom come... ♪
James:
♪ Well, you can kiss my bloody bum ♪
♪ Damn your eyes ♪
♪ My name is Samuel ♪
♪ Samuel ♪
♪ And I'll see you all in hell ♪
♪ I'll see you all in hell ♪
♪ Damn your eyes. ♪
(clanking)
You're rich, right?
I mean your family.
Well, I guess it depends on
whom you compare me to.
Poor people.
In that case, I reckon
you could say
I grew up comfortably.
Never rode with
a gentleman before.
Never thought I would.
(thunder rumbling)
James's voice:
"Friendship is the most valuable thing
a man can have.
It's worth more than money,
land, horses or cattle.
It might be the only thing
you never forget.
And it lasts forever.
Your father believed that.
Your mother did too."
You just have to hold
the cards steady.
Rattlesnake bites
are your thing,
not mosquitoes.
Etta bought these suits
so we could wear them, Butch.
Now get up off your sorry ass
and come downstairs with us.
Argentineans know plenty,
but not about poker...
Not about poker,
my friend.
You two are...
you're quite a sight.
All the more reason
for you to join us.
Go on, get out of here,
damn it.
I need some sleep.
Bring me up something to drink.
And watch yourselves.
Come on, Butch. Ain't nobody been
chasing us for a long time.
"Ain't nobody been
chasing us
for a long time."
Damn your eyes.
Shut up. We'd have been
long gone three days ago
if it hadn't been
for your mosquito bite.
I can't even pronounce
the name of this damn place.
San Juan.
Anyways,
and why the hell haven't
they put cuffs on us?
They probably don't have
any handcuffs.
This is humiliating.
You don't say.
(knocks on door)
Oh, here we go.
(speaks Spanish)
Sir.
Here are your gringo bandits.
One's sick.
Sorry to hear
you've not been too well.
Oh, it's just an insect bite,
Mr. Mackinley,
nothing serious.
Yes, these places...
you never know
what'll be the next
damn insect or vermin
to rip a piece off of you.
Look.
Snakebite,
two years ago at Chaco.
There's a saying around here:
"Dos pasitos"..."Two steps."
They say by the third step
you're dead.
I got lucky.
This one
was last winter in Atacama...
a scorpion
the size of a clock.
I could hardly walk
for two months.
Then I was left
with this lump.
But I'm sure
I'm not telling you
a damn thing you don't
know yourselves.
We've all been
in the same places.
It was about time
we met face to face
finally.
Go to hell, Mackinley.
Let's get it over with.
- I can't wait.
- (knocks on door)
(speaks Spanish)
Open. It's the sheriff.
Sundance:
Mr. Albion Mackinley,
May I introduce
Miss Etta Place?
Well well, Mackinley.
My, you're a gentleman.
I thought all Pinkerton men
were bloodthirsty thugs
sold to the highest bidder.
You gonna run
in your underwear?
What?
(laughing)
(speaking Quechua)
(both laughing)
(speaking Spanish)
I have a gift for you.
It's a gringo machine.
Silver is best used
for other things.
I don't understand that time.
Yeah, me neither.
Don't do that! It's mine!
Keep it.
It's something
to remember me by.
Cheers.
To the two of you.
I'm going to go.
It's dark out.
Yana,
you know I'm going back
to my country tomorrow.
For good.
Spend the night here, please.
I can't.
My family's waiting for me.
It's dark out.
Sure.
I have rain gear.
- No?
- No.
Goodbye, Mr. James.
Take care of yourself.
What about all this?
This?
Eh, it's just a place.
Yana and her family
will make good use of it.
They live off the land.
More?
About two months ago
I got a letter from San Francisco.
A woman I'd loved very much
died of tuberculosis,
left an only kid...
a son I've never
seen before.
So I figured...
now might be a good time
to go back
and pay him a visit, you know,
keep each other company.
Sometimes I think
there's only two moments
in a man's life:
One's when he leaves home;
and the other one's
when he returns.
Everything else is just
in the middle.
Well, looks like
we'll be headed
in different
directions, ain't we?
- (footsteps)
- (horse tack jingling)
Mr. James?
Yana?
(horse neighs)
(snoring)
Good morning.
What do you want?
We found your horse
in the desert four days ago.
Where is he?
He's dead.
But we have your blankets
and your money.
James:
So?
Where's your friend
the Spaniard?
What friend?
- Fucking gringo!
- (gunshot)
(horse neighs)
(Yana panting)
(gun clicks)
(panting)
(gunshots)
Yana.
(James groaning)
Yana!
That's enough.
All right, let's get
this over with.
Go.
Argh!
Shit!
Here, you might need
to use this.
Thanks for that.
They're smart.
Someone must have told them
we were together,
so they sent two women
so we wouldn't suspect.
When they realize
they are not coming back,
they will come after us.
(speaking Aymara)
(train horn blowing)
(crossing bells dinging)
Is he waiting outside?
Yeah.
It's a long trip.
If I made it here,
I can make it back.
We all can.
He'll forgive you.
You know what he's like.
Nothing to forgive, Butch.
I'm not walking out on you.
I'm just defending
what's ours.
Conductor:
ISale a Oruro!
(horn blows)
Conductor:
Pasajeros con destino a Oruro
a abordar el tren.
ISale a Oruro!
Come with me.
Come on.
You're not young anymore.
Truth be told,
we're still losing, Butch.
You'd never have any peace.
(train horn blows)
Conductor:
IUltimo llamado!
(bell dinging)
I love you both.
Tell him.
Wait, what will you name it?
Ryan.
She'll come back.
I know it.
Of course.
Who could stay away
from all this?
♪ If the world from you withholds ♪
♪ All its silver and its gold ♪
♪ And you have to get along ♪
♪ With meager fare ♪
♪ Just remember in God's world ♪
♪ How he fed them little birds ♪
♪ Take your burden
to the Lord ♪
♪ And leave it there ♪
♪ Leave it there ♪
♪ Oh, leave it there ♪
♪ Take your burden
to the Lord ♪
♪ And leave it there. ♪
The Uyuni Salt Flats.
There's nothing
more beautiful,
like a sweet death.
It'll be tough,
but it's the only way
across those mountains.
The other side...
I can catch me
a boat back home
from Chile or Peru.
(chuckles)
Come on over here, son.
Get down.
Drop your pants.
Are you nuts?
If we don't heal
those saddle wounds,
you can't ride.
You're gonna die out here.
Come on, turn around.
You ready?
This might sting a little bit.
Oy.
(grunting)
Argh!
There you go.
- Fuck!
- (chuckles)
Your ass is softer
than a bookkeeper's.
You okay?
Yeah.
James: It's been a long time
since I've been out here.
I like these places.
They can't be used.
They got no owners.
But they will.
That's how life works.
Well, I hope I'm dead
when that day comes.
James, I wanted to say,
all that happened
about Yana and...
Nah.
Look, I knew the risks
as well as you, going in.
There's nothing to say.
We should shelter up
down there.
It's gonna freeze tonight.
James:
These horses ain't gonna last very long
at this altitude...
no air, no water.
Eduardo:
What did you do in your country?
(James chuckles)
I think you got a pretty
good idea, don't you?
(Eduardo chuckles)
James:
We covered more than six states
back in the day,
some of 'em bigger
than this whole country.
Of course things were
different back then.
There was room
for everybody.
Then the railroad came in
and the big ranchers
and everything changed.
It turned into a kind of a war.
We ended up on the losing end
of the stick.
And why Bolivia?
It was far far away.
Far away from what?
Everything.
See, one day
I woke up
and found myself alone.
Seemed like everybody I knew
was either dead or in jail.
They thought I was dead too.
So I just did
what any good
dead person would do.
I went off and raised me
some horses.
20 years...
that was a big change.
Quiet times.
You see, I'm too long
in the tooth
to go off and be what
I used to be, you know...
just an ordinary
old bandit.
You should have become
a rancher too.
You'd be rich now,
instead of being here with me.
Rich?
I've been my own man.
Ain't nothing richer than that.
Had some good friends too.
They don't sleep.
Sure you killed a few not-so-friendly
in those days, huh?
Me? I've never
had to kill nobody.
So far.
Come on, let's get these
horses saddled up.
(speaking Aymara)
James:
They must be very well paid.
I've never seen anybody
take so much punishment.
Eduardo: We should have never tried
to cross the salt flats.
James: It's the only way.
Otherwise they'd have surrounded us
and we wouldn't even
see it coming.
This way all they can do
is track us
and see whose horses
die first.
(horse huffing)
Vamos.
(grunts)
(horse huffing)
Grab the rifle and the water
and come on.
Mount up.
- (gunshot)
- (horses neigh)
Come on, let's go.
(yelling in Aymara)
Three men on horseback.
We still have a few minutes.
We stand a chance here, right?
I don't know.
James,
I'm glad I'm with you.
You know, before I met you...
damn the day...
I thought if I was gonna
die of old age,
I might as well
go back home to do it.
But, hell, this seems like
as good a day as any to die.
We are not gonna die, old man.
Of course not, son.
Nobody ever does.
Just in case, we ought
to bury this money
before Patiño gets
his hands on it again.
Too late.
They are too close.
They're gonna surround us.
They know we're here.
(whispers)
Dios mio.
What are we gonna do?
(cocks rifle)
All right, look.
You take the good horse
and the money.
Head southeast.
You follow that mountain range.
- If you're lucky, you'll wind up in Tupiza.
- What?
I'm gonna take the other horse
and head southwest.
Their horses have to be wiped out by now.
I'll meet you down there.
- But...
- It's the only way to do it... splitting up.
- They'll kill us.
- This desert will kill you before they do.
I don't want to be
by myself.
Your horse will make it,
don't worry.
All right, just remember...
southeast, okay?
And don't buy one of those goddamn
mansions full of flowers, all right?
- You spend that money quick.
- But...
(whistles) Hiya!
Shit!
(whistles)
Yahoo!
Yahoo! Yah!
Yah!
- (gunshot)
- (horse neighs)
(grunts)
(grunting)
(speaking Spanish)
Don't move.
Don't move!
Drop the gun,
you son of a bitch.
(panting)
(gun clicks)
(clicks)
(speaking Spanish)
How many times did we go out
hunting together, my friend?
(cocks gun)
Fucking Spaniard!
(gunshot)
(horse huffing)
(gunfire)
Whoa.
Get on, Sundance.
Ain't nobody following us.
They think we're back
at the corral.
The bullet's still inside.
You think the Chilean and the Yankee
will make it?
When they find their bodies,
they'll think they're us.
Then we're free.
I like being dead.
Hell, if I'd only known sooner.
Give me your hand, Sundance.
I should've gone with Etta
and the boy.
A son... that's more than a lot of people
have to say for themselves.
Don't you think?
What makes you think
he's yours, you desert dog?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
He'll still be my son.
Let's head for
the mountains, Butch.
We'll cross those mountains
and go home.
Damn Bolivian army...
worst aim I've ever seen.
(pounding on door)
(speaking Spanish)
Goddamn little doctor!
I told you, I'll pay you.
I was just fine in the bar!
That's not why I called for you.
Mr. Mackinley,
come in, come in.
When you worked
for the Pinkertons,
you came here to Bolivia
chasing bandits, right?
Well, that's excellent!
I found my memory!
And it turns out it's
a goddamn Bolivian quack.
If I remember right,
you always said
the men they killed in San Vicente
weren't your bandits.
Well, you might have been right.
But...
you're not too drunk, are you?
Fuck off.
Well,
now we're going to see
if you were right or not.
Look.
Sweet Jesus.
Sweet suffering Jesus,
it's him.
It's him, isn't it?
Yes.
Robert Leroy Parker.
Butch Cassidy.
All of them will apologize to me.
All those bastards.
What's he got?
A bullet wound,
dehydration and fatigue.
He just needs to rest.
Rest...
(distant rooster crows)
Here we are.
You and me.
(coughing)
Water!
You're in poor shape,
even worse
than the last time
we saw each other.
What the fuck are you
doing in Bolivia?
Haven't you got
anything better to do?
And where's my pistol?
What should I call you?
I've been going under Blackthorn.
Doesn't matter.
It matters.
Of course it does.
I never believed
you were dead, you know.
Strange world,
wouldn't you agree,
Mr. Blackthorn?
I'm what they call
an honorary consul...
$89 a month,
a one-bedroom house
with a bed too small
for my tastes.
I just greet the few
North Americans
that show up around here...
gold diggers,
people buying wool,
drunkards,
an occasional runaway...
not many people.
The last one came by
two winters past.
I spend the rest of time
looking out the window.
Huh, sad story.
Not much of a life.
No. No, it's not.
But I couldn't aspire
to much more...
until today.
Last night I thought
everything could
change for me.
I could even buy a huge bed
and travel home on it,
smiling and waving
as I passed.
But, Mr. Blackthorn,
these past few hours
at your side
have reminded me
of many things...
the fatigue,
the years of pursuit.
Carrying out one's duty is,
believe me,
exhausting.
Here in this
godforsaken village
I finally found some rest...
a stupid
but well-deserved rest.
Well,
I guess we can't be blamed
for growing older.
We're too old
to keep on playing.
Never was a game with me.
Of course it was...
an absurd, deadly game.
Eh, you never understood.
Doesn't matter.
Of course I understood.
I was part of the game.
But this time...
There's no handcuffs either.
This time you're on your own.
No one will come
to the rescue.
Do whatever
you need to do.
Take it.
Consider it a way
to continue resting.
An army battalion
is on its way here.
I sent for them.
This is the most important thing to have
happened around here
since... well,
since your death.
(chuckles)
I'll get you to a safe place.
You'll leave
and you'll never come back.
Things will still be the same.
You're a right pain
in the ass, Cassidy...
a right fucking
pain in the ass.
(speaking Spanish)
We're here.
There's food and chicha in here.
Thanks.
I know what you are, sir.
Please, don't steal from me.
Iván...
you won't say anything,
will you?
No, sir. You're my guest.
(church bells ringing)
James's voice:
"Dear Ryan, I have enough money now
for us to start
a brand-new life...
maybe horses, ranching.
I've met an old friend
of your father and mother's.
He remembers them often.
They were one of a kind.
There's not much blood
like yours left.
I'm on my way back.
I don't know how long it will take...
not more than two months.
With love,
your Uncle Butch."
Hey, I was just
writing about you.
I should have left you
in the damn clinic.
Eduardo Apodaca
is a friend of yours?
Have you seen him?
Where is he?
He's heading west through the canyons.
He was in Tupiza,
but made himself scarce
when he saw the uproar
caused by your resurrection.
I haven't betrayed you,
but my help stops here.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Damn chicha.
Is it money you're after?
You can stick your dirty
money where it fits.
You were better off
dead, Cassidy.
And I hope you soon will be.
I'll drink until I forget this,
but for you
all the liquor in this shitty world
wouldn't be enough.
In my day
the outlaws would have
robbed banks
and the Union Pacific.
They would never have stolen
from the mining families, no sir.
Mining families?
You better get off the bottle, Mackinley.
- You're losing your Irish mind.
- Go to hell.
He never stole from
the mining families.
It's Patiño...
the Suyana Mine.
You believe that?
He tricked you
into believing that?
Jesus, I almost pity you.
Your Spanish friend
didn't work for Patiño.
He worked for the miners.
The mine is theirs.
They took it from Patiño
two years ago.
What rock were you
hiding under?
The whole country
was talking about it.
The miners rebelled
against the owners...
overdue wages, murders...
the usual.
There was a huge battle.
A lot of miners got killed.
Then justice stepped in and...
this country is
full of surprises...
they decided in favor
of the miners.
They awarded ownership of the mine
to the surviving families.
This is no coincidence,
of course...
the mine was almost empty.
Even the Spanish engineer
who worked for Patiño
stood up for them.
Poor fools,
they trusted a Spaniard.
There are times
when you'd prefer to be dead,
don't you agree?
Goodbye and good riddance,
Mr. Blackthorn.
(children laughing)
(speaking Spanish)
Here you go, sir.
We'll catch him.
He can't be far away.
Or what do you think, Mackinley?
WANTED
$10,000 REWARD
No.
It's not him.
It's not the one
who escaped from the clinic.
Cassidy died years ago.
Are you crazy, Mackinley?
You recognized him yourself!
It wasn't him.
Of course it's him!
This is the man I left
in my clinic, with you.
You're a fucking sentimentalist.
Mackinley.
We're going to see
if you're right or not.
We leave at dawn.
And you're coming with us.
- (horse snorting)
- (hoofbeats)
Okay, let's go, kid.
(groaning)
Butch: Shit.
You'll get my suit dirty.
It'll help keep you warm.
Everybody will think we're dead
and look at us...
strong as trees,
snow-covered trees.
Bolivia.
God damn it, Bolivia.
Always knew
you'd be the last.
Everybody's dead and you...
you're all alone now
so far from home,
my poor friend.
Okay.
Do it.
Now is a good time.
(gunshot)
James.
Hey.
Or should I say Butch?
Mr. Butch Cassidy himself.
(laughs)
I knew it.
That explains
so many things.
You know what?
In Tupiza
everyone was shouting
that the famous
gringo outlaw was alive.
And me buying new clothes...
can you imagine?
Take it easy.
They still must be far.
So here we are
just a few hours
from freedom
and the good life.
Are you okay?
You can't think
I abandoned you, right?
I just couldn't stay there
with so much going on.
And I knew you'd turn up.
That mine didn't belong
to Patiño?
And your name is not
James Blackthorn.
Well, we all have our secrets.
But now all the cards
are on the table.
No. You're right.
It wasn't his any longer.
So what?
It had different owners...
owners anyway.
$50,000, James.
That's no lie.
Come on, let's go.
Look, there are
your mountains.
We're almost there.
I'll be your gang now...
you and me, James.
You and me.
You said yourself...
you were dead,
breeding horses
in that old house.
Now you have money
and you have it all...
your name, your life.
You're a damn legend,
and here you are.
Here you are.
Here I am.
(screaming)
Have you gone crazy?!
Motherfucker!
They'll be here shortly.
This time they've got
the army with them.
But you shot me!
Son of a bitch!
Is it the money?
How can you, bastard?
You never did see
the difference, did you?
For the Indians?
For a bunch of miners?
For them?
And what about me?
I'm your friend.
I gave you everything...
everything.
I saved your life.
I gave you
your name back, I did.
Difference?
What's the fucking difference?
Are you going to leave me
like this,
you son of a bitch?
Are you?
Okay. Okay.
Give the money
back to them.
Give the money back
to them,
but don't leave me
here, please.
Please.
Damn you, Butch Cassidy!
Damn you!
I could have killed you!
I could have killed you
and I didn't.
But they'll do it for me.
They'll track you down
and kill you like a dog.
Don't leave me here, please.
♪ To the gallows ♪
♪ I must go ♪
♪ I must go... ♪
Bolivia.
Dammit! Bolivia.
(gunshots)
♪ I'm just a poor ♪
♪ Wayfaring stranger ♪
♪ Traveling through ♪
♪ This world below ♪
♪ There's no sickness ♪
♪ No toil, nor danger ♪
♪ In that bright land ♪
♪ To which I go... ♪
We're not done yet.
We'll continue.
♪ To see my father ♪
♪ I'm going there ♪
♪ No more to roam ♪
♪ I'm just going ♪
♪ Over Jordan ♪
♪ Over home ♪
♪ I'm just going ♪
♪ Over Jordan ♪
♪ Over home. ♪
You know what, Mackinley?
This place is famous
for how easy it is to get lost.
You helped the gringo.
We'll take your horse.
So pray the God of the Mountains
spares your life.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
(all cheering)
(instrumental music playing)
♪ My name, it is Sam Hall ♪
♪ Sam Hall ♪
♪ And I hate you,
one and all ♪
♪ I hate you, one and all ♪
♪ Damn your eyes ♪
♪ I killed a man, they said ♪
♪ So they said ♪
♪ 'Cause I bashed
his bloody head ♪
♪ And I left him there for dead ♪
♪ Damn his eyes ♪
♪ To the gallows
I must go ♪
♪ I must go ♪
♪ To the gallows
I must go ♪
♪ I must go ♪
♪ To the gallows
I must go ♪
♪ While you critters
down below ♪
♪ Yell up,
"Sam, I told you so" ♪
♪ Well, damn your eyes ♪
♪ I saw Molly in the crowd ♪
♪ In the crowd ♪
♪ And I hollered
right out loud ♪
♪ "Hey there, Molly,
ain't you proud? ♪
♪ Damn your eyes" ♪
♪ Now the preacher,
he did come ♪
♪ He did come ♪
♪ Now the preacher,
he did come ♪
♪ He did come ♪
♪ Now the preacher,
he did come ♪
♪ And he preached
till kingdom come ♪
♪ Well, you can kiss
my bloody bum ♪
♪ Damn your eyes ♪
♪ My name is Samuel ♪
♪ Samuel ♪
♪ And I'll see you all
in hell ♪
♪ I'll see you all in hell ♪
♪ Damn your eyes. ♪
(instrumental music playing)