Come on, boys!
The way you're lollygagging around here
with them picks and them shovels. . .
. . .you'd think it was 120 degrees.
It can't be more than 114.
Dock that Chink a day's pay
for napping on the job.
Yes, sir.
Now, come on, boys,
where's your spirit?
I don't hear no singing.
When you were slaves,
you sang like birds.
Go on. How about a good
old nigger work song?
Nigger work song?
Hold it. What the hell is that shit?
I meant a song.
A real song.
Something like:
-"Swing low"?
-"Chariot"?
Don't know that one, huh?
Well, how about "De Camptown Ladies"?
"De Camptown Ladies"?
"De Camptown Ladies."
Oh, you know.
What in the wide, Wide World of Sports
is going on here?
I hired you people to try to get
a little track laid. . .
. . . not to jump around like a bunch
of Kansas City faggots!
Sorry, Mr. Taggart.
I guess we kind of got caught up.
Dummy, the surveyors say they may
have run into some quicksand up ahead.
Better check it out.
Okay, I'll send a team of horses
to check out the ground.
Horses?!
Why, we can't afford to lose
no horses, you dummy!
-Send over a couple of niggers.
-Okay, Mr. Taggart.
You and you.
Sir?
Sir, he specifically requested
two niggers.
But to tell a family secret,
my grandmother was Dutch.
Get on that handcar and take
it down to the end of that line!
-Just trying to help you out.
-Get!
I didn't know your grandma was Dutch!
-Bart?
-What?
Am I wrong. . .
. . .or is the world rising?
I don't know,
but whatever it is, I hate it.
Hey, Charlie. Let me ask you something.
What is it that's not exactly water. . .
. . .and it ain't exactly earth?
Quicksand!
Oh, shit! Quicksand!
Hot dang, now we are in trouble!
They in trouble.
Lyle, get your rope there.
Get over there quick.
Right, Mr. Taggart.
That's it. It's coming.
Dang, that was lucky.
Doggone near lost
a $400 handcar.
Yeah, we can take it right off to the--
Just a little to the left
of that hill over yonder.
But we're gonna die, Bart.
They're gonna leave us here to die.
Take it easy, Charlie.
My foot's on the rail.
Then maybe down that canyon,
I think it's pretty level there.
We can't swing back to the right
because of that hill there.
That looks like the way
we'll have to go from here.
Yeah, we'll put her right down
through over that ridge.
Come on!
Well, boys, the break's over.
Don't just lay there getting a suntan.
Ain't gonna do you
no good nohow!
Here. Take that shovel
and put her to some good use.
Come on, now.
-What?
-Don't do that, now.
-Uh-uh, baby.
-Come on, don't do that.
I have to.
Send a wire to the main office. . .
. . .and tell them I said--
Send wire, main office. . .
. . .tell them I said, "Ow." Got you.
And right here, Mr. Lamarr,
is where we run into quicksand.
Quicksand. Quicksand.
Splendid.
And so the railroad has gotta go
through Rock Ridge.
Rock Ridge. Rock Ridge.
Splendid.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Rock Ridge. Rock Ridge.
-Be still, Taggart. Be still.
-Yes, sir.
My mind is aglow with whirling,
transient nodes of thought. . .
. . .careening through
a cosmic vapor of invention.
Ditto!
"Ditto"?
"Ditto," you provincial putz!
-I'm sorry, sir.
-A plan. A plan. We need a plan.
What in the hell was that?
Next!
Boris, we can't hear ourselves think!
Oh, sorry, Your Worship, but I've got
two men at home, sick with the flu. . .
. . .and it's utter chaos down here.
I'll try to keep it as quiet
as possible.
But as you can see. . .
. . .this one is a doozy.
Yes, the Dr. Gillespie killings.
Well, do your best.
-Now, let's see. Where were we?
-Rock Ridge.
Rock Ridge.
Yes, when that railroad
goes through Rock Ridge. . .
. . .that land will be worth millions,
and I want it.
I want that land so badly. . .
. . . I can taste it.
There must be a way.
-Clumsy fool.
-I'm sorry.
Wait a minute.
There might be a legal precedent.
Of course! Land snatching.
Let's see. "Land:
See snatch. "Snatch.
"HaIey v. united States.
Haley, 7. United States, nothing."
You see, it can be done.
It can be done.
Unfortunately, there is one thing that
stands between me and that property.
The rightful owners.
There must be some way
of scaring them off, driving them out.
Getting rid of every human being
alive in that--
-Oh, it's down the hall and to the left.
-No, sir. Sir?
-What?
-I've got it.
You do? What? What? What?
I know how we can run
everybody out of Rock Ridge.
-How?
-We'll kill the first-born male child. . .
. . . in every household.
Too Jewish.
Let's see.
-I got it! I got it!
-You do?
-What?
-We'll work up a number six on them!
-I'm not familiar with that one.
-That's where we go riding into town. . .
. . .a'whopping and a'whumping
every living thing. . .
. . .that moves within an inch of its life!
Except the womenfolks, of course.
You spare the women?
No, we rape the shit out of them
at the number-six dance later on!
That's marvelous.
That's so creative, Taggart--
Why, Taggart, you've been hurt.
That uppity nigger went and hit me
on the head with a shovel.
I'd sure appreciate it, sir,
if you could find it in your heart. . .
. . .to hang him up by his neck
until he was dead.
-Got him locked up downstairs.
-Consider it done, stout fellow.
Boris.
I've got a special.
Can you work him in?
I couldn't possibly sneak him
in until Monday, sir. I'm booked solid.
Monday. Splendid.
Oh, thank you, sir.
And don't you worry.
Why, we'll make Rock Ridge
think it's a chicken. . .
. . .that got caught
in a tractor's nuts.
Splendid.
That's all right.
It's all right, Taggart.
Just a man and a horse
being hung out there.
There was a peacefuI town
Called Rock Ridge
Where peopIe lived in harmony
They never had no kind of troubIe
There was no hint of misery
The town saloon was aIways lively
But never nasty or obscene
Behind the bar stood anal Johnson
He aIways kept things nice and clean
And all at once the trouble started
A pack of murderers and thieves
Like swarms of locusts
They descended
Their aim
To make the townsfolk flee
Oh, shit.
Well, that's the end of this suit.
Have you ever seen such cruelty?
Now is a time of great decision
Are we to stay or up and quit?
There's no avoiding this concIusion
Our town is turning into shit
Be seated.
Now, I don't have to tell you
good folks. . .
. . .what has been happening
here in our beloved little town.
Sheriff murdered. . .
. . .crops burned. . .
. . .stores looted. . .
. . . people stampeded. . .
. . .and cattle raped.
Now, the time has come to act.
And act fast!
I'm leaving.
You get back here, you
pious, candy-ass sidewinder!
There ain't no way that nobody
is gonna leave this town!
Hell, I was born here
and I was raised here. . .
. . .and dadgum it,
I'm gonna die here!
And no sidewinding,
bushwhacking, hornswoggling. . .
. . .cracker croaker is gonna
ruin my biscuit cutter!
Now, who can argue with that?
I think we're all indebted
to Gabby Johnson. . .
. . .for clearly stating
what needed to be said.
I'm particularly glad these lovely children
were here today to hear that speech.
Not only was it
authentic frontier gibberish. . .
. . . it expressed a courage
little seen in this day and age.
What are we made of?
Our fathers came across the prairie. . .
. . .fought Indians, fought drought,
fought locusts, fought Dix!
Remember when Richard Dix came in here
and tried to take over this town?
We didn't give up then. . .
. . .and by gum,
we're not gonna give up now!
Olson Johnson is right!
What kind of people are we anyhow?
I say we stay and fight it out.
Dr. Samuel Johnson's right
about Olson Johnson's being right.
And I'm not giving up
my ice-cream parlor. . .
. . .that I built with these two hands
for nothing or nobody!
Howard Johnson is right!
Thank you, Van.
Well, if we're gonna stay. . .
. . . I think it's a big mistake.
We're gonna need us a new sheriff.
Now, who's it gonna be?
Why don't we wire the governor
to send us a sheriff.
Why should we get
our own men killed?
Howard Johnson is right.
We'll wire the governor.
Then let us pray for the deliverance
of our new sheriff.
Will the congregation please rise?
I shall now read from the books. . .
. . .of Matthew, Mark, Luke. . .
. . .and duck.
We've got to do something.
Governor, governor.
-May I disturb you for a moment, sir?
-Yes, what is it?
If you will just sign this, governor.
Right here.
-Yes, yes. What the hell is it?
-Under the provisions of this bill. . .
. . .we would snatch
200,000 acres of Indian territory. . .
. . .which we have deemed unsafe
for their use at this time.
-They're such children.
-Two hundred thousand acres?
Two hundred thousand acres?
What will it cost, man?
What will it cost?
A box of these.
You crazy? They'll never go
for it. Then again, they might.
Little red devils love toys.
May I try one?
-Please do, sir.
-Thank you. Thank you.
These things are defective.
-Right as usual, sir.
-Showoff!
-Sir, just sign this, sir. Right here.
-Okay, give us a hand here.
All right, sir.
Work, work, work.
Work, work, work, work, work.
Hello, boys, had a good night's rest?
I missed you.
-Just one more bill for you to sign, sir.
-What the hell is this?
This bill converts
the state hospital for the insane. . .
. . . into the William Le Petomane
Memorial Gambling Casino for the Insane.
Gentlemen, this bill
will be a giant step forward. . .
-. . . in the treatment of the insane gambler.
-Yes, bravo. Beautiful.
Thank you. Thank you, Hedy.
Thank you.
-It's not Hedy. It's Hedley. Hedley Lamarr.
-What the hell are you worried about?
This is 1874.
You'll be able to sue her.
-Just sign here, sir.
-Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
-That's it.
-All right, help me in with this.
Just think of your secretary.
That was a very good suggestion.
-All right.
-Thank you.
Okay, is that it? Anything else?
Just this urgent telegram
from Rock Ridge that arrived last Friday.
Last Friday. Read it!
Read it, you wild bitch.
"Sheriff murdered. Church meeting
bombed. Reign of terror must cease.
-Send new sheriff immediately."
-Holy underwear!
Sheriff murdered? Innocent women
and children blown to bits?!
We've got to protect
our phony-baloney jobs.
We must do something
about this immediately! Immediately!
Harrumph, harrumph, harrumph.
-I didn't get a harrumph out of him.
-Give the governor a harrumph.
-Harrumph.
-You watch your ass.
Gentlemen, please rest your sphincters.
-Well put.
-Thank you very much, sir.
As attorney general, I can assure you. . .
. . .a suitable sheriff will be found
to restore the peace in Rock Ridge.
Meeting is adjourned.
I am sorry, sir. I didn't mean
to overstep my bounds. You say that.
-What?
-Meeting is adjourned.
-It is?
-No. You say that, governor.
-What?
-Meeting is adjourned.
-It is?
-Play around with this for a while.
Thank you, Hedy.
-No, it's Hedley!
-It is?
Give these out to some
of the boys in lieu of pay.
Here you go. Frankie,
Johnny, Patsy, Kelly.
And one for Miss Stein,
my beloved secretary.
Play with these, boys,
in lieu of the other things.
This frigging thing is warped.
Why do I always get a warped one?
A sheriff!
But law and order
is the last thing I want.
Wait a minute.
Maybe I can turn this thing
into my advantage.
If I could find a sheriff. . .
. . .who so offends
the citizens of Rock Ridge. . .
. . .that his very appearance
would drive them out of town.
But where would I find such a man?
Why am I asking you?
Oh, welcome to Hanging House.
Not to worry.
Everyone is equal in my eye.
Not my ear. Not in my ear.
-Not in the ear. Not in the ear.
-Sir?
Governor?
-Yes?
-Official business, sir.
-Is it important?
-It's very crucial.
Be with you in a minute.
Throw something on
and stay in that position.
Oh, sorry, gentlemen.
Forgive me, I was just walking
the parapet, taking a look around.
-What can I do for you?
-Governor, as per your instructions. . .
. . . I'd like you to meet
the new sheriff of Rock Ridge.
I'd be delight-- Wow!
I've got to talk to you.
Come here.
Have you gone berserk?
Can't you see that that man is a ni--?
Wrong person. Forgive me.
No offense intended.
Have you gone berserk?
Can't you see that man is a ni--?
-Don't worry, sir.
-I've always trusted your judgment. . .
. . . but haven't you taken a giant leap
from your good senses?
Please don't fly off the handle, sir.
I am about to make you
an historic figure.
-Maybe even get you a cabinet post.
-A cabinet post!
-Yes.
-Did you say that?
-I said that.
-Wonderful.
Yes, the first man ever to appoint
a black sheriff.
-Just think, sir. Washington, Jefferson--
-Lincoln.
Le Petomane!
Sir, you have the seeds
of greatness in you.
Nurse them, caress them,
pour water on them.
Don't shortchange yourself, sir.
It'll never work.
They'll kill him dead in one day.
One day is all we'll need to secure your
name in the annals of Western history.
And to get, for you, a nomination for--
Dare I say?
-Dare. Dare.
-The presidency!
-Wow!
-Hail to the chief!
Hail to the chief!
Fourscore and seven years ago. . .
. . .our forefathers
brought forth on this--
-Are you coming back?
-In a moment, dear.
Gentlemen, affairs of state
must take precedent. . .
-. . .over the affairs of state.
-Yes, of course, sir. We understand.
-Will you make the arrangements?
-I'll make the arrangements.
Especially the funeral.
Good luck, boys.
Wonderful working with you.
Good luck!
Hurry up, get those flags up.
He'll be here soon.
Hey! I just got a telegram
from the governor's office.
The sheriff will be here at noon!
Noon? I'd better rehearse my speech.
"As honorary chairman
of the welcoming committee. . .
. . . it is my privilege to extend to you. . .
. . .a Laurel and Hardy handshake."
-Wonderful !
-Lovely.
-Excellent.
-Gabby, can you see him yet?
The sheriff's coming.
-Ring out the church bells.
-Strike up the band.
Hey! The sheriff is a ni--
-What did he say?
-The sheriff is near.
No!
The sheriff is a ni--
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
"As chairman
of the welcoming committee. . .
. . . it is my privilege to extend a Laurel. . .
. . .and Hardy handshake to our new--"
Nigger.
Excuse me while I whip this out.
"By the power vested in me. . .
. . . by the Honorable
William J. Le Petomane. . .
. . . I hereby assume the duties
of the office of sheriff. . .
. . . in and for the township
of Rock Ridge."
Gentlemen, let us not allow anger
to rule the day.
As your spiritual leader, I implore you. . .
. . .to pay heed to this good book
and what it has to say.
Son. . .
. . .you're on your own.
Hold it!
The next man makes a move,
the nigger gets it.
Hold it, men. He's not bluffing.
Listen to him, men.
He's just crazy enough to do it.
Drop it, or I swear I'll blow
this nigger's head all over this town!
Lordy, Lord, he's desperate.
Do what he say.
Do what he say!
Isn't anybody gonna help
that poor man?
Hush, Harriett.
That's a sure way to get him killed.
Help me! Help me! Help me!
Somebody help me!
Help me! Help me!
Help me! Shut up!
Baby, you are so talented.
And they are so dumb.
Order.
Goddamn it! I said, order!
You know, Nietzsche says:
"Out of chaos comes order."
Blow it out your ass, Howard.
Now, everyone be quiet. . .
. . .whilst we listen
to Harriett Van Johnson. . .
. . .our esteemed school marm,
as she reads a telegram. . .
. . .that she herself has composed
to the governor. . .
. . .expressing our feelings. . .
. . .about the new sheriff.
"To the Honorable
William J. Le Petomane, governor."
-We can't hear you !
-Forgive me.
I'm not used to public speaking.
"We, the white, God-fearing citizens
of Rock Ridge. . .
. . .wish to express
our extreme displeasure. . .
. . .with your choice of sheriff.
Please remove him immediately.
The fact that you have sent him here. . .
. . .just goes to prove. . .
. . .that you are the leading asshole
in the state."
The drunk in number two must be awake.
Are we awake?
We're not sure.
Are we black?
Yes, we are.
Then we're awake. . .
. . . but we're very puzzled.
I think I'd better straighten myself out.
Need any help?
All I can get.
Thanks.
That's okay. Sit down over here.
Hey, maybe you should
eat something first.
No, thanks. Food makes me sick.
A man drink like that and he don't eat,
he is going to die.
When?
-What's your name?
-Well, my name is Jim.
But most people call me. . .
. . .Jim.
Okay, Jim, since you are my guest
and I am your host. . .
. . .what are your pleasures?
What do you like to do?
Oh, I don't know.
Play chess.
Screw.
Well, let's play chess.
Checkmate.
-What?
-Checkmate.
Why, you devious son of a bitch.
Happy days.
Man, why you do that to yourself?
You don't really wanna know that.
-I do, I do.
-Well, if you must pry. . . .
I must, I must.
I don't know if you ever
heard of me before. . .
. . . but I used to be called. . .
. . .the Waco Kid.
The Waco Kid.
He had the fastest hands in the West.
In the world.
Well, if you're the Kid,
then show me something.
Maybe a couple of years ago
I could have shown you something. . .
. . . but today. . . .
-Look at that.
-Steady as a rock.
Yeah, but I shoot with this hand.
See, I knew you wasn't no Waco Kid.
You was just pulling my lariat.
Oh, dearie, dear.
Well. . . .
Okay.
See that king?
-Yeah.
-Put your hands on both sides of it.
Now, when I say "go". . .
. . .you try to grab it first.
Man, that's no contest.
You a mile away.
Yeah.
Anyway, when you hear the word "go". . .
. . .you just try to grab it.
Ready?
Ready.
Go!
Hey.
You looking for this?
Well, raise my rent.
-You are the Kid.
-Was.
Yeah, I was the Kid.
Well, what happened?
It got so that every prairie punk
who thought he could shoot a gun. . .
. . .would ride into town
to try out the Waco Kid.
I must have killed more men
than Cecil B. De Mille.
It got pretty gritty.
I started to hear the word "draw"
in my sleep.
Then one day. . .
. . . I was just
walking down the street. . .
. . .and I heard a voice behind me say:
"Reach for it, mister."
I spun around.
And there I was face to face. . .
. . .with a 6-year-old kid.
Well, I just threw my guns down
and walked away.
The little bastard shot me in the ass.
So I limped to the nearest saloon. . .
. . .crawled inside a whiskey bottle. . .
. . .and I've been there ever since.
Have a drink.
Thanks.
Anyway, that's all ancient history.
Now, you tell me your story.
What's a dazzling urbanite like you. . .
. . .doing in a rustic setting like this?
If you really must pry. . . .
Oh, I must, I must.
Well, back in '56. . .
. . . my folks and I were part of
this long wagon train. . .
. . . moving West.
Well, not exactly part of it.
You might say
we was bringing up the rear. . .
...when suddenly,
from out of the west. . .
...came the entire Sioux nation.
And let me tell you, baby,
they was open for business.
Naturally, the white folks
didn't let us travel in their circle. . .
. . .so we made our own.
-Cop a walk. It's all right.
-Thank you.
Take off.
They darker than us!
And the rest is history.
Impressed?
Always like to keep
my audience riveted.
Goddamn!
-How about more beans, Mr. Taggart?
-I'd say you've had enough.
I understand there's a new sheriff
in town.
-Who wants to kill him?
-I do! I do! Me! Me!
-Me! Me! Me!
-Mr. Taggart? Mr. Taggart, sir?
Why don't we give him to Mongo.
Mongo?! Holy shit, that's too cruel.
I'll be danged. That is a unique idea.
Down, boy. Down.
Down, Mongo. Down, boy.
Here, it's me, Taggart, your old boss.
Here, smell. Smell.
Smell, boy. Yeah.
Yeah, that's a good Mongo.
That's a good Mongo. Yeah.
Hey, how about it? How would you
like to mutilate that new sheriff?
All right! Here, have a cigar.
Oh, by the way,
I got a note this morning.
-From who?
-Well, I'm not sure.
It was addressed to the "deputy spade."
Well, once I establish myself
in this here town. . .
. . .deputy spade might turn out
to be a groovy position.
Here.
Listen, Bart. . .
. . . I want you to do me a favor. I don't
want you going out there this morning.
You can't win these people over,
no matter what.
They're just not gonna accept you.
I'm glad those fingers ain't loaded.
Just like old times.
Like I told you,
once you establish yourself. . .
. . .they've got to accept you.
Catch you later.
Good luck.
Well, good morning, ma'am.
And isn't it a lovely morning?
Up yours, nigger!
What did you expect?
"Welcome, sonny. . .
. . . make yourself at home"?
"Marry my daughter"?
You've got to remember
that these are just simple farmers.
These are people of the land.
The common clay of the new West.
You know. . .
. . . morons.
What the hell is that?
Mongo!
Santa Maria!
I believe in it. Any one of you
friends and neighbors gather around--
Holy shit!
And they say that now,
in Paris, France. . .
. . .even as we speak. . .
. . . Louis Pasteur has devised
a new vaccine. . .
. . .that will obliterate anthrax
once and for all.
Hey, you can't
park that animal over there.
It's illegal.
Think of it, gentlemen,
hoof-and-mouth disease. . .
-. . .a thing of the past.
-Never mind that shit.
Here comes Mongo!
I don't know what it is.
Sheriff, Mongo's back! He's--
Mongo's breaking up the whole town.
You've got to help us, please!
Did you hear that?
Now, it's "please."
This morning, I couldn't get
the time of day.
Who is this Mongo anyway?
Well, Mongo ain't exactly a who,
he's more of a what.
-What he said.
-Now, I don't know--
Oh, thank you, sheriff.
Oh, thank you very much.
Thank you.
The fool's going to--
I mean, the sheriff's going to do it.
No, no, don't do that. Don't do that.
If you shoot him,
you'll just make him mad.
Candy-gram for Mongo.
-Candy-gram for Mongo.
-Me Mongo.
Sign, please.
Thank you.
Mongo like candy.
-A little further down, to the right.
-You know. . .
. . . I thought sure that Mongo
would just mash him up. . .
. . . into little sheriff meatballs.
I just don't understand it.
-Be still, Taggart.
-Yes, sir.
My mind is a raging torrent,
flooded with rivulets of thought. . .
. . .cascading into a waterfall
of creative alternatives.
Goldarn it, Mr. Lamarr. . .
. . .you use your tongue prettier
than a $20 whore.
Shitkicker.
Wait a minute. That's it!
Of course. And it will work!
You bet it will. What will work?
Elementary, cactus-head.
The beast has failed.
And when the beast fails,
it's time to call in beauty.
-Beauty?
-Yes, of course.
She's never failed me before.
She'll turn him into jelly.
She'll bring him to his knees.
Where's my froggy? Where's my froggy?!
-I didn't see it when I come in.
-Look, damn your eyes, look for it!
-Taggart.
-Sorry, sir.
Hurry, get it. Will you look around?
-There it is.
-Give it to me. Hurry!
Quick, Taggart! Quick!
That was a close one.
Daddy loves froggy.
Froggy love Daddy?
-I don't know how you did it.
-He was nothing.
The bitch was inventing the candy-gram.
And they probably
won't give me credit for it.
Good evening, sheriff.
Sorry about the "up yours, nigger."
I hope this apple pie
will, in some small way, say thank you. . .
. . .for your ingenuity and courage
in defeating that horrible Mongo.
Well, thank you. Much obliged.
Good night.
Of course, you'll have the good taste
not to mention that I spoke to you.
-Of course.
-Thank you.
Good night.
I'm rapidly becoming
a big underground success in this town.
See, in another 25 years you'll be able
to shake their hands in broad daylight.
Well, I ain't gonna
hold my breath for it.
Come on, I don't wanna be late.
That Lili Von Shtupp
is opening tonight.
-Lili Von who?
-Shtupp.
Welcome. Come on in.
-Lili.
-Hedy.
It's Hedley. For you, my dear.
How ordinary.
Oh, Lili. Lili, Lili, Lili, legs.
Lili, Lili.
I cannot find the words
to truly express my joy. . .
. . .at the rekindling
of our association.
Bullshit. What's the job?
I love it when you talk dirty.
Come on, Lamarr, let's get down
to brass tacks.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to seduce and abandon
the sheriff of Rock Ridge.
You think you can do it?
Is Bismarck a herring?
Oh, Lili, you're magnificent.
Kiss me.
And now, folks. . .
. . .that gal y'all have been
waiting for. . .
. . .the Bavarian bombshell herself.
Let's hear it for Lili Von Shtupp!
Here I stand, the goddess of desire
Set men on fire
I have this power
Morning, noon and night
It's drink and dancing
Some quick romancing
And then a shower
Stagedoor Johnnies
ConstantIy surround me
They aIways hound me
With one request
Who can satisfy their Iustful habit?
I'm not a rabbit
I need some rest
I'm tired
Sick and tired of love
I've had my fill of Iove
From below and above
Tired
Tired of being admired
Tired of love uninspired
Let's face it
I'm tired
I've been with thousands of men
Again and again
They promise the moon
They're always coming and going
And going and coming
And always too soon
Right, girls?
I'm tired
Tired of playing the game
Ain't it a crying shame?
I'm so tired
Goddamn it, I'm exhausted.
-Hello, cowboy. What's your name?
-Tex, ma'am.
Tex Ma'am? Tell me, Tex Ma'am. . .
-. . .are you in show business?
-Nope.
Well, then why don't you get
your frigging feet off the stage!
Hello, handsome.
Is that a 10-gallon hat. . .
. . .or are you just enjoying the show?
Oh, Miss Lili. Oh, my lovely baby.
Oh, my pussycat.
Wanna dance, baby?
Tired
Tired of playing the game
Ain't it a crying shame?
I'm so tired
-She's tired
-Sick and tired of love
-Give her a break
-She's had her fill of love
-She's not a snake
-From below and above
-Can't you see she's sick?
-Tired
-She's bushed
-Tired of being admired
-Let her alone
Tired of love uninspired
-Don't you know?
-She's tired
Don't you know she's pooped?
I've been with thousands of men
Again and again
They sing the same tune
They start with Byron and Shelley
Then jump on your belly
And bust your balloon
Tired
Tired of playing the game
Ain't it a frigging shame?
I'm so--
Let's face it. . .
. . .everything below the waist
is kaput!
Tired
What's it say?
"I must see you alone
in my dressing room. . .
. . . right after the show."
Welcome. Come on in.
Far out.
For you.
A red rose.
How romantic.
Have a seat, sheriff.
Won't you excuse me
for a moment. . .
. . .while I slip into something
a little bit more comfortable?
Bitte, baby.
Why don't you. . .
. . . loosen your bullets.
I feel refreshed.
Isn't it bright in here?
There. Isn't that better?
Pardon me, I'll be back in a moment.
Goddamn it.
-How's it going?
-He's like wet sauerkraut in my hands.
-By morning, he will be my slave.
-Splendid.
-Just let me have a little feel.
-Out of here!
Where were we? Where are you?
Oh, yes. Let me sit down next to you.
Tell me, schwarzie...
. . . is it true what they say
about the way you people are gifted?
Oh, it's true.
It's true.
It's true, it's true.
Would you care for
another schnitzengruben?
No, thank you.
Fifteen is my limit on schnitzengruben.
Well, then, how about a little. . .?
Baby, please, I am not from Havana.
Excuse me, honey.
Besides, I'm late for work.
I got some heavy chores to do.
Will I. . .? Will I see you later?
That all depends on how much
vitamin E I can get my hands on.
No, no, you mustn't go. I need you.
I never met nobody like you.
I can't live without you.
Please, you're making
a German spectacle of yourself.
Auf Wiedersehen, baby.
Oh, what a nice guy.
Oh, dearie dear.
Look what the cat dragged in.
-What's happening in the clean world?
-Bad news.
I got a writ here for Mongo's release
signed by Hedley Lamarr himself.
Hedley Lamarr?
Why would a dude like Hedley Lamarr
care about Mongo?
You got me.
It's legal.
Them schnitzengrubens can wipe you out.
Wake-up time!
Okay, Mongo, you're free to go.
Mongo no go.
Oh, come on, Mongo.
You a free man.
Mongo stay with Sheriff Bart.
Sheriff first man ever whip Mongo.
Mongo impressed.
Have deep feelings for Sheriff Bart.
Oh, you better watch out, big fella.
I think Mongo's taken
a little fancy to you.
Mongo straight.
Listen, Mongo. Maybe you know.
Why is a high roller like Hedley Lamarr
interested in Rock Ridge?
Don't know.
Got to do with where choo-choo go.
Mongo, why would Hedley Lamarr care
about where the choo-choo go?
Don't know.
Mongo only pawn in game of life.
Choo-choo. I think this might be
a good time to mosey out. . .
. . .where they're building on the railroad
and maybe do a little snooping.
Damn. Damn.
Damn!
How you doing?
Hey, how you doing, Bart?
Hey, Bart! Hey!
Get down off that horse.
-What's happening?
-Yeah, man.
-Yeah! What's going on, big dude?
-You shifty nigga!
-They said you was hung!
-And they was right.
Look at that star.
Civil Service.
-Give me some more of that.
-All right, yeah.
Wait, wait. Back off, scamp.
You are addressing
the duly-appointed sheriff of Rock Ridge.
Rock Ridge? Hey, the railroad's
going through there.
Back up off him, brother!
Don't you rush him, brother. . .
. . .and mess up the brother's fines.
Well, holy mother of pearl.
It's that nigger that went and hit me
on the head with a shovel.
Now, what the hell do you think
you're doing with that tin star, boy?
Watch that "boy" shit, redneck.
You talking to the sheriff of Rock Ridge.
Well, now, if that don't beat all.
Here we take the good time and trouble. . .
. . .to slaughter every last Indian in the West,
and for what?
So they can appoint a sheriff
that's blacker than any Indian.
I am depressed.
Excuse me, Mr. Taggart, sir,
but I sure do hate to see you like this.
What if me and the boys
was to shoot that nigger dead?
-Would that pep you up some?
-That might help.
-All right, boys. On the count of three.
-I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Don't pay no attention to that alky.
He can't hold a gun, much less shoot it.
Like I said, on the count of three.
One.
Two.
Three.
Well, don't just sit there looking stupid,
grasping your hands in pain.
How about a little applause
for the Waco Kid?
All right, I'm through being Mr. Goodbar.
The time has come to act, and act quickly.
All of my plans have backfired.
Instead of leaving,
folks are staying in droves.
Why don't you admit it.
He's too much of a man for you. I know.
You gonna need an army to beat him.
You're finished.
Shut up! You Teutonic twat.
I must think.
Wait a minute. She said "army."
Of course.
An army of the worst dregs
ever to soil the face of the West.
-Taggart!
-Yes, sir?
I've decided to launch an attack
that will reduce Rock Ridge to ashes.
-What do you want me to do?
-Round up. . .
. . .every vicious criminal and gunslinger
in the West. Take this down.
I want rustlers, cutthroats,
murderers, bounty hunters. . .
. . .desperadoes, mugs, pugs, thugs,
nitwits, half-wits, dimwits. . .
. . .vipers, snipers, con men,
Indian agents, Mexican bandits. . .
. . . muggers, buggerers,
bushwhackers, hornswogglers. . .
. . . horse thieves, bull dykes, train robbers,
bank robbers, asskickers. . .
. . .shitkickers and Methodists!
Could you repeat that, sir?
Where's everybody going?
Read this.
Well, can't you see that's the last act
of a desperate man?
We don't care if it's the first act
of Henry V. We're leaving.
Now, wait a minute.
Wait just one doggone minute here.
Just give me 24 hours to come up
with a brilliant idea to save our town.
-Just 24 hours, that's all I ask.
-No!
-You'd do it for Randolph Scott.
-Randolph Scott.
All right, sheriff, 24 hours.
Black son of a bitch ! I ought to--
Next!
-Qualifications?
-Rape, murder, arson and rape.
-You said "rape" twice.
-I like rape.
-He'll do.
-Charming. Sign right here.
Take that badge.
Next!
Qualifications?
Arson, armed robbery, mayhem--
Wait a moment.
What have you got in your mouth?
-Nothing.
-Nothing, eh? Lyle.
-Gum.
-Chewing gum on line, eh?
I hope you brought enough
for everybody.
I didn't know there was gonna be
so many.
Boy, is he strict.
We gotta get in there close
and find out what's happening.
There's our ticket.
Hey, boys!
Look what I got here.
Hey, where the white women at?
Man, that was pretty. I liked that.
Be ready to attack Rock Ridge
at noon tomorrow. Here's your badge.
Badges?
We don't need no stinking badges!
Next!
-Qualifications?
-Stampeding cattle.
-That's not much of a crime.
-Through the Vatican?
Kinky. Sign here.
Why, Rhett, how many times have I told
you to wash up after weekly cross-burning?
See? It's coming off.
And now, for my next impression,
Jesse Owens.
Seize them! Catch them! Get them!
Mount up, men!
We'll head them off at the pass!
"Head them off at the pass"?
I hate that cliché.
-Say hello.
-Hello.
Listen to me, and listen to me good.
Get all the brothers together.
Round up all the lumber, canvas, paint
and nails you can lay your hands on. . .
. . .and meet me tonight, three miles
due east of Rock Ridge at midnight.
-You understand? Say goodbye.
-Goodbye.
Thanks a lot, brother.
-Get up.
-What's happening?
Get up, man. Listen, we gotta get
some nails, canvas and a wagon.
Folks, I know you're confused,
wondering what you're doing. . .
-. . . in the prairie in the middle of the night.
-You bet your ass!
I'm hip.
Now, before the sun comes up,
we're gonna build on this site. . .
. . .an exact replica of the town
of Rock Ridge.
Every building, every storefront,
every rock and every tree. . .
. . . right down to the orange roof
on Howard Johnson's outhouse.
I get it! Tomorrow, when Hedley Lamarr
and his men come riding in. . .
. . .to destroy the real Rock Ridge,
they'll destroy the fake Rock Ridge.
They'll think it's the real Rock Ridge,
but we'll know it's the fake Rock Ridge.
How are we gonna do it?
We ain't got the time or the people.
Wrong! There's why.
Who the hell are they?
Railroad workers.
They've agreed to help us
make our dream come true.
All they ask in return is a little plot of land
they can call their own to homestead.
Now, what do you say?
All right. We'll give some land
to the niggers and the Chinks. . .
. . . but we don't want the Irish.
-Everybody. Come on.
-No deal.
Prairie shit.
Everybody.
Oh, Lord!
Do we have the strength. . .
. . .to carry on this mighty task
in one night?
-Or are we just jerking off?
-Amen.
Okay, okay. We have done it.
Now let's see what we have done.
Men, you are about to embark
on a great crusade. . .
. . .to stamp out runaway decency
in the West.
Now, you will only be risking your lives. . .
. . .whilst I will be risking an almost certain
Academy Award nomination. . .
. . .for Best Supporting Actor.
Now raise your right hand
for the pledge.
Right!
-Now repeat after me. I. . .
-I. . .
-. . .your name. . . .
Schmucks.
-Pledge allegiance. . .
-. . .to Hedley Lamarr. . . .
-. . .to Hedy Lamarr. . . .
-That's "Hedley"!
-That's Hedley!
-And to the evil. . .
-. . .for which he stands.
Now go do that voodoo. . .
. . .that you do so well!
Hold it! Hold it!
Hold the happiness. We are in trouble.
Yep, we forgot one little detail.
Nothing's missing. Everything's here,
down to the last hitching post.
-People. There's no people.
-Hey, now, don't panic. Don't panic.
We just made a perfect copy
of Rock Ridge.
Now all we've got to do
is make perfect copies of ourselves.
But they'll be here in half an hour.
Right, so we've got to start working fast.
You men start working on the dummies.
Jim and Mongo, come with me.
I got an idea that'll slow them down
to a crawl.
-All right, let's go.
-Come on, you guys go over there.
Yeah, that's nice. That's nice.
Le Petomane Thruway?!
Now, what will that asshole think of next?
-Has anybody got a dime?
-I don't have any change.
Somebody's gotta go back
and get a shitload of dimes.
Hurry up. Speed it up.
Hell, we ain't ever gonna get to Rock Ridge.
Come on, move them through.
Move them through.
Well, they're through the tollbooth.
Look at this, they're buying it.
All right, here we go.
Hold your ears, folks.
It's showtime.
-Nothing.
-What are we gonna do?
Any minute now they're gonna discover
that the town is fake and pull out.
Jim, baby. You think you could squeeze off
a little shot from here. . .
. . .and set off the dynamite down there?
I'll give it a try.
Oh, Lord! Keep this man's eye keen.
And may God grant--
It's a fake!
We've been suckered in!
Okay, folks, let's wipe them out!
Forgive me, Lord!
You son of a bitch!
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
All right, cut!
Wrong!
Okay. Just watch me. It's so simple.
You sissy Marys.
Give me the playback!
And watch me, faggots.
Shit.
-Have you got it?
-Yes.
Sounds like steam escaping.
Action! Okay, wait till I get out.
Wait till I get out.
Okay. Playback!
Cut!
What in the hell do you think
you're doing here? This is a closed set!
-Piss on you. I'm working for Mel Brooks.
-Not in the face!
Thank you.
They've hit Buddy! Come on, girls!
-You vulgar shit!
-Why, you miserable pansy.
I'm parked over by the commissary.
You brute, you brute, you brute.
You vicious brute!
All right. All right.
-How many days do you have left, Joey?
-They lose me right after the bunker scene.
What the hell is that?
Get your pies for the great pie fight!
This is our studio commissary,
where some Hollywood stars eat.
Keep in line.
And now we'll go to
the special-effects department.
Yankee bean soup, coleslaw
and tuna surprise.
What the fuck's all--?
Taxi !
Drive me off this picture.
You dropped your beads.
One, please.
-Student?
-Are you kidding?
Pain in the ass.
-Look, Herman, I'm in Hedy Lamarr's shoes!
-Hedley.
Raisinets.
-Hey, watch out. Hey, you.
-Sorry.
Shit.
Freeze it.
-Okay, Lamarr, go for your gun.
-Wait, wait, wait.
-I'm unarmed.
-All right, we'll settle it like men.
With our fists.
Sorry, I just remembered.
I am armed.
How did he do such fantastic stunts
with such little feet?
Wow. You shot the bad guy.
-What do you wanna do now?
-Let's check out the end of the flick.
I sure hope there's a happy ending.
I love a happy ending.
Sheriff, you can't go now. We need you.
My work here is done.
I'm needed elsewhere now.
I'm needed wherever outlaws
rule the West.
Wherever innocent women and children
are afraid to walk the streets.
Wherever a man cannot live
in simple dignity.
And wherever a people
cry out for justice.
Bullshit.
All right, you caught me.
Speak the plain truth,
it's getting pretty damn dull around here.
Good luck, Bart. And God bless you.
Oh, Bart!
Bye, baby bro.
-Keep the faith, brothers!
-Bye!
Where you headed, cowboy?
Nowhere special.
I always wanted to go there.
Come on.