(GUN SHOTS)
MAN: Ah, delicious.
NARRATOR: If it sounds Spanish, man,
that's what it is.
It's a Spanish movie.
Now, okay. One, two, three, four.
(cow MOOING)
(BLEATING)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
The house of my father.
Love is not a game to play.
Dreams may come, then run away.
All is lost when we are one.
We are two or we are none.
A house is not of brick and sand.
It is built with blood and hand.
So the land is like our mother.
And on top.
The house of my father.
A house is not of brick and sand.
It is built with blood and hand.
So the land is like our mother.
And on top.
The house.
Of my father.
The house of my father.
ESTEBAN: Armando,
why do you care for the calf,
when all of our money is in the herd?
Esteban, one day my father's ranch
will be passed on to my brother and I.
We will want this calf
and many more like it.
I still say you care more
for the baby cow than for a woman.
Yes, it's true, Manuel,
but only because
I have not found the right woman.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I propose a contest.
Let's race back to the house!
(URGING HORSE)
I hope nothing bad happens
on the way home!
I'm riding a horse!
(MAN GRUNTING)
ARMANDO: Get down.
This is not good.
ESTEBAN: He's a drug dealer!
We should ride down and help this man.
And get killed?
Maybe he just wants to talk to him.
Holy mother.
Praying will not help that man.
Perhaps praying is all we can do.
What are we doing here?
Your brother may already be home!
Fuck, yeah!
Quiet.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
Father, is this a good time?
What do you want?
Pardon, nothing, sir. I was just...
Where have you been?
We were taking the cattle
to a new pasture as you asked.
What took you so long? There is much work
to do around here, Armando!
Is there something wrong, Father?
Leave me alone.
Armando.
Yes, Father?
Come over here.
Armando, forgive me.
I have many worries.
Please let me help, Father.
You are so much like your mother.
She had such a good heart.
And I know your heart
is in the right place,
but like your mother, you are not smart.
You have never been smart.
But I am smart, Father.
Yes, of course, Armando.
For my trouble,
I need someone who is very smart.
If you were truly smart,
you would know that you are dumb.
Look at your fat head.
(VEHICLE HORN HONKING)
Raul!
Raul, your brother.
It's Raul.
You arrange everything with the Japanese
and then give them the merchandise.
- Raul!
- Brother!
We are close brothers.
We have shared so much, man.
MIGUEL: Raul!
Papa!
Finally, the one with brains has returned!
You're the son I've always loved!
Fuck, I almost forgot.
Sweetheart.
May I introduce to you Miss Sonia Lopez?
Sonia Lopez.
It's an honor to meet you, sir.
It's nice to meet you.
Let me look at you.
You look amazing.
You must be Armando.
Armando Alvarez, Miss Lopez.
Welcome to our house.
Thank you, but please call me Sonia.
And I can call you Armando?
I would like that, Sonia.
Esteban de los Santos Escobar Chavez.
Sir.
Thank you, Esmeralda.
You're welcome.
Sir.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Raul, you have brought so much happiness
to our father.
I am an Alvarez, no?
(ALL LAUGHING)
If only we could keep the drug dealers
off the ranch.
Just this morning,
I was out with Manuel and Esteban,
and we came across a killing.
Why was I not told?
I saw that you had many worries.
They killed a man.
I believe it was by the Onza.
The Onza?
Miss Lopez. Sonia.
How nice to see you.
It's a pleasure that you're here,
because here...
Armando has never done anything
with a woman.
It seems like he's not interested in women.
Is this true, Armando?
Do you have no interest in women?
I would not say that, Miss Lopez.
I just have not found the woman for me.
What would this woman be like?
My woman, Miss Lopez,
must love the land as I do.
More than all the gold in the world,
she must find pleasure
in the scent of the cactus flower.
She would sleep beneath the stars
and let the wild west wind caress her body
and blanket her soul.
Her passions would be my passions,
her dreams, my dreams.
And our love would be a great song,
and the song would be true.
(LAUGHING)
Armando is
a ridiculously hopeless romantic!
What woman would sleep
in the dirt with him, please?
Sonia.
Come over here.
Father, I...
Excuse me. Miss Lopez, Sonia and I,
would like to ask your permission
to be married.
To get married?
You two? What a delight!
The Lord has blessed the Alvarez house.
Thank you!
For Raul and for Sonia.
Much happiness.
- Cheers.
- RAUL: For you, brother, cheers.
So it's true?
It says here that Raul is getting married
to this woman.
It's true.
She is the most beautiful woman
I have ever seen.
She is very pretty.
You don't sound happy, Armando.
Are you jealous of your brother?
Jealous?
No, Manuel, I could never
be jealous of Raul.
Maybe I love him too much,
and I am concerned.
Concerned?
I don't know.
He has changed.
I think you are jealous.
I am jealous.
If I had a woman like this...
I would never get out of bed.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Can I not share in your joke?
I'm afraid not, Miss Lopez.
The joke was about you.
Do you ride?
I haven't in a long time,
but I would like to.
- Esteban, please check on the herd.
- Yes.
- I shall meet you there later.
- Of course.
You ride well, Miss Lopez.
Good control, nice poise.
That is a difficult horse.
You have ridden before.
From the time I could walk,
my father put me on the back of a horse.
I see.
When I was nine,
my father was murdered in his bed.
They took me to the city
to live with my uncle.
Interesting.
My uncle was very mean.
He drank rubbing alcohol, and he hit me
and burned me with his cigarettes.
Interesting.
I ran away from him when I was 12.
But he found me, and beat me, and said
he would marry me when I was grown up.
Interesting.
And your uncle?
I have not seen him in a long time.
I have to ask you something.
Do you love Raul?
Raul has been very good to me,
and I have been good to him.
Do you love him?
I must know.
A race. I will show you how well I ride!
Giddy up!
Not if I can help it!
(ARMANDO LAUGHS)
This is beautiful.
What is this place?
It is called.
The Pond of the Seven Tears.
I swam here as a boy.
It is the most beautiful spot
I have seen in all my life.
How did you know to ride here?
The wind told me.
Sometimes the wind talks to me.
This is the place my mother was killed.
This was her favorite place.
I have much work to do.
Go then. I am only drying my hair.
Okay, but do not be long.
There are bandits in these hills.
Armando will protect me.
Ah. Yes.
My son,
this was my father's rifle.
He passed it on to me when I was a boy,
and today I am giving it to you.
Go. You must build our ranch.
Armando.
What do you want?
Armando, give me the gun.
- Boy, give me the gun!
- No.
No! Let me go! No!
Go! Don't touch me!
ARMANDO: She loved coming here.
I am sorry.
It was a long time ago.
I could stay here forever.
I doubt that very much.
Why is that?
(LAUGHS)
There is nothing to buy.
No shops,
no expensive clothes,
no fancy shoes.
(LAUGHS)
This is not Dallas.
Is that what you think of me?
Someone who needs fancy shoes?
It does not matter what I think of you.
You think I'm some kind of cheap woman
who is only interested in Raul's money?
Are you?
You never answered my question.
What question?
Do you love my brother?
Take me back, now!
Answer the question!
(GUNS FIRING)
B00905!
- Congas?
- Guns.
Where?
Over that hill.
Hunters?
Those are not hunters.
Perhaps someone is hurt.
It is not our concern.
You are a coward. A coward!
Sonia!
No!
Sir? Sir?
Please... God forgive me.
Easy. We'll take you to the hospital.
Let him die.
He is missing a hand.
Give me your water, Armando.
Waste water on that?
In the trunk. It's in the trunk.
Take it...
Here, take this.
I know you.
You are Sonia.
ARMANDO: I found some drugs!
Armando, please help me put him
on the horse.
He is coming.
The Onza.
Maybe God will be merciful.
He is dead!
He was dead a long time ago.
It looks like these belong to you now.
You are a rich woman.
Don't you want them?
Perhaps as a wedding present
from an old dying friend?
(LAUGHS)
You have answered my question.
You do not love my brother.
Let me go. You're hurting me.
I don't think you hurt so easily.
I know the kind of woman you are.
You know nothing about me.
I know that you will not marry Raul
if I can help it.
Do you think Raul is so innocent?
You lie!
You stupid rancher.
Your brother is a drug dealer!
You have done this!
So help me God, if it is true,
and my brother is involved in drugs,
you shall never have the name Alvarez!
I'll take care of my family.
Let the devil take care of you.
Are you so sure
that Raul is involved with drugs?
I don't know, Manuel.
I have sensed something since his return,
and this morning with Sonia...
Perhaps she is lying. Bitches are liars.
It is true. Bitches are liars.
But Miss Lopez is no bitch.
I like bitches.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
You two wait here
while I go and talk to Raul.
It is true, Raul?
What are you speaking of, Armando?
You are in the drug business.
I am in business in Mexico, Armando.
What's the difference?
Raul, you have brought shame to our family.
No, Armando. I am here to save this family.
There's a difference.
You are taking this family to hell!
(SIGHS)
Armando, Little Armando, listen.
Yes.
So I move drugs over the border.
So why do you care?
I do not sell drugs to my people.
I sell it to the Americans.
I don't sell drugs to our people.
No, no, no.
I sell the Americans drugs, but I'd sell
them chocolates if they wanted them.
But they don't!
This is not the America
our father held in such high esteem.
This is a country of babies.
They buy houses with no money.
TVs and cars with no money.
They stuff their faces like monsters
with shit burgers and grease.
It's irresponsible to feed candy to babies.
No, they are not babies, Armando.
They are all adults, and they are crazy.
They only cry like babies.
The damn Mexicans are coming!
They are going to fuck us up
and kill us with their drugs!
Fuck them!
Fuck their drug-addicted children!
Fuck them all.
Fuck their heroin-addicted wives
who stuff themselves non-stop with pasta.
Fuck their pot smoking doctors
from California.
Fuck them!
If they can't stop themselves
from shoving bags of shit up their nose,
then let's make a buck while we can,
Little Armando.
Yes, yes. If it was so simple.
But instead we have been infected
with greed.
We will all kill each other
feeding the shit-eating
crazy monster babies.
Look, Armando, this country will be strong
from America's weakness.
Sons of bitches.
What's up?
You are Raul?
You know very well who I am.
And I know very well who you are.
Onza.
The Onza.
So, Raul, what the hell are you doing here?
I am here visiting my family.
I am here because...
This is my land.
(CHUCKLES)
You motherfucker,
you think you're a big boy?
He's really funny. Isn't he, Armando?
Look, Raul.
I don't believe you.
You have already taken my woman,
and I think you are here
for something more.
The woman was never yours.
- Oh, no?
- No.
And I repeat.
I am here...
because...
this is my land.
Armando.
Yes?
Can I call you Little Armando?
I'd like that.
Do you know what your brother is doing?
Do you know what business he is in?
It's very dangerous for you
and very dangerous for him.
And it's very dangerous for your family.
(GUNS COCKING)
Easy, easy.
Not all dirty, little ranchers
like Canadian Slims.
RAUL: Yes, I like them.
All right then,
I only came to bring you this.
I think it belongs to you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Raul.
This is going to get very ugly.
That's okay.
Goodbye.
See you around.
See you later.
Bye.
“BYE bye.
- Bye.
(FLY BUZZING)
It does not seem
as if this Onza wants to follow your plan.
Armando, go home.
Mexico is no place for cowards.
(SINGING) I live my life on earth.
The dirt is all I know.
I am a ranchero.
And I know nothing.
I know nothing
(MANUEL WHOOPING)
Why does the moon shine at night?
I don't know.
Why does the bird take ﬂight?
Why does the turtle move so slow?
I don't know.
Come on!
Why do men hate each other?
I don't know.
Why does the brother fight the brother?
Why does the blue ﬂower grow?
I don't know.
How can I know anything?
What is there to know?
Long live Mexico!
I am a man of the land.
I am a ranchero.
And I don't know.
I live a simple life.
I'm friends with the cows.
I have no thoughts.
I am a ranchero
(PLAYING)
I don't know.
And I don't know.
Why is a woman so warm?
Why is my bed so cold?
These are the questions.
I'll never know.
I'm a ranchero.
And I don't know.
The only thing I'll ever know for certain
ls love
(ALL WHOOPING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(GROWLING)
Look at that.
Holy Mary, a white cat.
This is a rare thing.
Let me kill it.
No. You cannot kill this.
He is here for a reason.
Yes, so that I can shoot him.
I do not know the reason,
but I believe it has
something to do with me.
Look at this country.
Always such beauty.
Why is there so much pain?
Esteban slept on a rock last night.
I slept on a bottle of tequila.
(ALL LAUGHING)
What is this?
I do not know.
ESTEBAN: I don't like this.
FEDERAL POLICE
You two stay here.
Be careful.
Armando Alvarez?
Yes. That is my name.
I am Vincent Blancardo.
I was friend of your
father's in the old days.
You were the one who found my mother.
Yes, many years ago.
(CLEARS THROAT) Armando,
these men are from America.
They are with the DEA.
Yes, how can I help you?
(IN ENGLISH) Cut the shit, Blancardo.
- You speak American?
- Huh?
Do you speak American?
(IN SPANISH) No, sir.
I don't speak American.
(IN ENGLISH) Shit.
(IN SPANISH) Armando, I
need you to help me.
Of course.
We know that your brother is a drug dealer.
We also know that he is here
to take over the territory of the Onza.
I don't think I can help you, Mr...
Parker.
The name is Parker.
I think you can help me.
(IN ENGLISH) He's scared shitless.
He's gonna shit his pants.
(IN SPANISH) Listen, you piece of shit.
I make one call,
and I can get 10 helicopters
to come up over that hill
and turn your ranch
into a lit fart.
So you think about that.
BLANCARDO: It is better this way, Armando.
Talk to Raul.
Find out for this man.
Now go find out.
(IN ENGLISH) He'll squeal.
He's a fucking coward.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
I want to thank you all for coming today.
Tomorrow will be a great day
for the Alvarez family.
It's a pleasure to share
it with all of you.
My sister, Carmen,
has come from Guadalajara.
My other sister, Margarite,
has come from Puerto Vallarta.
My cousin, Hernan, and his wife, Doleta.
My friends for life.
Of course, Sheila from Atlanta!
(IN ENGLISH) Mexico is the bestico.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(IN SPANISH) Tomorrow will be
a double celebration.
The return of my son, Raul, to his land.
Also, he brought home this precious woman
with whom he gets to have sex.
I propose a toast to Sonia.
For Sonia! Friends.
- Cheers!
- ALL: Cheers!
For Sonia.
Cheers!
I'd also like to propose a toast
and thank those who have come from so far.
But I would like to
specially thank someone,
someone who many of you have often
called stupid, imbecile, fat head,
but he's a guy with a big heart.
I propose a toast
for my brother.
For your happiness, Armando.
Well, Armando?
You aren't going to toast
to your brother's happiness?
Yes.
To Raul's happiness.
May you enjoy all of life's pleasure.
Even if it means the
destruction of this family!
MIGUEL: Stop, Armando!
(ALL GASPING)
Please!
It hurts me to say it,
but tomorrow I do not wish
for you to be at your brother's wedding.
Do you understand me? Get out!
As you wish.
- RAUL: Armando...
- Let him go!
Armando!
Let me talk to him.
You stay with your guests.
Armando.
Go back inside, Sonia.
Go back to your people.
Don't make trouble, Armando.
Do you think I like
that Raul is mixed up in this business?
It is your business too.
We can change him.
But I need your help.
Armando,
there's something you need to know.
What is it that I must know?
This drug dealer they call the Onza.
He is my uncle.
I understand.
He will never stop until
he has what he wants.
You come from trouble,
and you carry it with you.
Then save us.
Save your brother.
Save your family.
Save me.
Some things are beyond saving.
(SINGING) La.
La La.
La La La La La.
La.
La La.
La La La La La.
La.
La La.
La
(ORGAN PLAYING)
(SINGING)
Father.
Raul, who did this? Was it Armando?
Easy, Dad, don't talk.
RAUL: Don't die on me.
Armando was right.
He was dead the day we came to his house.
RAUL: Hold on, Papa...
Hold on, you're gonna be fine.
MIGUEL: It has his
fingerprints all over it!
RAUL: What?
It had to be Armando!
How the hell could it be Armando, Papa?
Hello, Blancardo...
The deed is done.
Sonia?
She is alive, just as you wanted.
Good.
Raul?
Raul still lives.
So let me get this right...
I'm paying the police to protect me.
Do the police not honor
their obligations any more?
Don't worry.
He will come to you now.
We must figure out how to bring him back.
The woman.
His woman.
Sonia.
Little Sonia.
My little niece.
Fine. Thank you.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoa, stop! Hey, Armando!
Esteban, my friend.
Why are you in such a hurry?
They shot your father!
What?
The wedding! Gunmen shooting!
Raul?
Raul and the woman are safe.
Your father, Armando.
Your father is dying.
- (HORSE WHINNYING)
- Let's go!
Fast!
Armando, come.
Yes, Father?
It is me.
Do you remember your mother?
Yes.
I remember her a little.
She was a very beautiful woman.
She was a beautiful woman.
The most beautiful in all of Mexico.
You know, you have her eyes.
You have told me that many times.
The eyes of a small chicken.
Little chicken...
I have been very mean to you.
Calling you stupid all the time,
comparing you to donkeys and pigs,
laughing at the way you speak.
Giving you to the circus.
Perhaps I have never forgiven you
for the accident.
For this, I am very sorry.
I was hoping.
When I see your mother in heaven,
I could tell her that her home,
and her family are well.
What will I say now, Armando?
You must tell her a lie.
Tell her Raul has married
a beautiful woman,
and that she will have children
and the Alvarez family is known
throughout Mexico as an honorable family.
I will tell her a lie.
Because I am ashamed
of the truth, Armando.
I am ashamed.
Father...
I will kill the motherfucker
responsible for it.
He was not killed by any man.
He died of shame.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
It's Sonia.
She has taken one of the horses.
Find Esteban and look for her, Armando.
Please.
I can help you look for your woman.
But after she has been found,
dead or alive,
that is the last you will see of me.
(IN ENGLISH) This is all playing out
just the way we wanted.
Raul knows who is responsible
and he will take his revenge.
You will have a war.
Innocent people will be killed.
You should stop him.
Why?
It's just Mexicans killing Mexicans.
Let them kill each other.
(LAUGHS)
I do not think you're funny,
señor Kevin Parker.
I wasn't trying to be funny, Mr. Blancardo.
And the name is Greg.
(COYOTE HOWLING)
Do you think the water will
wash off your shame'?
Leave me alone, Armando.
I forbid you to swim in this place.
It is sacred to me.
Swim?
No.
I cannot swim.
No one ever taught me how to swim.
Sonia...
(GRUNTING)
Sonia!
(COUGHING)
Please, Armando, I don't want to live.
You would kill yourself?
You are a fool!
I cannot live.
Don't you know there is no escape for me?
You knew what you were getting into
when you came with Raul.
Yes. Yes, I knew.
He talked of living on this ranch,
and said everything would be different.
And you believed him?
Yes.
No.
I don't know...
Please, Armando...
Leave me alone.
Raul does not need me.
I have not come for Raul.
I have come for you.
Armando...
I am no good!
I am no better!
Look at them.
So peaceful.
I thought you said this was Raul's woman?
She does not look like Raul's woman to me.
This is Raul's woman.
Sonia, why are you sleeping
with this dirty rancher'?
Please, Uncle...
Well, whatever makes you happy.
Maybe Raul has no dick.
(LAUGHS)
Lately I've been enjoying
all these dick jokes.
What is it that you want?
This is the land of my father.
You are trespassing.
No, we aren't trespassing.
It is you who is trespassing
on your brother's woman.
That's a good one too!
Leave us alone.
No.
Take her.
We will see if Raul wants her back.
Stay away!
Or I'll beat you with these hands!
No, no, no. I didn't come to fight.
Kill him.
It is fitting that you should die
where your mother died.
If you had only let me rape her,
she would not have died that day.
You.
Kiss your mother for me, Armando.
You coward!
Hold on, the gun is still hot.
Shut Up!
No.
Let the coyotes take him.
We must save our bullets for the brother.
Let's go.
Do not underestimate Raul.
Raul was foolish to come into my territory.
He will lose everything,
including you.
(LOW GROWLING)
(GROWLS)
(MAN READING IN SPANISH)
(GROWLING)
I am Yik'in Chan Kwawiil.
The one that darkens the sky.
The Jaguar King of the mountain.
You know me as the Onza.
Your journey has only now just begun.
It is the time for your vision!
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(DISTORTED) Mexico is no place for cowards.
Save your brother.
Save your family.
Save me.
(DISTORTED) Kiss your mother for me.
(VOICES ECHOING)
I have hidden inside the mountains,
and you have hidden inside yourself.
The hiding place is irrelevant
when the hidden hide for no reason.
(COUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
I will not be struck!
By man or beast!
I am Armando Alvarez!
Again!
One more time.
I am Armando Alvarez!
Good.
I am
Armando Alvarez.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(TURNS OFF MUSIC)
Armando.
ARMANDO: He has Sonia.
Good. I knew you would go with me.
No, Raul.
I'll go alone for her.
Little Armando...
Don't be a fool.
I have been a fool for too long.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello, this is the Onza.
How can I help you?
He has assembled a small army.
Let him come.
I am ready for him.
Just keep the Americans away.
They want nothing to do with this.
They want you to kill each other.
Good.
After I kill Raul,
I will kill those fucking Americans.
Okay?
All right.
Bye.
This Onza is such a fucking coward!
Does he think he can come
into my house uninvited?
Does he think he can take any woman?
No!
I'm not going to let him kill
any more of my own flesh and blood!
This is the end of that fucking Onza!
You know what?
We won't allow him to fuck it up again!
This fucking Onza is done!
(YELLING)
You will see that your uncle can provide
you with all that Raul promised,
and much more.
You're so beautiful.
Thank you.
Ah! Bitch!
No one is coming for you.
He will come.
And he will kill you.
Raul? (SCOFFS)
I do not speak of Raul.
Are you referring to that filthy rancher?
Yes.
Little niece, you are a fool.
I told you a million times, I killed him.
He is dead.
The wind tells me he is not.
(WIND BLOWING)
(SNIFFING)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
(IN ENGLISH) All this, just so daddy's
little girl can score a dime bag.
(WHINNYING)
(IN SPANISH) I'm jumping!
The one they call the Onza.
My name is Armando Alvarez.
I am talking to you, Onza!
I'm surprised to see you alive.
I want the girl.
Let her go and the two of us will leave.
(CHUCKLES)
I can kill you now with one shot.
I am only giving you this one chance.
Release the woman and I will let you live.
(GUNS FIRING)
Armando, stay there.
Do you have a cigarette?
Yes.
What the fuck, Armando?
You never learned how to roll a cigarette.
I am sorry.
Damn it. I'm dying
and you're giving me this piece of shit?
I'm sorry.
Brother.
Yes?
She loves you.
I just realized this.
Go and get her.
Damn, our father would have loved
to have seen that.
Go. Go get her.
It's over.
I'm going to meet father now.
Stay here.
No.
Please.
Mexico will be a better place without me.
It's time.
(MAN SCREAMS)
I am Armando Alvarez.
I have come for your life.
How dare you come in like that.
Just like that, without an invitation?
You invited me when you took my woman.
You want her?
Here you go!
And now,
you both shall die!
ESTEBAN: Armando!
Oh, damn it.
I always thought that
when this moment arrived
there would be a lot of people.
A lot of TV networks.
Police.
The army, the president, and everything...
I won't be there, I won't
be able to see it.
Oh, shit.
Armando Alvarez.
You are under arrest for murder
and the trafficking of illegal drugs.
You will be extradited
to the United States,
where you will stand trial.
No, Mr. Blancardo,
there will be no trial.
- For my mother.
- You son of a bitch!
(IN ENGLISH) Holy shit!
Did you see that?
The greasy wetback shot him.
Son of a bitch!
It's a goddamn Mexican standoff.
I think I'll kill the bastard.
(IN BROKEN ENGLISH)
I speak the English perfect, Mr. DEA.
(GUN CLICKS)
(IN SPANISH) You are out of luck, wetback.
(GUN SHOT)
Not all Americans are bad, Armando.
Not all Mexicans are drug dealers.
Are you ready, Sonia?
Yes.
Let's go home.
Bye.
(SIGHS)
Do you want to walk?
(IN ENGLISH) Bye bye. Take it easy.
(LAUGHING)
(GROWLING)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
With every season comes a change.
A season ends and a new one comes.
But now a season has come to us.
It's a no good season.
A bird has wings so he can ﬂy.
His home is up in the sky.
His home is where his heart can sing.
Unless he has a broken wing.
My whole life has been a struggle.
I've chased a dream within a bubble.
And now that dream is fading slow.
I've made a world only I can know
ls this the end of what we are?
What we were is long ago.
I will not let this come to pass.
My name is Armando Alvarez
ls there a world where love is free?
A world where love was meant for me.
Must I always fight for love?
I will save my family.
From this greed and tyranny.
God will help me from above.
Must I always.
I Will definitely.
Fight for love!
ARMANDO AND SONIA
visions of love.
Hi, I'm Dan Haggerty.
You know, if you ask me,
nature is pretty damn cool.
You got trees, you got water,
you got more trees.
But there is nothing better,
and I mean, nothing better,
than a cool Haggerty Smoke.
Haggerty Smokes give me
exactly what I'm looking for,
and that's a kickass buzz.
You can get Haggerty Smokes
in your grocer's freezer department.
So you pick up yourself a pack,
they're totally tobacco free,
I wouldn't worry about the legalities,
and the next time you're out in nature,
look me up and let's get buzzed together.
I'll be looking for you.
I'm Dan Haggerty, for Haggerty Smokes.
(BEAR GROWLING)
HAGGERTY: Rockin', baby!
(LAUGHING)
Bring your old lady too.