(SIGHS)
(SIGHING) Ah!
Careful.
(THUD)
(GUNFIRE)
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
I did not tell you
to use your weapons.
I was to get a $500 bonus
for bringing him in alive.
And now
you've killed him.
The bed.
(EXPLOSION)
Look under there.
He blew the tunnel.
It's blocked with rocks.
Son of a bitch!
We have no idea
which way he's headed.
Well, the man
can't run forever.
We'll go west.
(PANTING)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(HORSES APPROACHING)
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
(MEN SHOUTING)
(GROANS)
What the fuck is this?
What?
You got
some kind of problem
with the mail service?
This is the third
goddamn time.
We lost two men
and there's no
fucking money!
(CREAKING)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Three kings.
BEN: Hmm.
(CHUCKLES)
(GUN COCKS)
Handle first.
And the other one.
Nice and slow.
(CLICKS)
Gentlemen!
Shall we bring this
to the magistrate?
Absolutely.
No way!
The cattleman is cheating.
I have three aces!
I'm sure you do.
If I were cheating,
wouldn't I win?
Well, you can't always
cheat luck.
If you look under the table,
you'll find two cards
on the floor.
You better run.
No, I think
I'll just shoot.
JOHN: You shoot,
they'll lock you up.
They'll call
the marshal.
It might take a week.
Well, that's
a fuckin' ordeal.
Yeah. That is
(CLICKS)
CATTLE JACK:
If I'm not mistaken,
that gentleman fixin'
to end our days?
That's Cincinnati
John Mason.
I ain't never been
to Cincinnati.
I don't think I have
to tell you boys.
You both are gonna
wanna leave town.
Three fuckin' aces.
That's far enough.
Hey, it's Mr. Three Aces!
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY) Hey.
Hey.
You're more than
welcome to join me.
Thank you.
I, uh...
BEN: And they
just attacked you
with no provoking?
It was time
to get up anyway.
Well, still.
So where you headed?
East.
(SIGHS) Everything
is east of here.
Promise.
Promise, Wyoming?
You've been there?
(SCOFFS)
I been there.
My name is McClure.
Ben McClure.
John Mason.
Cincinnati John Mason?
I ain't never been
to Cincinnati.
I work for the Express
in Promise
with a fellow by the name
of Dad Mason.
Is he any relation?
Some.
Holy shit.
Dad Mason's son is
Cincinnati John Mason.
(SIGHS)
I'm gonna show you
something here.
(GRUNTS)
(WHISTLES)
Well, that's nice.
Yeah, that's, uh...
Well, that's real nice.
That's for my girl.
Well, you know, (CHUCKLES)
hopefully.
Yeah?
Yeah.
It ain't a proper
engagement ring or nothin',
but it's all I can afford.
You know, that cost me
over a month's pay.
Mmm.
It's got
a half-moon on it
'cause that's on account
of her middle name is Luna.
Mmm.
So you going to Promise
to visit your father?
(SCOFFS)
I wasn't planning on it, no.
Well, I'm sure
he'd be happy to see you.
You think so?
I'd wager.
I would take that bet.
Well, a man's
got to be happy
to see his own son.
Yeah.
(COCKING)
DAD MASON: I told you
I'd shoot you on sight.
You're lookin'
right at me.
Yeah.
Well, my eyes ain't
what they used to be.
(GROANS) Oh!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I hate it
when you talk Mexican!
Spanish.
Whatever.
Supper's at 6:00.
Bring some whiskey.
I'll be right back.
Whoa!
Hey, you all finished
with birthdays?
John Mason?
Alice Gordon?
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS)
You're all, uh...
You're all done growin'.
Yeah, well, you too.
So, what brings you back?
Is it true that you shot
that Pinkerton Agent,
Big Earl Smith?
How long are you stayin'?
Do you need a place?
'Cause you can stay
with me and Rudd.
I've got... I made
some delicious stew
on the stove.
It's delicious.
I, really... I put...
I'm not sure
which question
to answer first.
(CHUCKLES)
John Mason! (LAUGHS)
$300! No questions asked!
(LAUGHING)
Okay, okay.
What I wanna know...
Is it true you shot
those horse thieves
before they even had
a chance to draw?
I told you.
I ain't never been
to Cincinnati.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I warned you!
I don't like Mexican!
(CLATTERING)
(LAUGHS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(GUNS COCKING)
Sorry to interrupt
your supper.
Charlie got himself
arrested again
and Jessie's still up
in Denver.
Express is fixin' to leave
tomorrow without an escort.
Just thought
you should know.
All right.
Where's that bottle?
(ROOSTER CROWING)
Coffee's on the stove.
You comin'?
I make it a habit
not to get involved
in government affairs.
What is it?
CURLY: Railway workers' pay
is comin' up this month.
It'll mean
some good money.
We don't rob
the Express.
We might make
an exception.
All right, I'll be
with you in a minute.
Unless you got
a problem with that?
I'm hoping you gentlemen
might put down those weapons
and make me rich.
We're deliverin'
the mail.
You don't mind
if we take a look?
There's nothing
valuable here.
Well, you'll forgive me
if I don't take your
word for it, won't you?
(GROANS)
Don't do it!
Shit!
(GRUNTS)
Son of a bitch!
Let's get out of here.
Fuck!
Hey.
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
DAD MASON: Ben?
Yeah, he's...
He's okay.
What?
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
No, no Spanish, Dad.
Come on, no Spanish.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Not Spanish! English!
Oh, shit.
(GROANS)
Oh, Dad!
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
Let's see
what we got, boys!
(GROANS)
A good man is dead!
Do you remember
when we got these?
I saw an opportunity.
Different kind of outlaw.
Yeah.
Pick it up.
You'll draw?
I'll draw.
Hardly seems fair.
Anytime.
You don't have to do this.
We plan everything
in great fuckin' detail.
No unnecessary violence.
Any questions?
Hell, what are we
gonna do with him?
Feed him to the pigs.
Whose?
What?
Well, almost all of us here
got hogs and no offense,
but he'd make some
good eatin' for 'em.
We'll figure it.
Well, that'd be great.
(GROANS)
Slow down now.
They did you
a good one there.
It's just a scratch.
Real sorry about Dad.
Me, too.
Maybe they did get me
pretty good.
John Mason.
(CHUCKLES)
Rudd Gordon.
I'm really sorry
to hear about Dad.
Thanks.
Not half as sorry as
those masked assholes
are gonna be.
It's good
to see you, John.
You remember Alice?
Been tendin' to you
for three days.
Mmm.
I'm gonna keep tendin'.
He needs to rest.
Just a couple hours.
Come on.
All right.
You mind if I keep this
for mendin'?
Ah.
Thanks, I don't think
it'll be necessary.
Oh, it's not necessary?
Well, how about
I be the one to decide
what's necessary around here
when it comes to textiles
and you just say,
"Thank you.
Thank you very much."
Thank you.
Very much.
(LAUGHS)
ALICE: But you don't know
for certain.
RUDD: Well, I suppose
not for certain.
Well, they've always granted
extensions in the past.
RUDD: Yeah, well,
not anymore.
Standard Rail says
they want it all.
ALICE: I just sent
a telegram asking for
another six months.
Alice.
No, where are we
gonna get $5,000?
I'll figure it out.
Hey.
Oh, look
who's finally up!
Good morning.
Mason.
It smells great!
Be my guest.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Well...
What's going on, boss?
He don't know nothin'.
No?
It's fine.
Can I speak with you
for a moment?
In private?
Come on in, man.
Phew!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well?
Do you know what happened
between John Mason
and his father?
His mother.
Dad Mason lost his wife,
John's mother.
A few years later
he met a woman.
Oh.
And John didn't approve.
He was still broken up
over his mother, yeah.
Hmm.
The new woman,
was she Spanish?
She was Mexican.
"She was Mexican"?
She died of consumption
a few years later.
Oh, bad luck.
Yeah, bad luck.
What's this?
Oh, that's the rail workers'
salary comin' in.
We gotta get that money
up to Canada, so...
The money's here now?
Well, no, I mean,
they don't tell us when
it's comin' in exactly
because, you know,
that's for our own protection
they say because, you know,
road agents and bandits
they'd do just about
anything to get their
hands on that kinda money.
So...
I would like to ask
for your sister's hand
in marriage.
Well, no kidding!
No, I'm not kidding.
Did you think
I was kidding?
No, Ben,
I just can't believe
it took you this long.
Oh, well?
Well, if she'll have you,
you're all right with me.
I'm just glad
I haven't killed you.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS) Thank you.
Okay.
All right, well,
I gotta go pick
somethin' up
from the depot
at Grey Falls!
Good luck!
Yeah.
Hey.
So, why did you come
all the way back here
to Promise?
What's the story
with you and Ben?
Ben McClure is a friend.
Now he's my friend, too.
I like to think that
you are my friend,
we're just, uh, different
kind of friends, so.
(GUN FIRES)
Oh, shit.
It helps me sleep.
Yup.
(MOANING)
(GUN FIRING)
Alice told me
I'd find you here.
Well, that's not bad
for shootin' leaves.
Let's see how you do
with a moving target.
(GUN FIRES)
Well, a little slower
than I remember,
but that's probably on
account of the whiskey.
(GUN FIRES)
(SCOFFS)
Dad was tryin'
to tell me somethin'
as he was dying.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I know you're losing
the ranch.
I overheard you and Alice.
Well...
(SIGHS)
I think that's what Dad
was trying to tell me.
Oh?
I wanna help.
Well, John, unless you got
$5,000 squirreled away,
I'm afraid we're movin'.
That's a lot of money, Rudd.
Ain't no way to come by
it honestly, I'm afraid.
I don't do that anymore.
Yeah, I know.
I am due a few hundred on
account of Dad's passing.
You are more than
welcome to that.
I appreciate that.
You got any more apples?
Ah!
That was me.
(CHUCKLES)
That was all me.
(LAUGHS)
Well, obviously
you're still drunk
because that was me.
You are still
so full of shit.
Let's go get
another bottle.
That's a whole
lot of money.
I ain't after the money.
(HORSES NEIGHING)
Hello, friend!
Be careful.
There are explosives
back there.
I'll be comin' for that.
(GROANS)
This could get real messy.
Move along now.
I said, move along!
Move out!
You okay?
Yeah.
I should start chargin'
for medical attention.
I'd pay for it.
Hey, where you off to?
A loose end
I gotta tie up.
Whoa! Whoa!
COCHRANE: Are you from
around these parts?
Born not five minutes
from here.
I can't stand this
god-forsaken place.
I can't wait
till I get back east.
It's civilized back there.
Money, medicine,
a man can get a decent
bottle of Scotch.
I'm lookin' for someone.
Anyone in particular?
Of course,
someone in particular.
A fellow named
John Mason.
I got three dead in Missouri
on account of him.
A man's gotta answer
for his crimes.
I mean, even if the victims
were devoid of any semblance
of moral rectitude,
the law is the law.
Well, spoken like
a real concerned citizen.
I imagine
that kind of concern
comes with a nice reward.
Yeah, I know John Mason.
He came through Promise
not two days back
lookin' for supplies
for a long trip.
Any idea which way
he was headed?
Sure could
use myself a drink.
He mentioned Nevada.
He said he had business
in Carson City.
Nevada.
Well, that there
ain't Scotch.
It's Bourbon.
From Kentucky!
Well, that's where Bourbon
comes from, doesn't it?
Well, you'd be surprised on
what passes for Bourbon
around these parts.
Mind if I be
keepin' that?
Not at all.
Thank you.
Gentlemen.
(MEN LAUGHING)
The next time I tell you
to get movin',
you fuckin' move.
Easy, boss.
Yeah, easy, boss.
I'm gonna
take my share.
Good afternoon, Sheriff!
You're Dad Mason's son.
John.
The name is Hayden.
I ought to arrest you
where you stand.
You and Alice Gordon
used to steal
my daddy's crab apples.
I'll give you this,
you were fast as hell.
You still run like that?
Only when I have to.
Well, your father
was a good man.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Still lookin' to get
the men that did him.
The masked road agents
started up last year,
small time robbin'.
They usually work over
the border in Montana.
Never killed no one
before Dad.
Well, I'd appreciate
you keepin' me informed.
Thanks again.
(GUN COCKING)
Take it off.
Please.
I was thinkin'
I'd meet McClure
at the station.
Oh, that's your trouble.
Too much thinkin'.
No, no,
he's all right, boys.
He's a friend.
Come on in.
Hey, what kept you?
Oh...
Yeah, never mind.
Look at this.
We got the money.
Who else knows
about this?
Nobody.
What about
those two gorillas?
Oh, yeah, I trust them
like I trust you, John,
with my life.
That's the rail workers'
pay, huh?
Yeah.
It's a lot of money.
Yep.
So, you comin'
to the Double Cross
for supper tonight?
I'll be there.
Atta boy.
So, what do you
think of Alice?
She's pretty swell, huh?
Oh, yeah, no, she's...
She's real swell.
Yeah.
Alice Gordon?
(COCKING)
And from
the sound of that,
I would say that
that is a peacemaker.
Well, if you know
this weapon then, uh,
I'm guessing you have
some understanding
of the mischief
it could cause
with a man's features.
May I come in?
He's supposed to have
killed a fellow in Tulsa
over a box of cigars.
(CHUCKLES)
A box of cigars.
Can you believe that?
No, John ain't like that.
Look, Miss Gordon,
you have no idea what
Dodge City can do to a man.
John Mason was sheriff there
for a while,
a good one.
Until things went bad.
And then really bad
as things sometimes do
in Dodge City.
May I offer you a drink?
What do you want with John?
What do I want with John?
Did you ever hear
the story about him
winning his freedom
from this hellhole
of a prison in Mexico?
About cutting cards
with this rich kid?
This kid who was a piece
of uneducated, loathsome...
I can't use the word in
the presence of a lady.
I love being in the presence
of a smart, beautiful woman.
What genius!
What a wonder that God
would take Adam's rib
and create Eve.
Brilliant.
Just brilliant.
(CHUCKLES)
Anyway, apparently
the prison was overcrowded
and they had just
brought in the Gaston Gang
and they needed room
to lock them up.
Have you not heard
of the Gaston Gang?
No, I have not.
Ah, nasty, very nasty.
Anyway, to make
a long story short,
the rich kid and John
were forced to cut cards
to see
who would be set free
and who would rot in hell.
Then John pulled
the big spade.
(CHUCKLES)
Lucky, huh?
What are the odds
of him doing that?
One in fifty-two.
Yes.
Yes, one in fifty-two.
I had the opportunity
to speak to two
of the Gaston Gang
who had been there
and they said that John
didn't touch the cards,
that the guards cut
the deck for them.
But the kid's family back
east doesn't believe that.
They think John cheated
and because the kid
died in prison,
they want their
pound of flesh
and that's why
they hired me,
to go find him.
And that's why
I want John Mason.
Because when
I bring him in,
or bring in
what's left of him,
that'll settle
all my debts,
give me
a little money to...
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
The aroma of you
is exquisite.
You are
a magnificent woman.
You know, I think you
should get the fuck
out of my house.
(GUN COCKING)
You're not only
magnificent,
you are very,
very persuasive.
COCHRANE: Hello, John.
I missed ya
at the ranch.
It's a little nicer
than your other place,
but that shack
had its charms.
To be honest with ya,
I miss it.
I'm sure you do.
You know, I had a nice,
little garden there.
That was a garden?
(COCHRANE LAUGHS)
You have to be
gentle with a garden.
Did I tell you
I nearly got hold of you up
in Medicine Hat
a year ago?
That would have been
real nice to catch up.
Alice is a very
impressive woman.
Very.
John.
They made me a marshal.
How's it feel?
It's interesting.
The reward
is dead or alive,
but I get a $500 bonus
if I bring you in alive.
You give me your word
that you won't run,
I'll give you
a little time.
I appreciate it.
I hear tell there's
an establishment
up at Great Falls.
Madam Kara's?
Madam Kara's.
Now would that still be
open for business?
Excellent.
Two days from now, huh?
A fork in the road
just outside the town
at dusk.
You come alone.
I know I don't need
to mention this,
but if you did decide
not to appear,
I would kill everyone.
Absolutely everyone.
Trouble?
Just a man lookin' for
a quiet place to retire.
He could do a fuck
of a lot better than
Promise, Wyoming.
Eh, I dunno.
I might have
some word on one of
the masked assholes
that done in Dad.
(GUNFIRE)
Pretty good, huh?
It's great.
Oh, you're late.
ALICE:
What's that, Rudd?
Me and the Dixie Boys
were on our way to
pick up them new hogs.
Then we came upon them.
They're all dead.
You sure?
Undertaker has them
at the church.
Let's go take a look.
It doesn't make
a whole lot of sense.
They all had
masks on 'em.
And two of 'em swore
up and down they were
the ones who done it.
These are Cochrane's boys.
What are they doing
robbin' the Express?
The money?
I don't see Cochrane.
No?
No.
I killed 'em all
pretty near.
Pretty near
might not do it.
JOHN: Pour the Kentucky's
finest. Yes.
ALICE: No.
Good job!
Did Mason tell you about
the plan that he had
to catch the outlaws?
Before you killed them,
I mean.
Mason wanted to use
the rail workers' money
as a lure,
flush 'em out.
Well, John and I
do know a little bit
about outlawin'.
That was a long time ago.
BEN: You did
some outlawin'?
Oh, we did some.
And then
we did some more.
Yeah, I think maybe
you should slow down.
I think I would like
to hear about this.
JOHN: Like I said,
that was a long time ago.
It wasn't that
long ago, John.
And you're my sister,
not my mother.
Oh, there,
you happy now?
(ALICE LAUGHING)
(KNOCKING)
Hey. Come on in.
You ready?
Yeah.
Good morning, Sheriff.
Alice.
Where you off to?
Sheriff said they caught
someone with one of those
masks in the other county.
It's only a 10 minute
ride from here.
You think them ones
Rudd handled
ain't all of 'em?
It can't hurt to ask,
get some more facts.
Let's go.
Where they goin'?
Sheriff said they found one
who had a mask on him.
Still alive.
Come on, let's go!
Where are you
taking me?
Promise, eventually.
I ain't done nothin'.
(GROANING)
Get up, get up!
You sure about that, huh?
Yeah.
JOHN: What's this?
Fuck you.
Sheriff, mind giving me
a minute here?
I'll be around
the corner.
Don't leave me here
with him! (GROANS)
You killed my father.
Who was in on it, huh?
It wasn't personal.
Who?
Who was in on it?
It was...
(GUN FIRES)
What the fuck?
He was going for
your other gun, John.
Rudd!
I swear, Sheriff.
He was going for
Mason's other gun.
Fuck!
He's got
the double X brand.
This man look
familiar to you?
Huh?
He looks like a cowhand
that maybe we had
a couple months back,
but, I mean, John,
they come and go!
You doing okay?
I'm okay.
Okay.
(GASPING)
I don't think
we should keep
doing this.
I agree.
It's very irresponsible.
What are you thinkin'?
I don't think Rudd
got the right guys.
BEN: What are we
lookin' for?
Fresh graves.
Shouldn't we get
permission first?
Or some assistance?
Hey!
Here! Here!
You take the upside.
(GRUNTS) That's one.
You know, Dad talked
a lot about you.
Did he?
Yeah.
He said you were workin'
in Texas as a marshal?
Ranger.
What?
Nothing.
Well, Dad says...
Well, he said that
you could shoot
the button off
a man's coat
at 100 yards.
Well, he was prone
to exaggeration.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I suppose he was.
Oh!
I think
I just hit one of 'em.
They dig some
shallow graves
around here.
No brands.
Not a one.
If it wasn't these ones
who did it, who was it?
(PANTING)
We gotta put 'em back.
Great.
ALICE: That was
the last extension.
There's still time.
They're coming to take
possession in a week.
Telegram says that
we can pay upon arrival.
Sure, Rudd,
how are we gonna get
$5,000 in a week?
I'll figure it out.
Thirty years I've been
savin' myself for you,
pretty lady...
(BOTH LAUGHING)
That was good!
...and I love you.
And I want you to make
babies with me.
Hey!
RUDD: John Mason!
McClure here is tryin'
to figure out a way
to ask my little sister
to marry him.
What do you think
about that?
I mean,
there's always room
on the bride's side
if you wanna
give her away.
She's been givin'
a little bit away,
my sister.
Hasn't she?
What are you
talkin' about?
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GUN FIRES)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
I come in peace.
Are you takin' over
for Dad?
Nah.
I'm just straightening up
a few things.
I'm leaving care of
the Express to McClure.
Oh.
John, I'm...
Hey, I know.
You really gonna
turn yourself in to
that bounty hunter?
I gave the man my word.
Well, things have
a way of workin' out.
Hey, I don't think
I've ever seen that
safe closed before.
The railway workers'
money came in.
Oh.
When's it headin' out?
But I guess you wanna
keep them details a secret.
No, I put the word out.
It leaves tomorrow morning.
You put the word out?
I'm trying to attract
a certain element.
They're all dead.
Maybe.
So you escortin'
that money yourself?
Yeah.
You wanna ride with me?
No, I try to
stay out of...
Government affairs.
I remember.
You still sore
about them horses?
Nah, there's no reason
for both of us to get
the lash.
John, you didn't even run.
Never been much
of a runner.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, I think we're
way past you takin'
your fuckin' hat off.
I understand you're going
to be escortin' the Express
with the rail
workers' money.
That's right.
You know, somebody
might actually
take it upon himself
to rob that Express.
I'm countin' on it.
You know, I'm gonna
be really pissed
if you go and get
yourself killed.
I'll keep that in mind.
I just have this feeling
that something terrible
is gonna happen.
We can't.
Ben is gonna ask for
your hand in marriage.
Ah, well, he doesn't know
where my hands have been.
(DOOR BANGING SHUT)
Shit.
(BOTH SIGHING)
Huh!
You're wearin'
McClure's ring.
McClure?
Where did you get this?
Rudd.
(GUN CLICKING)
ALICE:
Where you off to?
I'm gonna help Greyson
move some ponies.
You need the Winchester
for that?
John Mason's a killer,
you know.
Worked for the Pinkertons
out in New York City.
Killed for money.
Yeah.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, right?
Killing for money?
Where'd you get this ring?
Show me your shoulder.
I'm comin' with you.
No, I need you to stay here
and mind the office.
Dad worked
for the Express,
he didn't own it.
And I ain't askin'.
Hey!
Whoa, whoa!
Don't move and
lower your weapons.
We just want the money.
Hand it over and
nobody gets hurt.
I'm afraid this ain't
our money to give.
Come on.
You don't wanna do this.
Fuck.
Come on!
What happened?
I couldn't shoot him.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
You promise
you'll come back to me.
I promise.
Come on!
Where's the money?
I know
you took it, John.
Yeah, I took the money.
I also know
you killed my father.
Deputy, take Mr. Mason
into custody.
Sheriff's department
just got a little smaller.
We had to let
a few of 'em go.
(LAUGHS)
Don't do it, John.
Shut the fuck up,
Greyson.
Are you gonna put
the money back?
It doesn't seem to be
the safest place for it.
CURLY: John Mason,
you're under arrest for
stealing federal money
and assaulting
a peace officer.
You weren't a peace officer
when I assaulted you,
you sure as shit ain't
a peace officer now.
No!
Don't!
You get your hands
off him!
You son of a bitch!
ALICE: Let me go!
(GROANING)
RUDD: It was an accident.
Sure.
The marshal's comin' up
day after tomorrow.
Gonna be askin'
a whole lot
of questions.
Yeah, well, if two
of those questions are,
"Where's the money?"
And "Who killed Dad Mason?"
I might be able
to help him out.
You're gonna wanna
get me that money.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Dad saw your brand.
I ain't losin' the
Double Cross, John.
I never really cared
for that name.
I can see how
it's fitting though.
I love my sister, Mason.
But look into my eyes
so you know that
I'm telling you the truth.
I will sacrifice her
to save the ranch
that my daddy worked
so hard to build.
Now get me my money.
I'm gonna give you an hour
to get out of town.
How is it that you're
the one threatening me,
yet you're the one
behind bars?
Maybe you didn't
hear me.
Alice's life
is in your hands.
JOHN: Fifty-nine minutes.
Jesus Christ, Rudd!
What the hell
are you doin'?
Now's not a good time, Ben.
Okay.
Is there somethin'
going on between
John Mason and Alice?
I don't know if it's
anything serious,
but, um,
it's goin' on.
Okay.
Those bullets meant
for John?
They're in case
we need to talk.
Talk.
I want you to stay here.
Curly will keep
an eye on you.
JOHN: They're gonna
hang you, you know.
Shut up.
Hey, it's true.
You know, they say
a hanging man
shits himself
100 % of the time.
Shut the fuck up!
You're the one going
to hang for killing
them Pinkertons.
What?
I said Pinkertons.
Pinkertons.
I'm sorry, I can't
understand a word
you are saying.
You mumble,
you know that?
Open your ears,
Cincinnati John Mason.
I said Pinkertons.
Oh.
Yeah.
JOHN: I told you!
(GRUNTING)
(BONE CRACKING)
(PANTING)
I ain't never been
to Cincinnati.
You're not gonna give me
any trouble, are you?
Your brother did
what he had to.
For you.
I could do something
for you.
Okay.
What?
You hard of hearin'?
Well, what exactly
you sayin'?
Do I gotta spell it out
for you?
(CHUCKLES)
No, ma'am.
Nice and slow.
Uh-uh.
Everyone knows you
keep a Derringer under
your pillow, darlin'.
(GUN FIRES)
I had to switch
hidin' places.
And it ain't no
fuckin' Derringer.
Now how's about
you keep that little
hand cannon of yours
inside its holster
so that I don't have
to shoot you again
and get your blood
dirtying up my pretty dress.
You boys got your
stories straight for
when the marshal comes?
We get Mason to get
the money for us,
then his word
against ours,
Mason gets arrested.
You got it?
And no killin'.
(JOHN GRUNTING)
(EXHALES)
Would you mind
giving me a hand?
Oh, looks like
you almost got it.
We're gonna need McClure.
McClure, you in here?
(GUN COCKING)
What?
Great.
What's the plan?
(SIGHS)
Great coffee.
Oh, thank you.
Can I have a word?
All right.
You care about Alice.
So do I.
I need you to do
somethin' for me.
Get her out of town,
wait it out.
I'll come for you
when it's over.
All right.
ALICE: Goddamn you,
Ben McClure!
You know, I really wish
you didn't make me do this.
Goddamn it,
if you don't let me go,
I swear to God
I'll kill you myself!
Oh, come on now, Alice!
Look, all right,
get set down right here.
Stop it!
Just stop, all right?
I will let you go
soon enough.
Look,
John needs our help.
Yeah, I'll say he does.
Ben McClure,
did you do somethin'?
Greyson and Curly
are dead.
Mason and Alice
are gone.
He took the money.
He ain't goin' nowhere.
Time's up.
I just want my money.
You're under arrest.
Where'd you get
the tin?
Off the chest
of a good man.
A man you murdered.
Well, that's your word
against all of ours
and with your history
of violent behavior...
Hand over your weapons.
(DOOR BANGS OPEN)
Don't give 'em the money.
That ain't gonna help you.
It can't hurt.
McClure here got
himself all drunk
and jealous
and took the bullets
out of your guns.
I'm sorry, John.
I wasn't using my head.
Just give me
the money now.
It's all yours.
Boys?
You know, they ain't
gonna do you much good
without bullets.
You know,
it's a funny thing
when you take
the bullets out
of a man's gun.
It changes the weight.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GUNFIRE)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
That's enough.
Put 'em down, Mason.
It's over, Rudd.
Come on.
Put down the gun.
There's no more
money left.
You son of a bitch!
BEN: Hey, John?
Hey.
Oh, shit.
Yep.
It's all good.
I'm okay.
You're gonna be okay.
Rudd's boys
took the ring.
We'll talk
about it later.
Is he okay?
Yeah, he's gonna live.
Come on.
Okay, I got you.
I got you.
Dad wasn't supposed
to be at the Express.
We all got some place
we gotta be.
Eloquently put.
(COCHRANE LAUGHING)
You die first.
No, Alice...
Hey, put down your gun.
Now, looks like
your luck's finally
run out, John Mason.
You got a badge.
Your gardening
got boring for you,
did it?
Gentlemen?
You're here for Mason.
No, I'm not here for Mason.
It was Mason that
found me bleedin'
like a stuck pig
in the bushes near where
you left me for dead,
you son of a bitch!
You killed four good men.
Take him away.
Now, don't lose these.
Make sure he doesn't
lose these.
This paper sets you
free and clear
as far as Missouri
is concerned
and this is a telegram
from the people back east
saying that they accept
my conclusion
that you are not
responsible for what
transpired in Mexico.
Sorry I couldn't do
anything about Ohio.
Hey...
I know.
You've never been
in Cincinnati.
(LAUGHS)
John.
I got a train
takin' me east.
I'm never comin'
back here.
I always thought
I was gonna bid farewell
to you and you'd be dead.
But you're not.
Congratulations.
Goodbye, John.
Goodbye, Miss Gordon.
COCHRANE:
I hate the west!
I don't suppose you'll
help me explain to
the railway company
what happened to that
extra money, huh?
What extra money?
Let's just say
I left a little out
of those bags
that just exploded.
How much is a little?
Eh, I dunno.
Roughly.
Somewhere in
the neighborhood
of $5,000.
JOHN: You ever been
to Cincinnati?
ALICE: (LAUGHING) No.