There's the 23rd marker, sir.
Twenty three miles
in one hour and 14 minutes.
-Gentlemen, that is moving.
-Our engineer is trying to set a record.
COGGINS: I doubt if we can maintain
this speed on our regular schedule.
Why not? If this train can do it,
the rest of them can.
Providing Colonel Dodge's new town
is worth speeding to reach.
You wait.
Right now it's the end of the line,
but in a couple years,
it'll give more business
-than any town west of Chicago.
-I hope you're right.
You've stuck to that argument
for five years.
Why shouldn't I? I've raised that town
from two hog pens and a buffalo Waller.
(LAUGHING)
How big is it now, colonel?
Well, at the last census, gentlemen,
they had three buffalo wallers.
Look. There goes the stagecoach
from Wichita.
TWITCHELL: We'll be carrying the mail
from now on.
Listen to the darn snorting teapot.
She's already winded.
-By Jove, we'll run her into the ground.
-Better pull your whip to him.
-Willie.
-Yes, sir, boss?
You tell our engineer if that
stagecoach beats us, he's fired.
Yes, sir. And if this train
go any faster
I'm gonna get off and walk
because I don't like this zest of the Lord.
(LAUGHING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
He's making a good showing.
You know it.
-TWITCHELL: We'll get him.
-We'd better get up some speed.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
-COGGINS: There he goes.
-TWITCHELL: We've got him.
MAN:
Goodbye. See you in town.
Gentlemen, that's a symbol
of America's future. Progress.
Iron men and iron horses.
You can't beat them.
# (TEX SINGING) #
Lucky devils. Nothing to do
but eat and sleep.
Right. The only difference between you
and them is a pair of horns.
Oh, hush.
Say, Wade.
Let's cut out a couple of them.
No. We've killed our last buffalo, boys.
The railroads finished,
and so is our contract.
Besides, we've a little appointment
to keep, do you know? Come on.
# (SINGING) #
(HORN BLOWING)
Here comes our meal ticket
for six months.
That's what a steam engine looks like,
a coffeepot on wheels.
Let's pay our respects to the colonel.
-WADE: Hello, colonel. How are you?
-DODGE: Fine, son. Fine.
-See you soon.
-We'll be there.
Dodge, you know everybody
in Kansas.
They've been working for us, hunting
buffalo, to feed our construction gang.
Young Irishman is Wade Hatton.
Met him during the war.
He fought for the Rebels
in Jeb Stuart's cavalry.
Been everywhere, done everything.
Sort of a rover.
It takes all sorts of men
to build a railroad, huh?
No, sir. Just a couple of us Irishmen.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
-Men, we're gonna start moving.
-Watch those hides, they don't slip.
-MAN 1: We're gonna start moving.
-MAN 2: You drivers keep close together.
-YANCEY: Ready to start when you say.
-All right. Let's move fast.
SURRETT:
Whoa!
-BARLOW: Which one of you is Jeff Surrett?
-I am. Why?
I'm John Barlow, commissioner
of Indian Affairs from Kansas.
-You're under arrest. All three of you.
-For what?
For the illegal killing of buffalo.
We got those buffalo on free land,
just the same as he did.
He has a permit to furnish meat
for the railroad men.
Have you got any such permit?
-Is this your business?
-I made it my business.
When I found out you were
shooting buffalo on Indian territory
and letting the meat rot in the sun.
When Indians protested,
you shot them in cold blood.
-This has been going on all winter.
-Now you catch up?
We didn't wanna catch up. Just counted
the number of animals you killed.
You'd have made them stop us
long before this if you'd known.
Why? It seemed a better idea to let you
and your pals work your head off,
packing and curing those hides
until they caught you.
Oh, so that's why you waited
so long, huh?
The Indians might as well get
the hides in salable condition.
All right, Hatton.
But I hope you stick around Kansas
for a long time.
We'll collect for every one
of those hides, in full.
Right. If you're ever around our way,
look us up.
MAN:
All right, boys.
# (SINGING) #
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BAND PLAYING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
-Thanks, Tex.
-Congratulations.
Thanks. You've been a great help
in building this railroad.
The real work begins.
We've got to make it pay.
-That's up to you.
-No.
I've got other work to do.
We're looking further west.
I want you to take charge here,
help build up this town.
No, thanks. We're on our way back to
Texas, drive cattle to meet your railroad.
Besides, if we keep hanging around here,
these two will get civilized.
We'd better get out before he starts
eating with a knife and fork.
WADE:
A knife anyway.
You couldn't keep Wade here. He's the
most moving-on man you ever saw.
He was in the English army in India, then
got mixed up in some revolution in Cuba.
Then he started punching cattle
in Texas, before he enlisted in the war.
So he's either the greatest traveler who
ever lived or else he is the biggest liar.
(LAUGHING)
MAN: It gives me great pleasure
to introduce to you
the man who made
this progress possible:
Colonel Dodge.
DODGE:
Ladies and gentlemen,
today a great chapter of history
has been written
and we take justifiable pride
in bringing this railroad to the terminal
furthest west in this country.
Someday, and I believe it will be
in the near future,
a great city will spring from this
very spot upon which we now stand.
A city which will represent
all that the West stands for:
Honesty, courage, morality
and culture.
For all the noble virtues of civilization
I can see a great metropolis of homes,
churches, schools.
A fine, decent city, which will become
the flower of the prairie.
A city whose name...
-Whose name--
-Yeah, colonel.
Just what do you aim to call
this here perfect metropolis?
What are we going to call it?
Call it after the man who made it
possible. Dodge City.
That's right. Dodge City it is.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Hey, be sure and give
those cattle plenty of salt.
The more water, the more weight.
Cattle is sure some business.
They come to Dodge City
from all over the world, don't they?
Almost, son. Hold my horse.
Wait. You can't ship those cattle.
Where's my money?
You'll get it. Stop worrying.
You've got no right to ship those cattle
until I'm paid, $15,000, cash in hand.
We agreed.
I can't run to the bank
every time a train leaves town.
There are other cattle brokers
that will trust me.
Maybe they used to, Surrett.
But not since what happened
to Sam Chapin and Kit Sproull.
They trusted you too, didn't they?
But not me.
I'm coming to your place tonight
to collect.
Have the money waiting,
or I'm slapping a warrant on you.
You gotta get what's yours
when dealing with men like that.
-They're no good.
-Sure, Pop, but we can handle them.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Hold my horse.
I won't be but a minute.
Take your time, Pop,
but get all that's coming to us.
MAN:
Come on, boys, this is the place.
(MEN CHEERING)
# (SINGING
"MY HEART TURNED BACK TO DIXIE") #
-You look great, Ruby. I like that dress.
-Thanks.
-For luck.
-You don't need any.
That's right, I don't.
Not as long as I've got you.
That's me.
# (WOMEN SINGING) #
-Surrett, I was just looking for you.
-Hello.
-Ready to see me?
-I was on my way to get some money.
-I'll go with you.
-Mind waiting? I got some business first.
I don't mind.
But don't try and run out on me.
-This is your last chance.
-Don't worry.
I'll take care of you in a minute.
Come and wet your whistle.
-Hey, Jack.
-BARTENDER: Yes, sir?
Give Mr. Cole anything he wants,
on the house.
-What will it be?
-Glass of beer, please.
Yes, sir.
Nice-looking bunch of steers
we shipped today, huh?
They'd look better if I'd been paid.
What do you mean?
Haven't we always paid?
-Not from what I've heard.
-You've been listening to too much talk.
Maybe. Maybe not.
Are you calling me a liar?
I'm not calling you anything, Yancey.
-In fact, I'd rather not talk to you at all.
-Keep your hand off that gun.
(GUNSHOT)
MAN: In sure and certain hope
of the resurrection of the dead.
Father which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name
thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
as in heaven, so in earth.
Give us day by day our daily bread
and forgive us our debts as we also
forgive everyone that is indebted to us.
Lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from evil. Amen.
To have him go this way,
it's so, so cruel, so useless.
You promised you wouldn't cry, Mom.
-John, will you look after Mrs. Cole?
-You don't have to, Mr. Orth.
-I can take care of her.
-ORTH: That's right, Harry.
You're the man of the family now.
Well, funeral's over. There's your man,
marshal. Serve your warrant.
It's about time those gorillas
were taken in hand.
-What are you waiting for? Go on.
-Don't push me. I know my duty.
-SURRETT: Hello, marshal.
-Yancey,
I've got a warrant here to arrest you
for the murder of
(STAMMERS)
Matt Cole.
Why don't you go ahead and serve it,
then. What are you waiting for?
-Mind riding back into town with me?
-Yeah.
That's all right. You go ahead
and ride in with the marshal.
Why, sure, marshal. Come along.
Come on, boys. Come on, Al.
After all, the law's the law.
Just a minute.
This is your carriage.
-MARSHAL: Hold on!
-YANCEY: Get him in there. Hurry up.
MARSHAL:
I've got the law on my side.
Come on, boys.
We'll ride him out of town in style.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
Why try to make an honest town
out of Dodge City?
Surrett's crowd scares off
the law-abiding settlers.
They're all going on to Wichita
and Kansas City.
I tell you, Ellen, we're the public
disgrace of America.
You know what the New York
newspapers are saying?
There's no law west of Chicago.
And west of Dodge City, no God.
I'm afraid they're not far wrong.
It's becoming unsafe for a woman
to walk on the streets.
As for children, I almost wish Lee and
Abbie weren't coming to live with us.
They'll be all right, unless they're
as bullheaded as their father.
We haven't heard a word
since they reached Texas.
When do you suppose
they'll get here?
IRVING:
I kept the record somewhere.
-I always used to--
-There, on the table.
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
They left Fort Worth three weeks ago
with a cattle-drive party.
Now, let's see.
Yeah, they must have crossed
the Red River about here
then on up the Chisholm Trail
into the Indian territory.
I'd say they'd be about Broad Plain
by now.
ABBIE:
Tex! Tex.
-Have you seen my brother?
-Yes, ma'am.
He's over yonder
hotfooting it around.
He swiped one of the boss's horses.
I reckon he's drunk again.
I consider that
a very impertinent remark.
Yes, ma'am. I guess maybe I shouldn't
have said he's drunk, even if he is drunk.
(CHEERING)
I don't know what I'm gonna do
about you.
Broad Plain, huh?
Broad Plain.
This is where the Indians
are supposed to be.
If you keep up the fuss,
they'll be on our doorstep.
I wish they would attack us
or something.
It's dull plugging along like this
clay in and clay out.
But that's no reason for you
to act like a lunatic.
Maybe they don't even know
we're here. Let's tell them.
(CHEERING)
Lee, stop it. Stop it!
Lee!
Will you--?
WADE: Was that you who fired
those shots, Mr. Irving?
-RUSTY: Sure, it was him.
-What about it?
WADE: Nothing. It seems like
a silly waste of ammunition.
He won't do it again.
He was bored.
-Oh. Faith, now. That's a great shame.
-So am I.
Really? Well, I'm sorry.
Perhaps things will get enlivened
if that shooting stampedes the cattle.
Since you seem to know what troubles
him, I'd suggest you see he drinks less.
Them two is more trouble
than they're worth.
I'll certainly be glad to hand them
over to their uncle in Dodge.
Yeah. She sure is pretty, though.
Yes. I'd still trade the two of them
for one good cigar.
All right, this is it. Tex. Rusty.
Tex, get the steers watered. Rusty,
line up the wagons along the slope.
-Get moving, flat-neck.
-RUSTY: Oh, hush. I'll get moving.
All right. We're bedding down.
Watch your cook fires.
The grass is awful dry.
-Don't you wander off.
-LITTLE GIRL: I'm hungry.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
WADE: Get the teams hooked up.
Let's move out.
Move as soon as you're ready.
Tex, get the herd started.
TEX: Watch him. I caught him riding
in a wagon yesterday.
RUSTY:
Oh, hush. I wasn't...
Good morning. You rest well?
-MRS. HARPER: Thank you. Yeah, fine.
-Good.
Be sure you boil that water
before you drink it.
ABBIE: Two minutes after you were born,
you were telling the doctor what to do.
WADE:
Think so? I'm sorry, Miss Irving.
It's really no fun playing boss, but
someone's gotta say what's to be done.
Out here, trail boss sometimes even
has to take the law into his own hands.
Yes. Pioneering,
I believe you call it, don't you?
-You don't seem to be enjoying it much.
-Enjoying it?
Can anyone enjoy being jolted along
week in and week out
through heat and dust
with sand in your teeth, in your eyes
and in your hair?
Faith, now. If you didn't like sand,
you shouldn't have left home.
I wouldn't have, but we didn't have
much choice after Father died.
I see. I'm sorry.
-Can I take that? It looks heavy.
-No, thanks. I can manage.
I'm sure you can manage bigger ones
if you wanted to, but why should you?
-I happen to be in a hurry.
-We'll wait for you.
There. See?
If everyone would obey orders
as willingly as that
we wouldn't have any trouble at all.
My brother and I seem to be causing
a great deal of trouble.
No, no. Just your brother.
I think you spoil him by mothering him,
that's all.
Maybe I do.
May I make a suggestion?
Why don't you go to him--
(GUNSHOT)
(MOOING)
Lee.
Look here, Mr. Irving.
This ain't no picnic grounds.
Put up that gun
before you stampede them cattle.
Get down off your high horse.
Watch me shoot the handle
right off of this one.
-Are you out of your mind?
-Hi.
You're in time to witness an exhibition
of some real fancy shooting.
Drop that gun
before somebody takes it.
-Who's gonna take it away from me?
-You're drunk.
Don't start the lecture.
I've had enough of that.
Lee, don't! Don't!
(CHEERING)
It's a run!
Tex, head in those leaders
and keep them milling.
See what you did.
I hope you're satisfied.
I've been waiting to see a little action
since this trip started.
-You saw what nearly happened.
-What? I just gave you a little exercise.
Irving.
You're giving us trouble.
I'll have to be unpleasant.
Oh, let me alone. I'm not on
your payroll, and I'll do as I please.
You'll do as I please. You people in
the wagons came to us for protection.
You paid for it. Obey orders
until we get to Dodge City.
You may not realize it, but the Civil War
is over. You're no longer in the army.
Just sober up and stay sober,
or I'll confiscate your liquor.
You lay a hand inside our wagon,
and I'll blow it off.
Look, Irving.
We've got a special treatment
for bad boys like you.
Behave yourself, or you're gonna ride
into Dodge City backwards on a mule.
(RUSTY CHUCKLING)
Now we're moving.
You better get started.
-ABBIE: Lee, be sensible.
-Let me alone.
(LAUGHING)
I can hardly wait to see you
on that mule. You'll look funny.
Take that stupid grin off your face,
you big hyena.
(GUNSHOTS)
Drop that gun, Irving.
Drop it, I tell you.
Ah! Lee!
(MOOING)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
You killed him.
Here you are, Tex.
That's for Dr. Irving.
Take the shortcut into Twin Forks,
bear left.
-It's three hours to Dodge. Understand?
-Sure.
I tried to explain it. Tell him
I'll call when we get there.
I hope that doctor's more understanding
than his niece.
-Good luck. Get going, Tex.
-TEX: Adiós.
Miss Irving.
I know how you must feel about all this
and how you feel about my part in it.
But my shot was unavoidable. I'd never
have fired it except to defend myself.
I have no words to tell you
how badly I feel.
Will you leave me alone, please?
Well, well.
So this is Dodge City, huh?
It sort of smells like Fort Worth.
That's not the city, that's you.
Let's get you to a bath
before you're shot for a buffalo.
Gentlemen, can I hold your horse?
Lady, can I carry your basket?
Can I hold your horse?
Can I hold your horses?
I'll watch her real careful.
-What's the idea, sonny?
-HARRY: I'm in business.
I'm the man of the family now.
-WADE: You certainly make an early start.
-What do you charge?
HARRY: A quarter for keeping an eye
on your horses.
Fifty cents for watching them
extra good.
All right, we'll take a dollar's worth
of the extra good.
(CHUCKLING)
Didn't Shakespeare begin
by holding horses?
-RUSTY: Who?
-Hey, stranger, where's the money?
Oh, so you don't get
any credit here, huh?
-Well, here you are.
-HARRY: Thanks, mister. Much obliged.
WADE:
You're welcome.
-Shakespeare.
-RUSTY: Never heard of him.
-What part of Texas is he from?
-Stratford-on-Avon.
-Morning, boys.
-Good morning.
You fellows look pretty dusty.
WADE: It's on us about an inch thick
for each state in the country.
# (SINGING) #
-What's the news in Dodge?
-Just about the same as always.
Gambling, drinking and killing.
And mostly killing.
Had one here just the other night.
Coldest-blooded thing I ever heard of.
Yancey shot Matt Cole
at the Gay Lady.
Matt Cole?
I used to know him in Texas.
-What was the trouble?
How long since you been in Dodge?
Some time.
We ship up through Wichita.
Well, this town's run by a man
named Jeff Surrett.
Cole was trying to collect
for some cattle he sold.
Fifteen thousand dollars,
Surrett owed him.
Good morning, gentlemen.
How long before you're through
with him?
BARBER: Why...
-In about ten minutes, Mr. Surrett.
-All right, hurry it up.
I'm gonna take a bath. Yancey.
I'm sorry, there's somebody
in there already.
# (SINGING) #
Hey, shut that door.
There's a draft in here.
What's the idea? I always take
a bath on Saturday mornings.
-Get that fellow out of there.
-Sorry. I can't do that, Mr. Surrett.
-He ain't been in there half an hour.
-He's been there long enough.
Now, you tell him
to get his clothes on.
-All right, all right.
-Wait a minute.
What did you say?
My friend in there paid for that tub.
Much as you undoubtedly need to wash,
he needs it even more.
Well, if it ain't our old friend Hatton.
WADE:
Right. Quite a coincidence, isn't it?
Are you figuring on being around long?
No. Just as long as it takes me
to finish my job.
Maybe longer if it's interesting.
Any objections?
-We can make it interesting for you.
-Yes. I'm sure you might.
I hear you made it interesting
for Matt Cole the other night.
You always heard a little too much.
It's possible you boys were always
a little too noisy.
Come on, finish me up.
Put that green stuff on.
Make me smell like a geranium.
Say, Wade. You know, it just
come to me who that feller was.
It did? Marvelous.
Naturally, our nephew's death
was a great blow to us
but since your explanation,
I can understand how it happened.
There's no sense in holding
any grudge against you.
Thank you, sir.
We're used to death
here in Dodge City, Mr. Hatton.
Even of the people we love.
-That's hard to say, but it's true.
-Yes, I suppose so.
Well, thanks again, doctor.
Might I pay my respects
to Mrs. and Miss Irving?
No, my boy, I wouldn't advise that.
Mr. Evans wants you to come
as soon as you can.
-Oh, excuse me.
-Ellen, this is Mr. Hatton.
How do you do, Mrs. Irving?
He's come to tell us about Lee.
It's regrettable that we have to meet
under these circumstances, Mrs. Irving.
I'm sorry, my boy, but you see,
we never had any children of our own.
And to my wife, Lee was--
Well, you can understand
how she feels about it.
Yes, of course. Anyhow, it was
very gracious of you to receive us.
WADE: Oh, don't bother about that.
Thank you, sir, I--
Miss Irving.
I'll not trouble you with apologies.
But I would like you to know
that if I can be of service
-shall be only too happy.
-Thank you.
The only way you can be of service
is to keep out of my sight.
IRVING: I wouldn't take her
too seriously, my boy.
Women's logic and emotions
are often very confusing.
I think I've heard my father
say the same thing.
I'm sure that Miss Abbie has a more
biting tongue than my mother ever had.
Gentlemen, let's begin the auction.
One thousand six hundred and nineteen
head of prime Texas steer.
Grass-fed, fat, frisky, fresh off
the Chisholm Trail. Is that correct?
WADE: Go. But don't make any sale
until I tell you.
Right. The agent reserves his right
to refuse all bids. Who will start us off?
-What am I offered?
-Twenty five dollars a head.
AUCTIONEER: Twenty five
from Mr. Surrett. I'm going to 28.
Twenty-eight for the finest herd
of steers that ever come out of Texas.
-Mr. Cagle?
-No, sir.
Mr. Orth?
Here's a cash profit of $50,000
begging to be picked up.
-ORTH: All right, 28.
-Thank you, 28 is bid.
Who'll say 30? Thirty, 30, 30.
Nobody will raise it?
-Thirty dollars.
-AUCTIONEER: Thirty dollars.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
Anybody raise that?
Anybody say 32?
How about you, Mr. Orth?
Going to Mr. Surrett for $30.
Once. Going twice.
Hold on.
Mr. Surrett and Mr. Orth
be kind enough to step up here.
AUCTIONEER: Oh, Mr. Surrett, Mr. Orth.
Will you come over here, please?
-You offered $30. Was that cash?
-Do you own those cattle?
I'm the agent.
I'm protecting the owner's interest.
Oh, I see. Well, I'll give you part of it in
cash tonight and the balance in 30 days.
I see. How about you, sir?
I could've paid the full amount
in cash today.
You could've? They're yours.
-Mine? But he offered--
-I said, sold.
What? I made the high bid
on those steers.
I heard, but I prefer to make my deal
with cash buyers
who don't pay off
in the backrooms of saloons.
WADE: I'm at the Drovers Hotel. Meet me
at 3:00 in Room 15, we'll close this deal.
-I'll be there.
-Right. Deal is made, Mr. Auctioneer.
-Thanks. Good day.
-AUCTIONEER: Sold to Mr. Orth.
-Did you hear that?
-I'll put it on the front page.
-Who's that fellow?
-I don't know, but I'm gonna find out.
-ORTH: How are you, Harry?
-Hello, Mr. Orth.
-I'll hold your horse.
-Good.
HARRY:
For a quarter.
(ORTH CHUCKLING)
-Well, that's fair enough. Here.
-Thanks.
-How are you, Frank?
-CLERK: Fine. How are you?
-Just fine.
-MAN: Howdy, Mr. Orth.
HARRY:
Stick them up.
Rusty, we're done for.
It's Dangerous Ambrose,
the terror of the prairie. He's got us.
HARRY: Yes, sir.
I'm a pretty desperate character.
I can see that. Would you take ransom
if we offered it?
HARRY:
Try it and see.
How's that?
Thanks. I'll watch your horses better
than they were ever watched before.
WADE:
Well, that's fair enough. Here.
-I hope you stay in town a long time.
-I'll bet you do at that.
-Has Orth come in yet?
-Went upstairs a few minutes ago.
I'm Joe Clemens.
I'm editor of the Star.
I'd like to publish your impressions
of Dodge City, if you don't mind.
(GUNSHOT)
Somebody shot him.
He's laying right outside of Room 15.
SURRETT:
That's too bad, Hatton.
I don't think your deal with Orth
will go through.
I'm still offering $30 a head
for those cattle.
Listen, Surrett, those cattle
aren't for sale to you at any price.
It's a shame about Jack Orth
being killed, isn't it?
Must've been a big surprise to you.
Excuse me.
MAN 1:
Another murder. Four or five a day.
MAN 2:
Surrett's the undertaker's best friend.
MAN 3:
It's getting dangerous to live here.
Well, why don't you get out?
I see by that bulletin
that you're looking for trouble.
We're just printing the plain facts.
We put up with your paper
long enough.
-Now we mean business.
-Yancey,
are you scared of that fellow
from Texas?
We'll take care of him, but don't print
no story about Surrett.
Is that clear?
I'm waiting for an answer.
I reckon you get the general idea now.
Those clothes look as though
you're up to no good.
I ain't had store clothes on for a long
time. I felt like I wanted to clean up.
I got a call to make,
so you're on your own.
Just try and keep sober
and stay out of trouble.
I signed the temperance pledge
before we left Texas.
I know that, and you were drunk
when you signed it.
No, you're confusing the issue.
I'm a reformed man.
Even a reformed man gets into trouble
when the boys get paid off.
No. I ain't gonna touch a drop.
I'll mosey around and take in the sights.
-Don't become one of them.
-Don't you worry none about it.
After me getting
on my store clothes
I'm not gonna have anything
like that happen.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN:
Hey, mister.
Please help me over,
will you, young man?
Get closer.
Oh!
# (RUBY SINGING
"LITTLE BROWN JUG") #
-There you are, ma'am. Glad to help.
-Thank you.
(MEN LAUGHING)
-Hi, Rusty. Come on, have a drink.
-Come with us and get your feet wet.
-I was just leaving.
-What do you mean?
We got a lot of Kansas dust
to wash down. Come on.
Waste my pay on liquor and gambling?
Not me, boys. I'm on the pledge.
Why, you ain't serious, Rusty.
I'll tell you, boys, I've saw the light.
I'm through with your sinful ways
and your riotous living.
He must be crazy with the heat.
Come on.
A drink!
Hey, you old walrus, you.
How about a drink?
Come on.
Oh, I don't want that.
Give me one of those.
That's more like it.
# (WOMEN SINGING
"LIFE IS LIKE A MIGHTY RIVER") #
My gracious.
Howdy, young man.
Are you a stranger in town?
Yes, ma'am. I didn't know
this was just for womenfolks.
But it isn't. Not at all.
We are mighty glad to have you.
But first of all, let me introduce
our beloved president, Mrs. McCoy.
So delighted to meet you
in this charitable institution.
Well, ma'am, my name is Hart.
Algernon Hart.
Mr. Algernon Hart.
Well, Mr. Hart, you're just in time
for the meeting.
But first, come have a cup of tea,
Mr. Harvey.
-Hart, ma'am.
-Oh, I'm so sorry. Mr. Hart.
Come, girls, help me.
Now, here's your tea.
I hope you like it.
One or two?
Three, ma'am.
Are you married?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
# (SINGING
"MARCHING THROUGH GEORGIA") #
(CROWD SINGS ALONG)
Hey, Joe.
How about that "Dixie"?
Come on, right up here.
# (SINGING
"MY HEART TURNED BACK TO DIXIE") #
(CHEERING)
That's for the 5th Kansas Infantry.
We chased them
so far from Fredericksburg
they ain't stopped running yet.
They must've stopped running
long enough to get their picture took.
Nobody chased the 5th Kansas.
-Do you belong to it?
-All of us do.
Is that a fact?
You must have had to run
a long way to get to Kansas.
It's gonna be a longer run
back to Texas.
Oh, yeah?
It's that dreadful saloon next door.
Mabel, please close the shutters.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Hart.
And there I was, a poor orphan,
no ma and no pa,
brung up by Comanche Indians.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
No matter where you go,
fittin' ain't good.
It ain't no use to fight.
Fighting's a thing I--
Well, I don't like it myself,
and now I wanna--
(GLASS SMASHING)
That's a present from U.S. Grant.
That's for Robert E. Lee.
Yes, sir. And I wanna say to you,
sisters,
that when righteousness flows
from the str-- From the riv-- From the--
Oh, it was smooth.
Yippee!
Who's next?
(SCREAMS)
Rusty! Oh!
Come get these fleas out of my hair.
Stop it, you fools. Stop it, I say.
Stop it! Stop it!
Thanks, Rusty. Just in time.
Stop it, you fools!
(SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOTS)
TEX: All right, boys. Looks like we've
dusted this place off pretty good.
That's one fight you Yanks didn't win.
But take it easy.
We'll send a veterinary right over.
(MEN CHEERING)
Somebody's gonna pay for this,
and it ain't gonna be with money.
RUSTY: When I seen the light, it come to
me sort of vision-like, and I was saved.
Hey, Jeff, there's one of them
Texas heroes left behind.
-Let me take a sock at him.
-I'll handle this.
-You boys had a lot of fun, didn't you?
-We sure did.
That's fine.
I've waited for you or your pal
to make a move. This looks like it.
What are you gonna do?
I'll have fun paying back
an old debt with interest.
Come on, boys.
Let's take him out to the plaza.
MAN:
Bring him along.
-Hey, doc. Mr. Hatton.
-What's wrong, Joe?
Your men wrecked
the Gay Lady saloon.
-Anybody hurt?
-They're fixin' to hang one of your boys.
-Where are my men?
-They've ridden back to camp.
-Where's the hanging party?
-In the middle of the plaza.
You're loco. I ain't done nothing
to be strung up for.
Shut up!
Wade.
There they are.
SURRETT:
Hold on, boys.
Be careful, Mr. Hatton.
Take it easy.
That rope's strong enough
for both of them.
MAN:
Well, what do you think of this?
I've no wish to spoil your fun, Surrett,
but would you tell those men
to let him go?
As quick as he gets through
dancing around up there.
You heard what I said, I think.
Tell them to let him go.
All right.
String him up, boys.
WADE:
Put them up. Stick them up.
Keep reaching high, boys, or you know
what happens to Surrett.
Get over here, Rusty. Get his gun.
We may never be
this close again, Surrett.
I'm anxious to hear what the sheriff
has to say about this.
Start walking.
CLEMENS: What are you gonna do?
IRVING: There's no warrant.
Did he have a warrant to hang him?
IRVING:
Can't jail him without a sheriff's order.
We're going to get a sheriff's order.
Wait a minute. What's this?
Where's the sheriff?
-Somebody ran him out of town.
-Mr. Surrett's the law in Dodge now.
Oh, I see.
-Why don't you make him sheriff, then?
-Yeah.
That's not a bad idea.
Why not?
If I can be of any service
to you gents, let me know.
That's the first jail I've ever seen
you couldn't get in. Come on.
Good day, gentlemen.
-It was all a mistake.
-A mistake, eh?
You promised me
you wouldn't get into trouble.
Shucks, Wade,
I really wasn't in trouble.
You're the sort
who doesn't get into trouble,
until they nail the lid down
on your coffin.
What's that?
"Pure Prairie League of Dodge City."
Wait till I tell Tex about this.
RUSTY:
Don't tell Tex.
WADE: Gentlemen,
what's this all about?
You all look as though
you lost a dollar and found a dime.
CLEMENS:
Go ahead and tell him, doctor.
We've invited you here this afternoon
with a special purpose.
We want you to help us
clean up our city.
Our peace officers
have not been equal to the job.
They've either got killed or run out
of town. Won't you take the job?
Gentlemen, I certainly appreciate
your confidence in me,
but I'm afraid a position like that
isn't in my line.
You're asking me to turn policeman.
I have as much qualifications for that
as teaching the ballet.
You seemed qualified
the other day in the plaza.
I had to get that hardhead
out of there.
Any one of you
would've done the same. No.
We know what we're asking
and the chances you'd be taking,
but it's come to a showdown,
who's gonna run Dodge?
We or Surrett? We're inviting peaceful
immigration here.
Family men with women and children,
and we meet them with
what's called "Hell Street."
I can appreciate
everything you say.
As far as I'm concerned,
it can't be done.
I'm in the cattle business.
That demands all my time.
-I'm sorry.
-I wish you'd think it over, my boy.
-We need you.
-You're asking the wrong man.
-He isn't interested in innocent people.
-Abbie.
Why should he care
what happens to you?
Your struggle to make a living
in a decent city.
Dodge City needs a man
with a sense of public pride,
and the courage to back it up
fighting men of equal skill.
But his bravery consists of gunfights
with impulsive boys.
Abbie, stop it!
Well, gentlemen, I don't think much
remains to be said.
Mrs. Irving. Thank you.
Goodbye, gentlemen.
ABBIE:
Everybody, get in as quickly as you can.
Come along. Harry, keep out
of that lunch basket.
I can't seem to get my mind off
those pies. How long before we eat?
ABBIE:
Not till we get to Sycamore Springs.
HARRY:
I'll do my best to wait.
ABBIE: Is everybody in?
CHILDREN: Yes!
Here we go. Come along.
WADE: We cross the river here, Rus,
and bear due west into Wichita.
When are you starting?
First thing in the morning.
I'm sick of this town.
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
WADE:
Good morning.
I know that man.
-Hello, stranger.
-Hello there, Shakespeare.
-Here.
-Thanks.
You better watch that riverbed too.
It's probably gonna be dry.
(GUNSHOTS)
Steady.
I'll help you. Give me those reins.
(SCREAMING)
Let me through. Darling!
Oh, my little...
He was trying to help me.
-Get a doctor, quick.
-I'm afraid a doctor won't be any use.
Children.
This has got to stop.
Oh, my darling. My little baby.
RUSTY:
Come on. Come on.
WADE:
You're all under arrest.
Take them out, boys.
Go on.
Get in there.
I wanted to be sure you'd seen this,
Surrett, so I paid you a special visit.
I've seen it. It looks like you're trying
to run everybody out of Dodge City.
No, no. Not everybody.
Just the undesirable element.
There's no law in Kansas that prevents
a man from carrying a gun
-or coming or going where he pleases.
-There will be one.
Sit down, Hatton.
The merchants won't stand for this.
WADE: I think they will. They helped me
draw this law up.
They're willing to take their chances.
I want to be certain about you.
-Let's get down to cases, Hatton.
-Right.
-What cases?
-We have had a couple of run-ins
but I'll forget them
and see if we can't work together.
If you mean that,
my job will be easier.
-Your job is just what you make it.
-So I hear.
-The last sheriffs didn't do well.
-They weren't your type.
They were dumb sheep wearing badges.
In fact, I never bothered to talk to them.
-You'd have told them a thing or two.
-Not what I'm gonna tell you anyway.
Listen. There's no reason
that Dodge City can't be run properly.
As long as you don't try
to change things much.
Because this is a cattle town,
and that's what it's always gonna be.
More than $20 million of beef and hides
comes through here every year.
You know that. You bring them up.
You've been holding the wrong end.
The real money ain't working
for those Texas breeders.
It's here in Dodge City.
This is where they pay off.
-You mean on your roulette tables.
-Sure, coming and going.
If not for the Gay Lady,
that money would go out of Dodge City.
The trade would move
right on to Wichita.
You know that cattle crowd.
After months of work, getting those
cattle up here, they want fun.
They can't get it here,
they'll go where they can.
-And you'd go broke.
-Sure. But I ain't aiming to, Hatton.
You see, I make $100,000 a year,
one way or another.
Frankly, I don't need that much money.
I'd be willing to make a deal
with anybody that would, uh,
well, sort of see things my way.
Make a mighty good deal
for both of us.
A little friendly bribery?
You can catch more flies with molasses
than with vinegar.
True enough. Well, I hope you'll not
be offended, Surrett,
but I don't like the smell
of your molasses.
Better get rid of that gun.
You're north of Front Street here, and
that jail's apt to be a little crowded.
What's the matter? Didn't it work?
-He wouldn't listen to reason, huh?
-No, he wouldn't.
All right, Rus, let's go.
There's a lot to do.
(GUNSHOT)
Don't do nothing like that unless
I tell you to. This ain't the time.
They sure make a fellow
feel at home around here.
They'll even dig you a home
if you're nice to them.
MAN 1: One at a time here, fellows.
Line up there. Here you are.
MAN 2: Will we get this stuff back again?
CUSTODIAN: You sure will.
MAN 3: Disarm me? Not for no man.
MAN 4: Nobody gets my gun.
MAN 1: Never heard of such an idea.
MAN 2: Who does he think he is?
MAN 3: Bet 2.
MAN 4: I call it.
TEX: Raise it 5.
MAN 5: Call 5.
MAN 2: I'm dead.
TEX: King's up.
I guess we better quit.
PLAYER:
Quitting because you're winning?
-You read the sign.
-We don't believe in signs.
That sheriff's a big four-flusher, and that
sign's been bad luck to me all night.
(GUNSHOT)
Guess that'll show you
Hatton ain't bluffing.
That's right, gentlemen,
Hatton's not bluffing.
-You're all under arrest.
MAN 2: For what?
-For not believing in signs.
-All right, deputies, take them away.
-Let go of me.
-Go on now.
I tried to warn them, but I guess
they gotta learn through experience.
-I don't know what you warn about.
-What do you mean?
-You're north of Front Street, aren't you?
-Yeah.
-You're carrying a gun, aren't you?
-Right. You're under arrest.
-What?
Come on.
But, Wade, I'd feel undressed
without my gun.
Where you're going,
you won't need any clothes.
If I was you, I'd rather arrest
my brother than me.
Hey, Rusty, you are a traitor.
WADE:
Sorry, boys, I can't do anything about it.
Hey, Wade. You ain't gonna keep me
in here, are you?
You read that notice.
Three days in there won't harm you.
You can't do this to me
after all we've been through.
We fought the war,
built the railroad.
We ate, drank, slept, lived
and died together.
Now we're gonna be in jail together.
You in there and me out here.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(TRAIN BELL RINGING)
Isn't that wonderful, Joe?
That's seven families
that have moved into town.
That does my heart good.
There's the Turner family,
moving from Wichita.
After she said she'd never set foot
in Dodge again.
Welcome home, Mr. Turner!
-How do you do, Mr. Clemens?
-Hello, Joe.
Isn't that the sweetest bonnet
she's got on? It's brown moiré.
Moiré. Let me see.
Moiré? How would you spell moiré?
M-O-I-R-E?
Who in tarnation gives a hoot
what Mrs. Turner's wearing?
Just about every blessed woman
in town, that's all.
WADE: What happened in this fight
between the Indian and Jim Kendall?
I went into that pretty thorough.
There wasn't no fight.
They called each other names,
the Indian threw a knife
Kendall fired a couple of shots.
Nobody got hurt.
Oh, I see. It wasn't a real fight.
It was just a sort of friendly argument.
-Hello, Tex.
-Hi, fellows.
Come on in and sit down.
WADE: Why's that secondhand store
around your neck?
RUSTY:
Where have you been?
Around. Been doing
a lot of thinking lately.
WADE:
Thinking?
Hope you'll take that job I offered you.
We need another good deputy.
That's what I've been thinking.
I'm going back to Texas.
-What for?
-Oh, I don't know.
This place is getting too big,
calm and peaceful.
Rusty and I have stopped
all the fun, huh?
It's all right for women and children.
I've decided to go back to Texas.
If you made up your mind,
that's that.
-Sure there's nothing we can do?
-No.
-So long, Tex.
-So long, Wade.
Give him his gun, Rusty. Number 27.
If you're ever around,
that job will be waiting.
No, sir. I just don't fit
in a sissy town like this.
Certainly hate to see you go.
I'll miss you fellows, too, a lot.
We had a lot of fun together.
-Yeah.
-So long, knot-head.
But, you see, if I hung around here,
I'd be riding a sidesaddle.
Yes, I suppose so.
-All right, Rusty. Arrest that man.
-Who? Me?
-What for?
-He's carrying a gun, isn't he?
Give him back his old room.
-Morning, Joe.
-Hello, Wade. What's the news?
Haven't you read your paper?
-You got those tax notices ready?
-Running them off.
-Come in, come in.
-All right.
-Have a chair.
-You look as though you're pretty--
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
-ABBIE: Fred.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Would you set this in my copy, please?
-I will, ma'am.
-Oh, Joe.
-Good morning.
Did you want something?
I'd like have my curiosity satisfied.
What are you doing here?
-Well, obviously, I'm working.
-Obviously.
-But at what? And why?
-The town happens to be growing
and the paper needed someone who'd
write things that interest women.
Oh, I see.
Tell me, what are the vital interests
of your women readers?
What other women are wearing,
how to make a Lady Baltimore cake
with two eggs,
and whose baby is going to be born
and when.
-Fascinating.
-Anything else you'd like to know?
What do the doctor
and Mrs. Irving think?
They made the same stupid objections
you're making mentally now.
But when I decide on a thing,
I usually carry it through.
Yes, I noticed that. Of course,
people in general are inclined to think,
a newspaper office is an odd place
for a charming lady to be working.
-Are you the delegation sent to tell me'?
-No, no. I just stop trouble around here.
-I don't start it.
-What's wrong with my working here?
It's undignified. It's unladylike.
You ought to be home,
doing needlework.
Sewing buttons on for some man,
I suppose.
They come off.
Someone's gotta sew them on.
A fine career for
an intelligent woman.
-Here are your tax notices.
-WADE: Thanks.
There'll be wailing and
gnashing of teeth when they go out.
Abbie, I know this isn't in your line,
but as long as you insisted on the job,
will you stop calling them
cows in the stockyard?
They're steers. Steers.
I don't see a difference.
"A rise is expected this season
in the price of longhorn cows."
Never mind. I'll correct
this copy myself.
Well, I must be running along.
By the way, may I let you in
to a little secret?
What?
You've got a smudge of ink
on your nose.
-Bye. Goodbye, Joe.
-CLEMENS: Goodbye.
(ABBIE LAUGHING)
I'm sorry. Abbie.
-Is this proper respect for the law?
-I never saw the law fall on its face.
I didn't.
There's a saying in the British army:
"The law must save its face
in front of the natives."
What if the natives object to its face?
We just put them across our knee
and spank them soundly.
-You're not suggesting I'm a native.
-The only native of Kansas is the buffalo.
He's got a very hard head, a very
uncertain temper and a lonely future.
Apart from that, there's hardly
any comparison between you.
-Goodbye, Joe.
-Goodbye, Wade.
Good bye.
-I like that fellow.
-ABBIE: Oh!
(CHUCKLING)
Cows in the stockyard.
BARBER:
I ain't a man who believes in taxes
but I can see they're a necessary evil.
Somebody's gotta pay for schools,
churches and such things.
Especially now that the town's
getting so darn big.
Yes, sir. They do say there's nothing
certain except taxes and death.
Get up, Hatton.
-What for?
-The boys are outside waiting for a talk.
I see.
I'm really surprised at Surrett.
I thought he had more intelligence
than to send you in
on a silly day like this.
-You haven't got a chance--
-Shut up and get out of the chair.
Ten days for this customer.
Five to cool off, five to think it over.
You bet, Wade. I'll take care of it.
Come on, sonny boy, I'll buy you candy.
-What were you saying about taxes?
-What taxes?
I don't remember.
-Shall I trim your mustache?
-No, no. No, thanks.
I think I can manage.
See that big herd of buffalo grazing
away so peacefully down there?
The trouble with the buffalo is that
they had things too easy at the start.
It works the other way around too.
We had such a bad beginning,
we're bound for a wonderful future.
Typical Irish logic, totally unconnected.
Think so? It may be Irish,
but it's not unconnected. I can prove it.
Thirty years ago, my father met
my mother at the Londonderry Fair.
He'd come down to sell prize pig.
Big, fat, lovely pigs, they were.
And Mother was there after winning
the grand prize for her roses,
enormous, big things, as big as
your face and nearly as beautiful.
I don't suppose there were ever roses
like that in the whole of Ireland.
Well, what must happen?
The very last day of the fair,
Father's pigs get out and eat up
every single one of Mother's roses.
Root, stem, flower and all.
Did any two people ever get off
to a worse start than that?
Look at them now. Six big lusty sons,
a score of prize pigs,
and the most beautiful rose garden
in the whole of Antrim.
I envy those who've kissed
the Blarney Stone.
You do? It's cold on the lips.
I think we'd better get back.
-It'll be dark before we get there.
-You sure it's the dark you're afraid of?
-What do you mean?
-You're afraid I might kiss you.
You wouldn't dare.
Now, I wish I were as sure
of that as you are.
May I?
Thank you.
You know, I was just thinking,
the buffalo wouldn't be so badly off
if it didn't have such a one-track mind.
-Then the buffalo wouldn't be a buffalo.
-I suppose not.
You wouldn't be you unless you thought
you might like that kiss.
You seem very sure of my reaction.
Oh.
That's something you can never be
sure about till you've tried it.
Can you?
-Good morning, Abbie.
-Good morning, Mrs. Cole. How are you?
So-so. Just so-so.
Well, won't you come in and sit down?
There. Is there anything
I can do for you?
I'd like to run this advertisement
in your paper.
-That is, if it doesn't cost too much.
-Our rates are very low, I'm sure we can.
You want to sell your house?
No, I don't want to. I have to.
Abbie, let's get a new lead line
on this church bazaar story.
-How do, Mrs. Cole?
-Good morning, Joe.
ABBIE: Joe, how much will you
charge on this?
One, two, three, four...
Selling your house?
-You're not leaving town, are you?
-No, I just...
Well, I can't afford to keep it. I can't
even begin to meet the taxes on it.
I can't understand that.
Matt always made good money.
Why, just the day he died--
He collected $15,000 from Surrett,
didn't he?
That's what I thought too.
But I've never seen a penny of it.
Well, what have you done about it?
I've spoken to Jeff Surrett about it,
but he'll never give me an answer.
-Joe.
-CLEMENS: Yes?
It looks as if Mrs. Cole needs help.
We might be able to give it.
Yeah, it does look that way.
Mrs. Cole, would you mind
if we looked into this?
Mind, Joe? Oh, I'd consider it
a very great favor.
There are a lot of accounts
in this town to be settled.
Now, let's see.
How's the best way to tackle this?
There, the entry, the date
and figures, $15,000.
What Matt Cole did with
his money after is his business.
He had $10 when he was found.
He never left the saloon.
Hatton, I do not discuss
my customers,
but since you force me,
I'll give you facts.
Matt Cole lost that $15,000
playing roulette.
Playing roulette?
I'd like you to remember that.
Don't worry, I'll remember.
We'll all remember.
He never went near those tables.
He went to the bar,
and Yancey killed him.
-According to who?
-You'll find out in court.
If you've got such a clear case,
arrest me now.
No, I think we'll wait a few days.
I'll talk to a few more people
before we give you board and room
at the state's expense.
You're bluffing, Hatton.
You're holding a pair of deuces.
Am I? Munger killed Orth because
he spoiled a cattle deal for you.
Yancey killed Cole because he tried
to collect $15,000.
A dozen other citizens have
been killed doing business with you.
That's what the three of us
will prove in court.
We'll see if the jury thinks
we're bluffing.
Take that book with you.
I can hardly wait to write this story.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this will be the most important article
ever in the Dodge City Star.
(CLEMENS CHUCKLING)
There it is.
We'll have it out by noon tomorrow.
How did you find out
all this about Surrett?
Abbie, a good newspaperman
has two jobs.
One is to write the news
as it happens.
The other is to be ready
and write it first.
All but the end.
This is Jeff Surrett's morgue.
I must be an optimist at heart.
I've been getting it ready
for a long time.
Hey, you two, haven't you homes
to go to? It's past midnight.
You'd better be running along.
The doc will skin me alive.
We've got Surrett by his neck.
Well, let it go for the night
and resume your grip in the morning.
You two realize what kind of a target
you'd make from out there?
Come on, before your uncle
gets after Joe with a shotgun.
-I'll come stay till you're finished, Joe.
-CLEMENS: Don't worry.
I'm just gonna mark it for the printer,
then call it a day.
Don't hang around,
or Surrett might mark it for you.
They wouldn't try anything
at this stage.
Think not? I hope you're right.
-Good night. See you in the morning.
-Good night.
-Lock this door up when we go.
-I'm accustomed to being up after dark.
-Lock it.
-All right. All right.
-ABBIE: Good night.
-CLEMENS: Good night.
"The laws of Dodge City must be
respected, not only by one group,
but by all groups." Paragraph.
I like that.
(GUNSHOT)
What was that?
Whoever killed Joe Clemens ought to be
strung up. And I'll furnish the rope.
If he's got enough neck to put it on.
MAN: They sneaked up on him,
never even give him a chance.
IRVING:
The bullet went through his heart.
I can only blame myself for this.
But it's one thing they won't
get away with.
Little fellow sure was aces.
It's too bad.
I can't understand it.
Joe didn't have an enemy
in the world
except Surrett and his gang.
Who else could've done it?
Isn't it proof that Joe's story is gone
and the whole file on Surrett?
This door was locked.
I know because I tried.
It's an old lock. Any key will fit it.
-Nothing in here?
-No.
He always left his copy on top
so we could set it in the morning.
I'm sorry, sheriff. That's printer's ink.
You can't wash it. It has to wear off.
Did you ever read the contents
of Joe's files?
I certainly did. There was enough
to hang him.
(SILENTLY MOUTHS)
Keep that to yourself.
I think you ought to go to bed now.
You're looking tired.
Good night.
See the doctor
and Miss Irving home.
MACK:
Right.
RUSTY:
What's the next move, Wade?
WADE:
You sure he isn't in his office upstairs?
Surrett left town
on the 4:30 train this afternoon.
If you don't believe us,
ask the station agent.
He was halfway to Wichita
when it occurred.
You're barking up the wrong tree.
Thanks.
Your bet.
-TAYLOR: Three dollars.
-I call.
Who's winning all the money?
Been playing long?
Ask the bartender.
He's got a watch.
What do you know about
Joe Clemens, Yancey?
No more than you,
except he's dead.
How did you know he was dead?
I heard the boys talking. People
keep dropping in and out of here.
TAYLOR:
Bet you 5.
-HENCHMAN: I call.
-Yeah?
Three fives.
-You're under arrest, Yancey.
-YANCEY: For what?
For the murder of Joe Clemens.
-I'll be back in half an hour.
-I wouldn't count on that if I were you.
Take him along, Rusty.
What's the matter, Taylor?
Are you nervous?
Go ahead. Deal them.
Yancey seemed vague about this game.
Suppose you tell me what happened.
How should I know?
Ask one of them.
I'm asking you. Did Yancey ever leave
this table after the game started?
No. He never left the room.
I told you 100 times,
he never went out.
WADE: You're wasting time.
Answer my question.
No, he never left the table.
Stop lying. You're bad at it.
Yancey left that room sometime
between midnight and 1:00.
-No.
-What time?
-He didn't leave.
-Let me work him. I'll make him talk.
-TEX: You can't, I can.
-Let him alone.
If you're too stupid to realize
you're facing a charge of murder.
You deserve what's coming to you.
-What do you mean?
-I'll indict you for murder
-as an accessory.
-I had nothing to do with it.
WADE: You'll be dancing in thin air
like Yancey.
You wanna swing, or do you
want to save your neck?!
All right.
I'll tell you.
Come on.
He went out about 12:30.
Came back about half an hour.
That's better.
I'll do you a favor, Taylor.
Lock him up.
(KNOCKING)
-WADE: Good morning.
-MRS. IRVING: Morning.
-Did you get more out of Bud Taylor?
-I did. Where's the doctor?
-MRS. IRVING: In there.
-What did he say?
-Morning, Mr. Hatton. You'll join us?
-It's imperative you get Abbie out today.
Why?
Only two people beside myself heard
Surrett lie about Cole losing his money.
One was Joe Clemens.
That's why Surrett had him killed.
You're the other who can go to court.
Without you, he'll deny the thing.
That's why I should stay.
I started this, and I'll see it through.
Will you not be an idiot?
Your life isn't worth a nickel
as long as Surrett's out of jail.
You're the key to our case.
We can't go to trial for two weeks.
You'll be in danger every minute.
In this house, in the street.
Everywhere.
I know what he'd do.
You know I'm right, doctor.
Get her out of town.
-Stay out until I send for you.
-MRS. IRVING: You're right.
I see what you mean.
Abbie must take the next train.
And she can stay with the Merrills.
I'll pack a valise at once. Help me.
I'd never forgive myself
if anything happened.
I won't go. You can't boss me around.
Can I not? I'm the law
in this town, and you'll do as I say.
I don't care what you are.
I'll stay right here.
You're the most stubborn thing I've met.
I'm doing this because I love you.
-Well, why--?
-MRS. IRVING: You two. Stop arguing.
Don't worry, Mrs. Irving.
We've stopped.
What he needs is a rope.
He don't deserve a trial.
MAN: Hand him over to us.
We'll give him a trial.
Well, this is more like it.
The last time I saw a mob like that
was in Texas
for Curley Hawks' necktie party.
-TAYLOR: Mr. Brand, I wanna talk to you.
-You got 10 minutes.
-LAWYER: Hello, Yancey.
-Hello.
-What's going on? Why's the mob here?
-Now, take it easy. Take it easy.
Well?
You might as well know this now.
They wormed it out of Taylor
that you left the room.
They can't hang me on that.
Maybe a jury wouldn't hang you,
if you ever get to a jury.
-What do you mean?
-Well--
-What are you trying to say?
-Well...
Joe Clemens was a mighty
well-liked man, Yancey.
He had a lot of friends.
LAWYER: Half of Dodge City is planning
to break in here
-and take things in their own hands.
-Where's Jeff?
-He's gotta get me out of here.
-I telegraphed him an hour ago.
-He got off the train at Spearville.
-He got off? For what?
He's smart enough to know this town
will be warm for a few days,
so he's just kind of laying low
until the excitement blows over.
Too warm for him, huh?
So I get hung for doing his job?
-Yeah? Well, if you think that I'm--
-Shut up, you fool.
-Wanna tell the whole town?
-You bet I'll tell.
I'll tell who paid me to shoot
Joe Clemens and Matt Cole.
If I go, Jeff's going with me.
Now you telegraph him that.
Get me out before night,
or I'll give the story to Hatton.
-All right, but how can Jeff get you out?
-I don't know.
-That's his problem.
-All right, keep your shirt on, Yancey.
I got an idea how Jeff and I
can handle this. Yeah.
First, I'll see Hatton.
-What are you waiting for Hatton?
-MAN 1: Yeah, what are we waiting for?
-If you don't know what to do, we do.
-You bet we do.
-You gonna give us some action?
-MAN 2: We'll give him action.
MAN 3: You don't turn him over to us,
we'll come get him our own way tonight.
WADE: Listen, men. You put me
in this office to enforce the law.
I'm going to enforce it.
That means a fair trial
for any and all prisoners,
including Yancey.
And understand this:
There's gonna be no mob rule
around this town as long as I'm sheriff.
(CHATTERING)
-They're bringing up a post for a ram.
-You see? They're right at the door.
What are you gonna do about it?
Yeah, Wade. The whole town's set
on getting Yancey out.
You can't stop them, the five of you,
while they burn down the building.
Save trouble if we feed him
to the mob.
Throw my client
to that pack of hungry wolves?
Listen, no one's gonna get your client
but a jury. I promise you that.
Only one way to protect him.
He's gotta be taken out
of Dodge City before night.
Fat chance we'd have
of getting him to the station.
Get a closed carriage, drive to
Spearville, catch a train to Wichita.
Keep him in jail there
till he can be tried legally.
-Yes, that might work.
-It will work.
My client's entitled to a fair trial.
It's our job to see he gets it.
-You want me to rustle a carriage?
-Yeah.
Oh, wait.
-I got a better idea.
-But you agree. We gotta get him out.
Yes, but we'll do it my way.
-RUSTY: This is a sample of your future.
-WADE: Get in, Rus. Get in.
Hold them off as long as you can, Tex.
I'll send word from Wichita.
-Say, what--?
-Keep calm. This is official business.
I'm Sheriff Hatton of Dodge City.
I've got a prisoner here for Wichita.
-Well, all right, sheriff.
-Come on.
(HORN BLOWING)
-You mind locking this door?
-MAIL CLERK: Not a bit.
Get over there.
RUSTY: You can sit there and rest
your face and hands.
How many stops between here
and Wichita?
-None.
-Good.
Hey! Keep going!
I'll tell you what to do.
-Put them up.
-But, gentlemen--
-Take him away, Joe.
-Get in there.
Get your hands up.
SURRETT: Get them up, I said!
Now, unlock those cuffs.
(WHISTLE WHISTLING)
-We gotta stop. The train's on fire.
-Don't slow till the water tower.
YANCEY:
Hold it, Jeff. We're all gonna burn.
Got a friend of yours here, Hatton.
Take a good look.
Throw me those guns!
Pick them up.
Unlock those cuffs.
SURRETT: Come on, come on! Hurry up!
Bolt that door.
Rusty, this end!
Look out!
Rusty!
Hurry up!
RUSTY:
Ha-ha!
So the lamb killed the butcher.
# (PURE PRAIRIE LEAGUE SINGING) #
RUSTY: Listen to that. Singing hymns,
and it ain't even Sunday.
No one in sight even friendly drunk.
If this place ain't getting so pure
and noble, it ain't fit to live in.
I'm sure not going to Texas now.
Imagine them asking me to lead
the Pure Prairie League.
WADE: You're one of the leading
lights in it.
First thing, they will start
a chamber of commerce.
WADE: It's not possible.
RUSTY: What?
WADE:
Look. Colonel Dodge.
-Hello, colonel.
-Hi, colonel.
-Hiya, boys.
By golly, it's good to see you alive.
-It's good to be alive.
-Come on up.
-Wade, son, it's good to see you.
-Hi.
-Hi, Tex.
-Hi, colonel.
-How are you?
-Couldn't complain, colonel.
Sit down over there.
Wade, I came from Virginia City,
Nevada, to see you.
-WADE: Yes?
-I'm building a rail from San Francisco.
Richest square mile on earth.
Gold, silver, copper,
a solid mountain of the stuff.
But it's a bad town, a wild, murderous
town. Worse than Dodge City
before you cleaned it up.
That's saying a good deal.
-I want you to come.
-I knowed our luck changed.
We got 4,000 people out there.
Decent families living in terror.
-Think of them 4,000 poor people.
-Yeah. There might be more.
We need you, son.
The city is teeming with corruption.
What law we've tried has failed
because the men didn't have courage.
You can get plenty of men
for that job, colonel.
I'm getting married next week.
Oh, you can get married any time.
We'll even go on your honeymoon
to Virginia City.
-Oh, thanks.
-Getting married has ruined a lot of men.
DODGE:
Doesn't it mean anything to know that
there's terror and death you can stop?
WADE: Yes, it does, but the decision
isn't as simple as that.
If I were free, it might be different,
but I'll have a wife.
Abbie doesn't wanna go pioneering.
We're planning on coming back here
from New York and settling down.
There's a wagon train leaving here
the middle of next week for Nevada.
A great trip, wouldn't it?
Darling, I was just telling the boys
how we're settling down...
-Lemonade?
-Thank you.
-Lemonade.
-Thank you, ma'am.
Darling, I was telling Colonel Dodge
about our honeymoon.
How we'll see all the shops,
the theaters and Niagara Falls.
Colonel Dodge, when do we start
for Virginia City?
Wade, it looks like you're marrying
the right girl.
(TEX CHEERING)
Virginia City!
(English US - SDH)