♪ Through sunshine and shadow ♪
♪ From darkness 'till noon, ♪
♪ Over mountains that reach
from the sky to the moon, ♪
♪ A man with a dream
that will never let go ♪
♪ Keeps searchin' to find El Dorado. ♪
♪ So ride, boldly ride, ♪
♪ to the end of the rainbow; ♪
♪ Ride, boldly ride, ♪
♪ 'till you find El Dorado. ♪ ♪
♪ The winds become bitter, ♪
♪ The sky turns to gray, ♪
♪ His body grows weary, ♪
♪ He can't find his way. ♪
♪ But he'll never turn back ♪
♪ Though he's lost in the snow, ♪
♪ For he has to find El Dorado. ♪
♪ So ride, boldly ride,
to the end of the rainbow, ♪
♪ Ride, boldly ride,
'till you find El Dorado. ♪ ♪
♪ My daddy once told me
what a man ought'a be, ♪
♪ There is much more to life ♪
♪ Than the things we can see, ♪
♪ And the Godliest mortal
you ever will know ♪
♪ Is the one with the dream of El Dorado. ♪
♪ So ride, boldly ride,
to the end of the rainbow, ♪
♪ Ride, boldly ride,
'till you find El Dorado. ♪ ♪
¡Buenos Diás, Jefe!
¡Buenos Diás Miguel!
Tomás.
A big fellow, about 6' 4"
riding that Appaloosa stud out there,
he came in here a little while ago?
He in the washroom.
He shaves, he cleans up.
Thanks.
Hi, Cole.
That's a voice I'd know anywhere.
JP Harrah. Wait till I get
some of the soap out of my eyes.
I heard you were made sheriff...
What's the idea of the gun?
Just ' till I find out
which side you're on, Cole.
What do you mean?
I heard you were working for Bart Jason.
Well, Nothing's set yet.
He offered me good money, but I haven't
found out what I have to do to earn it.
Would you like to hear?
Yeah, go ahead.
Cole, that's about close
enough to that gun.
I just wanted to see
if you'd slowed down any.
Not that much.
What were you saying about Jason?
Well, he showed up here around the end
of the war with a pocket full of money.
Nobody seems to be able to
find out where he got it from...
but... everybody else
around here was broke.
You know how it was then.
Yeah, all over Texas.
Well, having money, he
started to grow.
Now, he can't grow any bigger
until he gets more water.
There's only one place to get it.
Trouble is, somebody was there
ahead of him. About 20 years ahead.
A man named Kevin MacDonald got here
when there was nothing
but Indians and coyotes.
Mr. MacDonald's got four boys and a
girl, and they've all worked real hard.
They hung together through
all the rough times,
and now that things are
beginning to look up,
MacDonald's in no mind to sell.
So he's holding and Jason's pushing...
and I'm standing right in the middle.
It's not the way it was told to me.
That's the way it is, Cole, I guess
you're supposed to take care of me.
Well, not that I couldn't... do it, Harrah,
but... I don't think I'd like that.
I'm glad to hear you say that.
Not that I couldn't handle you...
but... I don't think I'd like that either.
Suppose I tell Jason that
I had a long talk with you and...
and you scared me off.
Good enough?
Good enough.
You can put that thing down now.
There's somethin' familiar
about that gun.
I just had it fixed-up
the way you had yours.
You got lucky with it,
I thought I'd try it.
Ha!
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Cole Thornton, you decent? You'd
better be, 'cause I'm a comin' in.
Ah, it's good to see you.
You know when they told me you
were here, I didn't believe them!
I thought you'd forgotten
all about me, I thought that...
Hi, JP (LAUGHING)
What's so funny?
This whole thing. (CONTINUING TO LAUGH)
Do you know what
she's laughing about?
I gather you knew him
before you knew me.
Before you? I knew her
when she was a kid.
Didn't you know that, JP?
No, you never mentioned that.
Up until now, I thought you had good taste.
And, up until now,
I thought she had good taste.
(SIGH)...I'm awful glad
you two are friends.
We may not be when we
think this thing over.
If you aren't, I'm
through with both of you.
You know something, Cole, I think
We better get ourselves a new girl.
Yeah.
You better not. -Why not?
I'm girl enough for you both.
Say, can I buy you a drink?
Well, I'd like that very much,
but I promised JP I'd do
something for him, didn't I?
Yes, you did.
Of Course, if you want to do my errand...
No, you do your own work, Cole.
Will you buy us that drink
a couple of hours from now?
Yeah, sure will.
Where is this Bart Jason's place?
You take the main road
north out of town.
And after you cross the creek,
and you come to a big rock.
Big rock.
That's right. That's
MacDonald's boundary.
MacDonald's?
Yeah.
You ride east from there about 3 miles
and you get to Bart Jason's ranch.
Maudie, remember, I'm coming back.
Oh, I left some things...
I'll take care of it.
Thanks.
You mad at me, JP?
You know better than that, Maudie.
Ha... you must like that man.
Want me to tell you about him?
You don't have to tell me about Cole.
I know I don't.
That's why I want to.
I met Cole right after my husband
was killed. I did tell you that.
Yeah, you told me.
Well, there I was, stranded...
A gambler's widow,
not a chip to my name.
Cole was awful good to me. Gave me
a stake, helped me get on my feet.
Never would take a...
(SIGHS) I don't know, JP.
With Cole and me, I guess it's a...
I'll always think of him as a...
He's a top hand.
I guess so.
Yeah, well, Cole always was pretty lucky.
Have you known
him a long time?
Yeah, I've known him a long
time, since before the war.
We've... ah... traveled some together.
Sure, I know what that means.
It means either you saved his life,
or he saved yours, or both.
And neither of you
will talk about it... Men!
Would you like it set to music,
Maudie, with a full orchestra?
Well, I'll see you, Maudie.
Hey, don't forget to come back!
Well, I'm certainly not going
to leave you alone with him.
You're not a friend.
Hell!
(HORSES NEIGHING,
MEN CALLING WHOA!)
MacDonald! Kevin MacDonald!
Howdy, Roy. Something wrong?
Doc Miller sent me out, said to tell you
Bart Jason hired himself a gunhand:
Cole Thornton. And Thorton rode
out there about an hour ago.
Doc wanted you to know. He said
to tell you to be careful.
Thanks, Roy. Tell Doc I'm
much obliged to both of you.
Matt, you and Saul stay with me, we'll
take these horses back to the ranch.
Joey, get out to the
West Fork and tell Jared
to get back to the ranch
as soon as he can.
OK, Pa.
Luke.
Yes, Pa.
Get up there on that rock. If
you see anybody coming, fire
a shot into the air, that'll
give us a little warning.
All right, Pa.
Wait a minute, I ain't finished yet...
As soon as you fire that shot, you jump
on your horse and hightail it, you hear!
I hear you, Pa.
All right, let's go!
(SOUND OF GUN SHOTS, HORSES NEIGHING
AND CALLS OF 'LET'S GO!' AND 'HIYAH!')
Where can I find Mister Jason?
He's up at the main house.
¡Gracias!
Mr. Jason, you got a visitor.
Cole Thornton?
That's right.
I'm Bart Jason.
I've been expecting you. Get off your
horse, and make yourself comfortable.
I won't be here
long enough for that.
Here's what's left
of your expense money.
Sorry about the rest of it,
but that's the chance you take.
I've decided against working for you.
Before you even talked about it?
No, you wouldn't do that.
You must've talked to somebody.
I did. The sheriff.
His story is a little different
from yours
Well, perhaps the law
doesn't quite see it my way.
Since when did hired
guns get choosy?
You're paid to...
I'm paid to risk my neck.
I'll decide where and when
I'll do it. This isn't it.
You know Thornton, I've
got an idea you just
don't want to go up against
Sheriff J P Harrah.
You know, you're just about right.
You think he's that good?
I tell you he's that good.
And, Mr. Jason,
I see you don't wear a gun.
So I guess you always hire it done.
So, I'll give you
a little piece of advice:
If this bunch is all you've got,
don't tangle with Harrah.
'Cause they don't look tough enough
to me to stomp a stringy jackrabbit.
Well, Thornton, if that's
the way you think, I don't want you.
That's good enough for me...
Hey, fancy vest... go ahead
and pull that rifle if you want to,
but you better speak to your boss
before you use it,
'cause he'll be dead
before I hit the ground.
Don't be a damn fool,
Joe, get over there and
stay with the others
where he can see you.
I'll remember what you said,
Mr. Thornton.
You do that!
♪
(RIFLESHOT FOLLOWED BY GUNSHOT)
Hiyah!
Don't shoot no more, mister.
Please.
I won't.
Let me have a look at it.
It's bad, isn't it?
It isn't good.
My insides feel like they're on fire.
Maybe I can make you more comfortable.
No, don't touch me... please don't!
What's your name, son?
MacDonald.
Luke MacDonald.
I can't stand it.
Kevin MacDonald's boy?
One of 'em.
I'm gonna have to get you home.
No, don't move me.
Please don't move me.
It's no use. I know it ain't no use.
Pa told me. Just don't touch me.
Well...
There were two shots, Pa.
I heard 'em.
Well, Luke ought'ta be back by now.
I know that.
(GUNSHOT)
Oh, no.
Are we going, Pa?
Where?
Pa, Luke could
be in bad trouble.
If he is, we won't be
any help to him now.
He went there to warn us.
He's warned us.
Better off here, where there's cover.
Saul, find a good place inside that shed.
José and Miguel, go with him.
Danny, Felipe, come here.
Over behind that wall.
You gals, get in the house.
Matt, we'll wait inside.
All right, Pa.
♪
Matt, get over to that window.
Don't do anything till I say.
(♪ CONTINUES, CHICKEN CLUCKING)
MacDonald!
Kevin MacDonald!
(LATCH CLICKING, DOOR OPENING)
Come out and get your boy.
He's dead, ain't he?
He's dead.
José, Miguel,
get him down from there.
What happened?
Luke, he's been killed.
Well, I'm waiting to
hear what happened.
Well, I'll tell you
what happened.
You left a boy out there
to do a man's job.
He went to sleep.
When I came by, he woke up,
jumped up and started
firing his gun.
All I saw was somebody
shooting at me from the rocks.
Cole Thornton.
Yes, ma'am.
I don't believe you.
I don't care much, miss,
whether you do or not.
Pa's handling this. Just wait.
Get in the house, girl.
How do you know
he was asleep?
He told me that.
He told me his name. That's how
I knew where to bring him.
He said you told him what happens
to a man that's gut shot...
How he hasn't got much of a chance.
Did you tell him that?
Yeah, I told him that.
Then you're partly to blame.
You'll find two bullets in him.
One of them's mine.
He was hurtin' worse
than he could stand.
Had a handgun that I didn't see.
Any more questions
you want to ask?
No. I guess you're
telling the truth.
I guess, if you weren't, you'd
wouldn't ever have brought him here.
I'm much obliged to
you for that.
It don't help much.
♪
(RIFLESHOT)
I reckon you won't shoot
any more little boys, mister.
Next time you shoot somebody,
don't go near them till
you're sure they're dead.
(SPLASH)
I don't know why
you're still alive.
I don't know how I missed
you from that range.
You didn't miss.
Now get out of here.
♪
JP, open that window, will you?
That's better. The smell of that
chloroform's putting me to sleep.
Better hold him, Maudie.
Don't let him move too sudden.
All right.
He'll be waking up now.
It's all right, Cole.
It's Maudie.
All right, Maudie.
(GROGGY SIGH)
Who are you?
The name's Miller.
Some people call me a doctor,
and some... other things.
But... I'm the only one in town.
Did you get the bullet out?
Nope.
Well, then why this bandage?
Let's get to it.
I can't.
Why not?
Because I'm not good enough. That
bullet's right up against your spine.
If I go hackin' around
in there to get it,
I'll only finish what
somebody else started.
So what happens?
Well, you'll heal all right...
But when you get to a big town, find
a doctor who knows more than I do.
One of them new-fangled squirts.
They'll fix you up in no time, but
don't wait too long to do it.
Any chance of gettin' some coffee
or a shot of whiskey around here?
Linda.
Linda, bring both of them.
Doctor, can he be moved?
Well, sure, in a couple of hours;
but... don't go bouncing him around.
He can stay here.
I'll... I'll make him comfortable.
I've got a fine bed over at my place.
It's ah... it's narrow, and
it's hard and uncomfortable,
...but he won't get
bounced around.
♪ (BUGLE)
¿Qué Es?
Señor Bull. He comes.
Bull always announces
his arrival that way?
Same way, different tune.
You better let him in.
What's that you blowing, Bull,
advance or retreat?
Narry one. Couldn't let one
of General Hood's Texas
Cavalry boys go away
without playing goodbye.
Who's goin' away?
Cole's lighting out...
he's leaving tonight.
You got any objections, Doc,
I don't want to hear 'em.
I'm Glad to get you off my hands...
Where you going?
Sonora.
Folks down there got a silver mine...
a little trouble.
Think I might be of help.
Well, I brung along a little red-eye,
in case the sheriff runs out.
Somehow, I reckon he has.
Been here a long time,
nobody's offered me a drink.
Well, why didn't you speak up, Bull?
Thought you'd never ask.
Maudie, get him a glass, will you?
Well, what'll we drink to first?
Maudie...
I guess I should have told you.
Hmh... Cole, sometimes you...
♪ (GUITAR) ♪
I was hoping to see
you alone before you left.
It's better this way, Maudie.
Come back, will you?
I will when...
When you can forget Luke MacDonald?
When you can look at the other MacDonalds
and not... not feel you owe them?
Pretty wise for a kid, Maudie.
I think you must be the only person
who thinks of me as a kid, Cole.
I reckon I really don't.
Please don't.
I'll see you, Maudie.
♪
Hey!
That the way you make your living?
By golly, Cole,
it sure is good to see you.
What sheriff had to hire you
for a deputy?
You're looking
at him. Hi ya, Cole!
Dodd Draper!
The last time I saw you two,
you were ten jumps ahead of a
posse raisin' dust for Mexico.
Hey, heard you got shot.
Yeah, but that was six
or seven months ago.
How about supper?
And I'll buy you a beer, too.
We'd like to, but we're working men.
How about that cantina up the street?
Good place to eat?
Good as any. You sticking around?
Day or two.
Well, we'll see you later, Cole.
Señor...
your dinner will be ready
in one minute.
Gee Sevas, Gracias...
Buena Noches Señoras
Bring something to eat, comidas...
Plenty of it Si Señor.
Right away.
Something to drink, also, vamanos.
Señor?
A Five and a one.
Charlie Hagan.
Yeah.
You want something from me?
You don't remember me, do you?
No.
Do you remember this hat?
Well, why in the hell would I
remember a hat? (LAUGHTER)
You killed the man
that was wearing it
Ladies.
Si, Señor, si
Who was this fellow I killed?
A friend of yours?
You could say that.
When did I do this, boy?
Two years ago, come September.
You and three others.
Natchez-Under-the-Hill,
on the Mississippi.
He was a gambler, named Johnny Diamond...
and he was kind of an old man.
Shouldn't have taken four of you.
Do you remember, Charlie?
I remember. He was a cardsharp.
He was cheating.
No... no, he was good.
He didn't have to cheat.
It shouldn't have taken 4 of you, Joey.
No, it shouldn't of.
Well, I'm sure glad you remember, Mr.
Hagan. The other three did.
The other three?
Yeah, I caught up with them.
You're the last.
And now I think you better stand up.
Stand up, Charlie.
I'm curious to see how he does this.
He doesn't have a gun.
And like he said, it shouldn't
have taken four of you.
Stand up, Charlie.
You with the hat.
You killed Charlie 'cause he
killed your friend, right?
That's right.
Well, it happens, Charlie
was a good friend of mine.
So let's see you
do that trick twice.
(GUNSHOT WITH RICOCHET
AND GUN DROPPING)
I'd let it drop, friend.
Me?
You.
(GUN DROPS TO FLOOR)
Hope you don't mind.
Always seems to take
more than one doesn't it?
That's because they're no good.
Pick up your gun.
What?
You want to try again, now?
Pick up your gun.
Against him, or you?
Me first.
Why should you go first?
Pick it up.
Now, just a second...
Tell me about it later!
I'll tell you now! -Shut up!
Go on. You were plenty willing
when you had a kid...
Hold it! Don't get mad, mister.
Before you start anything, I can't
afford to lose another man.
You promise to
take Milt's place?
You got a lot of faith
in me, don't you, Nelse?
Faith can move mountains, Milt,
but it can't beat a faster draw.
There's only three men I
know with his kind of speed.
One's dead, the other's me,
and the third is Cole Thornton.
There's a fourth.
Which one are you?
I'm Thornton.
Aren't you glad you
didn't try, Milt?
Pick up your guns, both of you.
Real easy.
Like he said, real easy.
And take him out of here.
Thornton, I'd like to talk to you.
I'm Nelse McLeod.
I thought so. Pretty far
off your range, aren't you?
A little. Can I buy you a drink?
Why not?
You, too.
Glasses.
You working now, Thornton?
No.
Is it all right if music play now Señor?
Yeah, sure.
Muchachos, musica...
You say you're not working. What would
you say if I tried to hire you on?
First I'd ask about the money.
Money's good.
Then I'd ask about the job.
Well, good evening.
Thanks for the drink, gentlemen.
Just a minute, son.
I am not your son.
My name is Alan Bourdillion Traherne.
Lord Almighty.
Yeah.
That's why most people call me
Mississippi.
Mississippi?
I was born on the river in a flat boat.
You're pretty good with that knife.
Can you use a gun?
If I could, I'd be using one.
Good evening.
Just a minute, Mississippi.
Would you mind telling me why you have
such a great passion for my company?
Will you just relax
for a couple of minutes?
You were telling me
about the job.
There's a little range war
up in the El Dorado country.
El Dorado? Mind telling
me who hired you?
Fellow named Bart Jason.
Do you know him?
We met. He offered me the job a few
months back. I didn't take it.
Do you know who
you're up against?
Yeah. The sheriff, JP Harrah.
I understand he used to be
pretty good with a gun.
Not just pretty good, McLeod.
He's the...
The fourth man you told me about.
That's right.
Well, he used to be.
He's not any more.
Well, what happened?
What usually happens to a man?
A woman.
Seems like he tangled with some wandering
petticoat... he's been drunk ever since.
You figure to move in before he sobers
up, or... before they get a new sheriff?
And you're not coming in?
No.
I suppose you have your reasons.
It's probably just as well.
With two like us in
the same bunch...
sooner or later we'd have to find
out which one of us was faster.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
So long, Thornton.
I thought we were going.
Mississippi, just listen.
McLeod, would you like to walk out
that door first, ahead of us?
Nope. I don't believe I would.
I didn't think so.
Pedro, Milt, can you hear me?
We hear you.
I'm coming out.
Where are you?
Jeffe... over here.
Come on out.
Further into the light, hurry.
Now drop your guns.
Come here.
Inside.
That all right, Thornton?
Good enough.
Mississippi, get their guns.
If it's all right with you, McLeod,
we'll drop 'em at the sheriff's office
and your boys can pick 'em
up on their way out of town.
Sounds reasonable.
Much obliged.
Call it professional courtesy.
Want to get something
to eat, Mississippi?
Mr. Thornton, I would've walked
out of here and right into
those two fellas if you
hadn't stopped me.
I asked if you were hungry.
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm hungry! That shivaree you put
on in there interrupted my supper.
It wore out our welcome.
Now, we'll have to find
someplace else to eat.
Now?
Now.
¿Que quieres mas?
She wants to know
if you want something else.
Just coffee.
Café, por favor.
Not very hungry huh?
No, not so much.
A little green around the gills.
Yep.
I just finished something tonight
I've been two years doing.
What are you figuring on doing next?
Going back to the river?
I haven't thought much about
what I'm going to do next.
The river won't be
the same without old...
Well, if you're going to stay around here,
I've got two pieces of advice for you...
Get rid of that hat.
Learn how to use a gun.
I don't figure on
gettin' rid of that hat.
No?
No.
Johnny Diamond, he's the friend I...
ah... the man that raised me.
All he left behind was
a gold watch and this hat.
I had to sell that gold watch
a year or so back.
So, I guess
I'll just hang on to that hat.
What about learning to use a gun?
Johnny didn't believe in guns.
He always thought that...
He's dead. Think about that.
Unless you can learn to
stay out of trouble.
That's one thing even old Johnny
couldn't teach me to do.
Well, I'll be moving along.
Good luck to you.
Ah... you don't suppose
I could ride along with ya?
Nope.
That's plain enough.
Well, I hope everything
works out all right.
What works out?
Whatever it is you're going to do.
Pay for the meal, will you?
So long.
♪
Hold it, Cochise.
Steady boy. lt'll take a minute.
Cole! Cole Thornton!
Where are you?
Close enough to blow your hat off
if I hadn't 'a recognised it.
What are you doing here?
Looking for you.
Don't you know better than
to follow a man that way?
Sorry, I don't know there's another way.
You almost got shot.
You fall off your horse?
Yeah.
You hurt?
No.
Well, there's something
the matter with you.
Well look, I've got a
bullet in my back,
sometimes it presses
against something and...
I get a screaming pain,
then there's nothing...
it goes numb, and I
can't use this hand.
How long does that last?
Just for a while. Why
are you following me?
Well, I got to thinkin' about
what you're going to do.
And just what am I gonna do?
You're going to that
town, El Dorado, to help
your friend against
McLeod and his bunch.
How do you know
he's my friend?
That look on your face when you
heard he'd turned into a drunk.
Well, this thing's wearing off.
Give me a hand
up on my horse.
You sure your friend's
worth helping?
You just spent two years chasing some
fellas that killed a friend of yours.
You think your friend
was worth two years?
I guess I asked a fool question.
You did.
Give him a breather.
Slow him down.
I was wondering.
Just how good is this McLeod?
I don't know first hand, but
they say he's one of the best.
I figure he'd be pretty mad you...
you turning
him down and showing-up
on the other side.
I hope he is.
How come?
Fellow in his business
hasn't got a right to get mad.
He gets mad,
he's not so good.
So the madder he gets,
the better I like it.
Ha! Sure wish I was
there to see that.
Why do you want to keep
sticking your nose in this?
Maybe I could help.
You saved my life two times.
But I'm going to be too busy
to keep doing that.
You can't even use a gun.
You could teach me. I
need somebody to teach me.
Johnny Diamond always
told me to get the best.
Well, he was right there.
But you're not going to El Dorado.
Oh, I'm not, huh?
No, you're not.
"Gaily bedight,
A gallant knight,"
"In sunshine and in shadow,
Had journeyed long..."
What's that all about?
Just a poem.
One of Johnny Diamond's favorites.
Let's see: "Gaily bedight,
A gallant knight",
"In sunshine and in shadow, Had
journeyed long, singing a song,"
"In search of El Dorado."
"Over the mountains of the moon,
Down the valley of the shadow,"
"Ride, boldly ride..."
Always liked that poem, too.
Makes me want to ah...
Ride, boldly ride?
Well, it don't work out that way.
I'm learning that.
Oh, Hell! Hold it, Cochise.
Step down off that horse.
You always giving people orders?
You wanted to learn to shoot.
Right out there.
Hold it, Mississippi.
That's no way to use a handgun.
You gotta to draw and
fire, and you gotta be
quicker than somebody else
doing the same thing.
Like this.
I see.
How's that?
Were you aiming at that cholla?
No, the place you were shooting at.
'Fraid it's useless.
Well, we'll be passing through Cuervo.
I'll have a talk with the Swede.
Who's the Swede?
An old friend of mine... a gunsmith.
Aah!
There's the place.
Why, Cole Thornton!
Swede, good to see you.
And what brings you around here?
Well, I'm looking for a gun for a fella
that can't shoot... Mississippi.
Swede Larson.
Can you help us?
Yaha, I think, I've got just
the gun you're looking for.
Well good!
Wow!
How wide will that shot spread?
Well, now... I mean, how big a pattern?
I don't know. The fellow who used it
before, he couldn't see too good.
He just shoot where he hear
somebody talk.
What happened to him?
He has a fight in a saloon.
The piano player
he make so much noise,
he couldn't hear the other man, so
he just shoot the piano player,
and they hung him.
Looks pretty good to me.
Shoots good, too.
How about ammunition?
Four or five boxes ought to be enough.
Good.
Well, Mississippi, looks
like what you need.
It sure is!
Pay the man... Swede.
Cole, you come back soon.
A likely spot to
try that new gun.
Try that cactus.
(SHOTGUN BLAST)
You can't miss with that.
It's all right.
How far is it from here to El Dorado?
We'll be in there around midnight.
♪
Well, where are we headed?
To see a girl.
To see a girl?
Yes, a girl.
Don't you think I
could know a girl?
I always make you mad, don't I?
Mostly.
Hold it... this, yeah!
This is it.
Cole. Cole!!
Maudie, keep it quiet.
I got to talk to you.
I'll let you in.
Keep your eyes open.
Oh, You sure pick the
darnedest times to...
Who's your friend?
My name's Alan Bourdillion Traherne.
Just call him Mississippi for now.
Hi, Mississippi.
You stay out here and watch.
Couldn't I...?
No.
Cole, I'm so glad to see you.
I've got so many things to tell you.
Maudie, there's a lot
I've got to say to you but,
first I've got to
have some answers.
Are there any strangers in town?
No, no, I'd have known if there were.
This one you'd have noticed:
A dark, thin faced man,
with a scar here and a marled eye.
Nelse McLeod.
Nelse? I've heard of him.
Should've had four or five
riders with him.
He's not here yet.
Well, good...
at least we beat them in.
Now, about JP.
Want the whole story?
Just don't make it too long.
After you left,
I didn't see much of him.
Oh, he'd drop in for a drink once
in a while. I guess he was lonely.
One day a girl came into town,
just stepped off the stage and...
Well, you know how kind...
Yeah, she probably had big sad eyes and
a long sad story. That's his type.
Yeah. She was no good. I tried
to tell him, so did others.
Bull told him
and he knocked Bull down.
So JP had found out the hard way.
She ran off with a drummer.
He's... he's not been sober since.
It's been about two months.
Well, that he's going
to have to get over in a hurry.
Is he over at the jail?
He's still sheriff,
though I don't know why.
We'll mosey on... Oh, have you got
a room for Mississippi and me?
Oh... sure! Hey, have you
eaten anything lately?
No.
I'll have something ready
for you when you get back.
I'm glad you're here.
Don't tell anybody you saw us.
I won't.
Well, I found one thing out.
What's that?
You know a girl.
Ha!
Hold it!
It's as far as you
can come now.
Unless you've got
some business here.
I sure have got business here, Bull.
Cole Thornton.
Cole Thornton!
If it hadn't been so dark
I might have spotted you.
Might have anyhow, if I hadn't
been trying to figure out...
what that other fellow's
got on top of his head.
It's called a hat.
Well, I'll have to take your word for it.
Friend of mine.
They call him Mississippi.
Glad to know you.
Bull.
Glad you're here, Cole. Our
friend the sheriff ain't so good.
I just talked to Maudie.
He's back there... sleepin'.
Beins as how you've known him
longer than I have...
you know enough to be careful
how you wake him up.
'Cause he's a bad one
when he's drinkin'.
He ain't put that stopper back
in that bottle in a coon's age.
Yeah, I know. You got someplace where
you can put these horses under cover?
Sure.
Give him a hand.
Oh, Bull, I'd just as soon everybody
didn't know we were back in town yet.
What's up? Something in the wind?
Jason's starting some more trouble.
I ain't surprised. I got an itch on the
back of my neck like I used to get...
when a Comanche was around
and I couldn't see him.
(SCUFFING OF BOOTS)
(RINGING OF SPURS ON FLOOR)
(CINK OF DOOR)
(SQUEEKING OF HINGES)
(LOUD FOOTSTEPS)
(MATCH STRIKING)
(BLOWING OUT MATCH)
(MATCH HITTING TABLE)
(LOUD FOOTSTEPS AND SCUFF)
(SNORING)
(LOUD) Hey!
(SNORING CONTINUES)
(SCUFFING BOOTS ON FLOOR)
(BUCKET HANDLE HITTING SIDE OF BUCKET)
(MORE BOOT SCUFFS)
(WATER SPLASHING)
Aigh! Ugh!
Damn you, Bull...
Ugh! Oooo!
(BOTTLE HITTING FLOOR)
(CATCHING BREATH) What the
hell are you doing here?
I'm looking at a tin star
with a drunk pinned on it.
Cole Thornton.
(DRY LAUGH) How about that!
Whoo-Who!
How about that! It's good old Cole.
Help me up out of here, Cole.
Come on, just pull me right on up.
(PUNCH)
(CLANG)
Cole, he won't feel it.
Well, I owe him one.
(CRASHING ONTO BED)
Either one of you know a
fast way to sober a man up?
A bunch of howlin' Injuns out for hair
will do it quicker than anything I know.
Johnny Diamond had a recipe.
Let's see: Cayenne pepper;
mustard, the hot kind; ipecac;
asafoetida; oil of cloves... or was it...?
No, it was croton oil!
Croton oil? I'll be a suck-egg mule! You
know what that mixture will do to a fellow?
Guaranteed kill or cure.
Bull, you know where you could get
that stuff this time of night?
Greener's store would have it.
May have to wake him up.
Go on with him, Mississippi. Make
sure he doesn't forget anything.
I... Look out, Cole!
(CRASH) (PUNCH)
(FURNITURE BREAKING)
Well, aren't you going to get that stuff?
Well, he's all right.
Just get it before he wakes up again.
Sure.
Let's see, we've got ipecac,
mustard, cayenne,
that leaves us asafoetida.
Are you sure that Johnny
Diamond wasn't an embalmer?
Here's your gunpowder.
Gunpowder?
Yeah. Mississippi remembered it
on the way to the store.
Put it in.
All of it?
All of it.
I hope you don't blow him up.
Well, it looks done.
Well, let's get it into him.
Bull, you sit on his legs.
Cole, pin down his arms.
Don't worry about us.
Get hold of his nose. If he can't
breathe, he'll have to swallow.
Give him an extra one for me.
(SNORING FOLLOWED BY GAGGING)
All down.
Let's get out of here.
Lock him in.
(POUNDING OF METAL ON ANVIL)
Bull?
Yeah!
We're coming in.
Come ahead.
Howdy, Cole... Mississippi.
How's our friend?
Nary a peep. Not even moved, not
one twist the last two hours.
You reckon he'll
be all right, Cole?
Better ask Mississippi,
it's his concoction.
I don't know how all right
he'll be, but he won't
be drinking anything for a little while...
I can tell you that!
How come?
It does something to a man's stomach...
So it naturally won't hold any liquor.
You sure of that?
Sure, I'm sure... given he's human.
He's human all right.
He's got to be.
No other critter on earth would
make such a fool of himself.
(SHAKING CELL DOOR) Hey Bull,
come open this door!
He's still drunk. Open it yourself,
it ain't even locked.
(DOOR SLAMS OPEN)
(COUGHS)
(SCUFFS, SIGHS, COUGHS)
(SIGHS)
My friends.
My dear good friends.
You dirty, lousy, rotten,
sheep-herdin'...
What did you do to me?
What did you give me?
I'm all crawling inside.
Just hang on, sheriff.
It'll fetch you round.
Who are you?
We met last night.
Last night? When was that? Come on, Bull.
Where is it?
Top drawer of your desk.
(SIGHING) Nobody's
going to try to stop me?
Nobody.
(SIGH) That's a good thing.
Oh, you dirty...
Ooooo...
(DOOR CLANKS THEN SQUEEKS OPEN)
(DOOR CLANKS SHUT)
♪ (SALOON PIANO) ♪
Cole! Take a look.
All right, Bull.
You better wake up.
Bart Jason just brought
his outfit into town.
Could be to meet McLeod.
Yeah, could be.
You going to tell the sheriff?
No, let him sleep.
Here comes some more of them.
Whoa!
You gals go on down to the store and do
your shopping. We'll meet you back here.
...And stay together.
Go on with them, Joey.
Dusty out there.
Who are those people who've just come in?
MacDonalds. They come to town
every Saturday afternoon.
This is one Saturday
I wish they hadn't.
Bull, wouldn't it be a good idea if you
hung around where the MacDonalds are.
Yeah, I guess I'd better.
Kind'a watch out for 'em. We'll keep an
eye on... our friend across the street.
If there's any trouble down my way, I'll
toot my bugle, and you come a runnin'.
Toot my bugle! Hah...!
♪ ( WHISTLING TO THE SALOON PIANO TUNE) ♪
(CELL DOOR CLANKS, WHISTLING
STOPS, SALOON PIANO CONTINUES)
Hello, JP.
Hi.
Can you see a little
clearer from here?
Hey, Cole.
How long've you been here?
Got in last night.
Did we have a...
fight or something?
Or something.
Yeah.
Well, ah, what are you doing here, Cole?
Why are you here?
Waiting for a fellow.
The name's Nelse McLeod.
Oh, Nelse McLeod with the...
That one.
Want some coffee?
No, I don't...
I met him down
near the border.
Said he wanted me
to work with him on a job.
Range war.
But he said it'd be easy.
All we had to
worry about was a...
...drunken sheriff.
Sure you don't
want some coffee?
Nelse McLeod... and ah...
And he's working for Jason?
That's what he said.
Well?
I turned the job down.
Well, then... ah,
why are you here, Cole?
I owe the MacDonalds.
That enough?
Yeah, that's... ah...
that's plenty, Cole.
Cole, I gotta have a drink.
You won't find
anything around here.
Why?
I told Bull to throw it away.
Now would you like a cup of coffee?
No, I don't want any coffee, Cole.
I want a drink! Can't you see?
I've got to have it!
Well, go get one.
Where's my hat?
This yours?
Who are you?
We met last night and again this morning.
Now, is this your hat?
No, it's not my hat, but it'll do.
♪ (SALOON PIANO CONTINUES) ♪
Let me have some whiskey.
Just hold your horses, sheriff.
Good evening, sheriff.
Here you are.
I don't want a drink,
I want the whole bottle.
I'll have to fill one up for you.
Isn't that?
That's McLeod, all right.
(SALOON PIANO FINISHES
TUNE AND STOPS)
Well, well! I'm Glad to see you.
I've been waiting for you.
I brought some boys
with me here.
Hi. Nelse, it's a good
time for me to introduce
you to the man I
wanted you to meet.
Sheriff. This is Nelse McLeod.
McLeod, this is J P Harrah... the sheriff
of El Dorado. (EVERYONE LAUGHS)
He's the man who's responsible for keeping
order in this town. (MORE LAUGHTER)
Here you are, sheriff.
He's just getting his evening bottle.
(MORE LAUGHTER)
♪ (CONCERTINA) ♪
Don't you think you better, ah, get
out'a the middle of the street?
Cole...
Cole, they laughed at me.
Right in front of McLeod,
they just laughed at me.
They've been laughing at you
for a couple of months.
You just haven't been
sober enough to hear it.
(BOTTLE SHATTERING)
They'll laugh no more. I'll show them.
(GUN HITTING FLOOR)
(GUNSHOTS FOLLOWED BY
♪ BUGLING OF 'CHARGE')
What's that?
Bull.
Needs help.
What is it?
Wait a minute. Now wait for...
Wait for me.
Why?
Cole! Over here!
The men that done it
took off down this way.
Just a minute.
Jared. I asked you not to go.
I asked you.
Seems like you're always around,
Thornton, when one of my boys gets hurt.
How is he?
He's alive.
Joey's gone for the Doctor.
Who did it?
Matt, you were with Jared. What happened?
It was three of Jason's men. They came
up behind us. One of them took my gun.
Then he started
calling Jared names.
When he turned around, one of 'em grabbed
his arm, the other one shot him.
And then they ran away.
What did they look like?
I know what they looked like.
One of 'em was tall, one was short,
and one of 'em had a bad leg.
Let's go find them.
Just a minute!
You're not gonna go find anybody!
Well, look who's here!
You're a little late, ain't you?
What did you do stop off for a drink?
All right, I'm late,
I may be too late.
That's no reason for the rest
of you to get gunned-down.
Why do you say that?
Because you're outclassed.
Sheriff's right. Jason's
had you beat ever
since Nelse McLeod and
those 4 gunmen rode in.
Nelse McLeod?
Jason's been waiting for him.
You go up against him now, you'll be
doing just what Jason wants you to do.
What do you expect us to do?
Why don't you ask the sheriff?
The sheriff? You think I'm
going to wait on him?
(SIGHS) Just give me an hour, MacDonald.
You can wait that long to die.
You backing him up, Thornton?
No, he's not.
Let's say I'm on your side, and
this is no job for amateurs.
They run down this street
and turned left.
Too many for one man
to take after.
If I was you, I wouldn't be too all-fired
in a hurry to go up that street.
Them fellows acted just like they
wanted somebody to follow 'em.
I've seen Indians
act just like that.
Well, I'm going
down this side...
What are you
doing here?
I'm going down the other side.
Remember, I didn't ask you.
Come on, Bull, you follow me.
Not too close now.
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL)
(Whistling)
♪ (CONTINUES)
Señor...
Please don't turn around. It's better
if no one sees me talking to you.
(WHISPERING) Mississippi!
(WHISPERING) Just a minute.
(TO THE GIRL) Go ahead.
Is it that you look
for three men?
That's right.
One walks with a leg which is not good?
Another is very tall?
They're the ones.
They ran over there to the old church.
They have not come out yet...
I have watched.
Well... ah... Thank you.
Well, you do not need to thank me. I
do not like Bart Jason or his men.
Thanks again.
What kept you?
Talking to a girl, she said she saw...
A girl?
Don't you think
I could know a girl?
She said she saw the men we want run
up that street to the old church.
She said they're still there.
Are they still there?
Yes, sir.
Well, we can find out, alright...
(WHISPERING) JP!
Girl said they were
up at that church.
What are you going to do, sheriff?
Go a little closer.
(GUNSHOT)
Girl was right. They're up there.
Sure are.
Hit me in the bugle.
Look, got a dent in it.
(GUNSHOTS)
Alongside that big bell on that tower.
I'll show you.
(SOUND OF BELL HIT BY SHOT)
(TWO SHOTS HITTING BELLS... RINGING)
Ain't that pretty?
Bull, you go on shootin'. We'll
try to move up a little closer.
Just give me another gun, and I'll
play "Marching Through Georgia."
All right, start playing. Let's go.
(SOUNDS OF SHOTS AND BELLS)
Come on up,
we'll cover you!
Look, Bull, we'll shake them up a little.
You keep 'em occupied while we move in.
Ready?
Let's make some music.
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS MANY HITTING BELLS)
Here they come.
(OUT OF BREATH) All right, Mississippi.
You watch that roof and watch it good.
Sheriff, you...
you all right?
No, you ain't.
I'm getting out of here.
Alright Mississippi, I'm
going to hit that door.
Now you get around that...
behind that...!
Watch that other door!
Look out up high!
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS AND BELLS)
Ohhhh...
(CRASH)
(SHOTGUN BLAST)
(BELLS RINGING)
(CRASH)
One of 'em got away, Cole.
You ought to know. You missed him.
Mississippi!
Over here!
Where'd you come from?
I heard a noise.
Did you get him?
Who?
The fellow that ran
out of the church.
Well, yes and no.
What do you mean? Did ya' or didn't ya?
I hit the sign and the sign hit him.
That's Great!
He was limping when he left.
He was limping when he got here. Oh.
One of us must have done some
damage, there's some blood here.
Anyway, he got away.
Not very far.
Where'd he go?
That saloon, up the street.
Jason's place.
Well, sheriff?
If you ask me one more time
what I'm going to do next...
so help me Cole, I'm gonna flat quit and
leave the whole thing in your hands.
Here, give me that,
or we'll be here all winter.
Well, I guess I'm going
to have to go in after 'em.
You know who'll be
in there don't ya?
Well, there's two men I've got to get.
Two men?
There's the man that
shot the MacDonald kid,
and the man that sent
him out to do it.
Bart Jason.
That's right.
I was wondering when you'd
get around to that.
Look Cole, I may be a drunk, I may
not be able to load my own gun,
but I don't need you to
tell me how to do my job!
I just hope you're
good enough.
So do I. So do I.
Bull, look here...
I'm going to go
round the back...
and you walk along that
side of the street.
If they got somebody
posted outside, you walk
right on up to the jailhouse
and just wave to me.
You're gonna need this.
Yeah, but...
Watch it, the way your hand's shaking,
don't let it get near the trigger!
Now, don't get on me, Bull!
I ain't started yet.
Ah, this is really going to
be something to see.
Who the hell are you?
Now, wait a minute, JP...
He's a little green! The fellow
you're after has got a bad leg.
Sure, Cole.
(WINDED) The back door's
through there.
If you go in real quiet like,
they may not know you're there.
Give me time to go to the front.
We'll watch.
You being fair?
What do you mean?
Letting him go in there.
Well, I'd hate to be the
one to try and stop him.
They all laughed at him, Mississippi.
That'll make the difference.
(WHISTLE)
All right, let's get on.
If you have to use that thing,
make sure which way it's pointed.
♪ ('CAMPTOWN RACES' ON THE PIANO) ♪
♪ ('SHOO-FLY' ON THE PIANO) ♪
What do you want here, sheriff?
I want two things.
First of all, I want to get the man
that just came in here.
Nobody came in here.
You just stay away from that gun, Elmer.
Move up the other end of the bar.
(BARREL CRASHING)
No, I wouldn't do it, McLeod.
The rest of you,
don't plan anything.
You decided to take a hand after all.
Never figured it any other way.
Mississippi, keep that gun pointed
right at this table, both barrels.
Go ahead, JP.
You...
You said that nobody came in here?
That's right, nobody came in.
Then, how come there's a trail of
blood leading right up to that table?
Joe, you're playing a lot of
sour notes on that piano.
I know I am.
You don't look very happy.
I'm certainly not.
Wouldn't you like to move
away from that piano, Joe?
You're darn right I would.
Well, then move!
(GUN SHOTS)
Ooooh!
Now, you said... (RIFLESHOT) I told
you, Elmer, get away from that gun.
Get up the other
end of the bar.
(SIGHS) You were saying that eh...
nobody walked in here.
Get up. Get up.
Nobody came in here,
huh, laughing boy?
Let me hear you laugh. Come
on, let me hear you laugh.
Ugh!
Now you, Jason...
Get out of my way.
You thought it was pretty funny too,
didn't you? Why aren't you laughing now?
It's the same drunken sheriff, the same
hat, the same outfit, why don't you laugh?
Let me hear you laugh!
Agh!
I don't know who you
think you are, Jason...
(RIFLE COCKS)
JP!
(SIGHS) All right, Cole.
You're a lucky man, Jason.
'Cause I wanted to kill you bad.
Come on, you're under arrest.
You just going to sit there, McLeod?
Well, there really isn't very much
I can do right now... is there, Jason?
I'll give you $1,000.
the day you get me out of jail.
$1,000.!
Let me tell you something, McLeod,
you make one move toward that jail,
and you're going to have a
hard time collecting that money,
because your boss
will be the first man shot.
So you and your boys get out of town
by morning, you understand?
You ready, Cole?
Whenever you are.
Let's go.
Cover us.
Get out of the way!
All right, Mississippi.
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL) ♪
What you looking at?
There's somebody out there
with a gun.
Everybody in town's got a gun.
Yeah, not pointing at us, though.
Where was this fellow?
In that livery stable
across the street.
It's too soon for one of the McLeods.
Think I'll take a look.
I don't know...
I'll be careful.
You go around the back way. Soon as
you're out the door, turn to your right.
If you're not back in five minutes,
I'll come after you.
(LATCH CLINKS SHUT FOLLOWED BY
CELL LOCK LATCHING)
Listen, sheriff...
You listen, Jason.
If you want anything more than bread and
water until the US marshal gets here,
you be absolutely quiet.
(METAL DOOR CLANKING SHUT)
(KEYS CLANKING DOWN)
(EXHALES SHARPLY) Well,
we got away with it.
Yeah.
You were... pretty good in there.
Like old times.
Eh, don't tell me how good I was.
I just got away with it
because I had a hangover.
I was too mad to be scared and just too
sick to worry about it. You know that.
I've been there.
Well, next time it's not going
to be so easy, is it?
Next time they'll be ready for you.
Say, who figured out that stuff
you people poured into me?
Mississippi.
Where is he, where is Mississippi?
Who is Mississippi?
Well, that's the kid... the fellow
that was around with us all night.
Well, where is he?
That's what I was asking Bull.
Across the street at the stable.
Saw somebody pointing a gun after us.
He ought to know better than that.
Want me to go after him?
Bull, you certainly ought to know better.
The first time in 2 months
I've felt like doing nothing for you...
now you don't want me to do it.
Was there something wrong with that,
or is it just my hangover?
You made better sense
when you was drinking!
Must be some whiskey around
here someplace...
♪
(CLANK THEN ANOTHER AS IT FALLS)
Hey, you're a girl.
Course I'm a girl.
Well, hold still...
Just hold still now, miss.
Hold still. You're going to lose
your clothes if you keep that up.
All right... All right.
I'll quit.
You sure?
I told you, didn't I?
All right.
How'd you know I was in here?
Ah, well, I saw your gun barrel sticking
out that window. Who are you after anyway?
Bart Jason. But you were
all so close around
him that I couldn't
get a clear shot.
Are you going to keep
sitting on my stomach?
Well, I'm ah, comfortable, and I...
Now I told you not to do that.
Don't do it and hold still!
What's your name?
Joey.
Joey?
Josephine MacDonald.
Well, come on.
Well, if you really are
a MacDonald, I... guess
you've got a right to be
want'n to shoot Jason.
Hey, I know who you are, you're one of the
ones that took him to the jail, aren't ya?
Yes, ma'am.
I recognize the hat.
Why do you wear that silly thing?
Well, never mind.
Why?
It, ah, it was given to me by an
old Cherokee Indian medicine man,
who told me, that as long as I wore it,
people wouldn't ask me fool questions.
That wasn't a fool question.
Hmm, well then I'll ask you one.
Why do you wear your hair
like ah, like some wild mustang
that needs a curry-comb and a brush?
I don't think...
Now don't do that again, 'cause I
can hit a little harder than you.
Damn you.
Look, if you are who you say
you are, I'm on your side.
I was wrong.
I ought not to be hitting you at all, I
ought to be thanking you for helping us.
Yeah, well...
Can I have my rifle back?
No, not just yet, not till we
find out who you really are.
I told you who I am.
Yeah, you just say so.
Come on, we'll go find out.
Bull, what did Mississippi say?
Goin' to the stable over
across the street.
Well, I guess I'd better go find out.
Hey, in the jail. Mississippi.
Come on, open the door.
Hold your horses.
Found this girl in that stable
across the street, pointing a gun.
Hello, Joey.
Sheriff.
Hello, Mr. Thornton.
Joey.
May I have my gun?
Sure.
Thanks.
Just who were you aiming
to shoot, Joey?
Jason.
Uh Ha!
Didn't the last time you shot
a man teach you anything at all?
There ain't any mistake about Jason.
We didn't have much hope you
were going to get him, sheriff,
so, Pa and the others are waiting for him
in different places, out on the street.
To be honest, we didn't think
you were good enough to get him.
Sober enough...
Well we were wrong.
Yeah...
Joey, you better
round up your family,
and tell them to go home and stay
there until this thing's over.
You can also tell them we've got
the man that shot your brother.
How is your brother?
Doc said he's got a good chance.
I'm glad.
You going to be able to
hold Mr. Jason, Sheriff?
Well, he'll stand trial, Joey.
Will he get what he deserves?
I don't know. I'm not the judge,
I'm just the sheriff around here.
Would it be alright if I
could I see him, talk to him?
Sure, just let me have that gun.
Never mind... Guess I'll be going.
You want me to go with you?
Why?
Well, I don't know...
They haven't gotten around
to shooting women yet.
Umm.
I reckon you all are doin'
what you think is right.
And for what you're doin', thanks.
All of you.
She would've shot that fellow.
She shot me.
Sh... Sh... She? Mmm.
She's something.
Hyah! Hyah!
♪ (HARMONICA) ♪
Cole, McLeod and 4 of his men
just left from across the street.
Don't figure he's pulling out, do ya?
Fellow in his line of work can't pull out,
once he takes a job.
Well, I hear he's part Injun.
Could be he might just want us
to think he's leaving.
Could be.
Got that hejee feeling in the back of my
neck that says Injun trouble's coming.
What time do you reckon it is?
Oh, around 11, 12.
Sheriff said as how he
wanted to be woke up.
What for?
Well, before he tried to
drink the town dry, we
used to make a patrol
about this time of night.
Well, don't wake him up. He's been
through enough for one night.
Mississippi!
You and I 'll have a look around.
If you're going to do that,
here's a couple of badges.
Raise your right hand.
I forgot the words,
but you'd better say, "I do".
(BOTH) I do.
Now you're deputies.
You suppose these'll do any good
if somebody takes a shot at us?
It'll give 'em a good mark to shoot at.
You'd better come lock
this door after us.
(LOCK LATCHING)
Take a look-see in at Jason's.
I'll take this side.
You! Jeffe?
Con permiso, amigos
♪
(WHISTLING LIKE A BIRD)
What was that?
I don't know, but I don't like it.
Hyah! Huyah!
Look out!
(GUNSHOTS, HORSES GALLOPING)
(SHOTGUN BLAST HORSES WINNOWING)
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
Get him inside.
Close the door.
(DOOR LATCHING)
You hit bad?
No, just a nick. I don't
think it got the bone.
Ain't nobody gonna tell me
what happened out there?
Bull, I told you to stay
back out of sight.
How's a body see anything
from around the corner?
I've got to cut this pant leg.
Go ahead and cut it, you got a knife?
Hey, ah, I suppose I've asked this
before, but just who... Who is he?
Tell him your name, Mississippi.
Alan Bourdillion Traherne.
Well, no wonder he carries a knife.
You need a Doctor to fix this.
Bull, you suppose you could
slip out the back door and
get Doc Miller over here
without getting yourself shot?
If I thought I would get shot, I
wouldn't go. Be back as soon as I can.
Here. Use this till
the Doctor gets here.
Cole, how did this mess get started?
Well, a bunch of men on horseback
came flying around the bend and...
What was the idea of diving
under those horses?
Diving under those horses?
Yeah, a man can't shoot good
when his horse is jumping,
and a horse will not step on a man.
He won't?
He will?
Alan Bourdillion Ter... who?
Terhain
Traherne!
Traherne.
Yeah.
There's nothing in there.
Sheriff, you've got nothing
to worry about.
Lift your leg a little, please.
Thornton, did you ever get
that bullet out of your back?
No, I never did.
I told you at the time, you needed
someone better than me to get it out.
I've got the
man right here who can do it.
Doctor Donovan, can you spare a minute?
Yes, Doctor.
Hold your finger right here.
No, no, here. That's it.
This fellow's got a bullet in him.
Went in the left side about here,
and moved toward the spine.
About here?
A little higher.
Oh yes, I feel it.
Uh ha.
This may hurt.
It did.
That's very odd.
Tell me does it hurt here?
No.
Doctor...
Just a minute, sheriff.
What do you think, Charles?
It's a challenge, isn't it?
I reckon he's got a more interesting
misery than you got, sheriff.
Look, Doctor, I don't want to take up your
time, but ah, mine's still bleeding.
You've got nothing to worry about, sherrif,
it's a good clean wound.
Tell me, it's giving
you trouble, isn't it?
Well, I wouldn't say...
Why don't you tell him the truth?
I can guess.
I can guess, there's a sudden
spasm of pain in this area
followed paralysis of one
side, probably the right.
Oh, it doesn't last very long.
But it lasts a little
longer each time, doesn't it?
What are you trying to tell him, Doctor?
That if he doesn't get that
bullet out of there, one of these
times he'll have an attack
and it won't just pass off.
McLeod may settle the whole problem for us.
But if I'm here after this is all over,
I'll come and see you, Doc, I promise.
You do that.
Now, Doctors, if you please.
Could you come here,
so I can rest my finger?
Surely, sheriff.
JP, why don't you settle down?
I just can't help it, Cole,
I've got the shakes so bad...
You've had them before.
Yeah, but not with a hole
in my leg and a whole bunch
of unfriendly people
hangin' around outside...
just waiting for somebody
to pop through that...
What do you want to do?
Quit?
(JP SIGHS DEEPLY)
The only thing I can figure is don't
use the door, don't go outside.
You mean hole up?
Well sure, they're not
gonna come in here after us.
When do you expect the
United States marshal?
Oh man, I don't remember
the last time he was here.
He was here.
You gave him a big welcome.
Flung a bottle at him.
An empty bottle?
Yeah, he wasn't that far gone.
When's the marshal due?
Ahh, four or five days.
Got enough food?
Plenty of coffee and water.
Ah Bull, do you suppose you could you slip
out that back door and bring us some food?
Without getting shot?
I wish you would.
I don't know what he wants me
to do, get shot or get food.
Want me to go with ya?
Yeah, if I get shot, you
can bring back the food.
And I'm also going
to bring back a big bar of soap.
This place'll never be Delmonico's,
but the food'd just taste better if a
fella I know, would use that bar of soap.
Bull, why don't you just get.
I'm going.
I suppose I could use a little bath.
I'd appreciate it.
Morning, Joey.
Morning Bull, I brought some...
Good morning, sheriff.
Joey, I'm taking a bath.
Ah, don't mind me, sheriff,
I was raised with four brothers.
Well, I'm not your brother.
Doc Miller sent you over these crutches
and some clean clothes.
He also sent you a bar of soap.
And I brought along an
extra one just in case...
I see, you already have some.
I've got a lot of friends, Joey.
Yeah, well, I guess I'll be goin'.
Morning.
Josephine!
Joey...
What are you doin' still in town?
We came to take my brother Jared home
this morning, he's a lot better.
Well, when you get back
to the ranch, you do what I say...
I remember what you said:
Stay close and watch out.
Right.
You look a lot better
without that hat.
Well, thank you, ma'am.
Wait a minute. Don't close that door.
Morning, Joey.
'Morning Maudie.
Hi, Mississippi, Bull. Morning, Cole.
Good morning, good morning, good morning!
I'd have more
privacy in the middle of the
El Paso railroad station.
(LAUGHING) Hello, JP. How are you?
I'm thinking of selling tickets,
Maudie, I'd get rich.
I got here just in time.
Here's a bar of soap for you.
Just what I need.
(Laughs) Hey, what happened to your leg?
Maudie, Maudie! Will you get out of here?
All right, JP; what happened to him?
Oh, he'll be alright! Got a
nick in the leg last night...
I thought you all might...
Maudie, I think you ought to have better
sense than to come around here...
I ought to have better sense
to come here? I brought
you some food. I think
I'll take it back...
No, no, now just a minute...
Cole, sometimes you make me so mad...
Maudie, Maudie...
What?
What he's trying to tell
you in his own sweet way...
is that it's not safe for
you to come here anymore.
Somebody sees you come in here,
they tell McLeod,
then McLeod tries to use you
to get to us.
Oh, I never thought of it that way...
Well, that's ah...
Something else. She oughtn't
to go out the front door!
'Cause McLeod and hisn'...
Well?
All right, let her come through
this way. I'll close my eyes.
(SHE LAUGHS)
Come on.
Ma'am you might just as
well leave that basket.
Sure, Mississippi.
(CONTINUING TO LAUGH)
Come on, Maudie.
♪
Hey, you in the jail!
(DOOR LATCH BEING TRIED)
Who is it?
It's me, Polly, I got a note for you.
Don't see nobody with her.
(DOOR UNLATCHING)
Come on in, Polly.
Hi, sheriff.
(DOOR LATCHING)
Maudie asked me to bring this to you.
I'm scared, sheriff. Those men waiting
around... All the girls are so scared.
I know, I know, Polly.
What does she say, Cole?
Just, what I was afraid of, some of
McLeod's men are hanging around her place.
She says watch out for ourselves,
'cause she overheard enough to know...
that they've got something planned.
Well, I guess you'd better
go on down there, Cole.
Yeah. Mississippi... you want to
"ride, boldly ride" again?
Might be some trouble.
"Over the mountains of the moon
Down the valley of the shadow"
"Here we come."
Go ahead, Bull.
(DOOR SQUEEKS THEN SHUTS)
♪ (PIANO) ♪
Look out!
(GUNSHOTS WITH PIANO CONTINUING)
The window. Get their attention.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Steady down! A man came in here.
Out the back way.
He goes through that door!
Runnin' fast! -Cole!
Don't these fellows look familiar?
Our friends from the border.
Milt and Pedro. Where's McLeod?
I don't know.
These are the people who wait
for people outside of doors.
Kind of makes you wonder
about that door, doesn't it?
You're learning, Mississippi.
Any particular reason why you...
want us to go out that way?
No, no, no, señor, he...
he went out that way...
Pedro's telling the truth.
He better be because you're going
out that door. You first, Milt.
No, no, no... please.
Come on, Milt.
Not that way.
(GUNSHOT)
I'm tired of being taken for a fool.
Move! Come on, Move!
Please, don't.
On your way. (GUNSHOT)
I lied. There's somebody out there.
I know.
Wait, I'll go. I'll go.
You sure will.
Don't shoot, it's Milt, don't shoot!
(BREAKING GLASS)
All right, Pedro,
it's your turn.
No, No, No, please! No, Please!
Please... I...
You're next. Move! (GUNSHOT)
Go on, Pedro, mo... ah...
Ah, Ah... eeeuh...
(GUN ON FLOOR) (THUD)
(GUNSHOT BLAST)
Cole! You all right?
What is it, Cole?
(THUD) Oooooh!
Well, Thornton,
this is better than I expected.
(COLE SIGHS) Pick him up and
take him out of here.
Give 'em a hand. Chuck! Dick!
♪
Can you see anything?
Well, there's hardly anybody
moving on the street.
They've run into trouble sure enough.
They should've been here or
sent somebody an hour ago.
♪
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Who is it?
Mississippi. Come on, open up.
(CLANKING OF DOOR, KEYS, LOCK)
Where's Cole?
McLeod's got him.
Well, right after that,
this fella come up
from behind me and, ah...
give me a headache.
I think it was Jim
Purvis, Jason's foreman...
From there on in, Maudie's goin'
to have to tell you what happened.
Well, was Cole all right?
Yeah, he was all right, when I saw him last
except his... his side seemed numb.
Did they take him away?
Yeah, they carried him out.
While they were gone,
we got Mississippi into my room. But...
when they came back, they
didn't seem to want him bad
enough to try to take him 'cause...
they had Cole already.
Yeah...
Well, it's not too good, is it?
It sure ain't.
I wouldn't look so happy if I were you,
because if anything does happen to Cole...
(GUNSHOTS)
(LOCK GIVES WAY)
(THUD)
Get back!
Stay back.
Sheriff!
Sheriff, can you hear me?
It's Nelse McLeod.
Yes, I hear you.
Your friend Thornton's got something wrong
with him... but it wasn't our doing.
We got four or five guns on him,
from across the street
so don't try and move him.
Bull, watch Jason. Mississippi!
We've got enough guns
on your boss to get the job done.
I expected that. (Door Squeeking)
Alright, McCleod, what's your deal?
You send out Jason alive,
and you get your friend.
(MUFFLED SPEECH)
All right, Bull. Let him out.
Sheriff, you can't do it.
You free Jason,
McLeod can do anything he wants to.
What chance you got then?
Just open the door, Bull.
(KEYS JANGLING)
That's far enough, Jason.
Come on Bull, you come
where you can watch him
all the way out the door.
All right, Jason. Come on.
Mississippi... Get back here by this
window. Don't open it. Just stand ready.
Slowly now.
Go on. Through the door, now,
close it behind you.
I can't close it with his feet there.
Move them.
That's right... slowly.
Alright, get him out of here and get
something in front of that door!
(MUFFLED SIGH OF PAIN)
Are you all right, Cole? (BREATHLESS)
I guess so. (CONTINUES TO BREATHE DEEPLY)
Well, JP...
you made a great bargain.
You sold out the
whole MacDonald family.
For what?
Go ahead, tell me about it, Cole.
Tell me about how if it was you,
you'd have done it different.
Well... you're going to have to face 'em
It's my fault... but... they'll blame you.
Yeah.
In the jail.
Thornton, I'm sorry
it had to end this way.
I'll always wonder
which one of us was best.
¡Gracias!
♪ (PIANO)
Can you feel that?
No.
Or that?
It's almost like it was last night, Doc.
Come on, last night your whole side
was dead, now it's just your arm.
It never lasted all night before.
You may have waited too long.
Can't you operate on him, Doctor,
and get that bullet out?
Well, I could, but he'd be laid-up, and
he says he has too much to do right now.
How he's going to do
it, I don't know.
Bull, you going to stand and
look out the window all day?
Yep. McLeod let us
leave town too easy.
Joey MacDonald and Saul MacDonald's
wife's coming.
Could be bringing trouble.
Mississippi, you slip out
that back door and see if
anybody's following them.
Bull, you watch 'em too.
(DOOR SQUEEKS OPEN)
Bull, Mr. Martin...
Sheriff, we want to talk to you.
What's wrong, Joey?
Lots of things.
My husband, Saul, Jason's men took him.
Took him?
Yes, they've got him.
Joey, you were supposed
to tell your family to watch out.
Cattle got to be
watered, Mr. Thornton.
A young Mexican boy was with Saul.
They sent the boy back with a message:
Said we can have Saul back alive if Pa was
to turn his water rights over to Jason.
And he's going to do it?
He ain't got any choice!
You know they're never going to
give Saul back, don't you, sheriff?
I'm afraid that... Jason doesn't want
Saul or your father around.
To testify as to how
he got the deed to that water.
You have to do something,
sheriff, you just got to!
Ain't nobody trailing
that I can see.
When is your father
supposed to do all of this?
Tonight...
8 o'clock. They're bringing Saul to Jason's
saloon. Pa's supposed to bring the deed.
They said they'd kill Saul
if anybody tried anything.
That's just what you said about Jason,
wasn't it, sheriff? That you'd kill him.
And then you didn't.
No, he didn't.
Well, what are you going to do now?
They've got McLeod,
and a bunch of gunhands
and they've got your brother.
You just
take a look around...
We've got two cripples,
a green kid and a noisy old...
Indian fighter.
...Indian fighter.
Now, how in the hell do I
know what I'm going to do?
Joey, you go back
and tell your pa
we're going to do
whatever we can,
but it's up to him whether
he gives up or not.
It's my fault. If I hadn't shot you,
none of this would've happened.
You will try though?
Yes, ma'am. We'll try.
I reckon, we'll be going.
Well, sheriff, just
what are we going to do?
I don't know, Bull.
Like I told the lady.
I just don't know.
(SOUNDS OF RIFLE LEVER ACTION
THEN DRY-FIRING TRIGGER RELEASE)
Can you hit anything that way?
If I can get close enough.
Load it, will you?
How're you going to
get close enough?
Ride up to the front of Jason's in a wagon.
You've got a wagon, haven't you?
Got a great big one.
Are you crazy, have you lost your mind?
He's making sense.
They won't think I'm any good.
I got away with it. He can.
Last time you took the
front door and I took the
back; this time, we'll do
her the other way 'round.
We'd better get goin' before
we're thinkin' about it too much.
I suppose the best time
to get there would
be... ah, just before
they expect MacDonald.
Eight o'clock, Joey said.
Well, Bull, guess you'd better
hook up a couple of wagons.
Well, come on, Mississippi...
before they think up something else.
Yeah...!
♪
Give me the gun.
Can you see it from there?
Can't see a thing.
How you going to
get down from there?
Well, that's easy.
I'm going to fall down.
JP... How're we going
to time this thing?
You know they're sure to have
somebody out in back watchin'.
You trying to tell me
how to run my job, Cole?
No, but I'm a little interested.
I don't know
how long I can keep
them busy out in front.
Well, we'll be just
as quiet as we can be.
If we can get the job done before you start
shootin', Bull will blow on his horn.
What if they shootin' before
he toots that bugle?
Well, in that case, partner,
you're on your own.
Wait a minute! I got an idea.
Can I ride into town with you?
It isn't gonna be pretty to see.
I'd like to be around.
You'll get off when I say so?
I'll get off.
Come ahead.
Give me something to lean on.
"And when his strength
failed him at length"
"He met a pilgrim shadow"
"Shadow, said he
Where can it be"
"This land called El Dorado?"
I'll see you, Cole.
I hope so.
I'm coming.
What are you doing
with that bow and arrow?
Like Cole said: got to
be quiet about this.
Can you hit the side of
a barn with that thing?
Ain't going to try to
hit a barn... just a man.
"Over the mountains of the moon
Down the valley of the shadow"
"Ride, boldly ride,
The shade replied"
"If you search for El Dorado"
H'yah!
(BUGLE PLAYING)
♪
H'yup... (SIGH)
Well, Maudie,
this is as far as you go.
All right.
Aren't you going to say anything?
Would it do me any good to say it?
Say what?
That this is crazy.
No, I'm not going
to say anything.
I'm just going to go out
and... buy you a pine box.
About six foot six ought
to be just about...
Maudie!
The MacDonalds. Hold 'em back. Tell
'em to give us five minutes... Hurry!
Bye, Cole.
Whoa!
♪ (SALOON PIANO)
Well, they've got a
lookout there alright!
Got to get rid of him.
You reckon' you can you hit him from
here with that bow and arrow, Bull?
Can't miss.
Any chance of him
yelling-out when he gets hit?
Plenty!
Hold it.
I got an idea.
Hold that. Take good care of that.
(WATER POURING OUT)
What in tarnation you doin'?
(CHINESE SOUNDING)
Chong-Tung-Poah... (LAUGH)
See you rater.
(CHINESE SOUNDING 'WORDS')
What are you trying to say?
(CHINESE-SOUNDING 'WORDS' CONTINUE)
You can't go in there.
Oh, no? (PUNCH FOLLOWED BY OOOOH!)
So solly. Come on.
Go on in, Bull.
♪ (SALOON PIANO CONTINUES
WITH MULTIPLE SOUR NOTES)
Joe never was much good
on that piano was he?
No, and you shooting them strings
out didn't help none, neither.
McCloed!...
Cole Thornton's comin'.
Chuck, you and a couple of boys
stay with the kid.
(PIANO ♪ STOPS)
Didn't expect to see you here,
Mr. Thornton.
Hello, McLeod.
I said...
My show, Jason.
Hi, Thornton.
There's a little question
unanswered between us.
Which one of us is best?
That's right.
I don't think we're going to find
out the answer to that question.
No?
No. Your gun hand's no good.
You just give me time to get down
off this wagon, and we'll find out.
Why should I give you any time?
Call it professional courtesy.
Don't even listen to him.
Why should you give him time?
Curiosity, Jason.
All right, Bull. Get that one
close to the MacDonald boy.
When you hit him, blow that bugle.
Well, my better judgment tells me that
I can't... (BUGLE ♪ BEING BLOWN)
(GUNSHOT)Hiyah!
(MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS)
Freeze it right there, Johnny.
Where's Saul?
In there, he's all right.
Joey, I told you
to stay out of this.
But Pa, I...
This is one time I'm glad she didn't!
I'm much obliged, Joey!
I owed you some.
Cole!
McCleod?
You didn't give me any... chance at all
...did you?
No, I didn't. You're too
good to give a chance to.
Yeah...
...I let a one-armed man take me.
JP, look.
Now that I don't need this thing...
it's working pretty good!
That's always the way, isn't it?
Hey Bull, what's going on out there?
Town's fit to bust out.
Be a big time tonight.
Every son feels like hollerin'.
How's your leg, Cole?
Ask the Doc.
Oh, it's not too bad! You know these
wounds were made by buckshot, don't you?
I thought they were.
(Coffee Spilling to Floor)
Who was using a shotgun?
Oh, there was a certain
young man with a...
I was using a shotgun, Doc.
You? I thought you were on their side.
He was.
I told you I was
no good with a gun.
Trouble is, Doc,
Cole was in front of the gun.
The safe place is behind Mississippi
when he shoots that thing.
You, too, Bull, huh?
I think I'll take a little walk.
See that gal?
What gal?
The one that thinks you look
better without that hat.
Why don't you tell her
why you're wearin' it?
Don't have to, I've
already told her
She's madder 'n a wet hen. Said you
let her make a fool of herself.
Ah, a host of friends...
I have a host of friends!
And, I'm sorry about that leg...
Forget it.
Yeah. I'll see you.
Mr. Thornton, that'll be a little sore
for a few days, but it'll be all right.
Yeah...
I Hope you have time
to let me fix your back.
Well, just as soon as
this leg heals, Doc.
I'll be ready.
Hey, Cole, where's Maudie?
I was wondering about that too.
I left her down the street just
before this ruckus started.
Ah, she'll probably
be around pretty soon.
Well, I wouldn't count
on that too much.
I just talked to her down at her place.
Well?
If'n you was running for president,
I figure, you wouldn't get her vote.
Well, what did I do?
Well, she said she was plum
through waitin' on a man...
whilst he's runnin'
around being a target for
anybody that had a
notion to shoot a gun.
Said she couldn't take it no more.
She said that?
Yeah, she said that, and she
added a few frills and dressing.
The main idea was,
the door was closed.
Well!
(JP WHISTLES)
Well Cole, what are you going to do?
What can I do?
Can't argue with a closed door.
Glad to hear you say that.
Better just drop the whole thing.
Well what can I...
Some other fool would just go down
there and try talking her out of it.
You can get into a lot
of trouble with women
like that. Remember
what happened to me.
You tryin' to say that I'm in
the same mess you were?
Why no, I didn't
say that, Cole.
You think I'm gonna make a
fool out of myself like you did?
Cole, you told me yourself, you cannot
stand to be tied down in one place.
How do you know I haven't
had enough of running
around selling my gun
arm all over the place.
You said yourself sittin'
right here on this desk that...
Don't put words in my mouth...
I'm not putting words in your mouth!
And if I'm gonna have somebody tell me
about women, it isn't going to be you.
Where is Maudie?
Down at her place.
That's my crutch.
Well, where's the other one?
Right over there,
right under your nose.
I can't make up my own mind!
You got it under the wrong arm, Cole.
Well, how would you know? You've been using
it first under one arm and then the other.
Fine friend! Trying to keep a fellow
from doing what he wants to do.
(JP LAUGHS)
I reckon' the way to get him to do
something is to tell him not to do it.
Not if he didn't want to
do it in the first place.
Reckon he'll stay here?
Yeah, could be.
Be a good thing to have him here.
Suppose you'll likely to wait a bit,
find a new gal,
make a fool of yourself
all over again.
Most likely. If you leave me,
Bull, I could be driven to it.
Well, I ain't said I was gonna leave ya.
You as much as said it.
Now, stop putting
words in my mouth.
I just can't do anything right
according to you. Bull, I need you.
You what?
I need you, Bull.
Well, now if you start being nice
to me, I'll quit you for sure.
Shock'd be too much. I'd as sooner
have you hungover and nasty.
Speaking of that,
how about a little drink, Bull?
Darn it! Took you a long time
to think of that one.
That was good work, sheriff.
Thank you, friend.
Sheriff, it looks like
you're going to keep your job.
Yeah, it'll be a nice quiet town
after you leave, Cole.
How do you know I'm leaving?
We just don't need
your kind around here.
♪