(TRUMPETING)
(DRIVER SHOUTING)
Get in there, Luke. Get in there.
That's it.
(CONTINUES SHOUTING)
Giddyap, now. Come on.
- Driver?
DRIVER: Get in there, Rosie.
Driver, how much farther
to this Hasenpfeffer...
...or whatever you call
the confounded place?
Hassayampa?
Oh, shouldn't be long now.
Once over the rise, and round the bend,
then along a piece.
We should've been there an hour ago.
Don't suppose we could've passed her,
do you, Fink?
Might have, at that.
(FINK CHUCKLES)
Don't you worry, soldier boy.
We'll get you there.
(CHUCKLES)
"Soldier boy."
What a country.
Forty miles from mudhole to mudhole.
Mule Creek, Deadman's Squaw,
Schmidt's Wells.
Hangman's Flats, Hassayampa.
At the end of the rainbow, Fort Apache.
Fort Apache.
Blast an ungrateful War Department
that sends a man to a post out here.
Anyway, I'll be with you.
I hated all those years
you were in Europe.
Better there than here.
I didn't mean it that way, Phil.
It's just that after all I've done and
been, to be shunted aside like this...
We're coming in.
Practically on schedule. Right, Fink?
Practically.
- Ma Macbean?
MA: Aye. I'm coming.
- Nice trip, boys?
- Smooth as a rock.
THURSDAY:
How far is it to Fort Apache?
Oh, the fort's 35 miles south of here.
Were you expected?
THURSDAY: I telegraphed.
- Oh, that.
Telegraphs doesn't mean a thing.
One day the wire's up,
the next day they're down.
Thirty-five miles south?
Madam, is there a livery stable here?
No.
There must be some way
to rent a vehicle.
- A what?
- A rig. Any kind of rig.
Nothing fit for the lassie to ride in.
Oh, my, that's a real bonny bonnet, miss.
- St. Louis?
- Boston.
- Oh, Boston, Massachusetts?
- Here.
Oh, my.
(MEN CHUCKLE)
MA:
Oh.
That's mighty pretty, Ma.
Oh, my.
Oh, would you not like a wee cup of tea
and get rid of the dust?
Thank you.
If it isn't too much trouble.
Not a bit, lass, not a bit.
Come on. Right in here.
Son, how about a drink?
THURSDAY:
Gentlemen, I could use one.
Women.
(SPITTOON DINGS)
MA: There's your towel.
You'll be as fresh as a daisy.
MICKEY:
Thanks, Ma.
Oh, I'm sorry, ma'am. I thought it was Ma.
I beg your pardon, miss.
Who and what are you, mister?
Lieutenant Michael O'Rourke, sir.
En route for duty at Fort Apache, sir.
- Get into uniform, mister.
- Yes, sir.
- Is there another wash-up back here?
- Through the lean-to, sir.
(FINK CHUCKLES)
Soldiers.
(SPITTOON DINGS)
(MEN SHOUTING)
SOLDIER 1: Hey!
SOLDIER 2: Hey, come on inside.
(BEAUFORT YELLS)
MICKEY:
Johnny Reb. Uncle Festie.
Timmy. Uncle Dan.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Your manners.
Ho!
Sergeant Mulcahy,
with ambulance and escort...
...for Lieutenant Michael O'Rourke.
Very good, sergeant. At ease.
"At ease," he says. Ha-ha-ha. "At ease."
(ALL LAUGHING)
MICKEY:
Hey! Hey!
(CHUCKLES)
- How much you pay for it?
- Seventy-five dollars.
I could've swiped you
one better than that.
It's tailor-made.
Well, look at the fit. A perfect soldier.
What do you think of it, ma'am?
Wonderful.
Ma'am, this is my godson,
Lieutenant O'Rourke.
Many's the time he's come to me
with a wet nose.
Attention!
I am Colonel Thursday.
I presume you have been sent for me.
- No, sir.
- What are you doing here?
Escorting the ambulance from Fort Apache
for Lieutenant O'Rourke, sir.
- Have you had no orders regarding me?
BEAUFORT: No, sir.
They couldn't have known
of your arrival, sir.
That's obvious, mister.
Unless it's the custom at Fort Apache...
...to provide transportation
for incoming second lieutenants...
...and leave a commanding officer
to travel shanks' mare.
You will, of course, sir,
accept my ambulance.
Thank you, mister.
- Sergeant, we'll leave in one half-hour.
- Yes, sir.
Get these men a drink
and put it on my account.
- We thank the colonel.
- We thank the colonel, sir.
Oh, may I present Mr. O'Brien.
O'Rourke, sir.
O'Rourke. This is my daughter,
Miss Philadelphia.
How do you do?
Your servant, ma'am.
Four bottles of cool beer, Ma.
And I'll have the same
with a whiskey chaser.
(BAND PLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC)
(DRIVER SHOUTING)
GUARD:
Halt. Who goes there?
MICKEY:
The new commanding officer.
GUARD:
Holy Moses.
MICKEY:
No, the new commanding officer.
♪ (BAND PLAYING WALTZ MUSIC) ♪
Attention!
(MUSIC STOPS)
At your ease, gentlemen.
- Thursday.
- Hello, Collingwood.
How do you do, Mrs. Collingwood?
Well, thank you, Owen.
And this must be Philadelphia.
You don't remember me, do you?
Emily Collingwood.
Your mother was my dearest friend.
Why, of course.
Oh, I've heard so much about you.
- We didn't expect you.
- So I see.
Captain York.
I'm Captain York, sir.
I bid you welcome, General Thursday.
I'm not a general, captain.
A man is what he's paid for.
I'm paid in the rank
of lieutenant colonel.
I remember you as a general
from the war, sir.
Very flattering. Didn't you receive
my telegraph, captain?
The wires have been down between here
and Fort Grant for two days.
We've had no communications.
Two days? The break
should have been repaired.
It's 110 miles to Fort Grant, sir.
I take it this dance is not in my honor.
- It's a birthday dance, sir.
- Birthday? Whose birthday?
General George Washington's, sir.
Shall I show you to your quarters,
or will you remain?
THURSDAY:
Well, under the circumstances, I...
Miss Thursday?
♪ (MUSIC RESUMES) ♪
Hi, Dad.
Mickey.
Woman of the house, your son is home.
- Son.
- Hi, Ma.
(MRS. O'ROURKE LAUGHING)
Oh, how fine you look.
But you're so tall.
Oh, Michael, stand over beside the boy
so I can see.
Oh, you're just exactly the same.
Now come over here and sit down
and tell me everything.
Gee, Ma, you haven't changed a bit.
Nothing has.
And why would it?
Four years is not so long.
Or did you think to find me
grown gray completely?
Woman, I'll leave you alone
with your son.
Lieutenant Michael O'Rourke, sir.
Have I the lieutenant's permission
to leave, sir?
Sergeant Major O'Rourke has permission.
Thank you, sir.
(MICKEY GRUNTS AND ALL LAUGH)
- Michael.
- God's blessing on you this day.
Boys, I'm not a drinking man,
as you know, but there are times.
And tonight, if the sutler's store
is still open...
Michael, darling, if it ain't,
I'll kick the door down with my bare fists.
(ALL LAUGH)
♪ (SOLDIER TRUMPETING "REVEILLE") ♪
♪ (SOLDIER DRUMMING) ♪
Dad?
PHILADELPHIA:
Good morning.
It's all right.
There's no one here but me,
and I've been up for simply ages.
MICKEY:
Oh?
Did you want to see Father or me?
MICKEY:
Well, neither, really.
Oh.
I just called to leave my card.
Oh, how nice.
But if you didn't wanna see me...
I mean, if you don't wanna see us...
...then what do you wanna leave
your card for?
- I didn't say I didn't wanna see you.
- Why, you did so.
I asked if you wanted
to see Father or me...
...and you said, your exact words,
"Well, neither, really."
Well, what I meant to say was
I didn't expect to see either of you.
Well, who did you expect to see?
After all, we do live here.
Why don't you sit down?
Good morning, good morning,
fair dancing partner.
- Good morning, sir.
- Relax, Mickey.
Got some bad news for you.
You've been assigned to my troop.
"Michael Shannon O'Rourke,
lieutenant, United States Army."
Leaving your calling cards already,
Mickey, eh?
He can keep his old cards.
Oh, he can't do that. Protocol requires it.
An officer, upon reporting
to a new post...
...must wait upon his commanding officer
at the first possible moment.
He will leave his card.
He will leave an additional card for each
lady in the commanding officer's family.
All other officers on the post...
...will leave their cards at the quarters
of the incoming officer, right?
Right. Now do you understand?
- It was just a duty call?
- That's it. Just a duty call.
But there's nothing in the regulations
that says an officer's daughter...
...should receive such cards
on her back porch in her nightie.
Pish-tush. This is not a nightie.
It's a dressing gown, isn't it?
- I wouldn't know.
- And I haven't received any cards, anyway.
Well, hand them over to her, Mickey.
Oh, I get it, Miss Thursday.
The lieutenant expected someone to meet
him at the door with a silver salver.
- A what?
- A silver salver.
He'd drop the cards in that
and hurry away.
You don't happen to have
a silver salver, do you?
A silver salver?
Our things haven't even arrived.
Why, last night,
I slept on a horse blanket.
O'ROURKE:
Attention!
Sergeant Major O'Rourke, sir.
At ease.
- Did you say "O'Rourke"?
- Yes, sir.
Place seems to be full of O'Rourkes.
Have the trumpeter sound
officer's call.
- Officer's call?
- How long have you been in the Army?
In the United States Army,
15 years, sir.
Then you've heard of officer's call.
Have it sounded.
Yes, sir.
- Derice, sound officer's call.
- Now?
No, next Christmas, you loony.
How long you been in the Army?
Then you've heard of officer's call.
Sound it.
♪ (TRUMPETING OFFICER'S CALL) ♪
"War Department, Washington, D.C.
Special orders number 687."
One. Lieutenant Colonel Owen Thursday
is hereby relieved of his present duties...
...and will proceed to Fort Apache...
"...and upon arrival will assume command
of that post. Travel directed..."
And so forth.
"By direction of the secretary of war,
William B. Stafford."
In compliance with these orders,
I take command of the regiment...
...relieving Captain Kirby York,
who has returned to his troop.
Captain Collingwood is relieved of
the duties of regimental adjutant.
Returned to his troop.
Lieutenant Gates is appointed adjutant.
At ease, gentlemen.
Gentlemen, I did not seek this command,
but since it's been assigned me...
...I intend to make this regiment
the finest on the frontier.
I fully realize that prolonged duty
in a small outpost...
...can lead to carelessness...
...and inefficiency,
and laxity in dress and deportment.
I call it to your attention
that only one of you...
...has reported here this morning
properly dressed.
The uniform, gentlemen, is not a subject
for individual whimsical expression.
We're not cowboys at this post...
...nor freighters with a load of alfalfa.
Mr...
...Murphy.
O'Rourke, sir.
Mr. O'Rourke, will you step forward?
Gentlemen, I call your attention
to Mr. O'Rourke's dress.
Being fresh from West Point...
...Mr. O'Rourke has not forgotten
Army regulations.
I trust my other officers will
remember them in the future.
And I will insist they be enforced
throughout the command.
Understand me, gentlemen,
I am not a martinet.
But I do want to take pride
in my command.
We here have little chance for glory
or advancement.
While some of our brother officers
are leading...
...their well-publicized campaigns against
the great Indian nations...
...the Sioux and the Cheyenne...
...we are asked to ward off
the gnat stings and flea bites...
...of a few cowardly Digger lndians.
Your pardon, colonel. You'd hardly
call Apaches "Digger lndians," sir.
You'd scarcely compare them
with the Sioux, captain.
No, I don't.
The Sioux once raided
into Apache territory.
Old-timers told me you could follow
their line of retreat...
...by the bones of their dead.
I suggest the Apache
has deteriorated since then...
...judging by a few of the specimens
I've seen on my way out here.
Well, if you saw them, sir,
they weren't Apaches.
We'll discuss the Apache
some other time, captain.
The immediate point, gentlemen,
is that I hope to know you all better.
If we don't understand
each other now, we soon will.
Questions?
Good morning, gentlemen. You may return
to your breakfasts or your other duties.
Captain Collingwood, will you remain?
Go on.
Gentlemen, are there any questions?
If there are none, I intend
to follow orders and have breakfast.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Report to your coop.
Sir.
Nothing personal in this, Sam.
No explanations, Owen.
We've never had them before.
- Although, once, I tried.
- There was nothing to explain.
No, nothing.
You did what you did.
Rode to glory.
I did what I did.
Wound up at Fort Apache.
- Well, you've wound up here too.
- Oh, by thunder.
I've not wound up. Not by a jugful.
They've pushed me aside,
sent me up to this tenpenny post.
But they'll not keep me buried.
I'll find something.
This isn't a country for glory,
Owen.
I'll take my risks. I always have.
Well, then all I can do is
wish you good luck.
And I wish you that sincerely.
Thank you, Sam.
Will you have a drink?
No, thanks, Owen.
It's a little early in the day.
Even for me.
Anything new about my transfer?
- Sorry, sir, nothing yet.
- Thank you.
- O'Rourke.
O'ROURKE: Yes, sir?
I require a mount. Have two or three
brought over for my selection.
- Yes, sir.
THURSDAY: O'Rourke.
Sir?
This Lieutenant O'Rourke,
are you, by chance, related?
Not by chance, sir. By blood.
He's my son.
I see.
How did he happen
to get into West Point?
It happened by presidential
appointment, sir.
Are you a former officer, O'Rourke?
During the war, I was a major
in the 69th New York Regiment.
The Irish Brigade, sir.
Still, it's been my impression that
presidential appointments...
...were restricted to sons
of holders of the Medal of Honor.
That is my impression too, sir.
Will that be all, sir?
Yes, sergeant. It will.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, ma'am.
Excuse me. Could you tell me
where Mrs. Collingwood lives?
- Oh, right in there, dear.
- Thank you.
- Good morning.
- Philadelphia. Philly.
I was just...
I know it's terribly early to call, but...
Nonsense. Come in, dear.
I'm so glad to see you.
I was just passing and...
My, what a beautiful sideboard.
And those candlesticks.
They were my Aunt Martha's.
I was her favorite niece,
so when she died...
...she left her fortune
to a home for stray cats...
...and the candlesticks to me.
They're lovely.
Everything is.
But our place, it's so bare and so dirty.
- Oh, you poor child.
- And there's no water.
- Mrs. Collingwood...
- "Aunt Emily."
Aunt Emily, what does a woman
do in the Army?
Our things haven't...
We haven't even got a coffeepot.
- Do I get someone to help me or...?
- Owen. Owen Thursday. That man.
Now, don't you fret, dear.
In times of trouble,
we call on Mrs. O'Rourke.
- Mrs. O'Rourke?
- Mrs. O'Rourke.
Martha, where's Mrs. O'Rourke?
SOLDIERS: Mrs. O'Rourke!
MRS. O'ROURKE: Oh, yes, what is it?
- Mrs. O'Rourke.
- Oh, yes, Mrs. Collingwood?
Yes, Mrs. Collingwood? Yes?
Mary, this is Colonel Thursday's
daughter...
...and this is Mrs. O'Rourke,
the wife of our sergeant major...
...and the mother
of a very fine young officer.
How do you do, Mrs. O'Rourke?
Sam told me about Michael's arrival.
How happy you must be.
Oh, I am.
- How does he look?
- Oh, he looks wonderful.
I mean, he makes a very fine officer.
Mary, this poor child has to set up house
in that bare barn.
Don't you worry,
I'll tend to everything.
Well, he is nice.
MICKEY:
Order. And one, two, three.
All right, now let's try it together.
Carry arm. One, two, three.
Put that piece on the ground.
Pick it up!
Put that piece down, soldier.
Captain, when you say "carry arm,"
you mean to carry this little gun?
MICKEY: Get back in line!
- Yes, sir. I was only asking.
MICKEY: Shut up and put your hat on!
- Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, soldier.
I was only trying to tell you.
(SIGHS)
- How's the boy doing, Festus?
- Oh, he's doing fine, Michael.
But nevertheless,
he's an officer and a gentleman.
And that's no job for a gentleman.
Well, then...
Come on.
Would Lieutenant O'Rourke
please step over to the stable, sir?
But these men, they're pretty rough.
Ah, but the sergeants... The sergeants
can take over the drill, sir.
Very well.
- Sergeants, continue with the drill.
MULCAHY: Yes, sir.
Now, the first thing to do after becoming
a soldier is to look like a soldier.
To look like a soldier,
you got to stand like a soldier.
Suck in that belly.
Get that hand out of your pocket.
Straighten up those legs.
Pull those feet out. Get that chin up.
Wait a minute, Daniel, darling.
Just one moment.
I'm gonna make this squad the finest party
of men in the American Army.
Get back in line there.
Hold your head up.
Head and eyes straight to the front.
Heels together and your toes apart.
At the approximate angle of 45 degrees.
I've never seen such a ragged line.
Just come out and look at yourselves.
- Get back there.
Now, is there any man here
from Tipperary?
Is there any man here from Cork?
Is there any man here
from County Sligo?
Yes, sir.
Now, we don't wanna show
any favoritism about this...
...but you're now an acting corporal.
Now, ahem, Sergeant Shattuck will take you
in the manual of arms.
That is, by numbers.
Meaning one, two...
Come on, get back in line there.
Get on your feet. Get in here.
Hello, son.
It's from your mother and myself.
Oh, gee, Dad, he's a beauty.
He's thoroughbred and Morgan.
Get on him, ride him.
MICKEY:
Come on.
Hey, Dad, he's a beauty.
He's a leaper, that one.
Go on, take him.
SHATTUCK:
...four. One, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
One, two.
(ALL SINGING)
There's Sergeant John McAfferty
And Corporal Donahue
They make us march up to the crack
In gallant Company Q
The drums they roll, upon my soul
For that's the way we go
Forty miles a day on beans and hay
In the Regular Army, oh
There's Sergeant John McAfferty
And Corporal Donahue
They make us march up to the crack
In gallant Company Q
The drums they roll, upon my soul
For that's the way we go
Forty miles a day on beans and hay
In the Regular Army, oh
- Those recruits, captain?
- Yes, sir. First day's drill.
They show promise.
A good officer, that O'Rourke.
West Point training, colonel.
(SPEAKS IN SPANISH)
Surprise.
Well, what do you think
of your new quarters?
Well, did you do all this yourself?
Naturally. Even moved the piano.
No. Mrs. Collingwood
and Mrs. O'Rourke helped me.
They were wonderful.
Mrs. Collingwood gave me
these things and the drapes...
...and Mrs. Grayson gave us
Great-Uncle Abraham.
He was a very famous man.
And Mrs. Tompkins gave us that chair,
and little Mrs. Bates gave us the stool.
Only it doesn't quite match the room.
And Francisco gave us Guadalupe.
How do you do?
She's our cook.
I'm proud of you.
Someday you're going to be
a proper soldier's wife.
(PHILADELPHIA CHUCKLES)
And Dr. Wilkens
wanted you to have this.
- It's a little rumpsprung...
- What?
But very comfortable.
And I helped with the dinner.
(BOTH LAUGH)
I'm sorry, I forgot to tell you.
It does that sometimes.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Good evening, sir.
I'm sorry to interrupt, but Fort Grant
is flashing a general alarm, sir.
Have any of our patrols reported,
Mr. Gates?
No, sir.
Keep the wire open to Fort Grant.
I'll return to the
headquarters immediately.
Yes, sir.
My cap and gloves.
What's your name?
Guadalupe.
But, Dad, dinner.
Don't wait for me. I may be hours.
There'll be other dinners, Phil.
Yes, Dad.
(SPEAKS IN SPANISH)
It's all right, Guadalupe.
We'll cook other dinners together.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- Phil.
ALL: Good evening, Miss Thursday.
- Having a party. I'm terribly sorr...
- No, you come right in, dear.
It's just a little welcome
for Lieutenant O'Rourke.
MICKEY:
Your servant, ma'am.
Couldn't have come at a better time,
could she?
- No one more welcome.
MICKEY: No, indeed.
Now, then, who shall get this prize?
Our host, of course.
I don't trust you, Sam Collingwood.
No, you shall sit here on my right,
next to Captain York.
Thank you.
So Lieutenant O'Rourke
can have a look at you.
- Well, I don't know whether that's fair.
- Why not?
- Because you'll have to look at him.
- Well, I hope she does.
- You don't drink wine, do you?
- No, thank you.
- Good girl, Philadelphia.
- Coffee, dear.
Were you born in Philadelphia?
No, Pomfret, Connecticut.
I was named after my mother.
Oh, she was born in Philadelphia?
No, Pawtucket, Rhode Island.
She was named after Grandmother.
Grandmother was the first
Philadelphia in our family.
Oh, then she was...?
PHILADELPHIA:
No, Provincetown, Massachusetts.
Ahem. Let's ta... Let's talk about horses.
Do you ride, Pawtu...? Po...? Phil?
- Yes, I do.
- Well, good.
We'll have to order some nice
young officer to take you riding.
Ahem. Emily.
- Shall we leave the men to their cigars?
- All right.
- Have a cigar, Kirby, and I'll join you.
- Sit down, dear.
I can't tell you how
wonderful it is to have
you here at the post, Mrs.
Collingwood.
Oh. Oh, I think you'll get along
even without me.
- Without?
- We're just marking time, you know.
Sam has applied for transfer
to West Point as instructor.
Oh, I didn't know.
When are you leaving, captain?
Leaving? Leaving for where?
I'm not going anywhere.
Leave my own party?
(LAUGHS)
Phil meant for the academy, Sam.
COLLINGWOOD:
Oh, that.
Soon, I hope.
Or they may reject me.
Oh, Sam. Sam, they couldn't.
They've had my application
a long time, dear.
You know how the Army is, Sam.
Yes, and I know its opinion of me.
And you know our opinion of you too.
Isn't that enough?
And you know what the men
think of you, sir.
Captain, lieutenant, my compliments.
♪ (SOFT ACCORDION MUSIC ♪
♪ PLAYING NEARBY) ♪
♪ (SINGING) ♪
♪ Well then, oh Genevieve ♪
♪ I'd give the world ♪
♪ To live again the lonely past ♪
♪ The rose of youth was dew-impearled ♪
♪ But now it withers in the blast ♪
♪ I see thy face in every dream ♪
♪ My waking thoughts are all of thee ♪
♪ Thy glance is in the starry beam ♪
♪ That falls along the summer sea ♪
♪ Oh Genevieve ♪
♪ Sweet Genevieve ♪
♪ The years may come ♪
♪ The years may go ♪
♪ But still the hand of memory weaves ♪
♪ The blissful dreams ♪
♪ Of long ago ♪
Bravo, Quincannon.
Thank you, Quincannon. Thank you.
One before each meal.
Sergeant, take him
back to the guardhouse.
(SINGING)
There was sergeant John McAfferty
And Corporal Donahue
DOCTOR:
This is against all tradition.
A man comes to serenade a lady,
and what does he find?
Her husband and half the regiment
on the balcony.
- I am crushed.
- You're a faintheart, doctor.
You only serenade
when husbands are around.
And for good reason, ma'am.
Seeing what a sorry
romantic figure I cut...
...the husband takes pity on me
and brings out his best port.
Oh, good evening, Captain Collingwood.
This is blackmail, but
you'll find the 18...
I know where it is.
Last time I looked,
there were four bottles of '46.
I expect to find my property intact.
COLLINGWOOD: The insolence of the man.
- One, two, three... It's all here.
You are an honorable man.
And since this is an occasion,
your glasses.
Come.
Let's drink a toast
to the young people.
Miss Thursday.
Mickey.
Then you will go riding
with me tomorrow?
Of course.
If you really want me to.
To the colonel's lady
and Mickey O'Rourke.
- Here's luck, huh?
- They'll need it, poor darlings.
Attention!
Men...
...today we gonna put you on the horses.
No more walking.
And by the time we get
through with youse...
...you'll be riding like senators,
the all of youse.
And your rough-riding sergeant
will be Sergeant Beaufort.
Relax!
Attention.
Gentlemen, this is a horse.
You will observe it has no saddle.
The reason it has no saddle...
...is because it will be easier for you
to stay on without the saddle.
Now, before we progress...
...did any of you gentlemen serve
with the Southern Arms...
...during the War Between the States?
Yes, sir. I had the pride, sir,
of serving with Bedford Forrest.
- I am proud to shake your hand.
- Thank you, sir.
I hope you have the pleasure
of buying me a drink on payday.
An honor, sir.
You are now an acting corporal.
- Sergeant...
- Please. Please, Sergeant Mulcahy.
MULCAHY:
Oh, let them have one.
And now, gentlemen,
this gallant soldier...
...this member of the greatest
cavalry force that ever lived...
...will show you Yankees how to ride.
(YELLING)
SERGEANTS:
Attention!
Now you see how easy it is, gentlemen.
Gentlemen, to your horses.
- Who will be the first volunteer?
- I am.
MULCAHY: Ah, come on. Get up here.
- Get him up here.
- A gentleman always remounts. Get up.
- That's it.
Come on, then!
(ALL CLAMORING)
That's it.
Stay on your horses, men.
And if you fall off, get on again.
It's an order in the Army,
and a custom...
...that when you fall off your horses,
you mount again like a gentleman.
SERGEANT 1:
Stay on that horse.
SERGEANT 2:
Get back on your horse.
Get back on that horse right now.
Get back on that horse.
SOLDIER: Hey, let go. Hey, get off of him.
Get him off.
SERGEANT 2:
Get back on that horse.
- Now, come on, get on that horse again.
SERGEANT 2: Get up there on that horse.
MULCAHY:
Hey, come back here!
Where do you think you're going?
Come back here with that horse.
- What's the matter with you?
SERGEANT 2: Get up there.
- Come on. Get off the horse.
- Stay on him there.
Watch it down there, boys.
Here! Here! Come back here!
- Come on. Get into it.
- There's a boy.
Hey.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Hey, get back up on that horse.
What's the matter?
Knees close together.
Everybody just get right where they...
- Hey, what are you doing?
SERGEANT 2: Get him up there. Come on.
Stay on that horse, will you?
Take the reins in both hands.
Press in tight with your knees.
Look at the legs on that one.
- One at a time on that horse.
- Hold him.
SERGEANT 1:
Watch out, everybody. Now listen to me.
SERGEANT 2:
Get that horse.
Sir, I beg to report I lost my Yankee cap.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
SERGEANT 2:
Hey, you, up there straight. Get up.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Isn't this wonderful?
What's that over there?
Blue Mesa.
Can't we go there?
Well, it's not as close as it appears,
Miss Thursday.
Are you anxious to return to the fort,
lieutenant?
Oh, no, Miss Thursday.
Don't you like the name of Phil, Michael?
Of course I do, Phil.
And right over there,
that's where the telegraph line is.
That's our main headache around here.
- Runs from here to Fort Grant.
- You mean, where the smoke is?
Smoke?
Is it an Indian signal?
No, it's not an Indian signal.
The line went dead, sir.
Right in the middle of the last word.
"Meacham reports Diablo's band
decamped from reservation.
Last seen headed S-O-U-T..."
South, obviously.
Or southeast or southwest.
Which means they may have crossed
10 miles from here or 200.
- We can't patrol all of it.
- I'm fully aware of that, captain.
Think they're headed for the border
to join Cochise?
That's my opinion, sir.
And these are the three
main passes to Mexico?
Well, there are others, but those
are the ones the Apache use most.
Two of them in our patrol area.
Captain York, you and Mr. O'Rourke
take a troop and patrol the area.
- Mr. O'Rourke is not on the post, sir.
- Why not?
- He's out riding, sir, with your daughter.
- He what?
- How long ago? When did they go out?
- Almost three hours past, sir.
- Three?
- Are you sure it's that long?
- Positive, sir.
- Blasted young fool.
O'Rourke, hasn't that idiot son of yours
sense to know this country's not safe?
Taking my daughter riding.
Your daughter is as safe with my son
as she would be with any man.
How safe is that
with the Apaches on the warpath?
MICKEY:
Phil, get back!
Collingwood, take out a patrol at once.
York, pass the word to A and B.
Tell them to turn to,
full field equipment.
Rations for a week.
MICKEY:
Wagon's burned. Two men dead.
Lieutenant Thursday.
Repair wagon, sir, burned.
Two troopers, Barry and Williams, dead.
Spread-eagle on the wheels, roasted.
- And my daughter saw all that?
- Yes, sir.
- I'll take your report inside, mister.
Are you all right, Phil?
Yes, Dad. I'm all right.
Take her inside, will you?
Must have jumped them at sundown.
It was a pretty big party.
Twenty-five or thirty, anyway.
Mescalero Apaches.
I found this.
- Blood.
- Apaches carry off their dead.
It's Mescaleros, all right. Diablo's band.
You say their trail led off to the south?
It headed that way, sir, but...
You didn't follow it
long enough to find out?
No, sir. I couldn't take that risk
with Miss Thursday, sir.
Your caution, Mr. O'Rourke,
is commendable...
...but somewhat belated.
My compliments
on the completeness of this report.
It speaks a knowledge
of the savage Indian...
...which I am sure you did not
acquire at the military academy.
I call it to your attention...
...that in taking my daughter riding
without bespeaking my permission...
...you have been guilty of behavior...
...more consistent with that
of an uncivilized Indian...
...than an officer and a gentleman.
If I have not made myself
sufficiently clear, mister...
...I will add this:
You will not again ride with my daughter.
And, for reasons which I feel it
unnecessary to go into...
...you will avoid her company
in the future.
But, colonel...
I speak to you not only
as your commanding officer...
...but as Philadelphia's father.
I think I am within a father's rights,
Captain York.
My daughter's life and safety
are precious to me.
And to me, sir, I assure you.
Then you will all the more readily
bow to my wishes.
Yes, sir.
Now, mister...
...you say the break was here?
- Yes, sir.
- Hmm. Excellent.
Send a wagon and a detail to repair
the wires and bring back the bodies.
Yes, sir. Sergeant major,
assemble a platoon from A Troop.
A platoon? I said a detail, captain.
An officer and four men.
But the Apaches may still be around.
I'm running a command,
not a debating society, York.
- Four men. I'll be in command...
- Mr. O'Rourke will be in command.
Mr. O'Rourke in command. Have them take
60 rounds of carbine ammunition per man.
That's a lot for men who've been
trained to shoot. Thirty will be ample.
Thirty will be ample.
And 18 per revolving pistol.
You'll call for volunteers.
With the colonel's
permission, I volunteer.
Permission refused.
Carry out your orders, sergeant major.
You'll leave within the quarter-hour,
Mr. O'Rourke. Questions?
Michael.
You know what's
expected of you now?
Sure, Dad, I know.
Derice, go get Quincannon
out of the guardhouse. Wait.
O'Feeney, go to the stables and find
Mulcahy, Shattuck and Johnny Reb.
Tell them they're volunteering
for a hazardous mission.
Beyond the call of duty.
Tell them their regiment is proud of them.
Now get going.
Come on, come on.
You spoke before of a platoon
from A Troop, Captain York.
I suggest you assemble it.
Light marching equipment,
but full bandoleers.
We'll leave in 30 minutes.
I'll command, you'll accompany.
- You mean we're gonna trail the wagon?
- At a striking distance.
Collingwood.
You remember the paper
that Captain Robert E. Lee wrote...
...when he was at the Point?
The one on the trap
as a military weapon?
I do not share the popular view
of Captain Lee's ability as tactician...
...but that paper impressed me.
Particularly the maneuver
that Genghis Khan employed...
...in the battle of Kinsha in 1221.
You recall...?
- Hadn't you better be moving, captain?
- Yes, sir.
What, no debate this time, captain?
No debate, sir. No questions.
Troop is ready, sir.
You're not properly uniformed, captain.
Nor are your men.
They look like scratch farmers
on market day.
Their hats should be creased
fore and aft like a fedora.
And I don't like exposed galluses.
Yes, sir.
THURSDAY:
Move out in a column of twos, captain.
YORK:
By twos! By the right flank!
Come on. Follow!
♪ (BUGLER TRUMPETING) ♪
Woman, go on about your business.
MULCAHY:
Whoa!
Uh-oh.
Get busy with the wire, sergeant.
All right, you men.
Get out those blankets.
- And work fast.
- Barry and Williams.
Many a pint I had with both of them.
- Why, you...
MICKEY: Sergeant!
(GUNSHOTS)
Johnny Reb, drop it.
Men, let's get out of here. Fast.
(GUNSHOT)
(ALL YELLING)
♪ (BUGLER TRUMPETING "CHARGE") ♪
(YELLING)
(DOGS BARKING)
- Bugler, raise those colors to full staff.
- Yes, sir.
THURSDAY:
Meacham.
This looks deserted.
He's here, all right. Meacham!
With the colonel's permission, sir.
The door is open, sir.
- Open the shutters. Get the stench out.
- Yes, sir.
Meacham.
- Well, Mr. York.
YORK: Let's go, Meacham.
PETE:
By your leave, sir.
Another exile in our wilderness.
Colonel Thursday,
our new commanding officer.
Your servant, Mr. Thursday.
- May the Lord...
- Colonel Thursday, Mr. Meacham.
Oh, bless you, I pay no attention
to military titles.
I don't believe in titles of any kind.
We're all his brothers, his children.
Even these savages entrusted to my care.
- I feed them and clothe them...
- And fill them full of rotgut whiskey.
I have a license.
Spirits have their uses.
This is not a healthy climate.
Perhaps the colonel would like a drink
after his ride.
No? Your health.
Mr. Meacham...
...a band of lndians
has left the reservation.
That's right. That Diablo and 30 others,
the ungrateful dogs.
I treat them well.
I have goods for them to buy.
- Knives, calico, wool...
- Cheap, shoddy trash.
No.
Mist... Colonel Thursday,
you know how children are.
They like their bright toys.
Winchester seven-shot repeaters
are not toys.
Captain York, I am attempting
to question Mr. Meacham.
Yes, sir.
(KNOCKS)
Right, sir.
There's no reason, to your knowledge...
...why a band of Apache should
go on the warpath?
Not the warpath.
Misguided maybe, like wayward children.
Mister, two of my troopers are dead.
Tortured to death.
Not by my Apaches.
Some other raiding party, perhaps.
How can you be sure?
We've taken Diablo and his band,
what's left of them.
- They'll be here soon.
- You'll keep them here.
You'll assign a troop
to keep them here.
That's what I've been telling Mr. York.
I leave it to you.
How can I, one lone man,
be responsible for all these savages?
Now you see what's happened.
Two of your men have been killed.
Brave men serving their country, as I am.
This wouldn't have happened
if the highhanded Mr. York...
- Oh, you mealy-mouthed...
- Captain York.
Mr. Meacham is a representative
of the United States government.
He will be treated with due respect.
- May I say something, sir?
- What is it?
No troop or squadron or regiment's gonna
keep the Apaches on this reservation...
...unless they wanna stay here.
Five years ago,
we made a treaty with Cochise.
He and his Chiricahuas
and some of the other Apache bands...
...came on the reservation.
They wanted to live here in peace,
and did for two years.
And then Meacham here was sent
by the Indian ring.
That's a lie. I'd been...
The dirtiest, most corrupt political group
in our history.
Then it began. Whiskey, but no beef.
Trinkets instead of blankets.
The women degraded, the children sickly,
and the men turning into drunken animals.
So Cochise did the only thing
a decent man could do.
He left. Took most of his people
and crossed the Rio Bravo into Mexico.
- He broke his treaty.
- Yes.
Rather than see his nation wiped out.
The law's the law, and I demand
that you soldier boys enforce it.
Any demands you wish to make...
...you will make through
official channels, Mr. Meacham.
Do not again employ that word
in my presence.
- No offense, sir. No offense.
SOLDIER: Ready, sir.
- Lead the way. Come along, sir.
- Where?
- To your storehouse.
- There's nothing in there.
Here, sir.
- Mister... Colonel Thursday, I protest.
YORK: Put it in writing.
- What's in these boxes?
- It's marked "Bibles," sir.
- That's all it is...
- Open them up.
What's this scale used for?
Weigh government beef rations.
Hmm. I seem to have gained 75 pounds
since I came to Arizona.
Bibles, sir.
Sergeant, pour me some scripture.
What's in this, brimstone and sulfur?
You know what it is.
I'm entitled to keep it.
Your license may permit you
to keep medicinal whiskey...
...but this is no whiskey.
You're not used to
frontier whiskey.
I don't know. I've
tasted most everything.
Sergeant, you a judge of whiskey?
Well, sir, some people say I am,
and some say I'm not, sir.
Tell me what you make of this.
Well...
...it's better than no whiskey at all, sir.
- Strike a match.
BEAUFORT: Yes, sir.
Since it doesn't appear to be whiskey...
...and since it seems to be of highly
inflammable and dangerous liquid...
...I find there's only one thing to do,
Mr. Meacham: destroy it.
MEACHAM: I protest. I'll write Washington.
I'll have you busted.
Mr. Meacham, you're a blackguard,
a liar, a hypocrite...
...and a stench in the nostrils
of honest men. If it were in my power...
...I'd hang you from the nearest tree,
leave your carcass for the buzzards.
But as you are a representative
of the United States government...
...I pledge you the protection
and cooperation of my command.
Good day, sir.
YORK:
What about these Winchesters, sir?
The pins are bent. Sergeant Mulcahy,
straighten them with this.
You heard what he said.
Destroy it.
"Destroy it," he says.
Well, boys...
...we've a man's work ahead of us
this day.
Unlock the door.
- Michael...
- Prisoners, outside.
Michael.
Private Mulcahy.
Private Shattuck.
Private Quincannon.
And Private Beaufort.
I'm ashamed of you, the whole of youse.
You're a disgrace to your regiment.
If there was a regulation for it,
I'd make you take the tippler's oath.
Michael.
Volunteers for the manure pile.
Left face.
Take them out of here.
GUARDS:
Hip! Hip! Hip! Hip! Hip!
Now all together, men.
♪ (SINGING) ♪
♪ There was Sergeant John McAfferty and ♪
- Oh, shut up!
- Shut up.
GUARDS:
Hip! Hip! Hip! Hip! Hip!
Assuming you found Cochise...
...would he listen to you,
would he believe you?
Cochise knows me, sir.
I've never lied to him.
And if you can assure him
decent treatment for his people...
I'll confess he interests me.
And these Eastern newspapers...
I hadn't realized Cochise
was so well-known.
Oh, he's known.
He's had the laugh on every troop
in the Southwest these three years.
Six campaigns, he's outgeneraled us,
outfought us, and outrun us.
That's just the point, sir.
There aren't enough troops in the whole
territory to make Cochise come back.
But one man, a man he trusts,
might persuade him.
A carbine against his spine
might be more persuasive.
Well, I'll go in unarmed, sir.
Can't fight my way in.
Either walk in or...
A man who brought Cochise back...
I'm for it, captain.
How many men will you need?
One, sir. Sergeant Beaufort.
- "Private Beaufort," sir.
THURSDAY: Why him?
He speaks Spanish, so does Cochise.
My Apache has its limits.
Shouldn't you take another officer
instead?
- Sergeant Beaufort was a...
- "Private Beaufort," sir.
Private Beaufort was a major
in the Confederate Army.
An aid to Jeb Stuart.
THURSDAY:
Hmm.
I remember Cadet Stuart.
- Quite.
- He was...
Were you saying something, captain?
I said, "Quite," sir.
I'd like to leave at once,
if the colonel has no questions.
- Hmm? What?
- Questions, sir?
No, no questions.
Proceed, captain. Take your ex-rebel.
- Thank you.
- That is all.
YORK: Ready, Sergeant Beaufort?
- Yes, sir.
- Anything is preferable to shoveling...
- That's what I thought.
Well, here we go.
BEAUFORT:
Private Mulcahy.
My compliments, sir.
Officer's pet.
Officer's pet, that's what he is.
How's your hangover?
(SPEAKS IN SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH) Sir, you're
the nicest Yankee I've ever known.
(SPEAKS IN SPANISH)
Ah.
Well, let's go.
(BREAKS)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Quincannon, if that's you,
you can wait till payday. I'm not gonna...
Oh. Having dinner?
Well, yes, I will have a cup of tea.
And if you urge me,
I may even take a piece of pie.
Good evening, lieutenant.
I haven't been seeing much of you lately.
Please don't stand.
- Phil... Miss Thursday, I...
- I had hoped you might call.
You did leave your card, didn't you?
This is your card, isn't it?
Isn't it proper,
Sergeant Major O'Rourke...
...for an officer to call
after he's left his card?
It would be, except that...
The colonel has forbidden me
to address you, Miss Thursday.
But you are addressing me,
aren't you, lieutenant?
And if a young man
hasn't enough gumption...
...to address a young woman who,
even if her father is a colonel, well...
...I don't think he's as brave
as I think he is.
- Do you, Mrs. O'Rourke?
- No, I don't.
Ma'am, your father is
Michael's commanding officer.
His orders will be obeyed.
Miss Thursday,
I'm afraid you'd best leave us.
Michael O'Rourke.
Sit down, dear.
And you sit down yourself.
And you, have you nothing to say?
Or have you learned your manners
from this big bull of a man?
There's much I'd say,
if I could get a word in edgewise.
Miss Thurs...
Miss Thursday...
...if I had any thought
that it really mattered
to you whether I spoke
to you or not...
But I couldn't believe you felt
the same way about me.
And what way was that, lieutenant?
Well, I...
Miss Thursday,
if you'll just step outside...
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH)
The colonel, he come.
He very angry.
He know she here.
Come, Philadelphia.
I'm here to bring you home.
I'm not ready to leave, Father.
I've been invited to dinner.
Won't you stay, colonel?
Thank you, Mrs. O'Rourke.
Another time, perhaps.
Well, at least allow me
to take your hat?
I beg your pardon. Come, Phil.
Colonel Thursday, sir, I would...
Mr. O'Rourke, I want no words
with you at this time.
- But, colonel, sir...
- You heard me, sir.
Now get out of here
before I say something I may regret.
This is my home, Colonel Owen Thursday.
And in my home I will say
who is to get out and who is to stay.
And I will remind the colonel
that his presence here, uninvited...
...is contrary to Army regulations...
...not to mention the code
of a well-mannered man.
Dad, please.
Colonel Thursday, sir,
what I've been trying to tell you, sir...
...is that I love your daughter.
And I ask her now,
in your presence, to be my wife.
Yes, Michael.
I see.
- Philadelphia, I ask you to reconsider.
- No, Father.
I tell you, this is not
a proper or suitable marriage for you.
I can't believe that.
Sergeant Major O'Rourke,
you will pardon me for speaking bluntly.
But as a noncommissioned officer,
you are aware of the barrier...
...between your class and mine.
O'ROURKE: I am, sir.
But Michael's an officer.
Not that it makes any difference.
It makes a difference in the Army, Phil.
The sergeant major knows that,
and his son should know it.
The Army, sir, is not the whole world.
No, but it's your world,
and your mother's world and my world.
I'm not as young as I once was.
With the colonel's permission...
- ...l'll put in for retirement.
- That won't be necessary, sergeant major.
Nor need you, mister,
give up your profession.
My daughter is not of legal age.
She cannot marry without my consent.
I'll be of age in two years.
Sergeant major, I beg your pardon for
entering your quarters without invitation.
Mr. O'Rourke, your pardon for my words.
Come, Phil.
I'm not a child, and I love Michael.
I'll arrange at once
for your return to the East.
You'll have two years
to forget each other.
(PHILADELPHIA SOBS)
Mrs. O'Rourke...
...my respects, ma'am.
- Ready?
- Ready.
(DOGS BARKING NEARBY)
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(BOTH SPEAK IN SPANISH)
Put the beer right back there on the table,
boys. One on each end.
Come on, step lively, step lively.
Krausmeyr, one sour note out of you
tonight and back you go shoeing horses.
The same goes for you, Derice.
(SNIFFS)
Now you've got your stripes back...
...I expect you to be on your best behavior
and set a good example for the men.
Oh, don't worry, Michael, my darling.
We'll be the models of decorum.
Now, where's the punch?
- Mulcahy, I...
- Michael.
Mulcahy, you'll not be spiking the
refreshments this year like you did last.
Oh, just one bottle.
- No, sir...
- Michael.
Ah, go on, the whole of youse.
- Good evening, O'Rourke.
- Good evening, doctor.
And Mrs. O'Rourke.
- It's a fine night for a dance. Clear and dry.
- Yes, sir.
- Which reminds me...
- Right over there, sir.
(CHUCKLES)
- Good evening, O'Rourke.
- Good evening, sir.
- And Mrs. O'Rourke.
- Good evening.
Oh, sergeant major, you have no idea how
I've been looking forward to tonight.
I'm forever telling the captain...
...that it's the noncommissioned officers'
dance that is the nicest dance.
Don't you think so, Mrs. O'Rourke?
- Well, of course I do.
- And, sergeant major...
- ...will you please claim me for a dance?
- With the greatest of pleasure, ma'am.
- Uh, by the way, I...
- Right over there, sir.
Thank you, Krausmeyr.
Again, on behalf of the officers
of Fort Apache...
...I wish to thank the noncommissioned
officers and their ladies...
...for this grand party.
The food is exquisite.
And the punch, wow.
Good evening, Krausmeyr.
And so, as is customary at Fort Apache...
...the commanding officer,
Colonel Owen Thursday...
...will lead out the wife
of our sergeant major...
...the charming Mrs. Michael O'Rourke.
With your permission...
Mrs. O'Rourke, may I have the honor?
It will be a pleasure, Colonel Thursday.
And now, Sergeant Major O'Rourke
will lead out the colonel's lady...
...in this case, his lovely daughter,
Miss Philadelphia Thursday.
And now, ladies and gentlemen...
...quickly take your partners
for the grand march.
(CHATTERING)
- My pleasure, miss.
- Thank you.
Get out of my way, Meacham,
or I'll break both your legs.
Of course, with your permission.
♪ (PLAYING CHEERFUL MUSIC) ♪
BEAUFORT: Walk him around,
then rub him down, will you, son?
O'ROURKE:
Captain York.
Sir.
(MURMURING)
THURSDAY: Well?
- Cochise has crossed the river, sir.
He's coming in with all his people,
wants to talk peace.
- He's returned to American soil?
- Yes, sir.
Now, with the colonel's permission...
...I'd like to shake some of this Mexican
adobe dust and get back to the dance.
There'll be no time for that.
The regiment moves out at dawn.
The regiment?
Cochise says he'll meet with you
and me and Meacham.
We'll take a small detail and go unarmed.
I've arranged a rendezvous
this side of the Dragoons.
Sergeant major, you'll stop the dance.
Pass the word to the first sergeants,
prepare their troops to march at dawn.
Troop commanders will meet
at headquarters at once.
Colonel, if you send out the regiment,
Cochise will think I've tricked him.
Exactly. We have tricked him.
Tricked him into returning to American
soil. I intend to see that he stays here.
Colonel Thursday,
I gave my word to Cochise.
No man is gonna
make a liar out of me, sir.
Your word to a breechclouted savage?
An illiterate, uncivilized murderer
and treaty-breaker?
There's no question of honor, sir,
between an American officer and Cochise.
There is to me, sir.
Captain York...
...you may have commanded
your own regiment in the late war...
...but so long as you command a troop
in mine, you will obey my orders.
You have your instructions,
sergeant major.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...officers and noncommissioned officers,
your attention, please.
By order of the commanding officer...
...this night's entertainment will conclude
with the playing of the next dance.
After the dance, all first sergeants...
...quartermasters, saddler sergeants,
farriers, cooks and bakers...
...report to me at headquarters.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...the noncommissioned officers
of Fort Apache...
...offer their deep regrets.
And on their behalf, I wish to thank you
for attending this dance.
Krausmeyr, if you please.
♪ (BAND PLAYING ELEGANT MUSIC) ♪
(BEAUFORT YELLS)
Is it to your taste, Johnny, darling?
♪ (TRUMPETING) ♪
Column of fours.
- First troop, fours left.
SOLDIER: Fours left.
BEAUFORT:
Fours left.
Ho!
(ALL SINGING)
I'm lonesome since I crossed the hill
And over the moor and valley
Such heavy thoughts my heart do fill
Since parting with my Sally
I seek no more the fine and gay
For each does but remind me
How swift the hours did pass away
With the girl I've left behind me
I seek no more the fine and gay
For each does but remind me
How swift the hours did pass away
With the girl I've left behind me
Mrs. Collingwood. Excuse me, ma'am.
It's Captain Collingwood's transfer, ma'am.
It just came through.
Oh, run. Run or send someone after.
Call him back.
Yes, Aunt Emily.
- I don't know.
- What is there to know? Go get him.
Sam's no coward. He never was.
Who's talking about cowardice?
Don't be a fool, woman.
Tom, get mounted.
Go bring Captain Collingwood back.
No.
- Keep this for the captain's return.
- Yes, ma'am.
I can't see him.
All I can see is the flags.
SOLDIER:
Squadron, halt!
(WHISTLING)
It's the encampment, sir.
Must be about a mile up.
Three hundred wickiups or more.
Very good.
Bugler, my compliments
to Captain York.
- Have him report to me.
BUGLER: Yes, sir.
Yes?
Is that approximately where you were
to meet Cochise, captain?
Just about.
My officers will address me as "sir,"
Captain York.
Yes, sir. Will that be all, sir?
It will not.
I propose to deploy the men,
two troops to the north, one to the east.
- We will then converge on the encampment.
- I wouldn't do that, sir.
I'm not asking your advice, captain.
I'm merely stating.
The Apache, sir,
are neither to the north nor the east.
Nor are they in their encampment.
But if you'd have been watching the
dust swirls to the south like most of us...
...you'd see that they're right there.
That's Alchesay.
They outnumber us four to one.
Do we talk or fight?
You seem easily impressed
by numbers, captain.
However,
I'll honor your word to Cochise.
Tell him we've come to talk.
YORK:
Ride on!
♪ (TRUMPETING) ♪
(BOTH SPEAK IN SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH)
Gentlemen, I have the honor...
...to present the great hereditary war
chief of the Apache nation, Cochise.
Get on with it, captain.
Take over, Beaufort.
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
Good afternoon.
(IN ENGLISH) Gentlemen, this is Alchesay,
head of the White Mountain Apaches...
...Satanta of the Mescaleros...
...and the Chiricahua
medicine man...
...named Jerome in our language,
but in Spanish, Geronimo.
Well, time to get on with it, Beaufort.
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
THURSDAY: What's he saying?
- That the Apaches are a great race, sir.
They've never been conquered.
But it is not well for a nation
to be always at war.
The young men die.
The women sing sad songs.
And the old ones are hungry
in the winter.
And so I led my people from the hills.
And then came this man.
THURSDAY: What did he say?
- Well, sir...
...a free translation would be that
Meacham's a yellow-bellied polecat...
...of dubious antecedents
and conjectural progeny.
Cochise's words,
of course, sir, not mine.
That's a matter of opinion.
He is worse than war.
He not only killed the men...
...but the women...
...and the children...
...and the old ones.
We looked to the great white father
for protection.
He gave us slow death.
We will not return
to your reservation...
...while that man is there...
...or anyone like him.
Send him away
and we will speak of peace.
If you do not send him away...
...there will be war.
And for each one of us
that you kill...
- ...10 white men will die.
- Are you threatening us?
- Don't interrupt. It's an insult.
- I'll not be threatened. Beaufort.
No preliminary nonsense with him,
no ceremonial phrasing.
Straight from the shoulders.
Do you hear me?
They're recalcitrant swine.
They must feel it.
He's only speaking the truth, sir.
Is there anyone in this regiment
that understands an order?
- What does the colonel wish me to say?
- Tell him I find him without honor.
Tell him they're not talking to me
but to the United States government.
Tell him that government orders them
to return to their reservation.
And tell him if they've not started
by dawn, we will attack. Tell him that.
(YELLING)
Bugler...
...sound forward.
♪ (TRUMPETING) ♪
Forward.
Forward. Ho!
SOLDIER:
Forward, ho!
I don't see them. Not a one.
Well, they're down there, sir,
among the rocks.
- Have you seen them, captain?
- I don't have to. I know.
- How?
- Because if I were Cochise...
...that's where I'd take up position.
And that dust cloud beyond?
It's an Apache trick. Probably squaws
and children dragging mesquite.
Very ingenious, captain.
You make me suspect your Cochise
has studied under Alexander the Great...
...or Bonaparte, at the least.
March your troops.
We'll charge in a column of fours.
Mounted in fours?
That's suicide, colonel.
- I tell you, they're down there.
- York!
Captain York, you're relieved
of command of your troop.
There is no room in this regiment
for a coward.
At your service, sir.
- Bugler, pick up Captain York's gauntlet.
- Yes, sir.
I'm no duelist, captain.
I will decide whether I will answer you
with pistols or a general court-martial.
You will remain on the ridge, in safety,
with the supply train.
Take O'Rourke with you.
Gentlemen, you have your orders.
Are there any other questions?
Captain Collingwood?
No questions, Owen.
THURSDAY:
Gentlemen, join your troops.
A charge. Mounted in fours.
- They're madmen.
- And I'm to stay with the wagon train.
And take O'Rourke with me.
You'll find Lieutenant O'Rourke
with his troops, sir.
And thank you.
Good luck.
- Good luck, men.
ALL: Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant O'Rourke, follow me.
- But the troops, sir...
- Don't argue.
- Mulcahy, take over.
- Captain York...
Get out of here, you scut, or I'll put you
across my knee and belt the pants off you.
Get out now.
(SOLDIERS CHEER)
As you were, men.
Good luck be to you.
(ALL CHEER)
YORK:
Wheel the wagons.
Get them on the ridge.
(SOLDIERS YELLING)
YORK: Come on, get the horses
up behind there.
MICKEY:
Come on. Get them over there.
YORK:
Get those teams off.
All right, break out
the picks and shovels.
MICKEY:
Come on. Get them over there.
SOLDIER: Come on.
YORK: Get them unhooked.
♪ (BUGLER TRUMPETING "CHARGE") ♪
(YELLING)
(GUNSHOT)
(ALL YELLING)
Carry on, boy.
What are you doing, man?
YORK: All right, get them over.
SOLDIER: Come on. Get it over. Let's go.
- Get her over.
All right, come on. Lean it over.
Lean it over there. Let's go.
Turn it over.
YORK:
Mickey.
SOLDIER 1:
Lean it over. Let's go.
SOLDIER 2:
Turn it over.
Get to Fort Grant.
Tell them where we are.
Tell them we may still be alive
if they hurry. Move.
And marry that girl!
Trooper.
Stand by your guns, men.
Stand by your guns.
Flarety, you're in charge.
I'll be back.
We've dug in on the ridge, sir.
Plenty of water and ammunition.
I sent a courier to Fort Grant,
if we can only hold out.
Here, get on my horse.
THURSDAY:
I'll trouble you for your saber, captain.
My saber?
I must rejoin my command.
The command is wiped out, sir,
and there's nothing we can do about it.
I'm not asking your opinion,
Captain York.
When you command this regiment,
and you probably will, command it.
Your saber, sir.
Any questions, captain?
No questions.
(GUNFIRE)
(COUGHS)
COLLINGWOOD:
This time, you were late, Owen.
You have my apologies.
Sergeant Major O'Rourke,
my apologies, sir.
You can save them, sir,
for our grandchildren.
(HORSES APPROACHING)
(APACHES YELLING)
Hold your fire, men.
Hold your fire.
(COCHISE SHOUTS)
(HOOF BEATS)
However, gentlemen, I warn you,
this may be a long campaign.
It may be weeks before you have
any headlines for your newspapers.
If we catch Geronimo,
that will be headline enough.
And more glory for your regiment.
REPORTER:
He must have been a great man.
And a great soldier.
No man died more gallantly...
...nor won more honor for his regiment.
Of course, you're familiar with the famous
painting of Thursday's charge, sir.
Yes, I saw it when last in Washington.
That was a magnificent work.
There were massed columns of Apaches
in their war paint and feather bonnets...
...and here was Thursday,
leading his men in that heroic charge.
Correct in every detail.
He's become almost a legend already.
He's the hero
of every schoolboy in America.
But what of the men
who died with him?
- Uh, what of Collingworth and...?
- Collingwood.
Oh, of course, Collingwood.
That's the ironic part of it.
We always remember the Thursdays,
but the others are forgotten.
You're wrong there.
They aren't forgotten
because they haven't died.
They're living. Right out there.
Collingwood and the rest.
And they'll keep on living
as long as the regiment lives.
Pay is $13 a month.
Their diet, beans and hay.
Maybe horsemeat
before this campaign is over.
Fight over cards or rotgut whiskey,
but share the last drop in their canteens.
Faces may change...
...and names...
...but they're there.
They're the regiment.
The regular Army.
Now and 50 years from now.
They're better men
than they used to be.
Thursday did that.
He made it a command
to be proud of.
- The command is formed, sir.
- Thank you, sergeant major.
And now it's time to move.
- Questions, gentlemen?
REPORTER 2: No.
REPORTER 3:
Thank you very much, colonel.
Gentlemen, this is my adjutant,
Lieutenant O'Rourke...
- ...who will take care of you.
- Gentlemen.
Mrs. Michael O'Rourke,
General Thursday's daughter.
- How do you do?
- And the Mrs. O'Rourke.
It's a pleasure, ma'am.
And this is
Michael Thursday York O'Rourke...
...the best man in the regiment.
Aren't you, you scut?
YORK:
Forward face.
Ho!
♪ (ALL SINGING) ♪
♪ I'm lonesome since I crossed the hill ♪
♪ And over the moor and valley ♪
♪ Such heavy thoughts my heart do fill ♪
♪ Since parting with my Sally ♪
♪ I seek no more the fine and gay ♪
♪ For each does but remind me ♪
♪ How swift the hours did pass away ♪
♪ With the girl I've left behind me ♪