[helicopter blades thrumming]
[truck horn honking]
[dogs barking]
[all singing in Spanish]
[men hooting]
- AH!
[children screaming]
[laughter]
- [speaking Spanish]
- [laughs]
- HEY.
- HEY, HEY.
- MAMA...
[grunts]
[laughter]
- [praying in Spanish]
[engine starting]
[children yelling]
- [speaking Spanish]
- [grunts]
[sighs]
YOU GOIN' FOR A RIDE?
- LOOKS THAT WAY.
- WANT SOME COMPANY?
- YOUR KNEE'S NOT RIGHT.
- THEN I'LL TAKE THE QUAD.
- THAT THING SPOOKS SHADOW.
YOU KNOW THAT.
THOSE STALLS STILL NEED
TO BE CLEANED OUT.
UNLESS YOU WANT TO PAY
SOMEBODY ELSE TO DO IT?
- NO. I'LL DO IT.
WHICH TRAIL ARE YOU TAKING?
- THE WASH.
- WHY DO YOU ALWAYS
GOT TO RIDE THE DAMN WASH?
- 'CAUSE IT'S THE BEST TRAIL.
- YEAH, IT IS.
THAT'S WHY WE CAN'T KEEP
THE DAMN MEXICANS OUT OF IT.
- IF I SEE ANY "DAMN MEXICANS,"
I'LL TELL 'EM HELLO FROM YOU.
- [sighs]
DID YOU BRING A WALKIE-TALKIE
WITH YOU?
- YUP!
DON'T LEAVE THAT COFFEE CUP
OUT THERE.
[gunfire and explosions
in video game]
- SHIT, DUDE!
WHAT THE HELL?
- WE'RE GOING SHOOTING TODAY.
- SO GO.
- COME WITH US, ASS HAT.
- I DON'T FEEL LIKE SHOOTING
CACTUS WITH YOU TWO
FAGGOTS TODAY.
- WE'RE NOT SHOOTIN'
CACTUS TODAY.
- COME ON.
- AH! YOU DICK!
[engine starting]
- [speaking Spanish]
[panting]
[speaking Spanish]
- [scoffs]
- [coughs]
[coughs]
[speaking Spanish]
[cursing in Spanish]
- THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. VERY.
- YOU'RE VERY WELCOME.
- THE NA--THE NAME?
- DO YOU SPEAK ENGLISH?
[laughs]
HIS NAME IS SHADOW.
- SHADOW.
- IT'S OKAY.
- SI, SI, WORK.
- OH.
- SI.
- [chuckles]
- YES, PLEASE.
GRACIAS, GRACIAS.
- SORRY.
- OKAY.
- GOOD DAY!
- GOOD DAY.
[chuckles]
- [grunts]
NO SHIT.
YOU GUYS!
YOU GUYS, COME HERE!
QUICK!
THERE'S SOME MEXICANS
RIGHT THERE IN THE WASH.
- WHERE?
- RIGHT THERE BY THAT TREE
RIGHT THERE.
- I DON'T SEE 'EM.
- USE YOUR SCOPE, DUDE.
- OKAY, YEAH, I GOT 'EM.
- YEAH, THOSE GUYS
ARE DEFINITELY ILLEGAL.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW FOR SURE?
- [chuckles]
DUH, SEAN.
YOU THINK THEY'RE HERE
JUST OUT FOR A STROLL?
- HAND ME THE 06.
- NO, DUDE, YOU CANT JUST START
SHOOTING AT THOSE GUYS.
- I SO KNEW YOU TWO FAGS
WOULD PUSS OUT ON ME!
LOOK, I TOLD YOU,
WE'RE ONLY GONNA SCARE THEM.
YOU DON'T SHOOT AT THEM.
YOU SHOOT NEAR THEM.
NOW, GIVE ME THE GUN.
- SCREW YOU.
- FINE.
[groans]
I'LL USE THIS OLD
PIECE OF SHIT.
SURE I DON'T MISS
AND HIT ONE OF 'EM.
- [sighs]
YOU'RE SUCH A DICK.
JUST MAKE SURE YOU AIM
WAY FAR AWAY FROM THEM.
- YEAH, NO SHIT, BOZO.
- I'M JUST GONNA SCARE 'EM...
BACK ACROSS THE LINE.
- [panting]
- [hisses, grunts]
OH!
- BRAD, WHAT THE HELL?
THAT LAST SHOT
WAS WAY TOO CLOSE!
- I DIDN'T HIT HIM, SEAN!
BESIDES,
THE POINT IS TO GET CLOSE
SO IT SCARES
THE SHIT OUT OF THEM.
- BRAD, CHECK IT OUT.
SEE THAT BIG OL' JUG OF WATER?
- YEAH. I GOT IT.
- YOU HIT THAT THING,
IT'LL SCARE THE HELL OF OUT 'EM.
PLUS, THEY WON'T HAVE ANY WATER,
RIGHT?
THEN THEY'LL TOTALLY
HAVE TO RUN THEIR SORRY ASS
BACK ACROSS THE LINE.
- GENIUS.
HEY, HAND ME SOME MORE
06 SHELLS, DUDE.
- LET ME TAKE A LOOK
AT THIS SHIT.
ARE YOU FREAKING CRAZY?
THE THING'S, LIKE,
RIGHT NEXT TO THEM.
YOU COULD TOTALLY
SCREW THAT SHOT UP!
WE'RE NOT USING MY DAD'S RIFLE
TO SHOOT THAT CLOSE
TO THOSE GUYS.
- OH, HEY, HEY, HEY.
IT'S COOL, IT'S COOL, IT'S COOL.
LOOK, WHY DON'T YOU
SHOW KEV AND I
WHAT A SAFE DISTANCE IS
TO BE SHOT AT?
IT'S A KILLER SCOPE
ON THAT THING.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA HIT 'EM.
- GO FOR IT, SEAN-O.
YOU COULD SHOOT THE TITS
OFF A FLY.
- [speaking Spanish]
[horse whinnies]
- OH!
[grunts]
- NO!
- OH, SHIT.
OH, SHIT. OH, SHI--
- SEAN, YOU JUST
TOOK OUT THAT LADY, MAN!
- OH, SHIT.
OH, SHIT! OH, SHIT!
- WHAT THE HELL
DID YOU SHOOT HER FOR, DUDE?
- I DIDN'T SHOOT HER,
ASSHOLE!
SHE CAME OVER THE WASH!
I WAS TRYING TO MISS
THE FUCKING MEXICAN!
- [groaning]
- [panting]
- OH, GOD.
- SHE'S MOVING.
SHE'S MOVING, DUDE.
LOOK, LOOK.
- YOU SWEAR TO GOD?
- I SWEAR TO GOD. JUST LOOK.
- [panting]
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
- WE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
- WHAT?
WE CAN'T JUST LEAVE HER THERE!
- YOU WANT TO GO
DOWN THERE, SEAN?
WHEN WE GET BACK,
WE'LL CALL 911
FROM A PAYPHONE OR SOMETHING.
BESIDES, THE MEXICAN GUY
WAS HELPING HER!
- [panting]
[whispers]
OH, F--
- [groaning]
- OH, WHAT HAPPENED?
- UH...
- WHERE'S ROY? ROY!
- MY HORSE?
- GET MY HORSE.
- JOSE!
- MY HORSE. MY HORSE.
- I-I-I GET HORSE.
- GET MY HORSE.
[groans]
SHADOW?
OH. SHADOW.
[groaning]
- I HAVE HORSE.
- ALL RIGHT.
[engine approaching]
- HEY.
HEY!
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
- ROY.
[groans]
- LIVY.
- IT'S ALL RIGHT.
- [sighs]
- WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
MY DAD'S GONNA KILL ME!
- DUDE, YOUR DAD'S NEVER GONNA
FIND OUT UNLESS YOU FREAK OUT.
- SHE LOOKED PRETTY BAD
TO ME, DUDE. MAYBE HE HIT HER.
- I DIDN'T HIT HER, YOU DICK!
I WAS AIMING AT THE GROUND!
- SHUT UP, KEVIN!
LOOK, WE GOT TO SWEAR
NOT TO TELL ANYBODY
ABOUT THIS EVER. NOBODY!
BECAUSE IF ANYONE FINDS OUT,
WE'RE ALL SCREWED!
- I'M NOT.
I DIDN'T EVEN SHOOT AT ALL!
- IT DOESN'T MATTER,
DUMBASS.
YOU'RE AN ACCESSORY
TO THE CRIME.
- SEAN'S THE ONE
WHO SHOT HER.
both: SHUT UP!
- [panting]
- AMIGOS!
- OKAY.
- WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO ASK YOU
SOME MORE QUESTIONS.
LATER.
TOMORROW, I MEAN.
OKAY, I'LL DRIVE YOU
BACK TO THE HOUSE.
- NO, NO, I GOT TO
PUT UP LIVY'S HORSE.
- ROY, WE CAN GET THE HORSE
BACK TO THE BARN.
[car engine starting]
- NOPE.
- UNCLE ROY?
[sobs]
- REALLY SORRY, ROY.
ROY, THE SHERIFF MENTIONED
THEY'D BE COMING BY HERE
TOMORROW MORNING, AND, UH,
KAYE AND I THOUGHT
WE'D STAY OUT HERE
WITH YOU TONIGHT.
IF THAT SUITS YOU.
[voices on TV]
- MOM! I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DO THIS ONE.
- CARRY THE 1.
YOU GOT IT.
[doorbell ringing]
DAVE,
SOMEONE'S AT THE DOOR!
[doorbell ringing]
DAVE?
- I'LL GET IT!
- CARLY?
CARLY.
CAN I HELP YOU?
DAVE?
- HEY!
- OH!
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
CARLY, COME HERE.
IT'S OKAY, HONEY.
COME HERE. COME HERE.
- ORALE.
- [speaking Spanish]
[engine starting]
[tires screeching]
- [speaking Spanish]
[car horn honking] approaching]
MIGUEL!
[laughs]
- [murmurs]
[hip-hop music playing]
[music muffled]
-  SHIRK SOME WORK
LET ME GET
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SMIRK
WHEN WE TOGETHER
WE THE LIFE OF THE PARTY
BABY
- ROLL THE WINDOW DOWN
PLEASE, SIR.
ROLL THE WINDOW DOWN
HOW YOU DOIN'?
SIR, CAN YOU TURN
THAT RADIO DOWN, PLEASE?
TURN THE MUSIC DOWN
PLEASE, SIR.
[music off]
COULD I PLEASE SEE
YOUR LICENSE,
REGISTRATION,
AND PROOF OF INSURANCE?
SIR, I NEED YOU TO TAKE
YOUR LICENSE OUT OF THE WALLET.
YEAH. TAKE THE LICENSE
OUT OF THE WALLET, PLEASE.
YEAH, TAKE IT OUT.
I'M GONNA NEED YOUR REGISTRATION
AND PROOF OF INSURANCE TOO,
MISTER..."HENRY."
풥ABLA INGLES?
- [news reporter] THE WIFE
OF FORMER MEDIO COUNTY SHERIFF
ROY MCNARY WAS KILLED
IN AN ATTACK
THAT MAY HAVE BEEN AN ATTEMPT
TO STEAL HER HORSE.
THE SHERIFF'S OFFICE IS LOOKING
FOR A MAN OF MEXICAN DECENT,
PRESUMED TO BE UNDOCUMENTED,
WHO WAS SEEN FLEEING THE SCENE.
WE WILL REPORT FURTHER DETAILS
AS THEY UNFOLD.
ANYONE WITH INFORMATION
REGARDING THE TRAGEDY,
PLEASE CONTACT THE MEDIO COUNTY
SHERIFF'S OFFICE.
- HEY, FLORA--
- WE WERE WATCHING THAT.
- YEAH, SEE,
JUST MOVE THE MOUSE,
AND YOU PUT THE LITTLE ARROW
OVER THE PICTURE.
YOU CAN CLICK ON THAT.
SCROLL IT DOWN.
- I KNOW HOW
TO USE A COMPUTER, RANDALL.
- YEAH, OF COURSE YOU DO.
I MEAN, IT'S THE SAME OLD THING
WE HAD WHEN YOU WERE ON THE JOB.
OKAY, WELL,
YOU LET ME KNOW HOW IT GOES.
[school bell ringing]
[laughter]
- GOOD MORNING.
I'M GOING TO BE
TEACHING THE CLASS TODAY.
MRS. EDWARDS HAS HAD
A FAMILY EMERGENCY.
- HEY, DID YOU HEAR
WHAT HAPPENED?
SOME ILLEGALS
KILLED MRS. MCNARY.
- MRS. MCNARY?
- SHE WAS RIDING ON HER RANCH,
AND THEY WERE TRYING
TO STEAL HER HORSE,
AND THEY KILLED HER.
- YOUNG LADY IN THE FRONT,
PLEASE TURN AROUND.
- I HAVE TO USE THE BATHROOM.
[retches]
[rifle shot echoes]
- SI.
- SAYS HE'S SURE.
- ROY'S HERE.
- HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
COME ON, NOW.
COME ON, BACK OFF.
- THAT'S NOT THE GUY I SAW.
[sighs]
- YOU'RE SURE?
- YEAH, I'M SURE.
- WELL, THEN,
THERE MAY HAVE BEEN TWO.
- WHY DO YOU SAY THAT?
- WELL, WE PICKED HIM UP
IN A STOLEN TRUCK, AND...
ONE OF THE THINGS WE FOUND
IN THE TRUCK WAS THIS.
YOU RECOGNIZE THIS?
- YEAH.
- SOON AS WE TOLD HIM
WHAT HAPPENED,
HE STARTED TALKIN'
PRETTY FAST.
HE TOLD US THAT HE
AND ANOTHER GUY
THAT HE WAS TRAVELING WITH
MET UP WITH A WOMAN ON A HORSE,
AND SHE GAVE HIM
THAT BLANKET.
HE SAYS THAT SOMEBODY
WAS SHOOTING AT HIM,
AND THE LADY FELL
OFF HER HORSE AND HIT HER HEAD.
- THAT'S A BUNCH OF BULLSHIT.
- I KNOW, I'M JUST TELLING YOU
WHAT THE MAN SAID,
KEEPING YOU IN THE LOOP
LIKE I PROMISED.
- I SHOULD HAVE SHOT
THAT SON OF A BITCH
WHEN I HAD THE CHANCE.
- I SAW THAT YOU HAD A FIREARM
ON YOU WHEN WE GOT THERE.
WERE YOU SHOOTIN' AT 'EM, ROY?
- NO.
- YOU SURE?
- YEAH, I'M SURE.
THERE WERE SHOTS.
- THERE WERE SHOTS?
- YEAH, THEY WERE RIFLE SHOTS.
THAT'S WHY I WENT OUT THERE
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
- WELL, WHY THE HELL DIDN'T YOU
TELL ME THAT BEFORE?
THAT'S PRETTY DAMNED
IMPORTANT.
- I DON'T KNOW, I--
HELL, RANDALL,
I MEAN, WE WAS--
- ALL RIGHT, SOMETHIN' ELSE.
NOW, OUR MAN IN THERE
I.D.'D THE SAME GUY YOU DID
IN THE MUGS.
- HE DID?
- HE DID.
- HELLO, MATTHEW.
- HOW ARE YOU, MARTHA?
- GOOD, GOOD.
GOT THAT GOOD APPLE WINE
READY FOR YOU.
- THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
- OKAY.
- [indistinct muttering]
- THERE YOU GO.
- THANK YOU.
- YOU GOT IT.
- ALL RIGHT.
- GIVE MY BEST TO YOUR WIFE.
- I WILL.
[police radio chatter]
- [sighs]
- NO.
- NO. OH.
- YOU'RE SURE THAT'S THE GUY
YOU STANDIN' OVER LIVY, RIGHT?
- YEAH, THAT'S HIM.
- WELL, THEN I'D SAY
WE GOT OUR GUY.
- HMM.
- WHAT?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- COME ON, ROY.
HOW MANY TIMES YOU AND I STOOD
HERE AND WATCHED THESE BOYS
LIE THROUGH THEIR TEETH
JUST SO WE'D SEND 'EM
BACK ACROSS THE LINE
WITH A SPANKING AND A WARNING?
- A BUNCH.
- I KNOW IT'S NOT MUCH
FOR COMFORT,
AND IT AIN'T GONNA
BRING LIVY BACK,
BUT WE GOT HIM,
AND HE'S GONNA BE PUNISHED.
- DID YOU ALREADY
HAVE YOUR BOYS DO A SWEEP?
- YEAH,
BUT THEY DIDN'T FIND ANYTHING,
BUT NOW I KNOW YOU
HEARD THOSE SHOTS TOO
I'M HAVING 'EM DO
ANOTHER BROADER SEARCH.
- YEAH, WHEN?
I TOLD YOU THAT YESTERDAY.
- TERRENCE IS DOIN' A TRANSPORT,
AND MATTHEW AND LEWIS
ARE PICKIN' UP THE SLACK,
SO SOON.
THIS AFTERNOON, OR EARLY
TOMORROW MORNING, LATEST.
- I'M GONNA GO.
- OKAY.
ROY.
WE GOT HIM.
[phone ringing]
- 풟UENO?
[cage door closing]
- PAULINA!
- [speaking Spanish]
[grunts]
VAMONOS!
[speaking Spanish]
VAMOS, VAMOS.
- [speaking Spanish]
[both speaking Spanish]
[all chatting in Spanish]
- [coughs]
[all yelling in Spanish]
- [speaking Spanish]
- HELLO.
- [muttering in Spanish]
- VAMONOS.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
[speaking Spanish]
- [screams and grunts]
- NO! NO!
NO!
[screams]
[struggling]
- [grunting]
- [screaming]
[whimpering]
- [whimpering]
- [speaking Spanish]
- HI [laughs],
THIS IS ROY AND OLIVIA'S.
LEAVE A MESSAGE
AFTER THE BEEP.
HI [laughs],
THIS IS ROY AND OLIVIA'S.
LEAVE A MESSAGE
AFTER THE BEEP.
HI [laughs],
THIS IS ROY AND OLIVIA'S.
LEAVE A MESSAGE
AFTER THE BEEP.
HI [laughs],
THIS IS ROY AND OLIVIA'S.
LEAVE A MESSAGE
AFTER THE BEEP.
- [speaking Farsi]
- HEY!
- NO, NO, NO.
[cries]
- NO.
- [speaking Spanish]
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
[cries]
- [crying]
- SHH, SHH, SHH.
- [cries]
- YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
- [speaking Spanish]
[phone rings]
- BUENO.
[phone ringing]
- [on answering machine]
HI, THIS IS ROY AND OLIVIA'S.
LEAVE A MESSAGE
AFTER THE BEEP.
[machine beeps]
- HELLO, I'M CALLING FROM
FAMILY FIRST FUNERAL SERVICE.
WE WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW THAT
WE'VE COMPLETED THE PROCESS,
AND YOU CAN PICK UP THE ASHES
AT YOUR CONVENIENCE.
[phone clicks]
[machine beeps]
[horse neighing]
- UNCLE ROY?
GOING FOR A RIDE?
- LOOKS THAT WAY.
- WANT SOME COMPANY?
- NO.
NO, I DON'T.
BUT THANK YOU, KAYE.
THANKS FOR OFFERIN'.
- YOU BRING THAT PONY BACK WET,
YOU'LL CATCH HELL FROM ME.
UNDERSTOOD?
- YES, MA'AM.
[horse neighs]
[groans]
[grunting]
- [speaking Spanish]
[gunshot]
[intense music]
[engine turns over]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'
UP HERE?
- THIS IS WHERE
THE SHOOTER WAS.
- THAT'S GOT TO BE WELL OVER
800 YARDS.
ARE YOU SURE IT
WAS FROM HERE?
- I SAW HIM FROM
THAT BLUFF OVER THERE,
ABOVE THE WASH
WHERE LIVY WAS KILLED.
THAT'S WHERE I FOUND THESE.
-ROY--
- FOUND THE LEADS
DOWN IN THE WASH.
MAYBE YOU COULD MATCH SOME
OF THOSE UP
WITH THE LEAD IN THAT BODY
DOWN THERE.
- ROY, YOU KNOW
YOU SHOULDN'T--
YOU SHOULDN'T
HAVE MOVED THESE.
HELL, YOU SHOULDN'T
EVEN BE UP HERE.
- THIS IS MY LAND,
RANDALL.
WELL, SOMEBODY'S GOT
TO DO YOUR JOB FOR YOU.
CHECK 'EM OUT.
THEY'RE MARKED.
SHOOTER MUST DO
HIS OWN RELOADS.
- DID YOU GET A
MAKER ON THE VEHICLE?
- NO.
SOME KIND OF A FOUR BY FOUR.
GREEN.
NOT MANY GUYS AROUND
WHO CAN MAKE THAT SHOT.
- YEAH, WELL, THERE'S PLENTY
OF PEOPLE PRETTY ANGRY
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
TO LIVY, ROY.
- WELL, THOSE PEOPLE GOT NO
MORE BUSINESS BEIN' ON MY LAND
THAN THE DAMN MEXICANS.
RANDALL, I WANT TO
TALK TO RAMIREZ.
- YOU KNOW
I CAN'T ALLOW THAT.
YOU'RE OFFICIALLY A CIVILIAN.
BESIDES, YOU'RE THE
SPOUSE OF THE VICTIM,
AND THAT MAN
IS THE PRIME SUSPECT.
HOW'S IT GONNA LOOK--
- I SPENT OVER 25 YEARS SITTIN'
IN THE SAME CHAIR YOU
PARK YOUR BUTT IN NOW,
THE CHAIR I PUT YOU IN.
I KNOW BETTER THAN ANYBODY
THAT THERE'S A LOT OF THINGS
YOU CAN'T DO AS SHERIFF,
BUT LETTIN' ME TALK TO RAMIREZ
AIN'T ONE OF 'EM.
- [sighs]
- I HAVE TO...
YOU GOT FIVE MINUTES.
JESUS, ROY.
- YEAH.
IT FIGURES.
- NO.
- 풠ARRO?
- SI.
- NO.
- OH, HI.
I'M SO SORRY I'M LATE.
- THAT'S OKAY.
WE'VE JUST BEEN
HERE A FEW MINUTES.
- I'M MARILY.
- HI.
- HOW DO YOU LIKE THE
FRONT OF THE HOUSE?
AND THE NEIGHBORHOOD?
- IT'S GOOD.
- OH, GOOD.
- GOOD.
- I HAVE THE CODE TO THE GARAGE,
AND I CAN OPEN THE FRONT DOOR
AND LET MYSELF IN THAT WAY,
AND THEN I CAN LET YOU IN.
[muttering]
AH, THERE IT IS.
[laughs]
OH.
OH-OH, MY--
- [speaking Spanish]
[tires screech]
[horn honks]
- SEAN!
SEAN!
SEAN LOUIS PAT!
- WHAT?
- YOUR DAD WANTS TO SEE YOU
IN THE GARAGE!
- WHY?
[pauses video game]
WHY?
[jars clattering]
- [speaking Spanish]
BUT HE SAID RIGHT NOW.
- THOSE WERE OUT ON THE GROUND
OFF THE SOUTH RIDGE
OF ROY MCNARY'S LAND.
AND MY .30-06 RELOADS.
I HAVEN'T BEEN OUT
THERE HUNTIN', SON.
BESIDES, I ALWAYS
PICK UP MY EMPTIES.
I EVEN MAKE A MARK ON 'EM
WITH A SHARPIE,
JUST SO I CAN TELL
WHICH ONES ARE MINE.
THOSE ARE MINE.
ANY IDEA HOW
THEY GOT OUT THERE, SON?
- WHAT THE HELL
WERE YOU THINKING?
WAS THIS YOUR STUPID IDEA?
DON'T YOU TURN
YOUR BACK ON ME!
- LET ME TALK.
LET ME TALK TO HIM.
[sighs]
WELL, THE BOYS ARE
TELLIN' DIFFERENT STORIES.
TWO OF 'EM ARE SAYIN'
THAT THEY WERE SHOOTING
AT THE MEXICANS 'CAUSE
THEY WERE BEATING ON LIVY
AND TRYIN' TO STEAL
HER HORSE.
- YOU KNOW DAMNED WELL
THAT'S NOT WHAT HAPPENED.
- DO I?
I MEAN, YOU THOUGHT
THOSE MEXICANS
WERE BEATIN' ON LIVY TOO.
I SAT HERE AND LISTENED TO
YOU TELL ME WHEN YOU PULLED UP,
THAT MEXICAN WAS TRYING TO STEAL
LIVY'S HORSE.
- RANDALL--
- THAT'S WHAT YOU SAID.
WHAT--WHAT DO WE GOT
HERE REALLY?
ROY, I MEAN...SO NOW WE KNOW
THAT THE BOYS
WERE SHOOTING AT THE MEXICANS.
LIVY DIDN'T DIE OF
A GUNSHOT WOUND, ROY.
THAT'S A FACT.
HE'S MY SON,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
- LIVY WAS MY WIFE.
WHO WAS THE SHOOTER?
- WELL, THE BOYS ARE
TELLIN' DIFFERENT STORIES,
AND THEY'RE ALL TRYING TO
BACK EACH OTHER--
- RANDALL.
WHO WAS THE SHOOTER?
- SEAN.
THE SHOOTER WAS SEAN.
FLORA, CAN IT WAIT?
- JUST THOUGHT BOTH YOU
SHERIFFS MIGHT WANT TO KNOW
THAT A LADY CALLED OVER HERE
JUST NOW AND SAID SHE FOUND
A BUNCH OF ILLEGALS HIDING
OUT IN A GARAGE IN PHOENIX.
SHE SAID ONE
OF THE ILLEGALS ASKED HER
TO CALL OVER HERE FOR HER.
SHE SAID THE WOMAN
IS MIGUEL RAMIREZ'S WIFE.
- MELINA RAMIREZ?
- SI?
FLORA?
[speaking Spanish]
- JESUS.
I'LL CALL YOU BACK IN A MINUTE.
ROY!
ROY, YOU CAN'T
TAKE HER IN THERE.
- WELL, FLORA AND
I JUST CAME BY.
WE, UH, BOTH HAVE TO PEE.
- OH, STOP!
YOU CAN'T TAKE HER IN THERE!
- NO, NO, DON'T.
- MISS FLORA,
SHE CAN'T BE IN THERE.
YOU CAN'T GO IN THERE.
- WHERE ARE THE BOYS AT?
- HM?
- WHERE'S SEAN?
ANYBODY BUT RAMIREZ
BEEN CHARGED YET?
- [cries]
- YOU KNOW THOSE BOYS
AREN'T FLIGHT RISK.
NOW, THEY'VE BEEN RELEASED TO
THEIR PARENTS RECOGNIZANCE.
- WELL, THAT'S A DUMB IDEA
SINCE IT WAS ON YOUR
AND THEIR PARENTS RECOGNIZANCE
THAT THE BOYS ARE OUT THERE
POPPIN' OFF ROUNDS AT PEOPLE
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
- [groans]
- [sniffs]
- [speaking Spanish]
- [cries]
[speaking Spanish]
[cries]
- NO, YOU TELL THEM--
- DID YOU TALK TO THE D.A. YET?
YOU TOLD HIM
WHAT'S GOIN' ON HERE?
YOU TOLD HIM ABOUT
YOUR BOY'S INVOLVEMENT?
HUH?
- [cries]
- [speaking Spanish]
- NO, NO, NO--
- YOU GO AHEAD AND YOU CALL HIM,
AND YOU TELL HIM
HOW YOU TAMPERED
WITH THE DAMNED EVIDENCE!
- [grunting]
[breathing heavily]
- HELLO, SENOR.
- HOLA.
THANK YOU FOR, UH,
BRINGING MIJA MY HOUSE.
- [speaking Spanish]
- GRACIAS.
- SON-IN-LAW.
- OH, SI.
- BUENO.
- [speaking Spanish]
- EVENING.
- GOOD EVENING.
- CITIZENSHIP?
- AMERICAN.
- DO YOU HAVE SOME I.D.?
- I DO.
- ROY?
- EDWARD.
- HI, FLORA.
HOW ARE YOU?
- OH, GOOD TO SEE YOU,
EDWARD.
- HEY, ROY,
LISTEN.
I WAS REALLY SORRY
TO HEAR ABOUT LIVY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN MEXICO?
- DROPPIN' OFF A FRIEND.
- OKAY.
- WELL, IT WAS GOOD
TO SEE YOU BOTH.
- SAME HERE.
[chatter in background]
- YOU CAN'T WALK IN HERE
AND TELL ME THAT RAMIREZ
IS WITHOUT BLAME.
I MEAN, NONE OF THIS WOULD
HAVE HAPPENED IF IT HADN'T BEEN
FOR THOSE GODDAMN MEXICANS
WALKIN' ACROSS YOUR LAND.
- NONE OF THIS WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED IF YOU'D CHANGED
THE COMBINATION ON YOUR
GODDAMN GUN LOCKER.
- OKAY, BUT YOU GOT TO DO
ONE THING FOR ME.
- THOSE BOYS GOT TO PAY
FOR WHAT THEY DID, RANDALL.
SEAN DOES TOO.
- I KNOW THAT,
AND I KNOW HE DOES,
AND HE'S GONNA HAVE TO LIVE WITH
IT FOR THE REST OF HIS LIFE.
- SO DO I.
- ALL I'M ASKING YOU
IS THAT YOU SAY SOMETHING
ON HIS BEHALF
AT THE DEPOSITION.
I'M ASKING YOU AS A FATHER,
AND AS A FRIEND.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
- RANDALL...
THE ONLY WAY I WILL DO THAT
IS IF HE TELLS THE TRUTH
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED OUT THERE.
- HE WILL.
- YOU KNOW, BEING A DUMBASS
IS NO EXCUSE.
- I KNOW THAT.
- ALL RIGHT.
[horse neighs]
- YOURS?
- MINE AND MY WIFE'S.
- [speaking Spanish]
- HORSE MAN.
- OH, SI.
- SHADOW.
- YEAH.
LIVY LOVED HER PONY.
- [grunts]
- COME ON, PHILLY!
ADVANCE.
- RIGHT.
- OKAY.
OKAY.
- BUENO.
- YEAH, SO YOU BETTER
ANDALE, SENOR.
GOOD.
- SI.
- OKAY.
- ADIOS.
- [grunts]
[inspirational music]