[Horse Neighing]
[Neighing]
[Neigh]
I'm looking
forJohn Russell.
Tres hombres,
Ish-Kay-Nay...
Whatever you call him.
I guess you must be
John Russell...
unless one of them is.
I can't hardly
tell you apart.
I'm Russell.
Who are you?
I'm Billy Lee Blake.
I work for Henry Mendez.
If he sent you for horses,
all we got are green.
We're not going to be
needing any more horses.
They're closing down
the stage line.
You're a bit out of touch
up here, ain't you?
Well, then,
what do you want?
Mr. Mendez
wants to see you.
He's waiting down at
Delgado's station.
He told me to tell you
to come on in.
All right,
you told me.
Let me have
my horse back
so I can get out
of here before dark.
You afraid of it?
I don't like what
I see in the daylight around here.
Go ahead.
Hombre.
Which name today?
Which do you want?
Anything but bastard
will do.
We'll useJohn Russell.
No Apache names.
No symbol names, all right?
All right.
Come inside.
We'll have some mescal.
You get home
all right?
I hear you're
out of work.
Well, I bought
my last horse from you.
The notices
go up this week.
After 20 years,
the railroad has come to Sweetmary.
It's progress,
my friend, change.
It's the law of life.
Anyway, I brought you here
about something else.
I thought you'd
want to know
that Mr. Russell died
three nights ago.
He went in his sleep.
Doesn't that affect you?
The man who raised you?
Seventy-eight years
is a long life.
Yes. He was an old man.
Not a bad one, either.
Anyway, he left you his watch
and a boarding house
on Walker Street
in Sweetmary.
It's two stories high.
I live there myself.
This is a big something
to think about.
Why?
Because you can live
among white men again...
on land that a white man
has given you.
You've been up
in the mountains too long.
It's time to
speak English to people
no matter what language
you think in.
And get your hair cut.
Why?
There's something
to be gotten out of this,
something to
your advantage.
At least go look at it.
I think that if you see it,
you'll keep it.
And there's a woman
running it...
good-looking woman.
Do I inherit her, too?
No, my friend.
That's up to you.
You can be white
or Indian or Mexican.
Now it pays you to be
a white man for a while.
Go to Sweetmary.
Say, "How are you?
I am John Russell.
I own the Russell place."
Put yourself on the winning
side for a change.
Is that where you are?
A Mexican is closer than
a White Mountain Apache,
I can tell you that.
How old is she?
Hey, uh, Mexico.
You got a bottle
back there?
I guess anybody
can come in here.
Yeah... if they
allow Indians.
Hey, uh, when did they start
letting Indians drink?
Maybe they've been
drinking that...
Apache slop they make
out of cactus juice.
Tizwin?
Yeah. Yeah,
that's right... tizwin.
Maybe that's where they bought
the nerve to come in here.
It would take a week
with tizwin.
They got time.
What else they got to do?
That ain't tizwin.
That's mescal.
Yeah, that's mescal.
Well, that's
still not allowed...
not even sticky
sweet Mex drinks.
Not for Indians.
Aw...
Iook at that.
They just can't hold
their liquor.
They sure can't.
Nobody knows why.
It's just
a fact of nature.
[Cocks Rifle]
No more, huh?
Before you leave,
you put money on the bar
for mescal.
[Puts Money On Bar]
Next time,
I'll drop you.
[Horses Ride Away]
I talk about bringing you
to a house
that has flowerpots
in the window
and napkins on the table.
A savage.
I don't know why
you say that.
I was thinking about it
in English.
[Door Squeaks]
Oh, it's so hot out there,
that wash dried
while I was hanging it.
I don't think
this meat is fresh.
Don't think about it.
Just cook it.
But it smells funny.
You think it'll be all right?
Yeah, if you put
chili peppers into it.
I wouldn't eat it myself
on a bet.
Hey, what's going on?
I'm moving you out.
I want you to
take your socks,
your cigar stubs,
your long johns,
and your nickel-plated
sheriff s badge
and amble back down the hall
to your own room.
Huh. I like it here.
Can't quite remember
how you got squatter's rights
in here anyhow.
Seems to me you
came by one night
to ask for
an extra blanket
and stayed a year.
You beginning to worry
about public opinion?
My public's getting
bigger than usual.
The new owner's
coming today.
What the hell is he,
a preacher or something?
He might not understand
this arrangement.
I'm not sure I do.
I don't like this.
I didn't think
you'd be crazy about it.
- I don't like it at all.
- Humor me.
I just want to keep up
appearances for a while.
Nothing to get
sulky about.
Jessie, you can't move me around
like you do the furniture.
I might not come back.
Sure, you will, Frank.
Where else are you going
to put your big, cold feet?
Are you kids up?
Coffee's on!
All right, Jess.
Come on,
she wants us down.
What if she does?
We're paying the rent.
What are you
going to do,
lie around all day?
Mmm. I might.
You know, the way
I calculate it,
you spend about 17 hours
out of 24 in bed.
I need a lot of sleep.
Reckon you'll come out to see
your shadow on Groundhog Day?
What's there
to get up for?
I don't have anybody
to talk to.
to visit.
Big excitement around here
is to watch Jessie
chop the head off
a chicken for dinner.
If you're hurting
for something to do
I'm poking through
every sock I own.
Try putting a darn
in some of them.
Darns raise blisters.
Buy some new ones.
You must think
I'm made of money.
- If you are, I never see it.
- Now I'm cheap, huh?
This isn't what
you promised me.
I promised you
I'd do the best I could.
What did you think
married life was gonna be?
Getting away from a hardscrabble
ranch on the Rogue River
and my old man who never raised
anything but kids and bad luck!
The lovemaking's fine, isn't it?
No, it isn't fine!
It's mostly something you want to do
and usually without taking a shave.
Look. You don't want
to have any kids.
You don't want to
keep house.
Now you don't want
to sleep with me.
I can do better to get
a dog to keep me company!
I'd like to see
these forks just once
without yesterday's
dried egg on them.
The walls
of this house
are paper thin,
Billy Lee.
What's that
supposed to mean?
It means you can hear
everything through them,
and I mean everything.
We fight a lot.
What's wrong
with you two?
Well, what isn't?
What did you
get married for?
So you'd have the right
to sleep in the same bed?
I guess.
Well, that part of it isn't
going to last, believe it or not.
She'll get fat,
and you'll get old.
Then what?
I'm not worried about then.
I'm worried about now.
You try living with
the 24-hour bellyaching
and see how you like it.
That's the price you pay
if you want it
where you can
nudge it in the night.
Billy,
time to go to work.
Well...
I see the silver's being
polished all nice and bright
for Mr. Russell.
And what's the matter
with that?
And who are you going
to all this trouble for?
A man who was carried off by
the Apaches when he was a child,
raised among red devils
to be a red devil.
Is that what I'm gonna have sleeping
in the bed in my front bedroom?
I'll tell you
something else about him.
When old man Russell found him
amongst some army
prisoners at Fort Thomas
and took him to his home,
gave him his name,
this ingrate went back
to the Apache again.
He had no use
for the white man.
So... you don't waste
your time with this, hmm?
He eats with the fingers.
When I get done with him,
he'll be eating
out of my hand.
You think so?
Uh-huh.
Mr. Russell?
I'm Jessie Brown.
I've been expecting you.
The gate seems to be
off the hinge.
I know. I've been meaning to
do something about that
sometime or other.
Come on in.
We can't talk here.
[Door Squeaks]
I hear it.
The roof s got
a nice, big leak too.
If it were raining now,
you'd drown right where
you're standing.
But it isn't raining,
is it?
Doesn't appear to be.
[Squeak]
Mr. Russell,
this house has got ten rooms,
two flights of stairs,
and one woman to
keep it all nailed down.
That's me.
All right.
Would you like to see
the rest of the house?
There's nothing else
to show you
except me
and the account books,
and you've already had
a fairly critical look at me.
Well, I'll take
a look at the books.
You might like to know
that old man Russell
had a fine funeral.
Everyone in the house
chipped in.
We bought him a horseshoe
of red carnations.
They didn't last
in this heat,
but they
were pretty.
And we got him
a marble headstone.
It has his name on it,
and underneath
we had them put,
"In the fullness
of his years."
Is that all right?
I'd settle for that
on my own slab.
What do you figure
yours is gonna read?
"Shot dead," probably.
Don't people like you,
Mr. Russell?
Only takes
one who doesn't.
Let's assume you're
going to have a future.
How would you feel about
going into business with me?
I'll make the same arrangement with
you that I had with old man Russell.
These are the accounts.
You'll clear $300 a year
without even
lifting a finger...
and you'll have a place
to hang your hats, besides.
I've had an offer
on this house...
for a herd of horses
down in Contention.
I think
I'm going to take it.
You knew that when
you walked in the door.
Let me ask you
something, lady.
This house here that
you're so hot about,
it's mine, isn't it?
Yes, it's yours.
I can sell it or not sell it,
whichever, right?
You can do
what you want to.
Was there anything
in that will
that made provision
for you?
Not a line.
Then it turns out
that I don't have
any responsibility
toward you at all.
You don't owe me
a thing.
No. Fact is, I don't.
And I'm not one
to quarrel with the facts,
Mr. Russell.
[Door Opens]
Anybody in there?
Just one.
Got something to say,
and I'd just as soon
nobody heard it.
Why? Something wrong?
Russell is selling
the house.
I'm high and dry.
Well, now, that's
kind of sudden, ain't it?
It's his house
and my luck.
If you're hurting for money,
I can let you have a little.
You can let me have
more than that.
- Like what?
- Make an honest woman out of me.
Come on, Jess.
You're already that.
Now, don't hedge.
I need an answer.
You appear to be it.
That's a hell of a romantic
way of looking at it.
You could do a lot worse.
I don't turn your pants
pockets inside out.
I don't say no
in the middle of the night.
When you got the stomachache, I'm
ready with the bicarbonate of soda.
When you get a cold, I'm the one
who brings up the croup kettle.
I know I'm not 20,
but that's not too bad.
Over the years, I have learned
to control my temper.
All that's true.
So? Yes or no?
Not a chance.
Well...
I've gone this far.
So if it's not
too undignified to ask,
why not?
Jessie, you could be the Queen
of Sheba with a rose in your teeth,
you could be Velvet-skin Annie
out of a Frisco hook shop,
the answer
would still be "no."
You got me in pretty
classy company anyhow.
I been working since
I was ten years old,
cleaning spittoons
at a dime a day.
It's now 30 years later and
all I can see out the window
is a dirt road
going nowhere.
The only thing
that changes the view
is the spotted dog lifting his leg
against the wall over there.
Saturday nights,
I haul in the town drunks.
I get their 25-cent dinners
and their rotgut liquor
heaved up over the front
of my one good shirt.
I wear three pounds of iron
strapped to my leg.
That makes me fair game
for any punk cowboy
who's had one too many.
No, Jess.
I don't need a wife.
I need out.
Doesn't seem to be
my day, does it?
I'm doing you
a favor, honey.
Anytime a man
weasels out on you,
it turns out that
he's doing you a favor.
Well, maybe you are, Frank.
Are you in charge here?
Henry Mendez.
It's urgent that my husband
and I get to Bisbee.
I want to arrange
to leave tonight.
- The line is closed.
- I'm prepared to hire a rig.
We don't have any.
What do you have?
Nothing at all, lady.
We got a mud wagon.
Who's going to drive it?
I could do it.
He doesn't have
enough experience.
The company would
not allow it.
I'm willing
to let him drive.
You might also
be willing to sue us
in case
something happens.
If I bought the wagon?
It's not mine to sell.
If I paid for more
than just our fares?
Well, you'll need
a driver, horses...
four, maybe six horses.
And the relay stations
aren't working anymore.
The same horses
will have to go all the way.
If they don't make it,
who's going to pay for them?
I'll buy the horses. So there's
no other problem, is there?
You want to get there
bad, don't you?
Settle it.
We'll go to the hotel
and have dinner.
That should give you time
to find a man and get ready.
I don't know, lady.
You'll make a month's wages
in three days.
You'll be ready.
Me and Doris want to get
out of here, so does Jess.
That's three more of us.
And Russell's looking
for a ride too.
All right,
that's four.
Why can't we do it?
Have I said we couldn't?
Whoa!
Is everybody ready?
I saw that fella Mendez.
I'm going along with you.
Going to Bisbee to get married.
What do you think?
Not much, but that's up to you.
Here's your ticket.
If there are any stops open
on the way, show that for meals.
Drinks are extra.
Hand it in when you
reach your destination.
Hey, this one's for him.
Want to hand it to him?
Sure.
I see you're
going to Contention.
I change there for Bisbee.
Yesterday I was in the army, and
next week I'll be a mining man.
Week after, I'll have a wife
all arranged for and waiting.
Isn't that something?
Yes, it is.
What did you do
with my house plant?
I stuck it in the boot.
It's O.K.
It better be.
I nursed that thing along
for six years.
[Door Opens]
- Cicero Grimes.
- Yes, sir.
Well, write it down, boy,
for the coach out front.
It's a special run.
I know that.
That's why I'm going on it.
I'm afraid
it's full-up.
You can get
one more on up top.
No one's allowed to ride with
the driver. That's a company rule.
They going?
Yes, sir. Both of them.
You got a ticket for
that stage out in front?
Well, that's it.
You can give me your ticket,
and you can take the next stage.
That's a funny idea.
No, that's not a funny idea.
That's a good idea.
See, you could stay here,
get drunk, have some fun.
Now, how's that sound?
But I'm gonna be traveling tonight.
No. I don't think so.
Leave him alone! You come late,
you find your own way.
What did you say?
I said why don't you
leave him alone?
The man wants to take
the stage, let him take it.
Well, suppose I take
your ticket instead.
You just walk in and take
someone else's seat?
Looks like it, don't it?
Somebody's pulling
a joke on somebody.
You think so?
What kind of a business
do you run here?
You let a man walk in
and say he's taking your seat
after paying the fare?
The company doesn't
do anything about it?
Friend.
This business is
between you and me.
We don't want anybody else
poking their nose into it, do we?
You wearing a gun?
You better get one.
You can't just threaten
a man like that.
There are witnesses here
seeing you threaten me.
They heard you call me
a dirty name.
I never called you anything.
And even
if they didn't, I did.
I didn't say a word.
Now, friend...
I'm going to step out
into the street here,
and if you don't come out
in about one minute,
I'm going to have to
come back in here.
You should have
done something.
You talking to me, lady?
Yes, to you.
It wasn't my business.
What if he'd taken
your ticket?
He didn't.
That soldier would have
helped you, and you know it.
I didn't ask him for any.
He didn't even
have a gun.
That's his business,
he don't want to carry one.
Takes a lot to light
a fire under you.
If it's all right
with you, lady,
I just didn't feel
like bleeding for him.
And even if it isn't
all right with you.
What if there were
Apaches out there now,
watching us?
Don't alarm yourself,
young lady.
The wild, free ones
are all up in the mountains.
The wild, caught ones
are at San Carlos.
I've heard
a lot of stories
about what Indians
do to white women.
They do the same thing
to white women
they do to Indian women,
and they don't mind it much,
red or white.
I don't know if the ladies
enjoy that kind of talk.
What kind of talk?
About Apache Indians
and what they do to women.
You saying
I got a loose mouth?
If he wasn't
saying it, I am.
Right. That lady
speaks right up, don't she?
Mm-hmm.
If you want to know
if I'm carrying a gun, I'm not.
My tongue is my only
weapon, Mr. Grimes.
And it's deadly.
I've lived among the Apaches
on a reservation...
the women grinding corn
and rubbing skins,
the men almost naked...
some of them quite striking.
Just when you begin to
find them almost beautiful,
they squat
and pick at themselves
with the dogs
sniffing at them.
I can't imagine
eating a dog
and not thinking
anything of it.
You ever been
hungry, lady?
Not just ready for supper,
but hungry enough
so that your belly swells up?
I wouldn't care
how hungry I got.
I know I wouldn't eat
one of those camp dogs.
You'd eat it. You'd fight
for the bones too.
Have you ever
eaten a dog, Mr. Russell?
Eaten one
and lived like one.
Dear me.
Mr. Russell
obviously feels sympathy
for the Indians' plight.
If you're a humane man,
you do.
But you have to live on
a reservation like San Carlos
to see that caring for them
is not a simple matter
of giving them food and clothing.
My name is Favor,
by the way.
I happen to be
the Indian agent at San Carlos.
As the agent,
I see all the problems
the Interior Department
is faced with...
natural resentment
on the part of the Indians,
their distrust,
their reluctance to
cultivate the soil.
They live where
they don't want to live.
That too, which can't
be helped for the time being.
Do you happen to know
someone at San Carlos?
Most of them.
- You've visited the agency?
- I lived there.
I don't think
I recognize you.
Did you work for
one of the suppliers?
No. I worked
for the police.
But the police
are all Apache.
Whoa.
Delgado's station.
- Mendez!
- Well, who else?
You can wash at the bench
near the kitchen door
and follow the path around the back
for the other things.
- Still got horses?
- A few more days.
Then change them for these.
I thought you had closed down.
That's a long story.
Get your woman
to make some coffee, eh?
Mr. Mendez.
I find myself
in an awkward situation.
I'm going to have
to rely on your tact.
You mean you have
a dirty job for me to do.
Giving as little
offense as possible
arrange to have Mr. Russell
ride on top with you.
How do I offend the man
without offending him, Dr. Favor?
My wife finds it disturbing
having him inside with us.
What is there about him
that bothers the lady?
I'm sure you know
his history better than I do.
I leave it in your hands.
And wash yours?
It's for the dust...
or whatever reason
you want.
Dr. Favor... says you shouldn't
ride in the coach.
They all say that?
I don't know
what they all say,
but he's paying
for most of it.
I don't think
he wants to argue.
What do you say?
Well, I say,
why make people unhappy?
Let them do
what they want.
It's not a big thing.
Why should we let it worry us?
What if I decide
to stay inside?
A man could catch his death
of cold riding up on top.
Is that worth
arguing about,
making trouble, getting
people angry and upset?
Or is it easier
to forget it? Which?
If you ask...
why I lend myself
to this...
it's a habit...
a lifetime of it.
I didn't ask.
Against the cold.
I want you
to hear this.
I was just telling him
that you're not the first
through here this afternoon.
About an hour ago,
three men came by.
- Did you know them?
- Some riders.
- But did you know them?
- They may work around here.
This station's
supposed to be closed.
What were they
doing here?
It happens.
People pass by.
What did they look like? Did they
say where they were going?
If you think they
planned to hold us up,
they wouldn't know
a stage was coming by today.
I want to go another way.
Is there one?
There's a road past
the old San Pete Mine.
It hasn't been used in years.
It's wild and hard to travel over,
but it ends up in the same place.
We'll take it.
We have women.
Any possibility of being stopped,
we should take precautions.
Start without delay,
if you please.
Hyah!
Get up! Get up!
Smoke bother you?
Would you put it out
if I said it did?
Oh, yeah.
My mama taught me
to remove my hat and my cigar
in the presence
of a lady.
Whatever else I take off
depends on
how lucky I get.
Oh, it's stuffy in there.
I noticed.
Listen, I had nothing to do
with your getting thrown out.
All right.
Although, frankly,
it wouldn't bother me a bit
if you had to walk
all the way to Bisbee.
It wouldn't bother
me either, lady.
Get up there!
Get up now!
Get up! Get up!
Giddup! Yes!
Giddup!
Ho!
All right,
everybody out!
Billy, take care
of the horses
and get a water bag.
Why have we made this stop?
If you're thinking of us,
we're not tired.
No. I'm thinking
of the horses... and me.
I'm tired.
We'll rest here
for a couple of hours.
I have to get some sleep.
If you're smart,
you'll do the same.
Hey, amigo.
This ain't the stage road.
We took a different way.
Different way?
You just take any old road
you feel like?
I think you'd better
talk to Dr. Favor.
No.
I'm talking to you.
We all agreed.
You were asleep.
I thought... he wants
to come with us so bad,
this will be all right.
Where's it go?
Same place.
We'll be in Benson tomorrow
if the road is all right
and nothing happens.
What could happen?
You better stop
right there, lady,
or I'm going to know
all there is to know about you.
Well, you could at least
have cleared your throat.
I couldn't.
My heart was in it.
It's hot.
These are heavy.
So you've seen my legs.
There are worse
walking around.
Some worse,
some better.
Well, you're not going to
have much to do with them,
so don't
let it worry you.
You're a pretty
thorny woman.
Has anyone ever gotten
within range of you?
Not that it's
any of your business,
but I was married once.
Been a widow
since I was 19.
My husband was
a sweet Missouri boy.
One night, they brought him home
on a kitchen door.
Been shot eight times.
Seems there
had been an argument
over the price
of a Mexican saddle.
He had a comic valentine
for me in his pocket.
The dead are dead.
You ought to bury them.
I'm sure
that's good advice.
Trouble is, Mr. Russell,
I think you feel the same way
about the living.
What do you want?
I hope I'm not
bothering you,
but it's so hot,
I was just cooking.
Whew. There's a nice little
breeze up here, though,
isn't there?
Everybody's
gone to sleep.
I can't sleep
when it gets this hot.
I just wake up dizzy.
That a fact?
This place
sure is spooky,
all those buildings
and nobody in them.
You know, I'm awfully glad
you're along with us.
If anything happened,
it's nice to know
there's somebody along
that could do
something about it.
That's what you think?
I saw you back
at the station.
You frightened the life
out of everyone back there.
Did you like that,
little lady?
I like to see a man
act like a man.
I think that you should
have what you like.
Oh! Don't do this!
You scared?
You never had it
like this, hmm?
You get hurt a little,
and then you...
get rubbed a little bit.
Ha ha ha!
[Sobbing]
- Where do you think you're going?
- I'm going to get my husband!
So he can charge up that hill
and get his head blown off?
You let go of me!
He's got to do something.
That man hurt me.
You wagged your tail in his face to
get his attention, and you got it.
You're disgusting,
you know that?
You talk so dirty.
Wipe your nose
and shut your mouth...
and tell everyone
you fell and skinned your knees
going to the public
convenience.
Here. Mop up.
Hyah! Hyah!
Hyah!
We're missing a water bag.
We started with three.
I must have left it
behind at San Pete.
Mendez will skin me.
Right down
to the bone.
[Doris Blake]
Oh, that's an awfully pretty kit.
[Mrs. Favor]
Yes. It's made of Spanish leather.
Geranium?
Jasmine.
Would you like some?
It's cooling.
Thank you. What does
a bottle like this cost?
The best years
of your life.
I like Dr. Favor.
He has
such lovely manners.
I was noticing his hands.
He keeps his nails
so nice and clean.
He's very proud of his hands
and feet, they're so small.
I, on the other hand, am proud
of his brain. It's very large.
He reads a lot, doesn't he?
Far into the night,
which is just as well.
'Cause when he takes his trousers
off and folds them neatly
and hangs them over
the back of a chair,
that sharp, exciting intelligence
of his doesn't count for very much.
All we're left with
is thin, spindly legs
with those
little blue veins on them
and all the knots
and bumps.
A love match, huh?
When I was 18
and a student of his
and I heard him read
Robert Browning.
But now I'm 35,
and I hear him cough up phlegm.
They all make
those noises...
bathroom noises
and bedroom noises.
Well, I suppose we've
all felt the same chill.
Not me. I like men.
They may have put
a little gray in my hair,
but I keep coming
back for more,
so they must have
something.
[Russell]
Hear, hear.
[Mendez Barking Orders
At Horses]
Whoa!
Everybody take a nice walk
to the top of the grade.
Hyah!
Well, I'm getting tired
of this trip.
I want a bath.
I want to sleep
12 hours.
I want a big, rare steak.
And then what?
I don't know.
I never know what's next.
Whatever it is, I'm going
to have to scratch for it.
That I do know.
Wish I could find a rich old man
and give it a rest for a while.
- Where? Out to pasture?
- Mm-hmm. I'm ready.
Let someone else
work up a sweat for a change.
put the meat on the table.
Glad to buy you dinner.
Mmm. There's
a lot of men
who will do that,
Mr. Russell.
Well, I'd just as soon
make it breakfast.
No, thanks.
I just take coffee in the morning...
nothing with it.
You know, we liked
not to have made it.
I figured you had
some catching up to do.
When you didn't come
by the main road,
we went back
to Delgado's.
He told us you'd
come this other way.
He didn't want
to tell us, but he told.
I tell you,
we done some riding.
Well, look who
we have here.
Hello, Jessie.
Feeling ornery,
Frank?
Let's not start
asking questions.
Just one...
what are you doing here?
Going bad, honey.
All right.
Break out that luggage.
Doc Favor's pretending
he don't see us.
Things kind of
close in on you,
don't they, Doctor?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
My wife and I
are going to Bisbee
to settle some affairs.
We'll be there
two days at most.
That's not where
you're going.
You're going to
hole up in Mexico,
or you're going
to get on a boat in Veracruz
and head out.
Hey, Lamar,
you know something.
He ought to be
over here with a gun.
He don't need a gun
to pull off a robbery.
He does it
with pen and ink.
- No.
- Yeah.
He just claims a higher
beef tally than what comes in.
Then he pays the trail driver off
for what's delivered,
charges the government for meat
that ain't even there,
and then pockets
the difference.
Ain't that right, Doctor?
The Indians go hungry,
but you don't.
All right.
Let's get to it.
What about
up in the boot?
A shotgun.
Do you think this
is worth your while?
You won't be able to
show your face again.
I purely appreciate that,
but don't give me
no more advice, please.
I'll bet you're dead
or arrested in two weeks.
You ain't gonna have
nothing to bet with.
- There are witnesses.
- I don't see no witnesses.
Lamar, you see
any witnesses?
No. Not here.
That man don't look
like no witness.
Hey, mister!
Are you a witness?
I've seen you someplace.
That bothers me.
Come on, mister.
Help me out.
Where was it?
Cicero!
Well, now,
lookee here.
How much did you steal?
Tell us so we don't
have to count it.
He figures he's helped enough
without giving us the tally.
- About 12,000, I figure.
- Somewhere around there.
Get it loaded.
Looks like you did good,
and we did better.
Boy, get up there.
Throw those two saddles down.
Amigo, you and you,
saddle them two horses.
I figured you'd
ride along with us a way.
I'd better not.
You'll be all right.
I'll be all right here.
You're coming.
One way or the other,
you're coming.
Friend, I'll thank you
for the buggy ride,
and we'll do it again
some time.
Hyah! Hyah!
Hyah!
[Closes Shotgun]
Kid, get down.
What?
Just get down
from there.
Hey, Braden.
Hold up a minute.
I forgot
a little something.
What are you
doing up there?
Getting my things.
You figure
you're going someplace?
Why stay here?
Just how far
do you think
you're going to get?
That's to find out.
Now, how far did you say
you're going to get?
Leave us some water!
Now how far?
Oh, about as far
as Delgado's.
What does that mean?
Maybe if
we all get thirsty,
we'll go to Delgado's
and get some mescal.
Jessie, do you want me
to do something about Braden?
There's nothing
to be done about him.
Russell!
Russell,
where are you going?
Russell!
Wait for us!
Russell, wait!
[Coughing]
Why didn't you
wait for us?
What did you want me
to wait for?
Look, we want to
get out of here
before they come after us.
Is there something
stopping you?
Man, what is
the matter with you?
This isn't happening to one person.
It's happening to everyone.
And you want me
to show you the way?
Sure.
You show us the way, we follow,
but we are
all together.
Together, huh?
I flatter myself
that I understand Mr. Russell.
We affronted his dignity...
a very necessary thing
to a man.
We asked him
not to ride with us.
Now he's telling us
we can't walk with him.
Isn't that right, Mr. Russell?
Maybe we don't walk
the way you walk.
Fair, but harsh.
But for all that, you're no longer
in a hurry, are you?
No. I'm in no hurry.
If you want
to go on, go on.
Leave the saddlebags
and the gun.
I thought
we'd get to that.
You forgot something,
didn't you?
Money.
An odd oversight for a man
who thinks of everything.
I was a little busy
back there.
He's thinking, "Why not
take my money out here?"
No law to stop him.
Your money?
You starved a bunch of Indians to
death at San Carlos for that money,
and now you're trying to get
your sticky fingers on it,
and meanwhile Grimes is
getting the time he needs.
Enough of this.
We have to move.
Why move?
Why not wait here for him,
maybe finish it?
Finish it?
You mean kill him?
They get close enough,
they're gonna kill you.
They didn't hurt anybody before.
Why would they wanna hurt us now?
They'll be running out of water.
You wanna give them yours?
- No.
- They'll kill you for it.
And if we don't
finish it, what then?
You got
no say in this.
Now, you can go on
or stay, whichever.
Either way, you leave the saddlebags
here. The belly gun too.
You're not a figure to command
too much confidence, Mr. Russell.
What if everyone
decides against you?
Then they've got you
to show them the way home.
It's the frying pan
or the fire,
as far as I'm concerned.
At least Russell
knows the way.
All right.
Everybody, stay put.
You got one thing
to do, kid...
watch him.
He can leave until
the time they come.
After that, no.
If he tries to leave
with nothing,
shoot him once.
If he takes the money,
shoot him twice.
If he picks up the water,
you empty your gun. Understand?
I don't understand
anything about this mess.
Mendez, you think
you can do this?
That's right.
Right there.
First, a shotgun
when they're close...
and I mean so close
you can touch them...
and then this
if you need it.
I'll be over there.
Where?
Right there.
If one of us
doesn't get a good shot,
the other
probably will.
Hit something, Mendez...
first the men,
then the horses.
I don't know.
Just to sit here
and wait to kill them?
If there was some
other way, we'd do it.
Maybe we can
outrun them.
If you run, they're going to catch
you. They're going to kill you.
You believe that
more than you believe anything.
All right.
And try not to puke.
You may have to lay
in it for a long time.
[Whinnying]
[Moaning]
Hey, hombre!
[Chuckling]
A compliment
on your shooting.
You have put a hole in me.
Whew! I never had
a bellyache like this
since I'm a little boy.
Hey, amigo!
Friend!
I am going to
give you back this bullet.
Tonight, Mendez,
not while the sun is out.
Why not?
Because you sweat a lot
and you'll want more.
Hey, hombre!
Look, amigo,
how close you come.
I tried to do better.
I think you moved.
You can be sure I move.
How do you prefer them...
tied to a tree?
That would be nice.
You like to
pull a trigger, huh?
I can do it again for you.
You could,
but first I have to talk
to this other...
this Favor.
He can hear you.
Tell him this...
Tell him
he give us the money
and some of the water,
and we give him
his wife,
and everybody goes home.
Ask him
how he like that.
You out of water, huh?
Ah, this Grimes,
he never bring canteen,
only whiskey.
He think it is
going to be easy.
It's going to get harder.
Not if this Favor
give us the money.
He hasn't got it.
He gave it to me.
Ohh!
Yousteal the money.
Ha ha ha!
All right.
We trade with you then.
You give us the money,
or we shoot the woman.
All right. Shoot her.
That nice
little soft woman?
You don't care
we shoot her?
She's nothing to me.
How about the others?
What do they say?
They say what they want.
I say what I want.
Tell Grimes
how things are up here.
Tell him he'd better
think some more.
All right.
I talk with Grimes.
Ha ha ha ha!
Mr. Russell...
we're getting more and more
worried about you.
If you can tell them
to shoot Mrs. Favor
without even flicking
an eyelash,
we're beginning to wonder
how you feel about us.
You're a lot of trouble.
Then will you tell me why
we keep trotting after you?
Because I can cut it, lady.
[Billy Lee]
There's no more cover.
It's just open country.
[Favor]
If we cross in daylight,
they'll ride us down
with their horses.
Then we leave
when it's dark.
Can we have
some water now?
Tonight.
Do you object
to our eating?
The biscuits,
not the beef.
It's packed in salt.
I figure we'll reach San Pete
tomorrow morning,
Delgado's, if we're lucky,
the next morning.
And then home.
It doesn't seem so far
when you look ahead.
The trouble is you have to
keep looking back.
Don't let that
get away from you.
I'm going to go
have a look at things.
My friend.
I want you to know
you did very well back there.
It took more nerve
than most have
to lie there
waiting for them.
Well, he shouldn't have
made me do it.
You didn't have to,
you know.
Listen, he makes sense,
whether you agree with him or not.
He makes sense, even if it kills
you... that's what you're saying.
It's just I never
shot at a man before.
- That's not an easy thing.
- I know, but it seems easy to him.
If he can kill two people,
he can kill five.
- For what reason?
- My money.
No. I know him
better than that.
Where money
is concerned,
I'm afraid
you don't know anyone.
All right. Wake up.
Wake up!
Come on. Wake up.
Get over there.
Throw me my gun,
please.
The saddlebags
and the water.
Maybe you'll leave us
your blessings
since you're taking
everything else.
[Russell] Do you think
you can carry all that?
I think so.
You better
put down that gun.
You got two ways to go...
put it down or use it.
Even if you tie me,
you're going to be dead.
You've persuaded me.
Will that do?
If you wanted to go
someplace, keep going.
I see. You're driving
me out, is that it?
Looks like it.
What am I permitted
to take with me,
if anything?
Your life. How's that?
Not overly generous.
They're probably
out there
waiting for one of us
to show himself.
You might make it.
If I don't,
it's the same as murder.
If you get there,
look me up.
We'll drink
on your luck.
If you get there.
Good-bye, my friends.
Take care
of yourselves.
Oh, it's getting cold.
You haven't
moved a muscle
in the last
hour and a half.
You don't get tired.
You don't get hungry.
You don't
get thirsty.
Are you real?
More or less.
I've known a lot of men,
but I never met one like you.
There's always
been something
that could rattle them
or shake them up a little.
You, maybe?
I've done it to
a couple in my time.
Where are they now?
Oh, they're all gone.
I've been
wedded and bedded
and loved and let down.
It hasn't always
been nice.
At least
it's been natural.
And you...
do you toss a girl
over the back of your horse
and ride off
into the pinon trees?
You asking
for a demonstration?
I think I'm asking
for trouble.
[Two Gunshots]
What does that mean?
I don't know.
A signal, maybe.
Maybe they found Favor.
Yeah, maybe that, too.
We'll hole up
in that shack on top
while it's daylight
and hope
they pass us by.
Why stop now?
If we keep going,
we get home.
Oh, man,
we're so close.
So are they.
There's blood
in my shoe.
You always bought them
a size too small.
Dr. Favor!
It's Dr. Favor!
He doesn't remember
we left water behind.
We have to tell him.
You don't do anything.
What do you mean
we don't do anything?
Take a look at him.
He's dying of thirst.
What did you think
would happen?
You just thought you'd
never see him again,
so yesterday,
it was all right, huh?
No. I should have
said something yesterday.
I'm saying it now.
Lady.
They could be
anywhere out there.
Don't press our luck.
Dr. Favor!
We left water behind
in the mine shaft!
In the mine shaft!
You will learn something
about white people...
they stick together.
They better.
[Sigh]
Well, I reckon
I will just take me
a little hike up that hill
and parley.
Any message you want
to send your husband?
Tell him I'm being
well looked after.
That's real wifely.
Hey!
I'm coming up to talk.
Y'all hold your fire.
Wait a minute. Wait!
He wants to talk.
That's no trick.
Let's hear
what he has to say.
You don't know
what he wants.
You have to find out
- Doesn't that make sense to you?
- All right.
- Anybody home?
- We can hear you.
Come on out.
We'll talk some.
You say what you want.
How'd you like
to go home?
What else?
It's looking at you.
See, we can stay here
just as long as we please.
I can send a man
for more water and chuck,
but you people
can't move around.
You can't move
unless I let you, right?
What's your offer?
You leave the money,
we leave the woman.
We have to
talk about that.
You do that.
We'll let you look at the woman
while you're talking.
That may help.
When you're ready,
bring the money down,
and you take her.
Suppose...
Well, suppose nobody
wants this woman.
That's all right,
but you ain't leavin' here
with the money,
and that's the main thing
you think about.
- Hey. I got a question.
- What's that?
How you going to
get down that hill?
Now, you hold on.
I'm going down this hill
the same way I come up it.
You hear me?
Now, you just hold on.
Aah!
[Gunshot]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Gunfire Stops]
Cicero Grimes,
meetJohn Russell.
Where's he going?
Up behind us
to close the back door.
How do we get out?
Hey, hombre!
How would you like that woman?
If you want
that woman, hombre,
you better hurry,
or maybe there will be
nothing left
in the sun!
Alex...
please...
help me.
Alex, help me.
Alex!
[Audra Sobbing]
[Audra]
Alex!
We have to
give them that money.
I think you know that.
Like you had to give
that one water, huh?
People help each other.
People kill each other, too.
I've seen that.
You're going
to see some more.
If you want to say
that it's my fault
we're stuck up here,
go ahead.
No. What I want to know
is why you helped.
Because he needed it,
just like that woman needs it.
It's not up to us to decide
whether she deserves
to live or not.
We only help, huh?
Do we have
another choice?
Not help.
Just let her die?
That's up to Grimes.
You mean,
you'd sacrifice her life
for that money?
Is that
what you're saying?
You go down there,
and you ask that lady
what she thinks of life.
Ask her what life is worth
to those Indians in San Carlos
when they run out of meat.
But she didn't
take the money. Favor did.
She said, "Those
dirty Indians eat dog,"
that she couldn't eat dog
no matter how hungry she got.
Ask her if she'd eat dog now.
I don't know what your gripe is
against the world.
Maybe you got a real one.
Lady, up there
in those mountains,
there's a whole people
who have lost everything.
They don't have a place left
to spread their blankets.
They've been
insulted, diseased,
made drunk and foolish.
Now, you call the men who did that
Christians, and you trust them.
I know them
as white men, and I don't.
Russell,
if nobody ever lifted a finger
until people were deserving,
the whole world
would go to hell.
We better deal
with each other out of need
and forget merit,
because none of us
have too much of that...
not me, not you,
not anybody.
If it bothers you,
why talk about it?
[Mexican]
Hey, man!
Do you hear me?
Come on down here!
I got something for you.
Hey, hombre,
whatever is your name...
do you hear me?
[Audra]
Alex!
Alex! Alex!
[Crying]
Alex, please!
Please help me!
Alex! Alex!
God sees this,
and if we live,
we must live in fear of him.
At least that's what
they frightened me with
when I was a child.
Don't be frightened,
Mr. Mendez.
There is no God.
Not in either of us, perhaps.
Not anywhere.
Nothing, Dr. Favor?
Nothing.
You're sure?
No reward in heaven?
Why lie to ourselves?
Well, hell, then?
A little bit of hell, maybe?
Ah, yes.
There's hell.
[Audra Faintly]
Alex?
[Doris]
By dark, she'll be dead.
Isn't somebody
going to do something?
All right.
Somebody want
to go down there, go ahead.
Just one thing...
You walk down there,
you're not going to walk back.
You leave the bag and start up with the
woman, they're gonna kill both of you.
You're saying that so nobody
will take the money and try.
They'll kill both of you.
That's why I'm saying it.
That's your wife down there.
You going to cut her loose?
Mendez, you going to save her?
Billy Lee What's-your-last-name,
you going to go down there?
This one won't.
That's his woman,
but he won't do it.
He doesn't care enough
about his own woman,
but maybe somebody else does.
But maybe somebody else does.
All right. You, lady.
You worry about his wife
more than he does.
Go on down there,
cut her loose, start back up again,
get shot in the back...
or in front, if the Mexican
by the trough does it.
In the back or in the front,
one way or the other.
Just give me your knife.
That's all I want from you.
You want a lot more
than that from me, lady.
All right.
Kid, come here.
I'm not looking
to get myself killed,
so pay attention.
You know how
to use this?
I guess so.
Ejects and loads.
It's ready now.
There's one in there,
and I hope
you only need the one.
Watch the Mexican.
After I go past him,
he'll come out
with his back to you.
If he touches his gun,
shoot him.
In the back?
I'll ask him
to turn around.
There's something else...
the money.
What about it?
Maybe it's you who will have to
take it up to San Carlos after,
but that's easy, huh?
I thought you were
keeping it for yourself.
Think what
you want to think.
That's up to you.
All of us thought so.
It belongs to those
people up there.
I grew up
on their land.
I hunted
every foot of it.
Maybe you take
the money back
I owe it.
I'll see it gets back.
Tell them to cut you out
a plain ten-dollar horse
by way of thanks.
All that trouble
you went to, huh?
It's a shock to grow old,
Mr. Russell.
Hey!
Got something for you.
Mister, you got
a lot of hard bark on you,
walking down here
like this.
Now I owe you.
You put two holes in me.
That's usually enough
for most of them.
Don't try it again.
That vaquero is more
than a fair hand.
You got the money?
Unless I brought
my dirty laundry by mistake.
Let me see it.
You look for yourself.
Come on. Hurry up.
Oh,
get out of the way.
Please get out of the way.
Well, now.
What do you suppose hell
is going to look like?
We all die. It's just
a question of when.
Mr. Mendez?
This one's still alive.
I would like at least
to know his name.
He was called
John Russell.