(stately music)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(loud explosion)
(horse whinnies)
- [Voiceover] All's clear!
(wagon rumbles)
(gun firing)
(urgent music)
(horses galloping)
(wind swirling, roaring)
(quick snapping)
(soft rattling)
- What's your pleasure?
- Whiskey.
Where's the boss?
- [Bartender] Who's asking?
- Name is Johnny...
Guitar.
- So?
- I have an appointment with Vienna.
- Vienna's busy, you'll have to wait.
- I could use a little dinner.
- Fix him up in the kitchen, Tom.
- Right this way.
- You ain't paid for your drink, mister.
- Now friend, don't rush the night.
I may be around awhile.
Take good care of these.
- [Tom] That's a lot
of man you're carrying
in those boots, stranger.
You know, there's
something about a tall man,
makes people sit up and take notice.
Yes, sir.
- [Voiceover] It's a Johnny Guitar.
Says he has an appointment with you.
- I'll see him later.
(wind howling)
- Sam, light a lamp and hang it outside.
- Nobody'll be in in this weather.
- [Vienna] And if they do,
how can they find the place?
Just hang a lamp.
- Never seen a woman who was more a man.
She thinks like one, acts like one,
and sometimes makes me feel like I'm not.
- Eddie, that's last month's paper.
How many times do you have to read it?
- I like to know what's
happening in the world outside.
- There'll be plenty going on here soon.
Just worry about that.
- I never believed I'd end
my years working for a woman
and likin' it.
- Spin the wheel, Eddie.
- What for? There's no customers.
- I like to hear it spin.
(ball rattling)
Please sit down.
More wine, Mr. Andrews?
- Oh, no more, thanks,
I'd better be getting
back to my crew.
We've a good deal of mountain
to blast through yet.
- But you have to wait
till the storm settles.
- Tell me, why did you
pick this spot to build?
How could you possibly know
that the rail road was coming this way?
- Some time ago, I ran into your surveyor
and we exchanged confidences.
- Ah.
- When the rail road comes through here,
how much do you think this
property will be worth?
- What's Albuquerque worth?
- How would you like to share in it?
I'll need all the help I can get.
- I couldn't help you, I'm
not very handy with a gun.
- I'm offering you an
opportunity to get rich.
- An opportunity to get
killed would be more accurate.
- I see you've been
influenced by my friends.
- They're determined people,
too determined for my tastes.
But I wish you luck, Vienna.
For whatever it's worth.
- Thanks, Mr. Andrews, but
I'm not trusting to luck.
A good gunfighter doesn't
depend on four leaf clovers.
And I think I...
(horses galloping)
- Expecting company?
- Not for dinner.
(dramatic music)
- [Driver] Whoa!
(wind roaring)
(roulette wheel rattling)
(bell rings)
- Keep the wheel spinning, Eddie.
(ominous music)
- Come on down, Vienna.
(roulette wheel rattling)
- Take a good look, Vienna.
- I'm sorry, Emma.
Your brother was a very fine man.
- How would you know?
He was one man who never
even looked at you.
- He was still a fine man.
- [Voiceover] We want the
Dancin' Kid and his bunch.
- [Vienna] Why come to me?
They don't live here.
- [Emma] You're one of them.
- Now, just a minute.
- We don't need you any more, Marshal.
- We got enough trouble,
Vienna, don't give us none.
- The only trouble we have
here is what you've brought in.
- Jenks!
- Yes, Mr. McIvers.
- You were driving the
stagecoach, you saw the killin'.
Who did it?
- [Marshal] Answer the question.
- Well, there was four of 'em--
- I didn't ask ya how
many, I asked ya who.
- The sun was shinin' in my eyes.
- A while ago, you said
it was the Dancin' Kid.
Say it now.
- You said it was the Kid, I
only said it could have been.
- Any more witnesses, Marshal?
- We don't need any more witnesses.
We're taking you and
your men into custody.
- Eddie, you can stop spinning the wheel.
Come and get me, Mr. McIvers.
- We don't want no shooting, Vienna.
- I'm not coming peaceably, Marshal.
- Now look here, this is a hanging matter.
We can't just go arresting
people without proof.
- If the Kid was here,
would you ask for proof?
- [Marshal] The Dancin' Kid
and Vienna aren't the same.
- I say they are.
They both cast the same shadow.
- Someone holds up the
stagecoach, your brother is killed
and all you can think about
is hanging the Dancin' Kid.
You know he didn't do it.
You all know it.
What's your real reason, Emma?
- 'Cause he's a killer.
- What has he killed?
Why do you hate him so?
What did he ever do to you?
Maybe you don't hate him.
- If you got something to say,
you'd better say it, Vienna.
- Let Emma say it.
- I wouldn't spit on him.
Oh, he was always eyeing me.
I never told my poor brother
because Len would have killed him.
That's why he held up the
stage and killed my brother.
Because now he thinks he
can get me, that's why.
- You've got it a little
twisted, haven't you, Emma?
Now you think you can get him.
- She's crazy.
- You want the Kid and
you're so ashamed of it,
you want him dead.
You want me dead, too.
Then maybe you can sleep nights.
- I won't sleep 'til I
see both of you hanged.
You and the Kid and all
of your filthy kind.
Look at her, standing up there,
staring down on us, like a somebody.
Go get her! Drag her down!
- I've never done a
thing to hurt any of you.
Don't make me do it now.
- You're nothin' but a rail road tramp.
You're not fit to live
among decent people.
- You better get out
of here while you can,
you and your men.
- We're here to stay, Mr. McIvers,
you'd better get used to that idea.
- We don't want you here.
- This was free country when I came.
I'm not giving up a single foot of it.
- You don't hear so good.
We don't want you here.
- You don't own the earth,
not this part of it.
- [McIvers] You stay and
you'll keep only enough of it
to bury you in.
- I intend to be buried here,
in the 20th century.
- You'll never see a train run through.
- Now you said it.
It took a long time for the
truth to come out, didn't it?
You and McIvers own the whole town
and every head of beef within 500 miles.
But that isn't enough, is it?
You've got to own everything.
You can't stand to see anybody else live.
Well, you're going to.
You're going to see a whole new town
right where you're standing.
A town you don't own.
The railroad's sending in people by tens,
twenties, hundreds and thousands.
You can't keep them all out!
Tell them, Mr. Andrews.
- I think you put it rather well.
- You're not building no depot here.
- That's for Vienna to decide.
- Vienna decided.
Now get out!
Get out, all of you!
- That's big talk for a little gun.
You can't shoot all of us.
- Two of you will do.
- You don't have the nerve.
- Try me.
- Stop pushing, Emma.
- Put down that gun, Vienna.
Put down the gun.
- Down there I sell whiskey and cards.
All you can buy up these
stairs is a bullet in the head.
Now, which do you want?
- All right, break it up here, men.
Break it up.
- I'm going to kill you.
- I know.
If I don't kill you first.
(guns firing)
(raucous laughing)
You wanted the Dancin' Kid, Marshal.
Here he comes.
(wind roars)
(laughing)
(coughing)
(rolling glass)
- Could you spare that smoke, friend?
I'll trouble you for a light, friend.
There's nothing like a good
smoke and a cup of coffee.
You know, some men got the
cravin' for gold and silver,
others need lots 0' land
with herds 0' cattle.
And there's those that got the weakness
for whiskey and for women.
When you boil it all down,
what does a man really need?
Just a smoke and a cup of coffee.
- And who are you?
- The name, sir, is Johnny Guitar.
- That's no name.
- Anybody care to change it?
- I hired you to play the
guitar, not insult my customers.
- Well, if these are your customers,
I'm not so sure I'll take this job.
- That's pretty strong talk for a man
who doesn't wear a gun.
- It's also bad manners.
- You must be the Dancin' Kid.
- That's the name, friend.
Care to change it?
- No. No, I like it.
Can you dance?
- [Kid] Can you play?
("Old Joe Clark")
I'm sorry, Emma.
- Where you boys been this afternoon?
- How does that concern you?
- Relax, Bart.
Marshal's only trying to do his duty.
- I'm still asking.
- Where were we this afternoon, Corey?
- Same place we are every day.
Working in our silver mine.
- What mine?
You got a silver mine, nobody ever saw it.
- Where do you think we get our money?
- Stealing. Killing honest
folks that work for theirs.
- That's harsh talk, Mr. McIvers.
- You boys don't ranch, you don't farm.
You got no business.
Still, you always got
plenty of money to spend.
- I told you, we got a silver mine.
- Maybe you better show
us that silver mine.
- Huh! And have every man within 500 miles
stamping on our necks?
- What is this?
We just did a day's work,
we came in here for a few
drinks and a little cards,
like we do every Friday,
isn't that so, Vienna?
- They never miss a Friday.
- She's lying, that tramp.
- Anyone else think I'm lying?
- She's one of them.
I say string them all up, all of them!
- Me too, Emma?
- [Marshal] Jenks, how many
men held up that stage?
- I think there was four.
- Come here, Jenks.
- What for?
- Take a good look at these men.
You recognize any of them?
- I told you, the sun was in my eyes.
- Jenks, you got me and
a dozen men behind you.
You don't have to be
afraid to tell the truth.
- I ain't afraid, Mr. McIvers.
I told you they wore masks.
How could I recognize anybody?
- You, come here.
- I got a name, mister.
- I said come here.
- Well, say it nicer.
- Don't start anything, go talk to him.
- [McIvers] Where are you from?
- Albuquerque.
- You come over the trail this afternoon?
- Uh-huh.
- You see anything?
- [Johnny] Yeah.
Yeah, I saw the stage being held up.
- What?
- (chuckles) From high in the mountains,
couldn't make out any details.
- Well, why didn't you
ride down and help 'em?
- With what, this?
(strums guitar)
- Where are your guns?
- I don't wear any.
- Maybe you got rid of them
right after the shooting.
- Now, you have a suspicious mind, mister.
- How come you don't go armed?
- Because I'm not the fastest
draw west of the Pecos.
(laughing)
- They're laughing at you.
Is that what you came here
for, to be laughed at?
(glass shattering)
- Now listen, everybody.
Listen good, 'cause I'm
only gonna say this once.
In 24 hours, mark it, 24 hours
this is gonna be closed territory.
We got a saloon in town.
We don't need one out here.
I'm passing a law against gambling
and drinking anyplace
outside the town limits.
That law goes into effect
in 24 hours, that's all.
- Well, it was nice meeting you all.
- You don't own this
whole territory, McIvers.
You've got no call asking us to leave.
- I'm not asking, I'm telling you.
- Supposing we don't?
- You got 24 hours.
- He can't make his own laws.
Tell him, Marshal.
- Now Mac, you know we
can't pass a law like that.
- 24 hours.
- Just a minute, Mac.
- Don't cross me, Marshal.
I give these people fair warning.
If they don't pull out,
I suggest you go fishing
'til it's all over.
Sounds like the storm's all over, boys.
Let's go.
- Mr. McIvers, I believe you owe me
for one bottle of whiskey.
(paper crackling)
- I don't want to owe you anything.
- Don't you ever forget that, Mr. McIvers.
- Come on, Emma.
- [Emma] And when they go,
you better go with 'em.
- [Driver] Ya!
# Oh, her name was Emma
Small, was Emma Small #
(strumming guitar)
- 24 hours, the man said.
Want me to help you pack?
- I threw away my trunk when I came here.
- McIvers has over 30 guns riding for him.
What are you gonna hold
him off with, a guitar?
- Mr. Guitar?
- Yes, ma'am?
- Still want the job?
- Well, a man's gotta
plant roots somewhere.
This seems like a nice, quiet place.
Friendly, too.
- (laughs) I like him.
I like you, mister.
Maybe you'd care to work for me.
- Just what is your business, sir?
- I'll find one.
All you have to do is
play that guitar for me.
- I like the first offer better.
- It's better you work for me.
- Let Mr. Guitar make up his own mind.
- All of a sudden, I
don't like you, mister.
- (snickering) Now that makes me real sad.
I always hate to lose a friend.
- That's the way it
goes, lose one, find one.
Play something for me, Mr. Guitar.
- Anything special?
- Just put a lot of love in it.
- He ain't gonna play so good,
all stretched out on that crap table.
- What's eating the fancy man?
- I don't know. What's your trouble, Kid?
- I'm in no trouble, he is.
Fooling with a strange woman
can bring a man a lot of grief.
- You a strange woman?
- Only to strangers.
- [Kid] What's going on with you two?
- Just what you see, friend.
- Oh, you picked the wrong
place to come to, mister.
- The lady sent for me, not you.
- Heads, I'm gonna kill you, mister.
Tails, you can play her a tune.
- Play me a tune.
(melancholy music)
Play something else.
(upbeat music)
- Play what you was playing before.
- The lady didn't like the tune.
- A troublemaker.
(off-key chord strikes)
- You want something?
- Yeah.
I wanna study you some more.
Have a drink.
- (sighs) Thank you.
- Don't go, have another.
- No, thanks.
- [Bart] Yes, thanks.
- [Johnny] I said no, thanks.
- I'm setting 'em up, all
you gotta do is drink 'em.
- Maybe, maybe he don't
like your company, Bart.
- Yeah, the guit' box man's
fussy who he drinks with.
- Your health, gentlemen.
- Now one more.
- I thank you kindly,
mister, but I had enough.
- I'll say when's enough.
Empty it.
- That one slipped.
- When a man can't hold onto a glass,
he should drink like
a baby, from a bottle.
Open your mouth, guitar
man, I'll feed you.
- Want me to stop it?
- I don't think so, not just yet.
- I said open your mouth, guitar man.
- Outside, please.
Bart, leave your guns.
(quick punching)
- Seems I've lost some of my charm.
- [Vienna] All of it.
- I always wanted to
shoot me a guitar man.
- That's a worthy ambition.
- What's the matter with me?
Now, tell me.
What do you see you don't like?
- Nothing, as a matter
of fact, I, I like you.
- But not enough, huh?
- Not that much.
- [Kid] I remember different.
- You remember, I don't.
(loud clattering)
That's the way it goes.
(loud shuffling)
(horse whinnies)
(loud thudding)
(wood snapping)
If you're smart, you'll
ride out of here and
keep on riding and you won't come back.
- That's what I should do
I never do what I should.
- Well, it's your funeral.
- Don't bury me yet.
(stuttering steps)
(playful music)
(forceful music)
(loud clattering)
(whimsical music)
- Put him on his horse.
You made a big mistake, mister.
Bart's not a man to forget.
He'll be getting back at you.
Thanks, Vienna, for a real nice time.
- Vienna?
- [Vienna] Yes, Turkey.
- You know, after what happened today,
I don't guess we'll be
seeing you any more.
I'm sure gonna miss you.
- I'm going to miss you a lot, Turkey.
- You know, you've been
about my only friend.
If you're gonna stay here,
you're gonna need somebody to,
sort of, look after you.
So, I'm staying with you.
- If you look after me, who's
going to look after you?
- You talk like I was a boy.
I'm a man.
- Every man's entitled to
be a boy for a little while.
You were cheated, Turkey.
- I'll prove to you I'm a man.
(gunshot)
(tense music)
- That was good shooting,
Turkey, for a boy.
Give me that gun.
(somber music)
You're still gun crazy, aren't you?
- No, I, I thought the
youngster was trying
to shoot up the place.
- Frank, Eddie and Sam didn't think so.
- I guess I acted a little hasty.
- If I hadn't stepped in front of Turkey,
you would have shot him.
Where are your guns?
- In my saddlebag.
- Suppose you leave them there.
I'll tell you when to use them.
- [Johnny] You're the boss.
- You haven't changed at all, Johnny.
- [Johnny] What made you think I had?
- In five years, a person
should learn something.
- Five years ago, I met you in a saloon.
Now I find you in one.
I don't see much change.
- Except I own this one.
Come here for a minute.
(dramatic music)
Do you know what this is?
- Looks like a lot of towns I've been in.
This town will be here next year.
You can own part of it.
Share and share alike with
Frank, Tom, Eddie and Sam.
- Why me?
- Maybe I'll need a gunfighter.
- Albuquerque's lousy with gunfighters.
- But I sent for Johnny Logan.
- I don't use that name any more.
- Oh, so you changed your name and thought
that would change everything, huh?
- You hired me to do a job.
- Is that all you came
here for, to do a job?
- No. No, I wanted to see you again.
Heard you had a little luck.
- Luck had nothing to do with it.
- [Johnny] I was being polite.
- I'm not ashamed of
how I got what I have.
The important thing is, I've got it.
- That's the way most people look at it.
- Except you, what
right have you to judge?
- I once loved you.
A man takes a pride in
something he really cares for.
He hates to see it trampled.
- A man can lie, steal and even kill,
but as long as he hangs on to his pride,
he's still a man.
All a woman has to do
is slip once and she's a tramp.
Must be a great comfort
to you to be a man.
- It was more of a comfort to think
that you were waiting for me.
- Did you honestly believe,
after five years, I'd be waiting for you?
- Well, I had a long ride
up here from Albuquerque.
I had to think of something.
But it kinda was nice to know
that we'd be together again.
- Well, that's very
generous of you, Mr. Logan.
Is that a proposal?
- A man's gotta stop somewhere.
This seems as good a spot as any.
- That's just about the
most touching speech
a woman ever listened to.
I'm overwhelmed.
- Maybe it's rushing it a little but
that's the general idea, isn't it?
- No, Mr. Logan, that
isn't my idea at all.
- [Johnny] Suppose you tell me.
- Oh, it's a sad story.
- I listen good to sad stories.
- Five years ago, I loved a man.
He wasn't good, he wasn't bad
but I loved him.
I wanted to marry him, to work with him.
To build something for the future.
- They should have lived
happily ever after.
- They didn't, they broke up.
He couldn't see himself
being tied down to a home.
- Looks like the girl did a smart thing
in getting rid of him.
- She was smart, all right.
She learned not to love anybody again.
- Five years is a long time.
There must have been quite
a few men in between.
- Enough.
- What do you suppose would happen
if this man was to come back?
- When a fire burns itself out,
all you have left is ashes.
- I'll do that.
- Thank you.
(solemn music)
(bright orchestral music)
(water falling)
(suspenseful music)
- Why us?
Why every time, us?
- Why don't you try and figure
out who held up the stage.
- There must be a hundred
gangs hiding out in Mexico.
They hit and run and we get the blame.
- [Bart] We got more
than the blame this time.
McIvers says we got 24 hours to get.
In case any of you dis-remember.
- Our silver mine's all played out.
It wasn't much to begin with.
We might as well pull out.
- What do you say, Corey?
- The Kid'll tell us what to do.
- [Bart] I asked you
your opinion, Mr. Corey.
- I told you, (coughing)
The Kid'll do the telling, Mr. Lonergan.
- Seems like the Kid has
other things on his mind.
- Meaning what?
- [Bart] Vienna.
You're still soft on her.
That's what's keeping us all here.
- You wanna go, go.
- You can't stay without a fight.
McIvers don't make small talk.
- It seems you lost your
taste for fighting, Bart.
- Depends on what I'm fighting for.
- [Kid] Sit down.
- And no woman's worth it.
- [Kid] You really think so, uh?
- I've known plenty, they're all the same.
No good.
- You know, you and Emma
would make a fine couple.
Yeah.
- What do you mean?
- Bart, you don't drink, you don't smoke.
You're mean to horses.
What do you like?
- Me. I like me.
And I'm taking good care of me.
- Maybe you're right, Bart.
This dust and sand is
bad for Corey's lungs.
Here.
How'd you like to come
home with me, Corey?
- Where's your home?
- New York.
- New York? I've been there.
Stinks of fish.
(laughs)
- And where you come
from don't stink, much.
- Well, let's decide,
we've gotta go some place.
- [Bart] I know of a place.
- I just decided.
We're going to California.
- The horses won't last.
- We'll buy fresh horses on the way.
- Did I hear you say buy?
- That's right, only idiots steal horses.
- [Bart] With what are we
gonna buy these fresh horses?
- With gold, Mr. Lonergan, with gold.
- We haven't any gold.
We hardly got enough silver
to plug up the holes in Bart's teeth.
- We stay around here,
we'll wind up hanging.
I hate to be run out for
something we didn't do.
So let's do something.
Something they can hang us for.
Mm, that's only justice, ain't it?
- Sounds like justice to me.
(somber music)
(wheel clattering)
- Having fun, Mr. Logan?
- I couldn't sleep.
- That stuff help any?
- Makes the night go faster.
What's keeping you awake?
- Dreams.
Bad dreams.
- Yeah, I get 'em sometimes, too.
Here, this'll chase 'em away.
- I tried that, didn't
seem to help me any.
- How many men have you forgotten?
- As many women as you've remembered.
- Don't go away.
- I haven't moved.
- Tell me something nice.
- Sure, what do you want to hear?
- Lie to me.
Tell me all these years
you've waited, tell me.
- All these years I've waited.
- Tell me you'd have died
if I hadn't come back.
- I would have died if
you hadn't come back.
- Tell me you still
love me like I love you.
- I still love you like you love me.
- Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
(loud crashing)
- Stop feeling so sorry for yourself.
You think you had it rough.
I didn't find this
place, I had to build it.
How do you think I was able to do that?
- I don't wanna know.
- But I want you to know.
For every board, plank
and beam in this place--
- I heard enough.
- No, you're going to listen.
- I told you, I don't wanna know any more.
- You can't shut me up, Johnny.
Not any more.
Once I would have crawled
at your feet to be near you.
I searched for you in every man I met.
- Look, Vienna, you just
said you had a bad dream.
We both have, but it's all over.
- Not for me.
- It's just like it was five years ago.
Nothing's happened in between.
- Oh, I wish--
- Not a thing.
You've got nothing to tell
me 'cause it's not real.
Only you and me, that's real.
We're having a drink at the
bar in the Aurora Hotel.
The band is playing, we're celebrating,
'cause we're getting married.
And after the wedding, we're
getting out of this hotel
and we're going away.
So laugh, Vienna and be
happy, it's your wedding day.
- I have waited for you, Johnny.
What took you so long?
(pleasant music)
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Well, what are we waiting for?
- Where are we going?
- To town.
- Like the man said, all a
fella needs is a cup of coffee
and a good smoke.
(whimsical music)
(peaceful music)
- [Johnny] Up, ho.
(rattling door)
(knocking)
- Bank's closed, Vienna.
- [Vienna] Why? It's no holiday.
- There all down at the cemetery
for Mr. Small's funeral.
- That still doesn't make it a holiday.
It's ten o'clock Saturday morning
and I want my money.
Wait here.
- Mm-hm.
- [Ned] I guess we can
accommodate you, Vienna.
- Thank you, Ned.
- [Ned] Why are you closing your account?
- Now that Len's gone, I'm
not doing business with Emma.
- [Ned] Do you want it in gold or notes?
- Notes will do.
(wagon rumbling)
(horses clomping)
(knocking)
- [Ned] No one else, Jake.
- Bank's closed, son.
- [Turkey] I wanna make a deposit.
- [Jake] Now, come back in an hour.
- [Turkey] Well, can
I leave this with you?
I don't wanna carry it around.
- Hand it over.
(scuffling)
(tense music)
- [Kid] Stay where we can see you, Ned.
- Well, looks like I
got me a front-row seat
at the show, huh?
- Want to be a hero or stay alive?
- I got a lot of respect for a gun.
Besides, I'm a stranger here myself.
- Unhitch the horses and keep him covered.
Help Corey!
- Got a gun?
- No, not this morning.
You didn't tell 'em what happened, eh?
(laughs)
- You picked a bad time
to do business, Vienna.
- You must be crazy.
Now they will hang the
stage killing on your neck.
Call your men off and get out of here,
no one will know.
Ned, tell him you'll forget about it.
- I promise you, Kid, no one'll know.
- But I want 'em to know and to remember.
I'm gonna leave this town so broke,
they'll never forget the Dancin' Kid.
- Emma will never let
you get away with it.
You don't know her, I do.
- Hurry it up in there.
That funeral ain't gonna last all day.
- Listen to me, so far,
you've done nothing wrong.
- You heard McIvers, we gotta go.
But we ain't going empty-handed.
- He told me to go, too.
But I'm staying.
Give this up and you won't have to go.
- And what have I got to stay for?
- What would make you give this up?
- You. And if I give this
up, could I hold on to you?
For how long?
- Sorry, Kid.
- What's taking you two so long?
(dramatic music)
You can't stop me, Vienna.
- I'm going to.
- [Kid] Don't try.
- You'll have to shoot.
- [Kid] I will. Keep 'em up, Ned, high.
Don't push me, Vienna.
Time's up, let's go.
Bart!
- I was only gonna wing him
so he couldn't follow.
- Yeah, I know, he's not going to follow.
Yee-ha!
- Now where to?
- Let's go home.
- (whip cracking) Come on.
Was I dreaming or did I
just see a bank held up?
- The Kid's no bank robber.
McIvers forced his hand
by giving him 24 hours.
- McIvers didn't put a gun in his hand
and wheel him up to the bank.
That was the Kid's idea.
- I tried to stop him.
- Who's going to believe that?
- Don't you?
- What I think doesn't matter.
- It does to me.
What are you thinking?
You and the Kid, hitting
the bank at the same time,
that don't look good.
He didn't take your money, did he?
No, he didn't.
This is all Emma needs.
Why does she hate you so?
- She's in love with the Kid.
- Last night, she was trying
awful hard to get him hung.
- He makes her feel like a
woman and that frightens her.
- By now, Emma's all worked up
and she's started on the others.
We've gotta get out and get out fast.
- Where do we go?
- We can't worry about that now.
We'll keep going until
we're out of the valley.
- I still want to go home.
(all shouting at once)
- It's a rough climb over those mountains.
- It's the only way out.
- We'd make better time
through the desert.
- Look, Corey, once we're into it,
the closest water hole is 400 miles.
I'm not chancing it.
- Maybe we oughta split
the money and separate.
- [Kid] We're riding together.
- What about it, Corey?
- We're riding together.
' [Turkey] So let's go!
(horses clomping)
(water splashes)
- They took it all. All of it.
- The Kid and his bunch.
- And Vienna.
- No, Vienna tried to stop him.
- She's one of them.
- I tell you, she wasn't.
- She was here, wasn't she?
- Yes, but--
- Jake, Vienna got you
to unlock the door, didn't she?
- Yeah, but they came later.
- How much later, a minute?
They planned this thing from
the very beginning, together.
You come with me, Jake.
We're gonna bring every cent of it back.
And Vienna was one of them, understand?
- Well, I did see him kiss her.
(ominous music)
(rushed music)
- Here, take a gun.
We won't need you, Emma.
- I'm coming along.
- You'll only be in the way.
- It's my money they got.
I'm going after it.
- They got a lot of my money, too, Emma.
The marshal's right,
you'll only slow us up.
- I'm riding with you.
And I'll be riding first.
(anxious music)
(tense music)
(horses clomping)
- [Kid] Hyah!
- [Man In Red] Hey you!
(echoing drowns out speech)
(loud blasting)
- They're closing the pass.
If you're thinking of
running, it's a little late.
I've got a hunch the posse will be
dropping in on you before night.
Same people who paid
you a visit yesterday,
only they won't be the same.
A posse isn't people.
I've ridden with 'em and
I've ridden against 'em.
A posse is an animal.
It moves like one and thinks like one.
- They're men with itchy
fingers and a coil of rope
around their saddle horns,
looking for somebody to hang.
And after riding a few hours,
they don't care much who they hang.
You haven't told me a thing I don't know.
- I haven't finished.
- Finish, but be brief.
- A posse feels safe because it's big.
They only make a big target.
I can ride around and pick off a few.
The rest of 'em will lose their guts,
turn tail, break up, and go home.
- I hired you for protection.
I won't have any killing.
- What do you think they're
coming to do to you?
Make up your mind, to stay is to fight.
(loud blasting)
- I'm going to stay.
I'm going to fight but I won't kill.
- To fight, you've got to kill.
I don't know any other way.
- You are gun crazy.
You'll never be any different.
It was a mistake to send for you, Johnny.
You can pick up your pay now.
(blasting)
(treacherous music)
- [Bart] Hyah!
(loud blasting)
You and your smart ideas!
(repeated loud blasting)
(horses neighing)
(loud blasting)
(horse sputters)
- (panting) I'm all right.
Help me on my horse.
(loud blasting)
- [Bart] We're not gonna get through that.
- [Corey] ls there another pass?
' [Kid] No.
- [Bart] If we ditch the horses.
- [Kid] We'll never make it on foot.
- [Corey] Then we'll
have to try the desert.
We can't stay here.
- We'll go back to the lair.
- [Bart] What?
- We'll be safe there.
Maybe we can't get out,
but they can't get in.
- It's like walking into a trap.
- Well, what's your idea, Mr. Lonergan?
- I said we should have
taken a desert route.
- [Kid] That was before. I'm asking now.
(loud blasting)
- Treat, you and your men
cover the desert trail.
The rest of you boys, come with me.
(horses galloping)
- You each have enough money to stake you
for six months, wherever you go.
If I'm still here by then,
I'll expect you back.
You'll each have a share, like I promised.
If I'm not here,
just keep wheeling and dealing.
The 24 hours aren't up yet.
If you run into the posse,
they'll let you through.
You'd better get started.
- Good luck, Vienna.
- See you, Vienna.
- Eddie.
This is for Tom, find him
and take him with you.
Mr. Logan.
That's for your trouble.
Vienna's is closed, Mr. Logan.
(somber music)
(ominous music)
(limb snaps)
(urgent music)
(horses clomping)
(water rushing)
- Where's Turkey?
- Well, he was right behind me
when we came over the bridge.
- Then he's somewhere between
here and Vienna's, come on.
Turkey must've passed
out, we gotta go back.
- We can't go looking now!
- We gotta find him before they do.
- These woods are gonna
be full in a minute.
We'd better get inside and quick.
- We go back for Turkey, they
cut us off from the lair.
We got no place to hide.
- How does that help Turkey?
- He took his chances.
- Kid, it could have been any one of us.
Besides, he's better off alone.
- You two go in, I'll look for him.
- You're coming with us.
- Take your hand off.
- You said we ride together, remember?
- Bart's right, Kid.
We gotta stick together.
Turkey'll have to make
it back as best he can.
(water splashes)
- They couldn't get through the mountains.
That fancy engineer said the
redhead Turkey got hurt trying.
- Let's go to Vienna's.
- Now, why should they go there?
Hey, Pete.
- We're wasting time.
- You just can't push
these men, Emma, wait.
- We gotta get to Vienna's.
- The men aren't ready yet.
- Well, get 'em ready or let me do it.
- My men are not killers.
They gotta be cold, tired and
hungry before they get mad.
- How long does that take?
- You've got five years of mad in you.
You can give them another five hours.
- There's no signs of
them trying the desert.
They've holed up somewhere.
- Probably in that place
they call their silver mine.
- [Marshal] Anyone of you men have an idea
where that mine is?
- I watched 'em leave Vienna's,
they followed this creek.
Then the camp's gotta be between
Vienna's and Furnace Ridge,
'cause there's nothing beyond
the ridge, I know that.
- If they got a camp
up there, I'll find it.
I know this stream good.
I've panned every inch of it, let's go.
- Hey now, wait a minute,
boys, I got a better idea.
- Wait, I'll say when and
I'm not saying it yet.
All right, Lou, you
know this country better
than anybody else.
Go ahead, we'll follow you.
Come on.
- Wait a minute.
(apprehensive music)
- Hey, someone's coming!
- [Voiceover] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
(horse whinnies)
- [Marshal] Hold that horse steady.
- [Voiceover] Hey, that's
one of their horses.
- Yeah, looks like they never
got to where they're going.
- Well, one of 'em didn't make it.
- Find him and you'd find 'em all.
- The only place between
here and town is Vienna's.
Reckon maybe you been
right all along, Emma.
- Of course I was right
but you wouldn't listen.
None of you, the last time, either.
There wouldn't have been any bank hold-up,
the stage wouldn't have been robbed,
my brother wouldn't have been killed.
I've been right about that
woman ever since she came.
I wanted to run her out
before she ever got in
but you wouldn't listen, none of you.
The Marshal says he has
to have legal cause.
Mr. McIvers thinks he can do it with talk.
And the rest of you
can't make up your minds.
Well, what are you waiting for?
You heard her tell how they're gonna
run the rail road through here,
bring in thousands of
new people from the east.
Farmers, dirt farmers.
Squatters. They'll push us out.
Is that what you're waitin' for?
(crowd murmuring)
You're actin' like she's some fine lady.
And doin' nothin' makes
all of you fine gentlemen.
Well, she ain't and you're not.
So you better wake up
or you're gonna find you
and your women and your kids
squeezed between barbed
wires and fence posts.
Is that what you're waiting for?
Well, I'm not.
(all murmuring)
- One of you boys better stay here.
Clem, you stick around.
(hooves clopping)
(somber music)
- Tom, what are you doing here?
Why didn't you leave with the others?
- We've got a visitor.
(loud stumbling)
- You shouldn't have come back, Tom.
- I won't be in the way.
- I can't have anyone here.
- Nobody notices me, I'm
just part of the furniture.
- Why do you think I sent
you away, all of you?
- What are you gonna do with him?
- I can't keep him here.
(coughs)
- He can't travel.
- Then I'll have to turn
him over to the posse.
But they'll hang him, he's just a boy.
- Boys who play with guns have
to be ready to die like men.
- Let me take him.
I'll hide him out in the cottonwoods.
(horses clomping)
It's too late.
You'll have to turn him over now.
- Help me, help me, Vienna.
(groans)
(gentle piano music)
- We came for the Kid and his bunch.
- That's what you said yesterday.
- [Marshal] We came for you, too, Vienna.
- Why?
I had nothing to do with robbing a bank.
Every man here knows that.
I don't have to hold up banks.
All I have to do it sit here and wait
for the rail road to come through.
And that is my intention.
- What was your business
at the bank this morning?
- If you remember, McIvers
gave me 24 hours to close.
I drew out my own money, paid off my boys
and I'm closed.
You can't buy a drink or turn a card.
I'm sitting here in my own house,
minding my own business,
playing my own piano.
I don't think you can
make a crime out of that.
Are you satisfied they're not here?
- No! I'm not satisfied.
If they're not here, she
knows where they are.
Ask her to tell you, Marshal.
- How would she know?
- She and the Kid spent
a lot of time together.
They didn't spend all of it here.
He's back in the lair.
And she knows how to get there.
Now ask her.
- Vienna?
- I can't help you, Marshal.
- [Marshal] You mean, you won't.
- I said I can't.
- Either you side with them or with us.
- [Vienna] I'm not
taking sides with anyone.
- You can't stay on the fence no longer.
It's not just Emma and
McIvers, the men are fed up.
Show us the way to the lair
and save yourself a lot of grief.
- I gave you my answer, twice.
- We won't take that.
(piano keys banging)
- And just what do you think
I've been taking from you?
Who are you and you and
you to break into my house
with your angry faces and evil minds?
Why do you come here?
I knew you would, but why?
I held up no stagecoach,
I robbed no bank.
But you're here again.
I know, and I know you know, I'm innocent.
Yet you stand there in
your funeral clothes,
like vultures, waiting for another corpse.
Why, you miserable, you hypocritical...
(dramatic music)
(loud crashing)
- Where's the rest of the bunch?
Where are they?
You've got a rope around your
neck, son, you'd better talk.
- It was Vienna's idea, wasn't it?
Tell us, don't be afraid.
We'll protect you.
- I got a rope around my neck,
how you gonna protect me?
- Tell us the truth if you want a trial.
- He's my prisoner, and I'm taking him.
- We're gonna get the
truth out of him first.
- Vienna got Jake to open
the bank for you, didn't she?
- Come on, Turkey, tell us.
I'll give you my word you won't hang.
- Stop making promises
you can't keep, McIvers.
- Stay out of this, Marshal.
- Just tell us Vienna
was one of your bunch
and we'll give you a chance.
- [McIvers] We might even
let you ride out of here.
- [Emma] You're only a boy,
we don't want to hurt you.
- The truth, son, that's all we want.
- Just tell us she was one of you, Turkey,
and you'll go free.
- [McIvers] Better talk, boy.
You'd better talk.
- What should I do?
I don't wanna die. What do I do?
- Save yourself.
- What'll you do to her?
- The law will take its course.
- You don't have to
say anything, just nod.
Was Vienna one of you?
- Well, was she?
(sobbing)
- He's a liar, you scared him into lying.
(quick smacking)
- You heard it from
Turkey's own lips, men.
What are you going to do now?
- What do you say, Mr. McIvers?
- Hang them!
- No! No. (gasping)
No, no, no.
- Let Mr. McIvers say it.
- Alright, I'm for it.
- Her, too?
- Her, too.
(sobbing)
- I'll shoot any man that steps up here.
I'm taking Vienna and Turkey to town
and I'm holding 'em for trial.
- You can take Turkey,
Marshal, but not Vienna.
- Put that gun away, Tom.
- Not 'til you all get out of here.
All of you!
(gun fires)
- Why did you do it, Tom?
- You'd do the same for me.
Look.
Everybody's looking at me.
It's the first time I ever felt important.
(dramatic music)
(intense music)
(glass breaking)
(gun fires)
(loud crashing)
(flames crackling)
(ominous music)
(disturbing music)
(horses clomping)
(horse whinnies)
(horse sputters)
- You said I wouldn't die.
You promised!
You promised me I wouldn't die.
You promised.
Mr. McIvers, you promised.
You said I wouldn't hang.
(quick whipping)
You promised me! Ah!
(frightening drum music)
- Hurry it up, Jenks!
- You wanna do it yourself?
This isn't my idea, Vienna.
- Never mind the talk.
Get it over with, Pete.
- What do you say, Mr. McIvers?
- Maybe we oughta--
- Maybe we oughta what?
- Nothing.
- Alright.
- I can't.
Not a woman.
- It's up to you.
- Not me.
- I'll give 100 dollars!
(voice echoing)
- You'll have to do it yourself, Emma.
(quick whipping)
(urgent music)
(hooves clopping)
(fire crackling)
Follow me.
Why did you come back for me?
- First chance I ever had to be a hero.
I couldn't pass it up.
Why did you bring--
- There's a mine shaft down here.
It'll take us out on the other side.
(wood thudding)
- Taking you out of here in that dress
is like carrying a lantern.
(wood crashing)
(fire crackling)
- Vienna!
- Johnny!
(flames crackling)
(flames roaring)
- This place looks pretty
safe, why can't we stay here?
- They know about this mine.
When the fire burns down,
they'll come looking.
- We'd better start thinking
of some other place.
- I have, but the Kid's there.
- Oh, that's why you brought us here.
- You and the Kid under the same roof?
How long do you think you'd both be alive?
- Which one are you worried about?
- What's your guess?
- I only know what I saw.
He didn't act like any stranger.
(tender music)
- I never said he was.
- Or even like a friend.
- He was more.
- Now tell me it was all one-sided.
- No.
No, it wasn't, but I never lied to him.
He knew there was someone else.
There always would be.
Even if you hadn't come back.
- How do I make sure?
If you're not sure by
now, telling won't help.
(dynamic music)
(fire roaring)
(loud crashing)
- Better wait, they may
double back this way.
(panting)
(fire crackling)
(water rushing)
(horse whinnies)
- That's Turkey's horse.
(water splashing)
(water spraying)
It's Vienna and Johnny Guitar!
- [Corey] Tell him to put his hands high.
- Where's the Kid?
- In the cabin with Bart.
Bart ain't gonna be
happy to see you, mister.
- We're gonna die here, that's for sure.
They'll find a way in.
- We'll have a chance
to shoot our way out.
- Yeah, some chance.
- If you don't like it here,
you can take your cut and get.
- Oh, no, I'm sticking right with you.
When I get it, you're
gonna get yours, too.
- You keep talking, you're
gonna get yours a lot sooner.
Drop it.
How'd you get in?
- Corey let us by.
- What'd you bring him for?
- There was a lynching last night.
He saved my life.
- Who'd they hang?
- Turkey.
- Turkey?
They hung Turkey.
And we could have gone back for him.
- Sure, and we'd all be hanging now.
You're wishin' it'd been me, uh?
- You read me like a book.
- Will you stop it?
You'll both get a chance
to hang soon enough.
- Some dry clothes in there.
Turkey's.
- Vienna's a good shot,
she'll come in handy
when the shooting starts.
What good is he?
- I didn't come here looking
for trouble, Mr. Lonergan.
- Bart's the name, all
my friends call me Bart.
- Thank you, Mr. Lonergan.
- Cut it out.
We got enough trouble outside.
Ain't it time you relieved Corey?
- Yeah, it's time.
- Well, what are you waiting for?
I wanna thank you for helping Vienna.
- I didn't do it for you.
- I didn't think you did.
Mind if I thank you anyway?
- No, not at all.
You got some dry clothes
that I could put on?
- In here.
(coughing)
- What are you so happy about?
- Why'd you let the stranger in?
- I couldn't risk a shot,
there's posse all around.
Besides, if Vienna brought him
along, he must be all right.
- He ain't all right with me.
- Who is?
Take it up with the Kid,
I'm still riding behind him.
- Doors are made to knock on.
(knocking)
- I'm knocking.
So it's the Johnny boy, huh?
- [Vienna] What if it is?
- I don't like it.
- [Vienna] Why don't you tell him?
- I will.
- What are you gonna tell me, Kid?
- Well, look at Mr. Guitar.
All dressed up and
looking mighty dangerous.
- What did you wanna tell me?
- I'm too scared, now that you got a gun.
- You'd better lay off him, Kid.
- I wouldn't hurt him.
- I wasn't thinking of you hurting him.
- [Kid] You mean he
might, uh, shoot himself
in the leg, trying to draw? (laughs)
- No. But if I were you,
I wouldn't fool around
with Johnny Logan.
- Are you Johnny Logan?
- That's the name, friend.
Well!
Pleased to meet you, Mr. Logan.
- I never shake hands
with a left-handed draw.
- Smart fella.
- That's how I keep alive.
- We have to figure a
way to get out of here.
Let's try to work together, just once.
- Anything for a friend.
- Could you spare a little breakfast?
- Sure, sure, help yourself.
- You wouldn't shoot a man in the back?
- In front of Vienna?
Why, she'd never forgive such bad manners.
- You'd better stick to your dancing, Kid.
You'll live longer.
(horse neighing)
(intense music)
(water spraying)
- No! No, Bart, don't shoot!
I wanna talk to you!
- Come on in!
Through the falls. Alone.
- Hold the men.
I'm going in.
I can handle Bart.
(dramatic music)
- Now, I was real fond of Turkey.
He was a good boy.
Hanging, hm, that's a mean way to go.
You couldn't have saved
him, huh, Mr. Logan?
- I had to make a choice.
- Yeah.
How'd Turkey take it? Hard?
- You ever know anyone
to take a hanging easy?
- How did it feel with that
rope round your neck, Vienna?
- Try it sometime.
- What was you thinking?
- I don't know.
- [Kid] Well, you must have
been thinking something.
- She don't wanna talk about it.
- I'm asking her, do you mind?
- Got any eggs?
- Top shelf.
- Get them.
- Let him get them, he's eating 'em.
Crawling on that bridge
and cutting that rope.
That was real brave
thing to do, Mr. Logan.
How you gonna thank him, Vienna?
- He hasn't asked for any thanks.
- Yeah, but he expects
plenty, don't you, Mr Logan?
- Sit down, Johnny.
- Let him stand.
(sudden snapping)
Look at him, Vienna.
Can't wait to shoot me.
Finger's just itching on the trigger.
(metal slapping)
Huh. Nice fella.
You've finally got someone
to do your killing for you.
That oughta make you real happy.
(door slamming)
- Sit down, Johnny.
(solemn music)
We've both done a lot of living.
Our problem now is how
to do a little more.
- [Kid] See anything?
' [Bart] Nope.
- Bart, keep away from the guitar man.
- [Bart] Why?
- His name is Johnny Logan.
(serious music)
Just thought I'd tell you.
- You told me.
(door slams)
- What's up?
- Plenty, the posse's found a way in.
Relax, they're still outside.
- And we gotta keep 'em there.
- Now will you just listen,
I just had a talk with Emma.
She don't want us, she wants
Vienna and the guitar man.
- [Corey] What about the
bank, the money we took?
- [Bart] Aw, will you listen!
Now listen, she'll settle
for half of what we got
and we get out of here into open country.
- Did you tell the Kid?
- No, I didn't tell the Kid.
- Well, why not?
Why not?
- Well, if you listen,
I'll tell you why not.
The Kid is still stuck on Vienna.
He'll never turn her over.
He'll put up a fight
and get us all killed.
Now I got a better idea.
- Well, I don't like it.
- You don't like it?
What don't you like?
Are you crazy?
I'm offering you a split and a chance
to get out with a whole skin.
I'm sticking with the Kid
and you're gonna, too.
- You don't make sense, Corey.
- I don't like the sense you make, Bart.
I think we ought to have a
talk with the Kid right now.
(sudden disturbing music)
(coughs)
(clatters)
- Some people just won't listen.
(serious music)
' [Johnny] Corey!
Kid!
(gun cocking)
(gun firing)
(urgent music)
- That's it!
(water spraying)
- Let's go!
Ya!
(dirt scrambling)
(gun fires)
(gun fires repeatedly)
Lou, I'll tell you when
there's to be any shooting.
- Looks like something's gone wrong, Emma.
(sinister music)
(gasps)
(gun fires)
(glass shatters)
- I'm coming up, Vienna!
(voice echoes)
- I'm waiting!
(tense music)
(gun fires)
- Mac, me and the boys had
enough of this killing.
- So have I.
It's their fight, has been all along.
Run and tell the others
there'll be no more shooting.
(suspenseful music)
(guns fire)
- Emma!
- Ah!
(gun fires)
(ominous music)
(gun thudding)
# Whether you go, whether you stay
# I love you
# But if you're cruel
# You can be kind, I know
# There was never a man like my Johnny
# Like the one they call Johnny Guitar #
(regal band music)