[ Squeaking ]
[ Crunching ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Men Chattering ]
GODDAMN VULTURE.
[ Spits ]
- [ All Gasping ]
- [ Gasps ]
¶ [ Honky-tonk Piano ]
¶ [ Stops ]
MISS KITTY.
MR. GAUNT.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE WHO'S
EVER HAPPY TO SEE ME.
EVERYONE IS DEAD WHEN THEY SEE YOU.
HAVE YOU EVER CONSIDERED
THE POSSIBILITY, MR. GAUNT,
THAT PEOPLE DON'T WELCOME YOU
'CAUSE YOU SCARE THE SHIT OUT OF 'EM?
I MEAN, WHEN YOU SHOW UP, PEOPLE DIE.
IT'S NOT CAUSE AND EFFECT, MARSHALL.
I SIMPLY HAVE A KNACK FOR BEING IN
THE RIGHT PLACE AT THE RIGHT TIME.
[ Glass Breaks ]
[ Both ] I'LL RAISE YOU...
A HUNDRED. FIFTY.
- ACES AND EIGHTS.
- ¶ [ Playing "We're In The Money" ]
[ Glass Breaks ]
REDEYE.
GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE. MOVE!
DEAD MAN'S HAND.
THEY SAY ON ALTEARTH THAT WILD BILL
HICKOK WAS HOLDING ACES AND EIGHTS...
WHEN HE WAS SHOT... DEAD.
SUPERSTITIONS FROM SOME
OLD PLANET LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
- RIGHT, MARSHALL?
- WHATEVER YOU SAY, MISS KITTY.
MEOW!
[ Glass Breaks ]
[ Electricity Zapping ]
WELL, I SAY, DUMP THIS CARD
GAME, COME UPSTAIRS WITH ME,
AND WE'LL PLAY SOME STRIP POKER.
IT'S THE ONLY GAME I LOVE TO LOSE.
OH, I HAD 'EM SHARPEN JUST FOR YOU.
[ Redeye ] MARSHALL STONE!
STONE, GET YOUR ASS OUT HERE!
I'M CALLING YOU OUT, STONE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER? NOT
MAN ENOUGH TO FACE ME?
OR MAYBE YOU'RE TOO MUCH MAN.
TOO MUCH HUMAN.
WE ALL KNOW WHAT GUTLESS
COWARDS HUMANS ARE, DON'T WE?
AH.
I'LL BE WAITING.
COME ON, MARSHALL. WE'VE
GOT BETTER THINGS TO DO.
IT'S A MATTER OF RESPECT, MISS KITTY.
SOME THINGS CANNOT BE IGNORED.
DON'T WORRY.
I WON'T HURT HIM.
RIGHT THERE WILL DO JUST FINE.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM, REDEYE?
YEAH! YEAH, I GOT A
PROBLEM. YOU, MARSHALL.
THAT WON'T BE A PROBLEM MUCH LONGER.
YOU ARE A SICK INDIVIDUAL.
DAMN RIGHT I AM. I'M SICK OF YOU.
I'M SICK OF THE GALAXICO. I'M SICK OF
THE GUILD. I'M SICK OF ALL THIS CRAP!
BUT I GOT ME HEAVY-CALIBER
VACCINE TO CURE MY ILLS.
- IS THAT A FACT?
- DEFINITELY.
LIGHTS OUT, MARSHALL.
[ Teeth Chattering ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Screams ]
NICE CATCH.
PRACTICE MAKES PERFECT.
SH--
SH-- SH--
[ Screaming ]
I GUESS THE FORCE FIELD WASN'T
WORKING UP TO SNUFF TODAY.
[ Hissing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Distorted ] YOU SON OF A BITCH!
NOT SO FAST, HALF-BREED.
BOYS.
MUCH BETTER.
WON'T BE NEEDING THIS ANYMORE.
[ Shrieks ]
NO POINT IN MY MESSING UP
SUCH A PRIME PUSSY AS YOURSELF.
- [ Hissing ]
- BORK.
ATTEND TO DEPUTY STELL
BARR, WOULD YOU, PLEASE?
[ Laughing ]
SO MUCH FOR GUILD INTERFERENCE.
THANKS TO THAT LOAD OF DACONIUM
WE FOUND, THIS TOWN'S UP FOR GRABS.
AND I KNOW WHO'S GOING
TO BE THE BIGGEST GRABBER.
[ Laughing ]
[ Clicking ]
GREAT. JUST WHAT I
NEEDED-- MORE GOLD.
[ Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
IT'S A GOOD DAY TO DIE.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Shrieking ]
FOR SCORPS, MAYBE.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE AM I
SAVED? I HAVE NOTHING.
WELL, IF YOU HAVE NOTHING, THEN YOU DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT LOSING WHAT YOU GOT.
YOU ARE WRONG.
THERE'S NO DEATH TO BE REACHED
WHEN ONE CANNOT SINK LOWER.
WELL, THINGS COULD BE WORSE.
SO LIVE. WHO ARE YOU?
ZACK. ZACK STONE.
ZACK ZACK STONE,
EITHER UNTIE ME OR KILL ME.
JUST STOP TALKING.
THAT WAS A PRETTY NASTY
SCORP HEADING YOUR WAY.
LUCKY FOR YOU IT WAS A BABY.
THE ADULTS USUALLY WAIT
FOR NIGHTTIME TO FORAGE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
I AM BUTEO. BUTEO.
LET'S GET SOME WATER INSIDE
YOU, BUTEO, AND THEN YOU--
NO. NO DRINK, NO FOOD.
NOT UNTIL I HAVE BURIED MY FAMILY.
WE GOT TO PLAN OUR NEXT MOVES CAREFULLY.
JUST 'CAUSE THE MARSHALL'S DEAD
DON'T MEAN THIS TOWN ROLLS OVER.
HE'S RIGHT. WE CAN'T
SIMPLY SHOOT EVERYONE.
NOW THAT THE MARSHALL'S DEAD...
AND THAT CYBORG DEPUTY
OF HIS IS NO PROBLEM,
AS LONG AS WE HAVE
OUR STASH OF DACONIUM,
WE'RE GONNA SHOW THE
GOOD PEOPLE OF OBLIVION...
THE GREAT ADVANTAGES TO
A TOWN RUN BY REDEYE...
AND HIS DEDICATED
ASSOCIATES. HEAR, HEAR!
ASSOCI-WHATS?
GANGS, BORK.
OH. RIGHT. [ Redeye ] EXCUSE ME, BORK.
I HAVE HEMORRHOIDS SMARTER THAN YOU!
[ Grunts, Chuckles ] HUH?
[ Redeye ] SPANNER,
YOU'LL WORK THE TOWN.
BE CHARMING. BE POLITE.
BE SYMPATHETIC.
WE POINT OUT THE GUILD WAS CHOKING US
WITH THEIR RULES AND RESTRICTIONS ANYWAY.
KEEP BORK WITH YOU AS BACKUP...
JUST TO REMIND FOLKS WHO
THE MUSCLE IS AROUND HERE.
WORMHOLE, SPREAD THE
WORD OF WHAT'S HAPPENED.
HEAD OUT TO THE LAST STOP CANTINA
AT THE OUTSKIRTS OF THE BADLANDS...
AND THEN MAKE YOUR WAY BACK TO OBLIVION.
NO PROBLEM, ROJO OJO.
OH, SORRY.
LASH, YOU JUST BE YOURSELF. [ Laughs ]
WE JUST MIGHT HAVE ONE...
TEENY, WEENY PROBLEM.
I HEAR STONE HAS A SON
OUT PROSPECTING SOMEWHERE.
HASN'T BEEN BACK TO OBLIVION
IN YEARS, FROM WHAT THEY SAY.
YOU DON'T THINK I SHOULD BE
CONCERNED WITH HIM, DO YOU?
I DON'T THINK YOU...
SHOULD BE CONCERNED...
ABOUT ANYONE.
ALL OF YOU ON YOUR WAY.
LASH, THERE'S A FEW THINGS I
THINK WE OUGHT TO TAKE CARE OF.
I WAS THINKING THE SAME THING.
[ Redeye ] MOVE!
OH!
MMM!
AREN'T YOU GOING TO ASK ME TO BE GENTLE?
YOU'VE GOT TO BE KIDDING.
[ Laughing ]
WELL, I...
GOT THE SONIC PROTECTORS UP.
THAT'LL KEEP THE NIGHT SCORPS AWAY.
YOU WANNA TALK ABOUT IT?
NO.
OKAY.
I'LL JUST KEEP ASKING TILL YOU DO.
KILLED MY WIFE,
MY CHILDREN.
THEY TOOK EVERYTHING.
EVEN A MERE TALISMAN OF MINE
WHICH IS USELESS TO THEM...
BUT HAS BEEN IN MY
FAMILY FOR GENERATIONS.
NOW ALL THAT IS LEFT TO ME...
IS THIS.
- THAT LOCKET?
- IT CONTAINS THE RAYS, YES.
MY WIFE MADE THIS FOR ME.
IT IS THE FIRST BIT OF
DACONIUM WE EVER FOUND.
NOW IT IS THE LAST THAT I OWN.
- NO, I COULDN'T.
- DO NOT INSULT ME.
IT IS YOURS.
WHO DID THIS TO YOU?
I ONLY SAW ONE OF THEM
CLEARLY SINCE IT WAS SO DARK.
IF I SEE HIM AGAIN, HOWEVER,
HE WILL DIE.
THAT'S POINTLESS. POINTLESS?
MY FAMILY'S SPIRITS
CRY OUT TO BE AVENGED.
VENGEANCE IS A HOLLOW PURSUIT.
IT WILL NOT BRING YOUR
FAMILY BACK TO LIFE.
[ Howling ]
AS YOU WISH.
WHAT IS IT?
A MAN IS COMING THIS WAY.
YOU CAN TELL THAT JUST
BY LOOKING INTO YOUR CUP?
THE LIQUID.
REFLECTIONS ARE MAGIC IF
YOU KNOW HOW TO READ THEM.
- SO WHO IS THIS VISITOR?
- HE IS THE ONE CALLED GAUNT.
GAUNT? THE FUNERAL MAN?
MUST BE BECAUSE HE FOUND ME.
GAUNT ONLY APPEARS
BEFORE DEATH, NOT AFTER.
THEN WHY IS HE HEADING HERE?
UNLESS ONE OF US IS GONNA DIE.
- YOU WOULD RUN, ZACK ZACK STONE?
- WELL, I SHOULD.
COME ON. HELP ME PACK THIS STUFF UP.
IF YOU RUN INTO A DEN OF NIGHT SCORPS,
YOU WILL ONLY HASTEN YOUR
FATE YOU SEEK TO FLEE.
EXCUSE THE INTRUSION, GENTLEMEN.
ZACHARY STONE?
- WELL, HOW DID YOU FIND ME?
- I LOOKED.
THE NIGHT SCORPS DID NOT ATTACK YOU?
FOR SOME REASON, THEY SEE ME...
AND SIMPLY SCATTER AWAY.
ODD, ISN'T IT?
I BRING UNFORTUNATE TIDINGS.
YOUR FATHER HAS MET AN UNTIMELY
ALLEVIATION OF EXISTENCE.
HE HAS SHUFFLED OFF HIS MORTAL COIL,
CLOSED THE CURTAIN ON OUR VEIL OF TEARS.
HE CAVORTS WITH THE HEAVENLY CHOIR...
AT THIS PARTICULAR POINT
IN ETERNITY'S ENDLESS MARCH.
WHAT?
HE'S DEAD.
JIM,
BEAM ME UP.
AH!
WHISKEY. SALOON'S DOWN THE
STREET, DOC, IN THE CATHOUSE.
THEY CUT ME OFF THERE.
HA. GOOD FOR THEM.
SELL ME A BOTTLE.
LIKE HELL.
ALL RIGHT.
[ Chuckling ] GIVE ME A BOTTLE.
LOOK.
WE'RE CLOSED.
BUT I'LL GO IN THE BACK
AND MAKE YOU SOME COFFEE.
I DIDN'T ASK FOR COFFEE!
I WANT BOOZE.
NOW!
THIS IS MY PLACE, AND
NOBODY ORDERS ME AROUND, DOC.
NOT EVEN YOU, AS MUCH AS I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU TOO, MATTIE.
NOW, GIVE ME THAT GODDAMN BOOZE.
DOC, IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN DACONIUM. THAT
HAD TO HAVE BEEN WHAT SCREWED IT UP.
I PROMISED HIM I'D PROTECT HIM.
YOU WANT THE COFFEE OR NOT?
I'M SORRY I SCARED YOU, MATTIE.
IT'S OKAY, DOC.
I KNEW YOU WOULDN'T REALLY HURT ME.
HELL, THIS STUPID
THING AIN'T EVEN LOADED.
[ Gunshot ]
SH--
[ Gaunt ] WE HAVE COMPANY.
I CAN SEE THAT.
WELL, LET ME UNDERSTAND THIS.
YOU DIDN'T WANT ME TO SAVE YOUR LIFE,
BUT NOW THAT I HAVE,
YOU'RE STAYING WITH ME.
THAT IS CORRECT. BUT WHY?
YOU NEED ME. I DON'T NEED YOU.
YOU DO NOT RECOGNIZE THE
FACT THAT YOU NEED ME.
IN THAT LIES YOUR GREATEST NEED.
FINE. WHATEVER. I'M GOING IN HERE.
WHY?
IT SEEMS THE MOST DISTASTEFUL PLACE.
[ Man ] YOU CAN HAVE THE MAP.
FORGET ABOUT THE BOXES.
FORGET ABOUT THE WEIGHTS.
I GOT TO GET GOING. I'M IN A RUSH.
I'M TELLING YOU, YOU OWE
ME. JUST GIVE ME THE 50.
GIVE IT TO ME NOW, I'LL GET LOST.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING? I
TOLD YOU, I WEIGHED IT.
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
I ALREADY WEIGHED IT. I TOLD YOU. 3.5.
HEY. AND I HAPPEN TO KNOW WHAT
THE GOING RATE FOR DACONIUM IS.
YOU, UH-- YOU DON'T EXACTLY
LOOK, UH, MATHEMATICALLY INCLINED.
I ADDED IT UP ON MY WATCH-COMP.
IT'S GUARANTEED. GUARANTEED
RELIABLE. GUARANTEED!
NOW, I KNOW THAT YOU KNOW THAT I KNOW...
THAT YOU OWE ME 54.97.
DECIMAL POINT AFTER THE SEVEN.
EXCUSE ME. EXCUSE ME.
UH, YOU ARE SLIGHTLY OFF...
BY ABOUT, UH, 5,000.
WHAT?
- WHAT KIND OF A SCAM ARE YOU RUNNING HERE?
- WAIT A MINUTE. WAIT A MINUTE.
THREE GRAMS.
UH,
ABOUT--
UH, 18 PERCENT. SEE,
SEE, THAT'S, UH--
300 DIRKS.
NOW, UH, YOU CAN TAKE
IT OR YOU CAN LEAVE IT.
THIS IS A SCAM. I'M GETTING SCAMMED!
MY WATCH-COMP COMES WITH
A GUARANTEE. GUARANTEE!
HEY, BUDDY, MAYBE YOUR
LEAD-LINED CASE LEAKED...
AND MAYBE YOUR DACONIUM THREW
YOUR WATCH-COMP OUT OF WHACK.
WHAT'S TWO PLUS TWO?
ASK IT.
54.97.
54--
THAT AIN'T RIGHT. THAT AIN'T RIGHT.
UH, LOOK ON THE BRIGHT SIDE, EINSTEIN.
UH, 300 WILL BE JUST ENOUGH,
JUST ENOUGH...
TO BUY YOU A NEW WATCH-COMP.
[ Snickering ]
WATCH THIS GUY. [ Snickering ]
BUSTER.
BEEN A WHILE.
ZACK.
LISTEN TO ME, FELLAS.
THEY KILLED GALAXICO, EVERYBODY.
THEY'LL BE CRAWLING TO US
UNDER REDEYE'S LEADERSHIP.
BUT...
REDEYE NEEDS MEN, THE RIGHT KIND OF MEN.
NO, UH, NEBULA BOYS.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
I'M HERE LOOKING FOR PEOPLE
WHO, UH, WANT TO SIGN UP.
WHAT'S IN IT FOR US?
YOU GET TO BE A PART OF
THE WINNING TEAM, HUH?
YOU GET OUR BIANNUAL NEWSLETTER.
YOU, UH-- YOU LEARN THE SECRET
HANDSHAKE. [ Scattered Oohs ]
BUT MOST IMPORTANT,
YOU GET OUR OFFICIAL "BETTER RED THAN
DEAD" BUTTON... [ Scattered Oohs ]
SO THAT EVERYBODY KNOWS
YOU'VE PICKED THE RIGHT SIDE.
ARE YOU SATISFIED WITH THAT AMOUNT?
I'M SATISFIED.
THAT MUCH CLOSER TO BUYING
MY PASSAGE OFF THIS ROCK.
YOU COULD PROBABLY HAVE
DONE BETTER IN OBLIVION.
LOOK, I'M NOT MR. POPULAR
IN THAT TOWN, ALL RIGHT?
DO YOU WISH TO DISCUSS IT?
NO.
VERY WELL.
I WILL JUST KEEP ASKING UNTIL YOU DO.
LOOK.
IT'S NOT LIKE I WISHED MY
FATHER'S DEATH OR ANYTHING.
YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND.
HE TRIED TO MAKE ME BE... YES?
SOMETHING I COULD NEVER BE.
WHAT?
HIM.
WELL, WELL, WELL. LOOK WHO IT IS.
THE GUTLESS SON OF THE LATE MARSHALL.
I REALLY DON'T WANNA FIGHT HERE, OKAY?
PEOPLE,
THE GUTLESS ONE REALLY
DOESN'T WANNA FIGHT TODAY.
OKAY?
I HATE NEBULA BOYS,
ZEKE.
HIS NAME IS ZACK.
OH, ZEKE.
THIS, UH, NATIVE...
IS YOUR FRIEND?
LOOK, BUTEO. THIS GUY ISN'T WORTH IT.
I REALLY CAN'T HURT ANYONE.
WHO CARES WHAT HE SAYS?
PEOPLE LIKE HIM SEEK OUT
WEAKNESS TO EXPLOIT, TO DESTROY.
IF YOU PRESENT YOURSELF
AS WEAK, HE WILL ATTACK.
LET HIM GO.
PLEASE.
ENOUGH, BUTEO! STOP IT!
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE HERE. I DON'T
WANT ANY TROUBLE FROM YOU GUYS.
BUTEO, LET'S GET OUT OF... HERE!
[ Yelling ]
[ All Gasping ]
GAUNT!
DON'T GO.
DON'T LEAVE BECAUSE THE
NEBULA BOYS ARE GONNA DIE.
ARE YOU DEAD SURE ABOUT THAT?
WHAT HAPPENED TO, UH, "I
DON'T WANNA HURT ANYBODY"?
WELL, I DON'T WANNA HURT ANYONE.
UNFORTUNATELY, YOU
HAPPEN TO BE STANDING...
RIGHT WHERE MY GUN'S ABOUT TO GO OFF.
BOO! [ Yelling ]
I THINK I'LL HAVE...
A BEER, MY GOOD FELLOW.
A SCHLITZ.
OH, UM--
UH-- UH-- UH--
WE'RE OUT OF SCHLITZ.
THEN, BUSTER,
YOU'RE OUT OF BEER.
WHERE IS MY GUN?
IT'S UNDER THE REGISTER.
I WAS AFRAID YOU MIGHT SHOOT OFF
SOMETHING YOU'D NEED LATER ON.
[ Groaning ]
[ Bell Jingles ]
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Cash Register
Rings ] MAY I HELP--
GOOD DAY, MISS MATTIE.
GET OUT OF MY STORE.
WHY, MATTIE, I'M APPALLED. IS
THAT ANY WAY TO TALK TO A CUSTOMER?
IT'S HOW I TALK TO MURDERERS.
OH, IS THAT WHAT YOU
CALL A FAIR FIGHT? MURDER?
THAT'S WHAT I CALL GUNNING
DOWN THE BEST MAN IN TOWN.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT UP WITH THAT KIND
OF TALK FROM SUZY HOMEMAKER, REDEYE?
MISS MATTIE,
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN VERY
FOND OF YOU. YOU KNOW THAT.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE I'M FEMALE AND HAVE A PULSE.
[ Wheezing Laugh ] NO.
BECAUSE YOU'RE A LADY.
A LADY IN THE BEST SENSE OF THE WORD.
THERE'S NOT NEAR ENOUGH
LADIES IN OBLIVION.
OH. HARD TO BELIEVE THEY
COULD PASS UP THE AMBIENCE.
DOESN'T IT BOTHER YOUR GIRLFRIEND...
YOU COMING IN HERE TELLING
ME HOW WONDERFUL I AM?
NO. I'M NOT THE JEALOUS TYPE.
BESIDES,
THERE IS PLENTY OF REDEYE TO GO AROUND.
MORE FOR YOU THEN.
I DON'T THINK YOU QUITE
UNDERSTAND, MISS MATTIE.
I... AM THE FUTURE OF THIS TOWN.
I'M GIVING YOU A CHANCE TO
GET IN AT THE GROUND FLOOR.
PROVIDING I LET YOU GET IN. THAT RIGHT?
THIS IS MY STORE. GET THE HELL OUT!
GET OUT!
AND WHAT A NICE STORE
IT IS. DON'T YOU THINK?
WAS.
WELL SAID.
STOP IT! [ Screams ]
[ Clattering ]
WHAT THE HELL--
ETHYL.
OOPS.
STOP IT! GET OUT!
SHOP...
TILL YOU DROP.
CANDY. I LOVE CANDY.
- DELICIOUS.
- OH! AH!
[ Lash ] REALLY, DARLING,
YOUR TASTE
IN JEWELRY--
NOW, LET'S SEE.
ANYTHING ELSE?
GET OUT. [ Crying ]
ANY MORE COCOA IN THE BACK?
THE NEXT ONE WHO SO
MUCH AS TWITCHES DIES.
I DO BELIEVE SHE'S ASKING
US TO LEAVE, MY FRIENDS.
NICE PLACE. [ Laughing ]
[ Crying ] HE LIKES YOU, MATTIE.
GET OUT.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
I LIKE YOU TOO.
WE COULD HAVE A GREAT TIME TOGETHER.
INSTEAD, ALL YOU'VE GOT IS
A TOTALLY THRASHED STORE.
NOW, IF YOU ASK ME,
YOU MIGHT WANNA DO SOME THINKING...
ABOUT WHAT YOU WANT OUT OF LIFE.
YOU--
YOU GOT THE HOTS FOR
REDEYE AND MISS PRISS.
WHAT ABOUT ME, LASH, HUH?
WHAT DO YOU GOT FOR ME?
I'M TEN TIMES THE MAN THAT
LIZARD HEAD COULD EVER BE.
PROVE IT.
WHO FOUND THAT BIG STASH
OF DACONIUM FOR REDEYE, HUH?
YOU GOT TO DO MORE THAN JUMP CLAIMS
BEFORE YOU CAN JUMP ME, SPANNER.
BESIDES,
A REAL MAN WOULD HAVE
KEPT IT FOR HIMSELF...
INSTEAD OF TURNING IT OVER TO REDEYE.
BUT THEN YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT, NOW, WOULD YOU?
[ Zack ] OBLIVION.
HOME, SWEET HOME.
THE FUNERAL WILL BE HELD LATER TODAY.
- I'LL HAVE ONE OF MY ASSISTANTS SUMMON YOU.
- WELL, THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
HEE-YAH.
MORE DISRESPECT.
HE WAS ALWAYS SO TIDY...
AND METHODICAL.
MY FATHER SHOWED ME THIS BOX ONCE.
HE TOLD ME IT CONTAINED
HIS MOST PERSONAL EFFECTS,
HIS MOST CHERISHED
VALUABLES AND MEMORIES,
AND IF ANYTHING EVER HAPPENED TO
HIM, HE WANTED ME TO HAVE IT ALL.
AND THAT'S WHY YOU CAME
BACK HERE, ISN'T IT?
YOU HOPE THAT THERE'S ENOUGH IN
THERE TO BUY PASSAGE OFF OBLIVION.
BUTEO, I DON'T BELONG IN THIS PLACE.
POP NEVER UNDERSTOOD THAT.
THIS WORLD... DRIES UP YOUR SOUL.
THERE ARE SOME WHO FIND BEAUTY
IN THE MOST BLEAK SURROUNDINGS.
YOU KNOW, NOW I KNOW WHY I NEEDED YOU.
'CAUSE I'D NEVER BE ABLE TO COME UP WITH ALL
THESE POINTLESS PHILOSOPHIES BY MY LONESOME.
[ Clanging ]
SON OF A BITCH.
SON OF A BITCH!
- HEY! WHAT'S GOING ON OUT THERE?
- WE GOT COMPANY.
- GET ME OUT OF HERE!
- I DON'T KNOW.
SHE LOOKS DANGEROUS.
I'M THE DEPUTY, YOU
MORON. WELL, THE EX-DEPUTY.
- DEPUTY?
- YES, THAT'S RIGHT, GENIUS.
THE DEPUTY. STELL BARR. OKAY?
NOW, PICK UP THE KEYS AND LET ME OUT.
SO...
YOU'RE ZACK.
MARSHALL MENTIONED YOU.
YEAH? WHEN?
EVERY NOW AND THEN,
WHENEVER HE WAS DRUNK AND PISSED.
HE SAID YOU WERE A COWARD.
ZACK IS NO COWARD. I OWE HIM MY LIFE.
- ZACK HERE RESCUED YOU?
- THAT IS CORRECT.
HMM.
HOW NICE OF YOU TO THINK ABOUT
SOMEONE OTHER THAN YOURSELF.
WHY AM I LETTING YOU OUT OF HERE?
ZACK STONE THINKS ABOUT
EVERYONE EXCEPT HIMSELF,
AND THAT IS HIS WEAKNESS,
AND IT'S ALSO HIS STRENGTH.
- IS THAT SO?
- I KNOW HIM BETTER THAN ANY LIVING BEING.
I HAVE READ HIS HEART AND HIS SOUL.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU KNOWN HIM?
TWO DAYS.
SOUNDS LIKE A QUICK READ.
SO YOU'RE GONNA TAKE
OVER BEING MARSHALL NOW?
LOOK, KIDDO.
I'M A CYBORG, OKAY?
AS MUCH MACHINE AS HUMAN.
I DON'T WANT THE TOP JOB.
ASIDE FROM THE FACT
THAT I HAVE NO DESIRE...
TO BE THE NUMBER-ONE
TARGET ON THE PLANET,
REDEYE HAS A HUGE STASH OF DACONIUM.
A FAIR FIGHT. [ Chuckles
] THAT'S ONE THING.
BUT HE CAN SHORT ME OUT WITH
THAT STUFF WITH NO PROBLEM.
- I'M NOT MESSING WITH THOSE ODDS.
- SO YOU'RE A QUITTER.
LOOK WHO'S TALKING.
LOOK. I WASN'T HIRED TO DO A JOB.
NO.
YOU JUST WALKED OUT ON YOUR FATHER.
THE MARSHALL ONCE MENTIONED TO ME...
THAT SHOULD IT BE NECESSARY,
HE'D PREFER A CLOSED-CASKET CEREMONY.
HE'D WISHED TO REMEMBER HIM AS HE WAS,
[ Man ] B-9!
FOR, MY DEAR FRIENDS,
WHAT IS THE BODY BUT
A MEANINGLESS SHELL,
A RECEPTACLE FOR THE SPIRIT
THAT MAKES US ALL WHAT WE ARE.
[ Man ] N-34!
CAN'T WE POSTPONE THE BINGO GAME?
IT'S DISRESPECTFUL!
IT'S THURSDAY.
WE ALWAYS HAVE BINGO ON THURSDAYS.
[ Woman ] BINGO! THANK GOD. THANK GOD.
[ Man ] CONGRATULATIONS.
FIND A SEAT, PLEASE.
[ Gasps ]
WERE YOU A FRIEND OF THE
MARSHALL'S? ME? NOT REALLY.
THE MARSHALL
DIED AS HE LIVED--
FIGHTING FOR WHAT HE BELIEVED IN.
RATHER THAN CHATTER ON MYSELF,
I'D LIKE THE MARSHALL'S
SON TO SAY A FEW WORDS.
GO.
[ Man Whispering ] THAT'S HIS
SON. [ Woman Whispering ] I KNOW.
HEY, POP.
MOST OF YOU DON'T KNOW
ME. [ Man ] MM-HMM.
SOME OF YOU DO AND
PROBABLY WISH YOU DIDN'T.
SOMETIMES I-- I THINK MY
FATHER FELT THE SAME WAY.
I KNOW HE DID.
[ Man ] G-49!
IT'S THURSDAY.
OH.
WELL, WE DIDN'T SEE
EYE-TO-EYE ON A LOT OF THINGS.
HE FELT TOO DIFFERENT.
BUT THE FACT IS, WE WERE
ACTUALLY MORE ALIKE...
THAN EITHER OF US WAS WILLING TO LET ON.
I REMEMBER WHEN I WAS 17,
[ Man ] I-17.
OH, CHRIST.
POINT IS,
MY FATHER TAUGHT ME THE
MOST IMPORTANT LESSON...
A MAN CAN
TEACH HIS SON--
THAT YOU'VE GOT TO STICK
TO WHAT YOU BELIEVE IN,
NO MATTER WHAT.
SOMETIMES THAT EVEN
MEANS NOT BEING A HERO,
EVEN IF SOMEBODY
WANTS YOU TO--
[ Man ] B-1. BE ONE.
[ Man ] AMEN TO THAT.
AND THE POINT IS...
THAT IT WAS THIS VERY
LESSON THAT TORE US APART,
THAT FACT THAT WE-WE JUST DIDN'T
BELIEVE IN THE SAME THINGS--
RIGHT. ONE OF YOU DIDN'T
BELIEVE IN HAVING ANY GUTS.
[ Man ] G-48. [ People Gasping ]
[ All ] IT'S THURSDAY.
OH. [ Man ] O-53.
SO YOU'RE THE MARSHALL'S BOY?
I'M THE MARSHALL'S KILLER.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO ABOUT IT?
[ Chuckling ]
WHO SAYS DIAMONDS ARE
A GIRL'S BEST FRIEND?
ROBO-BITCH.
THERE WILL BE NO VIOLENCE IN THIS PLACE.
- I'M NOT TALKING TO YOU!
- THERE WILL BE NO VIOLENCE IN THIS PLACE!
[ Man ] G-44.
JUST CAME TO PAY OUR RESPECTS.
[ Man ] N-40.
[ Redeye ] DIDN'T WANT TO MISS
SEEING THE DEARLY DEPARTED OFF.
I DO HAVE SOME ETHICS.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Man ] B-5.
WELL, PEACE LOVER,
YOU REALLY DON'T CARE
IF I PAY FOR WHAT I DID?
OH, YOU'RE GONNA PAY.
I'M JUST NOT GONNA
BE THE BILL COLLECTOR.
WE'RE GONE!
[ Man ] O-62.
YOUR DADDY MUST HAVE
REALLY HATED YOUR GUTS.
[ Man ] BINGO!
[ People Grumbling ]
[ Gaunt ] "ASHES TO ASHES, DUST TO DUST.
"YEA, THOUGH I FLY THROUGH
THE BLACK HOLE OF DEATH,
I FEAR NO EVIL, FOR THOU ART WITH ME."
DON'T SEE MANY NATIVES AROUND HERE.
BUTEO, IS IT? YES. BUTEO.
THEY SAY NATIVE MEN HAVE
INCREDIBLE RESPECT FOR WOMEN.
THAT IS TRUE. THEY ALSO SAY
NATIVE MEN MAKE THE BEST LOVERS.
AND HOW IS THAT?
WELL, BECAUSE OF... YOUR STAMINA...
AND ENDURANCE,
YOUR SENSITIVITY AND, UH,
WELL, THE REMARKABLE
SIZE OF YOUR, UH--
YOUR,
UH-- FEET?
YES. YOUR FEET.
COME ON, KITTY.
LET'S GO GET DRUNK.
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
EXCUSE ME.
I DIDN'T GET YOUR NAME.
MATTIE CHASE.
HOW WELL DID YOU KNOW
MY FATHER, MISS CHASE?
WELL ENOUGH TO KNOW
THAT I RESPECTED HIM,
MR. STONE.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN. YOU SHOULD'VE
STOOD UP FOR HIM IN THERE.
ONE VIOLENT ACT LEADS TO ANOTHER AND ANOTHER
IN TURN, AND I WON'T BE PART OF THAT CYCLE.
WHAT DOES VIOLENCE HAVE TO DO WITH
STANDING UP FOR SOMEBODY YOU LOVE?
I WANT PEOPLE NOT TO HURT.
LIFE IS HURT, MR. STONE.
YOU CAN'T SEPARATE THE TWO.
I'M WASTING MY TIME TALKING TO YOU.
'CAUSE YOU'RE NOT LISTENING TO ME.
OBVIOUSLY YOU SEE SOME POINT TO IT.
DON'T YOU GET IT? YOU'RE A DREAMER.
MY HUSBAND WAS JUST LIKE YOU.
HE HAD FAITH IN THIS WORLD.
HE SAID WE WERE PIONEERS. AND
AFTER SPENDING ALL OUR SAVINGS...
GETTING THE GENERAL STORE SET UP,
HE GOT KILLED.
GOT KILLED BY NIGHT SCORPS. HE LEFT ME
WITH A MOUNTAIN OF DEBT AND A DREAM...
BUT NO DREAMER.
ALL ALONE. IT'S BULLSHIT!
I KNOW IT'S BULLSHIT, MR. STONE.
OBVIOUSLY YOU'RE THE ONE
WITHOUT ANY HOPE HERE.
MAYBE YOU OUGHT TO CLIMB IN THAT GRAVE
WITH YOUR HUSBAND AND BE DONE WITH IT.
SORRY.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
YOU'RE RIGHT. I'M NOT.
HEY, DOC. YOU IN THERE?
YEAH. WHAT DO YOU WANT?
KNEW YOU'D BE HERE SOONER OR LATER.
WELL, HOW COULD I COME ALL
THE WAY BACK TO OBLIVION...
AND NOT SAY HEY TO DOC VALENTINE?
HOW ARE YOU DOIN', DOC?
HOW THE HELL DO YOU THINK?
[ People Chattering ]
[ Man #1 ] DO IT! [ Man #2 ] COME ON!
[ Man #1 ] LET'S GO! [ Man
#2 ] LET'S GO! DON'T GIVE UP.
HOLD IT TIGHT! HOLD IT REAL TIGHT.
THIS IS GOLD. COME!
THIS IS NOT YOUR USUAL HANGOUT, MATTIE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THAT LOUSY SON OF HIS.
ZACK'S A GOOD KID.
CHIP OFF THE OLD BLOCK.
TROUBLE IS, HE'S A EMPATH.
WHAT'S AN EMPATH?
MM, SOMEONE WHO EXPERIENCES
WHAT YOU EXPERIENCE,
ONLY MORE SO.
WHEN YOU SUFFER, HE SUFFERS.
ONE DAY ABOUT FIVE YEARS
AGO, THERE WAS A ROBBERY...
WITH A GUNMAN NAMED GROTH.
ZACK HAD TO HUNT HIM DOWN AND KILL HIM.
THAT'S WHEN ZACK LEFT TOWN FOR GOOD.
WHY?
WHEN HE KILLED GROTH, HE TOLD ME...
HE FELT EVERYTHING GROTH FELT.
I GUESS THAT WAS WHEN HE DECIDED
HE'D NEVER TAKE ANOTHER LIFE.
HE ALSO REALIZED HE'D BE
OF NO USE TO HIS FATHER--
MAYBE EVEN A
DANGER-- SO HE LEFT.
AND HIS MOTHER?
SHE VANISHED A LONG TIME AGO.
[ Men Shouting, Laughing ]
HEY!
WHO'S NEXT? COME ON! ANYBODY!
I COULD KEEP THIS UP ALL DAY.
WOULD YOU PLAY THIS GAME AS
A TRUE MAN, FOR TRUE STAKES?
I CAN TAKE ANYTHING YOU
CAN DISH OUT, NATIVE.
ARE YOU FAMILIAR WITH THE
CREATURE CALLED THE MON-DING?
- NO.
- RATHER POISONOUS.
I PURCHASED THIS ONE AT THE CIMMARON
EXOTIC PET SHOP DOWN THE STREET.
SUDDEN MOVEMENTS ATTRACT THEM.
[ Creature Growling ] [ People Gasping ]
THEY ARE ALSO VERY IRRITABLE...
AND DETEST BEING SHAKEN UP. [ Snarling ]
YOU GOT ONE OF THEM DING THINGS
IN THERE? THAT IT, NATIVE?
THAT IS CORRECT.
IF THERE IS ONE THING
THE MON-DING DETEST...
EVEN MORE THAN BEING SHAKEN UP,
IT IS FEAR.
IT WILL ATTACK ANY SOURCE
OF FEAR THAT IT SENSES,
AND THAT WHICH KNOWS FEAR...
BURNS AT THE MON-DING'S TOUCH.
BURNS AND DIES.
SO YOU CHALLENGE ME TO A
DEATH MATCH, HUH, NATIVE?
[ Scoffs ] WHY SHOULD I?
OTHERWISE,
THESE MEN WILL KNOW YOU AS A COWARD.
IT'S YOUR FUNERAL.
STAND BACK, PLEASE!
[ People Gasping ]
[ Growling ]
ARE YOU READY, TOUGH GUY?
[ Growls ]
IN THE NAME OF ALL THAT IS SACRED TO ME,
I AM READY.
ONE, TWO, THREE, GO!
[ Roaring ]
[ Gasping ]
YOU'RE GONNA DIE,
NATIVE. AIN'T YOU AFRAID?
I... FEAR NOTHING.
LEAST OF ALL, A MAN...
WHO WOULD KILL A FAMILY,
STAKE OUT THE FATHER,
ALL FOR DACONIUM.
THAT WAS YOU?
IF I DIE THIS DAY, I SWEAR...
BY THE GREAT GOD KUK, I WILL
HAUNT YOU UNTIL THE DAY YOU DIE,
AND I WILL SEE YOU IN HELL!
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Indistinct ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Growling Continues ]
WOO-HAH!
[ Gasping ] [ Laughing ] HOWDY.
NOT SO FAST, POCAHONTAS.
[ Spanish ] PENDEJO.
GLAD YOU COULD JOIN US.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
BORK! GET OUT HERE NOW!
AW, NUTS.
[ Groaning ]
WE'RE GONNA HAVE US A TRIAL!
SOMETHING'S GOING ON OUT THERE...
AND I DON'T LIKE THE FEEL OF IT.
STOP RIGHT THERE, JUNIOR! THIS
HAS GOT NOTHING TO DO WITH YOU.
HE IS RIGHT, ZACK. THIS
IS NOT YOUR CONCERN.
YOU TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF OF HIM.
ALL RIGHT. NOW WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
[ Chuckling ] MAKE A CITIZEN'S ARREST?
IT IS MY ROAD TO WALK, ZACK,
AND I WILL WALK IT ALONE.
ACTIONS HAVE CONSEQUENCES.
MY ACTIONS, MY CONSEQUENCES.
AND YOU BETTER WATCH OUT, OR
I'M GONNA BLOW A HOLE IN YOU...
LIKE I DID YOUR BIONIC DEPUTY.
STELL?
GREAT SCOTTY!
DOC! I'M COMIN'! I'M COMIN'!
I DON'T LIKE THIS ONE BIT.
I'M NOT GONNA GET ANY WORK DONE IN HERE.
[ Distorted ] I AM THE
ONLY LAW THIS TOWN HAS LEFT.
I HAVE GOT TO BE HERE
TO HOLD DOWN THE FORT.
IF I DON'T FIX YOU UP, YOU
WON'T BE HOLDING DOWN ANYTHING.
ZACK, GET ME THAT TRICORDER THERE.
[ Stell Moaning, Muttering ]
WHY DIDN'T HE-- [ Indistinct
] ANYWAY, HUH? WHY?
[ Chuckling ]
[ Crackling ] POWER IT DOWN, LASH.
TOO MUCH CHARGE WILL KNOCK HIM
OUT. I WANT HIM TO FEEL THE PAIN.
NATURALLY.
NATIVE. YOU STAND ACCUSED OF MURDER.
HOW DO YOU PLEAD?
THIS IS NO COURT OF LAW.
IT'S AS CLOSE AS YOU'RE GONNA GET.
THAT MAN SPANNER MURDERED MY FAMILY.
WELL, WE ONLY HAVE YOUR
WORD FOR THAT, DON'T WE?
THE WORD OF A MURDERER!
- YEAH.
- THE FIGHT WAS FAIR.
EVERYONE SAW!
WHAT I SEE IS I GOT A DEAD
MAN AND AN UPPITY NATIVE.
- IS THAT WHAT YOU ALL SEE?
- [ All ] YEAH!
WHAT I SEE...
IS THAT MY COURSE WAS CLEAR.
I SEE THAT THERE ARE TIMES...
WHEN YOU DO WHAT SHOULD BE DONE.
- AND THERE ARE TIMES WHEN YOU DO WHAT MUST BE DONE.
- [ Yawning ]
IT IS NEVER A CLEAR CHOICE. MM. MM.
YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO.
I LOVE THE WAY THIS GUY TALKS!
ARE YOU DONE?
BECAUSE WE REALLY
GOTTA GET STARTED HERE.
LASH.
OKAY, BOYS, GIVE ME SOME ROOM.
MAMA'S GONNA HAVE HERSELF SOME FUN.
[ Laughing ] YEE-HAW!
[ Whip Cracks ] [ Screaming ]
[ Cracks ] [ Screams ]
[ Doc ] THE BULLET DID SOME DAMAGE.
THERE'S NO EXIT
THROUGH THAT ARM, BUT--
YOU PROMISED ME WEEKS AGO
YOU'D PUT IN AN ACCESS PANEL.
DAMN IT, STELL! I'M A
DOCTOR, NOT A MAGICIAN!
[ Whip Continues
Cracking ] [ Men ] YEAH!
- THIS IS GONNA HURT.
- DO IT!
[ Screaming ]
[ Whip Continues Cracking ]
STOP IT! STOP! THAT'S ENOUGH!
DON'T GET YOUR KNICKERS
IN A KNOT, PRINCESS.
IT'LL ALL BE OVER SOON.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM, MISS
MATTIE? HE'S JUST A NATIVE.
I WON'T STAND BY AND
WATCH YOU KILL A MAN!
I'M AFRAID YOU HAVE NO CHOICE.
BOSS? [ Chuckles ] LOOK.
ACTIONS HAVE CONSEQUENCES.
YOU GET OUT OF TOWN, OR I'LL KILL YOU.
YOU AIN'T GONNA KILL NOBODY.
FOR ONE THING,
GAUNT AIN'T AROUND.
AND SECOND, YOU AIN'T GOT THE GUTS.
ARE YOU WILLING TO
BET YOUR LIFE ON THAT?
DON'T GIVE ME THAT SHIT, NEBULA BOY.
WE BOTH KNOW....
YOU GOT SYMPATHY.
[ Screaming ]
GET HIM!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Shouting ]
ALL RIGHT. WHO ELSE?
[ Zack ] WHO'S WITH REDEYE NOW?
WE DON'T NEED NO STINKING BADGES!
WATCH OUT, MATTIE.
I AM... SORRY, ZACK. TRULY, I AM.
IT'S OKAY. RIGHT
WORLD-VIEW, WRONG WORLD.
YOU DID WHAT YOU HAD TO DO.
THAT MUST HAVE HURT YOU,
ZACK, SHOOTING ALL THOSE MEN.
WHAT'S IT MATTER TO YOU? YOU GOT WHAT YOU
WANTED-- KILLING FOR THE RIGHT REASONS.
I HOPE YOU'RE HAPPY. GODDAMN IT.
[ Muffled Scream ]
WE COULDN'T BEAR TO LEAVE
YOU BEHIND, PRINCESS.
WE LIKE YOU TOO MUCH.
[ Whimpering ]
DELICIOUS.
[ Groaning ]
OOH, THAT MUST REALLY HURT.
NO, YOU IDIOT! YOU'RE
STANDING ON MY FOOT!
[ Sloshing ]
- EWW!
- LOOK.
HANDY, ISN'T IT?
[ People Chattering ]
GOOD TO HAVE THE LAW BACK IN TOWN.
THIS MAY SOUND LIKE COLD COMFORT,
BUT YOUR DADDY WOULD HAVE BEEN PROUD.
YEAH? YOUR MA TOO.
- I NEVER KNEW HER.
- I DID.
YEAH? WHAT WAS SHE LIKE?
SHE JUST SAID YOU WERE A HERO.
THAT MAKES YOU MARSHALL,
IF YOU WANT THE JOB.
YOU'RE EMPOWERED TO MAKE ME MARSHALL?
OH, HELL, KIDDO,
ANOTHER TWO DRINKS IN ME,
I'M GONNA MAKE YOU EMPEROR
OF THE GODDAMN GALAXY.
WELL, YOU'RE AWFUL QUIET.
I HAVE SAID "THANK YOU."
I HAVE APOLOGIZED FOR HAVING A HAND IN
MAKING YOU WHAT YOU DID NOT WISH TO BE.
BEYOND THAT, I HAVE NOTHING TO SAY.
NOTHING TO SAY?
BUTEO HAS NOTHING TO
SAY. DRINKS FOR EVERYONE!
- [ All Cheering ] -
EXCEPT-- - CANCEL THAT!
[ All Groaning ]
- YOUR ANGER AT MATTIE WAS MISPLACED.
- HE'S RIGHT, YOU KNOW.
"HE'S RIGHT, YOU
KNOW." IS HE EVER WRONG?
- NO.
AS YOU WERE.
I THOUGHT YOU WOULD WANT TO KNOW,
I'M ABOUT TO HEAD OUT TO THE BADLANDS.
- WHAT'S IN THE BADLANDS?
- PROBABLY REDEYE.
THAT'S HIS FAVORITE HIDEY
HOLE WHENEVER HE'S IN TROUBLE.
SOMEONE IS GOING TO DIE THERE.
WELL, MR. PSYCHIC,
GIVE REDEYE MY REGARDS.
WHAT'S GONNA GET HIM? NIGHT SCORPS?
I NEVER KNOW THE WHO OR THE HOW.
JUST THE WHEN AND THE WHERE.
YOU KNOW, I WAS A
LITTLE ROUGH WITH MATTIE.
MAYBE I OUGHT TO GO OVER TO THE GENERAL
STORE AND HAVE A LITTLE TALK WITH HER.
THAT IS GOOD.
SHE ISN'T THERE.
WHERE IS SHE?
WITH THE PEOPLE I SAW ESCORTING
HER OUT OF TOWN, I ASSUME.
OUT OF TOWN? WHERE OUT OF TOWN?
THE BADLANDS.
ATTENTION, EVERYBODY.
REDEYE'S KIDNAPPED MISS MATTIE.
WE'RE GETTING A POSSE
TOGETHER AND GOING AFTER 'EM...
TO PUT AND END TO THIS
THING ONCE AND FOR ALL!
[ All Cheering ]
I HEAR HE'S HIDING IN THE BADLANDS.
MR. GAUNT'S LEADING THE WAY.
WHO'S WITH ME? [ Native Language ]
[ Low Chattering ]
YOU GUYS SURE KNOW HOW
TO GET 'EM ALL RILED UP.
[ Wolf Howling ]
REMEMBER, WATCH OUT FOR NIGHT SCORPS.
AND REDEYE. AND NONPAYMENT OF DEBTS.
I TEND TO LOOK AT THE BIG PICTURE.
LOOK, IT'S REAL SIMPLE. WE JUST HAVE TO
KEEP A LOOKOUT FOR ANYTHING AND EVERYTHING.
THAT'S ALL.
YOU SEE ANYTHING IN THERE
BESIDES YOUR OWN REFLECTION?
SOMETHING BIG. BUT I
CANNOT QUITE MAKE IT OUT.
[ Gunshot ] [ Zack ] HIT THE DECK!
[ Shouting ]
DON'T TOUCH ME AGAIN.
[ Chuckling ] WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO? POKE ME TO DEATH?
NO. JUST GIVE YOU THE FINGER.
AW, SWEET DREAMS.
[ Shouts ]
[ Gunshots ]
I'M GONNA GET AROUND IN BACK OF
THEM. HOW ARE YOU GONNA DO THAT?
ANCIENT NATIVE TACTIC: RUN LIKE HELL.
[ Gunshots Continue ]
- I SUGGEST YOU GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE, DOC!
- WHAT ABOUT MATTIE?
WE'LL SEND HER BACK
WHEN WE'RE DONE WITH HER.
I'LL SLIP OUT THIS WAY.
[ Screaming ]
MATTIE!
[ Redeye ] HE'S IN DEEP SHIT NOW, BOY!
NIGHT SCORPS MIGHT BE
SCARED OF ALL THIS NOISE.
BUT WHEN THEY SMELL THE BLOOD, [ Smacks
Lips ] THEY'LL BE NO STOPPING THEM.
[ Grunting ]
HMM.
DON'T YOU EVER POINT
A FINGER AT ME AGAIN!
NEVER CARED FOR HANDGUNS ANYWAY.
[ Yelling ] NO!
[ Yelling Continues ]
[ Whimpering ] [ Roaring ]
[ Screaming ]
IT'S OKAY. IT'S OKAY. IS IT YOUR LEG?
YES, IT'S FINE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO RELOAD, MATTIE? YES.
YOU'LL NEED THIS TO KEEP
THE NIGHT SCORPS AWAY.
ZACK, LOOK, YOU OUGHT TO LET HIM BE.
NO WAY, MATTIE. IT ENDS HERE.
[ Wolf Howling ]
OH, SHIT. EVERYBODY KEEPS HURTING ME!
SURPRISE!
NOW, LET'S SEE HOW
YOU DO WITH MAX POWER.
REDEYE!
SHIT.
[ Both Growling ]
HOW DO YOU LIKE IT, BOY?
THE LATEST IN MINIATURE ENERGY BLASTERS.
SO LONG, MARSHALL.
A LITTLE SLOW ON THE DRAW.
LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON.
AAH.
DACONIUM. TURNAROUND'S
FAIR PLAY, ISN'T IT?
HOW DOES IT FEEL KNOWING YOU
GAVE UP EVERYTHING YOU BELIEVE--
ALL YOUR DREAMS-- JUST
TO FIGHT SCUM LIKE ME?
I'M NOT FIGHTING AGAINST YOU.
I'M FIGHTING FOR THEM.
PRETTY WORDS. UNFORTUNATELY, YOUR LAST.
[ Shouting ]
AAH! AAH! [ Groaning ]
GAUNT! AH, THE HELL WITH IT.
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Growling, Snarling ]
WHAT'S THE MATTER, NATIVE,
WON'T FIGHT BACK?
I DO NOT HURT WOMEN.
A MAN WITH INTEGRITY.
I COULD GO FOR YOU.
GERONIMO!
EVEN YOU HURT ME!
EVEN YOU!
NO. NO. OH, SHIT.
I AM IN YOUR DEBT STILL.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING I CAN DO...
COULD YOU LEND ME
A HAND?
I THOUGHT YOU
WERE ONLY INTO...
FUNERALS AND BODIES.
THERE'S ALWAYS
BINGO.
FEELS LIKE IT'S GOT THE WEIGHT
OF THE WORLD HANGING ON IT.
YOU WEAR IT WELL.
SURE THE SCORPS
ATE ALL OF HIM?
WELL, I MEAN, YOU KNOW,
NO PIECES LEFT TO REGENERATE?
DEAD SURE.
YOU AREN'T SORRY, ARE YOU?
WELL A PIECE OF ME
DIED WITH HIM,
BUT BETTER HIM AND ME
THAN INNOCENT PEOPLE.
LET'S GET ON OUT OF HERE.
HEYA.