(music) [ chorus vocalizing ]
(music) there's a hound dog
out in Texas (music)
(music) he says he belongs to me (music)
(music) when he's on the trail
I can follow his tail (music)
(music) through the land
of the wild country (music)
(music) he was born to roam
the mountains (music)
(music) the prairie land so free (music)
(music) he can go anywhere
run the fat from a bear (music)
(music) chase a bobcat
to his mountain lair (music)
(music) or run him up a tree (music)
(music) in the land
of the wild country (music)
(music) I call my hound dog
Savage Sam (music)
(music) he runs so wild and free (music)
(music) and if he don't know
where I am (music)
(music) he takes after me (music)
(music) through the land
of the wild country (music)
(music) we were born
to love the country (music)
(music) old Savage Sam and me (music)
(music) we were born in the west
in the land that's best (music)
(music) but folks out here
never get much rest (music)
(music) with dogs
and boys like me (music)
(music) in the land
of the wild country (music)
(music) I call my hound dog
Savage Sam (music)
(music) he runs so wild
and free (music)
(music) and if he don't know
where I am (music)
(music) he takes after me (music)
(music) through the land
of the wild country (music)
(music) we were born
to love the country (music)
(music) old Savage Sam and me (music)
(music) we were born in the west
in the land that's best (music)
(music) but folks out here
never get much rest (music)
(music) with dogs
and boys like me (music)
(music) in the land
of the wild country (music)
(music) [ vocalizing ]
Sam, you thievin' rascal,
You better
let me have that.
[ growls, barks ]
A little savage, ain't ya ?
Old Savage Sam.
All right, keep it.
But I tell you,
if Travis catches you
with that side of meat,
He's just liable to knock you
Sky west and crooked.
Dang your hide, Jumper !
Get out of there !
How many times
do I gotta tell you
to quit eatin' the sweet corn ?
Now git !
Bit off more
than you could chew, huh ?
- [ growls ]
What's for breakfast ?
Bacon and mush.
And milk, after you
finish the milkin'.
Bacon and mush.
Every mornin' in the world
it's bacon and mush.
Why don't you cook something
different once in a while...
Than bacon and mush
like Mama does ?
'cause I'm not Mama,
that's why.
Now you better
go milk that cow.
Milk the dang cow.
If you get an early start,
Maybe we can finish scrubbing
that new patch of ground
by night.
How much longer
will Mama and Papa
be in San Antone ?
Oh, could be
a couple of weeks yet.
Till Grandma dies ?
Now who said
she's gonna die ?
You know,
Grandma won't like it
up there in Heaven.
There's nothing to do all day
but squat around on a cloud,
Trying to pick
one of them old guitars.
Harps, not guitars.
Harps, guitars--
it's all the same difference.
Grandma don't know
how to play neither one.
Grandma's been sick before,
and she's got well.
Of course, maybe they'll
teach her how to play.
I don't suppose them angels
has got much else to do.
What's all this talk
about dying ?
I was just thinking,
if Grandma dies,
Mama's gonna be mighty sad.
It'll mean she'll have to
wait around until she dies...
Before she gets to
see Grandma again.
Then we'll all be tore up
'cause we won't get to see
Mama again till we die.
I don't like it.
Well, don't worry about it
and maybe you'll live longer.
Me, I ain't never gonna die.
I'm gonna live forever.
Why don't you milk that cow
so you have something
to live on ?  Now git.
Milk the cow.
Grub the brush.
Bacon and mush.
Arliss.
What ?
You know, I was just thinkin'
we could use some fresh meat.
And if we get through
with the work in time,
we might go huntin'.
Huntin' ?
You mean it ?
That's if we get through
with the work,
Which won't be likely
if you don't get to the milkin'.
I'll have that old cow
dry as a sunflower pod
afore the bacon's half fried.
(music) old Dan Tucker
was a mighty man (music)
(music) he washed his face
in a frying pan (music)
(music) combed his hair
with a wagon wheel (music)
(music) and he died of a toothache
on his heel (music)
(music) so get out the way
for old Dan Tucker (music)
(music) get out the way
(music) he's too lazy
to come to supper (music)
[ meowing ]
[ snarls ]
[ barking ]
Get him, Sam !
Fire right back, Sam !
Fire right back, boy !
Out fancy her, boy !
Go on, in and out.
She'll never lay
a horn to ya !
What on earth ?
[ Arliss ]
yee-haw !
Arliss, get that dog
outta here !
Dang you, Sam.
Now git !
Travis,
you quit taking sides !
Go on !
Get outta here !
[ Sam yelps ]
It's all right, Sam.
You had her beat.
Get outta here !
I sent you out here to milk,
not start a stampede.
I was milkin'.
[ moos ]
easy, girl, easy.
Easy, girl.  Easy, girl.
Actin' like a six year old.
I oughta cut me a sprout
and thrash your britches.
Guess you think
you're the boss,
big as Papa, huh ?
Well, Papa left me in charge
and said for you to do
what I said !
Now go calm that cow down
and finish milkin' !
All right.
Make me !
I'll bash you
with this bucket !
Wait till I get
my hands on you.
Arliss !
Ow !  Arliss !
Ow !  You quit chuckin' me,
you hear ?
I hear !
Arliss, you quit that,
or these chickens
won't lay for a month.
[ barking ]
- Sic him, Sam.  Grab him !
- Arliss !
I'll learn you
to boss me around.
Stay with him, Sam !
Arliss !  Sam, quit that.
[ Sam yelping ]
you quit hittin' my dog !
[ chuckles ]
When I get outta here,
I'll wear your tail end
to a frazzle.
Arliss !
Uncle Beck !
Say, what's going on ?
I could hear you hollering
on the next ridge.
Oh, what'd you got treed
there, a panther ?
No, sir.  Just Travis.
Travis ?  You mean
your brother Travis ?
Yes, sir.
Well, I'll be doggoned.
What you rockin' him for ?
Well, dang it,
he's getting too big
for his britches !
He's always
bossing me around.
Oh.  Tellin' you
what you can do
and what you can't, huh ?
Yes, sir.
He never lets me have
a say about nothin'.
[ scoffs ]
and he works me
like a slave.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Well, I don't blame you
for rockin' him then.
You don't ?
No, sir.
If it was me,
I wouldn't stand
for it one minute.
'cause I know what you're
going through, Arliss,
'cause your Papa...
Used to treat me
exactly the same way
when I was little.
Every minute of the day,
something like this,
"Beck, you go chop
the wood.
"Beck, go fetch the horses.
Beck, go slop the hogs.
Beck, go milk the cow."
That's why I wanted to
kill him a thousand times.
Who, Papa ?
You betcha.  Anything
makes me killin' mad...
Is some great big, lazy,
overgrown boy...
Workin' his poor little brother
half to death.
Let's get some brush.
We'll set fire to it
and burn him out of there.
Burn him out ?
Sure.
Like smokin' a possum
out of a hollow log.
You mean,
do that to Travis ?
Well, no,
that wouldn't do neither, no.
Dang fire's liable to spread
and burn the whole place down.
Well, here you go.
Use this.
[ gun clicking ]
Blast him outta there
with that.
Now, it'll make some holes
in that door you could
pitch a dog through.
But that's Travis
in there.
I know that, Arliss.
That's what you been telling me.
Now keep that arm steady,
boy.  Steady.
- [ whimpers ]
- see, now get
that front side down.
Make her set right there
in the middle of that groove.
Remember, you gotta squeeze
that trigger.
Aim a foot below
the top of that door,
and you're gonna catch him...
Right smack between the eyes
on the first shot.
You crazy or something ?
You think I wanna kill
my own brother ?
Well, Arliss, that's the general
idea I got from the way you was
whammin' them rocks in there.
Well, I didn't aim
to kill him.
Oh.  But you kill squirrels
with rocks, don't you ?
And you killed
that big turkey gobbler
with a rock.
Didn't you ?
Now, I believe if it was me,
I'd just go wash the dirt
out of that bucket...
And finish milkin' up
the cow.
Yes, sir.
Ah, ahem.
I reckon she'll give you
the milk without you
holdin' my gun on her.
Huh ?
Oh.
I reckon she will.
[ barking ]
I don't see how you do it,
Uncle Beck.
Now, any way I try to
manage him, it's like pokin'
a stick in a hornet's nest.
Well, that's generally the case
with being the older brother,
Travis.
Maybe what you gotta do
is learn to out figure him.
[ sniffs ]
hey, smells like
something's afire.
It's the bacon !
[ whinnies ]
Dang that Arliss !
Can't even milk a cow.
Hey, I picked-- whee--
I picked this up
in town for you.
A letter.
Yep, San Antone
it says.
It must be
from your Mama and Papa.
Mama says the doctor
had Grandma figured
for a goner,
But she fooled them.
That don't surprise me none.
Crowd you to kill
that little ol' lady
with a choppin' axe.
That's about the way
Mama puts it.
She says, "it will be
a while before Grandma
is back on her feet.
But she's
just doing fine."
Well, I bet on it too.
I never will forget
that little old lady
back in Sedalia.
When me and your Papa
was nothin' but
tow-shirted kids,
We couldn't swipe a peach,
turpentine a cat,
Ride the old milk calf,
nothin',
Without Grandma Bailey
swarmin' all over us,
three times a day.
[ sniffs ]
Burnt the breakfast,
didn't you ?
I got another batch started.
Mama never let
the breakfast get burnt.
Always had it
ready for me to eat,
The minute
I finished milkin'.
Now, maybe your Mama didn't
have to spend so much time
duckin' rocks neither.
I best be movin' on.
Oh, you don't aim
to eat with us ?
No thanks.
I don't blame you--
bacon and mush.
I ate early.
I got to hunt up
a missing heifer.
Probably hold up in some
thicket with a new calf.
New calf !
Golly, maybe I better
go help you hunt her.
Now you better help your brother
finish the grubbin' because
your Papa wants to sow...
That new ground
of winter wheat,
quick as he gets home.
Aw, heck !
You need any help,
you let me know, hear ?
I'll be looking in on you
every now and then.
You remember what I said now.
You got to learn to
outfigure him.
Outfigure who ?
Oh--
[ stammers ]
nobody.
Nobody particular.
Well, holler when
the bacon's fried.
I'm near starved.
Where you going ?
While you're cookin'
up the grub, I'll go
harness up Old Jumper.
He can pack in
the deer we shoot
when we go huntin'.
I said we might go when we get
the work done.  There's plenty
of time to get Old Jumper.
I need him, anyhow,
to ride to work on.
Ride ?  That field
ain't a quarter mile off.
If you think I'm gonna
do all that walkin',
then work too, you're crazy.
Be too plumb wore out
to hit a lick.
Now, confound it, Arliss, if
you're figurin' out some new--
[ clears throat ]
[ Arliss ]
figurin' out what ?
Figurin' out some new way
to make work easier,
Why, that's fine.
And takin' Old Jumper
to drag that brush,
I don't know why
I didn't think of that myself.
Well, come on, Arliss.
Go get 'em.
All right.
I'll bring along an extra rope
to clear away the brush with.
Good idea.  That's right
smart thinking, Arliss.
[ barking ]
Atta boy, Sam.
Warm up that scent, boy.
Sam's fixin' to pick up
a varmint trail.
Go get him, boy !
[ Arliss ]
nudge him out, boy.
He's in there someplace.
All right, Arliss,
she's tied.
Tote her down.
Stay with it, Sam.
You'll get him directly.
All right, Jumper, giddap.
Come on, Jumper, giddap.
Whoa, Jumper !
Dang you, whoa !
Arliss !
You and Jumper sure made
a mess out of that.
What do you mean ?
He piled the brush
right where you wanted it.
[ barking ]
It sounds like
Sam struck a hot one.
Yee-hoo !
Lookie yonder !
Yee-hoo !  Go get him, Sam !
Man, oh, man,
ain't he makin' that ol' cat
get high behind ?
One thing you can say for
old Sam, anytime he takes
to a trail, he'll hang with it,
Better than any dog
I ever heard tell of.
Come on, Travis.
We'll mount up, and we'll
jump her and follow her.
We got work to do,
remember ?
But that ol' cat's
been raiding the chicken roost.
We gotta catch him.
Sure we do.
And when Sam trees him,
we'll go right out and get him.
But, meanwhile,
we'll just keep
grubbing brush, right ?
Who ever heard tell of workin'
when you could chase a bobcat ?
Now, Arliss,
come on back here.
I'll set your britches
to smokin', you hear me ?
Travis !
Travis Coates !
Mr. Searcy.
[ chickens clucking ]
Injuns !  Injuns raiding
all over the place !
Get your gun, boy.
Get some bullets.  Break out
a fresh keg of powder !
Injuns ?
Where, at salt licks ?
Could be.  By now, they're
liable to have wiped out
the whole settlement.
Burnin', killin' scalpin'.
Draggin' poor screamin' women
off to a fate worse than death.
Lisbeth, honey,
would you mind slippin' down ?
This poor old pony
is gettin' a mite winded.
Yes, Papa.
Well, who saw the Indians,
Mr. Searcy ?
Well, I don't know.
Best I could learn...
Is they struck
at loyal valley last night.
Old Wiley crup, he come up
with 16 head of horses
missin' this mornin'.
What's that
I smell cookin', boy,
frijole beans ?
But, Mr. Searcy,
missing horses don't
have to mean Indians.
Horses can stray.
Not them horses.
Crup says Injuns got 'em.
Told Todd McDougal they did.
But he didn't
set eyes on 'em.
Wiley said it sounded
like Injuns to him, and you know
Wiley wouldn't tell a lie,
'less maybe there's
a little money involved.
[ sniffs ]
them beans just about done,
ain't they, boy ?
[ barking ]
What's that dog after,
Injuns ?
No.  Sam and Arliss
are trailin' a bobcat.
Thunder-ration, boy.
Don't you know no better
than that ?
Lettin' a helpless youngun run
footloose through them hills
just swarmin' with savages.
Them red devils are liable
to haul off and scalp
that boy any minute.
Eat that dog too,
if you ain't watchin'.
Injuns are partial
to dog eatin'.
If I was you,
I'd go get him,
Before we even bother
to set a foot
under that dinner table.
Oh, well, it might not hurt
to go get him.
Yeah, well, you just do that.
You just do that.
Lisbeth, honey,
you might ought to water
this poor old pony.
Shuck him out
a few ears of corn too.
Build back his strength
a little.
Yes, Papa.
And while you're out there
roundin' up the youngun,
I'll just be neighborly like
and go and look at them beans
of yours.
Be a cryin' shame
if they was left to burn.
[ gasps ]
Tarnation,
them beans is hot !
You know, about them Indians,
that's mostly just scare talk,
wasn't it ?
Well, you know Papa,
always trying to make things
bigger than they are.
Sometimes I wish he wouldn't,
well, you know, go on so much.
Oh, that ain't your fault.
Did you happen to hear just
what Tom McDougal did say ?
Well, now, yes.
What he told Papa was
that what Mr. Crup said
if it were ten years ago,
He'd just bet it was Indians
who stole those horses.
Yeah, that's about
what I figured.
It's been a long time
since Apaches come out of
those high mountains on a raid.
Well.
Still need to
round up Arliss, though.
I'm gonna finish that grubbin'
before sundown.
Um, would-- would you care
for a mite of company ?
I ain't seen a bobcat
in some time.
Close up, that is.
Well, yeah, sure.
Sure.
Wouldn't hurt none
to hang on to my belt.
Make more sense
than falling off.
Did you hear
about Betsy Miller
and George Floyd ?
No.  What about 'em ?
Got married
last Thursday.
Got married ?
I didn't know
they was old enough.
Oh, yes.
Betsy's eight months
older than me.
And George, well,
he's at least a few months
older than you.
That's more than old enough.
Wouldn't you figure ?
Yeah, sounds like.
My Mama and Papa
were even younger
when they got married.
[ clears throat ]
is that so ?
Oh, yes.
Mama says,
"getting married
is the best way...
For two folks to really
get to know each other."
[ barking ]
listen.
I think I hear Sam.
He's right over yonder.
[ horse whinnies ]
Well, I don't hear him now.
Me neither.
Be real quiet.
I wanna listen.
[ braying ]
that's Jumper.
There he is.
[ Arliss ]
go get him, Sam !
[ animals growling, barking ]
Arliss,
you come outta there.
Not till we get
this old bobcat, I ain't.
[ barking, growling ]
You leave that bobcat alone.
You keep messin' with him,
he's liable to eat you alive.
He can't.
I'm holdin' him off
with a stick.
Listen to him squall
when I poke him.
[ growls ]
Pesky Arliss.
Tryin' to reason with him...
Is like buttin' your head up
against a stoop and pole stoke.
[ bobcat roars ]
I'd better go in
and get him.
Sic him, Sam !
Just kill him !
That'll teach him
to leave our chickens alone.
Arliss,
you get outta there.
Travis, you leave go of me.
Not till
I get you out of here.
I ain't comin' out till
I'm darn good and ready.
Well, you get good and ready
'cause you're comin' out.
Oh, no, I ain't !
Ow !
You let go !
Quit kicking me !
Dang you, Travis,
let go !
Come on !
Arliss.
I'll learn you,
Travis Coates.
Ow !  Now cut it out !
You stop rockin' Travis,
you hear ?
Ow !
Hang on to him.
All right, Arliss.
You asked for it,
and you're gonna get it.
Dang you, Travis Coates,
when I get big,
I'm gonna fix you good.
Hold it.  Hold it !
[ men yipping ]
[ yells in native language ]
[ speaks in native language ]
[ all laughing ]
We better make
a run for it.
[ men yipping ]
Travis !
[ screams ]
You leave my brother alone !
Get him, Sam !
[ snarling ]
Chew on him, Sam.
Murderer !
[ speaks in native language ]
[ gunshots ]
Uncle Beck !
[ whooping ]
Yah !
Yah !  Yah !
Aah !
[ laughter ]
Travis !
It's all right.
They're just having
fun with him.
[ speaks in native language ]
Arliss, you gotta quit
fightin' 'em.
That little varmint
bothers me again
and I'll kill him.
And get us all killed before
we get a chance to escape.
Look out !
[ yells ]
You come back here with my hat,
you yellow-bellied coward !
Arliss, quit rilin' him.
Next time he'll be lifting
more than your hat.
So wild to get a scalp,
he'd even take it from a baby.
- Who you callin' a baby ?
- Arliss !
You've got to
quit fighting back,
do you hear me ?
Yeah, I hear.
[ speaks in native language ]
That's the one
that killed Sam.
The one
what stole my hat.
Killed Sam ?
Chopped him down
with a chunk of wood
while you were unconscious.
I tell you,
he'll pay for that.
Listen, don't start anything.
You're gonna mess up any chance
we got of gettin' away.
All right,
but I'll get him.
Travis, what's to happen to us
if we don't escape ?
Don't fret, Lisbeth,
we'll get away.
But supposin' we don't,
what then ?
Well, it's kinda hard
to figure.
They'll probably make me
into one of their slaves,
more than likely.
Oh, no !
Only reason I can figure for
them not killing me right off.
Well, I ain't
gonna be no slave,
and I'll swear to that.
No, being a youngun,
they'll probably
make you an Indian.
I'd like to see 'em try.
I'd just like to see 'em.
You just simmer down.
They ain't gonna make
no injun out of me.
Travis ?
Yes.
What do you reckon
they figure to do with me ?
I ain't really give that
proper thought.
They'll make me
some Indian's squaw,
won't they ?
Lisbeth.
That one.
He's as much as claimed me,
hasn't he ?
Say, maybe that's
the way to do it.
Do what ?
Get away.
Let's get some other injun
and that one into a fight...
Over who gets Lisbeth
for his squaw.
And in the fuss, you and me
could make a run for it.
Arliss !
Then we can hightail it
outta here and bring back help.
Maybe she won't be married yet.
Travis !
Hush up !
If they're gonna
make her a squaw anyway,
what's the harm ?
Arliss, be quiet !
Listen, Lisbeth.
Nobody's gonna touch you.
I promise.
But if you try to fight them,
they'll kill you.
I'd rather be dead
than see one of them
lay a hand on you.
Mush.
[ chattering ]
That one your Uncle Beck shot,
he's different from the others,
isn't he ?
Yeah, he's Comanche.
You can tell by his hair.
Others are Apache.
Why does he run
instead of ridin' ?
Is he crazy ?
No, it's easier to run.
Jouncin' around that horse
hurts his wounded leg.
Well, I hope
that bullet wound
bleeds him to death.
[ all laughing,
chattering ]
Look at 'em,
stuffin' their bellies.
[ chattering ]
This meat tastes funny.
Wonder what it is.
Horse meat,
more than likely.
Horse meat ?
Where's Old Jumper ?
Probably with the horses.
No, he ain't.
He ain't with the horses.
Travis, they've killed him !
They went and butchered
Old Jumper.
- Now how do you know ?
- I can't see him nowheres.
I can't eat none
of Old Jumper.
I tell you, I can't.
You don't know
it's Jumper.
If it ain't him,
where's he at ?
Well, he could have
gotten away.
- I didn't see him get away.
- You didn't see him
get butchered neither.
Now, Arliss, sit there and eat
'cause you don't know when
you're gonna get another chance.
But what if it is
Old Jumper ?
If it is Old Jumper,
he won't mind.
Jumper will know
you gotta eat.
Sure.
You know,
Jumper was a good ol' mule.
Plowed our corn,
packed in our meat.
Hauled our crops.
Drug up the logs
for the cabin, Papa said.
And now he's keeping us
from starving to death.
Do you remember the time
the hogs cut up you
and Old Yeller so bad...
And Jumper had to
bring you in home ?
Arliss, could you just
hush up about Old Jumper ?
Remember how we used to
have to tie a drag log
to his foot...
To keep him from jumpin'
into the corn ?
Sure was a good old mule.
Dang their
stinkin' hides.
Somebody's gonna pay
for killin' Old Jumper.
And I know just who.
[ men chattering ]
That oughta teach you something
about butcherin' Old Jumper.
[ speaks in native language ]
Put me down !
Gimme back my shirt !
What are they doing
to him ?
They admire his spirit.
Gonna make an Indian
out of him.
Lisbeth.
Get my knife
out of my back pocket.
How will
I ever open it ?
Bring it up to my mouth.
Shh.
[ whispers ]
Arliss.
Arliss !
Shh.  Be real quiet now.
I'm cutting you loose.
[ grumbling ]
Arliss,
you gone crazy ?
I wasn't leavin'
without my pants.
Let's git.
[ barking ]
Travis, that's Sam.
Sam !
[ barking continues ]
Sam's alive !
Come on.
Look out !
[ yelling in native language ]
- [ whinnying ]
- let me go !
You leave him alone !
No !
[ speaks in native language ]
[ Lisbeth screams ]
[ screams ]
no !  No !
[ barking in distance ]
Travis, that's Sam again !
- Aah !
- He's on the trail.
Come on, Sam.
Bring Uncle Beck !
[ yelling ]
[ barking ]
Troops, ho !
[ shouting in native language ]
Travis, look !
Forward, ho !
Wait !  Wait !
[ men shouting ]
That's a really
scared bunch of Indians.
Apaches from what
I could see through the dust.
Yeah.  Well, there's
no use chasing 'em
any farther.
I wonder what devilry
they've been up to.
Horse stealin'
it looks like.
Left by twos.  Ho.
[ panting ]
Wait !
[ screams ]
Easy, boy.
Whoa, now.
I won't hurt you now.
Hold it now.
Hold it, boy.
Easy.
[ growling ]
Sam.
Hey.  What's
the matter, Sam ?
It's me, Travis.
- [ whimpers, barking ]
- hey.
Come here,
you old hound, you.
Sure am glad
to see you, boy.
Listen, Sam.
If anything's gonna be done
for Lisbeth and Arliss,
Looks like we gotta do it.
Come on, boy.
Let's pick up that trail.
Hey !
Sam, come here.
Come here, Sam.
Come here.
Sam, now listen.
You gotta hold back
or you'll outrun me.
We gotta work together
on this or we don't
stand a chance.
All right,
let's try again.
[ barking ]
[ barking continues ]
[ panting ]
[ barking ]
Sam !  Sam !  Sam.
Sam, wait.
Sam.
Come back.
Get him off of me !
Travis !  Travis.
Quit that.  Quit that, boy.
Travis !
Take it easy now.
Easy.  Easy, Travis.
You settle down now.
Take it easy.
Settle down now.
Travis.  Travis.
Uncle Beck.
Easy now.
Easy, Travis.
We're with you now.
Gosh doggone it.
Tried--  tried to choke
a man to death.
[ Beck ]
well, get him
some water, crup.
Lisbeth, my baby girl,
is she all right ?
What about Arliss ?
Back's bad sunburned.
Them bruises look ugly too.
Best grease 'em.  Todd,
get that bacon rind out of
my saddlebag.
Here, son.
I have a clean shirt
in my saddlebag.
- Here.  Easy.  Easy now.
- You kill any of them
cutthroat savages ?
[ Wiley ]
they still got my horses ?
- Them thievin' devils.
- Sam.  We gotta get Sam !
Sam ?
He got a hot trail
on them Indians.
We gotta catch up with that dog
before it gets dark.
You think you can make it ?
He's gotta make it.
I tell you, them red devils so
much as touch my little girl--
- Of course I can make it.
- Let's go then.  You can
eat while we're riding.
Now hold on a minute, Beck.
We got a little problem here.
Seven men
and six horses.
Ride double.
Why, it's gonna be tough enough
of keepin' up with that dog
ridin' single.
And I say let's leave the boy
here and we'll pick him up
on the way back.
I'm goin'.
Now lookie here, boy.
I won't hold nobody up.
I'll take it afoot.
Afoot ?
Sure, I'll run alongside
and hang onto somebody's saddle,
like the Comanche.
Comanche ?  I thought
you said them was Apaches.
- They are Apache, all but one.
- Whoever heard of a Comanche
runnin' with Apache ?
What difference does it make ?
Our job's to find 'em.
[ pack ]  Beck's right.
Find 'em and kill 'em.
You say that Comanche kept up
hanging on the saddle ?
Yes, sir.
Well, if he can do it,
so can we.
Get up on that horse
and finish eatin'.
I'll take the first turn.
If we don't catch up with them
before they get to the mountains
we're never gonna find 'em.
Wiley, uh, I could use
a chaw myself.
Come on.
[ coughing ]
all right, who's next ?
I believe I am, Beck.
[ Wiley ]
no, you ain't.
Yeah, it's your turn.
Bud Searcy here's the
only one that ain't run yet.
Well, is that a fact ?
I reckon I lost count.
You mind totin' this for me ?
This old gun ain't no good,
Searcy.  An old pony'd get
swayback just a packin' it.
No good ?  Did I ever tell
about the time I blew a hole
through two savages...
Ridin' side by side
a thousand yards away ?
[ chuckles ]
never did see two more
surprised Injuns, till today.
Not to mention the buffalo
a-runnin' alongside 'em.
- Come on, bud.
- Beck, he's too old to run.
Who's too old ?
Happen to know I'm eight year
younger than pack underwood.
Yeah.  Eight years younger
and a hundred pounds heavier.
Why, 50 yards on foot
and your eyeballs would be
a-stickin' out on their stems.
Crup, if he wants to run,
let him run.  Now let's git.
Too old.  Did I ever tell you
about the time I run
a deer down on foot ?
Save your wind, Searcy.
[ screams ]
Look at that.
Could be Sam.
- Uncle Beck, it's Sam !
- All right, hold it.
Hold it.  No shootin'.
Beat 'em off
with your ropes.
[ screaming ]
[ whooping ]
Hyah !  Hyah !
Get out of here !
Get out of there !
Hyah !  Hyah !
Go on !  Get up !
Get up !
Hyah !  Hyah !
Go on !  Get out of here !
Get !  Get up there !
Get up !
Easy, boy.
Good old Sam.
[ whimpers ]
Let me see what
they did to you.
Cut him up much ?
Well, they chewed up
his paw pretty bad.
Oh.
Think he can
take the trail ?
I don't know.
Try him.
- All right, Sam.
Come here, boy.
- [ whimpers ]
Come to me.
- Come on, Sam.
- [ whimpers ]
What are we gonna
do now, Beck ?
I say leave him here
and let's get to ridin'.
The trail's gonna be tougher
to follow from here on,
especially at night.
Without that dog
we ain't got a prayer.
But that hound
can't even walk.
Hand him up here, Travis.
Wiley crup, you done
that on purpose.
Ah, quit your "bellerin'."
Searcy, a good bath
never hurt you none.
Man, now I guess
I seen everything.
Blowhards and pot hounds
allowed to ride while
good men are left afoot.
- All right, who runs now ?
- Reckon I do.
- You reckon you can ?
- Sure.
Let's git.
Travis.
Yes, sir ?
Take Sam down and see
if he can pick up the trail.
Supposin' he can't ?
He will.
Go, Sam.
Please, Sam.
Arliss, Sam.
Go find Arliss.
Come on, Sam.
[ growls ]
[ barks ]
- That's it, Sam !
- Stick with it, Sam.
Travis, go on,
pick him up.
We're on the right trail.
What'd I tell ya ?
[ barking continues ]
still say we're puttin' a heap
of Faith in a lame dog.
Right now a lame dog's
all we got.
Don't tell me
about right and wrong.
I'm not trying to
tell you anything, pack.
Then don't argue with me
about injun killing.
I wasn't arguing.
I merely said the reason
the Indians fight so hard...
Is the white man's
crowding in,
killing off the buffalo.
That's all.
Them Injuns don't own the land,
they don't own the buffalo.
Maybe not, but after thousands
of years they feel as though
they have a right to it.
They're gonna learn different.
And I learn 'em.
Sometimes hard to tell
who the savages are.
Dirty injun lover !
Quit that !
Quit it out, I said !
He can't talk to me
that way !
I said, quit it.  We go fightin'
amongst ourselves, we're never
gonna catch no Injuns.
Travis, you spell
crup a while.
It's about time.
My feets wore off clean up
to the hipbone.
I didn't mean
to get him so upset.
I know that.
I never saw a man
so full of hate.
Well, there's things that can
sometimes breed hate in a man.
Not like that.
You're new out here, white.
You're gonna find
this is a hard country.
You go to fightin' it,
and it fights you right back
every inch of the way.
Ain't Virginia.
I realize that, Beck.
I mean, out here...
A man puts in
a crop of corn and...
You bust your back
watering it and hoeing it,
And just before harvest
it gets set on by hoppers.
They hate the land.
And you got about 50 head
of cattle ready for market.
Then blight comes along
and kills 'em all off.
You get so you hate everythin'.
But not other people
the way he does.
Look, a couple of years ago,
pack come home--
He come one day and he found
his cabin burnt to the ground...
And his wife
and three kids was killed.
All of 'em was scalped.
And he about went crazy
grievin'.
That can turn into hate
real easy.
Come on, Sam.
That's a boy.
I just thought
you ought to know.
Come on.
[ Wiley ]
all right, let's go.
[ barking ]
Look it.
- They buried that fire
and let out in a hurry.
- How long do you figure ?
It couldn't be long.
The sand's still warm.
If we're that close behind
them red devils, now's the time
to crowd in.
That's what we're gonna do.
Travis, go get Sam.
[ barking ]
Come here, Sam.
- Whose turn is it to run ?
- It's mine, Beck.
Notice how many snakes and
spiders are movin' about ?
Yeah.
Come on.  Let's go.
[ birds cooing ]
If it wasn't the middle
of the day, I'd say those birds
are heading for their roost.
They are.
It's fixin' to rain.
Are you sure ?
Look it there.
Any time you see one of them
old boys on the prowl...
This far from water,
you can bet it's gonna rain.
Well, if it rains,
what happens to the trail ?
We'll worry about that
when it rains.
[ thunder rumbling ]
That's hail !
Crop 'em up behind Todd.
Head for them rocks !
Head for that cave !
[ thunderclap ]
This ain't the safest place
in the world, but
it's better than nothin'.
Not much.  If a ten-foot head
of water come a boilin' down
out of them hills yonder,
It'll drown every last
one of us afore we get a chance
to turn around and spit.
Wiley, if you knows of
a better place, why don't
you go crawl into it ?
[ thunderclap ]
We ain't through yet,
Travis.
How could Lisbeth
and Arliss live through
all this ?
Ah, them Indians can find
shelter, you can bet on that.
That's right, Travis.
They're a lot wilder,
know more about
the country than us.
Sure.
But the trail will be
completely wiped out.
We know they're headed
right for them mountains, and
Sam can pick up the trail again.
Man alive, Coates.
Pickin' up a trail after a Storm
like that might take days.
- I'll worry about that, crup.
- How long you figure these old
wore-out horses gonna last ?
Till they go down.
Then what ?
Then we're gonna
take out afoot.
- Afoot ?
- That's what I said.
Well, if that's your plan
you can count me out.
Figure on goin' home,
you can walk.
- Try and take my horse ?
- I wouldn't try it.
I'd just take it.
Coates,
I rode in here
on my horse.
I aim to ride out on him
anytime I please.
So don't nobody
try and stop me.
Wiley, you damn move
a hair...
And I'll be obliged
to blow a hole clean
through your backbone.
And this close
that ain't no brag.
[ thunderclap ]
You ain't got the gall.
Gentlemen, would you kindly
step out from behind Mr. Crup ?
Thank you, gentlemen.
Now, Wiley, would you care
to test my gall ?
That's better.
- It stopped !
- Well, let's get movin'.
What are we gonna do
about crup ?
Nothin'.
Aren't we gonna take his guns ?
He can't fight Indians
without a gun.
You old jackass, you.
Wiley, I could use a chaw.
Wiley, I'm askin' you
to do me a favor.
I want you to loan me
a chaw of tobacco.
[ chuckles ]
thanks.
Uncle Beck,
wait !
[ whimpering ]
go get 'em, Sam.
Hunt it out, boy.
It's all up to you now.
- Do you think he's got it ?
- I know he's got it.  Stay
with it, boy.  Stay with it.
[ Beck ]
come on in.  He's got it !
[ barking ]
Uncle Beck.
Uncle Beck,
we're gettin' close.
You sure ?
Yes, sir.
I'm real sure.
[ Beck ]
Sam.  Sam.
Here, boy.  Sam !
He's liable to run right
into them Injuns.
Y'all wait here.
Wait ?  I came to kill Injuns,
not to wait.
Beck said to wait.
Now I reckon we best do it.
Sam !
[ barking ]
Here, Sam.  Sam.
Come here.
Come here, Sam.
Come here, you.
Hold it.  Hold it.
Now quit that.
Quit it, Sam.
You bite me, I'm gonna
bite you right back, you fool.
[ whimpering ]
okay.
You get your mind set
on one thing, you're stubborn
as a one-eyed mule, ain't ya ?
All right.  Let's see
what's on the other side
of that hill.
[ men chattering ]
[ snarling ]
Travis.
You'll be needin'
some extra cartridges.
Thank you.
Did you see 'em ?
In the draw,
back of that hill.
Well, let's go.
Now wait.
Now just wait !
[ whimpering ]
You wait and listen.
They're fixin' to split up.
The only chance we got
is to keep 'em from gettin'
to their horses.
So I'm gonna ride in and
try and stampede their herd.
Y'all cover me.
Ya understand ?  Travis.
You take Sam and tie him up.
Put a muzzle on him
so he can't give us away.
Yes, sir.
White, you and Todd
circle that ridge.
Come up behind 'em.
Now, I'm countin' on the two
of you to keep 'em from gettin'
up to them mountains.
Hold your fire until you see me
come into that valley because
we got to surprise 'em.
Crup, you and bud
take cover down at the mouth
of that draw.
That way you can keep 'em
from gettin' out into
the open country again.
Once the shootin' starts,
we'll catch 'em in a cross fire.
Now, go on.
Come on, Bud.
Let's go.
And where do I go ?
You stick with me, pack.
Get up here.
[ snarling ]
Boy, Sam sure hates
bein' left out.
Well, he done his part.
The rest of it's
up to us now.  Come on.
We'll belly crawl from here.
Now, look, Travis.
When this thing opens up,
it's gonna go fast.
So you gotta be ready
for anything and everything.
Ya understand ?
Yes, sir.
Now, remember one thing.
We're out here to get Arliss
and Lisbeth back.
If we got to kill some Indians
to do it, that's the way
it's gonna be.
Now, when you go into a fight,
there ain't but one thing
you can bet on.
That's you're gonna be scared.
You feel that way too ?
Man and boy,
it's all the same.
[ man laughing ]
[ speaks in native language ]
They're fightin'
over Lisbeth.
Dirty red savages.
Hold it.
Hold, hold it, pack.
Let 'em get good and caught up
in their fightin'.
It'll give me a better chance
to stampede their horses.
Stick 'im !
There's my little girl.
Hold it !  Hold it !
You heard what Beck said.
What you waitin' for ?
[ men shouting ]
I'm gonna ride in now.
Y'all give me cover.
You dirty,
murderin' savages.
murderin' savages !
No !
[ gunshot ]
Travis !
[ groaning ]
[ whooping ]
Look out !
[ shouting in native language ]
Hyah !
[ whooping ]
[ screams ]
Uncle Beck !
I got him, Uncle Beck !
I got him !
You yellow-bellied varmint,
I'll fix you !
Who's gonna help you now,
you skinny little Apache ?
[ barking ]
[ snarling ]
Get him, Sam !
- Lisbeth !
- Papa !
Shoot him.
Shoot him !
He's out of our range,
but that old cannon
might reach him.
Give me it !
Let go.
Let go !
Shoot.  Shoot.
Ya did it.  Ya did it !
Man alive, what a shot !
Yeah.  We'll never hear
the end of this.
Oh, Travis !
[ sobbing ]
[ whinnies ]
[ grunts ]
[ snarling ]
Chase him clean
out of Texas, Sam !
[ barking ]
[ Beck ]
Arliss !
Uncle Beck !
Sam !
Here, Sam !
Come on, boy.
Did you see us fightin',
me and that old injun ?
I sure did.
Boy, we done that injun
under, didn't we ?
Well, you had a lot
of practice on your brother.
We sure cleaned
his plows good.
All the time I was worryin'
about you, I should've been
worryin' about them Injuns.
Come on up here.
[ grunts ]
Come on, Sam.
Papa ?
Papa, please
open up your eyes.
Mr. Searcy ?
- What's the matter with Bud ?
- Mr. Crup, the water, please.
It's a-comin'.
What's wrong with him ?
Dead, most likely.
Arliss.
Papa, please wake up.
- His pulse seems all right.
- Ah, they ain't nothin'
wrong with him.
Mr. Crup !
What happened ?
You made that brag shot,
and then you keeled over,
you old fake.
From hunger.
Weren't nice of you pourin'
that water on me, crup.
Boy, you'll never
live this down.
Two baths in one year.
Papa, are you all right ?
A mite feverish.
Tell you what, honey.
Why don't you start up a fire
and cook your Papa up
some hot grub ?
Bud, we ain't got time for that.
We gotta round up them horses
and get on home.
[ Arliss ]
come on, Sam.
What about the rest
of them hostiles out there
playin' dead in the grass ?
Pack, we got Arliss
and Lisbeth.  That's all
we come out here for.
I ain't leavin'
till I make sure every one
of them savages is dead.
Well, you're gonna have to
kill 'em all by yourself,
'cause the rest of us
goin' home.
Anytime you feel strong enough
to ride by yourself,
you just say so.
Oh, yes, Travis.
Just as soon as I feel strong
enough, I'll let you know.
Crup, did you see how
steady-handed I was...
When I lifted
my trusty old 55 and--
Bud, I seen how lucky you was,
and I don't wanna hear
no more about it.
Mr. White.
Mr. White, I bet down
in Virginia,
You never did see a shot
like the one I put through
that injun.
'course it weren't nothin'
unusual.  There were a time
once I--
Excuse me, Mr. Searcy.
I believe Beck needs me.
Hello, little Arliss.
Well, hi, Mr. Searcy.
Well, boy, I guess you must be
powerful grateful to me.
I run halfway across Texas
on foot just to save you
and my little girl.
Oh.  Mr. Searcy,
did you see me and old Sam
when we took on that injun ?
No, I didn't.
But I don't reckon you was
watchin' when I made that shot ?
Well, no, I wasn't.
But let me tell you.
I busted him with
some rocks, and then Sam,
he nailed him good.
And afore we got through
with that poor old injun,
I'll bet he wishes
he never even thought
of runnin' off with me.
Now look, Arliss.
It don't seem proper for a boy
to brag on hisself.
Why, this ain't no brag,
Mr. Searcy.
Every word
I'm about to tell you
is the gospel truth.
You see, the day we was caught,
Travis and Lisbeth was scared,
And Sam, he was hurt.
So I had to start out
fightin' them Injuns
all by myself.
There was one injun took
a particular dislikin' to me
right from the start,
So I knew I had to
fix him proper.
See, I had this little plan
right up here in my head,
And one day
when he wasn't lookin',
Why, I got me a club
and I busted it right
over his head.
Then dang them, they threw me
right in a pond, but I fought
'em off just the same.
You know, I never will forget
the day they killed
and ate Old Jumper.
I picked me up a tree branch
and clubbed the injun right
over the head and laid him low.
Then danged if I didn't
have to fight off
half a dozen of 'em.
I'd have licked 'em too
if one of them hadn't--
Sure you don't wanna come
to the ranch and get some grub ?
Nope, I'll just be helpin'
crup drive those horses
back to his place.
Then I'll be for wantin'
to get back home.
I reckon.
Well, uh, you tell the rest
of 'em I'm beholden.
It was just somethin'
that had to be done.
It was then and there they
decided to make an injun out
of me, 'cause of my bravery.
And I'll tell you somethin'
else, Mr. Searcy--
I can't wait to hear it, boy.
I was just gettin' ready
to escape when Uncle Beck
come down that hill...
Just a rippin'
and a tearin'.
Thought we'd never
see this place again.
It looks good, don't it ?
Well, bud, you wanna come in
and have a little bite to eat ?
I think I better.
I'm hungry, and my ears
plumb wore out.
I'll finish my story
later, Mr. Searcy.
It do got a finish, don't it ?
Yes, sir.  I was savin'
the best part for last.
[ mule braying ]
Jumper !
Jumper, you're alive !
We didn't eat you after all.
[ barking ]
I'm so glad.
You don't know how I missed ya
or how happy I am to see ya.
How many times do
I gotta tell you to keep out
of this here corn patch ?
- Now get, you ornery mule !
- [ barking ]
Dang mule !
[ Travis ]
let me help you down.
Thank you.
[ whistling ]
Well, I guess I better
go fix some grub.
No, Travis.
Cookin' is woman's work.
You go fetch some wood.
He's clean hooked, Bud.
She's planted his corn
for good.
Yeah.  Funny thing,
I never could learn for sure
what my little Lisbeth
liked in him.
Must've asked her
a thousand times.
She never let me know.
But now I can see for myself.
He must put her in mind of me.
You ?
When I was his age.
Oh.
'course I've never been
"tooken" by them Injuns.
Much too smart for that.
You was better lookin' too ?
Well, not much.
Maybe a mite.
But I was a much better horseman
and marksman as you can plainly
see from that shot I made.
- Yeah, that was dandy.
- [ snarling ]
[ yelping ]
Stay with him, boy !
Arliss.  Arliss !
He's quite a boy.
Yep.  Kind of reminds me
of me when I was a boy.
Sam !  Go get him, Sam !
Nail him, boy.  You got him !
Go get him, Sam !
Eat him up !
Get him, Sam !
Eat him up, boy !
(music) we were born in the west
in the land that's best (music)
(music) but folks out here
never get much rest (music)
(music) with dogs
and boys like me (music)
(music) in the land (music)
(music) of the wild country (music)
}}