'Custer is dead,
and around the guidon of
the immortal 7th cavalry
lie 212 officers and men.'
'The Sioux and Cheyenne
are on the warpath.'
'By military telegraph,
news of the Custer massacre is flashed
over the miles to the south west.'
'By stagecoach,
to the settlements and farms under
threat of an Indian uprising.'
'Pony Express riders know that
another defeat like Custer's
would stop the wagon trains from
crossing the plains for years.'
'From Canada to the Rio Bravo
10,000 Indians  - Kiowa, Comanche,
Arapaho, Sioux and Apache,
under Sitting Bull and Crazy
Horse, Gull, and Crow King
unite in a common war against
the United States Cavalry.'
Ho!
Come on, men!
Is that Major Cheadle, the paymaster?
Yeah. Looks like we ain't gonna
get paid for another three months.
BUGLE CALL
'And wherever the flag rises
over some lonely army post,
there may be one man, one captain,
fated to wield the sword of destiny.'
- Good morning, sir! 5.42, sir!
- 5.41!
And a lovely day it is,
sir. Colder than blazes.
Mrs Jefferson's had her baby.
The stagecoach run from here
to Sudrow Wells has been halted.
There's a despatch rider
from Paradise River patrol -
Private McKenzie's been shot.
A boy or a girl?
(COUGHS) It's a little trooper, sir.
When does the stagecoach stop?
It's finished. No
more stagecoach, sir.
McKenzie
- is he dead?
Yes, sir.
Oh. Good man, McKenzie.
Would have made corporal
in five or six years.
(SNIFFS) Your breath
smells like a hot mince pie.
Oh, Captain, darlin', I took
the pledge after Chepota -
And Bull Run, Gettysburg, and Shiloh.
And St. Patrick's
Day. And 4th of July.
- Oh, Captain, darlin' - -
Beats me why you hide the stuff.
Six more days.
Six more days and I retire.
The army won't be the
same when we retire, sir.
It's always the same.
The sun and the moon change,
the army knows no seasons.
We're in our prime and
they're retiring us.
It's an abuse of the
tax-payers' money.
And you've only ever
paid whisky tax. Ready?
Ready, sir!
Morning, gentlemen.
BOTH: Good morning, sir!
Well... carry on.
Good morning, Mr Allen!
Ho!
Mr Cohill...
Inspection.
That's Tyree and the
Paradise River patrol.
Ya.
- Report, Sergeant.
- I found him dead of a gunshot wound.
- Where?
- Near Red Butte, sir.
Horses are about to give in, sir.
Money box is gone, sir.
Cheadle?
What do you make of the wound, Doctor?
I'll need an hour, Major.
Fetch him to hospital.
- It's not Kiowa.
- No.
Nor Comanche nor Arapaho.
Not with those colours.
(CLEARS THROAT) Sir?
OK, put in your two cents worth.
Sir, these yellow, white and red arrows
are the sign of the Southern Cheyenne.
Bannocks and Snakes
use the same colours.
That's very true, sir. But look
at the clan mark on this arrow.
It's the sign of the dog.
It's from the bow of a
Southern Cheyenne dog soldier.
What would the Cheyenne
be doing this far south?
That's isn't my department, sir.
- Alert the post, Sergeant.
- Yes, sir!
- Get some rest, Tyree.
- Thank you, sir.
BUGLE CALL
Just a moment, Mr
Pennell, if you please.
Lieutenant, the post is
closed. Sorry, Miss Dandridge.
Sorry!
Mr Cohill, haven't you anything better
to do than run around being obnoxious?
If you have any
complaints about my orders,
submit them in writing
to Major Allshard.
Duplicate or triplicate?
- Don't be a spoilsport.
- That's what he is.
Just because I wouldn't go on
a picnic with you last Sunday.
Drive on, Ross!
- I'll arrest you.
- You wouldn't dare.
Someone arresting you, Miss Dandridge?
Lieutenant Cohill is ordering me -
- Sir, I was - - You're
at attention, Mr Cohill.
Proceed.
I don't wanna make a scene, Captain. I'm
sure that Mr Cohill is a fine officer.
I know his father, General Cohill.
But Lieutenant Cohill thinks Lieutenant
Pennell hasn't rank enough for me.
- If I could explain - -
You're at attention, Mr Pennell.
Do you wish to further
amplify your complaint?
Complaint? Oh, I'm not complaining.
Why, I love Fort Starke, and I
simply adore the entire cavalry!
- Our pleasure, ma'am.
- Yes, indeed.
Mr Cohill, wipe that grin off
your face. You have the floor.
Sir, I have denied Mr Pennell
permission to leave the post.
And for what purpose did
you wish to leave the post?
- Picnicking, sir.
- Picnicking?
Picnicking, Miss Dandridge?
Where? In St. Louis?
No, by the waterfall. I'm sorry -
Never apologise, mister,
it's a sign of weakness.
Mr Cohill, I see no reason why Mr
Pennell should not go picnicking.
Very good, sir.
Thank you, Captain Brittles.
But, Miss Dandridge, Mr Cohill
was right to stop you going out,
under the present emergency.
So, may I escort you to your quarters?
You may proceed with
your picnic, Mr Pennell.
You may pass Lieutenant
Pennell, Sergeant.
Pass Lieutenant Pennell!
Where are you having your picnic?
I'll tell you - New York, in about two
months, with Olivia on my arm.
And I won't be wearing any blue suit!
Ya!
REVEILLE
Here's the last report
on George Custer's outfit.
212 dead on the Little Big Horn.
Headquarters expects
hard and bloody winter.
Sitting Bull preaching holy war.
Take all necessary precautions.
Here's the list. I expect
you knew most of them.
George Armstrong Custer...
Tom Custer...
Austin Custer...
Calhoun...
Carp...
Crittenden...
Harrington...
Keogh...
Miles Keogh?
Well, Mary, only six more days to go,
and your old Nathan
will be out of the army.
I haven't decided what I'll do yet.
Somehow I just can't picture myself
back there on the banks of the Wabash,
rocking on the front porch.
Well, I've been thinking
I'll maybe push on west.
New settlements. California.
We had some sad news today, Mary.
George Custer was killed
and his whole command.
Miles Keogh among them.
You remember Miles.
Happy-go-lucky
Irishman...
who used to waltz so well with you.
Yeah, I know, I guess
I was a little jealous.
Never could waltz, myself.
Well, I'll take a trip out in the morning
- Cheyennes are around.
I'm gonna pick up the patrols
and drive them back north.
Probably be my last mission, Mary.
Hard to believe, isn't it?
Hard to believe.
I hope I'm not intruding, Captain,
but I've watched you come
out here to your family and...
So, I...
So, I brought you this.
Well...
I appreciate this very much.
It's called Cyclamen. It's a Greek
word. It means 'rabbit's ears.'
My wife called them Flaming Arrows.
She was... she was fond of gardening.
I'm sorry I made such a fool of
myself at the gate this morning.
You made a fool out of
two young lieutenants.
That's never against the rules.
- Then I'm forgiven?
- Ah! Forgiven!
Well, goodnight, Captain.
Goodnight, miss. Thank you.
She's a nice girl.
Reminds me of you.
REVEILLE
- Time, sir!
- Alright.
Well, old comrade, last patrol, eh?
Aye, the last of many, sir.
- Five more.
- Three more.
- Five more!
- Three more!
- Five! Can't you count?
- Three weeks before I retire, sir.
Oh. Days, weeks, what's the difference?
Are you going to stand there all morning?
- I'm sorry.
- Don't apologise...
BOTH: It's a sign of weakness.
- Ready?
- Ready, sir!
- Good morning.
- Morning
- Hochbauer.
- Good morning, sir.
- Once again we ride, eh?
- Yes, sir.
Morning, men.
- What's this? Hochbauer?
- Yes, sir?
- What's this?
- By order of Major Allshard, sir.
- There's no wagon goes on this patrol.
- Orders, sir.
- Orders, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Huh.
Morning, sir.
- Side-saddle,
Riley? - Yes, sir.
Ya!
Side-saddle! Major
Allshard, what in blazes -
Hold it! I know
- the wagon.
Yes, a wagon full of women's junk.
I can't hamper this
patrol with a wagon.
I'm sending my wife and her niece
with you, as far as Sudrow's Wells,
where they'll take the stage.
- That is an order, Captain.
- I protest.
- I expected you to. Put it in writing.
- I intend to.
I sat up half the night with this.
I can't keep the Dandridge girl here
- she ain't army.
Yes, for these reasons...
- Coffee?
- One... No. Yes!
There's a party of Cheyenne dog
soldiers raiding this territory.
I think -
- How many Rs in territory?
- Two.
Men, I want you to pay strict
attention to what I say.
There's gonna be
women with this column,
and I want you men
to watch them words.
Watch them words!
Watch them grammar!
Whose dog is this?
Nice dog. Irish setter.
Poor Abby says everyone will
think she's running away.
It's gonna be tough on me
- I'll be a bachelor all winter.
And in conclusion, I respectfully protest
the decision of my commanding officer,
to saddle this troop with
his female relations...
- One L.
- In this critical hour.
Signed Nathan
Brittles... and so forth.
Sounds very good, Nathan.
Give it to me, I'll file it.
- Hochbauer!
- Yes, sir.
I know this is a hard decision
for you. Gonna miss Abby.
I hate to hamstring you,
but you will be careful?
- Mac!
- Oh, forget it.
As you were, Hochbauer.
Well, here I am, all ready.
How did Nathan take the idea
of old iron-pants riding along?
- Under protest, my dear.
- Written protest, Abby, of course.
It's always my pleasure
to escort old iron-pants.
Well, as long as you're going -
That is the damn blastedest outfit
ever! Quincannon's old breeches.
Yes.
- Morning, Mr Cohill.
- Morning.
- I hope you approve of my uniform.
- Yes, indeed.
It's very lovely, Olivia.
So, Ross has branded you
with his yellow ribbon?
How do you know it
isn't for you, mister?
I'd be very happy if I thought
it were for me. Very happy indeed.
- Good morning!
- Trooper Dandridge reporting, sir.
Well, a proper trooper! Right
pretty, don't you think, Mr Cohill?
Yes, sir.
A yellow ribbon. Do you know
what that means in the cavalry?
- A sweetheart.
- It does?
- Who's it for?
- For you of course, Captain Brittles.
For me! I'll make these
young bucks jealous.
Good morning, Flint.
You look nice. I hope Ross
notices that yellow ribbon.
I hope you're wearing
that yellow ribbon for me.
Who else would I be wearing it for?
Right, by twos.
Yo!
MUSIC: Round her neck
She wore a yellow ribbon
She wore it in the winter
And the merry month of May
When I asked her
'Why the yellow ribbon?"
She said, "It's for my lover
who is in the cavalry."
Cavalry!
She said, "It's for my lover,
who is in the cavalry."
Cavalry!
She said, "It's for my lover,
in the US cavalry." END
Report.
I trailed Mr Rynders buckboard, sir.
About a mile below the painted
pole, he met two men in a wagon.
- Do you know who they were?
- No, it didn't seem prudent to inquire.
Why do you think they're so far south?
Well, that ain't my department.
We'll probably pick them
up on the next go round.
- Take the point.
- Yes, sir.
- Sergeant?
- Yes, sir?
Ride through that pass.
Romantic, isn't it, Miss Dandridge?
Guidons gaily fluttering,
bronzed men lustily singing,
horses prancing,
bunions aching.
Must you always be
so vulgar, Mr Cohill?
The cavalry doesn't
go in for refinements.
Cavalry! Silly business of dismounting
and walking every hour or so.
- It's like being in the infantry.
- We would be, if tired out our mounts.
You could ride in the wagon.
Army wagons don't have springs.
The men would rather
have finger bowls.
I think that's terribly
funny, Mr Cohill -
...greens and milk.
Oh, the army!
I planted 24 gardens, the
first 10 years of our marriage.
We never stayed long enough
to see a single bloom.
Could I ride back along the line? I'd
rather share the dust with Mr Pennell.
You've already thrown
enough dust in his eyes!
Mr Cohill, relieve Mr
Pennell of the rear guard.
Yes, Sir!
Are you enjoying your walk, darlin'?
Oh, yes. Yes, I am.
Yo!
Hold!
Can you make em out?
They look like Arapaho.
They're moving the whole village
- wagons, lodges, and all.
Well...
I don't know where you got your brains,
but God must have given you those eyes.
They're Arapahos alright
- heading the same way we are.
Now, why would they be moving on
Sudrow's Wells? Answer me that.
My mother didn't raise her sons to make
guesses in front of yankee captains.
Well, I'd soon find out if...
Oh, I can't risk it with those women.
- Officers' call.
- Yes, sir.
- Are those hostile indians?
- Rejoin the column.
- Captain Brittles!
- Get back in line.
I don't like it, Mr Cohill,
I don't like it at all.
Arapahos?
We're giving them a wide berth.
- Go through Twin Forks.
- But we'll lose half a day!
The ladies may miss the stage.
Would you rather they
missed their scalps?
- Take the column, Mr Cohill.
- Yes, Sir.
- I'm sorry -
- Oh, shut up!
You're relieved, Mr
Cohill. I'm taking over.
The old man hasn't spoken
to me in three hours.
The ladies may miss the stage.
You'll be lucky if he
talks to you in three days.
- It'll be his last chance to.
- Yeah?
So, you're still going to resign?
- Through channels.
- As adjudant, I'll tear it up!
Every second lieutenant can resign three
times during his first tour of duty.
You forget I don't have
to depend on cavalry pay.
That's right, I had
forgotten your silver spoon.
But I bet Miss Olivia
Dandridge hasn't!
Do you want to pull your blouse?
Hold your coat, Lieutenant Pennell.
Why don't you let Ross Pennell
go? He could be a fine officer.
- You're not his guardian -
nor am I. - I'll say it anyway.
Ross is a spoilt, rich kid.
The army's his only hope.
So, if you can't take it, let him be!
Buffalo!
- Buffalo, Mr Cohill.
- Yes, sir.
First time the herd's been this
far north since... summer of '68.
- You never saw a buffalo, Mr Pennell?
- No, sir.
Oh.
Before your time.
Sergeant, Quincannon!
Escort the ladies forward, please.
Aunt Abbey, that's really buffalo!
Yes, buffalo.
Aye, that's a lot of buffalo.
It reminds me of the old days
- when whisky was 50 cents a gallon.
- Sure hanker for some buffalo meat.
- I ain't never had none.
Beans is safer!
You mark my word, there'll be indians
around that herd thicker than flies.
What's your thinking? And don't
tell me it ain't your department.
Well, Captain, I ain't getting paid
for thinking. I read it this way.
If I was a young,
hot-blood, like Red Shirt,
anxious to show off in front
of them Cheyenne dog soldiers,
I'd be down at the counsel fire,
telling them I made the medicine
that brought back the buffalo.
I'd tell them about the Great Spirit.
How us Indians should all stick together
- quit quarrelling.
Join our Cheyenne brothers,
who took General Custer and drove
out the rest of the yankee soldiers.
That's what I'd tell 'em.
Of course, I'm just guessing, Captain.
Well...
Of course, I'm just
guessing too, Sergeant.
But if I was an indian
agent, maybe named Mr Rynders,
and I'd met a couple of men
who might be gun-runners,
I'm guessing I'd be mighty close
to that counsel fire of Red Shirt's,
ready to do a land office
business in repeating rifles.
Well, why don't we take the whole -
Miss Dandridge and her chaperone.
Keep it up! That's all
I ask! Just keep it up!
Sergeant, make for the Paradise
River. Pick up our patrol there.
Go to Sudrow's Wells and hold
the stagecoach for the ladies.
- Yes, sir!
- Tell them I've been delayed.
- Take the column, Mr Cohill.
- Yes, sir.
Ho-oh!
Ladies to the rear!
Mr Cohill?
Ya!
GUNSHOT
GUNFIRE
First two sets of fours
- forward!
Take the column, Mr Cohill.
GUNSHOT
GUNFIRE
It's Quayne's patrol.
Men, hold your fire!
Sound recall.
Yo!
Yo! Over here!
Alright, Mike? Alright, my boy?
WHOOPING
Commence firing, men.
Shoot over their heads.
Help him up. Men?
Corporal Quayne, sir, reporting
with Paradise River patrol.
- Arapahos jumped us at sundown.
- It was Red Shirt himself, Captain!
Shut up, McCarthy! Quiet
while I'm making this report!
Easy, Mike, easy.
They had us ringed at night.
We got away.
Made it to the relief point,
but you weren't there, Sir.
I wanted to be there,
Corporal. Proceed.
They flushed us at dawn, Sir,
and I got this.
That's a good, clear report.
It'll show on your record.
You'll get that extra stripe.
Thank you, Sir.
Sound for the wagon.
Easy, fella.
Good work, McCarthy. Good work, men!
You'll get you some whisky,
Quayne. You'll be alright.
Halt!
- What's happened?
- Quayne's hurt.
Cheyennes, laddie.
Same ones that killed them yankee
soldiers with General Custer.
WHOOPING
Easy, boy. Let's go.
The arrow head's right over
Quayne's heart. It's got to come out.
It's a risky operation. Can you halt?
You know I can't.
For 30 minutes, 20
minutes. For a man's life -
I couldn't give you five
minutes if it were my own son.
Quayne will have to
take a soldier's risks.
He knows that. I'm
the one who's begging.
I'll give you all I can.
Troop halt! Dismount leads.
Thank you, Nathan.
Hold your cap in the ranks.
Heinrich, as slow as you can.
Now, Mike, another slug.
After you, ma'am, if you please.
Down it goes.
THUNDER
(SINGS) For on her knee
She wore a yellow garter
She wore it for her lover
Who was far, far, away
Yes, we'll manage it, ma'am.
And when they asked her
Why she wore the garter
Breathe deep, Mikey.
She wore it for her
lover In the US Calvalry
Cavalry!
Easy, my darling.
Captain Brittles! Captain Brittles!
Ya! Ya!
0'Laughlin?
Here it is. I had to -
Not the details! How is he?
I think I can safely say,
he'll live to make sergeant.
Troop, halt!
Pass the word
- Quayne's doing fine.
CHEERING
Prepare to mount!
Mount!
Forward ho!
Thanks, soldier.
I'm so happy about Corporal Quayne.
Why? He's just another dog-faced
soldier in dirty shirt blue.
What do you care if he lives or dies?
Did you ever dance with him,
speak to him, or even look at him?
No, of course you didn't. No
officer's bars, not a gentleman.
I've been finding that some lieutenant's
bars are no guarantee of a gentleman.
You're glad about Quayne,
because it's a story with a happy
ending to tell back east at a tea party.
Now you can tell them
you've seen it all:
A real indian fight, a
man shot with an arrow -
- Mr Cohill!
- Your tour's just about perfect!
Uh...
Mrs Allshard's not well, Miss
Dandridge. Chloroform and all...
- Would you sit with her?
- Yes, Captain.
And thank you!
Mr Cohill, did anyone ever take
down your breeches and tan your hide?
Why, no, Sir - that is - yes,
Sir. My father, Sir, with a strap.
Well, I'm old enough to be
your father. Take the point.
They'll make a fine married couple.
Troop, ho!
THUNDER
RIDER APPROACHING
Over there, Sir!
Hey, ya!
GUNFIRE
Women to the rear!
- Doesn't Captain - - Oh, shut
your gob! You talk too much.
When he says, back to the rear, go!
- I'll give you a kiss.
- You'd better go, Miss.
- Well, I'd hate to
be kissed - - Shut up!
First two sets, forward.
Guard...
Yo!
ALL: Ya! Ya!
WHOOPING
- I'm glad to see you, Captain.
- Sorry to be late, Tyree. Report.
Cheyenne dog party
- about 30 Arapahos with them.
Well, that blows the lid, doesn't it?
Ma and Pa Sudrow, Sir.
- Children see it?
- No, Sir.
Found them hiding in the smoke-house.
Tyree...
It's about time I did retire.
Sir?
Would you take a
look at Trooper Smith?
Don't bother about me, Captain.
I trust you'll forgive
my presumption -
I commended the boy for the
way he handled this action,
in the best tradition
of the cavalry, Sir.
I take that very kindly, Sir.
Captain Tyree?
- Speak to him.
- Thank you.
Yes, Sir?
Sir?
I'm afraid he can't hear you...
Captain.
Poor things.
My Carrie-Sue.
Do you remember me? I'm Mrs Soldier.
You visited me at the fort and
we had a party. Do you remember?
See to your troop, Mr Cohill.
Mr Pennell
- picket lines.
You don't have to say it, Captain.
I know all this is because of me
- because I wanted to see the west.
Cos I wasn't... I wasn't army
enough to stay the winter.
You're not army yet, but never
apologise, it's a sign of weakness.
Yes, but I'm to blame for it.
Only the man who
commands can be blamed.
It rests on me.
Mission failure.
Well, we missed the
stage, Miss Dandridge.
Well, that's the best I can do.
I ran out of red flannel petticoats.
- You're mighty kind.
- Thank you.
- We thank you kindly.
- I'm proud to do it.
I am the resurrection and
the life, sayeth the Lord.
He that believeth in me, though
he were dead, yet shall he live,
and whoso shall believeth
in me, shall never die.
I know that my redeemer liveth,
and that he shall stand at
the latter day upon the earth.
I commend to your keeping, Sir,
the souls of John Sudrow,
and his wife, Martha.
I also commend to your
keeping the soul of Rome Clay,
late Brigadier General,
Confederate States Army.
Known to his comrades here, Sir,
as trooper John Smith,
United States Cavalry.
A gallant soldier and
a Christian gentleman.
Ready...
Aim
- fire!
Shoulder arms.
- With your permission, Sir.
- Granted.
- Bugler.
- We thank you, Sir.
LAST POST
I wouldn't go any
further if I were you.
You're almost across
the footlights now.
There may be a hundred
hostiles out there watching you.
BIRD-LIKE WHISTLE
Think that's a Whippoorwill?
Let's go back.
I'll walk myself, thank you.
Olivia.
The old man says don't ever
apologise, it's a sign of weakness.
But, I'm sorry,
for everything I've said and done.
I love you so -
- Right, let's get it over with.
- Are you crazy, mister?
You've been jealous since
she put on that yellow ribbon.
Button up that shirt.
Sneer all you like, but
keep your paws off my girl.
Alright, I'll accommodate you.
- Ross, don't.
- I quite agree.
Mr Pennell. I thought better of you.
Four years out here,
and still acting like a
wet-eared kid on the Hudson.
What is all this about, Mr Cohill?
Sir, I decline to
answer... respectfully.
Mr Cohill,
it is a bitter thing indeed,
to learn that an officer with nine
years' experience in the cavalry,
and to whom I am surrendering command
of this troop in two more days,
should have so little
grasp of leadership,
as to allow himself to be
chivvied into a go at fisty-cuffs
while taps still sounds
over a brave man's grave.
God help this troop when I'm gone.
- Sir - - You're
at attention!
- It was a misunderstanding.
- You get back to the troop area!
Mr Cohill, you will have the men
build their squad fires higher.
Make the fullest show of
bedding down for the night.
Then we're sneaking out,
heading for the river,
going back.
BIRD-LIKE WHISTLE
- Sorry, Ross.
- I'm sorry, Flint.
Our old friend Mr Rynders is
doing some trading down there.
Mr Rynders, eh?
Alright
Pass the word
- Mr Pennell forward.
VOICES CLOSE BY
Mr Rynders!
Indian agent. Ha!
(SPEAKS CHEYENNE)
- He said $50 is too much.
- Too much, huh?
Tell him I know he's got
the paymaster's money,
and I know he killed Major Cheadle.
And tell him it's $50, or no rifle.
(SPEAKS CHEYENNE)
LOUD WHOOPING
AGONISED SCREAMS
- (SCREAMING) Help!
- Sergeant?
- It's cocked, Sir.
- No, your knife.
Do you wanna chaw of tobacco?
No, sir. I don't chaw,
and I don't play cards.
Oh.
Chawing tobacco's a nasty habit.
Been known to turn a man's stomach.
I'll take a chaw, if you please, Sir.
Thank you, Sir.
Let's go.
Still figuring on resigning, mister?
No, sir.
Pass the word! Officers
and sergeants forward!
Officers and sergeants forward!
Sergeant Tyree! Find
me a trail to the river.
Right, Sir!
A rear guard will stay
here with one officer.
- Sir, I'd - - Thank
you, Mr Pennell.
Your offer to volunteer
will go on your record.
Do you still wish to make one?
Mr Cohill, you will be in command.
Take two squads, cover our crossing.
Deny the hostiles
the use of this ford.
First squad! Second squad!
Second squad has too
many old married men.
First squad! Fifth squad!
Wheel out. Follow in line.
- Can you swim, Dickie?
- No.
Well, I'm the best
swimmer in the world.
Once I swam the English Channel...
with an anvil on my chest.
You know what I've got?
I've got two jars of damson
plums on my pantry shelf.
- They're waiting for you to eat them.
- Tell her about the boat.
Captain - request permission
to stay with the rear guard.
Permission refused.
Mr Cohill, take the troops across.
I'll take your defence positions.
One pack animal to the rear! Get
back in the that wagon, Quayne.
Forward!
Hang on, Mike, here we go!
Come on, men!
Bugler! Sound officers'
call for Captain Brittles.
BUGLE CALL
I'll be back, men. I'll be
back, I promise you. Good luck!
Adjust your saddles and
lift your equipment, men.
Pass that on, will you?
It's time for me to take my medicine.
It tastes horrible!
Three parties of them, Mr Cohill.
This is the only crossing in 20 miles.
I need some time. You've
gotta buy me a long day.
Then we'll do it, sir.
I know you will, Flint.
Flint? It took you nine years to call
me that, sir. It was well worth waiting.
We'll get you out of here, son.
We'll get you out by noon tomorrow.
Prepare to mount!
Mount!
Flint, wait!
Well, haul off and kiss her
back, We haven't got all day!
Alright, Miss
Dandridge, if you please.
Get mounted.
- I guess that's how it is, Ross.
- I understand.
Forward...
Yo!
DISTANT GUNFIRE
I have to report the
mission a failure.
No, it was our fault! You did
everything a man could do -
I've never worn a coat of whitewash
yet, Abby. I won't start now.
I failed at Sudrow's. I failed to
keep Rynder's rifles from the tribes.
I'll leave the army a failure.
- Don't run yourself down
because - - Blast it, Mac!
I left Cohill and
two squads back there.
In a sound military move.
I'd like to rest the troop
for three hours and start back.
I'll have Cohill out of
there by noon tomorrow.
No, Nathan. The troop
can't leave till dawn.
Dawn? Troop ought to
leave before midnight.
Yes, if you were leading it -
but Pennell will need the daylight.
Pennell? That
babe-in-the-wood?
Fording a river against a swarm
of hostiles with Winchesters?
Aren't you forgetting
you're retiring tomorrow?
Tomorrow's all I need, Mac.
Look, 40 years a good soldier.
I can't leave Cohill
facing those devils.
You need more than a day.
They'll be there all winter.
Then I'll volunteer
as a civilian scout,
as an interpreter, anything.
And I thought you were fond of Cohill.
Fond of him?
When Cohill gave an order,
the men would look at you,
to see if he were
doing the right thing.
Do you want to ruin the boy?
I know, Mac, but...
Pennell must learn to cross
a river under fire. So did we.
And Cohill's got to run
his chances. We ran them.
That's what we get paid for.
Well, I guess you're right.
I guess you're right.
With your permission I'll
quit the post tomorrow.
Permission granted, Captain.
Where will you go, Nathan?
Oh, west, I guess, Abby.
California... New settlements.
Old soldiers, Miss Dandridge.
Some day you'll learn
how they hate to give up.
Captain of the troop one day
- every man's face turned towards you,
Lieutenants jump when I growl.
But tomorrow, I'll be...
glad if a blacksmith
asks me to shoe a horse.
Abby, if you start sniffling now...
- And as for you, young
lady - - I'm not crying.
I'd like to stand up and cheer.
Time, sir -
And it's a black day for the army.
Did you sleep well, sir?
No.
I didn't sleep at all.
Well...
Clean up the quarters after I'm gone.
Sell all this stuff and put
the money in the troop fund.
Give Mrs Allshard my extra saddle.
It'll be easier on her... disposition.
- And the oya, Sir?
- The oya?
Oh, yes.
The water bowl.
Well! How did it ever get there?
Now, how do you suppose?
- How long have you know it, sir?
- Since the battle of Bull Run, stupid.
And you've been deceiving
me all these years.
Well, there's that.
I'd say my retirement was
an occasion for a drink.
- Help yourself.
- No, I'd take no pleasure in it, sir.
But if it's an order,
here's to your health.
Only 14 days for myself and I'll be
wearing one of those monkey suits too.
Only one I ever owned.
I was a barefoot lad in blue jeans when
I left daddy's farm to join the army.
Well, Sergeant, I haven't
had a drink since that day,
but I'd like to drink
to your retirement.
No, sir! I'll do the honours for you.
Well, thank you.
Wait, Captain, till I get your blouse.
What?
- The men will like it, Sir.
- Oh, yeah.
Last time.
I'll review the troops
alone this morning, Sergeant.
Break in that suit of store
clothes for me, will you?
A suit?
Yeah! Try it on! See how it looks.
- C Troop, all present, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
Men,
I won't be going out with you.
I won't be here when you return.
I wish I could.
But I know your performance
under your new commander
will make me proud of you...
as I've always been proud of you.
One moment please,
Captain. Corporal Krumrein!
Sir, a small token from the troop.
They all put in the hat for it, sir
- even Sergeant Hochbauer.
It's solid silver, sir.
Brought from Kansas City.
There's a sentiment on the back.
"To Captain Brittles from C Troop."
(SNIFFS)
"Lest we forget."
(CLEARS THROAT AND SNIFFS)
Thank you, Corporal.
Thank you.
Thank all of you.
(SNIFFS) Take your troop, Mr Pennell.
Proceed on your mission.
Good luck, C Troop!
S0NG: THE GIRL I LEFT BEHIND ME
I'm lonesome since I crossed the hill
And o'er the moor and valley
Such heavy thoughts my heart do fill
Since parting with my Sally
I seek for one as fair and gay
But find none to remind me
How sweet the hours I passed away
With the girl I left behind me
Oh.
Give me a side view.
That's perfect! It's
made for you, Quincannon
You should go to the
sutler's and order one,
so that when you retire you...
Here, have a couple of
drinks while you're waiting.
You're out of uniform, Quincannon.
- Oh, I am, am I?
- You are.
Well, I'm in the proper uniform.
The uniform of a retired gentleman.
Hochbauer!
Yes, sir?
Sergeant Quincannon is improperly
dressed on duty and he's drunk.
Throw him in the guard house.
Alone, Sir?
Afraid of him? We'll
get you some help.
Wagner, give Hochbauer a hand.
Come, Fritz.
- How do I look, Connolly?
- What'll you have?
A little drop of whisky -
Irish - and I'll pour it myself.
And... and when I've drained
that up, just throw me out.
Hans, I want you to help
me arrest Quincannon.
I'd love to throw that
big Mick in the cooler.
You're under arrest, Quincannon.
By whose orders?
Captain Brittles'. Are
you coming peaceably?
Laddie, I've never gone any
place peaceably in my life.
You're just in time
for a drink, Wagner.
Ach, Connolly, the old
days, they've gone forever.
Connolly, did you hear
- the buffalo are back?
- Buffalo?
- Herds of them.
Men, now we want no unpleasantness.
A toast first, and the guard house after
- if you're able.
And it's on me
- I'm paying.
To Captain Nathan Brittles...
on his retirement.
To Captain Nathan Brittles!
I... I... I thank you comrades.
This has been a very pleasant moment.
Goodbye, Mr Connolly.
Goodbye, Mr Quincannon.
- Are you hurt, Hans?
- He's alright, sarge.
Come and have a little
sup before you go.
Wagner, come and join us.
Sanders! Waiter!
- What is going on?
- Are you alright?
I just had a nip for my cold, doctor.
To the guard house. Quick march!
Hup!
- Watch the steps.
- Aren't you ashamed?
- Eight of you against one man?
- Only seven, ma'am.
Forward, yo!
Alright, Nathan, I get it! Ten days
in the guard house and no charges.
Can't you make it two
weeks, Mac? Till he retires?
A man with a thirst like that couldn't
get by on less than a sergeant's pension.
I'll give you my word on it,
he'll retire as top soldier.
Thanks, Mac.
Well, on my way. Goodbye, Mac.
Say goodbye to Abby.
He will do no such thing. We
don't say goodbye in the cavalry.
To our next post, dear.
Could I haul off and
kiss you too, Captain?
- Goodbye, Doc.
- Goodbye, Nathan.
May the road be kind to you.
'Signal smokes, war drums, feathered
bonnets against the western sky.'
'New messiahs, young leaders,
are ready to hurl the finest light
cavalry in the world against Fort Starke.'
CHANTING
'In the Kiowa village,
the beat of the drums echoes in
the pulse beat of the young braves.'
'Fighters under one banner,
old quarrels forgotten,
Comanche rides with Arapaho,
Apache with Cheyenne.'
'All chant of war to drive the white
man from the red man's hunting ground.'
'Only the old men stand silent.'
'Even Pony That Walks has been
howled down at the counsel fires.'
Captain Brittles!
Captain Brittles, sir!
CHEERING
- Captain Brittles, glad to see you.
- And I, you, sir.
Report, Mr Pennell.
We effected the relief
with no casualties.
My compliments.
Report, Mr Cohill.
We've trailed them all day.
It's a big concentration
- Arapahos, Kiowas, Comanches,
800 or 900 Cheyenne Dog Soldiers.
They're getting ready to
strike, but we must strike first.
- I'm glad the Major sent you.
- He didn't send me.
- Then the orders haven't changed.
- Orders are orders, sir.
For the next four hours,
according to my brand new
silver watch and chain,
I'm an officer in the
United States Cavalry.
If I gave you a written order,
Flint, would you obey it?
- I don't need a written order.
- You're getting one.
Might come in handy
at our court marshall.
Sergeant Tyree, I'm ordering
you to volunteer again.
- Put your guard on.
- Yes, sir.
Guard on!
Stay here. Do nothing until I return.
If I don't, those are your orders
- don't lose them.
Locate the pony herd.
Are you ever scared, Captain Tyree?
Yes, sir. I'm tooing and tooting now.
DRUMMING
Ah, Nathan!
Nathan!
I am a Christian!
Hallelujah!
Old friend me
- long time, long time.
I come in peace, Pony That Walks.
Take of salt, Nathan.
Take salt.
Smoke pipe.
Good.
Pony That Walks, my heart
is sad at what I see.
Your young men painted for
war, their scalp knives red.
The medicine drums talking.
- It is a bad thing.
- A bad thing, Nathan.
Many will die -
my young men, your young men.
No good. No good.
- We must stop this war.
- Too late, Nathan.
Young men do not listen to me,
they listen to big medicine.
Yellow-hair, Custer, dead.
Buffalo, come back.
Great sign.
Too late, Nathan.
You come with me,
hunt buffalo together.
Smoke many pipes.
We are too old for war.
Yes, we are too old for war,
but old men should stop wars.
Too late, too late.
Many squaws will sing the death songs.
Many lodges will be empty.
You come with me.
We hunt buffalo.
Get drunk together.
Hallelujah! Hallelujah!
No, friend, I must go.
I go far away.
Then, Nathan,
my brother...
go in peace.
ALL: (KIOWA FAREWELL)
WHIMPERING
Easy, pup. Easy.
- Pass the word - mount.
HORSE WHINNIES
Bugler! Do you wanna get
busted back to horse-shoeing?
Mind that horse.
- Tyree?
- Sorry, sir.
Mr Cohill...
can you read the time by
my brand new silver watch?
Yes, sir. Twelve minutes to midnight.
Ah.
Gentlemen...
Bugler...
sound the charge.
ALL: Ya!
GUNFIRE
Sound recall.
RECALL
- Any wounded?
- No casualties, sir.
Ah. No casualties. No indian
war. No court marshall.
Have your troop follow the
hostiles back to reservation.
Follow a mile behind them.
Walking hurts their pride
- your watching will hurt it worse.
Can you read what time it is
by my brand new silver watch?
It's two minutes past midnight, sir.
Oh.
I've been a civilian for two minutes.
It's your army, Mr Cohill. Good luck!
BUGLE CALL
'So Nathan Brittles,
ex-captain of cavalry USA,
started west for the new
settlements in California -
towards the setting sun, which is
the end of the trail for all old men.'
'But the army sent a galloper
after Nathan Brittles...
that was Sergeant Tyree's department.'
Yo!
Captain Brittles!
Captain, for you, sir
- from the yankee War Department.
Oh, I knew it! Damn
blasted... I knew it!
They're trying to...
What?
Sergeant, it's my appointment.
Chief of Scouts,
with the rank of Lieutenant Colonel.
And will you look at
those endorsements!
Phil Sheridan, William
Tecumseh Sherman
and Ulysses Simpson Grant,
President of the United
States of America.
There's three aces for you, boy.
Yeah, but I wish you
had the full hand.
Huh? Full hand? What
do you mean full hand?
- Robert E Lee, sir.
- Oh.
(LAUGHS) Wouldn't have been bad.
Let's go!
APPLAUSE
Welcome home, Colonel, darlin'.
(SNIFFS)
Your arm, Colonel Brittles.
APPLAUSE
Sir, you should know that
Miss Dandridge and I -
Why, son, I knew it all the time.
Everybody on the post knew it,
above the rank of second Lieutenant.
Right, Mr Pennell?
One day, I'll be first Lieutenant.
- Yeah...
- ALL: In 10 or 12 years.
Will you stay for the dance, Colonel?
If you'll excuse me, Miss Dandridge,
I've got to make my report first.
Ladies and gentlemen...
thank you.
Thank you.
'So, here they are, the
dog-faced soldiers, the regulars,
the 50-cents-a-day professionals
of the nation's outposts,'
'From Fort Reno to Fort Apache to
Fort Starke, they were all the same.'
'Men in dirty shirt blue, marked in
the history books by a cold page.'
'But wherever they rode and fought,
that place became the United States.'