[majestic music
with a cantering beat playing]
[wind blowing]
[solo horn carries main theme]
[main theme repeating]
##
[wind blowing]
[secondary theme enters
with fuller orchestration]
[screeches]
##
[river rumbling]
[wings swooshing]
[majestic theme continues]
[screeches]
[birds chirping]
[wings fluttering]
SPI RIT [man's voice]:
The story that I want to tell you
cannot be found in a book.
They say the history of the West
was written
from the saddle of a horse
but it's never been told
from the heart of one...
not till now.
[birds chirping]
I was born here
in this place that would come
to be called the Old West
but to my kind,
the land was ageless.
It had no beginning
and no end...
no boundary
between earth and sky.
Like the wind
in the buffalo grass
we belonged here.
We would always belong here.
[spouting thunderously]
They say the mustang
is the spirit of the West.
Whether that West was won
or lost in the end
you'll have to decide for yourself
but the story
I want to tell you is true.
I was there, and I remember.
I remember the sun and the sky
and the wind calling my name
in a time when wild horses ran free.
[hooves thundering]
[majestic main theme
carried by orchestra and piano]
##
[music subsiding]
[wind blowing]
[labored breathing]
[whinnying]
[snorting]
[grunting]
[moans]
[neighing painfully]
[nickering softly]
[whinnying excitedly]
[high-pitched neigh]
[nickers]
[sniffing]
[fluttering snort]
[snuffling]
[squeaks]
[nickering lovingly]
[whinnies shrilly]
[burring]
[single nicker]
[electronic keyboard
playing soft, ethereal theme]
# Here I am #
#This is me #
# I come into this world
so wild and free #
[herd whinnies]
# Here I am #
# So young and strong #
# Right here in the place
where I belong #
# It's a new world #
# It's a new start #
# It's alive with the beating
of a young heart #
# It's a new day #
# In a new land #
#And it's waiting for me #
[snorts]
# Here I am #
[burps]
[both nickering]
[smacking lips]
# Oh, it's a new world #
# It's a new start #
# It's alive with the beating
of a young heart #
#Yeah, it's a new day #
# In a new land #
[whinnies]
#And it's waiting for me #
[snow whooshing]
# Here I am #
[nickering indignantly]
[whinnies]
[squealing nickers]
[ice cracks]
[snorting]
[self-satisfied nicker]
[nickering and burring]
[whinnying playfully]
[distant rumbling]
[neighs]
[gentle splashing]
[rumbling grows louder]
[frightened neighing]
[rumbling stops]
[snorts]
[Spirit squeals]
[majestic music swells]
[bellowing deeply]
[squeaks softly]
[neighing excitedly]
[whinnies]
[whinnying]
[nickering happily]
[grunts]
[exhilarated nickering]
[bellows]
[whinnies]
[high-pitched neighing
becomes mature voice]
And so I grew from colt to stallion
as wild and reckless
as thunder over the land
racing with the eagle,
soaring with the wind.
Flying?
There were times I believed I could.
[inspiring and dynamic melody playing]
[screeches]
[tempo of galloping increases]
[panting]
Like my father before me
I became leader
of the Cimarron herd
and with that honor...
came responsibility.
[growls]
[snorting]
[squealing playfully]
[warning neigh]
[all whinny]
[ferocious growl]
[squealing]
[neighing]
[growls]
[neighs]
[growling and neighing]
[alarmed whinnying]
[snorts]
[mountain lion growls]
[neighing]
[snorts forcefully]
[mountain lion snarling]
[snorting]
[herd whinnying happily]
[neighing excitedly]
[neighing triumphantly]
[easy ballad intro begins]
# I hear the wind across the plain #
#A sound so strong that calls my name #
# It's wild like the river #
# It's warm like the sun #
#Yeah, it's here #
#This is where I belong #
[burring]
# Under the starry skies #
#Where eagles have flown #
#This place is paradise #
# It's the place I call home #
CHORUS:
#The moon on the mountains #
#The whisper through the trees #
#The waves on the water #
# Let nothing come
between this and me #
# 'Cause everything I want #
# Is everything that's here #
#And when we're all together #
#There's nothing to fear #
[nickering]
# Ooh, ooh #
[burring]
# Ooh, ooh, ooh #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh... #
[warning snort]
[nickers]
#And wherever I wander #
#The one thing I've learned #
#Yeah #
# It's to here I will always #
#Always... #
# Return. #
[music ending]
[snorts]
[harmonica playing
"Red River Valley" faintly]
[nickers]
[snorting]
[harmonica playing continues]
[nickering]
[whinnies]
[chomps]
[neighs warningly]
[nickers determinedly]
Something new came
upon the land one night...
something that would
change my life forever...
and so, my journey began.
[soft, flowing music playing]
[sniffs]
[snorts]
[music changes to quiet,
pensive melody]
[nickers curiously]
[nickers warningly]
[frightened snorting]
[man coughs, glass clinks]
[nickers]
SPI RIT:
A wiser horse might have
turned and run
but I wanted to know
what strange creatures were here.
[men snoring]
[nickers softly]
[clanging softly]
[nickers]
[snorting]
[metallic clattering]
[thud, grunts]
Oh!
What the...?
[grunts]
Son of a...!
Shh...
[whispering]:
Look.
Man, look at that stallion!
It's beautiful!
[nickers curiously]
[snoring]
[squeals]
[yawning]
[snoring continues]
[alarmed nickering]
[moaning affectionately]
Mmm, Sadie Mae.
[smooching]
[snorts and squeals]
[both]
Ugh!
[gasps]
[neighs]
Get him, boys!
Easy, boy!
[neighing]
C'mon, boys! Let's go!
C'mon, boys!
[men shouting]
[men whistling]
[whistling and shouting]
[hooves thundering]
Hyah! Hyah!
[men grunting]
Where did he go?
I don't see him.
We'll find him!
[chomps]
[yells]
[neighs]
[men shouting]
What the...?
[whinnies]
##
[snorts]
[whinnying]
[high-pitched whinnies]
[all whinnying]
[thundering hooves approaching]
[men whistling and shouting]
Faster!
[whistling and shouting]
[neighs harshly]
[men shouting and whistling]
[grunts]
[shouting]
[neighs harshly]
[neighs]
[neighing]
[shouting and whistling]
What?
[horses whinnying]
Get him!
Ha! Come on! Ha!
Ha! Get him!
Hyah! Yah! Yah!
Come on, come on, come on!
[clinking]
Ha-ha! We got him now!
Ha-ha, you betcha!
Whoa!
Look out!
[grunts]
[whinnying]
[squeals]
[neighing]
[grunting]
Thought you got away,
didn't you, mustang?
[neighing harshly]
Over here!
Get back here!
You crazy?
Get back from him!
Take him!
Take him, Joe!
Get the horse!
[snarling]
He's ours now. Whoo!
[rope straining]
[nickering]
[neighing]
Hold him!
Watch him!
Watch the lines!
Come on!
He can do all the kicking
he wants now.
It won't do no good.
[neighing]
[panting]
[grunts]
[rocks clattering]
[neighing harshly]
[neighing sadly]
[grunting and nickering]
Careful... Careful...
[neighing angrily]
[whinnying]
SPI RIT:
I was scared, and I didn't know
what was going to happen to me
but at least my mother
and the herd were safe.
[neighing]
[whistles]
Come on! Let's go!
[bridle straining]
Yo... come on...
[pop intro playing]
# Gotta fight another fight #
# I gotta run another night #
# Get it out, check it out #
# I'm on my way
and it don't feel right #
# I gotta get me back #
# I can't be beat, and that's a fact #
# It's okay, l'll find a way #
#Ain't gonna take me down, no way #
# No, oh, oh, oh #
#Yeah, don't judge a thing
till you know what's inside it #
# Don't push me, l'll fight it #
# Never gonna give in,
never gonna give it up, no #
# No, oh, oh, oh #
# If you can't catch a wave then
you're never gonna ride it #
#You can't come uninvited #
# Never gonna give in,
never gonna give it up, no #
#You can't take me, I'm free #
[thunder rumbling]
[musical interlude]
#Why did it all go wrong? #
# I want to know what's going on #
#What's this holding me? #
# I'm not where I'm supposed to be #
# I gotta fight another fight #
# I gotta fight with all my might #
# I'm getting out, so check it out #
#You're in my way, yeah,
you better watch out... #
Open the gate!
# Come on! Don't judge a thing
till you know what's inside it #
# Don't push me, l'll fight it #
# Never gonna give in,
never gonna give it up, no #
# No, oh, oh, oh #
# If you can't catch a wave
then you're never gonna ride it #
#You can't come uninvited #
# Never gonna give in,
never gonna give it up, no #
[whinnying]
#You can't take me, I'm free #
[rhythmic hoofbeats]
# I'm free. #
[panicked neighing]
[soldiers yelling]
[gun fires]
[huffing]
What seems to be the problem,
gentlemen?
We got us a crazy one here, sir.
Pure mustang, Colonel.
Really?
[whickering]
The Army has dealt
with wild horses before.
This one will be no different.
[neighing]
[soldiers yelling]
SOLDI ER:
Come on, mustang.
SPI RIT:
I remember the first time
I saw a rattler
curled up in my path.
[chuckling]
Induct this animal, Sergeant.
Yes, sir!
SPI RIT:
This one didn't look like a rattler
but I was still thinking... snake.
SERGEANT:
Take up that slack.
Grab him! Grab him!
[soldiers grunting]
Come on, horse!
Okay, Murphy, he's all yours.
Whoa! He's a wild one.
[Murphy chuckles]
We'll see how wild he is
when I'm done with him.
[nickering]
- [groans]
- See that?
[grunting]
You want to fight, do you?
[shears snipping]
[chuckling]
[screaming in pain]
[grunted laughter]
Right.
[nickering]
[curious whinnies]
[grunting with effort]
[nickering]
[rope straining]
[blade clinks]
[groans]
[grunts]
[whinnying laughter]
[both whinnying]
[rope straining]
Make sure that's good and tight.
[whinnying]
- Murphy, look out!
- Watch out!
[groans]
[whinnying laughter]
SERGEANT:
He's a wild one.
[grunting and groaning]
SERGEANT:
You all right, Murph?
[bellows puffing]
[nickering]
Eh-heh... you...
[alarmed nickers]
[sizzling]
[chuckling]
[gasps]
[groaning]
SERGEANT:
Murph, you okay?
[whinnying]
SERGEANT:
Um... Corporal, round up
some volunteers to, uh...
take this animal to the stables.
Not the stables.
SERGEANT:
Sir?
COLONEL:
The corral.
It's time to break that horse.
[snorts]
#Well, you think
that you can take me on #
#You must be crazy... #
OFFICER:
Make sure it's good and tight.
#There ain't a single thing
you've done #
#That's gonna faze me #
[men clamoring]
# Oh, but if you want to have a go #
# I just want to let you know #
#Yeah, get off of my back
and into my game #
# Get out of my way
'cause I'm wild and untamed #
# Get out of my face
or give it your best shot #
# I think it's time
you better face the fact #
# Get off of my back... #
Okay, my turn!
#You know it's all just a game #
#That I'm playin' #
# Don't think
that you can find a way in... #
Lousy heap of horse flesh!
#That's what I'm sayin'... #
[nickering]
Come on!
Run out of there!
# Oh, now, if you want to have a go #
# I just want to let you know #
[whinnying laughter]
# Oh, get off of my back #
#And into my game #
# Get out of my face,
'cause I'm wild and untamed #
# Get out of my way,
or give it your best shot... #
Hey, we got a rider!
# But you know
this train is comin' off this track #
# Get off of my back #
[soldier screaming]
#Yeah, get off of my back #
# Get off #
[echoing]:
#Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah... #
# Get off, get off, get off, get off #
# Get off, get off, get off #
# Get off of my back. #
[nickering harshly]
[huffing loudly]
Sergeant!
Yes, sir.
Tie this horse to the post.
No food or water.
Three days.
Yes, sir.
[neighs and whinnies]
[nickering]
[huffs and grunts]
##
[nickers quietly]
[gentle melody plays]
SPI RIT:
My heart galloped
through the skies that night...
back to my herd,
where I belonged
and I wondered if they missed me
as much as I missed them.
[whinnies]
[rhythmic melody plays]
SOLDI ER:
Get some water over to the stable.
[men conversing indistinctly]
Yes, sir.
[smacking]
[nickers]
SOLDI ER:
We caught a hostile!
[nickers]
[soldiers grunting]
SERGEANT:
Bring him back this way!
[yells painfully]
[soldiers laughing]
Well, what do we have here?
We caught him
by the supply wagons, sir.
[groans in pain]
Ah, a Lakota.
Not as tall as the Cheyenne;
not as fine-featured as the Crow.
Take him away, gentlemen.
Show him our best.
SERGEANT:
Corporal, take him to the stockades.
Not the stockades... the post.
No food or water.
[groans painfully]
[grunts softly]
[soldiers murmuring]
CORPORAL:
Come on!
[burring]
What are you looking at, boy?
[grunts]
SPI RIT:
He was called Little Creek
and he seemed different
from the rest.
[soldier laughing]
[groaning]
[nickers softly]
Hey... [clicks tongue]
[burring]
[nickering]
[laughing]
[distant howling]
[hooting]
[nickers and snorts]
[distant howling]
[hooting]
[nickers gently]
[startled whinny]
SPI RIT:
There was just no end
to the strange ways
of the Two-leggeds.
[bugle playing reveille]
SERGEANT:
C Company! Ten-hut!
With the Colonel's permission, sir.
Incoming patrol reports
hostiles headed north.
COLONEL:
Ah.
The railroad has expressed concern, sir.
They've requested additional patrols.
How long has it been, Sergeant?
Sir?
The mustang,
how long has it been tied?
Three days, sir.
Good.
Fetch my crop and spurs.
[clinking]
[startled neighing]
[Colonel grunts, Spirit neighs]
You can break easy
or you can break hard, mustang!
[nickering]
No!
Back up! Back up!
Back up!
[neighing harshly]
Come on!
[clinking]
[nickering angrily]
Come on!
Come on... come on...!
Come on, mustang!
[men clamoring]
Ha!
[Colonel grunts, Spirit neighs]
[panting heavily]
[panting and chuckling]
[panting]
You see, gentlemen...
any horse can be broken.
Move along, mustang.
[scattered applause and cheers]
There are those in Washington
who believe the West
will never be settled
the Northern Pacific Railroad
will never breach Nebraska...
[panting]
a hostile Lakota...
will never submit to Providence...
and it is that manner
of small thinking
that would say this horse
could never be broken.
Discipline, time and patience...
are the three great levelers.
[snorts]
SPI RIT:
Sometimes a horse has gotta do
what a horse has gotta do.
Mustang?
SPI RIT:
And this was one of those times.
[whinnying]
[men clamoring]
[Colonel groaning]
[gasping]
[nickering]
[startled yell]
[Colonel screams]
ALL:
Oh, no!
[body thuds]
[burring and snorting]
[groaning]
SERGEANT:
You all right, sir?
Get off me!
[panting]
[neighing loudly]
[neighing continues]
Soldier... secure that horse!
[whoops]
[gunshot echoing]
[men clamoring]
##
[hooves pounding]
[horses neighing]
[grunts]
[grunts angrily]
[nickers]
[gasps, then grunts]
[hooves thundering]
SPI RIT:
I wasn't sure what happened back there
and I wasn't about to stop and ask.
All I knew was
that I was headed home.
[howling]
[nickers quietly]
[grunts with effort]
[laughing]
SPI RIT:
I couldn't believe it.
One moment I was free,
and the next... more ropes.
[grunts]
[nickers curiously]
[gate creaking softly]
[nickers]
Steady. Steady.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Nice and easy.
There you go.
That feels better now, doesn't it?
[gentle melody playing]
[nickers]
[smacking lips]
[birds chirping]
[crunches]
[whimsical melody begins]
[burring]
[neighs]
[nickers]
[snorting]
[whinnying]
[Little Creek whistles]
[snorting]
[nickering]
[chuckling]
[playful melody volume increases]
Hey, hey!
[neighing]
[laughing]
[grunting]
[snorts]
[blows]
[chuckling]
SPI RIT:
I couldn't understand it.
She treated this scrawny
Two-legged like one of our kind
prancing around him
like a love-struck yearling.
[snorting]
It was downright unnatural.
[burring]
Great mustang...
today I will ride you.
[snorting]
This ought to be good.
[neighing]
[grunting]
[laughing]
[nickering angrily]
[yelps]
[neighs ferociously]
[whinnying disapprovingly]
[snorts]
SPI RIT:
Mares!
Okay, Rain, let's see if you can
teach this mustang some manners.
[nickering]
[gate creaking]
[snorts curiously]
[neighing ecstatically]
[main theme soaring]
[squeals happily]
[music stops abruptly]
[snorts]
[whinnying angrily]
[tango playing]
[rope creaking]
[thud]
[nickering angrily]
[tango continues]
[nickering seductively]
[pause in music]
[strings flutter softly]
[whinnies]
[squeals]
[snorts]
[grunts]
SPI RIT:
Okay, I admit it, she was charming...
in a stubborn, irritating kind of way.
So, I let her show me her world.
[children shouting playfully]
[sticks clattering]
[speaking native language]
[child laughing]
[dogs barking]
[grunts]
[nickering]
[grunts curiously]
[snorting]
[gasps]
[groaning]
[neighing laughter]
[snorts]
[giggling]
[babbling]
Horsey!
[sniffs]
[giggling]
[snorting]
[child crying]
[acoustic guitar playing
poignant melody]
[giggles]
Mmm... whoo!
[woman calling to child]
Bye-bye, horsey.
[soft grunt]
[burring]
[birds chirping]
[snorts softly]
[nickers]
[neighs]
[romantic melody continues]
[nickers happily]
[nickers shyly]
[whinnies gently]
[romantic theme increases
in volume and dynamics]
[both whinnying]
[eagle screeches]
[neighing]
[screeches]
[whinnying sadly]
[neighing]
For the first time in my life,
I felt my heart torn two ways.
Hey, hey...
[grunts]
No!
Give it back!
Come on!
Mustang, no! Mustang!
Oh, come on.
Oh...
[panting]
[grunts and groans]
[nickering]
Hmm?
[gasping]
[burring]
[puzzled grunt]
[nickers shrilly]
[gasps]
[yells]
[grunting]
[neighing]
SPI RIT:
I had to hand it to that boy...
he just wouldn't give up.
[laughing]
[whinnying happily]
[guffawing]
[neighing]
[whinnying forcefully]
[sighs softly]
[piano and flute playing
soft, moving theme]
[nickers softly]
[wind blowing softly]
I'm never going to ride you, am I?
And no one ever should.
[nickering gently]
[grunting]
[snorts]
You can go.
[nickering]
It's okay, go.
Go on, get out of here!
[slaps]
Go home.
[melody continues]
[music swelling]
[whinnying excitedly]
[nickers invitingly]
[music fades]
[acoustic guitar plays
melancholy melody]
[whinnying encouragingly]
[nickers sadly]
SPI RIT:
I knew this was hard for her
and that she was scared
but more than anything
I wanted to share
my homeland with her.
[distant rumbling]
[nickers nervously]
[wind blowing]
[rumbling grows louder]
[alarmed neigh]
[both whinnying]
[men shouting]
[neighing]
[gunshot]
[screaming]
[neighing]
[clamoring]
[grunts]
Ah!
[gunshot]
[shrill war cry]
[warning neigh]
[hammer cocks]
[whinnying]
[gunshot, Rain screams]
[grunts]
[thuds]
[music intensifies]
[gunshot]
[frightened whinny]
[neighs, thunderous splashing]
[gasping]
[Rain whinnies]
[neighing weakly]
##
[music building]
[waterfall thundering]
[grunting]
[groans]
[whinnying]
[music fades]
[loud, frantic neigh]
[panting]
[baffled snort]
[alarmed whicker]
[gentle whinnying]
[nickering]
[whickers weakly]
[whimpering whickers]
[sharp groan]
[labored breathing]
[alarmed whinny]
[shrill neighing]
[whinnies lovingly]
SPI RIT:
I lay beside her that night, hoping...
praying that somehow
she would be okay.
[distant whistling]
MAN:
Hey! There's a couple
of horses over there.
[whistling]
[worried nicker]
[man clicking tongue]
[shouting in distance]
[angry whickers]
[snarling]
SOLDI ER:
Hyah!
[neighing]
SOLDI ER 1:
Ha!
SOLDI ER 2:
Leave the mare.
She's not going to make it.
[frenzied neighs]
[neighing]
[neighing shrilly]
[neighing frantically]
[soldiers grunting]
[resigned snort]
SOLDI ER:
Come on.
Come on!
[tongue clicking]
Oh, Rain.
Oh...
[Rain groans]
Easy, girl.
Easy.
It'll be okay.
SOLDI ER:
Come on.
Hyah, hyah.
[clicks tongue]
You saved my life.
Two more men on that brace!
Collins! Evans!
[whistles]
Bring it down!
Let's go!
Jackson, hey!
Grab ahold of that end!
[train whistle blows]
Got it!
This one's loaded.
[faltering hoofbeat]
[grunting]
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Come on.
It's gonna be okay.
[curious whinnies]
[blowing]
[baffled grunts]
[door rattling]
[slamming]
# Sound the bugle now #
[engine chugging]
# Play it just for me #
[wheels clacking]
#As the seasons change #
# Remember how I used to be #
# Now I can't go on #
[neighing]
# I can't even start #
# I've got nothing left #
#Just an empty heart #
##
# I'm a soldier #
#Wounded,
so I must give up the fight #
#There's nothing more for me #
# Lead me away #
# Or leave me lying here #
[instrumental break]
[roaring snowfall]
##
# Sound the bugle now #
#Tell them I don't care #
#There's not a road I know #
#That leads to anywhere #
[wind howling]
#Without a light,
I fear that I will stumble in the dark #
# Lay right down #
# Decide not to go on #
[alarmed neigh]
#Then from on high #
# Somewhere in the distance #
[blows]
#There's a voice that calls #
# Remember who you are #
# If you lose yourself #
[neighs]
#Your courage soon will follow #
# So be strong tonight #
# Remember who you are #
[instrumental break]
#Yeah #
#You're a soldier now #
# Fighting in a battle #
#To be free once more #
#Yeah, that's worth fighting for. #
[lock unbolting]
Come on.
Come on now.
It'll be all right.
Come on.
That's it. That's it.
[men shouting orders,
chains clanging]
[whip cracking]
[men shouting]
[worried nickering]
[whip cracking]
MAN:
Let's go!
Come on!
SPI RIT:
I didn't know why
we were brought here.
What I did know was we had to find a way
to escape and get back home.
MAN:
Clear!
[explosion]
No good!
We hit bedrock!
Well, that's it.
We're hauling the steamer
over the mountain.
That's crazy.
We got six days
to connect with Utah.
We move out at dawn.
[stirring majestic music plays]
##
[grunting]
[neighing]
Ready to go!
Hyah!
Move it out!
[chains clanking]
[hooves pounding powerfully]
Move it out!
[panting snort]
##
Hyah!
[neighs]
Whoa!
[snarls]
Get back in line!
[huffing]
##
[hooves thundering]
[chains clanking]
MAN [shouting]:
We're almost at the top!
Slow down up front!
[hammers clanging]
[curious snort]
##
[music crescendos]
SPI RIT:
That was the moment
I understood.
They were headed to my homeland,
and I had to stop them.
[neighing]
Get back!
Come on! Get back in line!
It's starting to slip!
Whoa! Pick up the slack!
Pick up the slack!
[whimpering]
Hold it!
[music stops]
Get the mules up here!
[grunting]
[grunts]
[chains clanking]
Secure it on the left!
Good work, boys!
[stirring theme music resumes]
[all neighing]
Hey!
Whoa!
Easy...
[snarling]
[shouting]
[neighing]
Get him. Get him.
Whoa!
[frenzied neighing]
[men shouting]
[nickers encouragement]
[loud rumbling]
[clanging]
[shrill neigh]
Hurry!
Bring the poles!
[rumbling]
Hurry!
[man grunting]
Hey, hold him there!
Go!
[growling]
[gunshot]
[neighs]
[gasps]
They're breaking!
I can't hold it!
Over here!
Get out of the way!
[loud rumbling]
[thunderous crash]
[rumbling]
[raucous rumbling]
[thunderous crash]
[metallic crashing]
[raucous rumbling]
Holy...!
[thunderous crash]
[metallic screeching]
[man yells]
[thunderous crash]
[explosion booming]
[both gasp]
[soldiers gasp]
[stirring music continues]
[neighs]
[men clamoring]
[music intensifies]
[neighs]
[determined neigh]
[neighing]
[inferno roaring]
[neighs frantically]
[grunting]
[whimpers]
[spirited neigh]
[inferno roaring]
[whooping]
[whooping echoing]
[thunderous splash]
[bubbles gurgling]
[birds twittering]
[labored breathing]
[questioning nicker]
[sniffing]
[curious nicker]
[delighted nicker]
SPI RIT:
I don't know where he came from
or how he got there
but I sure was happy to see him.
[lilting music plays]
##
[startled yell]
[exhilarated neigh]
[laughs]
[yells happily]
[laughing]
Whoo-hoo!
[shouting and whooping]
[gleeful neigh]
Ah, ah!
Oh!
[gentle melody playing,
backed with percussion]
I knew I would find you.
[acknowledging grunt]
[huffs]
[music fades]
[snorting]
[horses neigh]
MAN:
Halt!
[tongue clicking]
[hoofbeats approaching]
I don't believe it.
[alarmed whicker]
Go, go, go, go! Run!
Run!
[bullet ricochets]
Come on, come on!
- [gunshot]
- [Little Creek groans]
[gunshots]
[whistling]
[groaning]
[stirring orchestral theme playing]
[gleeful nicker]
[triumphant chuckle]
Whoo-hoo!
[laughing]
[gunfire]
[soldier whistling]
Hyah!
[laughing]
[delighted neigh]
[neighs]
SOLDI ER:
Hyah!
[neighs]
Yeah!
[grunts]
Ah!
[approving neigh]
[groans]
[gasps]
Whoa!
That's it!
Come on! Come on!
[panicked neigh]
[yelling]
Get off!
Ooh! Aah!
[grunts]
[groans]
Ooh!
[ecstatic neigh]
[laughing]
Whoa!
[gasps]
[music stops]
SOLDI ER:
Hyah!
[soldiers shouting]
We got them now!
Whoa!
Where did he go?
There they are!
Up there!
Oh, no.
SPI RIT:
Oh, yes.
[drumroll]
[determined neigh]
[music intensifies and builds]
[shouting]
[whooping]
[laughing]
[stirring theme playing]
##
[panting]
[music fades]
[cocking rifle]
[uncocks rifle]
[gentle melody plays]
[nickers]
Hyah.
[whistles]
[pop intro plays]
CHORUS:
#Whoa, oh, oh, oh #
# Don't judge a thing
till you know what's inside it #
# Don't push me, l'll fight it #
# Never gonna give it,
never gonna give it up, no #
#Whoa, oh, oh, oh #
#Ah, if you can't catch a wave #
#Then you're never gonna ride it #
# Can't come uninvited #
# Never gonna give it,
never gonna give it up, no #
[neighs]
#You can't take me #
# I'm free #
#Yeah, I'm free #
#Yeah... huh! #
[music fades]
[birds chirping in distance]
[acoustic guitar playing
playing melancholy melody]
[nickers sadly]
[whistles]
[distant dog barks]
##
[music swells
with orchestral accompaniment]
[whinnies happily]
[neighing ecstatically]
[neighing exuberantly]
[nickers lovingly]
[nickers softly]
[nickers]
[music softens]
[acoustic guitar continuing]
[nickers sadly]
You will always be in my heart.
[whines gently]
Take care of her
Spirit-Who-Could-Not-Be-Broken.
[burring gently]
##
[orchestral accompaniment joining in]
I will miss you, my friend.
[music swelling gradually]
##
[whinnying]
SPI RIT:
I had been waiting so long to run free
but that good-bye
was harder than I ever imagined.
l'll never forget that boy...
[neighing]
and how we won back
our freedom together.
[neighing]
[whooping]
# I hear the wind #
# Call my name #
[whinnies]
#The sound that leads me home again #
# It sparks up the fire #
#A flame that still burns #
#To you I will always return #
# I know the road is long #
# But where you are is home #
#Wherever you stay #
# l'll find the way #
# l'll run like the river #
# l'll follow the sun #
# l'll fly like an eagle #
#To where I belong #
# I can't stand the distance #
# I can't dream alone #
# I can't wait to see you #
#Yes, I'm on my way home #
# Now I know it's true #
# My every road leads to you #
#And in the hour of darkness #
#Your light gets me through #
#You run like the river #
#You shine like the sun #
#Yeah #
#You fly like an eagle #
#Yeah, you are the one #
# I've seen every sunset #
#And with all that I've learned #
# Oh... #
# It's to you I will always #
#Always return. #
[music fades]
[rock ballad plays]
BRYAN ADAMS:
# Here I am #
#This is me #
#There's nowhere else on Earth
I'd rather be #
# Here I am #
# It's just me and you #
#Tonight
we make our dreams come true #
# It's a new world #
# It's a new start #
# It's alive with the beating
of young hearts #
# It's a new day #
# It's a new plan #
# I've been waiting for you #
# Here I am #
# Here we are #
#We've just begun #
#And after all this time,
our time has come #
#Yeah, here we are #
# Still going strong #
# Right here in the place
where we belong #
# Oh, it's a new world #
# It's a new start #
# It's alive with the beating
of young hearts #
# It's a new day #
# It's a new plan #
# I've been waiting for you #
MAN:
#Waiting, waiting, waiting #
# Oh... #
# Here I am #
# Hey, baby, here I am #
# Here I am, here I am #
# Oh, right next to you #
# Right next to you #
# Here I am #
#And suddenly the world
is all brand-new #
# Here I am #
#Whoa, whoa #
#Yeah, yeah #
# Here I am #
# Here I am. #
[romantic music playing]
ADAMS:
# I can't believe this moment's come #
# It's so incredible that we're alone #
#There's so much to be said and done #
# It's impossible not to be overcome #
#Will you forgive me
if I feel this way? #
# 'Cause we just met #
#Tell me that's okay #
ADAMS/SARAH McLACHLAN:
# So, take this feeling #
# Make it grow #
# Never let it #
# Never let it go #
McLACHLAN:
# Don't... let... go... #
#You give me something
that I can believe in #
# No, don't... let... #
# Go of this moment in time #
# Don't... let... go... #
# I can't explain
the things that I'm feeling #
# No, don't... let... go... #
# I've been waiting all my life #
#All my life #
#To make this moment feel so right #
# Feel so right #
#The feel of you just fills the night #
# So, come on,
let's just hold on tight #
# Don't... let... go... #
#You give me something
that I can believe in #
# No, don't... let... #
# Go of this moment in time #
# Don't... let... go... #
# I can't explain
the things that I'm feeling #
# No, don't... let... #
# No, I won't let #
# Go #
# No, don't... let go #
# No, I won't... let go. #
[pensive music playing softly]
ADAMS:
# I had a dream #
# Of the wide-open prairie #
# Of the pale morning sky #
# I had a dream #
#That we flew on golden wings #
#And we were the same #
#Just the same #
#You and I #
# Follow your heart #
# Little child of the west wind #
# Follow the voice #
#That's calling you home #
# Follow your dreams #
# But always remember me #
# I am your brother #
#Yeah, under the sun #
#We are #
# Like birds of a feather #
#Two hearts joined together #
#We will be #
# Forever as one #
# My brother, under the sun #
# Under the sun #
# My brother, under the sun. #
[music fades out]