[Train whistle blows]
[Shouting and laughing]
THAT'S KISSING!
[Laughter]
MORE CHAMPAGNE!
MMM!
GIVE THE BOYS
ANOTHER 20 BUCKS.
WHEN YOU
START RUNNING LOW,
HOLLER.
THERE'S MORE WHERE THAT CAME
FROM, ISN'T THAT RIGHT, GIRLS?
YES!
OH, YEAH!
YEAH!
AND OPEN UP A BOTTLE
FOR YOURSELVES, TOO.
IT AIN'T EVERY DAY
WHEN GOLDIE OPENS
A NEW JOINT IN DENVER
AND GETS MARRIED
TO BOOT.
WISH WE COULD
GET OFF THE TRAIN
WITH YOU.
THAT'S ONE WEDDING
I'D LIKE TO SEE.
SURE WOULD.
I WISH YOU COULD,
TOO, BOYS.
ISN'T THAT
RIGHT, GIRLS?
YEAH!
DID YOU EVER SEE
SUCH A BUNCH OF
BEAUTIFUL BRIDESMAIDS
IN YOUR WHOLE
DAMN LIFE?
PENNY FOR YOUR THOUGHTS, LAT.
THEY AIN'T WORTH IT.
I WAS JUST THINKING,
BETTER GET SOME SLEEP.
WE GOT A BUSY DAY
IN DENVER TOMORROW.
A BUSY WEDDING DAY
AH DEE DAH
[Humming Wedding Day March]
DAH DAH-DAH DAH
GRRR!
[Laughs]
AH, GOOD NIGHT, BABY.
WHAT'S THE
NEXT STOP?
PURGATORY.
PURGATORY?
MM-HMM.
MINING TOWN.
IT AIN'T MUCH.
WELL, WAKE ME
WHEN WE GET
TO PURGATORY.
JUST ME.
NOT MISS GOLDIE.
YES, SIR.
MIDNIGHT
ON TIME, EZ?
SEE WHAT I'M WRITING?
MIDNIGHT
ON TIME, EZ?
I DON'T KNOW, MR. BARTON,
BUT IT SEEMS HIGH CLASS
TO WRITE DOWN THAT SHE IS.
DON'T LOOK LIKE YOU'RE WEARING
A GUN UNDER THAT COAT.
SMART.
HEARD OF A MAN GETTIN'
INTO TROUBLE MINDING
HIS OWN BUSINESS, EZ?
MIND MY OWN BUSINESS, HOW?
I SENT THE TELEGRAM.
TELEGRAMS ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE PRIVATE!
FROM THE TELEGRAPHER?
I SURE WOULD FEEL BETTER
WITH WEIGHT ON MY HIP, PA.
IF THAT PARTY MENTIONED IN
THE TELEGRAM IS ON THE MIDNIGHT,
YOU BEST BE UNARMED.
I SAID TO MIND--
[Gunshot]
[Gunshots]
THE SIDEWINDER!
YOUR SISTER'S NAME
IS PATIENCE.
PATIENCE!
STAY OUT OF
THIS, PA!
[Gunshot]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M TEACHING
THEM JACKASS MINERS
A LESSON!
[Dog Barking]
GIVE ME THAT GUN!
I KEEP TELLING YOU
NOT TO SHOOT
AT PEOPLE!
THEY HAD IT COMING!
ONE OF THEM SAID
SOMETHING VILE.
HE SAID
"DOES YOUR MOTHER
KNOW YOU'RE OUT,
CECILIA?"
YOU CONSIDER THAT
GROUNDS FOR SHOOTING
UP THE WHOLE TOWN?
I KNEW WHAT HE MEANT!
I SURE DON'T!
THEY'RE TRYING TO
RUIN MY GOOD NAME.
I'VE SWORN I'M
GOING BACK EAST
TO MISS HUNTER'S COLLEGE
ON THE HUDSON RIVER,
NEW YORK,
FOR YOUNG LADIES
OF GOOD FAMILY,
AND NOTHING'S
STOPPING ME!
EXCEPT MAYBE YOU
KILLED SOMEBODY!
I ONLY SHOOT
AT RIFFRAFF.
YOU SHOT AT US.
I MISSED YOU.
COULDN'T HIT A BULL'S
ASS WITH A BANJO.
SMART MOUTH!
HIT HIM, PA.
I'D HIT YOU FIRST.
TAKE HER HOME,
ORIVILLE.
DON'T YOU ORDER ME!
YOU HEARD ME! HOME!
NO STOPPING
BY THE CHINAMAN'S
FOR A BEER!
SHE GETS MEAN
WHEN SHE DRINKS!
HOW COME YOU EVER DID
CALL THAT GIRL PATIENCE?
YEAH.
[Train whistle blows]
CAN HEAR HER A LONG WAY OFF
WHEN THE WIND'S RIGHT.
AIN'T ENOUGH LATE TO MAKE IT
WORTHWHILE CHANGING THE BOARD.
[Whistle blows]
SOUNDS DOWNRIGHT
PEACEFUL, DON'T IT?
CALM BEFORE
THE STORM,
IF THAT CERTAIN
PARTY'S ONBOARD.
YEAH.
WELL?
WE'LL SAY WE KNOW
YOU DIDN'T GET OFF
AT PURGATORY.
WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU GOT OFF,
BUT WE KNOW IT
WASN'T PURGATORY.
DON'T OPEN UP, BOYS.
NOTHING BUT MAIL
FOR PURGATORY.
NO PASSENGERS
GETTING OFF HERE.
BE BAD MANNERS
TO CALL THE CONDUCTOR
A LIAR, SO LET'S NOT.
NO SENSE OPENING UP.
NOBODY'S GETTING
OFF AT PURGATORY.
[Whimpering]
[Dog barking]
EVENING. OR MORNING, RATHER.
IT'S 1:00 IN THE MORNING.
I GOT A WATCH.
JUST GET OFF
THE TRAIN?
DID YOU EVER HEAR OF AN EAGLE
PICKING UP A GROWN MAN AND
CARRYING HIM
CROSS-COUNTRY?
I CAN'T SAY
THAT I HAVE.
WELL, YOU HAVE NOW.
I COME BY EAGLE.
THAT'S HIM.
IF I HAD
MY RIFLE,
I COULD NAIL HIM
BETWEEN THE SHOULDERS.
THAT'S MURDER.
SO.
IT MIGHT BE
THE WRONG MAN.
GOT TO BE HIM--
BIG, MEAN, AND UGLY,
AND SNEAKING OFF
THE TRAIN.
HE GETS A ROOM,
WE ASK HIM QUESTIONS
AT THE HOTEL.
GOOD. LET'S WAIT
IN THE CHINAMAN'S
BACK ROOM.
PA, SHE'S GOING TO
GET HER ANOTHER BEER.
SO AM I!
[Rings bell]
CAN'T YOU READ?
THAT SIGN SAYS,
"TAKE A KEY.
GO TO BED."
THAT SIGN?
GO TO BED.
SIGN MUST'VE GOTTEN
A FEW STRAYS.
WE GOT LOTS OF
SHOOTING IN THIS TOWN.
HERE. REGISTER.
YOUR HANDLE AND
YOUR HOMETOWN.
ALREADY DID.
"SMITH."
IS THAT YOUR REAL NAME?
NOT THAT I'M NOSY.
GIVE ME A ROOM.
AW, KEEP
YOUR SHIRT ON.
OOH, SAY, THAT'S
REAL SILK, ISN'T IT?
YOU MUST BE RICH.
WELL?
WELL WHAT?
YOU RICH?
NOT THAT I'M CURIOUS.
IS THERE ANOTHER HOTEL
IN THIS TOWN?
AW, KEEP YOUR SHIRT ON--
YOUR SILK SHIRT.
HA HA HA HA!
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
HA HA!
COME ON.
HA HA! O.K.
HA HA!
JUST AS GOOD
A SERVICE
AS IN THE PALMER
HOUSE IN CHICAGO.
COME ON.
WATCH YOUR
STEP HERE.
TURN RIGHT. COME ON
UP AT THE TOP
OF THE STAIRS.
HA HA! YOUR
SILK SHIRT!
IF YOU HEAR A LOT OF SCREAMING,
DON'T PAY NO HEED.
ONE OF THE MINERS
HAS DELIRIUM TREMENS
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
HIS NAME'S SMITH,
TOO.
HA HA! MAYBE
YOU'RE RELATED.
HA HA HA HA!
THERE'S 2 WAYS YOU
CAN HAVE THE WINDOWS--
OPEN OR CLOSED.
CLOSED IS HOT.
OPEN, THERE'S FLIES.
EAT YOU ALIVE.
LET ME HELP
YOU UNPACK.
NEVER MIND.
OH, NO TROUBLE.
NO TROUBLE AT ALL.
HA HA HA HA HA!
WHAT'S THEM?
GRABBED THE
WRONG SUITCASE.
WHAT ARE
THESE THINGS?
THAT'S
A KEWPIE DOLL.
I WON ONE ONCE
AT THE STATE FAIR
TIME I WENT
TO DENVER.
AND GOT ROLLED
BY SOME FLOOZY.
SHUT UP.
STOP IT!
LET'S GO ASK
MARTHA PERKINS
ABOUT THIS MAN.
GOT CHANGE
FOR A $100?
NO, I HAVEN'T.
I'LL GET CHANGE
AND PAY YOU
WHEN I GET BACK.
PATIENCE BARTON,
YOU GET AWAY FROM THERE!
I COULD TELL
BY THAT STUPID FACE
HE WOULDN'T HAVE
ANY IMAGINATION. SMITH.
YOU COULDN'T EXPECT HIM
TO GO ROUND SIGNING
HIS OWN NAME
IN HIS BUSINESS.
AAH!
PATIENCE BARTON,
YOU GIVE ME
MY KEY BACK!
MISTER?
WANT TO BUY
A PAIR OF SPURS?
NO. I WONDER IF--
THEY'VE HARDLY BEEN USED.
LOTS OF WEAR LEFT IN THEM.
OUTLAST A DOZEN HORSES.
I DON'T RIDE.
THIS TOWN
GOT A DOCTOR?
[Chuckles]
BIG HUSKY FELLA
LIKE YOU,
WHAT YOU NEED
A DOCTOR FOR?
I FIGURED I'D TELL
THE DOCTOR THAT.
IF I TELL YOU,
I'D GET TIRED
OF REPEATING IT.
NOW, THIS TOWN
GOT A DOCTOR?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I'LL TELL THE MAN
WHEN HE SEES
THIS SUITCASE.
YOU'LL PUT
SOMETHING
TOGETHER.
HE MIGHT HAVE
SECRET COMPARTMENTS.
I'VE BEEN THROUGH
IT 3 TIMES.
I TOLD YOU, HE GOT
THE WRONG SUITCASE.
I'M TELLING YOU,
THE MAN GOT
THE WRONG SUITCASE.
[Gunshots]
[Shouting]
[Patience] HEY! PA,
MAKE HIM LET GO!
I GOT HIM!
I GOT HIM, PA!
YOU PROMISE
TO MARRY THAT GIRL
OR SOMETHING
OF THE SORT
NOT EVEN SOMETHING
OF THE SORT.
I DON'T KNOW
THE LADY.
WE WAS STANDING
BY THE SALOON.
SHE COME WALKING BY.
I SAID, "DOES YOUR MOTHER
KNOW YOU'RE OUT, CECILIA?"
KIND OF WITTY-LIKE?
THOUGHT SHE'D BLOW US
TO KINGDOM COME.
YOU NEVER SEEN SO MANY
FAST-LEAVING COWBOYS.
GUESS SHE JUST LIKES
TO SHOOT PEOPLE.
WELL, SEEMS TO
BE ALL CLEAR.
WHERE'D YOU SAY
THAT DOCTOR WAS?
YOU KNOW, I STILL DON'T SEE
WHAT A BIG HEALTHY FELLA--
HE'S PROBABLY SHOOTING POOL
IN THE BACK OF THE SALOON.
AT 1 A.M.?
IT'S A REAL
UPSIDE-DOWN TOWN.
WITH 3 SHIFTS
OF MINERS
COMING ON AND OFF
WORK ALL DAY LONG.
HE ANSWERS TO
DOC SCHULTZ.
THANKS.
YOU'RE SURE YOU DON'T
WANT TO BUY THE SPURS?
NO.
HEY, UH...
COWBOY'S GOT TO
BE PRETTY DOWN
TO BE WILLING TO SELL
HIS HORSE IRONS.
MY HORSE WENT FIRST.
THEN MY SADDLE.
BUT I'M SOBER NOW,
AND WHAT I GOT LEFT
IS THESE HERE SPURS
AND A MIGHTY
EMPTY BELLY.
OH, WELL. HERE.
HERE, YOU--
YOU EAT ON ME, HUH?
THANKS, FRIEND.
NAME'S JUG. JUG MAY.
UH, LATIGO SMITH.
NOW, YOU ENJOY YOUR FOOD.
I CAN'T THANK YOU
ENOUGH.
DON'T CRY. MONEY IS
THE LEAST OF MY TROUBLES.
LET'S SEE...
$100! MISTER,
YOU GAVE--
I AIN'T EVER
EVEN SEEN ONE.
HA HA HA HA!
I AIN'T NEVER EVEN
SEEN A HUNDRED--
IF I HADN'T BEEN HURRIED,
I COULD'VE GOTTEN HIM
RIGHT BETWEEN THE EYES!
YOU SURE DON'T
TAKE AFTER YOUR
POOR SAINTED MOTHER.
I HATE THIS TOWN
AND IF I DON'T
GET BACK EAST
TO MISS HUNTER'S COLLEGE
FOR YOUNG LADIES
OF GOOD FAMILY
I'M GOING TO HATE IT
A WHOLE LOT MORE...
AND EVERYBODY IN IT!
YOU AIN'T EXACTLY LOVED BY ONE
AND ALL AROUND HERE, EITHER!
THAT'S ENOUGH.
CAN'T YOU DO
ANYTHING WITH HER?
THIS IS
A FAMILY MATTER!
I'LL THANK YOU
TO STAY OUT OF IT!
COME ALONG,
ORIVILLE.
18 BLACK AND EVEN.
EVERYBODY WINS AGAIN.
CARE TO PLACE
A LITTLE BET, SIR?
YOU LOOKING
FOR TROUBLE,
MISTER?
NO, SIR.
DO I LOOK
DIMWITTED ENOUGH
TO PLAY THAT GAME?
AGAINST HOUSE RULES
TO ANSWER THAT KIND OF QUESTION.
HOWDY. DO YOU PLAY
POCKET BILLIARDS, SIR?
NOT NOW.
YOU DOC SCHULTZ?
SAYS SO ON MY LICENSE.
TOSS ME THAT PIECE
OF CHALK? THANK YOU.
IF A MAN
TELLS HIS LAWYER
HE KILLED
A GENT OR 2,
THE LAWYER CAN'T
TELL ANYBODY, CAN HE?
DON'T SEE THAT
CONCERNS ME ANY,
BUT YOU'RE RIGHT.
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN
COUNSEL AND CLIENT
IS SACRED.
SAME WITH A DOCTOR,
AIN'T IT?
A DOCTOR CAN'T TELL
ANYBODY WHAT ANYBODY'S GOT.
YOU MUST HAVE A VERY
INTERESTING DISEASE.
IT'S WORTH
$500 TO YOU.
GETTING MORE INTERESTING
BY THE MINUTE.
OF COURSE, I'LL HAVE TO
BLOW YOUR HEAD OFF IF YOU TELL.
I AIN'T NEVER SEEN
A CASE OF LEPROSY.
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU GOT,
I WOULDN'T KNOW.
IT AIN'T LEPROSY,
BUT CAN'T WE GO SOMEPLACE
WHERE WE COULD
BE ALONE?
WELL, THAT SOUNDS
LIKE A SOUND IDEA.
MY OFFICE IS RIGHT
UP THE STREET THERE.
GOING TO CHANGE
YOUR MIND ABOUT
MAKING A BET?
ONLY IDIOTS
PLAY ROULETTE.
DO I LOOK
LIKE AN IDIOT?
NO, SIR.
DON'T YOU
FORGET IT!
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
THIRD SHIFT.
THIRD SHIFT?
1ST AND 2ND GENERALLY
SET THE DYNAMITE CHARGE
AND FUSES.
3RD DOES THE BLASTING.
SOMETIMES IT
GOES ON ALL NIGHT.
YOU'LL GET USED
TO IT. COME ON.
PURGATORY SITS SMACK
ON TOP OF 2 MINES.
TAYLOR BARTON OWNS ONE,
COLONEL AMES THE OTHER.
BEEN FIGHTING EACH OTHER
TRYING TO TUNNEL
TO THE MOTHER LODE
FOR 2 YEARS NOW.
THE MOTHER LODE?
DEAD CENTER OF TOWN,
ACCORDING TO THEM
GEOLOGIST FELLAS.
LIKE BUILDING A RAILROAD,
COMING FROM EAST AND WEST--
FIRST TO ARRIVE
GETS TO DRIVE
THE GOLDEN SPIKE.
AND THE OTHER ONE
GETS THE SHAFT.
HYAH!
HYAH! HYAH!
SHE SHOOTS
AT PEOPLE, TOO.
NICEST GIRL IN TOWN.
I SURE AM CURIOUS
ABOUT THAT AILMENT
OF YOURS.
THIS IS
YOUR OFFICE?
I DOCTOR PACK MULES, TOO.
GOT A PAIN IN THE ASS,
COME SEE DOC SCHULTZ.
[Mule brays]
[Horse whinnies]
THAT'S BETTER NOW.
WELL...
WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM?
WELL, DOC, UH...
YOU PROMISE YOU WON'T
TELL ANYBODY, HUH?
ON MY HIPPOCRATIC OATH.
[Horse neighs]
IN ALL MY BORN DAYS...
I WAS DRUNK AT THE TIME.
I COULD'VE
GUESSED THAT.
WHERE'S THE
YOUNG LADY NOW?
NEVER MIND.
CAN YOU TAKE
HER OFF, DOC?
YOU MENTIONED $500.
CASH.
WELL, IF I EVER
KNEWED ANYTHING
ABOUT TATTOOING,
I'VE FORGOTTEN IT.
I'LL HAVE TO READ UP
ON THE SUBJECT.
YOU'LL BE AROUND?
LONG ENOUGH TO GET THIS OFF.
THEN I'LL BE LONG GONE.
YOU RUNNING AWAY
FROM THE LADY?
OF COURSE NOT.
BUT IF SHE SHOULD
SHOW UP,
YOU HAVEN'T
SEEN ME, HUH?
HOW WOULD I KNOW HER?
SHE'S GOT A LOT
OF THIS GOLD-COLORED HAIR.
OF EVERYTHING,
BUT MOSTLY SHE'S GOT
A LOT OF THIS
GOLD-COLORED HAIR.
WHAT DO I DO, DOC?
COME SEE ME IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
GIVE ME TIME TO READ UP.
YOU'RE THE, UH, DOCTOR.
JUST A MINUTE,
I'D LIKE TO SPEAK TO YOU.
I DON'T KNOW YOU
AND SEE NO REASON
TO START.
I WANT TO OFFER YOU
VERY PROFITABLE
EMPLOYMENT.
I'M IN BUSINESS
FOR MYSELF.
DOC!
YEAH!
WHO IS THAT FELLA?
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
AND SPEAKING OF BUSINESS,
YOU MINE OWNERS
ARE A DESPICABLE LOT.
YOU HIRE PEOPLE
TO KILL PEOPLE,
AND OTHER PEOPLE
HIRE PEOPLE
TO KILL YOUR PEOPLE.
THEN YOU GO ELSEWHERE
WITH YOUR MEDICAL BUSINESS,
I HAVE TO DOCTOR
JACKASSES TO MAKE ENDS MEET.
NOW, BEAT IT.
I GOT BUSINESS.
EVER BEEN TOLD
YOU'VE GOT A ROTTEN
BEDSIDE MANNER?
OUT!
AND YOU TALK TOO MUCH!
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND YOU.
LIKE TO PLACE A BET?
SORRY, I DIDN'T
KNOW IT WAS--
ASK ME THAT AGAIN,
I'LL PUT A PLEAT
IN YOUR SKULL.
YES, SIR.
I MEAN, NO, SIR.
SARSAPARILLA.
WHAT?
I'D WRITE IT DOWN,
BUT I DON'T FIGURE
YOU COULD READ IT.
SODY POP.
DON'T HARDLY ANYBODY
EVER WANT SODA POP.
DON'T YOU DRINK?
ONLY TO BE SOCIABLE.
AND I DON'T FEEL
SOCIABLE RIGHT NOW.
DIMWITS.
[Roulette wheel spins]
WHO?
IDIOTS PLAYING
ROULETTE.
OH. SOME PEOPLE
LIKE IT.
SUCKERS. AND
THE WORST KIND
OF SUCKERS.
HOUSE GOT ALL
THE BEST OF IT.
THEY OUGHT TO TAKE
ALL THE ROULETTE
DEALERS OUT
AND STRING THEM UP.
HOUSE GOT 8
THE BEST OF IT,
EVEN IF THE WHEEL
IS STRAIGHT,
AND IT AIN'T.
THE HOUSE GOT 8
THE BEST OF IT.
8. THAT MEANS
THAT 1 OUT OF
EVERY 12 TIMES,
THE HOUSE TAKES YOUR MONEY,
AND YOU HAVEN'T GOT A CHANCE.
ANYBODY WHO PLAYS ROULETTE,
OUGHTA HAVE THEIR HEAD EXAMINED.
OUGHT TO
JUST TAKE THEM OUT
AND LOCK THEM UP.
THEY OUGHT TO BURN
ALL THE ROULETTE
WHEELS.
$4,600
ON NUMBER 23.
I CAN'T TAKE
THAT KIND OF MONEY.
4,600 ON 23.
BOSS!
BOSS, THIS FELLA
JUST BET 4,600
ON NUMBER 23.
SPIN HER.
NUMBER 22.
THE MAN LOSES.
JUST COMES OVER ME
EVERY SO OFTEN.
NOTHING I CAN DO
ABOUT IT.
NUMBER 23 JUST
PULLS AT ME.
WELL...THEY SAY
MONEY ISN'T EVERYTHING.
IS IF A MAN'S HUNGRY.
YEAH.
THAT REMINDS ME--
I'M HUNGRY.
HOW MUCH YOU GOT LEFT
OF THAT $100 I GAVE YOU?
NONE.
WELL, I ATE UP
$20 OF IT.
BOUGHT A GAL SOME WINE.
SHE HAD A SICK MOTHER IN--
GAVE HER THE MONEY?
SEEMED LIKE THE
THING TO DO.
YOU IDIOT. DON'T YOU KNOW
THAT'S THE SUREST WAY
TO MAKE AN ENEMY
OF A WOMAN,
GIVING HER MONEY?
I LEARNED THAT
LONG AGO.
WELL...
LET'S TAKE A WALK.
NEED THE AIR
AND TIME TO THINK.
ABOUT THAT JOB I
WANT YOU TO DO--
I TOLD YOU
NOT TO BOTHER ME,
MISTER.
THE MAN SAID
SOMETHING
ABOUT A JOB.
I DON'T LIKE TO WORK.
TIRES ME OUT.
HOW WE GOING TO EAT
IF WE DON'T WORK?
WE?
SORT OF FIGURED
WE'D RIDE TOGETHER.
RIDE? HORSES?
YEAH.
I TOLD YOU I DON'T RIDE.
I'M A TRAIN MAN.
AT LEAST CARRIAGES.
MAN'S GOT TO BE
NUMB ON BOTH ENDS
TO EARN HIS LIVING
SITTING ON A HORSE.
I JUST DON'T
LIKE HORSES.
THAT'S CLOSE
TO TREASON
IN THESE PARTS.
UH-HUH.
LIVELY PLACE.
THIS IS A 2-SHAFT TOWN.
ONLY ONE OF THEM WORKS
FULL TIME.
HALF THE JACKASS MINERS
IS DRINKING--
A WOMAN RUN
THAT SALOON?
HMM?
DOES A WOMAN
RUN THAT SALOON?
MISS JENNY.
YOU STILL GOT THEM SPURS
YOU TRIED
TO SELL ME?
GIVE THEM TO ME.
YOU THREW ONE AWAY.
DID JUST THAT.
[Dog barks]
OPEN UP
ANOTHER TABLE.
MISS JENNY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I BROUGHT YOU THIS...
FROM SLIM.
WHAT IS THIS,
A JOKE?
MA'AM, I RODE
OVER 300 MILES
TO BRING YOU THAT SPUR.
THIS IS HARDLY
A JOKING MATTER,
POOR BOY DYING.
JUST ME AND HIM OUT THERE
ON THE PRAIRIE ALL ALONE.
WOLVES HOWLING
OFF IN THE DISTANCE.
"LAT," HE SAID TO ME,
"THERE'S NOTHING
I GOT LEFT EXCEPT
THIS ONE SPUR.
"I WANT YOU TO TAKE IT
TO MY ONLY TRUE LOVE
MISS JENNY."
I KNEW WHO
HE WAS TALKING
ABOUT RIGHT OFF.
ALL THOSE LONELY
NIGHTS ON THE TRAIL.
HE HARDLY TALKED ABOUT
ANYTHING BUT YOU.
AND WHAT A HEART
OF GOLD YOU HAD.
I KIND OF REMEMBER.
THERE MUST'VE BEEN A SLIM.
OH, BARTENDER,
GIVE THIS GENTLEMAN
A DRINK.
[Bartender]
YES, MA'AM.
IS HE WITH YOU?
YES, MA'AM, I AM.
MY NAME IS JUG MAY.
GIVE THEM BOTH A DRINK,
AND I'LL HAVE ONE.
NOW, ABOUT THIS SLIM...
HE WAS IN
LOVE WITH ME,
IS THAT IT?
MA'AM, THERE WAS NEVER
A TRUER LOVE NOR NOBLER.
THE MINUTE I LAID
EYES ON YOU,
I COULD UNDERSTAND WHY
THE BOY FELT THAT WAY.
YES, I CAN UNDERSTAND.
"MISS JENNY," HE SAID,
"SHE'S NOT LIKE
OTHER WOMEN."
HE SAID THAT
REAL OFTEN.
"NOW, MISS JENNY,
SHE'S...
"SHE'S KIND
AND GENEROUS TO A FAULT
"AND WOULD GIVE A MAN
HER LAST DIME."
YOU SURE
YOU'RE NOT LYING TO ME?
MAY I BE STRUCK DOWN
IN MY TRACKS AND--
YOU ALL RIGHT?
IF THAT'S
THE 3RD SHIFT, I AM.
SORRY. SOMETIMES
IT COMES WITHOUT WARNING.
NOW, GETTING BACK TO--
TO SLIM.
HE REALLY SAID
THOSE NICE THINGS
ABOUT ME?
OH, YES, MA'AM.
EVEN DYING, HE SAID
ALL THEM NICE THINGS
AND MORE.
OH, I'M TOUCHED.
NOT AS MUCH
AS YOU'RE GONNA BE.
THERE'S A NAME FOR
A MAN LIKE THAT.
MORNING, PATIENCE.
GOOD MORNING.
LOOKS NICE.
THANK YOU.
[Dog barking]
[Chimes ring]
TRY THIS.
OH, I LIKE IT.
WE'LL TAKE
THIS ONE.
YOU SURE GOT GOOD TASTE
IN PICKING HATS,
JUST LIKE
EVERYTHING ELSE.
IT'LL EMBARRASS
ME YOU PAYING.
MAYBE YOU BETTER LET
ME HAVE THE MONEY.
STAND THERE
AND BE EMBARRASSED.
I'LL PAY THE MAN.
BOY, HAVE YOU
GOT BRASS.
HMM?
ASKING A WOMAN
FOR MONEY LIKE THAT.
YOU THINK THAT'S WRONG?
THE WAY I
WAS BRUNG UP.
A WOMAN BROUGHT YOU UP,
DIDN'T SHE?
YEAH.
YOU SEE?
I MEAN, IT AIN'T
GENERALLY DONE.
DID YOU EVER KNOW A WOMAN
TO SHOW ANY SLOWNESS AT ALL
IN ASKING YOU FOR MONEY?
NO, NOW THAT I
THINK ABOUT IT.
I JUST MADE
ONE MISTAKE, THOUGH--
ASKING HER
IN THE DAYLIGHT.
COME ACROSS MUCH
EASIER AT NIGHT.
[Chimes ring]
[Cash register rings]
MORNING.
YOU BUYING YOURSELF
A NEW HAT?
THE LADY'S
BUYING HIM ONE.
WILL IT MAKE
OR BREAK YOUR DAY
IF I DO OR DON'T
BUY A HAT, STRANGER?
I DON'T WANT TO BE
A STRANGER TO YOU.
MY NAME'S COLORADO.
COLORADO McGEE.
YOU SOUND LIKE YOU EXPECTED
I SHOULD'VE HEARD OF YOU.
WELL, I NEVER HAVE,
SO WHAT DO YOU WANT?
ARE YOU AS FAST AS
THEY SAY YOU ARE, SWIFTY?
WHAT'D YOU CALL ME?
SWIFTY.
I'LL CALL YOU MR. MORGAN,
IF YOU LIKE,
BUT I'M GOING OUT
TO WAIT FOR YOU
TO COME OUT.
AND IF YOU DON'T,
ME AND EVERYBODY
ELSE IN TOWN
WILL CALL YOU
A YELLOW DOG.
[Dog whimpers]
GUNFIGHT?
YOU CATCH ON.
WELL, YOU JUST
GO ON OUT THERE.
I'LL BE OUT ON
THE COUNT OF 10.
YOU HIT THAT FELLA
FROM BEHIND.
JUST AS HARD
AS I COULD.
BETTER GET ME
ONE OF THOSE IRONS
OVER THERE.
WHAT'S THAT GUNFIGHTER
GOT AGAINST YOU?
I NEVER SAW HIM
BEFORE IN MY LIFE.
OH, MISS JENNY,
I'M SORRY THAT
A WELL-BROUGHT-UP
LADY LIKE YOU
HAD TO SEE
A THING
LIKE THIS.
LET'S GO TO THE HOTEL,
AND YOU CAN LAY DOWN.
LAT, FROM THE WAY
THIS FELLA'S
WEARING HIS GUN,
LOOKS LIKE
HE'S LEFT-HANDED.
IT WAS HIS RIGHT
TRIGGER FINGER
YOU BUSTED.
MISS JENNY,
WOULD YOU, UH...
TURN YOUR HEAD,
PLEASE?
GIVE ME THE IRON.
[Crunch]
IF I'D KNOWN YOU'D
SEND THIS PIPSQUEAK
AGAINST SWIFTY MORGAN--
MR. BARTON,
I CAN'T HELP IT--
DON'T TAKE
OFFENSE, LAD.
YOU'VE NEVER KILLED
ANYBODY OUTSIDE
OF THIS COUNTY.
YOU'RE JUST
LOCAL STUFF.
SWIFTY MORGAN IS
KNOWN FROM CANADA
TO THE MEXICAN BORDER.
IF YOU'VE GOT
A BETTER IDEA,
LET'S HAVE IT.
BUY THIS
SWIFTY MORGAN.
BUT COLONEL AMES
ALREADY BOUGHT MORGAN.
ALL GUNFIGHTERS
HAVE A PRICE.
THEY'RE A LOW ORDER
OF HUMANITY. REAL LICE.
LOOK HERE,
MR. BARTON--
SHUT UP!
WE OFFER MORGAN
ENOUGH MONEY
TO DOUBLE-CROSS
COLONEL AMES.
THAT
SOUNDS GOOD.
HOW CAN YOU BE SURE
THAT COLONEL AMES SENT
FOR SWIFTY MORGAN?
I KNOW WHAT GOES ON
IN THE COLONEL'S HOUSE.
HE'S SPARKING THE COLONEL'S
OLD MAID SISTER, THAT'S HOW.
YOU YOUNG--
I SEEN YOU OUT
BICYCLE-RIDING
WITH HIS SISTER
ON THE HANDLEBARS.
YOU OUGHT TO BE
ASHAMED OF YOURSELVES,
ACTING LIKE THAT
AT YOUR AGE.
YOU OUGHT TO SET EXAMPLES
FOR YOUNG PEOPLE,
INSTEAD OF CARRYING ON
LIKE A RANDY OLD GOAT,
HER LOOKING LIKE
A WINTERKILL PERSIMMON.
GET HIM
OUT OF HERE.
KID...
GET OUT.
ALL I CAN SAY IS
I'D HANG
MY HEAD IN SHAME
WAS I KIN TO YOU,
MR. OLD GOAT BARTON.
PIPSQUEAK!
I FIGURE WE CAN
HIRE SWIFTY MORGAN
AWAY FROM COLONEL AMES
FOR $5,000.
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY.
WE'LL LOSE MORE
IF WE DON'T GET TO
THE MOTHER LODE FIRST.
WE'LL NEVER GET THERE
IF WE DON'T GO BACK
AND START DIGGING!
AS TREASURER
OF THE COMPANY,
THIS CALLS FOR A MEETING
OF THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS.
WE'RE THE BOARD
OF DIRECTORS!
I MOVE THAT WE
SPEND THE 5,000.
SECOND.
YOU CAN'T SECOND THE MOTION.
YOU'RE CHAIRMAN OF THE BOARD.
THERE IS
PARLIAMENTARY
PROCEDURE.
COLONEL AMES ISN'T
WORRIED ABOUT PROCEDURE.
HE'S GOT FOUR GUNMEN
ON TOP OF OUR MINE
KEEPING US OUT.
HE'LL KEEP US OUT
TILL WE TAKE THE BULL
BY THE HORNS--
AND START FIGHTING
FIRE WITH FIRE.
LOOK.
COLONEL AMES.
WALKS LIKE
HE OWNS THE TOWN.
HE WILL,
IF WE DON'T HIRE
SWIFTY MORGAN.
LAST TIME
I WORE THAT DRESS
WAS AT THE GOVERNOR'S BALL
20 YEARS AGO.
AND THIS HAT,
THERE WASN'T A MAN
OR BIRD DOG IN PURGATORY
DIDN'T POINT
AT ME WHEN I WALKED
DOWN THE STREET.
YOU THINK I LOOK LIKE
A LADY OF THE EVENING?
WHAT'S A LADY
OF THE EVENING?
MISS ABIGAIL,
YOU DO LEAD
A SHELTERED LIFE.
CAN I PASS FOR A GIRL
AT MISS JENNY'S PLACE?
YOU MEAN
A DANCE-HALL GIRL?
DANCE-HALL GIRL.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE.
THEY GO CARRIAGE-RIDING
PAST YOUR WINDOW EVERY DAY.
I KEEP
THE SHADES DRAWN
WHEN THEY DO.
WHERE WILL
I PUT THIS?
THERE'S ROOM BACK--
WHAT ON EARTH?
I'M GOING TO DO
SOME BLASTING.
IN JENNY'S PLACE?
IN JENNY'S PLACE.
YOU'RE NOT
GETTING YOURSELF
IN TROUBLE?
NO, BUT I KNOW
SOMEBODY WHO IS.
OH, WAIT.
FOR YOU KNOW WHO.
MISS ABIGAIL,
WHY ARE
YOU SO DEAD SET
ON MARRYING MY PA?
HE AIN'T SMART,
AND HE SNORES
SOMETHING AWFUL.
DON'T BE INDELICATE,
MY DEAR.
YOUR FATHER
HAS CHARACTERISTICS
THAT YOU DON'T RECOGNIZE,
AND ALSO
SUCH A MARRIAGE
WOULD GIVE
MY DEAR BROTHER
APOPLEXY,
ROT HIS SOUL.
[Colonel]
ABIGAIL!
SPEAK OF THE DEVIL.
THE SERVANTS TELL ME
THE DAUGHTER OF THAT
HORRID TAYLOR BARTON
HAS SNEAKED
INTO THIS HOUSE.
OPEN UP!
[Banging on door]
SHE'S NOT
IN HERE, BROTHER,
AND STOP BANGING
ON THAT DOOR!
[Colonel] I INSIST
THAT YOU OPEN THIS DOOR!
OH, VERY WELL.
SATISFIED?
I WILL BE WHEN
YOU STOP SNEAKING OFF
WITH TAYLOR BARTON
AND RIDING
THAT DAMN BICYCLE.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN
RIDING IN OVER A WEEK.
TAYLOR'S GOT A FLAT.
HE'LL HAVE
MORE THAN THAT.
YOU TOUCH ONE HAIR
ON HIS HEAD--
ONE GRAY HAIR.
HE'S AN OLD MAN.
THERE'S SNOW
ON THE ROOF,
BUT THERE'S FIRE--
ABIGAIL!
HAVE YOU
NO SHAME, WOMAN?
WELL,
WHAT ABOUT YOU,
KEEPING TAYLOR'S WORKERS
OUT OF THE MINE?
HOW ELSE WILL I GET
TO THE MOTHER LODE
BEFORE HE DOES?
HIS SHAFT IS
RIGHT IN TOWN.
I HAVE TO TUNNEL
TWICE AS FAR.
THAT DOESN'T
GIVE YOU THE--
I'M TALKING ABOUT GETTING
TO THAT GOLD BEFORE--
GOLD! THAT'S ALL
YOU EVER THINK OF!
ALL TAYLOR BARTON
THINKS ABOUT
IS COURTING YOU
TO SPY ON ME.
AND I TELL HIM
EVERYTHING HE
WANTS TO KNOW.
HE'S USING YOU,
ABIGAIL.
HE SURE IS.
[Sighing]
MORNING.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M THE NEW GIRL.
YOU IS?
I GOT IN
THIS MORNING
FROM FRISCO.
IN FACT,
THAT'S MY NAME,
FRISCO.
WELL,
IT'S NICE WORK.
IT HAS ITS
UPS AND DOWNS,
BUT IT IS NICE WORK.
BEAT IT.
PUT 'EM UP.
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO
WITH THAT?
KILL YOU.
I'M A ROTTEN SHOT
AND GETTING AWFUL
TIRED OF MISSING YOU
WHY ARE YOU SHOOTING AT ME
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
SO I COULD GO TO
MISS HUNTER'S COLLEGE
FOR YOUNG LADIES
OF GOOD FAMILY.
NOW PUT 'EM UP.
WHY PUT MY HANDS
UP FOR THAT?
I DON'T FEEL RIGHT
ABOUT KILLING YOU IN BED.
COULD YOU TRY
AND GRAB ME?
THEN I'D GET MAD
AND LIGHT THE FUSE.
IT'S YOUR CHRISTIAN DUTY
TO TELL ME WHY YOU'RE
BLOWING ME UP.
THE MINE.
THE MINE?
IF MY PA DON'T GET
TO THE MOTHER LODE
BEFORE COLONEL AMES,
THEN WE WON'T
HAVE ANY MONEY,
AND I CAN'T GO TO MISS
HUNTER'S COLLEGE. UNDERSTAND?
NO, BUT WHAT'S
ALL THAT GOT
TO DO WITH ME?
DON'T PLAY THE INNOCENT,
MR. SWIFTY MORGAN.
YOU KNOW COLONEL AMES
SENT FOR YOU.
YOU THINK I'M
THE FAMOUS SWIFTY MORGAN?
KEEP IT UP.
YOU'RE GETTING
ME ANGRY.
IF I GET ANGRY,
I'LL LIGHT THIS--
I DON'T WANT TO DO THAT,
BUT I'M NOT SWIFTY MORGAN.
LIAR! MY PA IS SPARKING
COLONEL AMES' OLD MAID SISTER.
SHE TOLD HIM COLONEL AMES
SENT FOR YOU, MORGAN.
WHAT'S THIS,
A HOLDUP?
SHOW THE LADY
THE INSIDE OF ONE
OF THOSE BOOTS.
THE INSIDE OF THE BOOTS.
I HAD THOSE BOOTS MADE
IN AMARILLO A YEAR AGO.
LOOK INSIDE.
GO ON, LOOK.
"LATIGO SMITH."
$60 BOOTS. A MAN
CERTAINLY WOULD HAVE
HIS RIGHT NAME IN THEM.
YOU PROBABLY TOOK THEM OFF
SOME POOR FELLA YOU SHOT.
WHY, YOU'RE
THE BARTON GIRL.
WHAT YOU DOING
IN HERE?
YOUR SAINTED MOTHER,
ONE OF THE NICEST LADIES
TO SEW FOR THE BAPTISTS.
DOWN THE BACK STAIRS
WITH YOU. COME ON.
YOU HAVE NOT SEEN THE LAST
OF ME YET, MR. SWIFTY MORGAN!
HELLO, LADIES' MAN.
HA HA HA!
"I LOVE GOLDIE."
I WARNED YOU
ABOUT THAT.
NOT TO MENTION IT
TO ANYBODY ELSE.
I'VE STUDIED UP
ON TATTOOING.
I CAN DO THE JOB FOR YOU,
BUT IN EASY STAGES.
TAKE A COUPLE WEEKS.
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
DOC, DOES THAT 500
HAVE TO BE IN CASH?
WELL, MISS JENNY'S
CERTAINLY GOT 500,
BUT THEN SHE'S HAD EXPERIENCE
WITH MEN LIKE YOU.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
MEN LIKE ME?
GIVE YOU ANYTHING
EXCEPT CASH MONEY, HUH?
THERE'S ONE THING
THAT DON'T CHANGE
ABOUT WOMEN.
THAT'S THE FACT
THAT THEY'RE
CHANGEABLE.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
SO MUCH ABOUT WOMEN?
I WORKED AT IT.
HELLO, PATIENCE.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH HIM, DOC?
YOU KNOW A DOC CAN'T TALK
ABOUT HIS PATIENTS, PATIENCE.
DOC, WE'RE THE ONLY FRIENDS
WE GOT IN THIS SCURVY TOWN.
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF WE GOT MAD
AT EACH OTHER?
HE JUST GOT A LITTLE
TROUBLE WITH THE CHEST.
HIM?
HE LOOKS
STRONG AS A HORSE.
YOU'VE TAKEN
A DISLIKING TO HIM.
I HATE
PROFESSIONAL
GUNSLINGERS.
HIM, A GUNSLINGER?
THAT'S SWIFTY MORGAN.
I JUST STARTED
TAKING A LIKING TO HIM.
I'D HAD HIM SHOT BY NOW
IF PA HADN'T TAKEN
MY WINCHESTER
AWAY FROM ME.
PATIENCE,
STOP SHOOTING AT PEOPLE.
IF YOU WASN'T
SUCH A BAD SHOT,
THERE WOULDN'T BE
A YOUNG MAN ALIVE
IN PURGATORY.
I HEARD YOU SHOT
AT ELMER PRICE
YESTERDAY.
HE ASKED ME
TO MARRY HIM.
THAT'S REASON ENOUGH
TO SHOOT HIM?
DOC, YOU'VE SEEN ELMER?
UGH!
MORNING, DOC.
UH, MORNING, ELMER.
MR. MORGAN.
WHAT'D YOU CALL ME?
WE KNOW
YOU'RE SWIFTY MORGAN.
WE HAVE
A PROPOSITION
FOR YOU.
WE WANT YOU
TO DOUBLE-CROSS
COLONEL AMES.
THERE'S $5,000 IN IT.
NOW, LOOK, I--
$5,000?
CASH?
CASH.
SO YOU...YOU THINK
I'M SWIFTY MORGAN.
I LOOK TO YOU LIKE THE BEST
GUNMAN IN THE WHOLE SOUTHWEST.
KNEW RIGHT AWAY.
THAT SHARP,
HAWK-LIKE GAZE,
WAY YOU STAND.
WELL, I HATE
TO SAY THIS,
BUT THAT'S SWIFTY.
UH, SWIFTY...
COME OVER HERE.
COME ON.
THESE GENTLEMEN
KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
THERE'S NO USE
DENYING IT.
HOWDY.
NOW THAT
THAT'S SETTLED,
SWIFTY WOULD APPRECIATE IT IF
YOU DIDN'T BANDY HIS NAME ABOUT.
HE'S MODEST,
SWIFTY IS.
THESE GENTLEMEN
HAVE A PROPOSITION.
I SUPPOSE IT'S ALL RIGHT IF
I HANDLE THE BUSINESS DETAILS.
GO AHEAD AND FINISH YOUR GAME
WHILE I TALK TO THESE GENTLEMEN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
GO AHEAD.
KEEN EYE.
KILLED 5O,
THEY SAY.
EXAGGERATION.
32 TO BE EXACT.
NOW, SUPPOSE YOU SPREAD
YOUR CARDS ON THE TABLE
AND THE CASH.
THE CASH IS
IN MY SAFE.
AND IT'S BEST IF WE AREN'T
SEEN TOGETHER TOO MUCH.
YOU SLIP OUT
AND BRING THE MONEY
TO MY ROOM
IN 15 MINUTES.
RIGHT.
YOU CALLED ME SWIFTY.
THAT'S SHORT
FOR SWIFTY MORGAN.
THAT'S WHO THEY
THINK YOU ARE.
AND THEY'RE WILLING TO PAY
TO BACK UP THAT MISTAKEN IDEA.
I'M SUPPOSED TO PRETEND
I'M SWIFTY MORGAN?
GOODBYE.
THEY'RE WILLING TO PAY.
HOW MUCH?
$1,000.
WE'LL SPLIT IT
50/50.
THAT MEANS
400 FOR YOU.
SEEMS FAIR.
BUT I THINK THAT--
NO, NO, YOU DON'T.
THAT'S THE DEAL.
I THINK,
YOU STAND AROUND
AND LOOK TOUGH.
STOP THAT.
I TOLD YOU YOU'RE NOT
TO REACH FOR THAT GUN
NO MATTER WHAT.
SOMEBODY
SPITS IN YOUR EYE,
SOMEBODY CASTS DOUBTS
ON YOUR MOTHER,
YOU REFER
THE MATTER TO ME.
IF I'M SUPPOSED
TO BE SWIFTY MORGAN,
I'VE GOT MY REPUTATION
TO CONSIDER.
I'VE GOT ME TO CONSIDER.
PRIDE.
IF YOU START THINKING,
THE DEAL'S OFF.
NO $400.
I'M GETTING BETTER.
YOU WATCH.
IF IT EVER COMES
TO GUNFIGHTING,
YOU'LL NEVER LAST.
SURE YOU AIN'T FAST?
NO. I'M SLOW.
IT'S JUST...
YOU'RE EVEN SLOWER.
[Knocking on door]
THEY COME SNEAKING IN,
LOOKING AT THE REGISTER,
TRYING TO FIND
MR. SMITH.
I TRIED TO TELL THEM
I GOT FOUR SMITHS.
THANK YOU,
MRS. PERKINS.
WE WOULDN'T
WANT TO KEEP YOU
FROM YOUR WORK.
I SUPPOSE,
THE WAY THEY SNEAK IN,
THAT YOU'RE
ANOTHER GUNFIGHTER
THAT THESE STUPID MINERS
KEEP HIRING AROUND HERE.
I SUPPOSE
THEY'RE HIRING YOU
SO YOU CAN SHOOT
SOME OTHER MOTHER'S SON,
THEN SOME OTHER
MOTHER'S SON
CAN SHOOT YOU.
MARTHA, UNHINGE
YOUR JAW AND DEPART.
YOU SEE NOW
WHY I DEMAND MY RENT
IN ADVANCE EVERY DAY?
ANOTHER SMITH.
MORE OF THEM
COMING ALL THE TIME,
GETTING THEMSELVES
KILLED OFF.
THE MONEY?
SWIFTY IN THERE?
YES. THE MONEY?
BEFORE WE TALK
TO MR. MORGAN,
A LITTLE
SUPERSTITION OF HIS.
HE LEAVES
MONEY MATTERS TO ME.
I THANK YOU NOT TO MENTION
ANYTHING ABOUT THE TRANSACTION.
UH, SORRY. DIDN'T MEAN
TO STARTLE YOU, SWIFTY.
THAT WAS CLOSE.
DON'T EVER COME UP
ON MY BLIND SIDE
LIKE THAT.
[Crack]
NO, SIR,
MR. MORGAN.
[Gunfire]
THAT'S CLOSE ENOUGH.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I CAME TO SEE
THE KILLINGS.
WHAT KILLINGS?
YOU, FOR ONE,
AND THOSE OTHERS.
IT SHOULD BE
QUITE A SHOW.
THERE'S FOUR OF YOU
AND ONE OF SWIFTY MORGAN.
I THOUGHT MORGAN
WAS ON OUR SIDE.
THERE'S BEEN
SOME CHANGES MADE.
MORGAN, HE TOOK
THE COLONEL'S MONEY,
AND THEN TOOK MONEY
FROM THE OTHER
MINE OWNERS.
DON'T SOUND LIKE
FAIR DEALINGS TO ME,
BUT YOU FELLAS
WILL TEACH HIM
THAT HONESTY'S
THE BEST POLICY.
YOU ALL LOOK LIKE
MIGHTY BRAVE MEN.
WHEN'S HE COMING,
THIS SWIFTY MORGAN?
WELL, HE SHOULD BE
ALONG HERE ANY MINUTE.
HERE HE COMES.
YOU BOYS STAY HERE.
I'LL SLIP IN BEHIND HIM.
I'LL GO WITH YOU.
HEY, WAIT FOR US.
THEY RAN AWAY,
MR. MORGAN.
THEY RAN
WHEN THEY HEARD
YOU WERE COMING.
ACT LIKE
YOU'RE DISAPPOINTED.
RAN AWAY, DID THEY?
WELL, I'M SURE
DISAPPOINTED.
THEY WENT THATAWAY.
YOU CAN CATCH THEM.
I'LL JUST
LET THEM GO.
THEY LEARNED
THEIR LESSON.
I'M A PEACEABLE
FELLOW, REALLY...
UNLESS I'M RILED.
YEAH. BRAVO.
HERE'S MR. BARTON.
YOU DID IT, MR. MORGAN!
I SAID, "THAT BOY'S MORE
THAN THE STUPID COWHAND
HE LOOKS LIKE."
AND I HEARD THAT.
THREE CHEERS
FOR SWIFTY MORGAN,
WHO SAVED THIS TOWN
FROM THAT OCTOPUS
COLONEL AMES!
HIP, HIP, HOORAY!
WELL, WHAT ARE WE
WAITING FOR?
GENTLEMEN, START
YOUR JACKASSES!
LET'S GO TO WORK!
SWIFTY.
I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
WHERE YOU GOING?
TO GET SOMETHING
OFF MY CHEST.
WHAT IF THOSE
FOUR FELLAS
COME...BACK?
DON'T CROWD
MY GUN SIDE.
HOW LONG HAS HE
BEEN LIKE THAT?
EVER SINCE HE HEARD
THERE'D BE A GUNFIGHT.
CAN'T STAND
THE SIGHT OF BLOOD.
COME ON, DOC,
DRINK HER DOWN.
DON'T YOU THINK
HE'S HAD ENOUGH?
IT'S HIS OWN REMEDY.
WE KEEP IT HERE
IN CASE HE'S NEEDED
WHEN HE'S DRUNK.
DRINK IT DOWN,
WILL YOU, DOC?
THAT NO LIFE
LIVES FOREVER...
THAT DEAD MEN
RISE UP NEVER...
AND EVEN
THE WEARIEST RIVER...
WINDS SOMEWHERE
SAFE TO SEA.
BOYS, PUT HIM IN MY BED.
[Fat]
BE AS GOOD AS NEW
IN A COUPLE HOURS,
THEN HE CAN
TAKE CARE OF YOU.
SAY, WHAT IS THIS
STRANGE SICKNESS YOU GOT?
YOU MIND MY ASKING?
JUST ENOUGH TO BUST YOU
IN THE MOUTH IF YOU ASK AGAIN.
OH, EVENING, ELMER.
HOWDY.
SILVER DOLLARS,
CHARLIE.
AND A PINK LADY.
HEAR TELL
TAYLOR BARTON'S
GOING TO THROW A BIG WINGDING
AT THE MINE TOMORROW NIGHT.
GOING TO HAVE DANCE-HALL
GALS, MUSIC, THE WORKS.
THAT'S HOW I RUINED
THE BEST COLT .45
I EVER HAD.
MAN STARTED
TALKING TO ME WHEN
I DIDN'T WANT TO BE TALKED TO.
BENT THE BARREL
OVER HIS HEAD.
EXCUSE ME.
[Roulette ball rolling]
[Dealer]
16 RED AND EVEN.
THE BALL ROLLS.
PLACE YOUR BETS, SIR.
14 RED AND EVEN.
ALL BETS DOWN.
6 BLACK, EVEN.
BOSS!
HE JUST BET
$4,600 ON NUMBER 23!
SPIN HER!
HEY!
YOU MISSED ONE.
THAT POST THERE,
YOU MISSED IT.
WHY DON'T YOU GET MARRIED?
KEEP YOU
OFF THE STREETS.
YOU CAN GO RIGHT AHEAD.
I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL.
I DO THE SAME
THING OFTEN.
BEAT YOUR HEAD
AGAINST POSTS?
NOT POSTS SO MUCH.
MOSTLY IT'S
THE WALLS IN MY ROOM.
SOMETIMES IT'S A TREE.
OCCASIONALLY A ROCK.
YOU PLAY ROULETTE?
NO. IT'S ON ACCOUNT
OF THIS TOWN.
SOMETIMES
I GET TO FEELING
I'LL NEVER
GET OUT OF HERE.
I JUST WANT
TO CURL UP AND DIE.
I WANT TO BEAT MY HEAD
AGAINST SOMETHING.
YOU DON'T LIKE
THIS TOWN?
DO YOU?
I DON'T LIKE ANYTHING
WEST OF RIVERSIDE DRIVE.
WHERE'S THAT?
NEW YORK CITY.
ON THE HUDSON RIVER?
I WAS BORN
AND RAISED THERE.
TELL ME ABOUT IT.
TELL YOU
WHAT ABOUT IT?
ALL.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
THEY DON'T CARRY GUNS.
THEY GOT A COP
ON EVERY STREET CORNER
TO KEEP PEOPLE FROM
SHOOTING ONE ANOTHER.
AND, UH...
THEY DON'T RIDE HORSES.
NO, THEY GOT CARRIAGES
AND STREETCARS AND...
I THINK
I'M GETTING HOMESICK.
ME, TOO.
YOU'VE NEVER EVEN
BEEN THERE.
WELL, I'M
HOMESICK FOR IT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU COULD
LEAVE THERE
TO COME OUT HERE
TO THIS DAMN
ROTTEN WEST.
MY MOTHER'S FAULT.
YOUR MOTHER?
YEAH.
"GO WEST, YOUNG MAN,"
SHE SAID.
SAID IT A THOUSAND TIMES.
I'D ALWAYS BEEN TOLD
A BOY'S BEST FRIEND
WAS HIS MOTHER,
SO HERE I AM.
FRISCO, DODGE,
LODESTONE, DENVER.
SURE WISH I WAS
BACK THERE THOUGH.
I THOUGHT
YOU CAME WEST
FOR YOUR HEALTH.
MY HEALTH?
WELL, YOU KNOW,
YOUR CHEST.
MY CHEST?
DOC TOLD ME ABOUT IT.
HE DID?
WE'RE REAL CLOSE
FRIENDS.
HE WOULDN'T
HAVE TOLD
ANYBODY ELSE.
YOU AND DOC
BETTER NOT
TELL ANYBODY ELSE,
OR I'LL...
I'LL KILL DOC.
YOU WON'T HAVE
ANOTHER FRIEND HERE.
WHY ARE YOU
SO SENSITIVE?
LOTS OF PEOPLE
HAVE THE SAME THING.
THEY DO?
SURE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE
COME OUT WEST
FOR WEAK CHESTS.
YOU DON'T COUGH
AS MUCH AS MOST DO.
NO. NO, I DON'T--
[Explosion]
[Boom]
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
WOULD, UH...
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO TAKE A WALK,
MISS PATIENCE?
OH.
ARE YOU SURE
THE NIGHT AIR
WOULDN'T BE BAD
FOR YOUR, UM...
NOT BAD AT ALL.
[Coughs]
NO, NO,
NOT BAD AT ALL.
SURE IS ROMANTIC,
AIN'T IT?
YEAH, YEAH,
IT SURE IS.
UH...
LATIGO...
THAT, UM...
THING YOU HAVE,
IS THAT CONTAGIOUS?
I MEAN, UH...
COULD I
CATCH IT FROM YOU?
NO, NO.
NOT UNLESS YOU, UH...
NO, YOU COULDN'T EVEN
CATCH IT EVEN THEN.
GOOD.
OH, I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D GET TO
KISS A MAN
WHO'D ACTUALLY BEEN
TO NEW YORK CITY.
IN PERSON.
NEW YORK CITY!
SAY...
DID YOU HEAR BELLS?
YEAH.
[Bells jingle]
WHOA.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT MISS ABIGAIL
SEES IN PA.
HE'S AS DULL
AS DISHWATER.
[Laughing]
GOOD NIGHT, SWEET PRINCE.
GOOD EVENING,
SWEET PRINCE.
IT AIN'T
GOOD MANNERS
TO SPY ON PEOPLE,
COLONEL.
I SUPPOSE
IT'S GOOD MANNERS
FOR YOU TO PAY
CLANDESTINE ATTENTION
TO MY SISTER.
MY INTENTIONS
ARE NOTHING
IF NOT HONORABLE.
WE SHARE
THE SAME ANCESTORS
AS FAR BACK
AS ADAM AND EVE.
I DESIRE
NO CLOSER RELATIONSHIP
TO YOU THAN THAT.
TAKE HIM INSIDE.
MY PA GETS KILLED,
I'LL NEVER
GET BACK EAST
TO MISS HUNTER'S
COLLEGE IN NEW YORK
FOR YOUNG LADIES
OF GOOD FAMILY.
ON TOP OF WHICH,
HE'LL BE DEAD.
I SEE A SITUATION HERE
WHERE AN HONEST MAN
COULD MAKE A DOLLAR.
COME ON.
WHERE YOU GOING?
AMONG
MY OTHER BAD HABITS,
I'M A PEEPING TOM.
STOP IT!
GET YOUR HANDS OFF!
SHE KICKS
LIKE A MULE.
TAYLOR! OH, MY DARLING,
WHAT ARE THEY
DOING TO YOU?
NOTHING SO FAR.
WHAT WE DO
DEPENDS ON YOU.
OOH,
I WISH I HADN'T
BOUGHT YOU
THAT BOOK
ON NAPOLEON!
COLONEL, THIS
IS RIDICULOUS!
INDEED IT IS...
BUT NOT FOR LONG,
BECAUSE ONE OF TWO THINGS
IS GOING TO HAPPEN.
FIRST, YOU'RE GOING TO
GET YOUR WORKERS
OUT OF THE GROUND
AND PROMISE NEVER TO SEE
MY SISTER AGAIN,
OR SECOND...
THE OTHER THING
IS GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHAT OTHER THING?
MY BOYS WILL
TAKE YOU OUT
IN A SWAMP
AND PUT A BULLET
THROUGH YOUR HEAD.
THAT'S MURDER!
I STUDIED LAW.
OF COURSE IT'S MURDER.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
I'LL SAVE
YOUR FATHER'S LIFE
AND MAKE
AN HONEST DOLLAR.
[Abigail]
HE WAS SUCH
A NICE MAN AND...
I WISH I'D NEVER
GIVEN YOU THAT BOOK
FIVE YEARS AGO CHRISTMAS!
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
IN THERE.
WELL, YOU AIN'T.
HOW WILL YOU
STOP ME?
LIKE THIS.
LET ME GIVE YOU
SOME ADVICE,
MY UGLY FRIEND.
THAT'S SWIFTY
MORGAN'S, PAL.
SORRY,
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHO YOU WAS.
EXCUSE ME,
WILL YOU, MISTER?
LATIGO.
EVENING.
YOUR WINDOW
WAS OPEN OVER THERE.
I COULDN'T HELP
OVERHEARING
ALL THE JABBER
YOU FOLKS
WERE TOSSING
BACK AND FORTH.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN.
LIGHT ME.
ME AND SWIFTY MORGAN,
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE OVER
THIS LITTLE TROUBLE
THAT YOU MINERS
ARE HAVING.
THE WAY I SEE IT,
THE RACE
TO THE MOTHER LODE
IS JUST THAT--
A RACE.
YEAH, ME AND SWIFTY,
WE'RE GOING
TO BE AROUND
JUST TO SEE
THAT EVERYTHING
IS RUN FAIR...
AND SQUARE.
NOW LET ME
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU AND THIS
SWIFTY MORGAN,
BY THE POWER
OF SWIFTY'S GUN,
ARE GOING TO TELL US
WHAT WE CAN
AND CANNOT DO.
LONG-WINDED WAY
OF SAYING IT,
BUT THAT'S ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE LAUGHING.
I JUST THOUGHT
OF SOMETHING VERY FUNNY.
YOU AGREEING
OR WHAT?
I DON'T SEE
WHAT ELSE I CAN DO...
FOR THE MOMENT.
WHAT ABOUT
MISS ABIGAIL AND PA?
YOU WON'T LET
THE COLONEL SEPARATE THEM?
ME AND SWIFTY STAND
IN FAVOR OF LOVE.
YOU'RE LAUGHING AGAIN.
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU OUGHT TO
LET THE REST OF US
IN ON IT?
IN DUE TIME,
YOUNG MAN.
IN DUE TIME.
GOOD MORNING.
MORNING.
I BEEN UP
ALL NIGHT WORRYING.
WHAT ABOUT?
SWIFTY MORGAN.
WHAT IF HE FINDS OUT
I BEEN PRETENDING
TO BE HIM
AND COMES
LOOKING FOR ME?
THAT AIN'T
GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHAT IF IT DOES?
JUG, YOU LET ME WORRY
ABOUT SWIFTY MORGAN.
BUTCHER.
YES, SIR?
I WONDER
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF, DURING THAT
BIG WINGDING
TAYLOR BARTON'S THROWING
AT THE MINE TONIGHT,
ONE OF THOSE
DYNAMITE JACKASSES
WAS UNLOADED
IN AN ELEVATOR
AND ACCIDENTALLY
BLEW UP.
THE SHAFT
WOULD CAVE IN.
IT WOULD TAKE
A LITTLE TIME
TO DIG IT OUT,
WOULDN'T IT?
PROBABLY HOLD UP
OPERATIONS IN THE MINE
FOR A WEEK.
MAYBE MORE.
WHAT IF
SWIFTY MORGAN
CATCHES US?
YOU LET ME WORRY
ABOUT SWIFTY MORGAN.
GOOD MORNING.
OH, GOOD MORNING.
YOU HAVE TO WAIT,
SENOR LATIGO.
THIS GENTLEMAN
IS FIRST.
NO HURRY.
YOU HAVE MUCH SADNESS
IN YOUR FACE, SENOR.
JUST STOP TO THINK...
IT ALWAYS GETS DARKEST
JUST BEFORE THE STORM.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
WHEN IT RAINS,
IT POURS.
EVERY CLOUD
GOT A SILVER LINING.
TROUBLES
NEVER COME SINGLY.
YOU GOING
TO SHAVE ME
OR NOT?
SI, SENOR.
SQUEAKY WHEEL
ALWAYS GETS THE...
JENNY!
GOLDIE!
OH!
[Goldie]
IF YOU AREN'T A SIGHT
FOR SORE EYES!
[Jenny]
THIS CALLS FOR
A CELEBRATION.
A BOTTLE
OF CHAMPAGNE, FRANK!
PRIVATE STOCK.
SIT DOWN.
WHAT YOU DOING
IN TOWN, DEARIE?
I'M LOOKING FOR A MAN.
THE WOODS
IS FULL OF THEM,
THE MINES
ARE FULL OF THEM,
AND THE LONE PRAIRIE
IS LOUSY
WITH COWPOKES.
SO TAKE YOUR CHOICE.
THIS ONE WAS
VERY SPECIAL.
HERE'S TO US.
[Jenny]
WHERE IS THIS MAN?
[Goldie]
I DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S THE TROUBLE.
[Jenny]
HE RUN OUT ON YOU?
[Goldie]
THAT OR HE GOT
MISPLACED.
[Jenny]
IT'S HARD
TO MISPLACE THEM.
THIS ONE
WAS SPECIAL, HUH?
BOTTLED IN BOND.
14-KARAT.
THE BEST.
I HAVE ONE
ANSWERS THE SAME
DESCRIPTION.
FROM THE MINUTE
HE WALKED INTO
MY PLACE
CARRYING A SPUR--
SPUR?
JUST ONE.
[Goldie] HE SAYS,
"MA'AM, I BRUNG THIS
A LONG WAY..."
[Jenny]
"FROM SLIM!
"TALL BOY FROM TEXAS.
"LIES OUT THERE
ON THE PRAIRIE
"WITH YOUR NAME
ON HIS LIPS!"
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
HE SAID
THE SAME
THING TO ME.
GOLDIE,
YOUR MAN
IS MY MAN!
THEY'RE ONE
AND THE SAME!
[Goldie]
YOU MEAN HE'S
HERE IN PURGATORY?
[Jenny]
LET'S THINK
OF A NICE, CLEAN WAY
TO GET HIM MURDERED.
LADIES.
IT'S HIM!
IT'S MY LAT.
LET'S KEEP
THE RECORD STRAIGHT.
I'M NOT YOUR LAT.
I'M NEITHER ONE'S LAT.
I'M SORRY
IF I CAUSED YOU GRIEF.
SORRY
I TOOK YOUR MONEY,
BUT I'M GOING TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING ABOUT LOVE.
LOVE DON'T WORK
UNLESS BOTH PEOPLE GIVE.
YOU GOTTA GIVE
TILL IT HURTS.
FIGHT!
ARRGHH!
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
[Explosion]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
LAT!
LAT?
OH, LAT.
[Dancing music plays]
BOY,
I TELL YOU, LATIGO,
I JUST GET
PLUMB SICK
WHEN I THINK ABOUT
HOW THE SIDEWINDER
ALMOST BUSHWHACKED YOU
WHEN YOU FIRST
COME TO TOWN.
NOT TO MENTION
HITTING YOU WITH
THAT THERE CHAIR.
YOU HEAR THAT MUSIC?
PEOPLE'S JUST
DANCING IN THE STREETS
OVER WHAT YOU DONE
FOR THIS TOWN.
A MAN SHOULD
SPREAD HAPPINESS
AS HE WALKS
THROUGH LIFE--OW!
YOU'RE AS GOOD
AS NEW NOW.
THANKS A LOT, DOC.
I GOT DRUNK
LAST NIGHT
TO GET UP
ENOUGH NERVE TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING
I SHOULD'VE TOLD YOU
FROM THE START.
I WAS GOING TO PUT
JACKASS LINIMENT
ON YOUR CHEST,
MAKE YOU STING,
MAKE YOU THINK
THAT DAMN TATTOO
WAS COMING OFF,
BUT WHEN PATIENCE
GOT INVOLVED--
INVOLVED?
I COULDN'T CHEAT
THE MAN SHE WAS
GOING TO MARRY.
MARRY?
THE SIDEWINDER?
THAT'S WHAT
SHE TOLD ME.
WELL, SHE TOLD YOU WRONG.
OW!
MARRY?
THE SIDEWINDER?
LAT?
I THOUGHT
I OUGHT TO SEE YOU
FACE TO FACE.
I HOPE IT DIDN'T
HURT TOO MUCH
WHEN I HIT YOU
WITH THE CHAIR
I'M ALL RIGHT.
THE DOC JUST
SAID SO.
I JUST COULDN'T
HELP FEELING
THE WAY I DID.
I UNDERSTAND.
WHAT IF WE'D KEPT
GOING TOGETHER,
GOT MARRIED,
YOU'D BEEN KILLED
IN AN ACCIDENT,
AND I HAD TO
IDENTIFY YOU?
I'D LOOK THE FOOL.
YOU'D BE LAID OUT
WITH SOME
OTHER WOMAN'S
NAME ON YOUR CHEST.
"I LOVE GOLDIE."
NOW, WOULDN'T
THAT BE AWFUL?
I SAID I UNDERSTOOD.
JUST LET IT GO.
WHAT IF WE WENT
TO A PICNIC,
YOU GOT ANTS
IN YOUR SHIRT,
HAD TO RIP IT OFF,
AND EVERYBODY
WOULD SEE YOUR CHEST?
I WISH YOU
DID HAVE T.B.
INSTEAD OF
THAT DAMN
ROTTEN TATTOO.
I'LL BE DAMNED.
THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I EVER SEEN
THE SIDEWINDER CRY.
WELL...
SHE'S A
SENSITIVE GIRL.
EVERYTHING
UNDER CONTROL,
MR. MORGAN?
BETTER BE...
OR I'LL KNOW
THE REASON WHY.
OH, DARLING,
ISN'T IT WONDERFUL?
NO MORE TROUBLE
BETWEEN YOU
AND MY BROTHER.
I WISH
YOU'D KNOWN HIM
BEFORE
HE STARTED READING
THAT BLASTED
BOOK ABOUT NAPOLEON
AND STICKING
HIS HAND
IN HIS COAT.
LET'S DANCE.
YOU SURE YOU KNOW
ABOUT THIS BLASTING?
I GOT
ALL MY FINGERS
AND DON'T TALK
IN A HIGH VOICE.
LET'S GET AT IT.
I DON'T LIKE THIS.
WHAT HAPPENS
IF SWIFTY MORGAN
FINDS OUT
WHAT WE'VE DONE?
LET ME WORRY
ABOUT SWIFTY MORGAN.
TAKE US DOWN.
YOU'RE NOT DANCING,
MR. SMITH.
THAT MAKES
TWO OF US, COLONEL.
I SHOULD BE.
THIS IS A VERY
HAPPY OCCASION FOR ME.
IT IS?
WELL, IS ISN'T
EVERY DAY
YOU MEET
A FAMOUS GUNMAN
LIKE SWIFTY MORGAN.
COULD YOU
POINT HIM OUT TO ME?
THERE HE IS
RIGHT OVER THERE.
THAT'S HIM.
I'M SURPRISED
YOU DIDN'T
RECOGNIZE HIM
BY THE COLD,
DEADLY LOOK
IN HIS EYE AND...
YOU THOUGHT
OF SOMETHING
FUNNY AGAIN, HUH?
MATTER OF FACT,
I DID.
YOU THINK IT'S TIME
YOU LET ME IN ON IT?
IT IS
PRECISELY THE TIME.
SO THAT'S
SWIFTY MORGAN?
IN THE FLESH.
BUT THAT GENTLEMAN
HAS A BEAUTIFUL
HEAD OF HAIR.
SWIFTY MORGAN
IS BALD AS AN EGG.
AN EGG?
AN EGG.
SURELY, SIR,
YOU JEST.
WHAT ACTION
DO YOU SUPPOSE
SWIFTY WOULD TAKE
WHEN HE ENCOUNTERS
THAT FRAUD,
THAT COW NURSE
WHO IS USING
HIS FAMOUS NAME?
WELL, I'LL HAVE
TO THINK IT OVER.
YOU KNOW, I NEVER
SENT FOR SWIFTY MORGAN.
JUST WROTE
OUT TELEGRAMS
PRETENDING TO,
BECAUSE I KNEW
MY FOOL SISTER
WOULD TELL BARTON
I'D RETAINED
THE FAMOUS GUNMAN.
BUT I SENT HIM
A TELEGRAM TODAY
TELLING HIM
AN IMPOSTER WAS
REPRESENTING HIMSELF
AS SWIFTY MORGAN.
WHY AREN'T YOU
LAUGHING, YOUNG MAN?
SOMEHOW I JUST
CAN'T SEEM TO MAKE IT.
MY SHAFT!
TAKE A WEEK
TO DIG THAT OUT.
MAYBE LONGER.
BY THAT TIME,
THE REAL SWIFTY MORGAN
WILL BE IN PURGATORY.
WHAT THE HELL
DOES THAT MEAN?
TELL HIM
WHAT THE HELL
IT MEANS, MR. SMITH.
GOOD NIGHT,
GENTLEMEN.
GOOD LUCK.
LATIGO?
WELL, NOW, LOOK,
MR. BARTON,
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING,
AND, UH...
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THERE'S A TRAIN
TO DENVER TOMORROW NIGHT.
BE ON IT.
BOTH OF YOU!
WELL, LIKE I SAID,
A MAN SHOULD
SPREAD HAPPINESS
AS HE WALKS
THROUGH LIFE.
I THINK WE'VE BEEN
SPREADING IT
A LITTLE THICK.
TICKETS.
TICKETS, PLEASE.
MA'AM?
YOU GOT A TICKET, MISTER?
IN MY HAT.
SAY, AREN'T YOU
SWIFTY MORGAN?
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT SURE IS A PLEASURE
TO HAVE YOU ABOARD,
MR. MORGAN.
WHERE YOU HEADED?
PURGATORY.
HEY, YOU.
ME?
YOU.
GIVE ME A CIGAR,
CHARLIE.
LIGHT ME.
HERE YOU GO.
STAY OUT OF THIS.
LIGHT ME,
OR I'LL STOMP YOU.
YOU GOING
TO LET THAT--
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE GOING TO SAY.
EXCUSE ME.
HEY.
I'M NOT REFORMED
QUITE ENOUGH
TO PUT UP
WITH SLOBS LIKE YOU.
BARTENDER,
SARSAPARILLA.
I'M GLAD
YOU DONE THAT.
HE TOLD ON YOU!
HE...
HE WHAT?
HE TOLD ON YOU.
HE TOLD ME
THEM MINE OWNERS
GIVE YOU $5,000.
YOU TOLD ME
IT WAS JUST 1,000.
YOU GOT A RIGHT
TO BE SORE.
AIN'T SORE.
WHY?
WHEN YOU COME ALONG,
I WAS HUNGRY.
YOU GIVE ME
A $100 BILL.
I AIN'T SEEN
ONE BEFORE.
2 BITS.
WELL, I HAVEN'T
GOT ANY MONEY.
ON ME.
THANKS, JUG.
THAT'S REAL
NICE OF YOU.
YOU FED ME
WHEN I WAS HUNGRY.
LET'S DRINK UP
AND GET MOVING.
WHERE TO?
ANYWHERE, LONG AS
IT'S AWAY FROM HERE.
I AIN'T LEAVING.
WELL, NOW, JUG,
YOU KNOW FULL WELL
THAT THE REAL
SWIFTY MORGAN
IS COMING
TO THIS TOWN.
HE'S GOING
TO PUT BULLET HOLES
IN BOTH OF US
NO END,
EXCEPT
ONE OF US--ME.
I AIN'T GOING
TO BE HERE.
I'LL BE HERE.
WHY WOULD
YOU BE HERE?
BECAUSE IF I RUN,
PEOPLE WILL THINK
I'M SCARED.
AIN'T YOU?
WELL, YEAH,
BUT I AIN'T
GOING TO RUN.
WHAT DO YOU CARE
WHAT PEOPLE THINK
IF YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO BE HERE?
I GOT MY PRIDE.
THAT WON'T STOP
A .45 SLUG.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU'RE THE SMARTEST
FELLER I EVER MET.
YOU ARE A MINORITY.
YOU AIM HIGH.
SADDLE-POUNDING JOBS,
ALL THAT KIND OF STUFF.
THEY NEVER
INTERESTED YOU NONE.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M GOING TO DO--
AIM HIGH.
I MAY NOT HAVE MUCH OF
A CHANCE WITH SWIFTY MORGAN,
BUT SUPPOSE
I DOWN HIM.
WELL,
SUPPOSING YOU DON'T,
AND THE ODDS
ARE ABOUT 1,000
TO 1 THAT YOU WON'T.
YOU'LL JUST END UP
AN UNKNOWN CHARACTER
UNDER A WOODEN
CROSS ON BOOT HILL.
EVERYBODY WINDS UP
DEAD SOONER OR LATER.
US SMART ONES
TRY TO POSTPONE IT
AS LONG AS POSSIBLE.
MY MIND'S MADE UP.
JUG, I DON'T WANT
TO BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR GETTING YOU DEAD.
NOW, LET'S
BLOW THIS TOWN
AND LIVE TO BE
A RIPE OLD AGE, HUH?
MY MIND'S MADE UP.
IT'S MY CHANCE
TO BE SOMEBODY.
NO CHANCE,
THAT'S WHAT YOU GOT.
SWIFTY MORGAN
IS GREASED LIGHTNING
WITH A GUN.
I BEEN PRACTICING.
NOW, YOU JUST
SNAP YOUR FINGERS
WHEN YOU
WANT ME TO DRAW.
AW, COME ON,
JUG.
I'M SLOW, JUG,
BUT YOU'RE
THE SLOWEST.
WELL, I MIGHT GET IN
A LUCKY SHOT.
I GOT A FEELING
YOU'RE GOING
ON A LONG TRIP.
NOW, WHY
NOT GO ALIVE?
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO STAY. TAKE OFF.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
AS SOON AS
THAT KILLER
HITS TOWN,
I'M CUTTING OUT
THAT BACK DOOR.
UH, EXCUSE ME, SIR.
WHY?
YOU GOING
TO DO SOMETHING
I MIGHT TAKE
EXCEPTION TO?
OH, NO, SIR,
NOT WHILE
I'M IN MY RIGHT MIND, SIR.
I'M THE STATION
MASTER HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
SO FAR, SO GOOD.
YOU'RE
THE STATION
MASTER HERE,
AND YOU'RE
IN YOUR RIGHT MIND.
I'M ALSO
THE TELEGRAPHER.
CONGRATULATIONS.
SO, OF COURSE,
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
THE TELEGRAM
COLONEL AMES
SENT YOU
AND THE TELEGRAM
YOU SENT BACK.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHO I AM?
WHY, ANYBODY COULD
TAKE ONE LOOK AT YOU
AND SEE THERE'S A MAN
THAT KILLED 40 OTHER MEN
IN COLD BLOOD.
SHOWS, HUH?
PLAIN AS THE HAIR
ON YOUR--
ON A GOAT.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M SWIFTY MORGAN.
NOW WHAT?
THAT TELEGRAM
YOU SENT COLONEL AMES
SAYING YOU
WAS COMING HERE
TO DEAL WITH THE IMPOSTER.
WHAT ABOUT
THAT TELEGRAM?
I TOOK IT
TO THE AMES' PLACE,
BUT THE COLONEL'S
SISTER MISS ABIGAIL
GRABBED IT.
SHE RIPPED IT OPEN
AND STARTED YELLING,
"THAT FILTHY RAT'S
COMING HERE."
MEANING ME?
BEGGING YOUR PARDON,
SIR, MEANING YOU,
AND THEN
SHE SHOWED IT
TO MISS PATIENCE--
THAT'S A GIRL.
THAT FIGURES.
AND MISS PATIENCE
STARTED YELLING,
"THAT FILTHY
MURDERER IS COMING HERE,
"AND THAT BOY
POSING AS THAT
FILTHY MURDERER
IS GOING TO HAVE
TO GET OUT OF TOWN."
SO, I SUPPOSE
THIS IMPOSTER
TOOK OFF AS FAST
AS A HORSE WOULD
CARRY HIM.
NO, SIR.
HE DIDN'T?
RIGHT NOW HE'S
DOWN TO THE EAGLE
SHOOTING POOL.
WELL, NOW, HERE'S
WHAT YOU DO--
YOU TROT ON DOWN
TO THE EAGLE
AND TELL THIS--
THIS FAKER
TO COME OUT
IN THE STREET.
YOU TELL HIM
THAT THE REAL, GENUINE,
100, DYED-IN-THE-WOOL
SWIFTY MORGAN
IS WAITING FOR HIM.
OH, SIR,
I'D REALLY RATHER NOT
GET MIXED UP IN THIS
IF IT'S ALL
THE SAME TO YOU.
IT IS NOT
ALL THE SAME TO ME.
HE'S OUT
IN THE STREET!
GIVE ME A DRINK.
WHO'S OUT
IN THE STREET?
SWIFTY MORGAN.
THE REAL SWIFTY MORGAN.
HE'S GOING
TO SHOOT YOU
SO FULL OF HOLES,
YOU'RE GOING TO LOOK
LIKE A STRAINER.
HE'S REAL PUT OUT
ABOUT YOU TAKING
HIS NAME IN VAIN.
WELL, NOW,
DON'T GO OUT THERE,
YOU IDIOT.
LET'S GO OUT
THE BACK DOOR.
IT'S THAT TIME,
FRIEND.
YEAH,
I GUESS IT IS.
[Patience]
LAT!
THERE AIN'T NO LADIES
ALLOWED IN HERE!
I AIN'T NO LADY.
I'M PATIENCE BARTON.
SWIFTY MORGAN'S
OUT THERE.
I KNOW.
I WAS ON MY WAY
TO SEE HIM.
HE'S AFTER HIM,
NOT YOU.
I GOT HIM INTO THIS,
I'LL GET HIM OUT.
IF YOU GET
YOURSELF KILLED,
I'M GOING TO
HAVE TO MARRY ONE
OF THESE LOCAL CRUMBS.
PATIENCE,
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
A MAN CAN'T
RIDE AROUND.
THEN AGAIN...
MAYBE HE CAN.
I'VE GOT TO
SEE THIS.
I'VE GOT TO SEE THIS.
YOU THERE IN THE SALOON!
THIS IS SWIFTY MORGAN.
COME ON OUT.
[Latigo]
I ALREADY AM.
WHAT THE HELL DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
I'D AIM HIGH.
YOU HIT THIS DYNAMITE,
LIKE AS NOT,
YOU'LL BLOW
THE WHOLE TOWN UP,
YOU ALONG WITH IT.
YOU TRYING TO MAKE
A FOOL OUT OF ME?
NO. I'M TRYING
TO KILL YOU, MR. MORGAN.
YOU CAN'T GUNFIGHT A MAN
SITTING ON YOUR ASS.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
IT DOESN'T BELONG TO ME.
UH, BELONGS
TO TAYLOR BARTON.
I STOLE IT.
LIKE YOU STOLE MY NAME.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
[Swifty Morgan] NOT AS SORRY AS
YOU'RE GOING TO BE.
SWIFTY MORGAN HITS ONLY
WHAT SWIFTY MORGAN
SHOOTS AT.
I'M SORRY
ABOUT THAT, TOO.
ANYTIME YOU FEEL
LUCKY, MISTER.
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
[Explosion]
I SHOT MYSELF!
DON'T LET ME DIE
WITH MY BOOTS ON, MISTER.
HE DID IT!
HE STRUCK THE MOTHER LODE!
WE'RE RICH!
NO, MA'AM.
THE CLAIM BELONGS
TO TAYLOR BARTON.
HIS MULE DONE IT.
DO YOU HEAR THAT,
ABIGAIL?
IT'S MY ASS!
MINE, TOO.
LAT!
HE'S ALL
RIGHT, HONEY.
TAKE MORE
THAN DYNAMITE
TO KILL LATIGO SMITH.
YOU SAID
YOU COULDN'T RIDE.
I ALWAYS SAID
THAT WHOREHOUSE
WAS A GOLD MINE.
LAT,
THE TATTOO--
IT'S GONE.
IT'S BEEN
BLOWN OFF!
THE HELL
YOU SAY!
OH, NOW WE
CAN GET MARRIED
AND HAVE A PICNIC!
BOSS!
LATIGO JUST PUT
$10,000 ON 23.
I'M BACKING HIS PLAY!
[Coughs]
SPIN HER.
WELL, I'LL BE DAMNED--23.
23!
SURE IS GOOD
TO HAVE MR. LATIGO
ON BOARD AGAIN.
SERVE THE CHAMPAGNE,
SAM,
BUT NOT TILL
THE FOLKS
HAVE TIME
TO CATCH THEIR BREATH.
NOW, THE WAY
THIS STORY ENDS,
THOSE TWO GO TO DENVER
TO GET MARRIED.
PATIENCE--
SHE NEVER DOES GET TO GO
TO MISS HUNTER'S COLLEGE
ON THE HUDSON RIVER,
NEW YORK,
BUT SEVEN
OF HER DAUGHTERS DO.
TAYLOR BARTON--
HE GETS HIS FLAT FIXED
AND MARRIES MISS ABIGAIL,
THE COLONEL GOES BROKE,
SWIFTY MORGAN'S STILL
TRYING TO GET HIS BOOTS OFF.
AND ME,
I GO ON TO BECOME
A BIG STAR
IN ITALIAN WESTERNS.
THE END