[ Men Shouting In Hawaiian ]
COME ON IN.
OVER HERE.
HEY, LITTLE MAKA.
NO, THANKS, KIMO.
KIMO!  HELP!
THERE'S A MAN IN THE SURF!
[ Kimo ]
LOOK, THERE'S A MAN.
QUICKLY.
PULL HIM UP.
EASY WITH HIM.
QUICKLY.
PULL HIM UP HERE.
TAKE IT EASY NOW.
MAMA!
MAMA, COME QUICK!
MAMA, MAMA!
MY GOODNESS, BOY,
WHAT IS IT?
THERE!  A MAN, I FOUND,
JUST ABOUT DROWNED.
HE'S BAD OFF, MOM.
- FIX HIM GOOD.
- HE'S HEAVY.
- OH, BROTHER.
- HE'S HURT.
MISS MAKA.
WHAT YOU BOYS DOIN' HERE
MAKING NOISE IN THE NIGHTTIME?
IT'S ALL RIGHT, LILIHA.
THEY BROUGHT A MAN
WHO NEEDS SOME HELP.
THE SIDE ROOM.
KIMO.
TAKE IT EASY NOW.
ALL RIGHT, YOU BOYS.
DON'T STAND AROUND
WHERE YOU DON'T BELONG.
LILIHA!  WE'LL NEED HOT WATER,
ALCOHOL AND SWABS, QUICKLY!
YES, MISS MAKA.
- GOOD MORNING, KIMO.
- GOOD MORNING, LITTLE MAKA.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
WELL, I'VE FELT WORSE.
I JUST CAN'T
REMEMBER WHEN.
- WHO ARE YOU?
- I'M  BOOTON.
I ASKED YOU A STRAIGHT-ON
QUESTION, BOY.
NO, FOOLIN', SIR.
THAT'S MY NAME,
BOOTON MacAVOY.
- WHERE ARE WE?
- IN MOM'S SPARE BEDROOM.
NO, WHERE IN THE WORLD
ARE WE?
OH, WELL WE'RE ON KAUAI.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- ONE OF THE ISLANDS
THE SANDWICH ISLANDS.
HOW FAR IS THAT
FROM TEXAS?
OH.  WELL,
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN
GET THERE FROM HERE.
AT ALL?
I WENT TO HONOLULU
ONCE, THOUGH.
IT'S NOT AS BAD
AS MY SON SAYS.
WELL,
GOOD MORNING, MA'AM.
HONOLULU'S A COUPLE DAY'S SAIL
FROM HERE.
ARE YOU FEELING BETTER?
WELL, I'M BEGINNING
TO MAKE SOME RECOVERY.
YES, MA'AM.
AND YOU, YOUNG MAN,
YOU'RE NOT EVEN SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE.  NOW SCOOT.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO HELP.
IF YOU REALLY
MEAN THAT, SON,
I COULD USE SOME SHAVIN' SOAP
AND STRAIGHT RAZOR,
TO KINDA GET OUT
FROM UNDERNEATH THIS.
CAN HE USE
DAD'S RAZOR, MAMA?
WELL, NOT IF YOUR MAN
FEELS STRONGLY ABOUT IT.
SOME DO.
MY HUSBAND PASSED AWAY
TWO YEARS AGO.
OH, I'M SORRY
TO HEAR THAT, MA'AM.
YOU KNOW WHERE
YOUR FATHER'S THINGS ARE.
I'M HENRIETTA MacAVOY.
I'M PLEASED
TO MEET YOU, MA'AM.
YOU'RE LUCKY TO SURVIVE,
YOU KNOW.
WELL, YOU CAN'T DROWN
IF YOU WAS MEANT
FOR SOMETHING WORSE.
IT'S JUST
A FIGURE OF SPEECH.
JUST THAT, ME AND THE SEA,
WE DON'T GET ALONG TOGETHER.
OH, THEN YOU DID
COME OFF A SHIP?
COME OFF?  YES MA'AM,
I THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
I JUST WISH
I'D NEVER GOT ON IT.
YOU'RE NOT A DESERTER?
AS THE LORD AS MY WITNESS,
MA'AM, I AM A WRONGED MAN.
THAT MAY BE, MR.--
AH, COSTAIN.
LINCOLN COSTAIN.
MY FRIENDS CALL ME LINC.
MR. COSTAIN,
I SUGGEST AS SOON
AS YOU'RE WELL ENOUGH,
YOU GET YOURSELF
BACK TO YOUR SHIP.
GET BACK?
I WAS SHANGHAIED, MA'AM.
MORNING, BOSS.
YOU'RE LOOKING HANDSOME ALREADY.
LILIHA MAKE YOU SOME GOOD SOUP.
FIX YOUR BODY UP PROPER.
JUST WHAT MIGHT
THAT BE, MA'AM?
MAKE THIS FROM RAW FISH,
SOME LIZARD POWDER
AND DRIED SQUID.
SHE SAID IT WOULD
PUT HAIR ON MY CHEST,
BUT ALL IT DID WAS MAKE ME GAG
'TIL MY EYES WATERED.
BOOTON, BEHAVE YOURSELF.
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME
TO YOU, MISS LILI--
LILIHA.  YOU TAKE SOME.
GO AHEAD.
- YOU LIKE, NO?
- NO, THAT'S PRETTY BAD,
THAT IS.
ACTUALLY, I'M NOT VERY HUNGRY.
IF I COULD JUST HAVE MY PANTS
SO I COULD GET UP.
[ Henrietta ]
YOUR PANTS WERE SO BADLY TORN,
WE HAD TO MEND THEM.
MOM, THEY'RE
IN THE GARDEN AGAIN,
TEARING UP EVERYTHING!
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT IS IT, BOY?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
IT'S ONE OF THE ANIMALS.
A BIG ONE.  HE'S EATING UP
THE VEGETABLES AGAIN.
GET OUT OF HERE!
GET OUT OF MY GARDEN,
YOU HEAR ME!
YOU GET OUT!
GET!
ONE OF THE ANIMALS?
WELL, I'LL BE DOGGED.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME YOU HAD
CATTLE AROUND HERE, BUTTON.
- [ Henrietta ] LILIHA!
- BOOTON!
WE DON'T, THAT THING'S WILD.
BUT I SURE HOPE HE EATS
THE TURNIPS.
WELL, HE MAY BE WILD,
BUT HE AIN'T NO THING.
THAT'S ABOUT A THOUSAND POUNDS
OF PRIME BULL OUT THERE.
YOU STUBBORN,
WILLFUL, WORTHLESS,
MISBEGOTTEN BEAST!
THAT'S A RIGHT NICE VOCABULARY,
MISS MacAVOY,
BUT YOU'LL NEVER
TALK HIM OUT OF THERE.
[ Frantic Mooing ]
LOOK AT IT.
JUST LOOK AT IT.
- IS THIS SOUP?
- SOUP!
- OH, HI, COSTAIN.
- HOWDY, BARTON.
BOOTON!
LOOK WHAT
I GOT FOR YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT NICE OF YOU, SON,
BUT I'M NOT REAL HUNGRY
JUST NOW.  I JUST ATE.
NO, IT AIN'T TO EAT.
IT'S A REAL HAWAIIAN HAT.
FOR YOU.
DO YOU LIKE IT?
LIKE IT?
YEAH, YEAH, IT'S, UH--
IT'S REAL COLORFUL,
AIN'T IT?
MAKE YOU LOOK
REAL PRETTY, BOSS.
PUT IT ON.
IT'LL BE GREAT.
WELL, IT'S JUST
A LITTLE MORE DECORATED
THAN WHAT I HAD IN MIND.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.  MAKE YOU
LOOK REAL HAWAIIAN STYLE.
THAT REALLY IS QUITE BECOMING,
YOU KNOW.
IT'S TIME TO GO
INTO TOWN, BOOTON.
I DON'T THINK I'LL
GO IN TODAY, MOM.
I'VE GOT SOME THINGS I'VE BEEN
PLANNING TO DO AROUND HERE.
WELL, ALL RIGHT.
YOU BE SURE AND MAKE YOURSELF
USEFUL WHILE I'M GONE.
I'LL BE BACK BY SUPPER.
MA'AM.
MA'AM, YOU WON'T FORGET
TO ASK ABOUT A SHIP
FOR ME, WILL YOU?
I'LL CHECK THE SHIPS IN PORT
FOR A WORK PASSAGE SITUATION,
MR. COSTAIN.
THANK YOU, MA'AM.
AND IF I HAD
A GOOD-BYE KISS,
I JUST MIGHT BRING HOME
SOME ROCK CANDY TOO.
BYE, MOM.
HAVE A GOOD TRIP.
YOU BEHAVE YOURSELF.
COME ON, TUCK.
COME ON, COME ON.
[ Dogs Barking ]
HEY, SON.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER?
- SHE'S PROBABLY GONNA SEE
THAT BRYSON.
WHO'S THAT BRYSON?
HE'S SOME OLD MAN WHO
KEEPS PESTERING HER
TO MARRY HIM.
OH.
I SURE HOPE SHE DON'T.
- WHY IS THAT?
- WELL, HE WEARS PERFUME
FOR ONE THING.
HE'S ALWAYS PATTING ME
ON THE HEAD AND CALLING ME
"MY BOY."
THAT'S WHAT HE ALWAYS SAYS.
"WELL, MY BOY, YOU'RE
SPROUTING UP LIKE A WEED."
HE PROBABLY THINKS
THAT'S A COMPLIMENT.
WELL, IT'S NOT.
I'LL SAY THIS FOR HIM THOUGH.
HE'S GOT GOOD ROCK CANDY.
OH, WELL, THAT'S
A GOOD QUALITY TO HAVE.
A LOT OF MEN
DON'T HAVE THAT.
SAY, HOW 'BOUT YOU SHOWING ME
AROUND THE SPREAD?
WELL, SURE.
I'LL SHOW YOU WHERE
I FISHED YOU OUT FIRST.
DOWN BY THE CLIFFS
THERE'S SOME CAVES AND THINGS.
ALL RIGHT, HOLD IT UP.
CAN'T SEE IT ALL
IN FIVE MINUTES.
I DO WISH YOU WOULD BEGIN
TO TAKE ME A LITTLE MORE
SERIOUSLY, HENRIETTA.
I DO, CAL.
YOU KNOW I DO.
YOU KNOW WHAT A DISASTROUS YEAR
LAST YEAR WAS.
AND CROP PRICES DON'T
LOOK ANY BETTER THIS YEAR.
- THEN WITH THE INCREASED
BURDEN OF TAXES--
- OH, WE'LL MUDDLE THROUGH.
- WE ALWAYS HAVE,
HAVEN'T WE?
- YES, BUT THAT'S THE POINT.
THERE'S NO REASON
FOR A WOMAN LIKE YOU
TO HAVE TO STRUGGLE SO...
JUST TO EKE OUT
A MEAGER EXISTENCE.
WHY DON'T YOU PUT
THE PLACE UP FOR SALE?
BUT I DON'T WANT
TO SELL THE FARM.
YOU KNOW HOW MUCH
IT MEANS TO ME.
YES, I DO.
MY COMPANY IS GOING TO DO
GREAT THINGS IN THE ISLANDS.
AND AS MY WIFE,
YOU COULD--
I COULD HAVE ANYTHING
MY HEART DESIRES.
AND I KNOW
YOU MEAN THAT, CAL.
BUT DON'T YOU SEE.
IT JUST ISN'T POSSIBLE.
EVEN IF--
WITH THE AMOUNT OF MONEY
I OWE YOU,
IT IS NOT PROPER FOR US
TO TALK ABOUT ANYTHING
BUT A BUSINESS RELATIONSHIP.
MONEY MEANS NOTHING.
YOU KNOW THAT.
- IT MEANS NOTHING AT ALL.
- IT DOES TO ME.
- HENRIETTA, I WISH--
- PLEASE.
YOU KNOW HOW I FEEL ABOUT YOU.
THAT ISN'T GOING TO CHANGE.
IF EVER I CAN DO ANYTHING,
YOU JUST LET ME KNOW.
OF COURSE.
[ Henrietta ]
GOOD-BYE.
[ Chattering, Shouting ]
- AND WHO ARE THEY?
- THOSE ARE THE WORKERS.
- THE WORKERS?
- YEP.
WHAT DO THEY DO
WHEN THEY'RE NOT WORKING?
WELL, THERE'S LOTS OF WORK.
WE OWN 10,000 ACRES.
BIGGEST POTATO FARM
ON THE ISLANDS.
TEN-THOUSAND ACRES
OF POTATOES?
MOST OF IT'S OPEN COUNTRY.
POTATOES HAVEN'T BEEN
DOING TOO WELL.
TEN-THOUSAND ACRES, HUH?
[ Costain ]
THAT'S A GOOD-SIZED PEA PATCH,
EVEN WHERE I COME FROM.
- WHERE'S THAT?
- TEXAS.
THERE YOU CAN RIDE FOR
A MONTH IN ANY DIRECTION
AND NEVER TOUCH A FENCE.
- MUST BE BEAUTIFUL.
- OH, IT IS.
COSTAIN, DO YOU THINK
YOU COULD EVER LIKE IT HERE?
ME?  NO, NO.
NO, THIS FRUIT BOWL
AIN'T FOR ME.
SOME PEOPLE MIGHT LIKE
IT JUST FINE, THOUGH.
I SUPPOSE YOU'RE GOING
BACK TO TEXAS, HUH?
YOU BET.
- YOU GOT A WIFE THERE?
- HAVEN'T MET THE WOMAN
THAT COULD AFFORD ME.
- THEN YOU NEVER
DID HAVE ONE.
- NOPE.
I HAD SMALL POX ONCE THOUGH.
AMOUNTS TO ABOUT THE SAME THING.
YEAH.
I GUESS YOU'D NEVER
WANT TO SETTLE DOWN
AND LIVE WITH SOMEONE,
- NO MATTER HOW NICE
SHE WAS, HUH?
- YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
BUT YOU CAN'T HAVE KIDS
IF YOU AIN'T MARRIED.
YEAH, AIN'T THAT
A MERCY?
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO
WHEN YOU GET OLD?
DIE, I GUESS.
NO, I MEAN BEFORE THAT.
WHO'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU
IF YOU DON'T HAVE A SON?
I'LL SAY ONE THING
FOR YOU.
YOU GET A NOTION,
YOU SURE HANG ON TO IT,
BURTON.
BOOTON!
OH, YEAH.
[ Bell Ringing ]
- WHAT'S THAT?
- COME ON!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[ Shouting In Hawaiian ]
OH, NO.
THOSE CATTLE AGAIN.
[ Shouting ]
GO ON!  GET OUT!
OUT OF THE WAY!
HEY!
HEY!  HEY!
COSTAIN!
HEY!
OUT OF THE WAY!
COSTAIN, COME ON!
[ Cows Mooing ]
HYAH!  HYAH!
HYAH!
HYAH!  HYAH!  MOVE!
[ Bull Snorting ]
COSTAIN!  COSTAIN!
TURN AROUND, SON!
FACE HIM!
DON'T MOVE!
FREEZE!
[ Bull Snorting ]
ALL RIGHT, BOY.
RUN FOR THE HOUSE.
[ Laughing, Cheering ]
[ Snorting Continues ]
YA!  GET OUT OF HERE!
YOU SHOULD'VE SEEN
THAT CRITTER, MAMA.
I WAS REALLY SCARED.
AND THEN HE KEPT TWISTING THAT
BULL'S HEAD 'TIL IT FELL OVER.
AND THEN HE LET IT GO,
AND IT RAN OFF.
THAT MUST'VE BEEN
QUITE A SIGHT.
SO, YOU KNOW
HOW TO TAME THEM?
IT'S NOT A MATTER
OF TAMING THEM, MA'AM,
IT'S JUST A MATTER
OF HANDLING 'EM.
YOU COULD SURE HANDLE 'EM.
JUST LIKE YOU HANDLED THAT BULL.
POW!  RIGHT, COSTAIN?
BOOTON!
MR. COSTAIN.
MR. COSTAIN, YOU COULD PROBABLY
MAKE THOSE OLD CATTLE DO
WHATEVER YOU TOOK A MIND TO.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
IT DOESN'T MAKE MUCH DIFFERENCE.
NO POINT IN TALKIN' ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE IN THE POTATO BUSINESS.
WERE IN THE POTATO BUSINESS.
PRICES HAVE DROPPED OFF
TERRIBLY.
WELL, IT SEEM TO ME
LIKE YOU'RE...
STRUGGLING
YOUR WAY PAST A DOLLAR,
JUST TO GRUB AFTER A DIME.
YOU CAN GET $20 A HEAD
FOR THEM CATTLE IN CALIFORNIA.
BUT WHAT YOU DO
IS YOUR BUSINESS.
ME?  I'M ON MY WAY
TO TEXAS.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
MRS. MacAVOY,
DID YOU FIND ANYTHING
IN THE WAY OF A SHIP FOR ME
WHEN YOU WERE IN TOWN?
OH, NO.  I THINK IT'S
THE WRONG TIME OF YEAR.
- BUT MAMA--
- FOR SHIPS.
- I MEAN--
- WELL, I'LL JUST
HAVE TO MAKE DO.
I WON'T BE IMPOSIN'
ON YOU FOLKS.
I'LL HEAD INTO TOWN
TOMORROW AND WAIT.
AS LONG AS YOU'RE GOING TO WAIT,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL WAIT HERE.
BEG PARDON, MA'AM.
AND WORK--  HELP OUT.
I COULD PAY YOU.
A LITTLE, NOT MUCH.
ROOM AND BOARD TOO.
RIGHT, MAMA?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- JUST FOR A WHILE.
UNTIL YOU EARN SO MONEY.
YOU'LL NEED SOME MONEY,
MR. COSTAIN.
AND, WHO KNOWS?
WITH YOUR HELP, WE MIGHT
TURN THIS SORRY POTATO FARM...
INTO THE FIRST AND ONLY
WILD CATTLE RANCH IN HAWAII.
YOU, UH--
YOU SURE YOU'RE NOT
FROM TEXAS, MS. MacAVOY?
YOU WILL STAY,
WON'T YOU?
WON'T YOU, COSTAIN?
WELL, I'LL HIT HER A LICK
AND SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
BUT THAT'S ALL
I'LL PROMISE.
- ALOHA.
- ALOHA, MISS MAKA.
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
THIS MORNING...
ABOUT SOME CHANGES
THAT ARE GOING TO BE MADE
ON THE FARM TODAY.
MR. COSTAIN
IS A CATTLEMAN FROM TEXAS.
AND HE KNOWS HOW
TO HANDLE THE ANIMALS
AS YOU ALL SAW YESTERDAY.
YEAH.
WE HAVE NOT BEEN DOING WELL
WITH OUR POTATOES.
MR. COSTAIN FEEL
WE WOULD DO BETTER...
- IF WE CAUGHT THE ANIMALS
AND SOLD THEM.
- CAUGHT THE ANIMALS?
[ Murmuring ]
OH, NO, WAIT!
WAIT, WAIT!
YOU MUSTN'T BE FRIGHTENED.
MR. COSTAIN ASSURES ME...
THAT THE ANIMALS CAN BE HANDLED,
AND HE IS GOING TO TEACH US HOW.
AREN'T YOU, MR. COSTAIN?
ALL RIGHT, NOW.
THIS HERE ANIMAL IS A HORSE.
NOW YOU'RE ALL GONNA
HAVE ONE OF THESE TO CHASE
THEM BRUSH DOGGIES OUT THERE.
BRUSH DOGGIES.
THAT'S CATTLE.
YOU NEED ONE OF THESE
TO KEEP UP WITH CATTLE.
THERE'S ONLY TWO THINGS
YOU GOTTA KNOW ABOUT A HORSE:
HOW TO GET ON
AND HOW TO STAY ON.
THIS IS YOUR SADDLE, WHERE
YOU'RE GONNA SIT WHEN YOU RIDE.
YOU JUST SIT IN THERE LIKE
A ROCKING CHAIR, YOU SAVVY?
JUST WALK UP HERE AND
PUT YOUR FOOT IN THE STIRRUP.
THAT'S THE STIRRUP.  THAT'S
RIGHT THERE.  SEE IT?
PUT YOUR FOOT IN THE STIRRUP
AND SWING RIGHT UP.  SEE?
[ Cheering ]
GOOD.  NOW WHO'S GOING
TO BE THE FIRST TO TRY IT?
[ Chattering ]
WELL, THERE'S ONE THING
YOU CAN'T LEARN TO DO,
IS RIDE WITHOUT GETTING ON.
- NOW COME ON!
- GO, GO, GO!
COME ON.
ALL RIGHT, NOW.
YOU ALL WATCH HIM.
[ Cheering ]
TURN AROUND.
GO ON, TURN AROUND.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Whooping, Laughing ]
NOW YOU TRY IT.
[ Laughter ]
YES, IT'S TRUE.
THEY DO LIKE THEIR FUN.
LIKE IT?  THEY'D RATHER
GIGGLE THAN LAUGH.
THEY'D RATHER LAUGH THAN EAT.
THEY'RE LIKE A BUNCH
OF KIDS OUT THERE.
A SCHOOL GIRL'D
BE MORE SOBER, MA'AM.
WELL NOW, AFTER THEY
GET TO KNOW YOU BETTER,
AND UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE
TRYING TO TEACH THEM--
OH, AND ANOTHER THING.
YOU SAY YOU CAN'T BUY
ANY HORSES.
NOW, HOW DO YOU EXPECT
ME TO WORK CATTLE...
WITH ONE
OLD WALL-EYED REFUGEE
FROM A GLUE FACTORY?
- WELL, MAYBE--
- IF YOU COULD GET 'EM,
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY BRIDLES,
SADDLES, BLANKETS.
YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY SPURS, BOOTS.
MA'AM, THEY DON'T EVEN HAVE
ANYTHING DECENT TO WEAR.
WELL, IF WE NEED HORSES...
PERHAPS I CAN GET SOME.
I-I DON'T KNOW HOW.
YES, I DO.
I CAN GET HORSES,
AND I WILL.
AND THEIR CLOTHES
MAY NOT SUIT YOU,
BUT THEY FIND THEM
VERY COMFORTABLE.
YES, MA'AM, COMFORTABLE.
I THINK THAT'S THE RIGHT
WORD FOR IT.
BESIDES, ANYTHING THEY NEED,
THEY CAN MAKE HERE.
THERE ISN'T
A SINGLE THING NEEDED
THAT WE CAN'T MAKE RIGHT HERE.
EXCEPT FOR A--
A LITTLE DETERMINATION
AND LEADERSHIP...
FROM A MAN
WHO HAS THE KNOW-HOW.
AND THAT IS A FACT,
MR. COSTAIN.
WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO STOP
CALLING ME MR. COSTAIN, MA'AM?
WHEN YOU STOP CALLING ME
MA'AM, MR. COSTAIN.
IT'S JUST A FORMALITY,
HENRIETTA.
I DON'T THINK YOU SHOULD
EVEN BOTHER TO SIGN IT.
I WILL NOT TAKE ANOTHER
LOAN FROM YOU WITHOUT
GIVING PROPER SECURITY.
THIS IS A MORTGAGE
FOR ALL OF YOUR PROPERTY.
IT'S DISPROPORTIONATE,
IT'S NOT NECESSARY.
CAL, I OWE YOU A GREAT DEAL.
NOW I NEED MORE MONEY.
AND THIS IS THE ONLY WAY
I'LL TAKE IT.
BUSINESS IS BUSINESS.
- EVEN BETWEEN US?
- ESPECIALLY BETWEEN US.
ALL RIGHT.
- THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND GOOD NIGHT, CAL.
- GOOD NIGHT, HENRIETTA.
ANOTHER FAVOR
FOR THE LADY?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
YES.
WHENEVER SHE NEEDS MONEY,
SHE CAN ALWAYS ASK YOU.
AND I GIVE.
AND NOW, THE MORTGAGE.
MAYBE IF SHE OWE YOU MORE
THAN SHE CAN PAY BACK--
YOU COULD SAY THAT MRS. MacAVOY
AND I FINALLY ARE PARTNERS.
HOOEY-HOOEY!
[ Whooping, Cheering ]
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S ENOUGH,
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOU CAN GET OFF.
[ Laughing ]
AHHH!
ALL RIGHT NOW,
WHO'S NEXT?
[ Henrietta ]
MALAKOMA, MR. COSTAIN
IS WORKING UNDER MY ORDERS.
- DO YOU HEAR ME?
- WHAT IS IT?
WHAT DOES HE WANT?
- HE DOESN'T LIKE YOU AT ALL.
- HE'S CHALLENGING YOU.
YEAH, HE THINKS HE'S
SOMETHING SPECIAL AROUND HERE.
ALL RIGHT, PARTNER,
YOU'RE SOMETHING SPECIAL.
COME ON, LELEO.
COME ON.
MALAKOMA!
IF HE'S LOOKING TO GET A RISE
OUT OF ME, HE JUST DID IT.
NO, YOU MUSTN'T!
HE'LL KILL YOU!
WELL, YOU WON THAT ONE,
ALL RIGHT.  HERE.
HERE, LET ME SHOW YOU
HOW WE DO IT WHERE I COME FROM.
NOW, YOU GET OFF THIS LAND
AND DON'T COME BACK.
COME ON, LELEO,
GET UP THERE.
COME ON, LELEO.
COME ON, LELEO,
GET UP THERE.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
THEY'RE COMING,
THEY'RE COMING!
MOM, COME SEE!
THEY'RE HERE!
COME ON,
MOVE!  MOVE, YOU!
MOVE, MOVE!
AH, THANKS, BOSS.
FIRST, THE BLANKET,
THEN THE SADDLE.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Laughter ]
WHERE ARE YOU GOING,
BATTON?
BOOTON!
AH, SHUCKS.  WHAT'S THE USE?
I CAN'T GET THE DANG THING
TO WORK ANYHOW.
IN MY OUTFIT, WE ONLY QUIT
WHEN IT'S TOO DARK TO WORK
OR TIME TO EAT.
I DIDN'T HEAR
THE DINNER BELL, DID YOU?
NOW, YOU PUT THE STIRRUP
UP OVER THE HORN LIKE THIS.
UGH!
NOW, GO TO WORK.
[ Laughter ]
PUT THE REINS TOGETHER.
HOLD THEM IN ONE HAND.
THAT'S IT.
GET, GO ON.
WOULD YOU KEEP IN A CIRCLE?
KEEP IN A CIRCLE!
SLOW DOWN, SLOW DOWN!
KEEP YOUR FEET IN THERE.
BENTON, NOT UP AND DOWN.
SIT THERE LIKE A ROCKING CHAIR.
BOOTON!
[ Laughter ]
YOU WRAP IT AROUND
AND YOU GET IT TIGHT.
GOT THAT?
ALL RIGHT, KIMO.
IT'S YOUR TURN.
GET HIM, KIMO.
YEAH, GO GET HIM.
[ Cheering ]
[ Laughter ]
BUT THEY ARE LEARNING,
ACTUALLY LEARNING.
IT'S AMAZING.
YOU'RE MAKING YOURSELF
THE LAUGHING STOCK
OF THE ISLAND.
ONE OF THE CAPTAINS
WAS SAYING THEY'RE EVEN
TALKING ABOUT IT IN LAHAINA.
GOOD LUCK.
YA.
[ Goat Bleating ]
READY, BOSS!
GO TO IT.
[ Laughter ]
[ Bleating ]
- WHAT DO WE DO NOW, BOSS?
- WE COULD TRY SOME CARD TRICKS.
WE FINE, BOSS.
WE'VE NOT HAD ENOUGH YET.
WELL, I HAVE.
MR. COSTAIN?
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
A FRIEND OF MINE.
MR. BRYSON, MR. COSTAIN.
- MR. BRYSON.
- MR. COSTAIN.
SO THAT'S THEY WAY YOU PLAN
TO CATCH WILD CATTLE?
NOT EXACTLY, NO.
[ Laughing ]
MS. MacAVOY, TELLS ME
YOU'RE NEW ON THE ISLAND.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
- TEXAS.
- TEXAS?  HOW DID YOU HAPPEN
TO COME TO KAUAI?
I WAS UNHAPPY
WITH MY LAST EMPLOYER.
WHO WAS THAT?
MR. BRYSON TELLS ME
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO LOAD CATTLE
ONTO BOATS IN THESE WATERS.
IT WAS TRIED ONCE
ON THE BIG ISLAND.
TWO SHIPS RAN ON THE REEFS,
AND THERE IS NO ANCHORAGE
FURTHER OUT.
WELL, DON'T THEY
HAVE DOCKS IN HILEA?
NEVER NEEDED THEM.
WELL, HOW DO
THEY LOAD THEN?
MOSTLY BY LONG BOAT.
CAN YOU IMAGINE TRYING
TO LOAD CATTLE BY LONG BOAT?
WELL, THERE'S GOTTA BE A WAY.
JUST A MATTER OF FINDIN' IT.
MR. COSTAIN SAYS THERE
AIN'T NEVER BEEN A HORSE
THAT AIN'T BEEN RODE,
- AND AIN'T NEVER BEEN A RIDER
THAT AIN'T BEEN THROWN.
- IS THAT WHAT HE SAYS?
I WON'T CHALLENGE THE STATEMENT,
BUT I WILL THE GRAMMAR.
GRAMMAR NEVER WAS
MY STRONG SUIT.
YOUNG MAN, YOU ARE SPROUTING UP
LIKE A WEED.
AT LEAST HE'S GOT
GOOD ROCK CANDY?
- I BEG YOUR PARDON.
- EXCUSE ME.
GOOD MORNING, BOSS.
WHERE ARE THEY?
OH, BOYS NO TELL ME, BOSS.
MAYBE THEY GO WORK
SOMEPLACE ELSE, YES?
YEAH, MAYBE IT'LL SNOW
THIS AFTERNOON TOO.
BUT I DOUBT IT.
[ Shouting, Laughter ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
YAH!  WHEE!
WHOO-HOOEY!
YEE-HAW!  WHOO!
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING DOWN THERE?
COSTAIN!
WHOO-HOO!
LOOK OUT, COSTAIN!
AAAH!  AYE!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
COSTAIN?
[ Coughs ]
FINE!
JUST FINE.
YOU JUST CAN'T EXPECT TO CHANGE
A WHOLE CULTURE OVERNIGHT.
I DON'T HAVE
A LEAST NOTION OF CHANGING IT.
IF YOU JUST GIVE ME MY WAGES,
I WON'T BE TROUBLING YOU
ANY FURTHER.
YOU KNOW,
THIS IS SUNDAY.
THEY'RE ENTITLED
TO SOME RECREATION.
WELL, THERE JUST AIN'T ANY
SUNDAYS WHEN IT'S ROUNDUP
'TIL THE JOB GETS DONE.
WELL, PERHAPS
IF YOU MET THEM HALF WAY,
THEY WOULD BE ABLE--
MA'AM, THERE AREN'T
ANY "HALF WAYS" IN
THE CATTLE BUSINESS
IT'D BE EASIER TO MAKE
A CHERRY PIE OUT OF BARBED WIRE,
THAN TO MAKE A COWBOY OUT
OF THE BEST OF THE LOT OF 'EM.
THEY JUST AIN'T
CUT OUT FOR WORKIN'.
BOOTON SAYS
THEY'RE REALLY TRYING.
THAT'S WHAT'S FRIGHTENING.
THEY ARE.
- WELL, IF THEY'RE
SHOWING PROGRESS--
- THEY'RE NOT SHOWING PROGRESS.
THEY'RE JUST TRYING.
IT AIN'T THE SAME THING.
MA'AM, SUPPOSE I COULD
WHIP THEM INTO SHAPE.
IT'S NOT POSSIBLE,
BUT JUST SUPPOSE I DID.
RUNNING CATTLE IS--
WELL, IT'S NOT JUST
RIDING AND ROPING,
IT TAKES, IT TAKES PURPOSE.
AND YOU CAN'T TEACH THAT
TO SOMEONE LIKE YOU CAN
TEACH 'EM TO SIT A HORSE.
[ Sighs ]
I FIGURE YOU OWE ME $17,
BUT WHATEVER YOU THINK'S RIGHT.
MR. COSTAIN,
I COULD RAISE
YOUR SALARY.
IT'S NOT THE MONEY, MA'AM.
I THINK I OUGHT TO
GET BACK TO TEXAS BEFORE
I LOSE ALL MY STITCHING.
I HAVE NIGHTMARES
ABOUT THESE PEOPLE
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE.
WELL, THIS WON'T
GET YOU BACK TO TEXAS.
WELL,
IT'LL GET ME STARTED.
COULDN'T YOU AT LEAST
WAIT UNTIL MORNING?
I MEAN--
I DON'T KNOW, MA'AM.
I DON'T THINK SO.
IF I WAIT AROUND 'TIL MORNING,
IT'LL JUST MAKE THINGS TOUGHER
THAN THEY OUGHT TO BE.
MRS. MacAVOY,
THERE AIN'T NOTHIN'
PERSONAL IN ALL THIS.
YOU PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
MIGHTY KIND TO ME.
BYE, MA'AM.
COSTAIN!
MAMA, MAMA!
MAMA.
WHERE IS HE, MAMA?
HE'S GONE, SON.
- GONE?  YOU MEAN FOREVER?
- I'M AFRAID SO.
BUT HOW COULD YOU DO IT?
HOW COULD YOU JUST LET HIM
GO LIKE THAT?
I JUST DIDN'T LET HIM GO.
HE'S A MAN, HE DOES
WHAT HE WANTS TO.
- I COULDN'T STOP HIM.
- WELL, YOU COULD'VE TRIED.
YOU COULD'VE GOT ME UP.
I WOULD'VE MADE HIM STAY.
BOOTON, PLEASE.
[ Sighs ]
I BET $20.
TWENTY
AND RAISE TWENTY.
THAT PUTS ME OUT.
I DON'T HAVE ANYTHING
TO BET WITH.
OH, I WOULDN'T SAY THAT.
FIVE-CARD STUD,
GENTLEMEN.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
TAKING MONEY AWAY
FROM FOOLS.
[ Laughing ]
HE'S BEEN WINNING
ALL NIGHT.
I SEE YOU'VE FOUND AN EASIER
WAY TO MAKE A LIVING.
THERE'S AN EMPTY CHAIR
IF YOU FEEL LIKE SITTING IN.
ACE BETS.
DON'T TALK UNLESS
YOU'RE IN THE GAME.
BET 20.
[ Laughing ]
I HOPE YOU GENTLEMEN
WILL FORGIVE ME, BUT
I'VE GOT A SHIP TO CATCH.
- YOU LEAVING THE ISLANDS?
- WELL, THANKS TO THESE
GENTLEMEN GAMBLERS.
CAPTAIN, IF YOU EVER DOCK
IN FORT WORTH, YOU LOOK ME UP.
GIVE YOU A CHANCE TO GET EVEN.
[ Kimo ] YOU STAY.
WE BE COWBOY FOR YOU, BOSS.
NO SWIM, NO FISH,
NOT EVEN SUNDAY.
- WE WORK HARD, BOSS.
- NO WATER SLIDE.
NOT ANY KIND OF PLAY.
THEY MEAN IT, COSTAIN.
REALLY.
WE GOT CLOTHES
GOOD FOR CATCH COWS.
- OUR PANTS NO GOOD, BOSS?
- YOU STAY, BOSS.
- [ Booton ] COME ON, COSTAIN!
- PLEASE, STAY, BOSS.
- WHO BELONGS TO THIS BOAT?
- ME, MISTER.
COULD YOU ROW ME OUT
TO THAT SHIP OUT THERE?
IT'S A LONG ROW.
- COME ON, BOSS!
- [ Booton ] PLEASE STAY, COSTAIN!
- STAY!
- COME ON, COSTAIN!
[ Booton ]
COME ON, COSTAIN.
DON'T GO!
WE PROMISE TO WORK!
COSTAIN, I DIDN'T HEAR THE
DINNER BELL RING, DID YOU?
TURN AROUND,
ROW FOR SHORE.
[ Cheering ]
AND HE BOUGHT BOOTS
FOR ALL OF THEM?
YEP, WITH HIS POKER MONEY.
HE SAID WE JUST HAD TO HAVE THEM
IF WE'RE GONNA RUN CATTLE.
LOOK THERE.
[ Chattering ]
MIGHTY GOOD, BOSS.
[ Shouts In Hawaiian ]
[ Booton ]
YA-HOO!
[ Cheering, Shouting ]
- WE FINISHED NOW, BOSS.
- GOOD, HUH?
YEAH, BOSS.
WELL, ALL WE GOTTA DO NOW
IS FILL IT UP.
THAT'S A GREAT DEAL
OF MONEY, MALAKOMA.
MORE THAN YOU
CAN EARN IN A YEAR.
YOU DID NOT
GET IT FROM ME.
YOU DIDN'T COME HERE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOU AND MALAKOMA
NO TALK.
THAT'S IT.
I DON'T CARE HOW YOU DO IT,
BUT I DON'T WANT THOSE
CATTLE ROUNDED UP FOR SALE.
COSTAIN, COSTAIN!
YEAH,
WHAT IS IT LILY?
[ Speaking Hawaiian ]
- WHAT?
- ANIMAL IN FIELD, BOSS!
OH, YEAH?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S JUST SEE
WHAT YOU'VE LEARNED?
LET'S GO.
KIMO, CUT YOUR TEETH.
KIMO, SHAKE THAT LOOP OUT
AND GO TO IT.
[ Panting, Gasping ]
[ Men Chattering ]
KIMO, WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT HAPPENED?
HOW DOES HE KNOW HE'S DYING
IF HE DOESN'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT'S WRONG WITH HIM?
THEY CALL IT
DEATH BY SORCERY.
- WITCH DOCTOR.
- MALAKOMA IS ONE OF THEM.
I DON'T BELIEVE IN IT,
BUT THEY BELIEVE IN IT,
AND THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
THAT'S WHY THEY WON'T
WORK FOR YOU.
BUT WHY KIMO?
IT'S ME HE'S AFTER.
I DON'T KNOW.
I SUPPOSE HE FEELS THAT'S
THE WAY TO GET TO YOU.
[ Liliha Chanting ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
LILIHA, WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU, WOMAN?
LILIHA, LILIHA!
LILIHA, IT'S COSTAIN.
NOW STOP IT.
MALAKOMA GET YOU, COSTAIN,
FOR SURE.
YOU LEAVE HERE
OR YOU DIE.
YOU JUST TELL ME
WHERE HE IS.
MALAKOMA SAY TWO MORE DAYS,
KIMO DIE, THEN LELEO.
I'M NOT LEAVING.
SO IF WE'RE GONNA DIE,
WE'RE GONNA DIE.
THE ONLY CHANCE WE HAVE
IS IF YOU TELL ME
WHERE MALAKOMA IS.
NOW TELL ME, LILIHA.
HIM GO TABOO GROUND.
LIVE ALL ALONE
IN CAVERNS OF DEAD GODS.
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting, Groaning ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
ARE YOU LUCKY
I NEED YOU ALIVE!
[ Horse Snorting ]
ALL RIGHT NOW,
LOUD AND CLEAR, DO IT.
DO WHATEVER IT IS
YOU HAVE TO DO, OR YOU AND ME
ARE GONNA BUMP HEADS AGAIN.
NOW, DO IT!
[ Speaks Hawaiian ]
WHAT'D HE SAY, LILIHA?
HE SAY KIMO NO DIE NOW.
NO MORE ANNA NA.
KIMO?
- THE SPELL IS OVER.
- YOU BET IT'S OVER, FOR GOOD.
NO, NO, KIMO.
YOU REST.
[ Laughs ]
YES, MISS MAKA.
BOOTON, YOU WATCH HIM.
YOU BETTER GO FIND YOURSELF
ANOTHER ISLAND, BUSTER.
GET GOIN'.
WELL, DON'T STAND AROUND.
SHOW'S OVER.
COME ON, COME ON.
WE GOT A LOT OF WORK TO DO.
[ Chattering ]
MR. COSTAIN.
THEY'LL NEVER FORGET YOU
FOR WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
THEY'LL DO ANYTHING
FOR YOU NOW.
WE'LL SEE WHO FORGETS WHO
WHEN THE GOING GETS ROUGH,
MA'AM.
JUST REMEMBER WHAT
YOU LEARNED AND USE IT.
YOU MIGHT COME OUT OF
THIS DAY IN ONE PIECE.
MOUNT UP.
WELL, MISS MacAVOY,
YOU MAY OR MAY NOT OWN A BUNCH
OF MAVERICK CATTLE AT SUNDOWN,
BUT AT LEAST YOU WON'T
HAVE TO WONDER ANYMORE.
TODAY'S THE DAY
THAT TELLS IT ALL.
I KNOW, MR. COSTAIN.
THANK YOU.
[ Cows Mooing ]
[ Costain ]
THEY'RE BUNCHED UP IN THE BRUSH.
THAT AIN'T GOOD.
DON'T TRY TO ROPE 'EM IN THERE.
JUST HAZE 'EM OUT IN THE OPEN,
SO YOU CAN THROW
A GOOD LOOP AT 'EM.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S CUT THE BRUSH.
[ Shouts ]
[ Whooping, Whistling ]
WHOA!  NOT
THE FIRST TIME, BOY.
YOU'RE READY.
YOU'RE NOT THAT READY.
NO, YOU JUST HANG BACK,
WATCH HOW IT GOES THIS TIME.
NEXT TIME OUT,
IT'LL BE YOU AND ME.
[ Whooping Continues ]
[ Cow Mooing ]
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Horse Neighs ]
WHOO-HOO!
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Cow Mooing ]
[ Snorting ]
OYE!
HYAH!  HYAH!
HEE!  HEE!
HEE!
[ Cow Mooing ]
OH, HELP!
OHHH!
AYE!  OHH!
[ Costain ]
WITH MY BOOTS IN THE SADDLE
AND MY HAND ON THE HORN
I'M THE BEST DANG COW PUNCHER
EVER WAS BORN
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
GET BACON AND BEANS
MOST EVERY DAY
I'LL SOON GO TO GRAZIN'
ON PRAIRIE HAY
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
YOU CAN SING TO THE CATTLE
YOU CAN SING TO THE BIRDS
AND IT AIN'T GONNA MATTER
IF YOU DON'T KNOW THE WORDS
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
I TOLD YOU
THEY COULD DO IT.
WELL, IF THEY CAN LEARN
TO PUNCH CATTLE AS WELL AS SING,
THEY'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M GOIN' TO THE WAGON
GONNA DRAW OUT MY PAY
AND I AIN'T RUNNIN' CATTLE
EVEN ONE MORE DAY
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
COME A KIYI YIPPEE
YIPPEE YAY, YIPPEE YAY
YIPPEE YAY
WELL, JUST BECAUSE
IT AIN'T NEVER BEEN DONE
DON'T MEAN IT WON'T WORK.
A LITTLE LEADERSHIP
AND DETERMINATION, MR. COSTAIN.
YES, MA'AM.
[ Cows Mooing ]
HYAH!
THIS IS JUST A DRY RUN
TO SEE IF IT WORKS,
BUT I WANT TO TAKE 'EM
RIGHT OUT TO BLUE WATER.
[ Mooing Continues ]
- YOU ALL SET, BENTON?
- BOOTON!
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GIVE IT A TRY.
- OKAY.
- ALL RIGHT, BOSS.
ALL RIGHT,
POLE, POLE!
[ Mooing Continues ]
ALL RIGHT,
KEEP IT SMOOTH.
WHOA, BABY, HO!
EASY, BABY.  EASY, GIRL.
[ Mooing ]
WHOA, BABY, HO.
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Costain ] NOW, HO.
DON'T LET 'EM
SHIFT TO THAT SIDE.
THEY'RE MOVIN' AROUND.
DON'T LET 'EM SHIFT OVER THERE.
THEY'RE ALL MOVIN' OVER THERE.
KEEP 'EM OVER.  KEEP 'EM
OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE.
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Men Shouting ]
DON'T LET--  DON'T--
UGH!  GET THAT BRINDLE
BACK ON THE OTHER SIDE.
[ Cows Mooing,
Men Shouting ]
PICK 'EM UP!
[ Men Shouting, Whooping ]
HYAH!  HYAH!
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Frantic Mooing ]
YOU'RE NOT SO ORNERY
WHEN YOU CAN'T GET YOUR FEET
PLANTED, ARE YA?
YOU'LL TOW LIKE
A WASHTUB WITH HORNS,
BUT I THINK YOU JUST GAVE ME
THE ANSWER, BOSSY.
[ Shouting Continues ]
YEE-HAW!
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU CAN GET THEM CRITTERS
OUT TO THE SHIP?
WHAT MAKES YOU
THINK I CAN'T?
WELL, NO ONE
EVER HAS, LAD.
THAT'S BESIDE THE POINT.
DO YOU WANT THE CATTLE
OR DON'T YOU?
INDEED I DO, LITTLE LADY.
AS BAD AS YOU WANT TO SELL 'EM.
I'LL GIVE YOU 15 DOLLARS
A HEAD, LOADED ON.
SIR, YOU'RE A CAPTAIN,
NOT A PIRATE.
TWENTY DOLLARS A HEAD.
NOT A PENNY LESS.
ALONGSIDE.
[ Sighs, Moans ]
SEVENTEEN-FIFTY, ON BOARD.
THERE'S NO PROFIT IN IT FOR ME.
UH, A GENTLEMAN...
IS NOT SUPPOSED TO LIE
IN THE PRESENCE OF A LADY.
TWENTY DOLLARS.
ALONGSIDE.
[ Sighs, Clears Throat ]
UPON MY WORD, LAD,
I WISH YOU HAD LEFT
THE LITTLE LADY AT HOME.
ALL RIGHT, 20 IT IS, ON--
- ALONGSIDE.
- THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
- YOU'RE NOT LEAVING SO SOON.
WE'D LOVE TO STAY,
BUT WE'VE GOT MORE CATTLE
TO SELL, HAVEN'T WE?
YES, INDEED WE HAVE.
GOOD DAY.
AHHH!
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO LOAD CATTLE
ABOARD THOSE BOATS!
I WOULD NOT BET
AGAINST THAT MAN.
NO, NOT ON ANYTHING.
AND HE CAN'T DELIVER
CATTLE HE CAN'T FIND.
CAN HE?
- WHAT?
- STAMPEDE THEM.
WILL YOU DO IT?
SURE, WITH SOME GUNS
AND A LITTLE HELP,
THEY'LL GO, BUT--
[ Cows Mooing ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Mooing Continues ]
IT DOESN'T REALLY HURT 'EM.
I MEAN, THEY'RE A TOUGH BREED.
IT'S NOT ALWAYS TRUE.
IT JUST DEPENDS ON WHERE
YOU ARE AT THE TIME.
[ Mooing Continues ]
YOU ONLY DO THAT WITH--
YEARLINGS...
[ Cows Mooing ]
WHEN YOU KNOW YOU GOT
A LONG WINTER COMIN' ON.
[ Mooing Continues ]
'COURSE YOUR WINTER HERE
ONLY LASTS ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
WHAT'S WRONG, COSTAIN?
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Whooping ]
STAMPEDE.  STAMPEDE!
GET EVERYBODY OUT OF THESE HUTS.
EVERYBODY OUT!
[ Whooping Continues ]
WHOA!  WHOA!
LILIHA!  STAMPEDE.
GET ALL THE WOMEN AND
CHILDREN TO THE BEACH.
YOU MEN SADDLE YOUR HORSES.
NOW MOVE!  MOVE!
[ Shouts In Hawaiian ]
STAMPEDE!  STAMPEDE!
GO GET YOUR MOTHER!
[ Men Shouting ]
[ Whooping Continues ]
HYAH!  HYAH!
[ Gunshots Continue ]
LILIHA, I TOLD YOU
TO TAKE THEM TO THE BEACH.
NOW GO!
[ Whooping Continues ]
[ Miss MacAvoy ]
WHAT CAN WE DO?
GET UNDER THERE!
[ Whooping, Gunshots
Continue ]
[ Cattle Passing Overhead ]
[ Men Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
YOU TAKE CARE
OF YOUR MOTHER.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
HYAH!
[ Whooping Continues ]
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Shouting ]
RUN THOSE LEADERS!
RUN THEM!
COME BACK!
STAY WITH ME!
OKA, KIMO, TURN 'EM!
TURN 'EM!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Whinnies ]
AAAH!
MARRUJO!
FOR TWO BITS,
I'D TAKE YOU APART
AND FEED YOU TO THE HOGS,
BUT I NEED YOU
FOR SOMETHIN' ELSE.
COME ON.
[ Crickets Chirping ]
WHERE THE DEVIL
HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHAT HAPPENED
OUT THERE?
[ Costain ]
THE STAMPEDE, BRYSON.
IT WAS QUITE A RUCKUS.
SHOULD'VE BEEN OUT THERE
YOURSELF.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
GETTIN' READY
TO HAVE YOU PUT AWAY.
BUT FIRST THERE'S A MATTER
OF MRS. MacAVOY'S NOTE.
I WANT IT.
NOTE?  YOU CAN'T--
THAT'S A LEGAL DOCUMENT.
SHE OWES THAT MONEY TO ME.
AFTER TONIGHT,
WITH THE CATTLE SHE LOST,
THE GROUNDS AND THE
BUILDINGS GETTING TORN UP,
I FIGURE YOU AND THE LADY
ARE ABOUT EVEN, MISTER.
I WANT THE NOTE.
[ Cocks Gun ]
NOW.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL GET IT FOR YOU.
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Groans ]
[ Panting ]
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
HE'S ALL YOURS.
- ALL RIGHT ON YOUR FEET.
- COME ON NOW, LET'S GO.
[ Sighs ]
[ Shouting, Whooping ]
[ Cows Mooing ]
[ Shouting,
Whooping Continue ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
HEY, WATCH OUT NOW!
[ Mooing Continues ]
- CAPTAIN.
- OH, IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU, MA'AM.
AND ESPECIALLY
YOUR MERCHANDISE.
ALL RIGHT, OKA,
THROW A LOOP ON ONE...
- AND MOVE HIM OUT.
- RIGHT AWAY, BOSS.
[ Mooing ]
[ Mooing Continues ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
HEY!  OH-HO!
ALL RIGHT, LET HIM GO.
[ Mooing ]
[ Costain ]
KEEP PULLIN'.  STEADY.
TIGHTEN DOWN NOW, TIGHTEN DOWN.
[ Mooing ]
[ Costain ]
ALL RIGHT, TAKE HIM OUT.
WELL, BARRIN' TIDAL WAVES
AND BARBARY PIRATES,
YOU'RE ABOUT TO BE
IN THE CATTLE BUSINESS
ALL THE WAY.
[ Frantic Mooing ]
COME TO THINK OF IT,
I THINK WE COULD HANDLE
A TIDAL WAVE.
- STAND BY!
AWAY THE SLING!
- TAKE HIM UP.
- HOIST HIM AWAY!
[ Frantic Mooing ]
- LOWER AWAY!
EASY DOES IT, MATEY.
- STEADY!
- STEADY AS SHE GOES.
[ Cow Mooing ]
HEY, YOU KNOW, I THINK
I SOLD THEM BOYS SHORT...
WHEN I SAID THEY COULDN'T
DRIVE HOT NAILS IN A SNOW BANK.
I THINK THEY COULD.
I REALLY THINK THEY COULD.
- [ Sobbing ]
- HENRIETTA,
WHAT ARE YOU CRYIN' ABOUT?
I DON'T KNOW.  I GUESS
I NEVER REALLY BELIEVED
IT WOULD HAPPEN.
YOU MADE A BELIEVER
OUT OF ME, COSTAIN,
MISSUS.
HERE'S YOUR MONEY.
COIN OF THE REALM.
A MATE'S PAY TO ANYONE
WHO WILL NURSEMAID THEM
COWS BACK TO CALIFORNIA.
WELL, THAT'S MY CHANCE
TO GET BACK TO TEXAS.
I DON'T KNOW, CAPTAIN,
THAT RIGHT TEMPTIN',
BUT I DON'T THINK
I COULD LEAVE MRS. MacAVOY
WITH THEM PINEAPPLE COWBOYS.
THEY'D DRIVE HER DINGY,
AND I'M THE ONLY ONE AROUND
WHO KNOWS HOW TO HANDLE 'EM.
WELL, SUIT YOURSELF, LAD,
AND I DON'T BLAME YOU.
BUT I GOTTA GET THEM COWS
TO CALIFORNIA.
THANKS
TO BOTH OF YOU.
- GOOD-BYE.
- GOOD-BYE, NOW.
THEN YOU ARE GOING TO STAY?
AT LEAST FOR A WHILE, LINC?
WELL, FOR A WHILE, YEAH.
FOR A WHILE.
YOU KNOW, 'TIL THEY
GET THE HANG OF IT.
THEN I'M GONNA GET OFF
THIS FLOWER POT.
[ Booton Shouting ]
MAMA!  MAMA!
- GOOD HEAVENS,
WE'RE RIGHT HERE.
- TARNATION, MOM!
I SWAM ONE OF THOSE CRITTERS OUT
JUST AS SMOOTH AS BUTTER.
- DID YOU SEE?
- OF COURSE
WE DID, DEAR.
AND NOBODY COULD
HAVE DONE IT BETTER.
OH, WELL, NOW,
THAT'S A LITTLE THICK,
DON'T YOU THINK?
AIN'T NOBODY
GONNA PIN A ROSE ON YOU
JUST FOR DOIN' YOUR JOB.
YOU REMEMBER THAT,
BOOTON.
MOM, MOM, HE CALLED ME
BY MY RIGHT NAME!
DID YOU HEAR HIM?
HE SAID IT RIGHT
FOR THE FIRST TIME!
[ Booton ]
CAN WE DO IT TOGETHER
THIS TIME?  CAN WE?
WELL, CAN'T THINK
OF ANY REASON WHY NOT.
THROW YOUR LOOP.
[ Cows Mooing ]