NARRAToR: This place used to be known
as Bidancoje Canyon...
...after some Indian feller.
The first city council we ever had
decided to change the name to Santa Rosa.
Reckoned it was more dignified.
Can't say as how it made
a lot of difference.
There's a fella from the government
came by a while back...
...said we got 2406 folks living here.
I mean, you know, what with people dying
and new kids being born.
Damned if I know how he figured that out
from one day to the next.
Come to think of it, about the only thing
that makes Santa Rosa...
...any different from the other towns
in these parts is our sheriff.
In the first place, he's a foreigner.
An Irishman, which isn't
anything against him of course...
...but it sure gives him
a funny way of talking.
Another thing unusual about him,
he's never shot anybody.
KILPATRICK: Okay, Kevin, off you go.
Give it plenty of air. Go on.
Now, let it go. Good boy.
Here, I'll show you.
You gotta aim it very high...
...and let it float over the object
it's gonna drop on. All right?
You practice that
and get that right and I promise you...
...you can rope yourself a mustang,
kill a snake...
...or pull a little doggy out
of a bog hole.
That's a lot more than you can do
with a gun.
[WINDING BARREL]
BRAND:
You know something? It's shocking.
The price of ammunition's
a goddamn disgrace.
[LAUGHS]
CHoo CHoo: Maybe we better go down
to that hardware store...
...and give them a taste of my rail.
[ALL LAUGHING]
KATHERINE: Kilpatrick, leave the boy alone.
'Tis time for school.
KILPATRICK: A little homework won't
do him any harm. He's coming right in.
Go on to mind your mother.
Give it one more.
Plenty of air, let it swing,
now let it go. Good boy.
[CLAPS]
BRAND:
There she is. Ride in real slow.
Choo Choo takes care of the horses.
And Schoolboy and Jacob
and me just wander on inside.
Jacob, now, when I say something,
you listen to me, you nigger son of a bitch.
JACoB:
I'm listening, Mr. Brand.
[LAUGHS]
BRAND: Remember,
anyone gets in your way, kill them.
Pretty town, real pretty.
CHoo CHoo: Pretty town your ass.
It's that pretty money we want.
KEvlN:
Can I take the lariat with me to school?
KILPATRICK: Of course you can.
Don't forget, you must keep practicing.
KATHERINE:
The boy should be tending his lessons...
...not indulging
in a lot of tomfoolery with ropes.
KILPATRICK:
Do you want the boy to grow up useless?
KATHERINE: No, but I'd like him to have
a proper head on his shoulders.
Not like his father.
KILPATRICK: Katherine, I think you're
very beautiful, but you make no sense at all.
SARAH:
Good morning, sheriff.
KILPATRICK:
Good morning, Sarah. Fine morning it is.
MAN:
Good morning, sheriff.
KILPATRICK:
Good morning, boys.
- Good morning, guys.
BoB: Morning, Sean.
BILL:
Good morning, Sean.
KILPATRICK:
Bill, give me those handbills from Austin.
Bob, there are four strangers over there
by Jack's wearing guns.
- Keep an eye on them.
BoB: Right.
BRAND: Jacob, will you stop
counting that stuff and stash it away?
Let's get out of here.
TELLER:
You picked the wrong town, mister.
This is Kilpatrick's town.
KILPATRICK:
You better take the key.
BILL: See somebody you think you recognize?
KILPATRICK: No. That's what worries me.
TELLER: Do you realize your chances
are very remote?
We have the best possible protection.
BRAND:
You really believe that, don't you?
TELLER:
I do indeed, sir.
BRAND:
Well, shit.
We ain't got a hell of a lot
more to talk about, have we?
Goddamn it, I knew it.
Pesky, get that bell.
Bill.
[BELL RINGING]
Remember the plan. No shooting.
Frank, get over by the wagons.
Get the women and children safe.
Come on, now, get the town, boys.
Okay, boys. Get on the roof.
Keep down and no shooting.
BRAND:
Goddamn it, move. Move.
KILPATRICK:
Tom?
- Help with the wagons.
- Dan, no shooting.
Larry, on the roof, Larry.
Jake, keep those women inside.
Sam, get those children off the street.
Come on, Schoolboy.
Come on, goddamn it, move. Move.
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
CHoo CHoo: It's a trap, they blocked us,
they blocked us.
Let's get out of here.
BRAND:
Git, damn it, git. Come on.
[PEoPLE CHATTERING]
[WoMEN SCREAMING]
Get the hell off...
You could hurt somebody with that thing,
you know.
Goddamn it. Sit still.
[Bo Y CRYING]
Shut that kid up.
I want all these kids kept shut.
Not a peep out of them. Shut him up.
[CHILDREN CRYING]
[YELLING]
Drop it.
Bill.
I could've told him
to blow your head off.
Bill.
BRAND:
Hey, you.
Sheriff, here in the schoolhouse.
Hey, mister.
We got you all boxed in.
We're not gonna shoot you down,
not in my town.
We, uh...
We got your friends.
They're all alive.
Want us to show them to you?
I got something to show you.
I got me a little kid.
And I'll blow his head off
unless you drop them guns.
No, wait.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
You're not gonna kill that kid, are you?
If you make me squeeze this trigger...
...l'll blow him so wide apart
ain't nobody gonna put him together again.
Drop the guns! Drop them!
Let us go quiet.
This is Kilpatrick.
Kilpatrick speaking.
I want you to take your guns...
...your gun belts...
...throw them into
the center of the street.
You all hear me?
Drop them! Guns! Get out of there!
You too, Bill.
Please, Bill, please.
Bill, go to the center of the road...
...and make sure everybody's
thrown their guns down.
So we can see them.
And get their horses,
bring them right here.
And the saddlebags with the money.
Saddlebags with the money.
The saddlebags and the money, Bill.
Hi, kid. You all right?
Yeah.
- Good boy.
- Of course he's all right.
Good little kid.
You know something?
You were smart.
I heard you was a bright fella.
Kilpatrick, ain't it?
Yeah. Yeah, that's me. And you?
Brand.
Frank Brand.
I never knowed too many people'd
call me by my first name.
Well...
...you win the pot.
Yeah, I knows you'd see it that way...
...Mr. Kilpatrick.
You really weren't gonna
kill that kid, were you?
It's a goddamn good thing for him
that you didn't try to find out.
Yeah.
Grab ahold of him.
Mr. Kilpatrick?
Schoolboy, give me that kid.
Hey, now, wait a minute.
I gave you my town.
I want that boy.
Just a little insurance, Mr. Kilpatrick.
I'll drop him off for you
a little ways out of town.
Git.
Kevin!
Ma!
[WoMAN SCREAMS]
Katherine.
Oh, Katherine.
It's the boy, Katherine.
It's Kevin.
It's Kevin, you know.
Just wait.
I'll be right back.
I'm just going over
to talk to our little boy.
Wait now.
[MAN SPEAKING IN LATIN]
Amen.
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come...
...thy will be done...
...on Earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses...
...as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation...
...but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in the green pastures. He...
Why?
Why, Father?
[PEoPLE SINGING
"HAPPY BIRTHDAY" SoNG]
KATHERINE: Come now, Sean,
after all, it's the boy's birthday...
...and he has his heart set on it.
KILPATRICK: Katherine,
I don't care if it's the boy's birthday.
KATHERINE: It's only a toy gun.
All little boys want toy guns.
KEvlN:
Why can't I have a gun, Daddy?
KILPATRICK: Because you can't reason
with a gun, Kevin.
I know it's hard for you to understand.
If you have a gun then
another person wants to have a gun...
...and then another and another.
And pretty soon,
everyone has to live with a gun.
And that's very, very bad.
We must not allow guns
to do our thinking for us.
KEvlN:
I don't want to hear anymore.
You're a mean Daddy
and I don't love you anymore.
[GUNSHoT]
BoB:
Looks like they made it into Mexico.
BILL: They're two, maybe three hours ahead
of us. Wanna notify the Federales?
Sean, I said do you want to notify
the Federales?
Sean?
Federales?
Federales, Sean. Mexico.
Mexico?
What are you talking about?
BILL:
Don't do it, Sean.
I'm asking you, don't go.
Take care of Katherine, Kevin,
for me, will you?
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
BRAND:
Okay, let's haul ass out of here.
You like that hat, Schoolboy?
Every one of them bills is brand-new.
Every one of those bills are brand-new,
Mr. Brand.
Well, I just said,
them sons of bitches is brand-new.
Deaf as a post, that nigger.
Come on, Schoolboy,
you can't spend it here, you know.
Hat. New hat. Mine.
CHoo CHoo:
Yeah, yeah, I know, your hat.
BRAND: Come on, nobody gives
a shit about his hat.
Come on, Jacob, let's get out of here.
We just can't leave him, Mr. Brand.
BRAND:
I can leave him. Come on, giddap, git.
JACoB:
Schoolboy.
Schoolboy, listen.
Mr. Brand wants to leave.
- Come on, now.
- Hat.
- My hat.
- Nice hat, yes.
Nice hat, okay, come on. Come on.
JACoB:
Come on, Schoolboy.
[GUNSHoT]
A hundred dollars on Schoolboy.
Maybe we should go back.
There's $9000 down there in those bags.
Schoolboy or the sheriff,
one of them's gonna bring it to us.
[GRUNTS]
[RETCHING]
[GUNSHoT]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Who the hell are you?
Rudolpho Gutierrez.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
You're a lawman?
What the hell do you think that is?
This badge gives you no right
to kill people, senor.
You know who those bastards are?
GUTIERREZ:
I have been hunting Senor Brand...
...for a long time.
He is wanted here.
On suspicion for murder.
Suspicion?
You mean you don't know
if that's the man you want?
He must be identified.
I have a witness.
Identified?
Oh, I can identify him, all right.
For the rest of my life I can identify him.
I saw him kill my wife.
Katherine.
He...
...shot the...
...roses from her cheeks.
My son, Kevin.
He just...
...threw him under the horse's feet.
And the horses tromped him
and tromped him...
...and tromped him and tromped him.
- I'm sorry, senor.
I'm sorry for you.
But you have no authority here.
I'm gonna kill him.
- I'm gonna kill him.
- No.
No.
You do not kill him.
L...
I am going to catch him.
And bring him back for trial.
You are a sheriff, senor.
You know it is our job
to catch such pigs...
...not to execute them.
You go home now.
I will catch him.
And I will send you word.
You'll do that?
I mean, you'll really do that?
On the life of my wife...
...and my child.
I'm Kilpatrick.
Santa Rosa.
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHING]
Mama, get in there, get in there.
Watermelon. Well, I'll be goddamned.
Look at that.
I told you we'd find some food here.
JACoB: Not much here to eat.
- A nice juicy watermelon.
BRAND: What do you mean nothing here?
What do you call that?
BRAND: I gotta hand it to you, Choo Choo,
you can use that hunk of rail of yours.
That hunk of rail there's
a tribute to my daddy.
BRAND: How come?
- Like other folks got a tombstone.
It just happened that I couldn't find enough
pieces to bury him...
...to give him a real honest-to-God
tombstone, so I just...
I just got myself a piece here
that killed him.
What'd he do, blow himself up?
A train wreck.
My daddy threw me clear...
...all I got was my hand here cut off.
Snorting train must have dragged
my pappy 500 yards.
Next time it come through,
there was a piece of rail missing.
[CHoo CHoo LAUGHING]
Did I ever tell you about my daddy?
Well, when I was a yearling...
...I was 15 years old.
Because my mama done give me
a pair of them cavalry boots.
They was about that high
and blue-black.
Anyway...
...my daddy's herd...
...little herd, come down
with the hoof-and-mouth disease.
So, what you gonna do,
you know? We dug a pit.
Dug a big hole and drop them all into it.
Shot them.
Anyway...
...I was standing there
and I fell in the goddamn pit.
And my father laughed at me.
I shot him and I buried him with the cows.
But them boots, they stunk for a year.
Anyway, when anybody had ask me
what my daddy died of...
...l'd say, "What, my daddy? My daddy
died of hoof-and-mouth disease."
Hoof-and-mouth disease
with a human being?
Hoof-and-mouth disease.
Don't you find that funny, nigger?
Well, Mr. Brand...
...I don't know if it's funny or not.
I don't even know who my father was.
I'll be a son of a bitch.
CHoo CHoo:
Why, it's that goddamn sheriff again.
JACoB:
He's right.
Hope he's still got the money with him.
He's crazy. That son of a bitch is crazy.
A hundred miles into Mexican territory
and he's still playing sheriff.
He's a goddamn Yankee.
Don't care nothing about state's rights.
JACoB:
What are we gonna do about it?
Yeah, he is getting to be
a pain in the ass.
Got me an idea.
Hey, senora.
I think you can be of service to us.
[HoRN BLoWS]
What? What the...?
I'm Kilpatrick. I'm sheriff of Santa Rosa.
I'm the sheriff of Santa Rosa.
Senor Sheriff, now he saying
that he too is a lawman.
What kind of a lawman would shoot
two old people like that...
...until his gun run out of bullets?
See, this fella's pretty stupid.
He don't realize that us Americans,
when we come across the border...
...we do away with our badges of office.
That's out of respect to your authority.
What'd you think you was doing, fella?
Trying to fool all these simple people?
Because you got a little piece
of tin on your chest?
See, in United States you can buy a toy like
this just for a few pennies, a few centavos.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
You don't have to talk to me
because I'm a sheriff.
Just go and peek in his saddlebags.
I'll guarantee you he's got most of
the money that he stole in Texas.
Brand.
You understand Mex., fella?
They're saying they're gonna hang you.
Hope it hurts like a son of a bitch.
Brand...
...for the rest of your life
you'll remember this.
It was my wife...
...and my son you killed in my town.
Hang him.
GUTIERREZ: If you had not hit me so hard
in the wrong place...
If you had not hit me so hard
in the wrong place, senor...
...I would have been here sooner.
- Brand...
- He can't be too far.
I will go after him.
I come... I'll come with you.
No, no, no.
You stay here.
They will release you soon.
They will not try to hang you again.
Unless you complain about the food.
This is your food.
You still gonna bring him in alive?
After what he did to those...
...two old people?
You saw him kill them?
No one did.
Senor Gutierrez...
...when you catch him,
if he's not identified by a witness...
...you gonna release him?
- That is the law.
- Senor Gutierrez...
...what's the name of your wife?
Martha.
And your children?
Pancho and Miguel.
And you're gonna set him...
...free?
[GUTIERREZ SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
You ain't finished yet?
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Dumb asshole.
That blacksmith takes an hour
for each goddamn shoe.
Ain't no hurry.
Hey, Jacob.
Get out the cards.
We got an hour before the shoe's ready
over at the blacksmith's.
Why don't you have him fix
your new hand while you wait?
CHoo CHoo: One of these days I'm gonna
stuff this thing right down your throat.
- Come on, I wanna try it again.
- Try what?
The lady, the lady.
Oh, come on, I have no desire
to take your money.
Well, you've already taken
a goddamn thousand.
That's exactly what I mean.
Well, then give me a chance to get even.
All right. Okay.
- How much?
CHoo CHoo: Five hundred.
An ace.
Another ace.
The lady.
Now, this time try to concentrate, okay?
That one.
- That one?
- No, goddamn it, that one.
- Are you sure?
- You wanted me to pick the other one.
- You're bending the card.
- I won, didn't I?
You lose.
Why, you dirty, cheating bastard.
[MEN YELLING AND CHATTERING]
Damn it, will you cut out that bullshit?
We got ourselves some company.
You know who that is?
That's that son of a bitching
Mexican sheriff.
We get rid of one, now we got another.
- Let's get the hell out of here.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute, hold it.
He's been trying to take me
for about six months.
I figure it's time I give him a chance.
I figure it's time.
There he is.
Look at that big old boy riding in.
Big old sheriff.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Let's hear it for him, just like I said.
Hip, hip, hooray!
- Hip, hip, hooray!
MEN: Hip, hip, hooray!
[GUNSHoT]
- Hip, hip, hooray!
- Hooray!
BRAND: Okay, now,
we're gonna make him welcome, right?
Just like old Uncle Frank taught you.
- Hip, hip, hooray!
Hip, hip, hooray!
Buenas tardes, jolly good fellow.
You're under arrest.
You know the charges.
BRAND: Oh, I don't wanna hear any more
of them dreadful lies.
What I wanna know is, just the hell
how are you gonna do anything about it?
I'm surrounded by my loving people.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, my eyes.
[WoMEN SCREAM]
BRAND:
Jacob, get the hell out of here.
Git, come on.
[KEYS RATTLING]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Father.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
KILPATRICK:
Jailer.
Jailer!
Drop the gun.
Open the door and be quick.
Come on. Open the bloody door.
Get in.
May... May God forgive you.
Why wouldn't he?
That's his business, isn't it?
GUTIERREZ:
I have made the blacksmith my deputy.
He does not have any English...
...but he understands
that if you try to get away...
...he is to kill you.
[GUNSHoT]
Goddamn,
I wish there was a bounty on sheriffs.
I wouldn't have to go around
risking my ass robbing banks...
...carrying on, I'd take it.
Well, now we can take our time.
Nice and easy.
Hold him there.
Thank you, Jacob.
Hey, listen.
What was that you said back there...
...what you was gonna spend
your money on?
You seem awfully interested
in my money, Mr. Brand.
I just care what happens to my friends.
Like Schoolboy, Choo Choo?
You know, one of these days, Jacob...
...that old sense of humor of yours
is gonna get you killed.
Git, come on.
Hah, hah, hah, hah!
CHoo CHoo:
Pretty rough going, huh?
What you need is a new pair of boots.
Real good ones, like the ones I got on.
Say, how much they paying you
for this anyway, huh?
You, amigo, how much dinero
they giving you...
...for taking me to San Ignacio, huh?
[BLACKSMITH SPEAKS
IN SPANISH]
CHoo CHoo: Why, that's terrible.
That's a goddamn disgrace.
How they expect you to buy all those
things we've been talking about, huh?
Like horses and boots and girls.
Hey. Hey, amigo.
When was the last time
you were laid, huh?
Well, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna treat you to a girl,
a real muchacha.
[GUNSHoTS IN DISTANCE]
[GUNSHoT]
[CRACKS]
KILPATRICK:
Where's Brand?
Don't shoot.
KILPATRICK: Where's Brand?
- San Jose.
- You're a liar.
- No, I'm not. It's San Jose.
[YELLS]
CHoo CHoo:
Help me, man. Help me.
For God's sake, help me.
- Where's Brand?
- San Jose.
- Why San Jose?
- He's got a girl there.
He's got a girl there.
I'm sorry about your kid.
[CHoo CHoo GRo ANS]
GUTIERREZ:
Kilpatrick.
Ki...
KILPATRICK:
Can you wrap this around you?
WoMAN: Bastard. You are a bastard.
BRAND: Get out of my way.
WoMAN:
Bastard.
Get it finished.
We're getting the hell out of here.
I'm not going.
Three aces and a pair, gentlemen.
What did you say, nigger?
I said, I'm not going.
Frank.
Frank?
Seems like everybody's stepping
over the line, don't it, Jacob?
I thought we was partners.
Wanna tell me why you wanna
break up a friendship?
You know that sheriff back
in San Ignacio?
Well, the fellas around here
say they didn't hang him.
He got away...
...and he's on our trail again.
But it's not me he's after,
it's you he wants.
So I figure if we split up,
it's your trail he'll follow, not mine.
Well, now...
...you're not gonna run out on me just
because of an old Texas sheriff, are you?
I sure hate to lose you, Jacob.
Me or my money?
[LAUGHS]
Well, shit.
I guess when you get real deep down to it,
it's the money.
All right.
I'll give you a chance
to win some of this money.
What'll it be?
Stud poker, draw poker or Find the Lady?
Whoa, now, Jacob...
...if I found you was cheating me at cards,
I'd have to up and kill you, Jacob.
Got a business deal for you, though.
Remember you was talking
about opening up a whorehouse?
- Give me a thousand dollars.
- What?
Give me a thousand dollars.
Jacob, you're gonna force me
to draw on you?
- What for?
- Come on. I'll show you.
KILPATRICK:
Now tell me you fell off your horse.
I assume there were no witnesses. Right?
How did you get out of jail?
It was a small miracle.
Tequila?
Sî, tequila.
There we go.
Easy.
- Oh, come on.
- Is enough.
Is enough.
It's good for internal too.
Well, I can see that you're all right.
Brand?
I don't know.
KILPATRICK:
How long ago?
Six, seven hours.
Well, let's get going.
I think I'll go back to San Ignacio.
See a doctor, huh?
You're coming with me.
If you think I'm gonna risk
you telling your Federales...
...and having them swarming
all over my neck, no, sir.
GUTIERREZ: Federales will be here
soon anyway, my friend.
Already my deputy is on his way
to Nuevo Magdalena with a prisoner.
He will bring the Federales.
You mean the man with the iron hand?
Well, you can forget about the Federales.
Because your deputy is dead.
The prisoner killed him?
KILPATRICK:
Yeah, very dead.
GUTIERREZ:
I made a mistake.
KILPATRICK: You made a mistake
not killing him in the first place.
I should have brought him in myself.
KILPATRICK:
Let's go.
Come on.
GUTIERREZ: Senor, if you force me
to watch you kill this man, Brand...
...I will hunt you down.
Of course.
What I am saying is the truth.
If necessary...
...I will kill you.
What are you doing here?
Where is Brand?
Shut up. Brand and I made a deal.
She's yours,
15 minutes for 10 pesos, amigo.
That leaves a long ways to go
for a thousand dollars.
[SCREAMING]
GUTIERREZ:
You know...
...I have heard many stories of you.
The sheriff of Santa Rosa...
...who carries no guns.
A man who can win...
...without killing.
KILPATRICK:
Well...
...if I wasn't such a man...
...my wife and child would be alive now.
GUTIERREZ:
One thing, senor...
...if it was not your wife and child
but somebody else's...
...would you be here now?
KILPATRICK:
That's one of their damned horses.
They're in there.
[CHATTERING IN DISTANCE]
[GUTIERREZ GRo ANS]
Shut up.
I hope one of you survives.
I hate to go back
to my village empty-handed, you know?
Looks bad.
KILPATRICK:
Put your hands behind your back.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
GUTIERREZ:
If you'll untie me, I could be of help.
[WoMAN SCREAMING]
Where's Brand?
Brand.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Where is he?
MARIA:
Hey, what the hell is this?
What do you want here?
What are you doing this for?
Get out of here. Get out.
- Where's Brand?
- I don't know where the hell he is.
What are you doing?
- Where is he? Where is he?
- I don't know.
Where's Brand?
- Where is he? Where is he?
- I don't know.
I don't...
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
GUTIERREZ:
Enough.
That's enough.
KILPATRICK:
He was here, wasn't he?
He was here.
Yes, he was here.
He came to see our daughter.
How long ago did he leave?
About an hour ago.
That's the first time I see him.
In five years,
that's the first time I see him.
Now suddenly, he comes back.
He expects to find things
the way he left them.
Our daughter...
...I put her in the convent.
What convent?
I couldn't be a whore
with a child in the same room.
What convent?
The one in Sierra victoria.
I know the nuns
will take good care of her.
Is that where he's gone?
Yeah.
You know where that is?
Thirty miles back, the way we come.
Thirty miles, let's go.
It's a long ride.
GUTIERREZ:
Put on your clothes.
You know, you did not have
to shoot him six times.
Five times.
If it bothers you...
...l'll pay for it.
Katherine!
He cannot see anything.
You take him to doctor,
but in the next village.
Are you all right?
KILPATRICK:
Yeah, just a little stunned.
Let's go. Come on. Let's go.
I'm all right. I'm all right, let's go.
Let's go.
I'm all right.
I'll be back.
Would you get me...?
Get me some water
on that cloth for me please.
Thank you.
Gutierrez?
Gutierrez.
Gutierrez!
Help me, somebody, quick.
Somebody help me, quick. Help me.
MARIA:
I am going to take you to the doctor.
Doctor?
Doctor? No. No, the convent.
The convent, take me to the convent.
No, I couldn't.
He'd kill me if I took you there. I can't.
Take me to that convent.
I'll pay you for the time it takes you
to get me there.
All right?
Okay?
Yes?
All of it.
The whole saddlebag.
It's a deal.
It's a deal. Come on. Come on.
KILPATRICK:
Somebody's there.
- I cannot see...
- Shh!
It is magistrado, your friend.
- Gutierrez?
- Hm.
Is Brand with him?
- I cannot see.
KILPATRICK: You're lying.
MARIA:
Don't shoot. You're gonna kill him, stop.
No! No.
Do not kill him. You cannot see.
No, don't shoot.
The man is an animal.
That's what he is, an animal.
GUTIERREZ:
Stop it.
If you are going to judge men...
...begin with that pig
who fathered your child.
[MARIA SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[GUTIERREZ SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Here.
It's hot.
I'm sorry I hit you last night.
You give me no choice.
Now that we're apologizing...
...I really wasn't shooting at you either.
This is obvious.
Your gun, you can now notch
with one tree...
...two cactus bush, a rock.
- It was that bad, huh?
- No, that good.
First time I see you laugh.
We sheriffs don't have too much
to laugh about.
GUTIERREZ:
Tell me, senor...
...how did you become a sheriff?
It's a long story.
I stop you when my cup is empty, huh?
I guess it began when I was a youngster.
My father was...
My father was shot by a sheriff.
He didn't do anything wrong,
he was just wanted...
...for some questions
they wanted to ask him.
But my father wasn't one
to be pushed around.
So he resisted...
...and he was shot.
That's why I decided
to become a sheriff.
I decided if there were gonna
be good laws...
...they had to be...
Had to be enforced...
...by men with some sense of justice.
That's what I used to believe.
We two, we could catch this Brand.
And bring him to justice.
Oh, no.
Not Mr. Brand.
That kind of justice.
I've seen too many guilty men
walk out of courts of law, free.
Scared jury, bribed judge...
...clever lawyer, free.
That's not gonna happen to Mr. Brand.
No, sir.
I'm very sorry for you.
My cup is empty.
We go.
The horse must rest.
We'll stop here.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Water.
It's hot.
Hey, what? What is...? What's go...?
I'm sorry, senor.
I had to prove to myself
that you are blind.
I put a scorpion in your water.
We're that close, huh?
Just over the next hill.
We go.
Drop the gun.
Come on.
Now, I'm going in there alone.
And don't follow me in.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
I don't wanna kill you.
And I believe you don't wanna kill me.
You know I'm right.
Listen.
KILPATRICK:
I don't need you anymore.
Take him back to Nuevo Magdalena.
There's your money.
BRAND: Since my wife died,
I've been out of the country on business.
I would've been down here every weekend
just visiting. You don't understand.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Least I can do.
You know, I consider your offering
very generous.
It ain't an offering like charity,
it's just that I'm grateful...
...that you're looking after my girl.
Well, but as you see,
our situation is not quite desperate.
As soon as I get myself settled
in a good old job...
...l'll be back and take her off your hand.
- There's the little girl.
Has she ever grown.
Bless you, Sister.
You just look how she's grown.
I didn't expect her to recognize me
because it's been quite a while.
Hey, Luisy.
Luisy?
Just your old daddy.
Ain't she something?
Are you crying? Come on.
You ain't afeared of your daddy.
Wanna give your old daddy a kiss?
Come on.
Just a little old kiss
for Daddy like you used to.
Come on.
Luisy?
You know something? She is beautiful.
About the prettiest kid I ever...
[CHATTERING]
[GUNSHoTS]
You can't keep running away!
Do you hear me?
Brand?
[LUISY SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Brand!
I've got something here
that belongs to you.
Do you hear me?
Now, I'm coming out.
And I'm giving you...
...10 seconds to come out,
now, do you hear me?
One...
...two...
...three...
...four...
...five, six...
[LUISY CRYING]
...seven.
Take the money!
I got more hid!
You can take it all!
Eight...
...nine.
Don't!
LUISY:
Mommy.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
You were right.
Maybe I was not so right, senor.
What?
My witness is dead.
I have no other evidence.
I cannot hold him.
You...
You mean, you're gonna set him free?
That is the law.
KILPATRICK:
Did you hear that, Mr. Brand?
You're free.
You're free because the law says so.
BRAND:
Don't that beat all?
An innocent man, innocent.
You've been dragging me
halfway across Mexico.
Disgusting.
Ain't that so, big fella?
Well, now, look who we got back there.
I'll see you after.
Gonna have me a nice long walk.
I'm gonna get me a nice long drink.
You wanna join me?
To show there's no hard feelings?
Come on, big fella.
Tell them all. Tell them all in Mex.
Tell them the tequila's on Mr...
You are under arrest.
Kilpatrick!
Stop...
...or I'll shoot.
Subripped by: Tantico (Croatia)