(Theme song begins)
Chorus: "Look at those horses,
what are they draggin'?
"Heavily guarded,
what is that wagon?
"War Wagon, what is it for?
War Wagon, loaded with gold"
Most men are fightin' for a wagon full of gold
Scratchin' an' fightin' for a wagon full of gold
A piece of land, my cattle brand,
a place to rest my head
The feelin' of a woman's love are all you really need for livin'
Three years in prison made me
dream a lot of dreams
Sometimes a dream is not
as easy as it seems
But wrong or right I have to fight,
'cause when the truth is told
All men are fightin' for a wagon full of gold
Chorus: "Look at those horses,
what are they draggin'?
"Heavily guarded,
what is that wagon?"
Most men are fightin' for
a wagon full of gold
Scratchin' an' fightin' for
A piece of land, my cattle brand,
a place to rest my head
The feelin' of a woman's love are
all you really need for livin'
Chorus: "Look at those horses, what are they draggin'?"
Three years in prison made me
dream a lot of dreams
Sometimes a dream is not
as easy as it seems
But wrong or right I have to fight,
'cause when the truth is told
All men are fightin' for, a-strugglin' for,
a-searchin' for, a-strivin' for...
a wagon full of gooooooold!!!
Sheriff,
Taw Jackson's back in town.
Are you sure?
He's ridin' down the street right now,
big as life.
Goin' huntin'?
Don't do anything real fast now, Taw.
You fellas seem real jumpy.
- How'd you get out?
- Parole.
What. after only three years?
Good behavior.
This paper says I have to report in to
the local law officer wherever I am.
Check-in day is every Monday.
Figurin' on stickin' around, are you?
For a while.
- Your old spread belongs to Mr Pierce now.
- I heard that.
It's his legally, he doesn't want trespassers,
so you stay off it.
Oh, I'll sure do that.
Maybe prison
took some of the starch out of you.
Maybe.
- Where's Lomax?
- In Randado. The Oriental Palace.
- Billy Hyatt's in Chubisco.
- Levi?
He's down by Mesquite,
with Calita's gang.
- What about the shipment?
- The big one's four days from now.
Doesn't give us much time.
Nope.
Put back that salt.
The salt!
Pierce catches you stealin' now,
you won't be worth a damn to me.
- Mr Pierce.
- Did it get here yet?
No, not yet. But it will be here in time the trip after next.
That's when we want her.
Alright, let's clean her up.
- Check the rim on the left front wheel.
- Yes, sir.
Beauty!
Mr Pierce,
Taw Jackson's in town.
What?
He's out on parole.
- Where is he?
- I don't know, I haven't seen him since this morning.
You mean you let him go?
Don't you know he could take a shot at Mr Pierce.
Get Hammond and Brown.
You think he'll try somethin'?
Wouldn't you?
Mr. Pierce.
Get fresh horses.
I want you in Randado before sun-up.
Find Lomax.
I want him to kill Taw Jackson.
I'll pay him anything he wants.
You'll pay him anything, sir?
I'll go for 10,000.
Hell, Mr Pierce, we'd be willin' to do it for
a lot less than $10,000.
If you could. Lomax is the one man
that can, so get movin'.
Yes, sir.
Boss, you know the way they feel
about each other.
Lomax would probably ride all the way
over here to kill him for nothin'.
Unless there's money in it,
Lomax'll ain't gonna do nothin' for nothin'.
And I want Taw Jackson dead.
- What'll ya have?
- Whiskey.
I understand, ah...
Lomax is around.
So?
- I wanna see him.
- Yeah, and who are you?
Taw Jackson.
Enjoy you're drink.
It'll be your last.
Well, that'd be a shame.
Kinda hoped
that my last drink'd be a big one.
Bottle's in front of you. Pour all you want.
- Gonna shoot me in the back?
- You deserve it.
- You caused me a lot of embarrassment.
- How?
You're the only man I ever shot,
and didn't kill.
Well, if it makes you feel any better,
that slug you put in me
kept me in hospital for six months.
(Gunshot)
Lomax.
What made you think
I wouldn't kill you?
Curiosity.
Well, you're still alive.
Now what's to keep you that way?
- Money.
- How much?
Your share'll be over 100,000.
That's what I've always said
the world needs:
More simple understanding to bring
people together. Lhotse! Khaloo!
- Yeah, we can talk upstairs.
- What I have to say is private.
Can't get more private. Neither one
of them speaks a word of English. C'mon.
Come on in!
God, I hope this meeting will be friendlier
than the one 3 years ago.
Taw: Couldn't be much unfriendlier.
Do you know why Pierce
wants you to kill me?
So he could legally steal your land,
once he found there was gold on it.
You were a hard working ranch hand
just defending your property.
But you got shot, framed,
and sent to jail.
I always thought that was kind of amusing.
Nice to find a fella
with a keen sense of humor.
Old Pierce
found a lotta gold on your land.
That ore assays out
at $643 a tonne, normally.
But they've hit the mother lode,
which'll be 1,200 per cent richer.
Until the lode runs out.
For a man out a short while you know
a lot about Mr. Peirce's business.
- He's important to me.
- You thinkin' about his gold?
- My gold.
- Forget it.
In town or at the mine, you can't get
within a mile of it. Have some grub.
No thanks.
How about outta town?
I guess you don't know about his new toy.
A little iron-plated thing
he calls the "War Wagon".
Takes an average of 50,000 in gold
from Emmett to the rail head in El Paso.
- Forty-three and half miles away.
- There are a few guards.
Thirty-three of them. Twenty-eight
outriders, and five in the coach.
Each man is armed with a Henry repeating rifle,
two Colts and 200 rounds ammunition.
- What's all of this got to do with me?
- We're going to take that wagon.
We are?
You taken a look lately
at the cemetery at Emmett?
There's a big bunch of cheap wooden crosses,
in one corner, all crowded in together.
That's a tribute to the last fools
who tried to stop the War Wagon.
You like facts? $1.15 for the casket,
and 12 cents for the crosses.
Pierce foots the bill.
$1.27 seems a poor price to pay
for a man's life, especially mine.
In four days, Pierce is going to make
the biggest gold shipment...
ever made out of the territory.
A half a million dollars.
A half a million? How we gonna
take it, with the Prussian army?
With three other fellows.
Five of us.
Five? I'm kinda glad I didn't
kill you tonight. You're funny as hell.
- Wanna hear how?
- How we end up in jail or on the run?
- Not if we do it my way.
- No chance.
$100,000, Lomax, that's your share.
You're ready to listen?
- Why me?
- You're good with guns.
Besides, you're the only safe cracker I know.
- How'd you ever find that out?
- An old friend of yours in prison.
For the last time,
are you gonna listen?
Alright.
Let's hear it.
Stony Flats.
The War Wagon.
(Rooster crows)
(Knock on door)
Yeah!
- One condition.
- What's that?
My time till the robbery costs $100
a day, and if I fire my gun $500.
Haven't got that kind of money.
I'll take a marker against
your share of the gold.
Deal.
You always wear a gun
over your underwear?
Just lately.
(Church bell ringing)
- Morning, Mr Lomax.
- Hello, Smitty.
You want I should saddle your horse for ya?
Please.
Your in the third stall on the left.
(Dog barking)
There he is.
- Lomax!
- Morning, Lomax.
What do ya want?
- Mr Pierce would like to talk to you.
- What for?
It's about Taw Jackson.
What about Taw Jackson?
Well, Mr Pierce said he'll go
all the way up to 10,000 dollars.
- Hey, Taw, you hear that?
Taw: I heard.
You're worth a lot of money.
Dead.
Taw, this wasn't our idea at all. We're just
deliverin' a message for Mr. Pierce, that's all.
Yeah.
What's your answer?
Tell him that I'm interested in his offer,
and I'll be thinking about it.
Yes, sir, we sure will.
Come on.
- The boss ain't gonna like that answer.
- I know it.
Why don't we do it?
That would make Mr Pierce
very grateful to us.
Ain't no better time!
Now!
Mine hit the ground first.
Mine was taller.
Yes, sir,
a good way to start our partnership.
- How's that?
- A $500 day.
- I didn't ask for your help back there.
- Well, I can't afford to let you get killed...
unless I do it.
- Hey, why are we headed south?
- To pick up Levi Walking Bear.
- Levi who?
- Walking Bear.
He's running with Calita's gang,
down on the border.
- Pretty rough outfit.
- Yeah. Well, we need him.
He's worth 100,000 dollars to ya.
Ninety.
Taw: Buenos días.
- Buenos días.
(In Spanish):
Whose pigs are these?
Yours?
Fine.
Information?
- Buenos días, Señorita.
- Welcome, Señor. Tequila?
Sure.
Thank you.
Salud!
- You're a pretty little girl.
- Little girl?
Well, you're not a little boy.
Where's Calita's camp?
Don't know.
Are you sure?
Well, then.
How about a drink?
A little one.
That's good!
Gracias, Señor.
- Where did you get that?
- I sleep on this ring.
Yes, every night like this.
For the tequila.
- Do you not want anything else?
- Later.
- Let's go.
- Go where?
Calita's. Third canyon south,
two miles up.
You have to appeal to their intellect.
(Gunfire in the distance)
Let me guess which one's your friend.
Hey, don't shoot!
- Well...
- Yeah.
Yah!
Come on. Yah!
Those gallon jugs are only trash,
shoot them up!
Hey!
Hey, comrades! Ready?
- Who the hell are you?
- Shut up. Don't drop your arm.
What?
- Where ya goin'?
- Another target.
Get outta here!
My horses! Where are my horses?
Looks like we made it.
Thanks, Taw. You might say I owe
you fellas my life.
Yeah, yuh might.
Lomax,
Levi Walking Bear.
- So you're Lomax.
- What was that all about back there?
- We were playin' poker.
- So?
I was cheatin'.
- Hey, you got a bargain, big man.
- How's that?
Two $500 days for the price of one.
Thanks.
Hey! Why'd you stick your necks out for me?
We got a job for yuh.
Lomax, I want you to swing over to Chubisco.
- Chubisco?
Pick up a kid named Billy Hyatt
and bring him out to the old mission.
Sure hate being away from yuh.
I'm afraid that's how it's
gonna have to be.
Don't let anything happen to yuh.
Not likely.
A beautiful thing to see.
Friendship.
Yeah.
You seen a fella around here
named "Billy Hyatt"?
Yeah.
- Where?
- There.
Uh!
Billy Hyatt?
What are ya doin'?
- You Billy Hyatt?
- Yeah.
Stand up.
- I can't even sit up.
- Come on now, I said stand up!
I'm doin' ma best.
- Got a horse?
- Huh?
- Have yuh got a horse?
- No.
Come on.
I ain't goin' no place.
Let me alone.
Billy: Let me off, Mister.
- Not yet, sonny.
- My head's splittin'.
Yuh stink!
Tell me kid, what are you good for?
- Good for?
- You heard me.
- Nothin'. I'm good for nothin'.
- I believe it. Taw must be loco.
- Taw Jackson? Is he out?
- We're on our way to join him.
Doggone! Me and him spent two years
in prison together.
Heart-warming.
- That means Taw must be ready to...
- Yes?
A thing we talked about.
Listen, mister, this has gone
far enough. Let me down.
I will, sonny, I will.
What'd you do that for?
You share my horse,
I want you sober.
And cleaner.
You can walk yourself dry.
Who's that?
- The War Wagon.
- So that's it.
Mister?
- You in with Taw?
- More or less.
Then I reckon I can tell you
what I'm good for. Explosives.
Explosives?
- Hammond and Brown get back?
- No, Sir.
What about Lomax?
Lomax? Not again.
Hello, Jackson.
It's Monday morning,
and I'm reporting in.
That's no concern of mine.
Why don't you tell the deputy here,
or the sheriff.
- Same thing, you own 'em.
- Alright, Taw, you're duly reported in.
- I understand you're stayin' on at my ranch.
- What used to be your ranch.
Why not? It's the nicest place around.
- I oughta know. I built it.
- And you did a real fine job.
- I'll be out there one day this week.
- Thinkin' of tryin' to get it back?
- Think about it all the time.
- You wouldn't stand a chance.
Tell you what I'll do for you, though.
I'll see that you get buried on that land.
Between then and now, I'm comin' out
to pick up my personal possessions.
Are they still there?
- How would I know?
- They all disappeared, somehow.
- Ain't nothin' there belongs to you.
This man's wearin' my gun.
You're mixed up about that.
My Pa gave me this when I was a kid.
If you want it back, Taw,
why don't you just take it away from him.
It's mine.
- What's goin' on?
- Just collectin' somethin' that belongs to me.
- Who started it?
- Well sheriff, I guess you could say, I did.
The shells in here belong to him.
You tell him, he can come and get them,
anytime.
Throw some water on 'em.
(Horse neighs)
Taw!
I heard.
- Hey, Taw!
- Hello, Billy.
How ya keepin'?
- You look worse than you did
when you were in jail.
Ah, nothin' a drink wouldn't fix.
- Got anything?
- He's a drunk.
He drinks.
Way he's been shakin', I wouldn't
trust him with a firecracker.
- Is that true, Billy?
- I reckon, some folks look at it that way.
But I'm alright, Taw. I can handle my end.
- There's a lot at stake here, Billy.
- I can handle it.
- Good enough.
- I don't trust drunks.
Neither do I. But Billy stays here.
And there's nothing around this place stronger
than that cowboy coffee you're drinkin'.
You're sure he knows explosives, huh?
He handles them like you do a gun.
Hope you know what you're doin'.
In the distance: "Hayah!
Hayah!
That'll be Wes.
Come on, come on.
- Sit down!
- Wes.
- What's she doing here?
- She goes every place I go.
Lomax, this is Fletcher.
He's going to haul the gold away.
- Why him?
- I work for Pierce.
Ain't nobody figurin' on finding half a million
in gold Pierce's own flour barrel.
Half a million?
When do we split it up?
Wouldn't be too smart to flash gold
around right after the robbery.
Lomax: Maybe we should wait about six months.
- Six months?
Let's don't spend it before we get it.
Keep your eyes off my wife!
- Your wife? I thought she was your daughter.
Well, she ain't!
- Billy!
- You keep away from her!
- A drunk kid and a crazy old man!
How the hell...
Cut it out, all of ya!
I didn't bring you here to be the best
of friends. We've got a lot of things  to do,
and only three days to do it in.
Come on over here.
This map shows the run
from Emmett to El Paso.
First thing in the morning, Billy, I want you
to ride it, and check these two places.
Find out how much dynamite
you're gonna need.
The wagon takes five and a half
minutes to cross Stony Flats.
That's where we'll hit it first.
- Well, see ya later, partner.
- Where you goin'?
To town.
- I've got another business associate there, remember?
- I remember.
We wouldn't want him to be impatient,
would we?
And hire somebody else.
Take good care of him.
Levi...
Let us pass!
Alright.
We walk from here.
Dumb Indians!
- Looks like they're getting ready to move out.
- They are.
Squaws, old men, children.
Pierce has starved them out.
He'll have all the land, now.
- What about Wild Horse?
- Him and the warriors are staying.
Pierce'll hunt him down too.
Dumb Indians!
And you're smart?
Sure! Cause I've learned to live in the
white man's world. Do what they do.
Grab all you can, anytime you can.
Wait here.
(Horse neighs)
- Your enemy is my enemy.
- Taw!
- Chief Wild Horse, Natani Jackson.
- Too many warriors have died.
- He says, "Your enemy is his enemy."
- Good.
No. He says he will lose
too many braves.
Ask him does he ride
with warriors or women.
If you want my tribe
and my warriors, I will do it.
He will do it, but he wants more
of everything.
He does or you do?
- Bargain with him.
- What exactly do you want?
He wants 600 bullets.
20 rifles.
A dozen blankets.
And 30 pounds of salt.
Tell him he drives a hard bargain.
But we'll agree.
You can stay.
But the white man must go.
It is done. And he wants me to stay
for dinner, but you're not welcome.
Having a white man in his camp offends him.
- You can tell him...
- What?
Nothing.
- Three sixes.
Player: Beats me.
Hello, Lola.
It's been a long time, Lomax.
- May I join you?
- Sure.
It looks like you're still a winner.
I lose every once in a while.
How's your laundry service?
- Oh, they can't even speak English.
- A pity.
Any limit?
If there was, you wouldn't play.
- Fifty.
Player 1: I'm out.
- Lola!
- Hello, Mr Pierce.
Player 2: Too rich for me.
- Two cards.
- You get my message?
Yeah.
- Took you long enough to get here.
- I had things to do.
Those two men I sent for you,
what happened to them?
I last saw them in the main street
in Randado. Three ladies.
You win, precious.
- Let's go someplace private.
- I like it here.
Hey, bartender, how much you get
for whiskey around here?
Two bits.
That's two cents.
- You gonna give me an answer or not?
- I'm thinkin' about it.
- How much is that?
- 27 cents.
Set it right there.
- Keep the change.
- Thanks.
I'll go twelve thousand.
Twelve?
I changed my mind about the tip.
Give me another two cents' worth!
Go out and walk it off.
Listen, I figure on bein'
an important person some day.
You wanna think about treatin' me right.
Oh, I will, I will.
- What do yuh say?
- I'm still thinking about it.
- Come on, bartender.
- Not for two cents. No.
But I done told you,
me and my friends, we're gonna be rich!
Sure. Well, come back then.
Hello there, cowboy.
You havin' trouble gettin' a drink?
I'm gonna buy this... hey!
What's goin' on down there?
Sheriff, this drunk just insulted the lady.
Lock him up till he sleeps it off.
- What'd he do?
- You didn't notice?
- No.
- You been workin' saloons too long.
- What'd you do that for?
- I hate bad manners.
My deal?
Look, I'm gettin' tired of this run-around.
Just give me a yes or no
on the twelve thousand?
Yes.
And I want it done quick.
- Don't push me. I'll do it when I'm ready!
What's your pleasure?
Stud.
What room is Señor Lomax in?
Five, Señor.
Five?
- Who's there?
Taw: It's me.
We may be in some trouble. Billy's missing...
- He's in jail.
- Jail?
- Drunk.
Why that miserable...
Do you know how close he came to naming
all his soon to be rich friends to the whole town?
No.
That close.
Well,  I'll guarantee that
he'll never take another drop.
You'll guarantee that when he
gets his shaky hands...
on some dynamite he won't
blow us all sky high?
- As far as his work goes,
he knows what he's doin'.
I don't care what he knows.
I've stayed alive this long
by what I know.
And that is not to rely on anybody.
I always go it alone.
Precious?
Always?
Is anything wrong?
No, baby.
You just straighten out that kid.
You know Pierce upped the ante on you.
You're worth 12,000 to me. Dead.
And 100,000 alive.
One's a gamble. Other's a sure thing.
Lomax, nothin's a sure thing.
Precious?
Well, I didn't feel much like shootin' you
this morning anyway, partner.
Neither did I... "Precious".
Hey!
I haven't got time
to tell you what's on my mind.
Get out to Wes's place, and wait for me.
Supposed to meet Taw here.
How's your hand?
- I said, how's your hand.
- Fine.
Wes is due back any time.
You best wait in the house.
- Don't he let you talk to anybody?
- To nobody.
Reckon you can talk to me, then.
I'm nobody.
- How old are yuh?
- Eighteen, I think.
Me too... far as I know.
Say...
how come you're married to Wes?
I ain't, really. He bartered me.
Bartered yuh?
Folks traded me for twenty dollars
and a horse. They's poor.
I'd call that a lot worse than poor.
Ain't much never mind.
About same here as it was with them.
- Do your work and keep your mouth shut.
- Twenty dollars and a horse.
Seems to me you're worth...
a little more than that.
How come you're in on this stealin'?
For the money.
I'm gonna have me 100,000 dollars.
That'll make me a very important person.
Why?
'Cause it will.
(Fletcher arriving):
Yah! Yah! Yah! Yah!
Get up, mule! Ya! Whoa.
- What are you doin' here?
- Taw told me to meet him here.
- Did he tell you to hang around my wife?
What'd ya expect me to do?
Wait up on top of the mountain, someplace?
Don't sass me, boy.
Girl: He ain't done nothin'.
Will you get back to work! Go on!
Leave her alone!
- Come on, boy.
- Fletcher! Put it away.
Come here, Billy.
Billy,
from now on...
you're not going to say a word,
you're not gonna make a move, unless I tell yuh.
You get that?
You go over the route?
- Yeah.
What are yuh gonna need?
First, I gotta know, how long is the war wagon,
from the lead horse back end?
Forty-seven and a half feet.
Then, I'll need about 500 feet of two-ounce
hemp twine, four bottles of gin...
Gin?
You said time is the most important thing,
didn't yuh?
That's right.
So then I ain't figuring on dynamite.
Fuses don't burn that dependable.
- What are you figurin' on?
- Nitroglycerin.
Nitro?
- Wes!
- Yeah.
He's figurin' on usin' nitroglycerin.
You know where there is any?
Yeah, Pierce has got some,
he uses it at the mine.
- Where does he keep it?
- At your ranch, in a safe.
- In a safe? You know the combination?
-No.
Let me show yuh somethin'.
Ever see a shell like this before?
Yeah.
Well, I took in 10,000 rounds
to Pierce last week.
A Gatling gun.
Whiskey.
Mr. Pierce?
I just seen Taw Jackson go in the
Lucky Deuce, and Lomax is in there.
Get the sheriff.
I want this whole thing to be legal.
Bartender, set 'em up on me.
I buy my own.
You refusing my hospitality?
I'm ignoring it.
Well, I take that as an insult.
You take it any way you want.
Whiskey!
I said, whiskey!
- We don't serve Indians.
- Then I serve myself.
- Have one with me.
- Sure.
No thanks!
- You too good to drink with Indian?
- That's right.
Fight!
(Woman screaming)
Oh!
(More screaming)
Uh!
Oh no!
("Oh, Suzanna" begins playing on piano)
Aaaaaaaaaahhhhhhhh!!!!!!!!!!!
Oaf!
- You might say I saved your life.
- Yeah!
- What you do that for?
- Get the horses!
Pierce! I'm the one you hired
to kill Taw Jackson.
You trying go back on your deal?
Why didn't you shoot him
when you had the chance?
What chance?
He never went for his gun.
- What are yuh gonna' do?
- I'm goin' after him.
Lomax!
What sort of stupid stunt was that,
walking into the saloon that way.
- We need you tonight.
- I wasn't suppose to join till morning.
The plans have changed. The kid wants to use nitro.
- Nitroglycerin?
- Which is in a safe you'll have to open.
Forget it! I'm not gonna be anywhere
near that drunk kid and nitro.
Lomax, that cut's it!
Nobody takes a half a million sittin'
on their backside.
Either you quit acting like a prima donna,
or we call the whole thing off.
- Alright. It'll cost ya 2,000 more,
your share.
- Not my end, it won't.
- Then let's forget it.
You can have 2,000 of mine.
- You're a good Indian.
- Alright, Levi.
Go pick up Wild Horse.
We'll get the kid.
Hey, Taw.
For a minute back there at the saloon,
I thought you were gonna draw.
For a minute back there,
I was.
It'll be that shack on the left.
What a place.
Yeah.
Well, might as well relax till dark.
Nitroglycerin!
Don't!
You got five minutes.
Get goin'.
- That you, Frenchy?
- Yeah.
- What's up?
- You want a cup of coffee.
"I want a cup of coffee."
Yeah, me too.
Just leave it,
right there.
Sure you know what you're doin'?
That's far enough.
You two get over in the corner.
Now, Shack, get rid of that gun,
nice and easy.
What are you doin' here?
Just visitin'.
- And I've gotta give you credit.
- For what?
For your good taste.
You haven't changed a thing.
- What do you want?
- My belongings.
- Everything in here belongs to me.
- How about my clothes?
- I burned them.
- Even those in the attic, in the trunk?
- There's nothin' up there but an old pair...
- Why don't you go get it?
- We'll wait here.
- Do what the man says.
Just exactly!
Yes, sir.
It could take a little time.
Why don't you make yourself comfortable?
I'm comfortable.
Well?
Yeah.
Careful!
- Does it always smoke like that?
- Huh?
Does it always smoke like that?
Yeah.
- These what you mean?
- That's it.
- You'd risk your neck for those rags?
- Whose neck?
We've got two minutes.
Get going.
- Thanks for your hospitality.
- Glad you got what you came for.
So am I.
Oh, ah...
Don't anybody get too anxious
to go out this door.
Well, don't stand there,
go get him.
Yes, Sir.
Come on!
Bunkhouse!
It's Taw Jackson. Get him!
- Where are they goin'?
- Pierce has run 'em out.
All except Wild Horse.
Bring her on out!
- That's really something, Mr Pierce.
- She's practically a piece of heavy artillery.
- Alright, load her up and let's get moving.
- Yes, sir.
Load her up!
- Everything set with Wild Horse?
- He's on his way.
It's that time.
- Come on!
- Yeah.
- Hold it steady.
- I'm tryin'.
- How hot's it get around here?
- Ninety, ninety-five. Sometimes more.
You better get me a canteen, then,
so as I can water them down a little.
Yeah.
- You need any more help?
- I can rig the twine.
- I'll just wet 'em down once more.
- I'll see ya later.
I got it.
- It's the next ravine, Wes.
- Right.
- We're running a little late.
- It's that extra weight, Mr Pierce.
- How's it going?
- I'll be ready.
- What's that?
- The Kiowa tribe.
Pierce has got 'em beat.
They're moving out.
Look's like
Wild Horse's men are ready.
You think he's gonna fall
for that old dust routine?
You better hope so.
You got 100,000 ridin' on it.
- Mr Pierce!
- Yeah?
We're bein' followed.
Looks like the whole Kiowa tribe.
Have the riders drop back!
Everybody pull back!
Hold it!
Let's get back to the wagon.
- Well.
- Yeah.
- What's goin' on back there?
- I don't know, Mr Pierce.
But it looks like the boys
are comin' back.
Indians don't blow up bridges.
Knock on it!
- There's a crossing upriver.
- That's about three miles away.
We got no choice.
Let's go.
Mr Pierce!
Look!
Gimme a hand here.
That oughta hold 'em.
Let's go.
We're goin' the wrong way.
Here they come.
We're on the wrong road.
What the hell...
Let's get out of here!
- You're hired to guard this gold.
- Not me!
- He's right, Mr Pierce.
- You too?
I'm gonna dump it in this gulch!
Jump!
Look like you'll get your ranch back.
Get those barrel tops off.
That looks mighty pretty.
Alright, give me a hand.
Taw, that's the last of it.
Well, get goin'.
Take it easy.
Taw!
Yatahay!
He says to keep our hands
away from our guns.
Dirty, double-crossin'...
You leave that be!
Know what you're always sayin' about me?
Yeah, if we're all gonna die,
let's have one last drink.
- Is that...?
- Yep!
After you, Taw.
Don't mind if I do.
Get that wagon!
Indian expert!
Yah!
Hyah!
They're picking us clean.
Why didn't you stop them?
Well, just how do I go about that?
I'm afraid Taw's right, Lomax.
They'll fight you.
- Shut up, you Indian!
- I know my people.
- To them it's flour.
- What about the gold?
- For all they know, it's just food.
- Great, just great!
I'm out 100,000, my share and 2,000 from Levi.
Where are you goin'?
Back to my people.
And what am I supposed to do? Live with the
Indians for the next year and open up a bakery?
With Pierce dead, it don't even pay
to kill you any more.
Wait a minute...
You owe me $100 a day and plus 500
when I used my gun. That's $1,200.
I'm calling in your mark.
- Now?
- Now!
I haven't got that kind of money.
The only thing I own is standing right there.
- I'll take it.
- My horse?
You're damn right.
You'd leave me out here, 30 miles from nowhere,
without a horse? Penniless?
That's your problem, partner.
What happened?
Well, we lost part of it.
Toss me those saddlebags.
We'll still meet...
in six months and divide it.
But in the meantime,
you'll have to have something to live on.
- Be careful where you spend it.
- We will.
Thanks, Taw.
Billy!
When you catch up with Lomax,
tell him where you got it.
- He's gonna be mad.
- Yeah.
- How much? And what did you do with it?
- 100,000. I hid it.
Where?
- I'll let you know in about six months.
- Six months!
- I want it now.
- It wouldn't be very smart...
to start flashing gold dust around
right after a robbery, would it?
- What am I supposed to do till then?
- Well for one thing...
you better
make damn sure I stay alive.
- Thats a 24-hour-a-day job.
- That's your problem, partner.