[ Man ] Fire!
Aaah!
[ Grunts ]
[ Horse Neighing ]
[ Grunts, Groans ]
Bugler, sound recall!
[ Man Approaching On Horse ]
It's over!
Corporal Clemens, sir, from
Masters' Brigade at Dante's Crossroads!
Who gave you permission to come
ridin' across the face of my
command yellin' like a fool?
- Have you got a message for me
from General Masters?
- Yes, sir.
- Deliver it!
- That's it, sir!
- The war is over!
- [ Men Cheering ]
Lee surrendered to General Grant
in Virginia-- a place
called Appomattox Courthouse!
- When?
- Three days ago, sir!
[ Cheering Continues ]
Three days, huh?
General Masters just got word
himself, Colonel Thomas!
Our wires were down!
With your permission, sir!
Rig up a flag of truce,
Blue Boy!
- Short Grub?
- Yo!
Let's go!
I be a sergeant, sir!
Can I be of any service to y'all?
I'd like to talk
to your commanding officer!
Who be givin' orders today,Jim?
Yes, sir?
Major!!!
I've just received word that Lee
surrendered to Grant three days ago!
- Yes, sir!
- You knew it?
We received the news yesterday!
I don't think you understand,
Major! The war is over!
No, sir!
Are you telling me that
you intend to keep fighting?
- Haven't we just proven it?
- But why?
Because this is our land,
and you're on it!
We're all Americans!
Yes, sir! That's always been
the saddest part of it!
- Good day, sir!
- Colonel.
Thank you for your courtesy!
Damn!
Come on!
- Captain Anderson!
- Here, sir!
General Robert E! Lee
surrendered! Am I right?
Yes, sir!
That means that officially we
no longer exist as an armed body,
yet everywhere I look here
today I see armed men!!!
wearing uniforms
and flying the battle flag!
- Get it down!
- Yes, sir!
Jamison!
Yes, sir?
- Take down the flag!
- Yes, sir!
All right, people,
now listen to me, all of you!
We have about 2,000 miles to go!
Seven hundred of them are between
here and the Mexican border!!!
and through a Yankee
occupation army!
We are not gonna give the lowliest
blue belly we meet along the way!!!
any reason to suspect we're anything
but a band ofhomeless pilgrims.
Until we cross the Rio Grande,
arms and ammunition will remain
in the bottom of the wagons!
You men pack those uniforms away
and wear regular clothing.
The poorer looking, the better.
Now, once across the border,
we still have another 500 miles to go!!!
before we reach
a town called Durango!
There we will be met by representatives
of Emperor Maximilian!!!
who will escort us to Mexico City!
- Captain Anderson!
- Sir?
- We leave at midnight!
- Yes, sir!
[ Soldiers Singing ]
¶Hurrah, boys, hurrah ¶
¶Down with the traitor
Up with the star ¶
¶ Oh, we'll rally
'round the flag, boys ¶
¶ We'll rally once again ¶
¶Shouting the battle cry
of freedom ¶
¶ We will rally from the hillside ¶
¶ We'll gather from the plain ¶
¶Shouting the battle cry
of freedom ¶
¶ The Union forever
Hurrah, boys, hurrah ¶
¶ Down with the traitor
Up with the star ¶
¶ While we rally
'round the flag, boys ¶
¶ Rally once again ¶
¶ Shouting the battle cry
of freedom ¶
- ¶¶ [ Union Song Continues ]
- ¶ I wish I was in the land of cotton ¶
¶ Old times there
were not forgotten ¶
¶ Look away, look away
Look away, Dixie Land ¶
¶ In Dixie Land where I was born ¶
¶ Early on one frosty mornin'
Look away, look away ¶
¶ Look away, Dixie Land ¶
¶ I wish I was in Dixie
Hooray, hooray ¶
¶In Dixie Land
I'll take my stand ¶
¶ To live and die in Dixie ¶
¶Away, away
Away down south in Dixie ¶
Away down south in Dixie ¶¶
Whoa!
Ah, Mrs! Langdon!
My name is Benedict!
Thad Benedict, late of Pittsburgh,
but now of Natchez!
This here's my partner,
Jimmy Collins!
Word's goin' around,
Mrs! Langdon,
that you people are of a mind
to put your place up for sale!
- Is that right?
- I beg your pardon, sir,
but I'm the sister-in-law!
I believe you want to speak
to Mrs!James Langdon!
Ah, Mrs!James Langdon!
Thad Benedict is my name!
I was just telling your sister-in-law
here we heard the place is up for sale!
- Is that right?
- No, that is not right, Mr! Benedict!
Aw, come on, ladies, we've come
all the way from Natchez!!!
just to make you people
a handsome offer.
Mind if I get down?
Yes, she does.
And so do I.
My father restin' over there--
he minds too!
Well, well, well, well!
You must be Colonel Langdon!
James Langdon?
Well, uh, Colonel,
I'm here to do you a favor!
Well, let's see now!
Uh!!! Langdon Hall Plantation!
Ah, yes, here it is!
Fifteen hundred acres!
Is that right?
Six hundred acres bottomland,
four hundred in pasture
and five hundred in woods!
Two streams, three ponds with
a two-and-a-half mile riverfront!
[ Chuckles ]
Nice place!
Thank you kindly!
I imagine the house could use
a little work, though, huh?
It could stand it!
Yeah! Well, I'll just
have a look inside!
We just swept the floor,
Mr! Benedict!
You understand?
I'll give you 50 cents an acre!
That's my top offer!
You buzzards, you come down here lookin'
to get fat on the misfortune of others!
This house is not for sale!
Not now, not next year,
not ever!
- Colonel, we are businessmen!
- You're trash!
Well, well! You're a right
plain-talkin' gentleman, ain't you?
You hear what the man
said,Jimmy? Trash!
All right, who's
gonna pick your cotton,
and who's gonna plow up
all that bottomland out there?
And who's gonna chop
the wood when it gets cold?
Now, now,Jimmy! No need
to get uppity with the colonel!
Sixty cents an acre!
Take it or leave it!
-Just like that, huh?
-Just like that!
If I was you,
I'd grab it!
We're gonna get it
anyway, you know!
We'll get the house and every last acre
of land when they put it up for taxes!
Oh, I see!
And, uh, how do you know it will
be put up for taxes, Mr! Benedict?
You went busted outfittin'
that rebel regiment of yours!
Now, what do you say?
Sixty cents!!! or nothin'!
[ Horse Neighing ]
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
[ Whooping Continues ]
This belonged to
Granddaddy Langdon, Horace!
I think maybe
he'd want you to have it!
Thank you, sir!
- Little George!
- Yes, sir?
- Bring along that anvil and
as many tools as you can carry!
- Yes, sir!
Colonel, anybody goin' with us
talk that there Mexican?
Why don't you
stop lookin' at me?
I can't, Charlotte!
I just can't
keep my eyes off you!
Well, you make me uneasy,
Bubba Wilkes, so stop it!
You know, I've asked you a dozen times
to marry me, and you've never answered!
I'm too young to marry!
No girl who looks the way you do
is too young to marry!
Well, I am! If you don't
believe me, you can ask my daddy!
Ask your daddy! Your daddy knows there's
no man better suited to marry you--
Charlotte.
Maybe you'd better go on up
to the house and help your mother!
- You're a good junior officer,
Bubba Wilkes!
- Thank you, sir!
- Don't let anybody tell you you're not!
- No, sir!
But as a young man!!!
with a desire
for my daughter's hand!!!
you're pitiful!
It embarrasses me to watch you!
- I don't understand, sir!
- You sure don't!
You let moonlight and magnolia
blossoms go to your head,
and you forget the real
purpose of your mission!
Newby!
[ Thomas ] Don't tell me
I can't resign,Joe.
I volunteered into this outfit,
and I'll volunteer out!
There's still a lot
of work to be done!
Not for me, there isn't!
I came into this thing!!!
three years ago with
7 5 volunteers, all good riders!
Do you know how many
of those men are left?
No, but I imagine
you're going to tell me!
Well, if you'll look out
this window, you'll see ten!
Two of them
won't make Christmas!
I still can't understand what those men
have to do with you resigning!
They didn't join the army,Joe!
They joined me!
For three years
I've watched them fall,
and not one of'em quit
and not one of'em deserted!
Those that are left deserve
more than a pat on the back!!!
from some newspaper editor, and
I'm gonna see that they get it!
The army needs horses! Well, there's
plenty of horses in the Territory--
wild horses in Arizona and New Mexico--
and we're goin' after them!
- And sell them to the army?
- We're sure as hell not
gonna give 'em to the army!
All right! Write out a letter
of resignation, and I'll see that--
You came in mighty handy
a few times!
Take care of yourself!
We may need you again,John Henry!
You'll have a hard job
finding me,Joe!
Where to,John Henry?
Short Grub, I've been tryin' for three
years to get you to call me ''Colonel!''
Now it's too late!
- Where to,John Henry?
- West!
- The barn's yours, Newby!
- Yes, sir!
Good-bye, old lady!
How come you know they're
gonna get in here today?
'Cause I told him
to be here today, that's why!
Where do you think you're
gonna mail that thing, Solomon?
There's a Pony Express,
ain't there? Somewhere!
Still a long ways
to Oklahoma,John Henry!
- Anything could happen!
- Not to Blue Boy, it won't!
Come on, tightwad,
give me a chew!
Wait a minute, Baker!
I've only got one left!
- Come on, give me that!
- Hey, that's too big! Come on!
Give me that!
That's my last one!
Come on now, Frank!
I gave you a chew!
All right, I've had it!
Give me that, Frank!
- Give me that! Give me that!
- Hey! Hey!
[ Baker ] Well, I'll be damned.
Lookie yonder.
[ Whooping ]
Hello, Two Toes!
How's your wife?
Pregnant!
- What, again?
- Cold winter!
- How are you, McCartney?
- Mister McCartney!
John Henry, the least you can do
after I come all this way is say hello!
- Hello, Mr! McCartney!
- I broke my butt to get here!
You can show me some respect!
- Your cookin' still
as bad as I remember it?
- You go to hell!
You still got
that mangy old cat?
High Bred--
finest partner I ever had!
Cleans his paws
and buries his leavings!
Lot more than
some folks I know!
- Any trouble?
- No! Lost track of time, though!
I reckon I'm a day early
or a day late!
You're four days late, but they
don't know it! How are things at home?
Bad, like everywhere else,
I guess!
Yeah! Well, I guess
we better get organized!
[ Horses Neighing ]
[ Whooping, Whistling ]
Don't lose
those two over there!
Get 'em all!
[ Whooping Continues ]
[ Indistinct Shout ]
Take your time. I'll have
McCartney send you some grub.
That'll be damn nice of you! I hope
I can do the same for you sometime!
[ Horse Neighs ]
[ Sighs ]
Tough way to make a few dollars!
Fighting the damn war was
a hell of lot easier than this!
Not too close, Mudlow!
Might be catchin'!
It ain't right, you folks
holdin' anger on me!!!
just because I wouldn't
join your blamed old army!
- Go on, get!
-Just mean!Just mean folks!
Charlotte, I'd like to talk
to you tonight after supper!
After it's dark, you mean?
All you want to do is hold me
and hug me and kiss my lips!
Is there somethin'
wrong with that?
Well, a young lady's lookin'
for a mite more these days!!!
than huggin' and holdin'
and kissin'!
She's lookin' for somethin'
a teensy bit more substantial!!!
than periphery and trimmings!
Like what, Charlotte?
I've said all I'm gonna say,
Bubba Wilkes!
Well? Will you walk out
with me after supper?
Walk out? Walk out in these
dreadful swamps where--
where I could get eaten
by a tiger or somethin'?
Oh, you must've lost your
foolish mind, Bubba Wilkes!
And it just goes to prove you don't have
any true regard for me whatsoever!
A tiger?
[ Horses Neighing ]
The first good grass
you come to, give 'em a rest!
- All right,John Henry!
- We'll be back around sundown!
Hyah!
See'd your dust all day!
What you drivin'? Buffalo?
Stage arrived yet?
It's overdue! I ain't askin'
'cause I don't care!
But if your name's Thomas,
there's a couple of popinjays
waitin' inside to see you!
They've been here
for two days now!
I give 'em water the first day,
and they tooken root!
- Government agents?
- I ain't asked! They ain't said!
Are you the gentlemen
that were looking for me?
You are
MonsieurJohn Henry Thomas?
You have me at a disadvantage!
I am Monsieur Pierre Petain!
This is my companion,
Señor Luis Escodero!
We have the honor to represent
the emperor Maximilian of Mexico!
Oh!
Won't you have a chair,
Monsieur Thomas?
Well, thank you, no!
We're waiting for the stage--
We understand
you have many horses!
- Is that correct, Mr! Thomas?
- It could be!
We have been authorized by the emperor
to purchase all you can supply!
Well, I'm afraid you gentlemen
have made a long trip for nothing!
My horses are going
to the United States Army!
But, Mr! Thomas, we'll buy
the whole herd, sight unseen!
Top dollar, if you
drive them to Mexico!
- All expenses paid!
- Stagecoach is comin'!
I'm sorry, gentlemen!
Our army needs them!
Pardon me!
Whoa! Pedro Flats!
- Mr! Thomas?
- That's right!
My name is D!J! Giles, and this
is my associate, Mr! Ezra Parker!
- Howdy! This is Short Grub!
- We're out of the U!S! Army
purchasing office at Fort Clark,
and we understand you have
some horses to show us!
No, I have some horses
to sell you!
Three thousand, to be exact, and it's
the best herd you'll find anywhere!
Fine! Shall we go inside?
Thank you!
We'll cull your herd
tomorrow, Mr! Thomas,
as soon as our wranglers
arrive from Brackettville!
I suppose that out of 3,000 head,
we ought to able to find 500 or so
that we can use!
- Our usual procedure is this--
-Just rein up a minute, Mr! Giles!
You're goin' a little fast for me!
Do you mind trottin' through that again?
Not at all! I said
that out of 3,000 head,
we might be able to find
500 or so that we can use!
You know, animals
that meet our specifications!
Well, I have 3,000 for sale,
not 500!
Well, surely you don't
expect us to purchase!!!
just any old horse
for the United States Army?
Well, now there just ain't
''any old horse'' in this whole herd!
You'll take 'em all or none!
Mr! Thomas, I'm sure
you're aware of the fact!!!
that, uh, times are hard!
Maybe not as hard as you think!
The army's not that hungry
for horse flesh!
This country is going through
a period of reconstruction!
Money is in short supply!
Hmm?
Who can you sell 'em to
if not to us?
Monsieur Petain,
hold up a minute there!
-Just for the record,
what are you payin'?
- Twenty-five dollars a head!
[ Thomas ]
Last month it was 35.
[ Chuckles ]
But this month it's $25 a head.
Well, these gentlemen have offered
to take the whole barrel, sight unseen!
- Is that correct?
- That's correct, Mr! Thomas!
- And what's your top offer?
- Thirty-five dollars a head, of course!
You just bought yourself a herd!
And you can tell Maximilian!!!
he won't find better animals between
Montezuma and the Canadian border!
Just a minute!
You're selling horses
to Maximilian!!!
in preference to your
own country's army?
No, I'm selling horses for $3 5
in preference to 25!
You two figured to make
$1 0 a head!
Are you calling us thieves?
Well, Mr! Parker, yes, that's
a pretty accurate description!
Wait a minute!
I didn't do anything!
You should've!
Read that message again,
Sergeant!
''Eighteen rolling units
with men, women and children!!!
''passed through Gladesville,
Texas, 1 0:20 p!m! this date!
''Suspected Confederates!
Probable destination, Mexico!
Detain, search and turn back!''
[ Imitating Bird Call ]
What do you make of that?
It seems I've heard that bird
before, sir, at Missionary Ridge!
And if I'm not mistaken,
that's a gray-bellied sapsucker!
[ Horse Neighing In Distance ]
[ Imitating Bird Call ]
- [ Whistles ]
- [ Whooping ]
The river! Come on!
[ Man ]
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
[ Indistinct Shouting,
Whooping, Whistling ]
[ Whooping Continues ]
Get your weapons!
Real sorry, Miss Ann!
We didn't plan things this way!
Let 'em go, Sergeant!
McClarty, Gibbs!
Turn 'em loose! Let 'em go!
Giddap! Hyah!
[ Indistinct Shouting ]
[ Cheering, Whooping ]
- Sir, I don't mean to--
- I know, Sergeant!
But if I can't have the whole dog,
I don't want the tail!
Yes, sir!
[ Horses Neighing ]
We'll probably cross 'em
at the old monastery, Eagle Pass!
Bon. Well, if we do not
see each other again,
then we will rendezvous
on the plain at Durango!
- Bon courage, Monsieur.
- Thank you!
They are fine-looking
animals, Mr! Thomas!
- The emperor will be pleased!
- I hope he is!
But whether he is
or whether he isn't,
you have the money there
when the horses arrive!
[ Agreeing In French ]
What's troubling you?
Cavalry's comin' from Fort Clark!
Damn government agents!
Can they stop us?
Not if we get across
that river, they can't!
Let's take 'em to Mexico!
Let's go!
[ Horses Neighing ]
Well, what are you waitin' for?
Stop 'em!
We'll be mighty proud to stop 'em,
Mr! Giles-- all 1 2 of us--
just as soon as you tell us
how to go about it!
Next!
Mr! McCartney, when
are we gonna have some meat?
Right now, if you want it!
Belly cheater!
High Bred, you know
what good food is, don't you?
You mangy old cat!
- Hey, McCartney!
- Mister McCartney!
There's somethin' crawlin'
in these beans!
Well, you can speak to it,
but don't play with it!!!
or else the others'll want one
in their beans too!
Hold that plate!
Yes, sir, I can just feel
that money in my pocket right now!
What are you gonna do with it
when you get it?
Well, I had to give that
a lot of good thought,
but I somehow ain't come to set
right down on the notion yet!
[ Man ] I know what I'm gonna buy me--
some pack animals and traps.
Whatever's left over,
I'm gonna get drunk!
And if I ever sober up again,
I'm headin' for the Rockies!
Well, that might be fine
for you, Whitt,
but me bein'better bred,
I got higher ambitions.
Like what?
Like building a small library
under a big elm someplace!
Me and High Bred's gonna go to St! Louis
and open up a little cathouse!
[ High Bred Meows ]
- Everything quiet out there?
- Would you believe it,John Henry?
- I had to wake two of the men!
- Let's hope it stays that way!
You ain't expectin' trouble,
are you,John Henry?
Trouble? Well, let's see!
We got Maximilian on one hand!!!
and Juarez on the other
and bandits in between!
On top of that,
we're Americans in Mexico!!!
taking a cavy ofhorses
to a very unpopular government.
Why should we expect trouble?
How come you didn't
tell us that aforehand?
How come you didn't ask me?
John Henry, there's a box canyon
about four miles from here!
- Enough forage to fill 'em?
- No, sir, but
there's enough to hold 'em!
There's somethin' else!
I rode across two trails!
One was wagons and horses!
The second trail was many riders--
at least 40 and maybe 60.
The second trail ran
just down the side of the first!
Well, if you were to tell me
that a year ago!!!
in Virginia or Tennessee,
I'd suspect ambush!
It looked that way to me!
- Short Grub!
- Yo!
There's forage and water about
four miles ahead in a box canyon!
Move 'em in there and
hold 'em till we get back!
Where are you going,John Henry?
I don't believe it!
Pick up that bucket!
Well, howdy, Sergeant Newby!
Save your ''howdy''
for later,Jamison!
Right now let me see you
start currying that horse!
- Yes, sir!
-Just like old times, eh, Newby?
Just like old times,
Colonel!
Riders approachin'
Two riders a-comin'!
Margaret!
We have company!
Good afternoon!
My name's Thomas!
We're drivin' a herd
of horses south,
just over the hill!
I'm ColonelJames Langdon!
Mr! Thomas, what can I do for you?
Well, it isn't
what you can do for us!
We came to warn you that you're
probably riding into a bandit ambush!
Well, how do you
happen to know that?
Well, Blue Boy here
is a full-blooded Cherokee!
When he suspects somethin',
you usually get it.
There's 40 to 60 riders
moving parallel to you,
just out of sight.
Waitin' until we get
into those hills?
That'd be my guess!
- What did you say your name was?
-John Henry Thomas!
Don't I know you
from somewhere?
To my knowledge, Colonel,
we've never met before!
[ Sighs ] Well, we appreciate
the warning, sir!
It's late! Will you and your friend
join us for supper, stay the night?
Best offer we've had all day!
¶¶[ Bugle Call ]
There's nothin'
like a full stomach!!!
for facin' the unknown future!
Well, I hate to be
persistent, Colonel,
but, uh, I think
the future is pretty certain!
I fully agree!
I think they'll give you
a couple of days to get up into
the hills before they strike!
If this was my outfit, I'd hold
right here and make them come to me.
[ Langdon ]
That's good thinkin'
I've never yet let the enemy choose
the sight ofhis own destruction.
- I like to play in my yard!
- What are these bandits after?
Gold, horses!!! women!
We had an experience or two
with 'em before the... war.
Were you, perchance,
in the war, Mr! Thomas?
Yes, Captain, I was!
Would it be brash and
presumptuous of me to ask!!!
which side you were on,
Mr! Thomas?
Well, I favor to think that
I was on the right side, Mrs! Langdon!
I detect a shadow of animosity
towards my question!
Could it be that you
were a Yankee soldier?
What a question to ask a man!
Yes, ma'am,
I was a Yankee soldier!
Mr! Thomas!!!
I'm about to make my rounds
before I turn in tonight!
Would you care to accompany me?
Thank you, sir!
[ Horse Neighing ]
I suspected it when I saw those
Union trousers on that Indian boy!
My son was killed by Union cavalry
at Shiloh, Mr! Thomas!
We called it
Pittsburgh Landing!
- You were there then?
- I was!
May I ask your rank?
I was a colonel
in that cavalry!
John Henry Thomas!
Of course!
Well, you were on
George Custer's right flank!!!
when you charged the breastworks
at Madisonville, weren't you?
- We did a job that day, didn't we?
- You were damn cruel!
Cruel? ThoseJohnny Rebs had 40-pounders
looking right down our throats!
Did you think you
were comin' to a ball? Sergeant!
Yes, sir!
If I can find the time,
I'm gonna sit down and write
the social history of bourbon!
Tell me somethin',
Mr! Thomas!
Were you, by chance,
at Chickamauga?
I ask because I lost
my brother there-- Ann's husband!
I lost 23 in my command
at Chickamauga--
friends and sons of friends,
men that I'd known
all their lives!
- Now can I ask you a question, Colonel?
- Fire one, Mr! Thomas!
Why did you come clear out here
to continue a war that ended
months ago in Virginia?
Because I'm a stubborn man!
Does that satisfy you?
No!
I got no taste for losin'
to a lot of Yankee rabble!
- How about that?
- It won't wash!
You can be a very
aggravatin' man, Mr! Thomas!
- Sergeant!
- Yes, sir!
Let's just say
we haven't seen the end!
You'll see it quick enough
if you keep drinkin' this stuff!
Excuse me, Colonel!
Sergeant!
Help yourself!
[ Man Shouting ]
[ Little George ]
The young 'uns, now. Come on over here.
You get over here
with me right now!
Hurry, now!
Get tucked away! Come on!
- Come on, now.
- Mind a suggestion from
a Platte River Indian fighter?
Why don't you arm your women?
That's what we did on the
Bozeman and California trail!
[ Wilkes ]
Colonel!
[ Langdon ]
All our night pickets come in yet?
All butJamison, sir!
- Well, go get him!
- Carlyle! Little George!
It's Jamison, sir!
- All right!
- Take him down, George!
Captain, issue a rifle
to every woman knows how to use it!
Yes, sir!
Carry on, Sergeant!
Ladies!
Colonel!
- Looks like he wants to talk!
- We have nothing to talk about!
- Well, he's got you outnumbered!
Let's start from there!
- Finding ourselves outnumbered,
Colonel Thomas, is a fact of life
we've gotten used to!
With women and children
in the pot?
- I'll go, sir!
- No!
The colonel and I will go!
Let's understand
each other, Thomas!
Your Indian friend rode out of here
last night with no explanation!
He hasn't returned! One false move
on your part, and my men won't miss!
Friend, your men have been
missin' me for years!
As far as that Indian boy is concerned,
his father was Bold Eagle,
one of the bravest warriors
that ever rode a horse.
And on top of that,
he's my adopted son,
and I haven't done this much
explaining in years.
- Don't press me, Captain!
- Anderson!
Yes, sir!
Windage and elevation,
Mrs! Langdon! Windage and elevation!
Buenos días, señores.
Yo soy Escalante.
- Do you speak English?
-Ah, sí.
I speak English
most excellently!
- Then tell us what you want
and be damned quick about it!
- We want everything!
We're so poor,
and we need so much!
I'm gonna ask you one more time!
What do you want?
We want your wagons, your horses,
your guns and your gold!
And you also
have some women, señor.
- Is this fool serious?
- You can bet your life on it!
- But it's preposterous!
- Yeah!
- I have more ''mens'' than you!
- If you wanna lose most of'em,
you come right on ahead!
Otherwise, you'd better hightail
your ass right on out of here!
- I'll fight a thousand of you
before I give you a penny!
- I was hoping you'd say that!
Is the flap on your holster snapped
or unsnapped, my Confederate friend?
Snapped, my Yankee friend!
Well, I guess I'm his pigeon!
Hold your fire!
[ Men Shouting, Indistinct ]
Colonel!
You went out there to talk!
Why did you have to shoot the man?
The conversation
kind of dried up, ma'am!
[ Indistinct Shouting, Whooping ]
- Fire!
- [ Gunfire ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Man Shouts ]
Just like old times,
huh, Colonel?
- [ Crying ]
- Margaret!
- [ Sobbing ] I can't!
- [ Gunfire Continues ]
- [ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Whinnying Continues ]
Colonel, behind you!
[ Gunfire Tails Off]
- Don't tell me they're leavin'!
- No, ma'am!
They're reforming to charge again!
Leastwise, that's their plan!
[ Gunfire ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
-[ Gunfire Continues ]
- I'll be damned!
[ Battle Cries ]
[ Horses Whinnying ]
They're leavin' now, ma'am!
That's Blue Boy's little surprise!
Well, I'll be damned!
Mrs! Langdon, the colonel--
your brother-in-law--
said you lost your husband
during the war!
- Yes, Mrs! Thomas!
- I'm sorry!
You didn't know him!
Why should you be sorry?
My cavalry was
in that engagement!
Colonel Thomas,
I wanna thank you!
No thanks are necessary! They were
our enemies as much as they were yours!
- Their own people shoot 'em on sight!
- We're in your debt!
Colonel, why don't you take
all these people and go on home?
There's no tellin' what you're
gonna run into farther south!
In a day or two, we make contact with a
military escort from Emperor Maximilian!
We are going home!
It's ahead of us!
All right, Colonel!
[ Short Grub ] Who you wavin'at,
Blue Boy? [ Laughs ]
[ Cowboy ]
Hyah, hyah!
[ Shouts Continue ]
- Wanna tell me all about it?
- I was thinkin' about that girl!
- What girl?
- The Confederate colonel's
daughter, Charlotte!
- She's a pretty girl!
A little young, but pretty!
- I want her!
- You want her?
- And she wants me!
- How'd you figure that out?
- You raised me to know,John Henry!
I taught you what to do when the snow
comes, how to survive in a blizzard,
and I taught you how to deal
with men, but women--
Nobody knows
what's on a woman's mind!
Well, she wants me, and when
we go home, she'll be with me!
[ Man Shouting, Indistinct ]
Anything wrong,John Henry?
Not yet!
[ Cowboy ]
Yah,yah,yah,yah.
McCartney,
give me a cup of coffee!
Never mind!
I got his coffee!
This damn cinch is
pretty near cut in half!
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
Man's coming,John Henry!
From Colonel Langdon, sir!
I'm to wait for an answer!
We're in a new camp waiting
for an escort from Maximilian!
There's a map on the other side!
What's the matter?
Ain't you Yanks
ever seen a live one before?
Last time I seen a pretty
gray uniform like that,
it was all full of holes!
- Do you know what's in this, Sergeant?
- Of course I know!
There must've been a few words
in that camp before the colonel
sat down and wrote this out!
Yes, sir! A lot of words!
I thought Captain Anderson
was gonna have apoplexy!
And how about you personally,
Sergeant! What do you think about it?
Well, it ought
to be right interesting!
- Anything wrong,John Henry?
- You won't believe it,
but we've been invited
to a Fourth ofJuly party!
[ Thomas ]
We'll be on our best manners today!
- Glad you could join us!
- [ Thomas ] Thank you, Colonel,
for inviting us.
First time we've ever been invited
to a Confederate shindig!
Well, I'm not surprised,
all things considered! Get down!
- Thank you!
- Get down, all of ya!
Well, we didn't intend
to interrupt the festivities!
Well, what are y'all lookin' at? You
ever seen a Yankee before? Just people!
Start playin'! Captain!
- Sir!
- See that Colonel Thomas
and his men are taken care of!
- Sir, I--
- They're our guests, Captain!
Make sure they enjoy themselves!
Yes, sir! Wilkes!
I'm feelin' a little dry, Colonel!
Would you care to join me,
or don't you indulge?
Where's the sergeant?
I'll risk it!
- [ Laughs ] Follow me!
- Thank you!
You Yankee boys hungry? The captain
appointed me to tend to you!
There's a mess of beans
and ham up yonder, and there's
some coffee and grits too!
- Grits?
- I wouldn't touch 'em!
- Why not?
- Might be unclean!
- Well, it will be a change in cooking!
- I'll drink to that!
- Make yourself at home!
I'll be right with you!
- Thank you!
- Mrs! Langdon!
- Mr! Thomas!
That's a mighty attractive dress!
French, isn't it?
Yes! I bought it
in New Orleans before the war!
Seldom had occasion
to wear it since!
You surprise me, Mr! Thomas!
You have knowledge
of ladies' fashions?
Well, I was once married, and I have
knowledge of the cost of such things!
- Here you are, sir!
A little sippin' liquor!
- Ohh!
- Good!
- Somewhat finer
than what the sergeant provides!
[ Chuckles ]
May you be in heaven half an hour
before the devil knows you're dead!
- To your health!
-Jimmy!
- Excuse me, Colonel Thomas!
- Certainly!
Cousin Cora and that Sam-- Well,
they're havin' another go-around!
- Oh, shoot!
- Would you excuse us, please?
- Of course!
- Colonel, here! Help yourself!
- You said that you were
once married, Mr! Thomas!
- Yes, ma'am!
But lucky for me,
she left me!
I must say, Mr! Thomas,
that whatever your faults are,
you do have a quaint kind
of honesty!
Well, she was so busy being a lady
that she forgot to be a woman!
It was Indian country,
and she didn't like that.
It was cold in the winter, hot in the
summer and dusty in the dry spells,
and she didn't like that!
And when I wanna go huntin' and
fishin', I go huntin' and fishin',
and she didn't like that.
And I wanted children, and
she didn't like that either!
- She didn't like much, did she?
- She's happy now, I guess!
She's living in Philadelphia
with her cat, givin' piano lessons!
[ Chuckles ]
Won't you sit down, Mr! Thomas?
Thank you!
Is that Indian boy
really your adopted son?
Yes, but I'm as proud of him
as if he were my own blood!
-¶¶[ Fiddling Resumes ]
- Charlotte?
- How old are you?
- Sixteen!
Nobody ever looked at me
the way you do!
-[ Wilkes ] Charlotte!
- Oh, I'm gonna kill that Bubba Wilkes!
Charlotte!
Why are you afraid
to have someone see me kiss you?
Because-- Because
what I feel is private!
I've never
felt like this before,
and I want to keep it.
I want to keep it
just like it is!
-¶¶[ Continues ]
- Charlotte!
I believe
you promised me the next set!
- They bitin'?
- No!
Maybe you ain't
holdin' your mouth right!
My name's Hughlock Mudlow!
How are you fellas today?
Say, you wouldn't happen to have
a little jug of whiskey on you?
They won't give me one! They won't talk
to me 'cause I wouldn't join their army!
- Well, why wouldn't you join the army?
- I didn't wanna get shot!
- [ Spits ]
- Sure glad you fellas came over
here today though!
I ain't had nobody
to talk to in--
- Hey!
-[ Cowboy ] Yah!
[ Men Shouting, Indistinct ]
!!!two, three!
- Get him!
- [ Men Shouting, Indistinct ]
- Y'all don't have to ask me twice!
- Here goes another one!
[ Indistinct Chattering ]
- One, two, three!
- Come on, boy!
- Any more takers?
- You made your point,
BobbyJoe! Let it go!
Begging
the colonel's pardon!
You know, we got an Arkansas
razorback that's just whupped
everybody in our outfit!
Well, me and the boys was
just wonderin' if maybe you had
somebody might could take him!
Are you speaking of the manly
art of self-defense, Sergeant?
Yes, sir! I'm here to tell ya!
Root, hog or die-- no holds barred!
John Henry, it wasn't my idea!
Trot him out!
- Little George never lost a fight!
- Little George?
- He'd better have some meat on him!
- You sure about this, BobbyJoe?
- Trot him out!
- Well, go get him, Newby!
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
¶ Ring around the rosies
a pocket full of posies ¶
¶ Ashes, ashes we all fall down ¶
[ All Chuckling ]
Tell me it ain't
what I think it is!
I can't fight!
I'm tired of hurtin' people!
This time, you gotta fight! You've
got to uphold the honor of the outfit!
I can't!
Them blue bellies
called you yellow!
You know I ain't no coward!
You young 'uns,
you go on and play! Go on!
[ Children ] ¶Ring around the rosies
a pocket full of posies ¶
¶Ashes, ashes we all fall down ¶
- You wait right here!
Get you out of that blouse!
- Yes, Sergeant!
Well, gentlemen, here he is!
[ Onlookers Murmuring ]
- You sure you wanna
go through with this?
- Biggest Reb I ever saw!
[ Thomas ]
He's the biggest anything I ever saw.
Here!
I'll write your folks!
Huh? Oh!
I'm right proud to meet ya!
I'm Little George!
[ Onlookers Shouting, Indistinct ]
- Get him, BobbyJoe! He ain't tough!
- He ain't?
No!
Ooh!
This is fun, isn't it?
[ Shouting Continues ]
- Your man there is no coward!
- But he's outnumbered!
- [ Growls ]
- [ Man Whoops ]
[ Indistinct Shouting ]
Get in there, Yank!
[ Laughing Hysterically ]
[ Yells ]
- No, it's me!
- Oh!
Damn grits!
Ohh!
Well, it was bound to happen!
Bound to!
- I sure don't feel much like it!
- No! Me neither!
- [ Man ] Go get him!
-Just one fool thing after another!
Yep! It sure is!
[ Yells ]
Jimmy, can't you stop this?
Stop what?
It just started!
[ Grumbles ]
- [ Yells ]
-[ Yells ]
[ Yells ]
Thanks,John Henry!
- Well, now, I wouldn't call that
exactly fair, would you?
- No, I wouldn't!
- Oh, excuse me, sir! Ooh!
- Nice party,John Henry.
-Jimmy, this is ridiculous!
It's gone far enough!
- Ohh!
- Somebody ought to stop them!
- Not without takin' a lump, ma'am!
All right then!
Get him, Buster!
Hey, Newby,
will you look at Bubba?
Lieutenant Wilkes! Lieutenant!
Lieutenant Wilkes, is this
any conduct becoming an officer?
No, sir!
Hey--
Well, now, Colonel Thomas,
would you care to make this unanimous?
With pleasure, Colonel Langdon!
- [ Gunshots ]
- [ Horses Whinnying ]
[ Gunshots ]
Well, now, why'd you want
to do a thing like that?
I want this stopped!
I want this stopped now!
Well, that's civilization for you!
Not like Philadelphia!
- Huh?
- Nothing!
Oh, uh, Colonel,
Sergeant's got a barrel full!
Well, thank you, Colonel!
You've been a perfect host!
I've always heard
of Southern hospitality! Now
my men understand what it means!
Well, I thought my men'd
do better, Colonel, seein' as how!!!
this is the first time in years
we had you Yankees outnumbered!
Y'all come back, hear?
Windage and elevation,
Mrs! Langdon!
Always remember:
windage and elevation.
French!
- You suppose bandits done it?
- Bandits'd have stripped 'em!
More'n likelyJuaristas!
I want one man to go back
to those Southerners and tell 'em!!!
to forget their escort
from Maximilian.
This is it!
I might've known it'd be him!
He's been actin' kind of
peculiar lately,John Henry!
- Figure he's sick?
- Yeah!
Colonel!
There'll be no escort from Maximilian!
John Henry sent me to tell you!
- How does he know that?
- We ran across them four,
five miles south of here!
They're dead!John Henry
thinks theJuaristas did it!
- I see!
- Colonel, you're not
gonna believe that, are ya?
- Why should I not?
- Why would those Yankees bother
to send us word of anything?
- It just doesn't make sense!
- What reason would I have
in coming to you with a lie?
Yes, Captain, what reason?
It's late, son!
You may as well stay the night!
- Thank you, sir!
- Margaret, Ann? Set another place!
This young man's
joining us for supper!
[ Mouthing Words ]
-[ Langdon ] Captain Anderson?
-[ Anderson ] Sir?
- [ Crashing ]
- Double the night pickets
from here on in, Captain!
During the day, I want two men
ahead of the column, two men at
the rear and two on each flank!
Yes, sir!
- Good night, Captain!
- Good night, sir!
- Corporal?
- Yes, sir?
Jimmy, how far are we
from Durango?
Three days!
You know, I-- I've been thinkin'
an awful lot about home!
I have too, Maggie!!!
and my home is you!
Ohh,Jimmy!
[ Horse Whinnies, Distant ]
I knew it would be nice!
Why'd you ask me how old I am?
Do you care?
No! I'm glad you're young!
It gives us more time
to be together!
Oh, I'll always be young
if I always feel the way I do now!
When we go back to the Territory,
you'll be with me!
Take me now!!! tonight!
[ Charlotte ] Oh!
- [ Gasps ]
- You go to bed!
- [ Grunts ]
- Please, don't hit him!
Stop it!
[ Gasping ]
Hyah!
[ Horses Whinnying ]
- So Doc says, ''Sorry, partner,
you're gonna die!''
- [ All Laughing ]
¶¶[ Fiddle:Folk ]
Them ''hor-dorv-rees'' was mighty fine,
Mr! McCartney, but for my trimmings,
- I'd like a Kansas City steak,
well done!
- You go to hell!
John Henry, you ever hear
about that gal in St! Louis?
She had the dangedest itch--
- Shut up!
-¶¶[ Fiddling Stops ]
We're comin' down to the end
of it now! We've lost 500 horses
between here and the border,
and I don't think
that's very funny!
We lose any more, and somebody's
gonna be damned uncomfortable!
You know what?
I thinkJohn Henry's scared!
How 'bout some coffee?
- Kind of worried about him, ain't ya?
- Who?
Well, you're the worst liar
I ever came across,John Henry!
Blue Boy, that's who!
Well, he should've caught up
with us three days ago!
You don't reckon
he come across bandits, do you?
No, I think
he's too smart for that!
You know what I'd be
thinkin' if I was you?
I'd be thinkin' he made off
with that little Reb gal!
And I'd be thinkin' that he was just
about to the Rio Grande by this time!
Well, that's what
I been thinkin'!
Ah, he wouldn't do that!
Nah, he wouldn't do that!
Thanks, Short Grub!
- I've changed my mind!
- Oh-- Oh!
- Good morning!
- Well, here they are! You ready for it?
- We're all set to make the count!
- Good!
- Did you encounter
any trouble along the way?
Well, nothing to speak of!
Well, we're here, and the horses
are here! How about that money?
Oh, it's coming!!! by special courier
with a troop of the emperor's cavalry!
- He is most appreciative!
- Well, how soon is
that special courier due?
- Any day! Shall we make the count?
- Why not?
[ Horses Whinnying ]
[ Speaking Spanish ]
2,505 horses!
I am surprised, Mr! Thomas!
- How's that?
- Well, I thought you would
lose more on a long trip like that!
Well, I had an understanding
with my men!
- I asked 'em not to lose any more,
and they didn't!
- [ Both Chuckle ]
- How long we gonna be here,John Henry?
- Till they give us the money!
My men haven't been home for four years!
We're a little anxious!
So we won't be hard to find!
We'll be right handy!
[ Man Shouting Warning In Spanish ]
[ Continues Shouting ]
¶¶ [ Band Plays
''I Wish I Were In Dixie'' ]
[ Newby ]
Company, halt!
Left by twos! Ho!
My compliments, sir!
¶¶ [ Stops ]
ColonelJames Langdon,
sir, Confederate States Army!
- My aide, Captain Anderson!
- General!
My name is Lazaro Rojas!
In the name of Emperor Maximilian,
I welcome you to our pueblo!
We have prepared a welcome banquet for
you and your people, Colonel Langdon!
Please, do us the honor...
of extending our invitation
to those of your party.
- Thank you very much, sir! Captain?
- Sir!
Lieutenant!
Dismount the troops!
- [ Wilkes ] Yes, sir!
Sergeant, dismount your troops!
- [ Newby ] Prepare to dismount!
- [ Newby ] Dismount!
- Ladies!
- ¶¶ [ Band Plays ]
- [ Chattering ]
-Saludas, uh--
-Amigas!
Sí, amigas!
- Thank you very much, sir!
- Salud.
Ah, salud.
¶¶ [ Fanfare ]
It's all right, kids!
It's gonna be all right!
[ Murmuring ]
Consider yourselves prisoners
of the Revolution!
I shall protest this
to Emperor Maximilian, sir!
We take no orders from
Maximilian, Colonel Langdon!
Our president
is Don BenitoJuarez!
-[ Drumbeats ]
-The drums of Mexico beckon us, Colonel!
Please!
-James!
- Will you excuse us, Mrs! Langdon?
[ Drumbeats Continue ]
[ Officer Shouting Command
In Spanish ]
[ Officer Shouts Command ]
If you think you're gonna scare us with
threats, General, you underestimate us!
No, no, Colonel Langdon,
we have estimated you very well!
Aside from the men in your party,
there are 3 2 women and 1 7 children!
You are friends of Maximilian!
He has brought the French
into our country, and they
have tried to ride roughshod!!!
over our people!
Now Maximilian has brought you
Southern Americans into our country!!!
because he can no longer
get help from Napoleon!
These Frenchmen
kill the entire population!!!
of a small village,
every man, woman and child...
-butchered.
- [ Officer Shouting Commands
In Spanish ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
-¡Atención! [ Shouts Command ]
- [ Drumrolls ]
[ Continues Shouting Commands ]
[ All ]
¡Viva! ¡Viva! ¡Viva! ¡Viva!
-[ Crowd Continues Chanting ]
- That is what happens, Colonel,
to invaders of my country!
- My people are not invaders!
- You are here, and you
are friends of Maximilian!
- But we're not your enemies!
What do you want of us, General?
- Our forces need horses, Colonel!
Not far from here,
there is a herd of 3,000!
- Thomas!
- Yes!
Thomas!
- I'm afraid I don't
understand you, General!
- You will deliver this to Thomas!
[ Rooster Crows ]
- I'll be damned if I will!
- I believe you will, Colonel!
Our Revolution needs those horses!
BenitoJuarez needs those horses!
I'm a Confederate officer!
You can't expect me to go beggin'
those Yankees for anything!
That's in the first place, and the
second place, they wouldn't do it!
They have no reason
to care what happens to us! General,
that man Thomas would spit in my face!
You will do as I say,
or you will all be shot!
I'm not askin' any Yankee
for anything!
Very well!
- [ Officer Shouts Commands ]
- [ Drumrolls ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Rifles Cock ]
General!
[ Officer Shouts Command ]
[ Gasping ]
- I'll go!
- [ Shouts In Spanish ]
You will have the horses
in this place by noon tomorrow!!!
or you will all be shot!
[ Snoring ]
-[ Child Coughs ]
- [ Snoring Continues ]
[ Mexican Soldiers Laughing,
Whooping, Shouting ]
[ Soldiers Talking In Spanish ]
[ Talking Ceases ]
[ All Grunting ]
[ Soldiers Laughing ]
[ Gasping, Crying ]
Don't leave me!
Please! Don't ever leave me!
All right! Get up! Get up!
Two Toes has dug up something!
- [ All Grumbling ]
- Come on! Get up!
- Mr!John Henry?
- Yeah?
Uh, we got company!
-[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
- Thank you, Mr! McCartney!
[ All Groaning ]
- [ Thomas ] What's all this?
- We found this man!
Found me?
You trapped me, you--
Here, untie him!
- [ Chuckling ] I told you
that uniform'd get you in trouble!
- Yeah!
- Mr! McCartney,
you got the coffee ready?
-All ready.
Good morning!
- Bonjour.
- Buenos días.
- Wake ya up?
- Ah!
Get a little coffee in ya
and settle down,
you can tell us what
it's all about!
I was given no choice!
That's why I'm here!
My family, they're all
gonna be murdered!
All of my people
are in his hands!
When we reached Durango,
they--
they gave us a party
and then they tricked us!
My people are prisoners
of a Juarista general!
I didn't want to come here.
I didn't want to cause you people any--
Aw, damn it! Here!
Read this!
General Rojas
is more eloquent than I am!
What does it say,
John Henry?
- That's good coffee! Thank you!
- You really think so?
Well!!! it's your game!
How do you wanna play it?
John Henry, we been dealt lots of tough
hands since the summer of'61 !
Here's one I wish we could pass!
- This don't leave us nothin'!
- We ain't never had nothin' nohow!
Wait a minute, BobbyJoe!
You mean you're willin' to give up
them horses to them Johnny Rebs?
[ BobbyJoe ] Well, I ain't
no Christian, but my mama was.
John Henry, remember
when I lost my horse!!!
- up there at Pittsburgh Landing?
- Yeah!
There I was without a horse, behind
that log and them Rebs was all over me,
but there was one
didn't have no gun!
Remember me telling you about that one
come crawlin'up to me behind that log?
Yeah, but what's that
got to do with this?
Well, this Reb, he said he was
all tuckered out and he wanted
to give himself up!
- So I told him to get the hell on
outta there! I didn't want him!
- [ Chuckles ]
- You know what he said to me?
- No!
- ''You got me whether you
want me or not!'' [ Laughs ]
- [ Laughs ]
All right!
Looks like you're
stuck with us!
John Henry, I--
- If we have to get there by noon,
we better-- Where's that--
-[ Departing Hoofbeats ]
Short Grub, you better throw
a couple of outriders in front
of the point when we get started!
- Yo!
- Break camp!
[ French ]
!!!Durango!
- YBenitoJuarez.
-Sí.
[ French ]
- Muy bien.
-Allez.
Crimeny sakes! Those Frenchies
have really found some help!
I thought we'd run away
from all that!
What about it,John Henry?
Looks like we got ourselves
mixed up in somebody else's war!
[ Man ]
Yeah, it sure does.
- What are we gonna do now?
- Well, that's already been decided!
[ Thomas ]
Bring the two chuck wagons up here
and fill 'em full of men and rifles.
I'll get 'em!
We'll give 'em a taste
of General Sherman's war!
I remember!
[ Shouting Orders In French ]
They're gettin' a little close,
ain't they,John Henry?
Yep!
- You ready, Colonel?
- Ready!
Break to the sides!
Turn 'em loose, McCartney!
Hang on, High Bred! Get out of my way!
Get up there now! Get up there now!
Short Grub, take care
of High Bred for me!
I said a lot of mean words
to the boys, ain't I?
- You sure have, McCartney!
- Mr. McCartney!
Well, you tell 'em
I meant every damn word!
Aah!
You! Two steps forward! Aquí.
You!
You! You!
And you!
You! ¡Grandote!¡Aquí!!
Mudlow! My turn!
[ Spanish ] Hands back.
¶¶[ Distant Drum:March ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Officer Shouts In Spanish ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Welcoming Shouts ]
[ Laughing ]
Oh, ho!
You have completed your mission,
Colonel Langdon!
Thank you.
- Well,John Henry--
- [ Margaret ]James!
[ Stifled Sobs ]
You must be Rojas!
General Rojas!
And you must be
John Henry Thomas!
You drive a hard bargain,
General!
War is war, Colonel!
You should know that!
Yeah, ya!!!
win one!!!
ya lose one!
It is cognac, the only good thing
the French have brought to my country!
May I propose that we drink
to the health and success!!!
of my President Don BenitoJuarez,
the Revolution
and the future of Mexico!
Hear, hear!
And, General, may I propose a toast
to the United States of America!
Not even for 3,000 horses?
To the United States of America!!!
and the Confederacy!
John Henry,
what are that
Indian boy's intentions?
Probably disgraceful, Colonel!
But it's not what he'll do to her,
it's what she's done to him!
[ Both Laugh ]
It ain't much like
old times, Colonel!
No, it ain't much like
old times, Mr! Newby!
What do you plan on doin'
once we get back home?
Well, the only place a man can raise
more hell than he can in a war!!!
is on the floor of
the House of Representatives!
An old friend of mine once told me
people like to vote for heroes!
So, I guess that's what I'll do!
That team workin' out all right?
Sure!
You goin' back to the
Oklahoma Territory, Mr! Thomas?
Yes, ma'am,just as fast
as I can get there!
- There many women out there?
- Some!
Good country, I suppose!
From the Missouri
to the Pacific Ocean!
Mostly good land
for farming and!!!
- raising cattle and!!!
raising a family!
- ¶¶ [ Harmonica: ''Dixie'' ]
Are you gonna raise a family?
Well, I, uh--
- Solomon, can't you play
any other tune?
- Sure, boss!
- ¶¶ [ ''Battle Hymn OfThe Republic'' ]
- That neither, Yank!
¶¶ [ ''Yankee Doodle'' ]
[ Spits ]
Sure do miss Mr! McCartney!
- Yeah, but not his cookin'!
- No, me neither!
¶ Put a feather in his hat
and called it macaroni ¶¶