[Man Narrating]
In 1853, a small group of Americans...
journeyed to Sonora, Mexico.
Their mission was to free that country
from a corrupt dictatorship.
Their leader's name
was William Walker.
[Shouting]
[Man Laughing]
[Shouting Continues]
Walker's forces
will never slip away to the rear.
His men would rather die first.
[Screams]
Turn and fight.!
They're only men and scared.!
[Cannon Blast]
Be prepared to sacrifice yourself
for freedom...
for justice,
for religious convictions!
Stand up and fight!
Fight, you pigheaded bastards!
Fight!
Fight.!
What the hell are you doing?
Get back in!
What are you... What are you doing?
Shit. Aw, fuck.
[Men Shouting]
Brigade! Atten-hut!
Men of
the 1 st Independence Battalion.
We came to Sonora with the boldest hearts
and the loftiest of intentions.
But I will not dissemble with you.
[Explosions, Gunfire]
Reinforcements have failed to arrive.
We are without food or water.
We're trapped.
Only an act of God
can save us now.
[Rumbling]
[Wind Whipping]
Crocker, prepare the men for departure.
We're returning home.
Yes, sir! Mr. Fry, follow me.
This is a magnificent moment for me.
It is a privilege to be at your side
at this great time.
Even if we are defeated,
it doesn't matter.
We will live on in history.
Mon frère.
Don't be so silly, man.
[Men Shouting]
¡Vámonos.! ¡Vámonos.!
[Shouts]
[Cheering]
[Walker Narrating]
Walker led his men to the American border.
Unjustly accused of violating
the neutrality of Mexico...
Walker was put on trial.
[Angry Shouting]
- Order! Order!
- [Man] Hold it down. Hold it down.
- Quiet!
- [Shouting Stops]
I demand quiet!
[Fans Creaking]
Does, uh... [Clears Throat]
Mr. Walker wish to make a statement...
before thejury
decides on a verdict?
Yes, Your Honor.
Unless a man believes that there is
something great for him to do...
he can do nothing great.
A great idea...
springs up from a man's soul...
agitates his entire being...
transports him from the ignorant present
and makes him feel the future...
in a moment.
It is the God-given right
of the American people...
to dominate the western hemisphere.
It is our moral duty to protect our neighbors
from oppression and exploitation.
- [Spectators Murmuring]
- It is the fate of America...
- To go ahead.
- [Scattered Shouts Of Agreement]
- That is her manifest destiny.
- [Man] Hear.! Hear.!
- Walker!
- Yeah!
[Clears Throat]
Your Honor...
we find the defendant,
William Walker...
[Whispers]
Not guilty.
- Not guilty.
- [Whooping, Cheering]
[Man]
Hear.! Hear.!
Hey, where do we go next, Colonel?
Hey!
[Shouting, Indistinct]
- **[Piano]
- ** [Violin: Off-key]
[Man]
We must move southward.
Only by expanding can we hope
to avoid a civil war...
and save those institutions
we hold most dear.
I assume you're including slavery?
Are you not, Mr. Squier?
[Squier]
I most certainly am, sir.
We must not be sentimental...
if we hope to preserve
that which is most precious to us.
My sentiments entirely, Mr. Squier.
Why, thank you, Mr. Martin.
How absolutely right we both are.
Pardon me?
Miss Martin says that perhaps not all
of our institutions are worth saving.
Well, perhaps not.
[Shouting] However,
I'm sure the little lady will agree...
that we must preserve
our way of life at any cost!
Otherwise, the barbarians
will surely stone the gates...
- and then where will we be?
- [Mr. Martin] Exactly. Well said.
Pardon me? I didn't get that.
Miss Martin has
a rather different view.
She positions herself
rather on the side of change...
rather than cultural preservation.
Well, that is very interesting, my dear.
Ellen. Please, Ellen!
Ellen!
I'm afraid she's not herself.
The strain of my recent trial.
Plus our approaching marriage.
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
Doctor, will you please take care of our guests?
Yes, William.
Gentlemen! The renowned Walker
has prepared a statement...
in the form of a quote
from President Buchanan.
"Expansion is the future
of our country...
and only cowards fear
and oppose it."
[Man] Mr. Cole, will the colonel
be returning to Mexico?
Mr. Walker has no plans
for the moment...
except to pursue
his private affairs in peace.
Well...
Ellen.
Ellen. You know I despise...
I despise slavery!
[Crowd Chanting]
Walker.! Walker.! Walker.!
Walker.! Walker.! Walker.! Walker.!
[Walker Narrating] In the flurry
of excitement following his acquittal...
Walker received an invitation
from that famous captain of industry...
Cornelius Vanderbilt...
considered by some to be the richest
and most powerful man in the world.
[Hammer Hitting Metal]
Colonel Walker,
I'm so pleased to see you.
I can't tell you how happy
this will make the commodore.
Give him some water,
would you, please?
Every day he's been asking,
"When will Colonel Walker arrive?"
- Is my horse gonna be safe with that man?
- Yes, he'll be fine.
You have been very much
on his mind.
Central America, Colonel.
There's land, and all of it
there for the taking.
Think of it, sir.
From ocean to ocean.
This way.
And the women, Colonel.
My God, the women.
Bare-breasted beauties
under trees...
laden with fruit.
Think of it.
Seven to every man.
If you please.
By the way, Colonel, have you had
an opportunity to read my book...
on the subject of Nicaragua?
No, I have not.
Well, then I will present you with
a signed first edition when next we meet.
It's my understanding you were educated
in Edinburgh, Scotland and Paris, France.
- That is correct.
- Good. The commodore likes an educated man.
And there he is,
the most powerful man on earth.
[Flies Buzzing]
Don't be nervous, Colonel.
Just remember three things:
Do not sit unless he invites you to,
always address him as "commodore"...
and, under no circumstances,
ask for any personal favors.
Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt,
may I present Colonel William Walker?
- Colonel of what?
- The American phalange in northern Mexico.
You caused quite a commotion
down there.
We had a shortage of supplies, no help from our
government. Otherwise we would have succeeded.
You fucked up, Walker.
Next time pick on a country your own size.
Are you entitled
to wear that uniform?
I'm entitled to do
anything I want.
[Passes Gas]
Mr. Vanderbilt, I came down here
on your invitation.
I did not come here to be insulted.
If you'll excuse me.
Sit down!
Please. Colonel, please.
Sit down.
- Does Nicaragua mean anything to you, Walker?
- Nothing at all.
Nicaragua's a fucked-up little country
somewhere south of here.
This worthless piece of real estate
controls the overland route to the Pacific.
[Squier Clears Throat]
[Vanderbilt] I now control
all transportation in Nicaragua.
But in order to continue to do so...
I need stability.
What's this got to do with me?
Nicaragua's a divided country, sir.
It is in the midst of a terrible
civil war. It is imperative...
What I need is for some man
to go down there and take over.
I want that country stable.
I want it done now.
They, uh... They tell me
you're a clever man, Walker.
Doctor, lawyer, surgeon.
All that Renaissance rubbish
they talk about these days.
[Men Chattering In Chinese]
Well? Can you handle thejob?
That's not the issue.
I plan to get married...
start a newspaper.
Then you would be wasting one
of life's golden moments, sir.
It is not every man who is offered
the chance to have a country of his own.
[Man Shouting Orders]
Walker's goals involve a higher purpose
than the vulgar pursuit of personal power.
Huh.
Do you prize democracy, Walker?
Universal suffrage?
The principles of our founding fathers?
Yes.
More than my own life.
Nicaragua needs democracy, Walker.
They need a canal as well.
I'm interested in Nicaragua, Walker,
and so are you...
whether you know it now or not.
Well, I'm sorry,
but I cannot oblige you.
- Good day.
- Now, Walker.
- Please.!
- I like him.
Get him a new hat.
[Hammer Hitting Metal]
- It was the cholera.
- [Man] Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
- Ellen.
- [Woman Crying]
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of God, pray for us sinners
now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
[Crying]
She's with God now, my son.
Don't talk to me about God!
What do you know about God?
Get out!
- [Crying Continues]
- All of you, out! Get out!
Now.!
[Whimpers]
How? How?
Oh, God!
[Sobbing]
I can't.
I don't... God, you bitch!
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Sniffles]
[Thunder Rumbles]
[Walker Narrating]
Walker determined not to look back...
- [Bell Dinging]
- but to face only the future.
- He accepted Vanderbilt's proposal
and set sail for Nicaragua.
- Prepare to cast off!
[Walker Narrating]
With him were 58 men...
whom the popular press
saw fit to term "Walker's Immortals. "
Walker,
I am Captain Siegfried Henningson...
late of the Corsican campaign
and the Balkan fiasco!
I am well-schooled
in military matters, sir...
having studied with Josef Penn,
Lubitsch and von Koch.!
I would be honored, sir,
if you would accept my services.
I will, of course, provide for my own needs
and will require no financial assistance.
What is your name again, sir?
Lieutenant... Uh, Captain
Siegfried Henningson at your command, sir!
- You are now Major Henningson.
- Sir.!
Cast off then!
[Walker Narrating] Never have I seen a collection
of such brave men assembled under one banner.
God bless them all.
The American phalange landed
at Realejo, Nicaragua...
where we were met by distinguished
representatives of the Nicaraguan Liberal Party.
- My brother, William Walker.
- How do you do, sir?
[Walker Narrating]
These natives were to be our guides.
- Aw, come on!
- Ow! My hair!
- Join the crowd.
- Jesus, stand up straight.
Start drumming, Mr. Turley.
* Oh, my darling Clementine *
- * You are lost and gone forever *
- [Women Laughing]
* Dreadful sorry, Clementine **
[Walker Narrating] From the day the Americans
landed at Realejo dates a new era...
not only for Nicaragua,
but for all Central America.
* Oh, I went down South for to see my Sal
singing Polly wolly doodle all day *
- *Because my Sal is a spunky gal *
- [Women Laughing]
*Singing Polly wolly doodle all day *
- [Laughing Continues]
- *Fare thee well, fare thee well *
*Singing Polly wolly doodle all day *
* Oh, I'm goin'to Louisiana
for to see my Susyanna *
- *Singing Polly wolly doodle all day *
- What are you doing?
- Move it!
- * Fare thee well, fare thee well **
You're on my shit list, Washburn.
Get up there.
[Man Shouting]
Get over here, goddamn it!
¡Vámonos.!
[Walker Narrating] We paused at the small,
unregenerated hamlet of Realejo...
to await the arrival
of the leaders of the Liberal Party...
- Listen up here!
- Generals Munoz and Castellon.
Proverbs, chapter 11, verse three.
"The integrity of the upright
shall guide them...
"but the perverseness
of transgressors...
shall destroy them."
Soldiers, we are now embarked
on a glorious destiny:
nothing short of the entire
regeneration of this republic.
Ours is a sacred trust...
and any man who betrays that trust...
by creating an act of transgression against
the hospitality of the Nicaraguan people...
will be judged
and dealt with accordingly.
There will be no excessive drinking...
no seducing
and no swearing in public places.
What's that? That mean
we can swear in private?
Quiet! The colonel's talking!
Gentlemen...
we are honored guests here...
and we will act that way
according to the moral dictates of God...
science and hygiene.
- Hear. Hear.
- That is all, Captain.
- Dismissed!
- [Cheering]
What's the idea?
Hey, stop! Stop, stop.
Stop, stop!
[Chickens Squawking]
Sanders, I know what you're thinking, but
believe me, even you can do better than that!
Achilles, you just stay outta this!
The colonel says this is a democracy.
[Bleating]
[Walker Narrating] Walker realized
that he would need to keep a firm hand...
on the moral conduct of the men.
Immortals!
Aim.!
Fire!
Men...
as of this moment...
we do hereby, under God...
become citizens of Nicaragua.
If there is any man who would say no
to this great privilege...
let him step forward.
It is our mission to introduce into the family
of enlightened and civilized nations...
a new sister.
To help us in our just cause...
are two of Nicaragua's Liberal Party...
and defenders of democracy...
Generals...
- [Whispers] Damn it.
- Castellon and Munoz.
Castellon and Munoz.
[Man]
Three cheers for the generals.!
Three cheers for democracy!
- Hip, hip!
- [Men Mumbling] Hooray.
- Hooray.
- Hip, hip.!
- Hear! Hear!
We march for Rivas.
As God is on our side...
victory will be ours.
- Hurrah!
- Rivas.!
[Cheering, Whooping]
[Shouts]
Back!
- [Squawking]
- [Screaming]
It's a parrot, sir.
Watch your step.! Look out.!
Don't do that!
Aw, shit!
- [Man] What the hell?
- [British Accent] You chaps do crash about a bit.
- Lost your way, have you?
- We're marching to Rivas.
Really? What on earth for?
We're liberatin' the country
for democracy.
How very peculiar.
You must be American.
Not no more.
We're Nicaraguans now.
- You draw that?
- Yes.
Why?
- What do you think, Captain?
- I think we oughta...
What do you think of these new guns?
I like 'em.
Six shots, and good-lookin' too.
- I wish we had 'em for that firing squad.
- [Henningson] We wait until nightfall.
Then we attack from the south
and from behind the church.
- We will go straight in.
- That's right, Colonel. I'm with you all the way.
Just jump right in and grab 'em by the throat.
Don't give 'em a chance to get set now.
Excuse me, but haven't we just been assured
by Generals Castellon and Munoz...
that we're to be met
with no resistance?
Castellon is an indecisive old man.
Munoz is a conceited troublemaker.
William, forgive me,
but these men are our allies.
At any rate, we will go in hard
with our eyes open.
First impression in a country
is very important.
Forgive me, but this is idiotic.
I prefer the last impression.
First and last are often the same.
I didn't know
you were a pedant, Henningson.
History never smiles on pedants.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Lieutenant, may I have
a word with you, please?
[Henningson Grunts] l, who have studied
military strategy with Lubitsch...
Colonel, sir, could I have a word with you
one moment, uh, alone, sir?
- Certainly.
- [Man] Shut up, Henningson.!
- What seems to be the problem?
- Well, there's no problem, sir.
I was just wonderin' though
perhaps maybe if, uh...
if I could be excused tomorrow
from being the drum major.
It's just that every time I've seen
pictures of battlefield scenes...
and, uh, I always see the drummer boy
lying dead next to his drum...
and, uh, if it's all the same to you, sir...
I'd like to trade my rifle in
for a drum.
I mean, I'd like to trade
my drum in for a rifle.
As long as you are under my command,
no harm will come to you.
Lieutenant.
Straighten up.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Some men abandon all reason
before going into battle.
They become so seized with fear that...
that often the battle is lost
before it's begun.
I know this will not
happen with you, Timothy.
Thank you for your confidence, sir.
Sir, uh, I feel I have to tell you...
The men are awfully confused about
just what exactly we're fightin' for here.
I mean... I mean, I know, and they know,
that the liberals are our friends...
and the conservatives
are our enemies, but...
well, to tell you the truth, sir,
I can't tell 'em apart.
They all seem the same to me.
That is no concern of yours, Timothy,
nor of the men either.
All you have to remember...
is that our cause is a righteous one.
I know that, sir.
I hope you do, Timothy.
I sincerely hope you do.
Get some sleep.
Yes, sir.
- Come on.!
- [Walker] Turley, move 'em out.!
- [Shouts Echoing]
- Above!
[Shouts, Gunshots Echoing]
Come on!
[Screaming]
Let's go, boys.! They won't know what to do
without us.! We need to split.! Let's go.! Move it.!
Attack.!
[Screaming]
[Gunfire Continues]
Colonel, what are you doing?
I'm doing the only thing
I know how to do... advance!
You dumb shit!
There's no reason for you
to talk to me that way, Timothy.
Sorry, sir.
It's just you're gonna get yourself
and everyone else killed.
Then we'll be together again,
won't we?
[Man Shouting]
What the hell? Come on, go.!
We must get into a house, Colonel!
- For God's sake, why?
- What?
For our own protection.
Yes. Yes.
- Good idea, Major.
- Come, please! Come!
- [Walker] So, Dr. Jones, how is your day going?
- Just fine, William.
We have 11 dead, several wounded.
- How 'bout yourself?
- [Walker] Well, thank you.
Now that we have a plan, I feel sure
there will be a successful outcome.
Splendid, William.
- After you.
- No, no, no. I insist. After you.
- No, please.
- Well, let's go in together.
Very well.
[Man]
Colonel.! There's a room back here.!
- Is there a piano?
- Yes, sir.
[Gunfire Continues]
Take care of the window.!
- Get your fat ass out of here!
- But I'm hungry!
[Man] Why don't you serve him
if you admire him? Follow him.!
God! I'm hungry!
- You heathen!
- * Darling, I'm growing old *
I'll shoot your eyes out!
[Laughing]
- Goddamn music.
- * Silver threads **
[Screaming]
Get him out ofhere.!
Move it! Get him out!
Get him to a doctor!
We need somebody to dig through
the walls. It's our only way!
We don't have time.
We have to charge them bastards.
- Rout 'em out like we did before.
- Dear God!
- We have repeating rifles!
- [Henningson Shouting]
- They have muskets!
- We shouldn't stand a chance!
We're soldiers!
We kill people for a living!
- Yes, sir!
- Shit!
The colonel's leavin'!
- Move out!
- Come on.!
Men, we must leave immediately!
What about the wounded?
The wounded will have to
take their chances.
- Go out the back when the charge goes off!
- You are not in command here!
You're right, Colonel.!
Forget about the wounded. Damn 'em.!
We need another diversion. The men'll
charge through the hole after the blast.
Nay, the powder
will be enough of a diversion!
That is not my considered opinion, Major!
- You men! You, you, you, you, you!
- [Gunshot]
- After the blast, charge through the hole!
- I'll go when you go!
Everyone else, out the back!
We'll meet outside the town!
Damn it! Fuck you, Colonel!
Benito's not goin' through no goddamn wall!
Huh?
- Major?
- [Man] What?
No way. Oh, wait, wait, wait.! Wait.!
- Open the door!
- The fuse is burning!
[Screaming]
Oh, shit.!
[Gunshot]
[Shouting In Spanish]
[Child Shouts, Crying]
[Spanish]
[Crying]
[Crying Continues]
[Walker Narrating] Suffering a temporary setback
and wishing to protect his men at all costs...
Walker decided
to make a strategic withdrawal...
to the seaport of San Juan del Sur.
As always,
his men's spirits remained high.
Dr. Jones.
When you were a little boy...
did you ever have a moment
when you were sitting outside on the lawn...
and you picked up a blade of grass
or a beetle...
and you just looked at it?
And it was whole and perfect
and totally outside of time.
**[People Singing In Spanish]
William!
Uh, Colonel, sir.
You're late, Cole!
You were supposed to come by sea.
But, Colonel, I brought new recruits.
Prussian troops from Ecuador.
** [Singing, Indistinct]
[Lowing]
Magnificent tactics.
I commend you, General.
What do you mean, "tactics"?
Who is this man?
Victoire, mon général.
I'm Bruno von Namzer.
À votre service.
Je vous salue.
Now, I take it,
you will invade Granada.
- You mean you don't know?
- Know what?
You have inflicted such heavy casualties
on the enemy that he has abandoned Rivas.
His troops are racked
with dysentery and cholera.
You broke their spirit, William.
You are victorious.
You have won.
We won!
- [Cheering]
- [Horse Whinnying]
We have won!
- We racked them with cholera and dysentery!
- Now is the hour of my destiny arrived.
- [Man Laughing] We've won!
- I cannot lose.
[Walker Narrating] Determined to end
the civil war and reconcile the divided nation...
we marched upon Granada,
a bastion of conservative power.
**[Drum, Tin Whistle]
The American phalange
entered the capital at dawn...
where we were welcomed
as liberators.
Captain Hornsby?
[Hornsby]
Immortals, charge.! Charge.!
[Men Shouting, Whooping]
Watch it! Come on, Hornsby.
Here... You must...
Goddamn it! My arm!
Captain Hornsby.
[Man]
Get out of the house.!
- Captain Hornsby, I must object...
- [Man] Take 'em, boys.! Tag 'em and bag 'em.!
[Bells Chiming]
- [Woman Screaming]
- [Gunfire]
Quiet, you ammo firers!
Listen up!
Colonel's about to speak!
[Man]
Dismount the prisoners.!
Citizens of Nicaragua!
Today the city of Granada...
and the entire country of Nicaragua
have been liberated.
[Few Men]
Hooray.!
It is our sacred duty to join together
and unify this great nation.
Today, however,
is a day of celebration.
- Tomorrow we must...
- [Gunshot]
- Colonel!
- [Shouts In French]
Fire!
[Bruno]
Shoot the prisoners.! Kill them.! Kill them.!
[Body Thuds]
[Crowd Gasping]
It is not my time to die!
[Together]
It is not his time to die!
The assassin's bullet
has struck correspondence...
from that great Nicaraguan patriot
General Castellon!
It is he who has saved my life...
as it is I who shall save
the life of this country!
- [Men Cheering]
- [Speaking Spanish]
[Men]
Walker.! Walker.! Walker.!
Walker.! Walker.! Walker.! Walker.!
- [Spanish]
- We want Walker.! We want Walker.!
We want Walker.! Walker.! Walker.!
[Man]
Colonel Walker, we are here to thank you...
from the deepest of our hearts...
- [Man Coughing]
- [Woman Speaking Spanish]
for the ending of our civil war...
[Spanish Continues]
and bringing us the precious gift...
of freedom.
- Hear. Hear.
What are we doing here?
[Spanish]
What are your intentions...
toward the office of the presidency?
Turn it down
and offer it to Corral.
You'll own him,
and everyone will be happy.
Tell 'em you'll take
commander in chief of the armed forces.
I am deeply grateful
for the extraordinary privilege...
of being offered
such an exalted position.
However, I must regretfully decline.
It would be more beneficial
to the country...
if Walker were to protect
the democratic process...
as commander in chief
of the armed forces.
[Chattering, Laughing]
- Yeah!
- The army. Now we're talkin'.
I would therefore
like to nominate as president...
a great hero and patriot.
General Ponciano Corral.
[Shouts In Spanish]
- Walker! Walker!
- [Gunshot]
[Cheering Continues]
- [Applause]
[Man]
Colonel Walker.!
[Popping Sound]
Your country is primitive,
but it's full of possibilities...
for democratic advancement.
[Fireworks Popping]
[Spanish]
We must first establish agrarian reforms
before we proceed...
to equalize the social classes,
and above all...
We must separate church and state.
Don't you think?
[Chuckles]
Yes. We must make English
the official language...
so as to end discrimination
against Americans.
We will end conscription.
Release the natives from the army
so that they may resupply the labor force.
The Amer...
The American phalange will...
be responsible for national security.
And I do think we should provide
for free elections within the next six months.
If you think that's possible.
You must be patient with me,
Doña Yrena.
I'm a shy man in these matters.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Moans]
[Man]
What are you guys doing?
[Shouting In Spanish]
- [Man Shouts In Spanish]
- Look at that!
[Walker Narrating] Walker's Immortals
initiated various cultural and civic reforms...
including the construction of a theater
in the traditional European style.
[Woman]
I went to that shanty you callin'a house.
I went to give the girls a bath.
There was no water.
No water on Tuesday?
There was also no toilet paper,
no beer.
- This is Managua?
- No, this is Granada.
- Look at 'em floggin' those kids!
- Come on!
[Walker Narrating] Walker, seeking literacy
above all other gods save hygiene...
started a newspaper,
El Nicaraguense.
I know that guy.
He owes me seven bucks.
Next thing you know,
they'll be institutin' slavery.
It's the same racist, macho, sexist shit
we turned our backs on.
It doesn't have
the feel of victory in it.
It should be glorious and proud,
like the French revolution.
- Yeah, I think so too.
- But that's the way it was.
- That's beside the point, Mr. Doubleday.
- Well, what do you think?
- Shall I send a copy to the commodore?
- [Walker] Yes, absolutely, Byron.
- And ask him for more money, if you would.
- [Man]James, come on.
Come on, come on.
Hey, Billy, my man.!
Top gringo
and heavyweight generalissimo!
[Laughing]
We're his brothers.
- Really? I didn't know he had any brothers.
- Well, he does, okay?
William, we came down
as soon as we heard.
Everybody's talking about you in the States.
You're famous, man!
Yes, James.
Well, that's all relative, of course.
If you'll excuse me,
I have work to do.
Well, wait just a minute.
You know, we've been on the road for months
here comin' down here to help you out.
Yeah!
And all you can say
is you have a lot of work to do?
Yes. That's all I can say.
If you will excuse me.
Come on, come on, come on.
Maybe when you get some time, huh?
It's good to see you, James.
You too.
[Moaning]
- [Whip Cracking]
- [Man Screaming]
- [Moaning Continues]
- [Bell Tolling]
Ellen.
Oh, Ellie.
- [Spanish]
- Oh, Ellie.
[Moaning Continues]
Willians.
[Gunfire]
[Man Shouting In Spanish]
- [Bell Tolling]
- [Shouting Continues]
- [Whip Cracking]
- [Man Screaming]
- [Tolling Continues]
- [Whip Cracking Continues]
[Screaming Continues]
[Weeping, Screaming]
One must act with severity...
or perish.
What are you... Hey!
Put that... Put that down!
What are you, some kind of hick?
And don't give me that look!
I bring you down here
to the Paris, France of Central America...
and you're behaving like you're still
in some hamlet in the woods some...
[Man Chattering]
[Man] There's power for you, huh?
Man doesn't even recognize his own brother.
[Laughing]
[Walker]
What about Honduras and Costa Rica, Byron?
- Hey.
- Don't you think they need democracy too?
- [Cole] Try to pay attention
to the matter at hand.
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
- Vanderbilt's plans are with Nicaragua...
Who the hell
do you think you are, Willie?
I'm your goddamn brother!
You throw me a bone, for Christ's sake!
Don't you ever talk to me that way
in public again.
You are welcome here
only if you contribute.
I have many brothers here,
and they're all equal in my eyes...
Don't give me that bullshit!
I don't believe in equality and neither do you!
You make me an officer
and give me some money...
or, by God, I'll stink up the place.
- [Kisses]
- Yeah! Yeah.
You and James will be lieutenants.
Nothing more until you earn it.
[Whispers In Spanish]
What about the money, Willie?
Put me in charge of the treasury.!
[Walker]
Get out of my way!
Boys, he made me a general.
You're a corporal.
[Walker Narrating] Walker realized that
he could no longer trust his former allies.
In particular, he determined to keep
a sharp watch on so-called President Corral.
[Snarls]
[Man Speaking Spanish]
[Man #2 Speaking Spanish]
[Spanish]
I have an interesting letter here, sir.
"Lost is Nicaragua.
"Lost Honduras,
Salvador and Guatemala too...
unless we all unite
against the gringo."
I want you to arrest Corral.
[Hornsby]
Of course, sir.
Assure him he will
receive a fair trial.
Don't worry, Colonel.
We'll take care ofhim.
William, want me to join 'em?
You'd better hurry, James.
[Spanish]
[Man]
Execution souvenirs, medallions.
[Walker Narrating] Corral was found guilty
of treason and sentenced to die.
The entire country
rejoiced at this news.
There was no doubt in anybody's mind
thatjustice had been served.
William.
[Spanish]
[Munoz]
Yrena, por favor.
General Walker, Corral is
like a father to his people.
Then he is a tyrannical father
who would betray his children.
He was calling on foreign troops
to start an insurrection.
Treason must be punished.
I have no choice.
[Spanish]
[Shouting In Spanish]
Doña Yrena says that it's...
it's a terrible mistake to kill Corral.
A mistake, General.
In this case, I entirely agree with her.
Morally, as well as politically.
You will lose everything
you have gained... up to now.
She said something else.
She called me a name.
What did she call me?
She called you a dog's asshole.
You know they are right, William.
If you persist in this,
everyone will hate you.
I cannot help that.
Sometimes a leader must listen
to a higher law.
What you say may be true, but it
is not, in the final view, important.
- Listen to reason.
- I ask you never to speak of this matter again!
- If you want my opinion...
- [Cole And Bruno] Enough.!
General Corral shall not be
executed today at noon.
[Speaking Spanish]
He shall be executed
this afternoon at 2:00.
[Translator Speaking Spanish]
Muy bien.
Gracias.
- [Sobbing]
- [Men Shouting In Spanish]
[Spanish]
[Shouting]
[Man Shouting Orders]
[Shouting Orders]
Fire!
[Man Speaking Spanish]
[Woman Wailing]
- [Hornsby] That son of a bitch has taken off.
- [Henningson] Probably Costa Rica.
- [Cole] We need to find him and bring him back.
- A few rides after his funeral...
[Hornsby] Do you know what it's like
out there in that damn country?
[Cole]
I may not, but I know what it's like here...
and I know we're in trouble
without a president.
- Gentlemen, if you want my view...
- I don't, actually. And neither does anyone else.
No need to get a wild hair
up your ass, Mr. Cole.
I was only making a suggestion.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Perhaps the time has come
for an election.
There has already been an election.
I won.
Gentlemen, the morning paper.
- [Walker] Thank you, Mr. Rudler.
- Yes, sir.
- [Man Speaking German]
- [Man #2] Congratulations, Mr. President.
[Walker]
James.
[Henningson]
What has this man done to my newspaper?
[Rudler Laughing]
[Birds Chirping]
**[Car Radio: Up-tempo Latin]
- **[Man Singing, Indistinct]
- [Crowd Chattering]
[Shouting, Chattering]
**[Continues]
You're quite a hero
back in the United States, General.
Do you have any plans to go back?
Nicaragua is my country. As long as
I am needed here, I will never leave.
Your country is in a state of chaos.
Guerrilla wars are taking place.
And yet, you refuse
to engage the enemy. Why?
A protracted war against
scattered guerrilla groups...
would not only be disheartening
and dissatisfying...
but it would be too exhausting
for our American troops.
Have you anything to say
to the American people?
I certainly do.
Climb on board one of Commodore Vanderbilt's
steamships and come on down and see us.
[Man] The truth is, President Walker, that
Cornelius Vanderbilt is taking advantage of you.
His transit company,
which guarantees overland passage...
from the Atlantic to the Pacific...
is not paying you what they should.
He is, to put it bluntly,
exploiting you and the entire country.
Shame, shame.
Why are you telling me this?
Simply put, we propose to start a new company
and make you an even better offer.
But to do this, you must
revoke Vanderbilt's license...
and grant our company one instead...
on most favorable terms, of course.
You're telling me that Vanderbilt has
not been paying me what he owes me?
There's no question about that.
- That is inexcusable.
- [Cole] No doubt.
But we mustn't forget that
without Cornelius Vanderbilt...
we wouldn't be here today.
That's true. Whatever good fortune
we have, we owe it to him.
Not only that, but he would be
a terrible man to cross.
I hardly think, gentlemen...
that Commodore Vanderbilt...
is responsible for my great...
our great victories in the field.
May I have a word with you, please,
William? I mean, Mr. President.
Certainly, Byron. Anything
you wish to say, you may say here.
Walker does not resort
to whispers and subterfuge.
Our great victories
notwithstanding, William...
we are utterly dependent
upon Cornelius Vanderbilt.
His ships are our lifeline
to the United States.
They provide us with money,
munitions, medicine and men.
We cannot risk
incurring his displeasure.
Traitor! Traitor! Traitor!
Gentlemen...
it was granted to me
in our recent constitution...
that I have the authority and the autonomy
to do whatever I want.
Don't I?
- Don't I?
- [Man] Absolutely, Mr. President. Absolutely.
- Ja.  Yes, sir.
Don't I?
Yes, you do.
I will not be betrayed by a man as vulgar
and insidious as Cornelius Vanderbilt.
I will, therefore,
revoke his permit.
I will also commandeer his vessels.
From this day on, they will be
the property of the Republic of Nicaragua.
[Chuckles]
You cannot be serious.
- Wanna bet?
- Surely, President Walker,
it might be more advantageous...
to be a little more diplomatic.
Not to use force, but rather diplomacy.
For you, perhaps, but not for me.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I have work to do.
Forgive me, sir, but I must contradict you.
Your work is here! Sir! Come back here!
- [Henningson Speaking Foreign Language]
- I've had it with you, foreign weasel!
You have the nerve to come over here
barely speaking the language.
Taking our jobs!
Poleaxing our women! Take that!
And that! And that!
You bastard!
I cannot help noticing, sir,
during the time I've spent with you...
that you've betrayed
every principle you've had...
all the men who supported you.
May I ask why?
No, you may not.
- [Muttering]
- I'm still not clear on what exactly are your aims.
[Walker]
The ends justify the means.
- What are the ends?
- [Walker] I can't remember.
[Vanderbilt] You two scumbags went
behind my back and cut into my action.!
Nobody does that!
Do you understand?
Nobody fucks with Vanderbilt!
We are both sure, Commodore Vanderbilt,
that we can reach some sort of accommodation.
After all, we are all civilized men.
Civilized men?
From now on,
you're gonna be shoveling shit!
And if your mouths are not too full of it,
you'll thank me for the privilege!
- Thank you. Thank you, sir.
- That's how civilized I think you are!
- Thank you, sir.
- [Shouts]
- [Growls]
- Thank you, Commodore.
You've not only betrayed
the commodore...
you've betrayed yourselves by putting
faith in that lunatic extremist Walker.
Now look.
You've upset the commodore.
What were you thinking of?
Did you seriously imagine...
this pathetic madman
was in charge down there?
- No, of course not. We didn't...
- Get out of here!
Both of you!
[Grunting]
What should we do about Walker?
- [Train Passing]
- [Crossing Bell Ringing]
No one will remember Walker.
No one will remember men who lose.
[Men Chattering]
[Woman Screaming]
[Man]
Look at that fat cat Walker.
Struttin' about as if he was a king.
One thing he didn't ken,
it's Vanderbilt that's runnin' the show.
If he ever opposed the bloke...
we'll be up to our necks in shit.
What have I got, Doctor?
It's cholera.
[Laughing]
[Sobbing]
[Woman Screaming]
- [Men] Hurrah!
- [Man] What means this shouting?
I fear the people choose
Caesar as their king.
- Hurrah!
- While men...
Ah! That's mine.
Another general shout!
[Screaming]
I do believe that these are for
some new honors heaped on Caesar.
[Man #2] Why, man, he doth bestride
the narrow world like a colossus.
Hey, bring on the darky!
- Hurrah!
And we petty men
walk under his huge legs...
and peep about
to find ourselves...
[Officer] Where are you going?
[Groans]
- [Man] You bastard!
- We are in crisis on all fronts.
We must have your attention.
Is there no way you could not have
waited till at least intermission?
- Shit!
- The men are going mad.
They're defacing the cathedral,
pillaging the precious artifacts.
[Walker]
The priests must take their chances. This is war.
[Henningson] Mr. President,
the men are on the point of mutiny.
- No, they are not.
- [Henningson] Are you all right, sir?
- [Jones Muttering]
- Vanderbilt has diverted his steamships
to Panama, cut off our supplies!
We have no new recruits, no money,
very little ammunition.
Very little ammunition.!
[Cole]
We have lost control of León, Masaya...
- Chinandega, Matagalpa...
- And every major Nicaraguan town.
[Bruno]
Rubbish. Defeatist nonsense.!
- Pure unadulterated horseshit!
- [German]
- Food!
- Booze!
- Money!
- Justice!
[Together]
Food! Booze! Money! Justice!
Food.! Booze.! Money.! Justice.!
- You!
- What?
- Are a disgrace.
- I'm a disgrace?
This whole operation is
a fucking disgrace, Your Worship.!
You are stripped of your rank. You can either
stay here as a private or you can leave.
Hey, private this, Willie!
Anderson.
[Crowd Gasping]
- Holy shit!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Ah, shit!
- Give me his medals!
Give me his medals!
I want his medals!
Mother never liked you anyway.
Let me have men
about me that are fat.
Yon Cassius has
a lean and hungry look.
He thinks too much.
Such men are dangerous.
Men...
I have found a solution
to our problem.
Slavery.
[Excited Shouting]
What do you mean?
- We don't need no slaves!
- [Thunder Rumbling]
- We need money and weapons.
- Fuck you, Walker.
- And medicine.
- Silence!
We will introduce
slavery into Nicaragua.
The South will have no choice
but to rally to our cause.
[Crowd Shouting]
[Cheering]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Thunder Rumbles]
[Walker Narrating]
There were rumors that several neighboring
countries had invaded Nicaragua.
You can't do this to me.
I'm an American citizen!
- Walker sent out agents to see if this was true.
- I have friends in high places!
None of the agents returned.
"The Indian of Nicaragua...
"in his fidelity and docility
and in his capacity for labor...
"approaches nearly the Negroes
of the United States.
"In fact, the manners of the Indian
towards the ruling race...
"are now more submissive than those
of the American Negro to his master.
[Coughs]
"The advantage of Negro
and Indian slavery in Nicaragua...
"will therefore be twofold.
"While it will furnish a certain labor
for the use of agriculture...
"it will also tend
to separate the races...
and destroy the half-castes
who cause the disorder."
[Coughing]
"The Battle of Rivas, June 29, 185 5.
"Not more than a dozen went out
to drive away upward a hundred.
"And their charge swept
the enemy completely away.
"There was no thought of rank.
"But each one went forth
with his revolver...
"ready to do the part
of a true man in the fray.
"Never have I seen a collection of such
brave men assembled under one banner.
God bless them all."
[Gunshots In Distance]
- [Gunshots Continue]
- [Henningson] I have studied with Josef Penn.
I have studied with Lubitsch
and von Koch!
And you have the presumption
to talk to me of military tactics.
- [Both Shouting]
- [Groans]
[Shouts]
- [Machine Gun Fire In Distance]
- Bruno... and the Germans...
they have a vision.
Always be a straight shooter, James.
I like the sound of that.
[Floorboard Creaks]
[Door Closes]
I must speak with you.
- I don't understand.
- There is no time.
You speak...
I have spoken to you in many ways,
but you have not heard me.
But now you must, Willians.
Everything depends on it.
Did you see this?
[Machine Gun Fire Continues]
I beg you. Please.
If we have a lot of death,
we will have a revolution.
We must not have that
if we are to survive.
We are both aristocrats.
I am not an aristocrat.
I'm a social democrat.
What's the matter with you?
[Spanish]
I only want what is best for the
Nicaraguan people. I'm surprised at you.
Now leave me alone.
I have important work to do.
Are you quite sure of that?
Absolutely! And shut the door
on your way out.
Okay.
[Walker]
Bruno.! Bruno.!
Mon général.!
Yrena, what are you doing? Bruno!
Général?
[Clicking]
[Spanish]
[Footsteps Departing]
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Panting]
Instruct the men to burn the town.
- Ja.
- [Machine Gun Fire Continues]
[All Shouting]
[Shouting Orders, Indistinct]
What are you doing? Idiot!
- You are an idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
- [Man Laughing]
What is this?
[Shouting]
[Laughing]
[No Audible Gunshots]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Bomb Whistling]
[Woman Screaming]
- [Gunshot]
- [Explosion]
[Laughs]
[Whinnies]
[Groans]
[Indistinct]
[Shouting, Indistinct]
[Gunshot]
[Air Raid Siren Wailing]
[Siren Continues]
[Crowd Chanting]
Walker.! Walker.! Walker.!
[Chanting Continues]
[Chanting Stops]
[No Audible Gunshots]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Groans]
You men, get the colonel's
brother's body outta here.
- [Machine Gun Fire]
- [Man Screams]
[Bomb Whistling]
[Woman Wailing]
**[Children Singing, Faint]
- [Machine Gun Fire]
- [Man Screams]
Mr. President.
- It's been a long time, Doctor.
- It doesn't seem like it.
[Screaming]
- [Henningson] Mr. President.
- Yes.
Granada has been put to the torch.
- How many have we lost?
- [Hornsby] Nearly all, sir.
We must leave immediately.
- I will speak to my men one last time.
- Immediately!
- I insist, Major.
- Sir, I... [Groans] My arm!
[Woman Screaming]
Immortals, attention!
Unless a man believes that there is
something great for him to do...
he can do nothing great.
A great idea springs up
in a man's soul.
It agitates his entire being.
Transports him
from the ignorant present...
and makes him feel
the future in a moment.
Reduced to our present position
by the cowardice of some...
the incapacity of others
and the treachery of many...
we are yet writing
a page in history...
that it will be impossible
to forget or erase.
You all might think
that there will be a day...
when America will leave
Nicaragua alone.
But I am here to tell you, flat out...
that that day will never happen...
because it is
our destiny to be here.
It is our destiny
to control you people.
So no matter how much you fight,
no matter what you think...
we'll be back...
time and time again.
By the bones of our American dead
in Rivas and Granada...
I swear that we will never abandon
the cause of Nicaragua.
Let it occupy your every
waking and sleeping thought.
From the future,
if not the present...
we may expect a just judgment.
[Gunshot]
[Machine Gun Fire]
- * Onward Christian soldiers *
- [Bomb Whistling]
* Marching as to war *
- * With the cross ofJesus *
- [Bomb Whistling]
- [Man] What about the prisoners?
- [Walker] Shoot them!
[Hornsby] You heard the colonel.
Shoot the prisoners!
- * Christ the royal master *
- [Gunshots]
- [Man Screams]
- * Leads against the foe *
* Forward into battle *
* See his banner go *
* Onward Christian soldiers *
* Marching as to war *
- * With the cross ofJesus *
- [Helicopter Whirring]
* Going on before **
[Helicopter Whirring]
**[Continues, Indistinct]
I have been instructed
by the State Department...
of the United States of America...
to return all American citizens
to their homeland.
[Excited Shouting]
Yes!
Sorry, only U.S. citizens.
Only U.S. citizens.
That's it.
U.S. citizens! U.S. citizens.
Get your hands off me!
Goddamn it, get 'em off!
[Man Shouting In Spanish]
Shoot him! Shoot him!
- [Machine Gun Fire]
- [Screams]
[Screams]
My arm.!
Please, listen to me.
[Screaming]
What is your nationality, sir?
I'm William Walker, president
of the Republic of Nicaragua!
I'm sorry, sir.
Move it out!
Colonel!
[Machine Gun Fire]
[Man Shouting Orders In Spanish]
[Spanish]
Let me say to those who invoke
the memory of Vietnam...
there is no thought...
of sending American combat
troops to Central America.
[Man Announcing]
Maneuvers designated Operation Big Pine...
are being conducted less than 10 miles
from Honduras's border with Nicaragua.
Nicaraguans consider the exercise
a serious act of aggression.
The United States insists
the maneuvers are purely defensive.
This maneuver is designed to help
the Hondurans to defend their own country.
And it doesn't... it doesn't envision
any involvement of U.S. ground forces.
[Announcer] So far, 80,000 U.S. troops
have participated in the maneuvers.
Those leading the exercises
say it's all being done...
for the sake
of peace and self-defen...
The political side of the U.S. presence
here was not lost on some of the troops.
It's kind of a show
to, like, Nicaragua.
Yeah, I think we're sendin'
a message to them.
[Baby Crying]
[Crying Continues]
[Child Crying]
[Sobbing]
**[Man Singing In Spanish]
*Did you see my *
*Family *
* We had a sweet *
*Simple glory *
* We had a gallant *
* Who works for me *
*For I *
* Was once an Immortal *
* With General Walker's *
* Gringo army *
* Yeah, I *
* Was once an Immortal *
* With William Walker's *
* Gringo army *
*Must be seven years *
* That I followed him *
*All across *
* The southern sea *
*And I never *
* Thought I'd hear the hammer *
*Beating on the iron *
* Of slavery *
*For I *
* Was once an Immortal *
* With General Walker's *
* Gringo army *
* Yeah, I *
* Was once an Immortal *
* With William Walker's *
* Gringo army *
* Yeah, I hear the order *
* Go to the barricade *
* You're going hungry *
* Without any guns *
*So, señorita *
*For the last time now *
*Share some love *
* With the unknown one *
*For I *
* Was once an Immortal *
* With General Walker's *
* Gringo army *
* Yeah, I *
* Was once an Immortal *
* With William Walker's *
* Gringo army *
**[Vocalizes]
* Yeah, I *
*Became an Immortal *
*In William Walker's *
* Gringo army **
**[Ends]