[Man Narrating]
There she stretches, a wide-open country...
facin' what some history fellers
are bound to call a restless period.
Nobody seems to know
what started people...
pullin'up stakes and shiftin'about.
But every day,
they're pushin'past the Missouri...
and across the rollin'Kansas plains...
stoppin'here and there
to build a settlement or a railroad...
ploughin'fields, raisin'a crop,
then movin'on again...
their eyes fixed
on the shinin'mountains.
Cattle drives block their paths sometimes.
Outlaws turn back the faint-hearted.
Still, they roll on westward
in covered wagons...
on horseback and afoot...
every man jack lookin'
for somethin'different-
some for land
to replace worn-out acres...
some for new opportunities,
and some probably just for the devil of it.
Yes, sir, here it is, 1891.
You'd think everybody'd gone
where he was goin'.
Why, right here in
this little Kansas town...
there ain't a day
people don't pack up and start out...
east or west...
dependin' on how they feel...
bringin' their wagons here
for me to patch up and mend...
load with axle grease.
Then they're off again.
Thanks for the outline
of American history...
but all I asked was,
where do the Daltons live?
Fine folks, the Daltons.
You a friend of theirs?
Knew 'em 20 years ago back in Missouri.
That so?
Too bad about Frank gettin' killed
by outlaws in Indian territory.
He was the marshal down there.
Got elected the year
Annie married Tom Freeman.
I understand Ben
has a farm around here.
It's the best farm in the county.
If they'd only run a few cattle
on that lower 40.
But you can't tell Ben nothin',
nor Bob either for that matter.
And once you get in an argument
with Grat, you got Emmett in your hair.
You couldn't be persuaded to tell me
where the Daltons live, could you?
I've only got a few hours
before the stage leaves for Guthrie.
What you wanna go to Guthrie for?
Well, I've got business-
- I wouldn't be hung in that town.
I got drunk there once with an Indian.
Like to had smallpox.
Listen.
If I ask you just one question,
will you answer "yes" or "no"?
Well, I'd be glad to, stranger.
Is the Dalton farm close to town?
Yes.
- Good.
And no.
It's two miles out on the state road.
But the bridge
across Wash Creek's down...
so you gotta take
the Franklinville Pike...
as far as the schoolhouse.
The schoolhouse, hmm?
- You'll see a windmill there.
A windmill.
But that's Jim Carter's,
and he's gone to Kansas City.
But there's a road down that goes-
- Thanks very much, but I think I can find it.
If you're gonna be around here
for a while, young fella, look me up.
We'll get together
and swap stories.
I'm not stayin' that long.
Gabby sort of a feller.
~~ [Parlour]
Uh, you on the end,
move over a little.
Little more, please.
Little more.
You see anything green
around here?
Sorry, it was funny.
- You better dry up and blow away.
[Gunfire]
Now, Nancy! I'm goin'!
Now- Get away from me!
Let go! Look out!
That gun's liable to go off!
- Now, Nancy- [Shouts, Indistinct]
Nancy, don't you do anything
you'll be sorry for!
I won't. But if you don't
get away from there...
you baby-faced prairie dog,
I'll shoot ya right through that fella's vest!
No!
[Nancy] Come on!
Get away from there, you coward!
I'll teach you to run around
with that fuzzy-headed blonde!
Leave me alone! Let go!
- If we get shot, mister, it's all your fault!
Give me that gun, Nancy.
Not until I've had one more shot
at that overstuffed tomcat.
Carryin' on with another woman!
And his kisses still hot on my lips!
- [Laughter]
Why, that-
Come here, come here, come here.
I'll cool him off.
Where are those supplies I sent you for?
[Clears Throat]
S-So help me, Bob...
I was goin' after 'em
when I was waylaid.
Well, you'll start waylaying a new job
if you don't get movin'. Go on!
Well, I'm goin'.
Come on! Give me that gun,
just for one more shot!
- Come on, Nancy. Come on.
Just one more!
- Come on. Come on.
[Gunshot]
- Help! Save me, mister! Save me!
Don't let him shoot me!
Come on! Get out from behind there,
you yellow little pup!
[Gunfire Continues]
Oh, he's got an awful temper!
Don't let him shoot-
[Laughing]
- Look out!
Sorry.
[Laughing]
It was funny, wasn't it?
- Yeah!
It was kind of funny.
- [Laughing Continues]
But I know a funnier one.
[All Laughing]
Hey, what is this?
[Continues, Indistinct]
Hey. Come on.
- Let me up!
Thinks he's a funny guy! Punch ya-
- Why, what's going on?
How'd you come to go in there?
[Sighs]
If you ain't a sight!
Can't you keep out of trouble
even on my birthday?
Ah, I slipped, Ma.
- Ah, you slipped!
And you, Emmett.
Look at that shirt!
And just when the man's all ready
to take our picture.
Why didn't you stop him, Bob?
- I did, Ma, but-
That's the fella that started it.
The idea of a grown man
picking on a boy! I'd like to-
Don't hit 'im, Ma.
- Yeah, come on.
Maybe you'd like to try that again.
What is this, the best two out of three?
- Any way you want it!
Now, wait a minute! Wait a minute!
- Ah, listen, you-
Grat, stop it!
Let's get the picture taken.
I got ploughin' to do.
- Wait a minute.
Bob, Grat, Emmett, Ben?
Yeah?
- Dalton?
Yeah.
You wanna make somethin' out of it?
- [Laughs]
And to think
I didn't recognize that brogue.
What brogue?
- Happy birthday, Ma Dalton.
You-
- Just a moment!
I'll handle this meself.
Young man, I ought to slap you.
- It wouldn't be the first time, Ma.
Remember the scrawny kid on the
next farm that gave you all the mumps?
Tod Jackson, as I live!
- [All Chattering]
Well, well, if you ain't
a sight for sore eyes.
It's nice to see you, Ma.
- What's the idea of you two
pickin' on your best friend?
I didn't know who he was.
Well, I guess that makes us even
for the time I pushed you down the well.
Come on. This calls for a celebration.
Drinks are on you, Grat.
No, you don't. There'll be no drinkin'
till after the picture's taken.
Ah, Ma!
- You heard me!
Go get yourself some dry clothes.
- I'll pick up Tod's things first.
Yeah.
- What are you doin' out here, Tod?
I'm on my way to Guthrie. I'm going
to practice law there with my friend.
What's the matter with our town?
- It's lively enough.
There's room for
a good lawyer right here.
We could team up.
I put 'em in, you get 'em out.
You're not goin' anywhere
until you visit with us a while.
Yeah, we're givin' Ma
a birthday party tonight.
Like to have you see the farm, Tod.
- Well, I-
I'd like to, Ben, but-
- Sure! You'll have to stay, Tod,
until I wash your clothes.
Why, look at them.
- I guess that settles it.
Where's the telegraph office?
I gotta send a message to my friend.
It's down at the railroad station. I'll go
with you. The boys'll take care of the bag.
You'll do no such thing.
Tod'll go by himself.
I'm having that picture taken
if it's the last thing I do.
Hurry along, now.
- Meet us here when you're through.
All right.
- Got everything now?
[Voices Overlapping]
Oh, Bob? Bob Dalton?
Can I speak to you a moment?
- All right, Mr Winters.
I'll be right back, Ma.
- All right, hurry.
Come on. I got it.
- Come on, boys.
Anything wrong?
- No, no, no.
What size glove does your mother wear?
Oh. Darned if I know.
Well, find out for me, will you, please?
I wanna bring a little gift
to the party tonight.
Yeah, sure, I'll find out.
Emmett'll know.
Hey, where's the telegraph operator?
Down near the cattle chute
somewhere.
Thanks.
[Lowing]
One, two, three...
four, five, six...
seven, eight, nine...
10, 11, 12, 13-
I'm looking for
the telegraph operator.
15, 16. That's me.
17, 18, 19, 20.
I'd like to send a message.
- 21 - 21 -
Write it out, please. 22-
- Pencil?
22- 22-
23.
- Paper?
23, 24, 26...
27-
- You missed 25.
25, 26, 27-
- What's the date?
28.
- Thanks.
29, 30, 31...
32, 33, 3-
33, 34, 35.
How many do you make it, Miss Julie?
- 35,Joe.
There you are.
Can I help you?
Thank you.
I can take your message now.
"John Payne, Guthrie, Oklahoma.
Delayed. See you next week."
You could have five more words
for the same price.
What do you suggest?
- Well, I only send the telegrams.
It's going to take me quite a little time
to put what I'm thinking into five words.
Maybe I'd better come back tonight.
- We close promptly at 6.00.
But I can get in touch with you
at your home if it was important.
Not very well. I'm going to a party.
- Really? So am I.
It couldn't be the same one.
- Oh.
Too bad. Say, how would this be
for the rest of the telegram?
"Am greatly impressed with Kansas."
Not very original,
but the meaning is clear.
How soon could I come back
for an answer?
I can give you one now.
You're wasting your time. Stop.
Come home at once. Goodbye.
~~ [Fiddle, Accordion]
What's her name?
- I wish I knew.
But she was sure beautiful.
- Oh, that's a great help.
Can you supply
any more lurid details?
Well, her features
were the usual kind...
but, uh, they were
put together so cleverly.
Oh. Well, I'm gettin' warm.
What kind of eyes did she have?
Sort of soft sapphire.
Sort of soft sapphire? Let's you and I
approach this from another angle.
Where'd you see her?
- Down at the cattle pen.
[Laughter, Shouting]
~~ [Singing, Indistinct]
- [Voices Overlapping]
Blindfold her.
- Yeah, tie it good! Come on, Ozark!
Yeah, tie it good.
Come on, Ozark! Ozark!
You don't have to worry about me, honey.
I'm a one-woman man.
Ozark!
- Hey, Ozark!
Go on, get out,
and don't scratch the buggy!
- Oh!
Scat! I'm comin'! Go on! Go on!
Come on, Ozark!
- Ozark!
Hey, Ozark!
- Come on, Ozark!
Hurry it up! Come on!
What's goin' on here?
- A little more up there. Here we go.
There you go, Ma.
- [Laughing]
Oh! There ya are!
Happy birthday, Ma!
- Happy birthday, Ma!
For land's sakes!
- Do you like it, Ma?
Oh, do I like it?
Why, it's wonderful!
Oh, boys, you shouldn't have done it.
Now you can drive to town in style.
I think I'm going to cry.
- Oh!
But I'm not usin' my new hankie!
- [Laughter]
Ah, give me a loan of yours,
Mr Winters.
If things turn out all right, honey,
I'll get you one of these for your birthday.
Oh, Ozark.
- Oh, that ain't nothin'.
How about you and me
steppin' off in a dance?
Dance, did you say?
Clear out of the way, boys.
[All Chattering]
~~ [Continues]
Fine woman,
that mother of yours, Ben.
Yeah, yeah, she is.
You know, she can milk a cow
just as fast as a man.
Hmm?
- Mm-hmm.
It's too bad it's so dark. I'd like to
show you around the farm, Tod.
I can see it tomorrow, Ben.
I'm planning to stay over.
Good. I'm anxious for ya to see it.
We got some mighty good land.
Runs clear down to the creek,
and every bit of it planted in wheat.
Yes, sir. Mighty good land.
Plenty of snow in winter,
and not enough rain in summer to do-
Oh.
So this was the party.
Well, hello.
I'm certainly glad to see you're here.
Really?
- You didn't pay me for that telegram.
Hey, there. Hello, Julie.
- Oh, hello, Bob.
Thank you.
Forgive me for being late...
but this telegram came for you
just as I was closing up.
Oh, what's it say?
They want you to leave for Benton
immediately to testify at some trial.
I was afraid of that.
Oh, I'm sorry. Tod, this is Miss Julie King.
This is my old friend, Tod Jackson.
How do you do?
Julie's gonna marry me
if I ever stay home long enough.
I've already met Mr Jackson.
Yes, we, uh-
we sent a telegram together.
Oh. Yeah, yeah,
I forgot about that.
By the way, Julie, Tod was telling me about
some mysterious girl he met this afternoon.
How interesting.
- Oh, it wasn't important.
According to Tod,
she was a strange-looking girl
with funny eyes like, uh-
What were they like, Tod?
- I forget.
Sapphires. Yeah, that's it.
Sort of a soft sapphire.
[Ma] Julie!
- Happy birthday, Ma!
Oh! Thank you, darlin'.
I want you to come and see
what the boys gave me.
- All right, dear.
Uh, you wouldn't try
and steal my girl, would you, partner?
Oh, I hadn't the slightest idea
she was your girl.
[Man]
Bob Dalton!
Bob Dalton! Bob!
What's the matter, Martin?
- They put me off my farm.
Who did?
- Rigby and his surveyors.
Said the place belonged to the Kansas
Land and Development Company.
I've lived there 10 years.
I worked that land. It's my home.
Nobody can put you off your farm
if you've got a properly recorded deed.
Isn't that so, Mr Winters?
- That's the law, Ben.
[Man]
They put Jim Hawkins off his place.
Well, if you ask me, it's about time
we were takin' the law in our own hands.
Come on, men!
- Shut up, Grat. That won't do any good.
Bob's right.
We've got to do this legally.
I suppose it's legal for Rigby
to run a new survey...
and tell a man
he don't own his own farm.
I'm for runnin' him out of the country!
- What good'll that do?
What's your opinion, Tod?
- Has anyone taken
one of these cases to court?
What's the use of wastin'our time?
All the courts are in town.
No farmer ever got a square deal
from town folks.
That's right, Tod. Somebody's got
the town folks worked up against us.
Hmm. Why, uh-
Why don't you form
an association or a grange...
like they have in some
of the eastern states?
Then you could pool your interests...
and fight this Kansas Land and
Development Company more effectively.
Would you be willing
to handle it for us, Tod?
- Hold on, Bob. I'm on my way to Guthrie.
What do you wanna ride 200 miles
to find clients for when you've got
all you need right here?
Kansas needs you
more than Oklahoma, Tod.
Well, I thought you were quite impressed
with Kansas, Mr Jackson.
Looks like I have a job.
Gee, thanks, Tod!
- [Voices Overlapping]
[Woman Screaming]
She's gonna kill me!
You keep away from me! Oh!
Oh, dear! Oh, Ozark, help me!
What are they fightin' about?
Me.
- [Laughter]
More chicken
before I put it away?
If I eat another piece,
I'll cackle.
Or lay an egg.
When did you first meet Bob?
On the Fourth of July.
He put a firecracker
under my chair.
Nice, romantic beginning.
I hated him.
- What made you change your mind?
Bob changed it for me.
When he wants anything,
he has the manners of a locomotive.
That's funny.
- What?
I'm like that too.
That's fine. And suppose
you get up a little steam...
get back to town
and do some work.
Oh, now,
why did you have to bring that up?
No good lawyer takes more than
three hours for luncheon.
I'm not such a good lawyer, Julie.
I haven't made much headway
with those land grabs.
But you've only
been here a week.
In that time,
I've accomplished absolutely nothing.
I haven't an idea in my head.
Well, I don't know.
I think you've got a lot of ideas.
Come on. Get up. Get up, lazy.
Ah. The key to success.
There's something restful about
watching a woman work.
Yeah, so I've noticed.
Where'll I put it?
Must be the family man in me.
Over there
should impress the customers.
Nice day for a picnic.
We went on a picnic yesterday...
the day before,
and for eight days before that.
Today, we're going
to finish this office.
Come on, now. Get to work.
Still a nice day for a picnic.
Have you heard
when Bob's coming home?
No.
Why couldn't Bob be a lowdown,
no-account worthless Indian?
But he isn't, so I'm going
to Guthrie where I belong.
What about your work here?
If you think I'm gonna stick around
and watch you and Bob Dalton
raise a family, you're crazy.
I can't help it
if I'm in love with you.
If I were a man in love with a girl
who was engaged to somebody else...
I'd-I'd go to that other person
and tell him how I felt.
And what do you suppose
he'd think if I did?
I don't suppose he'd like it.
That's why I'm going to Guthrie.
Oh, you're like all lawyers.
You can talk well enough in court...
but you haven't the courage
of your convictions.
If you loved this girl,
you'd do something about it.
I'm open to suggestions.
- Well, I think-
I mean- Oh, go to Guthrie!
Oh, Tod.
We're in an awful mess.
- [Footsteps Approaching Rapidly]
Excuse me.
Has this place got a back door?
- No.
I guess I'd better get back to my office
before the shooting starts.
Huh? Tod, wait a minute.
- Yeah?
How much would
two divorces cost me?
If the judge were reasonable,
about 10 years.
- Oh.
Oh!
It ain't worth it.
[Clicking Tongue]
Ben! Ben!
Ben!
- What is it?
Rigby and his men are surveying our land.
- Where are they?
Down in the lower pasture.
- Go get Grat.
Here they come, Rigby.
All right, keep on working.
I'll handle it.
What are you doing on our land?
I'm afraid you've made
a mistake, my friend.
According to our survey, your line ends
on the other side of the road.
You're not gonna pull that game
on us, Rigby. Get out of here.
I don't want any trouble with you, Dalton.
We've got a job to do here, and-
Your job is over!
- Emmett! Emmett!
Look out, Emmett!
All right, pick him up
and get out of here!
[Man]
His head must've hit on the rock.
What's the matter?
Why don't you get him up?
He's dead.
- Dead?
Maybe you'll stay off
other people's property after this.
Better take him up to the house.
The only way to find out who's behind this
Kansas Land and Development Company...
is have someone go to the capital
and search the records.
Sounds like a good idea.
I'll get busy on it.
But it's too bad
you're leaving us, Jackson.
Well, I'm sure you'll be able
to handle it better than I could.
Besides, you know everyone around here.
- Well, people are gonna be
mighty disappointed.
But our loss is Guthrie's gain.
[Chattering]
I wonder what's going on down there.
[Winters]
Jim! Yo, Jim!
What's all the excitement?
- We just arrested Ben Dalton.
What happened?
- He killed one of Rigby's surveyors.
I'd better get down there.
- This change your plans, Jackson?
I'll let you know.
[Door Opens, Closes]
You fellers wouldn't-
- No!
Oh.
A judge couldn't perform
a marriage ceremony, could he?
You'll have to wait
till court's over.
We'll wait.
You are upset, aren't you?
Not about the trial.
Still going to Guthrie
when it's over?
There's nothing else
for me to do.
Please close the door a minute.
Look, Tod, you may not have guessed it,
but we aren't children.
I was doing all right with my life
till you popped up.
Why won't you let me talk to Bob?
- I can't, Julie. Bob's my friend.
All right, he's your friend. Is that sacred
relationship all that's left in the world?
What about me?
- I know it's unfair to you, Julie-
"Unfair." Aren't you noble?
According to your beautiful ideals,
I'm supposed to crawl away
somewhere and die...
so that you and Bob can be friends.
Oh, there you are.
- Bob, we were afraid
you wouldn't get here.
Got here as soon as I could.
Hello, Julie.
Say, what is this whole thing
all about?
Rigby. He's making a lot
over an unfortunate accident.
- Uh-huh.
But we haven't got
anything to worry about.
How's Ben takin' it?
- Worrying more about his planting
than the trial.
He would.
Oh, darling, you're beautiful.
Haven't changed your mind
about her eyes, have you, Tod?
He's got other things to think about.
Well, I think I'll leave
you two old friends to talk this over.
I imagine Bob would like
to see Ben before the trial.
Yeah, yeah, I would.
I'd better go and cheer him up at that.
Oh. Almost forgot.
I got this for you
in Benton, Julie.
Know what kind of a stone it is?
Sapphire. Here.
- Why, it's beautiful, isn't it, Tod?
Yes.
Oh, I don't want you to feel slighted.
Here. See you in court.
I hope you have
more to say for Ben.
Good luck, Ben.
- Thank you, Julie.
We're all behind ya.
- That's nice of you, Mr Winters.
How do you feel, Ben?
Sit down right here.
Hello, Ozark.
You think you got troubles.
Kinfolk?
- Nearly.
Everybody rise.
Hear ye, hear ye.
The court of the 18th district
of the state of Kansas is now in session.
Judge Lucius Thorndyke presiding.
Be seated.
The case of the People v. Ben Dalton.
Is the State ready?
Ready, Your Honour.
[Judge]
Defence ready?
Ready, Your Honour.
I object!
- Object to what?
[Laughter]
- I apologize, Your Honour.
Proceed with the selection
of the jury.
Would you, uh, have any scruples against
inflicting the death penalty, Mr Osborne?
Not me.
- The State accepts Jim Osborne.
[Judge] You may question
the prospective juror, Mr Jackson.
If it please the court, the defence
has full confidence in Mr Osborne...
in spite of the fact that
he once was accused of stealing a horse.
Objection, Your Honour!
This juror isn't on trial.
Nobody ever proved
I stole that horse!
Counsel will refrain
from personal remarks.
I apologize, Your Honour.
I'm sure the gentleman
who told me about it was mistaken.
Who said I stole that horse?
What's his name?
I believe it was, uh,
juror number three, Mr Norris.
Who, me?
I never said no such thing!
Any time Jim Osborne wants to steal
a horse, that's his business.
What do you mean, that's my business?
I sold that horse to Ed Pickett.
Didn't I, Ed?
Well, I paid for it. But when I went to
the barn the next morning, it was gone...
and two sets of harness with it!
Why, you-
- [All Shouting]
We can't let Jackson get away with this.
Those are our men.
I'm afraid my learned colleague
knows that as well as we do.
Order! Order!
Take your hands off my pistol!
- [Shouting Stops]
This court will be forced
to dismiss Jim Osborne...
Ed Pickett and Pete Norris
from jury service.
Fifteen minutes' recess.
I see. Well, now, Mr Rigby...
suppose you tell us in your own words
just what happened.
Well, I'd taken my surveying crew out
to verify the boundary...
of the Kansas Land
and Development Company's property.
Objection, Your Honour. The defence
can prove by three witnesses...
that Rigby and his men
were on the Dalton farm.
Is this true, Mr Rigby?
- It is not.
We've just filed a complaint
against the Daltons for trespassing.
We've owned that property for 10 years!
- [All Shouting]
There'll be no more demonstrations
in this court!
What occurred next?
Emmett there picked up the surveying
instrument and broke it on a rock.
Then what happened?
Ben Dalton rode up
behind Mason...
and smashed his head in
with the barrel of his gun.
That's a lie!
- Hey, get that man!
[Yelling, Shouting]
[Man]
Come on! Break it up!
Grat, stop! Stop it!
- Come on! Break it up!
[Judge]
Order!
- Pull yourself together!
Order! Order! Order!
Is there any doubt about the character
of the Daltons after this display?
Your Honour, I demand a mistrial!
- Denied!
And lock that man up
for contempt of court!
You'll lock nobody up!
And I'm taking Ben outta here too.
Come on, Ben.
- You can't do this, Bob.
Sheriff, arrest that man!
This community is going
to learn to obey the law!
Why should we obey laws that are twisted
to fit the needs of thieves and liars?
Take it easy, Bob.
- Arrest him!
He's a deputy marshal.
- Don't let that stop you, Sheriff.
I'm fed up with the law around here. This
court can accept my resignation right now!
Wait a minute, Bob.
Come on! Get goin', boys!
Step out, Grat.
- [Women Screaming]
Drop that gun!
- I said, step out, Grat!
[Woman Screams]
Bob!
- Grat, get Ben out of here. Come on!
Bob-
- Come on!
Sorry about this, Julie. I'll get in touch
with ya. Thanks for tryin', Tod.
Hey, wait for me!
- [Chattering, Shouting]
Order! Order! Order! Order!
Thanks, Bob. You got me
out of there just in time.
This ain't right, Bob.
- Nothin's right any more.
Go on! Go on, get going!
They've got our horses!
Hey, will you stop that?
What do you think you're doin'?
Just keepin' in practice
in case we ever do get any food.
Gee, we oughta know somebody around
here that can sneak us in something to eat.
[Person Whistles]
- There's Bob.
Is Ma all right?
- Did you see Tod?
Couldn't get through. Posse's blockin'
every road. Take a look at that.
Seems we robbed another bank
and got away with a thousand dollars.
That makes me ashamed of myself.
Why do they print lies like that? We
haven't been 60 feet away from this barn!
Give a dog a bad name.
Yeah, they're blamin' us
for every crime in the country.
What's gonna happen to Ma?
- And the farm?
Listen. "Local firemen hold
annual pie-eating contest-"
Shut up, will ya?
- Well, Bob, what are we gonna do?
I don't know!
That's great.
We go home, they hang us.
We stay here, we starve to death.
Bob.
Couldn't we take our fight to another
county where we could get a fair trial?
That's a good idea, Ben, but it
takes money. We haven't got it.
Suppose I know a way
to get a hold of some money.
How?
- Grat, we ain't gonna get
in any more trouble.
I'm with you, Grat.
- You're right here in this barn with Ben,
and you'll stay here till I tell you to leave!
What's on your mind, Grat?
Remember our old friends, the Kansas
Land and Development Company?
- Yeah.
The Benton stage carries
their payroll every Wednesday.
If you ask me,
this is a crazy idea.
All this monkey business
just to hold up a stagecoach.
If it'd been me,
I'd just stick it up and get it over with.
Aw, Grat, Bob generally knows
what he's doin'.
He does everything for the b-
[Howling]
That's enough.
There's only one stagecoach.
We'll do it different this time.
Pull up!
Ben!
- Emmett, somebody's comin'!
[Shouting]
It's Ben.
Where have you been?
We thought we'd go down home
and see how everything was.
And?
- They burned the house! Ma's gone!
Where's Emmett?
- I couldn't hold him, Bob.
He acted like he was crazy.
Got on his horse and went toward town!
- Give me this horse, will ya?
No! Come here!
- Let me go!
Hold it a minute!
- No!
[Telegraph Machine Tapping]
Anybody see you?
- I don't know. Where's Ma?
What have they done with her?
She's all right. Quick.
In the baggage room, out of sight.
Where is Ma, Julie?
They didn't hurt her, did they?
She's all right.
She's with Tod.
Anyway, you'd all go after her.
How long since you've
had anything to eat, Emmett?
- I don't know. I ain't hungry.
You'll feel better after you've had
something. I'll get my lunch box.
There he is!
- Run!
Get out of here! Get out of here! You've
got no right in here! Get away from me!
[Shots Firing]
Come on! Open the door!
Let go of me! Let go of me! Let go of me!
- Come on!
Drop that gun!
- [Shouting]
We're gonna get Grat
sooner or later!
We got him!
Come on, boys!
Get him up to the square!
Makin' up lies. Drivin' 'em away
with a price on their heads.
Burnin' our home. Why?
- I wish I knew.
If it's the land they want,
tell 'em they can have it if-
if they'll just leave
my boys alone.
I've, uh, I've tried to talk to Rigby,
but I can't get anywhere.
For some reason-
- Tod, they've caught Emmett!
Where is he?
- A mob has him. They're taking him
down the street. Quickly!
[All Shouting]
Somebody bring a rope!
Get back, all of you! Get back!
[Groaning]
Tod!
I'm all right, Julie.
What can we do?
How can we stop them, Tod?
Wait!
Out of my way!
Out of my way, you scum!
Leave my boy alone,
you dirty heathens!
For shame on all of you!
Is it a pack of wild animals you are?
Don't let that old woman stop ya!
- "Old woman," is it?
I might have known
you were responsible for this!
You're to blame for
whatever my boys have done!
Why don't you hang him?
[All Shouting]
Climb in! Come on! Get in!
Oh, Ma! Oh, Ma! Ma!
He's all right, Ma. Really, he is.
- [Wailing]
We'd better get her out of here.
Some of you ladies help me, please.
[Yelling]
In here, you.
We'll take over
from here, Sheriff.
Come on. In you go.
You all right, Emmett?
Go on. Get goin'.
- Yeah.
Lock it!
Where do we go from here?
- Just relax.
[Shouting]
[Men Shouting: Faint]
Hello. Operator, get me
the sheriff's office in Benton.
Yeah. Quick! What? What?
All right! Hey! Get something
to smash in the door with!
The sheriff won't shoot anybody!
Plenty of horses out there.
- Yeah, if we could get to 'em.
I've been thinkin', Bob. Maybe if I went
out there and talked to those people...
I could make 'em
understand about-
Oh, you'd just be
wastin' your breath, Ben.
Only thing that mob'll
understand is a bullet.
Yeah, and maybe they'll get one.
Say, Bob, I got an idea-
- Save it.
[Ringing]
Hello?
He's tied up right now.
Get down!
[Banging Continues]
- [Man] Come on out here!
One more like that oughta bring 'em in.
- Yeah. Get ready.
We'll get 'em out!
Lookin' for somebody?
It's the Daltons! All of'em!
[Shots Firing]
Go, boy!
You all know me.
We've got no quarrel.
I'm just a farmer,
like some of you.
I've got nothing against anybody-
- [Shot Fires]
[All Muttering, Indistinct]
[All Clamouring]
Get out of here!
[Train Engine Chugging]
[Train Whistle Blowing]
I hear the Daltons stuck up
number four last night.
Yeah, but it'll take more than
them boys to slow me down.
All right.
You'd better get ready.
Think you can make it, Emmett?
- Don't worry about me. I'm all right.
All right. You and Grat
Take the other side. Go on!
Come on! Huh!
You ready?
Now, you take that one
and I'll take this one.
All right.
- Now, Emmett, you keep
your back to that door...
and don't you take no sass
off of nobody.
Now, do it. Go on.
All right, everybody! Reach! Reach!
- [Woman Screams]
Come on. You take the engine.
I can handle this.
Start opening that safe.
"Daltons believed operating
with Dulin gang.
"Posses search countryside
as former Dalton hideout discovered.
"Daltons kill express messenger
in another daring train robbery.
State offers $ 15,000 reward
for capture of Daltons."
Gets worse every day.
I don't think I'll ever
quite understand it.
The family we knew-
what's happened to it?
We can't go on like this, Julie.
No matter what happens to Bob,
we have our own lives to live.
Tomorrow, we're going to be married.
- Oh, Tod, darling, we can't.
[Hoof Beats Approaching]
- Not till we've told him.
Hey, Sheriff, think they might
be hiding out here in Oklahoma?
In this state? I wish they was.
We'd soon corral 'em.
Well, it's too bad they ain't.
Sure put a feather in your cap
if you could catch 'em...
now that election's coming up.
Wouldn't do no harm.
- [Man] Sheriff! Sheriff! Sheriff!
They're here!
- Who's here?
In Pete's Caf!
- Who's in Pete's Caf?
The Daltons.
- Oh.
Oh, in-in Pete's?
- Yeah.
Well, well, we've gotta do
something about it!
Here. Get everybody in town! Surround
the place! Tell them to bring their guns!
Get your gun. I'll get mine.
- Let's go!
So I says to myself, says I...
them Daltons might never come around
these parts, and then again, they might.
And if they should,
I'm one fella that's prepared for them.
Now, suppose they come here
like you fellas did.
You're sittin' around eatin' your vittles,
and you pay no attention to me.
And I'm putterin' around here
with my salt and pepper.
Come up like that. I gotcha.
What could you do?
Oh. I see.
Nice balance. One like
you used to have, Emmett.
No, mine had a longer barrel.
- My granddaddy said
it was the best-shoot-
Did you say "Emmett"?
Grat.
Bob.
Oh, excuse me. This is Clem Wilson.
He's probably new to you.
How are ya?
- I never heard of him.
Funny, me talkin'
about you fellas like that...
and here you are
right in my own place.
[Chuckles]
Nobody'll believe me.
They say I'm the biggest liar
in this town.
Here.
- No, no. Keep it. It's no good anyhow.
Will you have a piece of pie
or something?
Have a lot of pie.
They're free.
Thanks very much.
Come on, everybody- Ow!
Get your guns! They got the Daltons
cornered in Pete's Restaurant!
They got the Daltons cornered!
Come on!
Ain't you gonna help 'em, honey?
I sure am!
All right, you Daltons!
Come out with your hands up!
Take a look in the back!
What's all the shootin' about?
- Dalton boys down at the rest-
Is that so?
Hyah! Get out of here!
Not a chance out the back way.
All right. All right.
Looks like you joined up with us
at the wrong time, Clem.
Yeah. Don't it?
[Bullet Whizzes]
- Ho! Hey, dag-blame it!
Now, watch where your shootin'!
Get that stagecoach out of the way!
The Daltons are in there!
Well, I'm out here, and it ain't
gonna do them Daltons no good...
if you shoot one of my six horses!
Well, get out of there, I tell ya!
- I'll get out of here and I'll stop it!
Quit shootin'!
And that goes for you in there too!
Good old Ozark.
Come on! Hurry! Let's go.
Get 'em out of there, I tell ya.
- Can't you see my horses are all nervous...
and you're a-shootin?
They cost $50 apiece!
Now, stop it and get out of there!
And you get out too!
You stop it in there!
Well, I think they're all ready now.
Hyah! Get out of here!
Hold your fire.
I guess we got 'em.
Any of you Daltons still alive,
come out with your hands up!
What's the matter? They all dead?
- Dead?
They looked mighty lively
climbin' in that stagecoach.
What? Get your horses, men!
And they didn't pay for nothin' neither.
Nice goin', Ozark.
- Hyah!
Come on!
Hey, Ozark.
Look what I brought ya.
Oh, thanks, Grat!
Mmm! Lemon too!
Whoa!
- No! Come on, come on, Ozark!
It was my pie!
- All right. Come on. Let it go!
Oh, that's thanks for ya.
It was good too!
Hey, here they come!
Never saw anybody like you, Bob!
Oh, come on, will ya?
- [Shouts]
[Shouting]
Wait a minute. We're not
getting anywhere with this.
We'll get rid of the coach. Come on.
- [Shouts]
[Yelling, Indistinct]
[Yelling Continues]
Hey, hurry up!
They're gettin' closer!
Hey, Bob!
Hey, what about me?
I ain't no butterfly!
Bob!
Grat! Clem! Somebody gonna
get me off of here?
[Wailing]
Come on, boy!
How are we doin'?
- Not so good!
[Horse Whinnying]
[Whinnying Continues]
[Men Shouting, Indistinct]
[Horses Whinnying]
Giddy-up! Giddy-up!
If we don't get some faster horses
pretty soon, we're gonna have company.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
- What about an iron horse?
[Train Engine Chugging]
Looks like we lost 'em.
- Yeah.
Close, though, wasn't it?
- We're safe enough now.
Top of this car
fits me a lot better...
than that harness horse
I was just astride of.
Now that we're rid of those deputies,
what do you say we make
this train pay dividends?
No sense passing on that.
- Take a look, Emmett.
Get away from here, quick!
Listen. Did you hear
something on the roof?
Probably one of them Daltons
up there ropin' a calf.
If this is a new game
we're playin', I don't like it.
What's the matter with you?
- We gotta get off this train.
It's loaded with deputies.
There must be a hundred or more in those
coaches back there, and look up there.
Hey, there must be something
pretty valuable aboard.
Yeah. They even brought their horses along
to chase us with when we take it.
Looks interesting.
Let's have a quick look. Come on.
Those Daltons'd be surprised
if they stuck up this train.
Aw, they ain't within a hundred
miles of here. Go on. Deal.
[Knocking]
- Who is it?
Deputy Smith.
All right. Come on. Freeze.
Drop 'em. Come on. Come on.
All right. Get over there.
Get over there.
Come on. Get 'em up.
Lay on the floor now.
All of you.
Fella in town told me the Daltons
had been seen way out in California.
Bet four bits.
Just a waste of time
getting us to guard this train.
I'll raise you a buck.
Give me a hand with this thing.
All right. Toss it out now.
All right. The party's over.
Come on, now. Outside.
All right. Come on. Let's jump.
- Wait a minute.
Why not take the horses?
- Why not?
I want the pretty one.
- Why?
Well, you made me lose
my lemon pie, didn't you?
Go on!
- Watch out for that first step!
All right! Go on!
What are you waiting for?
Hey, wait a minute! Look! Look!
- What is it?
I'd have sworn that was
Grat Dalton we just passed.
Grat Dalton?
[Chuckling]
Hey, wait a minute! Look!
There goes another one!
Looked like Emmett.
- Emmett? Emmett?
Will you stop seeing outlaws
and let us finish this game?
Well, it did look like him,
anyway.
[Bob] Come on, Ozark.
Get him out of here.
But I'll eat my shirt
if that ain't Ozark Jones!
Well, that may not be Ozark Jones,
but that's my horse!
I hope you can swim.
Come on!
[All Clamouring]
- Stop the train!
Stop the train!
[Clamouring Continues]
What happened?
- The Daltons!
They got the gold.
- They took our horses.
Eh. Well, you fellers
saved the train, anyway.
Whoa. There you are, ma'am.
Thank you.
- Hey!
Ma!
- Julie, darlin'! Oh, my dear.
Oh, it's like old times
seein' you again.
I came just as soon as I got your message.
- I knew you would.
That's all right. It's me brother Tim.
- [Man] How do.
You've had news, Ma?
Bob came home
night before last.
You mean he's there now?
Don't you want to see him, Julie?
Oh, Ma, I don't mean
to seem heartless, but...
so many things have happened.
Don't worry, darlin'.
I understand.
I'm just sorry
I brought you clear out here.
No, darling. I'll see him.
Thanks.
Giddyap.
How is Tod, Julie?
- He's fine.
Though he's been awfully busy.
Spends most of his time in Kansas City.
Still trying to help my boys?
He's never given up hope, Ma.
He's such a good friend...
but I'm afraid it's too late, darlin'.
Julie!
- Hello, Bob.
Howdy, Miss Julie!
- Remember me?
Hello, stranger. Clem Wilson.
- It's nice to see you all again.
Now she's seen the outside.
I want to talk to her alone.
Oh, I catch on.
- See you later.
I'll be upstairs if you want me.
- Thanks, Ma.
It's been kind of tough on you,
hasn't it, Julie?
Well, I guess we showed them
they picked on the wrong family.
Bob, we'd better have a talk.
I know what you're gonna say,
but don't let it worry you.
This outlaw business is all finished.
The boys are going to California,
and you and I will go to South America.
Bob, there's something
you've got to hear. I'm not going.
So we'll go to California with Grat and
Emmett, or anyplace else you want to go.
You've got to listen to me.
- I forgot how dark your hair was.
And your eyes,
they are like sapphires.
Don't you understand, Bob?
I'm not going with you.
What's the matter? You scared?
- You know it isn't that.
What's to stop us?
Are you trying to tell me-
Nah. Nobody'd try to play my hand.
You're just scared.
Did it ever occur to you
that I might've changed?
What do you mean?
- I don't love you, Bob.
I'm not sure I ever did.
- Come on. Let's hear the rest of it.
No matter what you think, what's
happened to you has nothing to do with it.
Oh, I wanted to tell you before
Ben's trial. Tod wouldn't let me.
Uh-huh. Tod Jackson!
- Wait a second!
Ma!
[Emmett]
Do you think he'll go for it?
- Why not?
Where are you going?
- I've got something to attend to.
Look, if I'm not back tonight,
don't wait for me. I'll meet you
in Denver at the Mountain Hotel.
Wait a minute, Bob.
Me and the boys have been talkin'.
How about taking over the bank
in town before we split up?
Nothing to it, Bob.
- I told you we were through, didn't I?
Now, get out of here
the way we planned- all of you.
I still think we're crazy to pass it up.
- So do I.
It'll be a long time before we're this
close to the old home town again.
Uh, Bob says we're through.
- But why?
It's a shame to leave
all that money down there.
- Yeah.
That town owes us plenty.
- It sure does.
It sounds good, but what
about Bob's orders?
He won't even know about it
till we give him his share.
What about it?
Sure is a pretty girl
works in that bank.
[Knocking]
- Come in.
Hello, Jackson.
Come in. Come in.
Been up to the capital, I hear.
Did you also hear I found
what I was looking for?
Oh, you mean the Kansas Land
and Development Company.
Yes, I did. Uh, sit down, sit down.
You covered up pretty cleverly
with your holding company,
dummy directors and Rigby, didn't you?
They all served their purpose.
And a very profitable purpose,
I might add. Have a cigar.
You mean the railroad that's taken
that land off your hands for a right of way.
You know everything, don't you?
- Including something you overlooked.
Did you ever hear of
a federal grand jury, Winters?
Oh-ho! You're wasting your time.
I've faced lots of them.
You should know it takes years
for those fellows to vote on indictment.
Well, there's one jury that won't be out
long when they get this information.
Drop in any time, Jackson.
And they have a price too.
But, uh, you won't like paying it.
[Door Opens, Shuts]
Ring the sheriff's office.
Quick!
Where are they?
Right! Bill! George!
Bob! Have you gone
completely crazy?
This town's swarming with marshals.
- You're awful worried about me, ain't ya?
Why didn't you stay where you were?
I would have come, had you sent for me.
I bet you would. Well, I couldn't wait.
I just had to see you.
Well, I have news for you.
- Yeah?
Something that might give your boys
a chance to come back.
I've found out Caleb Winters is head of the
Kansas Land and Development Company.
That's fine. There wouldn't be anything
personal you want to tell me, would there?
What?
- You've been doing all right
for yourself, haven't you?
Stop that!
- He's gonna get what's comin'to him!
You beast! Have you no decency left?
- Shut up!
You can't control our lives!
- Shut up and get out!
- Bob!
You keep out of this, Ma!
- Keep out of it?
Keep out of it, you say?
That's just the trouble.
I've kept out of it too long.
But when you turn on the only two friends
you've left in the world, then I'm gonna-
Shut up! I know what I'm doin'!
- Son!
Oh, son, what have you come to?
That's not your son, Ma.
Your son would've understood
that when Tod and I fell in love...
we could no more help ourselves than
he could help what's happened to him.
Your son would've understood that, Ma.
- Oh, Bob.
You can't make your own laws.
Why don't you go away
and leave us alone?
Do you hear me? Leave us alone!
Funny how things
get twisted, ain't it?
Oh, Bob.
- [Shots Firing]
Nobody leave this room!
Julie, will you tell Tod I'm sorry?
I will, Bob.
- [Sobs] Son!
It's all right, Ma.
Don't worry.
There's Bob!
Keep him covered!
Bob!
- I'm all right.
Lot of smart boys, aren't you?
- Well, we just-
Never mind. Where are the horses?
- In the alley.
All right. Look out.
I'm comin' in.
Grat! I'll try it first.
Give me one of your guns.
Let me go!
- Shut up. Let me have it.
All right.
- Go ahead. What are you waiting for?
Emmett!
- Get goin'.
Get over there!
Well, Ozark Jones! I've been waiting
to get my hands on you-
Nancy! Not now, Nancy!
- Well, you want to be a bandit, do ya?
Let go of my-
- Put that gun down
before I pin your ears back!
Nancy!
- [Screams]
Oh, Nancy, I'm sorry.
Honest, I didn't mean to do it, Nancy!
But I'm in an awful h-
- [Shot Fires]
[Nancy Screams]
Ozark!
This is no good.
We're gonna have to make a run for it.
How about you, Grat?
- I can make it.
All right. Hey, Clem. Come down here
where I can get ahold of you.
All right.
Ready? Come on!
Go on! I'm all right!
Go on, Emmett!
[Gunfire Ceases]
Times sure change fast
here in Kansas.
But the people keep right on
movin' around...
bringing their wagons
in here for me to mend.
And then off they go again-
some west and some south.
Pretty soon, there won't be nobody
left at home here in America.
All we want to know is, what time
does the stage leave for Guthrie?
What do you want to
go to Guthrie for?
Just a minute. Just a minute.
We have to go to Guthrie.
All we want to know is,
what time does the stage leave?
Well, they discontinued it last week.
Put it on the run
to Oklahoma City.
Say, you and your sister'd
enjoy that trip.
But we don't want to go
to Oklahoma City.
And I'm not his sister.
Come to think of it,
you don't favour each other much.
She's my wife.
- Do tell.
You know, that reminds me of a couple
that hung around here for a week once...
waitin' for the Guthrie stage.
And you know what they finally did?
- Uh-huh.
They took the train.
[Chuckles]
Now, who do you suppose told 'em?