[Thunderclap]
Hey, look at that!
Look. Right through him.
[Thunder Rumbling]
Prospector.
Skinny little feller. Them bones
ain't hardly as big as my little finger.
Let me see it.
[Thunder Rumbling]
Apache.
Apache country, ain't it?
There are a few Apaches around here.
Mostly they're farther south.
That's all we need-
to run into some crazy Indians.
All this country
around here like this?
Pretty much.
Up north there are
lots of canyons and draws...
if you know which ones are open.
Those hills over there back
right up into the mountains.
Those are salt flats down south.
[Chuckles] Even a rattlesnake
couldn't get across 'em.
[Thunderclap]
[Dog Barking]
[Barking Continues]
I wonder if she's got any plans
after she gets through ridin' that horse.
- [All Laughing]
- What'll it be?
- Well, this is a whiskey saloon, ain't it?
- We got whiskey.
- Then we'll have whiskey.
- [All Laughing]
[Clears Throat]
- Beat it.
- Give him one.
It ain't necessary.
They tell me this town was full of
Confederate sympathizers during the war.
- Is that right?
- There was some seceshes here.
I was a Union man myself.
You ask anybody. They'll tell you.
Well, what about the marshal?
He a Union man too?
I never ask a man his politics.
Where is he now?
- Around.
- No, he ain't.
He's out puttin' up tax warrants.
I seen him go.
You fellows plannin'
on bein' in town long?
Depends on what you got to offer.
Depends on what you got
on your mind, sonny.
- Where do you keep your water?
- There's a well out back.
Let's fill 'em up- all of' em.
I'll take care of my own.
[Clears Throat]
Hand me another bottle.
A full one.
Yes, sir. I sure would like
to know what she plans to do...
after she gets through
ridin' that horse.
[All Laughing]
Now lay down, everybody.
Why don't you do like he said?
Never mind, you.
Open it up.
[Horse Whinnying]
[Dog Barking]
Drop back, Jed.
Keep your eyes open.
Just like robbin' a kid's piggy bank.
I kinda liked that town.
Nice and obligin'.
Yee-ah!
[Gunshot]
- Fire!
- [Gunshots]
[Gunshots Continue]
Let 'em go! Save us
the trouble of hanging 'em.
Whoa.
Whoa! Whoa!
Them garrison soldiers
just can't take country like this.
Maybe they've got sense.
Sure was mighty inconsiderate
of old Jed to get hisself killed like that.
He owed me six bits.
I'd feel a lot better if there
were seven of us instead of six.
This desert's a mighty unlucky place.
A man needs all the odds he can get.
Hey, that reminds me.
Hadn't we better be starting back?
- Back where?
- Where we come from.
Right into the lovin' arms of the army?
Are you crazy? Why, it's a good 70 miles
across this sink. Maybe more.
It's just a place.
A place can be crossed.
Speak for yourself.
I'm easing back, soon as it's dark.
Well, that's up to you.
There's your share.
Make your choice.
[Horse Whinnies]
[Horse Trotting Off]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Gasps]
I sure never thought
I'd come to this...
but I guess I'm gonna have to trade
some whiskey for some water.
Ain't nobody gonna trade me some water
for a good swig of real nice whiskey?
[Horse Whinnying]
[Coyote Howling]
Put that back!
Give me that!
Look out, you fool!
You'll spill it!
- Give it to me!
- Oh, no, you don't!
Give it back!
Give it to me! Give it to me!
[Shouting, Struggling]
- Give it to me! Give it to me!
- Oh, no, you don't!
Leave go of his canteen...
and cut it out!
You too!
You shouldn't
oughta done that, Stretch.
You might've hurt me.
[Coyote Howling]
Oh, my poor feet.
The way they hurt.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say it was gonna rain.
Walrus, bring your horse up here.
Kind of noble, aren't you?
A horse is a useful animal.
No use lettin' him suffer
just because he belongs to a jackass.
Looks like he's not the only
jackass on this trip.
I told you we'd never make it.
Nobody said you had to come.
- [Chuckles]
- [Man Chuckles]
Old Walrus here has got nearly
a thousand dollars in his pocket.
Can't even buy hisself
a drink of water.
Don't that beat the devil?
Look at that old lizard there.
He's better off than you, Walrus.
Yes, sir, a heap better off.
That ain't right.
You got no call to do that.
What's eatin' you?
It's just a lizard.
It wasn't doin' you no hurt.
What'd you have to kill it for?
Well, of all the-
Say, what's got into you anyhow?
- A lizard!
- Shut up.
All this fuss over one little lizard.
[Panting]
If I don't get some water pretty soon...
I'm just gonna fall down and die.
Yeah, it looks that way.
Come on, boy.
Come on. Come on.
[Snickering]
[Gunshot]
I think I see...
a town over there.
- [Chuckles]
It is a town. I can see it.
I can see it! It's a town.
Water. Water!
[Chuckles]
It's a dead one.
A ghost!
[Scoffs]
[Gun Cocks]
We just come in across the sink.
[Panting]
We need water bad.
There's a spring here,
but you'll never make it.
You just point it out.
We'll make it.
It's up behind those big rocks
at the head of the street.
Get up.
Water.
[Water Flowing]
[Gasping, Sputtering]
Anybody home?
What about me
coming in for a minute?
- Stay where you are.
- What you scared of?
Nothin'.
What are you carryin' that gun for?
Ain't nobody gonna shoot nobody.
- What do you want?
- Somethin' to eat.
How long are you gonna stay here?
Four or five days maybe.
Hard to say.
It ain't far to Alkali.
You can make it easy if you try.
Horses need rest.
So do we.
I ain't got enough
in the house to feed six men.
We got money, if that's
what's botherin' you.
I don't want your money.
I just want you to get outta here.
We aim to. Meanwhile,
we can't live on fresh air.
Now, listen, lady. I don't know why
I'm standin' here arguing with you.
There's six of us, and
we usually take what we want.
Not from around here.
All right, lady.
If that's the way you feel about it.
I don't like women
who act so high and-
Why, you dirty, little-
I wouldn't go stirrin' up no trouble
with that girl if I was you, young fella.
Quite a punch
you got there, ma'am.
Come in mighty handy
when you get married.
You're right, son.
She's as tough as a pine nut.
She oughta be.
She was raised with Apaches.
- Apaches?
- Yeah. Fine people if you understand them.
- Any of 'em around here?
- Oh, from time to time.
- Come on, Grandpa.
- Just a minute.
What about that food?
Do we get it peaceful
or don't we?
Well, we might arrange
for one night, Mike...
seein' what a lean belly he's got.
I'll send a couple
of the boys up after it.
You shouldn't have given in
to him like that, Grandpa.
I know what I'm doin'.
Don't feed 'em, and right away
they begin "suspicioning."
[Laughing]
Now, you act as if nothing
had happened and leave this to me.
What you goin' to all
that trouble for, Dude?
- You ain't hardly seen her yet.
- He's seen her all right.
Course, it was kinda worm's-eye view-
him right at her feet eatin' dust.
What do you reckon a girl like her's
doin' anyway livin' in a town like this?
The old man's
a prospector, most likely.
A little loony. Lots of old-timers
like him all through these hills.
- Yeah, but her?
- Somebody's got to look after the old fool.
Hmm. Look!
Kinda cute-lookin', ain't she?
Right nice swing to them hips too.
Yeah. And when she tucks in that shirt-
Better let me help you
with that bucket, ma'am.
- Looks heavy.
- I can manage.
Just the same, ma'am, somebody oughta help
you carry that bucket up to the house.
Well, now wait a minute, lady.
You don't mean you'd shoot
a big, handsome fellow like me?
[Laughs]
If you got to shoot somebody...
why, pick on Half Pint or Walrus.
They don't amount to nothin' no how.
I've told you once.
Well, as long as I'm goin'
your way anyhow-
[Stretch] You heard what she said.
Sit down.
- But I was just-
- Shut up.
- I got a right to-
- Shut up!
You gotta hit some people
in the head with an ax.
Now, listen, all of you. I'm figurin' on
layin' up here for three or four days...
till the horses get their legs back,
and I don't want any unnecessary trouble.
- Stay away from those people.
- Listen. You ain't-
Yes, I am. I ain't talkin'
just to hear my own voice.
I'm ordering you.
If I catch any of you messin' around
that house, somebody's gonna get hurt.
- Is that clear?
- That include you too?
That includes everybody.
There's an old saloon
down at the other end of the town.
We'll bunk in it.
Gets kinda cold around here at night.
[Snoring]
- Where you goin'?
- Outside.
I can't sleep nohow with this fathead
snorin' like a wounded buffalo.
- Turn over!
- [Muttering]
[Groaning]
[Snoring Resumes]
Sure is still tonight, ain't it?
I wonder what Dude's up to.
Brother, am I sure gonna throw a shoe
if he gets anyplace with that gal.
From what I saw, she'll tear him
in two if he tries anything.
[Coyote Howling]
What are you doin' here?
Lookin' for one of my men.
I told you if anybody came up here,
he was liable to get shot.
I wish you wouldn't keep
pointin' that thing at me.
Women got no business
carryin' guns.
- They're apt to shoot somebody
they don't mean to.
- Not me.
You know,
if you was prettied up a bit...
you might look almost like a female.
[Grunting]
[Muffled Shouting]
[Mike]
You-
[Grunting Continues]
[Whimpers, Panting]
[Grunting]
Just wanted to show you how safe
you'd be if I really wanted to get rough.
You smell. Even Apaches
are cleaner than you.
Why, you-
Didn't anybody ever tell you
before that you smell bad?
Mike! Mike!
What happened?
It's nothin', Grandpa.
It's just-
I just caught someone
prowlin' around out here.
Did you get him good?
Maybe I should have.
[Laughs]
Good thing she can shoot
as straight as she can, young fella.
Most women'd have lost their heads at a time
like this, and you'd have been done for.
Ain't every girl can miss
that close... on purpose.
- Do you need any help?
- No!
[Laughs]
Better be gettin'
back on inside, honey.
Ain't likely he'll bother
anybody else tonight.
He's gonna be kinda dizzy.
[Laughs]
Mike, how'd you
come to shoot him?
I don't know.
He grabbed me.
He made me feel-
I don't know.
I wish I'd let him die
of thirst when he came here.
[Coyote Howling]
What were you doing up there?
I was lookin' for you.
I guess you didn't hear what I said
about stayin' away from that girl.
[Chuckles] Looks like you didn't
even hear it yourself.
Anyhow, I wasn't bothering about her.
I was just nosing around,
following a hunch.
- What kind of a hunch?
- Gold.
It doesn't make sense-
that old man and a girl like her...
living up here just for their health.
Sure enough, they've got half a dozen cradles
and a big sluice box down in the canyon.
Well, how do you know it's not just old
equipment left around here like everything else?
Because there's a shack down there too.
Apaches been living in it.
I could smell 'em
the minute I opened the door.
Strong as a fox's den.
Well, suppose they have
found some gold, what of it?
Too much money layin' around in banks
for us to worry about any little dab they got.
Maybe it isn't so little.
Well, anyhow, we're not
sticking around to find out.
We're movin' on as soon
as the horses are fit.
Well, I don't know about you...
but I'm getting a little tired
of all this robbery business.
I've got a bullet floating
around in me, right here.
Some tinhorn gambler
who yelled like a stuck pig...
because he dropped
a few hundred dollars.
Claimed he'd been cheated.
Which he had, but that's
neither here nor there.
I don't know if I ever told you...
but I used to have
a big faro layout in San Juan.
Best-looking woman in camp
waiting on me hand and foot.
Then bang-
Along comes this tinhorn-
puts a bullet in me.
When I got on my feet again,
the money was all gone.
Her too.
She lit out with a fellow
who ended up beating her.
[Laughs]
Which wasn't a bad idea either.
As for me, I was just
a down-at-the-heels sharper...
with one bad lung,
looking for a stake.
But I told them
I'd come back, loaded.
That's why I joined up with you.
Maybe now's the time.
Not interested.
Just thought I'd mention it.
Need any help getting back to bed?
I'm staying here
for the rest of the night.
I'll send the kid
with your saddle and blanket.
By the way...
that woman I was telling you
about in San Juan-
Her name was Lucy.
This girl kind of reminds me of her.
Same figure.
[Coyote Howling]
[Wind Howling]
[Chuckles]
[Sniffs]
[Sniffing]
[Singing Folk Song]
[Continues]
[Ends]
Now wait a minute, boss. I ain't doin' nothin'
none of the rest of them ain't doin'.
- And what's that?
- Lookin' for the old man's gold, like Dude said.
Where are the old man and the girl?
They're up in the hills somewhere.
They lit out as soon as they heard us comin'.
- Put that down and come with me.
- All right, boss.
All right.
Get in there where I can
see what you're doing.
So you fellows figure
you got a new boss, eh?
- We want that gold.
- Dude said you wasn't interested.
- So we took a vote and-
- Decided that Dude's the leader. Is that it?
It just happens that votes
don't mean a thing to me.
You wanna get rid of me,
you've gotta run me out.
You ain't got no objections
to bein' rich, have you?
We ain't arguin' about that now.
We're talkin' about who's boss.
[Chuckles]
Personally I don't care who's boss...
long as we get that gold.
Now you're talkin'.
[Gunshots]
No sense bangin' away like that, Mike.
You're just usin' up good bullets.
If I could just get one of 'em,
it might change their minds.
Looks like they got gold all right.
- Yeah, that's what we've been tellin' you.
- Let's get it.
My way. Understand?
Gonna get mighty hot
up on that hill after a while.
Them two'll get good and thirsty.
All we gotta do is sit tight.
Sit tight?
Like a bunch of scared rabbits?
- Well, there's six of us. Let's root 'em out.
- Go ahead.
It couldn't be that you're worrying about
somebody else getting killed, could it?
You and Lengthy get in the house...
and see if you can find out
where they got the ammunition hid.
Cinch they couldn't
carry it all up there.
You and Bull Run
look around the barn.
[Gunshot]
[Gunshots]
Whew.
Mighty hot sun.
Almost tempts a man
to drink water.
Well, I declare!
There's one of them
wavin' a flag of truce.
[Laughs]
Tryin' everything, I guess.
It don't seem exactly right
to shoot a man wavin' a white flag, Mike.
I'll teach them to come around here,
chasin' us out of our house.
Wait till he gets up a little closer.
You can always get him
if he gets nasty.
That's close enough.
[Voice Echoing]
It's the only white shirt we got
in the outfit. Belongs to Dude.
He's kind of particular.
Don't wanna get it dirty.
Look, I shaved.
Changed my shirt too.
Smell like a lily.
Even combed my hair, right
around the part you gave me.
What do you want?
I thought maybe you and me
could make a deal.
There's only one deal
we'll make with you:
Get out of Yellow Sky and stay out,
or we'll shoot the lot of you.
Them bullets of yours ain't gonna last
forever. We found your ammunition.
Soon as you use up the ones you got,
my boys are gonna come up and get you.
Well, at least you
won't be among 'em.
Oh, don't a flag of truce
mean nothin' to you?
With thieves like you?
Now, nobody's gonna hurt you
if they can help it.
But we know you got gold,
and we're gonna get it.
Come on back to the house and tell us where
it's hid. Maybe we'll cut you in for some.
You might as well be comfortable
while you're gettin' robbed.
Ask him what kind of a deal.
You can't make a deal
with him, Grandpa.
Fifty-fifty's better than nothin'.
Anyhow, it don't do no harm to ask.
Sit down and keep your hands in sight.
We haven't made up our minds yet
what we're gonna do with you.
Get down!
Dirty, double-crossin'-
Grandpa!
[Groaning]
Oh, I gotta get you back to the house.
It's bleedin' bad.
Oh, I've bled before.
[Groaning]
[Gunshots]
Hold your fire!
They're givin' up!
Bull Run and Walrus, get up there.
Somebody's been hit.
I sure hope it ain't that girl.
I got a different future
picked out for her.
[Coughs]
I've seen a lot worse than that.
Didn't even break no bone.
Don't look like you got
no lead to probe for neither.
That's right. Just got
a hole in my leg.
Uh, probing is usually
a two-quart job.
[Men Laughing]
You'll have to excuse us, ma'am.
You see, we're used to
men getting shot...
and the boys just haven't
stopped to remember...
that this is your grandfather
and the only one you've got.
Look, why don't you go?
Can't you see he wants to go to sleep?
I think we oughta get this deal
of ours settled right now.
- Where's the gold?
- He can't talk now.
Tomorrow when he's feeling better,
he'll tell you anything you wanna know.
- All right, Mike. Might as well get it over with.
- But, Grandpa, you're not-
If we don't, first thing you know,
they'll be twisting my arm for me.
Did you ever have a fellow
twist your arm for you?
It don't feel so good.
Get me my pipe.
I don't supposed it'd do
any good to tell you boys...
we haven't got any gold?
Yeah, that's what I thought.
You'd just keep hunting for it
until you'd made a nuisance of yourself...
until somebody got killed.
Now, wouldn't you?
Suppose I admit
that we have got some gold...
but don't tell you where it is?
Now, you wouldn't do a mean thing
like that to us, would you, Grandpa?
Let me give you boys
a little history of things here.
About 15 years ago, heavy silver
was hit here in Yellow Sky.
[Chuckles]
The town boomed overnight.
Me and Mike here-
Oh, she was just a baby then.
I was a young fellow myself-
not a day over 60.
[Laughing]
Well, we was late gettin' here...
and didn't manage to put our hands
on anything worthwhile anyhow...
so it didn't matter one way or the other
to us when the veins pinched out.
Well, it was right hard
goin' for us for a while...
but we finally hit
on what we were lookin' for.
Pretty soon we hired us
two or three young Apaches...
from the old chief, Colorado.
[Laughs]
Then things began to hum.
You know, I've been smokin'
a pipe for 60 years.
[Laughs, Coughs]
I'm still havin' trouble with my puffer.
Yeah. What was I talkin' about?
Gold.
Oh, yes. Yes.
Mighty dangerous thing...
if you want it
out of plumb greediness.
I've seen it ruin many a man.
Of course, I had good reasons
for wantin' it myself.
Now, Mike here-
I'm the only one she's got.
So, you see, I wanted to see her
took good care of before I died.
Come to the point.
What about our deal?
- What's your idea of a deal?
- Depends on how much you got.
- Well, now, countin' the dust-
- Don't tell 'em, Grandpa.
- Don't tell 'em anything more!
- Well, Mike, I thought-
I had to do something. I couldn't
let you stay up there and die.
- Now, listen, ma'am.
I've been tryin' to be patient with you-
- That money's yours, Grandpa.
I know how hard you worked
and sweated for it.
They got no right to it. Of course,
you can't understand that, can you?
'Cause you're no good.
None of you.
- You're just born takers.
- You still haven't said how much you got.
It ain't just the money.
Look at him. He's an old man.
All he's dreamed about is seein'
this town come to life again...
with people livin' here and
workin' and-and stores open.
The stage comin' through
from Alkali.
And all because of him
and what he done.
You see, Mike? They don't even
know what you're talkin' about.
Uh, how about 50-50?
How much?
Oh, 50,000.
Fifty thousand dollars?
[Grandpa]
Around that.
I think maybe we can do business.
Where is it?
Go show 'em, Mike.
Mike?
It's cached in the mouth of that
old silver mine up under those big rocks.
When you came here this morning,
we went up and knocked out a few timbers.
It's buried now.
- If you want it, you'll have to dig for it.
- Want it?
Oh, my back feels like it's broke.
From now on, I'm stickin'
to robbin' banks.
You sure don't catch that
old Dude doin' no work.
Oh, he wouldn't be no good nohow...
with that lung of his.
'Sides, somebody's got to keep an eye
on the girl and the old man, don't they?
That's what's bothering me.
He may keep too close an eye on her.
Why don't you shut up
about that girl?
Once you get your hands on all this gold, she
won't look no better than a broken-down squaw.
Well, that's a lie.
She'll never look anything but pretty.
Well, of all the-
You too?
[Men Laughing]
Whoa!
- [Muttering]
- [Men Laughing]
[Mutters, Grunts]
Go on, Lengthy!
Go on and kiss her!
She ain't got no gun on her this time!
Ride her, cowboy!
Ride her!
But watch yourself.
- Ow!
- Looks like she's got a burr under her saddle!
[Laughing Continues]
Why, you-
Let him up!
You let him go!
[Groans]
Let him up.
- Let him up!
- I ain't lettin' nobody up.
He hit me, and I'm gonna
give it to him... good!
[Grunts]
[Gasping]
[Laughing]
[Laughs]
[Gasping]
[Coughing]
You fellows just won't
listen to me, will ya?
It wasn't my fault. She came down here
swingin' herself pretty fancy.
- I'll leave it to Walrus.
- [Walrus] That's right, boss.
Looks like she was
just askin' for trouble.
From now on,
stay away from my men...
and stop swinging' your hips
all over the place!
I don't know what you're so sore about.
She's just a girl.
I ain't gonna argue about it.
[Singing Slow Ballad]
[Continues]
[Stops]
Still worryin' about
what happened this afternoon?
Nah.
[Groans]
- You're mad at me.
- No, I ain't mad at nobody.
Just thinkin', huh?
That house up there...
keeps remindin' me
of our place back home in Ohio.
I just see my mama now,
standin' on the back porch...
callin' me to come in
from whatever I was doin'.
And my old man yellin' at me to "Wash your
hands before supper, Luke, doggone it."
And all of us sittin' down,
and him sayin' grace.
Poor boy.
I was afraid that was it.
You're in love.
I got a right to remember,
haven't I?
Sure.
[Singing Slow Ballad]
[Continues]
[Continues, Faint]
[Singing Ends]
[Harmonica]
[Panting]
- Let me go.
- Why?
Thought you was enjoyin' it.
We got... no business
kissin' each other, you and me.
- Look here, lady.
This ain't somethin' you argue about.
- No. No. No!
What's the matter?
Where you goin'?
Inside.
Grandpa'll be missin' me.
Oh, he can't be
in that much of a hurry.
- His leg hurts him. He's worried.
- What about?
- You runnin' off with all the gold
and leavin' us nothing.
- I gave him my word, didn't I?
Yeah, your word.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Footsteps]
Thought I'd... drop in, see
how you're gettin' along.
[Sniffles]
Sit down.
Uh-
I thought maybe it might...
ease your mind some about that gold...
- if you knew somethin' about me.
- What kind of somethin'?
Well... that I come from good people.
When I give my word, I mean it.
My folks was all farmers,
sound stock.
They moved to Kansas from Indiana
when I was about two years old.
Folks went through all the worst
of the Border War.
Old man come pretty near gettin' killed
by some of Quantrill's men.
Seems like I had a gun in my hand
ever since I was about so high.
Somebody always shootin' at us
or us shootin' at them.
Either chasin' somebody
or gettin' chased.
Then a few years ago,
along come an epidemic.
My old man died. Ma too.
- Course I was off in the army by then.
- Which side?
Blue pants.
[Snickers] My ma was sure
a stickler for religion.
Church was about 10 miles away, but she
used to go every Sunday, winter or summer.
I remember one Sunday, her and me
almost got lost in a blizzard.
I could read the Bible by the time
I was seven years old.
We used to have
one of them big, thick ones...
with all the family births
and deaths and marriages in it.
- Why are you tellin' us all this?
- Ah, just sort of talkin'.
I been givin' that deal of ours
a little thought, and, uh-
I figured maybe with you
laid up here and all...
you're gettin'
kind of worried about it.
All I can say is that I'm stickin' to it
a hundred percent.
I've seen some
mighty big liars in my time.
Now, if you ain't tellin' the truth-
That's a Bible there, ain't it?
Yes.
I ain't seen one in years.
I hereby swear on this good book...
that I'm goin' through with our deal...
to the letter.
Well, young man...
if you don't mean it...
I don't see no point
in you comin' here blasphemin'.
Shake on it.
[Stretch]
I guess I better be goin'.
Haven't you got
any better name than Mike?
Constance Mae.
Dawson's mine.
James Dawson.
Ah- I guess the war
has upset a lot of those boys...
and set them off on the wrong foot.
You know, I've seen a lot worse fellows
than him keep their word.
I'll put out your light now, Grandpa.
It's time for you to go to sleep.
Yeah.
[Sniffs]
Come on.
Let's get it.
- Come on!
- Come on.
Ah, we've been sold. Maybe the sacks
are buried around here somewhere.
Here's one of them.
Here it is. I've got it!
[Imitates Rooster Crowing]
[All Laughing, Shouting]
- [Rumbling]
- Look out. It'll cave in!
[Coughing]
I'm gonna get me some new clothes.
Hey, look. What's that?
[Drums, Distant]
Holy Moses.
Apaches.
[Drums Continue]
Looks like that old man
wasn't as... loony as we figured.
Yeah. Let us dig his gold
out for him...
then his Indians show up
just when we find it.
Maybe those folks are...
worse off than we are.
Aw, shut up, you jape.
They told us them Apaches
was friends of theirs, didn't they?
[Panting]
We're sure gonna be mighty rich corpses.
[Whooping, Shouting]
[Gunshots]
[Shouting, Gunshots Continue]
Funny they haven't rushed us.
Maybe they're waitin' for sunup.
Indians always like sunup.
We better try to find out
what they're gonna do.
- Wait a minute. What about all that gold?
- You carry it.
Maybe you fellas are givin' up
on that gold, but I ain't.
I want it now out of
just plain ornery meanness.
[Shouting, Gunshots Continue]
[Stretch]
Stay here.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Shouting, Gunshots Continue]
[Door Closes]
[Knocking]
Well, that was
quite a little powwow.
Yeah. Apaches like
to hear theirselves talk.
Looks like they ain't
the only ones around here.
All right, turn 'em loose on us.
They may finish us, but we'll get
our share of them before they do.
Do you think I'd turn
crazy drunk Apaches loose on ya?
They're friends of yours,
ain't they?
- Why, yes, but l-
- You sent for 'em, didn't you?
Well, did you or didn't you?
Why, I didn't know they was
within 50 miles of here...
till some of the boys that used to work
for me slipped in here last night.
Seems like they'd had some trouble over
at the reservation. They were out to kill.
Took a lot of coaxin' on my part,
but I... finally got them to promise...
to bring the big chief here
to talk to me.
You know, he's an old friend of mine.
[Chuckles]
I just got through telling them...
that if they went back to the reservation
and behaved theirselves...
I'd talk to the Indian agent myself
and have their troubles took care of.
Huh. Took a heap of arguing
on my part.
That's what they're gonna do.
What about us?
Why, I told 'em
you was working for me.
[Drums]
[Walrus] Reckon what them
fool Indians are up to now?
[Half Pint] Maybe Stretch give
the old man a good talkin' to.
He's a great one for makin' deals.
It's that honest face of his.
One look at him and you say,
"By gum, there's an honest thief."
- [Laughing]
For all we know, they'll be back.
So let's stop shooting off our mouths
and start loading this gold.
[Stretch] I wouldn't be in too big
a hurry about that if I was you.
[Walrus]
Where'd you come from?
I told you to meet me behind
them rocks. You didn't do it.
- Well, you see, Dude here-
- I'm givin' the orders around here.
[Dude]
We'll talk about that later.
Right now, we wanna know
what those Indians are up to.
The old man told 'em to move out.
- For good?
- Huh. He must've been shot
in the head, not the leg.
Well, come on.
Let's load up and git.
Just a minute.
Before we talk about loadin',
there's one thing I wanna get straight.
- What about our deal with the old man?
- Well, what about it?
There's a fortune in there-
enough for everybody...
includin' the old man and the girl.
[Laughs]
Now it comes.
Up to last night, I figured
the same way you fellas did.
I was just tryin' to save us a lot of trouble
when I said we'd split 50-50.
If it hadn't been for them Apaches
comin' in, maybe I'd still feel the same.
But the old man played it square,
stuck to his bargain.
If it hadn't been for that, we'd all
be layin' around here dead right now.
Whether you like it or not,
we're givin' 'em their full share.
If that don't suit you, you've got a fight
on your hands and you better get at it quick.
It's a free country, ain't it?
Majority rules. I say we take a vote on it.
I told you once before.
I don't like votes.
We busted our backs
diggin' this stuff out, boss.
We've been scared off by Indians,
shot at by an old desert rat...
- and that he-girl of his.
- Throw down your guns.
It's five to one.
Nobody's anxious to see you dead,
Stretch, but we want that gold...
and we want all of it.
There's plenty more left here. If that girl
and the old man want it, they can dig for it.
I've waited all my life
to make a killing like this...
and I'm not giving
half my share to anybody.
[Ricochets]
Give up now,
and we'll call it quits!
You better do like he says, 'cause
we're gonna play billiards with you...
till we run you out of them rocks.
Then we're gonna pick you off
like a turkey.
[Dude]
Fan out! We gotta flank him.
- [Bull Run] But I don't think-
- Who cares what you think?
You're in this now
whether you like it or not.
[Echoing]
Come on! I'll keep you covered!
[Panting]
[Footsteps]
- What are you doin' runnin' around here?
- You're hurt.
Get down!
Can you make it to the house?
- I gotta get their horses.
- Horses are already in the barn.
- Well, we had him.
- [Half Pint] That fool girl.
Almost filled us full of holes
with that buffalo gun of hers.
[Walrus] Come on! Let's go back
and load up and get out of here.
And spend the rest of your days...
waiting for Stretch
to stick a gun in your back?
Not me. I'm not leavin'
till we get him.
I wanna sleep nights.
- [Door Closes]
- What happened?
Oh, me and the boys
had a little... argument.
About our deal?
Couldn't see it your way, eh?
Huh. We figured that was it.
[Mutters]
Grandpa!
You shouldn't get out of bed.
Aw, a lot healthier down here.
Here.
Thanks.
What'll they do next?
It's hard to say
with me not there to tell 'em.
You've got yourself
quite a granddaughter, mister.
[Grandpa Chuckles]
I know that.
It's her future that's worrying me.
[Sighs]
Yeah.
[Coyote Howling]
Mighty quiet out there.
- [Horse Whinnying]
- Shh!
- Means they're leavin'.
- Might...
if Dude's got anything
to say about it.
He's gold crazy.
Can't tell about Lengthy.
He's got other things on his mind.
You, Walrus, Bull Run-
cover the back door.
I told Half Pint to take the front door
soon as he gets back.
I'll cover the window.
If he comes out...
- let him have it.
- Wait a minute.
Before anybody starts giving orders
around here, let's get one thing settled.
I got first call on that girl,
understand?
- Ah, who cares about her?
- I do.
All right.
Go ahead and take her.
All I want is that gold.
Come on. Let's go.
[Gun Cocks]
Stretch!
You listening?
We know that if we try to blast you out,
some of us are gonna get hurt.
On the other hand, if we run off
with the gold and leave you still alive...
we've got sense enough to know that
you'll keep looking until you find us.
So we've decided
to do what you wanted-
split with the old man and the girl.
Course it's not exactly
what we'd like to do...
but you can't have everything.
What do you say?
[Whispering]
Get in back!
I'm gonna open the door.
[Shouting]
That suits me! Come on in!
Did you get him?
[Lengthy] Yeah, I'm sure we did.
I saw him fall.
Why, you dirty-
[Glass Shatters]
Hey, lady! Lady!
It's me- Walrus.
I got Bull Run with me.
He's bleedin' somethin' awful.
[Groans]
This ain't no trick, ma'am.
I got it in the belly.
Looks like the kid's done for.
Let him in.
Bring him in!
[Grunting]
There you are.
[Footsteps]
- We thought you was dead.
- Well, you was wrong.
[Door Closes]
- [Pan Clatters]
- [Water Gushes, Stops]
[Bull Run]
I hurt, Stretch.
I was kind of wantin'
to get back to see my folks...
but I hurt, Stretch.
Can't just let him lie there and die.
- [Gunshot]
- [Pottery Shatters]
There ain't nothin'
you can do for him now, ma'am.
[Walrus]
Funny thing.
He was the only one against
comin' here in the first place.
What are they gonna try next?
Guess they ain't gonna try nothin' but...
get each other and winner take all.
Where are they now?
Dude took a shot at Lengthy, tried
to get him in the back of the head...
just when he thought he'd got you.
Then he let out for town,
Lengthy after him.
Guess they didn't figure
I was worth botherin' about.
- Where are the horses?
- Down at the saloon, where we left the gold.
- Half Pint's coverin' the front door.
- Tell him to get in here.
Hey, Half Pint!
Dude and Lengthy run off!
Ain't either of them aimin'
to share that gold with nobody.
Me and Bull Run is... in here.
Keep your hands up and come on in.
[Gun Cocks]
Get over there on the floor.
- Where you goin', boss?
- Where do you think?
Now, you stay here, Mike.
[Coyote Howling]
[Wind Blowing]
[Creaking]
Go on.
- [Horse Whinnies]
- [Bags Hit Floor]
[Whinnying]
[Clicking]
[Panting]
[Whimpering]
[Sighs]
- [Table Clatters]
- [Gasping, Panting]
Grandpa!
Grandpa! Grandpa!
[Dogs Barking]
- [Blows]
- [Dice Rattling]
[Snaps Fingers]
Come on. Raise your hands.
It's all there,
every cent we took.
Let me have that. No, no.
Not that. The hat.
[Snickers]
How much you pay for that?
- That doesn't matter. You can have it.
- How much did you pay for it?
Four dollars.
- Oh, uh, thanks.
- [Exhales]
And he has my hat.
Here they come, Grandpa.
[Walrus]
Whoa. Whoa.
- Well?
- We did it.
So help me.
It hurt, but we did it.
I paid for it.