Now, I say we stop off at Juan Petrón's
for one jolly big dram
and one ginger beer with cream.
- Who gets the whisky?
- The one closest to the coffin.
Anyway, if I buy you a dram, you must
promise not to tell the other boys.
It's a promise.
(gunshot)
Oh, no. Not another hanging.
Shit.
- Howdy.
- (man) Come on, lad.
Hurry up. Don't be afraid.
- You want to play games?
- Red-assed Mexican.
You do it with your horse!
- Mexican greaser!
- White chickenshit!
- Come on, greaser. Cut me down!
- Hey, knock it off! Knock it off!
Cut me down, Mexican!
Knock it off.
You know better, Chavez.
- Navajo! Navajo!
- That's enough!
John's back. Wash up,
and into supper clothes.
Now! Both of you!
- Who are them?
- "They", William. "Who are they?"
They are the boys of the dregs.
The flotsam and jetsam
of frontier society, if you will.
We've got room in the bunkhouse,
my young man.
If you don't want to stay,
the Santa Fe runs out of Albuquerque
in the morning.
Glad you're back, Doc.
Start hauling the rope inside.
John bring another hard case in?
- Hope it ain't another Mexican.
- Mexican-lndian.
If you do wish to stay,
we have just the job for you.
- (grunts)
- Argh!
- He ain't all there, is he?
- You son of a bitch!
(laughs)
Hey, did you know pigs
is as smart as dogs?
Yeah, it's true.
I knew a fella in El Capitan,
taught his pig to bark at strangers.
What you doin' here, boy?
We work for Mr Tunstall
as regulators.
Mr Tunstall's got a soft spot
for runaways, derelicts, vagrant types.
But you can't be any geek off the street.
Got to be handy with the steel.
Earn your keep.
Go on, go on, get!
Not that I'm a pistoleer or a knifesmith
like that greaser Chavez Chavez.
I'm a pugilist. (laughs)
But then, I ain't expectin' you
to know that word, hog boy!
(oinks)
- You don't even know why I'm here.
- Sure I do.
You're a runaway,
derelict vagrant like the rest of us.
Footpad, maybe? Petty thief?
Rob a bank? Kill somebody?
Killed somebody, huh?
(man) Regulators!
You ain't no regulator! Stay here with
the pork. You might learn something.
Cattle look spooked in the lower 40.
Let's take a look.
Smart ass.
Well, now.
Look at those appetites, hm?
William. Have some more.
You ever worked beef before, Billy?
Did the chow line.
But, uh, I got a way with cattle.
(laughter)
What's so jolly funny,
Master Steven?
That's no proper table manners.
Got a way with hogs. (oinks)
Congratulations, Charles.
You and Steven
will do the dirty crockery alone.
Sorry, John. Struck me funny.
And to William. Both of you.
Apologies, William.
Just hackin' on you, that's all.
Yeah, we was just hackin' on you.
Rumour has it you killed a man, Billy.
You don't seem like the killing sort.
Yeah, Billy, what you kill him for?
He was hackin' on me.
(gulps)
"There are...
plenty of men...
who will never secede..."
Succeed.
Suc..."...who will never
succeed anywhere."
Got a whole roomful of 'em right here.
Well done.
William.
- Yeah, sure.
- (John) Well, excuse me, Billy.
Very sorry to offend you.
But we're congregated here
to learn to read and write.
You need more than skill with a firearm
to succeed in the New World, Billy.
So take up the journal
and start where the other boy left off,
or you can go straight back
to your home on the streets.
"Young men who don't know
how to do any kind of business
and have no energy or application
had better stay at home near their
relatives so they can be taken care of."
"They are not wanted here
and will only come to grief."
"But men of enterprise
are practically sure of success."
Splendid.
A splendid reading, William.
Thank you.
Good night, gentlemen.
(all) Good night, Mr Tunstall.
(horse whinnies)
(grunting)
Shit.
Whoa! Son of a bitch!
- Good afternoon, gentlemen.
- Afternoon, John.
Mr Dolan and Mr Murphy here
are complainin' about their
merchandise wagon being plundered
on several occasions
on the way into town.
They think you're behind it.
- That's a fargin' lie, and you know it!
- Richard.
Sheriff Brady.
Until I'm pronounced a thief
and shaken out of Lincoln.
I've never touched his property.
I have no cause.
Well!
The belted earl has spoken.
Look behind you, Earl.
All I see are hired thieves.
(John) These boys are promising
young men acquiring an education.
I've had you pegged as the type that...
that likes...
- educatin' young boys, Englishman.
- (laughter)
Tunstall.
Rumour has it you're bidding against
me for the government beef contracts.
It is just rumour, isn't it?
Lawrence, you have a beef outfit
and a store.
I have a beef outfit and a store.
We're both going to try to make money.
It's simple, and it's fair.
You see our good sheriff
sittin' on that horse?
Do you know how much money
he's got invested in my store?
His life savings, John.
It's not just Brady who wants me
to get those contracts.
It's the territorial district attorney,
the chief justice,
This is a family thing, John.
Don't come prancin' in with your fat,
foreign capital, tryin' to change things.
I made a very long steamship journey
from London, Mr Murphy,
so I shall be damned if I'm going to be
dissuaded by political corruption.
So I'd like you to take your threats and
your sheriff and get off my property.
You're ambitious, Earl.
But you'd be better off selling
ladies' undergarments in Hampstead.
(laughter)
All right, men, that's enough.
Put 'em away.
This is a new country. We won't
bow down to you no more, Englishman.
Get ready for hell.
Come on!
Back to work, chaps.
Mr Tunstall?
My name's J McCloskey.
I heard you're having
some trouble finding help.
McCloskey?
You're one of Murphy's boys.
Used to be. He fired me.
I called him a fat sow.
Did you?
Lovely.
Bunkhouse is over there.
- (gunshots)
- Get down!
(laughs)
Regulators!
Let's dance.
(? Jig)
- Look at Billy Bonney go.
- He ain't all there, is he?
He's there enough to be dancin'
while we pull our tallywhackers.
Damn straight.
Come on.
We have to expose this ring, Alex.
Can you get me in to see the governor?
Murphy's beat us to it,
and he brought the governor
a nice, fat campaign contribution.
They're tightening the yoke, John.
They want me out, too.
With me gone, no lawyer would be
crazy enough to represent you.
You've heard of English tenacity,
haven't you?
Here's to enough grit
to finish the last round.
Besides, if we gave in and left,
who'd look after my boys?
- Oh, uh, medicine.
- Oh.
Yes, I shall receive my degree
from St Michael's in July,
and then I shall practise here in Lincoln
until my missionary to the islands.
Isn't that nice?
Howdy. My name's Doc.
(Murphy) What can I do for you,
young man?
If you're an acquaintance
of the young miss,
Why, certainly.
Thank you.
- What's your name?
- Yen Sun.
That's beautiful.
You're a friend of Mr Murphy's?
- He is my guardian.
- Oh.
- Hello, there.
- Hello back.
William Bonney, sir.
Pat Garrett. Pleasure.
Excuse us, friend.
We have a request for the band.
Pat Garrett.
I'll bet I get to be just as big as him.
Nah...
bigger.
"So shows the snowy dove
trooping with crows,
as yonder lady
o'er her fellows shows."
- Pardon me?
- Oh.
That's a poem.
I'm a poet. I wrote it.
I'm sorry, young man,
but we must be gettin' along.
We're getting along famously.
You're part of the Tunstall company.
- (Doc) Yes, I am.
- Ah.
Then I'll be expectin' to see you follow
your Englishman out of Lincoln.
You tell him... Tell that slug to leave
no slime on the road behind him
when he crawls back
to Wharf Street.
- (woman) OK, Doc.
- Hey!
Alex! How ya doin'?
- Someone break up your dance?
- Yeah. He's the girl's guardian.
- Guardian? That's a gentle euphemism.
- Why?
He had a shirt ruined
in a Silver City laundry.
He took the Celestial woman's
daughter as payment.
- What?
- She's house entertainment.
- You can dance with Susan. It's safer.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- Out of the way, mister.
- I do beg your pardon.
- Come on. You and me.
- No, no, no.
No, it's you and I.
- Isn't that right, John? You and I?
- Yes, yes, it is.
You... and I.
- Pugilist.
- He's somethin'.
Happy New Year!
(cheering)
? And never brought to mind?
? Should auld acquaintance be forgot
? And days of auld lang syne?
? For auld lang syne...
? Should auld acquaintance be forgot
? For the sake of auld lang syne?
? For auld lang syne, my friend...
(whooping)
Go on, Billy. Boys will be boys.
Hah!
Woo-hoo!
Woo-hoo-hoo!
Hah! Hah!
No, no! There's too many!
Get out of here!
"For as much as it has pleased
Almighty God in his wise providence
to take out of this world
the soul of our deceased brother,
we therefore commit
his body to the ground."
"Ashes to ashes, dust to dust."
Murphy's henchmen
have to be brought in.
I'm going to take it to court
and bring Murphy down.
Have you talked to Sheriff Brady?
You're the justice of the peace.
You can serve warrants
through special constables.
What special constables? No one's fool
enough to go after Murphy's people.
Deputise them.
Those are just boys.
Ain't one of 'em over 21.
- Murphy's men will shred 'em in half.
- Will you deputise them?
Hell, no. No, I won't, Alex.
Not me.
All right, then. You go tell 'em.
(shouting)
Lugar peligroso.
- Bad medicine, my friends.
- You got that right.
- You grew up in a hole worse than that.
- Yeah, but I've been cultured since.
OK. Henry Hill's been in there
with a lady since noon.
We'll show him the warrant,
take him home.
Yeah. Yeah. We gotta take him.
I'd say we do.
Hey, uh, Billy?
Why don't you go inside
and have a look-see?
Go on, Billy. See if Hill's in there.
If he is, bring him to us.
(man) Yeah, give me two cards.
- I'll take two.
- Hey, Hill, want another drink?
Got to drain it first.
I'll have Janey here give me a hand.
Doc says not to lift nothing too heavy.
You talk to me like that, Henry Hill.
Now what the hell's he doin'?
Get up.
Ah. Oh, Lord. (grunts)
(passes wind)
- Henry Hill?
- Yeah?
Howdy.
Oh, God.
Shit!
- By the way, you're under arrest.
- (gunshots)
Shit!
Oh, shit!
Bonney! You weren't supposed
to smoke anybody!
We got warrants! We're the law!
(laughs)
(Doc) "Nine men lay dead
or at death's door
following a gunfight
between Henry Hill, 45,
and what patrons called a kid."
"A local miner identified the kid
as one Henry McCarty,
also known as William H Bonney,
19 or 20."
"The kid, Billy, killed Mr Hill, then took
on an onslaught of Hill partisans,
bringing the damage
to six verified slayings."
"Bonney is believed to be captain
of a deputised gang."
Captain?
How come it don't say nothin'
about the two I got?
El Chivato. Billy the Kid, huh?
(boy) Murphy's going to want blood,
brains and balls for this.
- I'm getting out of here.
- Hey, Doc.
Don't be stupid.
You know they'll be looking for us.
Yeah, I know.
I'll be back in one minute.
Howdy.
- I cannot accept those. Thank you.
- You walk awful fast for a little thing.
Come on, Yen, I just want to talk.
- You must like trouble.
- You think I look like trouble?
I'm a poet carrying flowers,
of all things.
And a gun. It's a big gun.
It's a big town.
Come on, Yen, please.
Stop!
Look. If you don't want to take these,
that's fine.
But you take a message
to your guardian.
You tell LG Murphy
the regulators are going to clean house.
They can't own us like they own
a little China girl for the price of a shirt.
You tell him that.
Yen, I'm sorry.
So, Dick...
who's next?
You.
- Shit.
- What's wrong?
I mean I found some. Horseshit.
They come down
from the Sierra Bonitas this morning.
Horses been grazin' wild. Pretty damn
good, don't you think, Baker?
Not that good.
- Buenos dias, shitheads.
- Up.
By killing Henry Hill,
you started a war.
By killing Mr Tunstall,
y'all started the damn war.
Just the same, we're talking 50, 60 men
against your... what? Six or seven?
- We're with the ring, Dick.
- We're going to bury you.
Quiet, Bonney.
We're taking you to jail. No killing.
Objection, Your Honour.
These boys are going to the grave.
I said quiet! I don't need that kind
of talk. The law don't talk like that.
- The law don't kill innocent merchants.
- Shut up, dirt face.
Uh-huh!
Hey, Billy, easy.
Dick, we shouldn't go
by way of South Fork.
- Why's that?
- I think Murphy will ambush us there.
Hey.
- What?
- I saw that.
What? What did you see?
- He knows what I just saw!
- What you talkin' about?
Where's the ambush? In Lincoln?
You're steering us away from Capitan
cos your men - Murphy's men -
are waiting to jump us in Lincoln.
Billy, McCloskey's with us.
He's a regulator.
- He used to ride with Murphy!
- That was a long time ago.
- He's a spy!
- He's been with us. We made a pact.
- Right, McCloskey?
- Right.
Jesus, Billy.
Come on.
Ah, shit. I'm sorry, McCloskey.
It's all right.
We're all upset about John.
I'm sorry I didn't
sniff you out sooner, traitor!
(Richard) Billy!
- Oh, shit!
- Billy!
Billy, what the hell...? Jesus!
Hold your fire!
- Halt!
- Shit!
No!
- Hold your goddamn fire!
- Get that son of a bitch!
Oh, God!
- Court adjourned.
- Moron! You're out of line!
He was right.
McCloskey was acting strange.
Then we just killed
three more Murphy men! Right?
- Right.
- Oh, Christ!
- Brady's going to hang us for sure!
- What do we do now?
Everybody close their fargin' lips
for a second and let me think!
We better skin out of here.
OK, everybody,
skin up the river. Now!
You! You better stop
believing the newspapers.
You ain't no captain, and you sure
as hell ain't no Robin Hood.
Whatever you say, Dick.
Get that idiot on a horse.
Hah!
"Advices from Lincoln say the young
lad of iron nerve and marvellous skill
including a miraculous
shot of 50 yards."
There's a picture here.
It says "Billy the Kid" but it ain't Billy.
Let me see that.
Well, that's me.
That's bullshit.
Papers can't get anything right.
"Sources say that the kid,
a left-hander, is tall, handsome,
and unequalled in the elements
that appeal to the holier emotions."
Jesus, this country needs a hero!
"Murphy has hired none other than
John Kinney and his Doña Ana bunch
to hunt down Billy the Kid
and the gang."
Oh, great. John Kinney.
Who's Kinney?
(Doc) It says he's an ex-soldier
who suffered an injury
and is now a bounty hunter.
- What's that mean?
- It means he can whoop some ass.
- Hey, Doc. Come here for a minute?
- Yeah.
(Charles) Read the rest.
- What's up?
- We can't go north.
We can go through the Valley of Fires,
but there's the Mescalero reservation.
They're having a good year with scalps.
I don't think so.
I don't know what the hell to do.
What the hell's he doin'?
We've come to a place
where we are lost.
When an Indian is lost, he reaches
into the spirit world to find the way.
We're lost right now,
but I'll find us the way.
Oh, Christ! That's all we need,
more red-ass Navajo mambojahambo.
We're running out of time here, Chavez.
Is that any good?
Chavez, what is that?
Peyote.
Dick?
(Doc) Butterflies.
Yeah.
Just like a butterfly.
Butterfly flies to a flower,
stays with it.
It doesn't know why,
it just feels it.
Oh, yeah.
She's...
She's my flower.
I'm her...
(gunshot)
Did you guys see the size
of that chicken?
Oh.
We don't know why.
We just feel it.
(gunshot)
(Steve) Oh, God!
You guys! You guys!
Wow.
This is great.
This is great!
Did you see the size of that
cock-a-doodle-goddamned-do?
That's real. That's real!
I'm her butterfly. She's mine!
- (Richard) Regulators, saddle up!
- (war cry)
Godless heathens.
(war cry)
Regulators!
Hey, Doc, Doc!
Did you see the size
of that chicken?
? Gather 'round the coal house, babe
? Two hands 'round and go again
? Allemande left
and a turn to your partner
Howdy.
How are you, sir?
Hey, Chavez,
how come they ain't killin' us?
Cos we're in the spirit world,
asshole! They can't see us!
? There's the girl
with the golden hair...
Hey, did you know
we're in the spirit world?
(Richard) Lord, forgive us
for our wrongdoings,
for our misguidance
by heathen religions.
Thank you for keeping us alive.
Please guide us
in doing the right thing.
Oh! Ow!
Our Father, who art in heaven,
Please, Dick, it's getting cold!
I could've killed you, Dick.
I could've killed you...
but I don't want to kill you. I want to eat.
When we've finished this meal,
you rodent,
we're going outside to see
who has the right to run the regulators.
Richard, would you be so kind
as to pass the gravy, please?
- Mighty well-heeled man coming.
- Just one?
- Uh-huh.
- Oh, Lord, it's Buckshot Roberts!
- We got a warrant for him.
- Is he coming to surrender?
- Don't look that way.
- (Billy) He any good?
He's killed more people
than smallpox.
Well, hell, introduce us.
We got a warrant for you, old man.
I ain't got no business with that war
no more, peckerhead son of a bitch.
I'm on my own. I'm here to get that $150
Sheriff Brady's putting down for the kid.
The rest of you little shits
is only worth 110, but I'll take it.
What a sweet disposition.
Let's dance.
(screams)
Chavez!
Argh! Ah, shit!
Damn.
(groans)
Chavez?
What?
- (Roberts) You little sons of bitches!
- Go into the shitter.
- What?
- Billy, go in there and cut him in half.
I'm daring you, Billy.
(Roberts) Y'all can't blast me!
Screw that!
(groaning)
Cover me.
Dick!
Son of a bitch!
Dick, we're coming to get you!
He's dead, Charley.
We got to go get him!
You want to cross
in front of that shithouse again?
What are we gonna do?
Dick got his guts blown out!
- He's our foreman!
- Come on.
- Doc, what are we going to do?
- Get the hell out of here!
Come on, Charley!
Regulators! Let's rack out now!
OK!
- Where to, Doc?
- I'm going into Patricio if it looks safe.
I'll write Dick's mother in Vermont,
get some clean wraps for this.
Well, whatever you do,
don't go near Lincoln.
See you.
What you doin' there, Billy?
Well, sir,
with the sight filed down,
I got an eighth-of-a-second drop
on our good Sheriff Brady.
(gunshot)
Billy, we can't touch the sheriff.
Dick said so. You know that.
Besides, we can't keep this up.
Well, Dick ain't around any more,
is he, Charley?
Brady's in desperate need
of being removed from office.
We're not going after Brady.
No Murphy men. No more.
I told you I would find the way,
and the way is west.
West, huh?
West is that way,
and the bastards we got to kill
are that way.
The only bastards going to get killed
are us, Chivato. Let it go.
Let it go? Murphy's taking inventory
in Tunstall's store right now!
That means nothing to you?
It means nothing to me?
Murphy and his politicians
have taken more blood from me
than they ever will from you.
Oh, yeah?
How do you figure?
The Red Sand Creek Reservation.
- What's he talking about?
- I don't know.
My mother's people.
Murphy and Company was under
contract to supply us with beef.
Two winters ago,
he sent only rotten meat.
No corn, no flour, only rancid beef
crawling with worms.
So I went out with a band
to a trader's camp to try and get food.
Oh, yeah, they welcomed us in,
and then they opened fire on us.
I got away - only me!
But when I got back to the Red Sands,
I found out that the army had already
heard about our "big Indian uprising".
And they paid us back.
My mother was cut by a sabre
from her privates to her neck.
My sisters were just babies. They had
their heads bashed in with boot heels
so the army could save bullets!
Everybody on my reservation
was butchered.
And it means nothing to me?!
Oh, yeah, I went to Lincoln
to take Murphy's head,
and that's when
John Tunstall found me.
And he took me in, and he taught me
a better way to bury Murphy.
Murphy buried him
the old Irish way, Chavez.
That's right, Steve.
And he starved out your family, Chavez.
Now he's doing it to every small farmer
in the territory.
But you wanna run, go ahead.
Just go right on ahead.
Bye. You got no loyalty, Navajo.
(Steve) Navajo!
He ain't nothin' but a piece
of chickenshit in the rain.
No.
We had our ceremony
back there on the ridge, Chivato.
Now, I don't know
what your vision told you,
but mine told me we're headed
for blood, blood like a river.
I'm the last of my clan,
the last of my people.
If I die, and I'm not afraid of dying,
the sacred hoop is broken.
Now I have to go west
to make my people live again.
Charley...
will you come with me?
You ain't sayin' much, Dirty Steve.
Cos he ain't got much to say,
Charley.
Old Steve understands the meaning
of the word "pals", don't you, Steve?
See, you got three or four good pals,
then you got yourself a tribe.
There ain't nothing
stronger than that.
We're your family now, Chavez.
You walk away from us,
you break our sacred hoop.
We got to stick together, fellas.
That's the only way I see it.
? When Irish eyes are smiling
? Sure, it's like a morning spring
? In the lilt of Irish laughter
? You can hear the angels sing
? But when Irish eyes are smiling
Shh! Shh! Shh!
It's me - Doc. OK? Shh!
(laughter)
I know you've come to lay with me
then cut me into tiny pieces!
You're the bandit
who eats children and old people!
I eat meat and potatoes.
Who told you that?
My benefactor.
Your benefactor?
That's the man that eats people.
Yen, if you want to stay here,
tell me now, and I'll go.
Do you want to stay here?
In China, girls are not necessary.
When we have floods,
fathers let the girl babies wash by.
My benefactor has made me necessary.
He hasn't made you necessary.
He's made you a slave!
I'm sorry.
Necessary is something
you can't do without.
I can't do without you.
I keep the flowers that you offered me
in a little room inside my head...
Often, I say yes.
I want to ask
something else of you now.
I want you to go with me to Roswell.
There's a railroad
going to New York City.
Two days, we could be on a train,
in another country, in a city together.
"The Bird", by Josiah G Scurlock.
That's Doc.
"Once upon a midnight dreary,
as I pondered weak and weary,
there came a knocking
at my... back porch."
Ain't very original, is he?
He's been gone an awful long time.
I have a feeling
he's gonna be makin' a run for it.
Who? Doc?
Nah, Doc likes me.
If I stay, I'll be a stiff in a photograph.
The only chance I have is to run.
- They would chase us.
- I'm used to that.
No.
I am unclean.
That is not for a young man.
Yen, I used to ride with the Dirty
Underwear Gang of Liberty, Missouri.
Then John Tunstall taught me
the past is like an old yellow novel.
When you're finished with it,
you toss it out and start a new one.
OK?
- You're necessary.
- (footsteps)
(knock at door)
- Go with me. Come with me, Yen.
- No.
(Murphy) Yen Sun!
Yen Sun!
(keys rattle)
- Hey, Steve!
- What?
Doc's back.
I told you he'd come back.
Regulators, let's saddle up!
Sheriff Brady,
we're gonna have a lot of fun now.
What the hell's he doin'?
(Steve) He ain't all there, is he?
Is he?
Top o' the mornin' to you, girls. (laughs)
Reap the whirlwind,
Sheriff Brady.
Reap it!
- (Billy) It's for you.
- (Alex) You weren't to touch Brady!
Sheriff Brady sent the men
who killed John.
- It was a good move for us.
- It wasn't.
- Yes, it was!
- Have you seen The Independent?
The governor's revoked
your deputisation.
You're wanted by the legitimate law
as well as those outside the law.
You're being hunted by John Kinney,
Murphy's men, and troops!
Fort Stanton, Billy! The US Army.
The governor's put
a $200 bounty on your head.
You were supposed to serve
11 warrants and expose the ring.
Instead, you went on the warpath,
on a rampage.
Now Richard's dead.
We're livin' up here like fugitives.
What the hell
do you think you're doin'?
I don't know.
Maybe I'm tryin' to get some attention,
or to get President Hayes
to look this way.
They let Murphy and his bankers get
away with anything. I can't allow that.
The more bastards I dust,
the more news stories they write.
The more troops they send after us,
the more President Hayes has to come
down, see for himself what's going on.
Then he'll find out
who's really doing the killing.
Alex.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna try to reach
the president myself, legally.
It won't be easy
to get past the governor.
I got plans for the governor.
What if you can't get in touch
with Hayes?
I'll go back to Lincoln
and reopen John's store.
- That's what John would want.
- We'll escort you.
You'd be a death sentence to anyone
now, Billy. I don't want your help.
You didn't see
what they did to John.
We did.
Christ, Billy.
Thank you, Billy.
Billy, please, go to Old Mexico.
Please.
(Billy) Gentlemen, let's ride.
- Alex...
- What the hell happened, Doc?
It is a whirlwind out there.
When you're in it,
you can't get out.
I'm sorry.
I was wonderin'
if you remember that China doll -
you know, at the dance...
the fandango?
I was sort of thinkin',
cos you're a lawyer and all,
maybe there was a legal way...
I don't even have enough ground
to stand on any more, Doc. I mean it.
OK. Yeah.
Thanks.
Take care of yourself, Alex.
OK?
- What's the matter?
- I don't know.
He's just bellyachin'
about somethin' or another.
He got mighty spooked.
Dirty Steve told me, Billy. He told me
what they're writin' in the papers.
Steven told him about the party
Sheriff Peppin's plannin' for us.
Party?
Oh, you mean the hangin'.
Cállate, Chivato.
Goddammit, Billy!
You ever seen a man hanged?
His face turns purple,
and his eyes come up on him.
I seen Red Smitty hang.
Billy. I don't think Charley
wants to hear about Red Smitty.
I think what he'd like to hear
is that we're not going to hang.
You mess your trousers, they say.
Gals watchin' and everything.
Well, if we get caught, Charley,
we're gonna hang.
But there's many a slip
'twixt a cup and a lip.
We got to do somethin'
before they catch us.
Y'all got to let me do somethin'.
OK, Charley.
Charley, this is your last wish?
Get your carrot wet?
You could do that in Juárez.
Somethin' called a special woman, dirt
face. You'll understand that one day.
All right, gentlemen,
square up and shell out for Bowdre.
We'll be in the den.
- Yell if you need any help.
- You know what to do, don't you?
What's your name?
Charley.
Well, Charley,
I don't remember you
but I guess you remember me.
I meet so many young men
out for the first. You know how it is.
Why don't you come over here,
Charley?
Uh, ma'am,
I just want to hold you.
Whatever your pleasure, Charley,
but it all costs the same.
(man) Darlin', when a man rides
200 miles for a job,
you can bet
he's gonna get that job done.
If this Billy the Kid's
around town like people say,
he is $200 flat dead on this bar.
You can't kill what you can't catch.
These mestizos,
they say that Billito's half horse,
half devil.
But who knows? Maybe a strong,
big Texas man like you can do...
You gonna kill Billy the Kid?
Does a horse piss
where she pleases?
(man) If he's man enough
to come around here.
(Billy) Is that the gun
you're gonna shoot him down with?
Can I touch it?
Please?
You know, sir, I do admire you,
and I sure would like to touch the gun
that's gonna kill Billy the Kid.
- You know iron, boy?
- Yes, sir.
Go ahead, then.
Have a look.
Pass her back.
That gun killed Ed Rollins.
Is that right?
Let's have a little round of stone fence
for every little lady in the house.
OK. Pass it back, son.
Stroke a gun like that, you might as well
be strokin' a man's woman. Pass it up.
Whoop!
All right. Now, you best be on your way
before you get hurt.
Uh, I'm leavin' right now,
and I wanna know what to look for
in case I run into him.
Dresses like a dandy,
and he's a left-hander.
People say he's fond
of whistlin' sad ballads.
Now, you get out in the street
and see somebody that fits that bill,
you just come whisperin' to me.
OK.
Bye-bye.
Hey! I see him!
Right there!
Don't you see him?
Is that so, now?
You know, boy,
I'm gettin' a little tired of your wise lip.
Before I have to drop your britches
in front of all these fine ladies
and spank your little bottom blue.
(? Whistles sad ballad)
Yeah, sure.
You are a testy little cuss.
(gun clicks)
(clicks)
(? Continues whistling)
(laughs)
Hey, Doc, how many
does that make? 25?
Five.
We'll call it ten, ten even.
How'd that be?
Whatever you say.
It's John Kinney!
Come on!
Whoa!
God! Argh!
Where are they?
"His hat was covered
with gold and jewels."
"It sparkled in a dazzling, blinding
manner when one looked upon it."
Aah! Oh!
I know, I know.
It breaks my heart, too.
"The shoes worn by this young,
left-handed prince of the plains
were low-quartered with patterned
silver spurs in the heels."
I ain't left-handed.
Billy,
I was thinkin' about our course.
It looks like we've just done
a big circle twice.
And?
It also looks like
we're going back into Lincoln.
We are.
- Ain't a good idea, Billy.
- Billy, what are you thinkin'?
Billy, we're lucky to be alive.
Goin' back to Lincoln, that's crazy.
- We'll find the men who killed John.
- It's 100 against five!
(mocking) "It's 100 against five!"
We take Murphy, and the ring falls.
We take him, we win this war.
Then it'll be over.
- Can't get to him, Billy.
- (Chavez) It's not just 100 men.
There's bounty hunters, too,
everywhere we go... but not west.
I chose your way,
but I don't trust it any more.
California sounds about right to me.
You're all scared.
- And you're gonna fail the test.
- What test?
You have to test yourself every day.
Once you stop testin' yourself,
you get slow.
When that happens, they kill you.
You fellas don't feel that?
Like when John Kinney's
riding up on our ass
and the blood goes
right to your head?
Ha-ha! Woo!
- It's quite a sensation.
- (Doc) Yeah, I bet it is.
I'm sure you hear trumpets sound
and angels sing a hymn.
I shit in my goddamn britches!
OK? We've taken enough
goddamn Murphy scalps!
We cannot win this war,
not the five of us.
Do you understand?
No.
Billy, you want to get
the president's attention, go ahead.
You want to keep testing yourself?
Fine.
Come morning, I'm a Mexican.
Yeah, Billy. Yeah, me, too.
Mexico, huh?
- Yeah.
I see. You're testin' yourselves,
and you don't even know it.
- Old Mexico - that's a hoot.
- What do you mean?
They'll cover every possible which way
from Texas to Arizona.
John Kinney knows everyone
along the border.
There's a full day's ride
through them thorns,
which also makes a good hiding place
for scalp hunters and Indians.
The chances of making Old Mexico?
Well, hell.
That's the test of all tests,
if you ask me.
I'm in.
I'm really not liking him.
- (woman) ¡El Chivato!
- (man) ¡El Chivato!
¡El Chivato!
"Dear Governor Ax-tell..."
- Axtell.
- Right.
"I have heard that you will give..."
What is it?
- 200.
- "...$200 for my head."
"Perhaps we should meet and talk."
"I am at the Juárez village
at the border."
"Send three men
and instruct them not to shoot,
as I am unarmed."
"In short, sir,
I surrender."
"Your obedient servant,
William H Bonney."
Damn good ridin' with you, Chavez.
Many nights, my friend...
many nights, I put a blade to your throat
while you were sleeping.
I'm glad I never killed you, Steve.
You're all right.
"PS,
I changed my mind. Kiss my ass."
Charley's gettin' married!
(? Lively music)
Anybody asks you
where you got that hat,
tell them Billy the Kid gave it to you.
Now, go on, get out of here.
(gun cocking)
- Pat Garrett.
- That's right.
What are you doing in here?
No one's supposed to come in here.
Going back to Louisiana
for family business.
Wanted to see the boy
who's become a sensation.
- How'd you find me?
- I'm a tracker.
Gonna be hell as a sheriff.
- What are you saying, Pat?
- The officials have asked me to run.
Well, then, I'm asking you to run, too -
that way,
or I'll take your shittin' scalp
like I did Brady's.
Billy, I ain't the law yet.
I've come to tell you some bad news
about a friend we share.
McSween, Tunstall's lawyer.
- What about Alex?
- He's going to die tomorrow.
He and his wife, at his house.
Murphy knows
he's coming back to Lincoln.
They're going to pay him a visit.
- What time do they expect him?
- Suppertime.
To give the man and his wife
a rightful escort across the border.
Ain't been to Louisiana for a spell.
I'll see you, Billy.
Hey, Garrett.
Are you my friend?
Yes, I am, Bill.
(gunshot)
(Billy) Regulators!
(gun barrel clicking)
(Billy) Hey, Charley.
Maybe you should stay.
You can't shoot
worth a piss anyhow.
Your girl's crying.
Giving me a headache.
Charley, you got a wife now.
You should stay.
Ain't easy havin' pals.
Hah!
- Alex?
What in the name of...?
Alex, let's go. Word's out -
they're gonna come kill you.
Dammit, Billy,
I told you not to come here.
- I'm not leaving my house.
- (Billy) If you stay, they'll kill you.
Then I'll have to go around
and kill all the guys who killed you.
- That's a lot of killing.
- You heard me, Billy.
You heard me!
We can't just stay here
and hope that the good Lord saves us...
Susan, I'm sick.
I can't go to Old Mexico.
Out in the middle of the street!
Come on!
Don't fret, Alex.
The trip's postponed.
- They're coming around the front.
- Shit.
Bring those wagons up. Quickly!
Keep the house covered.
It's Peppin.
Get that wagon over!
Joe, move it!
- Murphy men.
- (cocks gun)
Charley?
How's it over by you?
Can we break?
Uh.
Hey, Charley! How is it?
It... it's John Kinney.
I think the word you got was a trap
to get us all together in the same place.
My God, look at them all.
It's gonna be a massacre.
Take care of the horses!
- It... it's John Kinney.
- Well, maybe they just want us.
No.
They figure they can end the war
right here, in one fell swoop.
- That's what they're about to do.
- It's John Kinney!
Thank you very much, Charley!
Jesus.
Come on, move it.
Charley.
Oh, God.
Hanging for sure now.
Hm.
All right.
Take a look
at the firepower down here.
Y'all come on out! Real slow!
You up there, Bonney?
Let's have some fun, Doc.
Yeah, I'm here, you bastard!
What the hell
are we gonna do now?
We're gonna show these guys
they've finally met their match.
- Hey, Peppin?
- I'm hearin' you, Bonney!
I see you got Charley Crawford
down there with you.
Yeah, we got a whole lot...
- Oh, my God!
- Damn!
Hey, Peppin? Charley Crawford
ain't with you any more!
Bastard! Fire!
- You all right, Doc?
- Yeah.
Boy, these boys won't give up!
You OK, ma'am? You OK?
You OK?
- Charley?
- Yeah.
Take two rifles, go on upstairs.
Doc? You go up with him.
Load heavy!
Steve? Go on up
and cover the north side.
Alex?
This may be your last chance
to handle John's case.
Active participation in a gun battle
(man) We know you can shoot, Bonney!
We can, too! Give it up!
Chavez?
(creaking)
Chivato.
(Billy) They sent in the troops. (laughs)
Billy, we're good,
but this is getting ridiculous.
Dismount!
I like these odds. (laughs)
Mr Murphy. Judge Bristol.
- We got all the rats in one hole.
- What's been taking so long?
We didn't want the army here.
We don't need that kind of attention.
- Son of a bitch.
- (man) Quite a bit of excitement.
Why are you here, Nathan?
I was dispatched here
to make sure it doesn't get out of hand.
If you have any hopes
for a political future,
you will respond to our suggestions.
And what do you suggest, sir?
Full military attack. Destroy them.
China! Soldiers, stop her!
Yen!
Stop her! China!
China!
(Doc) Yen!
- (Murphy) The troops're being fired on.
- Cover me.
But your... the girl!
- Burn it!
- Excuse me?
Burn it!
- (Nathan) Mr Murphy!
- Never mind, Colonel.
Tell your troops not to mind my men
when they go around back.
(Nathan) Sergeant,
put your men on the line!
- Six squads up front.
- Come on, let's go.
Fire!
(Nathan) Hold your fire!
Dammit, cease fire!
Hey, Billy, please.
I got to go. I got to go.
I got a wife. I got a wife.
She's this little Mexican gal. Please!
Charley, start whipping some ass
or you'll never see her again!
Now, come on, Charley.
Go on, now! Come on, giddup!
That's it. Come on, let's go!
They lit it, boys!
They lit the house!
(Nathan) Mr Bonney!
Mr McSween!
This is Colonel Nathan Dudley!
Come on out with your hands high!
"With your hands high."
I better reason with him.
Hey, Colonel Shithead!
You can kiss my ass!
Goddamn it, Billy!
You get President Hayes down here,
then we'll come out!
- We'll see how they like that.
- (gunfire)
Hey, Kinney, you bastard!
I'm going to shoot your ass!
I'll shoot you from here to Patricio
if I have to, you shit dog!
- Yeah, Charley.
- (Charley) Maniac!
(yells)
Get 'em!
Maniac!
Yeah, Charley!
Yeah!
- Yeah, Charley!
- Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah, Charley!
Yeah!
Woooo!
Yeah.
(laughs)
Yeah, Charley.
Alex! Get Susan out of here!
- Come on, get out.
- Stop.
- No, I want my things.
- Susan, come on, get out!
(screams)
There's a woman coming out!
Let my wife come out!
Hold it. There's a lady coming out.
Hold your fire!
Yen, go home.
- Go!
- I stay with you.
Necessary.
(coughs)
Colonel.
Colonel, can I do anything for you, sir?
Back in the tent, perhaps?
I have no time for complaints.
Go to the other side of the street
so I can do my j...
- You animal.
- Get her out of here! Take her away!
Leave me alone!
Alex!
Where's Chavez?
Where the hell's Chavez?
- I don't know!
- What?
He's gone.
He must have skinned out!
I knew it! That dirty Mexican dog!
I... I...
I knew we shouldn't have trusted him!
I knew it!
We're gonna die in here and he's
out there doin' it with his horse!
I knew it! I just knew it!
(coughing)
Yeah!
(roars)
Run!
Chavez!
Yeah!
Regulators!
Billy!
(screams)
Hey, Kinney, you bastard,
it's you and I!
Doc!
Go, go, go!
He's getting away!
Dudley! Get that son of a bitch!
- Ride, boys!
- (Murphy) Dudley!
- Get that son of a bitch!
- Ride!
Those bastards...
Reap it, Murphy,
you son of a bitch.
Now it's over.
(Doc) Advices from Lincoln report Jose
Chavez Y Chavez moved to California
where he changed his name
and took work on a fruit ranch.
Josiah "Doc" Scurlock was reported
to have left the West for the East,
taking with him a Celestial bride, her
mother, and 14 brothers and sisters.
Susan McSween saw her husband's
and John Tunstall's dreams to fruition
by becoming one of the most
prominent cattle women of all time.
Governor Axtell was forced to resign
by president Rutherford B Hayes
and both the Murphy-Dolan faction
and the Santa Fe ring collapsed.
William H Bonney -
also known as Billy the Kid -
continued to ride,
never leaving New Mexico.
He was caught in Fort Sumner
by the sheriff Pat Garrett and killed.
Sources report that he was unarmed
and shot in the dark.
He was buried with Charley Bowdre
in Old Fort Sumner.
Advices report that an unidentified
person snuck into the graveyard
The epitaph read only one word:
"Pals."