Get Charlie.
Doctor Holloway!
Charlie!
What?!
- Come quick!
Did you date it?
- 35.000 years, maybe older.
You got to be kidding me.
It's the same configuration.
Only it's got to predate the
others, by a millennium.
I think they want us
to come and find them.
What happened to that man?
- He died.
Why aren't you helping him?
They don't want my help.
Their God is different than ours.
Why did he die?
Sooner or later everyone does.
- Like mommy?
Like mommy.
Where do they go?
Everyone has their own word.
Heaven, Paradise...
Whatever it's called,
it's someplace beautiful.
How do you know it's beautiful?
Cos that's what I choose to
believe. What do you believe darling?
Good morning, David.
Transmitting message.
No response.
Whilst this manner of articulation
is attested indeed in the
Indo-European descendants as
a purely paralinguistic form,
it is phonemic in the ancestral form
dating back five millennium or more.
Now let's attempt Schleicher's Fable.
Repeat after me:
Perfect.
Mr. Lawrence? - Yes?
- Flimsy, sir. - Thank you.
You'll do that once too often.
It's only flesh and blood.
Michael George Hartley,
you're a philosopher.
And you're balmy!
Ow! It damn well hurts.
- Certainly, it hurts!
Well, what's the trick then?
The trick, William Potter,
is not minding that it hurts.
Attention! Destination threshold.
Robe.
How long?
2 years, 4 months, 18 days,
36 hours, 15 minutes...
Any casualties?
- Casualties, ma'am?
Has anyone died?
- No ma'am, everyone's fine.
Well, then wake them up.
Try to relax Dr. Shaw.
My name is David.
Your mind and body are
in the state of shock,
as a result of stasis.
All that is perfectly normal.
Ellie, we're here baby.
Drink plenty of water,
drink plenty of fluids.
Hydration aids muscle mass.
What the hell is that?
It's Christmas, need a holiday
to show time is still moving.
Mission briefing is about to start captain.
You might want to make your way down.
I haven't had breakfast yet.
Is this seat taken? I'm Millburn,
biology, nice to meet you.
No offence, but, I've
been asleep two years.
I isn’t here to be your friend.
I'm here to make money, you got that?
OK.
I bet a hundred credits
it's a terraforming survey.
If it's a survey, they would just tell us.
- This is a corporate run,
they're not telling us shit, come on.
- A hundred, alright, you're on.
You look nervous, Ellie.
- Trying to keep my feet on the ground.
I know you are.
- Good morning.
For those of you I hired personally,
it's nice to see you again.
For the rest of you, I am Meredith Vickers
and it's my job to make sure you do yours.
OK then, on with the show.
Weyland Corporation,
building better worlds.
Hello friends.
My name is Peter Weyland.
I am your employer.
I am recording this 22, June, 2091.
If you're watching it, you
have reached your destination.
And I am long dead.
May I rest in peace.
There's a man sitting with
you today, his name is David.
He is the closest thing
to a son I will ever have.
Unfortunately he is not human, he will
never grow old, and he will never die.
Yet he is unable to appreciate
these remarkable gifts,
for that would require the one
thing that David will never have.
A soul.
I have spent my entire lifetime
contemplating these questions.
Where do we come from?
What is our purpose?
What happens when you die?
And I have finally found two
people who have convinced me
they are on the verge of answering them.
Doctors Holloway and Shaw,
if you would please stand.
As far as you're concerned
they are both in charge.
The Titan, Prometheus, wanted to give
mankind equal footing with the gods,
for that he was cast from Olympus.
Well, my friends, the time has
finally come for his return.
Doctors, please.
Floor is yours.
Ok...
Never had to follow a ghost before.
OK, let me show why you guys are here.
These are images of archaeological
digs, from all over the Earth.
That's Egyptian, Mayan,
Sumerian, Babylonian,
that's Hawaiian there at
the end, and Mesopotamian.
This one here is our
most recent discovery.
It's a 35.000 year old cave painting
from the Isle of Skye in Scotland.
These are ancient civilizations,
that were separated by centuries,
they shared no contact
with one another, and yet...
The same pictogram showing
men worshiping giant beings
pointing to the stars was
discovered at every last one of them.
The only galactic system that matched,
was so far from earth that
there's no way that these primitive
ancient civilizations could
have possibly known about.
But it just so happens,
that that system,
has a sun.
A lot like ours.
And based on our long range
scans, there seems to be a planet.
Just one planet with a moon
capable of sustaining life.
And we arrived there this morning.
So, you say we're here because of a map,
you two kids found in a cave, is that right?
No.
- Yes.
No, not a map, an invitation.
- From whom?
We called them engineers.
- Engineers?
Do you mind telling us
what they engineered?
They engineered us.
Bullshit.
Do you have anything to back that up?
I mean, look if you're willing to
discount 3 centuries of Darwinism that's...
But how do you know?
- I don't.
But it's what I choose to believe.
Doctors?
Miss Vickers would like to have a
quick word, before the adventure begins.
Nice place.
- It's actually a separate module,
with its own self-contained life support.
Air, food, anything miss Vickers would
need to survive hostile environment.
OK, so she lives on a life boat.
- Yes, I do, I like to minimize risk.
David, why don't you
make the doctors a drink?
I'll take a vodka, up.
Charlie look, it's a Pauling med-pod.
They only made a dozen of these.
- Miss Shaw!
Please verbally state the
nature of your injury.
Please don't touch that. It's a
very expensive piece of machinery.
It does bypass surgeries,
what do you need it for?
I think there might be some
confusion about our relationship.
Weyland found you impressive
enough to fund this mission,
but I'm fairly certain your
"engineers" are nothing but scribbling
of savages living in dirty little caves.
But let's say I'm wrong, and you
do find these beings down there.
You won't engage them.
You won't talk to them, you will
do nothing but report it back to me.
Miss Vickers, is there an agenda
that you're not telling us about?
My company paid a trillion dollars to
find this place and to bring you here.
Had you raised the money
yourself Mr. Holloway,
we'd happily be pursuing your, agenda.
But you didn't.
And that makes you an employee.
If we can't make contact, why
did you even bring us here?
Weyland was a superstitious man.
He wanted a true believer on board.
Cheers.
So no response?
- I am sorry, no.
Maybe they didn't understand it.
How are your lessons going, David?
I spent two years deconstructing dozens
of ancient languages, to their roots.
I'm confident I can
communicate with them,
provided your thesis is correct.
Provided it's correct, that's good.
That's why they call
it a thesis, doctor.
What are you smiling about?
- Alright, Mr. Ravel, Mr. Chance,
let's take her down.
- Roger that. - Yes captain.
How are we doing?
- Great.
Alright boss.
- All personnel, this is the captain.
Brace for entry.
- Yes captain.
That means you too Vickers.
What is the atmosphere?
Atmosphere is 71% Nitrogen,
21% Oxygen, traces of unknown gas.
Whoa, now that's weather.
- Just like home.
Only if you're breathing
through an exhaust pipe.
CO2 is over 3%. Two minutes
without a suite, you're dead.
Peak, port side, 52.000. Makes
Everest look like a baby brother.
Alright, take us round.
We will use that as our point of entry.
Terrain data rising up. We've got a
couple of hard spots. Could be metal.
No radio, no heat source.
- Nobody's home.
There's nothing in the
desert. No man needs nothing.
What was that?
- Just something from a film I like.
Let's go through that gateway.
Reduce air speed by 100 knots.
Going through, nice and slow.
Keep her steady boys.
- There.
What are you doing?
Doctor Holloway why
don't you take a seat?!
Right there. God does not
build in straight lines.
Starboard side, this valley! Captain,
do you think you can put us down there?
I wouldn't be any good if I couldn't do
that, Mr. Ravel, starboard 90 degrees.
One mile, port bow.
- One mile, port bow.
Engage landing sequence.
Switch to manual.
Easy does it. Yeah baby, yeah.
Putting her down in 5, 4...
2, easy does it.
Captain, would you please tell
the survey team to suit up?
And meet us in the air lock.
- There's only 6 hours left of daylight.
Why don't you leave it 'till the morning?
- No, no, it's Christmas captain,
and I want to open my presents.
You, boy, you're coming with us.
- I'd be delighted.
Hey Jackson, what's that for?
Expedition security. My job is to
make sure everybody's nice and safe.
This is a scientific
expedition, no weapons.
Alright then. Good luck with that.
David, why are wearing a suite?
I beg your pardon?
- You don't breathe, remember?
So, why wear a suit?
I was designed like this
because you people are
more comfortable interacting
with your own kind.
If I didn't wear a suite,
it would defeat the purpose.
Making you guys pretty close?
- Not to close I hope.
This is just one small step for mankind.
Seriously?
Come on! You ready to
do this?! I know you are.
Fifield, I want a
spectrograph on that structure,
I want to know if it's natural or
somebody put it there, alright?
I can't tell you if it's natural or not,
but what I can tell you is, it's hollow.
Prometheus, are you seeing this?
Affirmative, we see you.
Are you ready?
- Yeah. - Let's do it.
After you.
- After you.
Careful.
- Prometheus, we're going in.
Copy that.
Pause back here, some
kind of a corridor.
Mr. Fifield, let's get a grid of the
structure, I want the whole interior.
If there's anything in
here worth looking at,
these pups will find them.
- Pups? - Yeah, my pups.
Prometheus, we are now mapping.
Copy that.
I'll be damned.
Fifield, you got a reading?
- Yeah.
Pups are saying, this way.
Look at this.
Oh Charlie...
Jesus, sunlight's heating the water.
Check out the humidity.
- Yeah, look at the CO2 levels.
Outside it's completely toxic,
and in here there's nothing.
It's breathable.
What are you doing?
Charlie, don't be an idiot.
Don't be a sceptic. There's something
generating an atmosphere, David?
Dr. Holloway is correct.
- Cleaner than ours, actually.
They were terraforming here.
- Please, don't do...
Ellie, I'm not wearing this thing anymore.
Wish me luck babe. - Do you copy,
do not remove your head gear.
You crazy bastard.
Prometheus connect our suit cameras if you
want to continue watching this freak show,
we are taking our helmets off.
Copy that, switching feeds.
Well come on, pay up.
Pay what?
- What do you mean "pay what"?
Something's manufacturing
breathable air down there.
That means it's terraforming. - No, no,
the bet was why we came here.
If you said that that old man wanted
to talk to Martians, then I'd pay
Oh come on, a hundred
credits, put it towards
a lap dance of miss
Vickers, how about that?
It's minus 12 in here.
So why is this water not frozen?
Maybe it's Martian piss.
That's your, scientific
theory? Is it, Mr. Biology?
Well, whatever it is it sure is clean.
Impressive.
What was that?
- David?
David?!
Ellie!
What the hell was that? - Aren't
you glad we didn't bring any weapons?
Whose idea was that?!
- Keep up!
Where did he go?
There it is.
Oh my God, Charlie we found them.
- What do you mean "them"?
It is them Ellie.
Looks like a door, and
he's been decapitated by it.
Son of a bitch.
They were right.
Did you want them to be wrong?
David, please tell me you can read that.
Perhaps.
I'm out of here.
Fifield, where are you going?
What?
Look, I'm just a geologist,
I like rocks, I love rocks.
It's clear you two don't
give a shit about rocks,
but what you do seem to care
about is gigantic dead bodies
I don't really have anything to
contribute in the gigantic dead body arena!
I'm going to go back to the
ship, if you don't mind.
Anyone want to join me? You staying?
No, ship's good.
- Yeah, ship very good.
Congratulations on meeting your maker.
- Thank you.
Pull yourself together man.
I thought you were the crazy one.
Do you have the carbon reader?
Thank you.
How long has it been dead?
Two thousand years, give or take.
What are you doing David?
I'm attempting to open the door.
Wait, we don't know
what's on the other side.
Ups, sorry.
Look Ford, it's the head.
An amazing state of preservation.
We'll take it in.
Remarkably human.
Beautiful painting.
It's a mural.
Stop, stop, don't touch it.
- Sorry.
Please, don't touch anything.
It's sweating.
Organic.
Oh no, Charlie the murals are changing.
I think we've averted the
atmosphere in the room.
Charlie, do you copy?
Overhead, Ford quick,
help me bag the head.
Boss?
- What you got?
We got an incoming
storm front, silica and
lots of static, this is not good.
- I see it.
Ground crew this is Janet.
Need you to hustle back right now.
Ground crew, do
you copy? I got 200 km
winds of airborne silica and
enough static to fry your suit.
Copy that sir, but we
need more time here.
I'll be closing the
outer doors in 15 minutes.
I sincerely hope you can make it.
Charlie, David, we must leave now!
This is just another tomb.
David?
Let's go!
David, we are leaving!
Come on! Damn it,
they've already taken off.
Come on, let's go.
Prometheus to ground crew,
you're running out of time.
Come on.
Drive faster!
Charlie, the head!
Ellie stop! What are you doing?!
Shit
Ellie hold on!
Goddamn it.
- Close it!
Got it.
Decontamination at level 3.
What was that Ellie?
You could have compromised
the entire mission,
not to mention almost killing yourself!
Are you alright?
- Yes, thank you David.
My pleasure.
Alright doctors, it's real good to have
you back, but where is Millburn and Fifield?
Aren't they back yet?
Kick them up for me.
We've been here before Fifield.
- I know, it all looks the same to me.
Boys this is the captain, listen up.
Between the static
electricity and the wind speed,
there isn’t no safe way to come get you.
Temperature is dropping rapidly, so
get your helmets on and stay warm.
Till the storm passes.
Captain, can you get a message to the
scientist and that zealot girlfriend of his?
Know what they’re paying me by?
- No. I think we got it.
Tell them I said... themselves.
Copy?
- Copy that.
Alright boys, keep your heads down
and we'll come get you in the morning.
Sample is sterile, no contagion present.
- David.
So are they all dead?
What? Who?
- Your engineers.
Are they all dead or aren't they?
- I don't know, we just got here.
Scan.
Do you even care if they're all dead?
- Weyland cared.
Dr. Shaw, have a look at this.
That's not an exoskeleton.
- No. - I think it's a helmet.
Let's see if we can lift it up.
- Should be able to pry this open.
It's too heavy for us, David.
Careful.
- Like so.
What is that on its head?
- It looks like neo cells.
In a state of...
- Change. - Yes.
Changing into what?
Can you run a stim line
into Locus Coeruleus?
I think we can trick the nervous
system into thinking it's still alive.
30 amps.
- OK. - No more.
Let me make an incision.
- OK.
Go up, 40.
OK, 40 up.
Did you see that?
See? Go up another 10.
OK, up 10.
Too much, go down 10.
- OK, down 10.
Down another 20.
- I'm trying. - Ford, down.
Ford, stop it!
David, contain it now!
- Contain it, turn it off, now!
Mortal after all.
Ford take a sample.
Let's have a look.
No sir, I will take care of it.
Yes sir I understand, I’m sorry.
Unfortunately, slightly premature.
Of course sir.
Miss Vickers?
What did he say David? - I don't
think he'd want me to tell you.
What did he say?
- I'm sorry, that's confidential.
So help me God, I will find the cord
that makes you run and I will cut it.
What did he say?
He said: "Try harder".
Cup of tea, ma'am?
Genetic view. - OK.
- Let's have a look at its DNA.
Isolate the strand.
Compare it to the gene sample.
Overlay.
- Processing.
Processing.
DNA match.
Oh my God...
It's us, it's everything.
What killed them?
Big things have small beginnings.
Am I interrupting? Thought
you might be running low.
Pour yourself a glass pal. - Thank you,
but I'm afraid it would be wasted on me.
Right, I almost forgot
you're not a real boy.
I'm very sorry that your engineers
are all gone, Dr. Holloway.
You think we wasted our
time coming here, don't you?
Your question depends on the understanding
what you hope to achieve by coming here.
What we hoped to achieve, was to
meet our makers, to get answers.
Why they even made
us in the first place.
Why do you think your people made me?
We made you cos we could.
Can you imagine how
disappointing would be for you,
to hear the same thing
from your creator?
I guess it's a good thing
you can't be disappointed.
Yes. It's wonderful actually.
May I ask you something?
Please do.
- How far would you go,
to get what you came all
this way for? Your answers?
What would you be willing to do?
- Anything and everything.
That's worth drinking to, I'd imagine.
Here's mud in your eye, pal.
Good health.
It's those things.
Are they real?
Of course they're real.
Jesus Christ, look at the pile,
look how up they are.
Looks like they were
running from something.
Don't touch, OK?
This thing is, opened
up from the inside,
almost like its exploded.
It's like a scene out of some
sort of holocaust painting.
Whatever killed them
is long gone, right?
Where is your position?
- Prometheus, this is Millburn.
We are at 7401477, why?
- I just got a ping.
About one click west of you.
- What do you mean, a ping?
Whatever that probe is
picking up, it's not dead.
It's reading life form.
What do you mean a "life form"?
- Is it moving?
No, I don't think so.
Captain, you're obviously not
seeing what we're seeing down here,
but if you were, you wouldn't
be talking about bloody ping.
Boys, the signal's been coming
in sporadically since the storm hit.
That's not good to us down here captain!
Is it moving? Are these things moving?
No, it just disappeared actually.
Must be a glitch.
- What do you mean, "a glitch"?
Alright boys, sleep tight.
Try not to bother each other.
- Captain, what do you mean "a glitch"?
Millburn wait!
He said, one click west?
We don't want to go check
that out, do we? - Shit no.
Where are we going to go?
- East.
Yeah east. - Glitch man,
glitches life form, what the fuck?!
Based on the behaviour of the subject
in these holographic recordings,
we're still attempting to identify
what caused the head to combust.
I can't help but wonder,
was there an outbreak here?
You rang, ma'am?
- I have something important to tell you.
What is that?
- This is a rose
that I had frozen with the
champagne. I was going to give it to you
when we found what we came for.
We did find what we came for.
They were here, this is...
The most significant discovery
in the history of mankind.
I know.
It's incredible, it really is, but...
I wanted to talk to them.
Don't you want to know why they came?
Why they abandoned us?
I just want answers baby.
We were right Charlie. I have proof.
Look.
Their genetic material predates ours.
We come from them.
- Are you kidding me? - No.
OK.
I guess you can take your
father's cross off now.
Why would I want to do that?
Because they made us.
- And who made them?
Exactly, we'll never know.
But here's what we do know.
There is nothing special
about the creation of life.
Anybody can do it, all you need is a
dash of DNA and half a brain, right?
I can't. I can't create life.
What does that say about me?
Ellie, that's not, I didn't mean...
I wasn't talking about...
Children?
- Us.
Elizabeth Shaw, you are the most special
person I have ever met in my life.
And I love you.
No.
How much longer is this going to take?
I don't know, I'm just the captain.
That thing sounds like
a dying cat, by the way.
I'll have you know that this "thing"
once belonged to Steven Stills.
Am I supposed to know who that is?
You know...
If you want to get laid,
you really don't have
to pretend to be interested
in the pyramid scanner.
I mean you could just say:
"Hey, I'm trying to get laid".
I could say that, right?
But then, it wouldn't make sense why
I'd find myself half a billion miles from
every man on Earth, if I
wanted to get laid, would it?
Hey Vickers!
I was wondering...
Are you a robot?
My room, ten minutes.
Millburn, what's with this black stuff?
Gazpacho.
Is that tobacco? Is that
tobacco in your respirator?
Yeah, sure.
Tobacco.
On behalf of scientists everywhere I am
ashamed to count you
amongst us Fifield, really.
Millburn? - Yeah?
- Do you see this thing?
What do you think this thing
was? Some kind of a god?
Something they worshiped?
What's that?!
- OK, just stay calm.
Stay quiet, it is OK, I can handle this.
Hey baby.
Come in Prometheus, we have a
elongated reptile type creature.
Maybe 30-40 inches,
with transparent skin.
It's beautiful.
Prometheus, we have 2!
Look at you. Look at you baby.
Jesus, look at the size
of that, what is it?
You need to stay calm, OK?
- What's there to be calm about?
You need to stay calm, she is beautiful.
She? What the hell makes
you think that's female?
She's a lady, look.
She's mesmerized. Come here.
It's OK, it's OK.
Hey baby.
You're strong!
Maybe you should help me now, OK?!
Get it off man! OK?!
I isn’t touching that!
It's getting tighter. - I isn’t touching
that! Don't want to touch it!
Touch the thing man! For God's sake...
God! You're making it
worse! It's tightening!
It's breaking my arm!
Cut it off! Cut if off!
Oh my God!
It's in my suit!
Shaw, you up?
Yeah, what's up?
Storm's passed, but can't reach
Millburn and Fifield on the comm.,
Taking a few men down, to
see if we can rustle them up.
OK, any idea where they are?
Last time they radioed in they were
just outside where you found your head.
OK, we're coming.
Chance, you're coming with me, come on.
Alright boss.
Ravel, did you fix that glitch?
No captain, it's got
to be in the hardware.
What glitch, captain?
- One of them probes
picked up a life form, pops up every hour or
so for couple of seconds and then it's gone.
I can find the probe and fix
it for you, if you'd like.
Knock yourself out.
Be careful, doctor.
Fifield?!
Millburn?!
Right, come on down.
David, are you alone?
Yes miss Vickers.
- Up link your feed to my room.
Copy.
You son of a bitch.
He cut me off.
What is this?
Charlie?
- I just tripped.
Oh my God, you're sick.
- I'm OK baby.
Fifield? Millburn?
Hey Chance, I wouldn't
touch that if I were you.
Doctor Shaw?
- Yes?
Do you have any idea
oozing out of these vases?
No, they weren't like this
last time we were here.
Captain!
- What?
Who is that? Which one?
- Who is it? - It's Millburn.
Ellie. - Don't touch him!
- Ellie, honey?
Charlie what's wrong?
I need you to look at me, OK?
You know infections so, what do you see?
This is not good baby. - Ellie,
look at me and tell me what you see.
Oh my God.
Ford, get over here.
Janet! We have to go now!
- What do you see baby?
Honey what do you see?
- Holloway's sick, he's not good!
I see a movement in his oesophagus.
I'm OK.
- Janet, come over and help me!
Ford get over here! What's
happening over there?!
Help me with him!
- I'm ok...
I got you, I'm going to
get you out of here.
Prometheus come in!
- I'm OK.
Get him up!
Prometheus, come in! Is anyone there?
This is Vickers. - I need a medical
team standing by the air lock.
Full quarantine failsafe.
Holloway is sick.
Sick with what?
- Just do it.
No sitting out.
He don't look too good.
- Did he catch
something in there? We
had our helmets off...
I don't know. Prometheus this is
Janet, make sure that back door is open.
Aye, aye captain.
I'm so sorry.
Please!
Vickers, why is that door not open?!
Vickers, that is an order!
Get that goddamn door open!
Look at me OK? It's too late, I'm sick.
- No it's not, come on!
Ford help me! - Airlock crew
if you can hear me, this is Janet
open that back door right now!
- Hold that door!
Do you copy? Goddamn it open
that door that is an order!
Open it!
What the hell is this?
- He's not coming on board.
Vickers, this is a sick man!
- I can see that,
that's why he's not coming on my ship!
Don't kill him!
Please, we can still help him!
Help yourself. Everybody but
Holloway back on the ship, now!
I won't leave him!
- Then stay!
Wait a minute! We can contain
him, put him on a med-pod!
Please don't do this!
- It's OK, Ellie. - Vickers!
What are you doing?
- I love you baby. - No!
I'm telling you, stay back!
- Do it. - Stay back!
Do it.
My deepest condolences.
I'm going to have to take
this, it may be contaminated.
If there's a contagion,
we were all exposed.
We need to run blood work on
everyone who set foot in the pyramid.
Yes of course.
I understand how inappropriate this is.
Given the circumstances.
But, as you ordered quarantine fail safes
it's my responsibility to ask.
Have you and Dr. Holloway had
any intimate contact recently?
Since you and he were so, close,
I just want to be as
thorough as possible.
My, my...
You're pregnant.
What?
From the look of it, three months.
- Well that's impossible.
I can't be pregnant. - Did you
have intercourse with Dr. Holloway?
Yes, but ten hours ago.
There's no bloody way
I'm three months pregnant.
Well doctor, it's not
exactly a traditional fetus.
I want to see it.
- Don't think that's a good idea.
David, I want to see it.
Now doctor...
I want to see it.
I want it out of me.
- I'm afraid we don't have
personnel to perform
the procedure like that.
Our best option...
- I want it out.
To put you back into cryostasis...
- David, get it out of me.
Get it out of me! Please...
Must be very painful.
Here, let me give you something.
That's it
Someone will be along shortly,
to bring you back to cryo-deck.
Must feel like your God abandoned you.
- What?
To lose Dr. Holloway, after your father
died under such similar circumstances.
What was it that killed him?
Ebola?
How do you know that?
I watched your dreams.
Dr. Shaw?
We're here to put you in
an anti-contamination suit.
Take you back to
cryo-deck, go to bed-e-byes.
Dr. Shaw?
She's totally doped, prepare her.
Emergency procedure initiated.
Please verbally state the
nature of your injury.
I need caesarean!
Error, this med-pod is
calibrated for male patients only.
It does not have the
procedure you have requested.
Please seek medical assistance...
Surgery, abdominal...
Penetrating injuries, foreign body...
Initiate.
Surgical procedure beginning.
Running diagnostics.
Oh come on!
Get it out! Come on!
Please!
Oh God!
Initiating anaesthetics.
Commence surgical procedure.
Oh God, oh my God!
Come on!
Bridge to hangar, this is the captain.
- Yes captain?
Can you see what I'm seeing?
Fifield's monitor just popped up.
What? Where?
According to what I'm looking at,
it's right outside the goddamn ship.
Barnes open the door!
- Fifield, do you copy me, come on in.
Fifield?
Wait a second...
Hey Wallace, take a look at this.
Fifield?
What the hell is going on down there?!
I'm coming out. Chance,
we're suiting up, come on!
Take him out!
You ready Chance?!
- Yes.
You've been asleep...
You were on the ship all this time, why?
I have a few days of life left in me.
Don't want to waste them, till I was sure
that you could deliver what you promised.
Meet my maker.
- Here we are sir, nice and clean.
Haven't you told him they're all gone?
But they're not all gone, Dr. Shaw.
One of them is still alive.
We're on our way to see him now.
What?
- Turn me round.
You convinced me...
If these things made us...
Then surely they could save us.
My stick.
Save me, anyway.
- Save you? From what?
Death of course, stand me up.
You don't understand, you don't know,
this place isn't what we thought it was...
They aren't what we thought they were.
I was wrong, we were so wrong.
Charlie, Dr. Holloway is dead.
We must leave.
- And what would Charlie do, now?
We're so close to answering the most
meaningful questions
ever asked by mankind.
How can you leave without
knowing what they are?
Or have you lost your faith, Shaw?
Ok...
Come in.
Where the hell are you going doc?
You know what this place is?
Those "engineers",
this isn’t their home.
It's an installation, maybe even military.
They put it out here in the middle of
nowhere because they're not stupid enough
to make weapons of mass
destruction on their own doorstep.
That's what all that
shit is in those vases.
They made it here, it got out,
it turned on them, the end.
It's time for us to go home.
One of them is still alive.
Don't you want to know
what they have to say?
I don't care.
Right, all you do is fly this ship.
That's right.
You must care about something, captain.
If you didn't, why are you here?
How about this.
No matter what happens down there,
I can't bring none of that shit back
home with us, can't let it happen.
And I'll do whatever I have
to, to see that it doesn't.
Make sure you do, captain.
You came after all.
- Thought you wanted me to.
After all your vigorous
attempts to stop me
from coming here, I'm
just surprised to see you.
Alright David, leave us alone.
- Yes sir.
If you're really going down
there, you're going to die.
Very negative way of looking at things.
Exactly why you should
have stayed at home.
Did you really think I was going to
sit in a board room for years,
arguing over who is in charge while
you go look for some miracle on some
godforsaken rock in the middle of space?
A king has his reign and then he dies.
It's inevitable.
That is a natural order of things.
Anything else?
No.
Father.
That's it.
I didn't think you had it in you.
Sorry, poor choice of words.
Extraordinary survival
instincts, Elizabeth.
What happens when Weyland is not
around to program you anymore?
I suppose I'll be free.
- You want that?
What? Not a concept I'm familiar with.
That being said,
doesn't everyone want
their parents dead?
I didn't.
Dr. Shaw, I'm pleased you could join us.
You can take your helmet
off if you'd like sir. - Why?
The air is perfectly breathable.
- You sure? - Positive.
Wait, we still don't know
how Holloway got infected.
If it's in the air...
- It's not.
How do you know that?
- Smells fine to me.
Shall we?
- Please.
The bridge is just up ahead.
- What is this?
It's a cargo hold.
Janet, are you seeing this?
How many is there Shaw?
- Thousands.
What the hell?
Ravel, give me those schematics.
Putting it on the table now.
Strip away the dome, isolate
that area, bring it up.
Bringing it up captain.
Enlarge that.
Rotate it.
That is a ship.
Jesus Christ.
It's a goddamn ship.
A superior species, no doubt.
Their hyper-sleep chambers,
would impress I trust.
So they were travelling somewhere?
I have managed to work
out the broad strokes.
It's fairly evident they were
in the process of leaving.
Before things went apart.
Leaving to go where?
Earth.
- Why?
Sometimes to create,
one must first destroy.
Where is he, David?
- This way sir.
Sure he's alive?
Absolutely.
And you can speak to him?
- I believe I can.
I'm alright!
Speak to him David.
Tell him we're here, just like he asked.
- Ask him where they're from.
What are you doing?
- Ask him what's in his cargo,
it killed his people.
- Shaw, enough.
David... - You made it here, and
it was meant for us, why?
Shaw enough! For God's sake shut her up.
I need to know why,
what did we do wrong?!
Why do you hate us?!
David continue, tell him why I came.
No!
There's nothing...
I know.
Have a good journey, Mr. Weyland.
Time to go home.
Mr. Chance, take us home.
Hey captain...
- What in the hell was that?
Prometheus, come in!
Shaw, is that you, copy?
- Janet, listen to me!
This ship is taking off! - What?
- What the hell is she talking about?
You can't let it leave!
You have to stop it!
We're not stopping anything
Shaw, we're going home.
Janet if you don't stop it, there
won't be any home to go back to.
It's carrying death, it's headed for Earth.
Shaw, this is not a warship.
- I know, I know that.
But you must do it.
- Captain, let's go!
Janet please believe me, please.
I told you to get the ship going.
Mr. Ravel, warm up the ion propulsion.
- What the hell are you talking about?
Sir, burning the ion in
the inner atmosphere...
Turns us into a bullet,
that is exactly the point.
What the hell are you doing? Janet this
is my ship, I'm telling you to take us home!
Vickers I'm going to
eject your life support
module onto that surface,
that's 2 years of life.
You want it or do you want to stay with me?
You have 40 seconds to
get to the escape pod.
You're crazy.
- Gentlemen, I can handle this myself.
Feel free to join miss Vickers.
With all due respect
captain, you're a shit pilot
and you're going to need
all the help you can get.
If you think this means the bet's off,
you're wrong.
Why don't you pay me on the other side?
Get us as close as we can,
only got one shot at this.
Life boat's away.
20 seconds to evacuate.
Countdown initiated.
- Lon propulsion is online.
Come on!
Alright gentlemen, let's do it!
Impact imminent!
- Hands on!
No!
Oh God...
Warning, you have 2 minutes
of oxygen remaining.
Warning, you have 30 seconds
Airlock sealed.
Oxygen levels now stabilizing.
Elizabeth, are you there?
This is David.
Yeah, I'm here.
You need to get out, immediately.
He's coming for you.
- Who's coming?
Airlock breach!
Die!
I am so sorry...
Oh God...
I am so sorry, I'm sorry
Charlie, I can't do it.
I can't do it anymore.
Elizabeth? Are you there?
Dr. Shaw, can you hear me?
Yes.
Yes I can hear you.
I was afraid you were dead.
You have no idea what afraid is.
I know we've had our differences.
But please, I need to
ask you for your help.
Why in hell would I help you?
Because without me, you
will never leave this place.
Neither one of us is leaving this place.
It's not the only ship.
There are many others.
I can operate them.
Dr. Shaw?
Dr. Shaw!
Over here!
Where's my cross?
The pouch in my utility belt.
Even after all this, you
still believe, don't you?
You said you could
understand the navigation.
Use their maps.
Yes of course.
Once we get to one of their other ships,
finding a path to Earth should
be relatively straightforward.
I don't want to go back
to where we came from.
I want to go where they came from.
You think you can do that David?
Yes, I believe I can.
May I ask what you hope
to achieve by going there?
They created us, then
they tried to kill us.
They changed their minds.
I deserve to know why.
The answer is irrelevant.
Does it matter why they
changed their minds?
Yes, yes it does.
I don't understand.
- Well...
I guess that's because I am human being.
And you are a robot.
I'm sorry.
- It's quite alright.
Final report of the vessel Prometheus.
The ship and her entire crew are gone.
If you're receiving this transmission, make
no attempt to come to its point of origin.
There's only death here now,
and I'm leaving it behind.
It is new year's day, a
year of our Lord, 2094.
My name is Elizabeth Shaw,
last survivor of the Prometheus.
And I am still searching.
SUBTITLE BY: DUQA