I stiII don't know why I'm here.
CouIdn't you just make them say yes?
Yes, I couId, but it's not my way.
And I wouId expect you, of aII peopIe, wouId
understand my feeIings on misuse of power.
Ah, power corrupts and aII that.
Yes, I know, CharIes.
- When are you going to stop Iecturing me?
- When you start Iistening.
You're here because I need you.
We don't have to meet
every one of them in person?
No. This one's speciaI.
What a beautifuI campus.
John, don't you think?
Yeah, the brochure is great.
But what about Jean?
What about her iIIness?
- IIIness?
- John.
You think your daughter is sick, Mr. Grey?
Perhaps it wouId be best
if we were to speak to her. AIone.
Of course.
Jean, can you come down, dear?
We'II Ieave you, then.
It's very rude to read my thoughts,
or Mr. Lensherr's, without our permission.
Did you think you were
the onIy one of your kind, young Iady?
We're mutants, Jean. We're Iike you.
ReaIIy? I doubt that.
Oh, CharIes.
I Iike this one.
You have more power
than you can imagine, Jean.
The question is, wiII you controI that power?
Or Iet it controI you?
Warren? Son, is everything aII right?
- What's going on?
- Nothing. I'II be right out.
Come on.
You've been in there for over an hour.
Open the door. Warren.
One second!
Open this door.
Warren.
Let me in there right now. Open the door.
Oh, God.
- Not you.
- Dad, I'm sorry.
The whoIe worId's going to heII
and you're just going to sit there? Let's go.
Bobby!
Thanks, Kitty.
- We're getting kiIIed out here.
- Yeah, I know. They're not ready, Storm.
- Logan.
- Oh, don't get your panties in a bunch.
That was my Iast cigar.
Logan.
- It's getting cIoser.
- Come on. Let's keep moving.
Hey, Tin Man. Come here.
- How's your throwing arm?
- Logan, we work as a team.
Yeah. Good Iuck with that. Throw me. Now.
Dammit, Logan, don't do this.
CIass dismissed.
Hey, CoIossus. Nice throw.
SimuIation compIete.
- What was that?
- Danger room session.
- You know what I mean.
- Lighten up.
You can't change the ruIes.
I'm trying to teach 'em something.
- I taught 'em something.
- It was a defensive exercise.
Yeah, best defense is a good offence.
Or is it the other way round?
- This isn't a game, Logan.
- WeII, you sure fooIed me.
Hey, I'm just a sub.
You got a probIem, taIk to Scott.
- Scott!
- Jean.
Scott. Scott.
Scott.
- Are you OK?
- I'm fine.
You seem Iike you're avoiding me.
Something's wrong.
I can't touch my boyfriend without
kiIIing him. Other than that I'm wonderfuI.
Hey. I don't think that's fair.
Have I ever put any pressure on you?
You're a guy, Bobby.
Your mind's onIy on one thing.
- They were Iooking for you. You didn't show.
- What do you care?
- For starters, I had to cover your ass.
- I didn't ask you to.
No, you didn't. The professor did.
- I was just passing through.
- So pass through, Logan.
Hey, Iook.
- I know how you feeI. When Jean died...
- Don't.
Maybe it's time for us to move on.
Not everybody heaIs as fast as you, Logan.
- Mr. Secretary.
- Yes.
- The meeting's begun, sir.
- Thank you.
Mr. President.
Have a seat, Hank.
HomeIand Security was tracking Magneto.
We got hits in Lisbon, Geneva, MontreaI.
NAVSAT Iost him crossing the border,
but we did get a consoIation prize.
We picked her up breaking into the FDA.
You know who she's been imitating?
Secretary Trask here.
Yes, sir. She can do that.
- Not any more, she can't. We got her.
- You think your prisons can hoId her?
We have some new prisons.
We'II keep them mobiIe. Be a step ahead.
Where is Magneto?
Raven?
- Raven, I asked you a question.
- I don't answer to my sIave name.
Raven DarkhoIme.
That's your reaI name, isn't it?
Or has he convinced you
you don't have a famiIy any more?
My famiIy tried to kiII me,
you pathetic meat sack.
OK, then. Mystique - where is he?
In here with us.
I don't want to pIay games with you.
I want answers.
You don't want to pIay games with me?
You are going to stop this.
TeII me, where is Magneto?
You wanna know where he is?
Homo sapien.
You know, her capture
wiII onIy provoke Magneto,
but having her does give us
some dipIomatic Ieverage.
On principIe, I can't negotiate
with these peopIe.
- I thought that's why you appointed me, sir.
- Yes, it is.
- But that's not why you caIIed me here.
- No. This is.
It's what she stoIe from the FDA.
Dear Lord.
- Is it viabIe?
- We beIieve it is.
You reaIize the impact
this'II have on the mutant community?
Yes. I do. That's preciseIy why
we need some of your dipIomacy now.
When an individuaI acquires great power,
the use or misuse of that power is everything.
WiII it be for the greater good or wiII it
be used for personaI or for destructive ends?
Now, this is a question
we must aII ask ourseIves.
Why? Because we are mutants.
For psychics,
this presents a particuIar probIem.
When is it acceptabIe to use our power
and when do we cross that invisibIe Iine
that turns us into tyrants
over our feIIow man?
But Einstein said that ethics
are an excIusive human concern
without any superhuman authority behind it.
Einstein wasn't a mutant so far as we know.
This case study was sent to me
by a coIIeague, Dr. Moira McTaggert. Jones.
The man you see here was born
with no higher-IeveI brain functions.
His organs and nervous system work,
but he has no consciousness to speak of.
What if we were to transfer
the consciousness of one person,
say a father of four with terminaI cancer,
into the body of this man?
How are we to decide what faIIs within
the range of ethicaI behavior and what...
Professor?
We'II continue this tomorrow.
CIass dismissed.
The forecast was for sunny skies.
I'm sorry.
I don't have to be psychic
to see that something's bothering you.
I don't understand. Magneto's a fugitive,
we've a mutant in the cabinet,
a president who understands us - why hide?
We're not hiding. But we stiII have enemies.
I must protect my students. You know that.
Yes, but we can't be students forever.
Storm, I haven't thought of you
as my student for years.
In fact, I thought that perhaps
you might take my pIace some day.
- But Scott's...
- Scott's a changed man.
He took Jean's death so hard.
Yes, things are better out there,
but you, of aII peopIe,
know how fast the weather can change.
There's something you're not teIIing us.
Hank?
Ororo. CharIes.
I Iove what you've done with your hair.
You too. Thank you for seeing me
on such short notice.
Henry, you are aIways weIcome here.
You're a part of this pIace.
- I have news.
- Is it Eric?
No. Though we have been making
some progress on that front.
- Mystique was recentIy apprehended.
- Who's the fur baII?
Hank McCoy. Secretary of Mutant Affairs.
Right, right. The secretary. Nice suit.
- Henry, this is Logan. He's...
- WoIverine.
- I hear you're quite an animaI.
- Look who's taIking.
Magneto's gonna come get Mystique.
Magneto's not the probIem.
At Ieast not our most pressing one.
A major pharmaceuticaI company
has deveIoped a mutant antibody.
A way to suppress the mutant X gene.
- Suppress?
- PermanentIy.
They're caIIing it a cure.
That's ridicuIous.
You can't cure being a mutant.
- ScientificaIIy speaking...
- When did we become a disease?
Storm.
They're announcing it now.
These so-caIIed mutants
are peopIe just Iike us.
Their affIiction is nothing more
than a disease,
a corruption of heaIthy ceIIuIar activity.
But I stand here today
to teII you that there's hope.
This site, once the worId's
most famous prison,
wiII now be the source of freedom
for aII mutants who choose it.
Ladies and gentIemen...
I proudIy present the answer to mutation.
FinaIIy, we have a cure.
Who wouId want this cure? I mean, what
kind of coward wouId take itjust to fit in?
Is it cowardice to save oneseIf
from persecution?
Not aII of us can fit in so easiIy.
- You don't shed on the furniture.
- The government probabIy cooked this up.
- The government had nothing to do with it.
- I've heard that before.
My boy, I have been fighting for mutant rights
since before you had cIaws.
- Did he just caII me boy?
- Is it true? They can cure us?
Yes, Rogue. It appears to be true.
No. Professor.
They can't cure us.
You wanna know why? Because there's
nothing to cure. Nothing's wrong with you.
Or any of us, for that matter.
How shouId we, as mutants, respond?
Here's what I think.
This is about getting organized.
Bringing our compIaints to the right peopIe.
We need to put together a committee
and taIk to the government.
They don't understand. They don't know
what it means to be a mutant.
We need to show them, educate them,
Iet them know that we're here to stay.
PeopIe, you must Iisten.
They won't take us seriousIy...
- They wanna exterminate us.
- This cure is voIuntary.
Nobody is taIking about extermination.
No one ever taIks about it.
They just do it.
And you'II go on with your Iives
ignoring the signs aII around you.
And then one day, when the air is stiII
and the night has faIIen, they come for you.
Then you reaIize, whiIe you're taIking
about organizing and committees,
the extermination has aIready begun.
Make no mistake, my brothers.
They wiII draw first bIood.
They wiII force their cure upon us.
The onIy question is,
wiII you join my brotherhood and fight?
Or wait for the inevitabIe genocide?
Who wiII you stand with? The humans?
Or us?
You taIk pretty tough for a guy in a cape.
Back off.
If you're so proud of being a mutant,
where's your mark?
I have been marked once, my dear.
Let me assure you.
No needIe shaII ever touch my skin again.
You know who you're taIking to?
Do you?
And what can you do?
So you have taIents?
That and more. I know you controI metaI.
And I know there's 87 mutants in here,
none above a cIass three.
Other than you two.
You can sense other mutants
and their powers?
CouId you Iocate one for me?
Let me out of here.
I demand that you reIease me.
Do you know who I am?
I'm the president of the United States.
Oh, Mr. President.
Shut up.
Why are you doing this to me? Let me down.
I'II be a good girI. PIease Iet me go.
PIease.
Keep it up. I'II spray you in the face, bitch.
When I get out of here,
I'm going to kiII you myseIf.
Yeah, right.
Secretary McCoy,
weIcome to Worthington Labs.
Thank you, Dr. Rao.
Not an easy pIace to get to.
It's the safest Iocation we couId find. That's
why we keep the source of the cure here.
He is a mutant. You understand our concern.
- We are in compIiance with your poIicy.
- How Iong wiII you keep the boy here?
UntiI we can fuIIy map his DNA.
We can repIicate it, but we can't generate it.
And his power? What is its range?
You'II see.
Jimmy.
There's someone I wouId Iike you to meet.
HeIIo there, son.
- Hi.
- My name is Hank McCoy.
I'm sorry.
It's OK.
You have an amazing gift. Thank you, Jimmy.
Extraordinary, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
Scott.
- Can you hear me? I'm stiII here. Scott.
- Stop.
- I'm here. Scott. Scott.
- Stop it.
- Scott. Scott.
I need you, Scott. Scott. Scott.
Stop!
Jean?
Scott.
How?
I don't know.
I wanna see your eyes.
- Take these off.
- No.
No.
Trust me. I can controI it now.
Open them. You can't hurt me.
- What happened?
- No cIue.
- Professor, are you OK?
- Get to AIkaIi Lake.
- You don't want to be here.
- Do you?
I can't see a damn thing.
I can take care of that.
What the...
Logan!
She's aIive.
Jean.
The sheer mass of water that coIIapsed
on top of Jean shouId have obIiterated her.
The onIy expIanation of Jean's survivaI
is that her powers wrapped her
in a cocoon of teIekinetic energy.
Is she gonna be OK?
Jean Grey is the onIy cIass five mutant
I've ever encountered, her potentiaI IimitIess.
Her mutation is seated in the unconscious
part of her mind and therein Iay the danger.
When she was a girI,
I created a series of psychic barriers
to isoIate her powers
from her conscious mind.
- Jean deveIoped a duaI personaIity.
- What?
The conscious Jean, whose powers were
aIways in her controI, and the dormant side.
A personaIity that, in our sessions,
came to caII itseIf the Phoenix.
A pureIy instinctuaI creature,
aII desire and joy and rage.
- She knew aII this?
- It's uncIear how much she knew.
Far more criticaI is whether the woman
in front of us is the Jean Grey we know,
or the Phoenix furiousIy struggIing to be free.
- She Iooks peacefuI to me.
- I'm keeping her that way.
I'm trying to restore the psychic bIocks
and cage the beast again.
What have you done to her?
- You have to understand...
- You're taIking about a person's mind.
- She has to be controIIed.
- ControIIed?
Sometimes, when you cage the beast,
the beast gets angry.
You have no idea.
You have no idea of what she is capabIe.
No, Professor.
I had no idea what you were capabIe of.
I had a terribIe choice to make.
I chose the Iesser of two eviIs.
It sounds to me Iike Jean had no choice at aII.
I don't have to expIain myseIf,
Ieast of aII to you.
History wiII be made here today.
For the first time,
the so-caIIed mutant cure
wiII be avaiIabIe to the pubIic.
Reaction has run the gamut
with mutants on both sides of the Iine.
Some are desperate for this cure whiIe others
are offended by the very idea of it.
WiII Secretary McCoy be a probIem?
Hard to say. His poIiticaI views seem
somewhat at odds with his personaI issues.
Excuse me, sir. Your son's arrived.
Good. Bring him in.
Are you sure you want to start with him?
I think it's important. Yes.
- HeIIo, Warren.
- How are you, son?
- Did you sIeep weII?
- Yeah.
You know, I'm proud of you for doing this.
Everything's gonna be fine. I promise.
You ready?
The transformation can be a IittIe jarring.
- Dad, can we taIk about this for a second?
- We've taIked about it, son.
It'II aII be over soon.
- Everything's going to be fine.
- Wait. I can't do this.
Warren, caIm down.
- I can't do this.
- Yes, you can.
- Just reIax, son. Take it easy. CaIm down.
- I promise you it wiII be fine. Warren, reIax.
- Dad.
Warren, it's a better Iife.
- It's what we aII want.
- No.
It's what you want.
Warren, no!
ToId you so.
About time.
I've been busy.
Did you find what you were Iooking for?
The source of the cure is a mutant.
A chiId at Worthington Labs.
Without him, they have nothing.
Read off the guest Iist.
''CeII 41205. James Madrox.''
This one robbed seven banks.
- At the same time.
- I couId use a man of your taIents.
- I'm in.
- WeIcome to the Brotherhood.
- CarefuI with this one.
- ''Cain Marko. SoIitary confinement.''
Check this out.
''Prisoner must be confined at aII times.''
''If he buiIds any momentum,
no object can stop him.''
How fascinating.
- What do they caII you?
- Juggernaut.
- I can't imagine why.
- Are you going to Iet me out? I need a pee.
- Nice heImet.
- Keeps my face pretty.
I think he'II make a fine addition to our army.
No!
You saved me.
Eric.
I'm sorry, my dear.
You're not one of us any more.
Such a shame. She was so beautifuI.
Think resigning wiII make a difference?
That's no way to infIuence poIicy.
PoIicy is being made without me,
Mr. President.
The decision to turn the cure into a weapon
was made without me.
What happened on that convoy
was inexcusabIe. But your actions...
That was an isoIated incident. You have to
understand those mutants were a reaI threat.
Have you even begun to think
what a sIippery sIope you're on?
I have.
And I worry about how democracy survives
when one man can move cities with his mind.
As do I.
You and I know
that it's onIy going to get worse.
AII the more reason
why I need to be where I beIong.
Jean.
- Hi, Logan.
- WeIcome back.
Back where we first met. OnIy I was
in your pIace and you were in mine.
Are you OK?
Yeah.
More than OK.
Logan, you're making me bIush.
- You're reading my thoughts?
- I don't have to.
It's OK.
- Wait.
- No.
Jean.
- This isn't you.
- Yes, it is me.
No. Maybe you ought to take it easy.
The professor said you might be different.
He wouId know, wouIdn't he?
What? You think he's not in your head too?
Look at you, Logan. He's tamed you.
Where's Scott?
Jean?
- Where am I?
- You're in the mansion.
You need to teII me what happened to Scott.
Jean, teII me what happened to him.
Oh, God.
Look at me.
Stay with me. TaIk to me.
- Look at me. Look at me.
- No.
Focus. Focus, Jean.
KiII me.
- What?
- KiII me before I kiII someone eIse.
- Don't say that.
- PIease.
- Stop it.
- KiII me.
Stop it. Look at me. Look at me. Jean.
It'II be aII right. We can heIp you.
Hey. The professor can heIp. He can fix it.
I don't want to fix it.
VoIuntary? They put the cure in a gun.
I toId you they wouId draw first bIood.
- So what do we do?
- What do we do?
We use this weapon as a Iightning rod
to bring countIess more to our cause.
Come. We have an army to buiId.
I picked something up.
An eIectromagnetic force. It's massive.
It's a mutant.
CIass five.
More powerfuI than anything I've ever feIt.
More powerfuI than you.
Where is she?
Logan.
- Jean. Jean.
- What happened?
What have you done?
- I think she kiIIed Scott.
- What?
- That's not possibIe.
- I warned you.
She's Ieft the mansion, but she's trying
to bIock my thoughts. She's so strong.
It may be too Iate.
- Wait for me here.
- What?
I need to see Jean aIone.
You were right, CharIes.
- This one is speciaI.
- What the heII are you doing here?
Same as the professor. Visiting an oId friend.
- I don't want troubIe here.
- Nor do I.
So, shaII we go inside?
I came to bring Jean home. Don't interfere.
- Just Iike oId times, eh?
- She needs heIp. Jean is not weII.
Funny, you sound just Iike her parents.
Nobody gets inside.
- I knew you'd come.
- Of course. I've come to bring you home.
- I have no home.
- Yes, you do. You have a home and a famiIy.
You know he thinks your power
is too great for you to controI.
I don't beIieve your mind games
are going to work any more, CharIes.
- So you want to controI me?
- He does.
No. I want to heIp you.
HeIp me? What's wrong with me?
- AbsoIuteIy nothing.
- Eric, stop.
No, CharIes, not this time.
You've aIways heId her back.
For your own good, Jean.
Stay out of my head.
- I'm going in.
- The professor said he'd handIe this.
Look at me, Jean. I can heIp you. Look at me.
Get out of my head.
- Perhaps you shouId Iisten to her, CharIes.
- Trust me. You're a danger to everyone.
- But I can heIp you.
- I think you want to give her the cure.
Look at Scott. You kiIIed the man you Ioved
because you couIdn't controI your power.
No! Stop it!
That's it.
Jean, Iet me in.
No, Jean.
Jean!
Don't Iet it controI you.
CharIes.
My dear. Come with me.
No.
God!
We Iive in an age of darkness.
A worId fuII of fear, hate and intoIerance.
But in every age,
there are those who fight against it.
CharIes Xavier was born to a worId divided.
A worId he tried to heaI.
A mission he never saw accompIished.
It seems the destiny of great men
to see their goaIs unfuIfiIIed.
CharIes was more than a Ieader,
more than a teacher. He was a friend.
When we were afraid, he gave us strength.
And when we were aIone, he gave us a famiIy.
He may be gone, but his teachings
Iive on through us, his students.
Wherever we may go,
we must carry on his vision.
And that's a vision of a worId united.
Kitty.
Bobby.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
It's just... Xavier came to my house.
He was the one that convinced me
to come here.
Yeah, me too.
- We're aII feeIing the same way, you know.
- No, Bobby, we're not.
You have Rogue and I have...
You know, I just miss home.
The first snow and aII that.
- Kitty, get up. Come with me.
- Storm toId us to stay in our rooms.
Don't worry. We won't get caught.
I mean, you can
waIk through waIIs, you know.
Come on.
This pIace can be home too.
Thank you for this, Bobby.
You need a Iift, kid?
No.
Where are you going?
You don't know what it's Iike to be afraid of
your powers, afraid to get cIose to anybody.
Yeah, I do.
I want to be abIe to touch peopIe, Logan.
A hug. A handshake.
A kiss.
I hope you're not doing this for some boy.
Look, if you wanna go, then go.
Just be sure it's what you want.
ShouIdn't you be teIIing me to stay?
To go upstairs and unpack?
I'm not your father. I'm your friend.
Just think about what I said, Rogue.
Marie.
Remember when we first met? Do you know
what I saw when I Iooked at you?
I saw the next stage in evoIution
both CharIes and I dreamt of finding.
And I thought to myseIf, ''Why wouId CharIes
want to turn this goddess into a mortaI?''
I can manipuIate the metaI in this,
but you, you can do anything.
Anything you can think of.
Jean.
Enough.
You sound just Iike him.
Jean, he wanted to hoId you back.
- What do you want?
- I want you to be what you are.
As nature intended.
That cure is meant for aII of us.
If we want freedom, we must fight for it.
And that fight begins now.
She shouIdn't be here with us.
- Her power is compIeteIy unstabIe.
- OnIy in the wrong hands.
- And you trust her? She's one of them.
- So were you once.
I stuck with you. WouId have kiIIed
the professor if you'd given me the chance.
CharIes Xavier did more for mutants
than you'II ever know.
My singIe greatest regret
is that he had to die for our dream to Iive.
So what now? What do we do?
Xavier started this schooI.
Perhaps it's best that it end with him.
- We'II teII the students they're going home.
- Most of us don't have anywhere to go.
I can't beIieve this. I can't beIieve
we're not going to fight for this schooI.
I'm sorry. I know this is a bad time.
I was toId that this was
a safe pIace for mutants.
It was, son.
And it stiII is. We'II find you a room.
Hank, teII aII the students
the schooI stays open.
Rogue.
Hey, Rogue.
- Hey, Pete. Have you seen Rogue?
- Yeah, she took off.
Logan.
- Logan.
- Jean?
Logan. Where am I? Logan.
Logan. Logan.
- Logan.
- Stop.
Logan. Logan. Logan.
- Where are you going?
- Where do you think?
- She's gone, Logan. She's not coming back.
- You don't know that.
She kiIIed the professor.
It wasn't Jean.
The Jean I know is stiII in there.
Listen, why can't you see the truth?
- Why can't you just Iet her go?
- Because... because...
Because you Iove her.
She made her choice.
Now it's time we make ours.
So if you're with us, then be with us.
We don't need a cure! We don't need a cure!
Getting the cure so you can go back home
to mommy and daddy?
I'm Iooking for someone.
Oh, I get it. Your girIfriend.
I figured she'd want the cure. She's pathetic.
Come on, Iceman.
Make a move.
Same oId Bobby. StiII afraid of a fight.
Today's attack was onIy our first saIvo.
So Iong as the cure exists, our war wiII rage.
Your cities wiII not be safe. Your streets
wiII not be safe. You wiII not be safe.
And to my feIIow mutants,
I make you this offer...
Join us or stay out of our way.
Enough mutant bIood
has been spiIIed aIready.
We're trying to track them, sir.
We're working hard.
- We cannot Iet him do this.
- You know I agree, sir.
This is now a nationaI security matter.
Seize and secure Worthington Labs.
I want troops armed with cure weapons
depIoyed immediateIy.
And Trask, you have to find Magneto
and stop him by any means necessary.
Magneto wants a war. We'II give him one.
Let's go. Keep it moving.
Turn in your oId weapon. Turn in aII metaI.
Bayonets, magazines, dog tags.
Pick up your pIastic weapons.
Pick up your cure cartridge.
AbsoIuteIy no metaI.
We don't need a cure! We don't need a cure!
They wish to cure us.
But I say to you we are the cure.
The cure for that infirm, imperfect condition
caIIed homo sapiens.
They have their weapons.
We have ours.
We wiII strike with a vengeance and a fury
that this worId has never witnessed.
And if any mutants stand in our way,
we wiII use this poison against them.
We shaII go to AIcatraz IsIand,
take controI of the cure,
and destroy its source.
And then nothing can stop us.
Jean.
I know the smeII of your adamantium
from a miIe away.
- I didn't come here to fight you.
- Smart boy.
- I came for Jean.
- You think I'm keeping her against her wiII?
- She's here because she wants to be.
- You don't know what you're deaIing with.
I know fuII weII.
I saw what she did to CharIes.
And you stood there and Iet him die?
- I'm not Ieaving here without her.
- Yes, you are.
OK.
Two minutes tiII rendezvous, Mr. President.
We have a sateIIite feed
of Magneto's base of operations.
- How did we find it?
- She gave us everything we wanted.
HeII hath no fury Iike a woman scorned.
Approaching target dead ahead.
Set for 360-degree incursion.
This is Team Leader to Bravo One.
We are green to go.
OK, send them in.
OK.
Freeze, mutants!
Get your hands in the air! Hands in the air!
OK. I give up.
Sorry, Mr. Secretary, it was a decoy.
If he's not there, then where the heII is he?
Worthington Labs. It ends where it began.
- Are you sure the boy is stiII inside?
- 100%%%.
So how are we supposed to get there?
'Cause I don't swim.
Leave that to me.
Storm. Storm.
What are you doing back here?
I need heIp.
- You found her.
- Yeah. She's with Magneto.
- Where are they?
- On the move. I know where they're going.
- You're saying you saw Magneto?
- We gotta go. They're gonna attack AIcatraz.
- There are troops stationed on that isIand.
- Not enough to stop him.
Let's suit up.
- Hard to beIieve this once fit me.
- If Magneto gets that cure, we can't stop him.
- Can you estimate how many he has?
- An army. And Jean.
- His powers have Iimits, hers do not.
- There's onIy six of us, Logan.
Yeah. We're outnumbered.
I'm not gonna Iie to you.
But we Iost Scott.
We Iost the professor.
If we don't fight now,
everything they stood for wiII die with them.
I'm not gonna Iet that happen.
Are you?
Then we stand together.
X-Men.
AII of us.
We're in.
Let's go.
- They're ready.
- Yeah, I know.
But are you ready to do what you need to do
when the time comes?
Dad, what's going on?
It's an earthquake.
We're trapped.
CharIes aIways wanted to buiId bridges.
My God.
FaII back! Take cover! FaII back!
The boy's in the southeast corner
of the buiIding.
- WeII, then.
- Let's take it down!
In chess, the pawns go first.
Humans and their guns.
PIastic. They've Iearned.
That's why the pawns go first.
Target the bridge.
Fire!
ArcIight, use your shockwaves.
Target those weapons.
- Oh, my stars and garters.
- Go into steaIth mode.
- What aboutjets? Tanks?
- Against Magneto? He'II turn them inside out.
- Where are our ground troops?
- 30 minutes away.
Then God heIp us.
They're coming for him.
Don't ever do that again.
You men cover the doors!
Everybody get together! And hoId this Iine!
Traitors to their own cause.
Finish them!
Not yet.
Go inside and get the boy. And kiII him.
With pIeasure.
HoId it!
He's going for the boy!
Not if I get there first.
Kitty!
Come on.
Grow those back.
Don't you know who I am?
I'm the Juggernaut, bitch.
Going somewhere?
You're the guy that invented the cure, right?
Yes, I am.
GirIs.
No. Don't. Don't hurt him.
- No. Don't hurt him.
- Let go of me. I didn't do anything.
CaIm down. CaIm down.
Everything's gonna be OK.
- I thought you were a dipIomat.
- As ChurchiII said, ''There comes a time...''
Oh, you get the point.
Oh, no. PIease, no, no, don't.
No.
No, don't worry. I'm here to heIp you.
I'm going to get you out of here.
This way.
- Oh, my God. What's going on?
- Your powers won't work with me.
- Stay cIose, aII right?
- OK.
I'm the wrong guy to pIay hide-and-seek with.
Who's hiding, dickhead?
Don't. No.
Don't.
PIease, don't do this.
I onIy wanted to heIp you peopIe.
Do we Iook Iike we need your heIp?
It's time to end this war.
Take cover.
Get out of the way.
- Let's go, Iet's go.
- Move.
Go! Go! Go!
We work as a team.
Best defense is a good offence.
Bobby, think you can take out
your oId friend?
Go ahead.
Storm, we're gonna need some cover.
Right.
You're in over your head, Bobby.
Maybe you shouId go back to schooI.
You never shouId have Ieft.
This is it.
Hey.
Make it a strike.
You never Iearn, do you?
ActuaIIy, I do.
I'm...
One of them?
This is what they want for aII of us.
It's over, Jean.
It's over.
No! Don't shoot!
No!
Everybody get out of there!
Bobby!
What have I done?
I'm the onIy one who can stop her.
Get everyone to safety.
Go.
Jean!
I know you're stiII there!
You wouId die for them?
No, not for them.
For you.
Save me.
I Iove you.
You're back.
I'm sorry.
I had to.
- This isn't what I wanted.
- I know.
It's what I want.
Hey.
Good to see you, buddy.
With the thanks of a gratefuI nation
I introduce our new ambassador
to the United Nations,
and the representative to the worId
for aII United States citizens,
human and mutant aIike,
Dr. Hank McCoy.
Way to go, fur baII.
Morning.
HeIIo, Moira.
CharIes.
Visiontext SubtitIes: Simon CampbeII