BOY:
O malefic one,
your humble servants
make you these offerings.
The bones of wolves
ground into powder,
fat from the flesh of geckos
rendered into candles.
The rune that is your name,
unspeakable
by our unworthy tongues.
O malefic one,
we beseech thee,
grant us the power
to destroy our enemies.
BOY 2:
Especially Brad Turner,
who, if I have anything
to say about about it,
has given me
my last swirly.
I'm just saying.
It's humiliating.
We beseech thee,
grant us the power
to destroy our enemies.
We ask this in your name.
[RUMBLING]
[GROWLING]
[WHIMPERING]
Whoa.
That was so cool.
Yeah, but I don't
feel any stronger.
Me either.
What a rip.
Just a lousy light show.
That's what I get,
buying a book of spells
on the Internet.
My head's goin' right back
in the toilet tomorrow.
Don't forget the wedgies.
I don't know
if I can take it anymore.
Me either.
So I stopped
wearing underpants.
BOY 3: All right, Alan, I
guess we'll see you tomorrow.
And don't forget,
these have to be back
at the costume shop by 4,
or we lose our deposit.
[YAWNS]
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Gee, Stew,
did you forget your dice again?
All right, I'm coming.
[SCREAMS]
It's your move, Hawkgirl.
Check in five moves.
We'll see.
Diana told me you used
to regularly beat Batman.
Difficult to believe
from the current pitiful level
of your game.
I should have known better than
to expect a proper challenge
from a woman.
Such scintillating repartee.
I get better conversation
from the android.
You are aware
I'm in the room?
Check.
I win again.
Huzzah.
It's just a game.
[CRASHING,
PIECES SCATTERING]
You disgust me.
Join the club.
I could've told you
that wouldn't work.
She was once one
of the fiercest warriors
I'd ever met.
What's she doing here?
Trying to find her way.
Leaving the Justice League
was difficult for her.
I provided her sanctuary,
a place to meditate
on her life and future.
We must allow her
the time she needs to...
Excuse me.
New game?
[WIND WHISTLING]
John,
this is Dr. Fate.
We may have a problem.
[BEES BUZZING]
[RUMBLING]
I wasn't
expecting you back so soon.
The garden needed work.
Don't go, Inza.
This is your place.
I'm just a visitor here.
My husband
and I have offered you
our hospitality.
We respect your privacy.
Treat this area
as you would your own home.
Aquaman thinks
I've been here too long.
Flowers bloom
when they're ready, Shayera.
Not before.
I'm no flower.
I don't know what I am.
I'm not Lieutenant Shayera Hol
of the Thanagarian empire.
Not anymore.
I've been stripped
of my rank,
exiled from my home world.
I'm not Hawkgirl.
That was always a sham.
Most people on Earth
will never trust me again,
and I can't blame them.
When I do my job,
people get hurt.
People I care about.
And what happens
when you don't do your job?
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING,
APPLAUSE]
[CAMERAS SNAPPING]
[WOMAN SINGING]
[COMMUNICATOR BUZZES]
Green Lantern.
Go ahead.
You're on in five, love.
Wendy, get a move on.
Copy that,
she's on her way.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
You're early.
I'd say
I timed things perfectly.
I meant for our dinner date.
The fashion show's not over
for another half an hour.
It's over for us.
We've got
Justice League business.
I figured.
Aren't you dressed yet?
It doesn't take me
as long as you.
Come on, Vixen.
I'll fill you in on the way.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[GROWLING]
Dr. Fate called it.
Solomon Grundy's back.
The zombie guy?
A heavy hitter.
I read about him
in the files.
Yeah, he's tough.
But we can handle him.
Funny thing is,
he's supposed to be dead.
Aren't all zombies,
by definition, dead?
Uh...
[GROWLING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING]
[GROWLING]
Oh, man, don't do it.
[ELEPHANT TRUMPETING]
[GRUNTING]
[ROARS]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[SIREN WAILING]
John!
[MOANS]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[ROARS]
Come with it, then.
Get the Lantern
somewhere safe.
I could've handled him.
[GRUNDY ROARS]
You may get your chance.
In the meantime, humor me.
Come on, Grundy.
We've been through this before.
You don't
have a chance against me.
Let's talk it over.
Maybe I can help.
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
AMAZO:
Checkmate.
You are improving.
This time it took me 16 moves
to defeat you.
That's nearly double
the number it took last time.
[SCOFFS]
Set up the board.
Solomon Grundy's grave
is empty.
Tell me where to find
those responsible.
Then dig more graves.
We are dealing with something
far more sinister
than mere human avarice.
Grundy's grave
was forced open from the inside.
The site reeks
of chaos magic.
He left
under his own power?
Far more power
than he ever evidenced before.
Behold.
[ROARING]
They need our help.
So does Grundy.
Let's try and get there
before the League kills him.
AMAZO:
That scenario seems...
unlikely.
DR. FATE: In any case, are
you certain you're up to this?
Doesn't matter.
Bad guy or not,
he sacrificed his life
to save ours.
We owe him
the benefit of the doubt.
Very well.
I learned the hard way that
the energy dampening properties
of this device
can disrupt fundamental forces.
So I've kept it hidden
in a pocket dimension,
away from the magic that
must flow freely in my home.
But if you are truly ready
to take up the fight again...
I'm ready.
[GRUNTS]
[RUMBLING,
GLASS SHATTERING]
[SOBBING]
VIXEN:
Hang on.
I'm coming for you.
Come on.
I'll get you down.
[ROARING]
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[SCREAMING]
[SIGHS]
Shayera?
Hate the beard.
[SIGHS]
You okay?
Do I look okay?
Better than Grundy's
about to.
DR. FATE: Perhaps we
can be of assistance.
Okay, let's throw a wave
of our big guns at him.
Me, Fate and the android.
We let him
out of the tower now?
I'm curious to see
how you would dissuade him.
HAWKGIRL:
Hold up.
Before golden boy
teleports him into the sun,
I want to try talking to him.
Shayera, wait.
Grundy!
It's me.
[GROWLING SOFTLY]
Remember?
Bird Nose?
[GROWLS]
[GRUNTS]
[MOANS, GASPS]
Back!
[GRUNTING]
What's happened to him?
I'm sorry.
I sense nothing
of the Grundy we know
within that shell.
He is nothing but rage.
Then it is time
I brought this to an end.
No, don't hurt him.
In my travels through space,
I've attained mastery of forces
all but incomprehensible
to humans.
I...
Wait.
[ROARS]
Something's wrong.
The creature is somehow feeding
on my energies.
He adds my power to his own.
My presence here
puts you all at risk.
I will retreat
several light-years distant
until I can determine how
to counter this effect.
Tell us something, doc.
Grundy was revived
with chaos magic,
accumulative
and with no known outer limit.
My magics are as useless
as Amazo's technology.
Then I say we take him out
the old-fashioned way.
[GRUNTING]
No way it's this easy.
Sure it is.
The android half-fried him
with the cosmic thing.
All we had to do
was seal the... Yahh!
[GROWLING]
Put her down!
[GRUNTING]
[MOANING]
You heard the man.
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
Don't make me do this, Grundy.
[SCREAMING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
I don't see him.
Neither do I.
There must be lead
in those old sewer pipes.
Guy tends to leave a trail.
We'll find him.
And then Pretty Polly
can bash him
with her magic mace.
Why does it hurt him?
DR. FATE:
It's made of nth metal.
Your people's technology
was developed specifically
to repel magical creatures.
It disrupts the magic
that animates him.
The creature knows only rage
and seeks only oblivion.
Your mace may be
the one object on earth
that can grant him peace.
What are you saying?
Your favorite movie's
Old Yeller.
You know exactly
what he's saying.
Is this my destiny?
To be a destroyer?
To betray yet another friend?
It's not that simple.
It never was.
Hey, how 'bout we discuss it
for another couple of hours?
That way,
he's sure to escape.
Only you have the power
to put that creature
out of its misery
and to stop it
before it hurts anyone else.
GREEN LANTERN:
You don't have to, Shayera.
I'll do it for you.
Give me the mace.
Forget it, John.
He was my friend.
It's my responsibility.
I'll do it myself.
[GRUNDY GROWLING SOFTLY]
Shhhh, it's ok.
I know what you want.
What you need.
Close your eyes.
That's long enough.
I'm going in after her.
It's over.
[CAMERAS CLICKING,
REPORTERS SHOUTING]
WOMAN:
Hawkgirl! Hawkgirl, over here.
Hawkgirl,
do you think today's act
can possibly make up
for your complicity
in the Thanagarian invasion
of Earth?
Do you have a comment
on your dismissal
from the Justice League?
Hawkgirl was never dismissed
from the League.
She can come back
whenever she likes.
I recused myself, because...
well... anyway,
Superman broke the tie.
I believe in second chances.
I believe in redemption.
But mostly...
I believe in my friends.
MAN:
Traitor!
WOMAN:
Go back where you came from!
[SHOUTING]
Back off.
She doesn't have
to take that from you people.
HAWKGIRL:
Yes, I do.
But it's okay.
I guess I deserve
some of it.
You saved our lives.
God bless you,
chica halcón.
GREEN LANTERN:
You deserve that too.