I'M WISHING ON A STAR
TO FOLLOW WHERE YOU ARE
I'M WISHING ON A DREAM
TO FOLLOW WHAT IT MEANS
AND I WISH
ON ALL THE RAINBOWS
THAT I'VE SEEN
I WISH ON ALL THE PEOPLE
WHO REALLY DREAM
I'M WISHING ON A STAR
TO FOLLOW WHERE YOU ARE.
Girl:
MY NAME IS VIRGINIA AND I LIVE ON THE EDGE OF THE FOREST.
( chuckling ):
WELL, KIND OF.
MY DAD'S A JANITOR.
THAT'S HOW WE GOT
TO HAVE AN APARTMENT
ON THE EDGE OF CENTRAL PARK.
AND YOU MIGHT THINK
THAT THE FACT
THAT I STILL LIVE WITH MY DAD
IS A BIT SAD AND...
WELL, YOU MIGHT BE RIGHT...
OH!
BUT, I DON'T KNOW,
I'M ALL HE'S GOT, REALLY
AND I'M SORT OF PERMANENTLY
BETWEEN BOYFRIENDS
AT THE MOMENT.
SO, YOU KNOW...
I'M JUST A WAITRESS
AT THE GRILL ON THE PARK
BUT ONE DAY, I'M GOING
TO FIND A PARTNER
AND OPEN A RESTAURANT
OF MY OWN.
ALL I NEED'S A GOOD MAN
WHO'S INTERESTED IN FOOD.
DID YOU SEE THIS?
THIS HAS
BEEN CHEWED.
IT'S NOT MY JOB.
THIS IS AN ELECTRICIAN'S JOB,
BUT WHO GETS TO DO IT?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO WORK, DAD, LIKE
I DO EVERY DAY.
OH. UH, ON THE WAY BACK...
USE THE STAIRS.
JUST IN CASE.
( cawing loudly )
WHO'S THERE?
SO, WHERE EXACTLY ARE WE GOING?
TO BEANTOWN, IN THE SOUTHWEST
CORNER OF YOUR KINGDOM, SIR.
YOU'RE ACCEPTING
THE THRONE THAT
THE CRAFTSMAN THERE
HAVE MADE FOR
YOUR CORONATION.
WELL, IS IT MUCH FURTHER?
CAN'T WE STOP
AND GO HUNTING OR SOMETHING?
VERY SHORTLY,
SIR.
WE MUST MAKE A BRIEF STOP
AT THE SNOW WHITE
MEMORIAL PRISON.
( sighs )
I HATE THESE OUTER PROVINCES.
THE PEOPLE ARE SO COMMON.
YOUR STEPMOTHER
HAS APPLIED FOR PAROLE AGAIN
WHICH WE WILL, OF COURSE,
TURN DOWN.
OH...
IT'S SIMPLY A ROUTINE
COURTESY VISIT.
STOP IT!
YOU'RE PATHETIC.
CALL YOURSELVES TROLLS?
YOU MAKE ME ASHAMED.
SORRY, DAD.
IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
THIS IS THE LAST TIME
I COME AND RESCUE YOU.
DAD, TAKE OFF
THE MAGIC SHOES.
I CAN HANDLE THEM.
( groaning )
Father:
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M STARTING TO THINK?
THAT THE ONLY KIND
OF PEOPLE
THEY WANT
IN THIS COUNTRY
ARE GUYS LIKE ME.
YOU KNOW, GUYS WHO WILL WORK
FOR SCRAPS, DO SIX JOBS...
BASICALLY,
BEND OVER AND TAKE IT.
WANT TO KNOW
SOMETHING, DARLING?
TEN, 15 YEARS TOPS
THIS COUNTRY IS FINISHED
AS A DEMOCRACY.
AS A CARING SOCIETY, WHERE
PEOPLE DO THINGS FOR EACH OTHER
WE'RE DONE, WE'RE FINISHED
WE ARE OUT
OF HERE.
YOUR BARBECUE RIBS
ARE ON TOP OF THE MICROWAVE.
( bell dings )
TONY
I HAVE BEEN CALLING
THIS ELEVATOR FOR THE LAST HALF HOUR.
I THOUGHT YOU
FIXED IT.
I DID, SIR,
BUT IT'S BROKEN AGAIN.
DON'T TAKE
ALL NIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT TO LOOK
AT THAT BOILER.
IT'S DRIVING
EVERYBODY CRAZY.
THERE'S AIR
IN THE PIPES.
THE WHOLE SYSTEM'S GOT
TO BE DRAINED AND BLED.
Tony:
YES, SIR.
I JUST HAVE TO FIX
THE LEAK IN NUMBER NINE
AND THEN I'M ON IT.
TONY, I AM ONLY GOING
TO TELL YOU THIS ONCE.
THERE ARE AN AWFUL LOT
OF PEOPLE OUT THERE
WHO WOULD
LOVE YOUR JOB--
AN AWFUL LOT
OF PEOPLE.
YES, SIR.
DRAIN THE SYSTEM...
I'D LIKE TO DRAIN HIS SYSTEM.
BYE, DADDY.
Tony:
OH, OH, OH, LISTEN.
DON'T GO THROUGH
THE PARK. PROMISE?
YUP.
YOU GOT A COAT?
YOU'RE GOING TO GET COLD.
OH, WHAT DID YOU
FIX ME FOR DINNER?!
Woman:
WAIT!
COME TO ME.
( snorting )
WELL, THIS IS MARVELOUS,
ISN'T IT?
NOT EXACTLY THE RED
CARPET TREATMENT.
I'M SURE THEY WON'T
HAVE FORGOTTEN
ABOUT OUR VISIT,
YOUR MAJESTY.
CHECK IT OUT!
OH, YOU WERE RIGHT.
"MAXIMUM SECURITY."
WE'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE IN HERE!
DAD, NO ONE'S
EVER ALLOWED IN THERE.
THIS IS WHERE
THEY KEEP THE QUEEN.
THIS IS REALLY BAD.
NO, DAD, DAD, PLEASE.
THIS COULD BE A TRAP.
DAD, DON'T.
NO, DAD!
Woman:
OPEN THE DOOR.
OPEN THE DOOR
TO EVERYTHING YOU DESIRE.
GILES?
HELLO?
GILES!
HELLO, PRINCEY!
( laughing )
DID THAT HURT?
I'D LIKE
YOU TO MEET
MY SISTER.
NOW, HE'S MINE.
I GET THE FIRST SHOT.
YOU WERE FIRST
LAST TIME.
I ALWAYS GET THE FIRST...
Woman:
ENOUGH!
YOU'RE A LONG WAY
FROM YOUR CASTLE, WENDELL.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
HAVE STAYED THERE.
MY SILLY
LITTLE STEPSON.
YOU... YOU...
YOU WILL PAY FOR THIS.
ON THE CONTRARY.
I THINK THAT YOU WILL
BEG AT MY FEET FOR FOOD.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THIS IS?
THIS IS A VERY
SPECIAL KIND OF DOG.
THIS IS A MAGICAL DOG.
I HOPE YOU LIKE
DOGS, WENDELL.
YOU'RE GOING TO SPEND
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE AS ONE.
( laughing )
( barking )
COME, COME, PRINCE WENDELL
YOU DON'T GREET PEOPLE
ON ALL FOURS
DO YOU?
( troll laughing )
Troll:
GET HIM!
BRING HIM BACK TO ME
ALIVE!
WE'LL GET HIM.
HE'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
HE CAN'T ESCAPE.
WE'RE IN A PRISON.
Queen:
WELL, YOUR HIGHNESS...
JUST WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO SAY FOR YOURSELF?
WH-WH-WH-WH...
WHERE'S MY TAIL GONE?
Virginia:
I GUESS YOU GET TO A CERTAIN AGE
AND YOU REALIZE
THAT NOTHING EXCITING
IS EVER GOING TO HAPPEN TO YOU.
MAYBE THAT'S
JUST THE WAY IT IS.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE SOME PEOPLE
JUST HAVE QUIET LIVES.
( prisoners shouting )
Man:
GIVE US SOME FOOD, SAY.
I HAVEN'T HAD ANY FOOD
SINCE YESTERDAY.
LET US OUT.
COME ON--
JUST GIVE US THE KEY.
LET US OUT.
YOU.
HELLO.
WHAT ARE YOU?
ME?
A VERY, VERY FINE CHAP...
DO NOT MAKE ME ASK AGAIN.
I'M A...
SHH...
HALF-WOLF.
IF I GIVE YOU YOUR FREEDOM
YOU MUST AGREE TO SERVE ME
WITHOUT QUESTION.
OH, BREAKFAST, LUNCH, DINNER.
I AM YOUR WOLF.
"LOYALTY" IS MY MIDDLE NAME.
I'VE TURNED PRINCE WENDELL
INTO A DOG.
GOOD IDEA.
FIND HIM BEFORE THE TROLLS.
OH... TROLLS!
WAIT!
GIVE YOUR WILL TO ME.
BE MINE
TO SUMMON
AND CONTROL.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH.
( grunting )
( barks )
Wolf:
HUFF... PUFF.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
OH...! OH!
WOW!
Troll 1:
SUCK AN ELF!
WHERE ARE WE?
WOW.
WOW, GET A LOOK
AT THAT.
THIS ISN'T PART
OF THE NINE KINGDOMS.
THIS IS A MAGICAL PLACE.
LOOK AT ALL THOSE LIGHTS!
Troll 2:
THEY MUST GO THROUGH A TON OF CANDLES!
Troll 3:
MAYBE WE SHOULD CLAIM THIS KINGDOM!
THAT'S A SENSATIONAL IDEA.
LET'S GRAB IT
BEFORE SOMEONE ELSE DOES.
I HEREBY
CLAIM THIS LAND
AND ALL ITS
INHABITANTS
IN THE NAME
OF THE TROLL NATION.
HENCEFORTH,
IT SHALL BE KNOWN AS...
WHAT SHALL WE CALL IT?
( gasping )
THE TENTH KINGDOM!
AH.
All:
THE TENTH KINGDOM!
IN A MONTH, I WILL
HAVE CRUSHED THE HOUSE OF WHITE.
I WILL HAVE WENDELL'S CASTLE
AND HIS KINGDOM
AND FOR HELPING ME TO ESCAPE
YOU MAY HAVE HALF HIS KINGDOM
TO RULE.
HALF THE FOURTH KINGDOM--
BUT IT'S HUGE.
WHAT'S YOUR PLAN?
WHAT DO I HAVE TO DO?
SIMPLY ALLOW ME THE USE
OF YOUR CHILDREN
UNTIL THEY'VE CAPTURED
THE PRINCE FOR ME.
THAT'S ALL?
TELL NO ONE WHAT
YOU'VE SEEN, OF COURSE.
DO I GET TO CHOOSE...
WHICH HALF OF THE KINGDOM
I WANT?
( moaning softly )
( moaning )
OH, MY GOD,
I'VE KILLED IT.
ARE YOU OKAY?
OH, I'M SORRY.
( whimpers )
WHERE'S YOUR MASTER?
HOW COME YOU
DON'T HAVE A COLLAR?
( trolls grumbling in distance )
COME ON, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
( grunts )
Troll 2:
AH...
( gasping )
HELLO.
( grunting )
( laughing )
( footsteps approaching )
OH, MY WALLET.
( sighs )
Troll 2:
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S NOT EVEN LEATHER.
ARE THERE ANY OTHER
SHOES IN HERE?
WHAT'S THIS?
( groaning )
( grunts )
...Night fever, night fever
We know how to do it...
MORE MAGIC.
( faintly ):
Night fever, night fever...
( distant howling )
( distant siren wailing )
( howling continuing )
NO.
VIRGINIA, JUST LEAVE.
GO.
( barks )
( grunting )
THERE.
THERE'S BEEN AN INCIDENT.
AHA!
LOOKEE LOOK.
DOG HAIRS.
AH, CALFSKIN--
NICEY NICE...
SQUEAKY CLEAN.
( growling savagely )
"IF FOUND, PLEASE RETURN
TO VIRGINIA LEWIS
APARTMENT 2006, NUMBER TWO
EAST EIGHTY-ONEST STREET."
"EIGHTY-ONEST
STREET"? "EIGHTY-ONEST STREET"?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT IT SAYS,
"EIGHTY-ONEST."
HOW ABOUT THIS WAY?
COME ON,
LET'S GO!
LET'S GO.
( panting )
( sniffing deeply )
( exhales ecstatically )
( gasps )
MEAT!
( growling softly )
( music playing softly )
( people chatting )
HI.
Woman:
OH, AND WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN, HUH?
I'VE BEEN
COVERING FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
YOUR HEAD...
YOU'RE BLEEDING.
I SMASHED MY BIKE
AND I LOST MY WALLET
AND I'VE PICKED UP
A NEW BOYFRIEND.
OH...
( laughing )
WELL, HELLO.
I HIT HIM WITH MY BIKE
BUT I DON'T THINK HE'S HURT.
HE'S NOT BLEEDING
OR ANYTHING.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
I DON'T KNOW. HE
DOESN'T HAVE A COLLAR.
UH-HUH...
COME ON, LET'S SEE, HUH?
YOU LOOK LIKE A PRINCE
TO ME, HUH? YES.
HELLO, PRINCE.
HELLO.
( music playing softly )
( footsteps approaching )
OH...
( snarling )
( growling softly )
TASTY.
REMEMBER WHAT YOU CAME HERE FOR.
FIND THE PRINCE.
BUT HUFF PUFF...
A WOLF'S GOT TO EAT,
HASN'T HE?
CAN'T WORK ON
AN EMPTY STOMACH.
HELLO.
( sniffing )
( gasping ):
I SMELL DOG!
WOULD YOU
BELIEVE IT?
WORK AND PLEASURE COMBINED.
ALL RIGHT, YOU CAN STAY IN HERE
AND I'LL CHECK
ON YOU WHEN I CAN.
DON'T MAKE A NOISE
OR YOU'LL GET ME THE SACK.
( barks )
SHH!
( whispering ):
QUIET OR I'LL PUT YOU OUTSIDE.
Woman:
SO, THE SPECIALS ARE
Wolf:
LAMB?! LAMB...
NEW SEASON'S LAMB, I
HOPE-- YOUNG AND JUICY
AND FROLICKING
PROVOCATIVELY
IN THE FIELDS,
BOUNCING UP AND DOWN
WITH SOFT, FLUFFY WOOL.
( gasps )
STOP IT.
PULL YOURSELF
TOGETHER.
SOME SHEPHERDESS
NOT REALLY PAYING ATTENTION
TO THE FLOCK
PROBABLY ASLEEP,
IF I KNOW LITTLE GIRLS...
WELL, I'M NOT GOING TO EAT HER.
( chuckles )
NOT IF THERE'S
A LAMB FILET
OR A NICE FAT
RACK OF CHOPS!
I'M NOT GREEDY!
WELL, I AM GREEDY.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I JUST SAID THAT.
I HAVE A SUBSTANTIAL APPETITE.
BORN TO GORGE...
THAT'S ME.
( horn honking )
( yells )
SUCK AN ELF!
( horns honking )
( grunting )
Troll 1:
ALL RIGHT.
( brakes squealing )
( glass breaking )
( radiator hissing )
( yelling )
( hissing louder )
OUR CARRIAGE
IS HERE.
( laughing )
( music playing softly )
OKAY.
Wolf:
NO, NO!
SORRY, WHAT
CAN I GET YOU?
RARE IMPLIES
DANGEROUSLY COOKED!
WHEN I SAY, "RARE"
I MEAN, JUST
LET IT LOOK AT THE OVEN
IN TERROR
THEN, BRING IT OUT TO ME!
NO FRIES, NO
VEGETABLES--
JUST MEAT!
RED...
AS A YOUNG GIRL'S FIRST BLUSH.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I MISSED THAT.
I'LL HAVE A JUG OF MARGARITA, A DIET COLA AND TWO BEERS, OKAY?
( Prince Wendell barking )
AND MY WIFE WILL HAVE...
I'M SORRY,
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
SHE'LL HAVE
A DOUBLE, BIG...
( dishes clattering )
Man:
...COLD PLATES!
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT
I'M TAKING YOU OUTSIDE.
( sighs )
( chuckles )
OKAY, CANDY, VERY FUNNY.
YOU CAN COME OUT.
I SUPPOSE
YOU WROTE THAT, EH?
( barks )
BARK ONCE.
( chuckling ):
OKAY...
BARK TWICE.
( barks twice )
( shrieks )
OKAY, SO,
YOU GOT THE LAMB SPECIAL
AND SIX GLASSES OF WARM MILK?
YEAH.
OKAY.
OH, OH, OH, OH!
UH-HUH?
I ALMOST FORGOT.
UH... I'M LOOKING
FOR THIS LOVELY LADY
WHO, UH, FOUND MY DOGGIE.
OH, SO, IT'S YOURS.
OH...
I'LL TELL VIRGINIA.
SHE'S OUT BACK.
CAN YOU...
UNDERSTAND
EVERYTHING I'M SAYING?
( barks )
S-STOP IT!
WELL, WHO'S IN DANGER?
BOTH OF US?
( barks )
WHOA.
JUST WAIT A MINUTE.
OH, YOU CAN'T
COME IN HERE.
UH...
UM...
SHE MUST'VE GONE HOME,
YOU KNOW?
MAYBE SHE HURT HERSELF
WHEN SHE FELL.
OH... POOR LITTLE SAUSAGE.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
WHERE SHE LIVES?
THAT WAY,
I CAN THANK HER.
UH... WELL, I...
I CAN'T TELL YOU
WHERE SHE LIVES.
YOU KNOW, UM, I DON'T
KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
OH...
YOU CAN TELL ME.
( snarls )
( distant siren wailing )
THIS IS MY STOP.
YOU GOT TO GO NOW.
( sighs )
OKAY, YOU CAN
JUST STAY ONE NIGHT
AND, THEN,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
( barks )
I'VE GONE CRAZY.
HOW CAN I BE TALKING
TO A DOG?
( barking )
YES, I HAVE.
DON'T TRY AND REASSURE ME.
( snoring softly )
THAT'S MRS. GRAVES
FROM NEXT DOOR...
AND HER HUSBAND...
AND THEIR SON ERIC.
( barking )
( sighing incredulously )
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO THEM?
( elevator bell dings )
( elevator doors creaking )
WAIT HERE.
( barks )
SHH!
WAIT.
I'M GOING TO GO SEE
IF DAD'S ALL RIGHT.
( elevator bell dings )
( door creaking continuing )
( whispering ):
DAD.
WAKE UP.
( door closes )
Troll 1:
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOOK.
HERE THEY ARE.
( sighing admiringly )
SOFT COW.
NICEY NICE.
( troll growling )
Troll 2:
WALK THE CAT WALK.
( chuckling )
HELLO THERE,
GIRLIE.
THESE SHOES...
THEY'VE BEEN
VERY BADLY CARED FOR.
THEY'RE-THEY'RE SCUFFED,
AN-AND CRACKED
AND NEGLECTED.
( crashing )
YOU HAVE NICE SHOES
AND SO TINY.
WE HAVE HUNDREDS
OF PAIRS
AT HOME.
SO, WE KNOW
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Virginia:
WHO ARE YOU AND WHAT HAVE DONE
TO MY DAD?
AW, HE'S JUST SLEEPING.
HIT HIM WITH A BIT OF
TROLL DUST, THAT'S ALL.
"TROLL DUST"?
I AM BURLY THE TROLL
FEARED THROUGHOUT
THE NINE KINGDOMS.
Troll 3:
I AM
BLABBERWORT THE TROLL,
DREADED THROUGHOUT
THE NINE KINGDOMS.
Troll 2:
AND I AM
BLUEBELL THE TROLL
TERRIFIED
THROUGHOUT THE NINE KINGDOMS.
( yelling )
( gasps )
( crackling )
Burly:
SO...
WHERE IS HE?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Blabberwort:
PRINCE WENDELL.
WHO?
THE DOG.
( yelling and gasping )
WE ARE GOING
TO COUNT TO THREE
AND, THEN,
WE ARE GOING TO MAKE YOU
INTO A PAIR OF SHOES.
ONE...
I'LL CUT THE SHOES.
TWO...
I WILL SHAPE THE SHOES.
THREE...
I WILL STICK...
ALL RIGHT!
I'LL TELL YOU
WHERE HE IS.
HE'S...
HERE.
HE-HE'S JUST,
UH... OUTSIDE.
Burly:
SHOW US!
TAKE US TO HIM.
( groaning )
GO THROUGH THE DOOR!
BE CAREFUL!
SHUT UP, BLUEBELL!
( elevator bell dings )
WHERE IS HE?
( bell dinging continuing )
HE'S HIDING...
UH... BEHIND THOSE DOORS.
( grunting )
( yelling )
( gasping )
Burly:
THAT ROOM WAS NOT THERE
A MOMENT AGO.
YOU ARE CRAFTY.
THERE'S NO ONE
IN HERE!
OH, YES, HE'S HERE.
I'M... I-I'M JUST GOING
TO OPERATE THE SECRET DOOR
AND SHOW YOU
WHERE HE'S HIDING.
NO!
( yelling )
IT'S A TRICK!
( screaming )
SUCK AN ELF!
( yelling )
OPEN UP!
ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
DAD'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I THINK IT'S YOU THEY'RE AFTER.
( knocking )
( snoring )
( knocking continues )
OH, WHATEVER IT IS, GO AWAY.
GOOD EVENING!
TROLLS HAVE BEEN
TO VISIT YOU FIRST,
I SEE.
NO MATTER!
TONIGHT AND TONIGHT ONLY
I AM AUTHORIZED TO MAKE YOU
A UNIQUE OFFER.
NAMELY, THE END
TO ALL YOUR PERSONAL
AND FINANCIAL PROBLEMS.
HEY, HOLD IT A SECOND.
TAKE ANOTHER STEP,
I'M CALLING THE COPS.
IT'S PRIVATE PROPERTY.
UNDER THE TERMS OF THIS POLICY
I AM, IN EXCHANGE
FOR INFORMATION
AS TO THE WHEREABOUTS
OF YOUR DAUGHTER
ABLE TO OFFER YOU
THIS MAGIC BEAN
WHICH, ONCE EATEN,
WILL GIVE YOU SIX
GLORIOUS WISHES.
( whooshing )
IS THIS HER?
THIS CAN'T BE HER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
OH, SHE'S SUCCULENT!
WHAT A DREAMY, CREAMY GIRL!
( whimpering )
( howling )
( fiercely ):
TASTY, OR WHAT?
( all grunting rhythmically )
( all yelling )
( fierce yelling )
( exhausted sigh )
I'VE BEEN THINKING
BACK OVER THE YEARS
AND I FEEL THIS IS QUITE
THE WORST SPELL WE HAVE EVER BEEN PUT UNDER!
WE'VE HAD SOME STINKERS
BUT NOTHING LIKE THIS.
SHE'S A POWERFUL LITTLE WITCH,
THAT ONE.
I THINK...
WE MIGHT BE IN HER POCKET.
HMM?
WHAT?
I THINK
SHE MIGHT HAVE SHRUNK US
AND PUT US IN A MATCHBOX
IN HER POCKET.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
YOU'RE FALLING
TO PIECES.
GET A GRIP ON YOURSELF.
HOW CAN WE BE IN A MATCHBOX,
YOU IDIOT?
WHERE ARE ALL THE MATCHES?
( soft boinging )
WHAT THE HELL'S IT DOING?
SIX... BIG WISHES.
IMAGINE HAVING ANYTHING
YOU DESIRE.
AND FROM THE LOOK OF
YOUR MODEST SURROUNDINGS
I'M SURE THERE
ARE MANY THINGS THAT YOU'D LOVE TO CHANGE.
I... OH...
WELL, YOU KNOW, I WOULD...
UH... JUST GET THE HELL
OUT OF MY APARTMENT
ALL RIGHT?
( growls )
WELL...
THIS IS A JOKE, RIGHT?
NO! NO...
IT'S A STANDARD
MULTIPLE-WISHES DEAL--
SIX WISHES; NO GOING BACK
ON WISHES ONCE MADE;
NO MAKING FIVE WISHES AND
WISHING FOR ANOTHER THOUSAND.
NOW, COME ON,
IS THAT A FAIR DEAL
OR WHAT?
NOW...
WHERE... IS YOUR...
LOVELY DAUGHTER?
WHAT DO YOU WANT HER FOR?
SIMPLY TO RECLAIM
MY LITTLE DOGGY
WHICH SHE FOUND EARLIER.
DOG?
THERE'S EVEN A REWARD INVOLVED
WHICH I INTEND
TO GIVE HER PERSONALLY.
( sighs )
IF SHE'S NOT AT WORK
SHE'LL BE
AT MY MOTHER-IN-LAW'S. OOH.
SHE'S ALWAYS TRYING
TO TURN VIRGINIA AGAINST ME.
DOES THIS MOTHER-IN-LAW
LIKE, UH, FLOWERS?
SHE LIKES MONEY.
THAT'S THE ONLY THING
THAT IMPRESSES HER.
ADDRESS, PLEASE.
IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE.
WAIT. HOLD
ON A SECOND.
HOW LONG DOES THIS
TAKE TO WORK?
OH, DON'T WORRY--
THE FIRST THREE HOURS...
ARE THE WORST.
( sighs )
ANYTHING I WANT, HUH?
( snorts )
OOH...
'KAY.
ALL RIGHT...
FOR MY FIRST WISH...
( stomach grumbling deeply )
FOR MY F...
( grumbling continues )
( groaning in pain )
Virginia:
HELLO?
Grandma:
WHO IS IT?
IT'S ONLY ME, GRANDMA.
HI.
( laughing ):
FOR A MOMENT THERE
I THOUGHT IT WAS YOUR MOTHER.
( laughs )
WELL, I'M SORRY
TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
WOULD YOU MIND
IF I STAYED THE NIGHT TONIGHT?
YOU KNOW,
SHE'LL COME BACK ONE DAY.
SHE'LL JUST...
SWAN IN WITHOUT A WORD.
YOU DON'T THINK
SHE COULD BE IN ASPEN, DO YOU?
SHE ALWAYS
LOVED THE SNOW.
( laughing ):
WELL...
I THINK SHE WOULD HAVE
COME BACK BY NOW.
I DON'T KNOW, 14 YEARS
IS A LONG TIME FOR APRES-SKI.
DON'T BE CHEAP, DEAR.
( Prince barking )
( little dog barking )
GOD... WHAT'S THAT?
THIS IS A STRAY
I PICKED UP TODAY.
WELL, JUST KEEP HIM
AWAY FROM ROLAND.
HE'S PROBABLY GOT FLEAS.
AW, YOU DON'T
HAVE FLEAS.
DO YOU HAVE
FLEAS? NO. SHH.
SHH.
( Roland barking )
THANKS.
YOU KNOW
YOU COULD STILL BE SOMETHING
IN SOCIETY, VIRGINIA.
I HAVE CONNECTIONS, YOU KNOW.
YOUR MOTHER'S DEBUT
AT THE RITZ CARLTON
WAS... AH...
A CORONATION.
AT NINETEEN
SHE COULD HAVE HAD ANY BACHELOR
IN THE WHOLE OF NEW YORK...
AND WHAT DOES SHE END UP WITH?
DAD.
DON'T THROW AWAY YOUR LIFE
THE WAY SHE DID, VIRGINIA.
I CAN SEE THE WHOLE THING
HAPPENING ALL OVER AGAIN.
YOU'RE A WAITRESS,
FOR GOD'S SAKES.
WHO ARE YOU GOING
TO MEET?
SOME... ELIGIBLE
SHORT-ORDER COOK?
( Virginia laughing )
NO.
( knocking on door )
( knocking louder )
UH... SO, OF COURSE
YOU NEVER FIXED THE PIPES
LIKE YOU PROMISED--
THAT I'VE COME TO EXPECT--
BUT THIS!
I CAN, UM... THIS...
I CAN EXPLAIN ALL OF THIS,
AND I'M GOING TO...
I'LL GET ON IT RIGHT AWAY,
MR. MURRAY. NO.
"I'M GOING TO GET ON IT"
IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
I WANT YOU AND YOUR DAUGHTER
OUT OF THIS APARTMENT TODAY!
YOU'RE FIRED!
FIRE... FIRED?
NO, PLEASE, MR. MURRAY...
WHAT, YOU BIG JERK?
I WISH
YOU AND YOUR ENTIRE FAMILY
WOULD KISS MY ASS
AND BE MY SLAVES
FOREVER.
WHAT DID YOU JUST SAY?
OH, MASTER.
( short laugh )
Burly:
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK THIS SPELL WILL LAST?
IT CAN'T LAST LONG.
100 YEARS?
AT MOST.
MAYBE ONLY 50.
WELL, WE'LL JUST
HAVE TO MAKE
THE MOST OF OUR IMPRISONMENT.
AND AGREE NOT TO EAT
EACH OTHER.
ABSOLUTELY.
WE'LL DO
THE HUNDRED YEARS
AND MAYBE IF WE'RE LUCKY
WE'LL ONLY HAVE TO DO
TWO-THIRDS OF THE SPELL
AND GET OUT EARLY.
( doorbell rings )
( gasps )
OH.
I... THERE MUST BE
SOME MISTAKE.
I DO APOLOGIZE.
I WAS LOOKING FOR
VIRGINIA'S GRANDMOTHER.
I AM SHE.
THAT CANNOT BE.
HER YOUNG SISTER, PERHAPS.
HER MOTHER
PERHAPS.
BUT HER GRANDMOTHER?
PAH!
YOU ARE A...
DAZZLING BEAUTY.
OH.
WELL, I, I DON'T
HAVE MY MAKEUP ON
OR ANYTHING YET.
MAY I COME IN?
I HAVE FLOWERS.
YEAH, BUT WHO ARE YOU?
I AM VIRGINIA'S SUITOR.
HER BETROTHED.
BETROTHED?
SHE DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT A FIANCE.
HOW LIKE HER.
HOW MODEST.
MOST GIRLS WOULD
BRAG AND BOAST
ABOUT DATING THE HEIR
TO AN ENORMOUS FORTUNE
BUT NOT VIRGINIA.
OH, WELL, DO COME IN.
I'LL, I'LL JUST GO
AND GET DRESSED.
OF COURSE.
GET DRESSED.
( humming )
OKAY, WISH MASTER, GIVE ME
A NEVER-ENDING SUPPLY OF BEER.
TWO?
YOU CALL THAT A WILD NIGHT
WHERE YOU COME FROM?
OH!
HEY, OH, MURRAY! MURRAY!
MURRAY! YOU GOT
TO SEE THIS.
THE REFRIGERATOR,
IT JUST KEEPS GO...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M WORRIED THAT THEY'RE
NOT CLEAN ENOUGH, MASTER.
SHALL I LICK YOUR SHOES AGAIN?
LET ME SEE YOUR TONGUE.
ALL RIGHT,
FIVE MORE MINUTES.
HOW IS YOUR MOTHER COMING
WITH THAT DOOR?
OH, UH... AL-ALMOST
DONE NOW, MASTER.
JUST HURRY...
STOP. NO, NO.
ONCE WAS ENOUGH.
HERE. OPEN THIS.
WHAT SHALL I WISH FOR
NEXT?
I WISH...
I WISH I HAD SOMETHING
THAT WOULD CLEAN THIS APARTMENT
ALL BY ITSELF, AND I WOULD NEVER
HAVE TO LIFT A FINGER.
( whirring )
OH, HERE WE GO.
( gasping )
( laughing )
HERE WE GO.
CLEAN, CLEAN
CLEAN, CLEAN,
CLEAN, CLEAN.
CLEAN.
AW, I GOT TO GET THIS CLEAN.
OH, OH, LOOK HERE.
OH, THERE'S DUST
ALL OVER THE FLOOR.
PICK IT UP.
PICK IT UP. PICK IT UP.
OH, HERE'S SOME OVER HERE.
HERE'S SOME MORE. OH...!
( muffled shrieking )
I AM SO BAD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M DOING THIS.
OH, STILL...
I SUPPOSE YOU
WOULD LOOK BETTER
SURROUNDED BY POTATOES.
WHERE'S THE GARLIC?
THE ROSEMARY?
OH! WHAT DO I HAVE
TO WORK WITH HERE?!
THREE-YEAR-OLD DRIED HERBS?
( groaning )
AH! YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO FIT IN THE
OVEN, ARE YOU?
NOT IN ONE PIECE, ANYWAY.
SHEPHERDESS
MAKES GREATNESS
THE LITTLE LAMBS ARE LONELY
SHEPHERDESS...
( gasping )
OH, WHAT AM I DOING?
I SHOULD UNTIE YOU.
HMM.
OH, A POOR OLD LADY
FRIGHTENED OUT
OF HER WITS.
I SHOULD UNTIE YOU...
BUT FIRST I'LL PUT
A DOLLOP OF FAT
IN THE OVEN TRAY.
Virginia:
GRANDMOTHER?
OH! OH... GUESTS ARE UP.
BREAKFAST ISN'T READY.
GRANDMOTHER?
Falsetto voice:
IN HERE, DARLING.
( knocking )
GRANDMOTHER?
Falsetto voice:
IN HERE, DARLING.
GOOD MORNING.
DO YOU WANT SOME
COFFEE OR TOAST
OR SOMETHING?
HMM?
( whimpering )
WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU GOT A COLD?
( whimpering )
GRANDMA?
SURPRISE!
OH, BOY!
YOU'RE FANTASTIC.
YOUR PICTURE DOESN'T
DO YOU JUSTICE.
WOW!
OH, NO.
HOW DID THIS GET HERE?
NO. NO...
OH, NO.
BY THE WAY,
WHERE IS THE DOG?
SLEEPING IN
IF I KNOW ROYALTY.
OH, YOU SMELL GREAT.
I'VE HAD LITTLE TEASERS
OF YOUR SCENT BEFORE, VIRGINIA
BUT IN THE FLESH.... AH!
PERFUMES ARE NOT FOR ME, NO.
I RESPOND FAVORABLY
TO THE AUDACITY
OF A WOMAN
WHO FLAUNTS HER OWN AROMA,
AND YOU, VIRGINIA--
YOU SMELL LIKE SUNDAY LUNCH.
YOU KEEP AWAY FROM ME.
OH, BEAUTIFUL EYES,
BEAUTIFUL TEETH.
ALL THE RIGHT STUFF
IN ALL THE RIGHT PLACES.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT,
I AM IN LOVE.
MMM...
LET ME PUT YOUR
MIND AT REST.
NOW THAT I'VE SEEN YOU
EATING YOU
IS OUT OF THE QUESTION.
NOT EVEN ON THE MENU.
OH, NOW, I KNOW THIS
IS GOING TO COME OUT OF THE BLUE
BUT HOW ABOUT A DATE?
WE'VE STARTED BADLY
BUT I TAKE
ALL THE BLAME FOR THAT.
COME ON,
GIVE US A CHANCE. PLEASE.
OOH!
OH, YOU ARE ONE DYNAMIC LADY.
THERE'S NO QUESTION THAT...
( howling )
( sighing )
( faint shrieking )
( shrieking )
OH, MY GOD.
GRANDMOTHER!
OUT OF MY WAY.
WORK, WORK, WORK.
Tony:
NO, NO, NO, NO.
OKAY, OKAY, FINE.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S ENOUGH. GO.
GO DO SOMETHING ELSE.
MM-MM-MM-MM...
NO. HEY, GET UP.
GET UP. GET UP.
LISTEN, YOU'VE ALREADY
KISSED ME THREE TIMES TODAY.
LET ME KISS YOU
AGAIN, MASTER.
NO! GO CLEAN SOMETHING.
YOU'RE RIDICULOUS.
MASTER, OH,
WONDERFUL MASTER
MY WIFE HAS
A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
OH, REALLY?
WELL, I'LL
TAKE CARE OF HER.
YOU GO GET ME A BEER.
YES, MASTER.
IT'S MY HUSBAND'S
ROLEX OYSTER.
SOLID GOLD.
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S NOT ONE
OF THOSE CHEAP IMITATIONS?
OH, NO, MASTER.
WHOA! OH!
( gasping )
I BOUGHT IT FOR MY
HUSBAND'S 40th BIRTHDAY
BUT YOU MUST HAVE IT.
ALL OUR POSSESSIONS
ARE YOURS NOW.
MURRAY, I'M GOING
TO TAKE YOUR WIFE OUT
AND BUY HER SOME UNDERWEAR.
OF COURSE, MASTER!
HELP YOURSELF!
Woman:
MASTER?
I, UM, I THINK THERE MIGHT BE
SOMEONE TRAPPED IN THE ELEVATOR.
I CAN HEAR VOICES
AND BANGING.
YES, WELL, I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU'VE NOTICED
BUT I'M NO LONGER
MR. FIX-IT
SO WHY DON'T YOU GET
YOUR RICH BEHIND OUT THERE
AND FIX IT YOURSELF?
AT ONCE, MASTER!
I THINK WE NEED
SOME SPENDING MONEY.
UM, WISH MASTER,
HOW ABOUT A MILLION DOLLARS?
( doorbell rings )
( gasping excitedly )
( chuckles )
( laughing )
OH, YES, I'M RICH!
I'M RICH! I'M RICH!
SAY HELLO TO BENNY!
CAN I HELP YOU?
OH, I HOPE SO.
I'M VERY CONFUSED.
YOU MUST BE
PAUL'S REFERRAL.
HE SAID YOU'D DROP BY
TO MAKE AN APPOINTMENT.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT I'M DOING HERE?
LET'S GET TO KNOW
EACH OTHER A BIT
BEFORE WE TACKLE
THE BIG QUESTIONS, OKAY?
YEAH. BIG QUESTIONS.
NOW I'M GOING
TO GIVE YOU A WORD
AND I WANT YOU
TO SAY THE FIRST WORD
THAT COMES
INTO YOUR MIND, OKAY?
GAME, YEAH.
HERE WE GO. "HOME."
COOKING.
"COWARD."
CHICKEN!
"WEDDING."
CAKE.
"DEAD."
MEAT!
"SEXUAL."
APPETITE.
"LOVE."
( gasps )
TO EAT ANYTHING FLUFFY!
( grunts )
SORRY. SORRY.
MORE THAN ONE WORD.
START AGAIN.
Tony:
YOU KNOW, MURRAY, THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
LISTEN, I WANT EVERYBODY
OUT OF HERE
EXCEPT YOUR WIFE.
I HAD NO IDEA YOU HAD
SO MANY RELATIVES.
OF COURSE, MASTER.
( vacuum cleaner munching )
YOU CAN GO.
BE WITH YOU IN
A MOMENT, MURRAY.
JUST GOT TO PUCK UP
TO THE MASTER.
UH, UH, DON'T PUCKER.
HEY, HEY, CUT THAT OUT.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
STOP!
CLEAN IT UP. CLEAN IT UP.
CLEAN IT UP.
CLEAN IT UP! CLEAN IT UP!
CLEAN IT UP!
OH, JEEZ!
I SAID...
STOP!
STOP! STOP!
( sirens wailing )
( officers yelling )
Officer:
UPSTAIRS! MOVE IT! MOVE IT!
I CAN'T STOP IT, MASTER!
THANK YOU!
THANK YOU, MASTER!
I'M TRYING!
IT'S NOT GOING TO STOP, MASTER!
MASTER, WAIT!
COME ON!
PLEASE, LET'S GO!
( all yelling )
WHOA! WHOA!
MOVE! MOVE!
WAIT A MINUTE! WHOA!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?!
SPREAD 'EM!
ALL RIGHT!
WHAT HAVE I DONE?!
BINGO. LOOKIT HERE.
THE MONEY FROM THE ROBBERY.
NO! HOLD ON
A SECOND. NO, NO.
THAT JUST APPEARED
IN FRONT OF MY DOOR.
I'VE BEEN IN MY APARTMENT
ALL DAY.
ALL THESE PEOPLE
CAN VOUCH FOR ME, RIGHT?
All:
YES, O MASTER.
I'VE BEEN HERE
ALL DAY JUST
HAVING A BEER WITH FRIENDS.
YOU KNOW, I THINK
YOU'RE STILL HOLDING BACK.
WHAT IS
REALLY TROUBLING YOU?
OKAY, ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
DOC, I MET THIS
TERRIFIC GIRL
AND I REALLY, REALLY,
REALLY LIKE HER
BUT THE THING IS THAT...
GO ON, SAY IT.
SAY IT!
I'M NOT SURE WHETHER
I-I WANT TO LOVE HER
OR EAT HER.
( growls )
OH, OH.
OF COURSE,
I BLAME MY PARENTS.
THEY WERE BOTH ENORMOUS.
THEY COULDN'T STOP EATING.
EVERY DAY I CAME HOME
FROM SCHOOL
IT WAS, "EAT THIS. EAT THAT.
EAT HER!"
YOU SHOULDN'T PUNISH YOURSELF.
OH, I SHOULD. I SHOULD.
I'M BAD. I'M SO BAD.
I'VE DONE SO MANY BAD THINGS!
BUT THAT WASN'T ME, YOU SEE?
THAT WAS WHEN I WAS A WOLF.
DOC, I WANT TO CHANGE!
I WANT TO BE
A GOOD PERSON.
OH, CAN'T THE LION
CUDDLE UP WITH THE LAMB?
CAN'T THE LEOPARD
RUB OUT ALL ITS SPOTS?
THIS IS THE EXACT SPOT
WHERE I FOUND YOU
SO THIS IS REALLY
WHERE WE HAVE TO GO
OUR SEPARATE WAYS, OKAY?
( sighs )
LOOK, I'M NOT THE ADVENTURE
TYPE, YOU KNOW?
I MEAN, I'M A WAITRESS.
THIS JUST REALLY...
THIS ISN'T MY THING.
WHOEVER THESE PEOPLE ARE
WHO WANT YOU
THEY CAN HAVE YOU.
NO, I GOT TO GO.
GOOD-BYE. I GOT TO GO.
( whines )
HERE IS THE READING
LIST I STRONGLY RECOMMEND NOW.
OKAY.
WHY DON'T YOU COME BACK
AND SEE ME NEXT WEEK?
OH, BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I WON'T BE HERE NEXT WEEK.
UH, UH, UH, UH.
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO INTIMIDATE ME
WITH SUICIDE.
THAT'S BETTER.
OKAY.
Policeman:
IF YOU COOPERATE
AND GIVE US
THE DEALER'S NAME
MAYBE I'LL PUT IN
A GOOD WORD FOR YOU.
"DEALER"? WHAT DEALER?
I'M NOT TAKING DRUGS.
YEAH, RIGHT.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER STEALING THE MONEY
BECAUSE YOU WERE
UNDER THE INFLUENCE
OF THESE MAGIC
MUSHROOMS, RIGHT?
"MAGIC MUSHROOMS"?
NO, I DIDN'T TAKE...
WELL, I SWALLOWED
THE BEAN, BUT...
I ALMOST FIXED
THE ELEVATOR NOW, MASTER.
WE WILL BREAK THE SPELL.
TRUST ME.
I TRUST YOU.
I TRUST YOU MORE.
NO, I TRUST YOU MORE.
YEAH!
I TRUST HER MORE.
I TRUST HER!
I ALWAYS TRUSTED HER!
SUCK AN ELF!
( all yelling )
Burly:
WE'RE MOVING.
WE'RE GOING DOWN.
IS THAT GOOD OR BAD?
WE ARE ABOUT TO ENTER
THE UNDERWORLD.
PREPARE YOURSELVES.
( bell dings )
( all yelling )
THIS ISN'T THE UNDERWORLD,
YOU IDIOT!
THIS IS WHERE WE CAME IN.
MAGIC, INDEED!
HOW DID SHE DO THAT?!
AH, SUCK AN ELF!
( Wolf gasps )
SHEEP! SOMETIMES I LIKE SHEEP.
OOH!
EXCUSE ME. I NEED
EVERYTHING ON THIS LIST
AND ANYTHING ELSE
YOU MIGHT THINK IS USEFUL, PLEASE, MISS?
( gasps )
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND IF MY PLAN IS SUCCESSFUL
I WILL CERTAINLY INVITE YOU
TO THE WEDDING.
THAT'S MINE.
THAT'S MINE, TOO.
Tony:
HEY, HEY, COULDN'T WE COME TO SOME KIND OF DEAL?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I CAN GIVE YOU ANYTHING
YOU WANTED.
ANYTHING WHATEVER.
I'M SERIOUS.
A HOUSE IN THE HAMPTONS,
BOATS, CARS, WOMEN.
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
IT WON'T MAKE IT ANY BETTER
TRYING TO BRIBE US.
WHAT HAVE I GOT TO LOSE?
I WISH I COULD ESCAPE
FROM THIS POLICE CAR RIGHT NOW.
( chuckling )
WES, THE BRAKES
ARE FAILING.
( horn beeping )
NO!
"HOW TO MARRY THE GIRL
OF YOUR DREAMS."
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I'M LOOKING FOR.
OH, MY GOD!
Officer:
STUPID IDIOT!
STOP THAT MAN RIGHT NOW!
HE'S GETTING AWAY!
HEY, PAL!
THANK YOU. THANK YOU!
NO, WAIT!
YOU HAVEN'T PAID FOR THOSE!
LOOK, I CANNOT TAKE YOU BACK
TO WHERE YOU CAME FROM
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU CAME FROM.
NO, LOOK, THIS
REALLY IS IT, OKAY?
GOOD LUCK.
I DIDN'T DO IT!
DAD?
DAD!
YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO ME.
DON'T BET ON IT.
COME ON!
FAN OUT, YOU GUYS, FAN OUT!
IS THAT THE DOG
THAT GUY WANTS?
WHY DON'T YOU
JUST GIVE IT TO HIM?
DAD, I DON'T THINK
HE IS A DOG.
HE'S TRYING
TO SAY SOMETHING
TALK TO ME OR SOMETHING
BUT I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT HE'S SAYING.
TRYING TO TALK?
YEAH, I DON'T KNOW.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU WATCH THIS.
I WISH THAT I COULD UNDERSTAND
EVERYTHING THIS DOG IS SAYING.
WHAT?
YOU'RE IN TERRIBLE DANGER.
BOTH OF YOU.
IT WORKED.
IT WORKED!
IF YOU VALUE
YOUR LIFE
YOU HAVE TO DO EXACTLY AS I SAY.
LISTEN! SHH. WHAT?
WE HAVE TO FIND THE WAY BACK.
HE'S TALKING.
CAN'T YOU HEAR HIM?
NO.
( police voices coming closer )
COME HERE.
WHAT?!
( all yelling )
WHY ARE ALL THESE
COPS AFTER YOU?
AND WHY ARE YOU
WEARING HANDCUFFS?
THEY THINK I DID
A BANK JOB.
WHAT?
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
STOP RABBITING
AND HELP ME FIND THE MIRROR.
NOW, IT'S A MIRROR
BUT IT MAY NOT
LOOK LIKE A MIRROR FROM THE OTHER SIDE.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK
VERY, VERY CAREFULLY.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A MAGIC MIRROR.
YEAH, OF COURSE WE ARE.
( Prince Wendell barking )
JUST LOOK FOR A PIECE OF FOREST
THAT DOESN'T FIT.
I'M SURE THIS IS WHERE...
LOOK.
THERE IT IS.
Tony:
THAT'S WEIRD.
Blabberwort:
THERE THEY ARE!
IF YOU VALUE YOUR LIVES,
FOLLOW ME.
UH, UH... COME ON.
( gasps )
WHERE THE HELL ARE WE?
I DON'T KNOW
BUT I'M PRETTY SURE
IT'S NOT CENTRAL PARK.
FOLLOW ME.
THE DOG SAID FOLLOW HIM.
HURRY UP!
WHAT HAPPENED TO EVERYBODY?
WELL, THE
SAME THING
THAT HAPPENED
TO YOU, OLD CHAP--
TROLL DUST!
IT LOOKS LIKE
IT'S STARTING TO WEAR OFF.
IS THAT DOG
TALKING AGAIN?
COME ON.
SO, WHAT SHALL WE DO
WHEN WE HAVE
OUR OWN KINGDOM?
AH, I KNOW, I KNOW.
WE'LL HAVE SERVANTS--
THOUSANDS AND THOUSANDS
OF SERVANTS
TO POLISH OUR SHOES.
DAD, LET'S GO HOME.
NO, I CAN'T
GO BACK YET.
POLICE ARE ALL
OVER CENTRAL PARK LOOKING FOR ME.
WELL, WE CAN'T STAY HERE.
SHH! I CAN SMELL THE TROLLS.
HE SAYS HE CAN
SMELL TROLLS.
WE'LL HAVE
FOOTWEAR PARTIES
WHERE YOU HAVE
TO CHANGE SHOES
SIX TIMES AN HOUR!
AND ANYONE FOUND
HAVING DIRTY SHOES
WILL HAVE THEIR FACE SEWN UP!
( laughing )
COME ALONG, THEN.
FOLLOW ME.
WHOA. HOLD ON.
I'M NOT GOING TO FOLLOW YOU.
WHERE ARE WE?
WE'RE IN THE SOUTHERNMOST PART
OF MY KINGDOM--
WHERE I WAS ATTACKED
BY MY STEPMOTHER
AND TURNED INTO A DOG.
THIS IS THE SNOW WHITE
MEMORIAL PRISON, HOUSING
THE MOST DANGEROUS CRIMINALS
IN ALL THE NINE KINGDOMS.
ALL RIGHT, BACK UP.
THE NINE WHAT?
KINGDOMS.
I AM PRINCE WENDELL
GRANDSON OF THE LATE SNOW WHITE
AND SOON-TO-BE-CROWNED
KING
OF THE FOURTH KINGDOM.
AND WHO
MIGHT YOU BE?
I'M TONY LEWIS, JANITOR.
I THINK YOU ALREADY KNOW
MY DAUGHTER
VIRGINIA.
THE "TROLL KINGDOM."
"RED RIDING HOOD FOREST." WOW!
WAIT. HOLD ON A SECOND.
SO WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S CINDERELLA-SLEEPING BEAUTY
FAIRY TALE STUFF?
WELL...
THE GOLDEN AGE WAS
ALMOST 200 YEARS AGO
WHEN THE LADIES
YOU REFER TO
HAD THEIR GREAT MOMENTS
IN HISTORY.
THINGS HAVE GONE DOWNHILL
A BIT SINCE THEN.
"HAPPY EVER AFTER" DIDN'T LAST
AS LONG AS WE'D HOPED.
ALL THE RULERS
OF THE OTHER KINGDOMS ARE
DUE TO ATTEND MY CORONATION.
SOME WILL HAVE
TO TRAVEL GREAT DISTANCES.
THE KINGDOMS ARE VAST.
NO ONE CROSSES THE BORDERS
EXCEPT ON SPECIAL OCCASIONS.
WHO WAS THE STEPMOTHER
WHO TURNED YOU INTO A DOG?
SHE IS THE MOST DANGEROUS
AND EVIL WOMAN ALIVE.
SOUNDS LIKE MY MOTHER-IN-LAW.
LOOK, WE CAN'T
SIT AROUND TALKING ALL DAY.
WE MUST FIND
MY STEPMOTHER'S CELL.
THIS WAY.
VIRGINIA,
HE SAID FOLLOW HIM.
COME ON. COME ON.
LOOK!
THERE'S A DOG BOWL DOWN HERE.
THAT'S THE DOG
THAT'S GOT MY BODY!
OH, IT'S OUTRAGEOUS!
WHAT DID SHE DO, THIS WOMAN?
SHE POISONED
MY MOTHER AND FATHER.
TRIED TO KILL ME, AS WELL.
BASICALLY, POISONED
HIS MOM AND DAD
AND TRIED TO
KILL HIM, TOO.
VIRGINIA, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I... I FEEL WEIRD BEING IN HERE.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH. I'M JUST GOING
TO WAIT OUTSIDE FOR A MINUTE.
THE TROLLS HAVE BEEN HERE.
OKAY, JUST DON'T
GO TOO FAR, OKAY?
STAY OUTSIDE
THE DOOR.
VIRGINIA!
PRINCE! PRINCE! PRINCE!
I WASN'T SCARED.
IT'S JUST THAT PEOPLE MUSTN'T
SEE ME AS A DOG, ANTONY.
IT'S DEEPLY, DEEPLY
EMBARRASSING.
I COULD CARE LESS
ABOUT YOU
BEING A DOG!
VIRGINIA! VIRGINIA!
WHERE ARE THEY?
I NEVER SHOULD HAVE
TRUSTED TROLLS TO DO ANYTHING.
BE CAREFUL
WHAT YOU SAY.
I'M THE ONLY REASON
YOU GOT OUT OF PRISON
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
OF COURSE,
YOUR MAJESTY
AND FOR THAT I'M
ETERNALLY GRATEFUL
BUT I CAN'T STAY
HERE ANY LONGER.
NO ONE MUST SEE
THE PRINCE LIKE THIS.
( barking )
HAVE YOUR CHILDREN
BRING THE DOG TO ME
WHEN THEY RETURN.
I AM NOT
YOUR LACKEY!
I AM RELISH
THE TROLL KING!
YOU WILL DO WELL
TO REMEMBER IT.
OF COURSE, YOUR MAJESTY.
AND I WILL
REWARD YOU HANDSOMELY
WITH HALF
OF WENDELL'S KINGDOM
AS I PROMISED.
JUST EXACTLY WHEN
DO I GET IT?
SOON.
BUT NOW I MUST GO.
I HAVE STAYED
TOO LONG ALREADY.
( panting )
OH, GET IN
THE CARRIAGE!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
THERE'S NOWHERE YOU CAN HIDE.
WHEN THEY FIND OUT
YOU'VE ESCAPED
THERE WILL BE
ROADBLOCKS EVERYWHERE.
THEY'LL SEARCH EVERY HOUSE
AND CARRIAGE IN THE KINGDOM.
NOT EVERY CARRIAGE.
SHOULDN'T WE GO
BACK FOR THE DOG?
NO, WE CAN'T.
THE TROLL DUST
WILL BE WEARING OFF.
( ringing )
WAIT A MINUTE!
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
THEY'RE ALL WAKING UP.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
OH, THE QUEEN
WILL BE VERY ANGRY.
AW, THE QUEEN CAN SUCK AN ELF
FOR ALL I CARE!
WE'VE CAPTURED
THE WITCH FROM THE TENTH KINGDOM!
LET'S GO TELL DAD.
WHAT ABOUT THE WITCH'S FATHER?
PERHAPS HE'S A GREAT WARLOCK.
OH, HE'S HANDCUFFED.
A GREAT IDIOT,
MORE LIKELY.
I WISH I COULD BE THERE
WHEN THE GOVERNOR FINDS HIM
IN THE QUEEN'S CELL.
( laughing )
Tony:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I CAN'T FIGHT.
IT WAS SOME
KIND OF SPELL.
ME AND THE LADS
BEEN LAID UP FOR OVER A DAY.
I'VE SEARCHED
EVERY INCH OF THE PRISON
BUT THE QUEEN'S
GONE, SIR.
I HAVE BEEN
THE GOVERNOR
OF THIS PRISON
FOR 12 YEARS.
NO PRISONER
HAS EVER ESCAPED BEFORE.
THAT'S A VERY IMPRESSIVE RECORD.
WHATEVER
YOU DO, ANTONY
DON'T TELL HIM I'M A DOG.
WHY NOT?
SPEAK WHEN YOU'RE SPOKEN TO!
BECAUSE
THE QUEEN HAS GOT
SOME TERRIBLE PLAN.
MY WHOLE KINGDOM
MAY BE IN JEOPARDY.
NO ONE MUST KNOW
I'M HELPLESS.
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE IS THE QUEEN?
I WISH I WAS HOME.
I WISH VIRGINIA AND I
WERE BACK IN
OUR APARTMENT
IN NEW YORK NOW.
WELL...
IT SEEMS YOU'RE NOT.
( coughing )
( gagging )
OH, NO, ANTONY!
YOU DIDN'T SWALLOW A DRAGON
DUNG BEAN,
YOU MORON!
I GUESS THAT MEANS I'VE HAD ALL
MY WISHES, HUH?
HOW DID THE QUEEN ESCAPE?
I'M TELLING YOU, I HAVE NO IDEA!
THEN WHY WERE YOU FOUND
LOCKED IN HER EMPTY CELL?
I AM AN INNOCENT VICTIM.
I HAVE NEVER BEEN IN TROUBLE
WITH THE POLICE MY ENTIRE LIFE.
THEN WHY ARE YOU
WEARING HANDCUFFS?
WELL, BECAUSE I'M WANTED
FOR ARMED ROBBERY
WHICH I DIDN'T
HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH EITHER.
OH, CARRY ON, ANTONY.
YOU'RE DOING
SPECTACULARLY WELL
SO FAR.
I'M FROM
A DIFFERENT DIMENSION.
I CAME HERE
FROM A DIFFERENT DIMENSION
LED BY THAT DOG,
WHO IS ACTUALLY PRINCE WENDELL.
OH, I TOLD YOU NOT TO SAY THAT.
PRINCE WENDELL?
LOOK, I CAN MAKE YOU
BREAK ROCKS
WITH YOUR TEETH
FOR 100 YEARS.
( clinking )
I'M TELLING YOU,
IT'S THE TRUTH.
THAT IS
THE QUEEN'S DOG.
SHE HAS
BEEN PERMITTED
TO KEEP HIM IN HER CELL
FOR THREE YEARS.
DON'T INSULT
MY INTELLIGENCE.
I'M NOT. IT'S THE TRU...
ALL RIGHT, I'LL PROVE IT.
BARK ONCE
IF I'M TELLING THE TRUTH.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF BARKING, ANTONY.
HE IS BEING JUST STUBBORN.
YOU HAVE TO
LET ME GO IMMEDIATELY.
I THINK MY
DAUGHTER WAS ABDUCTED BY TROLLS.
THAT'S ENOUGH!
I'LL GET THE TRUTH
OUT OF YOU
SOON ENOUGH.
WARDER, REMOVE HIS HANDCUFFS.
ISSUE HIM
WITH PRISON UNIFORM
AND PUT HIM IN
UH... YES!
PUT HIM IN 103
WITH ACORN THE DWARF
AND CLAY FACE
THE GOBLIN.
CLAY FACE THE GOBLIN?
I DON'T WANT TO BE PUT
IN ANY ROOM WITH CLAY FACE...
NO!
WHERE'S
MY DAUGHTER?
WHAT ABOUT
THE QUEEN'S DOG, SIR?
GET THE FURNACE
GOING.
I'LL SLIP
SOME RAT POISON
IN HIS DINNER TONIGHT,
AND WE'LL CHUCK HIM
IN THE INCINERATOR TOMORROW.
Prince Wendell:
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
ANTONY, DID YOU HEAR THAT?
YOU HAVE TO GET ME OUT.
IT'S YOUR DUTY.
GET HER IN THE BOAT.
GET HER IN THERE.
HEY, THAT'S MY BOAT.
IT'S OURS NOW.
NOW, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
( trolls yelling )
Blabberwort:
SIT DOWN AND STEER!
( all yelling )
MIDDLE BUNK.
SO, WHAT ARE
YOU IN FOR?
UM... ACTUALLY,
A PRETTY SERIOUS BANK ROBBERY.
COUPLE OF PEOPLE GOT HURT
BUT THAT'S THE WAY IT GOES.
AND YOU?
AGGRAVATED ASSAULT.
I'VE VERY EASILY
AGGRAVATED.
I'M ACORN.
GOT ANY METAL
ON YOU?
KNIVES? FORKS?
COAT-HANGERS?
SORRY.
IF YOU GET
STABBED...
SAVE THE KNIFE
FOR ME, WON'T YOU?
OF COURSE.
DO YOU LIKE
CARVING?
WELL, NOT FLESH
OR ANYTHING.
LOOK WHAT I'M DOING.
AH.
YOU'VE GOT REAL TALENT.
MY NAME'S CLAY FACE,
THE GOBLIN.
TONY.
WHAT ARE YOU IN FOR?
CARVING.
WILL YOU BE MY FRIEND?
WHAT EXACTLY DOES THAT ENTAIL?
Bluebell:
ROW!
Blabberwort:
WHEN WE'RE HOME, I'M GOING TO LET YOU HAVE IT!
KEEP ROWING.
I'M ROWING.
ANY MINUTE NOW...
I'M SURE PRINCE WENDELL
WILL ARRIVE
TO RECEIVE THE CORONATION THRONE
WHICH OUR CRAFTSMEN
HAVE TIRELESSLY SPENT
THE LAST TWO YEARS MAKING.
HE'S NOT COMING,
IS HE?
OF COURSE HE IS.
HAVE NO WORRY.
I'M SURE HE'S BEEN DELAYED
FOR A VERY GOOD REASON.
HORRIBLE NEWS.
THERE'S BEEN A BREAKOUT
FROM THE PRISON.
THE QUEEN
HAS ESCAPED.
THE QUEEN?
THE QUEEN.
PUT UP THE ROADBLOCKS.
SHE MUST BE CAUGHT
OR WE'RE DOOMED.
OH, WONDERFUL NEWS!
WONDERFUL NEWS.
PRINCE WENDELL
IS COMING.
THANK GOODNESS.
HE'LL KNOW WHAT TO DO.
( townspeople cheering )
WELCOME TO BEANTOWN
YOUR MAJESTY...
PSST. ANTONY.
OVER HERE.
BEHIND THE
GOVERNOR'S DOOR.
HOW DID YOU
KNOW IT WAS ME?
YOU HAVE
A DISTINCTIVE UNWASHED SMELL.
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
I'M SCRUBBING THE FLOOR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK I'M DOING?
HAVE YOU GOT A SOAP BAR?
WELL, YES.
WHAT, DO YOU WANT ME
TO WASH YOU?
NO, JUST STAY THERE.
DON'T GO AWAY.
PRINCE...
THIS IS THE
GOVERNOR'S MASTER KEY.
MAKE AN
IMPRESSION IN THE SOAP.
HE'LL BE BACK
ANY MOMENT.
HERE.
VERY STUBBORN STAIN, SIR.
Bluebell:
I THINK SHE'S WAKING UP.
GOOD MORNING.
( all laughing )
GET SOMEONE OVER HERE.
Prisoners:
WE PROMISE TO SERVE PRINCE WENDELL
KIND AND BRAVE MONARCH
OF THE FOURTH KINGDOM
AND PLEDGE TO MEND
OUR NAUGHTY WAYS
SO THAT WE MAY ALL LIVE
HAPPILY EVER AFTER.
( all grumbling and muttering )
WHAT IS THIS STUFF?
BAKED BEANSTALK.
BAKED BEANS?
BEANSTALK.
( gags )
MY GOD!
I CAN'T EAT THAT.
IT TASTES LIKE
AN OLD MATTRESS!
NO, IT DOESN'T.
OLD MATTRESS HAS
A SWEATY, MEATY TASTE.
AND HOW OFTEN IS
THIS ON THE MENU?
THREE TIMES A DAY.
THAT'S BEANSTALK JUICE.
TAKES A BIT
OF GETTING USED TO.
( gags )
LISTEN, UM...
LET'S SAY I WANTED
TO TALK TO SOMEBODY
AND I WANTED TO GET
SOMETHING... MADE.
FOR INSTANCE--
FOR THE SAKE OF ARGUMENT--
A SMALL PIECE OF METAL.
WHO WOULD I HAVE TO TALK TO?
I MEAN, WHO'S MR. BIG
AROUND HERE?
IF YOU WANT ANYTHING
BOUGHT, SOLD, BORROWED
OR MADE IN HERE
YOU HAVE TO SEE
THE TOOTH FAIRY.
UH... THE WHO?
THE PRISON DENTIST.
AH.
UH... AND HOW WOULD I GET
TO SEE HIM?
OH, UM...
THAT'S EASY.
OH, YEAH?
( yells )
( knocking )
OH, OH...
THAT'S NO GOOD.
THEY'LL ALL HAVE
TO COME OUT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "COME OUT"?
YOU HAVEN'T EVEN
LOOKED IN MY
MOUTH YET.
SIT DOWN.
I-I...
COME ON.
THERE. THAT'S IT.
( chuckles )
THERE.
W-WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME CANDY?
WHAT? YOU'RE A DENTIST.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE
GIVING PEOPLE CANDY.
WHY NOT?
WELL, BECAUSE
IT ROTS TEETH.
AH, RUBBISH!
WELL, OF COURSE
IT DOES!
WELL, EXCUSE ME.
WHO IS THE TOOTH
EXTRACTOR HERE, EH?
YOU OR ME?
WELL, I-I...
I'M JUST GONNA...
WH-WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M JUST PUTTING
THE STRAPS ON.
STRAPS? WHAT DO WE NEED
STRAPS FOR?
YEAH. THE STRAPS OF COMFORT.
TOOTH DECAY IS CAUSED
BY THREE THINGS.
NUMBER ONE: POOR DIET;
NUMBER TWO:
NOT BRUSHING PROPERLY;
AND NUMBER THREE...
BAD FAIRIES.
( groans softly )
( demented chuckle )
YOU KNOW, I-I THINK
I COULD, UM...
AH, JUST LET...
AH!
DOES THAT...
DOES THAT HURT?
OW! AH! UH-HUH.
GOOD.
HOW ABOUT THIS?
WHOA! NO.
WAIT A MINUTE...
( sharp groan )
NO, NO!
AH... LOOSE TEETH.
I THOUGHT SO.
OH...!
DON'T YOU WORRY.
WE HAVE A BAG
OF MAGIC TEETH HERE.
YOU CAN'T...!
( whispering ):
I CAME TO YOU FOR HELP.
HELP?
YEAH. I...
I'VE GOT TO GET A...
A KEY MADE OUT OF THIS.
WHAT'S IT WORTH?
UH....
OH, OH, LOOK, LOOK.
SEE THAT?
OH...
OW! THIS...
IS A HAND-WORN...CLOCK.
THE LITTLE HANDS GO AROUND,
AND IT TELLS THE TIME
VERY INTRICATELY.
I...
( loud ticking )
WE CALL THEM WATCHES.
AH, BUT THIS IS A ROLEX.
SOLID GOLD.
AH.
YEAH... WELL, AS
LONG AS IT'S NOT
ONE OF THOSE
CHEAP IMITATIONS.
OH...
AW, HEY!
( men chatting )
HEY! WHAT...?
HEY, LOOK!
PRINCE WENDELL'S CARRIAGE!
RAISE THE BARRIER!
YOUR MAJESTY!
( barking )
Chancellor:
DO YOU MEAN TO SAY HE JUST DROVE RIGHT THROUGH BEANTOWN
WITHOUT STOPPING?
THAT WAS ON WEDNESDAY,
LORD CHANCELLOR
AND HE HASN'T BEEN
SEEN SINCE.
THE THRONE MAKERS
ARE FURIOUS.
THEY'RE THREATENING
TO BOYCOTT THE CORONATION.
IT'S SO UNLIKE
THE PRINCE
NOT TO SEND WORD
OF WHERE HE IS.
PERHAPS IT'S
JUST, UH...
CORONATION NERVES.
I'M SURE
HE'LL TURN UP SOON.
LET US NOT FORGET
THAT THE EVIL QUEEN
IS NOW AT LARGE.
WHERE IS WENDELL?!
WHERE IS HE IN HIS KINGDOM'S
GREATEST HOUR OF NEED?
THINGS LOOK VERY BAD INDEED.
TERRIBLE.
QUITE AWFUL!
STILL...
I EXPECT IT'LL
ALL TURN OUT
HAPPY EVER AFTER.
OH, YES.
NOW, TO THE REAL CRISIS:
THERE IS A SHORTAGE
OF BLUEBELLS
THROUGHOUT THE KINGDOM.
MY COLOR SCHEME
FOR THE CORONATION BANQUET
WILL HAVE TO BE
COMPLETELY RETHOUGHT.
Burly:
SHE'S AWAKE.
STRIP HER.
( moans softly )
( yells )
OH, MY GOD.
YOU'RE A CAPTIVE
OF THE MERCILESS TROLLS NOW.
THE MERCILESS!
WITHOUT MERCY.
AH!
PRETTY LITTLE FEET.
NICEY NICE.
WHO RUNS YOUR KINGDOM?
MY KINGDOM?
WHO'S IN CHARGE?!
AH! THE PRESIDENT!
WENDELL WAS TRYING
TO RALLY AN ARMY
FROM YOUR KINGDOM
TO ATTACK US,
WASN'T HE?!
NO!
( Virginia yells )
THIS COULD BE
A LONG TORTURE SESSION.
I'LL TELL YOU ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO KNOW.
TORTURE FIRST, THEN YOU TALK.
IT'S BETTER THAT WAY.
RUSH A TORTURE,
RUIN A TORTURE.
( chuckling )
( door creaking )
( whispers ):
DAD'S HERE.
Blabberwort:
DAD?
WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE OFF THE SHOES?
Relish:
IN THESE SHOES
I AM ALL POWERFUL.
I CAN RULE THE WORLD.
Burly:
COME ON, DAD.
JUST SLIP 'EM OFF.
Relish:
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
YOU'RE A DAY LATE!
UH...
WELL...
HE...                   HE...
WHO'S THIS?
SUPPOSED TO BRING BACK
THE DOG.
OH, FORGET
THE DOG, DAD.
WE'VE DISCOVERED
ANOTHER KINGDOM.
THE MYTHICAL
TENTH KINGDOM.
TALKED OF
ONLY IN MYTH.
DON'T TALK
RUBBISH.
THERE IS NO
TENTH KINGDOM.
Bluebell:
OH, BUT THERE IS
AND THIS WITCH PUT US
IN A BOX OF MATCHES.
YOU WERE CAPTURED?
BY THIS... GIRL?
SHE'S A WITCH.
HOW MANY OF THEIR SOLDIERS
DID YOU KILL
BEFORE YOU WERE CAPTURED?
NONE.
NONE SURVIVED.
WHO WANTS TO BE WHIPPED FIRST?
IT'S TRUE.
LOOK AT THIS.
...Gimme that night fever
We know how to show it...
THEY ARE CALLED
THE BROTHERS GIBB.
AND THE SONG--
IT CONCERNS
A DEADLY FEVER
THAT ONLY STRIKES
ON SATURDAYS.
Relish:
THERE'S MORE TO ALL THIS...
THAN THE QUEEN IS TELLING ME.
( whispering ):
PRINCE
I'VE GOT THE KEY!
OH, BRILLIANT.
THE GOVERNOR'S
IN THE KITCHEN
MAKING ME ANOTHER
POISON DINNER.
QUICK! USE IT NOW.
OPEN THE DOOR.
THERE ARE SPARE
UNIFORMS IN HERE.
YOU CAN PUT ONE ON
AND-AND JUST
MARCH ME OUT OF THE PRISON.
OH, COME ON, HURRY UP!
SHH! SOMETHING'S
WRONG WITH THE KEY.
IT'S NOT TURNING.
MUST BE A...
YOU MUST REALLY
LOVE PAIN.
WHAT? OH, NO, NO, NO, NO!
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I-I WAS JUST COMING
DOWN THE HALL
AND I TRIPPED
ON THE LOOSE BRICK, AND I FELL
AND I FOUND MYSELF
IN FRONT OF YOUR DOOR
AND I FOUND THIS.
DID YOU LOSE ONE?
TAKE HIM DOWNSTAIRS
AND GIVE HIM 50
BEANSTALK LASHES.
RIGHT NOW!
NO, YOU KNOW,
THAT'S NOT NECESSARY.
I WAS COMING TO ASK YOU,
DO YOU HAVE A LAUNDRY HERE?
OH, DEAR.
SORRY ABOUT THAT, ANTONY.
NO. LISTEN,
I DON'T...
HERE, BOY.
Tony:
YOU'RE HURTING ME.
HERE YOU ARE, DOGGY.
THERE.
THAT SHOULD GIVE YOU
A NICE... LONG... SLEEP.
( whip cracks )
( scream )
( echoing scream )
( whip cracks )
Tony:
OUCH!
YOU WILL DANCE FOR ME
AND WHEN YOU'VE
FINISHED DANCING
YOU'LL TELL ME
HOW TO INVADE YOUR KINGDOM.
UH, YOU KNOW, I'M NOT...
I'M NOT MUCH
OF A DANCER, REALLY...
ACTUALLY.
YOU'LL DANCE
WHEN YOU WEAR THESE.
( sizzling )
WAKE ME
WHEN THEY TURN RED.
( creaking )
( sniffs )
CONCEAL THE COACH
THEN PREPARE A ROOM
FOR THE PRINCE.
WELCOME HOME.
WE HAVE MISSED YOU,
YOUR MAJESTY.
( door closes )
WHO'S THAT?
SHE WAS THE STEPMOTHER
WHO POISONED SNOW WHITE
WITH THE APPLE
ALL THOSE YEARS AGO.
SHE WAS ONCE
THE MOST POWERFUL WOMAN
IN ALL THE NINE KINGDOMS
AND THIS WAS BUT ONE
OF HER FIVE CASTLES.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO HER?
WHEN SHE WAS FINALLY CAUGHT
THEY HEATED A PAIR
OF IRON SLIPPERS
OVER RED-HOT COALS
AND MADE HER DANCE
AT SNOW WHITE'S WEDDING.
SHE CRAWLED OUT INTO THE SNOW
DRAGGING HER RAW,
BLISTERED, USELESS FEET
INTO A SWAMP NEARBY.
THIS BROKEN WOMAN
WAS ONCE THE FAIREST
OF THEM ALL...
BUT SHE KEPT
HER MAGIC MIRRORS
AND SEARCHED
FOR A SUCCESSOR
AND THAT, OF COURSE
WAS ME.
I WILL FINISH
HER WORK
AND DESTROY THE HOUSE
OF WHITE FOREVER
AND PITY THE FOOL
WHO TRIES TO STAND UP TO ME!
Woman:
I AM DEAD
BUT MY WORK IS UNFINISHED.
THE HOUSE OF SNOW WHITE
SURVIVES.
YOU MUST COMPLETE THAT WORK.
IN THE RUIN OF MY CASTLE
YOU WILL FIND THE SOURCE
OF MY POWER.
THESE ARE MY GIFTS.
THEY GIVE YOU MY POWER.
MIRRORS TO TRAVEL.
MIRRORS TO SPY.
MIRRORS TO REMEMBER.
MIRRORS TO FORGET.
MIRRORS TO RULE THE WORLD.
SO GOOD TO HAVE THE POWER BACK.
FRYING TONIGHT.
KEEP AWAY FROM ME.
Virginia:
I MEAN IT!
FRYING TONIGHT.
Burly:
LISTEN TO THIS.
"A PRESENT FOR THE STRONGEST,
BRAVEST TROLL."
( trolls laughing )
OH, YOU KNOW WHAT
IT SMELLS LIKE?
( all sniffing )
LEATHER!
SHOES!
IT COULD BE BOOKS.
AND MY SIZE BY
THE LOOK OF THINGS.
THEY'RE MINE!
IT'S A PRESENT FOR ME
AND YOU KNOW IT.
THEY'RE MINE.
MINE. LOOK.
LET'S SPIN A COIN
TO DECIDE
WHO GETS IT.
HELLO.
RESCUE IS AT HAND.
DON'T COME ANY NEARER.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT WHO I USED TO BE.
I'VE HAD EXTENSIVE THERAPY.
I REALIZE I HAVE BEEN
USING FOOD
AS A SUBSTITUTE FOR LOVE
AND I HAVE THE BOOKS
TO PROVE IT.
BREAKING THE CYCLE.
HEAL YOURSELF IN SEVEN DAYS.
STOP BLAMING YOURSELF, PLEASE.
AND HELP FOR
THE BEDWETTING CHILD
BUT I'VE GOT THEM ALL!
YOU COME AN INCH CLOSER
AND I SWEAR I'LL
SHOUT MY HEAD OFF.
OOH. THAT IS WHAT IS KNOWN
AS AN EMPTY THREAT.
( sniffing )
( whimpers )
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND ME
SAYING THIS
BUT I GET THE FEELING
YOU STILL DON'T
COMPLETELY TRUST ME.
I DON'T TRUST YOU AT ALL.
YOU TRIED TO EAT MY GRANDMOTHER.
OH, NO...
I WAS JUST BEING PLAYFUL.
SEE, WOLFIES
JUST PRETEND
TO DO NAUGHTY THINGS.
I WOULD HAVE NEVER
REALLY EATEN HER.
SHE WAS A TOUGH OLD BIRD.
I WOULDN'T HURT
A SAUSAGE.
BUTTER WOULD NOT MELT
IN MY MOUTH.
WELL, IT WOULD MELT.
OF COURSE, IT WOULD MELT,
BUT VERY SLOWLY.
OH... PUFF!
I GIVE YOU
MY SOLEMN WOLF WORD
YOU ARE SAFE WITH ME.
YOU ARE AS
SAFE AS A...
BRICK-BUILT PIG HOUSE.
NOW, WAIT HERE A MOMENT
WHILE I PLAN OUR ESCAPE.
WE ARE IN ROMANTICALLY
RECKLESS DANGER.
HOW ARE YOU AT CLIMBING?
I NEARLY FELL OFF
THREE TIMES COMING UP.
Virginia:
THOSE INCREDIBLE SHOES.
THEY MADE HIM INVISIBLE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
YEAH, BUT THEY MADE HIM
INVISIBLE.
DON'T TOUCH THEM.
THEY'LL MAKE YOU
WANT TO WEAR THEM ALL THE TIME.
BALCONY OR CORRIDOR?
THAT IS THE
QUESTION.
I'M NOT GOING TO TOUCH THEM.
I JUST WANT TO SEE
HOW THEY WORK.
THEY'RE WORKING
ON YOU EVEN NOW.
JUST LEAVE THEM
WELL ALONE.
CORRIDOR, I THINK.
OOH! NO. BALCONY... QUICK.
THERE'S SOMEONE COMING.
EXCUSE ME...
WHERE DO YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING, EXACTLY?
GOING BACK TO PRISON...
THAT WOULDN'T BE
MY FIRST CHOICE.
I'M GOING TO FIND MY FATHER
THEN I'M GOING TO GO
RIGHT BACK HOME.
ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT!
BUT NOT THIS WAY.
VIRGINIA, PLEASE LISTEN.
YOU WON'T SURVIVE FIVE MINUTES
UNLESS YOU FOLLOW ME.
NOW, WE MUST AVOID THIS ROAD.
GO THIS WAY.
( thunder rumbling )
NO WAY AM I GOING IN THERE.
( distant growling )
"BRAVE JACK."
JACK?
JACK AND THE BEANSTALK.
FIRST MAYOR OF BEANTOWN.
YOU KNOW, THIS USED TO BE
A VERY PROSPEROUS AREA
BEFORE ALL THE BEANSTALKS
SPROUTED EVERYWHERE
AND POLLUTED THE LAND.
THE TROLLS WERE GIVEN IT
AS THEIR KINGDOM.
THAT'S WHY THEY HATE
PRINCE WENDELL SO MUCH
BECAUSE HE HAS
A JUICY, FERTILE KINGDOM
AND THEY HAVE
A POLLUTED, DISGUSTING KINGDOM.
VIRGINIA?
( thunder cracking )
VIRGINIA? VIRGINIA?
VIRGINIA, PLEASE TELL ME
YOU DIDN'T TAKE
THE TROLL KING'S MAGIC SHOES.
VIRGINIA? VIRGINIA?
VIRGINIA?!
IDIOTS!
FOOLS!
I CAN'T LEAVE YOU
ALONE FOR A MINUTE.
YOUR MOTHERS
WOULD BE ASHAMED OF YOU.
NO, NO, NO, DAD,
IT WASN'T OUR FAULT.
THE WITCH, SHE TRICKED US
WITH THIS MAGIC SHOE BOX.
"BEST WISHES FROM WOLF."
VIRGINIA...
I KNOW YOU THINK
YOU'RE SAFE IN THOSE SHOES
BUT NOTHING COULD BE FURTHER
FROM THE TRUTH.
ANYTHING A TROLL HAS IS BOUND
TO BE BAD AND DANGEROUS.
VIRGINIA...
WHERE ARE YOU?
OH, NO.
Wolf:
HELLO AGAIN.
( gasps )
THEY'RE NOT
FULLY RECHARGED.
YOU SEE?
THEY DON'T STAY
INVISIBLE VERY LONG
WITHOUT A PROPER BREAK.
IT'S A DESIGN FAULT
IN THE SHOES--
ONE OF MANY, IN FACT.
YOU'RE NOT HAVING THEM.
HAVING WHAT?
THE SHOES--
THEY'RE MINE.
IF YOU DON'T GET
RID OF THEM NOW
YOU WON'T BE
ABLE TO LATER.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
OH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
OH, I DON'T WANT THEM.
THEY MADE ME FEEL
SO STRANGE.
GOD, I FELT SO POWERFUL.
YOU KNOW, BEING INVISIBLE.
JUST AMAZING!
FANTASTIC!
HOW DID YOU KNOW
WHERE I WAS?
( sniffs )
I COULD SMELL YOU.
OH...
FOLLOW ME.
( distant growling )
THERE ARE ABOUT
70 BEANSTALKS LEFT
BUT NOT MANY ARE OCCUPIED
THESE DAYS.
GIANTS DRINK SO MUCH.
REALLY TOUGH TO REPRODUCE.
CAN I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
YEAH, OF COURSE.
DO YOU THINK
I'M SEXY?
YOU'RE THE KIND OF MAN
I SUPPOSE I SHOULD
BE SCARED OF.
OH, VIRGINIA, AS MUCH AS
I WOULD LOVE TO BELIEVE
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING
TO ME RIGHT NOW
I'M AFRAID IT'S THE SHOES
THAT ARE TALKING.
YOU'D SAY ANYTHING
TO PUT THEM ON AGAIN.
GIVE THEM BACK.
COME ON, GIVE THEM BACK...
OH, GOD.
OH, I'M REALLY SORRY.
THAT WAS WEIRD.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT CAME OVER ME.
OH, THEY BRING OUT
VERY STRANGE THINGS,
THESE SHOES...
WHATEVER YOU'RE
SUPPRESSING.
I'M NOT SUPPRESSING ANYTHING.
( sniffs )
WHAT?
TROLLS...
THEY FOUND US.
OH, CRIPES, WE'RE
IN BIG, BIG TROUBLE NOW.
THEY HAVE DOGS.
THEY'RE GOING
TO SNIFF US OUT.
RUN! RUN!
Trolls:
OVER HERE!
THEY FOUND A SCENT!
I SEE THEM UP AHEAD!
( thunder booming )
THIS WAY!
THE DOGS ARE ON THE SCENT!
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE NOW.
THEY CAN SMELL THEM.
DON'T LET THEM ESCAPE AGAIN.
BLUEBELL, COME HERE.
BLABBERWORT,
GOT ANY MAGIC MUSHROOMS?
NO.
I'VE GOT SOME
DWARF MOSS.
IT'LL REALLY BLOW
YOUR HEAD OFF, THOUGH.
LOOK AT THIS.
LAST TIME I TOOK IT
I SAW FAIRIES
FOR THREE DAYS.
NICEY-NICE.
ROLL US A GIANT.
THIS MAY BE A LONG NIGHT.
( distant growling )
Relish:
BLUEBELL...
BURLY, BLABBERWORT
WHERE ARE YOU?
COMING, DAD.
THE BEANSTALK
HAS A POTENT SMELL.
IT PUTS OFF THE DOGS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL ME.
WE'LL STAY UP HERE
FOR A LITTLE WHILE
TILL IT'S SAFE.
SO HOW DO DID YOU GET INVOLVED
IN ALL THIS ANYWAY?
OH... I FOUND MYSELF
AT A LOOSE END AND...
YOU WERE IN THAT PRISON,
WEREN'T YOU?
WHAT WERE YOU IN FOR?
WELL, NOTHING MUCH--
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SHEEP-WORRYING, THAT'S ALL.
PUTTING A WOLF
INTO A PRISON CELL
WITH NOWHERE TO BOUND
ONLY ABLE TO STARE AT THE SKY
THROUGH BARS--
NOW, THAT'S INHUMAN.
SO, YOU THINK
MAYBE I SHOULD...
YOU KNOW,
PUT THEM ON AGAIN?
WHAT?
I MEAN, THE SHOES
ARE PROBABLY
FULLY RECHARGED...
NO... NO!
WELL...
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S JUST MY TAIL.
YOUR TAIL?
WHAT?
IT'S NOT VERY BIG
AT THIS TIME OF MONTH.
IT'S JUST A LITTLE BRUSH.
YOU'VE GOT A TAIL?
YEAH? SO? YOU HAVE
SUCCULENT BREASTS.
I DON'T GO ON
ABOUT THEM ALL
THE TIME, DO I?
WHY DON'T YOU TOUCH IT?
IT'S PERFECTLY
NORMAL.
IF IT'S NORMAL, HOW COME YOU
KEEP IT HIDDEN ALL THE TIME?
BECAUSE, IF YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
PEOPLE DON'T LIKE WOLFS.
COME ON. GIVE IT
A STROKE.
IT WON'T BITE.
( gasping )
WHAT? WHAT?
WITH THE FUR--
NOT AGAINST IT.
SORRY.
( sighing )
I'VE GOT KEYS GOING MISSING;
I'VE GOT TROLLS AND WOLVES
AND QUEENS MISSING...
WHAT IN THE FAIRYING FOREST
HAS HAPPENED TO BASIC SECURITY
IN THIS PRISON?
SIR, WHILE WE WERE
SEARCHING THE PRISON
WE FOUND THAT THE DOOR
TO THE CELLARS
WAS UNLOCKED AT THE TIME
OF THE QUEEN'S... BREAKOUT.
Governor:
"CELLAR?" DID HE JUST SAY "CELLAR"?
IT IS POSSIBLE SHE
ESCAPED THAT WAY.
WHAT'S DOWN THERE?
YOU.
IT'S JUST SOME OLD JUNK, SIR.
IT'S BEEN THERE
FOR HUNDREDS
OF YEARS--
BEFORE THIS PLACE
WAS A PRISON.
Governor:
THE MIRROR!
TAKE THE WORK DETAIL
OFF THE LAUNDRY ROOM.
HAVE THEM CLEAR OUT
THE WHOLE PLACE TOP TO BOTTOM.
NOW, GET OUT.
OH, NO! THAT'S THE MIRROR
TO THE OTHER WORLD!
I'D BETTER PUT ANTONY'S NAME
ON THE WORK DETAIL.
"TONY...
LEWIS."
Governor:
ALL RIGHT, NOW, PAY ATTENTION!
EVERYTHING HERE
HAS TO BE CLEARED OUT
SO FORM A HUMAN CHAIN
AND CHUCK EVERYTHING
INTO THAT BOAT MOORED THERE.
UH, EXCUSE ME?
WHAT?
WELL, WE'RE KIND OF
FAR AWAY FROM THE BOAT.
AREN'T WE IN DANGER
OF THE MORE
DELICATE OBJECTS BEING BROKEN?
WHAT DO YOU THINK THIS IS,
LEWIS--
AN ELVES' UNDERWEAR PARTY?
LOOK, THIS IS SCRAP.
NOW, DO AS YOU'RE TOLD.
AND SHUT IT.
HUFFITY-PUFFITY,
THERE IT IS!
OH...
OH, GOD,
I HOPE HE'S OKAY.
HE CAN TAKE CARE
OF HIMSELF, RIGHT?
I MEAN, HE CAN STAY
OUT OF TROUBLE
FOR ONE DAY, AT LEAST...
CAN'T HE?
WELL, FROM WHAT I KNOW
ABOUT YOUR FATHER
I VERY MUCH DOUBT IT.
ALL RIGHT, MIRROR, ON.
MIRROR! ON! ON!
MIRROR...
LEWIS...
WHAT IN THE FAIRYING FOREST
DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?
IT'S NOT WORKING.
LISTEN, LEWIS, YOU LITTLE
PRISON PRINCESS
THROW THAT MIRROR
ON THAT BOAT NOW.
UH... NO, I CAN'T.
UM, I'M AFRAID IT'LL BREAK.
AS YOU HAVE REFUSED
TO OBEY MY INSTRUCTIONS
I AM GOING TO PUSH YOU
INTO THE RIVER.
AND AS YOU ARE CONNECTED
BY LEG IRONS
TO EACH OF YOUR COMRADES,
THEY WILL ALSO, SADLY, DROWN.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, YOU WAIT HERE.
I'LL PUT THE MAGIC SHOES ON
AND I'LL GO BACK
INSIDE THE PRISON.
NO WAY! YOU'LL
NEVER COME BACK!
YOU JUST WANT THEM FOR YOURSELF.
OH, NO, I DON'T!
YOU DO!
OH... YES, I DO, BUT...
OH, I'M FIGHTING IT,
UNLIKE YOU.
( growling )
I HAVE AN IDEA--
I'LL WEAR THEM,
YOU HOLD ONTO ME
'CAUSE IF YOU'RE TOUCHING ME,
WE'LL BOTH BE INVISIBLE!
NO! I WILL WEAR THEM...
AND YOU WILL HANG ONTO ME!
YOU ARE HOPELESSLY ADDICTED
TO THOSE SHOES.
AND I'M NOT
TOO FAR BEHIND!
CURSES!
NOW WE'LL HAVE
TO KILL HIM.
MMM.
A TOMB!
SHH!
WE'VE BEEN DIGGING
FOR 31 YEARS.
OH, PLEASE TAKE ME WITH YOU,
PLEASE!
YOU CAN TRUST ME!
AT HOME, I'VE GOT
ESCAPE FROM ALCATRAZ
ON VIDEO.
I KNOW HOW
TO DO THIS!
BEST WE SUFFOCATE HIM,
I THINK.
NO...
I TRUST HIM.
WELL, THANKS.
I WOULD GIVE YOU
MY WATCH, BUT, UH...
IT ALREADY WENT
SOMEWHERE.
Virginia:
TEN MONTHS JUST FOR BEING CHEEKY?
WHAT ARE THEY GOING
TO DO WITH DAD?
Wolf:
THEY'LL PROBABLY BRING YOUR DAD TO A PLACE LIKE THIS
WHERE NEW PRISONERS USUALLY GO.
LET'S GO THERE.
Virginia:
PUPPY SLAYING?
WHAT ABOUT PRINCE?
( barking )
LISTEN! LISTEN,
THAT MUST BE HIM.
THAT'S PRINCE.
VIRGINIA, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
WE CAN'T TAKE
HIM WITH US.
HE'LL DRAIN ALL THE
POWER IN THE SHOES
AND WE'LL BECOME
VISIBLE.
VIRGINIA!
( grumbling )
( groaning )
HEY, HEY... HEY, GUYS,
WAIT UP, HUH?
SORRY, TONY, IT'S EVERY MAN
FOR HIMSELF.
NEVER MIND, JUST GO
RIGHT AHEAD. GO, GO!
I THINK HE'S LEADING US
TO DAD'S CELL.
THIS IS IT!
DAD? DAD, ARE YOU
IN HERE?
OH...
THEY'RE EXHAUSTED.
I TOLD YOU THIS WAS
GOING TO HAPPEN.
( barking )
LOOK!
BOY, YOUR FATHER
SURE WORKS FAST.
YES!
SURE YOU DON'T WANT
TO COME WITH ME?
A GOBLIN TRAVELS FASTEST ALONE.
YES!
( laughing )
OW!
THERE'S SOMETHING
BLOCKING THE TUNNEL!
( sniffing ):
TONY, IS THAT YOU?
WHO'S THAT?
IT'S ME-- WOLF!
I GAVE YOU THE MAGIC DRAGON
DUNG BEAN, REMEMBER ME?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
JUST STAY AWAY FROM ME.
WE'RE IN A TUNNEL TOGETHER.
HOW CAN I DO THAT?
I'M ALMOST OUT, TOO...
BUT I'M STUCK...
LOOK, JUST GIVE
ME A PUSH.
OKAY.
( grunting )
COME ON.
( whimpering )
OH, DAD...
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WE HAVE TO FIND A WAY
TO GO BACK IN
AND GET THE MIRROR.
WHAT? NO, NO, WE DON'T.
I THREW IT ON A TRASH BARGE.
I THINK IT'S ON THIS RIVER
RIGHT HERE!
WHICH ONE?
IT WAS RIGHT HERE.
WHERE?
THEY MOVED IT.
I BET YOU
IT'S OVER HERE. WHERE?
IT WAS RIGHT HERE.
LOOK, THEY TOOK IT.
ACORN'S STOLEN IT.
OH, NO!
HE'S GOT OUR MIRROR!
MIRROR, WAKE FROM YOUR SLEEP.
( glass shattering )
SUMMON RELISH THE TROLL KING.
TONY, GET THIS THING MOVING.
LOOK, THERE THEY ARE.
DON'T LET THEM
GET AWAY.
OH, CRIPES!
( yelling )
DAD!
LOOK.
OH, MY GOD! LOOK OUT!
GET THEM! HIT THEM!
HIT THEM
WITH SOMETHING!
HIT THEM!
YOU DOG!
IN YOUR DREAMS
TROLL BOY.
WHAT A PATHETIC DISPLAY.
HOW DARE YOU CALL YOURSELVES
MY CHILDREN.
YOU ARE THE MOST...
( eerie whooshing )
( yelling )
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, DAD?
WHAT'S WRONG?
MIRROR...
FIND ME A MIRROR.
OUT!
GET OUT!
SO GOOD OF YOU
TO JOIN ME.
YOU DO THAT
AGAIN TO ME
AND I'LL KILL YOU.
WELL?
WELL, WHAT?
HAVE YOUR CHILDREN
CAUGHT THE DOG FOR ME?
NOT EXACTLY.
YOU DO SURPRISE ME,
YOUR MAJESTY.
HOW COULD HE POSSIBLY ESCAPE
YOUR TINY LITTLE GRASP?
DON'T YOU TALK TO ME THAT WAY.
HE MUST BE CAUGHT.
SEND YOUR CHILDREN AFTER HIM.
AND WHAT ARE YOU STILL
DOING IN WENDELL'S KINGDOM?
RETURN TO YOUR PALACE
IMMEDIATELY.
AWAIT MY FURTHER ORDERS.
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU.
( distant bird calls )
VIRGINIA, WOULD YOU SAY
THAT YOU WERE HUNGRY
FOR LOVE AND APPROVAL
BUT DESTINED
FOR REJECTION?
I'M QUITE HAPPY
AS I AM, THANK YOU.
WAIT!
NO! NO!
NO!
WHAT DID YOU DO
THAT FOR?!
I HAD TO FOR
YOUR OWN GOOD.
YOU THREW AWAY MY SHOES!
YOU WERE ALREADY DREAMING
OF WEARING THEM TONIGHT,
WEREN'T YOU?
YES, I...
HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT?
MAGIC IS VERY NICE
BUT IT'S VERY EASY
TO GET ADDICTED.
BUT WHY DIDN'T YOU WANT THEM?
HOW COME YOU WERE ABLE
TO RESIST THE SHOES
AND I WASN'T?
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
SUCH A STRONG DESIRE
TO BE INVISIBLE.
ANTONY, I KNOW THAT
AS MY NEW MANSERVANT
YOU WILL NEVER
LET ME DOWN.
YOU WILL WILLINGLY GIVE
YOUR LIFE TO SAVE MINE.
BUT I WONDER IF YOU'D
LIKE TO SWEAR
A FORMAL OATH
OF ALLEGIANCE.
DESTINY HAS BROUGHT
US TOGETHER--
THAT MUCH
IS CLEAR.
MY DESTINY
IS TO RULE THE
FOURTH KINGDOM, OF COURSE
BUT WHAT IS YOURS?
SOMEONE AS LOWLY
AND INCONSEQUENTIAL
AS YOURSELF
MAY YET HAVE AN
IMPORTANT PART TO PLAY
EVEN IF IT IS
ONLY CATERING
TO MY EVERY WHIM
WHILST I'M TRAPPED
IN THE BODY OF A DO...
WHAT WAS THAT?
NOTHING.
UH... A FISH,
I DON'T KNOW.
( crowd shouting )
I INSIST YOU LEAVE.
TROLLS ARE NOT ALLOWED
IN THE FOURTH KINGDOM
WITHOUT PROPER PERMITS.
THIS IS A GROSS VIOLATION
OF THE NINE
KINGDOMS TREATY.
SHUT YOUR MOUTH.
UNLESS YOU LEAVE
THIS INSTANT
I SHALL NOTIFY
PRINCE WENDELL
AND SOLDIERS
WILL BE SENT.
( crowd shouting )
I AM DECLARING WAR
ON THE FOURTH KINGDOM.
AND I CHALLENGE PRINCE WENDELL
TO COME AND FACE ME
WITHIN SEVEN DAYS
OR I WILL CLAIM HIS KINGDOM
AS MY OWN.
RISE AND SHINE!
WAKEY, WAKEY.
( howling )
IT'S ANOTHER
BEAUTIFUL DAY
IN THE FOURTH KINGDOM.
SLEEP WELL, VIRGINIA?
ACTUALLY, NO.
I JUST GOT TO SLEEP
AN HOUR AGO.
OH, YOU SHOULD HAVE
JOINED ME ON DECK
SLEEPING UNDER THE STARS.
IT WAS QUITE MAGNIFICENT.
YOU'RE OUTSTANDINGLY
GORGEOUS IN THE MORNING.
PERT FROM THE FRONT...
AND A VISION FROM BEHIND.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
WHAT?
DON'T LOOK AT MY DAUGHTER
LIKE THAT.
WAS IT THIS LOOK, TONY?
( panting )
I CAN'T HELP IT.
IT'S ANIMAL PASSION.
OH, JUST...
LOOK, JUST STAY AWAY FROM HER,
ALL RIGHT?
YOU'VE GOT A CRIMINAL RECORD.
WELL, HOW CAN I STAY
AWAY FROM HER?
WE'RE ON A VERY SMALL BOAT.
I MAY BUMP INTO HER ACCIDENTALLY
AT ANY GIVEN MOMENT.
HEY, WILL YOU STOP
TALKING ABOUT ME
AS IF I'M NOT HERE?
MANSERVANT...
WE NEED TO GO
UP ON DECK.
BRING A BUCKET
AND A SHOVEL.
FIRST OF ALL, I'M NOT
YOUR MANSERVANT.
AND IF YOU THINK
I'M GOING... OW!
WHAT THE...?
CRIPES!
WHAT IS THAT?
WHOA.
HUFFITY, PUFFITY.
THAT'S ONE HELL
OF A FISH.
GOLDEN RIVER GOLD FISH.
YOU THINK
IT'S MAGIC?
OH, GOODNESS
GRACIOUS, YES.
THIS IS THE FAMOUS
ANYTHING-YOU-TOUCH-
WILL-TURN-TO-GOLD FISH.
WHAT'S THIS?
"WARNING...
...FINANCIAL EMERGENCY.
Tony:
LOOK AT THAT.
"STICK A FINGER
IN MY MOUTH
"TURN AROUND
TILL YOU FACE SOUTH.
"TOUCH A THING
THAT YOU WOULD PRIZE
"AND YOU WILL NOT
BELIEVE YOUR EYES.
"HERE IS MAGIC
TO BEHOLD
ALL THAT GLITTERS
CAN BE GOLD."
YOU REALLY THINK
IT TURNS WHATEVER YOU TOUCH INTO GOLD?
I'M SURE IT DOES, BUT...
WE DON'T NEED TO TURN
ANYTHING INTO GOLD, DO WE?
WELL, NO, BUT I MEAN,
GOLD IS GOLD, RIGHT?
THINK ABOUT THE GUY
THAT OWNED THIS BOAT.
HE WAS NO FOOL.
HE'S PROBABLY NOW LIVING
IN THE LAP OF LUXURY
IN SOME NINE KINGDOMS
CONDOMINIUM
WITH A MOUNTAIN OF GOLD
IN HIS BACKYARD
AND EVERYTHING
HIS HEART DESIRES.
BEST LEAVE IT
ALONE, TONY.
BEST LEAVE
IT ALONE.
YEAH...
WELL, OH, YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
BEST LEAVE IT ALONE, TONY.
BEST LEAVE IT...
( clamoring and screaming )
EXACTLY WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE PLAYING AT?
WE HAD A BARGAIN.
I WOULD GIVE YOU HALF
OF WENDELL'S KINGDOM
IN RETURN FOR
YOUR COOPERATION.
YOU'VE DONE QUITE WELL
SINCE I BROKE YOU
OUT OF PRISON.
IT IS ESSENTIAL
THAT THE CORONATION PROCEED
ACCORDING TO MY PLAN.
IF YOU REMAIN IN
WENDELL'S KINGDOM
THEN YOU'LL RUIN
EVERYTHING.
A CRISIS WILL INEVITABLY ENSUE.
WHAT'S "ENSUE" MEAN?
IT MEANS LEAVE BEANTOWN,
RETURN TO YOUR KINGDOM
OR YOU'LL RUIN EVERYTHING.
I MIGHT, I MIGHT NOT.
BY THE WAY, HOW ARE
MY CHILDREN DOING?
THEIR INTELLECT AND BRAVERY
QUITE TAKE MY BREATH AWAY.
YEAH. WELL, YOU LOOK AFTER THEM.
I WANT THEM BACK IN ONE PIECE.
IF YOU'LL ONLY BE PATIENT,
YOUR MAJESTY
I WILL GIVE YOU
WENDELL'S KINGDOM ON A PLATE.
BUT I'M HUNGRY NOW.
MORON!
MIRROR, TALK TO ME.
WHY HAVEN'T YOU
FOUND WENDELL YET?
HE IS WITH OTHERS,
BUT I CANNOT SEE THEM.
WHO?!
THREE TRAVEL WITH WENDELL--
ONE WHO CAN TALK WITH HIM,
AND ONE WHO CAN HURT YOU.
THEY ARE TRAVELING
DOWN THE RIVER
TOWARDS US, UNKNOWINGLY.
SHOW ME.
I CANNOT.
WOLF IS WITH THEM.
WORK ON HIM.
MAKE HIM TALK TO ME.
( tape playing "Night Fever" )
...WHEN YOU REACH OUT FOR ME
YEAH, AND THE FEELIN'
IS RIGHT
I GET THE NIGHT FEVER,
NIGHT FEVER
WE KNOW HOW TO DO IT
NIGHT AFTER NI-NI-NI-NIGHT
NIGHT FEVER, NIGHT FEVER
WE KNOW HOW TO SHOW IT
I'LL BE FOREVER MAKIN' MUSIC
HERE I AM
( music slowing )
PRAYIN' FOR THIS MOMENT TO LAST
LIVIN' ON THE MUSIC SO FINE
BORNE ON THE WIND
MAKIN' IT MINE...
AHH!
THEIR MAGIC IS USELESS,
THE BROTHERS GIBB.
ROW FASTER.
SHUT UP, BLUEBELL.
I'VE ROWED ALL NIGHT.
OH, SHUT UP, BURLY.
OH, BLUEBELL, STOP EATING
YOUR HEAD LICE.
I WASN'T CHEWING.
I WAS JUST KEEPING IT
UNDER MY TONGUE.
STOP TALKING.
AND ROW FASTER,
BLABBERWORT, FASTER.
OH, LOOKEE LOOK.
LOOK THERE.
( groaning )
A BOOK.
"WOMEN WHO LOVE MEN..."
"...WHO HATE WOMEN."
NICEY-NICE.
THAT'S NOT NICE.
Tony:
WOLF! YOU DOING SOMETHING WITH DINNER OR NOT?!
UH, YEAH. UH-HUH.
UH... COME ON.
I MUST LOOK BEAUTIFUL
FOR VIRGINIA.
HELLO, WOLF.
( gasping )
OH... GO AWAY.
LEAVE ME ALONE.
YOU AGREED TO OBEY ME.
NO.
YES.
I CONTROL YOU.
NO.
WHY CAN'T I SEE YOUR COMPANION?
WHAT MAGIC
IS GOING ON HERE?
MAGIC? WELL, UH...
IS THERE FOOD,
OR ISN'T THERE FOOD?
NO. I WASN'T TALKING TO ANYBODY.
I WAS MAKING DINNER.
WHERE IS IT?
IT'S...
WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT? I...
WHA...?
HEY.
FISHY, FISHY, FISHY?
( tapping louder )
( coughing loudly )
"THERE IS MAGIC TO BEHOLD.
ALL THAT GLITTERS CAN BE GOLD."
HUH.
( blowing )
HELLO?
OH, MY FINGER OF FORTUNE.
Virginia:
DAD?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I THOUGHT I HEARD A CRASH.
OH, HI. JUST, UM, CLEANING UP
A LITTLE OF THIS ACCIDENTAL...
GLASS BREAKAGE.
DID YOU PUT YOUR FINGER
IN THAT FISH?
UH, NO, WELL,
TECHNICALLY, UM...
YES.
( gasping )
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
WE'RE RICH NOW. WE'RE RICH.
WE'RE OUR OWN BANK.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I COULD TURN THIS
ENTIRE BOAT INTO GOLD.
YES, AND THEN IT WOULD SINK
AND WE WOULD ALL DROWN.
GOOD POINT. OKAY, I'LL WAIT.
I'LL FIND THE
RIGHT THING
AND THEN I'LL HAVE
THIS HUGE LUMP OF GOLD.
YOU'LL BE THANKING ME.
YOU WILL BE THANKING ME.
OH, YES.
( panting and sniffing )
GET SOME BONES.
JAWBONES.
GNAW BONES.
MUST FIND SOME BONES.
( panting )
MISTRESS WON'T GIVE ME
ANY BONES.
STEAL SOME BONES.
BURY THEM UNDER THE SHEETS...
AND CHEW THEM
WHEN SHE'S GONE TO BED.
OW!
AHH...
( panting and sniffing )
NICE BONES...
Queen:
STAND UP.
STAND UP PROPERLY.
I'M SCARED.
OF WHAT?
I'LL FALL OVER.
IT'S SO HIGH UP HERE.
CAN'T I GET ON ALL FOURS?
DO YOU KNOW WHO YOU ARE?
CAN I HAVE A BISCUIT?
YOU ARE NOT A DOG.
YOU ARE PRINCE WENDELL.
YOU ARE RULER OF
THE FOURTH KINGDOM.
PRINCE WENDELL
LOVES BISCUITS.
GET DRESSED.
YOU HAVE A WHOLE
LIFE TO LEARN.
BEFORE YOU CAN
BE CROWNED KING
YOU MUST BE SEEN
TO DEMONSTRATE
BRAVERY, ROYALTY,
AND INTELLIGENCE.
( panting )
( barking )
WHAT A CHALLENGE.
OH, NO.
WHAT'S WRONG?
UH, NOTHING.
JUST, JUST A FEELING.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
IT'S ACORN'S BOAT.
IT'S MOORED
RIGHT THERE. LOOK.
WATCH THE FINGER.
THERE. RIGHT THERE,
RIGHT THERE.
ANTONY, SOMETHING REALLY
STRANGE IS HAPPENING.
I FEEL IT. I FEEL
LIKE I'M TWO PEOPLE
AT THE SAME TIME.
WHAT?
I HAVE TO GO BACK
TO THAT CASTLE.
W-WHAT, WHAT CAS...?
IT'S AN OLD RUIN--
THAT CASTLE.
WHY GO THERE?
LET'S GO TO ONE
OF ACORN'S BOATS.
NO. I'M SURE
MY HUMAN BODY IS THERE.
WAIT!
HEY!
OH, MY GOD.
PRINCE, COME BACK!
COME BACK.
WHAT IS WRONG
WITH HIM?
PRINCE!
WELL, WE CAN'T
GO AFTER HIM.
BUT...
LET'S JUST GO
FIND ACORN
AND GET THE MIRROR
BACK, OKAY?
GOOD IDEA.
LET HIM GO. LET HIM GO.
LET HIM...?
Burly:
FASTER!
ROW FASTER!
I CAN'T ROW
ANY FASTER.
MY HANDS ARE BLEEDING.
"MY HANDS ARE BLEEDING."
OH, SUCK IT UP, BLUEBELL.
BOTH OF YOU JUST SHUT UP.
SHUT UP. LOOK.
THERE'S
THE RUINED CASTLE.
WE SHOULD REPORT
TO THE QUEEN.
EXCELLENT IDEA.
STEER US OVER
TO THE SHORE.
ACORN'S BEEN HERE ALL MORNING.
HE LEFT LESS
THAN A HALF HOUR AGO.
WITH THE REST OF THE STUFF
THAT WAS ON THE BOAT?
YEP.
WHEN'S HE
COMING BACK?
HE'S NOT.
HE SWAPPED THIS LOVELY BOAT
FOR MY HORSE AND CART.
I RECKON I GOT
A GREAT DEAL.
WELL, WHICH WAY
DID HE GO?
HE SAID HE'D USE THE ROAD
THROUGH THE FORREST.
IF YOU HURRY,
YOU COULD CATCH HIM.
OH, GOOD IDEA,
GOOD IDEA. LET'S GO.
LET'S GO.
HOLD ON A SECOND.
WHAT ABOUT PRINCE?
WELL, HE'S OFF.
HE WANTS TO BE
ON HIS OWN. SEE--
MY HEART IS
BREAKING, BUT, UH...
LET'S FOLLOW THE MIRROR.
TON...
YOU SAID SO YOURSELF--
HE'S BEEN NOTHING
BUT A NUISANCE.
YEAH, I KNOW, BUT I...
LOOK, UH...
IT FEELS WEIRD LEAVING HIM.
HE MUST HAVE RUN OFF
FOR A REASON.
YOU'RE GOING TO
LOSE THAT MIRROR. DAD.
ALL RIGHT, NO. WAIT, WAIT.
LOOK. 15 MINUTES.
DAD.
ALL RIGHT, 15 MINUTES.
WHILE YOU'RE
WAITING TO EAT
TRY TO KEEP YOUR TONGUE
INSIDE YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S SOMEWHAT VULGAR
TO HAVE IT HANGING OUT
ALL THE TIME.
I'M STARVING.
WHERE'S MY BOWL?
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
A LOVELY MEAL.
OH.
JUST AS SOON AS YOU'VE
LEARNT TO USE A FORK...
AND A KNIFE.
UNTIL THEN,
YOU WILL STARVE.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOMETHING
TO DRINK, YOUR MAJESTY?
BOWL OF WATER.
NO, A GLASS
OF WATER.
A PRINCE NEVER
DRINKS FROM A BOWL.
A GLASS OF
WATER, PLEASE.
YES.
IS THERE ANYTHING
ELSE YOU REQUIRE?
UH, MY WOOLLY BALL.
NO, WE DON'T PLAY BALL
AT THE TABLE.
MAJESTY,
THE THREE TROLLS HAVE RETURNED.
YOU PRACTICE USING
YOUR FORK AND KNIFE
AND I WILL RETURN
TO TEST YOU IN TEN MINUTES.
FORK... KNIFE.
Prince:
I'M SURE I'M HERE.
IT MUST BE ME.
I CAN SMELL ME.
( Prince barking )
( sniffing )
( barks )
( barking )
YOU.
IT'S ME.
YOU...
IT'S ME... I'M YOU... OH.
IT'S ME.
IT'S YOU. IT'S ME...
HELLO.
YES, YES. GOOD DOGGIE.
GOOD DOGGIE.
FORELEGS, PLEASE.
NOW, IF YOU CAN JUST
REACH UP AND TOUCH ME,
WE CAN CHANGE BACK.
OH, COME ON, YOU
DUMB DOG, REACH UP.
I DEFINITELY CAN'T REACH YOU.
WAIT HERE.
YOU CAN'T HEAR ME
BUT I'M GOING TO GO FOR HELP.
NOW, DON'T WORRY,
I'LL BE BACK
IN JUST A MINUTE. DON'T MOVE!
WHERE IS PRINCE WENDELL?
AH, YES.
PRINCE WENDELL.
I SENT YOU
TO GET HIM.
A NOBLE MISSION
FOR ANY TROLL.
SO WHERE IS HE?
YOU IDIOTS!
I'VE SPOKEN
WITH MY MIRROR.
PRINCE WENDELL IS VERY NEAR.
HE MAY EVEN BE
IN RIVERTOWN BY NOW.
WOW. THAT'S A
STROKE OF LUCK.
GO AND FIND HIM!
IF YOU RETURN AGAIN
WITHOUT THE DOG
I WILL MAKE YOU EAT
EACH OTHER'S HEARTS.
WELL, THAT DIDN'T GO
TOO BADLY, CONSIDERING.
HEY!
PRINCE?!
PRINCE!
ANTONY!
PRINCE.
I FOUND MYSELF.
LOOK OUT!
OH! GET OFF MY ARM!
JUST LEAVE HIM ALONE, ALL RIGHT?
I GOT HIM. I GOT HIM.
HE'S JUST A DOG, YOU COWARDS.
ANTONY!
DAD!
TONY!
HEY!
DAD!
OH, THANK GOD
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
DID YOU FIND PRINCE?
UH...
ARE YOU OKAY?
I DEFEATED
THE TROLLS.
THAT'S THE
GOOD NEWS.
GOOD.
IS THERE ANY
BAD NEWS, TONY?
DO YOU THINK THAT BOATMAN
MIGHT HAVE A CHISEL?
DAD, WHAT EXACTLY IS
THE BAD NEWS?
YEAH.
WELL...
I THINK HE'LL COME APART
FROM THE OTHERS PRETTY EASILY.
HUNTSMAN...
YOU SUMMONED ME,
MY LADY?
NEITHER WOLF NOR THE TROLLS
HAVE CAPTURED THE DOG YET.
SOMEONE IS TESTING ME.
COMPARED TO YOU...
THEY'RE NOTHING.
WHY CAN'T I SEE THEM
IN MY MIRRORS?
SOMETHING'S CLOUDING
MY VISION...
BUT THEY ARE NEAR.
THEY HAVE LEFT
THE RIVER.
THEY ARE ABOUT TO
ENTER YOUR FOREST.
I WILL FIND THEM.
NOTHING ESCAPES...
THE HUNTSMAN.
"EVERY ASPECT OF MY LIFE,
I AM GUIDED
"TO MY HIGHEST HAPPINESS
AND FULFILLMENT.
"EVERY DAY, IN EVERY WAY
"I AM BECOMING A NEW
AND BETTER MAN.
"I AM SENSITIVE
TO THE NEEDS OF WOMEN
"I AM LISTENING TO MY EMOTIONS
"AND I AM ONE WITH MYSELF
AND..."
( grunts )
OKAY.
RIGHT.
"I AM FULL OF... PEACE
AND SERENITY
"AND I HAVE CONTROL...
( sizzling )
"OVER ALL OF MY DESIRES
AND...
AND..."
TONY, YOU'RE RUINING THE BACON!
I CAN SMELL IT BURNING!
( growling softly )
TONY...
( gasps )
BACON.
( chuckling )
I FEEL TERRIBLE.
LOOK AT HIM.
Wolf:
IT WAS A SIMPLE MAGIC FISH SPELL
GOLD FINGER MISTAKE, TONY.
IT WAS ALMOST PREDICTABLE.
BUT I'VE KILLED HIM.
( sighing ):
THINGS HAVE A WAY OF BOUNCING BACK HERE.
I WOULDN'T WORRY
ABOUT HIM TOO MUCH.
REALLY?
YOU'RE NOT JUST
SAYING THAT?
I'M AFRAID I AM
JUST SAYING THAT.
WHAT...
WATCH THIS SIMPLE
PRINCE-ALERTNESS TEST.
COME ON.
FETCH.
THAT'S NOT FUNNY.
IT COULD GET FUNNY
IF WE KEEP ON DOING IT.
WHY ARE YOU TWO
STILL SITTING HERE?
I TOLD YOU
TO GET PACKED UP.
WE'RE MAKING
SANDWICHES.
WE'RE MAKING SANDWICHES.
THE MIRROR IS GETTING
FURTHER AWAY ALL THE TIME.
IF WE LOSE THIS TRAIL NOW,
WE'RE NEVER GOING
TO GET HOME.
OH, BUT, VIRGINIA,
BREAKFAST IS BACON
AND NOTHING SETS
MY NOSTRILS TWITCHING
LIKE BACON IN THE MORNING--
LITTLE PIGS PARADING UP AND DOWN
WITH THEIR CURLY
CORKSCREW TAILS...
( gasping )
BACON SIZZLING AWAY
ON AN IRON FRYING PAN.
( gasping )
BASTE IT, ROAST IT, TOAST IT
NIBBLE IT, CHEW IT
BITE RIGHT THROUGH IT
WOBBLE IT, GOBBLE IT,
WRAP IT
'ROUND A COUPLE OF CHICKENS
AND AM I RAVENOUS!
( growling )
LET'S FINISH THESE
ON THE MOVE.
WAIT, WAIT A MINUTE, VIRGINIA.
VIRGINIA, UH, WAIT.
VIRGINIA... WAIT,
WAIT, VIRGINIA.
UH, WHAT DO YOU SEE?
UH...
A LOT OF TREES?
NO.
YOU SEE NOTHING.
LOOK AT EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED HERE LAST
NIGHT WHILE YOU SLEPT.
LIKE WHAT?
YOU SEE THAT CLEARING?
YEAH.
ABOUT MIDNIGHT...
A BADGER TROTTED
ACROSS THERE
AND, THEN, TWO HOURS LATER,
A MOTHER FOX TOOK THE PATH
BUT OUR PRESENCE
SPOOKED HER.
SO, SHE WENT BACK
INTO THE TREES.
THEN, A HALF AN
HOUR AFTER THAT
ANOTHER FOX APPEARED--
MALE THIS TIME, YOUNG
AND OUT COURTING.
I RECKON HE GOT
HIS PORRIDGE
BECAUSE I DIDN'T SEE
HIM COME BACK...
OR-OR OVER THERE.
YOU SEE OVER THERE
WHERE THE UNDERGROWTH
IS DISTURBED?
A NOISY, LITTLE WILD BOAR
WAS SNUFFLING ABOUT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
HE DIDN'T WAKE YOU UP.
OH, OH, OH,
AND RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU
YOU SEE THE PASSAGE
OF THE MOLE?
OR-OR OVER THERE
A STAG AND A DOE
WATCHED THE SUN COME UP
WITH ME.
AND THAT'S NOT TO MENTION
THE ALL-NIGHT RABBIT PARTY
OR THE WEASELS
OR THE PHEASANTS
OR THAT-THAT OWL.
OH...
AND YOU SAW NOTHING.
I STAND CORRECTED.
YOU MOST CERTAINLY DO.
( chuckles )
GREAT.
CAN WE GO?
OH, TONY?
I AM BUT A POOR OLD LADY.
SPARE ME SOME FOOD.
SORRY, WE'RE DOWN
TO OUR LAST SIX
BACON SANDWICHES.
GOOD SIR...
I ONLY GIVE
TO REGISTERED CHARITIES.
YOUNG LADY...
SPARE ME SOME FOOD, PLEASE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
WHAT I HAVE.
OH...
WH... VIRGINIA...
YOU ARE SUCH A SOFT TOUCH.
YEAH, "SOFT TOUCH."
HEY.
SINCE YOU HAVE BEEN KIND
I HAVE A LESSON
FOR ALL OF YOU.
TAKE THIS STICK.
BREAK IT.
AND THIS ONE.
( Virginia chuckles )
PUT THESE THREE TOGETHER.
NOW, TRY AND
BREAK THEM.
OKAY.
I CAN'T.
( chuckles )
THAT IS THE LESSON.
( whispering ):
GOOD LESSON.
OH, WOW.
I THINK MAYBE THAT WAS
ONLY WORTH ONE SANDWICH.
"WHEN THE STUDENTS ARE READY,
THE TEACHER APPEARS."
YOU DIDN'T GO
TO MY SCHOOL.
UM, EXCUSE ME, MISS,
DID YOU HAPPEN
TO SEE A DWARF
DRIVING A CART?
VERY EARLY
THIS MORNING.
HE TOOK THE MAIN ROAD
THROUGH THE FOREST
BUT YOU MUST NOT.
YOU MUST LEAVE THE PATH.
WAIT.
THE ROAD'S
THE ONLY
SAFE THING IN
THE WHOLE FOREST.
NOT FOR YOU.
SOMEONE IS FOLLOWING YOU.
THEY INTEND TO KILL YOU.
( gasps )
WHOA. WAIT.
WAIT, WHAT IS
THIS INTENT TO KILL?
( panting )
OH, THERE'S A MAN WHO CONTROLS
THIS FOREST-- THE HUNTSMAN.
I'VE HEARD
HE SERVES THE QUEEN
BUT HE CERTAINLY
WOULDN'T EXPECT US
TO LEAVE THE ONLY ROAD
AND GO INTO THE FOREST ITSELF.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE ONLY A FOOL WOULD GO
INTO THE DISENCHANTED FOREST.
WELL, LET'S NOT.
OKAY, FROM NOW ON,
I WILL LEAD.
YOU STEP WHERE I STEP.
WAIT... I...
( grumbles )
( rustling )
( barking echoing )
IS IT JUST ME OR DO
YOU HEAR MOANING?
I HEAR MOANING.
YOU'RE GOING
TO HEAR LOTS OF THINGS.
THE FOREST IS...
IT'S MAGICAL.
( moaning echoing )
( gasps )
Virginia:
CRIPES, WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
DO YOU ACTUALLY KNOW
WHERE WE'RE GOING?
I'M FOLLOWING MY NOSE.
WHO IS THIS HUNTSMAN?
( Tony grumbling )
AW...
WE CAN'T WALK
ALL NIGHT.
YES, WE CAN.
WHOA... SHH.
DO YOU HEAR SOMETHING?
( horse snorting )
( owl hooting )
( horse whinnying,
people chattering )
Wolf:
GYPSIES.
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
UHH...
JOIN US, OF COURSE.
POACHERS.
THEY'LL KILL US
IF THEY SO CHOOSE.
DO NOT REFUSE
ANYTHING THEY OFFER
BUT DO NOT CONSUME
ANYTHING THAT YOU HAVEN'T
ALREADY SEEN THEM EAT FIRST.
IT'S LIKE HAVING
DINNER AT YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S HOUSE.
I THINK
WE SHOULD SIT DOWN.
HOW ARE YOU?
( festive music playing )
WHEW, THIS IS
THE BEST HEDGEHOG
I'VE HAD IN WEEKS.
( cheering and applause )
NOW IT'S YOUR
TURN, STRANGER.
Tony:
WELL, NO, I DON'T ACTUALLY PLAY.
THEN SING US
A SONG.
NOT A SINGER.
TONY
SING.
LET'S NOT INSULT
OUR HOSTS.
BUT... I CAN'T
THINK OF ANY SONGS.
IS OUR HOSPITALITY NOT WORTH
A SONG?
I DON'T. I CAN'T...
SURE.
I, UH...
UH...
UM...
( haltingly ):
PICKED UP A BOY JUST SOUTH OF MOBILE
GAVE HIM A RIDE
FILLED HIM
WITH A HOT MEAL
I WAS 16, HE WAS 21
GYPSIES, TRAMPS
AND THIEVES
WE HEARD IT
FROM THE PEOPLE
IN THE TOWN
THEY CALLED US
GYPSIES, TRAMPS AND THIEVES
BUT EVERY NIGHT
THE MEN WOULD COME AROUND
AND LAY THEIR MONEY DOWN.
( clapping )
Virginia:
THAT WAS GOOD.
Tony:
WELL... HEY, I...
( birds chirping )
Bird:
SET ME FREE.
SET US FREE.
PLEASE,
WE'RE JUST LITTLE VICTIMS.
MAGIC BIRDS.
VERY RARE,
VERY HARD TO CATCH.
ONLY THE GYPSIES KNOW
HOW TO CATCH THEM.
LITTLE VICTIMS.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT, GIRLIE.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN
TO THEM?
Wolf:
THEY'LL HAVE THEIR WINGS BROKEN.
BE SOLD
TO RICH PEOPLE.
WE WON'T, WILL WE?
THAT'S AWFUL.
SEE, SOME PEOPLE,
THEY EAT THEM
BELIEVING THAT THEY ABSORB
THEIR MAGIC.
THEY DON'T,
DO THEY?
THAT'S TERRIBLE.
I HAVE SIX
LITTLE BABIES WAITING TO BE FED.
THEY'RE STARVING
TO DEATH WITHOUT ME.
THAT'S AWFUL.
SET US FREE.
PLEASE
IS HE REAL GOLD?
WHAT? NO, NO. OH, GOLD.
NO, NO, PLEASE DON'T.
NO, NO, NO.
IT'S JUST GOLD PAINT.
I BOUGHT A COUPLE-- A PAIR--
TO PUT AT THE END
OF MY DRIVEWAY.
SET UP A TABLE.
I SEE GREAT WEALTH
COMING TO YOU.
YEAH! THAT'S WHAT
I LIKE TO HEAR.
AND PASSING
STRAIGHT THROUGH.
OH, THAT WAS THE BEAN I HAD.
AND WHAT ABOUT THE FUTURE?
I FIND THE FOOL...
UH-HUH.
AND THAT CARD?
WHAT'S THAT CARD?
THE FOOL'S FRIEND--
THE OAF.
HE IS JOINED BY
THE BUFFOON...
AND THE VILLAGE IDIOT.
WHAT? I...
I WILL READ THE GIRL.
OH, NO, THANKS.
YOU ARE FULL OF ANGER.
YOU CONCEAL MUCH
ABOUT YOURSELF.
I NEED A LOCK
OF YOUR HAIR.
YOU HAVE
A GREAT DESTINY
WHICH STRETCHES
WAY BACK IN TIME.
I'M JUST A WAITRESS
SO I DON'T THINK
THERE'S ANY PRIZES SO FAR.
YOU HAVE NEVER FORGIVEN
YOUR MOTHER FOR LEAVING YOU.
AS I SAID
I'M NOT REALLY INTERESTED
IN HAVING MY FORTUNE READ.
( panting )
LOVE AND ROMANCE, PLEASE.
MARRIAGE, CHILDREN,
HOW LONG IT'S GOING TO TAKE
FOR THE CREAMY GIRL
OF MY DREAMS TO SAY YES--
THAT SORT OF THING.
I SEE DEATH.
OOH!
A YOUNG GIRL DEAD...
TORN TO PIECES.
NO!
OH, NO. SEE, I WAS THINKING
MORE ALONG THE LINES
OF THREE GIRLS AND TWO BOYS.
I SEE A FIRE
BEING BUILT.
YOU ARE GOING
TO BE BURNED ON IT.
NO!
YOU ARE NOT
WHAT YOU SEEM.
YOU ARE A WOLF.
SO IS YOUR GRANDSON.
YOU MUST STAY
WITH US TONIGHT.
FRIENDS MUST
STAY TOGETHER
IN THE DANGEROUS FOREST.
YEAH.
( bird screeches in distance )
( magic birds twittering )
SET US FREE.
SET US FREE! SET US FREE!
PLEASE SET US FREE!
Wolf:
SHH.
Birds:
SET US FREE!
SET US FREE, PLEASE!
PLEASE SET US FREE!
SET ME FREE!
PLEASE SET US FREE.
( loud twittering )
SET US FREE!
PLEASE
PLEASE SET ME FREE!
WHAT THE HELL
IS SHE DOING?
VIRGINIA.
VIRGINIA!
PLEASE SET ME FREE!
DON'T. DON'T.
COME ON.
( buckets clatter )
UH-OH!
OH!
Tony:
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
GO, GO! COME ON, GO!
AFTER THEM!
QUICK!
VIRGINIA!
I'LL GO
TO THE RIGHT.
( men shouting )
Gypsy Queen:
COME BACK!
NO ONE IS THERE!
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
THE OLD WOMAN
CALLED OFF THE HUNT.
MAYBE WE
JUST GOT LUCKY.
LET'S JUST GET GOING.
THE SOONER WE
GET OUT OF THIS FOREST, THE BETTER.
HELP ME GET PRINCE
UP ON THE PATH.
CAN'T WE
JUST BURY HIM?
WE COULD
ALWAYS COME BACK
SOMETIME
IN THE FUTURE.
I'M NOT GOING
TO LEAVE HIM.
I GOT HIM INTO THIS MESS;
I'M GOING TO GET HIM OUT.
OH!
I WISH I KNEW WHY
THEY GAVE UP SO EASILY.
THAT'S NOT LIKE GYPSIES AT ALL.
STRETCH IT, TWIST IT,
MAKE IT GROW
LIKE A RIVER,
MAKE IT FLOW
MAKE IT PULL
AND PINCH AND TWEAK
MAKE IT GROW TILL SHE GROWS WEAK
MAKE HER MOAN AND SCREAM AND CRY
MAKE HER WISH
THAT SHE WOULD DIE!
( horse whinnying )
"ALL POACHERS
"WILL BE KILLED
BY ORDER OF THE HUNTSMAN."
HE'S HERE.
HE'S OVER THERE!
I SAW SOMETHING MOVE!
( screaming )
( all yelling )
( horse neighing )
WHAT?
WHAT ARE
YOU LOOKING AT?
UM... YOUR HAIR.
IT LOOKS...
WELL, DIFFERENT.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S BECAUSE I WENT
TO THE BEAUTICIAN LAST NIGHT.
NO, IT'S NOT THAT.
IT'S, UM...
WELL... IT'S GROWN.
GROWN?
SO IT HAS.
MY GOD!
OH, MY GOD, IT IS LONGER.
THAT'S SO WEIRD.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
THE GYPSIES!
OF COURSE.
THEY HAD SOME
OF YOUR HAIR.
THE GYPSIES
HAVE CURSED YOU!
CURSED ME?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
CURSED?
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
UM... BRAID IT?
OW!
STOP IT!
YOU'RE JERKING IT!
I'M SORRY.
IT'S NOT THAT EASY--
YOU'VE GOT A LOT
OF SPLIT ENDS.
( groans )
HOW LONG
IS IT NOW?
OH, DON'T ASK.
UH, WHERE ARE WE GOING?
( thunder crashing )
OW!
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
THIS IS CRAZY!
WE CAN'T KEEP GOING.
WE'VE GOT TO STOP SOMEWHERE.
WHERE ARE WE GOING
TO FIND SHELTER
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE FOREST?
I DON'T KNOW!
CRIPES! LOOK!
( laughing ):
OH-HO-HO!
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
COME ON!
( banging )
ANYONE HOME?
Wolf:
IT'S OKAY-- NO ONE'S BEEN HERE FOR A LONG TIME.
HEY... HEY, COME LOOK AT THIS.
ARE YOU THINKING
WHAT I'M THINKING?
THIS IS SNOW WHITE'S COTTAGE.
GOODNESS GRACIOUS ME
THIS IS THE SEVEN DWARFS' HOUSE!
IT'S BEEN LOST
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
THESE BEDS ARE SO TINY.
SEE, THIS IS
A GREAT PIECE
OF OUR HISTORY.
IT'S A PITY PRINCE IS A STIFF.
THIS IS HIS GRANDMA'S COTTAGE.
CRIPES!
Wolf:
WE REALLY SHOULDN'T HAVE A FIRE
IF SOMEONE'S
FOLLOWING US.
I DON'T CARE-- I'M NOT GOING
TO BED WITH WET HAIR.
YOU KNOW, HERE'S A QUESTION
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D BE ASKING:
WHAT HAPPENED TO SNOW WHITE
AFTER SHE MARRIED THE PRINCE?
SHE BECAME A GREAT QUEEN--
ONE OF THE FIVE WOMEN
WHO CHANGED HISTORY.
FIVE WOMEN?
SNOW WHITE, CINDERELLA,
QUEEN RIDING HOOD
GRETEL THE GREAT
AND THE LADY RAPUNZEL.
THEY FORMED
THE FIRST
FIVE KINGDOMS
BROUGHT PEACE
TO ALL THE LANDS
BUT THEY'RE
ALL DEAD NOW.
SOME SAY
CINDERELLA'S
STILL ALIVE
BUT NO ONE'S SEEN
HER IN PUBLIC
IN NEARLY 40 YEARS.
SHE WOULD BE
NEARLY 200 YEARS OLD.
( heavy sigh )
THE DAYS OF "HAPPY EVER AFTER"
ARE GONE.
THESE ARE DARK TIMES.
( crickets chirping,
birds squawking )
( soft snoring )
Virginia:
WHAT'D YOU SAY TO THAT BOY IN THE GYPSY CAMP?
NOTHING MUCH; JUST WOLF STUFF.
WHAT'S "WOLF STUFF"?
OH, I DIDN'T NEED TO SAY
ANYTHING TO HIM--
I WAS JUST WITH HIM.
HE HAD NEVER SEEN
ANOTHER WOLF
AND HE WAS SCARED.
IT'S A LONELY PATH IN
LIFE TO BE DIFFERENT, AS YOU KNOW.
WHERE'S YOUR MOM?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
SHE WALKED OUT ON US
WHEN I WAS SEVEN.
( groans )
SAD TO BE LEFT
WHEN YOU'RE SO LITTLE.
I VERY RARELY THINK ABOUT HER,
TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
SHE'S NEVER REALLY BEEN
A PART OF MY LIFE.
WELL, WHAT HAPPENED?
OH... SHE JUST LEFT HOME.
WOULDN'T YOU IF YOU
WERE MARRIED TO MY DAD?
WELL, THEY'RE JUST...
TOTALLY DIFFERENT PEOPLE.
YOU'VE MET MY GRANDMOTHER,
RIGHT?
MY MOTHER WAS LIKE THAT.
IT WAS A COMPLETE MISMATCH.
THEY NEVER SHOULD HAVE
GOTTEN MARRIED TO BEGIN WITH.
ANYWAY...
IT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
WHERE IS SHE NOW?
I HAVEN'T A CLUE
AND I COULDN'T CARE LESS,
REALLY.
DON'T YOU...
WONDER WHAT SHE'S LIKE?
SHE COULD HAVE GOTTEN BACK IN
TOUCH WITH ME, BUT SHE DIDN'T
AND THAT'S FINE, YOU KNOW?
I MEAN, IF SHE DOESN'T WANT ME
I'M NOT GOING TO WASTE MY ENERGY
THINKING ABOUT HER.
OH.
"OH" WHAT?
"OH." JUST "OH."
"OH," AS IN AN ENCOURAGING,
NONCOMMITTAL NOISE.
"TRY NOT TO COMMENT
AS YOU LISTEN"
AS MY VERY GOOD SELF-HELP BOOKS
TAUGHT ME.
( sneezes )
YOU MUST DO SOMETHING
MAGNIFICENT WITH YOUR LIFE.
( laughs )
OH, YEAH? WHY?
BECAUSE YOUR HURT
IS VERY GREAT.
THEY JUST SPLIT UP, OKAY?
GOD! DOESN'T THAT EVER HAPPEN
WHERE YOU COME FROM?
OF COURSE NOT.
WE EITHER
LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER
OR WE GET KILLED
BY HORRIBLE CURSES.
YOU DON'T TRUST NOBODY.
I DON'T TRUST YOU, NO.
WELL...
YOU MAY NOT GET HURT...
BUT HUFF AND PUFF,
YOU WON'T GET LOVED, EITHER.
( groaning sleepily )
OH, MY GOD.
OH, MY GOD!
WHAT?
( whimpering )
GOODNESS, ME! CRIPES!
IT'S EVERYWHERE!
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO?
TONY? TONY!
VIRGINIA,
IT'S... IT'S...
IT'S GROWING
UP THE STAIRS!
( labored grunting )
YOU KNOW WHAT? IT'S NO GOOD.
NOTHING CUTS THROUGH THIS.
WELL, WHAT IF IT
NEVER STOPS GROWING?
WELL, I'M GOING TO DIE
OF LONG HAIR!
NO.
DON'T DESPAIR.
BECAUSE YOU SAVED MY LIFE
I'LL TELL YOU
HOW TO CUT YOUR HAIR.
OH, PLEASE.
DEEP IN THE FOREST
THERE IS A WOODSMAN
WITH A MAGIC AX
THAT, WHEN SWUNG
NEVER FAILS TO CUT
WHATEVER IT HITS...
AND IT WILL CUT YOUR HAIR
AND CURE THE CURSE.
OKAY, WE BETTER
GET MOVING
BEFORE VIRGINIA'S HAIR
GETS TOO LONG.
OH, THESE APPLES
LOOK GOOD, THOUGH, HUH?
TONY! NO!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
DON'T EAT THAT APPLE!
HEY, HEY, HEY,
HEY, HEY! WHY NOT?
THINK ABOUT WHERE YOU ARE--
SNOW WHITE'S COTTAGE.
YEAH?
THAT APPLE TREE
HAS PROBABLY GROWN
FROM THE PIPS OF THE APPLE
THAT POISONED HER.
AW! IS NOTHING SAFE
AROUND THIS CRAZY PLACE?
COME ALONG--
WE HAVE MUCH TO DO
IF WE'RE GOING TO KEEP
UP WITH THE MIRROR.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT THE HAIR;
I GOT THE DOG.
Tony:
BE CAREFUL... IT'S TRIPPING...
NO KIDDING.
"IT'S TRIPPING."
Tony:
YOU KNOW, I DIDN'T CURSE YOU.
OH, OH, OH!
I GOT A SCENT. Tony:
I'M SURE IT'S THE HUNTSMAN.
HE'S NEAR-- WE
MUST MOVE FASTER.
HELLO? I CAN'T GO
ANY FASTER.
VIRGINIA, THIS MAN
IS GOING TO CATCH US WITHIN AN HOUR...
ALL RIGHT!
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
I'LL HIDE YOU.
THIS HUNTSMAN
IS VERY GOOD
BUT HE FOLLOWS TRACKS.
HE CANNOT SMELL THINGS
LIKE AN ANIMAL.
I'LL LEAD HIM IN A BIG CIRCLE
AND THEN COME BACK
WHAT?
FOR YOU TOMORROW.
NOW, HURRY!
LET'S START WITH PRINCE.
OKAY.
THAT'S THE BEST I CAN DO.
ARE YOU OKAY?
( gasping ):
OH, OH, OKAY.
NOW, DON'T BREATHE, OKAY?
NOW, DON'T BREATHE AT ALL
UNTIL I RETURN, OKAY?
AH. OKAY, GOOD. OKAY.
( stifling sneeze )
( sneezes )
GO! GO! RUN!
RUN! RUN!
HURRY!
FOLLOW ME!
RUN! RUN!
( gasping )
VIRGINIA!
OW!
( whispering ):
VIRGINIA... VIRGINIA!
OW!
STOP IT! YOU'RE HURTING ME!
OW! LET GO!
LET GO OF ME RIGHT NOW!
OW... OW...
( yells )
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE'S GOT VIRGINIA--
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
NO!
YES!
WE'LL NEVER FIND HER!
WHAT?
OH, NO!
IT'S ALL MY FAULT!
OH, IT'S ALL MY FAULT!
OH, HO...
( howling )
( groans in pain )
SHH.
( Virginia screaming )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0