[SCREAMS]
[SHOUTS]
[CHATTERING]
[MEN LAUGHING]
MAN 1 :
Seventy, 71 --
-Come on, will you?
-Shut up.
You're making me lose the count.
Seventy-two.
Close enough. It's a hundred.
Let's go.
No, wait!
No!
Hey, hey, hey.
Alice, Alice, wake up. Hey.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Jesus.
[SCREAMING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[BAND PLAYING ELGAR'S
"POMP AND CIRCUMSTANCE NO. 1 "]
DAN: And as adults,
we must now prepare for a new life...
...outside this wonderful environment
known as Springwood High.
So let's blow this pop stand.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Alice. Yvonne.
Woo-hoo! Woo-hoo!
YVONNE: What's wrong with you?
Let's see a smile.
I had kind of a long night.
Dan keeping you up again?
Girl, you better put a lock on that window.
The Dan part was nice.
These things are wild.
What do you think?
-You look like a nun.
-Dying to break her vows.
Find me a man.
Fabulous.
-Maybe I should spell it out for you.
-Maybe God's trying to tell you something.
-When are you gonna run away with me?
GRETA: Next life.
-What's that?
-My undying love.
-Have some.
ALL: Ha, ha.
Mark, give it up. It's hopeless.
No, no.
I think I'm starting to wear her down.
Have a taste, anyway.
Greta, that's not what a cover girl
puts in her body.
-Shit.
-Mm. She read you.
MARK:
Ladies, ladies, where's the party tonight?
Why don't we go to Alice's?
No. My dad's got this thing
about drinking in the house.
-Well, we gotta do something.
-Listen, guys.
I got swimming practice
until 6:30 tomorrow.
-So?
-That means they're gonna give me the key.
So I can lock up after I'm done.
Pool party.
-All right.
MARK: I like that.
Oh, damn, I gotta work tonight.
GRAY:
Hey, Mark, picture time.
Come and get immortalized.
Parents and brats. Ha-ha-ha.
[MOCK LAUGHING]
Greta, photo opportunity, dear.
Damn, they caught me.
I have to go gnash my teeth
for the paparazzi.
You go on ahead.
I'll catch up with you later.
-Okay. See you.
-Okay.
-Bye.
MARK:
Okay.
GIRL:
Hi, Alice.
[GASPS]
-Hey, beautiful.
-Oh, Jesus, don't do that.
Sorry. I got a present for you.
-You got the tickets.
-Yeah.
They're coach seats,
but, uh, this plane stops in Paris.
-It's gonna be a great summer.
-Yeah, I know.
Hey. What's the matter?
Nothing. It's just I didn't see my dad
at the ceremony.
Well, he'll show up.
Hey, come on, what's really wrong?
I had one of those dreams last night.
-About him?
-Well, not exactly.
It's that--
I just felt like I wasn't in control.
For the first time since all that.
Look, if you don't dream him up,
he can't hurt you or us, remember?
-You're right.
-There you go.
-Love you.
-I love you.
Hey, Dan, Dan.
-Alice.
-Hi.
-You look sweet today.
ALICE: Thank you.
-Hi, darling.
-Hi.
Dan, this is Coach Ostrow.
He's interviewing next week.
Finest quarterback in the state.
You know what they say.
This boy feels the need for speed.
So I've heard.
Um, Dad, could, uh,
we get into this later?
I mean,
summer's just starting and I just--
Hey, Dan,
we're talking about your future here.
Excuse us, dear.
-Now, listen, come here.
-It's okay, Dan.
-Check it out.
-We take care of our boys.
We got the right cars....
WOMAN: Say cheese.
-Cheese.
WOMAN:
Another one. There you go.
-That's great.
-All right.
Congratulations, Alice.
You looked beautiful up there.
I'm so proud of you.
-Gee, thanks, Dad.
-You do look beautiful.
I was afraid you weren't coming.
I watched from behind the stands.
I didn't wanna embarrass you.
You know, "the drunk showed up."
That kind of thing.
That's in the past. Unless you've stopped
going to your meetings.
No. A deal's a deal.
Come on.
Where are we going?
Oh....
-To take a picture.
DENNIS: I don't take good pictures.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Uh....
-Call me when your, uh, shift ends, okay?
-Okay.
Goodbye, sir.
Don't worry.
I'll have her home by August.
Just kidding.
-See you later.
ALICE: Bye.
Thanks for everything, Dad.
-You sure you don't want a ride to work?
-No, it's just across the park.
Okay. Have fun tonight.
ALICE:
Okay.
GIRL:
Oh, sorry.
GIRLS [SINGING]:
Freddy's coming for you
Three, four, better lock your door
Five, six, grab your crucifix
Seven, eight, better stay up late
[GIRLS LAUGHING]
Come on. Run, let's go.
GIRL [SINGING]:
Seven, eight, better stay awake
Nine, ten, he's back again
ALICE:
Wait.
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
Let me go! Let me go!
-All right, now, hold her steady there.
-Calm down.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Just do exactly what I say.
No!
Help me.
Why is this happening again?
Oh, please don't let him do this.
[AMANDA SHOUTING]
Don't panic, Amanda.
We have a breech birth here.
It's backward.
-Aah!
-We're going to have to turn it around.
DOCTOR:
Take a deep breath.
I'm gonna need you to push. Now push.
Push. Push.
[SCREAMING]
Holy shit.
What is it?
[BABY CRYING]
Careful.
Sister, this is one of God's creatures.
Take solace in that.
That is no creature of God.
Stop it. Give it to me.
DOCTOR: Watch it.
-Don't let it get away.
[BABY FREDDY GROWLS]
No! Not again!
[SCREAMING]
[ALICE SCREAMING]
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
It's a boy.
You can't come back.
I locked the door on you.
-But I found the key.
-Aah!
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
Your birth was a curse
on the whole of humanity.
[HISSES]
I will not allow it to happen again.
You brought me back to give you life,
but now I must take yours.
We'll see, bitch.
We'll just see.
-I must be released from my earthly prison.
-How?
Look for me in the tower.
FREDDY:
You'll never find her.
-Alice.
-Anne.
Oh, God, I'm glad it's you.
It was terrible.
-What happened?
-I was in the dream.
And I don't know how,
but now he's back.
I thought you were dead.
You're four hours late.
Four hours?
I wish I had a prescription
for whatever it is you're on.
What?
Listen, thanks a lot, Alice, for nada.
Bombs away.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
All right.
What did your dad say
about you and Alice going to Europe?
Nothing. Just screamed a lot and tried
to convince me I'm throwing my life away.
-Who's throwing their life away?
-Dan, and he's taking Alice with him.
Pretty good dive, Yvonne.
You've been practicing.
That's right.
Two hours a day, six days a week.
GRETA:
Have another one. You need it.
No, I got a shift in a couple of hours.
Aren't you going in?
No, my mom's got this asshole jerk-off
photographer coming over to dinner...
...and I'm not supposed
to mess up my hair.
Hey, aren't you sick of your mom
trying to run your life?
-Yeah.
-Don't let them.
Sure, no problem.
You know, he's right. Sometimes
I feel like I'm living with Melicertes.
YVONNE & GRETA:
Who?
Melicertes.
He's this ancient guy I read about, right?
Who, like, killed his kids...
...because he didn't like the way
they were running the kingdom.
You're really weird, you know that?
[GRETA CHUCKLES]
Screw them.
Open the champagne. Let's have a party.
YVONNE & GRETA: All right.
-No, no, that's for Alice and me later.
Sorry.
-Are you okay?
-Oh, my God.
Oh, God, I could have gone all night
without looking at that.
I think it's very strange how
you draw all your comics...
-...loaded with blood and guts.
MARK: Ugh.
That freaks you out.
-Yeah, it's just a little blood, guy.
-I know what it is, you big, dumb jock.
BOY:
Yo, Dan.
Dan, telephone. Come on.
I'll be right back. Don't touch this, okay?
Okay, we'll guard it with our lives.
[ALL LAUGHING]
ALICE:
Dan, it was Krueger.
DAN: What?
-It happened while I was awake.
-Do you understand what I'm saying?
DAN: Wait a second, how could--?
He must have dreamt himself up.
I don't know.
Jesus, Dan, I'm scared.
DAN:
All right, stay right there.
-I'm on my way.
ALICE: Okay, I will.
-Just hurry, okay?
DAN: Okay, bye.
Shit.
YVONNE:
What happened? Somebody die?
-No, I gotta go.
-Alice beckons.
Hey, Romeo,
you forgot the secret ingredient.
There he goes,
the fastest man on three legs.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
--SK, the sounds of Springwood.
It's a beautiful evening here
in downtown Springwood...
...and we'll be back with the music
in just a moment.
Right now, we're open for your calls.
So go ahead, you're on the air.
MRS. JORDON: I'm calling about
my wayward ex-son Daniel...
...who's been acting
like an ungrateful dickweed...
...ever since he was seduced
by that bimbo slut whore Alice.
Mom?
FREDDY: If I were you, lady,
I'd kill the ungrateful piggy.
Put your pedal to the metal, Dan.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
[CAR HORNS HONKING]
Bad year, Dan.
[LAUGHING]
[FREDDY SHOUTING]
Better buckle up, dear.
[SCREAMING]
[PHONE RINGING]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[DAN SCREAMING]
FREDDY: Yee-haw!
-Aah!
This boy feels the need for speed.
Gotcha.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
Fuel injection.
[SCREAMING]
Power drive.
Fast lane.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
Hey, Danny, better not dream and drive.
MAN: Coffee, please?
ALICE: Yeah.
DAN:
Alice!
Dan!
[TRUCK HORN HONKING]
No!
He just came fucking flying
out of nowhere.
It was some kind of a frigging jet.
I didn't even see him.
FREDDY:
Hi, Alice.
You wanna make babies?
[LAUGHING]
Dan.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
You're all right.
It's okay, honey, I'm right here.
Alice, Dan's been in an accident.
It was no accident. It was Krueger.
He used to come in through my dreams
and not anymore.
He found some other way.
No, Alice, I'm sorry.
But it was no dream.
Dan's dead.
ALICE [SOBBING]:
No. Not Dan.
He got Dan.
Honey, I'm so sorry.
Daddy, it wasn't an accident.
Krueger killed Dan.
Calm down, take it easy.
You're in shock.
The police found fragments
of a champagne bottle.
Dan didn't drink. You know that.
I mean, it was probably for me
to celebrate our trip.
-I mean, we gotta do something.
YVONNE: Alice.
Dan's already dead, don't you see?
It's starting again.
These sorts of outbursts
aren't entirely uncommon.
Many women have them
at the beginning.
Especially if they have suffered
a traumatic shock.
Don't worry, young lady.
You're gonna be fine.
What do you mean?
What's he talking about?
What's wrong with me?
Nothing.
You're just a little pregnant.
The doctor wants to keep you overnight.
MOORE:
Just for routine observation...
...to make sure
you're as comfortable as possible.
DENNIS:
You're gonna be fine, honey.
Everything's gonna be okay.
-Hi.
-Hello.
-What's your name?
-Jacob.
Really? I've always loved that name.
Shouldn't you be in your room, Jacob?
It's lonely there.
-Well, my name is--
-I'm sorry your boyfriend got killed.
How did you know that?
I could tell you were sad.
I just wanted to see if you were all right.
Jacob, wait. Don't go.
MRS. GIBSON: Greta, dear,
it's time to get your beauty sleep.
We don't want circles
under those beautiful eyes.
GRETA:
Okay, okay.
ALICE: Have you visited
that little boy on my floor?
You know, Jacob?
He has kind of, um, sad eyes.
YVONNE:
There aren't any little boys on your floor.
Well, he must have wandered in
from the children's ward.
I was just wondering
what's wrong with him.
We don't have a children's ward.
Well, he was wearing a hospital robe.
I don't know what to tell you.
-Well, did you call everyone?
-Yup.
Listen, um, let's keep this dream stuff
between you and me, okay?
Amanda Krueger
was part of a religious order...
...that ran that asylum in the 1940s.
She was raped by lunatics
and had the baby there.
That baby grew up
to be Freddy Krueger...
...who murdered 20 or 30 kids
right here on Elm Street.
He got caught, but the courts
cut him loose on a technicality.
So the parents of the murdered kids
got together and killed him.
Torched him.
But that was just the beginning.
He keeps on killing.
But he kills people in their dreams,
their nightmares.
He uses my dreams
to bring him his victims.
It's my fault that Dan's dead.
Stop saying that. That's bullshit.
Let's talk about the baby.
Yeah, congratulations.
-I guess.
-That's not what we're here for.
Dan's parents
were really pushing him hard.
He was bitching about it at the party.
He was under a lot of pressure.
-We all are.
-Pushy parents can drive you nuts.
What does that have to do with it?
YVONNE: When Dan died,
you weren't even asleep.
You even said so. End of story.
He must have found some other way.
Listen to me.
This isn't some kind of joke.
He gets in through my dreams somehow.
And I thought I could control it,
but something's changed...
...and I don't know what he'll do next.
MARK:
Look, Alice, we all know you're upset.
The bottom line, Alice
if anybody's trying to hurt you...
...supernatural or not,
they're gonna have to go through us first.
All of us. Right?
That's what I'm afraid of.
[SOBBING]
[COUGHS THEN CLEARS THROAT]
How was the meeting?
-Sobering.
-Very funny.
-Alice--
-When did you become a smart shopper?
Ever since my little girl became a mom.
You disappointed in me?
No.
No, I'm not.
I sort of hope it's a boy.
It'd be nice to hear a boy
playing around in the house again.
Just don't make a habit of it.
[OPERA MUSIC PLAYING
ON SPEAKERS]
It's true. People are always
mistaking us for sisters. Ha, ha.
Greta certainly has the perfect body
for modeling.
-You know, Eileen Ford is a friend of mine.
-Ooh.
I told her about you.
She's very interested.
Greta, you're being offered
the opportunity of a lifetime.
I think you should show a little gratitude.
One of my friends
died yesterday, Mother.
Do you mind if I take a few hours off
to remember him?
But we're having a party, dear.
I read about him.
Drunk or something, wasn't he?
Oh, he was just a friend of Greta's.
Not someone special.
Not someone she was seeing.
You understand.
No thank you. I'm not hungry.
Aren't you eating?
GRETA:
I really don't feel up to it.
Really, dear, you ought to try something.
You're the one who's always
slapping my hand about my weight, Mother.
MRS. GIBSON:
That's why we diet, dear...
...so we can eat at social events
and not upset the other guests.
GRETA:
Tell you what.
Why don't I just eat
the whole goddamn tray...
...go throw up,
and come back for seconds, all right?
FREDDY:
Madame, if I may.
Bon appétit, bitch.
[GUESTS LAUGHING]
Mm. Fillet de Barbie. Ha, ha.
Nothing but the best for Greta.
Open wide.
Second helping.
Don't talk with your mouth full, dear.
You are what you eat.
[LAUGHING]
[GRETA GROANING THEN SCREAMING]
Oh, poor baby. There.
[COUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
Greta.
Dad.
Dad, help.
[COUGHING]
Greta?
DENNIS:
Honey? How's dinner coming?
YVONNE:
I can't believe this shit is happening.
ALICE:
Just hang in there, Yvonne.
YVONNE: Man, I know Mark
is gonna be wigging out.
ALICE:
We just gotta keep tight.
We'll get through, okay?
I know he's back here somewhere, girls.
I think he's pretty upset.
Mark.
ALICE:
Hey.
-Mark, are you okay?
-I'm fine, just aces.
I wanna talk to you guys about Greta.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry,
but Greta's dead today.
Perhaps we could, uh, interest you
in someone else.
-Look, it was an accident, just like Dan's.
-No accident.
I tried to warn all of you about Krueger.
-Alice, please.
-I thought about that.
She must have fallen asleep
while she was at the table.
-This is getting a little sick, guys.
-Too bad.
I don't understand what's happening.
Krueger has to use my dreams...
...but he got to Dan and Greta
while I was awake.
How's he doing it?
-Why don't you two stick to reality?
-Why don't you shut up and let her talk.
Two of us have died
in the past two days.
Does that strike you
as particularly normal?
-Mark--
-I'm not finished.
I loved Greta, a lot.
And if maybe, just maybe,
someone or something killed her...
... I'd like to hear about it.
-I'm not gonna listen to this anymore.
-Then get out.
Hey, come on.
Yvonne, wait a minute,
wait a minute. I'm sorry.
[SIGHS]
I'm an asshole, okay?
I know I'm not dealing with this
very well...
...but it's not your fault, and, uh....
I'm so sorry.
It's okay. Ha, ha.
You stick around for a while?
I wish I could, but, uh....
I got a shift tonight. I gotta get going.
I'll stay with you for a while,
if you want.
YVONNE: Bye, you guys.
-Yeah.
ALICE:
See you.
Do you think I'm an idiot
for being in love with her?
Nobody thinks that.
MARK: I mean, I know I didn't stand
a chance in hell, but--
ALICE:
She cared a lot about you.
MARK: Well, maybe it was her mother
who killed her...
...with all that Polly Perfect shit.
ALICE:
It wasn't her mother.
We have these scumbags here
on the hot seat tonight.
MARK: The Phantom Prowler wouldn't have
been afraid to tell her how he felt.
If I only had a 10th of his guts.
Jesus, he's not even real
and he's more of a human being than I am.
This guy isn't one
of your comic book characters, Mark.
He's not the Phantom Prowler.
He's for real.
Tell me more about this Krueger guy.
You look tired.
Why don't I make some coffee?
There's a lot to tell.
Mark?
Mark, no.
MARK:
Help!
-Mark?
MARK: Help!
Mark, take my hand. Take it.
[GRUNTS]
We gotta get out of here.
Mark, come on.
Aw. Oh, shit.
Jacob?
Oh, hello.
Hi.
You don't look very well.
Are you feeling all right?
Been having bad dreams.
Is this where you live, Jacob?
Just waiting for someone.
It's sad about Greta.
Is that who you're waiting for?
No.
ALICE: I don't think this is a very nice place
for you to be.
Maybe we should go look for your mom.
She doesn't want me around.
ALICE:
Oh, I'm sure that's not true.
I'll bet she's very worried about you.
-I would be.
-No, you're not.
You don't even care about being a mom.
How come you don't think about me?
-Who said I--? What?
-I like you.
I wanna stay with you.
How come you don't like me?
Who said I don't like you?
My friend with the funny hand.
Come on, honey.
We're gonna get out of here.
No, I have to go now. He's calling me.
Jacob, wait.
Jacob.
Holy shit.
He's really real, isn't he?
Are you okay?
He's doing something to my baby.
I know it.
He's trying to hurt Jacob.
-Who's Jacob?
-My baby.
What, you named him already?
Yeah. I guess so.
I gotta get away from here.
Someplace where Krueger can't find him.
Whoa.
Slow down.
Now, how you gonna hide
from a guy like that? Huh?
-Leave the planet?
-I don't know.
Look, if you're worried about your baby...
...call Yvonne
and have the doctor check him out.
I'm gonna go see
what else I can find out about Krueger.
-You had me scared. What's wrong?
-Krueger's trying to do something to him.
Alice. Honey, no. I love you, but you're
gonna have to get a hold of yourself.
Mark knows I'm not crazy.
Ask him to show you his hands.
I think you just need
to calm down, okay?
What I can't figure out
is how he's getting in when I'm awake.
Do unborn babies dream?
Yeah. They do.
But do us both a favor.
Don't mention any of this to Dr. Moore.
Alice.
I can't believe you had me drag Dr. Moore
down here on a Sunday morning for this.
ALICE:
I'm sorry, Yvonne.
YVONNE:
I thought it was something serious.
ALICE:
If this isn't serious, I don't know what is.
YVONNE: Don't dare say a word.
You're gonna get me fired.
ALICE:
Dr. Moore, do unborn babies dream?
MOORE: As the fetus develops,
it can spend up to 70 percent of its day...
...in a dream state.
More as it matures.
-Will I be able to sense them?
-Alice.
Is that why you're here?
To see if your baby's having nightmares?
We're here to find out
everything we can, aren't we?
Frankly, I have found nothing about you
that would indicate the necessity...
...of ultrasound
at this stage of your pregnancy.
I just wanna make sure
my baby's all right.
Well, the heart seems strong.
Let's hear it.
[HEART BEATING OVER MONITOR]
There's your baby
[CHUCKLES]
[MONITOR BUZZING]
Get her file.
FREDDY:
See any family resemblance? Ha-ha-ha.
Feeding time.
Soul food for my boy.
Don't touch him.
What's he doing to my baby?
MOORE:
Please, young lady, try to keep calm.
Your baby is perfectly healthy.
A little large for so early on,
but as normal as I've ever seen.
He's taking their souls, their spirits,
and making the baby like him.
YVONNE:
Look, sweetie, you're tired.
You'll feel better
after I take you home and rest, okay?
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Greta and Dan were there.
Krueger killed them.
Now, he was feeding them to Jacob.
Alice.
Alice, stop and listen to yourself.
Do you know what you sound like?
Completely insane, but I'm not.
And if you're my friend,
you would believe me a little.
I am your friend,
and I'm worried sick about you.
It's time to leave the Twilight Zone
and face reality.
-Krueger is reality.
-So is your baby.
-You got more to think about than yourself.
-What do you think I'm doing?
Look, whether you believe it or not,
Krueger is back.
He's after my baby, and if I don't try
to do something about it, who will?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
YVONNE: You're not doing yourself or your
baby any good by acting like a crazy woman.
Why don't you take off?
Leave Springwood. Cool off for a while.
Goddamn it,
you don't just run away from this guy.
He finds you in your dreams.
He found a lot of other people
before he found us.
-You too?
-He invited me to his house last night.
Look, we're all tired, and we haven't
had any sleep since Friday night.
-That's the only reason you're alive.
-No, it's not.
Yvonne, look through this stuff, will you?
She's not crazy.
You okay?
I know what's happening.
Krueger's using Jacob's dreams.
We gotta stop him.
Well, there is one way.
Have you thought
about not having the baby?
I mean, no baby, no baby's dreams.
No, I can't do that.
I saw him inside of me growing.
He's part of me and Dan.
I wanna keep him.
Okay, then we'll find another way.
I've seen her.
DENNIS:
Alice, can you come down a minute?
Oh, hi.
Alice.
Mr. Jordan and I wanted to see
how you're feeling.
Well, come sit down.
This really isn't a good time.
Maybe you could come back.
Frankly, we wondered
what you intend to do with your baby.
What I what?
Well, I've thought about it
and I plan to keep him.
We were concerned that all this
might be a little bit too much for you.
I mean, being single and everything.
What Mr. Jordan means
is that we're aware of the burden...
...that raising a child would place on you.
We want to help.
We want to adopt it
and to raise it as though it were our own.
Look, I appreciate
what you're offering, but, no.
He's my responsibility.
And ours.
It's our grandchild.
Doris,
maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
Look, Alice, we're worried
that in your present condition...
...that you don't have the ability
to take care of a child.
What are you talking about,
my condition?
We got a call from Dr. Moore.
He said that Alice was hysterical and that
she was having paranoid delusions.
You don't understand.
We know you've been through a lot...
...but there is more at stake here
than just your feelings.
You're not taking my baby.
-Well, the courts might not agree with you.
-But I do.
I've heard enough of this crap.
You think you can just walk into my house
and threaten my daughter?
Oh, please,
we have a legitimate claim to it.
He's not a thing.
He's part of me, and I'm not giving him
to you or anyone else.
They think I'm nuts.
That's their problem.
No, it's our problem, Mark.
If I don't deal with this,
they really might try to take Jacob.
-You said she committed suicide.
-Yeah, that's what the papers thought.
She spent the rest of her life
in the asylum.
After Krueger's trial, she flipped out,
and hung herself, so they thought.
-Meaning?
-Meaning they couldn't prove it.
No body.
But I've seen her grave.
Uh, empty plot.
A memorial stone.
Vacant. They never put her under.
Cool, huh?
I don't understand.
If she killed herself,
her soul is gonna be in torment.
Where'd you hear that?
Right here, somewhere.
Yeah. "Transmigration."
"Soul of the sinner."
Yeah, yeah.
"Trapped in its earthly resting place."
In the dream, she was trying to stop him.
She started to tell me how,
then the door slammed.
He must have done it.
We have to find where she died
to release her soul.
I want you to stay awake
and watch me, okay?
Hey, no problem.
Hey, you missed practice.
What happened?
Did you fall in love or something?
Don't ask.
You don't even wanna know.
Is the pool still open?
I think if you hurry.
Ah.
Amanda!
[SIGHS]
[SHOUTING]
[SCREAMING]
FREDDY:
Hey, Alice.
Let's rock 'n' roll.
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
[GRUNTING]
Where are you going, piglet? Ha, ha.
The party's just starting.
I know exactly what you're up to.
I thought I was up to, uh, Yvonne.
[SCREAMING]
Why don't you just shut up.
[SHOUTING]
What happened?
He's scared to come in
because of Amanda.
Hey, are you all right?
-Oh, God.
-Yeah.
You're not crazy.
We have to find Amanda. She's the key.
Come on. Come on.
MARK:
Jesus.
Alice!
[SHOUTS]
MARK:
No.
No. No.
[SCREAMING]
-No!
FREDDY: Ha-ha-ha.
-Mark, help me, please.
-Ha, ha.
-Greta?
-Is she delicious or am I crazy?
-You leave her alone.
-Try some.
[SHOUTS]
[WHIMPERS]
[SHOUTING]
Time to die, you scar-faced limp-dick.
[LAUGHING]
Faster than a bastard maniac.
More powerful than a loco madman.
It's Super Freddy.
Told you comic books was bad for you.
[SCREAMING]
[BOTH GRUNTING AND SHOUTING]
[FREDDY LAUGHING]
[GASPS]
Mark!
No!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Oh, God. Oh, shit.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER RADIO]
Damn it.
Nothing in that room was up to code.
It's a miracle they both weren't killed.
No, he won't hurt me. He needs me alive.
Who? What's she talking about?
No one, officer. She's just very upset.
OFFICER: Maybe both of you
should come down to the station.
Yvonne.
What's going on? Where's Mark?
Mark fell asleep.
Krueger got him.
No. God.
Hey, hey, come on.
I need you to be strong now.
Listen, we have to get to Krueger
before he gets to Jacob again.
YVONNE:
How do we stop him?
Through Amanda.
So we have to find her?
Yeah.
Just don't ask me to take a Jacuzzi
with that guy again.
You know, I was in the tower
when he used you to distract me.
DENNIS:
Alice.
What are we gonna do?
I want you to go to the asylum,
the one I told you about...
...where all of this started and find her.
Alice, Alice,
you're coming home with me.
No, Dad, I've got something to do.
-Alice, you're coming with me right now.
-Dad.
Find Amanda, and hurry.
ALICE:
Come on out, Krueger.
The game's over.
Okay.
I was stronger than you.
So you picked on Jacob, you bastard.
You're trying to make him like you
so you can live through his dreams.
Well, I won't let you.
You hear me, Krueger?
Okay, if you won't talk to me,
maybe you'd like to talk to Amanda!
[GROWLING]
Come on, you fucking coward.
[PEOPLE LAUGHING AND SHOUTING]
[ALICE SHOUTING]
[SCREAMING]
[FREDDY SCREAMING]
Good night, asshole.
[SCREAMING]
[JACOB LAUGHING]
I'm your real friend, Jacob.
Just like a daddy.
Cootchie-cootchie-coo!
-Cootchie-cootchie-coo! Ha, ha.
-Ha, ha.
I gotcha. I gotcha.
I gotcha, I gotcha....
-Mommy, meet my friend.
-Oh.
[CHUCKLES]
Nice try, Alice.
Thanks, babe.
It's my new look. Like it?
-Mommy.
-Come downstairs.
He won't hurt you. He needs us both.
I've got you both. Ha, ha.
Come on, Jacob, it's time to go home.
[GRUNTS]
ALICE:
Jacob, run!
[GRUNTING]
Come on, come on.
Come to Papa. Jacob.
DAN:
Jacob.
It's all right, son.
Dan?
Now, come with me.
Jacob, he's not your father!
[AS FREDDY]
Kids. Always a disappointment.
ALICE:
Okay.
Where is he?
Inside you, where he hides.
What do you mean?
Where he hides out. Inside.
-That's how he found me.
-But how?
He says it's easy
because he knows you so well.
All right, Krueger,
this time it's for keeps.
[SHOUTING]
[FREDDY SCREAMING]
FREDDY:
Come on, Alice.
Now we can really
get to know each other.
[ALICE SCREAMING]
[YVONNE SCREAMS]
Thank you.
ALICE:
Get out.
AMANDA:
Jacob.
Jacob, Alice will not triumph.
Only you can help her now.
JACOB:
Hey, leave her.
Let's go. I wanna learn stuff from you.
She's no fun anymore.
Teach me? Ha, ha.
AMANDA:
Now, Jacob.
Unleash the power he has given you.
School's out, Krueger.
[SCREAMING]
FREDDY:
No.
[SCREAMING]
AMANDA:
Stay back.
Take your baby and leave.
[SCREAMING]
FREDDY:
Let me out.
[BABBLING]
Hello.
Yeah, little sweetheart.
YVONNE: You did good work, Alice.
-So did Dan.
-Is he still keeping you up at night?
-Oh, it's okay.
[GRUNTS]
He has the rest of his life
to catch up on his sleep.
YVONNE:
Yeah.
ALICE:
Hi, honey.
Sweet dreams, Jacob Daniel.
Hey, cutie.
-How's my little grandson?
-Hey.
Look, look.
Are you hungry?
-We all are.
-Ha, ha.
Hey, sweetie.
[GIRL HUMMING "FREDDY"
NURSERY RHYME]
[English - US - SDH]