PORTIA:  An admissions
officer must have
a strong constitution
to be on the receiving end
of an entire nation's
application panic,
to endure
the frustration and anger
of all the so-called
millennial parents
who just realized...
Come on, hurry up!
PORTIA:  ...there isn't room
for every perfectly nurtured,
organically fed,
well-tutored offspring.
Okay, I'm your tour guide.
There's no point
trying to impress me.
I have absolutely
no power over
your fate here.
The people
with the power
are right in there.
The admissions officers.
And, no, that sign
is not an omen.
Except for some of you.
Almost all of you, actually.
We had 26,241
applications last year,
1,308 of those applicants
are attending school here.
(DOOR OPENS)
(ALL GASP)
James,
tours leave at 9:15.
It's 9:25.
Sorry. I thought I'd wait.
We had a, uh, late arrival.
I'm sorry. Our GPS lied.
No worries, Mrs. Lafont.
Welcome to Princeton.
So what's
the secret to getting in?
The secret...
Just be yourself.
If this is
the right place for you,
then this is
where you'll end up.
James?
Okay, let's go see Princeton!
We're going to play
a fun game.
It's called "Spot
the Nobel Prize Winner."
PORTIA:  What's
the secret to getting in?
There has to be one, right?
Well, there is,
but I can't tell you.
Not yet.
What I can tell you
is everyone
thinks we're sadists.
That we like saying no.
This is not true.
No.
Portia.
You're second reader
on my territory this season.
Yes, I know.
As are you. On mine.
That's the way it works.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, I'll just wait until
you catch up. With me.
(PHONE RINGING)
PORTIA:  We are
in this job
for one reason.
Hello?
JOHN:  Is this Portia Nathan?
PORTIA:  To say...
Yes?
Wow, I didn't
think I'd get you.
It's John Pressman
from The New Quest School
in Keene, New Hampshire.
Yeah.
I sent you a few e-mails,
and left a couple of messages.
Can you please
e-mail me
your information
and I will call you back?
Hey, not so rough.
How'd you like
to have your udder
yanked like that?
Sorry, I was just
talking to a student.
Uh.
CLARENCE: People!
Everyone, please.
I have a couple
of announcements.
There is an announcement.
Portia, we're a new
developmental school,
and we have
our first graduating
class this year.
I know you're gonna
be making your school visits
in the next few weeks.
Our kids would
gain a lot from it,
and I think you would, too.
Right,
I will look into it.
I got to go.
I went to Dartmouth,
same time as you...
Bye.
Thank you for calling.
So, we're breaking records
in application numbers,
naturally,
because we've been
number one for so long.
Number one until today.
Princeton
has just fallen
to number two.
What this means
is that we all have
to work harder than ever.
Because I want
to go out on top.
Yes, you see,
the rumors are true.
I have decided
to retire
and pass the baton
to a worthy successor.
I'm spending
an extra four days
in the Andover
Hotchkiss triangle.
And I've added
five full days
to the San Francisco
Bay Area
in Northern California.
And I've added
a number of new schools.
In fact, I was just talking
to the co-founder of Quest,
a developmental high school
with their first year
of college applicants.
Clarence,
we're going
to be back on top.
We're going to
make that happen
by working together.
Right, Portia?
Absolutely.
As a mother myself,
I know the importance
of teamwork.
And I'm not a mother,
but I know
the importance of it, too.
Can't go it alone.
CLARENCE: Good.
Because you two
are my superstars.
And nothing
would make me happier
than if one of you
were to have this
office next year.
(SNIPPING)
Okay.
Class of 2016.
Pediatric surgery
best combines
my love of children,
of science,
and my desire
to give back
to my community.
Yes, but you
didn't challenge
yourself academically.
B's in physics
and you didn't
take AP Chem.
Since 1841,
every male in my family
has attended the place.
Student body president
and gymnastics
national champion.
Educated family.
Privileged upbringing.
Unfair advantage?
Twenty-four hundred
on the SAT. 4.5 GPA.
And my poetry,
written in my
mother's psych ward,
will be published by Knopf.
And my father is Cuban.
And in a wheelchair.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hey, can I get
some advice?
No. Applicatus interruptus.
You know the rule.
Never start a folder
if you can't finish it.
(SIGHS)
I have to start
over anyway. Okay.
This kid from Alaska,
Aput Kunayak. Uh...
High grades,
but low scores.
President of 10 clubs,
but that might be
because of his ADD.
We want to accept people
who will succeed here.
I once fought
for a bipolar Inuit girl,
and she lasted 19 days.
Do you think he might fail?
Maybe. I like him.
It's so hard.
You have to toughen up
or you won't last here either.
Now outsies.
I'm swamped.
Portia?
I hope it's you.
Thank you.
Back to work.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR BELL RINGING)
RACHAEL: Portia?
Hello?
Portia? Portia. Portia.
I'm so sorry.
I've got an emergency.
Can you just
watch the kids
while I run to the vet?
Because Richard's at
his Faulkner seminar.
Me? Mark should
have been home
20 minutes ago.
And it's our poetry night.
And, really,
I'm the last person you want
watching your kids.
(KIDS CRYING)
Quiet.
Did someone die?
Rachael's dog's sick.
She begged me.
Good times.
(CHILDREN CRYING)
I've got essays to grade.
(CRYING STOPS)
Oh, it's okay.
Aw, it's okay. Mommy's here.
What did you do to them?
Rachael,
you know Portia's
not good with kids.
It's not her fault.
Kids just don't
take to some people.
I don't know
what you were thinking.
Sorry, he's right.
They're like pit bulls.
They can smell fear.
Good night.
Take them all.
"A man may do no
synne with his wyf,
"Ne hurte hymselven
with his owene knyf."
You know,
if I get Clarence's job,
this would
be my last travel season.
Lovely and wonderful.
And I've ordered everything,
you just have
to pick up the chicken.
And I will stop and get
the famous bean
salad on my way home.
(GRUFF VOICE)
Ah, the famous bean salad.
Is that horrible
Woolf woman
going to be there?
(NORMAL VOICE) Uh.
Helen is the preeminent
Virginia Woolf scholar.
It was quite a coup
to get her from Cambridge.
But I think
she has other plans.
Lovely and wonderful.
Oh, I like this life.
I do, I do.
Good. So do I.
It's so wonderfully simple.
Well, we're simple folk.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Woof.
Excuse me?
You just patted me
on the head like a dog.
Oh, did I?
(BOTH LAUGH)
Good, doggie.
"Whan that Aprille
with his shoures soote
"The droghte of Marche
hath perced to the roote."
Hi.
Thank you so much
for coming.
My pleasure.
We love
Deerfield students.
Oh, I'm so pleased.
Good.
So, can I help you
bring in your things?
Yes, please.
(VOCALIZING)
WOMAN: (IN VIDEO)
Princeton,
in the nation's service
and in the service
of all nations.
So, you all want to
know the secret formula
for getting in, right?
Take out your pens.
Write this down.
There is no secret formula.
GPS:  Left on Pony Run Drive.
PORTIA: But I will tell
you what not to do.
No champagne.
No baked goods.
And when you phone,
it is noted in your file.
So put the reins
on those eager
parents of yours.
We're looking for passion.
Whatever it's for,
doesn't matter.
Passion.
GPS:  Right on Shady Lane.
Does that mean
that every Princeton
undergraduate is a genius?
Or a prodigy?
Absolutely not.
Although, we certainly
wouldn't hold it against you.
Almost enough for everyone.
GPS:  Recalculating.
Recalculating.
Make a U-turn
as soon as possible.
(GRUNTS)
Hey.
Hi.
Portia Nathan.
Princeton admissions office.
I know. I'm John.
Yes. And you said
you went to Dartmouth?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, and my dad,
and his dad,
and his dad.
Um, a legacy.
A legacy of what,
I'm not really sure.
So, you're
chopping some wood here?
I'm showing them
how to build a sustainable
irrigation system.
This is
my Third World
Development class.
Well, nice ax.
Great ax.
So, let's get to it.
Yeah.
(VOCALIZING)
Hi, there.
You all want to know
the secret formula
for getting in, right?
Well, take out
your pens.
Take 'em out.
Yes?
I'll tell you
what I'd like to know.
Why should I apply
to an elitist institution
with a history
of anti-black, anti-gay,
and anti-female oppression?
Well, actually,
I reject that stereotype...
Speaking of rejection,
don't you reject
99.9% of your applicants?
Don't you just want
to drum up applications
to keep your
number-one position
on  U.S. News & World Report?
Actually,
I think it's number two
this year, right?
Yes, but...
Um, I'm sure
it's an aberration.
GIRL: Don't people
just need a college degree
if you want to pursue
the societally approved
definition of success?
Yeah.
Wouldn't you be better off
sitting
in your room
reading books
instead
of spending
all that money?
I'm sorry,
are you a senior?
No, I'm in sixth grade.
Yeah. Portia,
this is my son. Nelson.
I'm adopted.
I was born in Uganda.
I thought it would
be educational
for him to sit in on this.
How's it going so far?
You learning a lot?
Kind of.
Half and half.
Well, there you go.
Okay. Right.
Well, Nelson.
Sure, sitting in
a room and reading books
would be
very cost-effective,
but...
Princeton
is a corporation,
no different
than an oil company.
We should be
educating ourselves
to be citizens of the world
and not of some guarded,
suburban enclave!
What we want
is to leave the planet
better than we found it!
(APPLAUDING)
Okay. Well,
good luck with that.
Uh, wait, wait.
I wanna hear
about Princeton. Please.
Okay, fine.
But, first, I have
a question for all of you.
Just how will you
leave the planet better?
Will you eradicate disease?
You're gonna need
a medical degree.
If you want to create
new drug therapies,
that's a PhD.
Do you want to defend
the innocent
and secure justice for all?
I regret to inform you
that you will have
to go to law school.
There are plenty
of college graduates
out there
ardently hoping
to leave the world
better than they found it.
We are looking
for those people!
Students
with blazing minds
and hearts
who will change
the goddamn world!
(CLEARS THROAT)
(APPLAUDING)
All right, Portia.
Well done.
I bet you guys feel
like a bunch of assholes.
(LAUGHING)
Sorry, I probably
should have warned you.
We tend to encourage
that kind of spirited
debate here.
But you did well.
You can hit a curveball.
You know,
I'd really like to
introduce you to somebody.
This is Jeremiah Balakian.
He's a very special student.
My parents
work in a minimart.
They're not very educated.
Do you think
that matters or...
Of course not.
It's your application.
Maybe I should apply then.
Princeton seems
like a cool place.
It's very cool.
So you're saying
I should apply?
I'm not really
your typical student.
My brain sort of goes
on a little walkabout,
you know?
Yes, yes.
You should apply.
And if you
would like
to visit the campus,
we can match you
up with an undergrad
and you can spend
the night in his room.
Oh.
Then you could hang out
and get to know each other.
Um, I don't really hang
out with the applicants.
That's not how it works.
Right.
Because there's
over 20,000 of them.
Exactly.
Still, I think you
should get to know this one.
So, Portia, like
The Merchant of Venice?
Yes. My mother thought
if she named me that,
I would grow up to be wise.
Or Minerva. Or Sophie.
Except a lot
of people are named Sophie.
They probably
don't even know
what their name means.
Or if your name was Aushenaya,
or Ifiok or Saraswati.
I think you got lucky
if you had to be
called something
that stands for wisdom.
Well, thanks for this.
I have to go.
I have robotics class.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Interesting kid.
He's a great kid.
Yeah, he's become
like a part of my family.
I met him at a garage sale.
He was reading
a law encyclopedia.
We went and had coffee,
and talked for five hours.
He's a prodigy.
Well, be sure
to include all of that
in your recommendation.
Bye.
(CHUCKLING)
So, how long
have you been
at Princeton?
Since college.
Sixteen years.
Yeah? Wow.
That's a long time
to stay in one place.
Are you married?
No. But I live with someone.
Chair of
the English department.
You have kids?
Thousands.
Can you get these
cows out of the way?
Got it.
They're enormous.
That one's pregnant.
Where do you stay
while you're here?
My mom lives
about 10 miles away.
(MOOING)
(LOCK CLICKING)
Mom, it's me.
SUSANNAH: Who?
How many people
call you Mom?
Why didn't you tell
me you were coming?
I left a message.
I was visiting
a school nearby.
SUSANNAH: I never check
my messages.
Ah, it's a good policy.
Thought I'd spend the night
if it's all right with you.
I've got
to get up very early
and then hit a few schools
and race back
for Mark's department lunch.
How can you stand
those English
department gatherings?
What could be more dull?
Sometimes
you make sacrifices
for the person
you've been living
with for 10 years.
That's what a healthy
relationship is, Mom.
(CHUCKLES) Thank God
I'm not in one of those.
Yes. Thank God.
If I had to do what
I'm supposed to be doing
every minute of my life,
like you do,
I'd kill myself.
Did you just
say if you were me
you would kill yourself?
Portia,
don't exaggerate.
I'm working on my bike.
You know, they
actually have stores
where you can buy
bikes already made.
And did you know
that women
are the only exploited
group in history
to have been
idealized
into powerlessness?
Erica Jong.
Erica Jong, yeah.
(EXCITED) Hey, pups. Hey!
Oh. Hi, Gloria.
Hi, Betty. Hi!
You're so skinny.
Come on, let's get
you something to eat.
No, no!
They're not skinny.
They're lean.
Dogs are too
dependent on humans.
I'm not their slave.
They can get
their own damn food.
From where?
Outside.
Gophers, squirrels.
The neighbor's cat.
An unattended baby.
(CHUCKLING)
They're carnivores.
They're meant to be hunters.
Here, hand me that,
that chain break.
Mom, you look bigger.
These? Fake.
Fake?
You mean you
had a boob job?
No, no,
I had a mastectomy.
These are prosthetic.
I was wondering,
you know, women who
have really big breasts,
I thought, "I'd like
to see what that is like."
And I tell you,
they get so in the way,
it's unbelievable.
I'm thinking of trading
them in for a mid-size.
When? When did you
have a mastectomy?
I don't know.
Five weeks ago, or so.
Who keeps track?
They found a lump,
it was aggressive.
Hadn't spread yet.
I'm aggressive, too.
So I said, "What the hell?
Why push my luck?
Take 'em both."
Why didn't you tell me?
I am telling you.
Now.
I would have driven
you to the hospital.
Portia, I cabbed it.
I'm okay.
You know, I'm thinking,
you should start
calling me Susannah.
I think this could
help us avoid all this
mother-daughter
role-playing crap
that you
can't seem to shake.
You're welcome to stay,
but there's not
much for supper,
unless you want
to go pick some kale.
(CHUCKLING)
I'm remodeling
your old room.
I'm going
to go make
a tea kettle.
(TV PLAYING)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Portia Nathan.
John Pressman.
Look, I was wondering
if you wanted to
maybe get a drink
or a bite to eat
or something?
Maybe talk about
the application process
since we're new.
I could swing by
and pick you up.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
I guess I could eat.
The parents all think
their kids' acceptance
is the final referendum
on their parenting skills.
As far as I can tell,
parents exist just to
drive their kids insane.
Course,
what the hell
do I know, really?
Why, were you
raised by wolves?
Wolf. Singular.
One wolf.
And you never wanted kids?
Mmm.
I love that question.
Um.
It seemed unfair
to subject anyone
to the miserable
experience that I had.
Why would you?
There's no way in
hell I'd raise Nelson
the way I was raised.
Why not?
'Cause
I was raised by sheep.
(CHUCKLES)
So, Uganda.
Mmm-hmm.
I was working there.
Nelson's mom was a friend.
And she died in a car crash,
along with his uncle.
Nelson was two.
So you adopted him.
Seemed like
the only thing to do.
All my friends thought
for sure that I'd bail,
that I was not
ready to be a father,
but screw that.
Right. Screw that.
Nelson loves traveling.
He loves it.
We've lived in Indonesia,
we built a water
purification system
in Myanmar.
I'm sorry.
So, you're
just this single dad,
traveling
the world with his kid,
doing good?
When you put it like that
it just sounds so appealing.
(LAUGHING)
But I have that on
a T-shirt actually,
"Single dad,
traveling the world
with his kid, doing good."
You could borrow it
someday if you'd like.
I'm not sure people
would believe it on me.
Anyway,
it's the best thing
I ever did,
adopting a kid.
It's getting late.
Oh, no, I can't do that.
Actually, sorry.
I can't except gifts.
Excuse me.
Princeton wants to buy me
a chicken sandwich.
(LAUGHING)
(SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
(SWITCHES OFF RADIO)
PORTIA: Thank you so much.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Portia,
there's something
I want to ask you.
And I know this
is all a bit abrupt.
Yes?
Do you think you have room
for one more in your life?
One more what?
One more person.
Oh, John, that's so sweet.
But... You seem
like a great guy, too.
And you can handle an ax,
and you have a very
nice nose in your face,
but I have
a long-term boyfriend.
Long, long, long term.
And, you know, we are happy.
We're very happy.
We're so happy. It's...
Wow. Happy is one
of those words that
if you say it a lot,
it loses its meaning,
like fork.
Fork, fork, fork, fork.
Happy, happy, happy, happy.
Mmm-hmm.
Happy fork. It's not...
Portia, what
I mean... Look...
Goodbye. Thank you.
This was so much
better than kale.
Um.
Oh.
Okay. I'm sorry.
That's...
I was going for the cheek.
Yeah, that's okay.
Okay!
Well, nice catching up.
And best of luck
with the application
process. Here's my card.
I have your card.
I gave you my card?
Yeah.
That's great.
Then you have my card.
(MOANS SOFTLY)
(HONKING)
Oh, my God.
(CHUCKLES) Sorry.
It was there, you know?
You just...
What are you going to do?
Look, the reason that I'm...
Look, I'm an
admissions officer,
and you run a school,
and I live with someone
and I've had a really
long day and I'm
exhausted
and this never happened,
do you understand?
Portia... No.
Portia! Look, I asked
you here for a reason.
And it wasn't to kiss you.
Please communicate
with my associate,
Ben, in the future.
Portia, wait.
Wait. It's just...
I think...
I think maybe
Jeremiah's your son.
What?
Jeremiah.
I think
maybe he's your son.
Are you out
of your fucking mind?
All right,
you know what,
let me rewind.
At Dartmouth,
I was friends
with Shelley.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
And you need to leave. Now.
Portia. Wait.
(GUN SHOT FIRED)
Jesus!
She said leave her alone!
What the hell!
Mom, put the gun down!
No means no, asshole!
I have got
this under control!
Go inside.
You don't have shit
under control, Portia.
You never have.
Screw you, Mom!
I do so have my
life under control!
You could have been
somebody! God damn it.
You could have
been a trailblazer.
Right, like you?
Holed up here like
some crazy old witch?
You know what?
I'm just going to get
into my car, very slowly,
and let you two chat.
Portia, I'll call you?
Well, you're not very good
at returning e-mails.
Hmm.
You all right?
Fine. Watch where
you're waving that thing.
Your breasts
are sliding off.
(SIGHS)
PORTIA: Hi, everyone.
Just back from
a boring recruitment trip.
Uneventful.
There she is!
So, have you found
the finest young minds
in the nation for us?
I'm trying!
Of course she has,
she's our golden retriever!
I love this.
I love this bean salad.
Just beans and vinaigrette.
So simple, but it just works.
Yeah. Beans.
Oh, hello, Helen.
So glad you could
make it after all.
And I can guarantee,
personally, that next year,
all your
Virginia Woolf seminars
will be filled
with superhumans.
I'll never really understand
your admissions
system in America.
'Cause we just do tests.
We don't really care
about your childhood
or your recent
conversion to Buddhism.
Gray matter,
that's what counts.
Helen, would you mind
putting the bread
on the table?
Thank you so much.
I want you to know
that this, us, this life,
it's everything
that I've always wanted.
Helen, back so soon.
Could you put the salad on?
What's she got
against bean salad?
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Portia, we need to talk.
I can't do this anymore.
I'm sorry.
Oh, God. I hate
these lunches, too.
No. This. Us.
(HORN BLARES)
Is that Helen?
That's weird.
Portia,
I'm having twins.
What are you
talking about?
Twins.
Twins, I'm having twins.
Mark, you're talking
like a crazy person.
Helen is having twins.
My twins.
I'm leaving you.
I'm sorry. You had sex
with that woman?
You had unprotected sex
with that vile
Virginia Woolf scholar?
There's no need
to make a scene.
I am sorry.
You don't deserve this,
you don't.
You're loyal
and a good companion,
and...
Stop it with
the dog stuff!
...clean. What?
I have to go. Now.
No, no, you have to stay.
We have guests.
And we are a family unit.
You didn't want a family.
Neither did you!
No, that's true.
I really don't.
I can't stand babies.
They're repulsive.
(HONKING)
Oh, God,
she's backing out now.
(TIMER DINGS)
Oh, that's the chicken.
Would you mind terribly
taking it out? Goodbye.
I kissed someone!
Almost on purpose!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Mark had an emergency.
A student was
having a breakdown
about Robert Frost.
Two roads diverging in a wood,
and which to take.
So, who likes breasts?
Mark loves breasts.
The more the merrier!
In fact, why don't I
just put this aside
for him for when he gets home.
So, who likes legs?
Well, Mark likes legs.
(BOWL CLATTERS)
Who likes assholes?
I guess that's me.
Virginia Woolf was a twat.
Extremely overrated.
No Gertrude Stein.
I'll have a breast, please.
Oh, God,
damn it. Damn it.
Excuse me.
This is your mother?
Uh, yes.
I saw her lecture
on Frida Kahlo in 1977.
She was extremely hot.
Okay.
Is she well?
Your mother?
Yeah, she's fine.
Good.
Well, thank you for the party.
It was very pleasant.
(SIGHS)
Everyone is now leaving.
Okay. I shall
close this door behind?
Yes. I'll be right out.
(SIGHS)
(SOBBING)
Get to work.
I will always
be there for you.
Nothing will
ever change that.
(VOCALIZING)
(KNOCKING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Top of the morning,
Clarence!
Morning.
If you want to take
a couple of personal days...
Um...
Why would I?
Everyone knows?
About Mark, I mean.
Yes.
And that Woolf woman.
I'm very sorry about
the timing of this.
But I want you to know,
I am here for you 1,000%.
This is my life.
It's what I'm good at.
I know.
And, please,
rest assured, Clarence,
that nothing
will affect my work.
Nothing.
Well, that's great.
You just carry on.
(EXHALES)
Mmm.
And that was
the famous Blair Arch.
Here comes one
of our illustrious
admissions officers.
Clearly a very
busy time for you all.
Any words of wisdom
for hopefully
future Princetonians?
What?
Words of wisdom?
Oh.
Just get those
applications in,
and remember to be yourself,
'cause who else could you be,
that's who you're stuck with.
Okay, got the idea.
Let's keep moving.
Any budding
astrophysicists
in the crowd?
'Cause I've got
a treat for you next.
I'm Jeremiah, from Quest.
Hi. You remember me?
Yes, I remember you.
I'm Nelson.
I remember you, too.
I'm John.
Turns out we had
a chance to come
down here today,
to visit the campus.
What a surprise.
It's awesome.
It's like, ancient!
I'm sorry, but what...
What do you think
that you're doing here?
Jeremiah wanted
to see the place.
And you and I should talk.
You are out of your mind.
Almost forgot to ask.
Um, remember when you
said that I could spend
the night with an undergrad?
Is that still possible?
Okay. Yes.
That's possible.
Just catch up
with the tour and meet me
back at Admissions.
What are you doing?
You're not allowed in here!
Nothing happened
the other night.
Right, it was nothing,
so don't let it get
in the way of this.
This is Jeremiah's
birth certificate.
I knew Shelley,
your roommate
at Dartmouth.
She borrowed it to pick you
up after you had the baby.
Valentine's Day.
Shelley told me you
had the baby at 1:00 p.m.
on Valentine's Day.
That stuck with me.
I hate Valentine's Day.
It's a despicable holiday.
It sucks.
Here's the crazy part.
When Jeremiah
applied to Quest,
I saw this
and I put it together.
It says that he was born
and given up for adoption
Valentine's Day,
1995, at 1:00 p.m.
at Blaine Hospital.
I know you
didn't ask for this.
And I'm not trying
to ruin your life.
and I think he could use
a little more
connection in his life.
I didn't tell him anything.
It's your decision.
I'm just setting it up.
(SIGHS)
He has his parents.
He has you, right? Nelson?
Yeah, his parents
are great people.
But we're moving on.
Nelson and me.
Hey, maybe it
was meant to be.
And you don't
just barrel into other
people's lives like this.
This is bad form.
Bad form.
I am not some village
in need of a water system.
Hi.
John Pressman.
Quest School.
Oh, Clarence Hall,
Dean of Admissions.
Princeton.
It's quite
an operation
you have here.
Okay, well,
Mr. Pressman
was just leaving.
Right. Of course.
Hey, I heard about you guys
dropping to number two.
Sorry. But number
two is, you know...
That's good, too.
Here's the information
you wanted for your student,
the undergrad
he'll be spending
the night with.
Thank you.
And here is the information
you'll need on that student.
Ben, do you mind escorting
Mr. Pressman out?
And, Mr. Pressman,
in the future,
e-mail is the appropriate form
of communication.
JOHN: Right. Sorry.
Yeah, e-mail.
(LAUGHS) Will do.
All right. See ya.
You know, it's highly unusual,
it's actually unheard of,
for a school director
to be back here.
I know.
I think we should
hire a security guard
to keep the crazies out,
because it is
getting out of control.
Hmm.
(STUDENTS CLAMORING)
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
Yo, what's up?
I beg your pardon?
I'm looking for my roomie.
Can I help you?
Doing a great job.
STUDENT 1: So a zombie
will move and talk
as if it were awake
and genuinely aware
of its surroundings,
but its inner light is off.
JEREMIAH: Right,
and if it's logically
possible for
a creature to have
a brain just like yours
then consciousness
is not literally identical
to brain activity.
Exactly!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hi, you are not a student.
What? You trying to crash
or something here?
Yo, what's up?
I... Hi.
(STAMMERING)
Hi, everyone.
I'm from Admissions.
And we like to
come in and check on
our overnight
high school visitors.
So, Jeremiah,
are you warm enough?
Do you have
everything that you need?
Do you need
a Princeton sweatshirt?
Or did you remember
to bring your toothbrush?
I'm fine. Thanks.
Good. What is that?
It's diet soda.
Diet soda. Why diet?
I just like
the taste better.
So do I.
That's unbelievable.
I guess?
Just diet soda, no...
Yeah.
Great. Good.
Well, get back
to your zombie talk.
Okay. Thank you.
Dude, what
a cougar, huh?
(SOBBING)
What...
Hi.
You don't happen
to actually have
On me? No. No.
Why, you do need
a toothbrush?
Yeah.
Okay.
Soft bristles, right?
That's what kids,
teenagers, your age
are supposed to use, right?
Um, I think soft
might be more
for baby teeth.
I prefer to use just,
like, a medium.
Yep, don't listen to me.
You'd end up with
a mouth full of cavities.
Hey, how about this
rechargeable toothbrush?
That looks pretty cool.
Yeah, I don't think
I need that, as much
as I do appreciate
Thomas the Tank Engine.
I'm an idiot.
You just pick
what you need.
Just...
Okay, then.
Okay.
Well, I guess this is it.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
(RETCHING)
Portia?
Are you all right?
I'm fine. I'm great.
What are you doing here?
We're just
up the street.
HELEN: She said she's fine.
Have you been
drinking, Portia?
A little bit, you know me,
I'm a lightweight.
Where are your glasses?
Uh, I thought
I'd give contacts a try.
Well, all right.
Good to see you.
Oh, no.
Ugh.
That's harsh.
Yes. Yes it is.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Portia Nathan here.
Susannah here.
Your mother. Mom.
SUSANNAH:  Mark called.
I know he never liked me,
but he thought
you might be in need
of some comfort and guidance.
So, I think
this is all
a very good thing.
Getting left is
a good thing? Really?
I have to go.
Good. You're angry.
You need to express that.
Talk to me.
I'm here for you, sweetie.
Well, I actually
feel really sad and...
And that is exactly
why I knew that night on
the train 37 years ago,
the man reading
I'm OK, You're OK...
No, please,
not the train story.
I knew I needed his sperm,
but I did not need him.
Hey, watch yourself,
asshole!
Mom. Susannah.
I wanted a child,
but not some
moody relationship.
Sex with a stranger
on the New Jersey Transit
was the answer
to my problems.
It's not healthy to need
other people too much.
And now you need
to go out and fall
in love with yourself.
Well, I'm gonna
go do that.
Yup. Gonna go buy
a train ticket right now.
John, Portia again.
This is my eighth,
no, ninth message.
It's very important
that you not tell
Jeremiah a thing about
the thing,
the thing that
we were talking about.
Not a word.
Call me back.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
They hooked it up
'cause they didn't have
a shield on the horse.
But I wear it like a medal
'cause it tells
the world where I belong,
deep down in
the working class.
ALL: Yeah!
Hey, Princeton,
what are you doing?
Just observing the school
so that I can better
evaluate applicants.
Cool. I'm cutting class.
Cutting class
is never a good idea.
I hate geography class.
I hate maps.
You hate maps? Why?
Because you never know
where you'll end up on them.
Not with my dad.
Well, I'm sure your
dad has excellent reasons
for leading
a rootless
and impulsive life.
I'm sick of traveling.
I love playing bridge.
Besides, do they even
play bridge in Ecuador?
No idea.
How long have you
been at Princeton?
Sixteen years. But...
Wow. You totally rock!
Yeah? Thanks.
Why is that?
Because you're,
like, totally predictable.
So, can you tell me
where I could find your dad?
(COW MOOING)
I've been trying to reach you.
I left you a million messages!
Yeah, well,
sorry, I'm a little busy.
Cow's in labor.
I'd shake your hand,
but I...
Look, I never told a soul...
Stay back.
This cow doesn't know you.
Actually, I think we met
the last time I was here.
Do you even know
whether Jeremiah
wants to meet
his birth mother?
He wrote an essay
last year entitled,
"Nature versus Nurture,
"I wonder who
my birth parents are."
Portia, the wise!
Nelson told me you were here.
I just wanted
to thank you so much.
I had the best
night of my life.
There's nothing
I want more in life
than to go
to Princeton.
Nothing.
(COW BELLOWING)
Is something
wrong with that cow?
Where's the
goddamn vet! Ugh!
Well, I'm gonna
find my own way out.
Shit! This isn't right.
This isn't how it
looks on the Internet!
Okay, bye now.
Best of luck
with all that.
Come back.
Grab her head.
Calm her down.
You said stay back.
I changed my mind!
(COW BELLOWING)
She looks so mad.
Well, she's probably
protecting her young.
Hey there, little mama.
It's all gonna be okay.
Just focus on your breath.
Your terrible,
terrible breath.
Think how lucky
you are not to be on
a beef ranch right now.
I'm sorry.
That was inappropriate.
Where's the bull
that did this to you?
He's probably out
partying with his friends.
She's clamping again.
Jeremiah, get back here,
please. Fast!
You're not alone.
You're not alone,
okay, mama?
We're here with you.
You can do this.
'Cause it happens either way.
It happens either way.
All right, it's coming.
Portia, get back here now.
Horrible.
Grab a hoof.
Grab a hoof. All right.
On the count of three.
(CHOKES)
One.
(COW BELLOWING)
Two. Three. Pull!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
PORTIA: It's gross!
(PORTIA SCREAMS)
Boundaries!
Did you not see
my "Do not disturb" sign?
Yeah, I saw it,
but you're not the only one
who reeks of cow placenta.
Why do you have
"Do not disturb"
signs with you?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe for times like these?
Here, try this soap.
Look, he's a great kid,
and you're clearly
a great, mildly
compulsive, woman.
Take the leap!
I'm sorry,
who's mildly compulsive?
Why do you run around
fixing everyone else's life?
My life is fine,
thank you very much.
It's frigging great.
Ah, God,
the water just turned to ice!
Oh, oops, sorry.
Yeah, it's solar powered.
Bit finicky.
Jeremiah has to get
his application in pronto.
A unique talent that
demonstrates passion and
commitment would be good.
He has got to get
going on his essay.
And then you
have to prepare him
for an alumni interview.
You may have built schools
in third world countries,
and cleaned
contaminated water
from villages,
but you have never tried
to get a kid into Princeton.
Neither have you.
I am not trying!
I'm an admissions officer.
I am just helping you try.
As I would with any
outstanding student
who may have been overlooked.
There's nothing
improper going on here.
(SIGHS)
I'm going to exit
the shower stall now.
I'm going to remain
in the shower stall
for approximately 30 seconds.
Fantastic.
Hey.
Yes? How can I help you?
You think he has a shot?
Send me his transcripts.
JOHN: Nelson,
take a corner kick.
What was that?
Do it again.
I'm not good
at corner kicks.
Horse shit!
Put your heart into it!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
This is, without a doubt,
the worst transcript
I have ever seen!
D's and F's
in 9th, 10th
and 11th grade.
Suspensions, detentions,
a Special Ed class?
What the hell
were you thinking?
Did you read
the rest of it?
Why, am I missing
a police record?
Come on, man.
Quit half-assing it, huh?
You play like that,
those Ecuadorian kids
are gonna eat you up!
All right.
Jeremiah
got the top score
on eight
Advanced Placement tests
without ever taking
the Advanced
Placement courses.
And his SATs
are almost perfect.
God, did he...
Cheat? No.
He's brilliant. He's
the most brilliant student
I've come across.
Really?
Switch!
Regardless,
kids like Jeremiah
don't get into Princeton.
He is gonna be up against
kids that have
resumes 15-feet long.
So? Those kids are
so burnt out already,
all they want
to do is get stoned
and play Frisbee
for the rest of their lives.
Princeton would
be damn lucky
to have Jeremiah.
Hey,  fútbol, fútbol.
It's a world sport,
all right.
Did you get that
other thing I sent you?
In the box.
(SIGHS)
Very funny.
Look, he wants this.
He really wants this.
And I think
he would thrive there.
I can see it.
Look, I can't do anything
that could get
me into trouble.
But since you're
new to the process,
as a professional courtesy,
I can send you books,
resources,
everything that
one might need. Okay?
Great.
Goodbye.
What the hell was that?
I put my heart into it.
Fútbol.
I'll give you 10 bucks
if you can do it again.
They grow up so
damn fast, don't they?
Yeah.
Which one is yours?
With a megaphone.
Yeah. (SIGHS)
Right? Exactly.
Okay, okay, I heard you.
I heard you.
Let me.
It takes a village.
Get your hands
off my baby!
No, I was just helping.
What are you doing?
Everybody
needs a little help.
Get out.
I'm helping you.
WOMAN: Come on. Come on.
Right now.
I'm not...
I'm not a creep.
JEREMIAH:
When I was eight years old,
I realized my teachers
were not going
to be able to teach me.
So I became an autodidact.
I read everything.
mainly because
I didn't know how other
people lived their lives.
I learned several years ago
that I was adopted,
that my parents
tried so hard
to have on their own.
I think my voracious reading
came from a deep longing
for something
that was missing.
I was searching
for someone.
For my story.
(SIGHS)
To not feel so alone.
MARK: Portia?
(GROANS)
I knew you were taking
this all rather hard,
but I thought by now
you'd be back on your feet.
What?
It kills me.
It really kills me.
You'll get through this.
You think...
I know it seems impossible,
but you will.
No, this has
nothing to do with you.
(SHUSHING)
It's okay.
It's okay. I understand.
No, really.
(CYCLE BELL RINGING)
Oh, Christ!
I have to go.
Hang on in there!
Il Forno is one
of my favorite
restaurants, too.
That's amazing.
I know.
Hey.
Portia, sweetie,
you feeling all right?
Just terrific. Thanks.
Oh, good.
Then I think there
was an evaluation card
that was placed
on the wrong file.
A Jeremiah Balakian.
Balakian.
I think.
You didn't mean
to put "High Consider,"
did you?
Um, let me see.
No, that's right.
But he has
D's and F's
and suspensions.
But did you
notice that he also got
fives on all eight AP exams
without ever
taking any AP courses?
Yes. I'm going
to investigate that.
That's impossible.
No, apparently not,
if the child in question
is a unique, special child.
This isn't a child.
It's an applicant.
He's got no
extracurriculars at all.
The counselor
at his old high school
said he was shocked
Jeremiah was even
applying to college.
He's an autodidact.
He's an advanced reader
from the age of eight.
Leonardo da Vinci
was an autodidact.
So was Benjamin Franklin.
Oh, did this Balakian kid
discover electricity
or paint the  Mona Lisa?
I must have missed
that in his file.
He's a great kid.
CLARENCE: Portia, dear,
take a deep breath.
Teamwork, remember?
Of course.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
I forgot
you're in a
very fragile state.
Maybe you'd like
to step outside
and see how fragile I am.
Only kidding!
Only kidding.
Just a little levity
to enhance the teamwork.
Thank you for
your thoughts, Corinne.
(LAUGHS)
He's never getting in.
Never.
Calm down.
There's something
great I want to show you.
It turns out Jeremiah was
a state champion in...
You know what?
It's better if you
see it for yourself.
He's gonna be doing it
at Nelson's birthday party.
intellectual passion.
Everything
the books talk about.
Oh, State champion!
Thank God.
So, I'll send you
the address
to Nelson's birthday party.
It's at my parents' house.
I'll be there.
Good.
Is she coming to my party?
Mmm-hmm.
Why do you like
her so much?
I don't know.
She's weird.
She is indeed.
Doesn't matter anyway.
Right?
Sure it matters.
But about this
Spanish test.
This is your third
"try harder" in a row.
SeñorGarcia says you have
an aptitude for languages.
What if I don't?
What if I don't have
an aptitude for languages?
What if I'm not
a genius like Jeremiah?
I don't want you
to be a genius,
I'm not a genius,
but I want you to be able
to get by in the world.
Whatever.
En español.
Whatever! I have class.
Even Beckett emerged
from Gogol's  Overcoat.
Not to mention Pinter...
PORTIA: Professor Polokov.
Yes.
Portia Nathan.
Yes, the sad lady.
The sad lady?
That's not really
how I think of myself.
How is your mother?
She's fine.
So, I wonder,
would you consider
conducting some supplementary
admissions interviews?
A scholar
of your stature
would carry
a huge amount of weight
with the committee.
In fact, there is one
extremely unusual applicant
who's shown a strong interest
in literature and philosophy.
Why would I want to speak
with a high school student?
Of course, perhaps
we could make some
sort of arrangement.
SUSANNAH: I can't believe
you're pimping me.
I'm not pimping you.
He's a fan of your writing.
And I need him
to meet this applicant.
Besides, when's the last time
you went to a party?
With racist jockey
statues? Never.
Yeah, those are
pretty weird.
Hey, Portia!
Thanks for coming
to my party!
Hi, Nelson,
happy birthday!
Hey! I'm glad you
could make it.
So, this is
your parents' place?
Hmm. Yeah.
Well, my mom's now.
My dad passed
away a few months ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No.
It's nice to
see you again.
You're not packing heat
by any chance, are you?
Should I be?
No, we're all friendlies.
So, what is this?
That is a fossil
from the Jurassic era.
It's been in the same place
for 150 million years.
Oh, cool!
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
Mom, I would like
you to meet...
I'm Johnny's mother,
Mrs. Pressman.
Ah, no. No, we are friends.
Just friendly acquaintances.
Portia Nathan.
Of course.
What am I thinking?
He can't love anything
that's less than
a 10-hour flight from JFK.
Maybe we don't have to go.
Right, Grandma?
Nelson.
You're absolutely
right, Nelson.
There's nothing wrong
with staying in the same
place for a while.
Ask Portia. She's
been in the same
job for 16 years!
Yeah. And it's
a travesty, Nelson.
Portia was president
of her high school class.
Mom.
And she resigned
in protest over
funding
for the girls'
sports program.
She led
a school-wide walkout.
And the relevance
of all this is?
When you were nine months old,
you could walk.
She actually walked.
I don't mean
just stumble walking
like an infant or a toddler.
She walked with
absolute certainty.
One day I saw her tumble
over her shoelaces, John,
she did not cry,
she didn't fall down,
she sat down, carefully,
tied her shoelaces
in a double knot...
(LAUGHING)
...got up and kept going.
At nine months old.
There are a lot
of holes in that story.
You were fearless.
You were born an Amazon.
That's amazing.
I love it!
And what makes you think
she needs your approval?
Okay, that's
enough crazytown.
When Johnny got
admitted to Harvard Law...
Oh, God.
...he decided to go
and live in Outer
Mongolia instead.
Outer Mongolia?
You know what, Portia,
I'm with you,
enough crazytown.
Have another vat
of gin there, Mom.
Ms. Nathan,
Vladimir Polokov.
You are just as
beautiful today
as you were 30 years ago.
I just had a mastectomy.
I was just translated
into Finnish.
(CHUCKLING)
(SPEAKING FINNISH)
Brilliant.
May I get you
some iced tea?
Or something stronger,
perhaps?
Why not.
I'll stroll with you.
I'd love to.
It would be a pleasure.
It was a pleasure.
Your lawn jockeys
are just outstanding.
Aren't they fun?
And now, with a special
performance for Nelson
on his big day...
(WHOOPING)
(ALL APPLAUDING)
...performing
the act that won him
honorable mention
at the New Hampshire
state championships,
put your hands together,
(DRUMMING)
for Jeremiah Balakian!
I want to dedicate
this performance to Nelson.
Happy birthday, pal.
Honorable mention?
I thought you said he won.
He was robbed.
This is my other friend,
René Descartes.
Say, hello, René.
ALL: Hello, René.
How are you, René?
I think,
therefore I am.
(LAUGHING)
Did you say you're pink,
therefore you're ham?
Do you have any advice
for a young man, René?
Whatever you do,
don't put the horse
before Descartes.
(LAUGHING)
Hey, do you guys
want to see Descartes
philosophize backwards?
I think, therefore I am.
Oh, God.
That's terrible.
What was that?
Come on, that showed
originality, depth.
Are you kidding me?
Here, from the
Island of Misfit Toys,
we bring you
Jeremiah Balakian!
Are those birds?
Those are doves.
For the party?
No. You know,
my mom has a dove room.
Uh, by the way,
I know that wasn't
a perfect showcase,
but he can't pretend
to be somebody he's not.
Yes, he can.
You should try
it sometimes.
It's how humans behave
here on planet Earth!
I know how humans
behave on planet Earth
because I've actually
lived a few places
on planet Earth.
Wait! God.
Here, help me.
Aren't you ready yet?
I'm lighting them
as fast as I can!
Hurry up!
Do you like the cake?
It's very patriotic!
Nelson's idea.
Ow, how many frigging
candles are on this cake?
Oh, Fifty. You know,
it was my mom's idea.
Polokov was
looking at Jeremiah
like he had two heads!
Well, that's his
problem, isn't it?
Look, I want Jeremiah
to go to Princeton,
because he wants
and I actually think
he'd do great there,
but if he doesn't
get into Princeton,
well, that's fine, too,
because where
you went to school,
and what your background is,
that is just a box,
and I reject it.
I reject being put
into a box, okay?
Hi.
Hi, Mom.
How did it go?
It was good.
Mr. and Mrs. Balakian?
I'm Portia Nathan.
Oh.
I want to say
thank you so much
for everything
that you have
done for this boy.
You're wonderful people.
Uh, she's from Princeton.
Oh!
Well, you're welcome.
I love you.
Okay.
Uh, bye.
Portia.
(SCREAMS)
What are you doing here?
I want to come
live with you.
Why in God's name
would you want
to live with me?
Because you're a normal,
boring adult.
I bet you'd
take me
to Chuck E. Cheese!
What makes you
think I'm so boring?
You just are.
It's good!
At your age, you're
supposed to be boring!
I am the same age
as your dad.
JOHN:  Hello.
John, it's Portia.
I have Nelson.
You do?
He's fine.
He is?
Yes, he's fine.
Thank goodness.
Nelson, you know how much
I love this statue, right?
Yeah.
You rode a horse
three days through
Outer Mongolia
in the pouring rain,
living off of mare's
milk to bring it back.
That's right.
And I've dragged
it place to place,
across the world,
ever since I was 22.
That is nothing,
nothing compared
to how much I love you!
Please don't scare
me like that again.
Why? You do it
all the time.
Hide out in cars?
Run away!
And going across the world
and helping people
is not running away.
I know,
but why can't we ever
just do what I want?
Because you are a kid,
I'm an adult,
what I say
in this house goes!
(DOOR BANGS SHUT)
This parenthood thing.
Oh, it's a disaster.
So I hear.
I'm screwing it up.
Am I screwing it up?
You're asking me?
I don't know, it's just,
Nelson and I have
always traveled.
I wanted to give
him the kind of life
I didn't have as a kid.
I wanted to give
him the opposite
of what I had as a kid.
But, now, all of a sudden
he's turning into my mother.
He plays bridge.
He listens to Lite FM.
He asked for a blue
blazer with gold buttons
and anchors on
them for Christmas.
Does your mom
wear blue blazers?
No, that was my father.
How is it possible?
What am I doing wrong?
At least you're trying.
I mean, there's so many
different kinds of parents.
There's no one
best way to do it.
Or so I've gathered
with my vast experience
reading personal essays.
Speaking of which,
I have 15 essays
to get through tonight. So...
Right. Yeah.
Well, thank you
for bringing him back.
Of course.
So, you really are
leaving, aren't you?
Um, in a month and a half.
I thought...
Let's just
not think for a while.
Great.
(MELLOW SONG PLAYING)
NELSON: Hey, Portia?
Yes.
Are you going to be my mom?
What? No.
(SHUSHING)
I'm just messing with you.
Right.
Go back to sleep.
Guess you're not
so boring after all.
(BLOWING A RASPBERRY)
Good morning.
Hi.
Did you stay over?
Too long of
a drive back to campus?
I slept on the sofa.
Ah.
So did your mother.
We did not make it
all the way to the bedroom.
I didn't need to know that.
Interesting.
Unique, I would say.
Oh, really,
that's enough information.
The boy. Jeremiah.
Oh.
The ventriloquism,
weird. I liked it.
I will write
a recommendation.
Thank you!
Thank you, sad lady!
(WHISPERS) Mom?
Mom?
What are you doing here?
I wanted
to tell you
something.
I know, you slept with
that guy, didn't you?
I did.
Then we both got lucky.
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah. He's leaving.
It's okay. It's good.
It is good. You don't need
any commitments right now.
It's perfect.
No.
Honey, I'm exhausted.
That old Russian
guy, uh, gave
me a workout.
(CLATTERS)
Just take a nap.
Just for a bit.
Actually, I gotta
hit the road.
MAN: Next victim!
Good luck with
the fencing finals,
Sebastian.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
WOMAN:
Thank you so much.
Hi there!
Hi.
This is Jeremiah Balakian.
Good to meet you.
Are you Mr. Balakian?
No, his parents couldn't
make it, I'm his teacher.
Yeah, you look
like a teacher.
You might want
to tuck that in, son.
So, Jeremiah, why don't you
come in my torture chamber,
we'll have a chat
and you can tell me
I rowed crew, class of '81,
a lot's changed since then!
Hey! This kid,
he's terrific.
Yeah, great.
No, I mean,
he's authentic.
He doesn't want
to just go to Princeton
to meet future
business partners.
He loves learning
for the sake of learning.
That's what it's
about, isn't it?
(CHUCKLING)
Right.
Why don't you
go get yourself
a cup of coffee?
Yeah. Great. Thanks.
(WHISPERS) Prick.
Hmm.
Excuse me?
I just called you
a prick. I'm sorry.
Don't take it out on him.
That's my own thing.
That's not very nice.
I know.
So, Jeremiah,
tell me about yourself.
(MOUTHING)
Uh, myself, as in...
You mean in
relation to my soul?
Or do you
mean myself, like,
as a unified person, like,
the source of consciousness,
or do you mean myself, like...
Like as a narrative
center of gravity?
I'm not supposed
to discuss
alumni recommendations.
It was that bad?
Well, can we get him
a second alumni interview?
I'm afraid not.
Tomorrow,
the committee meetings
begin, and...
Look, I gotta go
home and get some sleep.
It's the last chance
I'm gonna have
for three weeks.
Your meetings
last three weeks?
I have to go.
Right.
Bye.
I have spoken
to the Judo Association,
and they have no record
of his national championship.
Thank you. Goodbye.
I just want
to say thank you.
I've tried to put on
a brave front about...
(MUMBLES)
I can't even say his name.
Mark.
Yes, him.
And honestly,
you're the only
person who's really been
so sensitive
to what
I'm going through,
and I appreciate it so much.
Men can be such pigs.
People are all pigs.
Uh, okay, yes.
I'm with you on that.
(SOBBING)
(GASPS)
Oh, no.
Oh!
Maybe we can
declare a truce,
because we women
have to stick together
in this man-eat-woman,
dog-eat-bitch world.
Sisterhood.
You are so right.
(LAUGHING)
Good.
Yeah.
Friends, today,
we begin the process of
choosing the most remarkable
freshman class
in Princeton history.
Here is
the order of territories
chosen randomly.
We begin with the West.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Corinne,
are you ready?
Yes.
Yulia Karasov.
Class rank two of 450,
magnet school in
a suburb of San Diego.
Her family
emigrated from Russia
10 years ago.
She's captain
of the cross-country team,
sports editor
of the school paper.
Math, 760.
Critical Reading, 710.
Writing, 740.
But the recs aren't special.
They admire her,
but they don't love her.
Show of hands for acceptance.
(CLARENCE CHUCKLING)
(SCREAMS)
Holy shit. That's the kid
that doesn't get in?
Sylvia Hadlock.
Applying from Los Angeles,
but she's originally
from our beautiful
state of New Jersey.
CORINNE: Wallace Thompson.
2100 combined SAT, class
treasurer, volunteers for...
(VOICES OVERLAPPING)
Alice Copley.
Her dream
is to be a prosecutor,
then serve on
the Supreme Court.
Alice's mother was murdered.
The murderer got
off on a technicality.
Alice would like to retry him
and put him away for life,
though she would
prefer the death penalty.
Excellent
extracurriculars.
2220 combined
SAT. 4.2 GPA.
I'm a little concerned
about a revenge fantasy
fuelling her academics.
Uh, Portia,
you were second reader.
I see you put "Maybe."
I might have
underestimated
her passion
upon first reading,
as we all sometimes do.
I think this girl's
self-knowledge
is impressive.
She's an excellent candidate.
CLARENCE: Vote.
Oh.
(LAUGHING)
Very good.
Dashiel Weld Broward,
fourth-generation legacy.
4.0.
Captain of his sailing club.
He led them to victory
three years in a row.
CORINNE: SATs?
Uh, 660, 710, 600.
He's just one of those kids
that doesn't test well.
But, oh,
can he read the wind.
So what you're
saying is that an unusual
candidate's strengths
in some areas
really do outweigh major,
and I mean major,
weakness elsewhere.
Yes.
Let's vote then.
For acceptance?
Aput Kunayak
from Nome, Alaska.
Managed to take
five AP classes
while working
on his father's reindeer farm
and starting and
running a shelter
for homeless sled dogs.
Had suffered from ADD,
but overcame it
to become a leader
in his high school.
He'd be
the first in his family
to attend college.
Now, Ben,
as you know,
we have room
for very few
of these iffy students.
But then again,
we have to make room
for the exceptional, right?
Let's vote.
Aput Kunayak.
Are you gonna
give me the file?
At last,
we come to the end,
the Northeast.
Portia, please begin.
(SIGHS) Thank you.
Richard Guinness,
Rye Country Day School,
state champion
in the 138-pound
wrestling class,
played Rolfe in
the school production
of  The Sound of Music.
Chess club,
makes an excellent soufflé.
Member of the team,
but not a leader.
Backbone
of the woodwinds section
was the highest praise he got.
He is the kind of student
you could always
call upon to help with
Martin Luther
King Day activities.
Who isn't?
That's 28 denies in a row.
Come on, Portia,
make us fall in love.
Okay, let's see.
Ah.
Jeremiah Balakian.
Jeremiah is our first
applicant from Quest,
a new school
in New Hampshire.
Developmental,
but academically rigorous.
Jeremiah is an only child.
Parents both
work at a Stop-N-Go.
Neither of them
attended college.
The first three years
of his high school life
were a disaster.
If you're wondering
why you are even
listening to this,
Jeremiah is also
a self-described autodidact
since the age of eight.
In fact, he is
the most well-read person
I have met.
Ever.
And why?
For his resume?
To impress someone?
For the sake of learning,
his passion for knowledge.
He had no plans
to attend college
until this past fall
when he switched to Quest
and came into contact
with teachers
who recognized his potential.
Last spring,
he took the SATs
and eight AP tests.
Wait, so he took
AP classes?
No AP classes,
no SAT prep courses.
But he got 5's
on all eight APs,
and 790,
780 and 790 on the SATs.
That's amazing.
I'm sorry,
what did you say?
That's amazing.
Amazing!
It's amazing.
Exactly.
Do you think he can handle
an intense academic community?
Thank you.
That's a great question.
The director
of his new school
says he is
"idiosyncratic, cerebral,
"a true original
whose abilities would lift
"the level of discourse
in any class he enrolled in."
You seem
passionate about him.
I am.
So what was his GPA,
I mean, before Quest?
D+, 1.5.
He was a lost kid,
and then he was found.
So, Corinne,
you were second reader,
I see you wrote "Deny."
Any second thoughts?
Well, he is like no
other applicant we
have ever considered.
His alumni interview
was not so great.
That guy sounded
like a jerk.
(LAUGHING)
And he has
a positive
recommendation from
no less of a scholar
than Vladimir Polokov.
Okay, maybe from
our perspective, he
could have done more,
made himself
more of a resume
and a paper trail,
but he took
himself from nowhere
to where he is today.
He educated himself,
purely by instinct,
not because he wants
to put away
his mother's killer.
He was as isolated
as someone in Nome, Alaska.
He was alone.
He was completely alone.
You know, and maybe
if his parents had been rich,
he would have
been exposed to more.
We have to make
room for these kids.
(SNIFFLING)
We have to make room
for kids like these.
Clarence, you told us
at the beginning of the year
to find that
undiscovered gem.
I found him.
CLARENCE:
Well, let's vote.
All in favor of admission?
He also received
an honorable mention
at the state
finals of ventriloquism.
We are in
the middle of a vote.
Brandt?
I'm sorry, Portia.
I just think
he's got a little
too much to overcome.
I mean,
the kid was
in Special Ed.
subconsciously identify
with applicants who
remind us of ourselves,
but, honey, no.
Okay, then. Deny.
Wait! Polokov
called him inspirational!
Portia,
please, sit down.
It's too risky.
He's just not
Princeton material.
I'm actually surprised
that you thought he was.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Tanisha Jones,
Brearley School, Manhattan.
GPA 4.3,
speaks semi-fluent Mandarin.
A CAPPELLA SINGERS:
Two, three, four.
(SCATTING)
(SINGING A CAPPELLA)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Portia Nathan.
BOB:  Hey. This is Bob
Barrow from Hotchkiss.
I wanted to talk to you
about one of our applicants.
All decisions
have been made.
Yes, but I wanted you
to know that
Jesse Bolton
is going to Yale.
Even though
he's a legacy, he is
definitely going to Yale.
Huh.
So, look, if you accepted him,
maybe that
place can go
to another
of our students.
Instead of Jesse
just rejecting Princeton.
Thank you for your call,
but all decisions
are absolutely final.
No changes can be made.
Uh, yes, but I...
(READING CARD ALOUD)
I'm sorry
you feel that way.
No, there isn't
an appeals process.
How wonderful
Elissa got so
many acceptances.
Harvard and Yale, too?
Listen, I'd love
to talk to you about
the financial aid
package we could offer.
No, seriously.
I'm so happy, too.
No, you rock. No.
Yes, I know he is a legacy.
And I certainly understand
why you would
never want to give
another penny to this
university ever again.
Wow. That is a new one.
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
Hey, I have somebody here
who wants to talk to you.
(CHUCKLES)
I got in.
Yes, I know.
This is the best
day of my life.
Best day of your life, huh?
Well, that's good.
Good. That's...
I'm very happy.
(JEREMIAH YELLS)
Look, we're having
a school dance here tonight.
I think you should
come and celebrate.
Oh, there you are.
Clarence wants to see you.
Yes, thank you.
I've been expecting that.
I have to go.
I'll call you later.
Have a seat, please.
So, I had a call.
Oh, yes?
From Richard Bolton,
class of '81.
Father of Jesse Bolton.
Do you recall
Jesse Bolton,
budding journalist,
writes for  The Boston Globe?
Is this coming back?
Mmm-hmm.
I remember Jesse Bolton.
We loved Jesse Bolton.
We accepted Jesse Bolton.
And yet...
Mmm.
So I asked
for the admit list.
Looked for Bolton, Jesse.
No Bolton, Jesse.
But I did find
Balakian, Jeremiah.
We sent Mr. Balakian
an offer of admission,
which he accepted.
The only thing is,
I don't remember
making him an
offer of admission.
But I do remember
your plea that we do so.
You have exposed
this office
and the university
to a completely
undeserved scandal.
If word of this
were ever to get out,
the damage would
be irreparable.
Well, I won't tell anyone.
That's right.
You won't.
What you will do
is submit your resignation
and take this week
to clear up your affairs,
and then I don't
ever want to see you
in this building again.
He's going to Yale.
Jesse Bolton.
The guidance
counselor called me.
We never had a shot at him.
Yale?
Well, that's
not the point.
I assume
you'll be standing
by the offer.
I don't see
how we can
rescind it without
the whole thing
blowing up in our faces.
The whole system
would be questioned.
We wouldn't want
that to happen.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCKING)
JOHN: Yeah?
Oh, hi.
Glad you're here.
I was just coming
down to the dance.
(LOCK CLICKS)
Um, you okay?
Yeah. Why?
You just...
You seem kind of intense.
I'm okay.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm great!
I'm supposed
to be chaperoning
this dance.
You're doing a great job.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
You can do this.
You having fun?
This is
the best day
of my life.
You have no idea
how happy that
makes me feel.
I want so much
for you to be happy,
and for you to have
all the things
that you want in life.
Thanks!
You know how
when you're swinging
on a rope swing
across a stream
and you're afraid to jump in,
and then you just do?
No. I'm kind
of afraid of heights.
Me, too.
You and I have
so much in common,
and it's not
as odd as it seems.
(CHUCKLING)
Jeremiah,
there's something
I want to tell you,
and it's going
to come as
quite a shock.
I am your mother.
What?
Your birth mother.
I've been trying to
figure out the best
time to tell you.
And I know.
I was speechless, too.
No, it's not that.
Uh.
It's just, you're not
my birth mother.
Yes. I am.
And I know this is
very sudden and...
No.
My birth mother
is named
Jeanie Shredder.
And she's a hairdresser
from Keene.
And I met her
and my half-sisters
a couple of months ago.
I put my name in at
the adoption agency,
and they contacted me.
No, no, Jeremiah.
You were born
on Valentine's Day
at 1:00 p.m.
at Blaine General to me.
No, I was born
at 11:00 p.m.
They said my mom tried
like hell to hold off
till the last hour
so I wouldn't have
some lame
Valentine's Day birthday.
It's a copy. See?
That's an 11
with one of the ones
missing.
It's faded.
You see?
I never told anybody,
because I didn't want
my parents to find out.
I was worried
that it would
hurt their feelings.
And I don't want
to hurt them 'cause
they're my parents.
Of course.
Uh.
This whole time,
you thought
you were my mother?
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't want
anything to get in
the way of you
getting into Princeton.
I'd have
to recuse
myself and...
So everything
you did was because
you thought I was your son?
No. I completely
believe in you!
I actually do.
But you were lying
to me the whole time.
I don't understand.
I can't tell
what's real.
I don't get it.
How'd it go?
11:00 p.m.,
not 1:00 p.m.
What?
Stay out of my life!
Or what's left of it!
JOHN: Hey!
Hold on!
Jeanie Shredder.
A hairdresser!
His mother is a hairdresser!
What? No. No, I read
the birth certificate.
A copy!
A faded copy.
Look.
What?
Eleven! That is supposed
to be an 11!
None of this was true.
This is all a stupid dream.
This is all in your head!
And I just jumped in
like a complete idiot.
I can fix this,
we'll contact
adoption services.
No! Do not fix anything!
I don't want
to ever see you again.
Go be a citizen of the planet.
I am so glad that you
are going to Ecuador!
Except for one thing.
What?
I feel sorry
for the Ecuadorians!
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Hi, come on in,
you can help me
grind sausage.
I've got something
to say, Susannah.
Having sex on a train
with a stranger
to get pregnant,
really not so great.
You didn't even ask his name.
So I will never
know who my father is.
Maybe he's in Paris.
Maybe he's in Hoboken.
Maybe he's President.
Obviously not that.
But I'll never know.
Because you forgot
one important thing
on your way
to self-empowerment.
Me.
Why didn't you
ask his name?
Why don't you
just shut up?
No, you shut up.
I got pregnant
and I had a kid
back in college
and I gave him
up for adoption.
I wasn't in the Netherlands,
I was living above
an auto repair shop.
Hiding from you.
'Cause I can't stand you.
And that's it.
That's all I have
to say. (SNIFFS)
Except, get some
goddamn dog food!
Wait, Portia! Portia!
Portia, don't leave.
Don't leave.
Portia, wait, wait.
I didn't ask the name
of the man on
the train because,
actually, I didn't have
a grand plan,
I made all that up.
(SOBBING)
It was all an accident.
A happy accident.
Because it led to you.
Baby, it led to you.
I wished so many times
that I could have
told you his name.
It's one
of the disappointments
of my life.
And I'm so sorry.
Please, come back in.
Mom, I have to go.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
Dad?
(SLOW SONG PLAYING)
(WHIRRING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(APPLAUDING)
Ah, my car!
(GLASS BREAKING)
PORTIA: Really?
Ow.
What happened?
Are you okay?
It's a slight fracture.
Fender bender.
It was dumb.
I'm sorry.
I mean about everything.
I was stupid and selfish.
A selfish asshole.
And I just wanted
to come here
and tell you
that I'm sorry.
Wait, um, how's Nelson?
Good. He's good.
How's his Spanish?
Terrible.
Is he ready for Ecuador?
You're not?
No, I passed on that job.
Nelson wanted to stay put,
and, you know,
I finally realized that
I want him to be happy.
So this decision right now,
I'm gonna let him make it.
Nelson really likes you.
(CHUCKLES)
Nelson likes me
because I'm so boring.
You're not boring.
I'm pretty boring.
I think you're exquisite.
You wanna go out sometime?
Yes.
I mean with me.
Oh, yes.
Good, I thought
it was important
to acknowledge
that it's maybe...
It's good to clarify.
I think so.
(LAUGHING)
Portia Nathan?
WOMAN: So, tell me
about yourself.
I worked in college
admissions for 16 years.
I used to spend
my days passing judgment
on young people who were
way more together
than I was at their age.
I'm figuring out
what I want to do next.
I've been living
at my mom's place
for the last two months.
I thought that
would drive me insane,
but actually we're
gonna be throwing
a graduation party
for a kid who
I thought was my son.
He's a great kid.
I killed my bonsai
tree by over trimming it.
I got pregnant in college.
And my boyfriend
had already dumped me
for someone else.
I didn't realize until
I was very far along.
And I didn't think
I could be a mother.
Ever.
Portia, did you mean it
when you said I could do this?
Yes, I meant it.
Thanks.
You're gonna do
great there.
My boy, if you are
truly outstanding,
you will probably be kicked
out of there after one term.
SUSANNAH: Cut it out, Vlad.
Excuse me.
Don't listen to him.
Have you decided
what your major is?
Philosophy...
Not philosophy,
women's studies.
You know,
that's enough philosophy.
to contact you?
How would you feel?
PORTIA:  I would feel nervous,
but lucky.
I would feel lucky.
I would
just be grateful
to get to know him.
I over watered it,
too, the bonsai,
I just drowned it.
It's okay.
Okay.
I can't promise anything.
But we'll contact you
if there's any news.
Okay.
JOHN: Hey.
Hey.
It's a thin envelope.
That doesn't mean anything.
Open it.
It says he's not ready
to meet me at this time.
Well, okay.
Well, then,
you're on the wait list.
That's not so bad.
No, it's not.
Hey, Portia,
everything okay?
Yes.
PORTIA:
What's the secret
to getting in?
I can't tell you.
You'll have to
find out for yourself.