(Whimsical score
playing)
- Hi.
- Here's a menu.
- Thank you.
I'll be right back
with you.
- Excuse me, miss.
- Yes?
I don't mean to bother you.
What?
I feel I know you
from somewhere.
Really?
Yeah, did you go to
San mateo high school?
- Yeah, how'd you know that?
- I went there too.
- So are you from here?
- Not really.
My mother lives up here
but I'm from San Francisco.
What about you?
San Jose.
I remember you now.
You were in
my English class.
- I was?
- Yeah, I sat two seats
behind you.
- You remember that far?
- Yeah.
So what do you do?
I'm a fashion model.
And a beautiful one too.
Thanks.
Well, it was nice
talking to you,
But I should
really get going.
I've got an audition
for a modeling job.
So it was good
talking to you.
Same here.
Nathalie.
Oh, hi again.
I was wondering if we
can keep in contact.
Sure.
Here's my card.
- Here's mine.
- Again.
Again, it was nice
talking to you.
- I'll see you later.
- Bye.
This morning flocks
of seagulls and crows
Were found dead
in downtown San Jose
And along highway 101.
The crows and seagulls
also caused an accident
On highway 101
near the 1st street exit.
Authorities are investigating
the cause of their death.
In other news today,
the population
Of polar bears
is declining rapidly
Due to the melting
of sea ice in the arctic.
As the sea ice melts,
the polar bears
Are forced to move
farther north.
Although some have survived,
many have died from starvation
Due to the difficulty of finding
enough food such as seals.
(Car alarm beeps)
What does it take
to win your business today?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, I'll give you that
and a 50% discount.
Can we close
the deal today?
Can I place
your order today?
Great, thanks.
We appreciate your business.
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, what's with
all the noise?
Caught the big fish.
Yeah?
How big was the sale?
$1 million.
- Awesome, man.
- Biggest sale of my career.
I'm proud of you.
(Cell phone ringing)
Nathalie?
Hey, Christine.
What's up?
I have great news for you.
Victoria's secret
wants you
To become their
cover girl model.
You're kidding.
No no,
it's the real deal.
That's great.
Yeah, of course I'll do it.
Thanks for getting
me the gig.
You are welcome.
You worked very hard.
So here's your chance
to impress them.
Congratulations again.
Okay, I'll talk to you soon.
Okay. All right.
Okay, I'll talk
to you later.
Thank you again.
All right.
Okay, bye, Christine.
Thanks.
Okay.
(Cell phone rings)
- Hello?
- Nathalie?
Who is this?
It's rod.
Oh, the guy
from the restaurant.
What's up?
Hey, it was nice running
into you at half moon bay.
Yeah, it was nice
meeting you.
So how's your day?
It's going well.
How's yours?
Great.
I made a big sale today.
Good.
Fantastic.
Thanks.
I closed a big job
offer today
With Victoria's secret,
Wow, congratulations.
I think you'll look great
in those lingerie.
Thanks.
So how about dinner
to celebrate your success?
- That was fast.
- I know a good vietnamese
restaurant.
Sounds delicious.
I'll see you then.
Yes.
Man, all air.
Whoo.
This heat's killing me.
I know, man.
What's with this weather?
A heat wave in winter?
I don't know.
Let's call it a day.
I met this girl nathalie
over the weekend.
Good for you.
Is she hot?
- Yeah. Fashion model.
- Lucky you, man.
Yeah, we're going out
this weekend.
Hope you score
with her, man.
Is that all you ever
think about... is sex?
Anyways, we're just
gonna go to lunch.
Just talk.
Get to know each other.
A day without sex
Is a day wasted, man.
I'll let you know
how it goes.
Anyways, I heard n.C.T.
Is going to be acquired
by oracle.
- Really?
I hope that's true, man.
- I know it's true.
You know, if that happens,
we'll all be millionaires.
Yeah.
There was a wildfire today
in the Santa Cruz mountains.
Dubbed the St. Martin
wildfire,
It has already burned through
30,000 acres of trees
And has destroyed
over 100 homes.
Currently there is 0%
containment of this fire.
However, firefighters
are hopeful
That within the coming days
the weather will become
more favorable
And help to extinguish
the St. Martin wildfire.
In other news, the first
green grand prix event
Was announced today
in San Francisco.
All cars for this racing
event will be powered
With hybrid or electric
technologies.
Parts of the streets
of San Francisco
Will be used
as the racing course
And the drivers will be
Hollywood celebrities.
(Doorbell rings)
Hi, my name
is Jerry Owens.
I'm from solar power
accessories.
We have
an appointment today.
Oh, yeah yeah.
Come on in.
Here's that estimate
I was telling you about.
Wow, $20,000 for
a 3 kilowatt solar panel?
Yes.
Where are you
gonna put it?
Come and I'll show you.
And that, sir,
is where we're going to
install your solar panel.
Okay.
Huh.
$20,000, huh?
Is there any way
we can lower the price?
For you, sir,
I'll knock off $1,000.
- $1,000, huh?
- Yeah.
- Okay, let's do it.
- All right.
Hi, nathalie.
Hi.
This is for you.
Thanks.
That's sweet.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
(No audible dialogue)
So why did you decide
to go into sales?
I like sales.
It fits my personality.
I started out
as a software engineer,
A b.S. In computer science.
Software development
was boring for me.
And I felt I was more of
a sales and marketing type.
So I switched to
a high-tech sales career.
That's interesting.
Some of my friends say
that my b.S. Degree
Stands for bullshit because
I was too much of a salesman
And not enough engineer.
Very funny.
I work at a start-up company
called n.C.T. Software.
Got the stock option.
Hopefully if the company
makes it big
By being bought out
or goes public,
I'll exercise
that stock option,
Cash out and walk away
with tons of cash.
My silicon valley dream.
I hope that happens
for you.
Thanks.
Tell me about modeling.
What do you like about it?
I love it.
It's fun and glamorous,
But hard work.
My mother
doesn't see that though.
She wants me to be
a real estate agent.
It's not for me though.
Do what you like, nathalie.
Follow your dream.
I have every intention.
So how come you never made
a pass at me in school?
I should have.
I was too shy.
Why don't you make
a pass at me now?
I thought I already had.
So what's your plan?
Family? Kids?
Whoa, now this is
getting serious.
I'm just curious.
I'd probably settle down
if I met the right lady.
- Hope you do.
- So do i.
So who's the right lady?
She's beautiful,
Kind, compassionate,
Honest and loyal.
- Is that all?
- Yup.
How about a nice figure?
Sexy?
That would certainly help.
What do you like
to do for fun?
Watch football,
especially the 49ers.
Also a part-time
eagles fan.
And a little exercise...
Tennis.
How about you?
I like to go to the movies.
And I like to hang around
with my best friends
And go dancing at the clubs...
Clubbing.
And I like to
spend time with Alex.
Alex?
He's really cute.
Who is Alex?
And I love him to death.
Come on, let me
see the picture.
Is he your boyfriend?
I can't wait
for you to meet him.
Come on, let me see it.
Come on,
let me see it.
All right.
Meet Alex.
You're right.
He is cute.
- So you're a cats lover.
- Yes.
If I could afford it,
I'd have at least 10 of them.
- Wow, a cat zoo?
- Yup.
You've got to be kidding.
Nope.
(Birds chirping)
Beautiful, kind,
Compassionate
and intelligent...
- I hope you find her.
- I will.
- That was fun.
- We should do it again.
I'd like to.
Good night.
See you next week.
Can't I come in?
Not on the first date.
I'm not that kind of girl.
Okay.
Good night.
- Hi, mom.
- Oh hi, honey.
- How are you?
- Oh, good.
I'm just fixing some lunch.
You want to stay?
I've actually
got to run soon.
But I needed to
pop in and see you.
I'm glad you did.
What's that smile
all about?
I don't know what
you're talking about, mom.
Oh, come on.
I see it all over your face.
Well, I did meet a guy.
You're kidding.
He is great, mom.
You know we went
to the same high school?
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
We had lunch over the weekend
and it was terrific, mom.
I mean, we hit it off
right away.
He's smart
and he's ambitious.
And he's interested
in what I have to say
Instead of trying to get
something from me.
So he's great.
Oh, that's fantastic.
Now what does he do
for a living?
He's a software salesman.
Oh listen, invite him
over for dinner.
I'd love to meet him.
Maybe in time, mom,
when we get better acquainted.
Well, I can understand that.
You know, look,
keep me...
You know, keep me informed
along the way.
- All right.
- How's modeling going?
It's great, mom.
I got a job with
Victoria's secret.
- (Gasps) No way!
- Yeah.
Are you serious?
Oh my gosh.
Oh, honey, you know
I've always been supportive
of your modeling career.
It's just such
a tough business to be in.
It is.
Thank you, mom.
I'm well on my way.
Well, listen.
If things don't work out,
It doesn't hurt to have
a secure financial husband
To support you.
Or, you know, a real estate
career to fall back on.
Okay, mom.
Thanks.
You told me about
a dozen times already.
You know I always
love your advice.
Actually, I've got
to get going.
I just wanted to drop by
and say hi to you
And to tell you
all about my new gig.
Well, does the gig
pay well?
- Yes, it does.
- Ooh, that's my girl.
(Cell phone ringing)
I need to get the phone.
Hello?
Hey, mai.
Yeah?
It's nathalie.
Oh, hi.
What are you doing?
What does it sound
like I'm doing?
Rick is here
in bed with me.
Sorry to interrupt.
Listen, do you want to go
on a double date with me?
I don't know.
Why?
I just met this guy rod
And he's terrific.
Sounds fun.
I'll let Rick know.
Great.
I'll set it up.
Want to go on
a double date with me?
Why not?
My friend nathalie
just met someone named rod.
You remember,
the fashion model?
Oh yeah.
With rod?
My buddy rod.
He was telling me
last week
He met a fashion model
named nathalie.
- Oh really?
- Yeah.
Man, this is gonna be fun.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Please help me give
a warm welcome
For our c.E.O.
Bill star.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have some great news.
Our board of directors has
agreed to the acquisition
Of n.C.T. Software
by oracle corporation
For $1 billion.
(Cheering)
A billion.
You guys...
You guys have worked hard
And you've all earned
your stock option.
Congratulations.
You you you you and you.
So I guess the meeting's
adjourned.
Congratulations.
Good work.
You bet.
- Congratulations.
- Way to go, bill.
The negotiating man.
Oh yeah!
- Thank you so much.
- What are you getting
with your money?
(Overlapping conversations)
So now you've got
a big payday with your
big stock option, huh?
Yeah, I earned it.
All those big deals
I did with n.C.T.
And millions of dollars
in revenue and sales.
Well, you've done
a great job, rod.
And we appreciate
your contribution.
Thank you.
(Laughing)
You like it?
I'm gonna get the real
Ferrari spider f430 soon.
So what are you gonna do
with your newfound wealth?
I think I'm going on break.
Early retirement.
No car?
Well, with that new
fashion model chick
You might want to impress
her with a Ferrari.
I don't think
she's materialistic.
When are you
gonna grow up, man?
Chicks love cars.
If you want to get
into their pants,
You'd better have
a nice hot Ferrari.
She's my hot Ferrari.
Besides, I love my mustang,
which is a plug-in hybrid.
It gets 100mpg.
Anyways,
I'm thinking about
Opening up a green
tech company.
Really?
Oh, by the way,
I know your
girlfriend nathalie.
She's my girlfriend's
best friend.
- Huh, small world.
- Yeah.
And they're planning on setting
us up for a double date.
- It's gonna be fun.
- Yeah.
(Chatting quietly)
Man, that was a good movie...
"an inconvenient truth."
That is it.
I'm getting myself a car
that's environmentally friendly.
- Yeah.
- Good, you're finally
listening to me.
That's right.
Hey, mai and I got
to get back to work.
So, uh...
Just trot off.
Work?
Yeah, you know,
sensual work.
Oh, I see.
Understood.
Well, you guys have
a good time.
Yeah, all right.
With mass solar's nano-based
solar panels,
They cost the manufacturer
for one watt of electricity 10¢.
That's a fraction
of the cost
Of a recurring silicon-based
solar panel
Which is $4 per watt.
So a 3-kilowatt
mass solar nano-based
Solar-powered system
would probably cost around
$300-$500.
At this price everyone
can afford solar power
For their home
or businesses.
With these panels,
Solar power will be
available and affordable
for everyone.
No need for leasing
or financing
An expensive $20,000
silicon-based solar panel.
Is there a patent?
Yes, mass solar
owns the patent to
this technology.
Good.
Who are your competitors?
Companies like sun power,
silicon valley solar.
But these companies'
solar panels
Are based on
silicon technology,
Which is very expensive
to manufacture.
That's why
it's for $4 per watt.
On the other hand,
mass solar's manufacturing
process
Is simple,
it's low cost
And it uses nanotechnology.
That's why we're able to
deliver 10¢ per watt.
So how much funding
are you requesting?
$10 million.
Guys, this is revolutionary
green tech.
Contingent upon agreement
on our terms sheets,
- we're going to fund you.
- Awesome.
- Oh, lovers on the moon.
- Yeah.
(No audible dialogue)
Oh, look how cute.
The sea is so beautiful.
Yes, it is.
You know, all life
came from the sea.
I mean, look at us.
We're made of water.
So...
So what is
your ideal man?
Well, for one thing,
He has to have a lot of
stock options invested.
(Chuckles)
At least you're honest.
He has to be kind,
honest,
Successful,
ambitious,
And opportunistic.
- Is that all?
- Yup.
So do you have, like,
a backup plan,
You know, if your modeling
career doesn't work out?
Not really.
I figure if I don't make
it big by the time I'm 30,
I figure I'll just
take it from there.
You should have
a plan b now.
I always do.
I mean, look at me.
I started out as
a software engineer
And ended up a salesman.
You sound like my mother.
(Laughs)
Good advice though.
Who knows? Maybe I will
consider a career
in real estate,
Or even becoming a wife
Of a successful
entrepreneur.
Look at these birds.
Stop, don't touch it.
It may be infectious.
(Weeps, sniffles)
(Doorbell rings)
- Oh hi.
- Hi, mom.
- How are you?
- Good good.
- This is rod.
- Hi, rod.
- So nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
Come on in, you guys.
Good to see you, honey.
Come on in.
Rod, nat tells me
That you are a very
successful salesman.
She did, huh?
I am very passionate
about my career.
So nathalie tells me
you recently retired.
Yes, I did.
And she mentioned that you were
gonna take an early retirement.
Yeah, a few months.
Just taking a little break.
So are you enjoying
your retirement?
I love the retirement.
I was a jeweler
for 30 years.
And sometimes I miss not
going into the jewelry store,
But, you know,
I really like retirement.
I like to travel.
I like to cruise.
And I enjoy
watching television.
And my biggest thing
Is I love to watch nat
And work with her
in her modeling career.
Wow, nathalie's
a lucky person to have
such a loving mother.
Oh, thanks, rod.
I appreciate that.
My big thing is to make sure
that she's happy
And successful in whatever
she chooses to do.
Thanks, mom.
Hello.
Here's your drinks.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Can I get you
anything else?
We're still
looking at the menu.
Thank you.
- Hope you enjoy.
- Thanks.
I really enjoyed
meeting your mother.
She seemed
to really like you.
I was so lonely
until now.
So do you think
I'm that right lady?
Maybe.
Do you think
I'm the ideal man?
Perhaps.
You know, rod,
I was just kidding
About the stock options,
Shopping and money
and all that.
All I want is you.
Are you sure?
Definitely.
Guys are usually just
into me for my looks
and sex.
But you're not
like that.
You're a real gentleman.
I feel like you
really respect me.
That means a lot to me.
I feel like I could be
with you for a long time.
Then I'm one lucky man.
I think my luck has changed
since I met you.
Really?
Why's that?
Last week the company n.C.T.
Software that I work for
Was bought for $1 billion
by oracle corporation.
And this week my start-up
company that I founded,
Mass solar,
got funded $10 million
By evergreen capital.
Wow.
You said that might happen.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
* that's a long time
* don't you owe me
some money? *
* I think somebody's calling me,
I've got to go... *
(Laughs)
* just hanging out,
hanging out *
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves a party
* just hanging out,
hanging out *
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves a party
* a cool summer breeze
* making me feel at ease
* the barbecue is broiling
* and Uncle Phil
is scoring *
* big mama's
in the kitchen *
* and everybody's wishing
* that she's fixing
* they're favorite dish
* just hanging out,
hanging out *
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves
a party *
* just hanging out,
hanging out *
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves
a party *
* just hanging out,
hanging out *
* just hanging out
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves
a party *
* we're just hanging out,
hanging out *
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves
a party *
* young ladies are doing
their makeup *
* and the brothers
can't wait to hook up *
* Jill Scott
is on the radio *
* and I hear somebody
say hello *
* so Thelma starts
to dancing *
* and grandma
starts to prancing *
* to make sure
that the fellas *
* don't try any glancing
* just hanging out,
hanging out *
* hanging out
with my family *
* having ourselves
a party *
* just hanging out,
hanging out... *
You are forever
beautiful.
Thank you.
So?
What do you think?
You look divine.
(Birds screeching)
(Bird roaring)
Rod.
What is it?
I think they're eagles.
What in the world?
Battery is dead.
What's going on?
Can they get in?
Not for the moment.
(Screeching)
(Thumps)
(Thumping)
Rod, they're breaking in
through the window.
Hurry, let's barricade it
with the bed.
Hurry!
That should hold 'em.
(Screeching stops)
I think they're gone.
Well, do you know
why they stopped?
I don't know.
Maybe they got tired.
Why would birds do
something like that?
I mean, why would
they just attack?
I don't know.
Anybody in here?
Come on.
- Name's rod.
- Ramsey.
- This is nathalie.
- Nice to meet you.
- My girlfriend Becky.
- Hi.
- You guys okay?
- Yeah, we're all right.
- I guess.
- Man, those birds were
attacking all night
Then they just
suddenly stopped.
We'd try to drive away but
I can't find my car keys.
- I lost them somewhere.
- They were attacking us too.
We have a van outside.
- You guys are more
than welcome to come.
- Yeah, come with us.
Thank you.
We need something
to protect ourselves.
Use these.
Here you go.
All right.
Let's all get our backs
to each other.
That we can see the birds
coming from every direction.
- Okay.
- Just like this.
- (Exhales)
- All right, ready?
- Rod: Let's go.
- Let's go.
Here they come!
(Screeching)
Open the door.
Becky:
The door's stuck.
Hurry up.
I can't hurry up.
Damn birds
scratched me.
Becky, hand me a gun.
Rod, drive.
(Gunfire)
Here, rod.
Take a pistol.
Let's go.
(Gunfire)
Hey, there's dead people
on the side of the road.
Let's go see
if there's any survivors.
Okay.
Becky, cover us.
I'll check out this car,
you check out the other.
Okay.
They're dead.
(Girl crying)
Come on, honey.
Come over here.
Come out from under the car.
Come on.
No, I don't want to come out.
The birds will bite me.
No they won't.
Come on.
I'll protect you,
I promise.
I'm scared.
They killed my mommy.
(Crying)
(Birds screeching)
- It's the birds!
- (Gunfire)
Boy:
Help!
Let me out!
- Help!
- Run for it.
Let's go.
Help!
Come on,
let's go.
Come on.
- (Gunfire)
- Come on!
- Let's go.
- Come on.
(Gunfire)
What's your name,
sweetie?
Susan.
We're gonna make this
feel all better.
Thank you.
Thanks.
- Oh, you want to play?
- Okay.
I'm hungry.
I've been under the car
for a long time.
Yeah, me too.
I'm starving.
Hey, the kids
are getting hungry.
We should stop and get
some food for them.
And some for us too.
There's a convenience store
close by.
We'll stop there.
Becky, watch Tony while
he sleeps, okay?
I'll stand guard.
You go get food and water.
Okay.
You want to get
some candy?
Okay.
- Get some for Tony too.
- Okay.
(Birds screeching)
Let's go, guys.
The eagles are coming.
Come on, guys.
Let's go.
The eagles are attacking.
Come on, let's go.
(Gunfire)
Hey, look.
There's an old guy
on the bridge.
Hey, mister.
What the hell are you
doing out here?
Hey hey!
Stand back!
These birds are contagious.
Now go away.
Hey, I thought I told
you to stand back.
These birds are
contaminated.
They have bird flu virus.
Now go away.
Could we just talk about it
at the picnic area?
You want to talk?
Okay.
All right.
We'll talk.
(Kids laughing)
Guys, this is
Dr. Jones.
How do you do?
- Hi.
Sir, don't you know
that these birds are
attacking people?
- These birds?
- Yes.
No way.
They're dead from
the bird flu virus.
- Bird flu virus?
- How do you know this?
I just tested their blood.
Then why are they
attacking us?
I don't know.
But what I do know
is global warming is
causing viral diseases
Such as bird flu,
west nile virus and SARS.
So what are you saying?
That global warming is causing
these birds to attack?
No.
I'm a scientist...
An ornithologist.
I can't state any scientific
fact without evidence.
But there is scientific
evidence to show
That because of our
burning of fossil fuels
And creating
greenhouse gasses
Which is causing
global warming,
It's raising the temperature
of the seas
And species like
the krill are dying.
So many bird species
can't find food
Like the neritic
krill.
They eventually
starve and die,
Wash up on the shore.
There's also evidence
that global warming
Is interrupting the birth,
mating and migration cycles
Of many species.
In fact,
in the last few years
40 species have become extinct
because of global warming.
However, there is
interesting research
That in prehistoric times
Birds did attack cavemen.
They used to claw
at their eyes and skull.
They'd either leave them
for dead or then come back
Because their injuries
were so bad
And finally
finish off the kill.
If they attack me,
I've got a little
present for them.
Well, you certainly know
a lot about birds.
Well, I should.
I'm an ornithologist.
I study and work with birds
for a living.
You should come with us.
It's safer.
I don't need protection.
I can take care of myself.
I've got my truck
and my trailer.
Besides, I'm not worried
about the blackbirds.
They're not
the dangerous animal.
It's the human species
that's the dangerous
And menacing
and terrifying animal.
Because of his fossil fuel
related activities,
He's causing global warming.
It's killing life
and earth itself.
It's the human species
That needs to quit playing
cowboy with nature.
We must act
more like astronauts,
Spacemen taking care of
our spaceship earth.
Well, nice meeting you.
Good luck.
Where's Becky?
She's taking a shit.
Nathalie's watching her back.
You're pretty
good at shooting.
How come you're still
not in the marines?
I just got tired of all
the fucking killing in Iraq.
Why can't we just give
peace a chance?
Right there.
- I'll cover you.
- Okay.
- (Screeches)
- (Screams)
(Gunshots)
Oh my God,
she's dead.
Rod!
Ramsey!
She's dead.
I couldn't do anything.
What do you mean
she's dead?
- (Birds screeching)
- Let's go!
(Gunfire)
Come on,
let's go!
The eagles killed Becky.
Fucking killed Becky.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Ramsey.
They got to her before
I got a chance.
I don't know what to do.
Hey, those people
on that bus are being
attacked by those birds.
- (Screeching)
- (People screaming)
- Let's go save them.
- We can't. We have no room.
- It's full in here.
- They killed Becky.
What if it was nathalie?
- (Birds screeching)
- (Gunfire)
Please help me!
Help!
Come on.
I've got to get
out of here.
Ramsey:
Come on, guys, let's go.
The birds are gone.
No they're not.
They're not gone.
They're gonna kill us
if we go out there.
Come on, let's go.
I don't want to.
They'll kill us.
Rod, I'm gonna go
get those people.
- Cover me, okay?
- Okay.
(People screaming)
- Come on, let's go.
- No.
- Come on.
Let's go.
- No.
- Come on.
Let's go.
Help me! No!
I don't want to go!
- Come on.
- No no!
- I don't want to go!
- Let's go.
- No!
- Don't make me
go out there!
- Follow me.
- (Gunshots)
- (Gasps)
- (Screaming)
(Screeching)
(Screaming, moaning)
(Moaning continues)
(Birds screeching)
(Gunshots)
I'm going out there
to save them.
Don't go.
If you go out there
you'll die.
They're dead already.
Yeah, you're right.
Let's get the hell
out of here.
Hi.
The eagles killed
our friends.
Do you have a phone I can
use to call the police?
No, I'm sorry.
All phones from
the eagle attack...
All phones
are dead up here.
Really?
Damn it.
Well, we need some gas.
Well, you know,
from the eagle attack
We are short on gas.
But it's $100 a gallon
if you want.
What? $100?
That's outrageous.
Well, either you
take it or leave it.
I have only a few
gallons left only.
It's a rip-off.
Fine.
Thank you.
Tony, Susan, can you guys go
get some water over there?
Then you can go get
candy for yourselves.
- Yay.
- Okay.
(Screeching)
(Gunshots)
Hey, look at
that man up there.
We should stop
and help him.
Okay.
- Howdy.
- Hi.
Can you sell me some gas
for my truck?
We only have a few gallons
and we need them.
We just bought some for $100
a gallon down the street.
$100 a gallon?
I've only got 50
in my wallet.
- We can give you a ride.
- Oh, no thanks.
Sorry, but we need it.
- You're gonna sell
me some gas now.
- Whoa, take it easy.
Take it easy.
I've got an extra tank
in the back.
Good.
Get it.
(Screeches)
Rod, let's get
out of here.
(Engine starts)
(Engine stops)
There's a creek over there.
We can get some fresh water.
Okay.
(Water flowing)
Who's there?
Come out or I'll shoot.
Don't shoot.
Peace, man.
Come down here.
Why were you hiding
in the trees?
This is my home.
I live here.
That's my house.
You live in a tree?
Sure do.
So you're a tree hugger?
You could put it that way.
I love trees.
They're my family.
I look out for them
and protect these
precious redwoods.
So you can play
in your tree house?
Sure.
Yes, that'll be fun!
No way, it's too dangerous.
The eagles might come there.
Oh, they won't.
You're very safe here
in the forest.
Haven't you noticed
those eagles
Seem to be going after people
in their cars and gas stations?
Besides, it's not the eagles
I worry about.
It's the dry drought weather
that's killing these trees.
There's not enough
rain and water.
Even worse, the spruce bark
beetles are eating
These trees
to death and turning them
from green to red.
I remember when those
beetles used to die out
during the winter.
But now with the dry climate
they've multiplied
And taken over the forest.
Take a look at that
dead redwood up there.
That was killed
by a bark beetle.
This damn global warming.
It's the cause of dry climate
and bark beetles
And death of the trees
and forest.
I can protect these trees
Against greedy
lumber companies
And bad campers who start
forest wildfires.
But it's impossible to protect
them against global warming.
- What's your name?
- I'm tom hill.
I'm rod. This is nathalie,
Susan and Tony.
You can come with us.
Oh, I can't.
This is my home.
I have to stay here
to protect these trees
from further harm.
Enjoy and appreciate these
trees while you can.
In a few years
they'll be gone.
- (Growling)
- I hear a Mountain lion.
I've got to get
back to my house.
You'd better get to your car.
It was very nice meeting you.
You too.
I think it's this way
to the van.
- No, it's this way.
- Are you sure?
What's that smell?
Smells like wood burning.
It's a forest fire.
Let's go, come on.
This way.
(Coughing)
(Engine starts)
- You see that lighthouse
over there?
- Mm-hmm.
That's where mai lives.
We should stop by and see
if she's there.
Okay.
- Oh my God.
- What?
That's mai's car.
- We should pull over.
- Okay.
Oh God, mai.
Mai, are you okay?
Mai.
Nat?
(Weakly)
Forgive them...
Mai.
Mai?
Mai!
God.
Mai.
Damn it!
We ran out of gas.
What are we gonna do?
If we're lucky someone
might drive by.
- I'm hungry.
- Me too, I'm hungry.
We've got to find a way
to get them some food.
- What should we do?
- I don't know.
Hey look, a fishing rod.
I can go catch some fish.
Oh look, a stove.
We can cook it.
Hey, good idea.
(Chatting quietly)
Hey, nat.
I'll go fishing over there.
How about you and the kids
go get some seaweed?
Okay.
You guys eat seaweed?
Seaweed's the best.
It's good for your health.
Nathalie:
Is that right?
Rod:
I caught a fish!
- He caught a fish.
- Yay!
Awesome.
I got a fish.
Looks good.
I got some seaweed.
Good.
I'm gonna go up to the van
and get the stove
So we can cook this.
Here you go.
This'll be good for us.
Yuck.
I want a happy meal.
Me too.
I know, you guys.
There's no happy meals
around here.
Just try the seaweed.
It'll be really good.
- No.
- No, I want a happy meal.
I don't know.
(Birds screeching)
Guys.
Guys, get up.
The eagles.
Come on,
we've got to go.
(Screeching)
(Gunshots)
(Thumping)
Damn,
I'm out of bullets.
Nat, you hit them if they get
through windshield, okay?
(Thumps)
(Screeching fades)
Look!
They're leaving.
I wonder why they
stopped the attack.