(♪ "Satellite"
by Santana featuring Jorge Moreno)
(girl) November 1958,
my senior year of high school.
While other girls were dancing to Elvis
and dreaming about prom dates,
I was reading Jane Austen
and dreaming about college.
And then my parents announced
we were moving to Cuba... in a week.
♪ Baby, I'm gonna make you
step outside
♪ The corners of your world and find
♪ That if you let your heart
open up your mind
♪ There's a whole new world
♪ On the other side...
Slamming doors and giving the
silent treatment couldn't change that,
but it was easier
than admitting I was really scared.
At least everyone else was happy.
Dad got his big promotion from Ford,
Mom got to travel in style,
and Susie, I swear
that girl could adjust in a hurricane.
♪ So what divides
♪ From the bittersweetness
love provides?
♪ I will redefine my place
within this union
♪ For what is a lie?
♪ And the better me can't show its side
♪ I will try to find my way
to higher ground
♪ Oh
♪ There's a million stories
♪ And a million ways
to get there from here
♪ Baby, I'm gonna
put your skin on mine
♪ Be inside you all my life
♪ But if you let your heart
open up your mind
♪ There's a whole new world
on the other side
♪ I'm gonna be your satellite
♪ And I'll hang over your world at night
♪ And I can hear you sleep
beneath the candlelight
♪ I can see your dreams
like they were mine
Not too shabby, huh?
Here's what I know about Cuba.
My high-school French
wasn't going to help me.
I didn't know a single person.
and though no one would talk about it...
Fidel Castro was leading the people in a
revolution against President Batista.
Not that you would know it
from this place.
♪ Sitting here
and wondering what it's all about...
This is Cuba.
Nobody cares what you do here.
- Susie, you want a smoke?
- Watch out. She's a bad influence.
- I'll take that as a compliment.
- She'll have you ditching classes.
As I recall, there's a certain someone
that likes to ditch them with me.
(woman) Don't forget
to sign up for mambo lessons.
Mambo classes are held every day...
Oh, my God.
June Cleaver is in Havana.
Actually, that's my sister Katey.
She's a real brain.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, she's probably going to Radcliffe.
What, majoring in fashion?
Why don't you join us?
There's room here.
- I'm James Phelps.
- Hi. Katey Miller.
Pleasure to meet you.
- Are you the...
- Yeah. Your dad works for my dad.
Yeah.
This is Sheila, Eve, Polly and Steph.
And I guess you know Susie, right?
- Are you really going to Radcliffe?
- I won't know until spring.
Oh. Watch out, girls.
If your head's in your books, you don't
have time to think about the weather.
chilly?
Oh.
- Shit.
- Oh, l'm so sorry. lt's my fault.
- Let me...
- No, just go get new drinks.
Stupid spic.
Excuse me.
You know, you'll have to pay for those.
- Hey, it wasn't my fault.
- Next time, be more careful.
- Excuse me, señior?
- How may I help you, señiorita?
I knocked into those drinks.
I'd like to pay for them.
That will not be necessary.
Accidents happen. Excuse me.
- Yo tengo...
- I speak English.
And I don't need your charity.
- It's not.
- Don't worry about it. It's OK.
- I'm sorry for what she called you.
- That was nothing.
- Not to me.
- Then why are you apologizing?
- You guys were so good.
- Your mother was good.
I was... OK.
- Dad?
- Hm?
I'm sorry
I haven't been excited about all of this.
Sweetheart, it's OK. Senior year is a
terrible time to drag you out of school.
- Especially when you're star of the class.
- Dad.
Come on, don't deny it.
Be proud of it.
You'll do great here too.
(Latin music)
I can't stand on your feet anymore.
- Hey, you remembered that.
- Yeah.
Very good!
Let's continue where we left off.
Book 18, page 285.
Katey, just do your best
to follow along.
- It's OK, I read it last year.
- (all groan)
Knock it off.
Well, then, perhaps you'd like
to begin reading at line 342.
"Now the suitors turned
to dance and song,
to the lovely beat and sway,
waiting for dusk
to come upon them there."
"And the dark night came upon them,
lost in pleasure."
(muttering)
Can anyone tell us
the significance of this passage?
It's a bunch of drunk guys doing it.
Athena wants the suitors
to keep invading Odysseus' house
so that he'll get angry enough to kill
them.
And why does the goddess want that?
She wants Odysseus
to find his strength... and courage?
Very good.
(bell)
Need a ride home?
No, I'm OK. I got a lot of
catching up to do.
A lot of girls don't let on
when they're smart.
- I know, I shouIdn't have said that.
- No, I like that.
I like that about you.
A bunch of us are going to our
country club on Saturday night.
There'll be a band.
The music's pretty cool.
Would you like to go with me?
-I really do have a lot of work to do.
- On a Saturday night?
Wow!
Come on. I'm sure even Homer took some
time off between the Iliad and the Odyssey.
Well, sure. OK.
OK.
(Eve) We're all here now. You can go.
(indistinct conversation in Spanish)
(man wolf whistles)
(Latin music)
You felt a sudden urge for Cuban
music?
The van left without me.
I've been walking for an hour.
- I can walk you back.
- Oh, no, you don't have to do that.
Yeah, you're right.
You'll find your way sooner or later.
Maybe in a week or a month.
Let me just say goodbye.
¡Abuelito!
- What was it you called him?
- Abuelito. It's my grandpa.
- I'm Katey. What's your name?
- Javier.
So, what,
you know, like, five words in Spanish?
Maybe ten.
- What are you studying so hard to do?
- I haven't figured it out yet.
Here. Let me take that.
I've never seen dancing like that.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
I like it. It's very...
- Very Cuban?
- Yeah.
(men singing in Spanish)
(horse whinnies)
- We should get off the street.
- Why?
You don't understand what they're
singing.
No!
That way!
So you've got... OK.
Oh, here she is. Thank you so much.
Thank God. Katey,
where have you been?
I missed the bus. I'm fine. I walked.
For heaven's sakes.
Katey, why didn't you call me?
For all I knew you could have been
kidnapped by rebels.
- It's not the rebels you should worry about.
- What did you say?
You're right. I'm sorry.
I should have called.
Honey, where's your book bag?
I left it at school. It was heavy.
(Latin music)
Oh, God.
It was good I had all these
boring American books with me.
They realized I couldn't be
a revolutionary.
I don't understand.
They were just singing.
There's not such a thing
as just singing here anymore.
You know, you're a pretty good dancer.
- I was terrible.
- Ah, yeah. Yeah, you were terrible.
But for an American, you move well.
Oh, thanks.
Why do you look in the mirror?
I was trying to remember the steps I
saw.
But what does looking have to do with
it?
Just... just feel the music.
You should see for yourself.
The real dancers are at La Rosa Negra
on Saturday night.
Oh, I can't.
I got invited to this country club...
thing.
- Hey, that was fast.
- Yeah.
Is that why
you want to learn Cuban dancing?
Just to impress your date?
- No, I wanted to...
- Don't worry. They won't dance like that.
Just learn the fox trot instead.
I already know the fox trot.
♪ Well, do you wanna dance
and to hold my hand
♪ Tell me I'm your lover man?
♪ Oh, baby...
(door closes)
Do we need to go shopping?
I just thought you might be going
to the country club Saturday night.
- Oh, you just thought?
- Mrs. Phelps took me to lunch.
You two aren't planning
an arranged marriage?
No, I should have thought of that.
He's so cute.
♪ Do you, do you, do you,
do you wanna dance?
- Yolanda?
- Yes?
Is this square?
- Square?
- Yeah, you know. Like a square.
Is square good or bad?
- It's bad.
- Si. It's square.
Oh, God.
I don't know. You're smaller than me.
Your dresses'll be...
Perfect.
- You're joking.
- Why? Is it square?
Definitely not.
It's not fair!
All of my friends are going,
so why would you go and I can't?
I am older than you.
Such a waste.
You don't even know how to have fun.
(groans)
(rock and roll music)
Sure you don't want me to stay?
Dad, don't.
- OK. Bye.
- Mm-mm.
Be careful.
Polly. Polly.
God, what did she do, paint it on?
Señiorita.
Wow!
- Oh, I don't know.
- Oh, I do.
- I'd like to invite you to the Club Palace...
- You been to the Palace yet?
- the annual Latin ballroom
amateur dance contest.
- I'll have to take you.
- Come and see Cuba's hottest dancers.
(band plays up-tempo version
of "Sleigh Ride ')
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah
♪ Listen
♪ Darling, you send me
♪ Darling, you send me...
You feel really good.
Am I making you nervous?
- No.
- Well, you make me a little nervous.
But don't tell anyone.
It'll ruin my reputation.
♪ At first I thought it was infatuation...
We're going to Polly's
for a little mojito party.
- Oh, yeah?
- Her parents are out of town again.
What do you think?
Steph can make a wicked mojito.
Oh...Well...
I'm sure we can get someone
to rustle you up a Shirley Temple.
Actually, James and I
are gonna go to a Cuban club.
Where?
La Rosa Negra.
Yeah, We're going to the...
(Latin music)
Look at the way they feel the music.
They're feeling it, all right.
I'll get us some drinks.
Hi.
- You look so Cuban.
- So do you.
Hi. I'm Javier.
- James Phelps.
- Yeah, I know you.
So the country club
wasn't all you expected?
We thought
we'd expand our horizons a little bit.
Oh, you mean
actually experience La Habana?
Do you mind if I dance with your date?
You'll have to ask her.
OK.
♪ Te quiero Havana,
the rhythm pumpin' in my heart
♪ In La Rosa we dance
to the tempo of love
- Shall we give your boyfriend a show?
- He's not my boyfriend.
♪ Let your body talk
till the voice in you says
♪ Baby
♪ I'm the one you find deep in the
groove
♪ That has your body and your senses
♪ I'm the heat inside
when rhythm and love collide
♪ Let me introduce myself
♪ Cuba
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Hey, mi música
♪ Hey, tu música
Lose your date?
Must be the yanqui
dancing with my brother.
Good of you to bring your girlfriend to
La Habana while you still have the chance.
Why? You gonna run us gringos out?
That's right, comebola, so keep
smiling.
(they laugh)
♪ Let me introduce myself
♪ Cuba
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Hey, mi música
♪ Orishas underground de Habana
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Hey, tu música
(Latin music)
Raoul y Esmerelda.
King and queen of La Rosa Negra.
When they dance, the floor is theirs.
You're as good a dancer as he is.
Katey, this is my brother Carlos.
- Hi. Hola.
- Arturo, Miguel.
Hola.
- We were just talking politics.
- Really?
- My brother loves talking.
- Javier doesn't like to talk politics.
The revolution would screw up
his job kissing your asses.
Where's the revolution tonight?
On the dance floor?
While you boys kiss and make up,
We're gonna get some fresh air.
Let's go.
#Let them go.
- I was enjoying the dancing.
- You were very hot.
(laughs nervously)
It's not the safest part of town.
No, don't.
Take me home, will you?
Stop it! Get off!
- You didn't say no to him.
- (material rips)
Katey! Katey, get back in
the damn car. I'll take you home.
(Latin music)
- Hey.
- Where is he?
- He's gone. He's gone. It's OK, I'm fine.
My dad works for his dad.
I just wanna forget about it.
Don't worry. I'll take you home.
Come on.
I should have seen it coming.
- I guess I'm not used to...
- Bastards?
- Guys.
- You never had a boyfriend in America?
No. I liked this one guy
but it didn't work out.
- Why not?
- He didn't know I existed.
Oh, yeah, that could be a problem.
This is as far as I go.
The staff
is not supposed to mix with guests.
It took me a long time to find this job.
You'd be in trouble
for walking me up there?
- Yeah.
- That's ridiculous.
Adiós.
Thanks for walking me home.
I'm sorry your evening was... so
difficult.
Not all of it was.
Oh.
(♪ "I've Had The Time Of My Life')
(man) My job is to make you look
beautiful.
Your job is to make
our bodies like one. Watch.
(Latin music)
Thanks. OK, that's it for today.
Oh... who's gonna enter
the big dance contest?
- Isn't it just for locals?
- It's for anyone who has the guts to try.
What about you?
- Me?
- Uh-huh.
No, I can't. I'm not good enough.
Sure you are. I've seen you practicing.
(Latin music)
Easy.
Whoa!
Think about it.
Katey, you left your sweater in my car.
- Just bring it to school.
- Wait a second.
Katey...
I'm really sorry. I was drinking.
I would never hurt you.
He's not here.
- They fired him.
- What?
Lois and your sister, they saw you.
- I'm sorry.
- I gotta go.
(door closes)
You need to keep your mouth shut.
The things you do have consequences.
- Lois is the one who blabbed it.
- Oh, right.
And you had nothing to do with it?
What were you doing
with that guy anyway? It's embarrassing.
Is that you talking
or is it those other girls?
He's not like us.
There is no "us," Susie.
- Hola.
I'm looking for Javier Suarez.
- Si.
- Chabe!
- Yes?
- I'm a friend of Javier's.
- ¿ Cómo?
- From the hotel.
I didn't know he had friends in the
hotel.
Um... is he here?
No. He's working there now.
You... don't see him?
- She's looking for Javier.
- I know her.
- Come inside, Chabe.
- Go with your grandmother.
So... what do you want with my
brother?
I need to talk to him.
You got him fired. Isn't that enough?
I know a way he can make some
money.
You yanquis, you come here
and you pour money into the casinos,
into the pockets of the gangsters
who run this country.
The same gangsters who murder
innocent people like my father.
- I didn't know.
- That's right. You don't know.
(Latin music)
Javi.
What is she doing here?
I feel terrible about what happened.
I went to your house...
- You told my mother I was fired?
- No, I didn't.
- So what do you want?
- I told her I wanted to talk to you.
I'm sorry you got fired.
Don'tworry. It's my fault. I knew better.
- Is this your newjob?
- That's right.
You make 'em, we steal 'em.
Isn't that right, Javi?
There's this... this dance contest
at the Palace, Christmas Eve.
- I think you should go.
- And see if they need any busboys?
That's not what I mean.
You know what kind of people
goes to the Palace?
I could get you in.
You'd have to be my partner.
You mean dance with you?
God, I'm not that bad.
- You didn't mind it last night.
- I wasn't trying to win a contest.
Oh, weren't you?
I'm sorry, but I have a lot of work to do.
The prize for the semifinals is $300.
The grand prize is $5,000.
The winners get to go to America.
I don't have time.
OK.
Here. Goto Papa.
We could use some help here!
I have to make a delivery.
Oh, a delivery! You hear that, Rafael?
Yes, medical supplies. You wanna
see?
Glad you have such a big heart,
Carlos.
Maybe someday you'll help your family.
Someday you'll realize I am.
Hi.
This contest... does it cost money?
No.
You know that it's ballroom dancing.
It's not what I do.
It's Latin ballroom.
If we mix what you do with what I do,
I really think we'd have something.
- I still have to teach you everything.
- Not everything.
I'll have to teach you a few things too.
Hm.
Can we do this?
(Latin music)
What?
- What are you doing?
- Just dancing.
But this is a routine.
You can'tjust do what you feel like...
- When I dance I have no routine.
- But this is a contest.
- We need a structure.
- Can I see that?
Huh!
First you learn to move and then
we'll worry about lists and words.
- How do you call this?
- Your hips.
Move your hips. A circle.
Come on. Come on, a circle.
That's a box.
What, are you crazy?
Why should I cover for you?
You want me to tell them what
happened?
- Well, hello there.
- Mom.
We're heading over for lemonade.
Care to join us?
No. No.
- We'll take a rain check.
- OK. You two have fun.
I'm gonna help Javier
and you're gonna help me.
♪ Guajira
♪ I love you too much...
(Katey) Your frame's really weak.
- Better?
- I could do without the bruises, thanks.
I can fit another couple between us.
It's not gonna be a crowded club.
We've gotta sweep
across the dance floor.
OK, I can sweep.
What are you doing?
Your steps are too big.
I'm sweeping.
- How's it going with James?
- I've got homework to do.
You know what, sweetie?
I've been wanting to ask you
if you have any questions or concerns.
You know, about you and James.
♪ Guajira...
It's like dancing
with my mother's ironing board.
- Close your eyes.
- Why?
Just do it.
♪ I love you too much...
It's awkward to talk about, but it's
important you not let a boy pressure you.
Even if you have certain feelings
when you're with James,
feelings that you aren't used to
having...
(Latin music)
Whoa! God!
Do you have to be such a guy?
OK.
OK, I'll be the girl.
A decision that you make now,
the choices you make,
could affect your whole life.
- Do you understand what I'm saying?
- Mm-hm.
You do? Oh.
♪ I love you too much
♪ Guajira
I didn't wanna waste the music.
No, of course not.
What's the problem?
Why are you so afraid to let me lead
you?
I'm not.
You are. When you're ready
to say you're afraid, let me know.
- Hey!
- Sorry.
No, no, no, stay. I'm almost done
anyway.
So what did you decide?
- I entered the contest.
- All right.
Good for you. So how's it going?
Oh, great. It's going great.
- Really?
- No, it's not.
God, I must have been crazy
to think we could do this.
It's in two weeks
and whenever he pushes, I pull,
and I'm flowing and I'm being free
and I'm making a circle
and I'm not an ironing board anymore
and it's still not working.
And now he says "You're afraid."
- Are you?
- No.
That's too bad.
Come here. Un momento.
Stand right here.
Let me see your frame.
Good.
A little pressure.
Mm-hm.
So where did you learn this?
- My parents. They were dancers.
- Really?
Relax.
Yes. Drop your arms.
Breathe.
Now just basic.
Good.
What did you mean
when you said "That's too bad"?
If you can't move through your fear
and connect with yourself,
there's absolutely no way you're
gonna connect with your partner.
Listen to me.
I know that it's scary as hell to let
another person touch that part of you.
But if you do, it's worth it.
Now forget everything I just said
and dance.
(Latin music)
The floor's yours.
I'll see you.
OK, I am.
You're what?
Afraid.
(Javier) So the movement has to
be fluid, like the water.
Afro-Cuban dance, it's the dance of
slaves.
When they danced,
it was their only time to feel free.
So they could be a bird, you know,
or do a flamenco step
and make fun of their owners.
Or just be in the sea instead of being
stuck on an island away from home.
It's a dance about being exactly
who you wanna be in that moment.
It has to feel and look
as natural as the waves.
Coming... and going.
Coming...
We were having dinner
and there was a knock on the door.
Suddenly two policemen
were taking my father away.
The traitor could have been anyone.
Batista has his spies everywhere.
That's the thing, you know.
My father never hurt anybody.
He was just a freethinker.
Someone didn't like his thoughts.
We had a funeral
but we never found his body.
Carlos disappeared for a while,
afraid he would be next.
Then this girl shows up with a baby,
says it's his and she cannot afford it,
and suddenly
I'm in charge of my whole family.
Maybe it's not what you want for
yourself, but you are making a difference.
There's a revolution out there
and what am I doing?
Just painting stolen cars
and baby-sitting...
No, you're keeping your family alive. That's
the most important thing you could do.
If we could really win this contest,
maybe I could bring my family
to America with us.
Your parents, they're... they're perfect.
You see how much
they wanna be in each other's arms?
For us to dance together,
I mean really dance,
that's how it has to be.
(slow Latin music)
(door closes)
Don't let us interrupt you.
- No, we were just...
- Yeah, we saw.
Listen, we have more stuff in the alley
if you want to do something useful, Javier.
I should get home.
Thanks for stopping by.
It's half an hour before curfew.
- What did you do, join the circus?
- Uh-huh.
You gonna tell me
you were out with James?
That's what you told your mother.
I never told her what Susie said.
Susie was wrong.
- OK.
- Good night, Dad.
Hi.
How long you gonna be mad at me?
The girls here...
I told Lois that I liked Jane Eyre
and she asked me what movie she
was in.
I'm really sorry that I told on you.
And what I said about Javier, I was
wrong.
- You gotta think for yourself, Suse.
- I know.
I miss you.
Well, I've been dying to tell you.
Can you keep a secret this time?
♪ I ain't come to fight tonight
♪ Too many ladies up in here tonight
♪ Everybody report to the dance floor;
please! Grab a girl!
♪ I never really knew
that you could dance like this
♪ She make her man
wanna speak Spanish
♪ ¿ Cómo se llama, bonita?
♪ Mi casa, su casa
♪ The way you move,
you got me hypnotized
♪ Especially when I look into his eyes
♪ Hey, Papi, I wanna
see you do the dance to the conga
♪ Hey, girl, I can see your body moving
♪ And it's driving me crazy
♪ And I didn't have the slightest idea
until I saw you dancing
♪ And when you walk
up on the dance floor
♪ Nobody could ignore
the way you move your body, girl
♪ And everything so unexpected,
the way you right and left it
♪ So you could keep on digging it
♪ Baila la calle de noche,
baila la calle de día
♪ I never really knew
that you could dance like this
♪ She make her man
wanna speak Spanish
♪ ¿ Cómo se llama, bonita?
♪ Mi casa, su casa
♪ The way you move,
you got me hypnotized
♪ Especially when I look into his eyes
♪ Hey, Papi, I wanna
see you do the dance to the conga
♪ Hey, boy, now that I see your new
rhythm I 'm in a state of shock now
♪ The way I can see your body moving
and I don't want you to stop now
♪ I like the way
you approach me so sensually
♪ You got me in a daze, boy
♪ I can't ignore the way you're dancing
♪ You got me in a trance
and I can't explain it
♪ Señorita, feel the conga
♪ Let me see you move
like you come from Havana
♪ Oh, I didn't know you did it like that
♪ Hey, you, Papi, don't you stop it
♪ I wanna see you move your body
♪ Oh, I didn't know you did it like that
♪ I never really knew
that you could dance like this
♪ She make her man
wanna speak Spanish
♪ ¿ Cómo se llama, bonita?
♪ Mi casa, su casa
♪ The way you move,
you got me hypnotized
♪ Especially when I look into his eyes
♪ Hey, Papi, I wanna
see you do the dance to the conga
(material rips)
Coño.
Where are you going?
It's Christmas Eve.
Mom said you were working tonight.
Come here. I need your suit.
What for?
I'm in a dance contest.
- Where?
- The Palace.
And you want my suit from Dad's
funeral?
To go to Batista's playground?
I want to win $5,000 on New Year's
Eve.
Wiggling your ass
for all the American big shots.
Cuban big shots, too.
Susie, your mother and I
have some very disappointing news.
I know you love
to decorate the Christmas tree
and sing carols and watch home movies,
but I'm afraid tonight We're all
gonna have to go to the Palace.
- All of us?
- Yes, Susie, all of us.
I know it's your big night with James, but
could you save your old man one dance?
- When did this happen?
- You know your father.
Blabs to everyone we were dancers.
So the Phelpses invited us
to the Latin ballroom contest,
where I hear the dancing is pretty
good,
but your mother and I'll be
looking out for mistakes.
(Latin ballroom music)
I can't wait to see the looks
on your parents' faces.
Don't remind me.
I really should be scolding you
for keeping her out till all hours.
Don'tworry, ma'am. We've done nothing
you'd disapprove of. I can promise that.
(singing in Spanish)
- Thank you.
- Here.
You two make a very cute couple.
So many ofthe girls coming over
from the States these days
get a little, you know, wild.
You're lucky to have such lovely
daughters.
(man) Ladies and gentlemen,
merry Christmas.
In just a few moments we'll begin
this evening's special event.
So when do we get to see
the championship dancers?
- Oh, We're hardly champions.
- Oh, you'rejust being modest.
Come on, I've never seen you guys
dance in public before.
I thought that if your husband
didn't mind, you and I might...
Oh.
James, maybe Katey would like to
dance.
Would you like to dance?
I have to find the ladies' room.
- I'll escort you.
- No, I'm fine.
(singing in Spanish)
- Where have you been?
- Sorry.
This is a crazy idea.
We're gonna win.
(man) Here's the moment you have been
waiting for. The Latin ballroom competition.
Three talented couples will be chosen to
compete in the finals on New Year's Eve.
- Que bonita.
- Gracias.
Señoras y señores, presenting the
brightest talent of the Havana night,
Lola Martinez.
(Latin music)
Where's Katey?
Just wait.
Oh, my God.
♪ Funny thing is when I look into your
eyes
♪ I sense something
so sincere in your disguise
♪ You whisper secrets
I hear only in my dreams
♪ Then Iwake up
to your tele-smoke screen
♪ I wait patiently while you play your
game
♪ Cos in the end
I'll be the winner all the same
♪ You'll see clearly
when the song comes to a stop
♪ I'll be the one
blowing kisses from the top
♪ So, baby, stop, you're surrounded
♪ I got my love, love all around ya
♪ One wrong move and I'll drown ya
♪ And that'll end ya, you should
surrender
♪ You'll never win unless you give in
♪ So, stop, baby, stop, you're
surrounded
♪ I got my love, love all around ya
♪ One wrong move and I'll drown ya
♪ And that'll end ya, you should
surrender
♪ You'll never win unless you give in
♪ So won't you give our love a chance?
♪ Or do you only wanna dance?
♪ You put your lips very closely to my
face
♪ And then you run away
and so begins the chase
♪ Cos when I want ya, I'll get you
anyway
♪ You know what I wanna do,
it ain't nothing new
♪ I'm tired of dropping clues,
so when I step to you
♪ Will you rise to my occasion
♪ Or will you make me
change your station?
♪ Stop, you're surrounded
♪ I got my love, love all around ya
♪ One wrong move and I'll drown ya
♪ And that'll end ya, you should
surrender
♪ You'll never win unless you give in
♪ So, stop, stop, you're surrounded
♪ I got my love, love all around ya
♪ One wrong move and I'll drown ya
♪ And that'll end ya, you should
surrender
♪ You'll never win unless you give in
♪ So won't you give our love a chance?
♪ If you take my hands and follow
my lead, I'll make you dance
♪ I can make you dance
♪ But if you get my feet and miss
the beat then I can't take that chance
♪ I can't take that chance
♪ If you take my hands and follow my
lead
♪ I'll make you dance,
I can make you dance
♪ But if you get my feet and miss
the beat then I can't take that chance
♪ I can't take it
♪ So, stop, stop, you're surrounded
♪ I got my love, love all around ya
♪ One wrong move and I'll drown ya
♪ So, stop, stop, you're surrounded
♪ I got my love, love all around ya
♪ One wrong move and I'll drown ya
♪ And that'll end ya, you should
surrender
♪ You'll never win unless you give in
♪ So won't you give our love a chance?
(cheering)
our three finalist couples for next
week.
And they are...
Couple number five,
José Melarde and Iris Mesa.
Couple number nine,
Tino and Lourdes Martel.
And couple number two,
Javier Suarez and Katey Miller!
What could we have possibly done
to make you wanna hurt us so much?
You humiliate us in front of everyone,
including your father's boss.
- Did you figure he'd lose his job...
- No one's losing their job.
- You're gonna lose your job?
- No. Please, go to bed.
- I didn't do anything to you.
- You lied to us.
I know, and I'm sorry.
But I knew you wouldn't let me...
Kiss a Cuban pool boy in front of
everyone? Damn straight, we wouldn't.
Why in the world would you want to
hurt James? I thought you liked him.
No, you liked him because he fits into
your perfect country-club world.
- There's nothing wrong with that world.
- He couldn't keep his hands off me.
- What? What happened?
- Nothing happened. I'm fine.
- Why didn't you tell us?
- Because I didn't wanna mess up your job.
Katey. How could you think that my job
would be more important than you?
I didn't wanna hurt you.
I just wanted to help Javier...
which is his name, by the way.
Oh, God, I love dancing with him.
Oh, Katey.
Did it ever occur to you
that that boy might be using you?
A nice American girl
who can be his ticket out of here?
You may love dancing with him but there
are more important factors, like your future.
Why does it have to be either or? You
gave up your passion but why should I?
(father) Katey.
Katey. Katey, wait.
- Honey, wait.
- I'm going to Javier's.
Your mother's trying to protect you.
I'm gonna be up there on New Year's Eve
no matter what you and Mom think.
No more lies.
He's out celebrating.
So if you want to wait for him...
(click of phone receiver)
That was Katey.
It's OK. She's with his mother.
- Was I wrong?
- No.
But neither was Katey.
Sometimes I wish we...
Ijust try to imagine what it
would be like ifwe hadn't had...
- Does it make me a bad mother?
- Of course not.
You were good. It's OK to miss it.
They sure spiced up our old routine,
didn't they?
I'll say. That wouldn't have gone over
too well at Rose Lane, would it?
No.
Bert, she's not a little girl anymore.
What are you reading?
José Marti. It was my father's.
We got rid of all his books just to
be safe, but I kept this one.
Hello.
- Javier?
- Yeah.
- If we don't win the finals...
- We will.
But if we don't...
I'm not gonna go to college
in six months.
You don't know how you are gonna
feel in six months.
- Yes, I do.
- No. No, you don't.
I don't want you
to give up your dreams for me.
But I have new dreams now.
(♪ "Have Yourself A Merry Little
Christmas" playing softly)
Susie, why don't you and I
go raid that buffet by the pool?
Sure.
Tree looks nice.
Your father and I discussed it...
and we think that you should do
a double turn at the finals.
You like the way I danced?
Katey...
if you're asking me to approve
of you and this boy, I can't.
But the dancing...
The dancing was incredible.
I think I should take
a little credit for that.
I think you should, too.
(Latin ballroom music)
Javier, these are my parents.
- Hi, Javier. It's nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
It's an honor
to meet such wonderful dancers.
This is from my mother's garden.
Thank you. That was sweet of you.
- This is for you.
- Thanks.
(man) Happy New Year,
ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight we bring you the winning couples
from the Latin ballroom competition.
(Latin music)
(singing in Spanish)
Do you want to dance?
Don't you dare!
(singing in Spanish)
Feliz año nuevo, ladies and
gentlemen.
Welcome to our Latin ballroom
amateur dance contest final.
You will dance on the stage
one couple at a time.
Tonight's winning couple will win $5,000...
You are up first.
Our first couple this evening
is Mr. José Velarde...
and Miss Iris Mesa!
(Latin music)
- Don't forget to look at the judges.
- Don't worry about the others.
Remember, you're the queen
of La Rosa Negra.
Our final contestants this evening...
Miss Katey Miller and Mr. Javier Suarez.
(Latin music)
He's got a gun!
(gunshot)
Go. I'll find you.
#Who are the others?
#Long live the revolution!
#How could you do that?
#With all those innocent people!
#Everything would have been fine
if you hadn't screwed it up!
#By killing people just like they do?
#It's not the same!
#Those people in there killed our father!
#But you could have killed
someone else's father!
#Dad would be ashamed of you.
#No.
#He would be ashamed of both of us.
#Goto hell.
#I miss him.
#Sometimes I think that any second
#Dad's going to walk through the front door.
#Looking for his books.
#What you just did...
#and all you've done for our family...
#Thank you.
#You're a pretty good dancer.
#You're a really lousy waiter.
(chanting)
#Batista has fled the country!
#Cuba belongs to the people again!
#Long live the revolution!
#- Did you know?
- No!
#Let's go!
(shouting in Spanish)
(man) Attention, all hotel guests.
President Batista has fled the country.
There is no immediate danger.
Please contact the front desk...
♪ Ohh
♪ Hay
♪ En mi corazon una inquietud
♪ Hoy te veo tan distante
♪ Hay
♪ Algo que me aleja de tu amor
♪ De repente tu cambiaste
- I can't believe it's real.
- Don't you wanna be out celebrating?
No. Iwanna be right here with you.
♪ Sé que me hara sufrir
♪ Anoche yo sentl
♪ Que me besaste diferente y me quedé
♪ Sin saber qué hacer
♪ Yo te conozco y sé
♪ Que algo no anda bien
Ven dime Ia verdad
♪ No quiero imaginar
♪ Que fue el beso del final
♪ Anoche yo sentl
♪ Que me besaste diferente
♪ Y me quedé
♪ Sin saber qué hacer
♪ Yo te conozco y sé
♪ Que algo no anda bien
Ven dime la verdad
♪ No quiero imaginar
♪ Que fue el beso del final
We didn't win the contest.
No.
But the consolation prize was pretty
good.
I'm so happy I can see all this with
you.
What?
Nothing.
Tell me.
Carlos... he always said
that when the revolution came,
Castro will kick out
all the yanqui companies.
But you don't really know that.
No. I'm just saying that...
What, that I might have to leave?
It could happen.
But they wouldn't do that. Not if the
whole idea is to give people their freedom.
Cuban people.
Well, then you'll come with us.
- I'm sure my dad can work it out.
- And my family?
We'll send for them,
just like we were always gonna do.
Katey, I wanted to leave
because of Batista, but now...
But you don't know what life will be like
here. I mean, what if it doesn't get better?
My father died for this.
I have to believe it will.
I can make a difference here.
You showed me that.
This is my country. It's my home.
(door closes)
Oh, thank God. Katey, are you OK?
We're leaving.
Yeah. Your father's making
arrangements.
(knock at door)
Give me that comb.
Your father's been the only man in my
life,
so I don't know what it's like
to say goodbye to someone.
Saying goodbye to dancing,
the other love of my life...
it broke my heart.
Then you were born, and then Susie,
and I loved you both so much that I...
- You're saying I'll get over it.
- No, I'm not. No.
No. I'm saying I know you're hurting.
Everything's such a mess.
You have a choice.
You can do nothing.
You can hide under the bed.
Or you can work through the knots.
(gate opens)
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you too.
- I am taking you with me.
- I am keeping you here.
(♪ "I've Had The Time Of My Life')
Javier said dancing is about being exactly
who you wanna be in that moment.
Dancing with him, I realized I was
becoming the woman I wanted to be.
We didn't win the contest, but we did
win something more important to us.
On my last night in Havana, we were
king and queen of La Rosa Negra.
♪ Hips start shakin' and movin' all
around
♪ Get them hips shakin' around
♪ Let's dirty dance
right here on the floor; girl
♪ Let's do our thing,
Iet's give 'em a show, girl
♪ But I don't know,
don't think they're ready for this
♪ Let's give it to 'em,
I hope they're ready for this
- ♪ You put your hand on my hip
- ♪ I put my hand on your hip
- ♪ Baby, I'll follow your lead
- ♪ Check it, it goes like this
♪ Baby, just follow the motion,
dancing is sexual motion
♪ Moving with so much emotion,
we gettin' dirty now
- ♪ It's how we dance
♪ Yeah, yeah, just dirty dancin'
♪ Just sexy dancin'
♪ Sexual dancin'
♪ Dirty, dirty dancin'
♪ I just wanna be dancin'
♪ Dirty, dirty, dirty dancin'
Dirty, dirty, dirty
♪ Bailar
♪ Yo quiero baila-Ia-Ia-Ia-Ia-Ia
- ♪ Bailar
- ♪ Let's dance, girl
♪ Shake it, shake it, shake it, don't
shake it
(cheering)
but we knew
that this wasn't our last dance.
♪ Baila la calle de noche,
baila la calle de día
♪ I never really knew
that you could dance like this
♪ She make her man
wanna speak Spanish
♪ ¿ Cómo se llama, bonita?
♪ Mi casa, su casa
♪ The way you move,
you got me hypnotized
♪ Especially when I look into his eyes
♪ Hey, Papi, I wanna
see you do the dance to the conga
♪ Señorita, feel the conga
♪ Let me see you move
like you come from Havana
♪ Oh, I didn't know you did it like that
♪ Hey, you, Papi, don't you stop it
♪ I wanna see you move your body
♪ Oh, I didn't know you did it like that
♪ I never really knew
that you could dance like this
♪ She make her man
wanna speak Spanish
♪ ¿ Cómo se llama, bonita?
♪ Mi casa, su casa
♪ The way you move,
you got me hypnotized
♪ Especially when I look into his eyes
♪ Hey, Papi, I wanna
see you do the dance to the conga
♪ Baila la calle de noche,
baila la calle de día
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Orishas underground de Havana
♪ Hey, mi música
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Orishas underground de Havana
♪ Hey, tu música
♪ Ven que te quiero cantar de corazon
asi
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ La historia de mis ralzes
♪ Rumba, son y guaguanco
todo mezclado
♪ Pa' que Io bailes tu
♪ Mira
♪ Ay quien no baila en La Habana
- ♪ Mira
- ♪ Dance all night
(rapping in French and Spanish)
♪ I 'm the one you find deep in the
groove
♪ That has your body and your senses
♪ I 'm the heat inside
when rhythm and love collide
- ♪ Cuba
- ♪ Let me introduce myself
♪ Cuba
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Orishas underground de Havana
♪ Hey, mi música
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Orishas underground de Havana
♪ Hey, tu música
(rapping in Spanish)
♪ Move your body, body
Move your body, body
♪ Clap your hands
♪ Move your body, body
Move your body, body
♪ Bring down your last defense
♪ I feel your innocence
♪ Slip into the night
♪ Baby, hold on tight
♪ Bring down your last defense
♪ I feel your innocence
♪ Slip into the night
♪ Baby, hold on tight
(rapping in Spanish)
♪ Let me introduce myself
♪ Cuba
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Orishas underground de Havana
♪ Hey, mi música
♪ Represent, represent, Cuba
♪ Orishas underground de Havana
♪ Hey, tu música