[ Man ]
Don't tell me
about my visa.
My wife is stuck in that hellhole,
and I am getting on that plane.
It's bad,Joe.
They're evacuating the villages.
The roads are washed out.
We're hearing gunfire now.
Can you--
Can you get to Calamar?
Can you get across the border
to Colombia?
They're putting us on the bus.
I don't know where they're taking us.
Joe? Joe?
Emily! Em--
[ Baby Crying ]
[ All Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Emily Darrow was not
just a doctor...
and a credit
to the medical profession...
she was a healer
and a credit to the human race.
Those who knew her
were changed by her...
inspired by her commitment
to give...
literally everything
of herself...
which is why
we're gathered here today--
to celebrate
this unique life...
not so much taken from us...
as given to us.
From her colleagues
at the university...
to her young patients here...
in Chicago Memorial's
pediatric oncology ward...
she will be sorely missed.
We're told in medical school that
the face of an emergency room doctor...
is the last thing a lot
of people will ever see.
I've tried to keep that in mind when I
see those frightened eyes staring out at me.
But I don't know
what Emily saw.
What image she took with her.
If there was
a compassionate face...
or she died
in a world of chaos.
And that I don't know this...
haunts me.
The divers saw inside, señor.
There is no one alive.
Then where is she?
Where's her body?
We are searching the shoreline
and jungle now...
but the bus is
under ten feet of water.
The river runs at 17 miles
an hour, señor.
There is nothing
you can do.
Por favor, go home.
I'm not going anywhere.
Not till this is over.
I assure you, señor,
it's over.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
No vitals, no pulse.
Put him in E.R. Three on the left.
What are you doing here?
I was paged.
What do we have? Wasn't this morning
your wife's memorial service?
There's nothing I can do for her, okay?
Except keep anyone from joining her.
Now, what do we have?
Six-car pileup.
Eleven injuries. Four went over to County
and six are coming here.
All right, let's go.
Stay with me. How extensive?
Third degree. Forty percent, maybe 50.
Did you tube him?
- Airway's crushed. Couldn't do a cryc.
- Pronounce him.
- Hit the windshield.
- All right, that's a blowout fracture.
Get a C.T. Find out
what else he's got.
What's this?
O.D. Attempted suicide.
Give her to Simon. I'm interested in
people who want to live tonight.
- What's her term?
- She hit the steering wheel.
- How pregnant? Anybody know?
- She looks no more than six months to me.
- She's souring. Let's get it out.
- At six months?
It might have a chance,
but not in there.
Look at her color.
It's still got a heartbeat.
Let's get it out of there.
-This requires consultation--
-Yeah, and let's order out for
pizza while we're at it. Move.
There's a procedure
in place for terminating
a pregnancy, Joe.
I'm not terminating
a pregnancy.
I'm delivering a baby.
Get Prenatal
down here now.
It was the right call.
Delivering a technically
unviable fetus
by Caesarean section...
without consultation
or permission of the mother--
Who was dead.
Not officially.
The baby's alive, Hugh.
I'm concerned, Joe.
So is the rest of the staff.
You refused to treat
a suicide today.
I passed her on to Simon.
As though she were
unworthy of you.
Can we discuss this
tomorrow?
Since Emily's death,
you have been working
around the clock...
24-hour shifts, I'm told,
seven days a week.
Think I'm losing my edge?
Just the opposite.
It's getting too sharp.
You're starting to cut
people around here.
You need time off.
You need to grieve.
I need to grieve?
Mm-hmm.
I am serious, Joe.
Take that time off.
Was it you
who reported me?
Passing on the suicide?
How is she doing?
She's waiting for a bed
on the psych ward.
- Why did you do this to me?
- Do what to you?
Bring me back.
Where were you going?
Someplace better.
Is that right?
I'll do it again too.
It's all I want now.
Well, unfortunately,
your heart disagrees.
It's waged quite
a battle tonight.
No one knows my heart.
[ Sobbing ]
Maybe that's why
it's still beating--
to give somebody
a chance to.
Let me tell you
about that better place
you think you're going to.
You better be
damn sure it's there.
'Cause crappy
as this place is,
it's all there is.
So go ahead.
Be my guest.
But when you
never wake up again,
don't say I didn't warn you.
Hi, Father.
Time for a rebuttal?
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
'And on her footfall,
in rustle of leaves...
"her whisper on the wind...
she speaks from a place
beyond mortal pain."
Hey, look who's here.
Joe!
Hey, you!
You're just in time
to finish the toast.
Pour him a beer.
Linda, can I have
another one, please?
Hey, Joe, "Rachel in Heaven"
Remember that poem,
third-year lit class?
Remember?
Yeah.
To Emily.
How are things
in the hospital?
I don't know why we try
so hard to save them...
if they've got
such a wonderful place
to go...
Iike "Rachel in Heaven."
That's where Emily is.
You can bet on that.
If anyone deserved
to go there, it was her.
Hear, hear.
She was the best of us.
The best of us.
I don't know
what the hell
she saw in you, though.
Lord knows I tried
for years to talk her
out of it.
She was the best of us.
And I have no idea
what she saw in me.
She saw the second
best of us.
You were a great team.
She was the heart,
you were the mind.
Together, you were unbeatable.
Where are you, Joe?
Nowhere.
I'm gonna go.
No, come on, man.
You just got here.
Like you said, Eric,
I'm a mind
without a heart.
Joe, come on.
Joe, that's not--
Don't leave, Joe.
Buddy, that is not
what I meant.
I know
you didn't mean it.
But you were right on, buddy.
I love you anyway.
All of you.
Thank you
for coming today.
See ya.
Hey, Doc.
[ Coughs ]
Hey, Miriam.
Sorry I missed the service.
I didn't want to cough
all over everybody.
Was it nice?
I guess.
I couldn't handle it.
Well, then you're not
gonna do too good with this.
They needed somebody to sign
for it. I didn't want to
leave it out in the rain.
It's a toy company
in Texas.
That'll teach her
to shop the lnternet.
Yeah, that'll teach her.
You'd think a professor
of law could be more precise
with her language.
It's all right.
You have a good night.
Hey, I saw through the
kitchen window Big Bird
didn't eat again.
- Should he go back to the vet?
- The vet said Big Bird
will outlive us all.
[ Laughs ]
[ Crackling ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Answering Machine Beeps ]
Hey,Joe, it's Hal.
I forgot to tell you
we are going on that
white-water trip.
[ Eric ] Gotta come,Joe!
[ Flora ] Don't leave me
alone with these guys!
I sent you a packet, okay?
See ya, buddy!
Love you!
[ Beep ]
Sound good, Big Bird?
You wanna go rafting
with my old college chums?
Nice to see you too.
[ Emily Chuckling ]
[ Joe ]
Why is that funny?
I just don't picture you
with a beak, I guess.
All right. Well,
just imagine soaring around
with me up there, flying.
If you do,
you're on your own.
Why?
Because eagles eat
bunny rabbits.
I'm a vegetarian.
In your next life too?
Yes.
You mean, if you got a chance
to come back, you'd want
to be earthbound again?
No. I'll fly around
with you up there.
But you know what
I'm gonna be.
Yeah, but...
if I'm a bird
and you're an insect,
Yeah?
how are we gonna--
You know.
We'll just have to
do enough of that
in this lifetime...
to make up
for the next ten.
[ Moaning ]
[ Emily's Voice ]
I'm going
because I have to,Joe.
Because it's who I am,
who we are...
what we dedicated
our lives to.
For God sakes, Emily,
you're pregnant.
We addressed this, Joe...
when we first met...
that we'd pack our kids
in on our backs
if we had to...
to show them
what was important,
to teach them our values.
It was naive, Emily,
all right? It was naive.
Our values?
I'm needed there, Joe...
and I'm going.
Whether you choose to
or not.
[ Banging Sound ]
[ Man ] So this thing
was a paperweight?
[ Joe ] Yes.
It was a present I gave her
for Valentine's Day.
Got to weigh half a pound,
and it was squarely--
I mean squarely--
on the bedside table
when I went to sleep.
So what are you saying?
I don't know.
Nothing, I guess.
Just that...
dragonflies were sort of
her thing, you know,
like a personal totem.
How lndians have buffalo heads
or tiger heads or hawks...
hers was a dragonfly.
She even had this small
birthmark on her shoulder
that kind of looked like one.
Said her grandfather
had one too...
on his--
on his butt, I think.
It's called
familial hemangioma.
I once skunked
an entire graduating class...
by putting it
on a final exam.
When she was alive,
I had to scour for
anything I could find...
with a dragonfly on it
to buy her a present.
Now? Now I see 'em
everywhere.
There was one-- There was
one bouncing against
my office window yesterday.
A real one.
Last night a package arrived.
She had bought
over the lnternet...
a mobile to put on
the baby's crib...
of dragonflies.
And then this thing last night
with the paperweight.
You know what I think?
I think you are literally
going buggy living
in that house.
Yeah, you should move.
You're rummaging around
in an empty nursery.
You're living with
a talking parrot
who won't even speak to you.
Never would.
Never liked me.
Would only talk
to Emily.
She even taught it
to announce her arrival
when she came in the door.
"Honey.
Honey, I'm home."
You ought to sell
that thing, Joe.
Get rid of it.
Stuck with it.
I promised her
I'd keep it forever, and I'd
put a provision in my will...
that if anything ever happened
to me, someone I trusted
would take care of it.
Would you?
Oh, no.
It's your promise, buddy.
It's not mine.
I need to live up to
my promises to her.
That's one thing
I need to do.
Okay, fine.
Any other promises
that I should know about?
Just one, but I'm
taking care of that one
myself, starting...
today.
Hi, Joe.
Hugh.
- I was kind of hoping you took
our conversation seriously.
- I did.
I convinced Joe to take
a couple of months off,
with all that's happened.
- Right,Joe?
- I promised Emily I'd
look in on her kids...
on the oncology ward
while she was gone--
I never did.
I thought this might be
a good day.
After six months?
On oncology?
I'm not sure how many
are left, but if it's
for Emily, fine.
Asshole.
You should
get away, Joe.
Isn't there someplace
you can go?
[ Boy's Voice, Echoing ]
Joe!
Joe, can't you hear me?
- All right. Hold C.P.R.
- I'm getting nothing.
Continue it.
Shock him at 30.
Let me in there.
Come on, Jeffrey.
Hang in there. Clear.
Keep it going.
Still nothing.
Charging to 60.
Shock him.
Clear.
- Nothing.
- Go again.
- He's not responding.
I said again.
There's no pulse at all.
-He's not coming back this time.
-Damn it, do it again!
Clear!
[ Steady Beep ]
[ Sighs ]
He's gone.
[ Steady Beep Continues ]
- [ Rhythmic Beep ]
- He's got a rhythm.
- He's back! Jump on it!
- He's coming back!
Yes, Jeffrey, yes!
Do you need to be here?
Put that O-2 mask on him.
Clear the room, please.
Get me an E.K.G.
You'll have to leave.
Don't let him pull out
that l.V. Jeffrey.
Jeffrey, can you hear me?
Ah, pupils reactive.
I just came on.
What happened?
They're stabilizing him.
He flat-lined,
and his heart started again.
That's our Jeffrey. His heart
stopped more times than anyone
in the history of science.
He'll come out of there
with all kinds of stories about
who he met in the tunnel...
and what they said.
[ Knocking ]
Hi, I'm Dr. Darrow
from Emergency.
I know who you are.
The hospital administrator
heard that you got in the way
in l.C.U. yesterday...
and asked to be notified
if you came back here
again.
Did the boy who was being
resuscitated last night--
Jeffrey--
Reardon.
Right. Is he--
Is he still on the floor?
Mm-hmm. He was one of
your wife's favorites.
Actually,
that's why I'm here.
I promised I'd look in
on her kids, but there
don't seem to be many left.
Be great if you could
give me a little help,
maybe not...
put in that call to
the hospital administrator.
Between you and me, Doctor,
the hospital administrator is--
how do I put it--
I use the word "asshole."
[ Chuckling ]
That about captures it.
Three-one-five.
He's a real trip.
You'll love him.
Thanks.
- Hello.
- Hi.
How's he doing?
Great.
Nice.
What is it?
I couldn't say.
Guess.
All right.
Crucifix made of Jell-O?
Man, you're good.
He's good.
He hasn't stopped drawing
them since he got out
of the l.C.U. yesterday.
So what is it?
I don't know.
That's why I'm asking.
Just woke up
thinking about it.
I happened to be
in the l.C.U.
yesterday, Jeffrey.
I know.
I saw you in there.
You saw me in there?
Yeah. You came in
through the back of the room
standing over my bed.
You saw me
come over to your bed?
Pretty sure it was you.
But the tie was different.
Jeffrey!
Could I ask--
We're not encouraged
to discuss these things.
There was a nun on the ward
interviewing kids who'd had
near-death experiences.
Sister Madeline
from Chaplain Services.
Stirred up all kinds of
trouble for the hospital
when some of it appeared...
on a TV tabloid show.
She never even
talked to me...
and I've got the best
near-death experiences
of anyone.
I'm allowed a coffee break
if there's a doctor with him.
In spite of hospital policy,
I think they need to talk
about it.
You're scheduled for
a CAT scan, Jeffrey.
Don't go without me.
So what are we talking
about here, Jeffrey?
What we shouldn't.
In the l.C.U. yesterday,
when I approached your bed...
it seemed to me
you were pretty--
- I was flat-lined.
- Exactly.
So how could you
look up and see me?
Couldn't.
- But you said--
- I looked down.
You looked down?
From the ceiling.
That's where I was
when I saw you.
Okay.
Don't believe me?
Should l?
Ever see that little
bald spot on top of your head?
Bend down here.
Come on.
Yeah, that was you.
[ Giggling ]
Jeffrey,
do you know my name?
You look like a--
a William to me.
I'm a Joe.
Does it ring a bell?
Emily's Joe?
Joe Darrow.
I saw her yesterday too.
What do you mean,
Jeffrey, you saw her?
She was there.
Where?
All around me.
Inside the rainbow.
The mist.
I was falling...
falling through it...
until she caught me...
then brought me
back up.
She kind of flew me.
She flew me out...
so I could come back...
and tell somebody something.
Tell what, Jeffrey?
To who?
Joe.
Tell me what, Jeffrey?
Tell Joe what?
It was loud in the rainbow...
Iike thunder in there.
- Tell me what, Jeffrey?
- I don't know.
You were calling my name.
Joe.
Joe!
Joe, can't you hear me?
All right, Jeffrey.
Joe! Joe!
Jeffrey, slow down.
Whoa, whoa.
Look at my eyes.
Just breathe.
Just breathe
a little bit, okay?
What happened?
I'm fine.
We were--
He wanted to know
what happened yesterday.
His heart stopped again.
I know.
- I was there, actually.
- He wanted to know
what happened...
while it was stopped.
Oh. Telling one of
his tall tales again.
Trying to get on TV.
I'm gonna give him a dust mop
next time so he can sweep
the ceiling while he's up there.
My daddy don't believe me.
He do the "bald spot"
on you?
[ Laughing ]
It don't work
on everybody.
Just us bald guys, huh?
Phew! Yeah, he got me
with that one too.
You had me going there,
Jeffrey.
It was the truth.
You don't believe me?
[ Woman Over P.A., lndistinct ]
What if I do remember what
she wants to tell you...
then would you believe me?
Do you remember it?
If you come back, I might.
[ Father ]
What who wants to tell him?
[ Jeffrey ]
His wife. She wants me
to tell him something.
Probably to take
out the trash, huh?
[ Chuckles ]
[ Woman Chuckling ]
[ Man ]
What?
[ Joe ]
He even had me believing
he saw my bald spot...
from the ceiling,
till I saw a mirror
behind my head.
[ Man ]
We can thank Mom for those
genes, right, Dad?
I hate to burst your bubble,
Joe, but I can see
your bald spot from here.
I think bald is sexy.
Really?
Yes.
I've got a parrot
that might turn you on.
Are you still
living with that
messy thing? Joe!
We're working on
our relationship.
Is it a talking parrot?
A listening parrot.
A bird after my own heart.
That's what I do
for a living: listen.
Really?
Gwyn's a grief counselor, Joe.
That's why I thought it might
be a good idea for you to meet.
Is that right?
I've heard a lot of clients talk
about the near-death experiences
of their loved ones--
how they'd wake up talking
about being in a dark tunnel...
moving toward the light.
And what's
your thought on it?
I'm just your parrot,
Joe. Just listening.
[ Man ] I can tell you
as an eye surgeon,
it's all very simple.
The tunnel is
literal tunnel vision.
And the white light
is the gradual bleaching out
of the optic screen.
As it grows bigger,
it would seem like
you're moving toward it.
How do you explain
their ability to recall
what everyone said...
around their deathbed after
they were declared dead--
to describe what
the doctors were wearing...
down to the patterns
on their ties?
[ Man ]
It's the way
we measure death.
Obviously the brain
is still functioning
on some subliminal level...
soaking up all the last bits
of what's left to hear and see.
That's what you get
for having dinner
with a family of doctors--
no discussion about
floating around
on the ceiling;
no tunnel;
no bright lights.
Next thing, they're gonna
tell us there's no tooth fairy.
Funny thing is,
I thought I heard him
calling out for me.
This kid.
I heard his voice
calling 'Joe. "
And when I introduced myself
to him, he asked me
if I was Emily's Joe.
Said that Emily
was trying to reach me.
Do you believe
she's trying to
reach you, Joe?
No, Counselor, I don't.
I can give you
an hour for free.
Bye, Joe. You want me to
package up dessert for you?
Sorry.
Use your phone?
Excuse me.
I am kind of busy
at the moment, yeah.
Well, isn't there anyone else
who can cover for me tonight?
All right. I understand.
I'll be right over.
I'm sorry.
I'd really like to stay.
No, you wouldn't.
It's too threatening.
It's about unresolved issues
you're not ready
to deal with yet--
guilt, anger
toward our loved ones--
that's why
we conjure up spirits--
from the Virgin Mary
to our dearly departed--
because we need to
talk to them,
not the other way around.
[ Scoffs ]
You asked if I thought
she was trying to contact me,
and I never answered.
Let me answer now.
She was my
ultimate partner...
my best friend and lover,
and I miss her
beyond belief.
I also know I'm never
gonna see her again.
Not ever.
And I'm just beginning to
understand what that means
so intensely...
that I sometimes wish that
I didn't have to wake up
anymore.
And the last thing I need
is someone telling me
what to feel...
or how to feel.
Anger, yeah.
Guilt, you bet.
But I don't need you crawling
up my ass with a flashlight
to tell me about it.
Keep going, Joe.
This is what you need.
I'll drop you
a check in the mail.
Hi.
Hey.
What's your name?
Ben.
I'm Joe, Ben.
I know.
Just admiring your artwork.
What is it?
She said you should
go there.
I'm sorry?
The lady.
The lady in the picture
down the hall.
She said you'd...
be coming to see me.
- The nurse?
- They said she was
a doctor here.
What doctor?
- She wants you to go there.
- Go where?
I'm not--
I'm not sure
what you mean, Ben.
Go where?
I dreamed of her...
in the ambulance
when I came here.
Then... I saw
her picture in the hall.
You know,
the lady doctor?
In the picture
of the Easter party,
with the cake on her nose?
Are you talking
about Dr. Darrow?
She died, I guess.
And you dreamed of her?
She wants you
to go there.
Go where, Ben?
The rainbow.
That's a rainbow?
This--
This is a rainbow?
Have we met before, Ben?
I don't know.
How do you know
who I am?
She showed me your face.
In a picture?
In my mind.
She said
I have to come back...
to tell you to go there.
To a rainbow?
Yes.
Well, how would l--
How would I do that, Ben?
Christine,
the boy in 312--
Ben?
Yes.
Did he know my wife?
I don't think so.
I think he just
came in two weeks ago.
Yeah. On the third
in a coma.
Septic shock.
Why, Joe?
Nothing.
Miriam--
The first kid,
he calls my name...
I follow him in
to the l.C.U....
where he flat-lines,
dies.
Then when he's resuscitated,
says he saw me while he's
floating around the ceiling.
And that Emily--
who he met in a rainbow--
sent him back
to tell me something.
Tell you what?
He doesn't remember.
But the next kid does.
You want jelly?
I got two kinds.
Are you taking me seriously?
Yes.
Is strawberry okay?
What does it matter?
Do you-- Do you hear
what I'm telling you?
I'm just trying to focus
on something real here, Joe.
And you think this isn't?
Doesn't sound it so far.
Listen to me, Joe.
After Hannah died, l--
I saw her everywhere.
She told me I know
she was watching over me...
if I saw a daisy growing
out of the ground with all
the petals missing except one.
We used to play
"She Loves Me,
She Loves Me Not. "
And one day,
I saw an entire field
of one-petaled daisies.
Well, there you go.
How do you explain that?
I was delusional.
Well, I'm not, okay?
I had these conversations.
Aren't you the guy that
doesn't believe in heaven?
This isn't heaven.
This is rainbows.
Oh. And she wants you
to join her
inside a rainbow?
According to these kids,
that's accurate.
Well, according to me,
they're putting you on.
So you think
they're lying.
I'm a lawyer, Joe.
Nothing is real
without evidence.
Have you personally had
any experience with Emily
since her death?
And if so,
has it been documented?
- You know the answer.
Of course I haven't.
- And why haven't you?
Because I haven't gone
halfway to heaven...
and she has no way
of reaching me.
It does sound nuts,
doesn't it?
Well, I wouldn't employ you
in my hospital
if I heard that.
And if I were you,
I'd stay away from there.
Isn't there somewhere
you can go?
I could go
on a white-water trip.
Just what I've always
wanted to see--
white water.
I'll take care
of Big Bird.
Get out of here.
Go see white water...
and get your head straight.
Wanna see?
They were the last thing
she sent us.
Hmm.
Sorry to break it
to you, pal, but, uh...
she was cheatin' on ya.
[ Wings Fluttering ]
[ Fluttering Continues ]
It's just a bug, Big Bird.
Attracted to the light.
Let's not get crazy here.
[ Fluttering Resumes ]
[ Big Bird ]
Honey, I'm home.
[ Squawks ]
[ Squawking Continues ]
Big Bird!
Big Bird, no!
[ Gasps ]
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Miriam ]
Hello?
[ Joe ] Miriam?
Joe?
Miriam, listen to me.
The bird, it's sick.
I had to leave it.
I'm on my way
to the hospital.
- Are you okay?
- Actually, I'm not.
I feel--
I feel like
I'm losing my mind.
What can I do?
It was acting
like it used to
when she'd come home.
I felt like she was there...
in the house.
Jesus, Joe.
I don't know what to do
about the--
The bird?
I'll take care of it.
I'll wake up the vet
if I have to.
You just...
hang in there, okay?
All right. Thanks.
[ Line Clicks ]
Is Jeffrey awake?
Not a good idea
right now.
Is he in his room?
Visiting hours aren't
until 10.:00,Joe.
Joe!
Joe.
Joe, there was some talk
around here I think
you should know about.
Where is he?
Jeffrey?
He's downstairs
getting blood work,
but can I tell you what l--
His nurse-- Is she with him?
Would you just listen
to me for a minute?
She said there was
a nun on the ward...
interviewing kids about
near-death experiences.
Sister Madeline.
Do you know
where she is?
She's no longer
employed here,Joe.
And you know why?
Because she overstepped
her bounds.
Where is she employed?
Would-- Would
Chaplain Services know?
Could you leave us
alone for a minute?
[ Woman Over P.A.,
lndistinct ]
What are you doing,
Joe?
You know
what I'm doing.
You gave me permission--
To look in on Emily's kids.
That was two days ago,
and you haven't left since.
I told you,
I promised my wife.
That you'd upset them?
Jeffrey's cardiologist saw
the readout on his E.K.G.
from 2:30 yesterday afternoon...
and he was damned upset
that your visit...
put him under
that kind of stress.
What is going on, Joe?
The bird's okay.
He will outlive us all.
I tried to clean up
some of the mess in there--
overturned lamp,
broken vase.
You didn't have to
do all that.
I didn't do all that.
I left some of it...
to discuss with you.
That weird picture
you told me
the kids were drawing?
The wiggly cross?
Is it the kids
drawing it,Joe?
Or is it you?
'Cause if you did this,
you need some help.
It's all over
the windows too.
Watch the bird for me,
will you?
[ Playful Chattering ]
Excuse me.
Excuse me. I'm looking
for Sister Madeline.
Is that--
May I ask
what this is about?
It's personal. Is that her?
- You'll have to call the office
for an appointment.
- Excuse me!
- Sir. Sir!
- Sister Madeline?
Sister Madeline,
could I speak to you?
Sir!
Please.
Sister Madeline?
Please,
are you Sis--
Please.
Are you Sister Madeline?
This is private property.
You are trespassing.
I know, I tried to call.
I'm sorry.
Chaplain Services only
gave me an address.
He'll call the police.
Please--
Just five minutes.
You people have done
enough damage.
- You don't understand.
- You don't.
No more journalists.
No more interviews.
I'm not a journalist.
I'm a-- I'm a doctor.
Head of Emergency Services...
at Chicago
Memorial Hospital.
Joe Darrow.
Emily's Joe.
Yes.
[ Whispering ]
That's why I need
to talk to you.
I need to know
about your work.
I've called the police.
I'd advise you to leave.
It's all right.
He's not a journalist.
He's still trespassing.
I'm sorry.
We agreed to hire
Sister Madeline...
with the understanding
that her presence here
wouldn't cause any disturbances.
[ Bell Ringing ]
Sister.
Yes, sir.
The police respond quickly.
I'd advise you to leave.
Do you have business
at the school, sir?
Beg your pardon?
Step over here,
please.
[ Police Radio Chatter ]
[ Sister Madeline ]
And I realized that in an age
where no one believes...
in miracles anymore,
I was witnessing miracles
every day.
And the pediatric
oncology ward...
was the perfect laboratory
to study it--
the near-death experience.
Being kids, they were
more open to what happens...
on the other side.
You're convinced it's not
just in their minds?
Just in their minds?
What we're experiencing
right now could be
just in your mind.
You're a doctor
because you dreamed...
of being one, right?
You imagined that...
for yourself.
If we can create this world
with what we imagine...
why not the next?
S-So you're saying,
belief--
Gets us there.
Did Emily believe?
Because I think
she got there.
I believe she's trying
to contact me.
Two kids have seen her.
One was flat-lined,
another in a coma.
In the tunnel?
ln a rainbow.
Trying to tell me something,
something urgent.
But I don't know what.
And they-- they--
they draw this...
after they've--
after they've seen her.
Have you ever seen
this before?
No.
I don't know.
Am l--
Am I just going nuts?
As nuts
as Christopher Columbus...
thinking there was
another side to the earth.
Talk to an anesthesiologist.
They'll tell you.
There are a hundred steps on
the ladder of consciousness...
between being
fully alert...
and being dead.
To put a patient under,
they bring them down...
only to the tenth rung.
Beneath that is
a descending gray scale...
Iike the depths
of an ocean...
no one has explored.
It's in those depths,
those murky depths...
she's finding them--
the children.
They're her conduit,
because she knew...
you'd find your way
to them.
Stay close to them.
Be with them when they slip away
so you can be with them...
when they first awaken,
before the details fade.
One of them...
will come back
with the answer.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
[ Man ] Careful. Careful.
Okay, let's go. Sit back!
Release forms.
I'll get it.
[ Chattering ]
- Where is it?
- Down the right.
- Careful with the transfer.
Watch your line here.
Keep it pumping.
Right here.
Hook him up to the ventilator
when you get inside.
I'll get the monitor.
This is Jeanette in Nephrology.
I need to speak
to Dr. Dickinson, please.
Monitors are ready.
Dr. Darrow!
Yes, it is an emergency.
No, I can't hold.
Keep me on the line.
Dr. Dickinson.
We've got a healthy kidney
up here. Just Dr. Darrow.
Joe.
Yeah.
Joe, I'm on my way over
to harvest a kidney...
and I want you
to protect it for me.
Tell me what to do.
All right. They're
coming in for other organs,
but that kidney is mine.
I want that made clear
in case anybody choppers in
and tries to grab it.
Stay on top of his vitals.
Don't leave the room
and hold off the vultures.
I don't want anybody cutting
until I get there.
Consider it done.
Put Jeanette
back on the phone, buddy.
I'm ten minutes away.
Jeanette.
Yes, sir.
- You're Dickinson?
- Darrow.
They told me not to leave him,
but I gotta get this monitor
over to the recipient.
I'll keep watch
in here.
Ventilator's set at 16.
That oughta keep
the organs fresh.
[ Helicopter Approaches ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Softly ]
Joe.
Come closer.
Dear God.
- [ Man ] We're from Lakeview.
What room's the donor in?
- [ Woman ] 215.
- Double doors on the right.
- Call air support.
I'll be right up.
Guys, we're gonna have to--
[ Continues, lndistinct ]
We're from Lakeview in Lansing.
We have a heart recipient
prepped and ready to go.
You're not supposed to
be in here.
Are you Dickinson?
Get out.
Just get out, please.
- Hey, take it easy, Doctor.
- Get him out of here, all right?
Get everyone out.
Dickinson said--
No, it's okay, Joe.
Dickinson's
in the parking structure.
I just spoke to him.
He said let's move 'em
both into surgery.
Let's go.
Wait, okay?
Hey, Joe.
It's all right.
It's not all right.
He's not ready to be moved.
Hey, what are we waiting for?
Come on. Move him out.
Charlie, wait a second.
What?
This man's not dead.
The brain scan jumped.
I saw it.
I saw it on the monitor.
Come on, Joe.
It's flat as a pancake.
Come on. Move him out of here.
Come on. Let's go.
Charlie, listen.
Charlie, there's
something going on.
Don't do this yet.
Don't kill this man.
Get ahold of yourself.
This man is dead.
He spoke to me.
I'm telling you.
Joe, please.
Joe, this man
did not speak to you.
It was Emily!
It was her voice.
I am not crazy.
You back off.
Don't talk like this.
You've gotta--
You've gotta listen to me.
Charlie, just hold off.
For one minute.
Leave me alone with him.
This is nuts, Joe.
- Come on. Get him inside!
- Hey! Easy! Easy!
Back off, man!
[ Charlie ]
Get him inside!
- Somebody get Security!
- Get him out of here!
- For God's sake, Joe!
- Get Security, will you?
Charlie,
one fucking minute.
Get him outta here!
Joe! We need Security
in two south right away.
Please, listen to me!
[ Groaning ]
[ Sirens Wailing ln Distance ]
[ Chattering ]
All right.
We're going down.
[ Police Radio Chatter ]
[ Officer Chattering ]
[ Joe ]
Thanks for coming down.
You posted bail?
First offense.
Got it waived.
I also spoke to the hospital
administrator who's willing
to drop all charges...
if you'll agree to take
a lengthy sabbatical.
I'll bet.
He said you claimed
a brain-dead organ donor
spoke to you. Is that true?
No.
Good.
It was Emily.
Speaking through him.
[ Sighs ]
You know, I could almost
understand it with the kids,
because they all knew her.
Of course
they're gonna dream about her.
She was key to their survival.
Okay, then how about
the kid who never even
laid eyes on her?
What kid?
The kid I told you about
in the kitchen.
The first time he ever met her
was in a coma, Miriam.
Remember?
I've got his admission records
to prove it.
That's evidence, right?
lsn't that what you wanted?
She's trying to reach me,
and she's becoming desperate.
Why?
Why desperate, Joe?
Oh, you don't think
she's still alive.
If a kid could see her
in a coma, then why...
couldn't she be trying to
communicate from one?
There were no survivors.
The Venezuelan government
searched the jungle for a month.
And never found her!
Exactly. And that's
why we're here tonight--
because you never saw her body
and never got closure.
Emily's dead, Joe.
That's what
this is all about--
your refusal
to accept that.
Look.
I understand it.
If I hadn't seen Hannah's body,
I wouldn't have believed it
either.
I'd still be waiting
for her to come home,
just like you are.
You have to
end this, Joe.
You gotta
do the hard stuff,
like I did.
Like everyone does.
You gotta
clean out the closets,
empty the drawers...
and take down the vacancy sign
that says "Emily's ghost
is welcome here"...
and get on with your life
without her.
[ Bag Crinkling ]
[ Softly ]
All right.
What about
that rafting trip?
What do you mean,
what about it?
Well, anything to get
your mind off of this.
So, you think
I should go?
Maybe I'll go
with you. Huh?
I'm mean with a paddle.
[ Chuckles ]
The river's up
this time of year.
It's gone from
a two-point difficulty
to a five.
I want us all to go home,
go over our river maps.
Note the hazard points,
the portages, the waterfalls.
Oh, check out
these safari pants.
It says to pack light.
I'm just bringing my thong.
Well, then,
I'm bringing my camera.
Well, it better be disposable,
because it's likely everything
is going into the drink.
Speaking of drink,
here's to adventure.
Yeah!
Adventure.
[ Dog Barking ln Distance ]
What do you think?
I think it's an idea
whose time has come.
[ Chuckles ]
No, I mean-- I mean,
do you think it'll sell?
The agent said
it needed a paint job.
Oh, get what you can
and get out.
Leave the memories behind.
You didn't after Hannah died.
Yeah, but I didn't have corpses
playing ventriloquist
with me either.
[ Both Laughing ]
I'm gonna miss you, Joe.
I'm gonna
miss your waffles.
Would you show it for me
if I'm gone for a week?
- I'm taking that white-water trip.
- With pleasure.
It's good to see you
joining the world again.
[ Car Door Opens,
Closes ]
[ Lightbulb Crackling ]
[ Lightbulb Pops ]
[ Clattering, Footsteps ]
[ Front Door Creaking ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Wind Chimes Jingling ]
[ Hal ] Hello.
Hal. Reading the map
of the river...
there's a symbol--
two wavery lines that
crisscross in the middle.
Waterfalls. Put a big
red circle around those.
We'll have to portage there.
They're too high
this time of year.
Joe?
A rainbow.
You are, uh,
the doctor?
Yes.
Muy bien.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Is my pilot here?
That is me.
Eh, Victor.
¿Cómo te vas?
I take you bags.
You been flying long,
Victor?
Don't worry.
I know how.
You have a license,
though, right?
;Sí.
Pretty much.
Juanajuapa.
Juanajuapa,
you've been there?
Sí, Juanajuapa.
This is it, right?
With the waterfall?
I don't know.
I've only been there
in the dry season.
Is my interpreter here?
The Yanomami
speak a little Spanish.
I speak a little Guaharibo.
You talk to them
through me.
Okay, we go.
Is that your girlfriend?
ln the picture?
It's my wife.
Used to be.
You come
to get her back, eh?
In a way, I guess.
There was an accident
here last spring.
A bus?
That washed away
on a road?
La Cruz Roja.
The Red Cross.
Yes, that's right.
You can probably see it
now that the river's
not so high.
It's just up ahead.
It's on the way.
The rock slide took more
than just a bus.
It isolated an entire tribe
from the outside world.
Can you see it
down there?
Nobody lived.
The Yanomami are still wearing
some of their clothing.
That's Juanajuapa
up ahead.
Some of the bodies
washed out of the bus...
down the river
and right into the village.
[ Victor ]
The guides we are meeting...
they work with
all the tribes
in the area.
Did I mention
they don't like outsiders?
It's a good thing
you have me with you.
[ Speaking Native Language ]
He said he cannot take you
to the village.
But, for a price,
he can take you
to their graves.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Señor.
We should go.
They, uh...
they wouldn't know,
would they, which, uh...
body was buried where?
Look. If--
If the weather gets...
any worse,
we don't get outta here.
And-- And that's
no good for nobody.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Speaking Native Language ]
Señors.
Señors, uh...
my wife.
Su esposa.
Mi esposa.
Red Cross.
- La Cruz Roja.
- Cruz Roja. Where?
¿Dónde?
Does any--
Does anybody know where?
[ Speaking Native Language ]
Which one?
- What are they saying?
- They say they know her.
[ Speaking Native Language ]
What's he saying now?
He says he wants to
take you to the village.
And he says that, no,
you need permission.
- [ Speaking Native Language ]
- What is he saying?
What the hell is he saying?
- I-l don't know!
- [ Speaking Native Language ]
Señor!
Señor, you cannot
go into the village!
It is forbidden, señor!
Señor! Señor, stop!
Señor, we can return
with government people...
but you must come back
with me now.
I said now, señor!
No, no, no, no jump!
[ Gasping ]
[ Metal Grinding ]
[ Ben's Voice ]
She wants you to go there.
[ Jeffrey's Voice ] Joe.
- [ Miriam ] Join her.
- [ Jeffrey ] Joe!
- [ Emily ] Joe!
[ Jeffrey ]
Joe, can't you hear me?
[ Emily ]
Joe?
[ Madeline ] A hundred steps
on the ladder of consciousness.
[ Ben ] Go there.
[ Miriam ]
No survivors.
[ Joe ] Where's her body?
- [ Miriam ]
Think she's still alive.
- [ Joe ] Emily!
- [ Emily ] Joe?
- Listen to me!
[ People Screaming ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Coughing ]
You are one crazy
son of a bitch,
you know that?
You are lucky
to be alive, señor.
You were not breathing.
It's been over an hour.
Get up.
We will cross the river
downstream.
And with a little bit of luck,
we can get to the airstrip
before nightfall.
Vamonos.
She lived through
the bus accident.
She made it
to the village.
No, you cannot
go to the village!
Stop! I cannot
go back without you!
They'll take away my license!
Stop, señor!
Señor! Señor, stop!
Don't do this!
[ Tapping ]
[ Tapping Continues ]
Señor!
The man said
we must have permission.
I've got permission.
No one's keeping me
out of there.
[ Yelling ln Native Language ]
Please. My wife.
Did you know her?
Mi-- Mi esposa.
Mi esposa.
[ Speaking Native Language ]
Doctore.
- [ Speaking Native Language ]
- Doctore. Mi esposa.
Mi esposa.
The waterfall.
She was here.
[ Speaking Native Language ]
She say
they knew her alive.
She came to help them...
until the river
brought her back...
dying.
[ Woman Speaking
Native Language ]
They could not save
her body...
but they save her soul.
[ Speaking Native Language ]
[ Baby Gurgling ]
[ Baby Cooing ]
[ Speaking Native Language ]
She said, "dragonfly."
[ Joe Narrating ]
I don't know if Emily
ever saw her...
at least while she was
of mind and body.
And I don't know
how the baby survived--
premature--
so small and fragile
in the middle of the jungle.
What I do know is
that Emily made sure our child
found her way into my arms.
What she taught me in life,
she taught me in death--
to trust, to have faith.
Because as a friend
of mine once said...
[ Gurgling ]
"It's belief
that gets us there. "
? Come ?
? Come out and play ?
? We miss your face ?
? And the funny things you say ?
? Be ?
? Just be yourself ?
? And nothing else ?
? Will push you away ?
? And I feel ?
? So much love ?
? When it's all mixed up ?
? It wraps itself around me ?
? Star ?
? We knew you well ?
? Yeah, all too well ?
? And there's nothing left to hide ?
? Don't hide ?
? And I feel ?
? So much love ?
? When it's all mixed up ?
? It wraps itself around me ?
? And when you get what you want ?
? When you know what you need ?
? And you tag me I'm it ?
? Olly-ox and you're free ?
? Let me play on your side ?
? Let me be on your team ?
? Let me state my case ?
? Don't go away ?
? Find ?
? What you already are ?
? Where it's not too close ?
? But never too far ?
? Don't go too far, too far ?
? And I feel ?
? So much love ?
? When it's all mixed up and ?
? Wraps itself around me ?
? Me, me ?
? And I feel ?
? So much love ?
? When it's all mixed up ?
? It wraps itself around me ?
? And I feel ?
? So much love ?
? When it's all mixed up ?
? It wraps itself around ?
? Me ?