(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
(KNOCKING)
Okay, I'm going to ask you
to take a deep breath in.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
And you can let it go.
(EXHALES FORCEFULLY)
Should I do it again?
No, one is good.
WOMAN: ...upset about?
Apparently...
...we had this fundraiser...
...and I brought cupcakes,
she brought cake pops.
And she's like,
"That's too similar."
I'm like,
"No, a cupcake is a cupcake.
A cake pop is cake
with a stick in it."
Cynthia? I'm going to ask you
to scooch down the table...
Mmm-hmm.
...and turn over, please.
We are grown women and we're
fighting about cake pops.
Let's get over it already!
But the real issue is...
...her daughter Alicia
is a very nice girl,
but not very smart,
whereas my daughter...
Hey, Eva.
Nice to see you.
Hey.
Come on up.
How's everything?
Great.
Excuse me.
ELLEN: Hey, Mom.
Where are you going?
To a party with Sarah and Will,
so they don't have to be alone.
Want to come?
Why?
Because you're leaving soon,
and I want to be with you.
I'm good, thanks.
Have fun.
Thanks, honey.
SARAH: She's driving
us totally crazy.
We can't find anything.
She puts things in
the weirdest places.
Like, if I leave my
bracelet in the kitchen,
she'll put it in
a kitchen drawer!
Why can't you just do it?
I always do it. I fired the gardener.
It's not fair.
We want to fire her,
and he won't do it.
It's not hard for you. Why
does it have to be fair?
You should do it because
it's hard for you.
Oh, please.
You're a grownup.
You can fire a maid.
That's the definition
of maturity?
Firing your friggin' maid?
Sarah, is this
color good on me?
You look good.
You look pretty.
WILL: That's good.
That's a nice look.
Whose party is this, anyway?
He's a book editor and she's an
interior designer. They know everybody.
Maybe some single men are here.
No.
Oh, shit, I see a patient.
EVA: Oh,
will you show me?
Show me who.
Come on, introduce me.
Stop looking. No.
God, you're such a wet blanket.
Oh, lookit! There's that
lady from my gym. What is...
Okay, bye.
Bye.
What is her name?
Oh, it's Hilary.
Hilary? Hilary!
Eva! Hi.
It's so weird to see you here.
Eva, this is Marianne.
Marianne, Eva.
How are you? Good.
Nice to meet you.
Eva is an incredible,
incredible masseuse.
Wonderful.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me a second. I have,
I have to find a bathroom.
That was abrupt.
Oh, my goodness! Look at
those shoes and that outfit.
With the purse?
It looks so nice.
Thank you. I should
bring you everywhere.
I love your outfit, too. Oh.
So you're a masseuse?
I am, yeah.
Yeah?
And what is it you do?
I'm a poet.
Oh. And I'm a dreamer.
No, really.
You're really a poet?
I am.
You do it for a living?
I do.
Wow!
You do, I don't. You're
a poet, now I know it.
Good one.
Feel free to steal it. (LAUGHS)
Can I give that to you?
Thank you.
Guess what?
What? I think I just
got a new client.
Yeah? Where?
Ah, right there.
WILL: She looks clean.
She's really nice and funny,
she's got great taste.
And very attractive.
I bet you think all the
women here are attractive.
Pretty much.
Hold this. There's not one man
at this party I'm attracted to.
MAN: Will.
Hey! Jason!
This is Albert.
Hi.
How's it going?
How are you? Hi.
So, this is a nice party. Got all
the nice white balls hanging down.
Eva was just telling
me that there are
no men at the party
she's attracted to.
Okay.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't know why you would
make that announcement, but...
Is that unusual?
No, actually, it's not unusual.
No offense.
No, that's okay. There's no one
here I'm attracted to, either.
Yeah, it's kind of
an ugly crowd, really.
Jason, you have a kid
in college, right?
Two. Yeah.
I have one leaving in the fall.
I do, too!
That's all I have.
Me, too.
Come on. Your kids are supposed to go away.
That's healthy.
No. Shut up.
Yeah, shut up.
(LAUGHS)
Do the guys get boners? No.
Haven't we been over this? Yes.
I get so nervous with massages.
I'm afraid I'm
going to get a boner.
You are? Absolutely. Absolutely.
Do they hit on you?
Okay, you're starting
to depress me.
No, they don't hit on me.
They don't get boners, either.
I do have one guy who has like a hundred
stairs going up to his house...
...and he never helps me
carry my massage table.
Did you ever ask him to?
She shouldn't have to!
No, I shouldn't have to!
Bye, guys.
Thank you. Love you.
(BELL RINGING)
Bye, honey!
Bye, Eva!
Thanks for the ride.
You're welcome, Chloe.
Oh, Maddy Price!
You littered, honey.
(IN FAKE ACCENT)
What did you say?
I said, pick up your trash.
You're not British.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) What a bitch.
(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
Come on in.
Thank you.
Nice to see you.
You, too.
You can just put your table
clown there if you want.
Would you mind
taking your shoes off?
Not at all.
Thank you.
And your socks, too.
Do you want some iced tea?
That sounds good.
Thank you.
I'm so happy you called.
Most people usually just
take my card to be polite.
MARIANNE: Well,
I'm not polite.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my, isn't this nice!
Wow.
Thank you!
Just make yourself
at home, look around.
I'm going to go change.
Everything is so pretty!
Can I live here?
That tea's kind
of fabulous, too.
I'm dating this guy.
He has no sense of humor.
That can be a dealbreaker.
I don't know what to
do... he's very sweet.
Sweet can be good.
Maybe you can find someone
else to tell you jokes.
Are you married?
Divorced. Ten years.
Are you still friends?
No, not really.
We share a daughter,
but other than that...
...it's hard to believe that I
ever had a laugh with that man...
...let alone
create a child.
I know what you mean about your ex.
We had zero in common.
I don't know how lever had a
real conversation with him.
It's crazy, right?
I'd like to call you pretty
soon if it's all right.
My right shoulder
is still very tight.
You should ice it tonight.
And drink plenty of water.
It's important
to stay hydrated.
Of course. Hey, do you want some chervil?
I'm drowning in it.
Sure.
I'll just give
you what I've cut.
I don't have anything
to put it in, but...
Oh, that's ideal.
Thank you.
Lovely. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
What is chervil? She said
she was drowning in it.
(PRONOUNCING H) It's a herb.
A what? (DROPPING H) An herb.
How long have you known me?
I can't understand
a damn thing you say.
Oh, my God.
Everything in that house was gorgeous.
I wanted everything.
She has no cellulite!
How can that be?
I've never seen
anything like it.
Nothing.
Will told me some guy you met
at the party wants your number.
Jason's friend, I think.
That's so funny. We both said we
weren't attracted to each other.
I don't know what to do.
He's kind of fat.
He is?
He's got this big belly.
Well, you've got
nothing to lose.
No, but he does.
(LAUGHING)
Your light came on.
You got a patient.
Better get a move on.
What happens if you
never go out there?
Do they...
(IMITATES GUNSHOT)
Was that inappropriate?
Bye.
I'm sorry about this. I swear to
God I made a dinner reservation.
No, it's okay.
It's fine.
What about you?
What do you do?
I work at the American
Library of Cultural History.
The what? Exactly. It's kind
of a television library.
Do you watch a lot of TV?
No, it's television history.
What's on now, I have no clue.
I tried to watch one of those
Housewives of Idiot Town...
...but I got so depressed, I thought
I was going to jump off a building.
I know what you mean. I tried to
watch one with my daughter...
...and I could not believe
what I was watching!
No brains, and the fake
cheekbones and fake boobs.
Do you like fake boobs?
No. I like real boobs.
I have real boobs.
That's working out for us then.
(CHUCKLING)
How long have
you been divorced?
About four years.
Was it mutual?
Not really. No.
Can I have her number?
Of course.
Imagine the time
that would save.
We should all put
a sign on our necks
with what's wrong with us.
Get it all out there.
Good idea. What
would your sign say?
I don't know. I'm a slob.
I have ear hair.
There are things
to get rid of that.
Researched, taken care of.
So you're a slob, huh?
Not like a dirty hoarder slob.
What kind?
A normal disorganized one.
Does your daughter
live with you?
Half the time.
It aggravates her sometimes. She and
her mother are very, very neat.
As a matter of fact,
their favorite store...
...I don't know,
it's... it's the store
with all the empty
boxes and storage.
The Container Store?
Yes. The Container Store.
The store that sells crap you can put
your crap in so you can buy more crap.
I love that store!
I love crap.
So did my ex-wife, and she puts it in
lovely, flowery and expensive boxes.
You should know, they have things
in sort of manly designs there.
Manly designs?
Yeah, like browns,
and little cowboy designs.
Little cowboys.
I mean, come on. It's hard
to live with somebody,
don't you think?
People's habits are...
Okay, listen to this.
I like guacamole.
But I don't like the onions in
guacamole, so I take a chip...
...and swirl it
around and separate
the onions from
the guacamole...
...so I can eat it. Now,
that drove her bananas.
It sounds pretty harmless.
I thought so, but by the end of
our marriage, it made her gag.
That's not nice.
You have...
...lovely hands.
I thought, as a masseuse,
you'd have big,
muscular hands,
but they're very lovely.
Thank you.
You have nice hands, too.
Kind of like paddles.
(CHUCKLES)
(BACKGROUND MUSIC
VOLUME INCREASES)
Did they just turn
the music louder?
No, I think you just got older.
(LAUGHING)
Excuse me! Do you mind turning
down the music a little?
I'm old.
No, I'm sorry.
No, you're sorry I'm old or that
you won't turn the music down?
I'm not allowed to
change it, ma'am.
He's so nice!
I find I don't
like younger people.
Eh?
I'm sorry, I picked
the wrong restaurant.
I'm having a great time.
This is delicious.
I can't hear what
you're saying, but...
That's probably why you're
having a great time.
What is this, tomatoes?
Tomatoes?
It's watermelon.
That's croutons next to it.
Doesn't that
defeat the purpose?
It's nonfat yogurt, not ice cream.
You can put stuff on it.
That looks good, man.
What? What?
People tasting?
ALBERT: Take a chance.
Put something in your bowl.
You're not buying a house.
He's happy.
I know. Give me this.
They have to test the flavors,
there's millions of them.
Very Berry Sorbet, and...
This is my daughter.
Wowie kazowie!
She's stunning! Lucky you.
She looks like her
mother, thank God.
Here's mine.
Right there.
She's beautiful.
You got any money?
I'm kidding.
Oh, my God.
(LAUGHS)
I had such a good time.
That was really fun.
I thought so, too.
I'm not sure.
Okay.
I mean...
...I mean, maybe.
I understand.
It's just... I'm not sure.
I get it.
I'm not deaf.
I'm a little deaf in...
Thank you very much.
I like your paddles.
I like your ass.
(LAUGHS)
My God.
Well, thank you.
Good night.
Hi!
Hi.
How was it?
Fine.
I mean, if he hooks up with someone
else, I'll feel like an idiot.
So don't do it.
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
I can't decide if I should
sleep with Chris or not.
I don't want to do
something I'll regret...
...but I also really like him,
so I don't know what to do.
And you're a virgin?
Yeah.
Don't answer that!
Here's what I say. You can't live
in fear of making a mistake.
If you want to do it, do it.
Mom.
What?
Stay out of it.
Ellen, honey, she asked me.
She did?
Right, Chloe? No?
My bad.
Quiet.
EVA: Ellen, I forgot to ask...
...what happened
to Maddy Price?
She was so rude to
me the other day!
CHLOE: She had a threesome with
Sage Berger and Brendon Weiss...
she thinks she's Taylor Momsen.
ELLEN: Don't tell my mom!
She can tell me stuff.
You never do.
Wait a minute.
They had a threesome?
ELLEN: Forget it, Mom.
What is happening?
Is everybody doing it?
ELLEN: Mom, shut up!
Come out!
You look beautiful!
Look at you two.
Come on!
We're not buying
the same dress, Mom!
We won't wear it
at the same time.
But you look stupid.
I think I look good.
You're so lumpy!
I'd wear that if I could.
Thank you.
No, you wouldn't.
Mom, you look crazy.
You are not the only attractive
girl in this family, Chloe.
Why can't you dress like Ellen's mom?
She looks normal.
So what happened
with not-so-funny guy?
MARIANNE: It didn't work out.
Oh.
No, it's fine.
What about you?
Do you have a boyfriend?
I had a very good first
date over the weekend.
Oh, how nice!
What's he like?
Funny.
We really never
stopped talking.
It was like we were
old friends already.
Be careful with that, 'cause
it could kill the chemistry.
No, no.
In a good way.
Really. I mean, it was just...
it was very flirtatious.
I didn't find him
attractive at first,
because he's not handsome
in the typical way.
But, um...
...I don't know... now I
find him kind of... sexy.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hi.
Did I get the day wrong?
No. Why?
Because you're wearing pajamas?
It's just brunch. It's Sunday.
I like to be comfortable.
Oh, good. Okay.
Come on in.
I got us that.
I'll make us some mimosas.
This is nice.
Thank you.
You carry a purse?
No, that's my daughter Tess's.
It was outrageously expensive, but
it was her 18th birthday, so...
Oh, my God! Bagels!
I love bread.
I really love it.
So, what's she like?
Your daughter.
She's very sophisticated... as
you can tell by the pocketbook.
"Pocketbook".
She's smart, lovely and funny,
and she's moving to New York.
Very far away.
It is far.
She's going to Parsons
School of Design. Oh!
I'm very proud of her.
I bet. I would be.
But part of me thinks
that I shouldn't let her go.
She's 18 and this is
a great opportunity...
...but if something
happens to her...
...while she's in New York,
I will never forgive myself.
Come on. But I know
what you mean.
This going away
to college thing.
We just send them off? And not
know where they are all the time?
Aside from the fact
that I don't know
what my life will be
like when she's gone.
And Ellen doesn't
want her dad and me
to take her there.
We take her...
...to the airport here,
but don't fly with her.
That would kill me...
just put her on the plane?
Heartbreaking.
We're going to have
to develop hobbies.
I guess so.
I already have one,
'cause I knit.
So I'll just spend the rest of my
life knitting. That's my plan.
That's funny because...
actually, I weave.
Like baskets?
Yeah, I do it in the garage.
Really!
No.
(LAUGHS)
Why would you think I'd weave?
I thought you were...
I didn't want to insult you.
I'm kind of glad you don't weave.
Me, too.
I've been picturing what it's going
to be like for her not to be here.
Even though she's only here half
the time, it'll be very different.
I can see your penis.
My God!
Your pajama thing
is a little bit open.
Shit! I'm very sorry.
What did you think?
(STAMMERING) I think
you are very healthy.
Thank you.
Go change your pants.
Be right back.
(GROANS)
What happened to you guys? Not
the details, just general...
We were... very different.
We never had sex.
Not my choice.
She just had no interest in it.
And I'm pretty sure
she had an affair.
Which was awful,
because it meant
that she did like sex,
she just didn't
like it with me.
You. Right.
She thought my job was stupid.
She thought I parented badly.
I thought she parented badly.
Why are you
wrecking my backyard?
You have a lot of weeds.
I thought this was all good.
No.
We never had sex, either.
Not his choice.
We were pretty out of
sync in that department.
We were pretty out of sync with Ellen, too.
Oh, my God...
...fought all the time
about how to parent.
That's good grass
you're pulling up.
I'll put it back.
Jesus.
Got yourself a...
blister thing going on?
Yeah.
Are you grossed out?
No.
You are. Are you
freaked out by my feet?
I have a little
problem with feet.
Have you looked
at your own feet?
I'm used to my feet.
Okay, well...
What's the deal?
It has to do with my mother.
She had feet?
She had spectacular feet.
Here we go.
They were red and
yellow and green
and purple and
swollen with veins.
I get it.
Don't do that.
I have to. I've never
had a pedicure.
I never saw the point
until this actual moment.
Would you like a Band-Aid?
Please!
That would be great.
And maybe a bag for my foot.
Stop it.
Two bags. Two bags
for the old bag.
I knew I shouldn't
have told you.
They're naked, right?
Yeah.
Are you ever attracted to them?
No.
I'm sure they're
attracted to you.
They're getting massaged.
Do they ever hit on you?
Sometimes, yeah.
I can give you a massage
some time, if you want.
I might like that.
I would definitely hit on you.
That might be okay.
Really?
Want a kiss?
Yeah.
You didn't actually open your
eyes at any point, did you?
No. No worries.
I kept my eyes closed.
I figured...
...if I couldn't see you,
you couldn't see me.
Oh, I saw you.
Oh, God.
I'm tired of being funny.
Me, too.
But you're not funny.
SARAH: I'm so excited for you.
He sounds great.
He is great. It was so cute...
he made a whole bruncheon.
Sweet.
Yeah, it was sweet.
Okay, good.
(WHISPERS)
We had such good sex.
(MOANS)
How fun.
I can't even imagine.
What do you think?
I liked how it was before. You're
going to give yourself a hernia.
Okay, you guys are done.
Thanks for your help.
Take your drawing
in the kitchen.
You can watch TV,
but no Cleveland Show.
KIDS: Please, Mom?
Okay.
Jeez. Way to
put your foot down.
I'm too tired to
be a good parent.
Maybe because you're
always moving furniture.
Hi, Cathy!
Hola.
You have no idea. Will
refused to fire her...
...so I let it go, hoping she'd get better.
But she got worse.
It was like she wanted to be fired.
She did such dumb stuff.
That is so interesting.
So I fired her. And she started crying.
Then I started crying.
Then we were hugging and...
I hired her back.
Of course you did.
You're nice.
Right? Some people would see
me as being compassionate
or soft-hearted.
Will thinks I'm a baby.
He wants me to fire her again
as a learning experience!
Jesus Christ!
That's our relationship.
Not your whole relationship.
Whatever.
He's a middle child who never got
enough fried chicken at dinner
and needs everything
to be fair.
Miss Sarah? Where should I put this?
It was in the bathroom.
Outside, with the
ping pong table.
Okay. No problem.
Jesus.
ALBERT: Wow.
I've never actually
seen wisdom teeth.
You do have a lot of fillings.
Are they the mercury kind?
The normal kind.
And a couple of crowns.
Yeah. Okay, your turn.
Well, I'd rather you didn't.
Well, I'd rather I did.
I'm going to get my glasses.
Come on. Open your mouth! No.
Open your mouth.
Make me.
Okay.
Oh, my God!
You're missing a tooth?
You are!
Yes, I am.
Let me see.
You can't tell... it's way back there.
It doesn't matter.
I need some kind of
hideous bone graft.
It costs a lot of money
and I'm putting it off.
My grandma Dee Dee had that.
Your grandma Dee Dee.
Thank you for that. Thanks.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, I'm so sorry!
It's okay. This is Ellen's best friend,
Chloe. This is my friend, Albert.
Hi.
Ellen didn't answer my texts.
I thought she was sleeping.
She's at her dad's, honey.
Is everything okay?
I thought we were
getting breakfast.
You hungry?
Let's see.
From 1975, Channel 4.
Well, what time?
Oh, come on.
Saturday morning.
Woody Woodpecker, Pink Panther,
McDuff, the Talking Dog...
...which I didn't
like but watched anyway,
Monster Squad,
Land of the Lost, then...
...Big John, Little John, which was
like the movie Big, but weirder.
That's incredible.
I thought I watched
a lot of TV!
I looked forward
to that lineup.
What, were you
neglected as a kid?
I was kind of
raised like a veal.
I was put in a dark room...
...fed and told
not to move.
Very relaxing.
(EXHALES)
CYNTHIA: ...and she's like, "I
might want to get another size",
but that's bullshit,
it is the right size.
She's petite, but very heavy
on top, so I got a medium!
But here's the thing,
I got it at Nordstrom Rack,
but I put it in
a Neiman Marcus box...
(ALARM BEEPING)
Oh, yeah, that's good.
Don't open the door.
Just pretend you
don't know I'm here...
...even though you
heard me lock my car.
Wow!
Amazing.
So what do you
do with all this?
Do you really want to hear this?
Yeah. I do. What?
I make sure things are
transferred to digital properly.
I make sure they' re logged in properly.
I write blurbs...
...so if anyone under 50 wants to
put down their phone and come in...
...and watch something original
and brilliant, they can find it.
Like what, for instance?
The Sid Caesar show.
The Jack Benny show.
The Dean Martin show.
So cool.
Yeah, it is.
I kind of love it.
On slow days...
...I can sit in my office and watch
episodes of What's Happening!!
No, you don't.
Well, if things...
This is my office.
That's Bob. Hey.
Did you ever see Flipper?
Of course I did.
Oh, God. It made me want a
dolphin as a pet so bad.
Really? That's
a lot of work.
(PERSON BLOWING NOSE)
What is that noise?
(MAN CRYING)
Somebody watching something.
It happens occasionally.
It's Taxi. The episode
where Alex's dog dies.
Buddy or Buster or something.
You hungry?
Starving.
Let's get lunch.
ALBERT: There she is!
Right on time.
Hi, honey.
Hi, Dad.
So, Eva...
Tess. Tess, Eva.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
You, too.
Seriously?
They have great chili!
I love chili.
Have you ever been to Lilly's?
No.
It's so good.
It's around the corner.
Lilly's it is.
I'll be studying
fashion design.
You obviously have good taste.
Thank you.
Eva has a daughter your age going
to college in the fall also.
She's going to Sarah Lawrence.
She's interested in English and history.
She loves history!
I think she wants
to be a writer.
Sarah Lawrence is
not what it used to be.
I mean, I'm sure
it's still good.
It's just gone downhill a lot in the
last few years. Some of my, um...
...let's just say not-so-smart
friends just got in. I was shocked.
I'm sure a lot of smart people
still go there. Oh, yeah.
I know. I'm just saying.
I think you should stay
home and go to school here.
At least you're
honest about it.
Mom acts like she's excited to be on
her own again, but I don't buy it.
Why don't we take it a little easy on Mom.
She's all right.
Don't judge till you
have kids of your own.
Except I'm not having any.
And why do you say that?
I want a career.
Anyway, I hate kids.
Really?
Right now we
have that in common.
TESS: Corey?
Listen, she doesn't know
what she's talking about.
She's too young to
know what she wants.
Dad, I'm going to go
get a coffee, okay?
Bye. Thank you
for lunch.
So nice to meet you.
You, too.
Yeah. Great.
Bye!
Bye.
Be careful!
She has a lot of friends.
EVA: You think she
has threesomes?
What? Why would
you say that?
I know, but apparently, it's
what they're doing these days.
That's what I heard.
Oh, my God.
Right?
I'm afraid that
window's closed.
There was a window?
How was the daughter?
Kind of awful, actually.
A real snob.
That's too bad.
I wonder what your
roommate will be like?
Me, too.
You want me to
call her parents?
No, I don't.
You hungry, honey?
Not really.
What did you eat yesterday?
I don't know.
Well, think. Tell me.
I want to know what you ate.
Cereal...
...a banana...
Where'd you get the banana?
Mom, you're crazy!
What?
What'd you have for lunch?
Okay, bye.
Where are you going?
I mean, he's kind of flabby and
middle-aged, but I don't care.
I'm flabby and
middle-aged.
It's funny, because our
middle-agedness is...
...comforting, and sexy to me.
Isn't that so incredibly sad?
But sort of good, too.
Yeah. I think that my ex, all he
wanted was for me to accept...
...his belly and
all his quirks.
In the end, I was completely
repulsed by him sexually.
Kind of terrible in bed
and just very clumsy.
Oh, no.
Just a sec.
Here. It's my last copy, but I
really want you to have it.
Wow! Are you sure?
Absolutely.
Oh, wow.
I'm a little intimidated. I'm
not really good with poetry.
Just let it wash over you.
Don't try to understand it.
I won't, believe me.
God, thank you so much!
I've loved our time together.
I know.
Do you think it would be weird
if we hung out as friends?
I would love that!
I would!
I want you to try this salsa,
'cause these tomatoes are amazing.
But careful! There's
a ton of onions.
One of the many
upsides to my divorce.
What do you mean? My ex hated
onions, so he would take a chip...
...and he would put it in the
salsa and tap, tap, tap...
...swirl, tap, tap, tap,
swirl, and so on,
until all the onions
were pushed...
...up against the side!
It kind of made me sick.
GIRL: Mom?
That's my daughter... she's not
feeling well. Be right back.
Hi, honey.
GIRL: Hi.
I don't feel good.
I feel... Right here.
Let me see.
They're swollen.
Listen, will you come meet my friend?
Just for a second, please?
Eva?
That's so weird, she was just here.
I'm going back to bed.
I love you. I love you, too.
You have bad breath.
I'm sick!
God!
Hi.
This planting I'm
admiring, it's so huge!
Thank you.
I wanted you to meet my
daughter Tess, but...
I have to go.
Okay!
Yeah. Okay.
Great!
All right.
So I'll call you and
we'll do something.
Wonderful.
Thank you so much!
It was so nice!
Thank you so much.
Have a great day.
Great, great, great!
MARIANNE: Bye-bye.
Are you okay?
I got it!
(EXHALES)
Do you believe that?
I am not shitting you!
Thai is an unbelievable coincidence.
What will you do?
I don't know!
Oh, shit! Your light went on.
Can you call me back, please?
Hi, Mom!
Hi! Did you take
your shoes off?
No. Since when
do I have to?
We're doing that now. It's cleaner.
And your socks, too.
You are not going
to believe this.
It turns out that the woman I've
been massaging is Albert's ex-wife.
Weird!
So weird.
I have been listening to her say the
worst things about the one guy...
...I started to really,
really like.
And I pictured the ex she was
talking about as this fat...
...irritating slob...
...and it turns
out it's Albert!
Fat Albert!
What? Who?
It's a cartoon. A cartoon!
But he's so not like that.
How do you know?
We had breakfast the other day.
He's sweet, funny.
Yeah, you liked him, right?
Totally.
Wait, what?
You weren't here.
We all had breakfast.
I haven't even met him.
Well, you will.
What did she say about him?
Oh, my God!
It's like this parade of horribles!
He's disgusting.
That he's like
this clown in bed.
Mom! Oh, my God!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I date sometimes. It's just
so hard to meet people.
And I'm not
attracted to anybody.
Really?
Really.
And you weren't attracted to your
ex-husband? That must have been difficult.
Well, I tried
really hard. I did.
But he would go on so many diets,
and then he would cheat...
...and then he would act
shocked when he got fatter.
...the behavior
around the weight.
Excuse me.
Are you Marianne Hope?
Yes.
Oh, my God!
I told you.
You are like our biggest idol.
This means so much to us.
She gave me a copy of Beautiful
Fruit when my mom died.
It saved me.
How wonderful.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, thank you.
Well, thanks very much.
Blessings.
Take care.
Blessings!
It's so cool
that you saved her.
But, he never got obese, right?
Well, it depends on your
definition of the word obese.
But initially,
um... you were...
...I don't know, you
liked him, more or less?
Unfortunately... less.
There were just so many things
that really got on my nerves.
Like what, though?
Sorry I'm being so negative.
I really am.
It's okay. It is.
It's just that I don't
really have anybody
I can bitch to
about things like this.
You can completely
bitch to me. Really.
Thank you.
Oh, sure.
I trust you.
Oh, good.
I do.
What's wrong with you? She
can find another masseuse.
I'm her friend. She doesn't
have any close friends.
I'm like it.
I feel so pulled in. She's
like a human Trip Advisor.
Albert is not a hotel.
But if you could avoid staying
in a bad one, wouldn't you?
Oh, my God.
She has said so many
bad things about him.
She's not perfect.
But she knows what she's talking about.
She's smart.
So are you.
Maybe she's ultimately right.
Are you right about Peter? You didn't
want him... does that make him unlovable?
By anyone normal.
You haven't said anything about
my furniture arrangement.
I don't remember
how it was before.
Hey! What do you think?
Oh, honey. Why do you
keep doing this?
She's filling a hole.
I'll fill your hole.
Different hole.
You're missing out.
Fun time!
Hi!
Whose car is this?
Tess is getting hers fixed.
This is a rental.
Sorry.
Why do you have it?
I'm letting her drive mine.
She likes it better.
Yeah, I bet she does.
You okay?
Yeah.
(ENGINE RATTLES)
What was that?
The gear skrinkle.
"Skrinkle?"
Why are you shaking that?
It spreads the butter around.
You put more butter on that?
No, I put regular butter. I asked for
butter. I didn't put more butter.
Oh, I thought it
came with butter.
This actor, I saw him
in a restaurant.
He was about three
and a half feet tall.
You need to whisper, okay?
What is she wearing?
It looks like her aunt
crocheted something
to put over a plant.
Shh!
You got to whisper.
I am whispering.
I'm whispering.
No.
ALBERT: I want to
ask you something.
And I really want the truth.
Okay?
Can you breathe
when I'm on top of you?
Yeah!
I'm planning on losing some weight.
I know I need to.
Was it an issue with your ex-wife?
Oh, my God!
Sometimes I ate
just to drive her nuts.
(CHUCKLES)
(BREATHING LOUDLY)
You have a cold?
No. No, I...
I broke my nose a couple times.
My doctor says at this point,
my nose is purely ornamental.
(LAUGHS)
Will you get it fixed?
Yeah, after the missing tooth.
You know, I think
Tess really liked you.
I could tell.
She seems so neat.
She really is a great girl.
I know she can be obnoxious
sometimes, but...
...she's young. She's really got a
good heart. She'll figure it out.
I kind of adore you already.
So what about you and Chris?
What's going on?
What? What?
We did it.
Really?
How was it?
Nice. I think.
No, it was good.
Congratulations.
I'm happy it was nice.
Even if we don't stay together,
I'm glad I got it over with.
I'm glad I took your advice.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey! Hi, honey.
When did you get here?
A couple of minutes ago.
Just waiting for you.
Look.
I've wanted to paint your
nails for like ten years.
I thought you
were too ticklish.
EVA: I know!
She's in love.
So I guess that
makes you not ticklish.
You weren't here.
Come be with us.
Actually, I have some...
CHLOE: Come on, Ellen.
Come back.
MARIANNE: Crazy day.
I had a wonderful call from
Joni Mitchell this morning.
She read the galleys to my new collection
and loved them, so that was...
You're friends
with Joni Mitchell?
Yeah, we have been for a while.
Do you want some water?
No, thank you.
And I met a guy!
A really nice guy.
He takes really good care
of himself. He's vegan...
...and he actually read
my work before he met me.
A poetry-reading vegan.
Oh, my God!
MARIANNE: I hope it goes well.
I tend to get my hopes
up a little early.
I just don't want to
be disappointed again.
With Albert, there was
always this bait and switch.
When we first started
dating, I thought,
"Oh, he's mature.
He can buy a house."
This house?
Yes!
But you should see where he lives now.
And he made...
...this dish of spaghetti
with eggplant and mozzarella.
Sounds kind of delicious.
But it turned out that
was all he could cook.
And he has no friends.
I mean, neither do I, but...
Well, me and Joni.
Yeah. That's true!
That's true, that's true.
Hi.
Hungry?
Yes.
Get ready for some
eggplant with mozzarella!
You okay?
Yeah.
Wow! This is
actually delicious!
Why do you sound surprised?
It's great.
How was work today?
Good.
I had two massages.
Barnacles?
Non-stop talking?
Boners?
There was this nice woman
in Santa Monica.
She talked a lot
about her ex-husband.
I just hope it
wasn't my ex-wife.
(COUGHING)
I got you a little present.
You did?
Now, it's just
a little present.
Oh, my God!
I saw it and thought of you.
This beautiful, wonderful...
I can't do it,
but let me help you.
Oh, my God.
Thank you so much.
Look.
Do you like it on me?
It's nice.
Maybe I shouldn't have?
Is it too soon?
No. It's just so nice.
Thank you.
Oh!
What?
Nothing.
You all right? Yeah. I don't
know what that was. Sorry.
Let me get here.
You okay?
(GIGGLING)
Stop! Stop!
Your beard is so tickly.
Sorry.
That's okay.
Okay, here I come again.
Oh, goodie.
Oh, my hair!
My hair, my hair!
I don't know what I'm doing, but this isn't
going very well, so let's just stop.
What?
You look cute in my robe.
Is everything okay? You have
like four hundred mouthwashes.
Yeah, I need to use them and...
...then I buy them and then I forget
about them and then I buy more of them.
And you have like 80
million toothbrushes.
I do?
I only use one of them.
So why don't you throw
the other ones out?
I don't know. Because...
they're my friends?
Are you all right?
You want to take
another shot at it?
I'm just...
I'm kind of tired.
Is that okay?
It's okay.
FRAN: You looked
so pretty.
Seriously, kiddo,
I'm proud of you.
Thank you, Dad.
We are so proud.
We have some graduation
money for you.
Thank you, Fran, Dad.
It's in fives.
Thank you for including me.
You really have
a fight with your mom?
Huge.
Where's your clad?
He lives in San Diego, but
you'd think he was in Alaska.
He never visits.
But I don't care.
He remarried this really weird
woman, and she never talks.
Hear, hear for
second marriages!
FRAN: It's kind of true.
It's good when everyone
is older and wiser.
Steady.
And people have figured
out how to compromise.
Or behave.
Thank you very much.
Nobody's talking about you.
Don't take it personally.
I'm talking generally.
If I got married again, I'd be on the
lookout for the inevitable problems.
Odd conversation.
Pretty weird.
Sorry, but maybe don't get
married a second time.
I'm not saying I will.
I'm just saying.
She's just saying.
Fran, what was
your ex-husband like?
Oh, he was actually a lovely, lovely man.
But not for me.
Very grownup!
He passed away.
Two years ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Could we get some
more bread, please?
Please, no more bread.
Why not?
I don't want to eat it.
Then don't.
More bread, please.
Are you going to eat it?
I don't know,
but somebody else might.
I probably will.
Me, too.
Bread eater, bread eater.
I'm sorry. So, Fran,
you eat bread, I see.
It's true!
So you get to keep
cookies in the house.
I can.
What are you talking about?
It's not a big deal, but I have
trouble controlling myself...
...so when Peter would
bring home things like...
...chocolate or good
bread, yummy stuff,
I'd eat all of it,
then hate myself.
And me for bringing it home.
So did you stop buying it?
Yeah, I did.
And got so angry.
I was not angry.
A little bit angry.
WILL: Well, he should
have been angry.
Why should he be deprived because
she can't control herself?
Because she's his wife and
he's trying to help her?
Yeah, but is that
really helping her?
Yes!
Not if we want her to
learn to control herself.
"We?"
I just said it's
not fair to him.
Why does everything have to be fair?
What are you, six?
Of course... What?
Let's keep it nice.
I just forget the
cookies are there. So...
EVA: That's why it's good you're
married to Peter and I'm not.
That is absolutely
the God's honest truth.
Ooh, it's cold out.
Nobody ate the bread,
by the way.
You did.
Yeah, exactly.
Exactly?
Let me ask you a question.
When people ask why we got
divorced, what do you say?
I say I don't think you and I
should have been together.
What about Fran? Did you
talk to her about us?
Right. She's
your wife. Right.
Yeah, okay.
That was fun, huh?
I started this blanket
when you were five.
I don't know what I was
thinking about this color.
I'm going to finish it,
so you can take it with you.
I'll probably buy
another one, in case.
What are you talking about?
This will be good.
Why are you looking at this?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
I just pulled it out.
I was trying to
remember what I knew.
Did I already know those
things about your dad?
I mean the things
we would fight about.
Probably not.
I think I did, actually.
I think I always knew.
Or felt them.
I just wasn't paying attention.
But look at what I got, huh?
I'm going to bed. No, stay
here and cozy up with me.
I'm tired.
Come on, Chloe.
Is that hard?
Not at all.
You want to learn?
Yeah.
I've been trying to teach
Ellen for the longest time!
Albert.
Are you still seeing his wife?
Well, she has a bad shoulder.
And she has no friends.
(GASPS)
What? Don't look
at me like that.
I'm screwed up.
MARIANNE: Just one second.
I'm in the middle
of some bullshit.
Can you just put
your table down?
I'll be right back.
Yeah. Take your time.
We did, we agreed
on it, Albert!
Because I was there!
I remember.
Oh, my God. Okay. Well, it is.
It's all worked out.
Yes, it is.
Okay, fine, good. Bye!
My God, I cannot wait till I don't
have to talk to him anymore.
What happened?
He thinks he should take
Tess to school, not me.
Tess wants it to be me,
because she told me.
But, I mean... Thank you. Can't
you both just take her?
I don't think so.
No, I don't.
He's such a wreck
about her going away.
She doesn't need that
kind of energy right now.
And he just focuses so much onto her.
She can feel it.
Isn't that kind
of nice, though?
I mean, that he focuses?
Well, maybe if he had a girlfriend or
something so it would balance it out...
...but I don't
see that happening.
Really? Why not?
Because he's a loser.
Uh-oh.
Such a mean word, but it fits.
How does it fit?
For instance-this
is typically Albert...
...when we were
first going out,
he had nothing next to his bed.
No table, nothing.
At first I thought,
"That's cute.
It's kind of bohemian."
Stuff like that.
So then we got
married and I went out
and bought these really
lovely bedside tables.
Then last year,
I saw all of his stuff
was on the side
of the bed again.
I mean, I took
the tables, granted,
but he never went
out and replaced them.
He's just content to just put
his shit on the floor again.
Metaphorically speaking, he's not
building a life for himself.
I mean, who would date
a person like that?
Right.
(PHONE RINGING)
I'm not picking up.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
ALBERT: Marianne,
please pick up the phone.
We haven't resolved anything.
I know you're there.
This is so embarrassing.
I'm sorry.
Fine. Don't deal with it.
(ALBERT HANGS UP) (SIGHS)
Okay, these are
just little things.
Ultimately, we just...
I never felt understood by him.
You know?
He didn't get the poetry.
He never got me.
Has anyone ever gotten you?
I don't know.
What about the flabby guy?
How's that?
Yeah. Maybe.
I need you to meet him.
We can do a double date.
Not so you can decide
what you think of him.
Please? I'm losing
all perspective here.
Exactly! You don't
need somebody else's!
Will you please just say yes
and do this for me? Please?
They had stars
and suns and moons.
I know. I hate those.
Why do women like things that look
like they belong to children?
You know what I love? Dollhouse furniture.
I would eat it if I could.
Sometimes I wish I was single, just
so I could have girlie sheets.
You would love that.
I have flowery sheets. They're not
all they're cracked up to be.
I like your flowery sheets.
Oh! Don't sell
me out, man.
We're new. I'd like her sheets if
they had little Mussolinis on them.
Talk to me when
you get night tables.
He has normal sheets,
but no night tables.
So I don't have night tables.
Maybe it's a metaphor.
Or maybe not!
I don't know.
I make a million compromises.
It just seems...
...not having flowery
sheets is not a big deal.
(SCRAPING CHIP IN BOWL)
I know. I know you
make compromises.
Really? What do
you think they are?
This is not the time.
Sometimes I wish
I was with somebody
who was more
interested in history.
What?
History.
Okay.
I'm just saying.
More guacamole?
Not for me.
I'd love some, actually.
You know how many calories
are in guacamole?
Ten.
Lay off the guy.
He likes guacamole.
You know what?
We don't need the guac!
I'll just stick
with the cheese.
You know what I'm going to get you
as a present? A calorie book.
Please don't.
Yeah. A calorie book as
a gift is not so good.
Eva tells me
you're a therapist.
Tell us about your
weirdest patient.
No, I can't She can't.
Of course you can! You don't
have to name names, mate.
You're so uptight
about confidentiality.
Shouldn't she be?
Well, you know.
Okay. I have one patient who
picks his nose and eats it.
Oh, man!
In front of you?
Yes.
Is he a child?
Are you making this up?
It is so gross and distracting.
He does it in this way he thinks I
can't see, but it's so obvious.
I won't say who it is,
but he is famous.
Really famous.
He is not!
I know who it is.
EVA: You do?
No, you don't.
I absolutely do.
Please, Sarah,
tell us! Please!
Okay! That's it!
Shaw's over!
I like being drunk. I really
think it's highly overrated.
Underrated!
You're shouting.
I am? No, I'm not.
You are. A little.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I don't want to wake
up the small people.
I'm sorry.
You want to know
something funny?
This one here can't whisper.
What?
Will you do it right now?
Will you show them?
I'm whispering.
That was a whisper.
Huh? What?
No, it's not.
Can I?
Yeah, that was a whisper.
What about me?
Yes, you can whisper.
(IN NORMAL VOLUME)
This is whispering.
No, it's not. That is
not a whisper at all.
You're picking on him.
No, I'm not!
You are.
You kind of are.
Okay, I'm sorry. I've just,
never in my entire life...
...have I met anybody who
couldn't whisper at all.
Whatever.
No. You are not allowed to
complain about her anymore.
Why the fuck is this
in the drawer? Cathy?
Did you put this in the drawer?
No.
Maybe one of the kids did.
That could be.
But I think you put
it there, 'cause I find
weird stuff in these
drawers all the time.
I clean the best I can.
I'm just trying to understand
the thought process.
You like the counters clean.
Yeah, but not by shoving weird
shit in the wrong drawers.
Does the ball
belong in the kitchen?
That's enough.
You know what,
Mrs. Sarah?
I find your crap everywhere.
You think I know
where to put it?
You leave stuff
all over the house.
You let your children
write on the walls.
You floss your
teeth and leave it.
You clean your own house.
You people disgust me.
But you is nice, Mr. Will.
Thanks, Cathy!
(DOOR SLAMS)
It really would have
been kinder to fire her.
Oh, my God.
Guys, my timing
might be a little off...
...but I think I put
the ball in the drawer.
Not funny.
Are you serious?
That wasn't a very
fun evening, was it?
God! Yikes!
Why do you care if I don't
know how to whisper?
What was that?
I mean, that was embarrassing.
I was just joking around.
That was complete... nothing.
A calorie book?
You're going to buy
me a calorie book?
Okay, well, I'm sorry.
I'm obviously not going to
buy you a calorie book.
I thought you
actually liked me.
I do like you.
Why do I feel like I just spent
the evening with my ex-wife?
(SIGHS)
Wait, what are you doing,
driving me home?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh.
Are you going to
spend the night?
No. Not tonight.
Okay.
Hi.
Ellen went out with friends, but I didn't
really want to go home. Is this okay?
I'm glad you're here, actually.
(GROANS)
I'm always so much more
comfortable at your house.
You know...
...you would be so welcome to stay
in Ellen's room once she's gone.
You'd have to check with your
mom, but the room will be empty.
Really?
Oh, yeah.
That would be awesome.
Thank you so much.
Sure.
Thank you.
Excuse me, Chloe,
but can I have my mom back?
Honey, we were just watching
something and passed out.
Next you'll be asking her to
move into my room when I'm gone.
I'm sorry.
No, it's not your
fault, sweetie.
I better go home.
Honey.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Chloe is needy.
Who's needy?
You know, I guess I am...
...just trying to feel
a little bit more separate.
Son of prepare.
But instead, I just feel
lonely and anxious and...
...Chloe is always here.
I'm so sorry about that.
But, Ellen,
you know you're my baby.
Right, honey? Give Mommy a hug.
Will you sit with me?
Can I see what Daddy
and Fran gave you?
I'm going to finish my blanket.
They get you anything else?
Oh, those are good. They don't
take up room. You'll use those.
Hey, did you ever get a
chance to look at my book?
Oh, I did!
You did?
Yes. Your poems
are beautiful!
I mean, not that I understand
them, but I like them.
Thank you. And I'm sure
you understand them.
TESS: Mom!
We're out here!
Dad's in the car.
I forgot my phone.
Good, because I finally get
to introduce you guys.
This is Eva.
Tess!
Hi?
You guys know each other?
Uh, yeah, we know each other.
This is Tess.
Mom, she's dating Dad.
What?
You didn't know that?
You date Albert?
I'm not sure what's going on right now.
Wait a minute.
ALBERT: Hello! Marianne!
Sorry to interrupt, but, Tess,
we really have to get going.
Hi!
Hi.
I don't understand.
What are you doing here?
She massages me.
We're friends.
I thought
You're friends with Marianne.
I met you...
...at a party and you
gave me your card...
No, no. I gave
you my card.
Yes. I think you
were at that same party.
Yeah, I remember the party.
And you met us both.
So now you're her masseuse?
Yeah!
For how long?
Ever since we all met.
EVA: Well, I didn't know...
...who she was,
or who you... are, were.
So...
...you put it together
at some point, right?
No.
No?
I'm sorry, at some
point, I, um...
When?
Well, I think...
What?
When?
When? Umm...
Yeah.
You got your phone?
Okay, let's go.
I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Should I not be here?
Probably not.
Oh, I screwed up big time.
What happened?
Oh, shit!
Oh, that's my mom.
Hi, Mom.
I'm sorry, do you have a daughter?
'Cause this one's mine.
Who do you think
you are, telling her
she should have sex
with her boyfriend?
You know what?
All she needs...
No, you shut it!
Dyke.
(LAUGHING)
CYNTHIA: I didn't tell you
about the kitchen remodel.
They talked to the guys in
Rome about the travertine.
Apparently when they were lifting
it up, it snapped or something...
Is your dad here?
He went to the market.
Sorry to just
come over like this,
but he hasn't been
returning my calls, so...
I'll tell him you came by.
What are you
gonna do with that?
You want one?
Oh, sure.
(NERVOUSLY) Hi.
You know how many
calories are in that?
I just want to talk.
It really was
a coincidence. Okay?
And I wanted it to stop.
But she needed massages and we sort of...
Oh, thank you.
We sort of became friends...
...and I didn't
know what to do.
She needed massages?
You knew what to do.
You just didn't do it.
Well, I was very torn.
So while you were being torn...
...she was poisoning
our relationship
and poisoning your
perception of me.
Why would you want that?
I don't know.
I mean...
Except maybe I was trying to protect
myself, you know, because...
...you know...
...because we'd both been
married before, and...
...you know how
things can turn out.
What about us?
What about...
...protecting us?
I didn't protect us.
And it didn't get
poisoned, Albert.
I still really wanted us
to keep seeing each other.
I wouldn't know how, you know?
I'm so, so, so sorry.
I know this sounds...
...corny...
...but you broke my heart.
And I'm too old for that shit.
(SIGHS)
And the worst part...
...the worst part of
it is that you made me
look like an idiot in
front of my daughter.
I'm the idiot!
I'm the idiot.
Look, I got a lot to do.
Tess and everything.
School.
When is she leaving?
Next week. School
starts early for her.
Yeah, same for Ellen.
(EXHALES)
I guess we have to
get those hobbies going.
Guess so.
Bye.
He just really,
really liked you.
I just really,
really liked him.
Computer,
what's the point in this?
You do all the thinking
where we...
Just digging shelters
in the snow
Build a house
of dream and domino
I know it's fallen down
Got my headphones on
and I won't hear a sound
No, it's all broke down
Eyes out on the road
but no one comes along
When you want them to
Let your hair hang long
Yeah, that old north wind
is blowing
How will you know
which one is your room?
It's all written down.
And remember, Mom,
we saw everything on our visit.
I don't remember anything.
I do.
She's going to be great.
You're going to be great.
(TEARFULLY) I love you guys.
I love you, too.
(SOBBING)
Computer,
what's the point in this?
You do all the thinking
where we...
Just building shelters
in the snow
Build a house
of dream and domino
I know it's fallen down
Got my headphones on
and I won't hear a sound
Yeah, it's all broke down
Eyes out on the road
but no one comes along
When you want them to
Well, we made a fine person.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
HAL: Hey, Eva!
Do you think you can help me?
Of course!
Oh, my God.
I'm such an idiot!
I'm sorry.
Sorry. Is that... Jeez.
This thing's heavy.
We always go to my mother's
house for Thanksgiving...
...and I get in a fight
with my sister and brother.
My sister's a middle child,
so she has issues.
Anyway, what are you doing?
Huh? What are you doing
for the holiday?
I'm going to my friend's house.
It's going to be
a small group, but...
That sounds nice.
Oh, yeah.
(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
SARAH: Hi, honey.
Oh, thank you so much.
No problem.
It really smells good in here!
Yeah? I can't
smell it anymore.
It's unbelievably delicious sound...
Sounding. Smelling.
You excited?
Oh, my God, beyond!
You think she'll
look different?
Yeah, maybe she grew
a beard or something.
You know how it is
at Sarah Lawrence.
No, she looks the same. I
Skyped with her yesterday.
Actually, I think
she's gained weight.
What time are
you picking her up?
Not till two.
We're eating at
five... you should just
come straight here
from the airport.
Oh, let's use the fancy plates.
But you say you
don't like them.
I know. But it's
Thanksgiving...
you're supposed to
use the ugly plates.
Okay, I'll see you. Bye.
Bye, Eva!
Bye, Cathy.
(SIGHS)
Hi.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
(ALARM BEEPS)
I don't always park
in front of your house.
I usually just drive by.
Sometimes I drive
by your house, too.
You do?
You look good.
You, too.
Thank you.
Is Tess coming home
for Thanksgiving?
She's already here.
She's over at her mother's.
I'm going over there later.
You want to come?
(LAUGHING)
And Ellen is...
This afternoon. She's
coming home this afternoon.
You been okay without her?
Oh, sure, yeah.
I mean, she's not going back.
'Cause I've built a cage.
What a good idea!
I've missed you.
I missed you, too.
Oh, I should tell you...
I bought some night tables.
You did?
No.
(LAUGHING)
No, I didn't.
Okay. That's good.
I like your toothy smile
It never fails to beguile
Whichever way
the wind is blowing
I like the way this is going
I like to watch TV with you
There's really nothing
That I would rather do
Then maybe we can go to bed
And get up and do it all again
I like the way your pants fit
And how you stand
and how you sit
Whatever seeds
that you're sowing
I like the way this is going
I don't care about the past
None of it was made to last
It's not who you've known
But who you're knowing
I like the way this is going