- Excuse Me
- Sorry
So I'm goanna make it on to
the earlier flight, right?
Are you goanna check that?
Oh. No, I'm goanna carry it on.
It's got valuables in it.
- Here
- Thank you
- God! Excuse me
- No, I'm sorry...
My bag is a little heavy.
I was looking at my phone.
I hate it when people do that.
You have a little...
...smudge
What are these?
Those are two barrelled carburettors
for a Pontiac tri-power.
Those are exhaust tubes for a '74 Z-28.
I restore old cars, so...
Hair dryer
Oh my God.
I'm so sorry...
- This is getting to be a habit
- Yea
Sorry about that.
- Here
- Sure
- Boston?
- Yeah
Gate 20
Enjoy your flight, Mr. Gracia.
Hello
I'm sorry, you're not
on this flight.
Well, I just checked in for
this one 10 minutes ago.
It must be some sort of mistake.
I'm sorry, the computer
shows that we're booked.
Listen Sherry.
Tomorrow my little sister is getting married.
I practically raised her...
I'm sorry, we are completely filled out.
Listen, can you help me out for a second?
She's my little sister. She's April and I'm June.
That's very sweet.
But the 11:50 will get you there by
tomorrow morning with plenty of time.
Your boarding pass, sir?
Sometimes things happen for a reason.
Thank you.
I should've seen it coming, boss.
It came undone.
Coming undone in our business
means you need a margherita.
It doesn't mean capping a dozen people
in a government lab and blowing it up.
It doesn't mean stealing an
object of critical importance.
Does he have the zephyr or not?
We believe so.
Uh, "you believe so".
I don't care what you believe, Fitz
I need you to clear...
- Put it back on.
- fix this. I want the Zephyr
We'll have it in hand by the
time he lands in Boston.
Find out who and what she is.
Should I just pick her up in Wichita?
No. I got a better idea.
Miss Havens.
We did find a seat for you.
MOVEMENT ALERT
Oh Fitz. What did you do?
No wonder these airlines
are going out of business.
There's nobody on the plane.
The captain has turned on
the "fasten seat belt" sign.
Please remain seated until the sign has been
turned off, and it's safe to move about the cabin.
I'm June, by the way.
I'm Roy Miller.
- Nice to meet you
- It's very nice to meet you
- Tequila on the rocks?
- Yea, just in time. Thanks.
So your sister's getting married tomorrow?
Excuse me?
Your sister is getting married
tomorrow. Congratulations.
Yea, thanks.
- You know, I'm a bad liar
- I'm sorry. How's that?
April is getting married,
but not until Saturday.
You had me fooled.
But, I do have a fitting tomorrow
so I do actually have to go home.
Hope this isn't goanna be a rough flight.
It might be.
You know, Wichita is a long
way to go for a carburettor.
It's not just any carburettor.
It is a triple deuce.
I am restoring a 66 GTO and
Kansas has the best scrap.
Really?
My dad had a garage, and when I
was a kid, he bought this chassis.
He used to take us to go
out and search for parts.
He died in '98 and now that
April's getting married,
I just figured, why not finish it up and
give it to her as a wedding present.
Kind of like a present from my
my dad too, you know?
- That's nice
- Yea...
I used to think that... someday
...when the last part went in.
I would just climb into that GTO,
and start it up
Just drive and drive and keep driving
until I got to the tip of South America.
- Cape Horn
- Yea
- It is beautiful how it still is
- Yes?
Pirate Islands.
- "Some day" is a dangerous word
- Dangerous?
It is really just a code for...
...never
I think a lot about the
things I haven't done
Diving the Great Barrier Reef...
Ride the Orient Express...
Travelling along the Amalfi Coast with
nothing but a motorcycle and a backpack.
Kissing a stranger on the balcony of
the Hotel Du Caps.
- Where is that?
- South of France
What about you?
What's your list?
Yours sounds pretty good.
- Thanks
- No problem
I'll just put this up here.
Is that all right?
You know, I'm goanna go back
and use the restroom.
I'll help you.
Thanks.
Turbulence, huh?
I'll be out in a minute.
A strange in the balcony of Hotel Du Caps?
What kind of line is that?
It's a really good line.
Did you see his hands?
By any chance?
They just snatched the bag right of the air.
Lightning fast reflexes.
Not cool
Obrigado!
Game's over, Roy...
Really?
Where's the zephyr?
Why is the girl on the plane?
Tell me.
Why did Fitz, put her on the plane?
Don't move, Miller.
So what are you goanna do?
Are you goanna let this opportunity
pass you by? No, of course not!
You're goanna walk right through that door.
You're goanna get right up on this.
It is not your first rodeo, woman.
I decided to join you.
Sorry...
It's okay
- It's that tequila
- Do not worry
My God, you're in a relationship.
I'm so sorry.
No, that's not it.
Okay, I'm all ears. What is it?
- Are we landing?
- No, not yet
Listen, there's no need to panic,
I have contained the situation.
- situation?
- Uh, yea...
- We've lost the pilots
- Where did they go?
- I mean they're dead
- The pilots are dead?
- Shot, yes.
- They were shot?
By whom?
I did, actually I shot the first pilot
and he shot the second pilot accidentally...
It's just one of those things.
Seriously... that's just great.
Really, I'm relieved you're
taking this so well.
Where are you going?
I have to check out things, think about landing
Would you mind putting your seat belt on for me?
This is weird.
- What's happening?
- Oh, hello
Sit down.
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
Everybody's dead in here...
Oh my god!
- Sorry?
- We're going down
Sure, this is a rapid descent.
Please, sit down.
- Sorry
- Are you a pilot?
- Who are you?
- Shoulder straps
Secure it right down there.
Right there.
You're done?
Here we go now.
Why can't we just land
at an airport?
No, no. That wouldn't be a good idea.
They'll be waiting for us.
What do you mean, waiting for us?
Who?
I think, the less you know the better.
What?
Ok, we're goanna have to pitch down here.
That's a truck!
Close, close!
God!
- This is good
- What's good?
Take a little sip of that.
It'll take the edge off.
- Are you shot?
- Yea, just a little scrape
That's good news.
June, we have to discuss
what's goanna happen next.
You need to go to the hospital,
and prison maybe.
There's people who'll come
looking for you now. Bad people.
I feel a little weird
Oh yea, that will pass when you fall asleep,
which should be a couple of minutes.
- What?
- I need you to listen, June
- Did you drug me?
- Yes
- You drugged me
- Yes, for your own good
These bad people who are going to come and
see you, they're goanna ask you about me.
You need to tell them that
you don't know me. June?
You need to tell them you
don't remember anything...
...and you need to avoid getting into
any vehicle with them at all costs.
- Wait. Who are them?
- Serious people, June.
They'll probably identify themselves as
federal agents, and they'll DIP you.
Dip me? In what?
Disinformation Protocol. They'll tell you a story about me,
about how I am mentally unstable, paranoid...
I'm violent and dangerous and
it'll all sound very convincing.
I am already convinced.
Here's a few common DIP
cue words to listen for:
Reassuring words. Words like
stabilized secure, safe.
If they say these words
particularly with repetition,
- ...it means they're going to kill you
- Oh, God!
...or intern you somewhere
offshore for a very long time.
Stay with me.
- If they say you're safe...
- They're goanna kill me
- Do not get in what?
- Vehicles
Any vehicles. You know?
Just run.
- I'm run
- Run
And if they ask you about me...
I don't know you.
I don't know you at all
Who are you...?
Eat a good breakfast, June
...Back to our top news story of the morning...
According to the FAA, approximately
at 7:30 last night...
All passengers died when
the aircraft suffered turbulence.
The plane was passing through an area of
turbulence and may have been affected by...
...wind-shear or lightning storm
causing an electrical failure.
Now this is all pre-conjecture,
and all that's left of the plane...
I'm coming!
Remember, do not tell anyone
Rodney?
Oh, thank God.
I wanted to make sure
were all okay.
Why?
- You were on that flight from Kansas, right?
- Yea
- I saw on the news about the crash
- What news? What crash?
- Anyway, you're alive
- I'm alive. Yes.
June... I told myself that if
I found you alive, that...
- I was goanna ask you to dinner
- How about I call you later, okay?
It's just another day.
It's just a normal day.
She's moving.
- Wow... and I gotta love the boots
- Yea.. I know
I promise I'll wear heels on the day.
- Can I talk to you for a second?
- Yea
- So, this weekend. I was thinking about dad's GTO
- Really?
I was sitting there and I was wondering how
you'd feel about maybe selling it.
You wanna sell dad's GTO?
- Ben and I. We really want our own place
- Excuse me
Anyone here belong to that
blue truck parked outside?
Yea, why?
You're about to get a ticket.
Forget to put enough
quarters or something.
I hate getting tickets.
Oh, excuse me.
Please step inside miss.
I'll just go grab a few things.
Miss Havens, good afternoon.
Special Agent Charles Fitzgerald.
Will you join us inside
the car for a moment?
We know you were on the
flight with him last night.
The one that crashed.
Who are you again?
FBI.
- You do know Mr. Miller
- No, I don't
Well, we chatted a little bit
before we passed through security.
I see.
And once you were on the plane,
What happened then? More chatting?
- Is this funny to you?
- No
He's dangerous Miss. Havens, and out of control.
- He said that you'd say he was crazy
- So you did talk to him
And what about me?
No, not you specifically.
About whom then... Simon Feck?
I don't know who that is.
Look this is getting really twisted around
and I think I should probably call a lawyer.
We're goanna take you to a secure location,
until agents can have Mr. Miller contained...
...some place safe.
- With you?
- Yes, ma'am
You wanna tell me where we're going?
Fellas?
Do not worry, you're safe.
- Excuse me?
- You're safe with us
I wanna know where we're going.
It is just a shortcut until the situation
is stabilized, to keep you safe.
You said that already.
Because, I meant it.
What is Jackson doing?
Shooter, shooter!
Get down! Get down!
Shooter on the freeway.
The dot is on your back.
Follow me now!
Are you insane?
I'm not going out that door.
God!
- Hey June
- I can't see
- Get out of the way
- Open the door
Open the door June...
Beautiful dress, by the way.
Wait a second.
Who are you?
What are you doing?
- Hey June
- What are you doing?
Please unlock the door.
Unlock the door, that way
I can help you.
June, door...
Just pull over!
Oh my god!
C'mon over here...
You're doing good.
Hold this.
Well, well, well!
Check this out.
Nice.
These guys load the barrel.
You're doing well June. Excellent driving.
Beautiful dress
Is it for the wedding on Saturday?
- Uh-huh
- Yea, that'll be nice
Please... stop shooting
people, okay?
I understand, you're in charge.
You stay here while I go have a word
with the guys in the truck. Okay?
- Okay
- Okay?
Actually I'm just goanna go
shoot them, and I'll be right back.
By the way, your timing, when
you opened that door was sublime.
You saved us, I hope you know that.
You saved us.
Hey, wait!
Wait!
There you are.
June?
Rodney?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Hey guys, say hello to June.
- That's some dress
- Thanks
- Everything all right?
- Yes
No, it's...
It's complicated.
You know what?
I've been feeling the same way.
You wanna talk? Maybe over some pie.
My point is...
My point is, that plane crash
made me think about our breakup.
You know this bell went off. Like "Bing"
Rodney, why have you given up?
You're being passive.
Getting back at her because she
didn't want the ring.
June does not want to be engaged right now
and that freaks your mom out. Big deal!
What about all the things you and June
wanted to do together, huh?
Our list, camping in Vermont,
with my brother and Sheila
Tickets to the Blue Man Group...
I wanna talk about
the plane crash. Okay?
- Sure. What about it?
- I was on it
I mean in it. I was in... it
So you were in the plane crash?
I wasn't supposed to be on it, but I was
and there was this guy who was...
Some sort of like secret
agent or something and he...
He killed everybody on board
and then he landed the plane
Next thing you know.
I wake up. I'm in my room.
I have no idea how I got there.
He must've drugged me or something.
And then I go to April's wedding cuz
I had to wear this ridiculous dress
And then these other guys,
these other agents come.
They snatch me off. Next thing you know,
I'm in Grand Theft Auto on the I-93.
Why're you touching my hand?
Because I'm here for you
- Geez, you are so stressed out
- Yea
And I get it, I completely understand
I mean...
- Wow, June!
- I know...
Your little sister is getting
married and that is stressful.
What are you talking about, Rodney?
You didn't even listen to
what I was talking about.
I would be the same way
in this situation.
What can I do to help?
- We can bring the guys over...
- No, no, no, no, no...
Christ...
Hi June.
Look, I'm sorry if I'm
interrupt anything but...
I'm Roy Miller.
Rodney Burst.
We're running out of time, and...
Maybe I didn't make it
clear enough,
but we're goanna have to stick
together because of our...
...situation
In case you didn't notice, Rodney
is a fireman so he's perfectly capable
of handling any situation that
comes up, thank you very much.
- You can leave us alone.
- I have no doubt.
Ever since I was a little kid, I've
had a great respect for firemen
And the fact of the matter is, I
don't think you guys get paid enough
- You're an engine tech?
- Yea, engine tech.
- Have you taken your lieutenant's exam yet?
- Yea, we're goanna
- How's that going?
- It's a bitch
Do you have a do
a tour of that hall...
That's where the action is...
- Rodney...
- House of flames
I've often thought... I...
I should've been a fireman
What?
Is this the guy?
Sorry, who are you?
I'm the guy?
- I'm the guy
- This is the guy
Rodney whatever happens,
please for your own safety
- Please stay out of it
- What are you talking about?
Everybody get down!
Everybody get down or
I will blow her head off
What did I just say?
- Rodney what did I say?
- Just calm down
Sorry, thought you were making a move.
It's okay, do not move
Pies for everyone!
Everybody gets pies, but no ice-cream.
We can survive, people.
Lincoln knew it. That's
why they got to him.
No one follows us or
I'll kill myself and then her.
- Get in the car please
- No
Watch your head.
- 560 Harris. They're getting into a blue Volvo
- Rodney!
Oh my God!
Rodney!
It's okay, I shot you
through and through.
No bone, nowhere near
the femoral artery. Okay?
It's goanna be better for you
to grow bone. It's all good. Okay?
You good?
Good?
I was forced to enter the restaurant, June,
because it proves you're my hostage.
Which cleared your name,
with the locals at least.
That is a start. Something to build on.
You shot Rodney.
Yea, I did.
- But I asked him to stay out of it
- You shot Rodney
Might be the best thing
that ever happened to him.
Yea, right because we all should
get shot every now and then.
Rodney is a good guy, June.
But not really right for you.
In my opinion, but a good guy...
He took a bullet.
He's goanna be a hero.
Probably get a promotion.
Stop the car.
Stop the car!
It's okay.
- Stop the car!
- I can not
I want to leave, stop the car
please, now
I'm not one of those, "I
told you so" kind of guys,
but I did warn you to stay
off the plane last night.
When?
When I said that sometimes
things happen for a reason.
That's not a warning...
That's not a warning, Roy...
That's an expression or a bumper sticker.
Next time try: June, if you get
this plane you will fucking die.
Maybe they did meant it when
they said that I will be safe.
Do you really mean that, June?
Yea.
Did you feel safe with them?
Do you think that I do now?
Okay.
Just so you understand,
right now out there on your own,
your life expectancy is like zero...
With me, it's up here.
Without me, here.
With me...
Without me...
I would advise going home,
but you know? It's up to you
So, right now I need
another car to keep moving
And someone else depending on me.
Someone, whose life is in danger.
Someone who trusts me...
Every second I waste chasing
you, I'm letting him down.
Rodney, what was it that you were thinking
when you performed the heroic action?
Well, I didn't think, I just did what
any man would do in that situation.
- You should be so proud
- Thanks
It really didn't even hurt,
it was kind of like a bee sting.
What a brave fire fighter.
Doctors tell me,
Rodney's going to be okay.
It's just a flesh wound.
A true blue Boston hero...
Back to you, Tom.
That's what it's all about.
That right there is what everybody wants.
A Burger King toy?
Open it.
It's warm. What is it?
A battery.
A battery?
It's code-named Zephyr.
I'm not sure, if it's just...
It's high output.
It never runs out.
What do you mean never?
That little thing there, is the
first perpetual energy source.
It's the sun.
So what, your flashlight
never runs out of juice?
It can power a lot more
than a flashlight, June.
- Really?
- Hmm.
How much more?
A small city or like a submarine.
It's big.
The guy who invented it,
is barely out of high school.
Simon Feck.
I was assigned with another agent to
watch him at a facility lab in Wichita.
and the other guy, the agent, is the
guy who picked you up this morning.
Fitzgerald.
A couple of weeks ago I found out that
he was going to sell the battery...
...and kill Simon.
So I got Simon out of there,
you know, some place safe.
Went back for the battery
and Fitz set me up.
He made it look like I went rogue.
That's when I met you.
So...
So what's next?
What is the plan?
Maybe get some rest.
Pick up Simon and get you
back to your sister's wedding.
I am pretty good at what I do, June.
Tonight...
...we're safe.
Scout's honour.
"Safe and secure?"
Good night, Roy.
Were you really a boy scout?
Eagle Scout.
- I was a brown eagle
- That's cool
Good night, Roy.
Pies for everybody... everybody...
Everybody gets pies...
So, what do you think?
Are we looking at another player?
We're looking at a pawn.
I talked to her and so did he.
She owns a garage. No passport.
Gone nowhere. Been nowhere.
She's a nobody.
You've been two steps behind
since this began, Fitz.
Are you sure someone's
not taking you to school?
Clean this shit up.
Brooklyn, NEW YORK.
This is the safe house?
Simon!
Simon?
Stay close.
Simon!
No time to play.
What is all this?
Simon. It's what he does.
It's kind of late.
Please keep guard.
Hmm... Made in Austria.
Who are these people?
Are they Fitzgerald's guys?
No, these are other guys
Other bad guys?
Worse guys.
Hold them.
Worse guys?
Now, June, listen carefully
and do exactly as I say.
On three, I'm goanna lay down cover...
...and you're going to run to
those shells over there, okay?
Okay
Ready...? One..
Sorry...
I panicked.
What number would you like?
Let's just stick with three.
Okay... 1, 2, 3.
Good work, thanks
Could be Antonio Quintana's men.
He is a Spanish arms dealer.
He also wants the battery.
Ready?
Let's move.
June, June...
What the...? How the hell
are we goanna get out of here?
Where the hell is Simon?
- I don't know, but he left a message.
- Message?
What I need you to do
right now is to wait here
What?
I'll go find us a way out of here
Wait, wait.
Stay down.
Roy!
June...
June!
Please stop saying my name.
You keep screaming my name
and it is freaking me out.
Okay, I understand.
- Drink this.
- What is that?
Brotine-zero.
They're goanna smoke us with D5.
Where's yours?
Shit.
Sorry.
June...
Will you listen to me?
We'll be out of here...
...in a couple of minutes.
I gotta do something...
Alright. We gotta go June.
We've been hit!
But, it's okay.
We get through this, we're home free.
Ready. Set. Go!
We're almost there.
ALPS
Hey there, sleepyhead.
How long have I been out?
18 hours.
Where am I?
My place.
We're off-grid.
No one's ever found me here.
It's a shame we can't stay longer.
We gotta rendezvous
with Simon. He's fine.
I figured out his code.
He's crazy 'bout trains.
He used the password I gave
him and went to Austria.
You drugged me again, Roy.
Yea.
You can't do that!
You weren't coping well.
I'm not sure if you were awake,
they would have even let you live.
What am I wearing?
A bikini.
We're in the tropics.
How did I get in a bikini?
June, I've been trained to
dismantle bombs in pitch black...
...with nothing but a
safety pin and a Junior mint.
I think I could get you into
those clothes without...
...looking.
I'm not saying that's what I did, but...
Sorry... Reflex.
Yea, I deserved that.
Hit me again.
I won't stop you.
June?
June...
June!
Pins and Junior mints...
"I'm not saying that's what I did."
Shit!
What is this thing?
Movement,Alert
5826, Amapola.
That's a '67 Grand Prix.
April!
April! I know, I'm ok!
I'm ok! I'm ok!
Listen, April....
April... April....
April, can you hear me?
April.
April, can you...
I know, I'm ok!
I'm ok! I'm ok!
What is Miller doing?
Who is the girl?
We do not know Antonio.
We traced her phone to the Azores.
We're in range now.
Until they contact the agency.
Perfect timing.
Lunch is ready.
You must be thirsty.
It's a coconut...
it's loaded with electrolytes.
Whoa...
Ok...
OK, just...
wow.
Yea.
You got skills.
My dad wanted boys.
Let me go!
You can get out any time you want.
I'll show you.
Hands like Houdini.
Turn your palms down, and all at once...
...throw your hands to the ground.
And your hips back...
Nice.
That was good.
Who are you?
Really.
I don't understand...
Run.
I don't understand.
I came on a plane.
My phone was secure.
It's secure.
Unless you didn't make a call.
No, I didn't make a call.
I took a call.
You took a call?
It was a quick one.
I thought we were off the grid,
and then my phone rang.
It was my sister and
I had to take the call.
No, I can't get into that.
I can't get into that thing.
Just put me out.
Use Broton 7 or whatever.
- It's okay
- You're grabbing my neck.
You asked me not to drug you.
Okay...
Hands like Houdini...
hands...
Roy?
Monte Casale, ALPS.
I can't feel my face!
Hey, it's time...
Pull on this traction system...
I have control of 50,000 metric tons.
This is diesel hydraulic.
Don't you want to see your Zephyr?
Yes...
- Excuse Me.
- Tell me lady.
Can you tell me where we are?
Of course, we are in Austria.
Austria...
Would you like some breakfast, Miss?
Yea, that would be great.
Thanks.
Okay, I'm goanna have some pancakes.
Scrambled eggs and...
a glass of milk.
Excellent.
- A Harvey Wall banger, please.
- Yes, sir.
Incoming Call.
Unknown Number.
You know, statistically
you're a lot more likely to die...
...riding on a train than any
other form of transportation.
10.3 times more likely than dying on a plane.
Simon?
Simon Feck?
Yes.
My name is June, I'm a
friend of Roy Miller's.
Have you found him yet?
Have you seen him?
No, not yet.
Don't you wanna answer that?
Yea.
But I can't, I'm not supposed to...
It may be Roy.
But he told me not to answer the phone,
because the signal could be tracked.
Oh, that's right.
Stay in the room.
I'm with Simon.
Did Roy happen to tell you why I'm here?
Are we supposed to meet him here or...?
What did you say that
drink was... Harvey...?
It's a Harvey Wall banger.
Do you mind ordering me one
of those, 'cos it looks great?
I'll just be right back.
You just stay here for a second,
I'll be right back.
Something's wrongs.
It's getting hotter, Roy.
She didn't answer her phone..
I told her not to, which is good news.
- I left a note. A Post-it.
- Roy, maybe the issue here.
This is getting too hot;
we need to cool it down.
Maybe she went to get something to eat.
Good. C'mon...
May I help?
Yea, I'm feeling a little bit strange.
So is it okay if I hang
out here for a while?
Of cause, I'll go get you some water.
Here you go.
Antonio Quintana wants to know,
where is the battery.
Where is the battery?
I'm sorry... I'm looking for...
Roy...
Miller.
You know him?
I... He's an assassin... platinum grade.
- He's trying to find Simon.
- Oh my God...
And to kill you...
Simon?
June, Simon.
Simon, Jume.
I'm okay, I got it.
Simon, please move!
You have quite some balls.
Hands like Houdini!
I'm so sorry...
But you were trying to kill me.
That's disgusting.
Oh, my God.
Just die!
Oh shit...
I gotta get you guys some place safe...
- He's not on the train.
- Oh, really?
The cameras at the station show him.
He must've gotten off
before the train stopped.
Always the classics, boy.
Salzburg, Austria...
Very nice.
Yes.
No, we just got here.
No, we're talking now...
No, I understand.
No, but it is great to
hear your voice too Naomi.
I'll meet you at the Caprice
as soon as you could be there.
It is a beautiful city.
Yea.
I've never seen anything quite like it.
Neither have I.
I have to go out for a bit...
Okay...
I... I was thinking about
ordering some room service.
Maybe we could have dinner.
That sounds great.
9 'o clock?
9 sounds great.
June...
Could you do me a favour?
Just stick around here... that's better.
Yeah of course, where else am I goanna go?
See you in a minute.
They're not goanna hurt you.
You are too valuable to them.
Just breathe and listen to the music.
This is something special for you.
I know you like it.
Cool! Thanks.
Order as much room service as you
like, but do not leave the room,
- Okay?
- Alright
I really need to talk to
you about the Zephyr later..
And we will.
Can I get you something?
Red wine please.
Right away.
You seem different.
Do I?
So, who's your company?
She is beautiful. The blonde.
She seems capable.
I've just met her.
She is a nobody.
Someone I picked up on the way.
That's a shame.
This is getting boring.
Are we goanna do the deal or not?
Don't speak to me like that.
I'll speak to you any way I please, Tony.
We both know you're lucky I'm here.
I have the battery.
I'm on a schedule.
The world of is full of bad
guys and people are calling.
Ask him the price...
Alright then...
What's your price?
I have a figure in mind...
What's it worth to you?
Are you angry about your island, Roy?
Tick, tick, tick, tick, tick, Tony.
I'm Isabelle George, director
of counter espionage at the CIA.
I'm sure you are.
Forgive me, I just...
I just don't know exactly what to believe.
That's understandable considering that the
last five days you've been fed a steady diet...
...of misinformation and fantasy by an
agent of ours who's recently gone rogue.
He said that Fitzgerald was the one
who wanted to steal the battery.
Well, let's examine the facts.
Miller told you that he was protecting the
Zephyr from people who wanted to misuse it.
But now he's trying to sell it to
an international arms dealer.
Antonio Quintana.
One of Europe's leading
weapons manufacturers.
Ask yourself, Miss Havens...
Has Roy Miller said anything
to you that's proven to be true?
He used you as a mule to carry the
battery through security, Miss Havens.
He's been playing you.
He's a spy. That's what he does.
He lies for a living.
Any love, empathy... we train
that right out of them.
What did you imagine?
The two of you would move into
a condo together? Get a dog?
You can't have a life
with him. That's fantasy.
But you can have your back...
She's been gone eight minutes.
We need you to get back
to the hotel before Miller.
What am I supposed to do?
Alright...
This pen is a transmitter.
Once you have confirmation
that Miller has not hidden the Zephyr...
...that it is somewhere
nearby or on his person.
You confirm this by
simply clicking the button.
Sorry, I'm late.
Everything go okay?
Sure enough.
It's getting hotter.
So, did you get your price?
I followed you tonight.
You have nothing to say.
Here's to Wichita...
Where we first...
...bumped into each other?
Do you think that was fate, Roy?
I do not believe in fate.
But I believe in luck.
I don't know what to believe.
That hurt more than I thought it would...
I'm going home.
He promised that if you turned
yourself in, he'll protect you.
I love your optimism.
Never lose it.
Get him.
Get her out of here.
He's not here, Sir.
They tell you you're going home?
You sit inside the helicopter, June?
You can't go home.
Shit!
Close the door!
Get in the car!
Don't let him escape.
He has the battery!
Hold your fire! He has the battery!
They secure the kid?
Yes.
They found Roy?
We'll find the body.
We have to.
He went down with the Zephyr.
Thank you guys...
Schwedelbach, GERMANY.
Aah... Fitz...
Fitz, I think we just made a wrong turn...
Ram stein is that way, West...
And I think we're going South.
You know what, you're right.
Tell him, we're back on track.
I don't have the battery, but
no one's goanna get it now.
Yea, I've got the next best thing.
I'll see you in Spain in two days.
Hi, Wilmer!
- How was the party?
- It was nice
I see the 'Goat' is still out there.
Yea.
I thought it was a wedding present.
It was, but...
I think I wanted her to want
it more than she wanted it.
Okay...
This just come in?
G-body Grand Prix.
Largest hood in history.
Gonne be a real beauty'.
Ru-pa...? No... Fe-pa...?
No, it's... Amapola 5826...
Let's see...
That's like an hour from here...
I think it's a safe house.
Here we go...
Who's out there?
I am not afraid to use this.
Oh, Frank! Look at her...
I wanna know what she's doing in my
lawn in the middle of the night?
I have the pistons you ordered.
Pistons?
For the '67 Grand Prix.
Molly, I didn't...
You're all wet. Please, come inside.
That Pontiac you have out
there, Frank, is a real classic.
I really love pre-70s Grand Prix'.
So, you two lived here long?
This old place?
It's been our home for forty years.
Sit down, honey.
Have a cookie.
Frank thinks we should
move, but I am uncomfortable.
And we can afford to stay, thanks
to Publisher's Clearing House.
You won Publisher's Clearing House?
Twice.
Plus we won two lotto quick picks and
Frank doesn't even remember buying.
Oh, I didn't buy 'em.
Oh, yeah. Like you didn't
order pistons off the Internet.
You don't know what you're
typing into that computer, Frank.
In a couple of minutes we'll
have your clothes, honey.
So...
Roy Miller?
This was one of his safe
houses, wasn't it?
What the hell are you talking about?
Honey, what's this all about?
I'm sorry, I thought...
Maybe I must have this all wrong.
I was just... looking for some
information about my friend Roy.
If you'd like to change, there's
a proper room right there.
That's our son Mathew.
We lost him in Kuwait.
It was a chopper crash.
He saved the lives of
two of his crewmen.
He used to always take care of everyone.
He was an Eagle Scout.
This was taken the day he
got that swimming badge.
He could swim clear across lake
Sunapee with practically one breath.
I just...
I believe we've... I'm June Havens.
I'm Molly Knight.
This is June Havens and
I'm leaving a message...
...on my own machine for whoever's
listening to this phone call.
I have the Zephyr...
I have the Zephyr and
I'm ready to make a deal.
I'm sitting on Route 28,
right outside New Hampshire.
And if you want the Zephyr,
you better come and get it.
Hey fellas.
So...
You want the Zephyr?
I got the Zephyr.
It's right here.
Come and get it.
Seville, SPAIN.
Come on...
Let's go!
Welcome to Espana.
It will take a while,
for it to take effect.
Today is the Festival of San Fermin.
Have you ever seen a
bullfight, Miss Havens?
My name is Antonio Quintana.
I know who you are.
What did he give me?
It is something we're
developing in my company.
A new kind of truth serum.
Really?
I have a few questions
for you about the battery,
since we both know what you
gave to my men was a joke.
I don't like you very much...
The truth?
Good.
It worked.
You know, I really like Miller though...
Did you know I was totally
wrong about him in Salzburg?
He wanted me to hear that phone
call so that I would follow him.
I'd turn him in and then
he could get me home safely.
He was trying to protect me.
It's crazy that I could feel so
powerful and capable around him.
Shut up...
- He takes care of me
- Shut up!
Where is the battery?
Where is it?
I bet you've never made a girl
an omelette, have you Antonio?
Don't test me, June.
Or got her to her sister's
wedding on time?
It's really the little things. Honestly.
- They count so much
- Enough!
Okay!
Miller is dead! Roy Miller is dead.
He's out. Est muerto! Comprendes?
No. No, he is not.
He can hold his breath
for a really long time.
Si est muerto!
He is dead!
I'm not goanna ask you again.
If you don't tell me
what I need to know...
...you're goanna die.
I do not know where the battery is.
Then why did you tell
everyone you had it? Why?
Because I was trying to find Roy.
This white bitch is driving me crazy.
Antonio, wherever there's bad guys like
you around Roy's not too far away.
You are going to kill her.
Kill her.
You're goanna die.
Finally.
Nice to meet you...
- John
- Antonio.
Too bad you couldn't get the battery.
Where is the boy?
I thought you would not?
Why don't you follow me down to
the river and bring the money?
Okay.
Is this thatching? Because, I've
never seen anything like that before.
We have really good architecture
in Boston, but nothing like this.
It's so clear.
It's time to kill her.
Is this all weapons money,
or is this family money?
Gardens... He likes gardens, huh?
So, do you guys take care of the garden?
It's so relaxing...
This really is a happy place.
Look at these trumpet flowers.
Ok, Eduardo, you don't
have to pull me around.
You can just tell me where you
want me to go, okay?
This way, Blondie.
See, now we're communicating.
Bet you're taking me
some place safe and secure.
Some place special.
Antonio's special place.
Oh, Antonio has a special place?
That's so nice!
Everyone should have a special place.
Come on.
Luis?
Is there a problem, Eduardo?
Shut up!
- Hi Roy.
- Hi June.
You're supposed to be home.
You're supposed to be dead.
- I can explain
- You don't have to
I came here to get Simon.
I just get caught up in something.
Oh, that's cool.
Be careful.
His name is Eduardo.
Eduardo, habla Engels?
I need you to listen, because when you wake
up you'll call your boss and tell him...
...that Roy Miller, that's me, has
the battery and escaped with the girl.
- Oh, you have the battery?
- Yea
Will you tell him?
Comprende?
Yes.
Let's go.
I'm worried about Simon.
I haven't seen him and my tracker is blank.
Being with you is so exciting.
You excite me, Miller.
- Took you long to get here
- 7 'o clock
I think I feel like having sex.
You know, really great sex.
Did they give you something?
You need to rehydrate.
Roy...
June...
June?
You don't seem very
happy to see me, Roy.
What?
Not really.
I am happy.
So the red dot is us?
No, we're yellow.
Red dot is Simon.
Grab tight.
Hello?
It's Eduardo!
He says his name is Roy Miller,
He said he has the battery.
- That's impossible.
- She disappeared with him.
No!
Miller is here.
There they are!
This way.
Follow me!
Oops...
There's Fitz.
I see him!
Slow... slowly...
Get the guns.
Okay.
- Here
- Wow!
- What next?
- Lead them
June Havens!
You've got skills.
- See you down the hill
- Are you sure?
No.
Freeze right there, Roy.
Hey, Simon.
- Get down on your knees, now.
- Roy!
Put 'em in the water,
in the water.
I just want the kid, Fitz.
Okay, well I hope you brought
what you want otherwise,
I'm goanna have to kill him,
and I swear to you I'll do it.
I believe you.
Just like Wichita.
- I understand
- Okay
I'm just goanna get the battery.
It's right here.
Please don't give it to him.
Roy, please don't give it to him.
Put it on the deck.
- Roy! Roy! Roy! Roy!
- Easy
- Please don't give it to him.
- Simon, it's goanna be okay
- Roy, don't give it to him
Shut up!
- Okay, okay, I'll make another one
- Simon don't talk
Make another one?
Am I dying?
No, you fainted.
I'm sorry.
That's okay.
No, I've been trying to tell you...
Why is it hot?
Because it's filled with power.
The battery! I messed up.
It's deteriorating.
I know. It's unstable.
You're a smart guy, Simon.
I know you'll figure it out.
Oh, my God.
Roy, you're shot.
Get help.
You're beautiful, June.
Stay with me.
We're here Miller,
we got you.
June...
WASHINGTON
It's been a spectacular
couple of weeks, Miller.
It's good to see you, Isabelle.
Hey, guys.
We cleaned house, Roy.
I have to thank you for that.
I trusted the wrong man.
That happens.
Simon's happy.
He's got a new life.
Where June?
I sent her home.
She gets it.
She knows you two lead different
lives, and she's moving on.
As should you.
You gave up those things.
You let go of who you were.
Family. Friends. That's the deal.
Why are we still talking about this?
Because the agency
invested a lot in you.
And you are an asset only
as long as you stay focussed.
You look good.
Get some rest.
We're goanna transfer you to a
secure facility tomorrow.
For your safety.
Nurse, what did you give me?
Brotine Zero.
Stay under there, Roy.
You're dead.
Make way, please.
Going to the mortuary.
Do not worry, Roy.
I got this.
It's time for a vacation.
Hey there, sleepyhead.
What day is it?
Someday.
Someday, Roy.
What am I wearing?
A pair of shorts.
How did I get into these shorts?
Roy, I've been trained to
rebuild a 6 speed transmission...
using only a pair of pliers
and a crescent wrench.
I think I can get you into a
pair of shorts without looking.
I'm not saying that's what I did.
You're both the navigator and the DJ.
We have a long way
to go to Cape Horn.
With me.
Without me.
With you.
Put some tunes on the radio, Mr. DJ.
Yes, ma'am.