For my daughter MingXia
London, 2:30 PM
Hi, Mom.
Hi, dear. I have bad news.
Your dad's prognosis isn't good.
You have to come.
-Did he ask you to call?
Not in so many words.
We saw each other for 15 minutes last summer.
You were there, we had nothing to say as usual.
Sebastien, with his flat, bank account,
insurance, the university...
Your sister's in Australia.
I'm all alone, it's too much for me.
I'll see if Gaelle can come.
Hi, love.
He's worse?
-I have to be there.
I'll come.
THE BARBARIAN INVASIONS
The body of Christ.
The communion's for me.
How's Mr Desmarais?
-I don't know. I'm not Mr Desmarais.
Sorry,
the computer system is a mess.
Constance Lazure.
- My wife Louise.
Must be hard having him here.
I threw him out 15 years ago.
So whether he's here
or humping co-eds in his condo...
Gimme a break. You know it's been
years since I "humped" a co-ed.
And Raphaelle Metellus?
-She was Dominique and Pierre's student.
You were her private tutor? "Kneel down,
open wide so that I don't feel your teeth."
I'd best continue my rounds. Have a good day!
-You too, Sister.
I called Sebastien to let him know.
You did?
-Aren't you glad?
Lovely, we can play his video games.
-He's still young.
Ok, but couldn't he have read
one book in his life?
Any book? Is that asking too much?
He may not read, but he earns
more in a month than you earn in a year.
Thanks a lot.
-That's ok, we had room.
It's flying to Belfast Monday...
-I'll probably have to stay longer.
My darling!
You must be exhausted.
What time is it for you? 2 a.m.?
Gaelle, how are you, dear?
-Fine, thank you.
Hello, sir.
-Young man.
Do you remember Gaelle?
-Gaelle is unforgettable.
How are you?
No private rooms?
-I'm lucky I'm not in the hall.
I tried, all I got was voice mail.
Dad's very sick.
Please get in touch.
What I see isn't encouraging.
But to be sure I need a PET scan.
See if they can do it.
They can send it by satellite.
It stands for
Positron Emission Tomography.
Sherbrooke has one, but
there's a 6-12 month waiting list.
Isn't he going to Burlington today?
They have one, -
but it's expensive. $2000 U.S.
You'll have to pay cash or by credit card.
Money's no problem.
-You're lucky.
You never listened to my body.
But I'm not laying a guilt.
-Look, I have to get dressed.
An ambulance is taking me to Burlington in 10 minutes.
-No more excuses!
For my radiation therapy.
-No!
The machines here are too old.
-Stop avoiding me.
This is my son, Sebastien,
he's going with me.
She's a woman I used to know, long ago.
I couldn't face coming alone.
You've never been here?
-Never.
But you see each other regularly.
Always on neutral ground.
Usually in restaurants.
Did he come to your place?
-Occasionally.
But you never came here.
No. I knew that this was where he
brought his mistresses.
If we're lucky, we'll find some little panties.
I'm glad Sebastien's going with him today.
It's important they talk, those two.
[Playing "America, The Beautiful"]
You know the saying, "Christmas in the scanner,
Easter 6 feet under."
I have the scan.
It doesen't look good.
Not good at all.
We can't be certain,
but the margin of error is almost nil.
Is he in a lot of pain?
Why don't you bring him here?
At least he wouldn't suffer.
We'll make sure of it.
I'm sorry, buddy.
Baltimore's not far.
7 hours by car, an hour by plane.
I won't go into EXILE.
-Wouldn't you like your own room-
with a bathroom, CDs?
-What CDs?
So you can listen to music.
They have that in civilized countries. AC too.
Know what that costs?
-Nothing. I'll take care of it.
I won't know a soul.
-We'll all go tomorrow.
No we won't. I'm not going to the States,
I don't feel like being murderd by raging idots!
I voted for Medicare, I'll accept the consequences.
-Only idiots refuse to change.
I want to be with my friends.
-Your friends? Where are they?
Dominique's away, but Pierre...
Meanwhile you've got no one.
Apart from that lunatic this morning.
Which lunatic?
-It's irrelevant.
The tears, rolling eyes: My Remy!
Who's he talking about?
-Marlene Dupire.
You didn't sleep with Marlene Dupire?
She's a certified nut, everyone knows!
You wrecked your family for her kind?
-I wrecked nothing!
You ruined Mom's life,
my adolescence, Sylvaine's...
Blaming me for her failure?
She loves the sea, she sails the world,
delivering yachts. Beats a 3rd-rate university.
You may be a millionaire,
but you know nothing!
I know I won't end up like you!
She's the reason I'm here.
She raised me, not you!
Don't you have a plane
to catch to Hong Kong?
I don't need you, not for one second!
Go to hell!
Fuck you!
-Go to hell!
We're going back to London.
-You can't.
We offer him the best hospital in the world,
he refuses.
You heard him. He'll never change.
You plan to have kids?
-Definitely.
Until you're a parent
you'll never understand.
He changed your diapers.
He called your teachers every month
all through school.
He so wanted you to do well.
When you had meningitis at age 3,
he rocked you in his arms
for 48 hours non-stop,
without sleep,
to keep death at bay.
You can't remember that.
What should I do?
Find his friends.
Find him a comfortable room.
That shouldn't be hard.
The Ministry forbids changing hospitals.
Anyway, they'd park him in the hall in Emergency.
The floor below is empty?
-2 years, now.
Could he move there?
-Ice cream with your pie?
You can always ask at Administration.
Good luck!
I'll leave you now.
You know, you're lucky to have such a caring son.
-You think so?
How many children  come here?
Look around! See many children at their parent's
bedside? I'm here every day, so I know.
I never see mine.
Did you have a father?
Was he ever hospitalized?
In the end.
-Did you visit him often?
He lived in Chicoutimi, I was teaching
in Montreal, and it was winter.. so...
You came from England?
London, Chicoutimi, for you...
same thing? Cancer has made you a bit confused?
When it's over, press End.
That stops it.
It's hard, but if you concentrate,
you'll manage.
Hi, Dad!
See, the Pacific Ocean.
We're sailing from Sydney
to New Caledonia,
on to Easter Island
and finally Valparaiso.
I'm sending you lots of sea air.
They say it's good for your health.
I have to go. Satellite connections
cost a fortune.
I'm sending you lots and lots of kisses.
Bye for now!
Security badge?
-Ms Pelletier? Lloyd's of London.
Didn't they give you one?
-No.
Last door on the right.
But next time you need a badge.
Hello.
Pauline Joncas-Pelletier.
Please have a seat.
Well now, my assistant has informed me that you
represent Lloyd's of London?
Nope, not at all, I said that just to get in.
My father's here on the 3rd floor.
I'd like to move him to the empty floor.
Set up something more comfortable.
That's wonderful!
[Snobby] Indead that complies perfectly with our awareness
programs involving family members.
But unfortunately our allocation
of infrastructure is determined
by the Ministry's ambulatory thrust.
It's absolutely impossible to target our
responses in terms of individual beneficiaries.
I'm sure our personel...
-I prepared this file.
You must understand, our resource allocation
aims at prioritizing responses
according to diagnostic parameters
defined by the Region 02 consultations.
Eh, seriously.
Even still, we're not quite in Third World.
Think it over.
[Snobby] Even if we close our eyes, we'd require
union integration and cooperation.
And that is a problematic!
-I'll handle them.
This file will be updated weekly.
I'll come back tomorrow. Thank you!
There's a room on the empty floor.
It'll take 5 minutes. I just want to show you.
I'll be back in 5.
Sorry, take the next one.
I want to set up a room on this floor.
We could...
Look, nothing happens
without the union.
Nothing starts or ends without the union. Clear?
-Why do you think I came to you...
You'd have to paint it,
scrub the floor...
Just a sec, man. Maybe you don' realize...
You're talking overtime, you realize.
And my guys don't... -Paid in cash.
Cash?
-Cash. One painter.
Two.
Six hours.
Eight.
What's the rate?
$40.
-$35.
I want a bed, curtains, chairs...
-Look, man, that's not us who does that.
You hire a crew, supervise the work.
And charge me reasonable admistration fees.
Reasonable?
-Under 19%
Here's $2500 for starters.
We'll settle up every 2 days.
Where's my laptop?
What?
-My computer.
On the floor.
-It's not there.
It must be.
-Nothing there.
The floor, not the locker.
I'm not crazy. -It's not there.
Someone must have taken it.
Who?
-I don't know.
It seems like you don't get it. I've had
50 emails since yesterday. How'll I recover them?
My entire deal with Norway.
I didn't have a backup. I was in the middle of doing it..
Do you even know what I do?
-No. I would know if you had ever explained it.
Why bother? You never listen!
There were, what, 3000 dead.
Historically, that's insignificant.
As a U.S. example,
50,000 died
at the Battle of Gettysburg.
What is significant,
as my old prof said,
is they struck at
the heart of the Empire.
In previous conflicts- Korea,
Vietnam, the Gulf War
the Empire managed to keep the barbarians
outside its gates, its borders
In that sense, people may look back on 9/11,
and I stress may,
as the beginning
of the great barbarian invasions.
Alain Lussier, thank you.
-My pleasure.
Excuse me, my computer was just stolen.
-Oh yeah? Fill out this form.
What for?
-It's for the police.
Look, I've had all these
since Monday.
The police ever investigate?
-No, only when there's physical violence.
Last week a woman was raped in the
old laundry room, so then they came.
Otherwise they'd be here 24/7.
It's easy to rob patients.
Their eyes are closed half the time.
And the union protects the employees.
There's not much we can do.
Ronald?
What can I do for you, pal?
-I lost or misplaced my computer.
Maybe in my dad's room. So, on the off-chance
someone should find a laptop somewhere...
We'll ask around,
but I can't guarantee anything.
In case.
-Right, in case. We'll check.
Thanks, I appreciate it.
Hello? Speaking.
Of course I remember you, Sebastien.
How are you?
Yes, it's been a long time.
He's very sick.
And he's all alone,
except for my mother.
I knew he was in hospital,
but I didn't realize...
I almost never come to Montreal, so...
Where is he now, is he still in hospital?
Pierre, I need you... now.
School's starting, we haven't found
a daycare, the kids are sick...
That's life. Always the same.
I'll try to get a flight.
You say that because times
are so terrible.
Not especially terrible. Not at all.
Contrary to belief,
the 20th centaury wasn't that bloody.
It's agreed that wars caused 100 million deaths.
A round figure generally loved by historians.
Add 10 million
for the Russian gulags.
The Chinese camps, we'll never know,
but say 20 million.
So 130, 135 million dead.
Not all that impressive.
In the 16th centuary,
the Spanish and the Portuguese managed,
without gas chambers or bombs, to slaughter
150 million Indians in Latin America.
That's a lot of work, Nurse.
150 million, with axes!
Even if they had Church support,
it was an achievement
So much so that the Dutch, English,
French and later Americans
followed their lead
and butchered another 50 million.
200 million dead in all!
The greatest massacre in history
took place right here. Right around us.
And not the tiniest
Holocaust museum.
The history of mankind
is a history of horrors!
They had a trial program with heroin
a little while ago.
See if it still exists.
Heroin's 800% more effective
than morphine.
At the end it makes a huge difference.
-Ok, thanks.
Get some rest.
-I will, good night.
Are you pals with the Premier,
or a hockey star?
His son takes care of him.
-Oh, I know, and "Dumbo" won't thank him.
My son is an ambitious
and puritanical capitalist.
Whereas I was always a sensual socialist.
-Sensual isn't half of it, Sister.
Lewd!- Debauched! -Bestial!
-Lascivious! -Perverse!
How are you, you lusty sinner?
-Better!
Give me a kiss, you randy snake!
You're back?
-Yesterday?
And Alaska?
-Lovely and cold, like me!
You see, Sister? My exquisite daughter-in-law, my
heroic wife, and two most charming mistresses.
I can die in peace.
-You'll burn in the flames of hell.
And I won't be alone. They're safe, but given the
depravity of these two, they'll roast alongside me.
Whereas you'll be condemed to play the harp on a cloud
for eternity, seated between John Paul II,
a surly Pole, and Mother Theresa, a slimy Albanian
His illness has reached his brain.
No, it's an ethnological truth,
Louise.
Albanians are often slimy
and Poles are always surly.
"for the misfortunes of Poland
are proof of God's existence!"
Hello. I'd like to meet someone, a police
officer or detective in the narcotics squad.
Have a seat.
Come stai, you big pig?
-What are you doing here, old queer?
This is Alessandro.
We've heard all about you.
Gilles Levac.
My partner, Kim Delgado.
Have a seat.
-Thanks.
My father's hospitalized here
in Montreal.
He gets rotten care, of course,
and he's in pain.
A doctor friend suggested
I get him some heroin.
I know little about drugs.
As a student I smoked pot.
Drugs are sold in every city,
and the police know where.
I hoped, perhaps naively, you could recommend some
spots where I can find high-quality heroin.
That's fascinating, except that...
our job is to arrest dealers,
not help prospective buyers.
think of me as a smart guy
trying to save time.
Think of me as someone not too dumb
who doesen't want to read a headline:
"Police Help Our Journalist
to Buy Narcotics."
I'm no... -She and I don't want to end
our days directing traffic in Chibougamau.
I swear I'm not a reporter.
-Why should I believe you?
I'm a market operator with MacDougall Deutsch.
It's easy to check.
It's easy to print phony cards.
Sorry to disturb you.
I'll have to try the discos.
Look, the Citrouillard family!
Claude, I don't believe it!
How are you?
Heroin used to be for the rich.
Now prices have dropped and that's changed.
But traditionally it's the
drug of musicians and poets...
You mean, ask my friends?
-I don't mean anything.
I'm repeating rumors circulated in the media.
-Ok.
What exactly do you do?
My dear, I'm the director of the
Canadian University Institute of Rome.
What exactly does it do,
the Canadian University Institute of Rome?
In fact we're a leading cultural agency that
assists Canadian university students in Rome.
And how many Canadian university
students are there in Rome?
In fact, a few.
Why do you ask?
We like to know how our taxes
are being squandered.
We're a very modest operation. Naturally
the director requires paid housing...
...where you're always welcome,
of course.
You haven't been hit by cutbacks?
-Quite impossible.
The Institute is buried in the budgetary
quagmire of Foreign Affairs.
The Minister himself
has no inkling we exist.
Who should I have slept with
to get that job?
I'm afraid that people I slept with
would've been blind to your charms,
however abundant they are.
Abundance has it fans, dearie.
-Not in Foreign Affairs.
This it?
Someone found it somewhere?
-That's it.
I have to get heroin for him.
I need someone with contacts.
I've been away too long.
The only powder I sniff now
is "Baby's Own."
I could try to ask my daughter.
Remember Nathalie? -Yes, a little.
I can't promise anything.
I rarely hear from her.
Hi, sweetheart.
It's mom. It's Diane.
I miss you, sweetheart.
Look,
remember Sebastien, Remy's son?
You often played together as kids.
He wants to meet.
He needs some information.
So call whenever you like,
at any time.
If you prefer not to talk to me,
I'll leave you his number.
We have to hit Costco before 6.
We need a shitload of diapers.
Children cost so much.
Why do people in the Third World
have so many?
What a dumb thing to say.
-Your poor students, if you teach such crap!
Did you get that book I mentioned?
-Which one?
Inner Healing by Swami Rapudanthra.
No, unfortunately not.
-I'll bring it. Your body's in your head.
Illness starts and ends in the head.
I keep telling Pierre that.
Well, we'll be going.
-See you soon.
How old is she? It's not about age.
Her breasts outweigh her brain.
Cut it out. -It's true! The quantity of blood
required to irrigate the mass
drains the brain. It's physiological.
-I do not want any comments.
She's given me two girls
who've transformed my life.
And a mere brush of her hand
makes me as hard as a bull.
Which you'll agree
is a godsend at our age.
Nathalie?
I think I would recognize you. Come.
Do you work full-time?
What do you do?
-Proofreader.
For a publishing company?
Boreal Press.
-So your hours are flexible.
My proposal is that
I pay for your consumption,
as well as my father's.
And a salary for the time you spend with him.
Want brown or white?
-I don't know anything about it.
To smoke or shoot up?
-I trust you.
You shouldn't.
-Why not?
You should never trust a junkie.
The're too used to lying.
It's right there.
How much do you need?
-$500.
It's pretty chilly, huh?
That girl's innocent. She's the daughter of
my father's friend and shes doing me a favor.
Arrest me, but forget her.
-You want me to arrest you?
Think I'm a fool?
-Not at all.
You located Olivier in two days.
Pretty good.
Olivier?
-The dealer.
Why not arrest him?
-Want me to arrest everyone?
Oh wow, recognize him?
-He's Michel Richer, the biologist.
You never bust suppliers?
All the time. We work 2,3 years, and
finally bust an Iranian gang.
Everybody's happy. Then Iraqis took their place.
Or the Lebanese, Turks, Italians.
There's too much demand.
It's an invasion.
What are you doing here?
I mean, now?
My job.
-I see.
Keeping the peace.
The fish are biting
in Zampino's pond.
Time to go fishing.
What did you study?
Why do you ask?
-Curious.
Criminology, minor in psych.
You?
Mathematics, minor in economics.
Take care.
-You too.
You don't remember me?
-No.
I was close to your mom.
You mean you slept with her?
-Not just that.
Were you married?
-Yes.
The married ones
never stayed till morning.
My sister and I would see them if we woke up at night.
From a child's perspective,
it must seem sordid.
We called it
sexual liberation.
What's that?
-Heroin.
It comes from opium, right?
It's morphine mixed with chemicals.
Will you inject it?
-We'll start by inhaling and then we'll see.
It's incredible to...
Be quiet now. Try to concentrate.
The first time is the best.
It's the one you long for later.
It's called riding the dragon.
Morning.
-Good morning.
It smells. Have you been smoking?
-Not on your life. Thats just a candle I light for my medi-mications.
Where's your IV?
-Dr Levesque had it removed.
Good morning, my doctresses.
Take a deep breath.
Does it hurt here?
-Oh, yes.
And here too?
-There too, yes.
Is it unbearable?
-Goodness, no!
You're in high spirits.
-Couldn't be higher!
How do you sleep?
-Like a baby.
Then I won't prescribe painkillers.
Forget it!
-That's wonderful.
I always say, the longer
they stay lucid, the better.
I plan to remain lucid till I die.
Wonderful, Mr Paranteau.
-Thanks so much, Dr. Dube.
I'm not Dr. Dube.
-How fitting, because I'm not Mr. Parenteau.
Who's he?
So it all started
with Maria Goretti.
Exactly. The girl who said, No!
-Which one was Maria Goretti?
A Portuguese peasant.
-Portuguese? Santa Maria Goretti!
She was Italian?
-From Nettuno.
Portugal, that's Fatima, the apparitions,
the Virgin, the shepherds.
The secret of Fatima.
-Which only the Pope could hear.
Poor Canada, in 1960.
-Look, we believed it.
So they filmed the edifying life
of Maria Goretti.
Starring?
-I've racked my brains.
Ines Orsini.
Of course! The Immortal Ines Orisini!
How could I forget?
I saw it at school in Padua with the Jesuits.
-Me, the Jesuits at Brebeuf.
Me, at the Chicoutimi seminary.
For the whole film the
immortal Ines Orsini
is covered from head to toe.
But at some point they had to at least suggest
the abject nature of the bestial desire
of the vile rapist.
So the exquisite Maria dips
her adorable toes into the ocean.
With a regal but modest gesture,
she lifts her skirt...
The thighs of Ines Orsini!
-Even I remember!
Oh, the rivers of sperm I spilled
dreaming of her thighs.
So that explains the rise of the St. Lawrence
River water basin.
For years I'd fall asleep with
a hard-on, dreaming of Ines Orsini,
until the day I saw Francoise Hardy
on TV singing All the Boys and Girls.
I was suddenly indifferent to Ines's holy airs.
-Maria Goretti, alone,
abandoned - the fate of womanhood
For a long time I slept with
Francoise Hardy. We were very happy.
Alas, I discovered Julie Christie in a film.
Our mad affair lasted six months,
till I met Chris Evert,
the tennis champ,
whom I left for the sublime Karen Kain
dancing carmen in Marseille.
All my life I went to bed
with the world's most gorgeous women.
Then one morning I woke up realizing
I'd fallen asleep dreaming of the Caribbean Sea.
I'd grown old.
Women had deserted my dreams.
It's been so long
since I dreamed of a man.
Why don't you explain to me someday
just what is it you do?
You're president of a Norwegian oil firm.
From a failing U.S. company
you've bought a North Sea oil field.
You can produce oil for $7 per barrel,
and you sell for $25.
But you want to limit your exposure
to fluctuating oil prices. How?
No idea.
-You see me, we do a swap.
What's that?
-A deal where my bank pays you
a fixed price
and you pay the floating price.
You contract to sell your oil at a fixed
price for a fixed period. In short,
I manage financial risk.
Are you good at what you do?
Pretty good.
Could you get the driver
to stop at the lake?
Probably.
I'd like to see the lake.
At Berkley I did my PhD alongside Locken and
Donaldson, two future Pulitzers.
They were no better than me,
but they were American.
Me, I came back here, I started
to teach, got married,
And then... then nothing else.
Your affairs kept you too busy.
-That was small time, like you said.
No, what I lacked was extravagance.
Basically all I ever succeded in was pathetic trysts
in poorly heated East End flats.
I was replaced by a TA within 48 hours.
The dean neglected to say goodbye.
The lowliest secretary
gets a cake for maternity leave.
Ladies and gentlemen, for health reasons
I'll be unable to complete this term.
Ms Raphaelle Metellus
will replace me.
Does this affect our deadlines?
No, deadlines and exam dates
remain unchanged.
Any other questions?
Good luck.
-Thanks.
So, as you saw last week, the 1840
election was particularly stormy.
The Whig party,
then newly formed, united four
distinct constituencies
First, the National Republicans, followers of
Adams and Clay, the party founders.
Irina's home, I have to go out.
Is Nathalie buying for you?
She's a friend.
If you're a regular,
maybe we should deal directly.
It's only temporary.
Everything in life is temporary.
"you can never swim
in the same river twice," said...
what's his face? You know...
You can't count on Nathalie.
She'll pull a fast one on you.
We'll see.
You know where I live.
-Sure.
What are you doing?
-I was waiting for you. I wanted to see you.
You're always on my mind.
-I know, you've told me.
At night I picture you bleeding
in an alley, in shooting galleries.
I'm always so scared.
It's unbearable.
You imagine too much.
You know this can't go on.
Of course I know. I know it better
than you. You can't do anything for me.
I know it's my fault,
that's what's killing me.
That doesn't change anything.
I don't need this.
You don't care much
about living, do you?
Not really.
I was like you at your age. Ready to
die at any time. I give a shit.
That's why the young people
make the best martyrs.
It's paradoxical,
but living grows on you,
when you begin to subtract:
I've got 20 years left, 15, 10.
When you realize it's for the last time.
I'm buying my last car.
This is my last trip
to Genoa, Barcelona...
I won't live that long.
-How do you know?
Overdoses are pretty frequent, you know.
But you can never tell. Maybe you'll
kick it and reach a ripe old age.
We can't decipher the past,
how can we know the future?
No one ever knows what'll happen to them.
Except me, now. I know.
Are you scared? -Sure am. I don't want to
stop living. I loved life so much. You can't know how much.
What was it you loved?
-Everything.
Wine, books, music, women,
above all women.
Their smell, their mouths,
the feel of their skin.
Were there many of them?
-Yes.
Don't they begin to seem the same?
-A bit, yes.
But I never get tired of them.
Still the great seducer? -No, not anymore.
With age, it's not the same thing.
At least you can enjoy wine just as much as before.
Unfortunately  not.
Not with my liver.
The trips you dreamed of,
did you make them?
Ah, in any case, nowadays there are tourists everywhere.
It's not the present you cling on,
It's your past.
That life is already dead.
-Perhaps.
I expected a musty antique dealer,
not a ravishing young lady.
I warn you, I'm no specialist.
At one time
everyone here was Catholic.
Like in Spain or Ireland.
At a very precise moment in 1966, in fact the
churches suddenly emptied out, in a few months.
A very strange phenomenon
that has yet to be explained.
So now we don't know
what to do with this.
The authorities would like to find
out if it has any value.
Commercial value?
-Yes.
Do you have any 18th-centuary
French cahlices?
The Americans snapped them up.
There are a few examples in the museums.
I'm sure this has great value
for people here, the collective memory.
But is there anything that we could sell?
-On the world market?
Honestly, I can't imagine it.
In other words,
this is all absolutely worthless.
I'll show you out.
Pius XII sitting on his ass
in his gilded Vatican
while Primo Levi was taken
to Auschwitz... That's not sad!
It's despicable! Hideous!
If what you say is true, and history
is a series of abominable crimes,
then someone has to exist
who can forgive us.
That's my belief.
I envy you.
If at least I'd written.
You wrote nothing?
-A few papers here and there, nothing serious.
What are you doing?
-It bugs me.
What would you have written?
The Gulag Archipelago,
The Periodic Table.
Really, you think you could have done that?
-Never. -So?
At least I'd have left a mark. We need to
succeed, even on our own terms.
To be a able to say we did our best.
It allows us to die at peace.
I'm a total failure.
-At least you realize it.
So many professors are smug,
unbearable.
I don't know your daughter,
but Sebastien's not exactly a failure.
Not thanks to me.
-You don't know that.
We thought we'd pay a visit.
-Everyone wonders how you are.
Not everyone, surely.
-You'd be surprised.
That last day in class
no one seemed very moved.
We had no idea at the time.
-Exactly. Now that you're gone...
We see what we're missing.
I'm touched to hear that. Sincerely.
We should be going.
We have a lecture by Mr Roby at 4.
-Off you go.
Good luck.
-Thanks.
-Don't give up.
-I won't.
Well I never.
-Surprising.
For illiterates, they're sweet.
It's not their fault.
No one taught them.
At this price we'll come anytime.
-We'll see.
I don't want it.
We agreed.
-No, thanks.
Do you want to split hers?
We're getting married next summer,
at my parents' in France.
You'll see, the chapel's lovely.
Louise and I married on
a grey February day in a dismal suburb.
So we could sleep together
without our families hassling us.
I want a wedding on the Loire.
6 months later I cheated on her.
That was fast.
-Indeed.
When I met Sebastien, I said: With him
it's forever, there'll be no one else.
I hope it lasts, for your sake.
Because, you know, love...
-No, no, no! Not "love."
Mom and Dad
talked about nothing else. "Love."
I love you. I love you too much.
I don't love you.
You can't build a life
on pop-song philosophy.
Love Me Tender. Love, Love Me Not.
It's ridiculous.
My parents divorced when I was 3.
For several years Dad continued
to come over for Sunday lunch.
Half an hour before he left,
I'd vanish.
I'd be lying on the ground in front
of his car so he couldn't leave.
Its out of the question that my
kids go through that.
So now my nocturnal pleasures are provided by
my giant-screen Toshiba at the foot of my bed.
No more curled-up toes?
That's over. I've seen enough ceilings.
-For ever?
I've closed the store, laid down my weapons,
hung up my skates.
Things are much quieter between us too.
-Well, well.
He's in Bologna all week
and I'm in Rome.
There's the weekend, but...
My wife falls asleep in bed
with the kids.
Great, you can reread Tocqueville.
That's what I did.
2000 pages on bible paper.
He's increasingly cultivated,
and his prostate increasingly swollen.
Sorry, I still enjoy it a lot.
In the country
there's an old cowboy I...
Cowboy? You're with a cowboy now?
Yes. There's an old cowboy
I invite over to shake my bush.
To shake your bush!
-Yes, but we had a fight.
I'll never understand men.
All my life I date asses
who thought only of escaping
after satisfying their base needs.
The other day, as a compliment,
I said to my cowboy:
To think we can still have sexual flings at our age.
He was incensed. He doesn't want to be a sex object,
talks about his masculinity.
-We love that!
Invokes father hunger goes on about exploring
his feminine side, his inner me.
It was unbearable.
The last thing I want is
a limp-dicked sentimentalist.
I want to be screwed forcefully.
That's all.
I'm sensitive
and smart enough for two.
A rub-down?
Would he like a rub-down? Does the
Muslim need to bow towards Mecca?
Does the Carmelite
long for the Holy Species?
Is this your first time here?
-Yes...
I don't know if you believe
in random acts of kindness,
but if you do,
render this sick man happy.
Give him the mother
of all rub-downs.
You will be repaid a hundredfold
in this life or another.
Am I in heaven already?
Are you my Valkyrie, my houri?
Oh joy!
Nathalie didn't show.
It's bad.
Your father's in withdrawal.
Know where Nathalie is?
-No idea.
She's disappeared.
-I warned you.
I may come back.
-Before 11.
I'm not supposed to do this.
You were right.
You said not to trust you.
Your dealer said that too.
Wake up. We've a contract.
What contract?
-I buy the dope, you look after Dad.
What's with him?
-He's waiting for you.
We're coming.
You honor a contract!
That's heavy, man.
-No its not "heavy." We had a deal. I'm counting on you.
At the market... my dad...
Y'know, my dad...
Want to trade dads?
Me, I made my life.
Perfect young man.
Perfect career.
Perfect fiancee.
I'm imperfect. It's sad.
It's very sad.
Where have you been?
I didn't know what to do.
Get a spoon.
-What?
A spoon.
Fill it to thirty.
I can't manage.
What is this?
-Don't ask, we don't have time.
You have to help. I beg you. Give him this.
He needs it. Please, I'll explain later.
What's in it?
-Heroin.
I beg you.
Shut the door, at least.
-I'm going.
Just this once.
-It'll soon be over.
Better?
We sat on your pier. He was never
happier than at the lake.
So I thought maybe could we borrow your cottage?
-Sure anytime. I'll get the keys.
What is it?
-The keys to the cottage.
What for? -I'm letting Sebastien use it.
He wants to take Remy.
Without asking me?
-I'm truly sorry.
I'm the one who decorated it.
-That's true.
The hours at Ikea,
don't they count.
Or the curtains I sewed? You lend our
house to strangers without asking!
Remy's not a stranger.
That's why Nicole
divorced Tom Cruise!
He'd lend their Colorado home
to anybody.
Thats enough. I'm lending my house
to my friend Reamy, and you shut up.
If that's how it is, I won't stay another
second. I'm taking the girls and moving out.
I'm sorry. Forget it, we'll manage.
No way. Use it whenever you like.
Don't worry. It's always this way.
That's life. -Thanks.
No news from Sylvaine?
No, I even called
the boat's owned in Chile.
I hope she's ok.
-She is, it's just the Net uplink.
The Pacific's big.
Goodbye.
Embrace the mystery
and you'll be saved.
Tell him you love him.
Tell him, and touch him.
Drink this one.
-Right now?
Here. Methadone's serious.
Now I trust you.
-Drink one a day.
Only one. No more, no less.
Come back on Monday.
If you screw up,
you're out of the program.
I still can't come to terms with it.
-You know you have to.
I can't accept it.
That's how it is. It's a law.
The very instant you shut your eyes,
millions more will also die at the same time.
But I won't be here anymore. Me.
I'll be gone for good.
If at least I'd learned something.
I feel as helpless
as the day I was born.
I haven't found a meaning. It's
Thats what we have to look for.
I have to keep searching.
We've been everything.
Separatists, independantists,
sovereignists, sovereignty-associationists.
At first we were existentialists.
We read Sartre and Camus.
Then Fanon,
we became anti-colonialists.
We read Marcuse and became Marxists.
-Marxist-Leninists.
Trotskyists.
-Maoists.
After Solzhenitsyn we changed.
We were structuralists.
Situationists.
-Feminists.
Demonstructionists.
-Is there an "ism" we haven't worshipped.
Cretinism.
-God no. Think of Guo Jing.
Who was he? -An archeologist
with a skirt slit to the crotch.
Even you remember. -In the 70s,
China opens up to the West.
Wou Jing  comes on a cultural exchange. The
university sends its trusty radical, me...
I enter the dining room of her hotel.
I spot her, and die.
Beauty that could melt Emperor Qin's
7000 terra cotta warriors.
I order tea, we make small talk.
I can see us doing Pekinese lotus.
-The Szechuan dragon.
To make myself appear intresting,
I dive in: "Your country has achieved so much.
We're so enviable. Your
Cultural Revolution is wonderful!"
Her lovely black eyes glaze over.
I'm mortified to realize
that she's thinking,
"He's either a CIA agent
or the worst cretin in the West."
So much for the lotus and dragon.
For two years she'd cleaned pigsties
on a re-education farm.
Father murdered,
mother committed suicide.
And some thick French-Canadian who's
seen the films of Jean-Luc Godard
and read Philippe Sollers
says that the Chinese
Cultural Revolution, is wonderful!
Cretinism doesnt sink any lower.
Voluntary simplicity.
Scrambled eggs with ossetra caviar
and fresh truffles. -From Tuscany.
And to stay in Italy, Castello Banfi Excelsus,
a modest vintage.
Why were we so dumb?
-Are we to infer congenital stupidity?
Not at all.
-Intelligence isn't an individual trait.
It's collective,
national, intermittent.
Oh, a new theory!
Athens, 416BC
Euripides premieres his Electra
Two rivals attend,
Sophocles and Aristophanes.
And two friends, Socrates and Plato.
Intelligence was there.
Firenze, 1504, Palazzo Vecchio,
on facing walls, two painters:
Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo.
An apprentice: Rafaello.
A manager: Niccolo Machiavelli.
Philadelphia, USA, 1776 - 1787.
Declaration of Independence
and the Constitution.
Adams, Franklin, Jefferson,
Washington, Hamilton and Madison.
No other country
has been so blessed.
I was born in Chicoutimi,
Canada, in 1950.
It's a miracle you're stupider.
in 1950, everyone was dumb,
in Athens and Chicoutimi.
In Italy you'd have supported
the Red Brigades.
Now it's Berlusconi.
-Philadelphia voted George Bush.
You see, you're not that dumb.
Intelligence has disappeared,
and it can take eons to come back.
From Tacitus to Dante was what,
11 centuries?
Ah but intelligence was off with the Arabs.
-True.
You're not hungry?
It won't go down.
-And you? -No thanks.
I never thought I'd see the day
you'd turn down fresh truffles.
Alas, that day is here.
A sip of wine?
Drink to my health
and tell me how good it is.
I'd like to die
just like Felix Faure.
Why am I not surprised?
I can dream.
-Who was he? Why?
Oh blessed Felix Faure, the
President of the French Republic.
His heart stopped beating,
while his mistress the admirable
Madame Steinheil, kneeling before him,
bestowed on him the most
glorious blowjob of all time.
My god!
-His enemies gloated:
"She seized him, the would-be
Caesar and he had a seizure!"
Henceforth Madame Steinheil
was known as the kiss of death.
I should be so lucky!
It's not our fault
if your heart is unstoppable.
I'd like to remind you that at a certain time,
I and several others here
blew you most heartily,
with enough force to capsize a schooner.
What do you know
about blowing buoys?
Well, sir, our efforts
earned gushing praise.
Heavens, that's hard to swallow.
I'm beat.
-Go to bed.
Aren't you coming?
-Not tonight.
The Middle Ages, the manuscripts...
The barbarians,
everywhere, tomorrow...
Their prince approaches.
Think you're funny?
I'm scared.
We'll do what you want.
It's your decision.
Know what I want for you?
To have as fine a son as you.
Heard from Sylvaine?
-No.
Tell her I thought of her.
I love you.
Not so long ago
I'd have jumped you without asking.
I might have let you.
-I suspected as much.
I wasn't here today. You didn't see me.
-Of course.
This just came in.
On a ship,
you call it the evil eye...
Striking a growler - an iceberg -
at night,
or a fire from an oil leak...
It's been too long
since I've seen you.
My Daddy, my Papuschka,
I've have missed you all my life.
Tell yourself I'm a happy woman,
I've found my place.
I don't know how you did it, but
you managed to pass on your lust for life
You and Mom raised incredibly strong
children. It's a miracle really.
You know, the first man in a
woman's life is her father.
You'll always be with me.
Friends, sharing this modest life
with you has been a delight.
I take your smiles with me.
Remy, Remy...
The man of my life.
My guardian angel.
It's a privilege to know you.
The privilege was all mine, Miss.
Mom doesn't want to live here.
I don't need to sell it.
You can move in for now.
IF THIS BE A MAN
HISTORIA AND UTOPIA
I love you.