[ President Clinton ]
The sun is shining,
- and I hope it's a good omen
for peace in Northern Ireland.
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
[ Irish Man #1 ] Not only because
of pressure from Mr. Clinton,
pressure from the south
of Ireland,
pressure from the Roman Catholic
hierarchy who want peace at any price--
[ Whirring Continues ]
- [ Irish Man #2 ] No surrender !
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
[ British Man ] You cannot hold
the process to ransom any longer,
so end the violence,
and end it now.
[ Irish Man #3 ]
What about the l.R.A. ?
- [ Irish Man #4 ]
They haven't gone away, you know.
- [ Laughter ]
Let's go, Danny.
Is 14 years not long
enough for you ?
Time to say
bye-bye, Danny.
[ Inmate Yelling ]
Quite a turnout,
isn't it ?
- Aye.
- Quiet, please. Shh.
[ Guard ]
One for the governor.
Thirty pounds.
Ticket for the boat.
Please sign.
[ Chattering, Shouting ]
- It's a wedding !
- Just throw the bouquet.
Go on.
[ Shouting Continues ]
- Jesus Christ. Danny Flynn.
- Come on ! Move it !
- [ Woman #1 ] That's Danny Flynn ?
- [ Woman #2 ] I think so.
There you go.
[ Grunts ]
[ Man ]
Thanks, Maggie.
That's lookin' great, Maggie.
Well done.
Liam looks well.
Why is your father comin'
to the reception, Maggie ?
- To keep an eye on you.
- [ Laughing ]
Sure. Why not ?
- Come on, Pat. Let's get
things organized for Joe.
- Right.
[ Cheering ]
- [ Cheering Continues ]
- Come on. Come inside.
Hurry up !
In the club.
- ♪♪ [ Wedding Processional ]
- [ Applause, Cheering ]
♪ Here comes the bride ♪
[ Chattering ]
Danny Flynn's out.
- Granddad !
- Liam.
Come here. Go on.
- Mr. Hamill.
- Sean.
- How are you, Jimmy ?
- Not bad, Mr. Hamill.
- [ Boy ] What about you, Liam ?
- Fine.
- Hello, Mr. Hamill.
- What are you readin', Brian ?
- Spiderman !
- [ Laughing ]
- Keep movin'.
- [ All ] Hello, Joe.
Hello, lads.
Hey, lads. l told you
my granddad was comin'.
How are you doin' ?
- [ Cheering ]
- Oh.
- You look gorgeous.
Absolutely gorgeous.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations, Josephine.
- Thanks for comin'.
This is a wee something
for ya. Okay ?
- Oh, thank you.
- Where's Maggie ?
Uh, she's through there,
I think.
I'll see youse later.
You did a great job, you.
The prisoners would be proud of ya.
Oh, thanks for comin', Da.
- What's wrong ?
- Nothin'.
Are you upset ?
Oh, I was just thinking
about things, you know ?
- [ Bell Tolling ]
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
[ Whirring Continues ]
♪ Let me down easy ♪
♪ Putting my heart on the edge ♪
- ♪♪ [ Continues ]
- Can I have a word
with you outside, please ?
- [ Boy ] What's the problem ?
- There is no problem. Let's go.
- What's happenin' ?
- I was only dancin' with him.
You're a prisoner's wife,
for God's sake !
- Oh, Jesus ! He was only
dancin' with the girl.
- ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
- It's all right. Relax.
- He didn't know
she was a prisoner's wife.
It's all right.
That's all right.
Her husband's stayin'
five years in prison.
If you go near his wife again,
understand,
I'll shoot
both your kneecaps off.
Sorry.
It's all right.
Don't be worryin', Agnes.
The trouble's sorted out.
- What's goin' on ?
- Nothin', Ma.
[ Siren Wailing ]
♪ We can't get no ♪
♪ Bad reaction, but we try ♪
♪ And we try, and we try
and we try ♪
[ Quiet Chattering ]
I wanted to tell ya
how proud we all are of ya.
How you stood by your man.
I know that when I was inside,
it was easy to do my time...
because I had
a strong woman behind me.
My wife Eileen,
God rest her soul,
stood by me and remained
faithful to the cause.
And now my daughter,
with her brave son, Liam,
keeps her house together until
her husband, Thomas, returns.
- On one day, and that day
may be sooner than you think--
- He's gonna sell us out.
- all the prisoners will come home.
- [ Cheering, Applause ]
And, and the Brits
will be gone,
and we will have peace
in Ireland.
And you--
you women
who stood by your men...
will be remembered
as the bravest of the district.
So I want youse
to lift your glasses...
to our prisoners' wives.
- The wives.
- [ All ] The wives.
Come on in now, lads.
Come on.
- Twopence.
- [ Coughing, Chattering ]
Hey, boy.
Hey, Flynn.
Danny Flynn.
Do you not know me ?
Ike ?
Ike Weir ?
Ah, ashamed of me,
are ya ?
- Pretending not to see me.
- It's good to see you, lke.
- What are you doin' here ?
- I needed a bed for the night.
Oh, the bad boys
didn't take care of ya ?
Bad boyos didn't give you
a party, huh ?
The big l.R.A. boyos
didn't give him a party.
- Where's all your big men now ?
- Take it easy, lke.
Take it easy ?
Don't you tell me to take it easy !
How come you don't blow yourself up
like the rest of the l.R.A. ?
- You tell 'em
Ike Weir's afraid of nobody.
- Sit down, lke.
Don't you tell me
to sit down !
You tell 'em lke Weir
doesn't need a gun to fight !
- [ Man ] lke, for God's sake !
- I.R.A. ? Fuck your I.R.A. !
Put your gun down, Danny Flynn !
Fight me like a man !
- Didn't I rear ya ? l coached him !
- [ Mutters ]
I trained him
when he was a child.
Destroyed his life.
Best fighter in Ulster.
Ah, he's gone.
Fell asleep.
[ Attendant ] Lights out.
Lights out in ten minutes.
How's the headache ?
Danny Flynn.
Jesus Christ, it is you.
- Got the price of a cup of tea ?
- Aye, come on.
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
The semtex is loaded.
We're all set.
[ Whirring Continues ]
- [ Engine ldling ]
- You've got 45 minutes.
Good luck.
We met last night,
you know.
You had a wee go at me.
Told me a bit of truth.
Well, to tell you
the truth now, Danny,
I don't want any breakfast.
I just want
a few shillin's for some wine.
Can you help me ?
No.
I look bad, don't I ?
Why didn't you stick
with the gym, lke ?
After you were arrested,
the Protestant lads
didn't show up.
They took it hard.
They were very surprised.
That was it for me.
They use it
as a community center now.
He's clear.
- [ Man ] Ah, there you are, love.
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Bells Jingling ]
- [ Chattering Continues ]
So what are you gonna do ?
Thought I'd try and get
a few fights in England.
Professional ?
Aye.
Just a few fights.
How old are you ?
Thirty-two.
Archie Moore fought
for the world title at 42.
Cha-cha.
Why, Danny ?
-I just want to set the record straight.
-[ Explosion ]
Jesus Christ !
It's across the river.
[ Ike ]
Another fuckin' bomb.
[ Car Alarm Sounding ]
[ Grunting ]
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
- [ Shouting ]
[ Whirring Continues ]
[ Chattering ]
Get the boat, Danny.
[ Siren Wailing ]
- Get the boat.
- [ Foghorn Blaring ]
[ Blaring Continues ]
[ Chattering ]
- [ Hammer Pounding ]
- What the hell
do you think you're doing ?
This is my home.
[ Pounding Continues ]
- [ Sean ] Is that his old house ?
- [ Man ] Aye.
[ Banging ]
[ Banging Continues ]
How's it goin', scrapper ?
[ Chuckling ]
How's the head ?
- Fine.
- You're out.
- Good behavior.
- You were never accused of that before.
- You missed the boat, scrapper.
- I'd no watch.
- You know Joe wanted you out of town.
- This is my home.
- You're gonna live here ?
- Aye.
You're a strange man, Danny.
All you had to do was walk
across a prison corridor...
and shake hands with some of
your old friends in the I.R.A.
Snubbin' people
is not nice.
But you never named names, and that's
why you're a healthy man. Understand ?
What are you lookin' at ?
lt's not my fault you got caught.
You should have run away.
- Why is he back ?
- I don't know.
- Why the fuck should I know ?
- Is it Maggie ?
- No, he wouldn't have
the balls for that.
- [ Laughing ]
So you say.
No, he knows he'd get
a fuckin' bullet in the head.
- Say, ''Bye-bye.''
- Bye-bye.
[ Children Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
Just wait
a wee minute there.
I'll see
if the community center's open.
[ Doorman ]
Okay. Come on in.
[ Old Man #1 ] Come on, come on.
Are you gonna deal or what ?
[ Old Man #2 ]
Ah, take time. Take your time.
[ Chattering Continues ]
Young Flynn, isn't it ?
- What happened to the ring ?
- [ Chuckles ]
That packed out
years ago.
I think it's stuck
under thon stage there.
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Boy ] There's a man standing there.
There's been
an approach...
to the community center.
Danny Flynn wants to set up
a gym there.
What do you think ?
- Boxin' ?
- Boxin'.
[ Jumping Rope ]
[ Sighs ]
- [ Sighing Continues ]
- [ Jumping Rope Continues ]
You're in good shape.
[ Sighs ] It's been a few years since
this stuff's seen the light of day.
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
- [ Hammer Banging ]
- Did you see this, lke ?
[ Old Man #2 ] You 20 years ago.
Your face wasn't so red.
- Aye, he was a tough man, Ike.
- Ah, there's young Joey Fitzsimons.
[ Old Man #1 ]
And young McCormack. He's dead too.
[ Children Chattering,
Laughing ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
Show us your jab. Hey.
[ Laughing ]
- Ma, I'm goin' to Ned's.
- Well, don't be late.
- Are you all right ?
- Aye.
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
Congratulations, Peter.
Harry.
[ Joe ]
Peter Mallon's been elected
to the army council.
I've decided I need
somebody more political.
All operations are to be
suspended from 12:00 tomorrow.
- Noon.
Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow.
- Why ?
- We're close to a deal, Harry.
- Includin' the P.O.W.s ?
Includin' the P.O.W.s.
So what are you
offerin', Joe ? Hmm ?
Peace, Harry. Peace.
Peace. I'm sure
you can deliver, Joe.
Left hand up.
[ Huffing ]
That's it, man.
Keep your legs moving.
- Your father's a boxer too, isn't he ?
- Aye.
- [ Huffing Continues ]
- Get your balance right.
Move your head.
Lift those punches.
That's it.
And again. And again.
That's it ! Good man.
Hey.
I see you've put up
the ring.
- Aye.
- Looks great.
Well, sweetheart,
did you die just so Joe Hamill
could sell us out ?
- Hmm ?
Nothin'.
Just talkin' to myself.
[ Bell Tolling ]
12:00 noon.
Peace in Ireland.
- [ Car Horns Honking ]
- [ Shouting, Chattering ]
- [ Honking, Shouting Continue ]
- [ Trash Can Lids Banging ]
- Ma, it's the cease-fire !
- [ Newscaster ]
There are continuing scenes...
- [ Bell Tolling ]
- of celebration on the streets
of West Belfast,
as 12:00 noon brought the
long-awaited I.R.A. cease-fire.
Protestant spokespersons
opposed immediate movement...
on the release of prisoners.
You get to know who
the troublemakers are quick enough.
Just keep an eye
on the tables.
No one comes into the city
center after dark,
so you only have to work
till 6:00 or so.
- You ever been to London ?
- Aye.
I got a few contacts there.
Come on.
lke, where's Danny ?
He's in the kitchen.
[ Utensil Tinkling ]
What's goin' on, Danny ?
What do you mean ?
I haven't seen you
in 14 years,
and now you're right
next door to me every day.
And when I do see you,
all I get from you is the odd grunt.
Do you not think
that's strange ?
Aye, it is strange.
Oh, forget it, Danny.
[ Ike ]
Come on. Pick it up.
That's it. Good man.
And again.
Move him about.
- [ Chattering ]
- Beautiful. And again.
Get the punches in.
That's it.
And again.
Keep your guard up, Danny !
Danny, come on in.
Look at these.
Look.
There's Maclean.
''Holy Family
Sweep the All lrelands.''
[ Sighs ]
What a waste of life.
Six of them dead. Why the hell
did you get mixed up with them ?
The police were burning people
out of their homes, lke.
Soldiers shootin' people
on the corner.
Why the hell do you think
I got involved ?
I don't know.
What's in the cupboard ?
- Ah, it's locked.
- We're lockin' up, lads.
There's only odds and ends in there
belongin' to the community center.
Fuckin' semtex.
- [ Vehicles Approaching ]
- [ C.B. Radio, lndistinct ]
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
- [ Train Whistle Blowing ]
These are explosives, Birdy.
Why the fuck didn't you tell me
he was rootin' around in here ?
Kept an eye on him.
The lock's broken.
- It's gone.
- [ Floor Creaks ]
Danny.
Can I have
a word with you ?
You're in trouble.
What did you do ?
I found some stuff.
Semtex.
Under the stage ?
[ Whispering ]
Bastards.
- Well, where is it now ?
- In the river.
Well, why didn't you give it
back to my father ?
So they can kill more
innocent people ?
What do you mean,
I mean
innocent people, Maggie.
Do you want to get
yourself killed, Danny ?
Not particularly.
- Why did you really come back ?
- What do you mean ?
I don't believe you just
came back here to box.
If you ask me
to leave, I'll go.
If I ask you to leave.
Well, how far
can you go, Danny ?
Turn around, start walking,
and when you've walked for 14 years,
then stop and think
about what you did to me.
I did it for ya.
Oh, my God.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm sorry.
[ Man On P.A. ]
The next train from platform one...
will be the 10:50 service
to Londonderry--
[ Continues, lndistinct ]
I think we're
safe enough here.
Ah, we're fine.
Don't worry about us.
Thank you.
You used to talk to me,
Danny.
You used to make me laugh.
Oh, go on, make me laugh.
Am I not funny ?
No.
[ Sighs ]
Talk to me, Danny.
Talk to you in my mind.
What do you mean ?
In prison, you get used
to silence, you know ?
I mean, at first, you, you hold on
to all the old voices in your head--
kids you knew at school,
old friends and such.
Well, after a while,
those voices start to fade,
and you end up talkin' to yourself
for a bit of company, you know ?
And then something
strange happens.
It's as if even your own
voice doesn't belong there...
in the silence.
It's unwelcome.
Go on, Danny.
[ Sighs ]
Well, in the end,
it's the silence
becomes your best friend.
And in the quiet,
a face will come to you, and,
and you talk to that person
without sayin' anything, and--
[ Sighs ]
Gee, I'm not makin' any sense.
Never make
any fuckin' sense.
What are you sayin', Danny ?
I've lived with your face
in silence for 14 years, Maggie.
You know, it's hard
to talk to the real you.
I'm not who I was.
Try the elbow.
Set down on the way. That's it.
Once more. That's it.
Snap on your jab.
That's it. One more.
Come on. One-two !
And again.
- [ lke ] And again.
- He wants to join.
He's the boss.
- One-two.
- Ike !
- Shadowbox.
- He wants to join.
Use the rest
of the ring, now.
Come here.
- No way, missus.
- Who are you to talk, lke Weir ?
Make him have
a blood test.
If he's clear and
he stays off the junk,
he can join.
[ Danny ]
Keep your head movin' now.
That's it.
Duck and weave.
Bob and weave.
- Well done.
- [ Chattering ]
Keep on the move.
That's it.
Come on. Hold on. Thumbs out.
That's it. Elbows in. Nice and tight.
Good. Very good.
Danny. Look at these.
Headgear's gone.
You can't spar with these.
Look at that.
- [ Sean ] And he didn't do it ?
- [ Chattering ]
[ Harry ]
Shh, shh, shh !
- What does that mean, Bootsy ?
- What ?
''Nonsectarian.''
Catholics
and Protestants together.
What about the Jews, Bootsy ?
And the Arabs ?
And the Muslims ?
l suppose they can come too,
if they want.
[ Cheering, Shouting ]
Liam, move in !
- Come on !
- [ Cheering, Shouting Continue ]
Holy Family's
always been nonsectarian.
Protestants
and Catholics together.
- Write that down !
- [ Bell Dings ]
And the winner is...
in the red corner:
Doyle from
the Holy Family Club,
Belfast.
I won !
You fought
a great fight.
Okay, Danny. Let's go.
Don't forget. It's your
first fight in a long time.
- You're gonna learn a lot.
- [ Cheering, Shouting ]
[ Cheering, Shouting Continue ]
[ lke ] Ladies and gentleman,
can l have your attention, please ?
l want to say
somethin' tonight.
Of the many people that gave
their lives in the Troubles,
this night is dedicated
to the members...
of the Holy Family Boxing Club
who've died.
Now all these boys' parents
are in the hall tonight,
so I'd like youse all
to observe a minute's silence.
Joe Fitzsimons, featherweight.
Died 1972.
Age, 24 years.
Brian Keogh,
light heavyweight.
Died 1973.
Age, 16 years.
John Maguire, featherweight.
Died 1983.
Age, 19 years.
Tony Walsh, bantamweight.
Died 1990.
Age, 20 years.
Harry McCormack, flyweight.
Died 1987.
Age, 13 years.
Sammy Orr,
lightweight.
Died 1986.
Age, 22 years.
Sammy's parents are Protestants
from East Belfast,
and this is their first night
in the club...
since the Troubles began
28 years ago.
And I'd like you all
to welcome them back.
[ Applause ]
- Did you know that was gonna happen ?
- No.
Sentimental shite.
- [ Announcer ] Round one.
- [ Bell Dings, Cheering ]
- [ Man ] Danny !
- [ Ike ] Balance now.
Keep your balance now.
[ Man ]
Hit him ! Hit him !
Come on, Danny !
- [ Cheering, Shouting Continues ]
- [ Ike ] Use your jab. Use the jab !
- Try hittin' him, Danny !
- Shut up !
- [ Woman ] Come on, lads ! Box !
- Danny's way off.
Move in, Danny !
[ Grunting ]
- [ Bell Dings ]
- I'm gonna fuckin' kill ya !
[ Whistling ]
He's showboatin' ya ! Don't let him
do that ! He's playin' around with ya !
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Boy ]
Hit him ! Come on !
Flynn should get
the Nobel Peace Prize for boxin'.
[ Man ]
Stay off the ropes !
That a boy, Danny !
Go on !
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Crowd Gasps ]
- [ Woman ] Jesus Christ, Danny !
- One, two, three,
- four, five, six,
- If he gets up, I'll fuckin' kill him.
- [ Man ] Come on ! Get up !
- seven, eight--
Box !
- Break ! Break !
- [ Bell Dings ]
You're not ready.
- Have you had enough, son ?
- I'll tell you when l've had enough.
- [ Bell Dings ]
- Finish him.
[ Man ]
Danny !
Get him down, Danny !
Go on, Danny !
[ Woman ]
Get off the ropes !
- Go on, Danny !
- [ Groans ]
- Are you okay ? Can you continue ?
- Yes.
- Go on, Danny ! Get him !
- Go on !
[ Man ]
Come on !
He can't put him down !
He fuckin' won't bow down !
Hold him, Danny !
[ Man ]
Come on, Danny ! Come on !
Stay on your feet, lad !
Stay on your feet !
[ Ike ] Don't go down !
Stay on your feet, Danny !
[ Man ]
Twenty seconds !
[ Ike ]
Stay on your feet, Danny !
[ Bell Dings ]
He doesn't look
much like a quitter to me.
[ Crowd Chanting ]
Danny ! Danny ! Danny !
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
What was that about, scrapper ?
- What do you mean ?
- Those were powerful emotions
you stirred up tonight.
- What are you up to ?
- I was just boxin'.
It's not just boxin', Danny.
It's a fuckin' statement--
standin' there
gettin' your head knocked off.
What was that about ?
I want the stuff back,
scrapper.
What stuff ?
[ Chuckles ] All right, Danny.
Play it whatever way you want.
Fourteen years wasn't enough
to teach you, then. Was it, now ?
- What'd he want ?
- Nothin', lke.
Good.
He ruined
your life once already.
- Don't give him a second chance.
- I won't.
You should have put him away
the first time.
You did him a favor.
He'll never forgive you for it.
[ Guard ]
I.D., please.
I.D. ?
Thank you.
I'm not too sure
about this, Maggie.
Well, it's safer than being
seen together in West Belfast.
Why didn't you ask me
to wait ?
- I would have waited.
- Don't be sayin' that.
Fourteen years, Maggie.
- I would have waited.
- You were only 16.
- Did you not trust me ?
- How the hell could I ?
I was mad in love with ya.
And I wanted
to keep it that way.
Not have it eaten up
day by day.
So you made the decision
for both of us ?
- You made your own
decisions too, Maggie.
- What do you mean ?
You married my best friend,
for God's sake.
Well, did you expect me
to remain faithful to you ?
I suppose I did.
I thought I was bein' romantic.
Mmm. Givin' you
your freedom or somethin'.
You were giving me my freedom, but you
wanted me to stay faithful to you ?
I was only 19.
[ Maggie ]
Mm-hmm.
- Shake my hand.
- What ?
Shake my hand, Danny Boy Flynn.
Billy Patterson, bantamweight.
- Jesus, Billy ! How are you doin' ?
- Good, good.
I'm doin' fine.
Don't look now.
But there's a car
behind ya,
and the last Catholic boy who was
in that car didn't die a happy death.
- So I'll walk you
to the peace line together.
- Let's go.
[ Car Engine Revving ]
Bye-bye, Maggie.
Good luck, Danny.
- Stop by and do
a bit of training sometime.
- Will do.
[ Children Chattering ]
- What's wrong ?
- I don't take gear from cops.
- Why ?
- 'Cause they won't let
my dad out of prison.
- Yeah, go on !
- [ Man ] That's great, Reggie.
What about you, Liam ?
[ Child Chattering ]
[ Man ] Come on, lads.
Come on. Photograph time.
- What's all this ?
- It's a gift.
- A gift from who ?
- Community relations.
- All right.
- Come here.
Group together like that.
- Community relations ?
- Aye. Reggie Bell.
This stuff is from the cops,
lke, and we can't accept it.
Listen, these kids have barely
got shoes on their feet.
Some of them
come here in rags.
Look at them now.
They look great.
Now I don't give a fuckin' shite
who these togs come from.
They're on their backs.
- All right.
- They're not comin' off.
We simply can't negotiate until
the terrorists lay down their arms.
The police are Protestant.
They're not welcome in Catholic areas.
ln contrast, it seems the whole
of Belfast, Catholic and Protestant,
is welcome at the recently reopened,
nonsectarian Holy Family Boxing Club.
- Takin' gear from the cops.
- The boys from the club...
recently received
a generous donation of equipment.
And Danny Flynn,
who fights out of Holy Family,
has signed up for a rematch
with Eddie Carroll at the city center.
[ Machine Gunfire, Gunshots ]
[ Men Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Trash Can Lid Banging ]
- [ Banging Continues ]
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
[ Whirring Continues ]
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Sirens Wailing ]
[ Wailing Continues ]
[ Officer ] Get them !
Get those sons of bitches !
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
Who fired at Danny Flynn
last night, Harry ?
I don't know.
My units shoot to kill.
You're in charge
of the district.
No.
I report to you.
Did you see this ?
He's fillin' people's heads
full of shit, Joe.
''Leave the fighting to Danny'' means
that all the people who are in prison,
who died, who didn't
surrender to the Brits--
that means that their sacrifices aren't
worth a lousy fuckin' boxin' match.
He's spreadin' dissent, Joe.
Maybe you're the one who's
spreadin' dissent, Harry.
I'm trying to hold it together
in a district full of junkies,
thieves and losers,
while all he's trying to say is
that everything will be all right...
if the Catholics and Protestants
will hold hands together.
It's shit, isn't it, Joe ?
ls it, Harry ?
Shit ?
You know we're gonna have
to live with them sometime.
- Who's ''them'' ?
- The Protestants, Harry.
The other half
of the population.
You're never going to be
treated as an equal, Joe.
Not if we keep
bombin' 'em, no.
I don't see any P.O.W.s
comin' home, Joe.
Well, last night
didn't help, Harry.
It didn't help at all.
[ Man #1 ]
Keep it goin', Bootsy. Keep it goin'.
And again.
- [ Ike ]
Throw your combinations, Danny !
- And again.
Let's go.
And again.
[ Man #2 ]
One-two !
- [ Ike ] Use the jab !
- Watch it !
- Danny.
- [ lke ] Come on ! Again !
That was a warning shot
they fired at you.
- I'll see you later.
- Aye.
You know, we can't keep doin'
what we're doin', Maggie.
What are we doing ?
[ Chuckles ]
You know what I'm sayin'. Come on.
Yeah.
You're right.
Give us a hug.
You're a dangerous
fuckin' woman.
You talked about voices in your head.
I couldn't stop them.
I thought my head
would burst.
And the only thing
that kept me sane--
- Ah, it doesn't matter now.
- Go on. I'm listening.
- It's not fair.
- Just finish it up, Maggie.
[ Sighs ] It was the sound
of your voice saying,
''Everything's gonna
be all right.''
Geez, I never said that.
Over and over again
in my head.
''Everything is gonna
be all right.''
Well, this is, this is okay.
This is, this is all right.
What ?
What is this ?
This is us.
You don't put a name on it.
- Who is it ?
- It's Danny. Can I come in ?
It's very late, Danny.
- You shouldn't be here. It's not safe.
- I know.
This is fuckin' ridiculous,
you know ?
All this talk, Maggie, you know ?
We're kiddin' ourselves.
I love you.
There's nothin' else to say.
We're not kids anymore, Danny.
Yeah, we are.
You're so fuckin' beautiful.
For 14 years
I was locked up.
Well, my feelings were
locked up inside of me.
And when I got
in the ring again,
you can't imagine the relief
it was to feel the pain--
to be back
in the world again.
I can give you up in my head,
but my body's cryin' out for you.
Don't.
Be with me.
No.
I'm going mad, Danny.
I have a scream inside of me
day and night.
Liam's upstairs.
Have I said too much ?
No.
But...
I think you've said
enough for now.
- I think you'd better go.
- Okay.
Is my da comin' home
or not ?
Don't build up
your hopes, Liam.
You said the prisoners
were comin' home.
[ Door Closes ]
What's wrong ?
We're this close to a deal,
but I'm gettin' no concessions
on the prisoners.
It's as though the Brits
want the cease-fire to fail.
Harry says the only thing
they respond to is violence.
♪♪ [ Band Playing ]
- It's a sellout.
- [ Man ] Go on, Belfast !
Belfast is comin'
back to life.
People see this man, who was
once committed to violence,
now fightin'
within the rules.
lt's caught
their imagination.
People are here together--
Catholic and Protestant--
with no animosity.
[ Ike ]
Don't be overeager.
If you go for him too early,
you're in trouble.
- Ike.
- Reg.
- How's it goin' ?
- Not bad.
- Kids enjoyin' the gear ?
- Just great.
[ Matt ] You know Reggie Bell,
R.U.C. community relations.
Good luck tonight.
lt's great for the city.
Great for all of us.
Lovely.
I'll leave you two.
- All the best, Reg.
- Thanks.
- l don't like bein' used.
- [ Matt ] What's wrong ?
- I don't like bein' used.
- He gave the kids all the equipment.
[ Ike ]
Concentrate on the boxin'.
♪♪ [ Band Playing ]
[ Applause ]
- Everything's set up.
- Okay.
Here comes Joe Hamill.
[ Applause ]
[ Man ]
I.R.A. bastard !
[ Booing ]
[ Heckling ]
- Bastard !
- Get out of Belfast !
[ Announcer ]
Stop fighting amongst yourselves !
Can we all sing together...
a song we all know,
''Danny Boy'' ?
- Where's Liam ?
- He's not comin'.
Did he say
he didn't want to come ?
That's right.
He said he didn't want to come.
♪ Oh, Danny boy ♪
♪ The pipes
The pipes are callin' ♪
[ Audience Joins ln ]
♪ From glen to glen ♪
♪ And down the mountainside ♪
♪ The summer's gone ♪
♪ And all the flowers
are dying ♪
Did you hear that ?
That'll put pride in your heart.
Frank Patterson's out front. He runs the
Commonwealth Sporting Club in London.
- He's got a big promotion comin' up.
- Not now, Matt.
It's on television.
lt's a fuckin' meat trade,
and we don't want it.
There's a good
few grand in it.
Forget about London.
Just concentrate on this fight.
All right.
Time to go.
No dressin' gown.
No nothin'.
♪ But come ye back ♪
♪ When summer's
in the meadow ♪
♪ Or when the valley's hushed ♪
♪ And white with snow ♪
[ Cheering ]
♪ 'Tis I'll be there ♪
♪ ln sunshine or in shadow ♪
[ Cheering Continues ]
♪ Oh, Danny boy
Oh, Danny boy ♪
♪ I love you so ♪♪
[ Whistling, Cheering ]
Okay, boys, let's go.
Follow my instructions.
Protect yourselves,
and shake hands.
[ Bell Dings ]
Stop !
Go to a neutral corner.
[ Referee ]
One ! Two ! Three ! Four !
Five ! Six !
Seven !
Are you all right ?
- [ Crowd Shouting ]
- Box !
Come on, Danny !
[ Cheering ]
[ Referee ]
One, two, three,
four, five, six,
seven, eight--
- You okay ?
- I'm all right.
[ Referee ]
Box !
One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten !
- [ Bell Dings ]
- [ Referee ] You're out !
[ Crowd Whistling, Cheering ]
Thanks very much.
Well done.
Great night
for the city of Belfast.
The crowd will be comin' out now,
Catholics and Protestants together.
The band will lead them
off down the street.
I'd like you to get as many
good pictures as you can.
- Yea !
- Danny ! Danny ! Danny !
They'll be coming out together, so
you can clear the barriers away. Okay.
[ Chanting Continues ]
Danny ! Danny ! Danny !
[ Chanting, Whistling,
Cheering Continue ]
[ Explosion Resounding ]
[ Chanting Stops,
Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Keep calm. You can all
see where your exits are.
[ Matt ]
Don't panic. Get up slowly.
Leave the building.
Ju-- Just keep calm.
There's absolutely
no need to panic.
Go out through the main exit.
They've killed the policeman,
Reggie Bell. Let's move.
Jesus ! Come on.
Let's move it. Move it !
[ Matt ] Follow
the exit signs behind you.
[ Joe ] McCormack ! McCormack !
I wanna talk to you now !
Go out through
the main exit.
- Cop killer !
- There's no need to panic.
- Catholic bastards ! Bastards !
- Follow the exit signs.
You're all right, son.
- Kill him ! Kill him !
- They killed a cop !
You're okay.
Take his hand now, son.
Keep calm.
Watch yourself now.
That's right.
- Good, lad.
- Oh, Daddy ! Oh, Daddy, no !
- You'll be okay !
- Daddy !
- Quit pushin' !
- Dad !
Robert ! Robert !
There's a kid
dyin' in there !
Give him some space !
There's a kid dyin' in there !
[ Shouting ]
- [ Shouts ]
- Stop it ! Stop it !
Irish pigs !
[ Man Shouts ]
Gary !
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Man ]
Oh ! Oh !
- Aaah !
- [ Woman Screams ]
- Run, Ned ! Run !
- Come on ! Run, will ya ?
[ Shouting ]
Where the fuck were you ?
What are these for ?
They're the keys
to the gym. Come on.
Where's the petrol ?
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
Should never have taken
that gear from him.
Don't even think
about it, lke.
He's a wife and
three children, Danny.
Anything that
belongs to the cops.
We'll burn it outside.
- I'm not takin' that outside.
- Why not ?
[ Mickey ] 'Cause, Liam,
the Brits are everywhere.
We'll burn it here.
Stop messin', Ned.
- Aaah !
- Mickey !
Mickey, roll over !
Oh, geez !
- Get him !
- Mickey, get up !
- Aaah !
- [ Fire Alarm Ringing ]
Gotta get outta here !
Let's get out ! Come on !
- Let's get out !
- Run, Mickey ! Get out !
The gym is on fire !
- The gym's on fire !
[ Man ]
The gym's on fire !
[ Sirens Wailing ]
[ Shouts ]
- [ Fire Alarm Ringing ]
- [ Coughing ] Oh !
[ Man On Megaphone ]
Get away from the building !
Get the pictures !
[ Man On Megaphone ]
This is for your own safety !
- You'd better leave right now !
- Come on, lke !
Time to get out !
- You can't go in there !
- I work in there !
- Step back !
- I work in there, and l have to get--
It's not safe !
Get away from the building !
Serves youse bloody well right
for takin' the stuff from the police !
I'm in the middle
of negotiations,
and you let off
this fuckin' bomb.
- What did you achieve by it ?
You achieved zero.
- Zero ?
Grow up. Stop livin' in the past
and get your head into the future.
You can keep goin'.
You can split this organization in two.
- But you're gonna have
to accept the consequences.
- What consequences ?
You know what
fuckin' consequences.
You don't have
all the guns, Joe.
A lot of the active servicemen won't
accept this peace bullshit anymore.
Are you threatenin' me ?
You're goin' soft, Joe.
Ya think so ?
You had men in prison...
who starved themselves
to death for you, Joe.
Ten of them.
Now you have Danny Boy Flynn...
wanderin' around the place makin'
a mockery of everything you stood for,
and you don't even see it.
But a child can see it, Joe.
A wee innocent child
can see the truth.
What are you talkin' about ?
Why don't you ask Liam
why he burnt down the gym ?
I just follow orders.
He's way out
of control, Joe.
- [ Door Opens ]
- [ Man ] Hello, Maggie.
- [ Door Closes ]
- [ Maggie ] Hi.
- lt's your da.
- All right.
Joe.
What's wrong ?
I don't want to lose you.
Sure you never will.
You've got to be
above reproach.
Tell me-- Tell me
you don't love Danny Flynn.
You've got to get rid of him.
What are you
talkin' about ?
- We've done nothin' wrong.
- That's not the point.
- Everybody thinks you did.
- Well, to hell with them.
To hell with 'em.
Maggie, Liam burned down
the gym.
Liam ?
- Where is he ?
- Upstairs.
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
What the hell did you
think you were doing ?
I saw ya.
I saw ya with him.
You're gonna run away
with him, aren't ya ?
No.
I'm gonna stay
right here with you.
I don't want to
see him ever again.
Oh, Liam.
- [ Footsteps Approaching ]
- Liam ?
- [ Door Closes ]
- Leave him, Maggie.
He's suffered enough.
He's suffered enough ?
Jesus.
My marriage was over
before Liam was even born.
I'm the prisoner here.
You and your politics
have made sure of that.
All l wanted was for you
to have a good marriage.
- [ Scoffs ] Like you and my mother ?
- Yes.
Do you know how much
it cost her to smile...
every time you walked
through the front door ?
She lived her whole bloody life
worried to death. And for what ?
Will ya look me in the eye
and tell me for what ?
I suppose she
believed in me, Maggie.
She thought the ground
that you walked on was sacred.
So did I.
I'm not going to lose Danny.
Then you'll have
to tell him to go.
Why ?
I can't protect him, Maggie.
You'll have to get rid of him,
or you'll find him in a pool of blood.
God help you.
God help you, Father.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Knocking ]
Maggie, come in.
I have to talk to you, Danny.
- Want a cup of tea ?
- Aye.
[ Flame lgnites ]
Danny, l-- l have something
to say to you.
I've been up all night,
and I--
I've written ya a letter.
[ Paper Rustling ]
''Dear Danny,
''It's taken me 14 years
to learn to live without you,
''and I don't believe that here
in this place you can ever be mine.
''It's not possible because
too many people are gonna get hurt.
''I have to protect
those I love.
''I'm so sorry, Danny.
God bless you.
Yours always, Maggie.''
What do you want ?
I'm askin' you to walk away.
I don't think so.
- You made a promise.
- What was that ?
You said if I asked you
to leave, you'd leave.
- Mmm, aye.
- Well, I'm askin'.
Have you been threatened ?
- Why do you say that ?
- Have you ?
I do have a mind
of my own, Danny.
I know I might very well be losin' it,
but I do have a mind of my own.
Is it your father ?
Is it Joe ?
No, Danny.
It's Harry, isn't it ?
Is it Harry ?
Tell me.
Just fuckin' tell me.
Don't, Danny.
You don't understand.
Half my fuckin' life I pissed away
and all the good things in it...
because of that sickly bastard
and his dirty little,
cozy little, fuckin' secret world
and all the dirt in it.
And now he's tryin' to turn us into
a dirty little secret. So, fuck him !
Let him know that
I love you, Maggie.
Go out and tell him now.
Go and fuckin' tell him.
I'll not crawl around in
the fuckin' gutter for him !
I'll kill him first.
I'll rip his fuckin' throat out !
Don't go outside.
That's what he wants you to do.
That's what he wants me to do,
and I'll fuckin' do it !
Liam burnt down the gym.
- He saw us together.
- What are you talkin' about ?
He thinks you're gonna
take me away from him.
Dear God.
God help him.
When he was born, Danny,
I held him in my arms,
and it made everything
all right.
I can't hurt him.
Come here.
I'm not a killer, Maggie.
But this place
makes me want to kill.
Oh, I wish we could stay
like this for-- forever.
You still have it.
What ?
My soul...
for what it's worth.
We can store the stuff in here
till we get the gym goin' again.
I'm goin' to London, lke.
I'm takin' that fight.
It's a bloody circus,
and you're
their performin' monkey.
We'll stay here.
We'll do things at our own pace.
I'm goin', Ike,
and that's it.
If you go,
you're goin' on your own.
I'm not runnin'
from anybody.
You can use the flat
while I'm gone, all right ?
[ Man ] Come on, Danny boy.
Move out of the corner. That's it.
Come on, Danny boy.
Get your feet workin'.
Stand in the middle of the ring.
- [ Bell Dings ]
- Ten seconds left in the round.
[ Huffing ]
- Where's lke ?
- He's over there.
Right there.
Can I talk to you ?
It was me who
burned the gym.
Why ?
I thought Danny was gonna
run away with my mother.
I'm sorry.
Are you gonna
build the gym again ?
Aye, of course, I will.
Sure, I will.
When ?
When Danny gets back.
See ya later.
[ Chattering ]
Champagne toast. Come on.
Let's get the bubbly out.
Quick as you can, please.
Serve the top table first.
Ladies and gentlemen, may l ask you all
to please stand and pray silence...
for your chairman
who will propose the toast ?
Your chairman.
The toast is the queen.
The queen.
[ Crowd Applauding ]
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten !
He's out !
[ Giggles ]
[ Coins Jingling ]
[ Man ]
And the third bout this evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
features from Nigeria--
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Come on, Danny.
[ Glasses Clinking ]
- Come on, lrish !
- [ Man ] Quiet, please.
[ Clinking Continues, Stops ]
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Applause ]
Gentlemen, can I ask you to confine
your appreciation to clapping ?
Bang. Jab him then. Bing, bing.
Keep movin'. Stay on your toes.
[ Bell Dings ]
He's doin' well here.
- Danny's ahead.
- [ Man On TV ] We're seeing
excellent movement from Flynn.
- Watch your heads. Watch it.
- [ Grunts ]
Come on. Break it up.
Break ! Break ! Move back !
He's runnin' around too much.
He can't keep that up.
Get off the ropes, Danny !
Off the ropes ! Jesus Christ.
Come on, Akim !
Come on ! Come on !
- Whoa !
- [ Bell Dings ]
- You're okay.
- [ Applause ]
Phil, get the cut.
Danny, you're cut.
[ Speaking Native Language
Rapidly ]
[ Man On TV ] This is it.
Here comes the clash of heads.
The lrishman's
too far behind on points.
He's got to knock Akim out
to win this bout.
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
- One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight--
You're okay. You're okay.
Get your hands up.
Box !
[ Gasps ]
[ Referee ]
Break !
[ Crowd Murmuring,
Applause ]
One ! Two !
Three ! Four !
Five ! Six !
Seven ! Eight !
Get your hands up.
Box !
Come on, Flynn.
Box on !
Come on, Flynn ! Box !
- Box on !
- [ Groans ]
- Box on.
- It's over.
- The fight's over.
I told you he was a quitter,
didn't I, Betty ?
- You should have stopped
the fuckin' fight.
- Flynn !
[ Applause ]
[ Man On TV ]
What an extraordinary ending.
You'll never fight
in this country again.
- [ Woman ] Hey !
- Are you happy now ?
♪ Oh, Danny boy, the pipes
The pipes are callin' ♪♪
That's some boxer
you got there, lke.
Throws in his own towel.
You teach him that ?
Aye, you laugh at Danny Flynn,
the only good thing that ever
came out of this district.
I know you, Harry ! You're only
interested in hurtin' people.
That's your only pleasure,
isn't it ?
Go and get yourself
another bottle of meths, lke.
- Take it easy, Harry.
- [ Coin Clatters ]
[ Harry Laughing ]
You tell all the big boys
in there how you ran away,
how you left Danny Flynn
to take the blame,
how he kept his mouth shut,
how he should've told and a lot more
innocent people would be alive today !
Shut your fuckin' mouth,
ya drunken wino, or I'll shut it for ya.
You killed
this district, Harry !
the one thing you loved.
- Come on, Harry. He's irrelevant.
- Leave me alone.
- Your own son !
- What are you talkin' about ?
You filled his head
full of shit !
And you sent him out
to die !
Go home. Go home !
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
He's dead.
He's dead, Liam.
Sorry, Liam.
[ Boy ] The army says
he could be booby-trapped.
- Come back, Liam !
- He could be booby-trapped !
- He's booby-trapped !
- Liam ! Come back !
[ Man On Megaphone ] Stay away
from the body ! You have been warned !
Stay back from the body !
Stay away ! Stay away !
You have been warned !
Danny.
They're watching the house.
Fuck 'em.
Can I come in ?
- My father's here.
- Good. I'd like a word with him too.
- Peter.
- Danny.
Danny.
I'm sorry about lke Weir.
I'm gonna build a gym for the kids.
Try and teach them somethin'.
You taught me to stand my ground,
and that's what l'm gonna do.
Are you back
for revenge, Danny ?
No. No, I'm back for Maggie.
Will she be safe with ya ?
She'll never be safer.
I don't know if we can have a life
together, Maggie. lt's up to you.
- You've more things
at stake than I have.
- Okay.
I'll not put her life
in danger.
We'll talk about that.
We'll work things out.
Nor am I gonna sneak around
as if we've done wrong. We haven't.
- And I'm not leavin'.
- It's a dangerous game you're playin'.
It's a dangerous game, all right, Joe.
I know all about that.
It's-- It's my home,
you know ?
No one's gonna drive me
outta my home.
Eternal rest grant unto him, Lord,
and may perpetual light shine upon him.
May he rest in peace.
May his soul and the souls
of all the faithful departed,
through the mercy of God,
- rest in peace.
- Amen.
[ Dirt Clatters ]
- Let's go for a walk.
- Yep.
Can I help ya rebuild the gym ?
Is that okay ?
Aye.
Why draw trouble
to yourselves ?
Because it's mad to run away
as if we'd committed some crime.
- Don't forget.
- It's no problem. lt's all right.
Mr. Hamill.
[ Liam ]
We're bein' followed.
I'm not gonna let you drive around with
a prisoner's wife. Get out of the car.
Get outta the car.
Did you forget your weddin' ring,
ya fuckin' whore ya ?
You're a prisoner's wife.
You know what that means, don't ya ?
Fuckin' whore.
You'd fuck anything, wouldn't ya ?
[ Grunts ]
Give me the fuckin' thing !
- Kill him !
- Stop it, you bastards !
Stop it !
- Jesus !
- [ Shouting ]
You know what we sacrificed
in this fuckin' war, don't ya ?
Harry ! Harry !
Let's do it clean.
[ Woman ]
Let him go, you bastards !
- Take him away.
- Move it !
- Danny ! No !
Danny ! Danny !
Danny !
What'd you think was gonna happen ?
You can't just walk outta here !
- Jesus !
- For 25 years we've been
living with this shit !
- Liam !
- Jesus Christ ! He's fuckin' dead !
[ Woman ]
He's fuckin' dead !
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
Let her go.
That's from Joe.
[ Maggie ]
Danny !
Move away.
End of story, peacemaker.
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
- Stand back.
Move it.
Get away from here, Danny.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Doors Closing ]
[ Van Departs ]
Danny !
You all right ?
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
Where are you goin' ?
We're going home.
♪ Cover my eyes
Meet me where ♪
♪ One step, two steps ♪
♪ Towards the morning ♪
♪ Past the door ♪
♪ In the alley ♪
♪ Feels like the future ♪
♪ Looks like the past ♪
♪ Love her, love her
Love her true ♪
♪ Mother, father, son ♪
♪ Walkin'
What do I see ♪
♪ The face, the face
haunting me ♪
♪ Love slides
Eyes roam back ♪
♪ The scream of an angel ♪
♪ ln my head ♪
♪ Feels like the future ♪
♪ Looks like the past ♪
♪ Makes me wanna kill ♪
♪ Love her, love her
Love her ♪
♪ True ♪
♪ Mother, mother ♪
♪ Father, son ♪
♪ The shadow of a gun ♪
♪ I break my love ♪
♪ No fear is here ♪
♪ With a fist and a cry ♪
♪ Fist and a cry ♪
♪ Feels like the future ♪
♪ Looks like the past ♪
♪ The shadow of a shadow ♪
♪ The father and the son ♪
♪ Can never be one ♪
♪ In the shadow of a gun ♪♪