( wind whistling )
( low, steady
drum beating )
( distant
siren wailing )
WOMAN WHISPERING:
Leonard...
I love you,
but I have
to go.
I have to.
( siren wailing )
( gasping, coughing )
Oh!
- Help!
- Hey! Hey, come here, man.
You all right, man?
- Should we call an ambulance?
- I don't know.
Just get-- get him down.
Watch out, watch out!
- He swallowed a lot of water.
- CHILD: Sit him up!
- Sit him up.
- MAN: Sit him up.
- Go!
- Child: Get him on his back.
I'll try C.P.R.
( man hacking )
Stop!
( spits )
Are you all right?
You all right?
What happened there?
I fell in the water.
No, he didn't!
I saw him.
- He jumped.
- MAN: Breathe, breathe.
What are you talking about?
I fell in the water.
- He just jumped in.
- Come on, I gotta go!
Just take it easy, man.
Where you going?
MAN: Where you going?
You gotta wait
for the cops, man.
Hey!
Hey, buddy, you even gonna thank
the guy who just saved your life?
Huh?
This guy right here--
he just saved your life.
Oh.
Thank you.
MAN:
Jesus.
Hey, ain't that the guy
that works over at the, uh,
the dry-cleaner
on Neptune Avenue?
MAN #2: Maybe. But he doesn't look
too dry to me now.
MAN #3:
Douchebag.
MAN OVER RADIO:
From New York 1 News,
This is
"New York Tonight."
- ( door opens )
- Hello?
I was beginning to think
you weren't going to make it.
We're having guests
for dinner tonight.
What-- what happened?
Huh?
You're all wet.
I fell
into the bay.
It's cold-- Mom, come
on, stop. I'm fine.
- You fell into the bay?
- It's not gonna happen again.
- Don't worry.
- Leonard.
It was an accident.
Can I change, please?
Reuben!
Mom, I'm fine!
I'm fine.
What is the matter?
I think he
tried again.
He said he fell
in the bay.
Leonard?
MOTHER: I think he forgot
his medication this morning.
REUBEN:
Leonard?
Listen-- the man who wants
to buy our business
is coming over tonight
with his family.
MOTHER:
Let's cancel that.
REUBEN:
No, they're almost here.
Look, if he still has
this bipolar problem,
he just has to
take his pills.
( louder ) It would be nice if
you joined us, okay?
'Cause we want you
to join us.
Okay.
( muttering )
Stupid stupid.
- ( doorbell rings )
- ( people chattering )
Hi, how are you?
Oh, enjoy.
Thank you!
- Hi.
- Hello.
I hope we're not late.
The directions were perfect.
- It smells good.
- How you feeling?
Good,
thank you.
Good. You remember
my wife Carol.
Hi, nice to
see you again.
- Thank you so much.
- MAN: And these are my kids--
- ( door opening )
- --David, my son.
David.
My beautiful daughter Sandra.
SANDRA: Oh thanks, Dad.
Pleased to meet you.
I have to go
to the bathroom.
Down at the end
of the hallway.
Hey hey, David,
what you got?
ALL:
Ohh!
David,
say thank you.
All right. Come inside.
Let me take your coats.
Yeah, take
the coats.
- This is a beautiful place.
- Yeah, you like it?
It's so nostalgic--
it's like the place I grew up in.
CAROL:
Eat what you'd like. Okay.
- They're not baked.
- They taste like baked.
Okay.
My wife-- my princess--
is in the kitchen getting dinner ready.
She'll be right out.
Anyway, help yourself.
It's homemade hummus.
I did it.
- CAROL: Oh!
- Yeah.
MICHAEL:
Mmm, terrific! Terrific!
- Ooh!
- This is my son Leonard.
- How you doing?
- Leonard? Michael Cohen.
- How do you do?
- Nice to meet you.
My wife Carol,
my daughter Sandra.
- Hi, how you doing?
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
MICHAEL:
...Not from the Catskills.
The Catskills that we
were talking about
Is like
the slums of the Catskills.
- Which part? Which part?
- South Fallsburg, Loch Sheldrake.
- Which is more west?
- Kiamesha. Kiamesha.
- RUTH: Is it more west than--
- We met at the Catskills.
SANDRA:
Just in time for the flies.
- CAROL: You were very--
- MICHAEL: And you were the prettiest one.
CAROL:
I paid him to say that.
MICHAEL: 35 years ago in
the Catskills.
CAROL:
Please don't make me older.
- Hey, you like magic?
- Yeah.
You ever heard of
the melting spoon?
No.
It's really cool.
MICHAEL: Now they put so many
things in your path.
I mean, all the inspections
and all of the licensing
and all the-- the different
technology-- the machines.
CAROL: It's amazing you can
run a business.
You know, my son's been
working with me a little
since he's been back.
You know?
I don't know how much he likes it, but...
( all laughing )
MICHAEL: What about it, Lenny?
Do you like it?
Do you like
the dry-cleaning business?
It's all right, you know?
It's good to help out the family.
REUBEN: He's a good photographer--
I'll tell you that.
- CAROL: Really?
- Yes. Yes yes.
Yeah, I gave him
an old camera
and now all he does--
he takes pictures all over the place.
MICHAEL:
Really?
RUTH:
Beautiful black-and-white photos.
- CAROL: Black and white.
- Thanks, Mom.
Yes, they are
beautiful photos.
- MICHAEL: Carol?
- Yes?
- Do you know what I'm thinking right--
- I know what you're thinking.
Listen, I have a little
proposition.
- Mmm, here we go.
- No no.
We have-- we have
a bar mitzvah.
David's bar mitzvah
is coming up next week.
Oh, and of course
you're all invited.
- You're invited.
- Oh, thank you.
- CAROL: Oh, yeah.
- But we have a photographer,
and he's taking the color shots and
he's taking the slides and the set-ups,
but my wife,
the artistic one,
she wants
the black and white.
- CAROL: Yes, we do.
- Lenny?
Do you think you'd be interested
in doing something like that?
Oh, I don't know
about that.
- I mean, I--
- CAROL: Why not?
I don't-- I don't really
do impromptu things.
- I mean--
- Oh, try. You'll see what happens.
MICHAEL:
I'd love to see his stuff--
just check it out a little bit.
Do you think I could?
Okay.
I'll show you some.
Leonard, why don't you show
Sandra your pictures?
I don't know if--
you want to see that now?
Yeah, I'd love
to see them.
'Kay.
Come on.
RUTH: I tell him all the time
but he gets angry at me.
( chuckles )
- Report back.
- I'll call you for dessert.
Eh?
I wasn't expecting
visitors.
Yeah, you've got
a lot of stuff in here.
Yeah.
I wasn't planning on being
home for so long, so...
I gotta organize this place.
I don't know what the fuck.
Oh, when--
when did you get back?
Uh, about
four months ago.
Mmm.
What are we doing?
Oh, yeah-- pictures.
You can sit down
if you want.
Okay.
- Let's see.
- You have a lot of DVDs.
Yeah.
You like movies?
Yeah, I love
movies.
Yeah? Like what?
What do you like?
Well, my favorite
movie is probably...
"The Sound of Music."
Not because of
the film, really,
but because, you know,
whenever it's on,
my family always watches it.
It's that kind of thing.
No, that's a good movie.
It's underrated.
Yeah.
Can I look at these?
Yeah, those are--
that's a good pile.
This is
the garbage pile.
Oh, these are nice.
Oh, thanks.
Yeah, this one I like.
Look at it.
This one's nice too.
But you don't have any
people in them really.
Yeah, well,
you know.
People look at 'em-- they
don't have to be in 'em too.
I like this one.
Thanks.
Gotta be in the moment.
( laughs )
So what--
what do you do?
I work at Pfizer in
the city-- it's a drug company.
Yeah, I know it well.
I have some ones with
some people in it.
I was just
going through these--
who's-- who's that
in this photo here?
Oh, that was-- I don't even
know what that's doing there.
That's so weird.
That was my fiancée.
- Your fiancée?
- Yeah.
You were engaged.
Yeah,
a couple years ago.
She's gone, though.
She moved away.
What happened?
You know, um--
We got these genetic tests
and we were both positive
- for Tay-Sachs disease.
- Oh.
It means if we ever had kids, they'd
be, like, dead after a year, so...
Yeah.
She didn't want to adopt
and, well,
that was that.
I'm so sorry.
Mmm, probably for
the best.
RUTH:
Leonard? Sandra?
Dessert's on the table.
Okay!
You know, um...
our parents
wanted us to meet.
Well, no, I have to
tell you the truth.
Actually, I wanted
to meet you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I saw you at
your parents' store
and I just...
You were asking
your mother to dance with you.
It was
very cute.
Sounds like something
I would do.
RUTH:
You two, dessert's on the table.
Yeah, we heard you
the first time!
Sorry.
She's really serious
about her desserts.
( laughs )
We should probably go.
She's...
gonna have an aneurysm.
- We'll hang out after.
- Okay.
Um, yeah. Okay.
I'm just gonna put this away.
( humming )
( woman laughing )
( giggling )
( clucking )
Leonard?
Stop horsing around.
Three deliveries--
one right near here
and the other two
are in Sheepshead Bay.
Okay.
And don't lose
the clothes again.
- You're gonna put us out of business.
- ( softly ) God willing.
- ( knocking )
- ( dog barks, baby cries )
MAN: We'll only be here
for a few months.
- Hey, don't walk away.
- WOMAN: Don't fucking touch me.
- Hey hey, where are you going?
- Get your fucking hands off me.
Don't walk away from me!
Michelle!
( footsteps approach )
Get the fuck
back up here!
Do not
disrespect me!
( door slams )
- Hi.
You're such
a spoiled brat!
Sorry.
- For what?
- You still think you're living up in great neck?
It's my father.
He's-- he's a little crazy.
You okay?
Yeah.
Hey, I can hear you talking.
Who are you talking to down there?
Do--
you live here, right?
Yeah. Well, my parents do.
I'm staying with them.
Oh, right.
Michelle, come back here.
Don't leave like this.
You want to
come in for a bit?
Yeah, maybe just--
that'd be great.
Just until he
calms down, maybe.
I don't want, like,
everybody to call the cops.
Yeah, that'd suck.
I'm Leonard.
- Michelle.
Yeah, you can
hear him screaming.
Come on up here!
Don't make me shout.
Hey, do you think
you want anything?
- No.
- RUTH: Hello?
Hi.
- Oh, Mom, this is Michelle--
- I'm-- I'm your neighbor.
Hello, neighbor.
Leonard,
your dad just came home.
We're going to have
Chinese food.
Okay.
That's nice.
( TV playing
low volume )
Oh, what are
those things?
- What, that?
- Yeah.
Oh, that's a dreidel.
Ha.
What?
It smells
like mothballs.
It does?
No, it's a good thing.
It reminds me of my grandma's house.
Yeah, well, my parents
are just trying to protect
all their, you know,
designer clothes and shit.
From what?
Mot-- moths.
( laughs )
Right.
Right right, moths.
Of course.
So you're new
here in the building?
Yeah, I just moved in
last week.
- Oh, cool.
- Yeah.
Oh, welcome.
Thanks.
Is your-- is that your bedroom
in the back, in the corner?
Oh, yeah, it's right--
it's right there.
Right there
to the right.
I can see you
from my apartment.
- Ha.
- I'm sure I--
I think I've seen you
through my window.
- Yeah?
- Don't worry, it's not, like, a weird thing.
- I'm not worried.
- Okay.
Wow, those are nice.
What is that, yiddish?
So you live
with your father?
Uh, no,
he's just visiting.
I live with my dog, Rex.
Hey, yeah, you know,
I think I heard him barking.
He doesn't sound too happy.
I mean, I don't speak dog.
Yeah, he kind of is.
He-- we move a lot and he
doesn't like it when we move.
So...
He liked Hoboken a lot,
which is weird.
But...
God, you guys have
a lot of books.
What are you, like,
one of those reader guys?
You, like, read all the time?
You're really smart?
- I don't know about that.
- I can see that.
I don't really read
very much, you know?
I've got ADHD,
supposedly.
Yeah, they say
everybody has that.
I think it's a conspiracy by
the drug companies, you know?
I think you're--
hello.
Hey, pop.
Hello.
Oh, this is Michelle.
Michelle, that's my father,
Reuben.
- Hi.
- I'm just going.
- You know, you don't have to go.
- You can stay as long as you want.
- No no, you're eating.
And it's fine.
I'm sorry.
I'm sure he's simmered
down now anyway, so...
- Thank you very much.
- Yeah.
- See you around.
- Yeah, I hope so.
Okay, bye.
Bye!
- RUTH: Bye.
- REUBEN: Bye.
RUTH:
Who is that girl?
New neighbor--
you met her.
I mean, Michelle.
She's new in the building.
I don't know.
I just met her myself.
Listen, Leonard, tomorrow
I have a lunch with Cohen.
He wants you to take
those bar mitzvah pictures.
His daughter is coming
to lunch too,
If you want to see her.
Hello?
Yeah.
I heard you, pop.
I'll come.
All right.
I'm sorry,
all right?
Don't be sorry.
( scoffs )
You're sleeping
all day again.
You're like
a vampire.
Oh, come on, Mom!
I'm up.
Aren't you having lunch with
your father and the Cohens?
Hmm? You don't want to be late.
Come on, here-- your pills.
No, I don't want to be late
for the beautiful Sandra.
She is beautiful.
I know.
I was joking.
Mmm. It's good
for business too.
We don't care about that.
You know that.
All right, all right.
Don't get bent out of shape.
Don't leave wet towels
on the floor.
They'll get
all moldy, okay?
Mom, I'm taking a shower.
You don't leave in the next minute,
I'm gonna show you the world.
Oh! Stop it.
( whistling )
( train approaching )
TRAIN CONDUCTOR:
Brighton Station and outbound Q local.
Transfer to b on
this platform. Next stop,
Sheepshead Bay.
Watch the closing doors.
( doors dinging )
( Leonard humming )
Hey.
What are you doing?
You don't say hello?
I didn't even
see you.
How you doing?
- Good.
- Cool.
You-- are you
going to the city?
Uh, yeah.
( horn honks )
Great, you can
keep me company.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, you ever
count doors?
- What?
- One two three four--
You try and guess which
door you're going to.
Eight nine 10--
I'm gonna be under 20--
11...
12...
- 13-- that's a bad number.
- No, it's a good number.
It is?
Excuse me.
So what do you do?
You work or...
Yeah. I work
at a law firm.
You're a lawyer?
I went to law school.
I mean, I didn't finish.
You know, I'm not a real lawyer...
No no no no. I'm not a
lawyer; I'm just an assistant.
An assistant for life.
What about you?
Do you work?
Absolutely.
I mean, my parents--
we got our own business.
Well, that's good.
You'll never get fired.
Yeah, there's no risk
in it, though.
It's like sometimes
you just feel fucking dead.
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
CONDUCTOR:
Next stop 57th Street.
For Queens-bound service,
transfer available to the N, R, W.
So let me
ask you something:
If you could do, like,
anything in the world,
You know, like,
anything you wanted to do,
what-- what do you
think it would be?
I like photography.
Really?
You're a photographer?
I'm gonna be.
Wow.
That's funny because I could--
I could sort of tell that you were,
like, creative.
God, that's very cool
that you're an artist.
Well, I-- I don't know
if you can call me an artist.
No, you know what? Never let
anybody discourage you from that.
I'm serious.
Really.
Wait, put your number
in my phone
and then we can,
like, text.
Oh, excellent.
Hey, I'm gonna give you
a special ringtone
so I know it's you
when you're calling.
All right.
Next stop, 57th Street.
Oh, shit,
this is my stop.
I gotta go to
a meeting with my boss.
You know, I'm going to the park,
like, six blocks away.
I'd rather just walk
than be in this stuffy place.
All right.
Hey, I could show you some
of my pictures sometime
- if you want to see something.
- Oh, that would be great.
- Yeah?
- I would love that.
So, Leonard, it was great
to hang out with you.
Oh, yeah.
You too.
And I guess I'll see you
around the building.
- Not if I see you first.
- ( laughs )
Yeah, I'll see you.
Hey, if you need a place to hide,
- you know where to come.
- Oh, yeah.
- I'll keep that in mind.
- All right.
- All right, I'll see you later.
- Bye.
RUTH:
I can't believe it.
It's 11 past 7:00.
You talk to him.
REUBEN: Where were you all day?
We were worried.
I tried you on your cell phone.
All we got was the message.
- Oh, yeah?
- What? You don't show up for lunch.
Yeah, there was
a terrorist alert--
- What?
- --In the subway.
- Terrorism?
- Yeah.
I'll just call
everyone and apologize.
( ringing )
- Hello?
- SANDRA: Hello?
Sandra?
It's Leonard.
Hi!
Hey. Hey, I'm so sorry
I missed lunch today.
I just-- I was down getting
equipment for my camera
and it's like you have to wait in line
forever after they give you the number.
I had the wrong
number and then--
No no no no, it's okay.
I got there late anyway.
It's okay.
Don't worry about it.
Yeah? Well, I don't know
what you're--
What you're doing
tomorrow, but...
I don't know, if you want
to go see a movie or something?
Maybe-- "Sound of Music"
isn't playing, but, you know...
- ( Sandra laughing )
- We could find, maybe, something.
My God, you're never going
to let me live that one down.
Okay, no.
Yeah, let's go.
( train approaching )
- Hello?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Yeah, that'll be fun.
Okay, then I'll call you--
I'll call you tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Okay? All right, have a nice night.
- Okay, bye.
- Okay, bye-bye.
( jazz playing )
Hi. What are you doing?
You're taking my picture?
- Yeah.
- ( laughing )
I was actually trying
to get your attention.
Oh.
You got it.
How you doing?
Good.
What's going on?
You look
all dressed up.
Oh, well,
I'm going out.
I'm gonna go dancing
with some friends of mine.
What about you?
What are you doing?
I was thinking about maybe going
out, but, you know, I don't know.
Leonard, we can't have that.
Come with us.
MAN: Hey, you heard of
a goddamn phone?
Hey, you know what, Doug?
There's a fucking storm coming, man.
( laughing )
Why don't you
come with us?
Yeah-- maybe, yeah.
- It's gonna be good.
- All right.
We're gonna leave in, like, 30 minutes.
Is that all right?
- Yeah. 30 minutes, downstairs?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, okay.
- I'll see you down there.
My account number?
5499...
- 1407...
- ( TV playing low volume )
143...
- 209.
- That's Western Mutual Life.
- And the expiration date is...
- And by...
- 03/25/11.
- ...The Corporation for Public Broadcasting,
- and by contributions to PBS stations...
- Yeah.
...from viewers like you.
Oh!
You look hot!
( laughs )
- Hey.
- BOTH: Hey.
- Hi.
- I'm Stephanie.
Dayna.
What's up?
LEONARD:
What's up, what's up?
- ( techno playing )
- Ah, this was my song with my crew, right?
- I was dancing-- but then I had my--
- STEPHANIE: With his crew.
I did.
I really did.
So I go, "who's gonna
rock this party right?"
And you guys go,
"L to the E-O-N-A-R-D"--
- My name, right?
- GIRLS: Okay.
Okay. So, who's gonna rock
the party right?
ALL:
L to the E-O-N-A-R-D.
Who's gonna rock
the party right?
ALL:
L to the E-O-N-A-R-D.
- Ladies--
- I can't spell!
What? You wanna bring it on?
'Cause I'll blow up your face
like Louis Armstrong.
And if you can't handle
the serious battle,
you mi-- you might want
to step up-- oh, shit.
- Aww!
- It was, like, 15 years ago.
I'm sorry! No, that was cute.
That was good.
- It was cute?
- Yeah, you are cute.
He's my new best friend.
- I was just about to say that.
- I gotta be out by midnight.
Michelle, what are you doing?
You still doing E.?
It's just
for a night.
God, don't take
another one.
Oh, come on,
I gotta do something.
I'm living in the middle
of fucking nowhere!
So, Leonard,
you go clubbing a lot?
- Yeah.
- DAYNA: You go clubbing?
Are you gonna bring it
on the dance floor?
I'll do what
I have to do.
( all laughing )
DAYNA:
He goes clubbing.
MICHELLE: I think you're gonna
like this, Leonard.
- Yeah.
- Are you gonna dance with me?
Maybe. I won't make you
look bad, you know?
- Hi, girls!
- Hi, Antonio!
ALL:
Hey! Hey!
- All right.
- Antonio!
- What's up?
- How you doing?
- This is my friend Leonard.
- You got I.D.?
- He's fucking with you.
- I'm only kidding. Go ahead.
Getting off in 10 minutes,
all right?
- Okay!
- All right.
Yeah.
Relax relax relax relax.
( upbeat music playing )
( all cheering )
( hip-hop song playing )
Michelle!
( distant siren wails )
- Are you all right?
- ( crying )
- What's the matter?
- Just go back inside, okay?
I'll be fine.
You know, you--
you can talk to me if you want.
You know, you can
tell me anything.
- Is it your father?
- Oh.
No.
That guy you're with?
Yeah.
I was-- I was supposed to
meet up with him tonight
but now he says
he can't make it.
He says he's gonna stay
with his wife.
He's married;
he has a son.
Oh, fuck, I'm so
fucking stupid.
Don't say that.
You're not stupid.
- I am.
- You're not stupid.
- I'm so fucking stupid.
- Don't say that.
No, you're not.
Come here.
Don't say that,
okay?
He keeps telling me
he's gonna leave them.
You know, he tells me
over and over.
And I never
asked him to do that.
And now I can't think
of anything else.
- I'm such a piece of shit.
- No.
Look at me.
You're very high right now.
You're very emotional.
You shouldn't think
about this right now, okay?
Let's just go home.
I'll take you home, okay?
- Ahh.
- You need to calm down.
You don't want to be out
here with all these people.
- Okay?
- Okay. Okay.
Don't worry about it.
We're gonna go home.
All right.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
I'll wait--
I'll wait right here.
Ahh, fuck.
Can I just get
my bag?
- I was in before. I left my bag.
- All right, go ahead.
Sorry.
( horn honking )
Fucking boyfriend.
Fuck.
- What's up, man?
- What up?
- I'm just going back in.
- You on the list?
- I was just in here.
- Yeah yeah, you and everybody else.
No, I just
came out, man.
I came out. I was
with Stephanie and--
I'm sorry, man. If you're not
on the list, I can't let you in.
- I was just inside.
- You're gonna have to move.
Go ahead.
Are you serious?
Ta-- taxi?
Who the fuck am I kidding?
I'll never get a taxi.
- ( machine beeps )
- FEMALE VOICE: You have one message.
( beeps )
SANDRA: Hey, Leonard,
it's Sandra.
- Hey, Sandra.
- Um, listen, I know  we had plans tomorrow,
but I totally forgot-- tomorrow
night's my dad's birthday party
and I gotta
go to that.
But my mom said your parents
are going to be going too
so I guess
you'll be with them?
We could go out
after if you want.
So just call me and let me
know if that's all right.
Okay?
Oh, and by the way,
you're not
going to believe this,
But "the Sound of Music" is
playing on cable right now.
And I still love it.
It's very good.
Okay, call me.
Bye.
( machine beeps )
( cell phone chiming )
MICHELLE:
Hello?
Hey, I'm back.
Leonard,
you're awake.
Yeah.
Yeah, you--
you okay?
Can you see me?
I can't see you.
No...
No, I'm--
I'm in bed.
Mmm. Oh, my God,
I'm so sorry about what happened.
I went back
into the club
and I went into the
bathroom and I passed out.
- What?
- I literally passed out in the bathroom.
Yeah, 'cause I waited
outside for, like, 30 minutes.
And they wouldn't let me
back in the club.
- I tried to call you.
- Oh, God.
I didn't know what to do.
I didn't want to leave you.
I'm so sorry.
It was crazy.
I have to go to the doctor.
I don't know what the fuck.
I'm just
stressed out, I think.
Yeah. I don't know.
It sounds like you're
In a really bad
situation with that guy.
It's horrible.
This guy,
You know, he's a partner
in a law firm where I work.
And I got into
this thing now.
You know, he pays
for this apartment.
And his mother
lives nearby,
So it's like the excuse
for when he comes out here.
Oh, yeah.
But you know,
he's not really like that.
He's actually
really amazing.
He's brilliant and
he can be really sweet.
I think
you'd like him.
My friends think he's never going
to leave his wife. What do you think?
I've never met him.
You know, I don't know.
I don't know what
your relationship is.
Ah. Well,
you know what, Leonard?
You should come and have
dinner with us tomorrow night.
He's always telling me, you know,
I should hang out with friends and stuff.
This way you could come
and eat with us
and then you could,
like, tell me
if you think he's
telling the truth, you know?
Because you're a guy and then you would
be able to know that kind of a thing.
Yeah, I don't know.
I gotta, uh--
I gotta check
my schedule.
You know, I got
a lot to do.
I can't tell if he's
telling me the truth, and...
if you came,
it would be so great.
I don't know, you know.
I gotta see.
I need this kind of,
you know, help right now
because I'm going crazy.
I can't--
You know what?
You know something?
I'll bet you he would take us
to his favorite restaurant.
It's called San Domenico.
It's in the city.
It's Italian and
it's really nice.
It's great food and we, like,
drink Brandy Alexanders.
It's the best.
Do you really want me to go?
Do you think it would make a difference?
I really really really
want you to go.
I think it'll make
a difference.
- Please.
- Ahh.
Okay, I'll go.
Thank you, Leonard.
I will officially shut up
now and let you go to bed.
Okay.
Hey, sweet dreams.
You too.
I'll see you tomorrow night.
Oh, wear
something nice.
Good night.
MAN ON RADIO:
The defense didn't really excel last week,
But I know in the past
Giant teams...
Hey.
I think I'll have
a New Year's party this year.
What do you think?
Well, it's not even
Thanksgiving yet, Mom.
No, but I like
to plan ahead.
Are you going out?
Yeah, I'm gonna get some dinner
with a couple friends.
I'll be back early.
- That's a nice suit.
- Yeah.
You look handsome.
Thanks, Mom.
I'm going to go out too
with your dad.
It's Michael Cohen's
birthday.
If you want to stop by
later, I'm sure...
You're going to
be welcome.
You gonna come?
Ahh, maybe I will.
I'll see you later.
Have fun.
( train approaching )
( romantic music
playing )
- Good evening.
- Ah, good evening, sir.
I'm here to meet
some people.
And do you have
a reservation?
Oh, it wouldn't be
under my name.
Do you know
when it's for?
6:30.
- Are you Mr. Kreandator?
- Kraditor.
Yes, you're with
the Blatt party.
You're the first
to arrive.
Would you like to wait at
the bar or go to your table?
I'll be seated.
Can I take
your coat?
Thank you.
Jeffrey.
This way, sir.
Would you like a drink
while you're waiting, sir?
Yes, I'll have
a Brandy Alexander, please.
( texting )
Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Sir, would you
like a straw?
I can bring you
a real straw if you'd like.
This is perfect.
Thank you.
Just...
Thanks so much.
Hey.
Hi.
- I can't stand up.
- Ron, this is Leonard.
- Nice to meet you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
- Shall I go, um--
- Shall I go here?
- Yeah, I'll sit here.
Oh, okay.
- I'll go around.
- I'm gonna come--
Um, she'll have-- oh, I see you've
got the same thing right here.
Very nice.
Brandy Alexander and a...
Maker's mark
on the rocks, please.
Right away, Mr. Blatt.
Nice to finally
meet you there, Leonard.
Nice meeting you
as well.
So Michelle tells me
you guys are neighbors.
Yeah. Yeah, we live right
across the way from each other.
- Nice. You guys can keep an eye on each other.
- ( Michelle laughs )
That's my old neighborhood, actually.
My mom lives out there.
- Is that right?
- You go to Totonno's?
- Oh, sure. I know the place.
- Yeah.
Good pizza.
It's really great pizza.
A lot of memories there.
So what kind of work
do you do?
I work for
my father's company.
Leonard's a photographer.
He's really good.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, really good.
What kind of photography
do you do?
- Fashion?
- Ah, land-- landscapes.
That's great.
That's good.
As long as you love it--
As long as you love
what you're doing.
And I think that we should get some
menus. Otherwise, we'll be late.
Well, they gave me
a menu already.
I don't know if it's...
( mumbles )
I don't know if Michelle told you--
we've got opera tickets tonight.
Oh, yeah.
We try to go as often
as we can.
I mean, you know,
I know she loves it.
Yeah, but you
like it too.
- I don't force you.
- Of course you don't.
Absolutely, I love it.
But I know how much it means to you.
That's true.
You know what the great thing
about it is for me?
- It makes you feel special when you're there.
- Mmm.
I mean, I'm lucky--
my law firm gives me a box.
But I'm telling you something:
If you've got somebody
that you love,
you take 'em to the opera.
Hey, darlin'.
Yeah, I ought to bring
my girlfriend.
That sounds romantic.
- What? You have a girlfriend?
- Yeah.
Leonard, you didn't tell me
you had a girlfriend.
- I didn't?
- No.
Well, we haven't
been going out that long--
That's probably why.
It would've come up.
A man's got to have his secrets, Honey.
Come on.
Come on,
leave him alone.
I'm going to go
to the ladies' room.
Again, baby?
I'll be right back.
Hey, listen,
Leonard.
Come here.
I want you to do me a favor.
I want you to--
I want you to keep
an eye on her.
I want you to look out for her
for me a little bit, if you can.
She in trouble?
I think she might
be using again.
I mean, I know I shouldn't
be saying this, but...
I mean, I can see
the signs.
- I haven't seen nothing.
- Yeah? Sure?
I mean, you know, she comes
from a good family,
plenty of money.
You know, and her father
goes and spends it all
and boom, that's it--
the whole thing goes to hell.
So, whatever, just do me
a favor, all right?
Just-- just keep
an eye on her.
Just don't let her get
involved in that kind of thing.
Yeah. I don't play
with that shit.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
You seem like you
have a good heart, you know?
To tell you the truth, you
kind of remind me of my son.
( footsteps approach )
- Hey.
- Hi.
What are you guys
talking about?
All right. Well, we're talking
about how beautiful you are.
Uh, the specials, please.
We're starving
- And we're kind of pressed for time.
- Yes, Mr. Blatt.
Can we have the specials?
( music swells )
Okay, Leonard, this is
where we part ways.
Yeah, it was
good to meet you.
It was good to
meet you too.
Hey, Carl, why don't you
take him where he needs to go?
That's nice.
Thank you.
No problem.
- Bye!
- Have fun.
Yeah, I agree.
( man singing aria )
( doorbell rings )
- Hi.
- Hey.
How you doin'?
Good good. Um, your parents
told me you'd be home.
They said you wanted me
to come over.
They're at
my father's birthday.
Yeah.
Yeah, come on in.
Come in.
Um, you want
something to drink?
Yeah, sure.
Yeah? Okay.
What is this
that you're playing?
- Oh, opera.
- Opera?
- You like it?
- Yeah.
- I've never been to the opera.
I've been to "the nutcracker,"
but-- when I was little.
Yeah? What do you want,
water, soda?
- Soda, please.
- Lot of options, yeah.
I was just out with
a couple friends,
with some business
I have to do.
Thank you.
Is this
your whole family?
Yeah. Well, actually
I was adopted.
I was in line to be
King of Denmark.
( laughs )
No, yeah, that is.
That's my parents-- that's where
they met, the workmen's circle dance.
My uncle Tobias
introduced them.
That's him right there
with the mustache.
- Oh my God.
- Yeah, my dad just came over from Israel.
- And...
- Oh.
Yeah, it's cute.
That's me.
My mom as a girl.
These are dirty,
aren't they?
What's the matter?
Umm...
Leonard, this wasn't your idea
for me to come over, was it?
What?
What do you mean?
It's okay you
didn't call me back.
I--
We don't have
to go out.
I mean,
There are a lot of
guys who just--
That want to
go out with me.
Oh my--
oh my God.
I do like you.
Well, it feels
a little strange
with my mother
staring right there.
( woman begins aria )
( Sandra
breathing heavily )
Mmm.
I should go
before your parents come home
and see us like this.
Are you kidding?
They'd be happy.
Probably picking out
baby names.
( laughs )
God.
( man begins aria )
So I heard you're going to
take the pictures
at my brother's
bar mitzvah next month.
Yeah.
I'm taking the black
and whites-- the art shots.
That's cool.
My friend's having
a party on Thursday night.
You wanna come?
I'll try to see
if I'm free.
Okay.
Will you call me?
Yeah.
I'll see myself out.
Okay.
- Bye.
( aria continues )
( dog barking )
( cell phone ringing
to "Für Elise" )
- Hey.
- Leonard, could you meet me up on the roof?
What time is it?
It's early.
It's like 6:30.
Could you come up?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I'll come up now.
- Thanks.
- Right.
( mutters )
- Hey.
- Hi.
It's fucking cold.
I know. I'm sorry,
but he's downstairs.
So what did
you think?
Leonard, what did you think of Ronald?
Tell me.
I don't know.
What-- what do you
want me to say?
Do you think he's going
to be with me for good?
Seriously.
I don't think so.
Sorry.
( sighs )
He's got this fucking business
trip he wants me to go on.
I don't know what to do.
Michelle, come on!
What are you doing?
Come on, seriously.
He's the kind of guy
who's got this
whole life,
His family
and shit.
You think he's gonna
leave all that?
I know
I would.
I'd definitely leave
everything for you.
Leonard, you're very sweet,
but I--
I think if you knew me better,
you wouldn't feel that way.
I don't care.
Leonard, listen to me.
You're like a brother
to me now.
Oh!
I know we've only known each
other for a couple of weeks.
But I-- I feel like I
could tell you anything.
You know? I need you
to be my friend.
You know, why don't you
tell Ronald, okay?
Tell Ronald.
Go away on your trip--
- Tell Ronald?
- I don't care.
Have a great time.
Leonard, where
are you going?
I don't think we should
see each other anymore.
Oh, Leonard,
don't say that.
Leonard!
( mumbling numbers )
Hey, Sandra,
it's Leonard.
Uh, I know it's really early.
You're probably sleeping,
but I was just checking
my schedule and I'm free.
And, yeah-- see about maybe
going out with you to this party.
So why don't you call me
when you get this?
All right.
Hey, Happy Thanksgiving.
Bye.
( guitar strumming )
( applause )
MASTER OF CEREMONIES: David, give us a turn.
Give us a turn.
How does he look?
And as our last event
of the day,
I'd like to invite mom,
dad and sister Sandra
to come up and give you support
for your candle-lighting.
We're gonna share the love.
Bring everybody
real close.
Come on in, come around.
Not so close.
It's been such a great
afternoon, everybody.
What a way to
wrap things up.
Our host, dad Michael,
would like to say a few words.
If you could give him a
tremendous round of applause...
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
I just want to say that--
how proud I am
That everybody took the time
to come to David's bar mitzvah.
And on behalf of
your sister Sandra
and your mother Carol,
I want to tell you
how proud we are of you.
I just have one question:
With all your gifts,
Can you make me
a $200 Loan?
( all laugh )
Okay, we're going to
light the last can--
Leonard, come on
up with us.
My daughter's boyfriend,
everybody-- come on.
We're going to light
a candle for David.
MASTER OF CEREMONIES:
All right, David, at this time
I'd like you to
close your eyes
and make a big wish.
( cell phone ringing
to "Für Elise" )
( all laugh )
He's very popular.
I thought it was on silent.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Help me count, everybody.
Here we go-- one two...
- Three--
- blow out those candles!
( band playing )
Ah, mazel tov!
Last dance, everybody.
Everybody up for the last dance!
Come on.
( door closes )
- MAN: Good night, Leonard.
- Bye.
- ( thunder rumbling )
- ( dialing )
MICHELLE:
Leonard?
I saw you called me.
What do you want?
I'm sorry.
I know you don't want
to talk to me,
But I don't-- I don't
know what else to do.
Um, I'm not
feeling well.
What's wrong?
I was supposed to go
to the doctor today.
I'm-- I'm at home
right now.
Ron was supposed to take me,
but I don't know where he is.
I started bleeding really
bad a few hours ago.
You're bleeding?
I may need to go to
the hospital,
but I'm afraid
to go by myself.
Can you come
with me, please?
Yeah, I'll come.
Thank you so much,
Leonard.
( thunder rumbles )
MICHELLE:
Leonard?
Hey. What are you
doing down here?
- ( groans )
- What happened?
I don't feel
very well.
I'm scared something's
gonna happen.
Wait here. I'll try
and get us a cab.
( phones ringing )
- ( intercom beeping )
- ( indistinct pages )
- ( door opens )
- WOMAN: Mr. Kraditor?
Come.
Is she awake?
Yeah.
But she's still
sedated.
Mmm, Leonard.
How you feelin'?
Is there another blanket?
I'm so cold.
Yeah, I can feel that.
Hey, she feels really cold.
Is that normal?
Yeah, that's typical
from the anesthesia.
She should be fine. She just needs
to see a doctor in a couple of weeks.
What'd they do
to her?
The doctor had to
perform a D. and C.
She miscarried.
She wasn't aware she was
pregnant until she came in today.
They said you're okay
and that's what's important.
I know.
- Rex, hi.
- ( dog yipping )
Oh, come in.
This is my dog, Rex.
Oh hi, Rex.
Oh.
Leonard, I gotta
go lie down.
Yeah, you should.
Okay, I'll bring you
the pillows.
Thank you.
I brought you
some water.
( pills rattle )
Thank you, Leonard.
Feelin' better?
Good.
I had these crazy
nightmares while I was out.
Yeah?
Don't worry.
I am here
to protect you.
( laughs )
Ow.
- Don't make me laugh.
- All right.
Oh, you'll protect me?
Yeah. I have
a black belt, you know?
Nightmares--
It's fine. Shh.
- ( door opens )
- Oh, fuck.
- RONALD: Honey?
- If he sees you, he'll go crazy.
- ( dog yipping )
- Hey, what are you doing, little guy?
Sweetheart?
Hey.
Oh hey, sweetheart.
You didn't call me.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't.
My wife was with me all day.
I'm sorry, baby.
I got here as quick
as I could.
Today of all days?
- It's my wife.
- Oh, fuck you.
She was just with me
all day.
Baby, I'm sorry.
I really am sorry.
I thought about you all day.
It was killing me,
thinking about you
at the hospital like that.
What happened?
What did the doctor say?
What's wrong?
Um, I don't feel very well.
I want to be by myself.
You're not gonna let me
stay with you,
- even just for a few minutes?
- No.
I don't want you to stay
with me for a few minutes.
Honey, I have to go
to London tomorrow night.
And then I'm not going to
see you for two weeks.
I'm sorry.
I tried to get here
as soon as I could.
Yeah.
Come on, baby. Aren't you
going to tell me what's wrong?
Ron, I would
really like it
if you would just
leave me alone.
- No, come on--
- Please.
- Don't be like that.
- Please can you just do that for me?
Okay, all right.
Well, I love you
very much,
more than anything.
( dog yipping )
( door closes )
That was fucking weird.
Leonard,
I'm sorry.
All right, I'll--
I'll call you--
No no no no, Leonard,
please don't go.
Please.
Leonard, could you--
Will you do me
a favor, please?
Yeah.
Could you write something
on my arm with your finger
while I fall asleep?
My grandma used to do it
when I was little.
Mmm.
( man whistling outside )
( whistling,
men laughing )
SANDRA: ...So funny.
Oh, you know what?
My parents finally got the
pictures back from the bar mitzvah.
Oh, they-- they like the
dancing shots in the ballroom?
They love them.
- Good.
- Thank you, dear.
You're very welcome.
Um, I got
something for you.
- A gift?
- Yeah.
It's-- you know,
it's winter out, it's cold,
and I noticed that
you don't wear any gloves.
Oh, these are nice.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You like 'em?
Yeah, it's got
the stitching.
I've never seen
anything like this.
- Cool.
- Little silver thing.
Good.
That was very sweet
of you. Thanks.
No big deal.
What's wrong?
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm just thinking
about a friend of mine.
She's kind of going through
some tough stuff, so...
I don't want you and I
talkin' about it--
No no,
it's okay.
I love your hands.
They're so gentle.
I hate these
fucking scars.
Leonard, I, um...
I want to take care
of you.
I feel like I
understand you.
You're different.
You don't pretend to be
something you're not.
So you don't have to
worry about anything.
You don't have to
be embarrassed.
Thank you.
You know, I got
a lot of stuff
going on
right now that's...
I don't even know what
it's like to just
be myself right now.
No, I-- I understand.
Are you in a hurry
somewhere or what?
No, I just wanted to
pay the check
so we could
get out of here.
Okay.
- ( phone vibrating )
- Oh, fuck.
Probably my father calling:
"How's the date?"
( laughs )
Uh, I gotta take this.
Yeah, it's my friend.
- Oh, okay.
- I'll be right back.
Sorry.
We'll go in a minute.
( vibrating )
- Michelle?
- Hey.
- I just got your text from yesterday.
Yeah, well, I knew you had your
two-week follow-up thing today.
How'd it go?
It went fine. Everything's--
everything's good.
The doctor says I'm good.
Good.
'Cause I didn't
hear from you.
No, I'm fine. I just
came home and got into bed
and I've been lazy.
Listen, Leonard,
Ron got back
from London today.
I decided I'm going to
go to his office later
and I'm just--
I'm just gonna end it.
Really?
Today?
Yeah.
I've been thinking about what
you said and you were right.
Nothing's going
to change.
It's not fair what
he's doing, you know?
It's not fair to me and it's
definitely not fair to his family.
He still doesn't even know what
happened to me at the hospital.
Well, do you want me to come
with you and wait outside or--
No, don't worry.
I'll be strong.
Just wish me luck.
Well, good luck.
Thanks.  I'll text you
after it's over, all right?
Okay. Bye.
MICHAEL: I haven't seen units
like that in 30 years.
They're ancient.
We gotta get something new.
There are some new
Italian machines
- they're Tintoretto.
- Tintoretto?
- Yeah, Tintoretto.
- REUBEN: Leonard?
Hey, pop.
Leonard.
Mr. Cohen.
Reuben, I'm going to
take off. We'll talk.
All right.
I'm glad I
caught you, Leonard.
- Listen, tomorrow...
- Yeah?
...Do you think you could come
by my office, above my cleaners?
- Yeah.
- I got something I'd like to talk to you about.
- How's noon?
- Uh...
Well, I think I have
to work tomorrow.
Go-- go meet
with Michael.
- The deliveries...
- It's okay.
Okay. Good.
I'll see you then.
Reuben.
I'll bring a nice bottle
of champagne for--
Oh, no,
we got plenty.
No, it's my pleasure.
- Yes, all right.
- Okay.
- I'll see you at noon.
All right.
Bye bye.
Hey, pop,
where's mom?
- There's no more Seltzer.
- She's out getting stuff.
She's having another one of her famous
New Year's parties tomorrow night.
How are you?
Are you happy
these days?
I'm okay.
I feel anxious.
I was just talking to--
to Michael.
I want to make sure
you'll be taken care of
with the merger
and all this.
It's why I'm doing it,
so you have a future.
You'll have
your health insurance.
I appreciate that,
Pop.
I'm going swimming in the ocean
with Polar Bear Club
On New Year's day.
Be careful
out there.
I will.
( phone vibrating )
What? Somebody is sending
you something here?
Yeah, it's just
my friend.
All right.
I forgot to do something.
I'll clean this up
later, all right?
Hey.
I just got
your text.
I've been worried
about you.
You all right?
It's over.
I did it.
He yelled and screamed
but I did it.
Sorry.
It's so fucked up.
I'm so lost, Leonard.
I have this friend
in San Francisco.
She's going away for a while
and she said I could
go out and stay at
her place.
So I'm gonna go out there
and figure things out.
Don't go.
I love you.
I do.
Oh, God.
Leonard--
I know you may not
want to hear it,
but it's true.
Leonard, you don't
love me, okay?
- Don't say that.
- I'm completely fucked up.
Don't say that.
I'm not a little kid.
This isn't some
stupid fucking crush.
You think I don't
know love?
I was supposed to
get married.
Her parents are the ones
that called it off
because of
this medical thing and...
then she went away.
I couldn't find her.
And I tried to hurt myself and
they put me in the hospital.
And I--
I didn't--
I didn't think that
I'd ever
love anyone again.
And I lov--
I love you.
I do.
Leonard, I...
You--
You think if I got to know
you that I wouldn't love you,
but I do know you and
I love you even more.
I understand you,
Michelle.
I'm fucked up too.
I will never
walk away from you.
Never.
He left you.
I'd never do that.
I'll take care
of you
because that's
what you deserve.
You deserve
to be loved.
And maybe you'll
learn to love me too.
Ahh!
( moaning )
( grunting )
I love you.
Oh.
You're so beautiful.
( church bells dinging )
( breathing heavily )
( cell phone vibrating )
( beeps )
( distant
siren wailing )
Hi.
That was beautiful.
Yeah.
You know what
I just realized?
I never really
saw you.
I never saw you
either.
I can feel you, you know?
I can really feel you.
Yeah.
Can you see me now?
Yes.
You're beautiful.
You're the most beautiful,
most amazing woman ever.
What are we
gonna do, Leonard?
I can't stay here.
He's not gonna keep
paying for this apartment.
And I think I've really
got to go to San Francisco.
Then I'll just
go with you.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
I told you, Michelle,
I love you.
I'll do anything for you.
Do you really
love me, Leonard?
Yes.
Michelle,
let's just go.
Tomorrow.
Yeah.
Fuck it,
let's just go.
Let's just get
the fuck out of here.
Yeah, fuck it.
I've got no reason to stay here.
I just want to be with you,
wherever that is.
- I don't care.
- ( laughs )
You're crazy.
That's what
they told me.
All right, I'm gonna
work on the tickets.
You don't worry
about anything, okay?
I'll call you
in a little bit.
Okay.
I love you.
Bye for now.
Bye.
Good night.
( TV on low volume )
( Ruth laughing )
( Reuben laughing )
Leonard?
Have you ever seen
"Benny Hill"?
I just got the new
DVD set.
Yeah, he's good, Pop.
What are you doing,
Leonard?
Just looking at some stuff
online, Mom.
What are you doing?
Do you need help?
No no, thanks.
I got it.
( Reuben laughing )
MAN:
This is the best we have at this price.
I just want it
to be right, you know?
Of all the rings,
I-I think this is
the best choice.
Yeah, it's nice.
I want it.
Very good, sir.
You'll be using
a credit card?
Cash.
I'll get you
your receipt.
Thank you.
Seven...
- MICHELLE: Hello?
- I got our tickets.
I'm packed and ready to go.
Is everything good with you?
Yeah,
everything's fine.
I called my girlfriend
in San Francisco.
- I'm excited.
- Me too.
So, listen, meet me in the
courtyard at 8:00, all right?
I got us a car to take us
to the airport.
- 8:00.
- All right.
I'll-- I'll definitely
be there.
I can't wait to
see you.
- Me too.
- Oh, one other thing.
- Yeah?
- I got you a surprise.
A surprise?
What'd you get me?
Uh, it wouldn't be
a surprise if I told you!
My God.
You are so weird.
I'll see you later.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
MICHAEL: I'm glad you could make it in
today for our meeting, Leonard.
Just take a look
around the business,
acquaint yourself with
what's going on here.
A kid's got to start thinking
about his future sometime.
Oh, I do.
Well, this is your opportunity
right here, right now.
It could be
a terrific thing--
A fresh start for
you and Sandra.
My daughter
is crazy about you.
And believe me, there's
lots of guys after her.
The most important thing is
to give her what she wants
because she is
my life.
So I'm going to ask you
a question now.
And I'm going to
be direct with you.
I hope you don't mind.
Are you a fuck-up?
I don't think so.
You-- you know why I'm asking
you this question, right?
Well, I think it's
'cause of Sandra.
It's Sandra
and the merger.
This is a terrific
thing for you,
a terrific thing,
to turn your life
around.
I understand that.
This business is
important to me.
Your father has a hell of
a good location out there.
And we're going to be
moving into that space soon.
And when we do, there is
an opportunity here
for you, for your father,
for your family,
for your future family,
If you apply yourself,
and I know you're going to.
I think you know how important
this is for everybody.
Yes.
Good. Good.
What's in the bag?
Just...
It's a surprise.
It's a gift.
- Oh.
- It's a secret.
Yeah, big secret.
Okay, so I'll
see you tonight, right?
Uh-huh, yeah,
at the party.
We're gonna celebrate
New Year's together.
I'm about to have lunch.
Do you want to have lunch with me?
No, I've got to go do some
shopping for my mom for the party.
- Okay.
- All right.
Good.
- Well, I'll see you later.
- Okay, Leonard.
- Thanks for coming.
- Bye.
( chattering )
REUBEN:
You know, we celebrate--
we celebrate the New Year
twice a year, you know?
Because at
Rosh Hashanah and...
- All right, it's good.
- Thank you, thank you.
It's a 1998.
- '98?
- 1998.
It's really very good.
I go there, and they
have a theater with--
For my princess.
Thank you.
MAN: Hey, Reuben,
you sure we got enough?
We've got this to last
until midnight.
We are in
a good shape, huh?
Good.
Reuben, why don't you
ask Leonard
- to help you with that?
- All right.
He's trying to open a box--
did you see that?--
With a plastic spoon.
- Enjoying?
- Having a great time.
( knocking ) Leonard, could you
help me for a minute?
I need to open
everything up.
Be right out, Pop.
( music playing )
Hey, Lenny, you still
taking all those pictures?
Hey.
Leonard, can you help me
with this, please?
( intercom buzzing )
- REUBEN: Hello?
- MICHAEL: Hi, Reuben.
- Yeah.
- I hope we're not late.
No, it's okay.
Come on in.
The Cohens are on
their way up.
- Oh, yeah?
- Sandra is with them.
Happy New Year, Pop.
Happy New Year.
- Leonard! You look so good.
- Yeah?
- Oh, thank you. It's nice to see you.
- Nice to see you.
( footsteps
approaching )
( chattering )
Will you both hurry up?
( laughing )
- Hi!
- RUTH: Happy New Year to you.
Hi!
There's lots of food.
- CAROL: Thank you so much.
- RUTH: I'll be right back.
Leonard?
Are you leaving?
I saw on the computer that you
checked travel sites last night.
You're going
with her?
Yes.
( man hooting )
I have to go, Mom.
But you don't even
have a bag.
I threw it
out the window.
You don't have to
worry about me.
I'm gonna be okay.
I love you
very much.
I know you do.
This is your home.
You come back here
whenever you want. Mmm?
Tell Papa that
I'm sorry.
And I hope I didn't
mess things up.
And that I'm happy.
- Are you happy?
- Yeah.
We want you happy.
I love you.
Thanks, Mom.
I have to go.
( dialing )
Uh, Michelle,
it's Leonard.
I'm downstairs.
It's 8:05.
Call me or I'll see you
down here. All right.
Bye.
( stone clacks )
( honking,
fireworks )
Please come.
Please come down.
I was just calling you.
The car's out front
waiting.
I'm not going.
He left his family
for me.
He told
his wife everything.
He says he wants
to get married.
I finally let him know
about my miscarriage
and that really
changed things for him.
Leonard,
You're such
a wonderful person.
But he left them for me.
You know, I've got to
give it a chance.
I feel like if I wasn't
with Ronald,
we could...
Just go.
I'm so sorry.
Go!
He's gonna pay you back
for the tickets, okay?
I'm sorry.
( people screaming )
( firecrackers exploding )
( waves crashing )
( wheezes )
( blows )
( guitar strumming )
Are you okay?
What's going on?
Where were you?
I got you something.
Yeah?
Oh my God.
Leonard.
I--
You're crying.
I'm just happy.
( man singing aria )
Subtitles by LeapinLar