old indian: the white man
called them buffalo.
we call them tatanka,
the majestic ones.
their story is the story
of our people.
tatanka lived in
the underworld
until he saw our people
in a vision.
he saw that
we were needy.
and for the love of us,
tatanka came up out of the earth
and became flesh
so that we could eat,
make our clothes
and our dwellings
from his hide.
[speaking
lakota language]
he called us
the buffalo nation.
soaring eagle,
a medicine man,
could not accept
the terrible vision
of growling bear,
the buffalo
would disappear,
and the lakota would live
in square houses.
man: i suppose the best place
to begin our family's story
is with grandsire abraham.
many was the time as a boy
i listened to his tale
of how a cannon subtracted a leg
at the battle of yorktown.
i'd have wagered both mine
to see what he saw.
my misfortune was to be born
in a drab age
and to have lived in
the stifle of a barn
where a man was only as good
as the things he crafted.
wheelwrights we were,
going back to the time when
they invented the damn thing.
wheelers made wheels,
but in my day, we'd seen
the wheels made the wheelers.
all the long day,
i lived in my books,
and by night, i dreamed
of a better life
beyond the mississippi.
morning, enoch.
hi, papa. how are you?
good.
nathan.
mornin'.
- nathan.
now, that is a thing of beauty.
man: anybody see jacob?
jacob?
at your age, i was
repairing cannon wheels
at valley forge.
at least you got to see
a bit of the world, sir.
that was the war.
we had no choice.
thank god you live in
a time of peace.
yes, sir.
apply yourself to the anvil,
and you're set for life.
it takes 10 years to make
a journeyman wheelwright.
another 10 for master.
you'll never lack for work.
they need wheels
in time of peace,
they need wheels in time of--
don't you sass me,
young man!
yes, sir.
you boys knock off
for lunch now.
except jacob.
you already had yours.
[laughter]
plow horse needs shoeing
out there.
good morning.
who do i see about replacing
a rifle cock?
that'd be me, sir.
if i may, sir,
how'd you come by that scar?
difference of opinion
with a cheyenne warrior.
savage thought my scalp
might look better
hanging from his belt,
but i favored
where god put it.
but then i fancied
his locks on my belt.
may i?
sure.
my goodness.
what in the sam hill is that?
ho. sacred.
grizzly...
on its hind legs,
about where that
first rafter starts.
goodness gracious.
must be hell out there.
it's more like
the garden of eden, son.
come across some tribes'll
give you the girls.
you got mountains
covered with snow in summer
and forests
that go on forever,
rivers that you
can't hardly see across.
sometimes
you wait half a day
for a buffalo herd
to run past.
big shaggy beasts.
3 times a horse.
horizon to horizon.
and the pacific,
unsullied by human hands,
as it was on
the eighth day of the world.
see if that'll work for ya.
thank you.
did you finish shoein' that
plow horse like i told ya?
fine young man
you got here.
if he doesn't get knocked
into a cocked hat first.
and you let the fire
burn down, too.
we could've
turned out another wheel
before the end of the day,
but not now.
think you can
put a sharper edge
on this for me?
yes, sir.
is that...human blood?
arkansas toothpick ain't
for cuttin' your steak.
so where are you
headed, sir?
st. louis to meet up
with mr. jedediah smith.
the jedediah smith?
god made only one of him
for all of us to look up to.
who's that?
mr. smith opened up
the deep west for trappers.
lookin' for a few good
mountain men to explore
the beaver populations
around the great salt lake.
how much can a man make
off a beaver?
they keep buyin' beaver hats
in london and paris,
upwards to 4,000
or 5,000 a year.
it's time for you
to get back to work now,
all of ya.
5,000.
oh, now, margaret,
that is a fine-looking goose.
do you believe
that beaver story?
jacob: sunday dinner
was another form of labor
with my father and nick...
my mother margaret...
say grace first.
my brothers ezra,
nathan, and jethro.
abraham: for what we are
about to receive...
grandfather abraham
presided over the ritual
with grandmother hannah.
the wheelers pounded iron
6 days a week,
but on the seventh,
we pounded each other.
president adams
is saying to europe,
"keep out.
it's all ours."
it needs another jefferson
to take it all.
but isn't the west
just one vast desert?
that's a common untruth,
mama.
west is all kinds
of terrain.
it's a veritable
garden of eden.
yes. jacob's just returned
from the west wing
of the house.
[laughter]
jacob,
in fact, has yet to discover
the western side of the barn.
[all laugh]
jacob: as with all rituals,
nothing ever much changed.
until that sunday,
when i looked around the table
and said my silent good-bye
to each and every wheeler.
old indian:
heyoka, the clown,
tried to lift their spirits
after growling bear's
dark vision.
for the boy, white feather,
there were only questions.
he sought answers
among his family.
white feather was determined
to discover the meaning
of growling bear's vision
and if the future it predicted
could be changed.
white feather did not
have words to match
what he knew to be true.
but he knew that a vision
was a dangerous thing.
he knew a vision
could kill a man.
jacob!
you hold up!
hyah.
jacob!
jacob.
jacob, wait. hyah!
hyah!
jacob!
hyah, hyah, hyah!
wait.
what do you figure?
just run out
and not tell nobody, hope
your fool scheme works out?
i don't expect mr. smith
and mr. fletcher are gonna
tarry long in st. louis.
and ma and pa--
what do we tell them?
tell 'em i love 'em.
i ain't got time to lose.
i made my last
wheeling wheel.
why would a frontiersman
accommodate you?
ask and you shall receive.
mr. eternal optimist.
nathan, i thought you had
more enterprise in ya.
jethro, you always
been a blade of grass
bends with the wind.
[whinnies]
wait up.
no.
you'll be the first wheelers
to give up the trade.
you'll stay behind
and pound on dead iron
till you become dead as iron.
ah...
come on, jethro.
now or never.
aw, come on.
hyah! hyah!
yahoo!
[drums beating]
[woman signing
in lakota language]
old indian: white feather
could not accept
growling bear's vision
that the buffalo
would not return.
a ceremony was performed.
the people danced to give
gratitude to tatanka
and pray that he would
live again and again
in the great
circle of life.
[men and women singing
in lakota language]
[shouting
and whooping]
to lead the buffalo
to the jump
was to taunt death.
white feather knew that
his brothers,
dostar and running fox,
were chosen for their
ability and courage.
he was proud of them,
but afraid also.
old indian:
tatanka spared the boy,
so on the day the boy's
mother was put to rest
white feather was renamed
loved by the buffalo,
and all agreed that he had
been called to walk the road
of the medicine man.
old indian:
and so loved by the buffalo
took no food or drink
in 4 days.
he cleansed his body
and mind to open his spirit
for a vision to enter.
hey.
let's stash the horses
over there.
wait till dark.
oh! mmm!
what the--hey!
hey, get your black
hands off of me!
let go of him!
when you let go of me,
when you let go of me!
you're dead as mutton
if you don't.
and so is your friend.
all right, i'm gonna
let go. let go.
who's in there?
you answer me, by god!
just a couple of
hungry boys out
for some eggs, sir.
how many are you?
just two of us
in here stealing
eggs, sir.
regret to say
the wolf
in our stomachs
overcame our
god-fearing souls.
well, you only had to
knock on my door
to discover
christian charity.
had your fill of eggs
to boot.
we only took enough
to keep the wolf
at bay, sir.
well, go on. take a few.
i had my hopes up.
what with a big reward
for a runaway slave.
you don't say. how much
is that reward?
100 silver dollars.
sir, with your
permission,
we'll be on our way.
what about the--
nathan, let the good
christian man go back
to his warm bed.
thank you.
thank you heartily, sir.
god bless, boys.
what objection
do you have to
100 silver dollars
when the only thing
that stands between
us and ruination
is $7.00?
man kept his word, nathan.
i intend to keep mine.
what man?
he's a runaway.
that money's mine.
not with my rifle! unh!
poor as job's turkey,
you won't even bend down
to pick up $100 just
laying on the ground.
man's gotta draw
a line somewhere,
nathan.
he did
the honorable thing.
you're a damn dreamer.
let go, nathan. no!
who made you captain
of this enterprise, huh?
[gunshot]
you won't be alive
when i catch you, boy!
there goes our
100 silver dollars.
[escaped slave laughing]
damn you, jacob.
stop running!
ha ha ha! not soon,
farmer boy! see you!
jaco
we'd been in st. louis
long enough to see
the sights and then some,
but it took us more
than a fortnight longer
to find what
we'd come for.
mr. fletcher.
jacob wheeler.
you remember
my brother nathan?
yeah, i remember.
you said you
needed men, sir.
heh heh heh! oh.
yeah, i said
i needed men.
mountain men.
well, we'll pull
our weight, sir.
do you suppose
you could introduce
us to mr. smith?
we've surely come
a long way.
st. louis is raining
mountain men,
jacob, my boy, nathan.
seasoned men.
men more indian
than white. heh!
men who can
speak apache,
cheyenne, mexican.
nathan, hold on.
i'm sorry, jacob,
maybe next time.
[steam whistle blows]
where the hell
you been?
[money jingling]
st. louis loves
the brothers wheeler.
i couldn't lose a hand.
10 times i tried
to quit, 10 times
they made me stay.
i have won this.
this is an escritura.
that's spanish
for deed."
i won that
at poker, too.
it's a mere
100 acres in tejas.
you, 25. me, 75.
what do you say about
that, brother jacob?
tejas ain't even
in the united
states, nathan.
so what?
well, they don't
speak english and
their catholics.
we have 100 acres,
son, who cares?
i've made up
my mind. i'm going
with jedediah smith.
you see that
furry creature?
that's the kind of man
jedediah smith wants.
but who cares beans?
we found our fortune
in tejas.
i want to see
the pacific ocean.
and then what?
i don't know.
i've got a bird
in the hand in tejas.
you're after the will
o' the wisp out west
with adventurers
and criminals.
well, i say
we stick together.
yeah, well, why should
i stick with you?
there's a reason why
our father gave you
the grunt work
and me the precise
measurements
of wheelmaking.
it's 'cause
you never had a head
except for dreaming,
and here you go again.
are you coming or not?
jacob:
i thought of our mother
vexed by her
perfidious sons,
always consoling herself
with the notion that
we had each other,
but we didn't allow her
even that much comfort.
i'll be leaving
from the steamboat
within the hour
if you change your mind.
nathan went south,
and i went west.
i put my best
foot forward
and bought a new
old suit of clothes
for the occasion of meeting
the great jedediah smith.
it was not easy
mr. smith
because he endeavored
to stay upwind of me.
and then suddenly
he stood in front of me.
jacob: well, sir,
i just want to see
what no white man
has ever seen before.
and if a horse
throws a shoe,
i'm a first rate ferrier.
been at it since i
could pick up a hammer.
can you shoot?
why, sir, i'm a hunter.
this is my rifle.
exactly what kind of
game do you hunt?
rabbits and deer, sir.
you ever kill a man?
no, sir.
i admire your
spirit, boy,
but only the best
of the best
will be chosen.
so you go on home.
nobody here'll think
the worst of you.
maybe next time
around.
with all due respect, sir,
you ever kill man?
my friend, mr. smith
cannot count
the savages that fell
to his hands.
well, you know what?
it's pretty easy
to kill a savage
out to scalp you.
but you ever hunt down
an innocent rabbit,
done you no harm,
cut it down in cold
blood and eat it?
[all chuckling]
jacob: nobody in wheelerton
would've believed
that i was riding
with a legend.
hearty as buck,
a crack shot,
a walking encyclopedia
of indians and their
strange habits.
mr. smith was like
no man i ever knew,
and i would never be
the same.
old indian: the buffalo jumpers,
running fox and dog star,
had their eyes on two sisters,
but had to prove themselves
to a more dangerous opponent
than stampeding buffalo.
a small skinned rabbit
did not impress
the girls' protective father.
[speaking lakota]
[giggling]
old indian: two brothers
married two sisters
and walked the path
of old tradition.
[infant crying]
[chanting]
loved by the buffalo studied
the power of plants,
of roots, and herbs.
he learned how to cure
the body and the spirit
using songs and ceremonies.
[moaning]
[drum playing]
[coughing]
[groaning]
[drum stops]
old indian: but the holy man
did not know all the powers
the boy was given.
[groans]
[gagging]
loved by the buffalo discovered
he had the power
to take another's pain
upon himself.
he knew the power
was not his own,
but that of wakan tanka.
watch this.
see?
[speaking lakota]
now watch this.
see?
[speaking lakota]
pot.
old indian: thunder heart woman
would carry the medicine wheel
that growling bear
gave to her brother.
in it she would
keep her family
and her memories,
and that gave her comfort.
[whooping]
jacob: days passed into months
until i lost track of time
altogether.
riding with mr. smith,
i saw the grandeur
and majesty of the west
as few white men
had ever seen it.
mr. fletcher,
is that path passable?
fletcher: that path
ain't even jackassable.
[men laughing]
jacob: everywhere i looked
i saw treasures
of immeasurable beauty,
and i longed for my brothers
to share them.
[growling]
get back.
give me
some room.
shoot him!
aah!
[bear growling weakly]
praise the lord for providing
our supper tonight.
amen.
praise the lord.
put me down there, boys.
fetch my bag, mr. wheeler.
aah!
jacob: what do you need
from it, sir?
here we go.
put my scalp,
mr. wheeler.
yes, sir.
thread the needle...
sew it back on, son.
go ahead.
sir, i ain't never done
nothing like that before.
neither have i, son.
uh, perhaps
mr. fletcher could--
i gave you an order, boy.
thread that needle
and sew my scalp back on.
yes, sir.
isn't this
gonna hurt, sir?
i believe it will, son.
but i think it'll hurt
the person being sewed
more than the sewer.
[men chuckling]
mr. fletcher?
yeah?
fetch my bible,
please.
hold still, sir.
thank you kindly.
[whispering]
unh! oh, goodness.
i'm sorry it hurts you
so much, son.
that's right, darling.
stretch 'em nice,
you get a good price.
old indian:
loved by the buffalo
began to walk the path
of a holy man.
the way was
long and dangerous,
but for one who communes
with wakan tanka,
many things are possible.
[grunting]
in the medicine wheel,
loved by the buffalo
learned the mysterious
realities of life.
he saw the sun and moon
and seasons come and go
in a circle.
he saw that all true power
moved in a circle.
jacob: when we descended
from the high sierras,
we came across
a friendly tribe.
they called themselves mohave:
the people who live
along the river.
and they called us
beaver-eaters.
mr. smith purchased horses
to replace those
we consumed.
one blanket,
2 knives.
a gift.
[speaking mohave]
thank you.
maricopa.
mohave man: maricopa.
ohh!
maricopa...
is just dandy.
dandy.
dandy. maricopa.
[men laughing]
ha ha ha ha ha!
[giggling]
fletcher: women!
[indistinct chatter]
very dandy.
dandy.
man: maricopa.
want some maricopa?
ohh, you are a most
unusual young man.
afraid not, sir.
well, there they are
down there.
what are you
doing up here?
seems like there was
this tiny jedediah smith
standing on my shoulder,
telling me to come
up here with you.
i want to be like you, sir.
much obliged, son.
you do me
great honor.
ah, but you see, sir,
i'm just an ape
of jedediah smith.
i want to be like you.
i really want
to be like you,
but there's a part of me
that i feel inside--
i want to be back
down there with them.
what does that make me?
makes you
a human being.
just like
the rest of us.
are you tempted,
too, sir?
come over here.
sit down, boy.
jacob...
we're as human
as the least of 'em
down there,
but we're also
more than that.
"as a man thinketh,
so he is. "
what do you
think you are?
the lord fashioned us
a little above
the beast,
a little below
the angels,
but he gave us
the choice.
and it's great, son.
some of these men,
they come west,
they lose
their souls.
west is a place
on the map,
not a way to live.
don't forget that.
a man has to know
his own mind.
you might begin
your own journal.
lebeck,
whispering: crow.
[owl hooting]
[cocks gun]
[door creaking]
[arrow thwaps]
unh!
[arrow thwaps,
baby crying]
[thunder heart woman
screaming]
[baby screaming]
baby! baby!
[thunder heart woman
screaming]
[men chuckling]
buenas dias.
[speaking spanish]
he says that
we are his prisoners.
tell him that maybe
it escaped his notice
that he's outnumbered
3 to 1.
[speaking spanish]
he said he would arrest us
if there was 1,000 of us.
[speaking spanish]
dismount!
they're gonna take you
to the governor.
all right, fletcher,
you look after the men.
jacob: the captain took
mr. smith away...
"to make the governor's
acquaintance," he said.
under ordinary circumstances,
we might've welcomed
the hospitality of
the san gabriel padres,
but there was no mistaking
the fact that we were prisoners.
jacob: our time among the mohave
was to cost us both dearly.
the soldados wanted
to set an example.
it didn't matter to them
if the men they brought in
as horse thieves
were innocent or guilty.
indians were indians.
it was a powerful trial to watch
the sun set day after day
over the horizon
i had sacrificed
home and family to reach.
whether any of us would live
to see the wide ocean
that had been the object
of our expedition
now depended on mr. smith.
gentlemen.
mr. smith.
gentlemen, gather around.
i got some news for you.
where you been?
the governor has given us
most generous
but strict instructions.
we must depart as we came
and never return
on pain of death.
jacob: we were forced
to return east.
i looked back and made myself
a solemn promise
that one day i would see
california again.
old indian:
loved by the buffalo knew
that a vision
from wakan tanka
would direct
the course of his life.
[drums, chanting continue]
[men whooping]
old indian: white buffalo woman
brought us the sacred ceremonies
so that we could ask for help
in our troubles
and give thanks for the gifts
from wakan tanka.
she taught us the sun dance.
[chanting intensifies]
[blowing whistle]
[tweet]
jacob: once we drank maricopa
with the mohave
and shared their women.
but after we had left them,
a party of beaver-eaters
had attacked their village
and left it in flames.
now we were forced
to run for our lives.
aah!
[gunfire continues]
move. move, jake,
come on.
[mohave whooping]
there. get in.
hurry up.
you ok?
hey, you all right?
fletcher: stay low.
smith: fire!
bully for you, young man.
that should hold 'em off
for a while.
mr. fletcher.
yeah.
the smoke is drifting.
what does that mean?
it means there's
a way out of here.
[coughing]
i got a pang tellin' me
it's time to hang
up the fiddle.
listen, you two just
follow the smoke,
and i'll--i'll keep
our friends amused.
ok? jacob,
bring me my gun.
thank you.
[coughing]
whoa.
listen, jacob,
i want you to have that.
no use a mohave
getting it.
they won't appreciate it.
learn to use it, son.
things can get
pretty personal...
[strained] out west.
thank you, mr. fletcher.
jacob, light!
jim.
yeah.
you're a man of
unfailing rectitude.
remember me...
to all the boys
at the rendezvous.
now get gone.
get gone.
[whooping]
aah!
[gunshot]
[drums continue]
[screeches]
[tweet]
[bird screeches]
[chanting continues]
[tweet]
jacob: mr. smith,
i can't do this.
of course you can.
it vents.
[chanting, drums continue]
[blows whistle]
jacob: now i'm stuck.
now i'm stuck.
i can't do this!
i don't wanna die like this!
oh, god! no!
smith: jacob!
old indian: the dancer
stares into the sun,
sun-up to sundown,
moving with the sun,
dancing,
tugging at his tether,
pulling, twisting,
trying to tear the skewer
through his skin.
and when he sets himself free,
he is reborn to the world.
he lays on a bed of sage
and recites his vision
to the holy man.
jacob: if we never
found this cave,
it would be over.
unh!
but in here like this,
we'll die by inches
and nobody will ever
hear from us again
or know what happened.
the lord revealed the cave
as he sent a fish
to save jonah.
jonah was drowning.
i don't need a sermon
when i'm so afeard!
"the fear of the lord
is the beginning of wisdom."
and take hold my boot,
move with me!
the fish swallowed up jonah.
jonah did not know
it was god
who sent the fish
to save him.
[blows whistle]
and jonah cried out
to the lord
from the belly
of the beast,
"lord, i do not want
to die like this!"
now let us pray
jonah's prayer.
"i cried by reason of mine
affliction unto the lord,
"and he heard me.
out of the belly of hell
cried i and thou
heardest my voice."
now repeat after me,
jacob.
"but i will sacrifice
unto thee..."
jacob: "i will sacrifice
"with a song
of thanksgiving..."
thanksgiving!
"salvation
is of the lord."
unh! "salvation
[jacob laughing]
[chanting continues]
[both sighing]
old indian:
loved by the buffalo had seen
how a vision could
kill its seeker.
now he, too, had
a terrible revelation.
the sickness of the spotted face
came to the lakota.
some believed it came
from the white man.
some were not as certain.
when loved by the buffalo
fell ill,
soaring eagle
told the people
it was loved by the buffalo
that brought the pox to them.
he told them
to send the boy away,
and only then would
the sickness leave.
but deep inside
his dark thoughts,
he hoped the sickness
would take the boy.
old indian:
growling bear made a song
to fight the sickness.
he gave it to
loved by the buffalo
to cure his brother running fox
and any who believed.
mr. smith and i
had stared death in the face
and lived to tell the tale.
we'd said our good-byes
and gone our separate ways.
so i decided to attend
the rendezvous
that mr. fletcher
had spoken of
with such fondness.
rob any
chicken coops lately?
ben franklin.
jacob wheeler!
ain't this some pumpkins!
look at ya!
look at you!
where in the sam hill
you been?
i been all over.
ha ha! come here!
ha ha ha!
i remember.
i never forget that.
i been treed
by grizzly bears and
tracked by blackfeet,
but i never
was so scared
as when i heard
that farmer tell you
about a reward
for a runaway slave.
no, sir! ha ha!
i sat in that coop
waitin' for you
to give me up.
mm. sho' enough...
you never did.
i thought about that
every day since.
i wanted to give you
a hundred beaver pelts
as a token of my thanks.
man: come on, join us
over here for a drink!
whiskey's just fine.
mountain man: yeah!
we've got
a young lakota girl.
her name...
is thunder heart woman.
she cooks and...
she knows
the fur trade.
[laughter]
and...she speaks
good english!
[murmuring]
she's pleasant
and agreeable.
[laughter]
well, sometimes!
bidding starts at $100.
100!
johnny fox:
what we got here?
look here!
[slurp]
looks like love
at first sight
to me!
mountain man: i see
my old friend johnny fox
survived another year
in the sierra nevada!
all right, boys.
anyone else
in the biddin' here?
200.
johnny: who's the greenhorn?
300.
4.
what you doing?
ben, you better
talk to your friend.
what was you thinkin'?
johnny fox can whips
your weight in wildcats.
you tryin' to buy
a sister, peach fuzz?
you even know
what to do with her?
[laughter]
i'm gonna set her free
and send her back
to her people.
men: whoa!
sets her free? why?
you of all people
know why.
i thought different,
you'd be back on
that plantation.
you backin' down?
not for flapjacks
or french ladies.
then it's rifles
at 20 paces.
hah!
[excited chatter]
there you go!
look what you done
got yourself into now.
come on, little coward.
come on.
now, you keep
on the move,
even when reloading.
make yourself small.
get on it, lad.
you still stand
back-to-back
with unloaded rifles.
and after 10 paces,
well...anything goes.
[thunder heart woman
chants]
mountain man: 1...
2...
3, 4...
5, 6...
7, 8,
9, 10!
[men shouting]
[thunder heart woman chants]
now, jacob!
run!
come on, jacob.
now, jacob, now!
aah!
[cheering]
you want more?
got your ear!
get up!
shoot him, jacob!
to hell with him!
come on!
move, jacob!
time to go home,
little boy.
time to go back to mama!
[laughter, shouting]
hey, hey!
thunder heart woman!
get ready to feel
some of johnny fox's
lightning.
[laughter]
ha ha ha.
come on, johnny!
[shouting and jeering
subsides]
[johnny exhales]
ohh...
mountain man:
ha ha ha ha ha!
sold, boys!
[cheering]
we must...
take out metal.
who are you?
i'm jacob wheeler,
ma'am.
ha ha ha ha ha.
well, now...
by rights...
his stuff is yours.
is there enough there
to cover what i owe ya?
oh, yeah. and then some.
[ben chuckles]
what's so funny?
oh, a...
true southern gentlemen
seeing a lady
to her daddy's front door.
even if it is a thousand
miles across cheyenne,
crow, and blackfoot
country.
a great man
once told me
that the west
is just a place
on the map,
not a way to live.
benjamin.
you take care. ma'am.
[sniffs]
[sobs]
what's wrong?
i have...
a baby
somewhere on earth.
crow took her.
i pray she is not
yet on ghost path.
where spirits go.
jacob.
[grunts]
[louder]
jacob.
[laughs]
[shivering]
[both laugh]
[murmuring in lakota]
old indian:
loved by the buffalo
knew he had been given
the sign he'd asked for.
he no longer
questioned his sanity
and understood
that wakan tanka
was guiding him.
whoo!
ha ha ha ha!
[giggling] it's heyoka.
heyoka makes us
see wakan tanka,
makes us laugh.
jacob: arriving
in thunder heart
woman's village
was like stepping
into a dream.
[speaking lakota]
jacob: i had looked to find
my destiny in california.
but it was in this place
among these people
that my life
was to take a course
i'd never imagined.
[speaking lakota]
i could not understand
their words,
but i could see the love
for a long-lost daughter
and sister
and feel her relief
in their embrace.
jacob.
she told them
about her captivity,
the fight with johnny fox,
how i'd risked my life
to free her.
i thought i understood her
to say the spirits
had brought us together.
and i figured, well,
she must have been
right about that.
[speaking lakota]
my father offers
his possessions.
well, tell him i just
want to marry you.
sometimes...
2 people go to
wilderness
for 2 weeks,
and they return
as husband and wife.
we kinda already
did that. ha.
woo-ha, woo-ha, woo-ha!
[old man speaks lakota]
this is making
of relatives.
take small bite.
[speaking lakota]
this meat
i place in mouth.
from this day,
my home your home,
and you his son.
at first,
i didn't understand
the pain in my heart
for thunder heart woman.
then it hit me.
her family
was making me a relative
while i know full well
my folks would never
do the same for her.
they'd call her a savage,
a soulless heathen.
why do i feel so at home
here among these people?
[speaks lakota]
[coughs]
[says
lakota word]
[laughter, chatter]
grab the wheel.
it's heavy.
help me unwrap it.
[speaks lakota]
take the rope off...
then you go around,
just like that...
[thunder heart
woman laughs]
you can save
the rope.
when i saw
loved by the buffalo,
i could not escape
the strange sensation
that i knew him
and he knew me.
he saw my scar,
and i saw his,
and i imagined
the force of the beast
that thrust its head
in his chest.
old indian: in the wheel,
loved by the buffalo
saw the threat,
the danger
coming from the people
of the wooden wheel,
but he could not say why.
he began to understand
what growling bear meant,
the webs made by spiders
to catch flies.
something would entangle
the lakota
in a time yet to come.
[loved by buffalo
speaks lakota]
you trick the iron
to subdue the wood.
your magic wrongs
wakan tanka.
[speaking lakota]
does your god
give you the wheel
of wood and iron?
no, no. just
the intelligence
to make it.
he will show you a wheel
made by wakan tanka.
great spirit
gives one gift
at birth.
[speaks
lakota]
we are born somewhere
on the medicine wheel.
we are born with
one of the great powers.
[lakota word]
wisdom...
strength...
[lakota word]
big heart...
braveness.
jacob: loved by the buffalo
left me wondering
what i was born with...
and what i had yet
to acquire on the wheel.
i would spend
most of my life
looking for the answer.
old indian: the time
had come to move the camp.
the grandparents
of thunder heart woman
chose to remain behind
to make their final journey
together.
why? why can't she
come with us?
she will not leave
her husband.
[speaks lakota]
we must respect
their wishes.
[whooping]
[chanting]
for the first time,
i stood in awe of
everything that god made.
i couldn't look at a tree
anymore
and see so many
board feet of timber...
couldn't look
at a beaver lodge
and see so many pelts.
now i saw little miracles.
we have a wheel
that takes you
from here to there.
but they have a wheel
that takes you to the stars.
old indian: soaring eagle
knew he had lost his place.
for the first time
in his life,
he knew the true meaning
of fear.
and loved by the buffalo
left his family
so that he might live
for all the people.
this was the price
of his gift--
to pursue his journey
to change the terrible vision
of growling bear.