Narrator: From the
ashes of the Civil War,
a new breed of American emerges...
determined to grab a piece
of the nation's untamed frontier.
Life was tough certainly
after the Civil War.
And you had this vast
continent that was unexplored.
And I think that fostered a
big migration to the West.
(horse whinnies)
Narrator: Over the course of 30 years,
more than 430 million acres of land
will be settled.
But as the US
government pushes the nation west,
former Confederates
hell-bent on taking back
what they lost become outlaws...
We intend to rob this here bank.
- Who's the cashier?
- (gunshot)
(horse whinnies)
Narrator: ...threatening
to reignite the Civil War.
In that day, you had to be
somewhat of a bad guy to survive.
- (grunts)
- (gunshot)
They were all tough and
nobody lived very long.
Narrator: On the plains, war breaks out
as tribes of warriors band together
to protect their way of life.
We deploy Custer and
1,200 men to track down
whatever remains of Crazy
Horse and Sitting Bull's war party.
If necessary, wipe them out.
Narrator: This is the story
of an age of violence like no other,
a time when blood is
shed and battles fought
by ordinary men who become legends...
as they fight to
determine the fate of the country.
Kiefer Sutherland: The
West shaped this country in ways
that people either don't
acknowledge or have taken for granted
or have simply forgotten.
The West was true freedom.
It was such a defining characteristic
of America.
Narrator: This is "The American West."
(gunshots)
You go to hell.
- You first.
- (gunshot)
(theme music playing)
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Narrator: The story of
the West begins at the end
of the Civil War...
where a young man named Jesse James
is a soldier in a fringe military group
known as Quantrill's Raiders.
Mark Lee Gardner: Quantrill's
Raiders were guerilla fighters
fighting for the South.
They didn't necessarily
fight in traditional ways,
and the way they fought could often
be very savage, very violent,
and their targets could be civilians
as well as military.
(horses whinny)
(gunshot)
(horses approaching)
We got to go! We got to go!
(gunshot)
- (men shouting)
- (gunshots)
There they go! Come on!
(gunshots)
(grunts)
(gunshots continue)
Get him!
- (gunshot)
- (screams)
- Can you run?
- No. (groans)
(gunshot)
(groaning)
Narrator: In the spring of 1865,
Jesse James is shot and captured
by the Union Army.
- (squishing)
- (groaning)
(labored breathing)
Now, say it.
I solemnly swear...
That I will bear the true allegiance
of the United States.
Say it.
(screams)
I will bear true
allegiance to the United States.
And discourage...
Narrator: Jesse James is forced
to pledge allegiance
to the Union.
Before he's released, the
Confederacy surrenders
and after four years of bloody fighting,
the Civil War comes to an end.
After surviving a near fatal wound,
Jesse James returns home to Missouri
only to find death and
destruction all around.
After the Civil War, the
South was hellacious.
It had been ruined.
And there was a great deal of resentment
of northern
authority, of federal authority.
There were a lot of people
who were mentally unbalanced
by that war, by the brutality of it.
Narrator: In the
border state of Missouri,
the fighting has been especially brutal.
David Eisenbach: Missouri
is one of the states
that stuck with the
Union during the Civil War,
but had large sectors of the population
that wanted to go with the
South in the first place.
So you had
Missourians fighting Missourians.
It's in this incredibly volatile,
literally brother against brother world
that we get Jesse James.
Narrator: Jesse soon
discovers that the war
has not only torn apart his homeland,
it's left his family with nothing.
You look good, Frank.
You look like shit.
(laughs)
I bet you gave them Union boys
hell, though, didn't you?
It's just real nice to be home.
Mom, I promise you,
we're gonna get back on our feet.
Me and Frank will figure out something.
Gardner: Jesse and his brother Frank
grew up in rural Missouri.
Their father had gone
off to the gold fields
during the Gold Rush and had died there.
Jesse's mother, Zerelda
James, was a single parent,
and I think that
created a very, very strong bond
between her and her children.
Narrator: Still reeling
from his time in battle,
Jesse knows he has to find a
way to provide for his family.
So he comes up with a plan.
He forms a gang...
and begins stealing.
Sutherland: When you think of
Jesse James and those families,
they have been stripped
of everything, they felt,
after the Civil War and
they were gonna come
and take what they
thought was owed to them.
- Jesse: Come here, come here.
- Let's go.
Here, take this.
Go, go, go!
Narrator: But the Union
Army quickly cracks down.
(men shouting)
Jesse.
Cover that up.
How you doing?
What's in the crates?
Food,
various sundries.
Got some sweet corn.
- You boys hungry?
- Want some water.
- We don't take orders from northern...
- Jesse: Frank!
We got water.
Fresh out of the creek.
Tastes like shit.
(pours water)
Yeah, well, I guess we're used to it.
Search the house. Take it all.
Soldier: Yes, sir.
Narrator: Fed up
with the North's presence,
Jesse James is determined to fight back.
(grunts)
Eric Foner: Jesse James
could not adjust to peacetime.
He was strongly opposed to
what was going on in the South
and in fact viewed the army after the
end of the war as being oppressive.
Narrator: As attacks
from Confederates like Jesse
escalate around the South,
news travels over 1,000
miles to the east
to the nation's capital.
These just came in.
You're dismissed.
Narrator: The man who has
to deal with the growing unrest
in the South is the same man
who recently claimed
victory over the Confederacy...
commanding general of the US Army
Ulysses S. Grant.
(men shouting)
Narrator: When the Civil War began,
Grant was considered
by many to be a failure,
a drunk with no future in the military.
But after a series of Union generals
were unable to secure
victory for the North,
Abraham Lincoln promoted
Grant to lead the US Army,
and he rose to the task.
John McCain: General Grant is
one of the true military geniuses.
He saw the objective and he
knew what needed to be done.
Narrator: With tensions
rising in the former Confederacy,
Grant is forced to deal with
the South once again.
H.W. Brands: When Grant
took control of the army,
he had to deal with
leftover matters from the Civil War.
Grant understood that
there was a feeling in the South
that this defeat was
something that still might be resisted.
And Grant had to attend to that.
Narrator: Grant knows he can't
let rebels like Jesse James
reignite the war.
So he sends more US
troops south to maintain order
and institutes strict martial law.
Just over a year since the
end of the Civil War,
it's North versus South again.
Narrator: With former
Confederate soldiers like Jesse James
lashing out against
northern authority in the South...
(gunshot)
General Ulysses S.
Grant sends armed troops
to enforce order.
Brands: During the
immediate aftermath of the Civil War,
military government martial
law was imposed
and Union soldiers were in occupation
of much of the South.
Southerners generally resisted this.
It was, from their
perspective, a continuation of the Civil War
in which northerners imposed their will,
imposed their ways on the South.
Narrator: But the
increased military presence
only makes things worse.
Jesse James and other
ex-Confederates like him
begin rioting.
(men shouting)
Narrator: With the Civil War
on the verge of starting up again,
Grant knows a new strategy is
needed to heal the nation.
So he and the US government
look to a plan laid out by
the man who led the country
during the Civil War... Abraham Lincoln.
Lincoln knew that the
key to healing the country
would be to give all
Americans the promise
of a new start in the West.
Redford: The value of
going into uncharted territory,
there's a chance for
enterprise and development
and a chance for
people to grow and to succeed
in ways they couldn't in
the overdeveloped East.
And also, I think, just the excitement
and the challenge of
uncharted territory...
that's a little bit of the American way.
Narrator: From the Missouri River
to the coast of California,
the frontier is nearly
500 million square miles
of wide-open land.
Danny Glover: You have
the Pacific Ocean on one end,
and you have the Atlantic
Ocean on the other end,
and all the vast land in between that.
It's the whole idea of
looking for opportunity,
looking for another life.
Narrator: The challenge is figuring out
how to get people to the
West as quickly as possible.
And Grant knows the answer.
The same way he was able to
rapidly move Union troops
during the Civil War.
Man: Whoa, hold up on that sleeper.
Get to work.
Narrator: The railroads.
Man: Hold up on that...
Narrator: To promote construction,
the government makes
the railroad companies
an unprecedented offer...
millions of acres of free land.
For every mile of track that
a railroad would build,
Congress would
provide the company with land
on either side of the track.
The land grants that Congress provides
really is the
sweetheart deal of the century.
Narrator: 175 million acres
are given to the railroad companies...
more land than the
entire state of Texas.
The railroads then take the
land they got for free
and sell it to the settlers...
using a massive advertising campaign
that promotes the West as
an uninhabited paradise.
(train whistle blows)
People were lured by this fantastic
sense of opportunity.
You can be a poor
immigrant and all of a sudden
there's an opportunity that you can
get 50 acres and start a life.
That's like winning the
lottery back then.
I mean, it was amazing.
Narrator: But as Americans
begin to head west by the thousands...
they're pushing into
land that's already occupied
by a people determined to defend it.
Narrator: As railroads expand west,
hopeful new settlers push into territory
that's been occupied for
thousands of years.
At the end of the last Ice Age,
nomadic hunters migrated
into the Americas
across a land bridge that
once connected Siberia to Alaska.
By 1865,
300,000 Native
Americans are living in the West.
The most numerous and
powerful people on the plains
are the Lakota Sioux.
But now their
homelands are being invaded.
For the Lakota people, 1865
is a major turning point.
With the railroads coming west,
there is literally and figuratively
a freight train coming right at them.
Narrator: Standing in the
path of the invasion
is a fearless young warrior.
His name is Crazy Horse.
Andrew Isenberg: Crazy Horse
was a very talented military leader
who was the chief lieutenant
of the Sioux in the
northern Great Plains.
Narrator: The land
is sacred to the Lakota
and Crazy Horse feels it's
his duty to defend it.
Redford: Native Americans,
when they saw the railroad,
they knew that there was now a vehicle
to invade them with and
it was protected by steel.
And it was fast.
Narrator: In 1866, Crazy
Horse takes part
in a bloody campaign
throughout the Wyoming territory.
Sioux in the northern Great Plains
are fighting against the
settlers who are moving into that area.
And they're winning.
Narrator: In the span of six months,
dozens of settlers are killed
and movement through the
territory is restricted.
News of the violence
makes its way to Washington, DC...
(tapping)
where it's received by the
man overseeing troops in the West,
famed Civil War general
William Tecumseh Sherman.
I just received word from
the Dakota territories.
Another six men have
been killed in a raid.
Narrator: General Grant knows
he can't let chaos on the frontier
threaten the government's
plan of unifying the country,
so he orders Sherman
to use military force.
(horse whinnies)
Narrator: In late 1866,
nearly 1,000 soldiers pour
into Sioux territory.
Crazy Horse knows it's up to him
to defend his land and his people
against an enemy with
superior firepower.
But he's confident he'll prevail,
thanks to a powerful
vision he had in his youth.
Karl Jacoby: Crazy Horse,
as a young man, had a vision.
(thunder rumbles)
(cawing)
And in this vision he sees
that whenever he's in battle,
he's very safe from the enemy and
the enemy can never hurt him.
And in essence he could be protected
from anything that the
enemy might do to him.
Narrator: Emboldened by his vision,
Crazy Horse sets in
motion a daring plan.
Jacoby: Several Lakota are
set to decoy the US Army,
and one of these people is Crazy Horse.
It's obviously a very
risky position to be in
because you're putting
yourself very close to the US Army.
Narrator: Crazy Horse lures the soldiers
away from the protection of their forts
into an open territory.
(man shouting)
Narrator: Once he has them in position,
Crazy Horse begins his assault.
Man: Ready!
Narrator: He charges alone...
Man: Aim!
Narrator: directly
into their line of fire.
Man: Fire at will!
(gunshots)
Narrator: It's a tactic
known as riding the brave line.
And it exposes the
soldiers' greatest weakness.
Man #2: Reload!
(whooping)
(all whooping)
(soldiers grunting, screaming)
(whooping)
Narrator: On December 21, 1866,
Crazy Horse claims one of
his greatest victories...
killing nearly 100 US soldiers...
in what becomes known
as the Battle of a Hundred Slain.
Now, in addition to trying to
contain the southern rebellion,
Grant must deal with an Indian war
that's beginning to rage out West,
threatening the future of the nation.
Narrator: After Crazy Horse and his men
kill nearly 100 US
soldiers in a single battle,
news travels back to Washington.
Incompetence.
These savages, they don't
fight the way we do.
Narrator: Commanding general
Ulysses S. Grant
is not only facing uprisings
in the South,
but a new war in the West.
Grant realizes the only
way to defeat the Indians
is to send his best
commander from the Civil War...
a man stationed 2,000
miles away in Texas
who's famous for both his victories
and his unconventional commanding style.
His name is George Armstrong Custer.
Anne Collier: George
Armstrong Custer was very flamboyant.
He had flowing blond hair.
Some say he curled it himself.
He wore a signature
costume, if you will,
that he called a uniform.
He had a red handkerchief, shiny boots,
and a broad-rimmed hat.
And he just showed
himself to be superior to others.
Where did you acquire that insignia
on your uniform, soldier?
West Point, sir. Fourth in my class.
Fourth in your class?
Gentlemen, we have a
celebrity in our midst.
Do you know what position I graduated?
Last.
And yet here I stand commanding you.
Why is there a button
missing from your coat?
You're a disgrace
to that insignia.
You are a disgrace to my unit.
And you are a disgrace to
every man who ever wore that uniform.
One month laundry duty.
Make it the end of the year.
Narrator: Though Custer is not
the army's most beloved leader,
he is respected for the killer instincts
he showed during the Civil War.
(cannonball whistling)
Cover their left flank!
Narrator: It was his daring charge
that contributed to
Robert E. Lee's surrender.
Lieutenant, why are you falling back?
You breach their
front lines and you push.
Burt Reynolds: A lot
of people laughed at him,
but not in battle.
He was a hell of a soldier.
Tremendous courage.
The thing that
scared people half to death
was being assigned to him
'cause you were gonna be in
the middle of everything.
(men shouting)
Narrator: But since the Civil War ended,
Custer has been relegated
to overseeing border patrol
at a remote post.
Custer was sent into exile.
He brooded over this, of course.
And he knew that he
needed to get back into action.
Sir.
Narrator: Grant gives
him the opportunity
he's been waiting for.
Hutton: Custer got
command of the 7th Cavalry,
which was going to
be the crack elite unit
for Indian fighting in the West.
Narrator: George
Custer finally has his chance
to step back into the limelight.
And it's an assignment that
will change the course
of American history.
(crickets chirping)
Narrator: In the years
following the Civil War,
former Confederate soldier Jesse James
has been leading an
uprising in Missouri.
Jesse: All right, boys, I'll
tell you what's going to happen.
Me, Charlie, and Frank will head inside.
Get around that counter, easy money.
Narrator: Until now,
Jesse's crimes have been small.
But as the North's postwar domination
of the South continues...
Jesse is starting to think bigger.
He decides that the best way to
express his hatred for the North
is to go after their wealth.
In the first 80 years
of America's existence,
there was not a
single armed bank robbery.
So at the time, banks
have minimal security.
And even in the South,
they hold mostly northern money.
Rob a bank and you're stealing
northern wealth.
Sutherland: Jesse
James wanted the money,
but he had a real
statement he was trying to make
that was as much political as
it was about robbing banks.
(people chatting)
Go.
- Everything in your vault.
- (people screaming)
Open the vault.
- Move.
- (gasps)
- Open the vault.
- Jesse: Hold on, hold on.
In the corner now.
I know you.
Where'd you fight?
- I didn't.
- You did.
You fought for the Union, didn't you?
No.
Let's open the vault, be on our way.
- You fought at Richmond.
- No, I didn't.
- Don't you shake your head at me.
- Jesse.
You're the man who shot Bill Anderson.
Gardner: The Civil War made Jesse James.
He killed men, he saw men killed.
Seeing death every day
changes the way you look at life.
Jesse mistook the teller
for the murderer of his
leader during the Civil War.
I found you, you son of a bitch.
(shouts)
We still need him to open the vault.
Bill Anderson was my friend.
(gunshot)
God damn it, Jesse. On the floor!
Frank: Come on, Jesse, we got to go.
Come on, now! Come on.
Gardner: That revolver shot
is somewhat of a release.
When Jesse fires that gun,
there's a welled-up bitterness
that's been boiling for years.
He still has the memories he witnessed
personally during the war.
Lots of his friends have been killed.
Jesse refused to forget.
A lot of his makeup was revenge.
Come on, Jesse. We got to go.
Jesse, come on. Come on, now.
Get, boys, get.
(clicks tongue) Come on.
Come on.
(hammer clicks, gunshot)
Narrator: Jesse
James has just pulled off
one of the first bank
robberies in America,
leaving one man dead and
earning the ex-Confederate
his first victory against the North.
A lot of the guys who became outlaws,
Jesse James and so forth, they were
all part of the Confederate Army.
And when the Union won that war,
robbing banks was their way
of continuing the
fight of the Confederacy.
Narrator: The crime makes
headlines across the state,
turning Jesse into a wanted criminal.
All right, it's on you, Frank.
There it is. (laughs)
It's a good day to be
Frank James, you know.
Sutherland: Jesse James certainly
had a very specific idea.
He was going to take
the money that he felt
was taken from him during the Civil War.
The press got wind of that.
And once they started reading
their own stuff,
they were, "Yeah, I'm
right. You know, I was questioning
whether or not I should have robbed
that bank, but now I know I'm right."
(laughs)
Narrator: With his reputation growing,
Jesse James is fanning the
flames of rebellion in the South.
Over 400 miles away,
the US government is
dealing with an even greater problem
than southern uprisings...
as Indian attacks by
warriors like Crazy Horse
are slowing down western progress.
But General Ulysses S.
Grant has an answer...
Civil War hero George Armstrong Custer.
Grant was quite happy with
the performance of Custer.
Custer was one of the great
heroes during the Civil War.
He was also willing to
do whatever was necessary
to deal with the Indian issue right now.
Narrator: For
Custer, it's the opportunity
he's been waiting for to
step back into the spotlight.
For months, Custer has
been hunting bands of Indians
across the southern plains...
Halt!
But hasn't been able to track them down.
Gardner: I think Custer
had the same ambitions
that any long-term military
officer had.
That was to advance in rank.
Advance in rank and to
win laurels, win glory.
That was hard to do in
the post-Civil War West.
I mean, you weren't
meeting a foe that was lined up
with 10,000 men on the field of battle.
You were meeting a very elusive foe.
So I think Custer was frustrated often
with what he wanted to do,
and I think he wanted glory.
Narrator: Finally,
Custer catches a break.
His regiment discovers a
band of Cheyenne Indians
camped near the Washita River
suspected of
attacking settlers and troops.
Get the men ready.
Half an hour.
I want to hit them with
everything we've got.
You have your orders.
Yes, sir.
Narrator: Desperate for
another chance at greatness,
Custer prepares a surprise attack.
Jacoby: Custer is quite
consciously, I think, very aggressive
in his war against Indians
because he's really
trying to reclaim the glory
that he experienced during the Civil War
when he was this American hero.
Narrator: It's only been three
years since the Civil War ended.
But now with Custer
riding into a battle for glory...
and Jesse James inciting
a rebellion in the South...
America is on the brink of
fighting a two-front war.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --