Previously on Continuum...
I'm not sure that you've got
what it takes.
I'm a really hard worker
with some fresh ideas,
I won't let you down.
Why all of this?
Leaving home so suddenly,
giving up your work?
I have to make my own way
for myself.
It's not for you, or Roland
or anyone.
I wanna protect my future.
Here are the new companies
I want you to invest in.
I'm looking for situations
that are win-win.
What can I do for you
agent Gardiner?
- Kiera Cameron.
- Agent Cameron is with Section 6.
I saw you...
I saw you survive
the explosion and fireball
and then vanish.
You can't do this,
not to me!
If you can't be with
the person you chose to...
[Grunting]
I spent the last couple of weeks
in a prison hospital recovering.
- Recovering from what?
- Sonya.
I think the term
"fighting machine"
has become something
of a cliché
in the development of
the enhanced soldier,
but what we've
accomplished here
is nothing short
of extraordinary.
Very impressive.
I speak for the entire corporation,
job well done.
However we've had to make
our funding decision
based on factors beyond
performance metrics.
It's too damn expensive.
We're cutting our losses,
the program's being terminated
effective immediately.
What does that mean?
What happens to these
soldiers?
Well we can't leave
anything operational
once we've shut down,
way too risky.
Terminate means terminate.
I've got two CPS officers
in the lobby
I just need to call them.
That won't be necessary.
I can take care of it.
Very good.
Everything okay, doc?
How's the CMR adjustment?
Quite the upgrade.
Civilian version is already
in the works.
I don't need any tech to tell me
you're upset about something.
You would be right.
Well maybe I can ease
your mind over dinner later?
It's gonna be difficult
for me.
I understand.
Well, maybe when
the project's finished...
What I mean is I hope when...
I hope when the program
is over,
that we're not also.
What's that?
You okay?
2077, my time, my city,
my family.
When terrorists killed thousands
of innocents,
they were condemned to die.
They had other plans.
A time travel device sent us
all back 65 years.
I want to get home.
But I can't be sure what I'll
return to if history is changed.
Their plan to corrupt
and control the present
in order to win the future.
What they didn't plan on
was me!
S02 Ep02
- Split Second -
Sync and corrected by dr. jackson
for www.addic7ed.com
You shot him...
didn't you?
You shot Travis.
What if Garza sees this?
I would certainly appreciate
your discretion.
You have it...
but now what?
She wants to bust
Travis out.
Let me worry about that.
- Alec...
- What?
Now's not the time okay,
I'm gonna be late.
What are you doing here
anyways?
I just wanted to see
where you work,
- I was in the neighbourhood...
- You're checking up on me.
Look, you don't have to
worry about me, okay?
I'm fine.
All right.
You don't have to do this.
What, the job? Actually I do.
I mean, I'm broke and frankly I
need to look at all my options.
Well good, that...
that's why I'm here,
to talk about your options.
Go on.
I know you don't have
all the answers
you're looking for right now.
But if you don't follow
the path of destiny
that shapes the future
as I know it,
the world won't end up
as it did in my time.
Is that necessarily
a bad thing?
I wanna go home.
I wanna get back to my family
and the only way I'm
gonna be able to do that
is if things stay on track.
Kiera... when you tried
to stop that bombing,
did you know that you were
possibly throwing away a chance
of getting home?
- I didn't have a choice!
- Yes, you did.
Choose to let hundreds of
innocent people die?
Don't be so naïve!
These decisions are going to
keep coming up.
At a certain point you're
gonna have to choose
between protecting the future
for your unborn family
or protecting the future for
yourself and those of us
who are alive now.
I gotta go okay,
I'm gonna be late.
I'll call you later.
Sorry.
Lois, you wanted to see me?
Operations tells me
you're still working the
mayor's assassination,
I thought we were
done with that.
Yeah, the police got
their guy.
So what's left to talk about?
Kiera Cameron.
I know that you asked
me to stay away...
She's vouched for.
Escher, remember?
The CEO of a corporation
giving orders
to our intelligence services?
That just doesn't add up.
My superior vouches for him,
for all we know
Pyron is Section 6.
Cameron is a cipher.
This Section 6,
a federal security branch,
doesn't really seem to exist.
Yeah, it is a puzzle
by any measure.
What's your gut telling you?
Cameron is connected to the
Liber8 organization somehow,
I'm sure of it.
She may be the key to stopping
them before the next attack.
You're not gonna let
this go, are you?
No.
Okay, I'll make
some arrangements,
put you in the crosshairs.
Liber8, Section 6, the bombing,
assassination...
Kiera Cameron.
You keep it under wraps
for now, no paper trail.
Of course.
Thank you.
And Gardiner...
don't embarrass me
or this office.
Sonya seems to be taking
her sweet time.
With what?
Busting Travis out.
I'm with you.
I just don't think
she's telling us everything.
Look, we both know that Sonya
would never let anything
happen to Travis.
She's just... following
Kagame's orders.
You know what?
Kagame's dead!
Yes... Kagame is dead
but he lives on in us.
And if he were here,
he's say leave no
comrade behind.
He would, but he'd also say
think before you act.
So when do we stop thinking
and start acting?
I've already initiated
a plan.
You won't need to lift
a finger.
Look, I know who you are,
I'm not interested, okay.
You know who I am?
The whole world knows
who you are.
A terrorist?
That's gonna change.
The truth about what was
going on in that building
you and Kagame brought down,
it's already filtering out.
The truth?
Some are calling you a hero
for killing those bastards.
I didn't kill anybody.
The White Guard,
Bulgakov.
Ukrainian nationalists
dying for their beloved Kiev.
- Sound familiar?
- It's just a book.
Okay?
We could protect you.
I already have protection.
Your movement is growing,
my soldiers there are prepared
to offer guardianship
until the day we can
all leave here together
to face the same enemy.
We can mobilize hundreds
more behind you,
it could get pretty messy
in here, Mr. Randol.
I think you're right
about that.
Stay away.
That wasn't necessary.
Just because you got your
own little fan club in here
doesn't mean you're safe.
Stay close to me until
I get us out of here.
- When's that gonna be?
- Soon.
I've already made contact.
Yeah, it better be soon.
I go on trial in a few weeks,
I think we know how
that'll turn out.
No, there won't be
any trial.
You have a destiny
to fulfill.
My destiny is dead.
They'll have to find
another way.
No, this is how it's supposed
to play out.
Was I not clear?
Time you went to school,
boy.
[Fighting noises]
[buzzing sounds]
Hey coach, you want
to see us?
Thanks guys.
Our friend Travis Berta
killed 6 members
of the Arian Nation
in prison today.
Worse things could happen.
I don't disagree but
it's still a problem.
Warden wants him transferred
out immediately
before a full-scale
riot erupts.
It's probably a good idea.
The further we keep Travis and
Julian Randol from each other, the better.
We still need to take every
precaution during the transfer.
Travis is unpredictable and far
more dangerous than you realize.
Are you offering your
services, agent Cameron?
I am.
Well I expected as much.
Ah, excellent timing.
Agent Gardiner has
been reassigned
to the Liber8 task-force
as our official liaison.
Regardless of the hiccups
that our joint operations
have experienced as of late,
we're ready to provide
any support that we can.
Well, thank you for that.
I'm sure all of us can agree
that we could always use
another ally in the war
against terrorism.
Now, Travis Berta is
a high value member
so I expect Liber8 to make
a move of some kind.
Now with all due respect, I'm
not sure that agent Cameron's
considered all the
variables in this case.
I don't know, maybe
she has and she's uh...
counting on them.
I'd be surprised if you could
find someone who understands
them better, agent Gardiner...
and I have a plan that will
keep any of your concerns
at a minimum.
You stay out of my way and
we all get what we want.
I look forward to that.
Excuse me...
No love lost, huh?
That guy needs a serious
attitude adjustment.
Easy, that is a shortcut
to an early retirement.
He's gonna be looking for
anything to call you out on.
Oh, I'm sure of it.
You're setting yourself up for
trouble if it goes sideways.
I know.
Hey, how about we hear
about this plan?
It's uh... it's gonna play out
something like this.
Sadler... do you have any idea
why all of the network
passwords aren't working?
Oh yeah, sorry... I forgot to
tell you about that.
I had to flash the
router with an open WRT
in order to put up
a new firewall.
Why did you do that?
Well, um... actually
you'll be happy to know
that I recalibrated the network
so that 46 percent
of the customers
can now use the automated
checkout system.
That'll save on labour
costs by 15 percent
and decrease
customer wait times
by a minute and 30
seconds on average.
Is that right?
Yeah, and you don't have
to do sales reports anymore,
it's all automated now.
- No sales reports?
- Nope, poof, gone!
Straight to head office.
In fact, the efficiency
of the system as a whole
has nearly tripled, it's
256 percent to be exact.
Okay... Sadler, here's what's
gonna happen.
First, you're gonna get me
a coffee.
Then you're gonna undo
all this mumbo jumbo,
none of this was even approved
by head office.
This'll save the
company money...
Look, I know what it's like
to be young and ambitious
and think you have the
answers to everything,
but you can't go messing with
the system just because
you think you have a better
way of doing things.
But I'm telling you...
No look, I'm telling
you to reset the network
to the way that it was and do
the job that I hired you to do.
I can un-hire you just
as easily.
Oh, and that coffee?
Make it black.
[Sighs]
Incredible.
What do you want?
You know who I am?
Right... well believe it
or not I know a little bit
about who you are as well.
Maybe even more than
you know about yourself.
Look, if Kiera sent you here
to talk me into whatever...
Kiera didn't send me.
You know I had a job like
this once, way back...
or is that way forward?
Mopping floors
and cleaning toilets.
Good, honest work my
father called it.
I hated that job but I guess
it did teach me something.
And what's that?
Well first off, money
and power doesn't mean
your shit doesn't stink.
More importantly,
the only thing separating me and
the future I wanted was will.
I had the talent
and the ambition,
all I needed was a chance.
The problem is, of course,
you're rarely given that chance,
more often than not
you've gotta take it.
So one day, on my
knees cleaning up
where some idiot had missed
with his piss, I did.
Then what did you do?
I quit.
I scratched and clawed
and willed myself
into my own business.
I put all that hard work
into Kellog Incorporated.
And here you are today...
you've come a long way.
That's one way to put it.
Look, what does any of this
have to do with me?
Oh, I don't know...
let's just say that
both of our futures
rely on your own will.
All you have to do is
look down and realize
that you're on your knees too.
The only difference is
you're a genius.
Anyway... listen, I'm uh...
I'm looking to set up
a new venture,
cutting edge stuff.
Also looking for
talented visionaries
to do visionary work.
You know, mold the future,
all that jazz.
Hey, money is no object.
Uh... are you being taken care
of, sir?
Why yes, thank you.
Alec here is taking
very good care of me,
he knows his stuff!
You know something, I'd
be careful if I were you.
'Cause someone might just uh,
just come along
and poach him away.
Wonderful.
Uh... have a good day, sir.
Alec, when you're done
with this customer
can you drop by my office?
My printer's jammed.
Printer jams, how novel.
You know there's no paper
in the future?
Or should I say no future
in paper.
Drop by for a chat unless
you've made up your mind.
Incredible.
[Clears throat]
Um... I just got word
from our prison connection.
They're dead, all of them.
- It's not a problem.
- How can you even say that?
- If Garza finds out who's behind this...
- Listen,
Do you honestly think any
of those Neanderthals
ever stood a chance
against Travis?
You planned this?
Killing Travis would
be a nice solution,
but we don't need him dead
so much as we need
him out of the way
and as far away from
Thaseus as possible.
I should've known you were
behind this circus.
I'll take that as a compliment.
You would.
Listen Travis.
I'll cut you a deal...
You tell me where I can
find Sonya and the others
and I'll put you out of
your misery quickly,
save you the trouble of
the long incarceration.
And miss all the fun?
It seems like you two
are getting along.
Seeing her makes me homesick.
Your new home's a four by
four cell, Travis.
No fear, this one.
Tell me something
I don't know.
Why don't you take shotgun, I'll
sit back here with Mr. Happy.
You look good in orange.
Hey Simon.
Think about behaving yourself
so I don't have to come over
there and keep you in line, huh?
- Please do.
- Oh that can be arranged.
Ready?
Let's get this show
on the road.
Convoy's pulling out.
Nothing like a nice drive
through the countryside.
The day is young.
I guess being a pessimist is part
of your job description, huh?
Well, I'm rarely disappointed
so that's a bonus.
It's not too late for you,
protector.
Join the fight, make this world
a better place.
What do you think
I'm doing?
I think you're fighting
for the wrong side,
you just don't know it yet.
Doesn't it ever bother you?
Oh yeah, it's starting
to bother me now.
I'm talking about the
inequality in the system.
Bankers and corporate
CEOs raking in fortunes
while the rest of us
fight just to survive
and take care of
the ones we love.
I guess I'm just used to it.
That's your problem
right there.
You're the reason these thieves
get away with it,
they need your complacency,
your unwillingness to fight,
to challenge the rules,
to tear down walls...
Blow up a building?
If that's what it
takes to prevent us
from becoming slaves, yes.
It's like I said,
no strings attached.
You're the brains,
I'm the money.
The lab?
It's yours to run,
hire some help if you like.
I don't need any help.
Even better.
Kiera will probably
appreciate the privacy.
Look, this has nothing
to do with her.
Okay.
Understood.
Look, I've seen what
you can do alone
so I really don't think we'll
have much of a problem.
Please... can I offer
you a coffee,
tea, soda, beer?
Soda please.
You seem pretty sure this
is a sound investment.
Yeah, an investment when you
know the payoff is not a risk,
it's a sure thing.
There are no sure things.
Well then I'm happy with
getting as close as I can.
Where are we?
It's all routine.
They'll come for me.
You know how all this
plays out, Cameron.
She hasn't told you,
has she?
[Laughing]
How does she do it?
It must suck to be you,
always two steps behind her,
almost like she can see things
before they happen.
Hey, can I ask you something
that might sound
a little bit weird?
I'm a time traveler, kid...
weird is my specialty.
What am I like in 2077,
like old me...
what's my deal?
Straight to the point,
I like that.
What did Kiera tell you?
Nothing.
Here's the deal, kid.
In 2077, you are
in today's terms...
Zuckerberg, Jobs, Buffett
and Gates all rolled into one.
Rich...
No, no, no... beyond rich,
epic wealth.
No, you don't understand, what am
I like as a person?
Uh... as a person?
Who gives a shit!
You're loaded, powerful,
like a... like a king.
I just really need to know, am I
a good person or am I a bad person?
Well it's not like we hung
out, you know.
Okay, I guess it depends
on your point of view.
Personally, I admire someone
who could work the system,
influence the masses,
execute a vision.
It's not for everyone but...
where are you going with this?
What if you're here
for a reason,
what if you coming back in time
wasn't an accident?
- You're talking about fate.
- No, I'm talking about design.
I'm talking about me.
Yeah, I put some of
the pieces together.
That we were sent back
by you.
So why did I send you back
here to help me?
Well that's obvious, to...
to change the future.
Your destiny is not to become
Santech CEO Alec Sadler,
it's bigger.
How do I know I can
trust you?
Well, I have been accused
of many things...
You know what, I'd better
get back to work.
Hey, kid...
Alec...
Here's some free advice,
detective...
cash in that shitty pension,
turn in that badge,
buy that motorcycle you've
always dreamed about
and a shitload of guns.
You're gonna wanna be prepared
for the changes
that are coming.
They really did a number
on you in prison,
we should be taking you
to the psych ward!
Yeah, I guess that's
where time travelers
would fit in best, huh?
Time travelers?
Time travelers,
we're all time travelers.
Brother, you have no idea
who the delusional one
in this relationship is.
I can tell you it's not me
and it's definitely not her,
so you do the math.
I don't know why you
don't just tell him,
we've already changed
the future.
You're never going back to what
you left behind, Cameron.
Why don't you just tell him?
Or maybe you just don't care
about him enough...
Tell him, Cameron!
Come on...
[Laughing]
Oh, my God!
Here we go!
[gunfire]
It's an ambush!
We're under attack!
[gunfire]
Move! Move! Move!!
Convoy's been hit,
returning fire.
Two officers down!
[gunfire]
Move! Move! Move!!
Move it!
Go! Go!
Right side!
[gunfire]
It's a diversion!
Hold your fire.
It's a diversion,
we've been set up!
Warn the second team!
The signal's down,
I'm trying to reestablish.
Just forget that, warn Carlos.
Carlos, come in.
I guess no news is good news,
that decoy must've worked.
Decoy?
Radio Betty, get an update.
Hey Betty, this is Carlos...
you read me?
- Anything?
- Nothing.
Carlos?
[gunfire]
Grab the wheel!
What did I tell you?
Decoy huh?
I think you'd better fasten
your seatbelt.
You're in for one
hell of a ride!
Simon?
Is he okay?
Let's see you get out
of this one, Protector!
Hang on, Carlos!
Here we go, stay with them.
They want us off the road!
Son of a bitch!
Dillon, Dillon!
We're under attack,
we need backup!
- Where are they?
- Dillon!
Where are they?
Damn it!
What the hell is going on?!
Hold on!
- Hang on!
- Kiera you okay?
Kiera?!
Carlos, what's going on
back there?
[Fighting noises]
[gunfire]
What the hell?!
Nice try!
Oh shit!
Oh, God!
Hang on back there!
Okay, we bought ourselves
a little time!
[fighting grunts]
Carlos?
Carlos?!
[fighting grunts]
Carlos!
- Carlos, you all right?
- Yeah, I got it covered!
Ahh!
Go to sleep.
Nighty night.
- What about now?
- Yeah, it's handled.
Nicely done. What do we do now?
I'll get on the radio, see if I
can find out what's going on.
Good plan.
Betty! It's Carlos, you there?
Inspector!
Yeah.
Carlos radioed in,
they were ambushed.
One dead guard,
they're driving blind on country
roads, waiting for backup.
Okay, well let's get
them some.
Redirect the decoy convoy
to their last known position
and send in air support
to cover the area.
How the hell did Liber8
get wind of this?
You think we have someone
inside feeding intel to Liber8?
Well, I wouldn't rule
it out.
Where's that backup?
It should be here any
minute now.
How did they know where
we were, Carlos?
There's only one reasonable
answer to that question...
A mole inside the VPD.
Either way, we can't risk
calling in for backup again.
Looks like the air support
finally arrived.
Who the hell are these guys?
What are they doing?
[gunfire]
Oh shit...
Hold on!
Get out of here, go!
God Damnit, Carlos!
We're sitting ducks!
GPS puts them in this area,
our units are 10 minutes away.
Don't you say a word.
I don't really need to,
do I?
You and I know there's
only two versions of this
that make any sense,
so you need to decide.
Do you have a problem
inside this department
or do you need to take a
closer look at Kiera Cameron?
She might not make it
out of this alive.
From what I've seen,
making it out alive
is her specialty.
Any sign of them,
are they gone?
I don't know where they are,
I can't see them.
We need cover!
Right there! That tunnel, go!
Hold on!
- Shit!
- Get out of here, go!
- Go!
- Hold on!
There we go!
Our friends are back.
What do we do now?
I have no idea.
- Oh shit...
- Oh God...
Kiera!
That clearly wasn't meant
for us.
Get me out of here!
Right there, there it is!
Come on! That was no accident!
These two are fighting
over us?
Two factions,
Travis is the prize.
Ready? Now!
[gunfire]
Come out!
If we stay here, we're dead!
What are our options?
We're gonna make
a run for it.
We're gonna be ripped
to shreds!
Stay as close to me
as you can.
- What are you, crazy?
- Now!
[gunfire]
Are you okay?
Yeah, I don't know how
but yeah.
[gunfire]
Nice work, Inspector.
Shit...
Problems?
Uh... you could say that.
I've lost contact
with our team.
What are you talking about?
The last transmission
said they were engaged
then a helicopter showed up.
Can you play it back
for me?
Where's Garza?
Oh, no.
The guns...
She took Travis' serum too.
This one has the latest
intel processor
and a terabyte of
hard drive storage.
Uh, I was told I need
to get a lot of rams.
Yes, this one has 8 gigabytes
or ram.
Dad, Dad!
What's bigger, a gigabyte
or a terabyte?
Dad, Dad!
Uh... a terabyte is one
thousand gigabytes.
Okay, I want a terabyte
of rams.
You can't have a terabyte of...
see, the way a computer's
memory works is that...
You gonna get that?
You know, this is uh...
this is where things start
to get a little murky
for me, agent Cameron.
You and Fonnegra,
apparently out of
ammunition at this point,
are able to escape
the focused crossfire.
Obviously.
And yet you couldn't make
out any identifying features
of either group, nothing.
She already told you,
the first group had all
the signs of Liber8...
they were bold but reckless.
The second group...
it was like a military strike,
they were precise.
What matters here is
that both groups
were apparently going
for the same thing.
You know what astounds me
Inspector Dillon?
Is that these two were put in
charge in the first place,
especially considering
that we're not even sure
where agent Cameron's
alliances really lie.
Hey... that is enough.
You know Gardiner,
I really don't care who gave
you the authority
to be a part of
this operation,
what I will not...
Inspector...
What I will not stand
for is you questioning
the loyalty of my officers!
Regardless of what
happened out there today,
the buck stops with me.
I didn't see the threat.
Is that right?
It was the right call.
Now I will file the report and
I will take the heat for it.
Yeah, I expect that
you will.
We're done.
Putting Travis Berta into an
unprotected decoy vehicle
is pretty cunning,
I'll give you that.
Go to hell.
Cameron...
We both know that you're
not what you seem
and I got a pretty good
feeling those answers
are gonna reveal themselves as
long as someone is watching.
I have work to do.
Oh, springing Travis
wasn't enough?
[cell phone buzzing]
It's Garza.
Yes?
Sonya... you were right.
You don't have much time.
Keep moving.
What's that?
You okay?
What was in that syringe?
Something to keep
you moving.
[gunfire]
We don't have much time.
Come on!
We can't assume
anything's normal
if there's a spy in
the department.
Yeah, I know.
We need to add another layer
of secrecy.
That's gonna get weird.
Going to get weird?
Could it be weirder
than time travel stories?
Yeah, that was...
pretty out there.
Yeah.
You know, what's strange was
how Travis decided he wanted
to lump you into his
crazy delusions.
Crazy is crazy.
Yeah...
Since you're in the
mood for out there ideas,
here's one I'd like
to run by you.
Shoot.
Our department spy, the mole,
knows just enough
to screw us over,
make us look bad and
undermine our goals...
like they want us
out of the way.
I'm listening.
What if it's Gardiner?
♪
A toast!
A toast to fear...
Fear infects the minds
of our opponents.
Fear slows them down
and opens the door to
self-doubt and inaction.
You see without their fear,
our bravery would
be meaningless.
You can't fear failure
because in doing so,
you are inviting failure.
I think it was T.S. Eliot
who said
only those who will
risk going too far
can possibly find out how
far one can go.
Let's do this.
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com