Thank you.
I can't believe
you remember that.
What, are you kidding me?
You singing
"Everybody Hurts."
Jules:
Oh sorry.
Yeah, my R.E.M phase.
(Chuckles)
Well, I couldn't take
my eyes off you, so...
Are you sure it didn't have
anything to do
with what I was wearing
maybe?
Uh, black leather miniskirt,
white tank top...
Seriously though,
you guys were good.
You coulda went
on the road.
I don't think so.
Yeah,
I got a confession.
Your best show -
five am,
morning after graduation,
on the roof
of the gym.
What?
You just got dumped
by Curtis
at that party...
Oh God,
I don't believe this.
You took your guitar,
you went up to roof
and you came up
with this...
Really gentle song-
you were up there?
I'm sorry.
It's just after I heard that
I thought...
I felt like I knew you.
You know there's this
wine tasting thing,
Niagara on the lake,
next weekend.
I was thinking, you know,
maybe we could go.
Um...
I mean we don't have
to stay over,
it could just be
a day trip.
I was just thinking 'cause
we've been seeing each other
for a while.
I... I just-
(loud pop nearby,
someone screams)
What was that?
That was gunfire.
(Screaming nearby)
Steve:
Hold on.
Jules:
Steve, wait!
(Car tires and brakes screech)
Steve: Hey watch!
(Tires screech,
horns honk)
Jules:
Stop!
Man:
Somebody's been shot.
Jules:
Winnie, it's Jules.
Oh hey, how are you enjoying
your day off?
Jules:
I've got shots fired.
Inside the Sultan Grill
on the Danforth.
Guys! Guys!
Sam: What's happening?
Winnie: Are you okay?
We're outside the restaurant
right now.
Is the shooter still inside?
I can't see.
Someone's shot, Jules.
I gotta get in there.
Jules:
No, Steve, we need to wait
for backup.
The shooter might
still be active.
Sam:
Jules, hang tight!
We're coming!
Team one, hot call!
Suit up!
He may be dead
before they get here.
Jules:
You don't go in there.
Steve!
Winnie:
Shots fired at the Sultan Grill
on the Danforth.
There's one confirmed
victim down.
Gunman:
I warned you!
I ask you a simple question,
all you have to do is answer.
Waitress: Eric...
Gunman: Now one more time!
Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa,
tell me where he is!
I don't know!
Where's Riyaz?
I'm sorry,
I don't know who that is.
Where are your hands?
Where are your hands?!
No, no cell phones.
Hey, all cell phones
on the floor now.
Now! Go get 'em!
Collect them!
Now!
Anyone caught attempting
to communicate with him
will be shot.
Do you understand me?!
It's gonna be okay.
Total communication blackout.
Steve:
I'm a medic,
I'm gonna help you.
You're gonna be okay.
All right.
Hey-hey-hey-hey-hey!
What're you doing?
He just wants to make sure
that he's okay.
Okay, well get away.
Come on get away.
Get away from him!
You, lock it.
Lock the door!
You, barricade it -
tables and chairs.
Come on!
Nobody's leaving
until I get some answers.
All right.
Okay.
You - knives, forks, uh...
Corkscrews,
any sharp implements.
If I find anything
that can be used as a weapon...
Go!
Come on, come on, come on!
That's good.
Get against the wall.
Hands where I can see 'em.
Go! Move!
(SUV's rumble up)
Set up a perimeter.
Get the uniforms
to keep these people back.
Let's do it now.
Parker:
We're dealing with at least
one shooter.
Wordy:
How many hostages?
Ed:
Ten, maybe more.
Sam:
Jules?
Limited vantage.
Looks like the front doors
are barricaded.
Maybe Jules can feed us
information from inside.
Sam:
No, if that gunman finds out
Jules is a cop...
All right.
Hey, quiet!
Hey, hey!
You guys clear outta here!
Go!
I want everyone to keep quiet,
I gotta think.
You, on the floor.
Knees. Here.
Hands behind the head.
You know what this place is,
right?
It's, it's a restaurant.
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
It looks very much like
a restaurant, but do you...
(Exasperated exhale)
Do you know what it is?
(Exhales forcefully)
What're you looking at?!
You know what
it's really for?
(Jules' phone buzzes)
Gunman:
You know who eats here
and what they want?
Huh?!
Where's Riyaz?!
(Parker's PDA beeps)
Parker:
Jules is okay.
She says there's one gunman,
18 hostages.
Ed:
What does the gunman want?
Gunman:
Riyaz should be here now.
Where is he?
(PDA beeps)
Parker:
Looking for Riyaz.
Who's Riyaz?
Hey, Spike,
see if there's a connection
between the Sultan Grill
and someone named Riyaz.
On it.
You told him not to come
because I'm here,
didn't you?
I don't even know who you mean.
I gotta try to talk to him.
Woman:
(Frightened gasp)
Jules:
Sir?
Hey, you stay
where you are.
I'm gonna stay
right here.
All right, good.
My name's Jules.
What's your?
Oh... (Laughs)
You're looking for somebody
named Riyaz?
Yeah, what,
you know him?
No, I don't.
But maybe I could help you
find him.
Oh well, he knows him.
And if he had just told me
where he was when I asked,
then this wouldn't have
happened.
(Sirens blip and wail)
No, oh no.
(Panicking)
No, no, okay...
Uh, everybody...
Go! Go!
Everybody against the door!
Uh, go to the front.
Everybody, go, go, go!
Get to the front.
Go. Get to the front.
Go now!
He's lining up hostages
against the window.
He's making a human shield.
Sam?
No vantage.
I'm coming down.
Hey, hey,
what're you doing?
Sir, this man is losing
a lot of blood.
He needs to go
to the hospital.
I said no one's leaving.
Jules:
Okay, well this is my friend,
Steve.
He's a paramedic.
If you let him look at him,
maybe he can help him
and then you can find Riyaz.
That's what you want,
right?
(Laboured breaths)
Yeah.
Just hang in there, buddy,
hang in.
Okay,
he's barely conscious.
Look, I'm gonna need
some napkins,
clean water
and plastic wrap.
I can get them.
Okay, go.
Stay where I can see you.
Come on, come on.
Move fast!
Okay, we know who
we're looking for.
The owner of the restaurant
is Riyaz Fayad.
Parker:
Good, now let's find out
who's got a beef with him.
Neighbours,
disgruntled employees.
What's going on, Eddie?
Ed:
All right, we got an air vent
on the roof.
Might be able to feed
a snake cam through that.
All right, go for it.
Let's do it.
Is Eric gonna be okay?
He's got decreased breath
sounds on the left side.
What does that mean?
His lung collapsed.
Oh my God.
Look, he needs chest
decompression.
Wouldn't happen to have a kit
in your purse, do you?
Can you improvise?
Yeah, but I need a pen,
I need some vodka...
A knife.
Sir?
What do you think I am?
An idiot?
Sir, I promise.
We're gonna hand it back
as soon as we're done,
please.
All right.
Jules:
Whoa, whoa,
what're you doing?
You try anything,
I'm gonna shoot her.
Waitress:
(Whimpers and cries)
I'm gonna get the vodka.
Gunman:
Okay, go.
Gunman: Just go!
Jules: I'm going.
(Approaching footsteps)
Jules: Here you go.
Steve: Thanks.
Steve:
Okay, the knife.
Jules:
Mm-hmm.
You got it?
Jules:
Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry
for getting us into this.
You were just trying
to help.
Okay.
(Grunt of effort)
Oh my God.
Okay, hand me the pen.
Okay.
(Motor buzzes)
Steve:
Hand me the plastic bag.
Yeah.
Steve:
This is gonna hold the pen
in place,
it's gonna protect the wound.
Pass me the knife.
Slide it across the ground,
come on.
(Panicked breaths)
(Knife clanks on table)
All right.
Angle it
a little to the left.
I'm in.
Ed: Spike?
Spike: Eyes are good.
Parker:
All right, Steve's taking care
of the gunshot victim.
I don't see any other wounded.
There's a lot of buzz
on Riyaz Fayad.
Terror watch blogs,
mainstream press,
they're all suggesting
he's a leader
of an extremist terror cell.
Anti-terror unit
investigating?
Spike:
Yeah, the details
are classified;
it'll take time
to get more intel.
Eddie, Fayad's being
investigated for terrorism.
You think he's connected
to the gunman?
Parker:
I don't know.
Why don't you go talk to him.
Spike.
Yeah, sending the address
to your PDAs right now.
Let's move it.
Parker:
Maybe he's got the information
we need to play things out.
Gunman:
You, you!
Gray shirt, come here.
On your knees.
Get on your knees.
Kneel!
Parker:
All right, that's it,
I'm calling in.
Gunman:
(Phone starts ringing)
Where's Riyaz?
Where is Riyaz?!
Woman:
I don't know,
I don't know.
Gunman:
Come on, we're running
out of time here.
(Phone rings)
Jules:
I bet that's the police.
Maybe they wanna help.
Gunman:
Yeah, you think so,
but, you know, no.
In the big picture,
they're just puppets.
There's nothing they can do.
Okay, but maybe you can help
show them the big picture.
And explain to them
why you wanna find this guy.
(Phone rings)
Uh... okay, fine.
Answer it.
(Phone rings)
(Jules beeps "answer" key)
Jules:
Hello?
So much for your day off,
huh?
Jules:
Yes. There's a gentleman here,
he's looking for a man
named Riyaz Fayad,
it's very important.
Can you help him find him?
Get me his name, Jules.
They'll help you find Riyaz
if you give them your name.
It's Davis Lagosto.
Jules:
Okay, it's Davis Lagosto.
I'll check him out.
Why do you need
to find Riyaz?
Riyaz Fayad is using
this restaurant as a front
for his terrorist operations.
Hey, I have reliable sources.
I'm just here to stop him
before he strikes.
Tell him Fayad's being
investigation by the ATU.
Riyaz is already under
investigation by the ATU -
the anti-terror unit.
And if he's a terrorist,
they're gonna do everything
they can
to bring him to justice.
No, by then
it'll be too late.
Why?
It's gonna happen
any day now.
What's happening?
He and his people,
they're gonna be planting bombs
on the subway.
How does he know this?
Jules:
Okay, if you know
of a terrorist act,
you have to tell
the police.
Get back!
Okay, I'm back.
What're you doing?
I thought you were helping me.
I am.
I'm talking to the police.
Davis: Put the gun down!
Parker: What's going on, Jules?
Okay, put it down.
Put down the gun!
I don't have a gun.
Put down the gun,
or I'm gonna have
to shoot you!
♪ Flashpoint 3x19 ♪
Terror
Original air date on January 18, 2011>
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==
♪
Put it down now!
I'm putting it down.
Davis:
Slowly.
Slowly, slowly.
Okay, good.
Get out...
Get over there!
Come on.
Get back.
All right,
hands above your head.
(Door shuts)
Wait, he didn't hang up
the phone.
Thank you, Davis.
We still have ears.
Spike:
Transferring the line
to headset.
Sam:
What do you have on Davis?
Parker:
Substance abuse?
Spike:
No, but we do have
breaking and entering,
assault...
A history of violence.
Also served time
in a psych ward.
What's he been diagnosed with?
I can't get details.
I'd have to get clearance.
Parker:
Well, it's some kind
of delusional disorder.
Let's see if we can track down
his family.
So this terrorist attack...
Parker:
Could be delusion,
could be there's a grain
of truth.
Riyaz Fayad is being
investigated.
Spike:
We're still waiting
on that call from ATU,
seeing if there's been
any chatter.
Police! Riyaz Fayad,
open up the door.
Do it now!
Police!
(Doorknob rattles)
Can I help you?
Yeah, we're here to talk
to Riyaz Fayad.
What do you want
with him?
Ed:
We need to ask him
a few questions.
Sorry, he's not here
right now. Hey!
Ed:
Police! Wordy.
Mrs. Fayad:
Leave him alone!
Ed:
Police!
Wordy:
Police! Stop right there!
Police!
Ed:
Right there! Right there!
Let's see some hands, now!
Wordy:
Do it now!
Don't come any closer!
Mr. Fayad, I'm officer Lane,
this is officer wordsworth.
Now we just need to talk,
but you need to put that
weapon down now.
Sir, we just wanna
talk to you.
I haven't done anything
wrong!
Mr. Fayad.
We have to consider that
a threat, sir.
I know how this works!
You capture me like an animal -
no lawyer,
no rights -
fly me off to some other country
to be tortured!
Mrs. Fayad:
Please, Riyaz, don't!
Mrs. Fayad, back in the house.
Back in the house!
Cashmira, stay back.
Mr. Fayad,
listen to your wife.
We just wanna talk here.
You knock on my door
with assault weapons
for a conversation?
We will put the guns away.
Please, put the pipe down.
Cashmira: Please, Riyaz.
Ed: Just help us out here.
Don't make this
any worse.
That's it.
Thank you, sir. Wordy?
Drop it, drop it.
Right down!
Ed:
That's it.
Wordy:
Turn around.
Up against the fence.
Just tell me if he's okay,
will you?
Parker:
Right now he's got a gun
and he's holding
several people hostage
inside a restaurant.
Oh, my God.
Davis, my boy.
Oh.
Parker:
Mr. Lagosto, we understand
that your son has a history
of mental illness.
Yeah.
He was diagnosed
paranoid schizophrenic
when he was 15.
So he suffers
from delusions?
Robert:
Yeah... yeah.
Davis thinks everyone's
out to get him.
Jules:
Hey, Davis, how you doing?
Are you okay?
Riyaz should've been here
by now,
where is he?
Well, the police
are looking for him.
Yeah, well,
we're running out of time.
Ed:
We have an armed man
who has barricaded himself
inside your restaurant
looking for you,
now we need to know why.
His name is Davis Lagosto.
You ever seen him?
No, I've never seen him
before.
Soldiers are all out
in the middle east, you know,
but where are they
when we need them here?
Why do we need soldiers
here?
Davis:
There are terror operatives
in every major city
in North America.
Of course we need them here.
Sounds really scary.
He thought his mother
was under orders to kill him.
So he came into our bedroom
one night
while we were sleeping,
with a rope,
tied it around her neck,
tried to strangle her.
I'm sorry.
That sounds terrifying, sir.
(Sighs heavily)
But we loved him,
you know?
(Exhales heavily)
There are dozens
of sleeper cells
all across this country.
It's not just al-Qaeda.
It's Hezbollah and Hamas.
Wordy:
Gunman's convinced that
you're planning an attack
on the subway system.
(Scoffs)
Of course.
'Cause I'm a "terrorist."
Ever since those
news reports came out,
they've threatened my wife
and my child.
They painted hate messages
on my home
and my restaurant -
all based on nothing.
He could be living
next door to you
and you wouldn't even
know it.
And you feel like
it's your responsibility
to do something about it.
I don't have a choice!
Robert:
There was an anti-psychotic.
It really helped
for a while.
Davis managed
to get through college,
got a degree
in chemical engineering.
What,
the drug stopped working?
Robert:
Yeah, he had a breakdown
after college,
had to be hospitalized.
Ed:
All right, Mr. Fayad,
can we take a look
at those threats?
Gladly.
Wordy, uncuff him.
Ma'am?
Is he on any medication
right now?
Robert:
I really don't know.
I...
I haven't seen my son
in over a year.
Why not, sir?
Robert:
The last time I checked him
into the hospital,
he got very angry;
he thought I was trying
to have him committed.
When he got out,
I tried to get him
to come home, but...
He didn't want any part of me.
Okay, where's he living now?
Do you know?
Robert:
He's, uh, at Harmony House.
It's a group home.
St. George Street.
Okay, just hang on one second,
Mr. Lagosto.
Get a hold of Harmony House.
I'm sure he's got
a social worker there.
Let's get in touch
with him.
Parker: Mr. Irwin?
Clive: Yeah.
How're you doing?
I'm sergeant Parker.
Thank you for coming.
Will you follow me
please, sir?
So you're Davis's
primary social worker?
Yeah, I've known him
for over two years.
Look,
this is all my fault.
Davis is my responsibility.
Look, we understand
that Davis has been charged
with assault in the past.
Now,
these violent outbursts,
do they happen often?
He's not some kind of monster.
He's sick.
Yeah, I understand that,
Mr. Irwin.
Look, paranoid schizophrenics
are prone to suspicion.
If they feel threatened,
they sometimes lash out
to protect themselves.
But Davis believes
that terrorists
are planning an attack
on the city.
What did he say?
He said that restaurant
is a front for a terror cell.
Has he mentioned
Riyaz Fayad before?
I don't think so,
but he's been talking a lot
about terrorists lately.
Do you know what might have
triggered that?
Terrorism's all over the news
these days.
Bombings in Madrid,
Chechnya...
Yeah.
Eric?
Waitress:
Oh my God!
What's happening?
His pulse is thready.
There's no breath sounds.
Angela:
Oh my God.
Come on, Eric,
hang in there!
Come on, buddy.
Hang in there, buddy.
Steve.
Waitress:
Why're you stopping?
Help, please!
Tell him to keep going.
Why're you stopping?!
I'm sorry, it's...
No!
Man: Oh my God.
Davis: Hey!
Is he dead?
Yes.
Oh.
Oh?
Okay, Angela...
That's all
you have to say?!
Eric never did anything
to you.
Davis:
Okay, shhh.
He harboured
a known terrorist.
Riyaz is not a terrorist!
What's wrong with you?!
Okay, she's escalating him now.
Jules:
Angela, you know what?
We need to stay really calm
right now.
Davis:
Hey! All right, just shut up!
Quiet!
Shut up!
Both of you!
You come in here
on a Muslim witch hunt...
No, you're not listening to me,
all right?
This is a front
for a terrorist operation.
You are not listening to me.
So then what does that
make me?
All right, oh my God,
you're one of them.
You're a black widow.
So now I'm a terrorist too?!
Aw crap!
Davis:
Everybody, get back!
Stay back, everybody!
Get back! Get back!
Davis, what do you see?
All right, she's got a bomb.
She's about to detonate a bomb.
Angela:
We're all terrorists!
Get down!
She's got a bomb!
All right.
Hey.
(Gunshot pops)
Shots fired!
Davis: Why'd you do that?
Jules: Are you okay?
I think so.
Oh my gosh!
Steve?
It's Steve.
He's been shot.
Steve.
I'm okay.
Just lay still,
Angela.
Sam:
Jules needs backup,
I wanna go in.
Parker:
From where?
This back door leads
right into the basement.
Parker:
Okay. Sam?
You're just covering on this,
all right?
She knows what she's doing.
I know she does.
Just saying.
Yes, sir.
Jules:
We gotta stop the bleeding.
Steve:
(Low pained grunts)
It's okay.
I got it, I got it.
Get back, get back!
Get back!
Jules:
All right, let's slow down.
Shut up! Shut up!
Hands above your head!
All right, I know that
you're afraid right now, Davis.
All right,
we have to find something
to bind her hands and feet.
We have to dismantle the bomb.
She's not gonna hurt you.
She's got a bomb!
Are you blind?!
Patron:
Oh my God.
Spike:
He's turning on Jules.
We gotta find a way
to get past his delusions.
He said we needed soldiers here.
Maybe I can talk to him as one.
Parker:
Go for it, Sam.
But, boss, this place has serious
security for a restaurant;
I'm looking
at reinforced steel.
After 9-11, a lot
of middle eastern businesses
have been targets for vandals.
I'm gonna have
to torch my way through.
Parker:
Copy that.
Riyaz:
This brick was thrown
through our window.
(Reading)
Die Arab pig.
Sayid was in the room
when it happened.
He was terrified.
Go back
to the middle east.
He was born in Vancouver.
Why didn't you report this?
You think anyone cares
about death threats
against a suspected
terrorist?
Why were you accused
in the first place?
Back in, uh... 2004,
I started donating money
to an Islamic charity.
I was told
it was a scholarship fund
for underprivileged kids.
I found out later that
the charity was a front
used to fund
terrorist activities,
including the London bombings.
And from that they assumed
you were the leader
of a terrorist cell?
I convinced a lot of other
members of my mosque
to donate
to the same charity.
We thought we were doing
something good.
ATU dragged us from our homes
in the middle of the night.
They interrogated us
for hours.
They froze our bank accounts,
confiscated our passports...
Once it got leaked
to the press,
that's when all the threats
started to happen.
Spike:
Hey, Ed?
Just got off the phone
with the anti-terror unit.
Excuse me one second.
Any intel
on a possible attack?
No. And they checked
with other agencies -
no chatter, nothing.
And Mr. Fayad?
Spike:
Well, he's gonna be on
a no-fly list for a while,
but they're wrapping up
their investigation.
He's been cleared
of any wrongdoing.
Ed:
Okay, good to know.
Thanks, Spike.
The ATU is clearing you.
What?
Really?
Oh my God.
Oh my God! It's over!
(Elated laughter)
Hey, Spike,
a lot of these email threats
are being sent from the same
I.P. address.
Spike:
I'll run a trace,
see if we can connect them
to Davis.
Jules:
All right, I'm just gonna
change this, okay?
Don't try to be the tough guy.
I know what it feels like.
I've been shot before.
I know how much pain you're in.
So, how do you like the date
so far?
You really know how to keep
a girl on her toes, huh?
Wait 'til you see what...
Ungh!
I have planned
for the next one.
Woman:
We can't. He's just gonna
start shooting again.
Man:
That's why we gotta do it fast.
Disarm him.
Woman 2:
There are a lot of us
and only one of him.
Steve, you're shivering.
(Steve shivers)
The room's spinning.
Your heart's racing
really fast.
Yeah, I'm cold.
I'm just going into shock.
I'm gonna go try
and get your jacket.
N-no...
Okay,
I want you to look at me.
I want you to keep
talking to me, okay?
I'm an idiot.
You're not.
It's not your fault.
No, I mean, I shouldn't have
waited so long to ask you out.
Let's save the deathbed
confession
for 50 years from now,
okay?
You gonna be there?
(Torch whirs loudly)
Parker:
Sam, let us know
when you're close.
Hey, guys,
those threats against Riyaz?
You were right;
the I.P. address traces back
to Davis's group home.
So he did make those threats.
Hey, Ed,
take a look at this one.
Okay, boss,
listen to this.
With one bomb,
you killed 26 people.
Time for you
and your followers
to get a taste
of your own medicine.
Taste of his own medicine...
Think Davis built a bomb?
His father mentioned
that he had a degree
in chemical engineering.
So why show up at the restaurant
with a gun?
Maybe he'd already
planted it somewhere;
he wanted to take the leader out
personally.
Ed:
Sounds like Riyaz
wasn't his only target.
Okay, boss, we're gonna head
to the group home.
Okay, Eddie, check Davis's room,
check everywhere.
Find out what he's building
and who he's targeting.
Ed:
Copy that.
Mr. Fayad?
Riyaz:
Yes, officer?
An officer's gonna take you
downtown for processing.
It's just procedure.
Uh, I'll go with you.
No,
you and Sayid go to the mosque.
Pray for Eric and the others
at the restaurant.
Cashmira:
Okay.
Man:
Come on, let's go.
Come on, come on.
Get back!
Sam, hostages are turning
on him.
Get in there now!
Get back against the wall
now,
or I'll shoot you all
one by one.
Jules:
Drop your weapon.
Drop your weapons.
Drop...
(Glass shatters)
Sam:
Everybody do what the man says!
Drop your weapons
and go back to where you were.
It's all right, buddy,
you can stand down.
I got this area of operations
contained.
Go back to where you were, now,
all of you!
Do it now!
Who are you?
Master Corporal Sam Braddock,
Special Forces.
I'm here to help.
You knew this place
was a front for terrorists?
Parker:
Sam, don't lie to him.
He's sensitive to deception.
I know what it's like
to feel afraid;
I served two tours
in Afghanistan.
I know what it's like
to walk down the street,
and wonder where they're
gonna strike again.
You feel helpless,
like you're never
gonna be safe.
That's what they want -
all of us to live
in a state of fear.
Yeah, that's why we gotta
fight back.
You know that operation
they're-
(gunshot pops,
patrons scream)
Davis and Sam:
(Struggling grunts)
Sam:
Settle down.
Davis:
(Grunts)
What are you doing?!
You lied to me!
Sam:
I didn't lie.
Subject in custody.
Parker:
Good work, guys.
Good work.
(Breathing hard)
Thank you.
E.M.S.
We need E.M.S. in here now.
Eddie, you find anything
at the group home?
Ed:
Boss, we're in the basement.
Davis is building
something here...
(PDA camera clicks)
Ed:
But it doesn't look like
any kind of bomb
I've ever seen.
Have a look.
Those fire extinguishers?
Uh huh.
They're all empty.
Watches, pesticides...
What's that on the floor?
(PDA camera clicks)
Castor beans.
Talk to me, Spike.
Castor beans
and pesticides -
major components in both ricin
and sarin.
Nerve gas.
Fire extinguishers
hold compressed gas,
watch is the timer...
He's made a chemical bomb
and it's already out there.
Parker:
Sam?
How is he?
Davis?
Davis, I'm sergeant Parker.
How are you doing?
You doing okay?
Look, I want you to know
that you're safe.
We're not gonna let anything
happen to you.
Okay?
But we could really use
your help right now.
We know that made
some kind of chemical bomb
and we need to know
where it is.
Davis, a bomb like that
could kill a lot
of innocent people.
Sam:
I don't think we're gonna
get anything out of him.
Parker:
Get him to the hospital,
regulate his meds.
Parker:
Keep an eye on Mr. Lagosto.
When he becomes coherent,
you question him again, okay?
Eddie, couldn't get anything.
You need to tear
that place apart
and figure out where
his next target may have been.
Let the social worker, Clive,
know that he's there,
he's safe,
but he's gonna meet us
up at the hospital.
Boss, the social worker's
not here.
Boss, I got something.
All right,
I'm on my way.
Jules:
I'm right here, Steve, okay.
I'm coming with you.
Nah, nah-nah.
You don't have to come with me.
Jules:
You're going into surgery.
You need somebody there
when you wake up.
Yeah, there's a bomb out there;
The team needs you.
Jules: Are you sure?
Steve: Yeah, I'll be all right.
Okay,
I'm gonna come by later.
(Siren wails)
(Gurney rattles)
You better suit up.
Jules:
Yeah.
I got into Davis's computer.
Those threats against Riyaz?
They're in Davis's outbox
but they're not in
his "sent" mail folder.
What does that mean,
Spike?
It means someone was using
his computer
as a proxy server.
Davis didn't send
those threats.
Someone was setting him up.
Can you trace it?
Yeah, I'm running a tunneling
program right now.
(Computer beeps)
Clive Irwin.
His social worker.
Spike:
So why would Clive
want to frame Davis?
Parker: Eddie.
Ed: Boss?
Parker:
Clive is now a person
of interest.
Wordy, let's get this open.
Wordy:
Copy.
Ed:
Boss, it looks like Clive's
been conducting
his own investigation
of Mr. Fayad.
What'd you find?
We've got articles
on domestic terrorism,
surveillance photos
on Mr. Fayad
and other Muslims.
Suspected cell members.
Clive's the one who's paranoid
about terrorism.
Spike:
I think I know why.
Clive's wife was killed
in the London terror attacks
a few years ago.
Carol:
Clive never got over
losing his wife.
Ed:
Did he ever discuss it
with Davis?
It's funny,
he never talked
about it to anyone,
and then a few months ago
they were playing chess...
When the bomb went off,
the train split in half.
She was thrown
onto the tracks.
I tried to go to her,
but I couldn't stand up.
Both my legs were broken.
(Long drawn out inhale)
I didn't know
if she was alive or dead.
Her face was turned away.
I just kept
calling her name.
I'm almost convinced
it's been a bad dream.
(Breathes deeply)
They say that Riyaz Fayad
was connected
to those suicide bombers.
There must be a way
to stop him.
I mean you can't blame Clive
for how he feels.
Okay, thank you.
Did you get all that?
Yeah.
Sounds like Clive's been
whispering in Davis's ear
for months.
Feeding his paranoia
about an attack
and convincing him
to build a bomb.
Well, Davis probably had
no idea
his friend was using him
as a weapon.
Setting him up
to take the fall.
Wordy:
One of the residents
said they saw Clive
driving away 20 minutes ago.
Where'd he go?
No idea.
Just said he's moving fast.
Well, if he was using Davis
to keep his own hands clean,
why would he take the bomb
himself?
'Cause Davis can't now
and the job isn't done.
It's gotta be the mosque.
Remember?
Clive didn't just threaten
Riyaz.
He said, "you and your followers
are gonna get a taste
of your own medicine."
He thinks it's their base
of operations.
Spike:
Lawrence and Avenue Road.
Parker:
Let's go, let's move!
(Siren wails)
Clive's car has been spotted
in the parking lot
at the mosque.
(Prayer is being recited
in the prayer room)
(Hushed prayer is recited)
(SUVs rumble up)
Zelovitsky: Sergeant Parker?
Parker: Yeah.
Dr. Zelovitsky,
I'm with Hazmat.
I'm heading up
the medical team.
Any idea what kind of toxin
we're dealing with?
It could be a nerve Agent,
maybe a derivative of ricin
or sarin.
It's hard to be specific
'cause it's a home brew.
We need to prepare
for hemorrhaging,
convulsions,
even fatalities.
Let's hope
it doesn't come to that.
Zelovitsky: We'll be ready.
Parker: Thank you.
Ed:
Okay, Spike,
what do we got?
Looks like Davis outfitted
the extinguishers
with artificial heads.
He presses
a manual detonator,
the cylinder will blow
releasing the gas.
Okay, can you disarm it?
Spike:
Yeah, if we find it in time.
Parker:
If we evacuate,
it'll tip him off.
He could release the toxin.
Okay, absolute stealth,
guys.
Spike, wordy,
you take the back.
Sam and Jules, west.
Boss, let's take the east.
Let's move it.
Cashmira:
Okay, babe.
You go ahead.
Mommy will be right over,
okay?
(Imam continues leading
the prayer session)
(Whispered response)
Cashmira:
Uh, can I help you?
Can I help you?
(Imam prays)
Masks on.
(Door pops open)
Sam:
I have a visual.
Parker:
Where?
Looks like the prayer room.
Ed:
Does he have the bomb?
Affirmative.
I have the solution.
Spike:
Sam, hold fire.
If the bomb hits the floor,
it'll blow.
Ed:
Spike, shut down
the ventilation system.
If the toxin's released,
we can keep it contained.
Copy that.
I'm going on in.
Ed:
Police!
(Frightened murmurs)
Team:
Police! SRU! Police!
Ed:
Right there!
Everybody exit the building.
Everyone exit the building
now!
Exit the room now,
do it now!
Nobody move.
Or I'll set off this bomb
right now!
Parker:
Clive, just put it down.
Put it down,
and move away slowly.
I don't expect you
to believe me.
Someone has to stop them.
Parker:
But will you just listen
closely to what I have to say
before you do anything
that you might regret here.
ATU -
anti-terrorist unit -
fully investigated Riyaz Fayad
and the others of this mosque,
and they've been cleared.
No they haven't!
Don't play games with me.
Parker:
They have.
None of them have links
to the terrorists
that were responsible
for your wife's death.
Clive, you push that button
and you're gonna die here.
Is that what you really want?
Is that what Laura
would want?
(Inhales shakily)
If that's what it takes.
Put it down.
Clive!
(Detonator clicks, gas hisses,
people cry out, panicked)
Ed:
Everybody get down
on the ground!
(Bomb explodes,
terrified screams)
Everybody out now!
Wordy:
Okay, through the doors
as quickly as you can!
Cashmira:
Sayid?!
Please wait,
I have to find Sayid.
Clive:
Ungh!
Wordy:
Everybody, out, out!
Go, go, go, go!
Sayid:
(Crying)
Wordy:
Move it, move it!
Ed:
Wordy, we gotta get to Sayid.
Let's go!
(Cacophony of hurried chatter)
We need these people contained.
Everyone needs
to be sprayed down,
that includes you!
Ed:
I hear ya, doc.
As soon as everyone's safe.
Zelovitsky:
Straight over to the blue tent.
Watch your step.
People will be there
to help you.
Wordy:
Keep going, keep going!
Ed:
Go! Go! Let's go!
Get outta here!
(Overlapping chatter)
Parker:
All right, team one,
full sweep
for anyone left inside.
Sayid!
Come on.
I got ya, I got ya.
Wordy:
Let's go.
We need some help!
Let's go!
Let's go, right here!
Come on!
Cashmira:
Oh my God, Sayid!
Ed:
It's okay.
Doc!
Cashmira:
Is he gonna be okay?
Baby!
Resps are shallow.
I need five milligrams
of atropine.
Ed:
They're gonna do everything
they can.
Cashmira:
Sayid, baby,
mommy's right here.
Come on, come on,
let's go!
Ed:
Finished my report.
Parker:
Thanks, buddy.
I hear you made a call
on Riyaz's behalf.
Yeah.
Boss, he only threatened us
because he was scared.
He thought we were
the rendition squad.
He saw what he feared
the most.
And he wasn't
the only one today
who something
that wasn't there.
Spike:
Hey, update from the hospital.
Five people still in serious
condition,
but they're expected
to pull through.
What about the boy - Sayid?
Doing okay.
Thanks, Spike.
Yeah.
♪
Hey.
How're you feeling?
Better...Now.
Can I just say something?
Sure.
Steve:
The last few months,
I've been doing a lot
of thinking...
Just about, uh,
the big picture.
Yeah. I have too.
Steve:
Just family...
Future and stuff.
(Breathes deeply)
(Clears throat)
And what I'm guessing is...
Our big pictures
aren't the same.
'Cause you're in mine,
but, uh...
I don't think I'm in yours.
Hey, it's okay.
It's all good.
There's no regrets.
Well...
Almost no regrets.
What do you mean?
Never got to finish
our ice cream.
Both:
(Laugh)
Ow.
(Steve inhales
and exhales deeply)
Just one favour?
Anything.
Promise me...
Keep singing.
Jules: (Singing)
♪ do you see me,
'cause I see you ♪
♪ but it's goodbye, bye ♪
♪ goodbye, goodbye ♪
♪ goodbye ♪
♪ goodbye again ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==