[ALARM BLARING]
[GRUNTING]
Move it,
slug-crunchers.
We're running
out of time.
[GRUNTING]
Whew! I could use a hand here.
CYBORG:
How 'bout a foot?
[CYBORG YELLS]
Titans, go!
[GROWLING]
Three raids in one week?
Man, this is seriously
gettin' old.
The H.I.V.E. Academy's
new leader
must be up to something.
[GRUNTS]
And wouldn't you like to know?
Aah!
Yes, we would.
Sweet. This crud
should be worth...
Ugh! Hey!
[ROARS]
[SCREAMING]
[MOANING]
Huh?
Aah!
Oh, you did not just do
what I think you did!
Check it out:
the world's dumbest magnet.
[LAUGHS]
[JINX SCREAMS]
Junk it.
Let's blow this place.
Yo, nobody pulls
a science fair on me
and gets away with it.
ROBIN:
It's okay, Cyborg.
We'll see them
again.
Sooner than they think.
[BEEPING]
# When there's trouble
You know who to call #
# Teen Titans! #
# From their tower
They can see it all #
# Teen Titans! #
# When there's evil
On the attack #
# You can rest knowing
They got your back #
# 'Cause when the world
Needs heroes on patrol #
# Teen Titans go! #
# With their superpowers
They unite #
# Teen Titans! #
# Never met a villain
That they liked #
# Teen Titans! #
# They've got the bad guys
On the run #
# They never stop till
Their job gets done #
# 'Cause when the world
Is losing all control #
# Teen Titans go! #
# One, two, three, four, go! #
Teen Titans!
[BEEPING]
BEAST BOY:
Tracking device.
Very sneaky.
Looks like the H.I.V.E.'s
secret headquarters
isn't so secret anymore.
So, what are we
waiting for?
We need to know what
they're planning first.
Otherwise, we could walk
right into a trap.
Do I hear an undercover
assignment comin' on?
Lucky for you guys, I happen
to be a master of disguise.
[GIBBERING]
Yeah, a green mongoose
is gonna blend right in.
Sorry, Beast Boy.
I was thinking of someone
with a slightly better disguise.
Huh. What are
you gonna do?
Dress Cyborg up
like a washing machine?
[SCREAMS]
CYBORG:
That isn't me.
That's my fully robotic
replacement.
Not nearly as charming,
but he can bench-press a bus.
Booyah!
Aah! Aah!
He still has a few bugs
to work out.
No fair.
I may be all green,
but he's half-metal.
How come he gets to go?
Because I have
a new toy.
[GASPS]
A holographic
generator!
Dude,
you look...
Unplugged.
Nice work.
If I didn't know better,
I'd think
you were just normal.
Uh... thanks.
Aw, yeah, baby!
Somebody's been workin' out.
[GRUNTING]
Huh?
Waah! Whoa! Hey!
Ahem.
Star. I didn't...
How long have you
been standing there?
Forgive me.
Your door was open.
Oh, it's cool.
Just checkin' out the old,
unimproved me.
I forgot what it was like
to have real hands.
Well... almost real.
They are most convincing.
However, my preference
is for... the original version.
[CHUCKLES]
This is the original version.
ROBIN:
Cyborg.
It's time.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Eww.
Whew. Okay.
Just play it cool,
and you'll blend right in.
[CHATTER STOPS]
[CHUCKLES, SNIFFS]
Ah, sloppy joes.
Just like the mad scientist
who created me used to make.
[CHATTER RESUMES]
Whew.
MAMMOTH:
You're in my seat.
Hey, newbie,
this is our table.
What do you think
you're doing here?
He looks familiar.
JINX:
Did you go to Darkway Prep?
MAMMOTH:
What's your name?
GIZMO:
Probably something lame. Oh, let me guess.
Snot Man?
No, wait.
Captain Nose-Picker?
Do you even have
any powers?
I'm hungry.
Get lost.
Yeah, scum,
take a hike.
[BEEPING]
Aah!
[GRUNTS]
[ALL LAUGHING]
[GROWLS]
[CYBORG ROARS]
CYBORG:
My name is Stone.
It looks like you need
to find a new table.
[GIGGLES
NERVOUSLY]
Not bad.
Let's just see
how he does
in combat practice.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[LOUD RUMBLING]
Gamma maneuver.
Hold on.
I don't know that.
Then get out
of the way.
Time to kick butt.
Aah!
[MAMMOTH GROWLS]
[GRUNTING]
GIZMO:
Ha! The newb is toast.
Hey, rocko,
had enough? [LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
Quit fooling around.
The headmaster
is watching.
[SCREAMS, GRUNTS]
[ALL GRUNTING AND GROANING]
[ROARS]
[CRACKS KNUCKLES]
[ALL GASP]
[ROARS]
[GROANING]
GIZMO:
We've gotta cross the finish line.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
Yes! Now, that's what I'm...
Zip it,
grapple-brain.
HEADMASTER:
You! Stone.
Sneaking into my school,
destroying my drones,
making my top students
look like amateur pickpockets.
You must think
you're very clever.
But you're not clever.
You're brilliant.
Well done, Mr. Stone.
Well done.
Whew.
I see a bright future
for you.
Heh, heh. Thanks.
Uh... great school
you have here, Mr., uh...
Blood. Brother Blood.
At your service.
And as for you three,
failure will not be tolerated!
You were already sent back
after graduating once.
Fail me again,
and I'll have you
sent to your doom!
Do I make myself clear?
[IN UNISON]
Yes, Brother.
Outstanding.
In a few days,
I will unveil
your class project,
the culmination
of all your hard work
over the last few weeks.
And when it is unleashed,
our foes will tremble
in our wake.
Tremble!
[ALL CHEERING]
ALL:
Brother Blood! Brother Blood!
Brother Blood!
Cyborg's
communication relay
has been deactivated.
Could be interference.
Let's just give him
a minute.
BEAST BOY:
Besides, who needs him?
This Cyborg
is way more fun.
[LAUGHING]
Booyah!
Any chance we could replace
Beast Boy with a robot too?
Cut it out. I don't think
Cyborg would appreciate...
CYBORG:
Appreciate what?
The fact
that he's already
the top butt-kicker
in his class?
Cyborg!
[WHISTLING]
Your infiltration
is successful, yes?
You bet.
Had a few close calls,
though.
What did you learn?
They're workin' on
some kind of class project.
Sounds heavy,
but no details yet.
Well, find out and get out.
The longer you're there,
the more dangerous it gets.
Believe me, I don't plan
on stickin' around.
GIZMO:
Well, what do you know?
It's the headmaster's
scrum-buffin' pet.
JINX:
Get him.
Don't bother trying
to run.
MAMMOTH:
You won't get far.
The whole school
is in on it.
In on what?
What do you think,
pie-for-brains?
Your initiation.
Ha, ha. That's it?
Don't laugh.
You have to eat
the unicycle.
[GRUNTING]
Huh?
[ALL LAUGHING]
[GRUNTING]
We have ourselves
a natural.
Take him to maximum.
[GRUNTING]
GIZMO:
Lunch is super today,
and the mashed potatoes
are dynamite.
[BOTH SNICKERING]
[WHISTLING]
[BOTH GASP]
[BOTH GIGGLING]
Hey! What are you slug faces
laughing at?
[ALL GUFFAWING]
So that's why any good
doomsday threat needs what?
[WHINING]
Mr. Stone?
Uh, effective
misdirection?
Correct. Moving on...
Congratulations.
You're one of us.
But that doesn't mean
we have to like you.
BEAST BOY:
So the plumber says,
"Just because
I'm a talking aardvark,
doesn't mean I can drive. "
[LAUGHS]
Booyah! Booyah!
Booyah!
[LAUGHS]
No word in four days.
That's it.
I'm calling him.
STARFIRE:
Robin, please,
we may endanger
his mission.
RAVEN:
Or we may save his life.
[KNOCKS HELMET]
Something's not right here.
BEAST BOY:
Tell me about it.
I can't figure out how
to make this thing burp.
[BURPS]
[LAUGHS]
What? I'm trying to make him
more realistic.
Cyborg, do you copy?
Cyborg, come in.
This isn't a good time, guys.
We've got a theory of mayhem
test tomorrow,
and I'm gonna bomb.
Please tell me
you're joking.
Yeah, uh, look,
sorry I haven't checked in.
I've been learning
their combat technique,
weapons, armor,
and we had a dance.
A dance? Cyborg,
you're there to find out
what the H.I.V.E. is planning,
not learn to tango.
I know.
This hasn't exactly been
a tea party, okay?
I need a little more time.
Or maybe it's time
we went on the offensive.
[COMPUTER BLEEPS]
I'm in.
Good. Just make it quick.
Okay.
I found the mainframe.
Whoa!
I think I just found
the class project.
They're building
something called...
BROTHER BLOOD:
An ion amplifier.
Cyborg, who's...?
Well, this is a surprise,
Mr. Stone.
Or should I say...
"Cyborg"?
Relax.
I don't want
to fight.
It's a remarkable weapon,
really.
Compact, elegant,
devastating in its power,
but it's nothing
compared to you.
What do you want from me?
Oh, it's not what I want
that matters.
It's what you want
and what I can give you.
[HIGH-PITCHED RINGING]
[GROANING]
My hand. I can feel it.
It's real.
No!
Serve me, and I can make you
what you once were.
I can give back
your life.
I'll do anything you ask.
Good.
Then I think it's time
for the other students
to see our little class project.
Clear.
Beast Boy, hurry up.
[BEAST BOY
GRUNTING]
Next time Cyborg
builds a robot,
he better leave
instructions.
Booyah! Booyah!
[IN UNISON]
Whew.
[BEEPING]
I'm picking up
Cyborg's signal...
directly
below us.
[SCREAMING]
Not good.
BROTHER BLOOD:
The Teen Titans.
So nice to make
your acquaintance.
I'd introduce you
to my students,
but I'm fairly certain
you've already met.
Attack pattern, alpha.
No mercy.
No mercy!
Ha! Ha!
[GRUNTS]
[YELLING]
Hah!
Aah!
[YELLING]
Cyborg, take it easy.
Come on. Come on.
How do you make
this thing...? Oh.
Attack mode.
ROBOT:
Teen Titans, go!
# You can't hit me #
MULTIPLE GIZMOS:
Crud!
[GROWLS]
[GRUNTS]
Enough, Cyborg.
It's time to drop the act.
This isn't an act.
[ROARING]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
[ROARS]
[BEAST BOY YELLS,
GRUNTS]
ROBIN:
Force field.
[YELLING]
Booyah!
Booyah this.
[ROARING]
GIZMO:
I knew it!
The stinking gag bag
is one of them.
BROTHER BLOOD:
No.
He's one of us now.
And I'm ready
to prove it.
I had a feeling
you'd say that.
This will amplify your power
by magnitudes unimagined.
Destroy them for me,
and you'll have
your reward.
Cyborg, no!
Please.
Come on, buddy.
We're your friends.
Sorry,
but I have new friends.
Psych!
[GROWLS]
A foolish choice,
my friend.
Very foolish.
You could have been
one of us.
I could have been
a lot of things.
Raven, get us
out of here.
I thought
you would never ask.
Sorry I had to play rough
with you guys,
but when I found out
what this could do,
I had to make Blood
trust me.
But if all those H.I.V.E. kids
were brainwashed,
why not you?
Because half my brain
is electronic.
He may have been able
to fool the man,
but he couldn't fool
the machine.
Which means,
next time we face him,
we have our own
secret weapon.
Goodbye, Stone.
For your thoughts
I will pay six grubfars.
If that's your way
of asking me if I'm okay,
don't worry.
I'm fine.
I never got to finish
high school because of this.
And when I was
at the H.I.V.E.,
for a while there
I actually felt normal.
I did not know you
before,
so to me,
you are normal.
BEAST BOY:
Oh, Cyborg!
You left the Titans.
That means you
have to be initiated
all over again.
ALL:
Come on, Cyborg. Oh, no.
I'm not wearing it.
You want me to do what?
I'm not puttin' that
on my head. Uh-uh.
Ain't gonna happen.
I'm not doin' it! No!
I said, no tights!
# T-E-E-N #
# T-I-T-A-N-S #
# Teen Titans #
# Let's go! #
# T-E-E-N #
# T-I-T-A-N-S #
# Teen Titans #
# Let's go! #
# T-E-E-N #
# T-I-T-A-N-S #
# Teen Titans #
# Let's go! #