(ENGINES WHIRRING AND WHOOSHING)
PILOT: (OVER RADIO) Mayday, Mayday, this
is Hesper Two-Niner-Niner in distress.
BOY: Dad!
PILOT: Engines 1 and 2 are off-line!
We're losing her!
(RUMBLING)
PILOT: Go! Go!
(CRASHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(♪♪♪)
Dad!
(DEBRIS CLATTERING)
KITAI: I've heard stories of Earth.
A paradise.
Until we destroyed it.
(♪♪♪)
The founding of the United
Ranger Corps 1000 years ago
was a global military effort,
an evacuation of Earth.
The Rangers would lead the settlement
of mankind's new home.
Nova Prime.
But we were not alone.
The aliens released the Ursa.
(SCREECHING)
Monsters bred to kill humans.
Technically blind,
the Ursa sees humans
based on pheromones
we secrete when frightened.
They literally smell our fear.
Humankind was again
in danger of extinction
and again turned to the Rangers
for the answer.
That answer came in the form of
the prime commander, Cypher Raige,
the original ghost.
He is believed to be
so completely free of fear
that to an Ursa, he is invisible.
This phenomena is known
as "ghosting."
(♪♪♪)
This isn't a race, cadet!
MAN: Raige.
Your test scores are very impressive.
In the classroom,
you are an outstanding Ranger,
but in the field, you collapse.
I'm not advancing you.
You may try again next year.
Sir, I am dedicated, have studied
and display conduct
becoming of a Ranger, sir.
I request that the commander
reconsider his assessment, sir.
Cadet.
Sir, my father's returning home tonight.
I haven't seen him in...
It's a very special day for our family.
And I have got to be able to tell him
that I am a Ranger, sir.
You tell your father
that I said, "Welcome home."
Dismissed.
(♪♪♪)
Faia.
Hi.
How were finals?
I wasn't advanced to Ranger.
Where do we look when we speak?
I was not advanced to Ranger.
You were not advanced to Ranger...
I was not
advanced to Ranger, sir.
That's all right. You're young.
I ran the canyons 11 seconds
faster than you did.
You weren't ready. Velan's a good man.
He knows his stuff.
If you were, he would have promoted you.
You weren't ready.
I'm not hungry.
I'm going to my room.
Are you asking me or telling me?
May I go to my room?
Denied! Sit down!
I have a last visit to Iphitos.
I'm flying tomorrow,
supervising training.
And after it's completed,
I'm announcing my retirement.
Retirement?
Maybe I'll work with you
in Turbine Division.
Together.
Please, no.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
I want my family back.
I want you back.
That boy in there
is trying to find you.
He's a feeling boy.
He's an intuitive boy.
He watched you read that book
with Senshi his entire life.
He's reading that book now.
He's reaching for you.
Don't get me wrong. I respect
everything you've done.
But you have a son in the other
room that you do not know.
He blames himself
for what happened to Senshi.
He thinks it's his fault.
He's drowning.
And he does not need
a commanding officer.
He needs a father.
(♪♪♪)
Pack your bags. You're
coming with me to Iphitos.
FAIA: This was a really good decision.
Now go make some good
memories together.
You take it easy on your father.
He's a little rusty.
Okay.
General Raige.
I was on the plateau.
You saved me and four others.
I just came from seeing
my baby girl's face for the first time.
Stand me up.
That won't be necessary, Ranger.
(♪♪♪)
MAN: Watch the left side!
Pull!
Perimeter's good.
(♪♪♪)
I'm reading Moby Dick.
Your mother told me.
That's great.
MAN: (OVER SPEAKERS) Our military transport
will arrive at training base on Iphitos
in seven hours.
I'm going to grab some rack time.
I recommend you do the same.
Hey. Can you read?
(SNIFFS)
I said, can you read?
Yes, sir.
Well, there's a sign back there.
"Authorized personnel only."
Why didn't you read that?
What's in the cage?
Might wanna go easy on him, sarge.
That's the prime commander's son
right there.
You're Raige's kid?
What's in there?
You wanna see?
SENSHI: Kit, we have to go right now.
Is that...?
They surprised us.
Sent ships, dropped those things.
An Ursa?
MAN: We're taking it to
Iphitos for ghost training.
You want to see if you can ghost?
(♪♪♪)
MAN: Ghosting is when you don't
have a trace of fear in you.
Most guys freeze.
That's your cerebral cortex
looking for an answer it doesn't have.
See? Even your brain knows
you're screwed.
Your blood is filling
with adrenaline now,
whether you know it or not.
Your heart's beating faster.
It's getting a little
harder to breathe.
Your neurobiological system
is telling you to run
but your knees
are too weak to move.
And it's too late anyway.
The pores on your skin
have already opened up,
secreting an imperceptible amount
of pheromones into the air.
And all you can think about
is when it's going to kill you.
(CHUCKLES)
Senshi!
(ROARS)
She sees you, kid. Heh, heh.
Attention on deck.
Kitai. Back to
your seat, now.
Rangers, go Redcon-1.
Secure all cargo!
(CHATTERING)
Behind your seat, there's a life suit.
Put it on. Strap in, full harness.
Yes, sir.
Good evening, general.
Captain.
What's the last known position
of the closest asteroid storm?
Category-four
asteroid formation.
Two thousand kilometers to starboard
at plus-four-five declination.
I detected graviton vibrations
in the hull.
But you detected how?
Graviton buildup could be a precursor
to mass expansion.
That storm could be on us in minutes.
But, sir, mass expansion
is one in a million.
If we try to navigate out,
the pull of our own graviton weight
could set the thing off.
Let's just hold course
and hope I'm wrong.
Just out of interest, sir,
how often are you wrong?
My wife would give a very interesting
answer to that question.
(RAPID BEEPING)
Graviton count's decreasing.
Eight hundred parts per million.
Six hundred and fifty.
Well, sir, there's a first time
for everything.
(RUMBLING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(KLAXON BLARING)
CYPHER: Turn into it. Match bearing.
Dad!
She's a dead stick! Engines off-line!
We're losing her!
Can you travel us out of here?
Where?
The anchorage. Lycia. It's closest.
Negative, sir. We cannot
Wormhole travel in the middle of this.
Do it.
Coordinates for anchorage at Lycia
locked in. No confirmation signal.
Travel us now.
Without confirmation...
That's an order.
Go! Go!
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Cabin pressure dropping.
Heavy damage to outer hull.
Breach possible in middle cabin.
(ALARM CHIMING
AND PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Find me something I can land on. Now.
I got something.
Bearing three-four-zero
by nine-five,
range 86,000.
(♪♪♪)
COMPUTER: Warning. This planet has been
declared unfit for human habitation,
placed under class-one quarantine
by the interplanetary Authority.
Under penalty of law,
do not attempt to land.
Repeat, do not attempt to land.
It's not possible.
The computer might have defaulted
back to a known demarcation point.
No, not here.
Travel us again.
Negative, sir. This ship
is going to tear apart at any moment.
Set her down.
Mayday, Mayday, this is
Hesper Two-Niner-Niner in distress.
We took damage from an asteroid storm
and are going down with bingo power.
(HYPERVENTILATING)
Dad, Dad, Dad!
(CRASHING)
Dad!
(SCREAMS)
(♪♪♪)
(CRASHING)
(DEBRIS CLATTERING)
(INSECTS CHITTERING)
(GASPING)
(♪♪♪)
(CYPHER EXHALES)
You all right?
You stay there.
Evaluate.
Good to go.
Confirm the Ursa is contained.
The back of the ship is gone.
Rangers, count off.
Rangers, count off!
Kit.
The cockpit is directly above us.
Go.
Left rear, there's a utility compartment.
Inside
there's an emergency beacon.
Silver.
Like a saucer. Bring it to me.
(♪♪♪)
(GROANS)
CYPHER: Consolidate. Inventory up.
(GRUNTS)
General Cypher Raige.
We crash-landed.
Two confirmed survivors.
Kitai.
The emergency beacon you brought me will
fire a distress signal deep into space.
But it is damaged.
There is another one
in the tail section of our ship.
This is us here.
That is the tail,
somewhere in this area.
It's approximately 100 kilometers
from here.
We need that beacon.
Do you understand?
Both my legs are broken,
one very badly.
You are going to retrieve that beacon
or we are going to die.
Do you understand?
Repeat what I just said to you.
I have to go retrieve the beacon
or we're going to die.
You have air filtration inhalers.
You need to take one now.
The fluid will coat your lungs,
increasing oxygen extraction
allowing you to breathe comfortably
in the environment.
You have six vials.
At your weight, that should be 20 to 24 hours each.
That's more than enough.
Your life suit and backpack
are equipped
with digital and virtual imaging
so I will be able to see
everything that you see
and what you do not see.
I will guide you.
It will be like I'm right there with you.
Take my cutlass.
It's the C-40.
The full 22 configurations.
Kitai,
every single decision you make
will be life or death.
This is a class-one quarantined planet.
Everything on this planet
has evolved to kill humans.
Do you know where we are?
No, sir.
(♪♪♪)
This is Earth.
The Ursa?
Three possibilities. The first and most
likely is that it died in the crash.
The second and less likely is that it is
injured very badly and still contained.
The third and least likely is
that it is out.
We will proceed, however, in
anticipation of the worst-case scenario.
Every movement will be
under protocol Escape and Evade.
If he's out there
I will see him long before
he gets anywhere near you.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Do exactly as I tell you
and we will survive.
(♪♪♪)
CYPHER: Kitai, calm down.
Take a knee.
Root yourself
in this present moment now.
Sight, sound, smell.
What do you feel?
My body feels heavier.
Very good. Earth's gravitational pull
is different than at home.
Very good.
Now let's go.
(GRUNTING)
Whoa, whoa!
What happened?
You didn't see that?
Kitai, what happened?
I'm fine. No change. I just slipped.
There's condensation on the stones.
I'm good to go.
(BIRDS CHIRPING & SCREECHING)
(♪♪♪)
General Cypher Raige.
Initiating remote probe recon.
Primary target,
Ursa.
(♪♪♪)
I want to reiterate that your naviband
is our sole means of communication.
Roger.
The temperatures on this planet
fluctuate dangerously, Kitai.
And most of the planet
freezes over completely at night.
But there are hot spots,
geothermal nodes
between here and the tail
that will keep you warm
during the freeze-over.
You must reach one
of these hot spots
each evening before nightfall.
Is that understood?
Copy.
Standard operating procedure until
I give you further instructions. Stand by.
(SCANNER BEEPING)
KITAI: Dad, are you there?
SENSHI: Hey, Dad, are you there?
Dad,
you there?
Hello?
I'm here.
A boy I know had this.
Mm.
It's a real book. From a museum.
It's Moby Dick.
Mm-hm.
He said I could even hold on to it.
Hold on to what?
The book, Dad. Heh.
Oh.
Hm.
Did they really kill these whales?
We, Senshi, for their oil,
and they almost disappeared.
Just before the age of carbon fuels.
Where's your brother?
Kit.
Hey.
KITAI: Dad, are you there?
I'm here.
(♪♪♪)
(CREATURE GIBBERING)
Where are you?
(♪♪♪)
My suit's turned black.
I like it, but I think it's something bad.
Your suit is made of smart fabric.
It has motion sensors.
I'm tracking a life form
moving toward you from the west.
It's closing rapidly.
Fifty meters.
Forty.
Thirty.
Twenty.
Ten.
It is right there, Kitai.
(GASPS)
Do not move.
Recognize your power.
This will be your creation.
(LOW GROWLING)
Stand down, cadet.
Get out of here!
Kitai!
Control yourself, cadet!
(CREATURES SNARLING)
(CREATURES SCREECHING)
Kitai, stand down!
Get away!
Kitai!
To your rear. Out to your rear.
(♪♪♪)
There's a river
250 meters straight ahead. Go.
They are no longer in pursuit.
Cadet, you are not being followed.
I repeat, you are not being followed.
Kitai, you are running from nothing'.!
Kitai!
(CREATURE SCREECH ES
IN DISTANCE)
Kitai.
Put my damn cutlass away.
You are not being followed.
Take a knee.
Take a knee, cadet!
If you want to die today that is fine,
but you are not going to kill me.
(PANTS)
Kitai, I need you
to do a physical assessment.
You are showing rapid
blood contamination. Are you out?
I'm dizzy.
Kitai, self-eval.
(KITAI GRUNTING)
(♪♪♪)
(WHIMPERS)
Dad, I can't stand.
Open your med kit.
You are going to have to administer
the antitoxin in sequence.
Inject yourself with the
clear liquid first.
Do it now.
I can't see.
The poison is affecting
your nervous system. Stay even.
Dad, please come help me. I can't see.
I can't do this by myself, Dad.
Please come get me.
Kitai, inject yourself directly
into your heart with the first stage.
Do it now.
(♪♪♪)
(GROANS)
Now the second. ASAP.
(WHIMPERING)
To your left, Kitai.
Left!
I can't feel my hand.
Dad, I can't feel my hands.
Press it into the ground.
Roll over on it
and press it into the ground, Kitai.
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Great work, cadet.
But you are going to have to lie there
for a moment.
The parasite that stung you
has a paralyzing agent in its venom.
So you are going to have to lie there
for a little bit
while the antitoxin does its job.
(♪♪♪)
CYPHER: It's time to wake up.
Son.
The temperature is dropping
five degrees every 10 minutes.
You have got to wake up.
Can you blink your eyes?
Son.
I need you to please blink your eyes.
Hey, Dad.
Hey.
That sucked.
That is correct.
You've got 9.7 kilometers
to the hot spot.
How about you show me that 1 OK
in 50 minutes, cadet?
Sir, yes, sir.
Ten mikes out. All good.
(CYPHER GRUNTING)
Who wasn't advanced to Ranger?
Who was it?
Watch him go. Watch him go.
Five mikes out.
MAN: Five mikes out.
CYPHER: Happy 19th birthday, Senshi.
FAIA: Here.
Dad, you help me.
CYPHER: No, Senshi, you go ahead.
You blow.
Come on, Dad. Blow.
Now, you know there's no way
I can actually do that from here.
No. I think you can. Heh.
Faia, you're right there. Help the girl.
You can do it.
I know you can.
(BLOWS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hot Spot 1 arrival.
H plus 54 minutes.
(GROANING)
Equipment check and consolidate.
Take your next inhaler.
Your oxygen extraction is bottoming.
Take your next breathing fluid.
Second dose of breathing fluid
compete.
Mm.
Count off remaining.
Four vials remain, sir.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Repeat.
Four vials remain, sir.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
Dad.
Dad!
I'm here.
How did you do it?
How did you first ghost?
Out for a run.
Alone.
Something we're never
supposed to do.
Ursa de-camos right in front of me.
I go for my cutlass.
It shoots its pincer
right through my shoulder.
Next thing I know,
we're over the cliff, falling,
30 meters straight down
into the river.
We settle onto the bottom.
It's on top of me.
But it's not moving.
And I realize
He's trying to drown me.
I'm thinking, "I'm gonna die."
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
"I'm gonna die."
"I cannot believe
this is how I'm going to die."
I can see my blood bubbling up,
mixing with the sunlight
shining through the water.
And I think, "Wow...
that's really pretty."
And everything slows down.
And I see its pincer
through my shoulder.
And I decide
I don't want that in there anymore.
So I pull it out.
And he lets me go.
And more than that, I can tell...
it can't find me.
It doesn't even know where to look.
And it dawned on me...
fear is not real.
The only place that fear can exist
is in our thoughts of the future.
It is a product of our imagination,
causing us to fear things
that do not at present
and may not ever exist.
That is near insanity, Kitai.
Now, do not misunderstand me.
Danger is very real.
But fear is a choice.
(♪♪♪)
We are all telling ourselves a story.
And that day, mine changed.
CYPHER: Fourteen kilometers to the falls.
That's our midway checkpoint.
KITAI: I'm reading you.
(BLEEPING)
(♪♪♪)
CYPHER: Kitai, get to the falls ASAP.
(BLEEPING)
I hear something.
I think it's water. A lot of it.
(WATER FLOWING)
(♪♪♪)
CYPHER: Inventory up.
Roger.
Food rations, half available. Flares, full.
Med kit, half available. Breathing fluid...
Breathing fluid, four vials available.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Why are you not showing me
the case?
What?
Show it to me now.
I thought that I could make it, sir.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(TAKES DEEP BREATH)
(♪♪♪)
Abort mission.
Return to the ship.
That is an order.
SENSHI: Don't come out.
No matter what.
That's an order.
Dad!
(SENSHI SCREAMS)
Ah!
No, Dad.
I can do it. I don't need many.
I can get across with just two.
You need a minimum of three inhalers
to make it to the tail.
You have exhausted your resources.
I can get across.
I can do it with just two, Dad.
This mission has reached
abort criteria.
I take full responsibility.
You did your best.
You have nothing more to prove.
Now return to the ship.
(BEEPING)
What was your mistake?
Trusting me?
Depending on me,
thinking that I could do this?
I am giving you an order...
to turn around...
and return to this ship.
You wouldn't give any other Ranger
that order!
You are not a Ranger.
And I am giving you that order.
What was I supposed to do?
What did you want me to do?
She gave me an order!
She said no matter what,
don't come out of that box!
Was I supposed to just come out
and die?
What do you think, cadet?
What do you think
you should have done?
Because that is all that matters.
What do you think
you should have done?
And where were you?!
She called out for you!
She called your name!
And you weren't there,
because you're never there!
And you think I'm a coward?!
You're wrong!
I'm not a coward!
You're the coward!
Kitai!
(♪♪♪)
(BLEEPING)
Kitai, you've got incoming.
(BIRD SCREECHING)
Do you copy? You've got incoming.
(KITAI GRUNTING)
(BIRD SCREECHING)
Kitai, dive!
Dive!
(BIRD SCREECHING)
(KITAI GRUNTS)
Kitai!
(CHIRPING)
(GROWLING)
(♪♪♪)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(CHIRPING)
(CHICKS CHIRPING)
(ROARING)
No!
Leave them alone!
(ROARING
AND KITAI GRUNTING)
Get away!
(BIRD SCREECHING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(SCREECHING)
(SQUAWKING)
Dad, I'm sorry. It's Kitai.
Where is my son?
(BEEPING)
(CREATURE GROWLING)
(SQUAWKING)
(♪♪♪)
(SNORTING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(HISSES)
(MOUSE SQUEALING)
(BLEEPING)
General Cypher Raige.
This is a message for my wife.
Faia...
I have lost contact with our son.
End message.
CYPHER: You have six vials. At your weight,
that should be 20 to 24 hours each.
That's more than enough.
I estimate four days to reach the tail.
Let's break it into sections.
Six hours to reach
the first geothermal site.
The first leg, 20 K to the mouth
of the North Forest. I'm right here.
KITAI: Five mikes out.
CYPHER: Keep moving.
KITAI: Hot Spot 1 arrival.
CYPHER: Take your next inhaler.
KITAI: H plus 54 minutes.
CYPHER: There is an escarpment.
Looks like it could be a waterfall.
We'll call that midway.
I can get across. I can do it with two.
CYPHER: Fourteen kilometers to the falls.
This is us here.
That is the tail.
You are going to retrieve
that beacon
or we are going to die.
(♪♪♪)
(SNORTING)
(SQUAWKING)
(BIRD SQUAWKING)
Leave me alone!
(♪♪♪)
(PANTING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING
AND INSECTS CHITTERING)
(WHISPERING INAUDIBLY)
GIRL: Wake up.
It's time for you to wake up.
Hey.
I was just about to come out that day.
No, you weren't.
But you did the right thing.
Dad says I should have tried.
He's just mad at himself.
That's all.
Why couldn't you ghost?
You're close right now.
I am?
Are you scared?
No. I'm tired.
(CHUCKLES)
That's good.
You filled your heart
with something else.
Now you got to get up.
I memorized some of Moby Dick.
Kitai, get up.
"All that maddens and torments,
Wake up."
"All that stirs up lees of things,
"All truth with malice,
all that cracks the sinews..."
Wake up!
(♪♪♪)
(PANTING)
Kit...
(♪♪♪)
(GRUNTING)
(BODY DRAGGING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING
AND INSECTS CHITTERING)
Hey, thanks.
(♪♪♪)
(COUGHING)
(GASPING)
(♪♪♪)
(COUGHING)
(PANTING)
(WHEEZING)
(♪♪♪)
No.
Mm-mm.
(♪♪♪)
(BLEEPING)
KITAI: (OVER RADIO) Dad.
(VOICE BREAKING UP)
Dad, it's Kitai. I made it to...
Kitai.
Dad, I made it to the tail. Do you copy?
Kitai, I'm here.
Are you okay?
Dad, do you read me?
I copy.
Dad, I made it to the tail. Do you copy?
Kitai, we have electrical interference.
You are in a black zone.
I repeat, you are in a black...
Dad, the Ursa is not contained.
Please copy.
(♪♪♪)
Dad?
I'm here.
I swear to you I'm here.
(BLEEPING)
(BEEPING)
(DEVICE WHIRRING)
(KITAI GRUNTING)
(♪♪♪)
Take a knee.
It is the ionic layer...
in the atmosphere
above your current position.
It is causing electrical interference.
That is why the beacon is not firing.
To your north.
The peak.
You must fire the beacon
from the peak of that mountain.
See it, Kitai.
Please...
see it.
Good boy.
(♪♪♪)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
It is a pheromone trigger.
He set it to scare you,
so he can track you. Keep moving.
(BEEPING)
(♪♪♪)
It has found you.
(BLEEPING)
(BEEPING)
CYPHER: Run.
Just run, Kitai.
Just run.
(RAPID BEEPING)
(RAPID HEARTBEATS)
(SCREECHING)
Ah! Unh!
(GROWLING)
(SCREECHING)
Unh! Ah!
(COMPUTER BLEEPING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(URSA SCREECHING
AND KITAI SCREAMS)
Unh!
Ah!
(URSA SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
(WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING AND BEEPING)
(ROCKS CLATTERING)
(URSA SCREECHES)
Ah! Unh!
(ROARING)
(GROANING)
(BEEPING)
(COMPUTER WHIRRING)
(GROANING)
(URSA SCREECHING)
SENSHI: Climb in here, okay?
It won't be able to smell you.
(♪♪♪)
Dad!
(SOBBING)
(♪♪♪)
CYPHER: Root yourself in
this present moment now.
Sight, sound, smell.
What do you feel?
(URSA GROWLING)
(WHISPERING) You're still in that box.
It's time to come out.
(♪♪♪)
(URSA GROWLING)
(GROWLING)
(URSA SCREECHING)
(SCREECHING)
(♪♪♪)
Yah!
(URSA SCREECHING)
(SCREECHING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(WHIRRING)
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(♪♪♪)
Stand me up.
MAN: General.
I said, stand me up.
(GRUNTING)
Watch his back.
Dad?
Yeah?
I want to work with Mom.
(CYPHER CHUCKLING)
CYPHER: Me too.
(♪♪♪)
(MEDICS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(CHUCKLING)
(♪♪♪)