[Mysterious instrumental music]
[Crashing lightning bolts]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Doc screaming]
Doc.
[Doc shouting gleefully]
[Laughing]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Doc.
-Doc!
-What?
[Screams]
Relax, Doc. It's me! It's Marty.
It can't be.
I just sent you back to the future.
You did send me back to the future,
but I'm back.
I'm back from the future.
Great Scott!
[Thunder rumbling]
[Rain falling]
[Thunder cracking loudly]
[Soft instrumental music]
[Soft instrumental music continues]
BUFFALO BOB: Hey, kids, what time is it?
KIDS: Howdy Doody time!
SINGING ON TV: "It's Howdy Doody time"
DOC: Great Scott!
[Singing on TV continues]
Howdy Doody time?
Date: Sunday, November 13, 1955, 7:01 a.m.
Last night's time travel experiment
was apparently a complete success.
Lightning struck the clock tower
at 10:04 p.m...
...sending the necessary 1.21 gigawatts...
...into the time vehicle,
which vanished in a flash of light...
...leaving a pair of fire trails behind.
I assumed Marty and the time vehicle...
...were transported forward through time
to the year 1985.
After that, I can't recall what happened.
In fact, I don't even remember
how I got home.
Perhaps the gigawatt discharge
and the temporal displacement field...
...generated by the vehicle caused
a disruption of my own brain waves...
...resulting in a condition of momentary amnesia.
I now recall that moments
after the time vehicle disappeared...
...into the future...
...I saw a vision of Marty
saying he had come back from the future.
Hey, Doc.
Undoubtedly, this was some residual image.
[Doc screaming]
Doc, calm down. It's me. It's Marty.
It can't be you. I sent you back to the future!
That's right, but I came back again
from the future. Don't you remember?
You fainted. I brought you home.
This can't be happening! You can't be here!
It doesn't make sense!
I refuse to believe you are here!
MARTY: I am here, and it does make sense.
I came back to 1955 again with you.
The you from 1985
is waiting to get a book from Biff!
Once I got the book,
the you from 1985 were in the DeLorean...
...and it got struck by lightning,
and you got sent back to 1885!
DOC: 1885?
It's a very interesting story, future boy...
...but there's one thing that doesn't make sense.
If the me of the future is now in the past,
how could you possibly know about it?
You sent me a letter.
DOC:
"Dear Marty, if my calculations are correct...
"...you will receive this letter immediately after
the DeLorean's struck by lightning.
"First, let me assure you I am alive and well.
"I've been living happily
these past eight months in the year 1885.
"The lightning bolt that hit the DeLorean...
"...caused an overload
which scrambled the time circuits...
"...activated the flux capacitor
and sent me back to 1885.
"The overload shorted out the time circuits...
"...and destroyed the flying circuits.
Unfortunately, the car will never fly again."
It actually flew?
Yeah. We had a hover conversion done
in the early 21st century.
Incredible!
"I set myself up as a blacksmith
as a front...
"...while I attempted to repair the damage
to the time circuits.
"Unfortunately, this proved impossible...
"...because suitable replacement parts
will not be invented until 1947.
"However, I've gotten quite adept
at shoeing horses and fixing wagons."
1885! Amazing!
I actually end up as a blacksmith
in the Old West.
Pretty heavy.
DOC: "I have buried the DeLorean
in the abandoned Delgado Mine...
"...adjacent to the old Boot Hill Cemetery
as shown on the enclosed map.
"Hopefully, it should remain undisturbed
and preserved until you uncover it in 1955.
"Inside, you will find repair instructions.
"My 1955 counterpart..." That's me.
"Should have no problem repairing it
so that you can drive it back to the future.
"Once you have returned to 1985,
destroy the time machine."
-Destroy it?
-It's a long story, Doc.
"I repeat, do not attempt
to come back here to get me.
"I am perfectly happy living in the fresh air...
"...and wide-open spaces.
"I fear that unnecessary time travel...
"...only risks further disruption
of the space-time continuum.
"And please take care of Einstein for me."
Einstein?
MARTY: He's your dog, Doc.
Einstein is what you call your dog in 1985.
"I know you will give him a good home.
"Remember to walk him twice a day
and that he only likes canned dog food.
"These are my wishes.
Please respect and follow them.
"And so, Marty, I now say farewell
and wish you Godspeed.
"You've been a good,
kind, and loyal friend to me...
"...and you made a real difference
in my life.
"I will always treasure our relationship
and think of you with fond memories...
"...warm feelings and a special place
in my heart.
"Your friend in time, Doc Emmett L. Brown.
"September 1, 1885."
I never knew I could write
anything so touching.
I know, it's beautiful.
[Dog whining]
It's all right, Copernicus. Everything will be fine.
I'm sorry.
It's all my fault you're stuck back there.
I never should've let Biff get to me.
There are plenty worse places to be
than the Old West.
I could have ended up in the Dark Ages.
They probably would have burned me
at the stake as a heretic.
Let's look at the map.
According to this, the time vehicle
is sealed off in a side tunnel.
We may have to blast.
MARTY: Whoa!
I think you woke up the dead with that blast.
Take this camera. I want to document everything!
DOC: This reminds me of the time I attempted
to reach the center of the Earth.
I'd been reading my favorite author,
Jules Verne.
I spent weeks preparing that expedition.
I didn't even get this far.
Of course, I was only 12 at the time.
You know, it was the writings of Jules Verne...
...that had a profound effect on my life.
When I was 11, I first read
20,000 Leagues Under the Sea.
It was then that I realized
I must devote my life to science.
MARTY: Check it out. Look at this.
DOC: My initials!
Just like in
Journey to the Center of the Earth!
That means the time machine
must be right through this wall!
DOC: It's been buried in here for 70 years,
two months and 13 days.
Astounding!
MARTY: "As you see, the lightning bolt
shorted out the time-circuit control chip.
"The attached..."
Schematic.
"Schematic diagram will allow you
to build a replacement unit...
"...with 1955 components, thus restoring
the time machine to perfect working order."
Unbelievable that this little piece of junk
could be such a big problem.
No wonder this circuit failed.
It says, "Made in Japan."
What do you mean, Doc?
All the best stuff is made in Japan.
Unbelievable!
[Motor grinding]
DOC: You know, when I was a kid,
I always wanted to be a cowboy.
Now, knowing I'm spending my future
in the past...
...it sounds like a wonderful way
to spend my retirement years.
It just occurred to me, since I end up in 1885...
...perhaps I'm now in the history books.
I wonder.
Could I look myself up
in the old newspaper archives?
MARTY: I don't know.
You always say it's not good
to know too much about your own destiny.
You're right, Marty. I know too much already.
Better that I not attempt to uncover
the circumstances of my own future.
Copernicus. Come on, boy!
MARTY: I'll get him.
Copernicus!
Come on. Let's go home, boy.
What's wrong?
What's wrong, Copernicus?
Come on, let's go.
MARTY: [Desperate] Doc, come here!
Quick!
What's wrong?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
You're not far off, Doc.
Great Scott!
Check this out.
"Died September 7, 1885."
That's one week after you wrote the letter!
"Erected in eternal memory
by his beloved Clara."
Who the hell is Clara?
-Please don't stand there!
-Right. Sorry.
I have to get another picture.
DOC: "Shot in the back by Buford Tannen
over a matter of $80"?
What kind of a future do you call that?
MARTY:
"Buford Tannen was a notorious gunman...
"...whose short temper and a tendency to drool...
"...earned him the nickname 'Mad Dog.'
"He was quick on the trigger
and bragged he had killed 12 men...
"...not including Indians or Chinamen."
DOC: Does it name me? Am I one of the 12?
MARTY: Wait.
"This claim cannot be proven
since precise records were not kept...
"...after Tannen shot a newspaper editor...
"...who printed an unfavorable story
about him in 1884."
MARTY: That's why we can't find anything.
DOC: Look.
DOC: William McFly and family.
Your relatives?
MARTY: My great-grandfather's name
was William. That's him. Good-Iooking guy.
DOC: McFlys, but no Browns.
Maybe it was a mistake.
Maybe that grave wasn't yours.
There could've been
another Emmett Brown in 1885.
Did you have any relatives here back then?
The Browns didn't come to Hill Valley
until 1908. Then they were the von Brauns.
My father changed our name
during World War I.
MARTY: Look.
[Doc gasps]
Great Scott, it's me!
Then it is true, all of it.
It is me who goes back there and gets shot.
It's not gonna happen, Doc.
After you fix the time circuits
and put new tires on the DeLorean...
...I'm going back to 1885,
and I'm bringing you home.
DOC: The clothes fit?
MARTY: Everything except the boots.
They're kind of tight.
Are you sure this stuff is authentic?
Of course.
Haven't you ever seen a Western?
Yeah, I have.
Clint Eastwood never wore anything like this.
-Clint who?
-Right. You haven't heard of him yet.
You have to wear the boots.
You can't wear those futuristic things
back in 1885.
You shouldn't be wearing them
here in 1955.
-As soon as I get there, I'll put them on.
-Okay.
I think we're about ready.
I put gas in the tank.
Your future clothes are packed.
Just in case,
fresh batteries for your walkie-talkies.
What about that floating device?
MARTY: Hoverboard.
DOC: All right.
It's gonna be a long walk
back to Hill Valley from here.
It's still the safest plan.
We can't risk sending you back
into a populated area...
...or to a spot that's geographically unknown.
You don't want to crash into some tree
that existed in the past.
This was all completely open country...
...so you'll have plenty of runout space
when you arrive.
Remember, where you're going,
there are no roads.
There's a small cave over there which will be
a good place to hide the time vehicle.
The new time-circuit control tubes
are warmed up.
Time circuits on.
I wrote the letter on September 1,
so we'll send you to...
...September 2, that's a Wednesday.
September 2, 1885, 8:00 a.m.
I get shot on Monday the 7th.
You have five days to locate me.
According to my letter, I'm a blacksmith,
so I probably have a shop somewhere.
All you got to do is drive the time vehicle...
...directly toward that screen,
accelerating to 88 miles an hour.
MARTY: Wait a minute.
If I drive straight towards the screen,
I'll crash into those Indians.
DOC:
Marty, you're not thinking fourth dimensionally.
You'll instantly be transported to 1885
and those Indians won't even be there.
Right.
Good luck, for both of our sakes.
See you in the future.
-You mean the past.
-Exactly.
[Adventurous instrumental music]
[Engine starting]
DOC: Happy trails, Marty!
[Revving engine]
DOC: Ready, Marty?
Ready!
-Set!
-Hi-ho, Silver.
[Revving engine]
[Shouting in Spanish]
[Adventurous instrumental music]
[Indians whooping]
Indians!
[Indian drum beat pounds rhythmically]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Screaming]
MARTY: The cave!
CAVALRYMAN: Charge!
[Bugle playing battle call]
Shit! The cavalry!
[Cavalry shouting]
[Bugle playing battle call]
[Sighing]
[Sniffs]
[Liquid pouring]
Damn, I ripped the fuel line.
[Bear moaning]
[Marty screams]
[Screaming]
[Roaring]
[Shouting]
[Sheep bleating]
Maggie! Fetch some water!
We got a hurt man here.
Mom.
MARTY: Mom, is that you?
MAGGIE: There, there.
You've been asleep for nearly six hours.
I had this horrible nightmare.
I dreamed I was in a Western.
I was being chased by all these Indians...
...and a bear.
MAGGIE: You're safe and sound now
here at the McFly farm.
"McFly farm"?
[Marty shouts]
You're my...
-Who are you?
-The name is Maggie McFly.
McFly?
Maggie?
And that's Mrs. McFly,
and don't you be forgetting the "Mrs."
MAGGIE: What might your name be, sir?
MARTY: It's...
Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood.
You hit your head, Mr. Eastwood.
Not too serious, but lucky for you
Seamus found you when he did.
Seamus.
Me husband.
[Baby squealing]
You'll be excusing me, while I tend to William.
William.
MAGGIE: That's okay, Will.
[Baby crying]
MARTY: That's William?
MAGGIE: Aye.
William Sean McFly,
the first of our family to be born in America.
MAGGIE: It's okay, Will.
This here is Mr. Clint Eastwood visiting.
He sure likes you.
Maggie.
I've got supper.
SEAMUS: I'm not one to pry
into a man's personal affairs...
...but exactly how is it
you came to be way out here...
...without a horse, or boots, or a hat?
Well, my...
...horse broke down and a bear ate my boots...
...and I just forgot my hat.
How could you forget a thing like your hat?
-Would you like some water?
-Yeah.
I'll tell you what I'll do, Mr. Eastwood.
I'll help you find your blacksmith friend.
You can stay the night in the barn...
...and tomorrow I'll take you
as far as the railroad tracks.
You can follow them straight into town.
I'll even give you a hat.
That's great. Thanks.
[Baby crying]
[Seamus exclaiming appreciatively]
SEAMUS: That's my William.
Wee Willy.
Yes.
I think you'll find the barn comfortable.
Never had any complaints about it
from the pigs.
MAGGIE: Seamus.
MAGGIE: A word with you.
SEAMUS: Aye.
SEAMUS: Will you hold him for a minute?
Are you sure you're not bringing a curse
on this house taking him in like that?
-He's such a strange young man.
-Aye, but I've just got a feeling about him.
Looking after him is the right thing to do.
That's important.
MARTY: Hey, buddy.
Look how the baby takes to him.
Little Will never takes to strangers.
It's almost as if he's connected to us.
MARTY: Hey, Will.
So you're my great-grandfather.
The first McFly born in America.
[Sound of trickling]
And you peed on me.
[Marty panting]
[Whistling]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Chickens clucking]
MAN 1: Give us some soap.
MAN 2: Here you go.
[Piano music plays]
[Heavy thudding]
[Horse snorts]
[Donkey braying]
[Gun fires]
Take a look and see
what just breezed in the door.
I didn't know the circus was in town.
Must have got that shirt off a dead Chinese.
[Men laughing]
[Spits]
What will it be, stranger?
I'll have...
MARTY:	..ice water.
OLD MAN: Ice water?
[Men laughing]
BARMAN: Water?
You want water, you better dunk your head
in the horse trough out there.
In here, we pour whiskey.
-Excuse me.
-For what?
MARTY: I'm trying to find a blacksmith.
TANNEN: Hey, McFly!
Thought I told you never to come in...
You ain't Seamus McFly.
You look like him, though,
especially with that dog-ugly hat.
[All laughing]
You kin to that hay barber?
-What's your name, dude?
-Marty...
Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood.
[Laughing]
-What kind of stupid name is that?
-He's the runt of the litter.
Boys, would you look-see
at these pearly whites?
I ain't seen teeth that straight
that weren't store-bought.
Take a gander at them moccasins.
What kind of skins is them?
THUG 1: What's that writing mean?
THUG 2: "Nike"? Is that Indian talk?
[Laughing]
Bartender, I'm looking for that no-good,
cheating blacksmith.
-You seen him?
-No, sir, Mr. Tannen. I have not.
Tannen.
You're Mad Dog Tannen.
TANNEN: "Mad Dog"?
I hate that name.
I hate it, you hear?
Nobody calls me "Mad Dog"!
Especially not some duded-up,
egg-sucking gutter trash.
Dance! Come on!
TANNEN: Come on, runt!
You can dance better than that!
Shit.
[Marty whoops]
[Grunts]
-You better run, squirrel.
-Get him!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Women shrieking]
[Marty shouts]
[Marty screaming]
[Thugs whooping gleefully]
TANNEN: We got ourselves a new courthouse.
It's high time we had a hanging!
[Cheering]
[Marty grunting]
[Gagging]
[Thugs cheering]
THUG 1: Look at him sway.
TANNEN:
Yeah, haven't had a hanging in a long time!
DOC: I shoot the fleas off a dog's back
at 500 yards, Tannen...
...and it's pointed at your head!
TANNEN: You owe me money, blacksmith.
DOC: How do you figure?
My horse threw a shoe.
You done the shoeing,
so that makes you responsible.
Since you never paid me for the job,
I'd say that makes us even.
Wrong!
I was on my horse when it happened,
and I got throwed off!
That caused me to bust a perfectly
good bottle of fine Kentucky redeye.
The way I figure it, blacksmith,
you owe me $5 for the whiskey...
...and $75 for the horse!
That's the $80.
If your horse threw a shoe,
bring him back and I'll reshoe him.
I shot that horse!
-That's your problem, Tannen.
-Wrong. That's yours.
From now on,
you better be looking behind you when you walk.
Because one day you're gonna get
a bullet in your back.
Doc!
Marty, I gave you explicit instructions
not to come here...
...but to go directly back to 1985.
I know, but I had to come.
It's good to see you, Marty.
DOC: You've got to do something
about those clothes.
-Dressed like that, you're liable to get shot.
-Or hanged.
DOC: What idiot dressed you in that outfit?
You did.
DOC: "Shot in the back by Buford Tannen
over a matter of $80"?
"September 7"?
That's this Monday!
Now I wish I'd paid him off.
Who's this "beloved Clara"?
I don't know anyone named Clara.
I don't know, Doc.
I thought maybe she was a girlfriend of yours.
My involvement in such a social relationship...
...here in 1885...
...could result in a disruption
of the space-time continuum.
As a scientist...
...I can never take that risk.
Certainly not after
what we've already been through.
MAYOR: Emmett! Hello, Emmett.
DOC: Hubert.
It's the mayor.
Excuse me, Emmett.
Do you remember last week
when you volunteered...
...to meet the new schoolteacher
at the station?
DOC: Yes, quite so.
We just got word she's coming in tomorrow.
Here are the details for you.
MAYOR: Thanks for all your help.
DOC: Anytime, Hubert.
MAYOR: Oh!
Her name's Miss Clara Clayton.
[Machine chugging loudly]
MARTY: Well, Doc...
...now we know who Clara is.
Marty, it's impossible.
The idea that I could fall in love
at first sight is romantic nonsense.
There's no scientific rationale
for that concept.
It's not science.
You meet the right girl, it hits you like lightning.
Please, don't say that.
That's the way it was for me and Jennifer.
We couldn't keep our eyes off each other.
God, Jennifer, I hope she's all right.
I can't believe we just left her on the porch.
Don't worry. She'll be fine.
When you burned the almanac in 1955,
the normal timeline was restored.
Once we're back in 1985...
...you just have to go to her house
to wake her up.
[Whistling]
DOC: Turn that valve over there,
all the way to the right.
Yeah, pull it all the way around.
Let's go!
DOC: Ice tea?
MARTY: No, thanks.
It's a refrigerator.
I guess Miss Clayton
will have to find other transportation.
If I never meet her, there's no possibility
of a romantic infatuation.
-You're the doc.
-All right.
DOC:
We'll get the DeLorean and get back to the future.
I tore a hole in the gas tank
when I was landing...
...so we'll have to patch it up
and get some gas.
You mean, we're out of gas?
MARTY: Yeah. It's no big deal.
We've got Mr. Fusion, right?
Mr. Fusion powers the time circuits
and the flux capacitor.
But the internal combustion engine
runs on ordinary gasoline.
It always has.
There won't be a gas station around here
until sometime in the next century.
Without gasoline,
we can't get the DeLorean up to 88 mph.
[Ominous instrumental music]
MARTY: So what do we do?
[Adventurous instrumental music]
-Twenty-four!
-It's no use, Marty!
Even the fastest horse in the world
won't run more than 35, 40 miles an hour!
MARTY:
Bartender said that's the strongest stuff they got.
Try it, Marty.
[Engine stalling]
[Engine chugging]
Give it more gas!
[Engine dies]
DOC: Damn!
It blew the fuel injection manifold.
Strong stuff, all right.
It will take me a month to rebuild it.
A month?
-You're gonna get shot on Monday!
-I know!
I wish...
Wait.
I've got it! We can roll it down a steep hill!
We'll never find a smooth enough surface.
Unless...
Of course! Ice!
We'll wait until winter
when the lake freezes over.
MARTY: Winter? What are you saying?
Monday is three days away!
All right. Let's just think
this thing through logically.
We know it won't run under its own power.
We know we can't pull it.
But if we could figure out a way...
...to push it up to 88 miles an hour...
[Train whistle blowing]
That's it.
How fast can she go?
Why, I've had her up to 55 myself.
I heard that Fearless Frank Fargo
got one of these up to near 70...
...out past Verde Junction.
Do you think it's possible to get it up to 90?
Ninety? Tarnation.
Who would ever need to be in such a hurry?
Just a little bet he and I have, that's all.
Theoretically speaking, could it be done?
I suppose, if you had a straight
stretch of track with a level grade...
...and you weren't hauling no cars...
...and if you could get the fire hot enough.
I'm talking about hotter than the blazes
of Hell itself.
It might be possible to get her up that fast.
When does the next train come through?
Monday morning at 8:00.
Here. This spur that runs
off the main line 3 miles out to Clayton Ravine.
It's a long stretch of level track
that will still exist in 1985.
This is where we'll push the DeLorean
with the locomotive.
Funny. This map calls Clayton Ravine
"Shonash Ravine."
That must be the old Indian name for it.
It's perfect.
A long run that goes
across the bridge over the ravine...
...over near that Hilldale housing development.
Right, but according to this map...
...there is no bridge.
MARTY:
Well, Doc, we can scratch that idea.
We can't wait for this thing to get finished.
DOC: Marty, it's perfect.
DOC:
You're not thinking fourth dimensionally.
MARTY:
Right. I have a problem with that.
DOC:
Don't you see? The bridge will exist in 1985.
It's safe and still in use.
As long as we get the DeLorean
up to 88 miles an hour...
...before we hit the edge of the ravine...
...we'll instantaneously arrive at a point
in time where the bridge is completed.
We'll have track under us
and coast safely across the ravine.
MARTY: What about the train?
DOC: It will be a spectacular wreck.
Too bad no one will be around to see it.
[Woman screaming]
CLARA: Help me!
DOC: Great Scott!
[Horses neighing]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
CLARA: Hurry!
DOC: Jump!
[Clara shouts]
[Clara panting]
Thank you, sir. You saved my...
...life.
Emmett Brown at your service, Miss...
Clayton.
Clara Clayton.
Clara?
What a beautiful name.
[Soft instrumental music]
DOC: May I help you inside with these?
That won't be necessary. I can take care of it.
-You've done more than enough already.
-But it's really no trouble.
She says it's fine, and we have to get going.
Ma'am, good luck
with your school teaching and everything.
Clara.
I'll straighten everything out
for the buckboard rental.
Don't worry about that.
I feel somewhat responsible for what happened.
That would be very gentlemanly of you,
Mr. Brown. Emmett.
You know, I'm almost glad
that snake spooked those horses.
Otherwise, we might never have met.
I suppose it was destiny.
Thank you for everything.
You're quite welcome.
I will see you again, won't I?
Of course. You'll see lots of me.
I have a shop in town.
I'm the local scientist, I mean, blacksmith.
What sort of science?
Astronomy? Chemistry?
Actually, I'm a student of all sciences.
Doc, we have to get going.
Yes. Excuse us, Clara.
We have to get going.
Toodle-oo.
What do you mean,
you'll be seeing lots of her?
I might see her again just in passing.
Did you see the way she was looking at you?
She did have quite a scare, right?
Miss Clayton almost ended up
at the bottom of Clayton Ravine.
Holy shit.
Clayton Ravine was named after a teacher.
-They say she fell in there 100 years ago.
-100 years ago!
-That's this year!
-Every kid knows that story.
We all have teachers we'd like to see
fall into the ravine.
Great Scott!
Then she was supposed to go over
in that wagon.
Now I may have seriously altered history.
Look, Doc, what's the worse that can happen?
So they don't name the ravine after her.
Let's get the DeLorean ready
and get out of here.
I wish I'd never invented
that infernal time machine.
It's caused nothing but disaster.
Doc, this is Marty.
Do you read me? Over.
Check, Marty.
MARTY: Great. These things still work.
All right. Once more,
let's go over the entire plan and layout.
-I apologize for the crudity of this model...
-Yeah, it's not to scale. It's okay.
All right. Tomorrow night, Sunday...
...we load the DeLorean
onto the tracks here, on the spur...
...by the abandoned silver mine.
The switch track is where the spur runs
off the main line...
...three miles out to Clayton... Shonash Ravine.
The train leaves the station
at 8:00 Monday morning.
We'll stop it, uncouple the cars,
throw the switch track and then hijack...
...borrow the locomotive and use it
to push the time machine.
According to my calculations we'll reach
88 mph just before we hit...
...the edge of the ravine,
at which point we'll be transported back to 1985...
...and coast safely across the completed bridge.
What does this mean? "Point of no return."
That's our fail-safe point.
Till there, we have time to stop the locomotive
before it plunges into the ravine.
But once we pass this windmill,
it's the future or bust.
DOC: Here you go.
Connect that to the positive terminal.
DOC: All right, you all set?
MARTY: Yeah. Go!
DOC: Train pulling out of the station!
Coming up to the switch track!
Stop at the switch track!
Throw the switch!
Pull up to the DeLorean!
Pushing the DeLorean...
...up to 88 miles per hour!
[Whistle blowing]
It couldn't be simpler.
[Door creaking]
CLARA: Emmett?
It's Clara.
Quick, cover the DeLorean!
CLARA: Hello.
DOC: Why, hello.
DOC: This is quite a surprise.
I hope I'm not disturbing anything.
We were just doing a little model railroading.
When my bags were thrown from the wagon...
...my telescope was damaged.
Since you mentioned an interest in science...
...I thought you might be able to repair it for me.
I would pay you, of course.
I wouldn't think of charging you for this.
Let's have a look at it.
CLARA:
I think a lens may be out of alignment because...
...if you move it this way the image turns fuzzy.
See?
But if you turn it the other way...
...then...
Everything becomes...
...clear.
[Clearing throat]
I could repair it right away
and have it for you tonight.
Tonight is the town festival.
I wouldn't dream of having you work
on my telescope during such an occasion.
You are planning on attending, aren't you?
-Actually, ma'am...
-Yes, of course. The festival.
In that case,
I'll see you this evening at the festival.
CLARA: Mr. Eastwood.
MARTY: Ma'am.
Thank you for taking care of my telescope.
DOC: You're quite welcome.
It's a nice telescope.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...as mayor of Hill Valley...
...it gives me great pleasure
to dedicate this clock...
...to the people of Hill County!
May it stand for all time!
Tell me when, gentlemen.
[Drum-roll plays]
CROWD: Three! Two! One!
Now!
[Band plays]
[All applauding]
MAYOR: Let the festivities begin!
In a way, it's fitting that you and I
are here to witness this.
It's too bad I didn't bring my camera.
Ready, gentlemen?
The only problem is,
we'll never be able to show it to anybody.
Smile, Doc.
[Man shouting gleefully]
[Band plays folk music]
[People whooping]
What great music!
Yeah, it's got a beat, and you can dance to it.
Step right up and test your mettle
with the latest products...
...from Col. Samuel Colt's Patent
Firearms Manufacturing Company...
...of Hartford, Connecticut.
Now, take this model, for example.
The new,
improved and refined Colt Peacemaker...
...selling to you tonight for the low price of $12.
-Good evening.
-'Evening.
You look very nice.
Thank you.
Would you like...
-Would you care to...
-I'd love to.
Young man, you want to give it a try?
MARTY: No, thanks.
Doc, this...
Son!
-Sonny boy!
-Doc can dance?
Son.
SALESMAN: I just told you that even a baby
could handle this weapon.
SALESMAN: Surely you're not afraid to try.
MARTY: I'm not afraid of nothing.
Come on, then.
Just step up here like a man.
Now, young man, what you do
is just ease that hammer back and...
...squeeze off a round.
Right on out there and be real smooth.
That's the way you do it.
[Chortling]
-Can I try that again?
-Yeah, go ahead.
Tell me one thing.
Where did you learn to shoot like that?
7-Eleven.
Buford, you sure that blacksmith
will be at this shindig?
Sure he's here. Everybody's here tonight.
You'll have to check your firearms
if you want to join in on the festivities.
[Tannen laughing]
TANNEN: Who's gonna make us, tenderfoot?
MARSHAL: I am.
TANNEN: Marshal Strickland.
I didn't know you was back in town.
If you can't read the sign,
I presume you can read this.
Pretty tough hombre when you're pointing
a gun at a man's back.
Just like you, I take every advantage I can get.
You gonna check your iron?
I was just joking with your deputy.
Of course, I'm gonna check my iron.
TANNEN: We all were, weren't we, boys?
THUGS: Yeah, right.
DEPUTY: Tannen.
Your knife, too.