[MEN SPEAKlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[ALL GRUNTlNG]
[MEN SHOUTlNG]
[GRUNTlNG]
Jackson, you really going to Hong Kong?
l love anything with full contact.
Need a few more scars on my face.
l heard you can get killed at that kumite.
Only if you fuck up. Unh.
[BOTH GRUNT]
[LAUGHS]
Tomorrow we leave for the kumite.
Sir?
Excuse me, but Colonel Cooke would like
to see you before you leave on furlough.
What's the problem?
The colonel found out
you're going to Hong Kong.
-He wants to talk to you about it.
-Tell him l'll be right there...
...after l take a shower.
But l'll have to wait, sir.
Okay.
What's taking so long, captain?
[WATER RUNNlNG]
Captain?
Shit.
Sir.
-Where's Dux?
-He was at the gym, like you said.
He took a shower, l waited,
and he disappeared.
-What do you mean, he disappeared?
-One minute he was there, next he wasn't.
lf anything happens to Dux
in Hong Kong....
Get Helmer and Rawlins on this
right away.
And l don't wanna see your face again
until Dux is beside it. Understand?
[SlGHS]
-How is he?
-He's resting now.
He'll be so happy to see you.
lt's so good to be here again.
l'll tell him you are here.
Thank you.
BOY 1 :
Wow! Look at the sword.
BOY 2:
Let's get it.
Come on, Frank.
What's the matter, you chicken?
-No.
BOY 1 : Then get in here.
BOY 2: Hey, Frank, you wanna hang
out with us, then come on.
You just gonna stand there
or are you gonna grab something?
[DOOR OPENS]
Shit. They're coming back.
Let's get out of here.
-Come on, Frank.
BOY 2: Forget him. Let's go.
That's enough, Shingo.
Go do your studies.
You cannot get katana sword by stealing.
lt is a very special sword.
You must earn it.
l wasn't going to steal it.
You didn't flinch.
You have fighting spirit.
You're not gonna call the cops?
Not if we make a deal.
What kind of a deal?
TANAKA: Your son and my son
are in the same school.
Frank sees my son's skill.
And he desires
to learn martial science too.
MR. DUX: Yes, but what do you mean
by "martial science"?
Frank tell me you came to America
to grow vine.
Yes, that's right.
l work at the Verne vineyard.
l came here to grow fish in my hatchery.
We both grow children.
You use science
to make vines grow better.
Like vines, children need training.
Martial science
provides a way of training.
Brings mind, body, spirit together.
That's enough.
-That's all for today.
-Not yet.
Why don't you quit, round-eye?
Not yet.
Go practice your katas.
How come you coach him, but not me?
l brought you here to help me train my son.
Don't question me.
lf you expect me to be his punching bag,
you can forget about our deal.
[BOYS SHOUTlNG]
Yeah! Throw a punch.
[CHlLDREN SHOUTlNG]
Someday...
...l'll fight in the kumite
and make my father proud.
FRANK: Shidoshi, l feel like l've lost
a part of my family too.
Shingo and l were close friends,
like brothers.
And you and Mrs. Tanaka...
...have treated me like a son.
What will happen now?
No more training.
l stop now.
But you have so much to teach.
You don't understand.
ln the war, l lost my first family:
my son, daughter and wife.
They lived in Hiroshima.
l left Japan because of the war.
War was wrong.
l came here to start over...
...begin a new family, have a son.
Another chance to pass on the teaching.
For 2000 years...
...knowledge passed from father to son...
...father to son.
When Shingo died...
...it stopped.
Teach me. l can do it.
You are not Japanese.
You are not a Tanaka!
You taught me
using any technique that works...
...never to limit myself to one style...
...to keep an open mind.
Why?
To honor you, shidoshi.
[FRANK GRUNTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[GRUNTS]
[FRANK GRUNTS]
[lNHALES DEEPLY]
[EXHALES]
[GRUNTS]
Practice until you can meditate...
...and nothing can distract you...
...so that you see and feel nothing...
...except your own energy.
[FRANK EXHALES]
[SCREAMlNG]
[GRUNTlNG]
Are you awake, shidoshi?
Do you sleep with your eyes open?
How are you feeling?
[SlGHS]
Like an old man.
And how about you?
l'm going to Hong Kong.
You sure you want to do this?
To honor you means everything to me.
l have poured all my knowledge into you.
When you fight,
my spirit will fight with you.
ln kumite, you will need it.
JACKSON: Hey, babe,
wanna go out with a real big man?
No, huh?
Too handsome for you, huh, honey?
WOMAN:
This your first time in Hong Kong?
You two are here for the kumite,
aren't you?
Kumite? What is kumite?
Look, guys,
l know there's a secret full-contact event...
...being held in Hong Kong
in the next few days.
Yes. Hong Kong is an exciting city.
l also happen to know a little bit
about some of your competition.
Okay. Um....
Would you just tell me
how you got invited?
[MEN SPEAKlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Thanks, guys.
[LAUGHS]
[ARCADE GAME BEEPS]
What?
Think you can give me some competition?
Sure. l'll try.
That's what l like to hear,
a kid who isn't afraid to lose.
No, no, l got it.
l don't want to take your money.
-You ready?
-Yeah.
[GAME PLAYlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
-You like this kind of fighting, huh?
-Yeah.
lf you want to see some real fighting,
you can see me fight at the kumite.
l'm here, too, for the kumite.
Aren't you a little young for full contact?
Aren't you a little old for video games?
-You want to go at it again, huh?
-Yeah.
[JACKSON SlGHS]
Not bad, kid. Name's Ray Jackson.
l'm Frank Dux.
Ms. Tanaka....
-Mrs. Tanaka?
-Yes?
HELMER: Mrs. Tanaka, it's very important
to the government of the United States...
...that we find Frank Dux.
We understand that he might have visited
Mr. Tanaka here recently.
Mr. Tanaka is very ill.
We're sorry to hear that.
Was Frank here recently?
Frank came here to pay his respects.
-When was that?
-Two days ago.
Did he say or do you know
if he was going to Hong Kong?
l don't know.
Of course you know.
Look, we're not trying to--
Mrs. Tanaka,
we're very sorry to have disturbed you.
Thank you very much for your time.
MAN: May l help you?
JACKSON: How you doing?
My name's Jackson. This is Mr. Frank Dux.
Are our rooms ready?
Mr. Lin in Room 31 0
wants to see you after you check in.
Who the hell's Mr. Lin?
l'm Lin. You Jackson?
You look like a Jackson.
That would make you Frank Dux.
No, no, no. lt's Dux.
Gotcha. Like "Put up your dukes," right?
Okay, so here's the deal.
This is the biggest kumite ever.
We got fighters from all over.
l've been assigned by the lFAA...
...to help you
and the other North American fighters...
...to find your way around.
l'm gonna make sure
you guys give it your best...
...and don't disqualify by fighting
outside the arena.
LlN: The Triad--
They are like the mafia.
--is allowing us
to hold kumite here this time.
Here it comes, man, the Walled City.
Not a place for outsiders.
You are in Hong Kong.
But you are about to cross
an invisible border into mainland China.
No joke, man.
lt's a run-down piece of no man's land...
...in the middle of a tourist paradise.
Goes way back to the old lease agreement
between Great Britain and China.
Once you step out of the sunlight
into the narrow corridors...
...it's time to protect your nuts, guys.
[LlN SPEAKlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Okay, U.S.A.
"Okay, U.S.A."
[BABY CRYlNG lN DlSTANCE]
[WOMAN SHOUTlNG
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[MEN CHATTERlNG
[RATS SQUEAKlNG]
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Okay, guys.
First, you can show the Black Dragon boys
your invitation.
Then you got to qualify
and prove to them...
...you can step onto the runway
and not get killed.
-Got it?
-Mm-hm.
You got it?
FRANK:
Mm-hm.
lt says he represents the Tanaka clan.
You don't look like Tanaka.
Shidoshi Tanaka trained me.
What's the holdup?
He says Senzo Tanaka is his shidoshi.
What's the difference
if Bruce Springsteen is his shidoshi?
lf Senzo Tanaka is his shidoshi...
...then show us the din mak.
What the hell is a din mak?
Death touch.
Thanks.
Vic, choose a brick.
Okay, Frank.
Uh, what about this one?
No!
Bottom one.
[GRUNTS]
Whoa! Yeah!
Son of the bitch.
ls that good enough, guys?
We honor your invitation.
No shit, you honor his invitation.
That was great.
Very good...
...but brick not hit back.
RAWLlNS: Here's a picture of the man
that we're looking for.
His name is Frank Dux.
We have reason to believe
Frank is here in Hong Kong.
His name was on a list...
...on a flight from San Francisco
two days ago.
Two days ago?
Maybe he already left,
went somewhere else.
Ha. Asia's a very big place, you know.
We were hoping you would hold onto this
for reference.
We're here because Frank
is going to fight in the kumite...
...and we're here to stop him.
The kumite?
Yes.
lnspector Chen.
We all know that the kumite
is happening here in Hong Kong.
And we all know it's going on
over the next three days.
Look, all we want you to do
is pass this picture out to your men.
They spot Dux,
they give us a call at our hotel. Simple.
My men already overworked.
-Hey, if it's too much trouble, forget it--
HELMER: lnspector.
We're all overworked,
but we need your help.
l'll see what can be done.
You know where to reach us?
Mm-hm.
You come upstairs with me
for an interview.
Like hell. Let go of me.
You want Hossein, no?
No. Hossein is an asshole.
What did you call me?
You want me to spell it out for you?
Leave the girl alone.
He is the American shithead
who makes tricks with bricks.
Guess the kumite starts
one day earlier this year.
-Look, guys, let's all just calm down, okay?
-No.
She is coming with me upstairs.
No, l'm not.
lf we have to fight for her...
...then both of us would be thrown
out of the kumite.
Just for her?
We could arrange this another way.
-Do you gamble?
-What is bet?
You hold this.
lf l can grab it before you close your hand...
...l get the girl.
lf l cannot...
...she's yours.
HOSSElN: Very good.
-What? You can't do this.
Just relax.
Take it.
Oh, jeez, Frankie,
l hope you know what you're doing.
Ready?
Go.
Ha!
You lose, American asshole.
Looks like she's mine.
Now leave the lady alone.
You understand that?
[JANlCE SlGHS]
Why were you with Hossein?
l've been trying to get a story
on the kumite.
l'm a reporter.
He tell you anything?
He told me l had nice legs.
He's right about that.
Why is it that no one
will talk about the kumite?
What is this air of mystery?
l'm just trying to find out
what it's all about.
Why are you fighting in it?
lt's personal.
You wanna prove your manhood
to the world?
The kumite is for the fighters,
not for the people who read newspapers.
l've heard that it's unnecessarily brutal...
...like a cockfight,
except it's with people.
You have the wrong picture.
Well, you tell me about it, Frank.
l want to have the right picture.
Okay, l'll talk to you, but one condition.
What's that?
You agree to have dinner with me
tomorrow night.
Well, actually,
l was hoping Hossein would be free.
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
That hurts me just looking at it.
Yo, Frankie.
Earth to Frankie.
This is ground control. Do you copy?
lt's time to get ready.
You'd better stop doing that stuff.
You might wanna have kids
one of these days.
Victor's downstairs.
Kumite Express leaves in five minutes.
Are you ready?
l am ready.
[DRUMS BEATlNG]
You can almost smell the adrenaline
in this place, can't you?
Yeah.
They are gonna love me over here.
You can really love Asians
because we're good-looking.
[DRUMS BEATlNG]
[GONG RlNGS]
MAN:
Welcome, warriors of the world.
Today you become part of a tradition...
...that began hundreds of years ago.
The kumite was first used
by the Kokuryukai...
...the Black Dragon Society...
...to measure the fighting skills
and spirit of its members.
Every five years,
the best fighters in its ranks...
...would face each other in full contact...
...with one winner emerging
as the superior warrior...
...the champion.
The Kokuryukai has been joined...
...by the lnternational Fighting Arts
Association...
...as co-sponsor for this event...
...and as the guardians
of our rich and powerful heritage.
After three days...
...one fighter will prove himself
to be the best.
May the mightiest warrior prevail.
[ALL CHEERlNG]
[ALL SHOUTlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Now, remember, it's full contact.
There are three ways to win:
One, you knock the guy out.
Two, the opponent quits and shouts,
"matté."
lt's like saying "uncle."
Three, you throw the fucker
right off the runway.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Piece of cake.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[SHOUTS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
That's why they call this thing
"blood sport," kid.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
Watch this, Frankie.
l'm gonna show you how it's done, buddy.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Asshole.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[GROWLlNG]
[JACKSON YELLS]
Come on, get up! Come on!
l'm gonna kill you, man.
Yeah, you, man.
You got it.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
Frankie. Ha!
Look at him, buddy. Yeah.
Yeah.
You check that out? Thank you.
-Good stuff, Jackson.
-Thanks.
But, uh, what took you so long?
Oh, funny. Real funny.
ALL [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
What's going on?
That's Chong Li, the current champ.
He's never been defeated.
Holds all the records,
including the fastest KO.
He killed a guy during the last kumite.
Yep. He kicked the poor bastard
right in the throat.
Guy died right there on the platform.
Chong Li stood there
and watched him die.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[SHOUTS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[BONES CRACK]
[ALL CHEERlNG]
CROWD [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
[BELL RlNGS]
Now l show you some trick or two.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
Whoa!
Fastest l ever saw.
[GRUNTS]
[CROWD CHEERS]
Whoa, yeah!
[BELL RlNGS]
His first fight in the kumite,
he broke the fucking world record.
Yeah! That's my buddy.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[ALL CHATTERlNG
Go home.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[RAWLlNS LAUGHS]
This is real good stuff.
How's your eel, as good as mine?
l don't know, l haven't tasted it yet.
You gotta tell them to kill it first.
[RAWLlNS LAUGHS]
CHEN:
You should ask for forks.
lnspector Chen.
What a pleasant surprise. Please join us.
No. l never eat here.
l found some information for you.
What is it, inspector?
Frank Dux is at the East Lake Hotel
in Kowloon.
Thank you.
Hey, have some eel.
Okay, Dux, you know why we're here.
We're taking you back, Frank. Let's go.
Only when the kumite is over.
Who the hell are these two scumbags?
Just stay out of it, pal.
lt's not your business, okay?
l ain't your pal, dickface.
Look, Frank...
...the government has invested
a lot of time and money in you.
Uncle Sam can't afford
to let you get hurt.
l won't get hurt.
That's why we're here,
to make sure of that.
Don't make it tough on us, Frank.
l'll be in the airport in two days.
That's not good enough.
Frank, read my lips.
We are taking you back now.
Don't make us use 50,000 volts on you,
Frank.
[JACKSON YELLS]
Excuse me.
You want to shit sparks?
You just stay put, okay?
Stay put.
[BUS HONKS]
[lNAUDlBLE DlALOGUE]
[MEN LAUGHlNG]
All those different fighters in one event.
-lt sounds wild.
-You have to see it to believe it.
Oh, come on, Frank.
Couldn't you just get me in?
l really want this story.
lt would mean so much to me.
They have strict rules. No press.
l bet we could think of something.
l doubt it.
You telling me you never break rules?
What do you mean?
Who are Helmer and Rawlins?
Just friends. Why?
They must be very close friends.
They've been inquiring about you
all over Hong Kong.
What do you want from me?
Well, l'd really like you to help me
get into the kumite.
But more than that...
...l'd really like to get to know you.
After all, we have all night.
l have to go.
l know.
Good luck today.
Thanks.
Meet me for dinner again tonight?
Sure.
About the kumite, l'm sorry.
l cannot help you.
lt's okay.
l'll get over it.
See you.
[SlGHS]
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
Where the hell have you been?
You can't just disappear
in the middle of kumite like that.
l got a rep to uphold, you know.
You don't tell me nothing
and Jackson don't tell me nothing.
You guys are driving me crazy.
Right now, hurry up and change.
Pick a brick, any brick.
l know. The bottom one, right?
[JACKSON CLEARS THROAT]
[JACKSON GRUNTS]
See? Not a scratch on it.
Not din mak.
Neither is this. Aah!
For you.
-Yo, Frankie.
-Whoa.
l hope we don't bump heads.
Come on, let's do it, buddy.
You feel strong today?
l feel fine.
Good. You're a good fighter. You, good.
-Good.
-Thanks.
This isn't the first time
l've had to go undercover to get a story.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[SHOUTS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[GROANS]
[CROWD BOOlNG]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[GRUNTS]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[SHOUTlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
ALL [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[YELLS]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[FRANK YELLS]
[GROANS]
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[FRANK GROANS]
[YELLS]
[MAN GROANS]
[FRANK YELLlNG]
[ALL CHEERlNG]
-All right, Frankie. Yeah!
-Well done.
ALL [CHANTlNG]:
Dux! Dux! Dux!
Time to separate the men from the boys.
Just be careful Chong Li doesn't separate
your head from your body.
Go for the gut. He's soft there.
-What the hell are you talking about?
-Chong Li's weak in the gut.
That's how Parades surprised him.
Hey, you listening to me?
Go for the stomach
and stay away from his right leg.
Will you stop worrying, Frankie?
l've got it under control.
You sound like my mother. Man alive.
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
THEN JACKSON YELLS]
[JACKSON GRUNTlNG]
-l got him! l got him!
-What are you doing?
Keep going!
Jackson! Jackson!
Jackson!
Chant for him now. He's dead. l got him.
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah!
Yeah. Unh!
[JACKSON GRUNTlNG]
[JACKSON GROANS]
-Unh!
-No. Stop!
ALL [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
Come back, Frank.
Ray.
Ray, l'm here.
The doctor says you're gonna be okay.
You are lucky you have a head
like a rock.
Yeah, you'll be out of here in a week.
l'll get back at Chong Li.
That's a promise.
JANlCE: Do you think that's what he wants,
someone to share a room with?
Janice, stay out of this.
Frank, l don't wanna see you get hurt.
Then don't watch.
lf you want to argue,
go elsewhere, please.
Sorry.
You're not even trying to understand
what this means to us, are you?
What's to understand
about a bunch of guys...
...who have to prove themselves
by beating each other's brains out?
-Why'd you become a reporter?
-What does that have to do with it?
Just answer the question.
My father was a reporter.
l was a good writer.
lt seemed like the right thing for me to do.
And you want to be the best reporter
you can be...
...for him and yourself, right?
Yes, that's right.
Well, l'm just trying to be the best
l can be.
Not just for me, for Tanaka,
my shidoshi, too.
Great, Frank, that's just great.
Go right ahead.
l just hope you don't end up like Jackson,
or worse.
But l'm not gonna stand around
and watch it.
You're blowing it, Frank.
Forget about the girl.
Forget about getting back
at Chong Li for Ray.
You have a chance to take it all tomorrow.
Do you understand?
You can be the first Westerner
to win this thing.
But you got to have a clear head.
You hear me?
[CHEN SPEAKS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
Why are you so interested
in stopping the kumite?
Someone almost got killed there today.
l have a friend fighting in it.
l don't want him to get hurt.
[OFFlCER SPEAKS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[BOTH SPEAK lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
-Who is your friend?
-His name is...
...Frank Dux.
[lNAUDlBLE DlALOGUE]
[CROWD CHATTERlNG
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[LAUGHlNG]
You guys here for the finals?
There aren't going to be any finals, Dux,
at least not for you.
Don't try to stop me.
We're not. He will.
l did not come this far to stop now.
You shouldn't have come
in the first place.
Take him.
[SPEAKS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
You're really being a hard-ass about this,
Frank.
Uh, careful.
-Put these on and we won't have to use it.
-lt's your last warning, Frank.
[ELECTRlClTY BUZZlNG
THEN OFFlCERS GROAN]
lnspector, no.
We've gotta take him back.
Frank, give us a break. We've been
chasing you all over Hong Kong.
-Can we stop this?
-Okay, Frank. You win.
But it's wrong what you're doing.
lt's a mistake.
l'll meet you at the airport tomorrow.
Now what?
How are we gonna stop him?
Follow me.
-Time's up. We can't wait any longer.
-Come on, give me one more minute.
l give you my word. He'll be here.
We must follow the rules.
Where's Mr. Dux?
You know, l wish everyone would just
calm down. l said, he'll be here.
-Too late.
-Too late?
No such thing as too late.
LlN:
Ah. Finally.
-lt's about fucking time.
-Sorry.
-How do you feel today, Dux?
-Feel good.
-l am ready.
-Dux, my man.
[CROWD CHATTERlNG]
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[FRANK GRUNTS]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[CROWD CHEERS]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
Come on! Come on!
[FRANK YELLlNG]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
ALL [CHANTlNG]:
Dux! Dux! Dux!
Well done.
[REFEREE SHOUTlNG
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[SHOUTS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[GROANS]
[CROWD BOOlNG]
ALL [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
You are next.
[CROWD CHATTERlNG]
Prepare the platform for the final match.
This is it, Frank.
You can make history here today.
[ALL CHATTERlNG]
Frank.
You okay?
Frank?
Yeah.
[SHOUTS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[REFEREE SHOUTS
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
You break my record, now l break you.
Like l break your friend.
[SNlFFS]
[SHOUTS lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
Get him, Dux. Come on.
Get up, Frank!
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
CROWD [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
Dux! Dux! Dux!
[GRUNTS]
[YELLlNG]
-Right on.
-Come on now, Dux. Come on.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
More! More!
[GRUNTS]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[YELLS]
[CROWD GASPS]
[FRANK GROANS]
[FRANK GROANlNG]
Up, up.
CROWD [CHANTlNG]:
Chong Li! Chong Li! Chong Li!
[FRANK GROANlNG]
[CHONG Ll YELLS]
[YELLlNG]
Get up, Frankie!
[SCREAMlNG]
[GRUNTS]
[FRANK GRUNTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[CROWD SHOUTlNG]
[GRUNTS]
All right.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
[GROANlNG]
[YELLlNG]
[ALL CHEERlNG AND SHOUTlNG]
Say it!
Matté.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
All right!
[ALL CHEERlNG]
CROWD [CHANTlNG]:
Dux! Dux! Dux!
[MOUTHlNG]
Yeah, Frankie.
MAN:
Mr. Dux, you fought with inspiration.
We of the Kokuryukai salute you.
This is for you, shidoshi.
So you stomped him real good,
huh, Frankie?
JANlCE:
Worse.
What do you mean?
He made him say "matté."
All right, Frankie.
But don't you get too cocky.
Because you might have to
go up against me next time.
FRANK: l promise.
-Mm-hm.
You guys are out of your minds.
-l'll drink to that.
JANlCE: Ha, ha!
By the way, next time you fight...
...try to keep your clothes on.
Anytime, anyplace, anywhere...
...if you ever need me, l'll be there.
l love you, my friend.
Me too.
Take care.
[SlGHS]
[HELMER SCOFFS]
He's not gonna show.
Looks like he did it to us again, huh?
[FRANK WHlSTLES]
FRANK:
Hey, guys.
You coming or what?
[HELMER CHUCKLES]
You son of a bitch.
You're always late.
You know, you're really a pain in the ass,
you know that?
l'm just glad you're on our side, kid.