FIRST THERE WAS THE COLLAPSE
OF CIVILIZATION --
ANARCHY, GENOCIDE, STARVATION.
THEN WHEN IT SEEMED
THINGS COULDN'T GET ANY WORSE,
WE GOT THE PLAGUE,
THE LIVING DEATH,
QUICKLY CLOSING ITS FIST
OVER THE ENTIRE PLANET.
AND THEN WE HEARD THE RUMORS
THAT THE LAST SCIENTISTS
WERE WORKING ON A CURE
THAT WOULD END THE PLAGUE
AND RESTORE THE WORLD.
[ THUNDER ]
RESTORE IT? WHY?
I LIKE THE DEATH.
I LIKE THE MISERY!
I LIKE THIS WORLD!
AAH!
COME ON, PEARL,
IT'S CLEAR!
I THINK WE LOST FENDER
AND HIS PIRATES.
WE'VE GOT A CHANCE
TO REACH THE BRONX TOWNSHIP
AND HIRE A SLINGER.
GET GOING, PEARL!
I'LL TRY
TO HOLD THEM HERE.
FIND A SLINGER
TO HELP YOU, PEARL...
NOW!
AAH!
GET HER.
LET HER GO!
TO ATLANTA?
TO CURE THE PLAGUE
WITH THE INFORMATION
THAT SHE'S CARRYING.
I WANT TO OWN IT.
OWN THE CURE?
I'D BE A GOD.
BUT THE MISERY
COULD BE STOPPED.
I LIKE THE MISERY.
THE WORLD COULD BE CHANGED.
I LIKE THIS WORLD.
GO TO HELL.
[ KICKS HEAD ]
BEEN THERE.
[ BLADE SLICING ]
UHH!
WOO! WOO!
WOO! WOO! WOO!
[ TRILLING AND YELPING ]
THANKS.
WAIT!
WHO ARE YOU?
WHY DID YOU HELP ME?
I THOUGHT IT WAS
SOMEBODY ELSE.
I CAN TRUST YOU.
FOR WHAT?
TO GET ME BACK
TO ATLANTA.
THERE'S A GROUP
OF DOCTORS THERE,
THE LAST ONES.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING ON
A CURE FOR THE PLAGUE.
THEY NEED INFORMATION
I HAVE.
I SWEAR IT'S THE TRUTH.
WOO! WOO!
I'M A CYBORG.
THEY CREATED ME
TO RETRIEVE DATA
FROM A COMPUTER SYSTEM
HERE IN THE CITY.
[ CLICK ]
STAY DOWN!
[ GUNSHOTS ]
THAT SLINGER
CAN'T HELP YOU NOW.
I'LL TAKE YOU TO ATLANTA,
AND YOU'LL GIVE ME
THE CURE.
AND IF YOU DON'T,
I'LL GIVE YOU
THE HORROR SHOW.
[ HOWLING ]
Pearl: GET ME BACK
TO ATLANTA.
THERE'S A GROUP
OF DOCTORS THERE,
THE LAST ONES.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING ON
A CURE FOR THE PLAGUE.
THEY NEED INFORMATION
I HAVE.
AAH!
[ SCREAMING ]
YOU THINK
WE'RE GOING TO SWIM
ALL THE WAY TO ATLANTA?
I...CAN'T...SWIM,
ASSHOLE!
I HATE THE WATER.
HEY, I CAUGHT
A NICE FISH HERE.
AAH! AAH!
YAAH!
AAH!
[ WOMEN CONTINUE SCREAMING ]
HOIST ANCHOR, MATES!
HA HA HA HA HA!
WE GOT US A SKIN JOB
TO TAKE TO ATLANTA!
UH!
SAY YOUR FINAL GOODBYES
TO YOUR DADDY,
AND LET'S BE ON OUR WAY.
I'M LOSING MONEY.
LET'S GO.
DON'T KNOW IF
I REALLY TRUST YOU.
DON'T OW IF THERE'S
REALLY ANY DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN SLINGERS
AND THE PIRATES
THAT KILLED MY PA.
BUT I GUESS I AIN'T
GOT NO CHOICE.
YOU'RE THE ONLY GUIDE
THAT ANSWERED THE POSTING
FOR THE PAY.
JUST GET US
OUT OF THE CITY.
IT'S WHAT I DO...
GET PEOPLE
OUT OF THE CITY.
LET'S GO.
YOU'RE GOOD WITH THEM.
I LIKE THEM.
[ HONING KNIFE ]
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WE'LL BE SAFE HERE.
AAH!
[ CRYING AND SCREAMING ]
UM...
ARE YOU LOOKING
FOR THAT WOMAN?
I HEARD
THE PIRATES SAY
SHE HAS A CURE
FOR THE PLAGUE.
THEY'RE TAKING HER
TO ATLANTA.
ATLANTA.
PIRATES WANTED A BOAT.
ALL THIS
FOR A STUPID BOAT.
WHY ARE YOU STILL ALIVE?
I HID WHEN THEY CAME.
I SAW THEM SETTING OFF
DOWN THE WATERWAY
TO CHARLESTON.
I WAS JUST GETTING READY
TO TAKE OFF
WHEN YOU SHOWED UP.
I FIGURED YOU
FOR ONE OF THE PIRATES.
I'M GONE.
Woman: SO ARE YOU GOING AFTER
THAT WOMAN WITH THE CURE
TO SAVE HER
FROM THE PIRATES?
I'D LIKE TO HELP.
MY FAMILY DIED
FROM THE PLAGUE.
SO DID MOST EVERYBODY
ELSE I'VE KNOWN.
SO AS SOON AS I HEARD
THE PIRATES
TA ABOUT THIS WOMAN,
I KNEW I HAD TO DO
SOMETHING TO HELP.
KEEP MOVING.
YOU DON'T WANT MY HELP?
NO.
YOU THINK YOU CAN
RESCUE HER BY YOURSELF?
IT'S NOT MY BUSINESS.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO TRY
TO SAVE THIS WOMAN?
YOU DON'T CARE?
WELL, WHAT DO YOU
CARE ABOUT?
FENDER.
THERE'S A CURE
FOR THE PLAGUE,
AND YOU DON'T
GIVE A SHIT?
WHAT KIND OF JERK
ARE YOU?
WHY DON'T YOU
RESCUE HER?
MAYBE I WILL.
YOU KNOW, THE SHORTCUT
TO CHARLESTON'S A FREE ROAD.
YOU CAN'T STOP ME
FROM TRAVELING.
GOOD LUCK.
NOT TOO MUCH.
SO DO YOU THINK
WE'LL FIND FENDER?
WE'LL GET HIM.
TELL ME SOMETHING.
I TRIED TO KILL YOU,
SO WHY DID YOU STAY WITH ME
WHILE I WAS KNOCKED OUT?
SORT OF GOES AGAINST
YOUR HARD-ASS STYLE.
IT'S BECAUSE
I FELT SORRY FOR YOU.
THE MAN HAS A HEART.
[ HAMMERING METAL ]
FENDER'S MAKING HIS WAY
DOWN THE INTRACOASTAL
WATERWAY TO CHARLESTON.
HE STOPPED FOR WOOD
AT HATTERAS YESTERDAY.
TORCHED A SETTLEMENT THERE.
I'LL CATCH UP WITH HIM
WHERE THE OCEAN MEETS
THE ROAD TO ATLANTA.
FOLKS GENERALLY
MAKE IT A POINT
TO STAY OUT OF
FENDER'S PATH, GIBS,
NOT GO LOOKING
TO KILL HIM.
I HEARD YOU'D
GIVEN IT UP...
FOUND SOME PEACE
IN THE COUNTRY.
THIS IS GOING TO
BE OUR HOME.
YOU SAID
YOU WANTED CHANGE.
STAY WITH US?
JUST FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
I WAS A FOOL, MASE --
STARTED TO BELIEVE
IN THE DREAM.
EVERYBODY'S GOT TO HAVE
A DREAM, GIBS,
A LITTLE HOPE.
LOOK AT OLD MASE.
GOT MY BAR, FAMILY.
HOW'S THAT FOR HOPE?
MAKE SURE
YOU PUT YOUR KNIVES ON
FOR THE RIGHT REASON, SON.
WHAT IF YOU KILL FENDER?
WHAT THEN?
WHAT ABOUT
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE?
AAH!
SO THE CURE'S NOT
IMPORTANT, HUH?
I GOT YOUR BALL.
HA HA HA!
KNOCK IT OFF,
OR I'M GOING TO
BASH YOUR BRAINS OUT.
HEY...
I DON'T THINK
THIS IS YOURS.
HEY, KID.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
THIS IS THE WASTELAND.
WE CAN'T GO THROUGH HERE.
FENDER HAS A BOAT.
WE'RE WALKING.
YOU WANT THE CURE.
I WANT FENDER.
SHORTCUT TO CHARLESTON,
MY ASS.
WE ARE LOST.
TYPICAL.
[ CRACK ]
YAAH!
[ CHAIN RATTLES ]
[ CRACK ]
AAH!
[ SCREAMING ]
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD.
DO YOU EVER
GET USED TO IT?
USED TO WHAT?
THE KILLING.
I DIDN'T MAKE THIS WORLD.
YEAH, YOU ONLY
LIVE IN IT.
FENDER'S BOAT
WILL PASS HERE.
GOOD, THEN WE'RE STOPPING.
YOU'RE JUST A WALKING
WOUND, AREN'T YOU?
SORRY.
I LIKE SCARS, REALLY.
SO WHAT DID FENDER
DO TO YOU?
YOU KNOW,
IF YOU LET ME HELP YOU,
YOU CAN HELP ME.
NO.
YOU STILL DON'T THINK
THAT WOMAN
IS WORTH SAVING?
I DON'T WANT TO
SEE YOU DIE.
SEE YOU DIE, EITHER.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO BE
HERE IN THE MORNING
WHEN I WAKE UP, ARE YOU?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
IT'S OKAY.
WHAT IS IT?
FENDER.
[ SEA GULL CRIES ]
YOU WERE CHOSEN
BECAUSE OF YOUR
MATRIX ENGINEERING
BACKGROUND,
AND THE MAKEUP
OF YOUR PERSONALITY.
YOU ARE THE PERFECT
CHOICE FOR THIS MISSION.
HOWEVER I THINK
IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT YOU UNDERSTAND
THE RAMIFICATIONS
OF THE DECISION
YOU'RE MAKING.
I WOULDN'T HAVE
VOLUNTEERED
IF I DIDN'T UNDERSTAND
THE CONSEQUENCES.
AFTER THE OPERATION,
YOU WILL NEVER BE
THE SAME AGAIN, PEARL.
THE PLAGUE HAS
DESTROYED SO MUCH.
WE'VE LOST
OUR HUMANITY.
WE'VE LOST OUR PURPOSE.
THERE'S NO MEANING
IN THIS WORLD.
I WANT TO CHANGE THAT.
Pearl: I'LL BRING BACK
THE DATA YOU NEED.
I SWEAR IT.
GOOD LUCK, PEARL.
DON'T WORRY, PEARL.
I'LL GET YOU
TO NEW YORK AND BACK.
WE'LL DOCK ANDEACH
THE INLAND ROAD BY NOON.
FENDER'S BOAT.
STAND NEXT TO ME.
WHO ARE THEY?
TAKE 'EM OUT.
MOVE.
WAIT HERE.
I'M NOT GOING TO
STAY HERE.
I WANT YOU OUT OF MYAY
UNTIL I SEE
WHAT'S GOING ON.
LOOK, I'M HERE TO MAKE
SURE THAT WOMAN LIVES,
AND I'M NOT GOING TO
LET YOU DO
ANYTHING THAT COULD
HURT HER.
NOTHING'S GOING TO
HAPPEN TO HER.
THAT'S A PROMISE.
A PROMISE.
FUCK IT.
OH, SHIT.
[ CLANK ]
YAAH!
GRR!
[ BOTH SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SHRIEKING HYSTERICALLY ]
[ KNIFE RATTLES ON GROUND ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ CLICK ]
FUCK.
COME ON!
MOTHERFUCKER!
[ GROANING ]
I TOLD MY SISTER THAT
SLINGERS KILL PIRATES.
I'M GONNA BE
A SLINGER SOMEDAY.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
YOU'LL DO SOMETHING
BETTER, HALEY.
[ WHOOPING ]
GO!
YOU KEEP
AN EYE ON HER.
MOVE.
[ THUMP ]
COME ON.
I'M NOT GOING WITH YOU.
YOU'RE NOT STRONG ENOUGH
TO GET ME TO ATLANTA.
FENDER WOULD
EVENTUALLY CATCH US,
MAYBE KILL ME,
CERTAINLY KILL YOU.
LOOK, FENDER
MUST BE DESTROYED.
IN ATLANTA WE HAVE THE MEANS.
I'LL LEAD HIM TO HIS DEATH.
NOTHING CAN STOP HIM
IN THIS WORLD,
NOT EVEN YOU.
YOU!
YOU TAKE HER.
YAAH!
YAAH-HAH!
[ DISTANT SHOUTING ]
OVER HERE!
[ GRUNTING ]
YAAH!
CAN YOU MAKE IT?
YEAH.
[ GROANING ]
I GUESS I SHOULD HAVE
STAYED PUT, HUH?
[ DISTANT SCREAM ]
COME ON.
LET'S GO. LET'S GO.
[ SCREAMING ]
[ DISTANT SCREAMING ]
RUN!
AAH!
AH-AH-AH-AH-AH!
YOW!
AAH!
AAH! AAH!
[ BONE SNAPS ]
STAND HIM UP.
[ REPEATED HITTING ]
HA HA HA HA!
LET'S GO.
HALEY.
HALEY!
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU'RE GOOD WITH THEM.
I LIKE THEM.
THEY LIKE YOU, GIBS.
THIS IS GOING
TO BE OUR HOME.
STAY WITH US?
JUST FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
[ GRUNTING ]
AAH!
[ SCREAMING ECHOES ]
IT'S UP TO YOU, HONEY.
[ SCREAMING ]
IF YOU CAN HOLD THEM,
THEY'LL LIVE.
AAH!
AAH! AAH!
[ GRUNTING ]
AAH!
FENDER!
TOLD YOU YOU WERE
GOING TO NEED MY HELP.
Fender: WHAT'S WAITING
IN ATLANTA?
Pearl:
WHAT I TOLD YOU --
THE LAST
OF THE OLD WORLD.
WHAT'S WAITING
FOR ME, CYBORG?
WHATEVER YOU WANT --
GUNS, WEAPONS...
THE CURE,
IF THEY FIND IT...
LIFE.
DEATH.
DEATH?
YOU THINK
YOU CAN STOP ME THERE.
NO, WE HAVE A DEAL.
YOU WILL FAIL.
OF COURSE I WOULD.
I KNOW
HOW STRONG YOU ARE.
DON'T LOOK DOWN ON ME!
I DON'T.
[ THUNDER ]
[ ARROW HISSES ]
MOVE!
GO.
AAH!
YAAH!
NO!
COME WITH ME!
HURRY!
I KILL SLINGERS.
AAH! AAH!
AAH!
YAAH!
STOP IT!
PLEASE.
AAH!
YAAH!
Gibs: NADY!
[ SCREAMS ]
FUCKER!
COME ON.
AAH!
YAAH!
FENDER!
AAH!
[ GROANING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
HALEY.
AAH!
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
HYAH!
AAH!
[ SCREAM FADES ]
WELCOME HOME, PEARL.
WERE YOU ABLE
TO RETRIEVE THE DATA?
YES, I WAS,
THANKS TO THIS MAN.
STAY WITH US, GIBSON.
THEY NEED US OUT THERE.
LET'S GO.
Pearl: IT'S STRANGE,
BUT I FEEL
HE'S THE REAL CURE
FOR THIS WORLD.