MOREAU:
Benedict.
Is this true?
You have found the boy?
Yes.
He's not safe here.
Nonsense, this is a fortress.
The full resources of the Order
are at our disposal.
Respectfully,
Benedict, the devil himself
wants this child.
Only one place is safe.
That is the Sanctuary.
The Rider must take him.
You do enjoy your wine, Moreau.
In a few days,
the winter solstice will be past
and with it the hour of the prophecy.
Then the boy will be
of no use to anyone.
By that time.
Brother,
you will all be dead.
This conversation is finished.
(EXPLOSION)
(GUNFIRE)
(BOTH YELL)
(GLASS BREAKS)
(IN ROMANIAN) They're inside!
(GUNSHOT)
(ALARM WAILING)
(NADYA GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Go!
(SCREAMS THEN THUDS)
Nadya!
I can help you!
Damn it. Danny!
I can protect you!
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
(GUNFIRE)
Where are they?
(SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Shut up!
(GUNSHOT)
(BENEDICT GRUNTS)
Perfect.
Who is this guy?
(HORN HONKS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
Screw this.
(GUNSHOT)
Duck!
JOHNNY:
It doesn't matter how far you run.
There are some demons
you just can't escape.
My name is Johnny Blaze.
I rode a motorcycle for a living.
I did a bare-ass, 360,
triple backﬂip
in front of 22,000 people.
(JOHNNY CHUCKLES)
It's kind of funny.
It's on YouTube. Check it out.
But when my dad got sick,
I did something
way crazier than that.
ROARKE: You look like you
could use a little help.
Are you willing to make a deal,
John?
Attaboy.
JOHNNY:
Do it.
Save his life.
Do it!
Yeah, that is right. I'm the guy
who made the deal with the devil.
I know what you're thinking.
Doesn't this kid watch movies?
Does this ever work out fine?
Let's just say good judgment
was not exactly my forte.
I was possessed by
an ancient demon.
In the presence of evil,
I change into a monster,
and I pray
on the wicked,
and I suck out their souls.
And you don't wanna be around
when that happens.
See, there's good and bad
in all of us.
And maybe you're not a murderer,
but you did something
you wouldn't want the Rider to see.
A white lie, an illegal download.
What about you? And you?
I've tried to fight it, to hold it back,
but the darkness inside me
only gets stronger.
That's why I had to run
halfway across the world.
(GASPS)
And I'm still running.
(MOTORCYCLE APPROACHES)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(MOREAU SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
Who are you?
My name is Moreau.
My brothers are dead,
as should I be,
if not for the intervention of God.
(CLAUDE-JOSEPH ROUGET DE LISLE'S
"LA MARSEILLAISE" PLAYING)
And you are John Blaze.
Go away.
MOREAU:
I can't do that.
(GAGS)
(GRUNTS)
Ah.
It likes
the dark places.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
The Rider.
(GRUNTS)
You thought that you could control it.
Make it work for you, huh?
That you were stronger
than this deep, hungry thing?
This
sickness.
(GRUNTS)
Why are you here?
Aah!
What do you
want from me?
I need your help
and you need your soul.
So we make a deal.
You know about making deals,
don't you, Johnny? Huh?
Nice bike.
This child.
He is in danger
and for more than his life.
You will save him.
I don't
save people.
(MOREAU CHUCKLING)
MOREAU: What brought you
out here, Johnny Blaze?
Thousands of miles
from your place of birth
and your dark rebirth.
You were brought here for this.
This little kid,
what makes you think I can find him?
This man that you met years ago
that put the curse
On you?
Roarke.
The devil has many names.
He is the link that connects you
to this child.
Let the Rider follow his stench.
It will lead you to the boy.
You said something
about a deal.
The church of my masters
is an ancient one.
We are prepared to give to you the one
thing you want the most of this world.
Bring us the boy,
and we will lift your curse.
(CROWD CHATTERING
IN ROMANIAN)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS)
Hello.
Hi.
I, uh... I noticed you were,
um, looking at me.
Yes?
Was I?
Nice suit.
Oh, thank you very much.
It's, uh...
Are you Roma?
Gypsy?
Why do you ask?
Well, what people say about...
What?
Listen, um.
I am a businessman.
Mm-hm.
I have a lot of money.
Yeah?
And...
And?
Hey, Mommy. Where's Daddy?
I, um... Excuse me.
No, no, no.
It's okay.
MAN: No, really.
No, really, I... Yeah.
Sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
DANNY: Somebody's gonna have
a lot of explaining to do.
We won't always have to do this.
Okay?
I wanna make a life for you.
This is a life.
You know I love you more
than anything.
I love you too, Mama.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
JOHNNY: So many times I've tried to keep
the Rider from coming out, but tonight,
I need him.
(GRUNTING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
IN ROMANIAN ON RADIO)
(KAJAGOOGOO'S "TOO SHY"
PLAYING ON RADIO)
♪ You're too shy, shy ♪
♪ Hush, hush, eye to eye ♪
♪ Too shy, shy ♪
♪ Hush, hush ♪♪
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hold on!
(GRUNTING)
What happened?
Hold on.
(SNARLS)
(MOTORCYCLE REVVING)
(EXPLOSION)
(EXPLOSIONS)
(YELLS)
NADYA:
Stay in and lock the doors.
(PANTING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
CARRIGAN:
Nadya.
(NADYA GRUNTING)
No!
CARRIGAN:
It's been
a long time, pumpkin.
NADYA:
Carrigan.
CARRIGAN:
I see you're still an unbelievable
pain in the ass.
Look, I got people after
Danny and me,
so just let me go.
Let me go!
I'm the people after you.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
DANNY:
No!
(GRUNTING)
Don't touch him!
DANNY:
Get off!
TERROKOV:
Get up.
Heh. Whoops.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(NADYA YELLS)
(CARRIGAN LAUGHS)
Oh! Unbelievable.
Still the fighter.
NADYA:
Carrigan.
Yes?
NADYA: Please.
He's my son.
I know.
But he's not mine.
And part of you
had to know it might
end up like this.
(SCREECHING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(SNARLING)
Well, kill it.
(GASPING)
Hungry.
Oh, God.
Slugthrowers, now.
Don't look at it.
(SCREAMING)
Whoa!
NADYA:
No!
Get some.
Move, now!
Get him in the car.
Get in!
Danny!
(MONITOR BEEPING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING IN ROMANIAN
OVER PA)
(GROANING)
Oh, you have awake.
Hi.
Heh. It's funny,
because when you walked in,
I thought I was still dreaming.
You have hallucinate?
No, no, man, I'm not hallucinating.
Ha, ha.
Look, I'm flirting with you.
(IN ROMANIAN) You're beautiful.
(JOHNNY SPEAKS IN ROMANIAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Okay.
Morphine?
You got any morphine?
Oh, no, no, morphine,
you already have.
Dilaudid, Valium? What?
Your wounds...
Very weird,
mister.
The poliţie want to talk to you when
you wake up. I tell them you wake.
No!
Please.
(IN ROMANIAN)
I'm fine. Let me go!
(NURSES SPEAKING
IN ROMANIAN)
Take a piss.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
ROARKE:
Carrigan.
I got your package, but the cost of
doing business with me just went up.
I don't understand.
What's not to understand?
I want more.
You understand that?
We had an agreement, Carrigan.
Changing the defined terms of an
agreement is something we just don't do.
You told me to get a kid.
Not a problem.
I've done that
for people before.
And I have history
with his bitch of a mom,
so there's no better guy for the job.
But what you didn't tell me
is that I'd be walking into the middle
of a goddamn horror movie.
(ROARKE LAUGHS)
CARRIGAN:
Oh, this is funny
To you?
(SPEAKS IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Three of my guys got turned
into matchsticks last night
by a dude on a motorcycle
with his head on fire.
Come again?
You heard me. I've seen things,
weird things, bad things.
But that thing last night? No.
No, no, no.
Put the boy on the phone.
Talk.
ROARKE:
Danny, do you hear me?
I want you to listen
very closely. Listen to me.
(WHISPERING IN
DEMONIC LANGUAGE)
(SCREAMS)
(ROARS)
What the hell was that?
Think of the child as a sort of computer.
You know computers, right?
I just uploaded
a little program.
A firewall.
Our friend on the motorcycle won't be
able to sense him now, to track him.
Of course, he still may be able
to find you,
so I suggest you keep moving.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Hello?
(ROARKE SPEAKING
IN DEMONIC LANGUAGE)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Who sent you to find me?
Is it the devil?
The devil that walks among men?
Does the devil own you?
Answer me!
The kid, Danny.
He's your son?
Bullets can't hurt you
when you walk with the demon.
But they'll do
what they're supposed to
right now.
Tell me why I can trust you.
You can't.
But if I don't find your son,
I'd just as soon be dead.
So if you
wanna pull
that trigger...
do it.
Please.
You tracked us last night.
Can you do it again?
I could feel him before.
I could sense him and then nothing.
No, no, he's not dead,
he's just blocked.
But you know something.
Let's go.
JOHNNY: Yeah, okay, well, let
me just get something straight.
The guy who kidnapped Danny
and tried to kill you and blew me up
with grenades,
you two were like
boyfriend, girlfriend?
Carrigan was a gunrunner,
a drug dealer, a mercenary.
I didn't care about that.
I just saw a ticket out.
Right, okay, and so Danny is...?
Danny, what, is Carrigan's son?
No.
Um...
When you met the seducer,
he offered you something.
Yeah. My father's life.
Shocker, he lied.
For me, it was only myself.
It was supposed to be big
for Carrigan, but it went bad.
I made it out a third-floor window.
I was choking on my own blood.
(COUGHING)
I knew I was gonna die.
I could feel it.
And that's when he found me.
ROARKE: You look like you
could use a little help.
Roarke.
He promised to take
the pain away,
to save my life.
But he asked
for something in return.
A son?
Maybe you can never understand.
No, I get it.
You're the devil's baby mama.
I guess that explains
why Moreau
wants
Danny so bad.
Moreau?
Yeah.
Black, French, alcoholic priest,
a dick. Know him?
He tried to help us.
I didn't let him.
Well, we're both gonna work
on our decision-making.
Where you headed?
Someone I know.
He does Carrigan's dirty work.
He'll know where to find him.
JOHNNY: Why does the devil walk
on earth in human form anyway?
I have no idea.
Maybe he doesn't know either.
Maybe he just
passes on from body to body,
through history,
waiting for the perfect fit
But I know one thing:
On Earth, he's weak.
His powers are limited.
He needs emissaries
to do his dirty work,
so he finds them or makes them
using his greatest power:
The power of
the deal.
(ROARKE SPEAKING
IN DEMONIC LANGUAGE)
Can I open a window?
You think you can just talk?
Your mom thought she could just talk,
until I kicked her little Gypsy face in.
(PANTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
CARRIGAN:
Grab him.
(GROANS)
KURDISH:
Get me... Get me out of here!
CARRIGAN:
I told you to stop eating the Twinkies.
Get me out of here!
Get off me.
Boss!
(ANKLE SNAPS)
(SCREAMING)
Come here.
Try that again, you little turd...
Ha-ha-ha.
(MAN SPEAKS IN SWEDISH)
What?
(IN SWEDISH)
Dude, what happened?
You speak English?
(IN ENGLISH)
Yeah. What happened?
Is that your van?
MAN: Uh, yeah.
Does it run?
Yeah.
(ON RADIO)
♪ Looks like love's the only way ♪
♪ And I'm happy just to be alive ♪
♪ Happy just to be alive, hey ♪♪
(GASPS)
When we get
where we're going,
the Rider's going to come out.
And when he does,
he'll destroy
whoever's got it coming.
Nadya, this thing,
there's no reason, no conscience,
just hunger.
In his eyes...
you're no different than Carrigan.
You're no different
than any of them.
I'm not afraid of you.
Yeah? Well, you should be.
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SPEAKS IN ROMANIAN)
JOHNNY: That's the guy?
He looks like he works
on a cruise ship.
Am I gonna regret taking you?
Um, yeah, probably.
(PIG SQUEALING)
(IN ROMANIAN)
Count every dollar!
I don't want these idiots robbing me.
Everyone's robbing me!
It makes my balls hurt!
(IN ROMANIAN) Hello, Vasil.
(IN ENGLISH) Long time, Nadya.
You look good.
Shut up.
(IN ENGLISH)
He's talked to Carrigan.
The last couple of days
and a few hours ago.
John?
(GRUNTING)
You talked to Carrigan?
I talk to a lot of people. I got
what you need for the shakes,
my friend.
(LAUGHING)
Carrigan must've told you
about that thing that killed
his men last night. Huh? Yeah?
That thing
is inside of me. See,
you're a bad man and this thing,
the Rider, he feeds on bad men.
And he's hungry. He's hungrier
than he's been in years.
That's why I'm shaking!
Because right now,
the only thing standing
between you and the Rider is me.
And he's just... He's...
(GRUNTING)
He's scraping at the door.
Scraping
at the door!
If you don't tell me
what I wanna know,
I'm gonna let him out.
(LAUGHING)
And when he's done with you, there won't
be anything left, do you understand?
Do you understand?
Shake your head yes or no.
Uh-huh.
Good.
Good girl.
Where's Carrigan?
Um...
I want the kid!
The kid Carrigan has!
You will tell me
or I will eat your
stinking soul! Aah!
The quarry. For more guns, more men.
He's putting together
a goddamn army.
I know the place.
You won't mention this
conversation to anyone?
No, no, no.
Huh? Ah.
Yeah. All right, well,
that was a good answer.
(DOOR OPENS)
Yeah, good.
NADYA: John.
(VASIL YELLS)
We gotta go.
We gotta go, we gotta go.
(BOTH GRUNT)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(CACKLING AND GRUNTING)
(DEATH FROM ABOVE 1979'S
"TURN IT OUT" PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
(MEN CHATTERING IN ROMANIAN)
FGM-148 Javelin.
Lock on, fire and forget.
American bunker buster.
Two-stage detonation.
The first creates
a super vacuum.
It sucks the oxygen from the air.
The next...
I know what it does.
Give me four of them,
with extra heads.
How many men you go up against?
Just one.
(MEN LAUGHING)
NADYA:
Danny?
Mom?
Are you okay?
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Ow!
What?
I think my ankle's broken.
Come on, hold on.
(NADYA GRUNTING)
(SCREECHING IN DISTANCE)
Oh, no.
Come on, hold onto me.
Showtime.
Hey!
(WHISTLES)
(SCREECHING CONTINUES)
What is it?
I don't care.
Give me that thing.
Give it to me.
Now.
(WEAPON BEEPING)
Shit!
That was awesome.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(GROWLS)
Reload. Just reload.
(SNARLING)
(ROARING)
(MEN YELLING)
(YELLS)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
Give me that.
(MEN SHOUTING IN ROMANIAN)
Okay.
(MEN SCREAMING)
I'm sorry, did that hurt?
It looked like
it did.
(GHOST RIDER SCREECHES)
(METAL GROANING)
(MAN SCREAMS)
(LAUGHING)
NADYA:
Come on.
Let's go.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
Hurry!
(GUN COCKS)
(MEN SHOUTING IN ROMANIAN)
(GRUNTING)
Sorry. Does it hurt?
It looks like it does.
What are you waiting for?
Do it! Do it!
He's coming.
(SCREAMS)
NADYA:
Unh! Let me go.
(SNARLING)
(GASPS)
DANNY:
Enough.
Let her go.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
So that happened.
(TRUCK HORN BLARES)
(LA MINOR'S "TIHIY VECHER"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
There you go.
It was a bee. I thought it was
gonna sting your face.
Well, are you feeling better?
Your leg's all healed, huh?
Like all by itself.
That's weird.
Where's my mom?
She's gassing up the truck.
Ahem. I know
that it's a little awkward.
Me rolling with you guys.
I mean, after everything that you've
been through.
Dude.
You're cooler than the guys
she usually hangs outwith.
Huh.
Hey.
So, what's next?
Moreau thinks that the danger
will pass in a few days.
If we just get Danny
someplace safe,
a holy place,
where his people can protect us,
then we can ride it out.
Okay.
I've already contacted Moreau. He's
gonna catch up with us on the road.
We gotta move fast because the ones
who are hunting us, they're not done.
Plus, I have some personal issues
I'd kind of like to get fixed.
ROARKE:
You're not done, Carrigan.
You were to bring me
Nadya's son.
I do expect you
to fulfill your obligation.
S... S... S... Sorry, jackass,
but I'm dead.
Inconvenient.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
What'd you do to me?
Gave you a second chance.
You're a little less than alive now.
But also more.
You see, I've given you power.
The power of
decay.
Of darkness.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
(MAN GRUNTING)
Whoa.
I want that boy, Carrigan.
Now you've got no
excuses.
DANNY:
The machine last night?
Yeah?
You made it change.
That's how it works.
Whatever he rides changes with him.
And what if he took a taxi?
Uh...
I don't know.
I don't know. Why?
Or a roller coaster or a ski lift
or a camel or a...
Dude.
What if you have to pee
while you're on fire?
Oh, it's awesome. It's like a
flamethrower, you know? It's like:
(MAKES WHOOSHING NOISE)
(LAUGHS)
When you change,
when you're him,
does it feel good?
Sometimes.
What does it mean?
Are we just bad?
No.
This power that we have
comes from a dark place,
but it's not who we are.
It never will be.
And we can use it to do good,
to help people. Ahem.
Like I'm helping you and your mom.
I know why you're helping.
She says you wanna get rid of it.
I can't ever do that.
(HORN HONKING)
(SHOUTS IN FRENCH)
(MOREAU LAUGHING)
Hey, Nadya. I hope you have
finished shooting at me!
JOHNNY:
Hey.
You wanna have some fun?
(BASS DRUM OF DEATH'S
"VELVET ITCH" PLAYING)
♪ I got a velvet
I got a velvet itch ♪
♪ In my jeans ♪
♪ I got a velvet ♪
Hang on.
♪ Itch in my jeans ♪
♪ How can you scratch it? ♪
♪ How can you ♪
Whoo!
♪ Scratch it right for me? ♪♪
(TIRE SCREECHING)
(SHIRLEY HORN'S "THAT OLD
BLACK MAGIC" PLAYING ON RADIO)
♪ That old black magic
Has me in its spell ♪
♪ That old black magic ♪
♪ That you weave so well ♪
♪ Those icy fingers
Up and down my spine ♪
♪ That same old witchcraft ♪
♪ When your eyes meet mine ♪
That is so weird.
♪ That I feel inside ♪
♪ And then that elevator ♪
♪ Starts ♪
♪ Its ride ♪
♪ And down and down I go ♪
♪ Round and round I go ♪
♪ Like a leaf
That's caught in the tide ♪
♪ I should stay away ♪♪
JOHNNY:
So this is it, Moreau's happy place.
These guys will lift my curse?
They don't even have shoes.
(MOREAU SPEAKS IN LATIN)
(SPEAKING IN LATIN)
Amen.
MOREAU:
(SPEAKS IN LATIN)
METHODIUS:
You mustn't be afraid.
It was God that led you here.
What's up?
MOREAU:
I know. A little
uptight. Not so bad
once you get to know them.
Now go on.
They will take
good care of you.
What about
you two?
We will join you later. We have some
business to complete between us.
I made a promise to you, John.
Why can't he come with us?
No!
JOHNNY: Danny.
Danny,
you're safe here.
We made it.
The only thing that can hurt
you and your mom now
is me.
I need to make sure
that will never happen.
It'll be all right.
I promise.
Whatever.
NADYA:
Come on.
Are you sure about this?
JOHNNY: Where are we going?
MOREAU: To my favorite room.
If there is one thing
these sons of bitches know, eh,
it's wine.
(MOREAU CHUCKLES)
This bottle would fetch
50,000 euros at an auction.
Moreau.
Oh, yeah.
What is it?
It's...
This thing inside of me.
I'd like to know before we, uh,
commence.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Zarathos was an angel,
a Spirit of Justice.
Sent to protect the world of men.
But he was tricked,
captured,
brought down to hell,
corrupted.
Driven insane.
Heh.
His mission to protect
the innocent was perverted
into a lust to punish
the guilty.
He became
the Spirit of Vengeance.
Yeah, but the angel,
the Spirit of Justice,
he's alive in there?
Somewhere?
He could be.
Do you feel him?
No.
(LAUGHS)
Cheer up, my man.
Soon you will be free.
This bottle...
Ah.
This one is over 2000 years old.
I've had my eye on it for a while.
(CHUCKLES)
When this is over,
we will share it, huh?
There's something else.
(SIGHS)
This thing that Roarke has
done to you is not easily undone.
You risk death.
(SCOFFS)
Worse than death.
You must confess
the one thing that is most
difficult for you to talk about.
Um...
My dad.
I didn't do it for him.
I made the deal for me.
I couldn't let him go.
It was selfish.
He was ready to die.
He knew it was his time.
And I thought I could change that.
I'm sorry.
This is the lamb of God
that takes away all the sin
from the world.
Happy are those
that are called to receive him.
You say that you're not worthy
to receive him.
I'm not.
Okay, that's good enough.
The body of Christ.
Ahem. Uh, amen.
You've been carrying this
bread around for a while.
May God lead you
into the eternal life.
That is, John, if today is,
in fact, your last.
MOREAU:
Where you go now, I cannot follow.
Are you ready?
Hello?
Hey.
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
Merry Christmas, you assholes!
(ROARKE LAUGHING)
Make the deal.
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
Moreau!
(LAUGHING)
You did it!
Moreau!
It worked.
NADYA:
No! Let me go!
Help me!
Hey! What are you doing?
NADYA: Get off me!
Let me go!
(MOREAU GRUNTING)
What are you doing?
(YELLS THEN GROANING)
What will be done.
MOREAU:
The day of prophecy is tomorrow.
We were to hold the boy
until the danger passes.
The danger will not pass,
Moreau.
As long as the boy exists,
the power
will always be inside him.
(GRUNTS)
You lied to me.
You lied to me!
This child must be destroyed.
No!
You might have protested
while the child was being conceived.
Now it is too late.
(IN LATIN) Take them away
until the thing is done!
(IN ENGLISH) Go!
MOREAU:
Danny's soul can still be saved!
That boy is one of God's children!
No!
He is not.
(DANNY GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(CHOKING)
(LAUGHING)
Pretty neat, huh?
Mm.
Peace, brother.
(GRUNTS)
(CARRIGAN GRUNTING
AND PANTING)
Damn.
Bet you're happy to see me.
Did Danny do this?
No. Somebody got here
before they could...
Before they could kill him.
JOHNNY:
There's no sign of him.
Whoever did this wanted
him alive.
I think we all
have a pretty good idea
who that would be, Moreau.
NADYA:
Yeah. So now he's
with Roarke. Some protectors
you turned out to be.
What exactly does Roarke
have in mind for Danny?
What are his plans for his son? Is he
putting money away for college? What?
MOREAU:
It is the day
of prophecy
As was the day Danny
was conceived.
The child must be
in his 13th year
before the rite can be performed
on the dawn of winter.
The rite.
Roarke fathered the boy as a vessel,
as a container for his power.
The ritual will transform
his essence,
his soul into the boy.
There will be no more Danny.
Only Roarke.
No!
Why the hell didn't you tell us this?
Hey.
You made a deal with Roarke!
Both of you!
Something I would never do.
The prophecy had to happen
at the dawn of a new day.
Maybe there's still time.
Do you know where Roarke has him?
I think so.
What, so now you want
to play hero?
You got what you wanted.
Yes, I did.
Thank you for holding up
your end of the bargain.
You're welcome.
JOHNNY:
If I can spend my last day
as a free man without a curse
over my head, I'll take it.
But I promised Danny
he'd be safe.
And if I walk away now,
I'm just trading
one demon for another.
So let's go.
(CHUCKLES)
Was there ever any doubt?
Don't
touch me.
Cutting it a bit close,
aren't we?
CARRIGAN:
You have any idea
what I had to go through
to get this little turd?
(DANNY GRUNTING)
Look,
the planets don't align for your
pagan party until daybreak tomorrow.
So get off my ass because
I'd say I'm ahead of schedule.
Danny.
Do you know who I am?
Well, I'm sure
your mother told you
a lot of things about me.
What's the matter
with your face?
(CHUCKLES)
MOREAU: Uzak Gökten.
The farthest point from heaven.
That is where the ritual is to take place,
according to the prophecy, of course.
Of course.
Without the Rider, we stand
very little chance against Roarke.
You were
supposed to have faith.
I do.
But also, I think
we should have weapons.
JOHNNY:
Guns
and wine.
Naughty priests.
I'm starting to like you again,
Moreau.
(CHUCKLES)
You wanted to know
why I look this way.
Think of
a flamethrower.
(LAUGHS)
Is that funny?
Okay.
A flamethrower
made out of papier-mâché.
All that
power.
But try to use it, you burn up.
This body I'm living in,
it's weak, human.
It's dying.
It was never made to do
the things that I can do.
But you,
you're only part human.
You have all the power
that I have inside of you.
Like father, like son.
But this
corporeal
form
can wield the power
without burning itself up.
To help you
relax.
(GRUNTING)
That will keep him sedated
until the ceremony.
Who are they?
MOREAU: Politicians, murderers,
people of influence.
The devil's soldiers.
They've traveled
from all over the world
to witness the anointing
of the new king.
JOHNNY:
Oh. The new king.
(SCOFFS)
Please.
MOREAU:
If Roarke succeeds,
he'll have a new form, one more
powerful than he's ever known.
And a shadow will
fall upon the earth.
(ALL CHANTING
IN DEMONIC LANGUAGE)
NADYA:
Twenty-five,
30 men. More inside.
The ritual has already begun.
Danny's soul
will be lost forever
at the break of dawn. This is
when Roarke is at his weakest.
Nadya?
(SIGHS)
You all right?
I've made a lot
of mistakes, Blaze.
But Danny...
Danny's the one...
The one good thing
I ever did.
Well, ahem,
that being the case,
we had better make sure he doesn't
turn out to be the Antichrist.
(ALL CHANTING
IN DEMONIC LANGUAGE)
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
Okay. Not much time.
What's the plan?
Plan is you go, you grab the boy,
you run and you don't stop.
What about you?
Me? I'm going through the front.
Okay. Ha, ha.
Not bad.
This might be good on a salad.
Johnny Blaze!
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
Go.
(SHOUTS IN FRENCH)
Ahh.
(SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Catch this one, huh?
What a waste of good wine!
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
(GROUP CHANTING IN
DEMONIC LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING IN
(ALL YELLING)
(SHOUTING IN LATIN)
That felt good.
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
Danny, listen to me.
I shouldn't have gotten rid
of the power.
I know that now.
He's gonna erase you, Danny.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(CHUCKLES)
Moreau.
I can still see the light!
Oh.
Ugh. That's gross.
ROARKE:
You have no power, Blaze.
You're nothing but an insect
like the rest.
Food for the mills
Of hell.
No.
Not yet.
Oh, you wanna watch?
The apple doesn't rot
far from the tree! Heh, heh.
Danny.
(PANTING)
This is not who you are.
It never
will be.
My powers and yours are the same.
That's what you said.
Right?
Dad?
Like father, like son.
Do it.
No!
Whoa.
MAN:
Whoa!
(JOHNNY GRUNTING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
(SHOUTING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GRUNTS)
(WEAPON FIRES)
(SPEAKS IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
(ROARING)
CARRIGAN:
Come here.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
CARRIGAN:
Enough!
I was never afraid of you.
(ROARING)
Roadkill.
(GROANING)
(ROARING)
You!
Worst fucking deal I ever made.
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
GHOST RIDER:
Go home.
(SNARLING)
NADYA:
Danny!
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
The angel.
Moreau
said that the Rider
was an angel that went crazy.
(LAUGHING)
I can feel him,
the angel.
I can feel him.
(GASPS)
Danny?
Did we win?
I'm gonna say yes.
Hell, yes.
JOHNNY:
My name is Johnny Blaze.
I'm the Ghost Rider.
(ENGLISH - US - SDH)