~~ [ African Drums ]
[ Beeping ]
~~ [ Choir Singing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Squeals, Grunts ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Camera Clicking ]
[ Grunting, Squealing ]
[ Growls ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Squeals ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Laughs ]
- [ Roars ]
- Jill!
Jill!
Jill, what did I tell you?
- But Joe started it.
- It's not good for them
to interact with us.
Besides, that wasn't Joe,
that was Marley.
- No, it wasn't. It was Joe.
- Joe's just a baby, Jill.
He's too big to be Joe.
Check.
Check the pictures.
~~ [ African Drums ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Screams ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Barks, Pants ]
- [ Growls ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Chattering ln Swahili ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Chattering ]
Hey, I said into bed.
See? I am in bed.
Jill, what made you think...
that that gorilla
we saw today was Joe?
- I was right, wasn't l?
- Yeah.
My notes say that Joe
is only six months old.
Either I got confused
or Joe is a very unusual gorilla.
- I told you so.
- Yeah, you did.
And Mommy's gonna write
in her journal...
that my trusted colleague
Dr Jill Young...
showed me the error of my ways.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughs ]
Now, go to sleep.
- [ Chimes Jingling ]
- ~ lmba wimbo wa upepo ~
~ Wakati unaji ~
~ Wa na ~
[ Together ]
~ lmba wimbo wa upepo ~
~ Wakati unajiwa na ~
Excuse me, Doctor.
- Night, Kweli.
- Good night, Jilly.
- What is it, Kweli?
- You must come. Quickly.
Mommy, can I come?
Stay here, sweetheart.
- I wanna go!
- No, no, no, no. You stay here, child.
- Poachers.
- East of the Village.
[ Ruth Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Chattering ln Swahili ]
- [ Dogs Barking ]
- [ Poacher ] N'Gai Zamu.
- N'Gai Zamu.
- They're at it again.
- N'Gai Zamu. Mystical monsters.
There is only one thing you should
be afraid of on this mountain,
and it's staring you
right in the face.
Gorilla. Fresh.
We're close.
[ Metal Rattling ]
- [ Barking ]
- [ Chattering ]
[ Roaring ]
- [ Roaring Continues ]
- [ Barking ]
Gotta stop them.
Everybody spread out.
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Roaring ]
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Gorilla Whimpering ]
- [ Squeals ]
- [ Chattering ]
[ Squeals ]
- Get the baby.
- Give me the bag.
- [ Squeals ]
- Don't worry. We want you alive.
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
Garth!
Garth! Kill him!
Joe!
Give me that gun!
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Gasps ]
- Aaah!
[ Whimpering ]
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Panting ] Joe?
- [ Whimpers ]
- Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh!
[ Dogs Barking ]
She's got to be here somewhere.
The woman's got
that damn devil with her.
[ Garth ] But I think you
might have shot her.
- [ Whimpers ]
- [ Strasser ] These people
want to live like heroes.
Let them die like heroes. Oh!
Oh! That little demon...
took off my thumb
and trigger finger.
- Monstrule! Monstrule!
- [ Garth ] What if you shot the woman?
- [ Garth ] We should help her.
- No! Let's get out of here.
Yeah. That looks bad. We better
get back before you bleed to death.
[ Strasser ] I will kill this
little monkey! I swear, I will kill him!
[ Garth ] You won't play
the violin again, that's for sure.
[ Strasser ] Shut up!
[ Whimpers ]
- [ Panting ]
- Mommy!
- [ Groans ]
- Mom, there were men and they--
- I know. I know.
- [ Groans ]
- Are you okay, Mommy?
[ Groans, Pants ]
Oh, look who's here.
Hello, Joe.
[ Whimpers ]
- He's scared.
- I know.
Poor baby.
He lost his mommy tonight.
He needs someone to protect him.
Will you do that for me?
Promise me you'll protect him.
I promise.
Ah.
[ Grunts ]
[ Together ]
~ Wimbo wa upepo ~
~ Wakati unajiwa na ~
[ Together ]
~ lmbo wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ndoto tamu ~
[ Jill ]
~ Una endelea ~
~ Milele ~
[ Choir ]
~ lmbo wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati unajiwa na ~
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ndoto tamu ~
- ~ Lala ~
- [ Whimpers ]
~ Mpaka usiku ~
Jill!
~ Upepo wa usiku ~
Come on, Joe.
Come on.
~ Wimbo wako na ~
~~ [ Choir Vocalizing ]
- You must be Pindi.
- The one and only, bro.
Come.
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Pindi Speaking ln Swahili ]
Six men, three cars. That's everything
you asked for, Mr O'Hara.
All paid for in advance
out of Pindi's own pocket.
[ Gregg ] These guys
wouldn't be poachers.
I asked for experienced trackers.
These men are the best.
I assure you,
the very best.
Let's get this show
on the road.
Hey, you've got
a nice piece here.
- What are we hunting, elephants?
- We're not hunting anything.
A-ha!
Tranquillizer darts.
I agree, much nicer
to animals than bullets.
- Your men know how to use these, right?
- Oh, sure, boss.
We only have professionals here.
So, you tell me.
Where are we going today?
There.
There?
That's not such
a good mountain, boss.
The men don't like it very much at all.
You see there is...
- a legend they believe in,
that a creature lives there.
- N'Gai Zamu.
Sacred guardian of Mount Pangani.
They say any man who enters his domain
is never heard of again.
You know it.
[ Chuckles ]
How strange.
That's not by any chance
what you're looking for, is it, boss?
Looking for a legend?
Why would I
want to do that?
[ Laughs ]
[ Pindi Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Pindi ]
What are you listening to?
Sounds.
Hmm. I understand.
Songs of the jungle.
[ Insect Buzzing ]
I know a guy. He can get you
a CD of jungle sounds cheap.
- Even cheaper if you--
- [ Animal Squealing ]
- [ Men Shouting ]
- Come on. Come on, let's go.
[ Shouting Continues ]
- [ Growls ]
- [ Men Shouting ln Swahili ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
- [ Growls ]
- [ Speaking ln Swahili ]
- See, boss, I told you
these men were the best.
- [ Growling ]
Oh.
[ Chattering ln Swahili ]
You're a beauty.
[ Growls, Shrieks ]
[ Growls ]
[ Roars ]
[ Growling ]
Okay.
Set him free.
Why bring a cage
if you're not keeping the animal?
'Cause I'm only taking this.
Yes. Yes, but...
I know a guy in Botswana.
He'd pay you 10,000 American dollars
for that leopard.
Now, I'm willing to split
with you 50-50.
Put him in the truck.
- [ Growling ]
- Put the cat down now!
- [ Growls ]
- You heard him! Put the cat down!
[ Pindi Shouting ln Swahili ]
[ Sighs ] They never understand me.
[ Rustling ]
[ Panting ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Roars ]
Excuse me, but I think
it's time to leave.
- Don't move!
- I'm not moving, but my bowels are.
Don't run!
Stay still.
[ Grunting ]
[ Howls ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Pants ]
[ Roars ]
[ Growls ]
- [ Roars ]
- [ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Roars ]
[ Growls ]
[ Grunts ]
Come on, he's gettin' away!
- Come on, we're going after him!
- What do you mean, "we"?
There's no way my men will risk
their lives with something like this.
I'll triple your pay.
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Speaking in Swahili ]
- [ Speaking ln Swahili ]
- [ Laughs ]
Don't use the tranqs
unless I give the signal!
Okay, when we catch up to him,
I want you men to herd him towards me!
- [ Gregg Shouting ln Swahili ]
- [ Pindi ] One second, one second.
Herd him towards us?
Why?
I gotta be close
to get a blood sample.
Real close.
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Men Shouting ]
[ Growls, Roars ]
[ Shouting, lndistinct ]
[ Panting ]
[ Roars ]
No, no, don't shoot!
- No!
- [ Growls ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
[ Grunting ]
- [ Men Screaming ]
- Whoa!
[ Men Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
They'll live.
- Bet you provide a great health plan.
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Gregg ] Look at the way he moves.
- Magnificent.
- [ Growls ]
Watch out!
You stupid fool!
[ Shouts ln Swahili ]
Come on, we're gonna lose him!
Come on, let's go!
What the hell is that guy
trying to do?
Hey! Hey!
[ Roars ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
I can't see him.
He's gone, long gone.
No, he's coming out
on the other side of those trees.
We gotta get in front of him.
[ Growling ]
- There he is!
- [ Roars ]
What's he--
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screaming ]
Get down!
[ Grunts ]
[ Growling ]
[ Screams ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Roars ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
Did you see that?
Did you see what he did?
Yes.
[ Quivering ] Yes.
Picked up the chain.
Did you see the intelligence?
Yes, I saw the intelligence.
- He almost took my head off!
- [ Laughs ]
[ Shouting ln Swahili ]
[ Men Chattering ln Swahili ]
- Hurry up, bro. Let's go.
- Get these men down the mountain
and bandaged up.
- You're not coming with us?
- Are you kidding?
Crazy American.
Okay!
[ Shouts ln Swahili ]
- [ Animal Growling ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Thud ]
[ Roars ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screaming ]
Joe! Joe!
- [ Roars ]
- No!
- [ Growling ]
- [ Screaming ]
Joe, stop!
Hey, can you get him
to put me down?
[ Panting ]
- Joe, drop him.
- [ Grunts ]
[ Breathes Deeply ]
- [ Speaking ln Swahili ]
- Where am l?
- The infirmary.
You've been unconscious
for an entire night.
- [ Grunts ]
- You're lucky to be alive.
I don't feel very lucky.
[ Groans ]
You crashed your vehicle.
It's waiting for you outside.
You're an injury behind.
The kicker was getting dropped
on my head by N'Gai Zamu.
- [ Laughs ]
- Oh, you think that's funny?
- You oughta try it.
- N'Gai Zamu is just
a legend, my friend.
No, he's a giant gorilla
with a mean backhand.
- Wait. There was a woman.
- A woman?
Out in the jungle, a beautiful woman.
She saved my life.
I think it would be wise for you
to see a doctor in Kimanjay.
I took the liberty
of calling one for you.
- Don't need one.
- But he's expecting you.
If you can drive,
I think it's best that you leave today.
[ Villagers Chattering ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
Our visitor must be feeling better.
Should leave the infirmary by today.
[ Jill ] Looks like he already has.
He's walking so soon?
Joe should've dropped him harder.
He's not a poacher, Jill.
The man works for animal conservancy
in California.
[ Sighs ]
He can't be trusted.
He's an outsider.
He said he was saved
yesterday by--
by a woman.
A beautiful woman.
- And what did you tell him?
- What can I tell him, Jill?
The man knows what he saw.
He's not a fool.
[ Whistles ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Growls Softly ]
- Hey, big guy.
- [ Growls Softly ]
How are ya? Hmm?
What were you doin', stompin' around
and lookin' for trouble yesterday, huh?
You're not supposed to
let people see you, remember?
Don't do that again, okay?
Please.
- Please.
- [ Grunting ]
- You wanna play?
- Okay. You ready?
- [ Grunting ]
- One, two,
three,
four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine,
ten!
Ready or not,
here I come!
Joe!
Where are you, big fella?
Coming to get you!
Oh, my!
I wonder where Joe can be.
Come out wherever you are.
- I found you!
- [ Growls ]
[ Chuckles ]
Yes, yes I did.
Yeah.
Trying to hide from me.
[ Jill Chuckling ]
You wanna come and find me?
Okay.
- [ Growls ]
- Close your eyes.
Ready? Go!
[ Grunts ]
[ Footsteps Thumping ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Joe Panting ]
Come on, Joe.
[ Roars ]
- [ Growls ]
- Nice monkey.
- [ Roars ]
- Joe.
[ Roars ]
Joe, it's okay!
Joe, run!
Get out of here!
- [ Growls ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Sighs ]
- Thanks.
Hide and seek's
not really my game.
- [ Groans ]
- Anything broken?
No. No, I think I'm--
[ Indistinct ]
- I think it's okay.
- Oh, good.
- I think it's still working.
- Oh, great.
- I can fix that for you.
- No, wait!
Hey, w-where are you going?
Wait, wait,
wait a minute!
Hey, hold on a second.
What's the problem?
You.
You're the problem.
This is the second time I've saved you
from being killed.
Next time I'm just gonna watch,
you understand?
Okay, all right.
You saved me, and I'm grateful.
Thank you, Miss Young.
I know who you are.
You're Ruth Young's daughter.
Did she know about Joe?
Did she have a theory on him?
How did you keep him a secret
all these years?
By keeping people like you
off this mountain.
People like me?
l-l wanna help you.
You go back to where you came from
and tell them what you saw,
this place will be
crawling with people.
That's gonna happen anyway.
Look, I'm not the only one
who saw him.
An animal as rare as Joe
means big money.
It's going to be tough trying to protect
him here. Maybe impossible.
Here is where he lives.
- He doesn't have a choice.
- That's not true.
The people I work for could take
care of Joe. They have the facilities.
A cage?
That's just what Joe needs.
No, no, not a cage, a preserve.
A place where he'll be free,
free from poachers, land developers.
- A place he'll be safe.
- But he won't be free.
How long do you think
he can stay free here?
The next people who come are gonna be
coming to hunt Joe down.
[ Man ] Quite an impressive facility
you have here, Mr Strasser.
- Thank you.
- Tell me, why is it...
that you keep such a low profile
about this wonderful place?
Our only interest is the well-being
of our animals.
Well, I think I've come
to the right place for Morris.
I'm sure you have.
He's grown out
of his habitat, and--
well, our zoo just doesn't have
the budget to do anything about it.
That's why he needs
a new home.
That's the telephone for you,
Mr Strasser. It's urgent.
Will you excuse me,
Mr Anderson?
- Sure.
- I'll be back.
Garth, see what the market is...
for the organs of this lovely panda.
- Ooh, big fella. We should get a lot.
- Strasser.
It's about time.
Do you know how long I've been waiting?
What do you want, Pindi?
Not what I want, boss,
what you want.
How about a giant gorilla?
- Talk.
- As big as three men.
- 2,000 pounds at least.
- You've been drinking, haven't you?
I swear to God, boss.
I saw him with my own two eyes.
He's-- He's huge!
- Don't waste my time, Pindi.
- [ Dial Tone ]
- Hello? Boss?
- 2,000 pound gorilla.
He's crazy.
Stupid girl!
What do you think you are doing?
- Huh?
- I found this
in the forest this morning.
Thought maybe you dropped it
and might want it back!
Poaching's illegal.
Get off this mountain.
[ Kweli ] Jill.
Jill, I need to talk to you.
Jill!
- Murderer.
- Yeah.
- [ Speaking ln Swahili ]
- [ Shouts ]
[ Speaking ln Swahili ]
Your mother slept in this bed.
She worked at this desk.
She died in this jungle. Do you plan
to do everything just like her?
My mother would have been proud
of what I did today.
Proud?
Of this foolishness out there?
Proud of you risking your life?
She risked hers.
Why shouldn't I risk mine?
I'm just trying to keep a promise here.
I promised to take care of Joe.
I will do everything it takes
to stop those poachers.
You cannot stop them.
Even she could not stop them.
The other gorillas,
they have moved south to safer lands.
- Joe stays behind.
- They won't accept him.
Joe needs me.
The danger here is building
for both of you.
I feel it, and so do you.
I know what the American
is offering, Jill.
Consider it.
That's all I ask.
[ Footsteps Departing ]
[ Chattering, Hooting ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Jingling ]
- Leaving?
- Yeah, I'm heading up
into the mountains.
See if I can throw some
of those dirtbags off Joe's trail.
Think it will work?
Not for long.
I'm just trying to buy you some time.
I suggest you get Joe
as deep into the jungle as you can,
as fast as you can.
- Okay.
- Okay what?
Okay, we'll go with you.
- We?
- Me and Joe.
We'll go with you to that place
of yours in California.
- You sure about this?
- No, I'm absolutely not sure
about this.
- But I'll do this on one condition.
- Name it.
- I'm in charge of Joe.
- Done.
- Done?
- Just like that?
- Just--
- You're not very trusting, are you?
- No, I'm not.
It must be tough for you then,
trying to measure me up.
- Trying to decide
if I'm full of it or--
- Or just a fool.
I guess we'll just have to
figure it out as we go along.
Look, what do you want me to say?
You'll be in charge of Joe, okay?
Come on.
We'll shake on it.
I don't shake.
That's not how
we make pacts around here.
All right, how do you
make pacts around here?
You have to endure a bite
from a Makiki spider.
- A what?
- You'll have a high fever,
hallucinations.
You'll say things, lots of things.
I'll hear what's in your heart.
Then, if your intentions prove true,
then we have a pact.
- A spider bite and hallucinations?
- That's right.
Then you'll trust me to take
you and Joe to California with me?
Absolutely.
Well? What do you say?
I say that's the biggest load of crap
I ever heard in my whole life.
Maybe you're not a fool after all.
- [ Gunfire ]
- [ Laughter ]
[ Chattering, Hooting Continues ]
Get your things together fast.
We're gettin' outta here
as soon as we can.
Makiki spider.
I don't know what else to do, Joe.
I just want you to be safe.
[ Sighs ]
You think he's okay back there?
- He's doing fine.
- Okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm just a little tense.
You think he's okay back there?
- I think he's okay back there.
- Good.
So, this is L.A., huh?
- Everything looks the same.
How do you know where you are?
- It's easy.
Ocean's that way, the mountains
are that way, Mexico's that way,
and Canada's that-a-way.
Don't worry about the rest.
You'll never see it through the smog.
Maybe you better check and see
if Joe's okay back there.
Mom! M-Mom!
Main gate to Dr Banks.
They're pulling up now.
- [ Chattering ]
- I copy that.
Okay, everybody,
Elvis is in the building!
[ Snorting ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
- [ Woman ] He's big!
- [ Man ] Did you see him?
The fun begins.
- [ Birds Squawking, Clucking ]
- You hear that, Harry? They smell him.
Who, Gregg or the gorilla?
All right.
I'm a little confused, O'Hara,
because you phoned us
to say you're bringing back
a 2,000-pound wild animal--
- Hello, Harry. Hiya, gorgeous.
- Welcome back, Gregg.
But security tells me
you requested no fire hoses
and no restraints of any kind.
- Come on, let me introduce you.
- Well, how are we supposed
to control this animal?
- With a giant rolled-up newspaper? Hi.
- Jill Young, I'd like you...
to meet Dr Harry Ruben,
who runs the place.
- Nice to meet you.
- And Dr Cecily Banks,
- who makes sure he doesn't screw it up.
- Nice to meet you both.
[ Joe Grunting, Thumping ]
Hold on, big guy.
I'm comin'.
I think he's ready to come out.
Harry, I think it's time
you met Joe.
I know it looks small,
but this is just the entrance.
- He has the entire hill to roam.
- Okay.
Jack, Vern, are we gonna have to
hose you guys down too?
- Come on, get the sedatives ready.
- [ Jill ] No, no, no.
- We don't need any of that.
- Don't worry.
We know what we're doing here.
Hey, whoa, hold on.
Harry, we had an agreement.
- The lady's in charge of Joe.
- How is she gonna handle--
- Easy, tiger. Come on.
- [ Joe Growling ]
Calm down. Calm--
Okay, guys. I got it.
All right.
You sure you got everything
under control?
Yeah.
Come on.
- You sure she knows what she's doing?
- She knows.
You want me to come in there
and get you?
There you go.
Come on.
Come look at your new home.
- [ Footsteps Pounding ]
- Come on. There you go.
Come on, Joe.
Come on.
[ Sighs ]
[ Harry ] Vern, what am I paying
you for? Get some pictures.
- All right.
- And get me in there, too.
You know, for perspective.
- [ Camera Shutters Clicking ]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Crowd Gasping ]
Okay. It's okay, Joe.
Hey. Hey, Joe.
Come on. Nothing happened.
You're not scared
of those people are you?
I promise nothing
will happen to you, okay?
- Come on, Joe.
- [ Jill ] Come on, Joe. Come on.
There you go.
Yeah, you big guy.
Come on, Joe.
There you go.
Come on, big guy.
Come on.
[ Crowd Applauding, Cheering ]
- I think he's gonna be fine.
- [ O'Hara ] I'm glad.
[ Harry ] Let's move
that platform out of there.
- Oh, no, I'm going back
in there with him.
- No, I'm sorry.
We can't allow that.
We don't have insurance to cover
anyone who's not an employee.
You're not serious.
- But I'm supposed
to be in charge of Joe.
- Yes, you are.
And I'm in charge of this facility.
[ Jack ] Let's go! Take it up.
[ Jack ] Okay, swing it up!
"And I'm in charge of this facility."
I mean, who does he think he is?
I bet that man has never spent
one night outside in his entire life.
Probably not. Well, here are
your new, deluxe accommodations.
I should be out there with Joe,
not here. Not in this--
this cage.
[ O'Hara ] Look, I know how you feel.
It's not exactly my idea
of "home, sweet home" either,
but at least you're close to Joe.
Where's Gregg?
Talk to you later. I don't know.
He collected his paycheck.
He's probably in some jungle by now,
looking for giant sheep.
Well, I think he should be here.
This is his discovery.
Excuse me.
Gregg's expertise is crashing Humvees.
It's not explaining primate behaviour to
the chairman of the conservancy board.
[ Cecily ] You know what I think, Harry?
I think you're jealous.
I'm crippled with envy, yes.
Just once I wanted to go into the field
and find a new species.
You know, anything.
A mollusc.
- [ Car Door Closes ]
- Here we go.
- Harry. Dr Banks.
- Hi.
So, let's go see him.
See, the gorillas in the Pangani
carry this recessive gene...
that pops up every four
or five generations with
this rare form of gigantism.
And that's where
the legend comes from.
[ Harry ] But I knew it was more
than a legend,
so I followed my gut instinct.
- I just had a hunch
that this thing was true.
- Pretty damn sharp, Harry.
All right, here we are.
- Pretty cool, huh?
- My, my, I should say so.
- Where is he?
- Um--
Uh, Joe?
- Come here, Joe!
- [ Fly Buzzing ]
Come here, boy.
Gorillas. There's never one around
when you need 'em.
- Even for the chairman of the board.
- Well, I came here to see him.
You know what, maybe--
You know what, I'll feed him.
- That'll get him to come out.
- Um, Harry--
Don't worry.
I know what I'm doing.
Elliot, you stay here.
I'm gonna go open the gate.
Silver, brown, blond, white. There are
nine different colours to choose from.
[ Woman On TV ] Ron, you have to ask
things like toxicity. This is safe?
[ Ron ] This product has been tested
for ten years.
It's not just a coloured spray,
like some of you might be thinking.
- It's just a plain, ordinary cosmetic.
- [ Chuckling ]
- [ Alarm Blaring ]
- And it just washes out in the evening.
[ Panting ]
- I was coming to get you.
- What's that noise?
Security alarm in Joe's habitat.
Come on.
- Joe-- Joe--
- What's happening?
- He's going crazy.
- Open the gate!
- [ Joe Roaring ]
- Open it! Open it!
[ Whimpering ]
- Hold it! Don't shoot!
- No!
Oh, God.
Harry, it's okay.
- It doesn't feel okay.
- Listen to me.
- Just jump out from behind the trees.
- No.
No, I'd rather not.
Just jump out and say,
"You found me."
Well, he knows he's found me!
That's the problem!
Harry, do what she says.
- You found me!
- [ Grunting ]
Oh, God.
He's playing with him.
Harry, he's playing with you.
- Hide-and-seek.
- [ Harry ] What?
Shh. Watch.
Joe, where are you?
Where could Joe be?
- Here he is!
- Feeding time over, Harry?
- Very funny.
- Good thing Joe didn't
want to play doctor.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Look at you, all happy.
Huh, Joe?
That makes me so happy.
- Harry.
- You know what?
That never happened before.
-It was weird, wasn't it?
-Put that girl in charge of the gorilla.
Elliot, she has
no scientific training.
That ape is the best fund-raising tool
this conservancy's ever had.
He's happy, I'm happy.
So, you really think that
she's gonna be able to, you know--
- Put her on the payroll, Harry.
- Okay.
- Did you see that? Did you see that?
- I saw, I saw.
- He was playing hide-and-seek with him!
- It's great.
You were right.
He likes it here.
Oh, my God!
On his second day he's playing!
- He likes it here!
- Mm-mm-mm-mm.
- You've got it bad.
- What are you talking about?
[ Cecily ]
You know what I'm talking about.
Usually you are out the door
as soon as the animal's in his habitat.
You have a very active imagination.
[ Chuckling ]
I don't think so.
- Oh, I think so.
- No, I don't think so.
I think Mister World Traveller has
goo-goo eyes for the gorilla girl.
Just close your eyes,
and then he's gonna do that.
And then you say, "You found me!"
Come on.
[ Woman On TV ] Behind me is the habitat
of what the experts are calling...
one of the world's most important
zoological finds of this century.
This is the home of what is believed
to be the world's largest primate,
a 2,000-pound gorilla named Joe.
Joe has been at the California
Animal Conservancy for
a little over a month now.
He was brought here from Africa
by Dr Gregory O'Hara,
- who told me that because
of Joe's remarkable size,
- My God, Pindi was right.
he is a natural target for poachers.
- Fortunately, the California
Animal Conservancy programme...
- He's beautiful.
is rescuing animals
and bringing them here...
- so they can--
- The most beautiful animal I ever seen.
And the most valuable,
that's for sure.
[ Woman On TV ] It can't escape
because it's surrounded by a moat,
and there are also electrical wires
around the entire perimeter.
- Isn't that the--
- Wait. Be quiet.
Joe was raised from infancy
by Jill Young, the daughter of
famed primatologist Ruth Young.
Their closeness stems
from a tragic bond.
Both Joe and Jill's mothers
were killed by poachers
12 years ago in the Pangani Forest.
- Bloody hell, that's him!
- They both became orphans
on the same night.
That's the little fella
who bit your finger off!
[ Sighs ]
I'm always amazed how,
if you wait long enough, the opportunity
for justice finally comes.
Garth, book us two tickets
to America.
We are going to pay a visit
to this incredible animal.
I think I know how to convince
his current owners to part with him.
[ Harry ] Now, this fellow is
one of only 300 wild yaks...
remaining on the planet.
Now, you may ask: Why should we care
if this subspecies of yak survives?
- But if we don't protect--
- Excuse me.
- Can we see Joe?
- [ Group Chattering ln Agreement ]
[ Harry ] Yes, you can certainly
all see Joe for the mere price of...
a diamond circle benefactor ticket
to tomorrow night's benefit.
But, you know,
this is for a good cause.
It's for the preservation
of an endangered species.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Gasps ]
You remember, don't you?
[ Laughing ]
- This is what you call
a good meal in a fine restaurant?
- ~~ [ Saxophone ]
Yeah.
It's my favourite restaurant
'cause they let you take off your shoes.
My granddad used to bring me
fishing down here when I was a kid.
Wow. The Pacific Ocean.
That's nice. Live music.
I hired him special.
Ten minutes ago.
You wanna dance?
What?
So, this is a date, or something?
Not that I'd know.
I've never been on one before.
Yeah, well, I guess most guys
are afraid of a girl's father.
I can just see a guy telling Joe
he's gonna get you home by midnight.
Well, nobody's ever had to tell Joe
what time they'll have me home by.
What's it like?
"lt"?
Yeah. This whole dating,
dancing, love thing.
Well, it's...
kind of like being bit
by a Makiki spider.
And how's that?
- You get kind of a fever.
- Fever?
Ah. And then?
And then you--
you find yourself saying things.
Lots of things.
What kind of things?
Things like--
- [ Both Gasping ]
- What is it?
I'm sorry.
It's this thing.
We gotta go.
[ Harry ] I don't understand
this animal.
- He's got everything he wants.
Why can't he just relax?
- Harry, stop. Oh.
He's ripping out saplings,
bam, bam, bam!
- Taking out irrigation pipe.
- Really? Oh.
One big yank,
here comes the flood.
- What happened? What's wrong with him?
- We don't know. Jill, do you?
- Is he okay?
- [ Joe Roaring ]
- Can you get in there
and calm him down...
- Joe?
before he relandscapes
the habitat?
Joe, it's okay.
It's okay.
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Unajiwa na ~
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Ndoto tamu ~
~ Lala ~
~ Mpaka ~
~ Usiku ~
~ Uisheni ~
~ Upepo ~
~ Wa usiku ~
~ Wimbo ~
~ Wako na ~
~ Wangu ~
~ Unaendelea ~
~ Milele ~~
- Impossible.
- [ Jill ] Please.
I wouldn't be asking you
to postpone the benefit...
unless I thought there was
something really wrong with Joe.
And I do.
From what I hear, you sang him to sleep
last night like a baby.
What's really wrong
about that?
Mr Baker, I swear to you,
Joe is still not himself.
He's nervous and agitated,
and he shouldn't be exposed
to a crowd of strangers right now.
If you can just delay the party
just a few more--
- It's too late, Jill.
- No!
- It's too soon.
- Miss Young,
let me give you some advice:
Stop worrying about Joe,
and start worrying about what
you will wear to the party tonight.
- [ Walkie-Talkie Clicks On ]
- Cecily?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- No, my fault.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
It's just--
- What?
- You must be Jill Young.
Yes?
[ Chuckles ]
And you look just like her.
- Who?
- Your mother.
- You knew my mother?
- Yes.
I'm an old friend
of your mother's.
I knew her when she was, uh,
only a little older than you.
- And you were just a tiny thing.
- Oh.
- What an incredible woman she was.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm Andre Strasser.
I've come here
to talk with your Mr Baker.
- Actually, I'm here for Joe.
- Joe?
And, in a way,
for your mother too.
I believe she would agree with me.
A magnificent wild animal
like Joe needs more space,
Iike the Raja Preserve
I run in Botswana.
Raja Preserve?
[ Chuckles ]
It's 20,000 acres there...
where the animals
are free to run.
Here it's such a shame to see Joe
living in a man-made habitat...
and being used as
an attraction to raise money.
But I upset you.
- No.
- Please.
I only mean to offer
an alternative.
Anyway, here is my card.
I'll be attending
the event tonight.
Maybe we can talk more
about this matter then.
I look forward to it.
Yeah. Bye.
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Harry ] Boy, I can't believe
all the V.I.P.s here tonight.
Ooh, don't you clean up nice?
- Cecily, you look ravishing.
- Thank you.
Harry, you got a little, um,
cocktail sauce on your shirt there.
Oh, great.
Now I look ridiculous.
No, you look fine.
They look ridiculous.
- Uh-huh.
- [ Harry ] Yeah, well, she doesn't.
[ Cecily ] I picked out the dress.
Aren't I smart?
Brilliant.
Harry, you're dripping again.
Oh, look at me.
I'm a mess here.
You know, I have to give
a speech tonight.
You think anyone'll notice?
No.
Hi.
I feel so stupid
in this dress.
You look anything but stupid.
Come on,
let's get a drink.
[ Woman ] She reminds me of somebody,
but...
I can't think who it is.
You, when we first met.
Why are they staring at me?
They're not staring at you, they're
staring at, uh, that banana tower.
- Very funny.
- [ Chuckling ]
Come on.
It's nice to see you all.
Good evening.
- Quite a turnout.
- All the better.
[ Dr Baker On P.A. ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
would you please take your seats?
Please. Can I have
your attention, please?
Can I have your attention, please?
- Take your seats.
- Ooh, I'm sorry. Oh.
Excuse me, sir, you, uh,
dropped your, uh--
- Key chain.
- Ah, of course.
Garth, you would lose your head
if it wasn't screwed on.
- Nice party, huh?
- [ All Chuckling ]
- [ Dr Baker Continues ]
Just take your seats.
- Where do we think he's from?
- I don't know.
- I'm Elliot Baker.
The world was once
a garden teeming with life.
A wondrous place to contemplate
creation in all its--
[ Dr Baker Continues ]
[ Jingling ]
[ Growling ]
[ Guests Gasping, Panicked Chattering ]
- So, you haven't forgotten me?
- [ Dr Baker ]
Can I have your attention?
As you can hear, the secret...
- announced itself loud and clear.
- Good.
Have you forgotten this?
[ Screaming ]
How much do you think he's worth,
couple of million?
After we sell him off,
piece by piece,
who knows how much we'll make?
- Ah, that got you going.
- [ Guests Gasping, Chattering ]
Now be a good boy
and frighten the ladies.
Can I have your attention?
Our guest seems to be telling you...
- that I'm talking too long.
- Okay, let's go.
We've done our job here.
I'd like to bring up to the podium
the director of our conservancy--
- [ Joe Growling ]
- [ Gasping, Chattering ]
Well, I suppose there's no need
to add to that introduction.
Here's Dr Harry Ruben!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
In the time it took you
to drive here tonight,
three species have disappeared
from the Earth.
Extinct. Never to be replaced.
We here at the conservancy
say this is a tragedy--
- [ Joe Growling ]
- [ Gasping, Excited Chatter ]
Well, uh, obviously Joe agrees.
[ Chuckling ]
- There's something wrong.
- [ Harry ] But, um,
tonight, instead of focusing
on what we've lost,
we'd like to introduce you
to something that we've found.
Ladies and gentlemen, behind
this curtain is the newest member...
of the California Animal Conservancy.
We are very happy and proud
to introduce to you,
- Mighty Joe--
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Guests Screaming ]
- Joe?
It's okay.
[ Jill ] Come on, Joe.
[ Jill Gasps ] No! Joe!
[ Gasping ]
My God, what's wrong with him?
He's out of control!
I'm going for the tranq gun!
No, Gregg!
I'll stop him!
[ Screaming ]
- Oh, my God!
- [ Screaming, Shouting ]
Move!
- [ Gun Fires ]
- [ Groans ]
Oh, God.
[ Whimpering ]
[ Gun Fires ]
[ Guns Firing ]
- [ Guests Gasping, Crying ]
- [ Sighing ]
[ Female Reporter ] The gorilla
literally crashed the party.
Officials here at the conservancy
are saying...
they don't know what caused
the animal's rampage.
More than a dozen people
were injured.
Eight of them remain
hospitalized today.
In fact, three lawsuits
have been filed so far,
and word has it the city's
attorney is calling for
the animal to be put to sleep.
Standing with me is the conservancy
board's chairman, Elliot Baker.
Exactly what is being done to assure
the public that Joe won't attack again?
Joe has been transferred to a special
steel-reinforced concrete bunker.
[ Male Reporter ] But what about
when you let him out?
That won't be happening any time soon.
In fact, I want to make it clear
that we will be doing...
anything necessary to ensure
the safety of the public.
[ Male Reporter ] With the number of
lawsuits the conservancy is now facing,
will you shut down the facility
to the public?
Joe.
I'm right here. Okay?
I knew there was
something wrong with him.
What do you think
happened out there?
Joe would have never hurt
those people unprovoked.
Something must've got to him.
- [ Door Opens ]
- Jill?
Could l, um, talk to you for a second?
[ Door Closes ]
Well, this wasn't
in the brochure, was it?
I promised you wouldn't be
put in a cage.
I'm sorry, Joe.
Then the city attorney
talked to Baker.
- I had nothing to do with this.
- With what?
Joe's gonna have to stay in here
until they decide
what they're gonna do with him.
- In here?
- Yeah.
Harry, look at him.
He's depressed.
He won't eat.
If he stays in here,
he'll die within days.
There is nothing we can do.
Either you tell them you're getting
Joe out of here, or I will.
This is way beyond
you and me.
Joe freaked out on some
very influential people.
Now he's a public relations nightmare.
No zoo will take
a 2,000-pound killer gorilla!
- He's not a killer!
- Okay, okay.
But unless you can write a cheque
for millions of dollars...
and find him
a big backyard somewhere,
then Joe's got nowhere to go.
I'm sorry.
Harry.
You're not gonna do anything?
[ Door Closes ]
I need your help.
- [ Cecily ] Good evening.
- Good evening.
- You can't go in there.
- It's okay. We're here
to give Joe more sedatives.
Wha-- I, uh--
Unless you want him
to get frisky on your shift,
I suggest you let us get on with our job
so you can get on with yours.
Come on, Joe.
We're leaving.
- [ Sighs ]
- Yeah.
Let's get you out of here.
- [ Shotgun Cocks ]
- What the hell are you doin'?
The gorilla needs medication,
and I've gotta take him
over to the clinic for that.
- Who says?
- Doctor's orders, and I'm the doctor.
Yeah, well, uh,
I take my orders from Mr Baker,
so, uh, put him back
in his cage now.
- [ Roars ]
- Easy, Joe, easy.
Officer, you don't want to point
that thing at him, believe me.
He didn't believe you.
Okay, come on!
Bring him out!
Come on, big guy.
Come on.
Come on, Joe.
Into the truck.
[ Sighs ] That's it.
Okay.
Thanks.
[ Sighs ]
I am gonna miss
those big ol' brown eyes.
You be good, Joe.
Goodbye, Joe.
I was just starting to get
the hang of hide-and-seek.
I, uh, I think you should be
all right up here at the gate.
Someone, uh, just called the guard away.
Urgent business.
You came through for us, Harry.
- Thank you.
- Good luck.
You be sure to write us
as soon as you get Joe settled, okay?
I promise.
Okay. You're all set.
So, you're gonna...
come to the airport,
or--
No, I'm gonna hang back and make sure
nobody notices Joe's gone,
give you guys a chance
to make a run for it.
Okay.
If you're ever in Botswana and
feel like taking me out for a
good meal at a fine restaurant--
That is, if you're not too afraid
to let Joe know what time you'll be--
Jill, we should go now.
The plane is waiting.
Come.
Let's go.
- [ Whispers ] Gotta go.
- Yeah.
- Hello.
- Hi.
[ Engine Starts ]
Don't worry, Jill.
Soon Joe will be
back home again.
So, what do you think?
How many minutes before the whole world
knows he's missing?
- Five.
- Hmph.
- How many minutes before
we're both looking through the want ads?
- Six.
What are you guys doin' here?
What are you guys
doin' here?
Baker wants us to clean up
the tent A.S.A.P.
Yeah, you should see some of the stuff
we found in the post-party melee.
We've got the fun job of figuring out
who all this stuff belongs to.
Somebody's head
is very cold right now.
- Look at this. What is this thing?
- [ Loud Jingling ]
Where did you find this?
- By the habitat.
We gotta find those two guys.
- What two guys?
What, that-- that one guy,
he was, what, Lithuanian.
Yeah, Russian.
Eastern European.
- Is everything okay?
- That thing's used by poachers!
[ Engine Starts ]
- Please, be careful.
- [ Gears Grinding ]
Always worrying, huh?
Your mother was a worrier too.
Always worrying
about the gorillas.
[ Chuckles ]
It made her a lot of enemies.
It led to tragedy.
My mother was brave.
So are you, my dear.
What? It's not pretty.
I know.
I'm sorry.
How did it happen?
Well, you could say
I had an encounter...
with a monster.
Monstrule.
[ Laughing ]
"Monstrule."
Oh! That little demon...
took off my thumb
and trigger finger!
Monstrule! Monstrule!
[ Horn Honking ]
- [ Horns Honking ]
- [ Tyres Screeching ]
Come on, come on!
[ Horn Honking, Tyres Screeching ]
[ Grunts ] Murderer! Aaah!
[ Panting, Yells ]
- Jeez!
- [ Groans ]
Joe! Get out!
Keep driving!
- [ Tyres Screeching ]
- [ Horns Continue Honking ]
Jill! Are you okay?
What did I do? Those are
the guys who killed my mother.
We gotta go!
Joe's in trouble!
Whoa!
[ Yelling, Groaning ]
[ Truck Horn Blasting ]
[ Strasser ] Stop it!
Ohh!
Get out of the way!
Come on, let's go!
Come on, move it!
Move it!
- Ohh!
[ Both Yelling ]
- Whoa! Look!
- Can you see it?
[ Onlookers Shouting, Chattering ]
[ Engine Sputters, Stops ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
What? Come on.
Nobody's seen an accident? What?
- [ Gasps ]
- Oh, my God.
Phat!
Come on. Come on!
- [ Horns Honking ]
- Will you just go!
[ Shrieking ]
[ Shrieking Continues ]
[ Wailing, Sobbing ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Onlookers Continue
Shouting, Screaming ]
- Come on.
- Wait.
The police will be here
any second.
We have to get away from here.
[ Woman Shrieking ]
Ape! Oh, my God!
[ Roaring ]
[ Alarm Blaring ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
Far out!
- All right!
- [ Alarm Continues ]
[ Alarm Falters, Stops ]
- [ Woman ] Turn it off!
- [ Satisfied Grunt ]
Go, Lisa, go!
Hurry!
- [ Engine Cranking ]
- Aaah!
[ All Screaming ]
- [ All Whimpering ]
- Oh... my God.
- [ Laughing ]
- Oh, my God. Shut up!
- What are you laughing at?
- That was so cool!
- Cool?
- He almost squashed us!
That was not funny at all!
[ Cashier Screams ]
- [ Whimpering, Panting ]
- [ Siren Blares ]
- Yeah!
- Go, Joe! Yeah!
- All right!
- Go, Joe!
Oh, no.
He's not here.
- Couldn't have gotten far.
- [ Woman ] Come on, girls.
- Come on. This way.
- Let's go.
Copy that.
Our orders are shoot to kill.
He's extremely dangerous.
Shoot to kill? He's not dangerous.
You're dangerous!
It's okay, Officer.
She didn't mean it.
-I meant it! They're going to shoot him.
-Not if we find him first.
- [ Helicopter Whirring ]
- What's that?
That's it.
We'll follow that helicopter.
- What?
- Come on!
[ Whines ]
[ Man ] I'm already 20 minutes late.
Who's gonna pay for this?
What are you doing?
We can't go after the gorilla now.
[ Strasser ] We need a car.
[ Man ] What is your supervisor's name?
- Would you please
step out of the vehicle.
- What's the problem?
Fifth time this year.
Hey. Hey!
Hey, I'm goin'!
I'm goin'!
-[ Doors Close ]
-You don't have to be so pushy about it!
Hello?
County Animal Control?
- You're not gonna believe this.
- [ Woman ] Honey, look at the birdbath.
Yes! Yes, it was
a gorilla, a big one!
- Did you guys see it?
- [ Barking ]
Andy, come on, sweetheart.
No, no. It's a gorilla, honey.
[ Joe Grunting ]
[ Whines ]
[ Roaring ]
SWAT One, SWAT One, this is Police 2-4.
We've found him.
[ Horns Honking ]
[ Truck Horn Blaring ]
[ Tyres Screeching ]
- [ Roars ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Pilot ] Yeah, Police 2-4,
SWAT One's on the scene.
He's goin' in the brush.
Don't lose him.
[ Growling ]
[ Rifle Shots ]
We've got him now.
[ Rifle Shots Continue ]
Look out!
Electrical wires!
Pull up! Pull up!
Where'd he go?
- He must have gone under that overpass.
- Well, cut him off.
Bring 'er down.
Must've gone up
that access ramp.
Let's go find 'im.
Let's go.
[ Growls ]
[ O'Hara ] Where's he headed?
[ Jill ] Look.
He thinks it's my flashlight.
He's going towards the light.
He thinks I'm calling him. That's it!
[ Riders Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Laughing, Yelling ]
[ Hooting, Screaming Continues ]
- Daddy!
- Hi, Mommy!
- Mom, I don't think you
should go on this ride.
- Why?
- Because you threw up last time.
- What if I promise
to throw up over the side?
I should go on this by myself.
Okay. I'll get us
some cotton candy.
- Okay.
- And no rocking, Jason!
- Have a good time.
[ Barker ] All you gotta do is
hit the pig on the bottom!
That's all you gotta do!
[ Joe Roaring ]
[ Crowd Screaming ]
Oh, my-- Honey, come on.
Come on with Mommy. Give Mommy a break.
- No, Mommy, let's stay!
- No, honey!
[ Mother ] Please!
[ Shouting ]
[ Confused Grunting ]
[ Growling ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Come on, let's stop it!
Come on, kids, outta there.
There's a wild animal loose.
- Find your parents. Go! Go!
- Whoa!
- [ Gunshots ]
- See that thing?
Yow!
- [ Growls ]
- Holy--
[ Loud Roar ]
Come on.
There she is.
Just what exactly
are you aiming at?
No! You can't do that.
If that girl starts telling people
who we really are,
our whole cover operation
will be blown.
She's not an animal.
- She's a human being.
- Joe!
Let's go this way.
- [ Rifle Shot ]
- [ Both Yell ]
That was very stupid, Garth.
- What was that?
- I don't know. Come on.
[ Woman Screams ] Fire!
[ Man Yells ] Fire!
- Go on! Find Joe!
- Joe!
You're not a hunter, you're a murderer,
and I don't want any part of this.
[ Groans ]
Anything else on your mind?
The fire's spreading fast.
Keep this wheel moving.
We'll get 'em out on the run.
Come on, you guys.
All right. That's it.
[ O'Hara ] Okay, come on.
Oh, my God.
[ Boy ]
Keep running! Hurry!
Move it!
Mommy!
[ Ride Operator ]
Okay, we got everybody off! Thanks!
Aaah!
- Go, go, go!
- Help!
[ Woman Screaming ]
It's an ape!
Jason!
[ Growling ]
Joe! [ Sighs ]
[ Gun Cocks ]
Goodbye, Jill.
Meet your mother...
in hell.
Goodbye.
- [ Gasps, Screaming ]
- [ Gunshot ]
[ Strasser Screaming ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Quiet Growl ]
Bring the marksmen
up here now!
[ Fire Truck Horn Blasting ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Horn Continues Blasting ]
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Policemen Shouting ]
- [ Shouting Continues ]
- We need paramedics. Over.
Jill!
Strasser was here. Joe just killed him.
We gotta get out of here now.
It's too late.
No. We gotta stop 'em.
Come on!
- [ Jason Crying ] Mom! Mom!
- [ Gasps ]
- Evacuate the area! Get out of the way!
- Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
- He's not dangerous!
- [ Officer ] Get out of here!
[ Sighs ]
Mom!
[ Continues Crying ]
Mommy, help me.
[ Whines ]
Joe?
- Joe!
- Fire upon my command!
[ Commanding Officer ] Ready!
Officer, I can't find my son,
and I never saw him
get off the Ferris wheel.
Look!
Oh, my God!
- Jason!
- Mommy.
Mommy!
He's gonna try and save him.
Don't shoot!
Hold your fire!
[ Whimpering ]
[ Whispers ]
Come on, Joe.
- [ Onlookers Chattering, Shouting ]
- Get the trucks in place.
[ Jason ] Help, please!
He's gonna be okay.
[ Shouting, Chattering Continue ]
- Mom.
- Hang on.
[ Moans Softly ]
- He's got him.
- [ Explosion ]
- [ Roaring ]
- Oh, no! Jason!
[ Whispers ]
Come on, Joe.
[ Beams Creaking ]
Oh, my God, it's gonna tip!
It's gonna tilt!
- Everybody get back! Run!
- Joe!
- [ Screaming Hysterically ] No! No!
- [ Joe Groans ]
- Get out of the way! Run!
- [ Wailing ]
- Come on! Come on!
- [ Jason Screaming ]
- [ Joe Roaring ]
No!
Aaah!
[ Jason's Mother Continues
Screaming, Wailing ]
Oh, please!
Oh, baby!
- Joe!
- [ O'Hara ] Easy does it.
Open your eyes.
Come on, big guy.
- Come on. Oh, yeah, honey.
- Mommy!
- Ohh. I'm here.
- [ Jill ] Come on, big guy.
- Open your eyes.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
Come on, Joe!
Joe?
No. No. No.
- Mommy, is he gonna be okay?
- I don't know, honey.
[ Sobbing ] No. No!
Joe!
Keep these people back!
- [ Jill Weeping ]
- Back it up!
No.
No!
[ Continues Weeping ]
[ Whispers ]
Don't leave me, big guy.
[ Gasps ]
[ Jill ] Joe?
[ Wheezes ]
- Joe?
- [ Wheezing Continues ]
- He's alive!
- He's alive?
- Joe!
- [ O'Hara ] He's alive!
- [ Laughing ] Joe.
- He's alive!
You big palooka.
That's no way to ride a Ferris wheel.
Joe!
Big guy, you scared me.
We gotta get him outta here,
get him somewhere safe.
Somewhere safe?
Somewhere safe means
a new home for Joe.
Where are we gonna get
that kind of money?
I've got some money for Joe.
Here. For Joe.
- Folks, let's help him out.
- [ O'Hara ] Thank you.
[ O'Hara Laughs ] Thank you.
Thank you.
[ Jill ] Dear Cecily,
I promised to write you when Joe
was settled, and now I finally can.
With all the contributions
people sent in for Joe,
we were able to buy a beautiful land
preserve that's even big enough for him.
[ All Cheering ]
Tome fahura!
We dedicated
the Joe Young Wildlife Park today,
and it was one of
the happiest days of my life.
At last...
I have kept my promise
to my mother.
The people here are saying N'Gai Zamu
the sacred guardian...
- [ Roaring ]
- has returned to protect the mountains.
Other people still say
N'Gai Zamu is just a legend.
I say legends live forever.
[ Joe Roars ]
[ Chorus ]
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Unajiwa na ~
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Ndoto tamu ~
~ Lala ~
~ Mpaka ~
~ Usiku ~
~ Uisheni ~
~ Upepo ~
~ Wa usiku ~
~ Wimbo ~
~ Wako na ~
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Unajiwa na ~
- ~ lmba wimbo ~
- ~~ [ Woman Vocalizing ]
- ~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Ndoto tamu ~
- ~ Lala ~
- ~~ [ Vocalizing Continues ]
- ~ Mpaka ~
~ Usiku ~
~ Uisheni ~
~ Upepo ~
~ Wa usiku ~
~ Wimbo ~
~ Wako na ~
~ Upepo ~
~ Wa usiku ~
~ Wimbo ~
~ Wako na ~
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Unajiwa na ~
~ lmba wimbo ~
~ Wa upepo ~
~ Wakati ~
~ Ndoto tamu ~
~ Lala ~
~ Mpaka ~
~ Usiku ~
~ Uisheni ~
~ Upepo ~
~ Wa usiku ~
~ Wimbo ~
~ Wako na ~
~ Wangu ~
~ Unaendelea ~
~ Upepo ~
~ Wa usiku ~
~ Wimbo ~
~ Wako na ~~