It's time to wake up...
...and get a life.
We live in a three-dimensional world.
Until now, the world of computing has been a flat world,
consisting of two-dimensional imagery.
Now, through the use of exclusive breakthrough technology,...
...ARC has made it possible for you to get a life.
A Life, where we can work and play in a life like world
of three-dimensional reality.
A Life, the living monitor.
Impressed?
Yeah, I am.
Would you put one of those in a box for me?
- Are you the lawyer?
- I'm Rita Dunne.
Obviously, no one from Nexim could be here today.
- I'd invite you in, but--
- Good luck, Mr. Jennings.
- I'll see you in two months.
- Yeah.
Home sweet home.
What do you think?
This is the exact same technology?
Not the exact same technology. No.
Ultimately, I decided to reconceive some of it.
I never liked the way the monitor looked.
And then it occurred to me who needs it?
Gentlemen, I am the future of computing.
And I would like to present you with Nexim's
new Freedom Line of display technology.
New from Nexim.
Freedom is in your future.
Launch this now.
ARC is not gonna last.
Who said 100 percent market share was impossible?
Get me Marketing immediately.
This far exceeds our expectations.
Congratulations.
Well, thank you.
You understand, Mr. Jennings, you've just done in
two months what we've been trying to do for three years.
Sometimes it's easier if you work backwards.
Cheers.
You won't remember me, will you?
No.
That's too bad.
Marker reached.
OK.
We're now extracting his memory
from the marker forward to the present.
Jesus, Rita.
Jesus Christ!
This is dangerous enough.
If this man's brain temp goes one C above 43, he's a veg.
Come on, Mike.
Here we go.
It's all clean.
Good morning, sunshine.
Hey, how you doing, big guy?
- OK?
- Yeah.
All right. Thank you. Take it easy.
Slow, slow, slow.
There's no hurry, OK?
- That's it. Good?
- Yeah.
Good man. Hey, Mike, look at me.
Look at me. Right here.
What's the last date you remember?
- October 19.
- Very good.
Mike, what's the last thing you remember?
The Red Sox made the playoffs.
OK. Let's get the legal out of the way, shall we?
Mr. Michael Jennings,
under the terms of your non-disclosure agreement,...
...you are considered never to have been an employee.
You also understand that all your work
is the intellectual property of Nexim...
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I never worked here. I never saw anybody.
I never was here. I got it.
Is my paycheck ready?
Alrighty.
- How you feeling, tiger?
- Good.
- Now let's hear you.
- All right.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Go!
In order to zero the full eight weeks
I had to heat your brain to 42.5 C.
- I'm fine.
- I'm saying it's getting harder, Mike.
- I said, I'm fine.
- You're slowing down actually. Come on.
I'd be faster if you'd shut up.
Show me what you've got, grasshopper.
That's it. That's more like it!
Yes! Go, go, go!
Go! Go!
Yes! Faster!
Beautiful!
Yes! One more! One more, Mikey!
Now you see how you did that?
How you focused?
- Yeah, I focus on your face.
- Oh, no. You know you Iove me.
Come on. Come on.
Don't be mean to the one who does everything for you.
Do you realize you've never once
asked me what I see when I erase your memory?
Basically, the last two months just never happened for you.
What's to know?
20 hours a day in a clean room...
...ripping off one guy's idea for a computer,
selling it to somebody else. You know.
What'd you do the last two months?
You know, the last thing I remember is
driving in Spain in the Aston Martin,...
...learning to dive in Belize with what's-her-name.
The seven-stadiums-in-seven-days trip.
It's great.
I mean, my memories are basically highlights.
It's good. It's a good life.
The stuff you erase, it doesn't matter.
What is it with guys like Rethrick?
- He's gotta have everything, huh?
- Well,...
...say what you want about Jimmy,
he started Allcom in his garage.
- Wait, wait. Don't you leave me alone.
- What? You'll be fine. Talk. Mingle.
I don't want to mingle.
Hello.
- I'm Michael.
- I'm Rachel.
Rachel Porter.
Is that Miss or Mrs?
- That would be Dr. Porter.
- Doctor. Well, excuse me, doctor.
It's all right.
What kind of a doctor are you?
- I'm a biologist.
- Really?
Do you work for Jimmy?
So it must be very top-secret biology that you practice.
Oh, yes. Isn't everything?
Let's go.
Excuse me?
I mean, I'm happy to continue blathering on,...
...trying helplessly to charm you,...
...but I thought maybe, you know,
cut to the chase and just, you know, go somewhere.
I'll tell you what, Michael.
I'm gonna walk over there and talk to a friend of mine.
If you get the urge to have a real conversation,...
...you'll know where to find me.
OK. Fair enough.
It was nice to meet you.
Giving up so easily?
You don't believe in second chances, now, do you?
In my experience, no, I don't.
- Good night.
- Mike.
- Jimmy.
- How you doing?
- Good. How you doing?
- Good to see you.
- You too.
- Thanks for coming.
- Thanks for having me.
- Come back this way.
- Sure.
Hey, Jimmy.
Now you're talking. Thank you.
Wait a second.
Isaac, disable fire protection, please.
Alarm disabled.
I don't think you'd look so good covered in foam.
Even in that spiffy suit.
What's the pitch, Jimmy?
I've known you long enough to know when
you're trying to sell me something. What is it?
When there was a time we were in school,
we wanted to change the world.
I thought we said we wanted to save the world.
Well, that's semantics.
- What's the job, Jimmy?
- Can't tell you.
Other than to say that it involves optics.
And you get stock options for this one.
Get a real piece of the company.
What if it doesn't work?
I get a real piece of nothing.
I promise you, it won't fail.
How do you know that?
Is this a real crystal ball?
I wish.
The point is, I'll guarantee that you do eight figures.
- Minimum.
- What's the catch?
The job may require a little bit more time than you're used to.
- How much more time?
- Two years. Maybe three.
- You're kidding.
- Deadly serious.
Jimmy, that's impossible.
You can't do it.
The longest anyone has ever done is eight weeks.
I know because it was me.
Assuming it were possible, would you do it?
- Give up three years of my life?
- Not give up, trade.
Three years in return for the rest of your life.
One big paycheck. You're done.
A lot can happen in three years.
You blink, it'll be over-- to you, it'll be two seconds.
A heartbeat, then snap, you're rich beyond your wildest dreams.
One big paycheck. You're done.
Mr. Jennings. John Wolfe.
Welcome.
You understand that you won't be allowed to leave the grounds.
You'll be assigned a residence right here on campus.
All your mail will be screened, no outside phone calls,
and anything you do receive will have to be inspected.
Okay.
I'm going to need all your personal belongings --...
...watch, wallet, anything else you're carrying.
I'm afraid nothing's allowed to be brought in.
All these items will be returned to you when you pick up your paycheck.
Sorry. Those too.
- Mike, hey, you made it.
- Yeah.
- Good to see you.
- See you too.
- Everything OK?
- Yep.
Sit down.
I assume Mr. Wolfe gave you all the fine print.
Yeah. He also took the last pair of sunglasses
I've managed not to lose.
I'm sorry.
What is this?
It's for your memory wipe.
We inject you with an isotope,
migrates to your brain lodges, serves as a marker.
Then, when we're done, another injection erases everything back to the marker.
No barbaric cooking of the brain.
All right.
- What have I gotten myself into?
- Let's go find out.
Initiating Blue Script directory.
Impressive.
This used to be our smallest unit.
Now it's our most profitable.
Excuse me Mr. Rethrick, may I speak with you for a moment?
- Have a look around. I'll be right back.
- OK.
Cycle complete.
Begin transmission of data.
All right! I give up! I give up.
Don't give up.
- Dr. Porter. I guess I'm lucky you didn't use thunder and lightning.
- True.
OK, well, I won't question your powers in the future.
Sorry, I just couldn't help myself.
I thought you said Marianne was on a plane tonight.
She was planning to make the
conference call from the plane, sir.
Look. I should probably apologize for my behavior the other day.
- I -- I get like that sometimes, and I shouldn't. I'm sorry.
- Careful.
You are in danger of sounding like you want a second chance.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
- Say something else.
- Excuse me?
Say something nice.
Quick, otherwise I'll forget it.
Was that little breeze for our boy here?
Well, I owed him one. Now we're even.
Well, be nice 'cause Mike's moving into the neighborhood.
Oh.
- See you around.
- OK.
- You ready?
- Yeah. Let's go.
You can still back out.
No hard feelings.
No, I want to stay.
Michael Jennings, meet the other half of your team, Dr. William Dekker.
- Nice to meet you.
- It's a pleasure.
Gentlemen.
Let's have a look at the next three years of your lives.
What happened?
Michael.
You're done.
- How long was it, Jimmy?
- It's been three years, Mike.
- How'd I do?
- You did good.
Your money's been transferred to your account at Reddy Grant & Associates.
You've got an appointment there today at 1:00.
Just go home, do the paperwork.
When you feel up to it, give me a call.
We've got a lot of catching up to do Mike.
Ninety-two million dollars.
Everyone at Reddy Grant associates appreciates your business sir.
Well, not as much as I appreciate my business, I promise you.
OK.
Just sign there.
- All right.
- Great.
- Your personal items.
- Yes.
You only needed four stamps.
Oh, well, guess I could afford the extra 50 cents.
I don't think this is my stuff.
- It's not?
- No.
- I-I-I don't know what happened.
- It's all right. Don't worry about it.
It doesn't matter.
Let's talk about my shares.
What I'd like to do is get some money now,...
...and, you know, put the rest away for long term, you know, to live off.
So how do we -- So how do we do that?
Mr. Jennings, you forfeited your shares.
I beg your pardon? What?
Yeah, here. Dated four weeks ago.
You surrendered the shares and stated to
deliver only the envelope of personals.
- Don't you remember doing that, sir?
- No.
I don't remember that, because I didn't do that.
Why would I do that?
I wouldn't do that. It doesn't make sense.
A mistake has been made, and it needs to be corrected.
- Well, I agree. It's a strange thing you did, but...
- It's not strange.
Strange is, you know, a little out of the ordinary, but still plausible.
Giving away $100 million in shares
in a Fortune 500 company for some,...
...uh, knickknacks isn't strange, it's insane.
No one would do that.
This doesn't make sense.
I mean, unless you think this is a
$40 million can of hair spray, uh, which is pink.
And, uh, you know, what is this, a $100 million book of matches?
I mean, you know.
I've been a little out of it for a couple of years.
I don't know, is this back in style now?
Is this-- Are these $100 million sunglasses?
Am I missing something here?
Okay, I'll look into it, but it's gonna take me some time.
- This is crazy. So I'm going to make some phone calls.
- Okay.
Mr. Rethrick's office.
- It's Michael Jennings. Tell him it's important, please.
- I'm sorry, he stepped away.
He won't be back until this afternoon.
I can try him on his cell phone.
Just have him call me as soon as he gets in. Okay?
- OK.
- Thank you.
Listen, guys, a mistake has been made here. All right?
- I'm not a traitor. I'm an engineer.
- A reverse engineer, right?
We only know that you accepted payment
of classified government technology.
Mike, that's called treason.
In this country, people get fried for that one.
Yeah, and you know what? In this country, when the FBI
harasses you, you also get an attorney-- Thanks very much.
- Not today you don't.
- What the hell is this?
This is what happens when the attorney general calls me and says...
...that Michael Jennings' cooperation is a matter of national security.
Look, first of all, that stuff isn't mine, OK?
A mistake--
What is?
Perfect fit. You were saying?
Well, let me show you a few pieces
of the puzzle that we're solving.
William Dekker, government physicist, weapons division.
Three years ago, his project gets shelved.
He didn't like that, so he sold his work.
Classified work.
Showed it to several major corporations.
We think Rethrick bought it.
Unfortunately, we can't link Rethrick to the sale, because Dekker died.
Natural causes.
"Natural" being gravity after a 140-foot
fall out of his apartment building.
So what does this have to do with me?
These are Patent applications filed this month.
They show designs based on Dekker's work.
Look whose signature is on every one of those documents.
Don't you get it?
It's your name on those patents!
Rethrick can claim he knows nothing
about Dekker or where the design came from.
So what you need to do is,
tell us everything you did for Rethrick. Right now.
- I can't.
- You'd rather spend reset of your life...
...in prison protecting your so called friend?
- Just help us, and we can work with you.
- I can't. I can't!
He wiped my memory!
I don't remember!
I'll tell you whatever I know.
I was set up, but I swear to God, you have to believe me.
I don't remember what I did for the past three years!
What?
Wait a second!
Wait!
We figured Rethrick might've tried a wipe, so we'll try an extraction.
You're not gonna see anything.
You're wasting your time.
We're getting something here.
Come on!
Shit.
We got nothing.
Hold on a second.
I need a smoke.
Boss.
He won't mind.
- Smoke!
- Shit!
- Goddamn it!
- I can't see anything!
Secure the door!
Where the hell is he?
- He's loose!
- Don't worry, he can't go anywhere!
Cover the door!
I'll get the lights!
I can't see!
Get low to the ground!
Stay low to the ground!
Mitchell!
See anything?
- Is that him?
- Klein, where'd you go?
Al, shut the door!
What's going on?
Good night, Mikey.
Copy that.
- Watch it, coming through!
- Go! Go! Go!
- Coming through!
- Out of the way!
- See him?
- I see him!
- Out of the way, lady!
- There!
- Move! Move! Move! Move!
- Out! Out!
- Coming through!
- All right, let's go!
Excuse me.
Coming through!
- Out of the way! Open those gates!
- Hey, man, watch it! man.
Come on! Come on!
Where did he go?
I'll get men at every stop!
He'll be long gone by then!
How the hell did he do that?
- Oh, sorry.
- You all right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm fine. Sorry.
- Be careful.
Hey! Hey!
Watch it!
Jane. Relax.
Everything's fine.
I know you talked to federal agents.
It's okay, cause it's been worked out now.
I just need to find out who-- who sent these items.
Can you help me out?
- Um, they were sent three years ago.
- No, no. Remember, there was a mix-up, see?
These weren't the ones that were sent three years ago. Somebody
else sent these. I need to find out who that is. I need to talk to them.
Oh, you're right.
Replacements were sent a few weeks ago.
- Who sent it?
- Well, you did.
That's you right here.
See? Twenty items.
I'm going to need all your personal belongings.
Michael Jennings died at three minutes after 3.
The government, left with no case, closed its investigation of Allcom.
So you see, it's impossible that he escaped
unless you changed something.
I didn't.
- What were you doing, exactly?
- I was eating pie.
He left the attorney's office exactly when it predicted.
- The Feds took him exactly when it predicted--
- But he didn't die like it predicted!
Michael Jennings is not a super agent.
He's an engineer.
Yet somehow he managed to escape from a double-Iocked room.
How? Was it fate?
No, fate was on our side. That means someone who
knew changed something. And it wasn't me.
And if it wasn't you, then who the?
Has anyone checked the machine since Michael walked out of here?
Find him.
"If you only look where you can't go,
you will miss the riches below."
Yeah, I'm already missing my riches.
"17-44-4-26-37-40-22."
A combination? A code?
A password?
"New Liberty Savings."
New Liberty Savings Bank, please.
What does that mean?
You're saying the bank doesn't exist?
That's comforting.
Who sent these items?
You did.
That's you right here. See?
Twenty items.
These are patent applications.
Look whose signature is on every one of those documents!
A mistake has been made here.
I'm not a traitor!
Dekker died!
Rethrick can claim he knows nothing about Dekker or where the design came from.
You have to believe me.
I don't remember what I did for the past three years!
Michael.
You're done.
Hello?
Jesus, Shorty.
You don't know how good it is to hear a familiar voice.
Michael?
Listen, man.
I'm in a-- I'm in a jam, and I need you.
All right.
Meet me at Union Station at 9:00.
- I'll be there.
- OK, buddy.
Outbound local from Seattle to Kent departing from track five.
Eastbound Spokane, gate ten.
Michael.
Say one word about this hat and I'm out of here.
Oh, man!
Oh, my God.
I told you not to take that job, Mike.
- Come on, let's get a table.
- OK.
Injections?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. You would have to do it that way, I guess.
But, of course, that's a chemical process.
So?
Well, you'd have some latent memories.
Maybe that's what I'm seeing.
Most likely. Memories that made it through the wash,
and then they got stirred up when the Feds went into your head.
Why would I have these things?
Explain this.
I sent myself this junk instead of the money.
Oh, brother.
I don't know.
But that's not the question you should be asking yourself.
- No?
- No. The question that you should be asking yourself is,...
...why did you give up all that money?
That's the most bizarre part of this whole thing.
Ninety million dollars.
Nobody changes that much in three years.
OK, all right, buddy.
I wanna figure out what you built.
All right, let's work backwards.
They told me I was working on a design by someone named Dekker.
- Dekker?
- Yeah.
- William Dekker?
- I think so.
What I heard was,
he was working on something level five for the Feds...
...when they came in one day and they just shut him down.
- What was it?
- Well, the consensus was a laser.
- Why was that?
- Because Dekker's drawings called for a mirror and a lens.
Now, the only thing that uses those is a laser, right,
or some kind of satellite camera to see things from far away.
Here comes the first number, 17.
Followed by 44.
- The lens required perfect optics.
- Four.
- The mirror...
- Twenty-six.
- So the capital outlay is huge.
- Thirty-seven.
- I mean, the word was, I think it was gonna cost.
- Forty.
- 500 billion dollars.
- And the bonus number is 22.
Who's gonna spend 500 billion dollars just to see something?
What?
There is no way I get out of that extraction
room without the cigarettes and the glasses.
I would've never gotten on that bus without the bus ticket.
If I didn't have the diamond ring,
I wouldn't have followed that kid to Reddy Grant.
Right.
I gave up that money just to make sure
that I would pay attention to these items.
Why?
Because I know what you'd spend 500 billion dollars to see.
The future.
If you selected five numbers and the bonus number,
you're a second-prize winner.
He used a virus.
The machine went down at 3:03 this afternoon.
3:03.
Can you program around the virus?
No. It's not that kind of virus.
Come on, I'll show you.
It's not in the software.
It's in the hardware.
He put a circuit somewhere in here.
It's like a poison pill.
But you can find it, right?
Yeah, I can.
Then do it.
Slight change of plans.
According to Mr. Stevens, we don't need Michael Jennings anymore.
Look, if we know anything,
we know that time travel's not possible.
Einstein proved that, right?
Time travel, yes.
But Einstein was very clear that he believed time viewing, theoretically,...
- ...could be accomplished.
- Mike, Mike. Come on.
Maybe we should just find Dekker...
- I can't talk to Dekker.
- Why not?
- He had an accident.
- An accident?
Yeah, he-- he fell out of his bedroom window.
Fell out of his--
He fell out of his bedroom window!
I see. Sure.
That could happen.
Oh, geez, wait a minute.
- We got to get ourselves out of here.
- Shorty, listen to me.
I think what happened was I used this thing,
I saw my future.
And I saw what I needed to change it.
But all I could get Allcom were these, uh, you know, innocuous items.
Each item has to be used at a specific time, at a specific
place to accomplish whatever it was I needed to get done.
I mean, without the stuff in here,
I'd already be dead.
Yeah, well, it's too bad that you don't
know what the rest of them are for.
What?
Gotcha!
Hey!
Great seeing you again, Mike!
Jesus!
Those guys do not look like feds.
Here. Listen to me.
Take this.
This will get you through that door.
Close it behind you. Understand? Go!
- OK!
- Go! Go on!
Shit!
Go!
Oh, God, I hope that was a good thing to do.
Shit.
Go.
Where's your gun?
He's got it.
So how are you, Mike?
You?
Why?
Don't remember?
You brought this on yourself, Mike.
So how does it feel knowing you're going to die?
Shit.
- So you are saying he designed his own escape?
- Mr. Attorney General, sir, we have no explanation.
Because after looking at all the evidence the only logical,
albeit hard-to-accept conclusion,...
...is that he was able to predict what was going to happen to him.
These are memories extracted from Jennings before he fled.
They don't seem to add up to anything.
Gladys.
That's all for today.
We knew Dekker was trying to design something,...
...but when he sold his plans, he wasn't even halfway done.
I don't understand.
Dekker was working at JPL on a laser-enhanced lens.
He claimed the lens was powerful
enough to see around the curvature of the universe.
...Dekker believed that if you could see
around a curve that went on forever...
...you would end up back where you started, looking at yourself.
Except you're not looking back at yourself now, in the present.
No, you are not.
You're looking at the future.
Can you imagine what'll happen if Jennings figures out what he's done,
and tries to profit from it?
- Any nation in the world would give him a king's ransom.
- Jennings won't do that.
I was this close to him. He never lied.
When he heard what he's being accused of, he was hurt and scared.
Fine, once you bring him in I'll give him the Medal of Honor.
That's if Rethrick doesn't find him first.
You think he really saw the future?
That would be something.
Café Michel?
My name is Michael Jennings.
And I can't remember if I made a reservation there recently.
Would you check that out for me?
Thanks.
I did?
OK.
Right. How many is it for?
Oh, no, thank you.
No, I'll be there.
Thank you.
Hello, you two.
Did he feed you?
Rachel, it's Jimmy.
- You all right?
- Why?
You don't know?
No.
May I come in?
When was the last time you saw Michael?
Yesterday morning.
He was pulling an all nighter at his lab.
Rachel, I'm sorry to have to be the one to tell you this.
Michael left Allcom yesterday.
Permanently.
- What?
- He finished his work.
- We erased his memory, and he--
- No.
- He left.
- No. He promised me.
He said he wasn't going to go through with it.
He made a lot of money on this one, Rachel.
He said he didn't care about the money.
So she doesn't know anything.
He wouldn't leave without her.
It's Michael. He'd be smart.
We're missing something.
As soon as she leaves for work, get in there.
And make sure she can't go anywhere alone.
I want to know what just happened.
Bye, guys.
Good morning, Dr. Porter.
Going somewhere?
Good morning.
I'm going to go up top.
Take my bag.
- You're gonna need this.
- Got it. Thanks.
Coming?
No, thanks.
I'd rather watch from down here.
Suit yourself.
Look, we've been through the bathroom and
tossed the rest of the apartment, too. Zero.
This is what I want you to do.
Go back in the bathroom.
OK, start turning left.
Tell me what you see.
The mirror.
We've got him.
She's supposed to meet him at Cafe Michel, 1 p.m.
Well, let's make sure she does.
I'm here to meet someone.
Michael Jennings.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
Sit at that table right there.
In the seat, with your back to the window.
Michael, thank God you're all right.
I thought I was never gonna see you again.
Michael, it's me.
Rachel.
Look...
You can't remember me.
No. I'm sorry.
Cops. We can't go in.
I'll have to wait for a clear shot.
Maya, stall for time.
Tell him you thought he'd remember something.
That you two were engaged.
I guess I thought you'd remember something.
We've been together for three years.
I don't know what to say.
I'm really sorry.
I'm trying.
That's how he's doing this.
Listen to me very carefully, Maya.
This is what I want you to say.
Michael, I can see you still have the envelope.
That means it's working.
I know you switched the personal items.
I helped.
- You left me a note on a mirror.
- I'm supposed to take something from you.
- I'm supposed to take something.
- Something I can use to get to Stevens.
- He's a man you worked with. He's trying to fix the machine.
- He's a man you worked with.
He's trying to fix the machine.
Work backwards, Michael.
Yeah. Take the swipe card.
That's the swipe card for the campus.
You're supposed to give that to me.
Rachel wouldn't be hurt if he hesitated,
she'd be impatient.
Look, Michael, if you can't trust me right now,
then we are lost. For good.
Nice.
OK.
I'd better get back.
They'll get suspicious soon.
Wait here.
I'll be back in half an hour.
And don't worry, we end up together.
Michael I love you.
- What's my favorite baseball team?
- What?
What's my favorite baseball team?
Who cares?
That would be the Red Sox.
Yeah.
- I think maybe we should go.
- Wait!
Now we can leave.
Come on.
Wait! Hold on.
- You have a car?
- I might.
You might?
Look for a BMW!
You gotta be joking.
Shit! Shit!
- Let me see that key.
- Why?
You're in the wrong section.
Jennings bought the BMW from Southgate Auto on the Internet.
He had the key mailed to him four weeks ago.
- What's the color of his car?
- It isn't a car.
They just turned on Pine.
Intercept them on Sixth.
- How good am I on this thing?
- You're OK!
- Look, I just said you're OK, OK?
- OK.
Hang on!
- Report of shots. Southgate BMW.
- Got it.
- Stop! I lost the envelope!
- What?
- I'll come back and get you.
- See you!
Got it!
Let's get out of here.
Take us down!
Mike, we can help you!
We know what's going on!
Let us bring you in!
He's headed for the tunnel!
Cut him off! Cut him off!
Duck!
Split!
You think Jennings foresaw that?
Maybe next time he'll see a nice quiet stakeout.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's OK.
It's all for you anyway.
And I -- I brought you some clothes.
I thought you might need them.
I hope it's OK.
Thank you.
These are mine?
You don't remember?
No.
You don't remember me, do you?
Well...
These are for you.
Happy birthday to you
- Happy birthday to you.
- You're so sweet.
I'm sorry.
I just don't remember.
I shouldn't have left.
So you're saying he sent himself
a different set of personal items...
...ones he'd selected after using the machine
and nothing our security would flag?
Everyday things combined with the power of foresight...
...transform Michael from engineer to escape artist.
I don't know about you, but I'd like to return the favor.
Michael, are you OK?
I'm all right.
Michael, I don't know what you saw in your machine,...
...but I remember, a few weeks ago,
you came back from your lab and you are pale.
You asked me the strangest question.
- What?
- If I knew it wouldn't work out...
...for you and I, before we were together,
would I have done it?
What did you say?
That I wouldn't trade our time for anything.
That's all we are, the sum of our experiences.
Besides, some of the best things in life are total mistakes.
- What?
- You know, when I checked this envelope out of Reddy Grant,...
...they told me I signed in 20 items, but there are only 19.
I don't understand.
What are these pictures of?
Michael, look at the rest of the pictures.
Look at the last one.
Oh, my God. It's the future.
The machine predicts a war, and we go to war to avert it.
It predicts a plague.
We herd all the sick together, create a plague.
Whatever future this predicts, we make happen.
We give over control of our lives completely.
I did this.
Seeing the future will destroy us.
If you show someone their future, they have no future.
If you take away the mystery, you take away hope.
I have to go back.
I have to destroy that machine.
It's impossible. The campus is huge.
There are hundreds of guards.
Hey, I would not have given up the three years we had
together unless I was absolutely sure I could get us 50 more.
Okay. So how do we get in?
- We don't.
- You said everything was happening...
...for a reason, and that includes me being here.
So come on.
Hey, Rachel.
Another day at the most.
I don't have many more places to look.
I guess you weren't as smart as you thought, Stevens.
Hey, Jennings wouldn't find it any
faster unless he knew where to look.
We've got the feeds from mass transit.
He could be anywhere by now.
Except he's not running away.
He could've given himself a way...
...to disappear,
but look what he gave himself instead.
His Allcom security pass.
He's going back.
Let's get a warrant to tap phone and data lines coming out of Allcom.
Put some bodies on that campus.
I want that machine!
Jennings and the girl were spotted.
What do you want me to do?
Nothing.
- Stay where you are.
- Nobody gets through!
- Sir!
- I didn't do anything!
Settle down!
All the metal detectors on level four
just went off at the same time. Ball bearings.
Just down the hall from the metal detectors.
Pull the guards off the Jennings lab.
Let him slip in, think he's fooled us.
Once he's fixed the machine, take him.
I built this.
This door shouldn't be open.
There's something wrong.
They're expecting us.
Let me close this door behind us.
And keep it shut.
- He's in.
- Confirmed. He's in.
Great. Once we confirm he's at the machine, let's go in after him.
I thought we were gonna wait for him to come out.
I can't wait! Whether it's Jennings or the machine,...
...I don't care, as long as I get one of them.
Let's go!
This will do. Watch out.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait, wait. What are you doing?
- Smashing the lock.
Hold on a second.
You can't just smash the thing.
They'll still be able to get in.
We gotta jam the outside reader.
Let's go.
Let's take a look at the future before we destroy this thing.
I bugged it.
I rigged it so Jimmy wouldn't use it against me.
Then you can fix it, right?
Now, where would I have planted that bug?
Maybe on one of the motherboards.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, we won't be needing this, OK?
You're dangerous with that thing.
You must have given yourself something to help you find it.
I don't know, what it would be.
The only things left are the bullet and, uh, this.
- A crossword?
- Yeah.
Look at this.
Twelve down.
Maybe it's here.
Nine, ten, eleven, twelve.
Let's take a look.
Maybe it's a circuit diagram.
I wouldn't have put it in the primary path.
Twelve down.
Take him.
OK, corridor three, sublevel A, Jennings' lab.
All right, let's put this thing to good use one last time.
Let's get us out of here.
That's in the lab.
It's the catwalk.
Look, I've changed my future before using this thing.
I can do it again.
We don't have any more time.
We got to destroy this before they get to it.
Reprogram the door to Jennings' lab, please.
Now.
He must've done something to the controller.
- How are we gonna get out of here Micheal?
- I don't know.
Clear!
- What are you doing?
- These things are liquid hydrogen.
They're used to cool the machine.
They fire in order.
Number one just fired.
When it gets down to number six here,
that's all she wrote.
I'll see you when this goes off, Jimmy.
Come on!
You see?
You judge too soon.
They went out through the vent.
Spread out, find them.
Position three standing by.
Come on.
Freeze!
Look out.
Seal off all exits to the lab.
All right, Jennings, let's see what you've been up to.
Rachel, go for the door, OK?
Drop the gun.
Looks like Michael's got a date on the catwalks.
Let's make sure he makes it.
- Let's go.
- No. We can't take the catwalk.
I know. We won't, I promise.
Come on, let's go.
- Michael! What are you doing?
- Rachel, go. Go. I'll distract them.
- Go, please.
- No!
Listen to me. This is my debt.
I built this machine.
- I have to pay for it.
- No! You come with me now!
You promised you'd change your fate!
Please, we don't have time.
If you love me, if you care about me. Go.
Have a good life.
Remember me.
Damn you.
Jimmy.
You want to kill me, come do it yourself.
Here I am. You want me?
Come get me.
- Hi, Jimmy.
- Hi, Mike.
- Looks like this is it, huh?
- Yeah, it is, Mike.
- You only have yourself to blame.
- That's a lie.
You can't change your fate, Mike.
You're gonna die today.
Maybe.
But you're not going to kill me.
That's right, Mike.
I've seen the future.
Still think you can change your fate, Mike?
I am the future, Mike!
- Rethrick has Jennings.
- Retire him.
- What?
- We have the machine.
We can't risk its creator falling into the wrong hands.
Come on.
Don't blame me.
You and Michael would've lived happily ever after, no memory wipe.
He's the one who saw something he didn't like.
He's the one who decided he wanted to stop the program.
Look at it this way, you did change the future, Michael.
Before you interfered you both would've lived...
...we would still be friends, instead of ending up like this.
It wasn't meant to be.
Giving up so easy?
Don't you believe in second chances?
To tell you the truth, I do.
Go, go, go.
Rachel!
Let's go.
Look.
Any records? Any papers?
Explosion destroyed everything.
- Are we trying to salvage that or what?
- I guess we don't get the machine, do we?
Any sign of Jennings?
No, I'm afraid he didn't make it.
What was Shorty thinking, starting a nursery?
I mean, these plants are on life-support.
What do you mean? Really?
He told me he had a green thumb.
Gangrene is more like it.
Lucky for Shorty, I'm a biologist.
Lucky for both of us, since I failed biology,...
- ...I'm no help to either one of you.
- So you say.
Too bad, though, because I'm looking for a partner...
- ...for a start-up company.
- Really? Doing what?
We're gonna save the world.
I don't think I'm your guy.
But would you settle for someone who wants to help you change it?
- Mmm, okay.
- Good.
So how does it end for us, Michael?
I mean, what's in our future?
You know, I don't know.
I kind of like it that way.
- I do know one thing.
- What's that?
I never want to forget anything ever again.
Break it up, break it up.
The birdman cometh.
- Shorty.
- It's dinner.
- You found them.
- Yes, I did.
- Who does everything for everybody around here?
- You do.
- You're right.
- You're my hero.
Thank you very much.
- You hear that? I'm a hero.
- That's great.
I think I remember.
Are those our birds?
Yes, of course they are.
We bought them together.
You remember the birds?
Well done. You could see into the future...
...and all you remember are Polly and Tweety over there.
- Why don't you remember something that would make us rich, huh, Mike?
- Wait a second.
What is it?
- I think there was something else.
- No, no, no.
The envelope's empty.
Don't worry about it.
Hold on. I'm working backward here.
"If you only look where you can't go,
you will miss the riches below."
I must've known you'd never get rid of these birds.
Alright?
Of course not. They're family.
So I knew this would be here.
What only looks where it can't go?
A caged bird.
"You will miss the riches below."
The riches below.
What is that?
Well, that's a $90-million lottery ticket.
- Wait. Wait a minute.
- It's $90 million.
- Nice.
- Yes, I'm proud of it.
Wait a minute. No.
- Wait a-- Hold on.
- What are you doing?
You know what?
I think now's probably a good time to discuss my commission, 33%.
- I thought it was 5.
- No, 33%.
- Thirty-three percent! We had a deal at five percent.
- He deserves it. - Absolutely.
- It was found on-- It was found on my premises.
- You know what? I'll come back. I'm going to cash this in.