[ Siren Blaring ]
[ Siren Whooping ]
[ Brakes Screeching ]
[ MenJeering,
Metal Cups Clattering ]
[ Speaking Chinese ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Shouting In Chinese ]
[ Responding In Chinese ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Yelling ]
[ Shouting In Chinese ]
[ Gasping ]
- [ Softly ]
You got maybe seven minutes.
- [ Radio Static Crackling ]
Six minutes.
[ Chinese ]
Almost got one
ofthe fuses fixed.
[ Shrieking ]
- Shh!
- [ Whimpering ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Chinese ]
[ Shouting In Chinese ]
Thirty seconds.
[ Continues Shouting
In Chinese ]
Get out now.
[ Chinese ]
[GuardShouting
ln Chinese]
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
- Yeah.
- It's Duncan.
What are you doing at home?
-Jogging.
- How long does it take you
to get to work?
- Harry, what time is it there?
- How long?
- Thirty, 40 minutes. Why?
- I'll give you 25 minutes...
before I transmit, ifyou want
to see the cable before they do,
- you'd better hustle.
- [ Hanging Up ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Beeping ]
[Phone Ringing]
[Picking Up Receiver]
- Duncan.
- What the hell's goin' on?
- Read the cable.
- Look, if I'm walking
into a shitstorm,
I've gotta know which way
the wind's blowing.
- Boy Scout's in trouble.
- What kind oftrouble?
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- Where are you calling from?
Are you in your car?
Are you out of
your fucking mind?
He's a big boy.
He can take care
of himself.
You call me from secure
when you get there.
Let's see
your driver's license.
[Alarm Wailing]
Sorry, sir.
You need to come
to the desk with me, please.
Mr. Muir.
[Tapping Keyboard]
Duty roster has you
checking out tonight.
Just a reminder:
on your way out,
we need to sign out
your I.D., card key,
parking pass.
It's a date.
[ Rapid Beeping ]
You got a cable
from Hong Kong?
You check
the operations center?
[ Chuckles ]
I go up there, Billy Nyland's
gonna want to collect...
that hundred I owe him
from the 'Skins game.
Come on, Henry.
Pull it offthe mainframe
for me, will you?
My last day.
[ Clears Throat ]
[Tapping Keys]
Gladys.
Cubans are in
the drawer on the left.
Ifthese walls could talk, huh?
All this history. I envy you.
- Bag yourjob.
You can bejust like me.
- No, really.
The debt this country
owes you guys.
Chuck, are we gonna
dance all night with
your hand on my ass,
or are you gonna
make your move?
You used to run
an agent named Bishop.
- Tom Bishop. Yeah. How is he?
- We'd like to take a look at his files.
Did you try Records?
Ofcourse, we have his main files.
It was your personals.
- What do you want to know?
- We'll have your Bishop
op reports downloaded...
andsortedin an hourortwo;
fornow, l'lljust takeyourfiles.
Grab yourselfa seat and
make yourselfcomfortable.
It's gonna take me a while
to dig 'em up.
Call my office as soon as
you have 'em. ASAP.
Oh, Muir?
Good luck
with the retirement.
The director sent this down.
Actually, it looks like
he signed it himself.
Oh, andHarkersaid
l'm supposedto collect
allyourfiles on Tom Bishop.
Finally get to use
one ofthese burn bags.
Hold this, till
you hear otherwise.
- You didn't see what I put in.
- Are we feeling a little
paranoid on our last day?
When did Noah
build the ark, Gladys?
Before the rain.
[Security Code Beeping,
DoorSliding Open]
Hey, Billy,
you got my hundred?
[Chattering On Radio]
Harker said to bring
this file up. You want
to buzz me through?
No, I can't, sir.
But I'll make sure
he gets it.
Sir?
[DoorSlides Open]
[Man]
Canyouget that
Chinese translator?
[Radio Chattering
Continues]
[Man Continues]
No, that looks
prettygood.
Looksgood.
...as for the upcoming trade
negotiations in the Far East,
a team of negotiators has been
working with the Chinese...
in an effort to streamline
theproceedings...
andlaythegroundwork for
the President's trip next week.
In other world news...
Jeez.
nowthat the Cold War
is finallyover, Berliners
areproclaiminga newera...
here where
Soviet and American tanks
faced each other...
in the darkest days
ofthe Communist--
Is this it?
It's all I could find.
Packed, misplaced--
you know how it is.
Moving day and all.
It's probably
mostly up here anyway.
Old school,
you know?
Muir?
Step this way?
Sit down here, please,
Muir?
Jesus, Aiken.
How long has it been?
[ Sighs ]
This task force
have a name?
- [ Blinds Whirring Open ]
- [Man]
This isa tough one, Troy.
I'm gonna
see you later.
You got it, Cy.
[DoorClosing]
[ Sighing ]
Good to see you.
Thanks for stoppin' by.
For the record, we've
been joined by Nathan Muir,
Near East ops.
[ Sighs ]
We're in the process
ofdealing...
with a fairly specific...
international flap.
We brought you in here
as a stopgap.
- Fill in a few holes for us.
- So I'm like
the little Dutch boy, huh?
[ Chuckling ]
Yeah!
Wejust need you
to be a team player
on this one, Muir.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Why is that funny?
Every time my coach
told me that, I knew
I was about to get benched.
[ Chuckling ]
Due to the nature
ofthis task force, Nathan,
there will be
certain information which
you don't need to know.
A weekago, Tom Bishop
disappearedin Hong Kong.
Last night he turned up
outside Shanghai.
He's been arrested
for espionage.
We're working up a profile
based on relevant personal
histories and op records.
This has to be handled
with kid gloves.
How long does the president
have to claim him?
- Twenty-four hours.
- Starting when?
As of now, Nathan.
Bishop has been classified
as a common criminal,
and will be executed
at 8:00 A.M. tomorrow
morning, our time.
What about the press?
Why not leak it and throw
the spotlight on China,
and buy us some time?
We need the press on this
like we need a third teat.
- You using the other two?
- [ Troy Chuckling ]
We don't want outside influences
to... limit our options.
What was Bishop
doing in China?
He was with an operation
for Harry Duncan.
Was?
Yes.
Until he took matters
into his own hands.
Well, where are they
holding him?
- Oh, I'm sorry, Nathan.
- It would be nice to know
what gaps are filled.
I've only got ten fingers
here, you know?
[ Inhales Deeply ]
I guess, kind of
tough timing, hmm?
A week before
the president's road trip.
You guys afraid there's gonna
be a congressional hearing?
That's why we're transcribing
and videotaping. Right?
Are you gonna
want me to testify?
- No.
- No?
Absolutely not.
- You met Bishop in Vietnam, right?
- Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
Spring of'75.
Hue had just fallen. Danang
would go in a couple ofdays.
And I had flown in country
to get an ARVN sniper...
who'dbeen with us
throughout the Phoenixprogram.
He wasa heavyhitter
namedBinh.
[Rock]
Spent the lastyear
RockyMountain way
lt's time to open fire
And we don't need
the ladies
Cryin' 'cause thestory's sad
[ Indistinct ]
- lgotsome badnews
foryou, sir. he's dead.
- Dead?
Just before dawn.
Caught a mortar round
with his teeth.
Got anybody else?
There's a staffsergeant
came my way a while back,
but he's nowhere near
Binh's 40 confirmed.
How many has he got?
Three kills.
Christ, and that's
the best you got?
He's a fine shot, sir.
Where is he?
Right over there.
Where, in the back?
Yeah.
There is another guy,
20 kills, but he's
at least two days away.
- Confirm that for me?
- Yes, sir.
Why ishe overthere?
They liveseparate...
from the other men,
cook their own food-- gook food.
Smells awful, sir.
Not to the enemy.
Send him in.
Yes, sir.
[ Men Chattering,
Shouting ]
- Yes, sir?
- Bishop?
That's correct, sir.
- [ Clears Throat ]
Where are you from?
- Hemet, California, sir.
Here.
Have a seat.
I take it you didn't get
to be a marksman putting food
on your mama's table.
No, sir, we have
a Safeway back home.
Where'd you learn
to shoot?
Boy Scouts, sir.
[ Laughs ]
Are you kiddin' me?
No, sir.
When did you get
pulled in?
I volunteered, sir.
[MuirNarrating]
He came acrossas one of
those idealistic types--
you know, a little bit
ofan attitude?
Starts out trying
to see what he's made of, and
ends up not liking the view.
- Who was the target, Muir?
- General Hun Chea.
He's Laotian?
Yeah.
Unofficial enemy.
Code name:
Red Shirt.
He's responsible for
the western flank of
the upcoming Saigon offensive.
His name--
Don't need
a name, sir.
You don't needit?
Oryou don't want it?
Yeah, I'll do it, sir.
Okay.
[HelicopterEngine Roaring]
The target willbe
at a location...
twenty-one clicks away,
tomorrow morning at 0900.
lt'sa high-poweredmeet-and-greet
with the Vietcong.
Will he be alone, sir?
He sometimes travels
with a bit ofan entourage.
''A bit ofan entourage?''
- Red Shirt located.
Do you have in sight?
- Red Shirt confirmed.
Niner-eight-zero to gate.
One-zero-zero-five
to table.
Wind...
five miles left.
Target in sight.
- [ Clicking ]
- [Helicopter Whirring]
Bravo Six, Bravo Six.
Delta Two. Over.
- Go, Delta Two.
- We have target in sight,
but no shot.
- Say again?
- No shot.
- Helo is obstructing target.
- Helo? NVA doesn't have air support.
Position injeopardy.
Ourposition is compromised.
Over.
- Say it again. Over?
- Shh. We're still a go.
[ Gasping ]
We have no go.
- [ Whispering ] Clear.
- Don't take the shot!
See ifyou can
get 'em back.
Delta Two, Delta Two--
[ Whispering ]
Move!
Come on, come on.
Delta Two, Delta Two.
Bravo Six, over.
[ Cries Out ]
[ Cries Out Again ]
Sorry about your man,
Captain.
You want to make
another pass, sir?
Hold it.
Go back again.
Hell ofan ad
for the Boy Scouts.
Didyou have
apresidentialfinding
authorizing those kills?
I don't believe
we've met.
- Who are you?
- Dr. William Byars.
National Security Council.
Was there
a finding, Muir?
[ Snickers ]
Well, we were in a place
we weren't supposed to be,
assassinating a general
from a country we weren't
at war with--
ofcourse, we weren't
officially at war
with North Vietnam, either--
- Is that a ''no''?
- Oh, come on, guys.
We're on the clock.
The president admits
Bishop is ours,
denies he's a spy,
we put out the fires
and negotiate a deal.
Unless I'm
missing something.
[ Whispering ]
Muir's secretary's on--
[ Indistinct ]
- [Whispering Continues]
- Mm. This will just take a second.
Stop recording.
Stop tape.
Your secretary's got
your wife on the line.
She says it's urgent.
Go ahead.
Want to take it outside?
No, no.
I'll take it in here.
That's fine.
- Hello?
- Got your message.
You want me to start a fire yet?
Oh, uh, right.
This'll just take a second.
Right.
[ Distorted ]
Tell you what.
Why don't you hold
that reservation, and, uh,
we maystill
be able to use it.
You mightjust.
As we speak, there are
three guys rummaging...
through everything
lspent a weekpacking.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
- Ifthere were any instances
of personal dysfunction,
- Right.
- emotional or psychological,
it could be helpful.
- [ Muir ] Okay.
[Man]lt's insubstantial.
Right.
[ Muir ]
Mm-hmm. Okay.
That'll be good.
Becausepresidentialfindings...
- have no real importance.
- You still there?
Y-Yeah.
So he was an assassin,
recruited to kill.
Sounds good.
Bye-bye.
[Hangs Up Receiver]
[ Sighs Deeply ]
Sorry. Wife planning
a retirement dinner.
Assassin?
I think I just
figured it out.
- The Bishop files.
- Where?
My office.
Closet.
It'll just
take a second.
l'llsend
a securityofficerdown.
No, hey, you guys...
have betterthings to do
than to rummage through
myoffice, right, Chuck?
[Agents Chattering]
[Tapping Keypad]
He's on his way down.
[Hanging Up Receiver]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[Gladys]
You were right.
It rained.
What about these?
- Burn 'em.
- What is this about?
Money.
Free trade. Microchips.
Toaster ovens.
And what does that
have to do with you?
Nothing. Get me
Digger Gibson's number.
Shit!
Agency's looking for
a reason to let the Chinese
kill Tom Bishop.
No!
[Rapping On Door]
Ah, they shut down
my secure line--
last day and all.
Can I use yours?
Thanks.
Aw, well--
[ Clears Throat ]
Oh, I'm sorry. It's classified.
Do you mind?
Oh! Uh, right.
There'snothing there.
lt'snot in English?
- lt'snot in English either.
- This faxjust came in
a few moments ago, sir.
Yeah.
So, sir, you and Muir
came up together, right?
Mm.
How well do you know him?
No one knows Nathan.
Not really.
Do you trust him?
He's a man who
got thejob done.
Is he on thejob now?
Office ofSecurity, Hong Kong.
Ten to seven this morning,
a call originated from
station to Muir's home.
He knew about Bishop
before he got here.
And he played dumb.
Yeah, this is Harker.
I need confirmation
on all calls...
in and out of
Nathan Muir's office.
[ Sucks Teeth ]
Gee, I'm hungry.
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Woman ]
Hong KongHerald.
- Digger Gibson, please.
- One moment, sir.
Hello?
Gibby, old boy.
Nathan!
To what do I owe
this honor?
Still have contacts at CNN?
I got something foryou.
Talk to me.
How about
''C.I.A. operative caught
in the act ofespionage''?
- Can you get that on the air?
- That'snotgonna be easy.
Come on, Gibby.
- That's never stopped you before.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Give me 30 minutes.
- Yeah.
I remember seeing
something about Bishop
in my South American box,
but it wasn't there.
Those op files
downloaded yet?
Let's go with this.
Bishop's recruitment.
Yeah.
Well, back then,
recruitment took time.
Bishop was evacuated
with the last ofthem
on the 30th ofApril,
andthatgave me a month
to do myhomework.
ltalkedto hisneighbors,
his teachers, hismom--
scoutmaster--
Pulled his dad's records
from the Pentagon.
Then started to move
some pieces around
on the board.
And my plan was
to isolate and alienate.
[Dire Straits,
''Soldiers lnArms'']
Your valleysandyourfarms
lhadhis C. O. give him
just menialduties...
with non-English-speaking
personnel.
Andlkept him in limbo about
even thepossibilityofgoinghome.
And then I watched...
and waited.
[Rock Guitar]
This consignment is
a complete misdirect.
It needs to go to
Military H.Q in Mannheim.
You understand?
[ Under His Breath ]
Fuck!
Then, in December, when
ldidn 't thinkhe could
take anymore,
- I made the move.
-  These mist-coveredmountains
Are a home nowto me
There she is.
[ Chuckles ]
But myhome is the lowlands
Uh, sorry sir. It's Bishop.
Sergeant Bishop?
Oh, Christ.
Ofcourse!
Hi.
[Woman]
Yeah, hi.
Sandy, this is Tom Bishop.
Tom, right?
- Yes, sir. Tom, sir.
- Tom. How are you?
Nice to meet you.
- Sandy?
- My second wife.
- Second wife?
- He asked me what
I was doing in Berlin,
and I told him I was there
as a military liaison ofa sort.
It's good to hear an American
voice again, I'll tell you that.
I'll bet, I'll bet.
What are you doing
for Christmas?
No plans.
[Dean Martin]
Oh, the weatheroutside
is frightful
But the fire isso delightful
[lndistinct]
Central Intelligence?
Train you as an agent.
You'd be working for me.
Mostly undercover.
[ Chuckles ]
Europe?
Wherever the action is.
What if I preferred...
tojust go home?
That's okay.
It's fine.
I can probably make arrangements
foryou to end your
tour ofduty in San Diego.
In which case,
I'll presume you'll forget
we ever had this conversation.
But look,
it's your choice.
Allthe wayhome
l'llbe warm
[ Chuckles Softly ]
The next day,
we started his tradecraft.
The technology
gets better every day,
and that's fine.
But most ofthe time,
all you need is a stick of gum,
a pocketknife and a smile.
That's disappointing.
[Man]
Guten Morgen, meine Herren.
Today we're going to be
discussing a radio set.
Notjust any radio set,
but a Russian radio set.
Every building, every room,
every situation is a snapshot.
While l'm sittinghere talking
toyou, l'm also checking
the room, memorizing it.
The people.
What they're wearing.
Then I ask the question,
''What's wrong with this
picture?Anythingsuspect?''
[ Shouting ]
You'vegotta see it,
assess it anddismiss
most ofit...
- without looking, without thinking.
- Without thinking?
It'sjust like breathing.
You breathe, don't you?
Always carry cigarettes
and a lighter too.
Great ice-breaker.
- Eine Kaffee, bitte.
- Zwei.
Okay, I want you to listen,
but I want your concentration
to be on something different.
Anything else, soyou
don't react. Understand?
Yes.
So when do I get
my first assignment?
When I decide
you're ready.
- What is your name?
- Michael Sandville.
The suit in the kitchen.
- Threat?
- Wait, how'd you see that? Ah!
- See that apartment building?
- Yeah?
Know anyone
who lives there?
No.
Within five minutes,
I want to see you standing
on one ofthose balconies.
[ Chuckles ]
Come on.
- Did you serve in Vietnam?
- No, I did not.
- Favorite color?
- Why don't we discuss it over coffee?
You just lost ten seconds.
Solicit information
from someone.
Gladly.
Theguy reading the menu.
Don't look at him.
- He wasn 't reading the menu.
- He's not reading at all. Threat?
Onlyto the hostess.
[Muir]
Youjustgave herfourpieces
ofpersonalinformation...
for one dubious,
impersonal fact.
Just trying to find out
where she got that dress.
Where are you from?
When's your birthday?
You know everything
about me. I don't know
a thing about you.
[Muir]
Okay, what didyou tellher?
One, you'restraight.
Two, you're engaged.
Three, tomorrow's your girl's
birthday, and four, you have
no taste in women's fashions.
[ Chuckles ]
What ifshe
were an asset?
You told her four lies
that now have to be true.
Okay.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[Lounge Piano]
[ Chattering In German ]
[ Groaning,
Speaking German ]
[Continues ln German]
[ Replying In German ]
I thought spies drank martinis.
Scotch, never less
than 1 2 years old.
Is that right?
Agency rules?
My rules.
All right, so what else?
What else do I need to know?
[ Exhales ]
Put away some money
so you can die someplace warm.
Don't ever touch it.
Not for anyone. Ever.
Okay.
Is that it?
Don't ever riskyour life
oryour career for an asset.
If it comes down to
you or them, send flowers.
[Jazz Piano]
He was a natural.
He couldtake an
East German who had
just come overthe Wall,
lookhim straight in the eye,
andaskhim togo back...
to the place hejust fled
and spy for us.
[Bishop Speaking
German]
Hegotsogoodat it he could
close in a single afternoon,
sendtheguyout with a smile.
Let me get this straight:
you allowed a contract agent
to develop assets?
He was that good.
I thought he'd make
a fine case officer someday.
Let's get on with it.
I'd like to hear whatever
you can offer about...
Operation Rodeo.
Rodeo?
- The Cathcart affair?
- [ Whispering, Indistinct ]
Hold transcription, hold tape.
I'll be right back.
[ Sighs ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
You know, this would go
a lot faster, you guys,
ifyou'd tell me
a little something
about the op.
What's it called?
Sideshow?
What about it?
- How'd you come by this information?
-Just stuffwe learn in the field.
[ Sighs ]
[Troy]
Sorryabout that.
Okay, where were we?
[Muir]
lthink we were
talkingabout...
Operation Rodeo--
right, Chuck?
You're on.
[ Sucking In Breath ]
My East German contacts...
discoveredthat we had
an unidentifiedmole in the embassy.
We hadthe ambassador
in ourcrosshairs,
until some information
leaked when he was
out ofthe country.
So thatjust left
onepossibility.
- Ah, Ann.
- Hello.
- [Man]Ann--
- ...Cathcart.
- [Muir] Yeah.
Bishop was involved
in a small but integral
part ofthe operation--
going East to bringacross
an East German functionary
namedSchmidt.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Ah, fuck!
The passport's in the glove box.
There's some vodka.
Spill it on your coat.
Ifthey stop us,
don't say a word.
Remember, you're drunk.
- And where is Mrs. Muir?
- Patricia left me
and filed for divorce.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, I'm so sorry, Nathan.
How is it I always
say the wrong things?
- [ Chuckles ]
- Patricia?
Yeah, my third wife.
- My God, how many wives
have you had?
- Four.
You want to hear
about them, or Bishop?
- You see that gentleman?
- [Young Woman] Yeah?
He's the ambassador.
Why don't you go over there
and say hello to him?
Okay.
Okay?
Your scotch is older
than she is.
Am I supposed to
feel bad about that?
They know.
They have my family
already, I know it.
Ifthey knew, they would
have stopped us.
Tomorrow, your wife, your kids,
will all be safe in Munich.
- I gotta make a stop.
- What?
- It's a scheduled stop.
I gotta make a phone call.
- They follow you.
Friedrich, it's all
taken care of, okay?
Ifthey ask, tell 'em
I got sick.
[ Klaxon Sounding ]
Why don't we go outside?
I'm sure we won't be missed.
I wish I could.
I have to stay
near the phone.
Working on
a Saturday night?
- [ Engine Roaring ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
Are you bringing
someone across?
- [ Whispers In German ]
- Bitte.
- Yes?
- Vodka did me in.
I'm comin' home.
- Throw out the bottle.
- Repeat that?
Throw out the bottle.
They know.
They don't know.
They don't fuckin' know.
They'll be waiting.
Drop as close to checkpoint
as possible.
- Negative, we're comin' across.
- No. That's an order.
- Let him go.
- [ Whispering ] They will kill him.
[ Retching ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gasps, Pants ]
Change of plans,
Friedrich.
No.
You will drive me across,
just as you said.
If I do that,
they'll kill us both.
This way, we still
have a chance.
You're a liar.
This way, you still
have a chance.
I can't help you.
-Just get out ofthe car.
- I will not get out.
- Get out ofthe car! Get out!
- I will not get out!
I will not!
No! No! No!
No!
Get out.
Get out!
Please.
My wife. My children.
I can't help you!
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Sobbing ]
[Chattering ln German]
[ German ]
Nathan, what happened?
What went wrong?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
Actually, one thing.
Don't ever question me again.
Ever.
What?
I gave you an order,
you take it.
You don't ask why.
Those ten seconds on the phone
could have blown the op.
The op was bringing
Schmidt across!
The op was
setting up Ann Cathcart.
And your end
had to look legit.
What are you telling me?
Schmidt was bait?
- Yes.
- Nathan, they executed him
on a shitty cellar floor!
It could have been you.
Let me tell you something
about Schmidt.
He went to the Russians
a week ago, and said he had
a contact, an American.
- Somebody he could use.
- Don't tell me that.
You didn't look in his eyes.
Don't tell me that!
He was your asset.
Somebody you used
for information.
Aw,Jesus Christ! You don't
just trade these people
like they're baseball cards.
It's not a fuckin' game!
Oh, yes, it is.
That's exactly
what it is.
And it's no kid's game, either.
This is a whole other game.
And it's serious and
it's dangerous-- and it's
not one you want to lose.
Nathan,
we killed this man.
We used him,
and we killed him.
Okay, then you gotta help me
understand this one.
You--
Nathan, what are
we doin' here?
Don't give me
some bullshit about
the greater good.
That's exactly
what it's about.
Because what we do
is unfortunately
very, very necessary.
And ifyou're not
willing to sacrifice
scum like Schmidt...
for those that want
nothing more than
their freedom,
then you better take
a hard look at your
profession, my friend.
Because it doesn't get any easier.
Why did you use me?
Do you want to walk?
Walk.
You should have told me
about the op.
You used me.
I did. And listen to this,
because this is important.
Ifyou had pulled
some stunt over there,
I wouldn't come afteryou.
You go offthe reservation,
I will not come afteryou.
Fuckyour rules, Nathan.
Okay. But tonight,
they saved your life.
Can we have
the relevant files
on Ann Cathcart?
Ann Cathcart's body
was found...
in the lobbyof
a cheap hotelin East Germany,
just two months after
she defected.
Yeah. Beaten to death.
- Vopos never solved the case.
- And Bishop was in Berlin
when this happened.
We were both in Berlin--
Do you recall
Bishop's reaction...
to the news that
Ann Cathcart was dead?
Motive and opportunity.
Nathan, you should leave here
knowing that we're looking
into every possible scenario.
What's ''Sideshow''?
You don't need to know.
Why are you trying
to burn Bishop?
Troy?
Hold transcription,
hold video.
Sideshow was a bugging op.
Listening to government offices
in eastern China.
- The trade talks?
- Mm.
And you're afraid
the lid to the cookiejar
is gonna slam shut on our hand?
Oh, come on, guys!
Chinese need trade status
more than we need to give it.
That's not necessarily so.
Twenty-four hours after capture,
Bishop's allowed to start talking.
That gives you, what?
Ten, twelve hours to make a trade.
Come on.
You're on the clock.
He doesn't know anything.
Bishop wasn't on Sideshow.
He wasn't working for us.
He was arrested during
a rescue attempt...
at a prison
outside Su Chou.
- Who was he after?
- Don't know.
[ Woman Screaming ]
Let go of me!
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[MaleAnnouncer]
Formore on this
late-breakingstory,
wego live to Hong Kong.
[ Announcer #2 ]
It has been confirmed
that the Chinese claim...
to have arrested an American
operative for the C.I.A.
While the State Department
remains quiet, official sources
say that the individual,
working out ofAmerican
consulate in Hong Kong,
was captured
in an act ofespionage.
lfconfirmed, this comes
at a badtime foran administration...
which is in the middle
oftrade negotiations with China.
The U.S. government is in theprocess
ofnegotiatinghis release.
The embassy promised
to keep us abreast...
We are so fucked.
ofthesituation asit develops.
- This is FrankNall, live in Hong Kong.
- Guess that limits our options.
I want to know what
you have to say about this,
and I want it
on the record.
When I was a kid,
I used to spend summers
on my uncle's farm.
And he had this plow horse
that he used to work with
every day.
He really loved
that plow horse.
One summer
she came up lame,
and could barely stand.
The vet offered
to put her down.
You know what
my uncle said?
No, Muir.
What did he say?
He said, ''Why would I ask
somebody else to kill a horse
that belonged to me?''
Get me Peter Brody
at the FCC.
ldon't care.
Justget him.
Looks like Bishop's
gonna be okay.
Good.
- What about the flag?
- Keep it.
Something to
remember me by.
You know where to store
this stuff, right?
Yeah.
What do I do with
the storage key?
If I need it, I'll send for it.
I'll send you a postcard.
- From where?
- Not a chance.
You'd show up and try
to clean the place, and scare
the native girls away.
[ Chuckles ]
I wish. I'll be working for
Andy Unger down the hall.
[ Sighs, Groans ]
You're gonna miss it.
You know that, don't you?
[ Sighs ]
[ Chattering ]
Thankyou. Thankyou.
Mm-hmm. Have a nice day.
Thankyou.
Mm-hmm.
[TVAnnouncer]
Formore on thisstory,
wego live to Hong Kong.
And, in a late-breaking
development ofthe incident
reported earlier,
rumors that Tom Bishop,
an alleged C.I.A. operative,
hadbeen captured
in an act ofespionage,
nowappears to be a hoax.
Tom Bishop died
1 4 months ago.
While the C.l.A. has
made no officialcomment,
sources close to the agency
have confirmed Bishop's death
late last year.
The discreditedstory
hasbeen attributed...
to an overzealous member
ofthe Chinese government,
who leaked the false information
in the hopes of undermining the
current U.S. trade negotiations.
This is FrankNall,
live in Hong Kong.
- [ Gasping ]
- Mr. Muir?
- [ Shouting In Chinese ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Chuckling ]
Told you you'd miss it.
Who do you trust
in military intelligence?
I co-signed
Martha Rayburn's car loan.
Listen, Gladys.
I gotta buy some time here.
l'mgonna needlmageryAnalysis
fora militaryprison nearSu Chou.
And ifyou use the phones,
don't use these.
Any chance I could
lose myjob over this?
Good. I didn't want to work
for Andy Unger anyway.
[DoorCloses]
[People Chattering,
LiveAndOn Radios]
I know who it is.
I know who Bishop was after.
Well, so do we.
But do you know why?
[ Snickering ]
I mean, ifanybody
knew the back story,
I mean, it would,
well, uh,
It'sjust that it would make
a congressional hearing
really worth watching.
By the way, that's not
in the op reports.
[ Beeping ]
Muir, you're not cleared
to be in here.
Relax, Kappler.
If I didn't have clearance,
how did I get in?
Where's this report?
I just came from
the seventh floor,
and there's some people
pretty disappointed
it hasn't arrived yet.
Hold on!
What report?
You were at the briefing.
I'm talking about Tom Bishop.
Bishop went rogue.
Yeah, andthey weregonna...
pull him out until
somebody up there--
and I'm not gonna say who--
said that your department claimed
there weren't enough resources.
Who said that?
Look, I can buy some time
while you pull this together.
Now, Operation Sideshow.
That'sneartheprison, right?
NearSu Chou.
China. Come on.
Any air support?
[Beeping]
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
Shit, that's probably Folger.
Yup.
[ Sighs ]
P'eng Hu Islands.
Commander Wiley's
outfit.
Forty minutes from
Su Chou Prison.
Thankyou.
Oh, hey,
l'm havinga little retirement
dinnerpartytonight.
- Services library. Say, 7:00?
- Sure.
You know, I uh--
[ Chuckles ]
I didn't know you liked me.
[ Laughing ]
[DoorClosing]
What was that all about?
What did Muir want?
What?
He wasjust talking.
- What about?
- His party.
I don't think
you're invited.
Gladys?
[Phone Ringing]
[Rings, Beeps]
Hello?
It's me.
- Where are you?
- First floor coffee shop.
- Talk to me.
- Imagery Analysis. They've got
every angle on the prison...
you could want,
collecting dust.
Gladys?
Get me whatever they have.
That'll have to go
through Folger's office.
I'm aware ofthat.
I also need info on an outfit
ofours in the P'eng Hu Islands.
- Commander Wiley's outfit.
- Muir?
Muir, wait up.
And call Kappler
in the map room.
- Tell him my party's cancelled.
- Your party?
- [ Hanging Up, Beeping ]
- [ Dial Tone ]
We're gonna need you
upstairs a bit longer.
[ElevatorDings]
What's that?
I said, we're gonna need you
upstairs a bit longer.
[ Sighs ]
[ Sighs Deeply ]
You got something
in your teeth.
Harker says you might care
to enlighten us on information
that's not in your op reports?
I just want
to help out.
Is it relevant
to the issue at hand?
I know who
Bishop was after.
Elizabeth Hadley.
Pull up what we have
on Hadley.
[Man Clearing Throat]
[ Beeping ]
It was a tip ofthe sword
deal, out of Beirut.
lntendedto be clean
andefficient in aplace
that wasanythingbut.
By '85, the place
was a nightmare.