[borg communicating]
[gasps]
Borg queen: locutus.
I am locutus of borg.
Resistance is futile.
[beeping]
Authorization picard--
4-7 alpha tango.
Admiral.
Catch you at a bad time,
jean-luc?
No, of course not.
I've just received
a disturbing report
From deep space 5.
Our colony on ivor prime
was destroyed this morning.
Long-range sensors
have picked up--
Yes, I know.
The borg.
Picard: captain's log,
stardate 50893.5.
The moment I have dreaded
for nearly 6 years
Has finally arrived.
The borg,
our most lethal enemy,
Have begun an invasion
of the federation,
And this time, there may be
no stopping them.
How many ships?
One, and it's on
a direct course for earth.
They will cross the federation
border in less than an hour.
Admiral hayes is mobilizing
a fleet in the typhon sector.
At maximum warp,
It will take us
3 hours, 25 minutes--
We're not going.
What do you mean
we're not going?
Our orders are to patrol
the neutral zone
In case the romulans
Decide to take advantage
of the situation.
The romulans?
Captain, there has been
no unusual activity
Along the romulan border
for the last 9 months.
It seems highly unlikely
they would choose
This moment
to start a conflict.
Does starfleet
feel
We need more
shakedown time?
We've been out in space
nearly a year now.
We're ready.
The enterprise e
Is the most advanced
starship in the fleet.
We should be
on the front line.
I have gone over all this
with starfleet command.
Their orders stand.
Number one, set a course
for the neutral zone.
[opera music plays]
Bizet?
Berlioz.
What do you have?
We finished
our first sensor sweep
Of the neutral zone.
Oh, fascinating.
20 particles of space dust
per cubic meter,
52 ultraviolet
radiation spikes,
And a class-2 comet.
Well, this is certainly
worthy of our attention.
Captain, why are we
out here chasing comets?
Let's just say starfleet
has every confidence
In the enterprise
and her crew.
They're just not sure
about her captain.
They believe that a man
who was once captured
And assimilated by the borg
Should not be
put in a situation
Where he would
face them again.
To do so would introduce
an unstable element
Into a critical situation.
That's ridiculous.
Your experience
with the borg
Makes you the perfect
man to lead this fight.
Admiral hayes disagrees.
[beep] troi: bridge
to captain picard.
Go ahead.
We've just received word
from the fleet.
They've engaged the borg.
Mr. Data,
Put starfleet frequency
1-4-8-6 on audio.
Aye, sir.
Woman: flagship to endeavor.
Standby to engage
at grid a-15.
Man: defiant
and bozeman...
Fall back to
mobile position one.
Second man: acknowledged.
Second woman: we have it
in visual range--
A borg cube on course
zero mark 2-1-5.
Speed--warp 9 point--
Borg: we are the borg.
Lower your shields
and surrender your ships.
We will add your biological
And technological
distinctiveness to our own.
Your culture
will adapt to service us.
Resistance is futile.
Third man:
all units, open fire.
Remodulate shield protection.
They've broken through
defense perimeter.
Fourth man: the cube
is changing course
0-2-1 mark 4.
First woman: flagship
to starfleet command.
We need reinforcements.
[garbled transmission,
explosions]
Man: casualties reported--
96 dead.
42 wounded on the lexicon.
[garbled transmission]
Lieutenant hawk.
Set a course for earth.
Aye, sir.
Maximum warp.
I'm about to commit
A direct violation
of our orders.
Any of you who wish to
object should do so now.
It will be noted
in my log.
Captain, I believe I speak
for everyone here, sir,
When I say...
To hell with our orders.
Red alert. All hands
to battle stations.
Engage.
[alarm blares]
Report.
Main power's off-line.
We've lost shields.
Our weapons are gone.
Unh.
Perhaps today
is a good day to die.
Prepare for ramming speed.
Sir, there's another
starship coming in.
It's the enterprise.
The defiant's
losing life support.
Bridge to
transporter room 3--
Beam the defiant
survivors aboard.
Captain, the admiral's ship
has been destroyed.
What is the status
of the borg cube?
It has sustained heavy
damage to its outer hull.
I am reading fluctuations
in their power grid.
On screen.
Number one, open
a channel to the fleet.
Channel open, sir.
This is captain picard
of the enterprise.
I'm taking command
of the fleet.
Target
all of your weapons
Onto the following
coordinates.
Fire at my command.
Sir, the coordinates
you have indicated
Do not appear to be
a vital system.
Trust me, data.
[beeping]
The fleet's responded, sir.
They're standing by.
Fire.
Mr. Hawk, pursuit course.
Engage.
Aye, sir.
[sound of borg]
What?
I can hear them.
I have a patient here
Who insists on coming
to the bridge.
Welcome abroad the
enterprise e, mr. Worf.
Thank you, sir.
The defiant--
Adrift,
but salvageable.
Tough little ship.
Little?
Mr. Worf, we could use
some help at tactical.
You do remember
how to fire phasers?
Sensors show
chronometric particles
Emanating
from the sphere.
They're creating
a temporal vortex.
Time travel.
Picard: data, report.
We appear to be caught
in a temporal wake.
Captain...Earth.
The atmosphere contains
High concentrations
of methane,
Carbon monoxide,
and fluorine.
Picard: life signs?
Population--
approximately 9 billion.
All borg.
How?
They must've done it
in the past.
They went back
and assimilated earth,
Changed history.
But if they changed history,
why are we still here?
The temporal wake
must have somehow protected us
From changes
in the time line.
[beeping]
Sir, the vortex
is collapsing.
Hold your course,
mr. Hawk.
We must
follow them back,
Repair whatever damage
they've done.
Come on.
Good night, eddy.
Go home.
You're gonna
regret this tomorrow.
One of the things
You should've learned
about me by now...
Is that I don't
have regrets.
Come on, lily.
One more round.
Z, you've had enough.
I'm not going up in that thing
with a drunken pilot.
I sure as hell am not
going up there sober.
What is that?
That...Is
the constellation leo.
No. That.
It's an econ.
After all these years?
We gotta get
to the phoenix.
To hell with the phoenix.
Aah!
Man: help! Help! Hurry!
Come on. Move. This way.
Run!
Aah!
Report.
Shields are down.
Long-range sensors
are off-line.
Main power's holding.
According to our
astrometric readings,
We are in
the mid-21st century.
From
the radioactive isotopes
In the atmosphere,
I would estimate
we have arrived
Approximately 10 years
after the third world war.
Makes sense.
Most of the major cities
have been destroyed.
Very few governments left.
600 million dead.
No resistance.
Worf: captain...
Mr. Worf,
quantum torpedoes.
Ready, sir.
Fire.
They were firing
at the surface.
Location?
Western hemisphere.
North american
continent.
Looks like
a missile complex
In central montana.
Missile complex...
The date? Data,
I need to know
the exact date.
April 4th...2063?
April 4th. The day before
first contact.
Precisely.
Crusher: then
the missile complex
Must be where
zefram cochrane
Is building
his warp ship.
That's what
they came here to do--
Stop first contact.
How much damage,
lieutenant?
Can't tell.
Long-range sensors
are still off-line.
We have to go down there,
find out what happened.
Data, beverly,
you're with me.
Have a security team meet us
in transporter room 3.
Computer, mid-21st century
civilian clothing.
Number one...
You have the bridge.
Over here.
They're all dead.
See if one of them
is cochrane.
Data, let's go check
the warp ship.
The structural integrity
of the missile
Appears to be intact,
But there is
significant damage
To various sections
of the fuselage
And primary
intercooler system.
You should have
the original blueprints
In the enterprise computer.
Commander la forge will need
to bring a team down here.
Hold your fire!!
We're here to help you!
Bullshit!
Captain...
I believe
I can handle this.
[gun cocks]
Greetings.
Captain, this woman
requires medical attention.
Severe theta
radiation poisoning.
The radiation
is coming from
The damaged
throttle assembly.
We are all going to have
to be inoculated,
And I have to get her
to sick bay.
Doctor...
Please, no lectures about
the prime directive.
I will keep her
unconscious.
Very well.
Tell commander riker
To beam down with
a search party.
We need to find
cochrane.
Crusher to enterprise--
2 to beam directly
to sick bay.
We have less
than 48 hours
Before this ship
has to be launched.
Picard to engineering.
La forge here.
Geordi, cochrane's ship
was damaged in the attack.
Get down here with
an engineering detail.
We have work to do.
Right.
I'm on my way, captain.
Alpha team, let's assemble
in transporter room 3.
We're heading down
to the surface.
Porter, you're gonna be
in command till I get back.
Aye, sir.
And, porter,
Check out
the environmental controls
While I'm gone.
It's getting
a little warm in here.
All right, let's go.
Isn't it amazing?
This ship used to be
a nuclear missile.
It is historical irony
that dr. Cochrane
Would choose an instrument
of mass destruction
To inaugurate
an era of peace.
It's a boyhood fantasy,
data.
I must have seen this ship
Hundreds of times
in the smithsonian,
But I was never able
to touch it.
Sir, does
tactile contact
Alter your perception
of the phoenix?
Oh, yes.
For humans, touch can
connect you to an object
In a very personal way,
make it seem more real.
I'm detecting imperfections
in the titanium casing...
Temperature variations
in the fuel manifold.
It is no more
real to me now
Than it was
a moment ago.
Would you three
like to be alone?
What have you found out?
There's no sign of cochrane
anywhere in the complex.
He has to be here.
There was nothing
more important to him
Than this ship.
This flight--
it was his dream.
Captain, we should
consider the possibility
That dr. Cochrane
was killed in the attack.
[sighs heavily]
If that's true...
Then the future
may die with him.
What do you think?
It's like the entire
environmental system's
Gone crazy.
It's not
just engineering.
It's the entire deck.
Maybe it's a problem
with the e.P.S. Conduits.
Hello?
Hey...
Eiger: are you
talking to me?
Is there anyone else
working maintenance
In this section?
Eiger: uh...
Not that I know of.
[zap] aah. Aah!
Paul?
Are you ok in there?
Aah!
[sound of borg]
Captain? What is it?
Picard to enterprise--
Mr. Worf, is everything
all right up there?
Yes, sir. We are experiencing
some environmental difficulties
On deck 16,
but that is all.
What kind
of difficulties?
Humidity levels
have risen 73%,
And the temperature
Has jumped 10 degrees
in the last hour.
Mr. Data and I are
returning to the ship.
Understood.
Number one,
take charge down here.
Aye, sir.
Damage to her cell
membranes is repaired.
She should be fine,
But I'd like
to run another test
On her spinal tissue,
And find out why
it's so hot in here.
Now what?
Crusher to engineering.
Crusher to bridge.
[gasps]
Commander worf,
I need to know exactly
what's been happening.
We just lost contact
with deck 16--
Communications,
internal sensors, everything.
I was about to send
a security team to investigate.
No. Seal off deck 16.
Post security teams
at every access point.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Hawk, before we lost
internal sensors,
What were the exact
environmental conditions
In main engineering?
Atmospheric pressure was 2
kilopasquals above normal--
92% humidity,
39.1 degrees celsius.
39.1 degrees celsius...
Like a borg ship.
They knew their ship
was doomed.
Our shields were down,
And somehow they
transported over here
Without being detected.
They'll assimilate
the enterprise
And then...Earth.
Picard to riker.
[static interference]
Enterprise to away team.
Respond.
Sir, main control
is being rerouted
Through main engineering--
Weapons, shields,
propulsion.
Quickly. Mr. Data,
lock out the main computer.
I have isolated
the main computer
With a fractal
encryption code.
It is highly unlikely
The borg will be able
to break it.
The borg have cut primary power
to all decks except 16.
The borg won't stay
on deck 16.
Wake up. You're all right.
Come on. Come on. Wake up.
Hmm...
Whoa, take it easy.
Stay calm.
You are all right.
Now listen to me.
You are
going to be fine.
I need you
to do as I say.
Alyssa...Is the e.M.H.
Program still on-line?
It should be.
Take it easy. That's it.
That's a girl.
I swore I'd never
use one of these.
Computer, activate
the e.M.H. Program.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
20 borg are about
to break through that door.
We need time to get out of here.
Create a diversion.
This isn't
part of my program.
I'm a doctor,
not a doorstop.
Do a dance, tell a story--
I don't care.
Just give us a few seconds.
[pounding]
According to starfleet
medical research,
Borg implants can cause
severe skin irritations.
Perhaps you'd like...
An analgesic cream?
Which way?
We need to get off
this deck.
Follow me.
First thing they'll do
in engineering
Is establish a collective--
A central point from which
they can control the hive.
The problem is,
if we begin firing
Particle weapons
in engineering,
There's a risk
we may hit the warp core.
I believe our goal should be
To puncture one of
the plasma coolant tanks.
Data?
Excellent idea.
Plasma coolant
will liquefy
Organic material
on contact.
But the borg are not
entirely organic.
True, but like all
cybernetic life forms,
They cannot survive without
their organic components.
I have ordered
all weapons to be set
On a rotating
modulation.
The borg
will adapt quickly.
We will be able to fire
12 shots at most.
One other thing--
You may encounter
enterprise crew members
Who have already
been assimilated.
Don't hesitate to fire.
Believe me, you'll be
doing them a favor.
Let's go.
[roy orbison's
ooby dooby plays]
[music blares]
Deanna!
Deanna!!
No, wil.
Don't turn off the--
Ñ(
who is this jerk?
Who told him he could
turn off my music?
Wil riker...
Zefram cochrane.
He a friend of yours?
Yes.
Husband?
No.
Good.
Now, this, deena--
Deanna.
This...
Is the good stuff.
Dr. Cochrane.
Shh.
To the phoenix...
May she rest in peace.
[gagging]
Ohh.
Ok...That wasn't so good.
[glass shatters]
Wil...
I think we have to
tell him the truth.
If we tell the truth,
the time line--
Time line?
This is no time
to argue about time.
We don't have
the time.
What was I saying?
You're drunk.
I am not.
Yes, you are.
Look, he wouldn't
even talk to me
Unless I had a drink
with him.
And then
it took 3 shots
Of something
called tequila
Just to find out
he was the one
We're looking for.
And I've spent
the last 20 minutes
Trying to keep
his hands off me.
So don't go
criticizing
My counseling
technique.
Sorry.
It's a primitive
culture.
I'm just trying
to blend in.
You're blended,
all right.
I already told him
our cover story.
He didn't believe me.
We are running
out of time.
Now, if we tell him
the truth,
Do you think
He'll be able
to handle it?
If you're looking for
my professional opinion
As ship's counselor,
He's nuts.
I'll be sure
to note that in my log.
[music starts again]
Data: captain,
I believe
I am feeling...
Anxiety.
It is an intriguing
sensation.
A most distracting--
Data, I'm sure
it's a fascinating experience.
But perhaps you
should deactivate
Your emotion chip
for now.
Good idea, sir.
[beep]
Done.
Data, there are times
that I envy you.
It's only me!
Doctor,
are you all right?
Yes. But we have
wounded here.
Worf: lopez,
Get these people
back to deck 14.
There was a civilian.
A woman from the 21st
century. We got separated.
We will watch for her.
Worf, she
has no idea
What's going on.
Try to find her.
Lower your weapons.
They'll ignore us till
they consider us a threat.
Picard: the
manual release.
Mr. Worf, hold
this position.
Computer: manual release
is on-line.
Perhaps we should
just knock.
Data.
Ready phasers!
Data, cover me.
Captain, they've adapted!
Picard: aah!
Regroup on deck 15.
Don't let them
touch you!
Captain!
Data!
Uhh!
Here!
Crewman: captain?
Help.
Please, help.
Aah!
You!
How the hell did you--
Back off!
Calm down!
Shut up!
Who are you?
My name is
jean-luc picard.
No! Who are you with?!
What faction?
I'm not a member of
the eastern coalition.
Listen--
I said shut up!
I don't care who you're with.
Get me the hell
out of here. Now!
That isn't going
to be easy.
You better find a way
to make it easy, soldier,
Or I'm gonna start
pushing buttons.
All right!
Follow me.
Slow!
[reactor pulsates]
Your efforts to break
the encryption codes
Will not be successful,
Nor will your attempts
to assimilate me
Into your collective.
Borg queen:
brave words.
I've heard them before
From thousands of species
across thousands of worlds
Since long before
you were created.
But now,
they are all borg.
I am unlike
any life form
You have encountered
before.
The codes stored
in my neural net
Cannot be forcibly removed.
You are
an imperfect being
Created by
an imperfect being.
Finding your weakness
Is only a matter of time.
[drill whirs]
[laughs]
Let me just make sure
That I understand you
correctly, commander.
A group of
cybernetic creatures
From the future
Have traveled back
through time
To enslave
the human race,
And you're here
to stop them?
That's right.
Hot damn.
You're heroic.
We're gonna
prove it to you.
Geordi?
There she is.
Beautiful!
All right,
take a look.
Well, well, well.
What we got here?
I love a good peep show.
That's a trick.
How'd you do that?
It's your telescope.
That's our ship,
The enterprise.
And, uh, lily's
up there right now?
Troi: that's right.
Can I talk to her?
We've lost contact
with the enterprise.
We don't know why yet.
So what is it
you want me to do?
Simple. Conduct
your warp flight
Flight
tomorrow morning
Just as you
planned.
Why tomorrow morning?
Because at 11:00
an alien ship
Will begin
passing through
This solar system.
Alien. You mean
extraterrestrials?
More bad guys?
Troi: good guys.
They're on
a survey mission.
They have no
interest in earth.
Too primitive.
Oh.
Doctor,
tomorrow morning
When they detect
the warp signature
From your ship
And realize that humans
have discovered
How to travel
faster than light,
They decide to alter
their course
And make first contact
with earth right here.
Here?
Uh, actually,
over there.
It is one of
the pivotal moments
In human history,
doctor.
You get to make
first contact
With an alien race
and after you do,
Everything begins
to change.
Your theories
on warp drive
Allow fleets of starships
to be built
And mankind to start
exploring the galaxy.
It unites humanity
in a way
That no one ever
thought possible
When they realize
They're not alone
in the universe.
Poverty,
disease, war--
They'll all be gone
within the next 50 years.
But unless you make
that warp flight
Tomorrow morning
before 11:15,
None of it
will happen.
And you people,
You're all...
Astronauts
On some kind
of star trek.
Geordi: look, doc,
I know this is a lot
for you to take in,
But we're running
out of time here.
We need your help.
What do you say?
Why not?
[phasers fire]
[click-whir]
It's pretty bad, sir.
It looks like they control
decks 26 up to 11.
But when they took
deck 11,
They--they just stopped.
The borg
have assimilated
More than
half the ship
In a matter
of hours.
Why stop there?
What is on deck 11?
Hydroponics,
stellar cartography,
Deflector control.
No vital system.
They would not
have stopped there
Unless it gave them
a tactical advantage.
Return to your
checkpoints.
Send reports
every 10 minutes.
Officer:
right, sir.
Something must've
happened in sickbay.
Where are dr. Crusher
and the others?
Why did you break
the cease-fire?
We didn't attack you.
Who did?!
There's a--
There's
a new faction
That wants to prevent
your launch tomorrow morning,
But we're here to help you.
This may be difficult
for you to accept,
But you are not
in montana anymore.
You're on a ship,
A--a spaceship
Orbiting the earth
at an altitude--
You wanna help me,
get me outta here.
All right.
You want a way out,
Here it is.
Lily: what is this?
Australia,
New guinea,
The solomons.
Montana will be up soon.
But you may want
to hold your breath,
It's a long way down.
Now listen to me,
I'm not your enemy,
And I can get you home.
But first you must
put that weapon down
And trust me.
Jean-luc picard.
My name.
That's my name.
What's yours?
Lily.
Welcome aboard,
lily.
Thank you.
[beeps]
Maximum setting.
If you'd fired this,
You would've
vaporized me.
It's my first ray gun.
There's no glass.
Aah!
Force field.
I've never seen
that kind of technology.
That's because it hasn't
been invented yet.
What?
There's more
I have to tell you.
Come on.
[beep beep]
Borg queen:
are you ready?
Who are you?
I am the borg.
That is a contradiction.
The borg have
A collective
consciousness.
There are no
individuals.
I am the beginning,
The end,
The one who is many.
I am the borg.
Greetings.
I am curious.
Do you control
the borg collective?
You imply a disparity
where none exists.
I am the collective.
Perhaps I should
rephrase the question.
I wish to understand
The organizational
relationships.
Are you their leader?
I bring order to chaos.
An interesting,
if cryptic response.
You are in chaos,
data.
You are
the contradiction.
A machine who wishes
to be human.
Since you seem to know
so much about me,
You must be aware that
I am programmed to evolve...
To better myself.
We, too, are on a quest
to better ourselves.
Evolving toward
a state of perfection.
Forgive me,
But the borg
do not evolve,
They conquer.
By assimilating
other beings
Into our collective,
We are bringing them
closer to perfection.
Somehow...
I question your motives.
That is because
you haven't been properly...
Stimulated yet.
You have reactivated
my emotion chip.
Why?
Don't be frightened.
I am not frightened.
Do you know
what this is, data?
It would appear
You are attempting
to graft organic skin
Onto my endo-skeletal
structure.
What a cold description
For such a beautiful gift.
[blows]
Was that good for you?
Ooh.
How many planets
Are in this
federation?
Over 150 spread across
8,000 light-years.
You must not
get home much.
Actually, I tend to think
of this ship as home.
But if it's earth
you're talking about,
I try to get back
whenever I can.
[beeps]
Good, they haven't broken
the encryption code yet.
Who, those bionic zombies
you told me about? The--
Borg.
Borg?
Sounds swedish.
Lily: how big
is this ship?
There are 24 decks.
Almost 700 meters long.
Lily: it took me
6 months
To scrounge up
enough titanium
Just to build
a 4-meter cockpit.
How much did
this thing cost?
The economics
of the future
Are somewhat
different.
You see,
Money doesn't exist
in the 24th century.
No money?
[whispers] you mean you
don't get paid?
The acquisition
of wealth
Is no longer
the driving force
In our lives.
We work
to better ourselves
And the rest
of humanity.
Actually, we're
rather like yourself
And dr. Cochrane.
Aah!
All right!
All right.
Come on.
Is-isn't there
another way around?
I know what
I'm doing.
Definitely not swedish.
Aah!
[gasps]
What the hell
are you doing?
[knock on door]
Perhaps something
in satin.
I'm sorry, gentlemen,
but we're closing.
And you do understand
We have a strict
dress code.
So if you boys don't
leave right now, I'll--
I'm looking for
nicky the nose.
The nose?
Hasn't been here
in months.
This is the wrong chapter.
Aah!
Computer,
begin chapter 13.
[beeps and whirs]
¶ if I say I love you ¶
Try to look as if
you're having a good time.
¶ I want you to know ¶
¶ it's not just because
there's moonlight ¶
¶ although... ¶
No, no, no,
look at me.
Try to act naturally.
There he is.
¶ you're all dressed up ¶
¶ to go dreamin' ¶
¶ don't tell me,
I know... ¶
Ruby.
This is not a good time.
It's never the time
for us, is it, dix?
Always some excuse,
Some case
you're working on.
I have to talk to nicky.
I'll see you later.
Ok.
But watch
your caboose...
And dump the broad.
¶ if I say ¶
¶ I love you ¶
¶ I want you to know... ¶
Well, well, well,
Look what
the cat dragged in.
What's shakin', dix?
The usual, nick,
Martinis and skirts.
Excuse me.
Whaa!
Hey, I'm gonna take that
personal in a second.
No offense.
Hey!
Ooh!
Woman: aah!
Yah!
Aah!
Hey!
I think
you got him.
I don't get it.
I thought you said
This was all just
a bunch of holograms.
If it's holograms--
I disengaged
the safety protocols.
Without them,
Even a holographic
bullet can kill.
What are you doing?
I'm looking for
the neuro-processor.
Every borg has one.
It's like a memory chip.
It will contain a record
of all the instructions
This borg
has been receiving
From the collective.
Oh, my.
Jean-luc, it's one
of your uniforms.
Yes.
This was ensign lynch.
[beeps]
Tough luck, huh?
We've got to get
to the bridge.
Cochrane: go on.
Jeez.
Ffft.
Geordi: doctor?
Yeah?
Would you mind taking
a look at this?
Uh, ahem, yeah.
Ahem.
I tried to reconstruct
the intermix chamber
From what I remember
in school.
Tell me if
I got it right.
School?
You learned about
this in school?
Oh, yeah.
Basic warp design
Is a required course
at the academy.
The first chapter
is called...
Zefram cochrane.
Well, looks like
you got it right.
Commander,
uh, this is what
We're thinking of using
To replace the damaged
warp plasma conduit.
[whirs]
Yeah, reg.
Yeah, that's good.
But you need to
Reinforce
this copper tubing
With a nano-polymer.
Dr. Cochrane, I know
this sounds silly,
But can I shake
your hand?
Oh, thank you,
doctor.
I can't tell you
what an honor it is
To work with you
on this project.
I never imagined
that I'd be meeting         reg.
The man who invented        reg!
Warp drive.
I'm sorry. Right.
Thanks.
Do they have to
keep doing that?
It's just a little
hero worship, doc.
Tell you the truth,
I can't say I blame them.
We all grew up hearing
about what you did here,
Or what
you're about to do.
You know, I probably
shouldn't even tell you this,
But I went to
zefram cochrane high school.
Really.
You know, I wish
I had a picture of this.
What?
Well, you see,
In the future,
This whole area becomes
an historical monument.
You're standing
almost on the exact spot
Where your statue's
gonna be.
Statue?
Oh, yeah.
It's marble,
about 20 meters tall,
And you're looking up
at the sky,
And your hand's
sort of
Reaching
toward the future.
I gotta take a leak.
Leak?
I'm not detecting
any leak.
Don't you people from
the 24th century ever pee?
Oh, leak.
I get it.
That's pretty funny.
Excuse me.
Female officer:
commander?
[lock clicks]
[phasers whir]
Captain.
Crusher: jean-luc.
Reports of my assimilation
are greatly exaggerated.
I found something you lost.
[gasps]
I am a klingon.
Picard: mr. Worf,
report.
The borg control
over half the ship.
We have tried to restore
power to the bridge
And the weapons systems,
But we have been
unsuccessful.
We have another problem.
I've accessed a borg
neuro-processor,
And I've discovered what
they're trying to do.
They're transforming
the deflector dish
Into an
interplexing beacon.
Interplexing?
It's a sub-space
transmitter.
If they activate
the beacon,
They'll be able
to establish a link
With the borg living
in this century.
But in the 21st century,
The borg are still
in the delta quadrant.
They'll send
reinforcements.
Humanity will be
an easy target.
Attack the earth
in the past
To assimilate
the future.
Then we must destroy
the deflector dish
Before they can
activate the beacon.
We can't get
to deflector control
Or a shuttlecraft.
Mr. Worf,
do you remember
Your zero-g
combat training?
I remember it made me
sick to my stomach.
What are you suggesting?
I think it's time that
we took a little stroll.
Hang on.
There's a humanoid
life sign up ahead,
511 meters.
[whirring]
Cochrane?
Mm-hmm.
It's him all right.
[beep beep beep beep]
[hums]
I have remodulated
the pulse emitters,
But I do not believe we will
get more than one or 2 shots
Before the borg adapt.
Then we must make
every shot count.
Magnetize.
[beep]
[hums]
[boots making
suction sounds]
Watch your caboose, dix.
I intend to.
How are you doing,
mr. Worf?
Not well, sir.
Try not to look
at the stars.
Keep your eyes
on the hull.
Picard: let's go.
Tell me,
Are you using
a polymer-based neuro-relay
To transit the organic
nerve impulses
To the central processor
of my positronic net?
If that is the case,
how have you solved
The problem of increased
signal degradation
Inherent to organo-synthetic
transmission acro--
Borg queen: do you
always talk this much?
Not always...
But often.
Why do you insist
on utilizing
This primitive
linguistic communication?
Your android brain is
capable of so much more.
Have you forgotten?
I am endeavoring
to become more human.
Human.
We used to be
exactly like them:
Flawed, weak,
Organic...
But we evolved to
include the synthetic.
Now we use both
to attain perfection.
Your goal should be
the same as ours.
Believing oneself
to be perfect
Is often the sign
of a delusional mind.
Small words from a small being
Trying to attack what
he doesn't understand.
I understand that you have
no real interest in me,
That your goal
is to obtain
The encryption codes
For the enterprise
computer.
That is one of our goals,
One of many...
But in order to reach it,
I'm willing
to help you reach yours.
Aah!
[exhales]
Is it becoming clear
to you yet?
Look at yourself...
Standing there
Cradling the new flesh
that I've given you.
If it means nothing to you,
why protect it?
I...
I am simply imitating
the behavior of humans.
You're becoming
more human
All the time, data.
Now you're learning
how to lie.
My...
Programming
was not designed
To process
these sensations.
Then tear the skin
from your limb
As you would
a defective circuit.
Go ahead, data.
We won't stop you.
Do it.
Don't be tempted
by flesh.
Are you familiar with
physical forms of pleasure?
Eh...
If you are...
Referring to...
Sexuality...
I am...
Fully functional...
Programmed in...
Multiple techniques.
How long has it been
since you've used them?
8 years...
7 months, 16 days,
4 minutes, 22--
Far too long.
We should bring
reinforcements.
There's no time.
It looks as if they're
building the beacon
Right on top
of the particle emitter.
Once all
the transponder rods
are in place,
The beacon
will be activated.
Well, if we set
our phasers to
full power, we--
No. There's a risk
that we'd hit the dish.
It's charged
with anti-protons.
We could destroy
half the ship.
We have to find
another way.
[panting]
Come on, come on.
Doctor?
Sir?
You still looking
for the bathroom?
I'm not going back.
Look, doc, we can't
do this without you.
I don't care.
I don't want
to be a statue.
Doctor--
You stay away from me.
We don't have time
for this.
Unh.
[gasping]
You told him
about the statue?
Picard:
for this to work,
All 3 maglocks will
have to be released.
O;-#
magnetic constrictors
are disengaged.
They've adapted.
Computer: warning.
Decompression
in 45 seconds.
[air escaping]
Hawk!
Ah.
Aah!
[beep beep]
[beep]
[hums]
Nnn. Unnhh!
We've had a change
of plans, data.
Assimilate this.
Only got an hour to go, doc.
How you feeling?
I got
a 4-alarm hangover,
Either from the whiskey
or your laser beam...
Or both,
But I'm ready
to make history.
Ha ha ha ha.
Troi to commander riker.
Riker here.
We're ready to open
the launch door.
Riker: go ahead.
[door opening]
Oh.
Look at that.
What, you
don't have a moon
in the 24th century?
Sure we do. Just
looks a lot different.
There are
50 million people living
on the moon in my time.
You see tycho city,
new berlin,
Even to lake armstrong
on a day like this.
Uh-huh.
And you know, doctor--
Please! Don't tell me
it's all thanks to me.
I've heard enough
about the great
zefram cochrane.
I don't know who writes
your history books
Or where you get your
information from,
But you people got
some pretty funny
ideas about me.
You all look at me as if
I'm some kind of...
Saint or visionary
or something.
I don't think
you're a saint, doc,
But you did
have a vision,
And now we're
sitting in it.
You want to know
what my vision is?
Dollar signs.
Money.
I didn't build this ship
To usher in a new era
for humanity.
You think I want
to go to the stars?
I don't even
like to fly.
I take trains.
I built this ship
So that I could
retire to some
tropical island...
Filled with...
Naked women.
That's zefram cochrane.
That's his vision.
This other guy
you keep talking about,
This historical
figure...
I never met him.
I can't imagine
I ever will.
Someone once said,
"don't try to be
a great man.
Just be a man,
and let history make
its own judgments."
That's rhetorical
nonsense.
Who said that?
You did...
10 years from now.
You got 58 minutes, doc.
You better
get on that checklist.
They're on the move again.
The borg
just overran 3 of our
defense checkpoints.
They've taken over
decks 5 and 6.
They've adapted
to every modulation
of our weapons.
It's like we're
shooting blanks.
We have to work
on finding another way
to modify our weapons
So they'll
be more effective.
In the meantime,
Tell your men
to stand their ground.
Sir.
Fight hand-to-hand
if they have to.
Aye, sir.
Wait.
Captain, our weapons
are useless.
We must activate
the auto-destruct
sequence
And use the escape pods
to evacuate the ship.
No!
Crusher: jean-luc,
if we destroy the ship,
we destroy the borg.
We're going to
stay and fight.
Sir, we have lost
the enterprise.
We should not sacrifice--
We have not lost
the enterprise,
mr. Worf.
We're not going
to lose it,
Not to the borg,
not while I'm
in command.
You have
your orders.
I must object
to this course
of action--
Your objection
is noted.
With all
due respect, sir,
I believe
you are allowing
Your personal experience
with the borg to influence
your judgment.
You're afraid.
You want
to destroy the ship
and run away.
You coward.
Crusher: jean-luc.
If you were
any other man,
I would kill you
where you stand.
Get off my bridge.
[door opens and closes]
So, what do we do now?
We carry out his orders.
Dyson, kaplan,
start working on a way
to modify the weapons--
This is stupid.
If we can get
off this ship
And then
blow it up,
let's do it.
Once the captain's
made up his mind,
the discussion is over.
Lily!
[door opens]
You son of a bitch.
This really
isn't the time.
Ok. I don't know jack
about the 24th century,
But everybody out there
Thinks that staying here
and fighting the borg
is suicide.
They're just afraid
to come in here
and say it.
The crew is accustomed
to following my orders.
They're probably
accustomed to your
orders making sense.
None of them understand
the borg as I do.
No one does.
No one can.
What is that
supposed to mean?
6 years ago...
They assimilated me
into their collective.
They had their
cybernetic devices
Implanted
throughout my body.
I was linked
to the hive mind,
Every trace
of individuality erased.
I was one of them,
So you can imagine,
my dear,
I have a somewhat
unique perspective
on the borg,
And I know
how to fight them.
Now, if
you will excuse me,
I have work to do.
I am such an idiot.
It's so simple.
The borg hurt you,
And now you're going
to hurt them back.
In my century, we don't
succumb to revenge.
We have a more evolved
sensibility.
Bullshit. I saw
the look on your face
When you shot those borg
on the holodeck.
You were almost
enjoying it.
How dare you?
Oh, come on, captain.
Yore not the first man
To get a thrill
from murdering someone.
I see it all the time.
Get out!
Or what,
you'll kill me
Like you killed
ensign lynch?
There was no way
to save him.
You didn't even try.
Where was your evolved
sensibility then?
I don't have
time for this.
Oh, hey, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to interrupt
your little quest.
Captain ahab has to go
hunt his whale.
What?
You do have books
in the 24th century?
This is not
about revenge.
Liar!
This is about saving
the future of humanity!
Jean-luc, blow up
the damn ship!
No!
Noooo!
I will not sacrifice
the enterprise.
We make too many
compromises already,
Too many retreats.
They invade our space,
And we fall back.
They assimilate
entire worlds,
And we fall back.
Not again.
The line
must be drawn here,
This far, no further.
And I will make them pay
for what they've done.
You broke
your little ships.
See you around, ahab.
"and he piled upon
the whale's white hump
"the sum of all
the rage and hate
"felt by his whole race.
"if his chest
had been a cannon,
He would have shot
his heart upon it."
What?
Moby dick.
Actually,
I never read it.
Ahab spent years
Hunting the white whale
that crippled him,
Quest for vengeance,
But in the end,
It destroyed him
and his ship.
I guess he didn't
know when to quit.
Prepare to evacuate
the enterprise.
Cochrane:
a.T.R. Setting?
Active.
Main bus?
Ready.
Initiate
pre-ignition sequence.
Begin auto-destruct
sequence,
Authorization
picard-4-7-alpha-tango.
[computer beeps]
Computer, commander
beverly crusher.
Confirm auto-destruct
sequence,
Authorization crusher-
2-2-betaharlie.
[computer beeps]
Computer, lieutenant
commander worf.
Confirm auto-destruct
sequence.
Authorization
worf-3-7-gamma-echo.
Computer: command
authorization accepted.
Awaiting final code
to begin auto-destruct
sequence.
This is captain
jean-luc picard.
Destruct sequence
alpha-one,
15 minutes,
silent countdown.
Enable.
[computer beeps]
Computer: self-destruct
in 15 minutes.
There will be no further
audio warnings.
So much for
the enterprise e.
We barely knew her.
You think
they'll build another one?
Plenty of letters left
in the alphabet.
Mr. Worf.
I regret some of
the things I said
to you earlier.
Some?
As a matter ofact,
I think you're
the bravest man
I've ever known.
Thank you, sir.
See you
on gravett island.
Data: captain.
[borg communicating]
Data.
Troi: control to phoenix.
Final launch-sequence
checks are complete.
Good luck.
Everybody ready
to make some history?
Always am.
I think
I forgot something.
What?
I don't know.
It's probably nothing.
Begin ignition sequence.
[troi counting down]
Oh, god.
Now I remember.
What?
Where is it?
We can't lift off
without it.
Geordi,
we've got to abort.
No. No, wait,
I found it.
Troi: 12, 11,
10,
9,
8...
7, 6...
Let's
rock 'n' roll.
[steppenwolf's
magic carpet ride begins]
[engines blasting]
¶ you don't know what ¶
¶ we can find ¶
¶ why don't you come
with me, little girl ¶
¶ on a magic carpet ride? ¶
¶ you don't know what ¶
¶ we can see ¶
¶ why don't you tell
your dreams to me? ¶
Turn that down a little?
¶ fantasy will set you free ¶
¶ close your eyes-- ¶
Hey! We've
got a red light
On the second
intake valve.
Ignore it.
We'll be fine.
Prepare first-stage
shutdown and separation
on my mark.
3,
2,
One,
Mark.
Ok, let's bring
the warp core on-line.
Oh, wow.
You ain't seen
nothin' yet.
If you see
commander riker
or any of my crew,
Give them this.
What is it?
Orders to find
a quiet corner
of north america
And stay out
of history's way.
Well, good luck.
To both of us.
You're not leaving,
are you?
Lily, when
I was held captive
on the borg ship,
My crew risked everything
to save me.
There is, uh...
Someone still
on this ship,
And I owe him
the same.
Go and find your friend.
[door opens]
[borg communicating]
Borg queen:
what's wrong, locutus?
Isn't this familiar?
Organic minds are
such fragile things.
How could you
forget me so quickly?
We were very close,
you and I.
You can still
hear our song.
Yes, I...
I remember you.
You were there
all the time.
But...
That ship...
And all the borg on it
were destroyed.
You think in such
3-dimensional terms.
How small you've become.
Data understands me.
Don't you, data?
What have you done to him?
Given him what
he always wanted,
flesh and blood.
Let him go.
He's not
the one you want.
Are you offering
yourself to us?
Offering myself?
That's it.
I remember now.
It wasn't enough
that you assimilate me.
I had to give myself
freely to the borg...
To you.
You flatter yourself.
I've overseen
the assimilation
of countless millions.
You were no different.
You're lying.
You wanted more
than just another
borg drone.
You wanted a human being
with a mind of his own
Who could bridge
the gulf between
humanity and the borg.
You wanted
a counterpart,
But I resisted.
I fought you.
You can't begin
to imagine the life
you denied yourself.
It's not too late.
Locutus could
still be with you...
Just in the way
you wanted--
An equal.
Let data go,
And I will
take my place
at your side,
Willingly without
any resistance.
Such a noble creature...
A quality
we sometimes lack.
We will add
your distinctiveness
to our own.
Welcome home...
Locutus.
Data, you are
free to go.
Data, go.
No.
I do not wish to go.
As you can see,
I have already
found an equal.
Data, deactivate
the self-destruct
sequence.
Data, no. Don't do it.
Data, listen to me.
Computer: auto-destruct
sequence deactivated.
Now enter
the encryption codes and
give me computer control.
Data!
Data...
He will make
an excellent drone.
Plasma injectors
are on-line...
Everything's
looking good.
I think
we're ready.
They should be
out there right now.
We better break
the warp barrier
in the next 5 minutes
If we're going to
get their attention.
Nacelles are
charged and ready.
Let's do it!
Engage.
Warp field
is looking good.
Structural
integrity...
Is holding.
Speed--20,000 kilometers
per second.
Sweet jesus!
Relax, doctor.
I'm sure
they're just here
to give us a send-off.
I am bringing
the external
sensors on-line.
30 seconds
to warp threshold.
Approaching
light speed...
We're at critical
velocity.
Qutum
torpedoes
locked.
Destroy them.
Watch...
Your future's end.
Data!
Resistance
is futile.
Aaah!
Whoooa...
Aah!
Aah...
Aaah!
That should be
enough.
Throttle back.
Take us out of warp.
Is that earth?
Geordi: that's it.
It's so small.
It's about to get
a whole lot bigger.
Captain.
Data.
Are you all right?
I would imagine
I look worse than I...
Feel.
Strange.
Part of me is...
Sorry she is dead.
She was unique.
She brought me
closer to humanity
Than I ever
thought possible,
And for a time...
I was tempted
by her offer.
How long a time?
0.68 seconds, sir.
For an android...
That is nearly
an eternity.
Picard: captain's log,
April 5, 2063.
The voyage of the phoenix
was a success...
Again.
The alien ship
detected the warp signature
And is on its way
to rendezvous with history.
My god...
They're really
from another world.
And they're going to
want to meet the man
who flew that warp ship.
Live long and prosper.
Thanks.
I think
it's time we made
a discreet exit.
[communicator beeps]
Riker to enterprise,
Stand by
to beam us up.
You gotta go?
I envy you...
The world
you're going to.
I envy you...
Taking these first steps
into a new frontier.
I shall miss you, lily.
Picard to enterprise,
Energize.
Report.
The moon's gravitational
field obscured
our warp signature.
The vulcans
did not detect us.
Captain,
I've reconfigured
our warp field
To match the
chronometric readings
of the borg sphere.
Recreate the vortex,
commander.
Aye, sir.
All decks
report ready.
Helm standing by.
Mr. Data, lay in a course
for the 24th century.
I suspect our future
is there waiting for us.
Course laid in, sir.
Make it so.
No, no. It's music.
I'll play you some.
¶ ooby dooby ¶
No, no...
You dance to it.
¶ ooby dooby dooby dooby ¶
¶ dooby dooby
doo-wah doo-wah doo-wah ¶
¶ well, you wiggle
to the left ¶
¶ you wiggle to the right ¶
¶ do the ooby dooby
with all your might ¶
¶ ooby dooby... ¶
Captioning made possible by
paramount pictures corporation
Captioned by the national
captioning institute
--www.Ncicap.Org--