MAN 1:
At ease.
Your name?
David Ackerman.
- How long have you been on the force?
- Two years, sir.
MAN 2: Speak up, Ackerman.
- Sir, two years.
You applied for detective
in Burglary, Auto Theft division.
Most of the young hotshots were
lining up for Robbery or Homicide.
Sir, I figured there would be more
openings in Burglary, Auto Theft...
...and I love chasing G-rides, sir.
- G-rides, Ackerman?
I'm sorry, sir.
Grand-theft auto.
Tell me something, Ackerman.
Why do you want to be
on the police force?
Because I want to help people, sir.
That's a lie, isn't it?
- Do you have any siblings, officer?
- No.
That's another lie, isn't it?
BOY:
Jump, Joey, jump!
- You had a brother, didn't you?
BOY: Jump, Joey, jump!
I... I was... I was just a kid.
BOY: Jump!
- You murdered your own brother.
It wasn't my fault.
Come on, jump. Jump!
Come on, Joey. Jump it!
JOEY:
David!
- You murdered your own brother.
- You murdered your brother.
You murdered your own brother.
[GASPING]
David, are you okay?
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
I'm a little tense
about the exam tomorrow.
Why are you doing this to yourself?
[TIRES SCREECHING]
MAN:
All right. Welcome aboard.
LOCO:
Good job. Go on. Get out of here.
MAN:
Thanks.
- Let' s get rolling, man.
- Why the hell not?
You got a light?
There must be 100 good reasons
why you shouldn't smoke those things.
But right now, I can't think of one.
Damn.
Feast your eyes on that.
Yeah, a real classic.
They don't make them
like that anymore.
Man, you got tachometers for eyes.
I was talking about the babe.
So was I.
- Morales is two minutes late.
STROM: We're out of here.
You shouldn't be getting
your hands dirty, ángel blanco.
What, and miss out on all the fun?
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- You're late, maricón.
- Not by my watch.
- Get yourself a better one, Loco.
- Go on. Get the hell out of here.
Come on. Let's go!
Let's wrap this thing up.
After all these months
of working on this deal...
- Let' s get moving, man.
- Take it easy.
Another couple of minutes
ain't gonna kill you.
[SIREN WAILS]
POWELL: Police officers!
Get your hands up! Up!
PULOVSKl: A little early
for Christmas shopping, ain't it?
- Who's up front in the cab?
- Santa Claus.
And I'm the tooth fairy.
Try again.
No one, man.
There's nobody here but us.
Nobody here, Nick!
Surprise.
[GUNSHOT]
No.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, man.
Motherfucker.
[SIREN WAILING]
[HORN HONKING]
[HONKING]
Son of a bitch.
- Cabrón.
- Motherfucker.
Jesus Christ!
Who is this insane motherfucker?
Later, you fucker!
MAN 1: Is he all right?
MAN 2: Anybody else in there?
MAN 1:
Anybody else in the car?
- You need any help?
- You got a light?
- Powell was a good man. Tough break.
- Yeah.
Good to see you
back on your feet.
Hey, Nick. Sorry to hear
about Powell, man.
PULOVSKl: Ray.
- Nick, good to see you up and around.
I've looked at the files.
Both those guys on the trailer are in it.
That one fella, Ken Blackwell,
an ex-CIA pilot that's gone sour...
...has about 300 drug flights.
- Nick...
And Loco Martinez has eight counts
of grand-theft auto.
Shut up, Nick. You don't waste any time
on polite conversation, do you, Nick?
That's what I like about you.
Either way, it don't matter anymore.
- What don't matter?
- The Strom case.
Because you' re being taken off it.
Homicide's taking over.
Homicide?
You know the only way to get to Strom
is to pin him to chop-shop operations.
But Homicide' s just gonna...
Look, kid. This is a private
conversation here.
- Nick, this is David Ackerman.
- Hello, David. Pleasure meeting you.
- Nick, that was your new partner.
- You're kidding me.
Let him back in, Nick, now.
Don't mind Pulovski. He's an asshole,
but you'll get used to him after a while.
- Flattery will get you nowhere.
- Listen, Nick.
I went over Ackerman's test scores
and records. The kid' s perfect.
Then how come his badge
is on upside down?
Kid, it looks like you forgot to dry off
behind your ears this morning.
Nick, be gentle.
Some of these virgins cry rivers.
[MEN CHUCKLING]
You' ve met Cheech and Chong.
[HONKING]
[SIREN WAILING]
ACKERMAN: What the hell' s going on?
- You'll find out as we go.
You mind letting me in
from the dark here?
The Jesse James look is out.
Why don' t you holster that thing.
In fact, why don't you
get a shoulder holster.
You don't want to
go around halfcocked.
Another thing, kid.
You gotta change the way you dress.
You look like an old fuck.
After all, we're working undercover.
You gotta dress youthful and hip.
Wear what you usually wear.
This is what I usually wear.
Do you have a reservation?
I see. Right this way,
gentlemen.
- So that's what those things are for.
- I never go to lunch without it.
STROM:
I wonder why you' re not covering me.
My people are cool, man.
Don't I know you
from somewhere?
I'm sure you're mistaking me
for someone else.
Well, there's no mistaking this German
beer. It leaves a little aftertaste.
- What the hell is that all about?
- Just a man with a poor taste in beers.
Hey, garçon, you got a light?
I'm sorry, sir.
No smoking here.
Mr. Ackerman? It' s been so long.
I almost didn't recognize you.
- How are you, George?
- Fine. This is a surprise.
I will get you an ashtray.
What's the deal here?
You used to work here or something?
Not exactly.
You'll find out as we go.
Don't jerk me off, Strom.
I don't like it.
You got problems? Fine,
but my people want their money.
I don't get it for them, then
I got fucking problems, capisce?
I just lost a major payload,
but my principal shops are still running.
By next Friday,
you'll have your money.
Well, you're so popular around here,
why don't you order for both of us.
- Do you want the best?
- Why not?
Oysters Rockefeller
and prime rib.
And we'll have a bottle of that
fancy French champagne too.
No, forget it.
I don't know if you're who
I think you are, but if you are...
...I want you to have this.
- Excuse me, sir. What about your meal?
- They'll eat it.
[LATIN MUSIC PLAYS]
- You ever worked East L.A. before, kid?
- I've never been to East L.A.
Jesus, I wondered who
ate these damn things.
Listen.
At the hotel this morning...
We obviously weren't there for lunch.
Who was that guy?
Just a guy I ran into the other day.
How'd you know
he was going to be there?
- Because that's my job.
Well, that's great, you know.
I'm supposed to be your partner here.
What about my job?
What about it?
Want to know what a real criminal is,
Ackerman?
It's the son of a bitch
who painted this car, that's who.
Yeah, that's what a real criminal is.
- Pulovski.
- Max.
What are you doing here?
Can you imagine defacing a work of art
like this with a color like that?
Guy ought to have
his ass removed.
I only been working here three weeks.
I don't need no trouble.
Did you hear what that puto
said about my car?
Put it back in your pants, Loco.
With the taste you beaners have,
he was being kind.
Son of a bitch!
PULOVSKl: I hear you been running
with a pretty fast crowd, Max.
I just dropped by to remind you
how short your legs really are.
Hey, I have not let you down.
I've been clean for over a year, so why
don't you stop looking over my shoulder.
Pretty fancy machinery around
here, Max. I'm glad for you.
Anything less than kosher comes in,
you'll call, right?
- You know it, man.
- Good man.
SARAH:
David, where are you?
What are you talking about?
I'm right here.
No, you' re not.
You haven't been here in a long time.
I just got a lot of shit
on my mind these days.
Here you are
finishing law school...
...and I' m a Burglary cop
in scenic downtown Los Angeles.
You know that doesn't matter to me.
Yeah, but I pick you up
after class...
...and I see you with all those
fucking together guys...
...with together lives,
and I just think sometimes...
...you're wasting your time
with me.
Don't make me feel like this.
I've always stood behind
every decision you've made.
I know that when there's
something wrong, you tell me.
But there's something going on
that you won't let me understand.
- I think something's gonna happen soon.
- What's gonna happen?
I don't know.
Something.
You know, I've been chasing around
after you for days, sarge.
- What the hell are we doing here?
- This is where the fun starts.
[LATIN MUSIC PLAYS]
Well...
Order yourself a drink, kid.
And watch your ass.
If you don't, somebody else will.
Excuse me.
Beer, please.
[YELLING]
[DOGS GROWLING]
- Get that animal!
- Get him! Get him! Get him!
What are you doing?
You can't come here.
Listen, Little Felix.
With your secondhand information,
I keep showing up late...
...and it's pissing me off, understand?
- Yeah.
Now, you're going to give me the name
of that pigeon nesting up at Strom's...
...otherwise, you'll be in deep shit. So
much, you won' t be able to see over it.
- You got that?
- Yeah.
I understand
what you're saying, Pulovski...
...but if I'm paid, I'll trade,
you know?
Thank you, Pulovski.
Thank you very much, man. I appreciate
that. You're all right in my book.
- You want some? I won't tell anybody.
- Knock it off.
That'll be 2 bucks.
LOCO:
Hey.
You tell your partner Loco was here.
You got that, boy?
- Hey, wait a minute! Hey!
- Hey!
[GROANING]
[GUNSHOT]
This is a crackdown.
Get back. Get back.
Now, all you people driving without
auto insurance are hereby under arrest.
[LAUGHING]
I didn't know you were
into group sex, kid.
You bastard!
Pulovski, you fucking bastard!
This shit is talcum powder, man!
You fucking double-crossing
gringo pig bastard!
Oh, man!
[YELLS IN SPANISH]
I'm crying.
PULOVSKl: What? Got a little gas, kid?
Too many of those candied doughnuts.
ACKERMAN: They took my badge.
- Fill out a report and get another one.
All right, I'm going in here.
See if you can back me up.
[OLDIES MUSIC PLAYS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[MOTOR STARTS]
God!
Hey! What are you doing?
Hey, you son of a bitch!
What the...?
You son of a bitch!
What are you doing?
Put me down, man!
I'm talking to you!
Put me down!
What the fuck are you doing?
I'm the cop that's footing your bills,
that's what.
So you and me are gonna make
a little arrangement.
No way, man.
I don't deal direct with pigs.
No!
Put me down, man.
Put me down!
Hey, no!
[DOG GROWLING]
[BARKING]
ACKERMAN:
Shit!
[GASPING]
[GROWLING]
- Jesus! My fucking beautiful Beemer.
PULOVSKl: You listen close, asshole.
I got enough to put you away
for a long vacation.
So like it or not, as of now
you' re working for me, understand?
All right, all right. Anything you say.
Just put me down, all right?
[GUNSHOTS]
All right.
Just put me down, right now!
[WHIMPERING]
Good. Good work, kid.
Now read them their rights.
Christ. What a dump.
You don't have to give it raves.
Here. Try that on for size.
- Cheers.
- You got suckered tonight, kid.
It'll happen again, but eventually
you'll learn to be prepared.
[COUGHS]
You still race?
Only on the freeway.
You got a light?
- I don't smoke.
- I told you, you gotta be prepared.
- Fucking gas company.
- Looks like you won some races.
Mostly local stuff. Smalltime.
- Who's this, your wife?
- Ex.
- Don't tell me. She hated racing.
- She loved racing. She just hated me.
- You got someone, kid?
- Yeah, I do.
That's good.
Come on out back.
- Wow. '69 Norton?
- Yep.
Beautiful.
- '67 TR6 Triumph.
- You know your bikes, kid.
Very sweet.
ACKERMAN:
I don't believe it. You got a Deuce.
PULOVSKl: Yeah, my pride and joy.
Pride and joy right here.
Let me show you my shop. This is
where I do all my tinkering around.
- Oh, wow. A '48 FL.
- Uh-huh.
Have a problem with this one.
Seems I'm better at riding it...
...than I am at fixing it.
This son of a bitch don't run.
- Well, you got the key?
- Yeah.
ACKERMAN: Thanks.
- Matches. How about that?
[MOTORCYCLE STALLING]
I told you so.
[CLICKING]
[MOTORCYCLE STARTS]
How about that? Hey, you're pretty
handy to have around, kid.
Hell, I got a whole yard full of stuff
you can start in on next.
I' m standing in front
of an East L.A. garage...
...which is the latest link in a chain of
six chop shops busted by the L.A.P.D...
...in the last three days.
This is Auto Theft
Detective Nick Pulovski.
You seem to have gone out of your way
to ensure we were here for these raids.
Well, that' s right, ma'am.
I realize that homicides and splashy
robberies get most of the headlines...
...but it' s about time this crime
gets the attention it deserves.
It' s impossible to make a real dent.
But it is possible to hurt individual
assholes who fuck it up for everyone.
Now, I happen to know of a prick
that' s responsible...
...for the whole fucking operation...
...and that son of bitch is hurting out
there, and I'm fucking liking it.
This is Connie Ling...
We' re going to be
moving on again, Liesl.
But first I have to
tie up a few loose ends.
Come on. It won't be so bad.
Sarah, if I die and go to hell,
it'll look just like my parents' house.
- Good evening, Lloyd.
LLOYD: How you doing?
[MUSIC PLAYS]
- Well, home sweet home.
WOMAN: David.
Sarah.
- Mom.
- Hello.
- Nice to see you.
- Nice to see you too.
Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- You look gorgeous.
- So do you.
- Thank you.
- Have fun.
- What happened to your face?
- Just cop stuff, Mom.
- Just cop stuff?
- Yeah.
Okay... Excuse me. Hello.
Happy birthday, Mom.
MAN:
Good seeing you, David.
- Hi.
WOMAN: Oh, hi.
ACKERMAN: Getting a little?
- Why?
Nick.
Hey, kid.
I didn't know we were on
a first-name basis, but how are you?
Not bad.
Are you here to arrest my mom
for substance abuse?
Very funny. Very funny.
I want to know what the hell
you' re doing on the force.
You' ve got it made here.
Your uncle says you' ve almost got
degrees in engineering and economics.
- So I gotta hear this shit from you also?
- Hey, lighten up, kid. It' s just a party.
- Who invited you?
EUGENE: I did, David.
My son doesn't talk
to us much, Mr. Pulovski.
If I hadn't seen you on the news...
...I wouldn't have known
who his partner was.
Let's take a walk.
You look like a man who likes
to get right to the point...
...so I'll be very direct.
- Why the hell not? Got a light?
Always given David
everything he wanted...
...but lately he just won't
take anything.
It's as though
he's cut me off completely.
David' s just not cut out for this,
Mr. Pulovski. He's not cut out for it.
I thought we were gonna be direct.
Yeah, so did I.
I want to guarantee David' s safety.
Mr. Ackerman...
...if you want a guarantee,
buy a toaster.
Hey, kid.
You tell your daddy next time
he needs a babysitter...
...tell him to check the yellow pages.
It's a lot cheaper.
Does he know he's not supposed
to smoke cigars in my house? David!
- Cigars are disgusting.
- I know. I know.
[STALLING]
Fuck!
SARAH:
I guess we should get a cab, huh?
[DOOR OPENS]
STROM: You're as adept at breaking into
houses as you are into cars, Morales.
You know me. I like to keep sharp.
- You want to talk about something?
- It's over, Morales. You' re over.
- What are you talking about?
- Shh...
I have no patience for any more shit.
That cop was learning
too much too quickly.
You rely too much on a nonexistent
racial solidarity, Morales.
Just a few ounces of the good stuff...
...and your friend Little Felix
was singing to me...
...like a canary
with his eyes plucked out.
No way.
I'm going to have to leave the country
if I ever want a breath of air.
Between the cops
and those fucking Italians.
You' ve caused me a lot of trouble.
Come on, Strom.
How can you believe a guy like Felix?
[CHUCKLING]
Look, I gotta go.
Come on.
You took me for a ride.
Now it's your turn.
Ciao.
[GUN COCKS]
The body is unidentified, Nick.
From the description, it sounds like...
...the bird you had nesting
in the chop-shop operation.
That him, Nick?
Absolutely not. That ain' t him.
Your plastic's not gonna help you now,
you lousy little fuck.
We could get in a lot of hot water
for this.
Relax, kid. Take your mind off my work.
Think about that little squeeze you had
at your daddy's bash the other night.
Just shut up about her, all right?
Why don' t we just get a court order.
They wouldn't give us one.
This ain't our case, remember?
Then why the hell are we here?
We both recognized Morales' body
at the junkyard.
- You fucking lied to Garcia.
- I didn' t lie to him.
- I just didn' t tell him the truth.
- Oh, Christ. Don't patronize me.
Think I like dragging around after you
all day? I fucking hate it.
And I hate the way you drive,
and I hate your stinking whiskey breath.
Well, I hate your uptight,
regulation-spouting, Boy Scout horseshit.
And I hate the little fucking creases
in your pants.
And I hate these fucking doughnuts.
These little ones
with the pinky shit on top.
Nobody eats that shit.
- Who the hell asked you anyways, huh?
- Shut up! I got him.
- Why do you want this guy so badly?
- He killed my partner.
I know about that,
but I'm not buying it.
There's gotta be something else.
Listen, kid.
All my life, I've been in a race...
...whether it was on the circuit
or the force.
I always seem to come up smalltime.
Except all of a sudden now...
...this guy Strom falls right in my lap
out of sheer luck.
Me and Powell, we make him as king...
...of the biggest chop-shop
operation in the Southland.
I'm wearing him down. Do you hear me?
He's running on reserve.
In fact, his engine's gonna blow...
...and I ain't gonna lose this one.
You can either stand out of my way or
you can be my partner and back me up.
Goddamn this son of a bitch.
Fuck this shit.
[MUMBLING]
That's got it.
Wake up, kid.
We just hit the jackpot.
[MUMBLING]
Good to see you, Mr. Strom.
We really missed you.
Good luck on the tables tonight.
I stopped believing in luck
a long time ago.
[BEEPING]
[ALARM RINGING]
[SCREAMING]
Mr. Strom.
Now listen carefully, paesan.
I am broke, desperate and very pissed.
I know you stupid wops
keep over $2 million in there.
You know the combination.
MAN:
Everybody, come on out.
All right. Up against the wall,
all of you. Come on.
STROM:
How did you know?
That's what happens when you live
with a bug up your ass.
You did good, Alphonse.
Now get out of here.
Hold it right there.
That's far enough.
Shoot her.
Shoot her now.
Freeze.
Amateur.
[GROANING]
Get the money.
- Ciao, pig.
MAN: There's nothing in here.
What are we gonna do?
Improvise.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[CAR STARTS]
STROM:
If you want him to die, shoot now.
There's already one dead cop
downstairs. Don' t make it two.
Hold your fire. Don' t shoot.
We can't let you out of here.
You know that.
Of course. In five seconds,
I'm pulling the trigger.
Five.
Four.
Three.
- Two.
- Hold your fire.
Let them out of the building.
Now listen to me.
This pig has cheated me
out of $2 million in cash.
That's exactly what you will
have for me in 24 hours...
...if you ever want to
see him alive again.
Two million bucks?
Are you out of your fucking mind?
That's not pertinent, is it?
I'm taking this car out of here.
I'm going to be flipping
through all your frequencies.
If I hear one static peep
about following us, the pig dies.
Yeah, I hear you. How can we
be sure you won't kill him anyway?
You can't, can you?
Nick, goddamn it all to hell.
COP: Freeze.
GARCIA: Hold it.
Hold it!
What do you mean, no money?
I mean the commissioner
and the mayor...
...decided not to set
a precedent inviting...
...every maniac in this city
to kidnap someone.
Whatever the hell we do, we're gonna
have to do it without $2 million.
- They'll kill him, goddamn it.
- Then they'll kill him.
He was gonna squeeze that trigger.
I saw it in his eyes.
They found the squad car ditched in East
L.A., captain. Bad guys are long gone.
You took it in the back, didn't you?
They' re not putting up the money.
Take a vacation.
Whatever happens...
...I don' t want to see your face
for at least two weeks.
YOUNG DAVID: Jump, Joey, jump.
Jump. Jump.
Help me!
David, please. Help.
[SCREAMS]
SARAH:
David.
David? David?
What happened to you?
What's going on?
It's time for me to stop being scared.
And for other people to start.
I don't like this.
Well, nobody asked you to.
Just make sure you're there.
Take her down to the shop, Cruz.
Well, cop...
...you wanted me so badly, now you get
to spend your last few hours with me.
Well, that makes me feel warm all over.
You know, I'm curious about one thing.
Why would a dumb Polack like you think
he could outsmart someone like me?
It's just that the arrogant fucking Kraut
like you is in the firing line. That's...
Liesl.
That's no way to treat $2 million
worth of merchandise.
Okay, Mr. Strom.
This place is completely rigged.
Now, this little device
just works by sound.
Punch in the sequence
anywhere from within 200 yards...
...enter it, and ba-boom,
she' s sky-high.
Well, it looks like I wasn't the one who
needed the longer legs, huh, Pulovski?
I'm going to have to leave this place
real soon, thanks to you.
But when I go...
...I go with a bang.
[KEYS CLANGING]
[MOTORCYCLE STARTS]
I'm looking for Loco Martinez.
Why don' t you run on home, or you'll
get hurt worse than before, faggot.
[MEN LAUGHING]
[SCREAMS]
[GUN COCKS]
[DOG GROWLING]
Shit!
[ACKERMAN GROANING]
Come on!
Who's next, huh?
You want a piece of me? Come on!
Come on, motherfuckers!
Come on!
Play fucking games?
- Come on! Come on!
BARTENDER: No!
Come on!
You gonna fuck with me?
Let's have a drink!
You fuckers thirsty, huh?
Have a drink!
Come on! Come on, motherfuckers!
Come on!
Let's get hot.
You can't do this, man!
You' re a cop! You're a fucking cop!
That's right. Tell me where I can find
Loco or I'll blow your brains out...
...and leave you here to burn.
- I don't know where Loco runs, man.
- Bullshit!
- I swear on the Virgin, nobody knows!
- What about Little Felix?
- Third and Howard, man!
- He runs a cleaners at Third and Howard!
- Third and Howard, huh?
I never did pay you for that beer.
MAN:
Come on! This way! This way!
I want the money
in a single black suitcase.
I will call later to inform you
of the drop-off spot.
There will be a man there
to pick it up.
- And then after, you will follow him to...
HARGATE: Wait a minute.
Pulovski has to be at the drop off.
So that your sharpshooters
can pick off my man and take the pig?
Who do you think you're talking to?
No Pulovski, no drop off.
[PHONE CLICKS]
Damn it! This guy is serious.
You listen to me. We got
no time, no money and no leverage.
You don't get it, do you, Ray?
Pulovski's dead already.
He just doesn't know it yet.
[PHONE RINGS]
Yeah?
I'm giving you one last chance.
You do as I say or the pig dies.
Okay, we'll do it, but I want to hear
Pulovski's voice, and I mean now.
It's for you.
Try and be smart.
GARCwA: Nick! Nick, are you there?
- Yeah, I'm here.
You damn fool!
I told you to get off this case!
But no, you had to be your
stupid, stubborn...
...son of a bitch self.
Look where it got you!
Now, you boys just take it easy
and save your money.
I've got these people
right where I want them.
[CHUCKLING]
You seem like a man
with a fairly adequate IQ.
I hope you respect my capabilities
more than your unreasonable friend here.
Further instructions will follow.
[PHONE BEEPS]
Sounds like Nick's got
them outnumbered.
Candy-gram for Mr. Mongo.
[BANGING]
[SCREAMING]
[YELLING IN SPANISH]
Get the fuck back!
Policía! Policía!
Shit.
Move! Move!
That's great.
This is all I fucking need right now.
Police brutality complaints
have been pouring in...
...from the East L.A.
division all morning.
Seems like a cop assaulted an entire bar
down there and burnt it down!
From the descriptions,
sounds like David Ackerman!
HARGATE: Ackerman?
- Yeah!
That damn yellow rookie.
I tried him at home.
His girlfriend answered, worried as hell.
Said he'd run off last night,
hasn't heard from him since.
Listen up! I need two volunteers
that know David Ackerman's face.
Wang! Lance! Get in an unmarked
and go out looking for him!
I want that fresh-faced punk
picked up on sight!
Lieutenant, give us a break.
It's not just a job!
It's a fucking adventure!
[MUMBLING]
Excuse me.
You can't go back there.
EUGENE: Our expectations are that...
- Okay, everybody out. The party's over.
What, do you want me to fax it to you?
Let's go! Come on!
Go on.
What do you think you' re doing?
You' ve been all over television.
Where you been?
I need $2 million...
...in four and a half hours.
That's it, then.
You continue making mistakes, and I
have to spend my life paying for them.
A man is going to die.
I didn't come to you
because you're my father.
I came to you because
you' re the richest person that I know.
Who do you think
you' re punishing, huh?
Putting yourself out where you could
get killed. I've already lost a son.
- You can't know how that feels.
- He was my brother.
You' re my only son!
It's your responsibility to be here for us!
My responsibility?
Where were you when I was in pain?
Where were you when I was hurting?
I've always given you everything
you wanted.
But you were never there for me, Dad.
Were you angry with me?
Did you blame me for something?
Well, I don't know,
and I really don't give a fuck anymore.
I'm through making mistakes.
You couldn' t buy me, Dad, but
you can sure as hell buy me some time.
I'll do it.
With a condition.
You forgive yourself.
You do what you gotta do...
...and when it's over, you quit,
give yourself a decent life.
- Deal?
- No.
This is my life.
This is my job.
Help me.
[LIESL INHALING]
Any chance of getting
a glass of water?
You think you' re a real man,
don't you?
A real tough American guy.
Pigs are all alike.
Without their badges,
they' re only half-men.
Without their guns,
they' re nothing at all.
Are you any different?
I said, are you any different?
You better be.
Because I hate anything useless.
When something is no good to me...
...I just cut it off
and throw it away.
It tastes like fear, pig.
Now I'll have something
to remember you by...
...when you' re dead.
Pure silver.
Strom wears an identical one.
When one of us dies,
the other takes his own life with it.
Romantic. Isn't it?
Bite it.
Bite it!
[ZIPPER UNZIPS]
[LIESL MOANING]
Don't lose it.
ACKERMAN: Sarah.
SARAH: David, where are you?
Never mind. Are you okay?
Am I okay?
Everybody' s worried sick about you.
Your parents have been calling all
day long. Lt. Garcia's here.
He says half the force
is out looking for you.
Okay. All right, look,
everything's fine.
Stay with the lieutenant. Tell him
I'll be there soon to explain, all right?
All right, I'll tell him.
I love you, David.
Admiring the view, Ackerman?
Lieutenant, that was David.
He'll be here in a minute.
That's great. Thank you, Sarah.
Is decaf okay? David hates caffeine.
Decaf's fine.
Don't worry. A couple more years...
...and David will be a speed freak
like us old-timers.
Christ. I don' t know what you've been
up to, but Garcia is pissing fire.
He wants you downtown,
like, yesterday.
Garcia isn't at headquarters.
Sure as hell is.
He called us from there five minutes ago.
- I gotta get home right now.
- No, you're coming downtown right now.
- What the hell are you doing?
WANG: Ackerman!
LANCE: What are you doing?!
- So long, guys.
Ackerman!
It's a nice place you got here, Sarah.
You got a washer, dryer, everything.
Me, I gotta go to the cleaners.
I was just there, as a matter of fact.
ACKERMAN:
Get out of the way! Move!
WOMAN: Watch it!
ACKERMAN: Get off the sidewalk!
Move your ass!
[KETTLE WHISTLING]
SARAH:
Lieutenant?
Coffee's ready.
- Officer Raymond Garcia. As you'll see,
his comments were quite unorthodox.
All I can say is,
we' re gonna do our best.
Everything that can be done to ensure
Pulovski' s safety is being done.
Oh, shit!
LOCO:
Bitch!
[SCREAMING]
[LOCO SCREAMING]
Ow!
Damn you!
Bitch!
Just for that,
I'm gonna make it hurt, puta!
No! No!
Come on, boy.
[GUNSHOT]
Goddamn it!
- I needed him alive!
- Then I should've let him kill you!
If I wanted him dead,
I would've shot him myself.
Maybe next time,
you aim for the kneecaps, huh?
I was aiming for the kneecaps.
Come here. It' s okay.
It's okay.
You want to know
what a real criminal is, Sarah?
What are you talking about, David?
Anyone who would deface a work of art
with a color like that...
...ought to have his ass removed.
MAX:
Third van's in place, Mr. Strom.
STROM: Good. Get up there,
help Liesl with the pig...
...get your car and you're out of here.
Get ready.
- What about Loco?
- Loco? Loco hasn't called in.
You handle it yourself,
and I save 50 grand.
Move!
We are moving, babe.
I think this little beauty here
is gonna do me just fine.
I'll see you later.
Going on a little trip, are we?
MAX:
Chill or die, asshole.
Now, you don't wanna go wasting $2
million worth of merchandise, do you?
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
Damn it, Liesl!
Hey, cop!
Are you listening to me?
There's no time for any more of this.
I wanted to keep you for insurance,
but now it's too late.
If you want to live, drop your gun.
All right.
Have it your way.
LIESL:
Don't lose it.
Fuck.
What the hell are you doing here?
- I thought you were dead.
- You should be so lucky.
PULOVSKl: That's twice you' ve let
me down, kid. Where's your key?
I'm gonna cut you a little slack.
Who's your backup?
ACKERMAN:
You' re my backup.
You' re a real precocious kid.
I could almost get to like you.
Wait a minute.
I was starting to enjoy that.
Pervert.
Hey, Nick, what the hell's going on?
Two hundred yards.
All right, you troublesome bastards.
Get in the car.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Get in the fucking car!
Say goodbye to your Polack.
- Fasten your seat belt.
- Are you fucking crazy?
Fasten your seat belt.
Holy shit!
Engineered like no other car.
I told you to fasten your seat belt.
You all right, kid?
I don't know.
- Are we done yet?
- No, we're not done...
...but you are.
ACKERMAN:
What the hell's that supposed to mean?
PULOVSKl: Means you did real great
back there, and I'm very appreciative.
But I'm going after that son of a bitch,
and I won't need you watching my ass.
Wait a minute. While you had
what's-her-name sitting on your face...
She did not sit on my face.
Whatever. Look.
I've been kicking ass and taking names,
trying to save your fucking hide.
I'll probably get busted
by the first cop that sees me.
You got a right to remain silent.
You got a right for an attorney.
- Fuck you, Nick.
- Your daddy will be able to make bail.
My daddy was ready
to bail one of us out.
Two million dollars for your ass.
- You tell him I'm obliged.
- Oh, he didn't do it for you, Nick.
I did it for you.
This is ridiculous.
We'll never see Pulovski alive.
MAN: There's a light-colored van
coming around the corner!
Captain, look.
That's it. Let him in.
COP 1: Get the barricades open!
COP 2: Open up!
- All right, get ready. This is it.
WOMAN: Sir.
MAN:
In position.
Get ready to grab the son of a gun.
MAN:
Ready?
What the hell?
Ray, what the hell's going on?
We didn't think we would have it
in time...
...but we do.
Give us a chance.
Look at it!
Hold everything.
We just bought 2 million bucks' worth
of time.
He's on the move.
Let's get this damn show on the road!
GARCIA:
Nick!
What the...?
I saw you die.
Welcome to hell, asshole.
What the hell's going on?
Who the hell knows,
but we're gonna back him up on it.
There's a turn up ahead.
You say left or right.
One mistake, I'll give you a smile
you keep the rest of your life.
Right. Right, man, right.
- Where you been rehearsing that stuff?
- Oh, I' m done rehearsing.
Good boy. Very good boy.
Strom would never send you out
without an escape route planned...
...so we're gonna lose the cops,
understand?
They aren't moving.
- What's going on?
- Who the hell knows.
Let's check it out.
I'll be damned.
[SIRENS WAILING]
Give him the keys.
Get in.
This thing isn't here for decoration.
You' ve been calling in. Call now.
- Hey, man, they've been calling me.
- That's bullshit, and you know it.
If you think about getting cute...
...I'll blow that shit you call brains
all over my partner here.
[PHONE RINGS]
STROM: You're behind schedule.
What's going on?
There was a delay, but I'm cool.
- I'll be there in 15.
STROM: Ten.
Shit all over your partner?
- Are you ready?
PILOT: Two minutes.
STROM:
Do you have it?
MAN:
It's all here.
Good work.
- Strom!
- Goodbye.
Liesl!
Here's the interest.
Ah! Ow!
[GUNSHOT]
PULOVSKl:
Split off!
Lousy bitch.
I better get Strom.
LIESL:
Out! Out! Out!
ACKERMAN:
Police officer!
Get out of the way!
I'm a police officer!
STROM:
Move!
Move! Move!
[SCREAMING]
Move!
STROM:
Get out of the way! Move!
Move!
PULOVSKl:
Police officer. Get back.
LIESL:
Get out! Get out of the way, bitch!
Out!
Out! Out!
Move it!
Get down! Get down!
ACKERMAN:
Move!
Hold it right...
Amateur.
[GRUNTS]
MAN:
He's got a gun!
[GUN CLICKS]
Goodbye.
ACKERMAN:
Strom!
I guess...
...you're gonna have to call
the ambulance, cop.
I don't think so.
A man's gotta live up to his word.
There's gotta be a hundred reasons
why I don't blow you away...
...but right now I can't think of one.
[SCREAMING]
You know that security guard only had
five bullets in his gun?
How about that?
Didn't I ever tell you
you should always...
...aim for the heart?
I was aiming for the heart.
That's my brand.
Where'd you get that?
Your house.
I picked it up the same time
I borrowed your bike.
It's nothing I can't fix.
Well, you're so good at fixing things...
...maybe you'll fix me a light.
The story of my life.
Hey, Dave.
Sorry to hear about Nick, man.
I always told Pulovski he'd get it
someday, and he didn't believe it.
Tough break for Pulovski.
Keep trying, fellas.
How's it going, Ray?
Nick! Where's the lieutenant?
- You're looking at him.
- What happened to Garcia?
He got kicked upstairs.
You got a problem with that?
No, not at all.
That's just fine.
You look pretty nice
sitting behind that desk there.
That's Lt. Pulovski to you or else
you'll be back on parking-meter duty.
- You got that?
- I got that.
I'm never too far
from your thoughts, am I?
My nightmares is more like it.
And keep that motorcycle out of my
parking place or I'll have it impounded.
And get your ass off my desk.
You don't park here either.
Listen, Nick...
Excuse me, lieutenant, sir...
I ran a make on that guy we've been
seeing all over town. Turns out to be...
Excuse me.
This is a private conversation.
This is Heather Torres.
Heather Torres?
Nice to meet you, Heather.
- Anyways, it's the same guy Homicide...
- That's your new partner.
Let her back in, David. Now.
I've been going through the files here.
Torres' test scores are outstanding.
Better than yours.
- She's perfect.
- Oh, yeah?
Then why is her badge on upside down?
I'd get yourself a backup.
Keep it.
Thanks.
Are you two gonna stand here all day
and bust my chops?
Get out there and arrest somebody.
Or something.
Why the hell not?
[CLEARS THROAT]
Looks a little wet behind those ears.
Thought you could use this.
You know what they say
about those virgins?
Yeah, I know all about it.
[ENGLISH SDH]