(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(METAL CREAKS SOFTLY)
(SOFT GROWLING)
(CHAINS CLANGING)
DUROTAN: There has been a war
between orcs and humans
for as long as
can be remembered.
But there was once a time
when we did not even
know who our enemy was.
Or what that evil green magic,
the Fel, had done to us.
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
But in the beginning,
how could we have known?
What choice did we have?
Our world was dying
and I had to find
my clan a new home.
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
DRAKA: Durotan...
I can feel your eyes.
I thought you
were asleep.
I was.
(GROANS)
Dreaming of a hunt
through the snow.
(DUROTAN SIGHS)
I've thought of a name.
Well, keep it
to yourself, wife.
I'll choose a name
when I meet him.
Or her.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh...
And how will
the great Durotan
name his son
if I do not travel
with him?
A son?
Can you hide
your fat belly?
Better than you can
hide your fat head.
(BOTH LAUGH)
(HOWLING)
So many clans in
one place, Orgrim.
Laughing Skull, Blackrock.
All have been summoned.
It will be a mighty warband.
Just wonder who's
left to fight.
(MALE ORC SOLDIER
SHOUTING lNDISTINCTLY)
MALE ORC SOLDIER:
Victory or death!
Blackrock, over there.
How much longer,
Blackhand?
We are ready,
Gul'Dan.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
What did she say?
She begs for you
to free her child.
But I need him.
I need all of them.
MALE ORC GUARD:
Move, half-breed!
(ORCS GROWLING)
What is that?
DUROTAN: Gul'Dan's magic.
(STAFF THUDS)
The fuel for my magic is life.
We only have enough prisoners
to send through
our strongest warriors.
But that will be enough.
The enemy is weak.
When we arrive,
we will take them as fuel!
(lNDISTINCT CLAMORING)
We will build a new portal!
And when it is complete,
we will bring through
all of the Horde!
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMING)
Let me go first.
MALE ORC SOLDIER:
For the Horde!
(WINCING)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(BIRDS TWITTERING IN DISTANCE)
(GROANS LOUDLY)
With child?
You dare bring that
wachook into my warband?
DUROTAN: Let me go,
Blackhand!
Draka!
(PANTING)
Push, little one. Push!
(SCREAMS)
(HIGH-PITCHED SHRIEKING)
(BLOWS)
(WAILING)
GUL'DAN: A new warrior
for the Horde.
KING MAGNl: Lothar.
Come. I've got
something for you.
What is it?
A mechanical marvel.
It's a boomstick.
Odd.
(PANTING)
Take water.
You might want to
head home, big man.
Someone's attacked
one of your garrisons.
Seems your king
needs you, Commander.
An entire garrison,
and no one saw anything?
We did find someone.
He was searching
the bodies here
in the barracks.
In the barracks?
Finally!
Are you in command?
(GROANS)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
LOTHAR: (IN ENGLISH)
That's the mark
of the Kirin Tor.
What are you doing in
my city, spellchucker?
Let me complete
my examination of the
body across the hall.
Now, why would
I do that?
Within that body is the
secret to your attacks.
What was that?
You must summon
the Guardian.
Medivh?
It should be he
who explains it.
Only the King
summons the Guardian.
Get him to Goldshire.
What kind of beasts?
MALE STORMWIND OFFICER:
Rumors, Your Majesty.
How does a garrison
of 30 men disappear
without a whisper?
KHADGAR: The Fel.
Or at least
its influence.
Is this him?
Mmm-hmm.
Your Majesty.
CALLAN: Dad.
Thank you, Sergeant.
So, who are you, mage?
My name is Khadgar.
I am the Guardian novitiate.
I was.
I renounced my vows.
LOTHAR: You mean,
you're a fugitive?
I'm not hiding.
Your Majesty...
I may have left my training,
but I didn't leave
my abilities behind.
I've sensed something.
Dark forces,
when it's strong,
it almost has a smell.
Knowing that something
so evil was so close,
I couldn't just ignore it.
GUARD 1: Where has
this happened?
GUARD 2: Is this true?
What's going on
out there?
Smoke, sir.
Southeast.
Your Majesty,
I urge you to engage the
Guardian with all haste.
OFFICER 1: They've reached
Elwynn Forest.
OFFICER 2: Grand Hamlet
is burning.
LADY TARIA: An attack?
What?
Stop requesting Callan.
Stay out of my business.
He wants to follow in
his father's footsteps.
LOTHAR: My son doesn't
need your help.
Tread carefully.
You talk to your queen.
You are my sister first.
When was your last
visit to Karazhan?
With you.
I don't know...
Six years.
And you've had no contact
with Medivh since?
Not for lack of trying.
Well, he can't
hide from us now.
The Guardian is summoned.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
Get on.
Good luck.
KHADGAR: Okay!
BLACKHAND: We need them alive!
WESTFALL WOMAN: My baby!
ORGRIM: This is not
for a warrior.
WESTFALL WOMAN: Let me go!
Frostwolves do
not join the hunt?
(SOBBING)
We prefer our enemies
armed with an axe,
not a child.
We have been
commanded, Durotan.
Respect the old ways.
There must be a worthy foe
somewhere on this dung heap.
Find them all!
Try not to kill too many,
we need them alive.
(SCREECHING)
Lothar.
LOTHAR: Moroes.
Look at you.
You haven't aged a bit.
Where is everyone?
Many things have changed.
The power that must
be locked away here.
The knowledge.
Where is he?
KHADGAR: I didn't know so
many books even existed.
Wait here.
And try not
to touch anything.
He sees no one?
World's been at peace.
Good you are here,
Lothar.
It will do
the Guardian
a world of good
to see a friendly face
beyond this old mug.
He can't refuse you.
Nor King Llane.
(SOFTLY) Not if
he's summoned.
(lNHALES)
Chop-chop.
MEDIVH: Did you summon
him, Moroes?
(PANTING)
No. He did not.
So...
You've become
a sculptor?
I'm making a golem.
Usually takes
years for the magic
to seep into the clay,
but up here
it's much faster.
Make someone to
keep Moroes company.
Help to clean up
around the house.
Thank you.
It's good
to see you, Lothar.
We need your
guidance, Medivh.
Our king summons you.
Who's the boy downstairs?
Hello?
Guardian?
Have a good look around?
Get some ideas what
you're going to do
with the place
once it's yours?
KHADGAR: Guardian,
I renounced my vow.
I didn't want
to come here.
I swear, Guardian!
I urged them to find you.
I told them.
You should be
the one to explain.
Explain what?
Fel!
(SCREAMS, GROANS)
In Azeroth?
In the barracks.
One the bodies.
LOTHAR: Guardian,
what is the Fel?
A magic unlike any other.
It feeds on life itself.
It pollutes the user,
twisting everything
it touches.
It promises great power,
but it exacts
a terrible price.
There is no place
for the Fel in Azeroth.
You've done
the right thing.
We'll go.
Hey! Go home, you.
Step in.
Medivh.
Your Grace.
It has been too long.
Come.
Help us get to
the root of these
troubles of ours.
What kind of beasts?
They're saying giants.
Armed giants,
wolves to carry them.
Huge unstoppable monsters.
What of the other
kingdoms?
Are they suffering
the same?
KING LLANE: All seek our
protection, yet none trust us
enough to tell us anything.
LOTHAR: We know nothing
about these
so-called monsters.
We need prisoners.
Even a corpse would
tell us something.
I don't know what
danger we're in, Medivh.
I exist to protect
this realm, my lord.
It is my very purpose.
I am the Guardian.
At least for
the time being, anyhow.
Yes.
What are we gonna
do about...
What is his name?
Khadgar, sire.
(CLANGING)
He'll be coming with us.
Well, then.
We better get going.
FOOTMAN: Halt.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(FLIES BUZZING)
it can't be.
Guardian?
(SCREAMS)
LOTHAR: Close ranks!
KAROS: Watch your back!
(ORC SCREAMING)
LOTHAR: Watch your flank!
To your left!
Watch your flanks!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
LOTHAR: (IN ENGLISH)
Watch your flank!
To your left!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Guardian!
(LAUGHS)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Die, you beast!
(SCREAMS)
Don't try and take them
on with brute force.
They're stronger.
Be smarter.
(SCREAMS)
The Fel.
SOLDIER 1: They're all dying!
KAROS: Only the green ones.
Kill that big bastard.
Durotan. Move.
(HOWLING)
KHADGAR: Guardian.
Guardian,
what did you do?
I was right, wasn't I?
It's here!
Where are you going?
Get these men
safely back to Stormwind.
I have to return to Karazhan.
You did well today.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
Where's the Guardian?
Karazhan.
We need a prisoner.
Where's your horse?
They took my horse.
Really? Just stay there.
GARONA: No!
(SOLDIER SCREAMS)
(SNARLING)
How much do you
love your master?
I'll do it!
Back off!
Pity.
He would have
made a good coat.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(CHAINS JANGLING)
(IN ENGLISH) Over here!
You took it alone?
Yes.
LOTHAR: Looks like
the runt of the litter.
You.
What are you?
And why do you
attack our lands?
He does not know
what you speak.
KHADGAR:
You speak our language?
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
and I will wear your tongue!
(lNDISTINCT TALKING)
I will not warn you again!
Tell him to stop.
You tell him.
(WHIMPERS)
You're welcome.
Have you a name?
You understand
our language.
Again.
Have you a name?
Garona.
She calls herself Garona.
KING LLANE: What kind
of being are you?
She seems more like us
than those beasts we fought.
Orc.
KING LLANE: Orc?
That's what you are,
or the beast in
the cage was?
I know every race in
the Seven Kingdoms.
I've never heard of "orc".
Show me where
you come from?
GARONA: This is not orc world.
Orc world is dead.
Orcs take this world now.
Not from this world?
How did you get here?
The Great Gate.
Deep in ground...
lnto magic brought
us here.
But how did you
learn our language?
Orc take
prisoner for the gate.
I learn from them.
KING LLANE: Prisoners?
Our people?
Are they alive?
Yes. Many.
Why?
GARONA: To feed the gate.
To bring in the Horde.
To take your world.
You'll take us to them.
No.
Or you'll end up like
your friend in the cage.
You think you're
fearsome?
Orc children have pets
more fearsome than you.
We're not trying to
be fearsome, Garona.
We're trying to
protect our people,
our families.
If you help us,
I give you my oath,
you will have
your freedom.
(lNDISTINCT CHATTER)
GUL'DAN: Fearsome Blackhand,
Warchief of the Horde.
You have allowed
the small-teeth
to kill your warriors.
Worse, you've shamed
your people by
running from an enemy.
Are you too weak
to talk, Destroyer?
The Horde has no
use for weakness.
Respect our tradition,
Warchief.
You know the penalty.
Death!
ORCS: For the Horde!
For the Horde!
GUL'DAN: Stop!
You dare interrupt
this judgment?
We fought hard.
Their warlock used
your Fel against us.
Only I can
control the Fel!
I see you and your
men have survived.
Perhaps Blackhand
kept you safely away
from the battlefield?
Maybe he knows
you're weak, too.
Do you wish
to challenge me,
little chieftain?
I do not question,
Gul'Dan.
But the Fel
is born of death.
It must have a price.
A price paid
in lives taken.
DRAKA: Will you
hold your son?
(COOING)
DRAKA: He will be
a great chieftain.
Like his father.
A born leader.
I was no leader today.
(GIGGLING)
He challenges
you already.
If Gul'Dan can infect
one as innocent as him,
what chance do
the rest of us have?
Whatever happens.
I see you.
This gate,
who showed it to Gul'Dan?
Who led him to Azeroth?
Gul'Dan called him
a demon.
Did you see it?
Not the face,
but the voice.
Like fire and ash.
(GATE OPENS)
(GASPS)
(CAWING)
I'll be here
if you need me.
(LATCH CLANGING)
Your mate.
I could kill you
before he even reaches me.
Lothar?
(CHUCKLES)
He is my brother.
The king is my mate.
You're the chieftain's
wife then.
I suppose so.
Then killing you
would bring me
even greater honor.
Not among my kind.
It is a cold night.
I thought you might
use these.
It will warm you.
(SNIFFS)
More of our villages
burn tonight.
One of them is
the village
of my birth.
I cannot imagine
what horrors you have
been through, Garona.
But this doesn't
need to happen.
We have had
peace in these lands
for many years now.
Peace between races
from all over the world.
What is...
I can have it removed.
There is a life
here for you, Garona.
With us.
A life of freedom.
If you want it.
The Great Gate.
"From light comes darkness
"and from darkness light."
Well, that's clear.
"Ask Alodi."
Alodi.
(BOTH LAUGH)
it's good to see
trees again.
And the snow.
Even from a distance.
Remember when we
would track blood ox
through the Frostwind Dunes?
There was always meat,
always life.
You don't think it's strange
that we lost our home
when Gul'Dan came to power?
One orc cannot
kill a world, Durotan.
Are you sure?
Look around you.
Does it not remind
you of something?
Wherever Gul'Dan
works his magic,
the land dies.
If our people are
to make a home here,
my friend...
Gul'Dan must be stopped.
We are not powerful enough
to defeat Gul'Dan.
No.
But with the humans' help,
we could be.
I want that weapon.
You'll have me
to protect you.
I need no one
to protect me!
What are you looking at?
Bookworm.
Take the first watch.
Respectfully,
Commander,
my name is Khadgar.
My deepest apologies,
Khadgar.
You see,
I thought we bonded
when I didn't put
you in a prison cell
for breaking into
the Royal Barracks.
Now take the watch.
Well, at least
you're not reading.
He wishes to lie with me.
Beg your pardon?
You would be injured.
I don't want
to lie with you.
Good. You would not
be an effective mate.
(CHUCKLES)
Why do you laugh?
I can't see how you humans
survive such a thing.
No muscles to protect you.
Brittle bones that break.
You don't look
that different to us.
How did you survive?
Broken bones
heal stronger.
Mine are very strong.
I'm sorry.
GARONA: Do not be.
My name...
Garona.
It means "cursed" in Orc.
My mother was burned alive
for giving birth to me.
They kept you alive, though.
Gul'Dan did.
He gave me her tusk.
To remember her.
My parents gave me
to the Kirin Tor when
I was six years old.
That's the last
time I saw them.
Or any of my
brothers and sisters.
It brings a family honor
to offer a child
to the Kirin Tor.
To have their son
taken up to the floating
city of Dalaran
and be trained by
the most powerful
mages in the land.
Less so, to have
them run away.
Well, that was cheerful.
GARONA: The Great Gate.
Why do they need
so many prisoners?
Like wood for a fire.
Green magic takes
life to open the gate.
LOTHAR: How many more orcs
are they planning on bringing?
GARONA: All of them.
This is just a warband.
When the portal
is opened,
Gul'Dan will bring
the Horde.
Get them back
to Stormwind.
We'll ride ahead.
KHADGAR: Garona.
We should go. it's not safe...
Durotan.
To the north,
there is a black rock
that touches the sky.
I would meet
with their leader.
To challenge him?
I saw you lead
the small-teeth to
our encampment.
They have seen
what is being built.
But only you know
what Gul'Dan has
planned for my people.
This magic is death,
to all things.
Must be stopped.
Tell him.
The black rock,
when the sun is highest.
GARONA: I will.
Chieftain.
If I return,
would you take me
into your clan?
You're safer here.
With them.
(MUFFLED BREATHING)
Is it as you feared?
The Fel is everywhere.
Then you mustn't leave again.
They need a Guardian's help
now more than ever.
Maybe the boy can help.
We need solutions!
Easy for you
to say that!
The Dwarven forges
must work overtime.
KING MAGNl: You treat us
no better than dogs.
We shall supply
you no more!
(SHOUTING) Enough!
You have all called on
Stormwind in the past.
Either for troops
or arbitration.
If we do not unite
to fight this enemy,
we will perish.
ALL: Hear, hear.
KING LLANE: Stormwind needs
soldiers, arms, horses.
KING MAGNl: We have our own
kingdoms to look after.
DELEGATE: Fight your own wars!
LOTHAR: Your Majesty.
Commander.
The orcs are
building a portal,
through which they
plan to bring an army.
If we do not stop them now,
we may never get
another opportunity.
ELF DELEGATE: Where is he?
Where is the protector
of Azeroth?
Where is the Guardian?
(SOFTLY)
Where is Medivh?
My liege.
I suggest
we take a recess.
LORDAERIAN DELEGATE:
Take as long as you like.
We're done.
(lNDISTINCT CHATTER)
Commander.
What's left of the
Fourth has retreated
from Stonewatch.
What's left?
Callan is among
the injured.
Dad?
I'm fine. it's fine.
You had me worried.
Where's the rest
of your troop?
They took most
of them alive.
We'll get them back.
Don't be in such a hurry.
You're all I have.
I know.
I'm a soldier.
He would not ask
for this meeting
if he thought he could
defeat Gul'Dan alone.
The Fel must
truly terrify him.
Durotan is scared
of nothing.
LOTHAR: The location.
The suddenness
of this meeting.
Sounds like a trap.
It is not.
Could be.
It is not!
What do you think?
It's too good
an opportunity to ignore.
I think we
have no choice.
We must stop the orcs
from opening the portal.
But we will need help.
And if he's lying?
Orcs do not lie.
What if he is?
There is no honor in it.
And where is the honor
in him betraying
his own people?
Durotan is
protecting his clan.
His enemy is the Fel.
Gul'Dan is the betrayer.
This orc, Durotan...
How do you know him?
GARONA: He freed me.
And he is loved
by his clan.
He is a strong chieftain.
LADY TARIA: Strong chiefs
must earn their clan's trust.
If we are to
expect you to join us,
we must earn yours.
To defend yourself.
With this?
Yes.
KING LLANE: Find the Guardian.
What is this?
Guardian?
The gate. We saw it,
in the Morass.
I've been putting
together all the clues
I can about it.
MEDIVH: This.
This drawing.
Where did you copy it from?
Guardian.
And this.
And this?
I've been researching
ever since I felt
the presence of the Fel.
I am the Guardian! Me.
Not you. Not yet.
I just thought you might
appreciate some help.
Don't presume
you can help me.
You have no idea the forces
I contend with.
If you want to help,
protect the king.
You leave the Fel to me.
Interesting choice.
Guardian.
STORMWIND GUARD:
Pack up and move
to the west gate!
(lNDISTINCT CHATTER)
You there!
Rise from your stall
and get moving. Now!
I need your help.
I found a book.
Of course you did.
There was an illustration
that showed a gate
like the one we
saw being built.
Sorry. Sorry.
Khadgar.
So then I tried to
show the Guardian,
but he became furious.
Burned all my research.
He would've burned this,
too, if it hadn't been
hidden in my robe.
No, turn the page. Here.
Look.
See?
What do you think
the image means?
The orcs were summoned.
From this side
of the gate.
They were invited in.
And the Guardian
burned your research?
He's probably just
trying to protect you.
Now go away.
A good spot
for an ambush.
Our sentries
are well placed.
I will check again.
(WIND HOWLING)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) I am King Llane.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
I'm told you wish to talk.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Ask him
if they plan to
return to their home.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Our world is destroyed.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
GARONA: (IN ENGLISH)
There is nothing
to go back to.
We are not responsible
for destroying your world.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) War with us
will solve nothing.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
He says, for orcs,
war solves everything.
Then why is he here?
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
To save my people.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
The Fel takes life
from more than its victims.
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) it kills
the earth and corrupts
those who use it.
Gul'Dan would
poison everything
with his death magic.
If my people are to survive,
Gul'Dan must be destroyed!
In two suns,
the humans we have captured
will be used to
fuel the portal.
If you attack our camp
and draw his warriors away,
Frostwolf clan will kill him.
Two days.
If we do this,
you will protect my
people until then?
(GARONA SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) I will try.
(GROANS)
FROSTWOLF ORC: Ambush!
LOTHAR: it's a trap!
Traitor, die!
LOTHAR: Retreat!
Back!
Protect our camp!
SERGEANT: Fall back!
At the rim!
STORMWIND OFFICER 1:
Protect the king!
STORMWIND OFFICER 2:
Stay together!
Focus, man. Like old times.
SERGEANT: Stand your ground!
Spread out!
Swords!
FEL ORC: Look out!
SERGEANT: Fall back!
(HOWLING)
(KHADGAR SPEAKING
OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) You all right?
You're no good to us dead.
Go! I'll get the others.
SERGEANT: Fall back!
We're all getting out.
Medivh will cover our retreat.
SERGEANT: Spread out!
Protect the rear!
Watch out!
Garona!
SERGEANT: Stay together!
Fall back!
Cover your ground!
Where's the bloody Guardian?
SERGEANT: At the rear!
Protect the king.
I got them.
Shield formation!
FOOTMAN: Kill the beast!
(CRACKLING)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Retreat to the plateau!
SERGEANT: Fall back!
Medivh.
Medivh! Take it down!
Medivh!
Hold on, son.
Dad.
For Azeroth.
(SHOUTING) Medivh!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Callan.
(CRACKLING)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
He's here.
What's wrong with him?
We need to get
him to Karazhan.
I'll get the horses.
KING LLANE: You won't make it
in time by road.
Take one of my birds.
(SCREECHING)
MOROES: Place him
in the font.
Moroes, what's wrong
with him?
I told him not
to leave Karazhan.
(WHIMPERS)
I have to go.
We need the help of
the Kirin Tor. Now!
Go.
There are medicines
I must prepare.
Sit with him.
You and the baby
must leave now!
You are a traitor,
Durotan.
No.
One who values
what we once were.
Like you used to.
That time has passed.
We are but fuel
for the Fel now.
There is still hope,
Blackhand.
Our children.
(BABY CRYING)
Do not make me take
more innocent lives,
young chieftain.
If I submit...
Would you
let my people be?
What will I call our son?
Go'el.
You.
Where's the old man?
He told me
to watch you.
The king?
He is alive.
Lothar's son is dead.
(SIGHS)
I argued
for the meeting.
Lothar will hate me.
This upsets you?
He is a great warrior.
He defends
his people well.
A good mate
for an orc.
I am no orc.
I am no human either.
When I was younger,
I used to feel
apart from my kin.
I traveled far and wide,
looking for
wisdom.
Feel a connection
with all the souls
I was charged
with protecting.
In my travels,
I met a strong
and noble people.
Among them, a female.
Who accepted me
for who I was.
Who loved me.
It was not a life
I was fated to have,
but it taught me something.
If love is what you need,
you must be willing to
travel to the ends of
the world to find it.
You left your mate.
Go find Lothar.
Step inside the circle.
This
is my gift to you,
Garona.
ORGRIM: Whole world in
exchange for a statue.
Gods are strange
creatures.
(GUL'DAN LAUGHS)
Frostwolves.
You are
a practical people.
Those of us from
the south have always
admired that about you.
When the portal opens
and the rest of
the Horde join us,
we will gift them the Fel.
All of them.
Durotan did not
agree to this!
And why would you care
what that traitor thinks?
It is time for a new leader
of the Frostwolf clan.
One who has
the best interests
of his orcs in mind.
One who appreciates
Gul'Dan's vision.
His power.
(GROANING)
Come...
I will grant you
the Fel.
Durotan,
he has poisoned
the Frostwolves
against Fel.
Let me gather them.
Bring them here.
Grant me the Fel
in front of them.
Let them see how
much stronger I become.
As I said,
a practical people.
This is a new dawn.
The time of the Horde.
Be feared
or be fuel.
(GROANING)
I'm sorry.
Callan's mother
died in childbirth.
I blamed him for it
for years.
I'm not gonna blame you.
He was so young.
In my entire life,
I've never felt as
much pain as I do now.
No...
(HOWLING)
No!
MALE ORC 1: Move out. Go!
Move!
Gul'Dan does not
want to waste his power
on the Frostwolves.
FEMALE ORC: Burn them!
Take the weak,
kill the strong!
(STRAINING)
MALE ORC 2: Get them!
I'll bathe in your blood!
Maybe.
But not now.
I can't give you long,
but I can give
you a head start.
For the sake of
your son, Draka.
Leave.
Now.
MALE ORC 3: Kill them all!
(BABY CRYING)
MALE ORC 4: Burn it down!
You should have
trusted in your Chieftain,
Orgrim Doomhammer.
MALE ORC 5:
She's getting away!
Wait for me.
ARCHMAGE: Khadgar!
ANTONIDAS:
How dare you return here!
FINDEN: Get out!
I come seeking
your wisdom.
ANTONIDAS: There is nothing
for you here now.
The Guardian
Medivh is unwell.
What?
He has been
poisoned by the Fel.
ARCHMAGE: What?
Ridiculous!
What do you know
of the Dark Portal?
You come back
and accuse the Guardian...
What is Alodi?
FINDEN: How does he know?
Alodi.
What is it?
An entity from
a time before the
Kirin Tor existed.
We think it served
a function similar to
that of the Guardian.
Protector.
No one beyond the
Arch Council knows
of its existence.
And it will stay
that way.
For you to mention it
in the same breath
as the Dark Portal
is too much
to be mere...
Coincidence.
Do I go in?
I don't know.
It's never done
that before.
ALODl: Khadgar...
KHADGAR: I know you.
From the library.
You're Alodi?
I used
the last of my energies
to summon you here.
The Guardian has betrayed us.
Medivh.
I saw the Fel
in his eyes.
He is consumed by it.
If he is not stopped,
this world will burn.
I don't have the power
to defeat a Guardian.
Guardian is but a name.
The true guardians
of this world
are the people themselves.
I know you see what
the Kirin Tor cannot.
It's why you left them.
No one
can stand against the darkness
alone.
I don't understand
what you want me to do.
Yes, you do.
Trust in your friends.
Together
you can save this world.
Always remember,
from light comes darkness
and from darkness...
Light.
Up, up.
Thank you, Moroes.
You'll recover, Guardian.
You always do.
No.
Thank you.
For everything you've done.
I'm sorry, old friend.
Seems that I have let
the orcs into this world.
The Fel, it has twisted me.
I don't even know what
else I may have done.
I just don't remember.
Everything I've
thought to protect, I have...
Destroyed.
I can't control the Fel.
No one can.
KING LLANE: Five legions
to block Deadwind Pass.
Another 10 here,
here, and here,
along Redridge Mountains.
Supply lines here.
While the Eastern
Sea hems them in
both south and east.
If we hold these
positions, we will
be at our strongest.
Containment.
Until there is
a better option, yes.
And when there's
10 times as many?
What then?
If there were
easy answers...
Our priority must be
to stop the gate
from opening.
Fail there, and it's
just a matter of time
before they beat us
with sheer numbers.
What do you suggest?
Send everything
we've got.
Destroy the gate,
free our people
and end the
immediate threat.
And the orcs that remain?
We'll take care
of them later.
After they've ravaged
the entire kingdom.
My lords.
KING LLANE: Medivh,
you are up and well.
I am.
I feel...
Restored.
KING LLANE: We need you.
We've been
agonizing over
our options.
Some of us believe
there are no options.
We need fresh eyes.
I have news.
I met with Durotan.
You met with Durotan?
MEDIVH: The rebellion
against Gul'Dan
is gaining strength.
With their help,
we can destroy
this gate.
That doesn't change
my plan.
MEDIVH: What plan?
Anduin believes
we should attack
with full force.
I'm concerned it
leaves the rest of the
kingdom defenseless.
MEDIVH: How many
legions would you need
to hold the orcs in place?
Five for
Deadwind Pass.
10 for the Redridge
Mountains,
10 more to
protect the city.
We've already
lost 18 legions.
That leaves one,
two, three.
Can it be done, Medivh?
LOTHAR: No, it can't be done.
With three legions,
Frostwolves
and my power...
With all due respect,
Guardian your powers
have proven
unreliable at best,
recently.
Llane, have I ever
let you down?
LOTHAR: Let him down?
Where have you even been
for the last six years?
Please, Anduin...
Medivh is the Guardian.
Not the one
you remember.
He's lost!
He's unstable!
And he won't be there
when you really need him.
Find your bearings,
Anduin.
I would march
into Hell for you
if I thought there was
the slightest
chance of victory.
But there isn't.
This is suicide.
Is this about Callan?
It was a tragedy.
If he hadn't
been trying so hard
to win your approval
he might still
be with us today.
Medivh.
Callan wasn't ready,
you knew it.
And you let him
play soldier anyway.
Anduin, stop! No!
You killed him!
Just save it!
Commander, please, sir!
Please!
KING LLANE: Varis.
Take him to
a cell to calm down.
You are no use
to us like this.
MEDIVH: We'll protect
the kingdom, my lord.
You and l.
(GATE OPENS)
Why are you here?
The King.
He goes to fight
the Horde.
With your Guardian's help
Durotan will kill Gul'Dan.
Don't trust him.
I have told you,
orcs do not lie.
Not Durotan.
Don't trust Medivh.
I will try to
protect your king.
Don't go with them.
Why?
I don't want you
to get hurt.
Come back alive.
MAN 1: Free us.
WOMAN 1: We're thirsty!
MAN 2: Spare us! Spare us!
WOMAN 2: Please!
We need your help!
ORC GUARD: Hey! Frostwolf!
Now, you're
enemies with all sides.
I'll tell them
it was you.
(GROANS)
What happened?
I'm sorry, Durotan.
I did not see
how we could side
with the humans,
against our own kind.
I was wrong.
Gul'Dan's Fel
magic is destroying us.
Where's Draka?
Safe.
But the rest...
They wouldn't follow him
if they could see
what he has become.
Then I'll show them.
There is no other
man I would entrust
the safety of my
family to, Varian.
Keep them safe
while I'm gone.
Ready?
I would feel better
if Lothar were
riding with us.
We'll be fine.
I will return to Karazhan,
get ready for battle.
Find me at the portal.
KHADGAR: Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Psst.
Guard!
I know you're
just doing your job.
And a good one at that.
But I've cooled down now.
So, if you'd just come
and open this gate...
So I can protect the King.
(YELLING)
Open the gates!
I am just following my...
(BLEATING)
Where the hell
have you been?
The Kirin Tor.
It only works on
the simple-minded.
Lasts about a minute.
Your armor, Commander.
(BLEATING)
Sorry.
They have a full
day ahead of us.
I just hope
we're not too late.
We can't go after them.
Not if you want
to save Azeroth.
My King needs me!
Azeroth needs you more!
If you want to save your King,
we need to stop Medivh first.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Where is Medivh?
We've got a demon
to kill.
ORC SCOUT: Can't be far.
Search over there.
I need that baby.
Check everywhere!
Search on the road!
Remember,
you are the son of
Durotan and Draka,
an unbroken
line of chieftains.
ORC SCOUT:
Search by the river.
(WHIMPERS)
(PANTING)
(CRYING)
I am Durotan.
Son of Garad.
Chieftain of
the Frostwolf clan.
And I am here to kill Gul'Dan.
A ghost cannot
invoke mak'gora.
You are the chieftain
of no clan.
Your people are
food for worms.
Some of us still
live, Warchief.
Shall I make
a quick end of them?
I always thought
you were one for
tradition, Blackhand.
Durotan.
Your clan was weak
and you are a traitor.
I accept your challenge
if only to
personally rip the heart
out of your pathetic body.
What of the portal?
You must be ready
when the incantation
begins.
This won't take long.
(ROARS)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
ORC: (IN ENGLISH)
Crush him, Gul'Dan!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
it's the incantation
to the orc home world.
He's opening the portal.
We need to shut him up.
GUL'DAN: The incantation...
I have no time for this.
Blackhand!
This is a mak'gora.
You will respect
our tradition.
Keep fighting.
Gul'Dan cheats!
ORC 1: That's cheating!
ORC 2: Shame on you!
ORC 3: You cheat, Gul'Dan!
ORC 4: This is not our way!
ORC 5: Traitor!
Gul'Dan!
You have no honor.
You will follow this thing?
Will you?
You will follow
this demon?
ORC 6: We will not!
I will not.
ORC 7: Demon!
ORC 8: He does not
even look orc now!
I follow a true orc!
A chieftain.
May your bones rot,
demon!
Anyone else?
And you, Warchief.
You will take the Fel
and you will become
stronger than any orc
has ever been.
And when the Fel
has remade you,
you will crush
the small-teeth.
Now claim my new world.
KING LLANE: Frostwolves.
GARONA: We are on
our own now.
We few, then.
Get to the prisoners.
We will free our people!
Charge!
Get to it, men!
Move!
(HORN BLOWING)
Attack!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) ldeas?
MEDIVH: (IN ENGLISH)
Very impressive.
Now try shutting him up.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Well, that went well.
It's moving! Do something!
Fine.
I'll handle this.
You take care of Medivh.
LOTHAR: Hey, over here!
Clay face!
(SCREAMING)
Now, men!
Fire!
KING LLANE: At the rear!
(SCREAMING)
Come, my orcs.
Let the Fel
unleash the full power
of the Horde!
HORDE WARRIOR 1: For Gul'Dan!
HORDE WARRIOR 2:
For the Horde!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Hey! Kid, wake up!
You all right?
Quick thinking.
Slicing its
head off like that.
Yeah.
Just how I planned it.
What now?
The Guardian has
to speak the
incantation himself.
As long as he's doing that,
we can get in close.
Distract him.
Then what?
Get Medivh in the font.
Is that all?
(SOFTLY) Medivh.
If there is something
of you still in there,
old friend,
come back to us.
(GROANS)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Medivh.
Come on.
Kill me.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) I've got nothing
left to live for now anyway.
After all, life is just
fuel to you, isn't it?
But Llane, he believed in you.
Don't kill your king.
Don't kill your friend.
Whatever you plan
to do, kid,
do it now!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Now.
Now! Now!
Now, kid!
The portal, it's closing!
Then do it now!
No.
You're stronger
than he is.
From light comes darkness,
and from darkness,
light.
(COUGHING, GASPING)
Show me your eyes.
(SCREECHING)
I have to go.
I'm proud of you.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Stormwind.
VARIS: My lord! Through
the portal, Stormwind!
Thank you, Guardian.
Varis.
Legion, forward!
SOLDIER: Attack!
Garona, ride with me.
VARIS: Run!
Varis,
set the men in
a perimeter.
Garona, Karos,
take what men we can spare
and free the prisoners.
And send them
through to Stormwind.
Form a line,
shield to shield!
KING LLANE: We will hold
as long as we can.
KAROS: Get to the portal!
Go!
Mercy! Thank you!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Stormwind.
SOLDIER: Need more powder!
KAROS: Help me push!
(STRAINING)
Come on, boys!
Put some spunk into it!
ORC: Go around!
We'll attack them
from behind the portal!
SOLDIER: Watch your flank!
Take care of him.
We should leave!
We save as many of
our people as we can!
It's the loneliness.
It makes us weak.
Khadgar.
I'm sorry.
I wanted to save us all.
I always did.
(CLAMORING)
PRISONER 1: No!
PRISONER 2: it's closed!
We've lost the Guardian.
FEMALE PRISONER 4:
No, no, no!
(PRISONER GROANING)
(lNDISTINCT YELLING)
(ORCS GRUNT)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMING)
GARONA: Blackhand comes
to claim the honor
of killing you.
Garona.
No good will come
from us both dying.
Look around you.
We're surrounded.
Your killing me
is the only hope
we have for peace.
You told Lady Taria
that killing her
would bring you honor.
Well, killing me
will make you a hero.
Survive.
Bring peace between
orcs and humans.
You must.
KING LLANE: You must.
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
(SWORD CLATTERS)
(GRUNTING)
No! My lord!
(ORCS CHEERING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
ORC MESSENGER:
She has killed
their chieftain, Gul'Dan.
The Horde embraces you.
Orc.
(WIND BLOWING)
(ORCS CHANTING
IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(ORCS CHEER)
Huh?
(SCREECHING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
BLACKHAND: Mak'gora.
(GRUNTING)
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
For my son.
Kill him.
Kill him!
Gul'Dan!
The mak'gora is sacred.
GARONA:
The human won. Fairly.
Let your warriors
honor their tradition.
I will not be disobeyed!
GUL'DAN: What are you
waiting for?
Do as I say!
Traitors!
(ORC GRUNTS)
Get out of my way.
I'll do it myself!
Who will obey you?
If you go to war
with your own kind...
if you do this,
you will lose the Horde.
And this war is
only beginning.
(SCREECHING)
(GROWLS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
For your son.
(GRUNTS)
So your spirit
can teach him.
(BELLS TOLLING)
Garona's dagger.
I pulled that
from Llane's neck.
Well, there has to
be an explanation.
Yes.
She made her choice.
I don't believe that.
Maybe you and I
didn't know her as well
as we thought we did.
LADY TARIA: There is
no greater blessing
a city can have
than a king
who would sacrifice
himself for his people.
But such a sacrifice
must be earned.
We must deserve it.
If we only show our unity
to mourn a good man's death,
was King Llane
wrong to believe in you?
CITIZENS: No!
MALE CITIZEN:
We will avenge him, my lady!
MALE CITIZEN 2: Lead us
against the orcs, Lothar!
ALL: (CHANTING)
Lothar! Lothar! Lothar!
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
For Azeroth!
For Azeroth
and the Alliance!
ALL: For Azeroth!
For the Alliance!
DUROTAN: You will
travel far, my little Go'el.
(GO'EL COOING)
DUROTAN: My world may be lost,
but this is your world now.
Take what you need from it.
Make a home for the orcs
and let no one
stand in your way.
MAN: My lord,
you should see this.
(GO'EL CRYING)
You are the son of
Durotan and Draka,
an unbroken line
of chieftains.
And our people need a leader
now more than ever.
(SNARLS)