-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
NUMB3RS 第4季第16集
ALAN:
Non-Newtonian
fluids, right?
CHARLIE:
Right, non-Newtonian fluids.
A fluid whose viscosity
is variable based
upon applied stress.
Yeah, see, Dad,
if you slap it...
it acts like a solid,
but if you poke it...
it's a liquid.
This is, uh, in your
lesson plan why?
It's an interesting study in transitional
system analysis.
Yeah, but I thought you teach
advanced number theory.
Well, the Riemann
zeta function, um...
What?
Students will get a kick
out of it.
And by the students,
you mean the teachers.
All right, you know what?
I think we're good, huh?
Hey,
looking good,
Professor Fleinhardt.
And I'm feeling good,
Professor Eppes.
Oh. Oh!
Uh, coffee, Alan?
Absolutely.
Oh, my.
More starch.
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
SYNC：无敌宝贝
All seven seals of the Apocalypse
were shattered
when Germany invaded Poland
in 1939.
Hitler delivered Lucifer
into the world.
It's documented.
????
"They were given
authority
over a quarter of the earth."
World War II Europe--
that's a quarter of the earth.
Did you want
some coffee?
I'd love some.
"To kill with sword,
famine, plague,
and by means of beasts
of the earth."
What beast of the earth kills
more than man himself?
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-You are welcome.
Here it comes.
Excuse me for a minute.
Reverend...
Walter...
Can somebody help us?
Craig...
All right, then you play back
in your stance, right?
Choke up and just punch it,
all right?
It's not a big
follow through.
Just punch it.
Punch it.
Okay.
Choke and punch.
Choke and punch it.
Are you enjoying this
at all?
Somewhat, I hope.
Yeah.
Beautiful weather,
sexy instructor--
what's not to like?
"Got a tight spot here.
Tight spot."
I'll say.
It's from O Brother,
Where Art Thou?
Uh, actually, it's from
Sullivan's Travels, originally.
Maybe the best movie
ever made.
I would've thought
you would've been into Heat,
or something like that.
"
What are you giving me the high hat,
girlie?"
United States Attorney's Office
doesn't take the weekend off.
Brooks.
DON:
What is this?
ROBIN:
Patmos Church--
government classifies them
as a dangerous cult.
They're not allowed
to receive medical attention,
or see a doctor--
only God can heal.
Paramedics got
a 911 call from inside,
looks like some
kind of mass poisoning.
So what are you doing out here?
You will not violate
our religious freedom!
The First Amendment
forbids your trespass.
Faith will heal
the righteous!
Normally we'd
break the gate,
but LAPD's already got
three lawsuits pending
from these wackos
and we're under
a consent decree.
ROBIN:
Okay, well, this
is some very gray first Amendment
real estate.
We believe in the power of the Lord,
not your wicked elixirs.
ROBIN:
Who called it in?
OFFICER:
Anonymous.
But we're sure it came
from an inside line.
Okay, well, if someone
in there wants help,
we might have grounds.
No.Stop! Stop!
You can't do this!
The First Amendment
forbids it.
You can't do it!
Read the First Amendment.
Let's go.
All right, back up.
It's okay, let them through.
God loves us, this is just
a message from him.
We're here to help you.
Let's go. Move back.
Back up, everybody.
Give us some room here.
"Nor did they repent their murders and
their magic potions."
Lady...
You don't even know who you are.
WOMAN: It's... coffee,
maybe... I...
Thank you.
Sure.
Is he going to be okay?
Patmos Church was
founded in 1978,
hit the NRM list in '93.
NRM?
"New Religious
Movement."
They feel the apocalypse
has been going on for 70 years.
Started with World War II--
and that the Book of
Revelation proves
that Hitler released Lucifer and
he is here on earth
specifically targeting them.
I thought cults believe they were
the first to get into Heaven.
Why are they still here?
We could call it a literal take
on theBible--
that only the
Chosen People,
144,000 Jews, were
raptured out in 1939.
Patmos believes
they're going to have to stay
here on earth
and fight with Lucifer for
their place in Heaven.
All right,
so how does this all relate
to refusing medical help?
I'm not really sure
that it does.
I mean, they've created
their own
littletrange patchwork
quilt of ideas.
Techs confirmed
the poison was arsenic--
delivered through the coffee.
You have two dead,
three in a coma,
and another 16 victims.
The ground water tested
normal and there's no residual
poison in the construction.
COLBY:
Jim Jones.
Instead of cyanide
in the Kool-Aid,
it's arsenic in the java.
Reverend Ezra makes the coffee
in the church kitchen
but he also leaves it
unattended.
So anybody has access to it.
Any chance we can track
the poison?
Arsenic is a common pesticide
and this area has
been an agricultural
for the past
hundred years,
so,I think it could have
come from anywhere.
You know, this could really
be a hate crime.
Angry neighbors, ex-member
with a grudge,
maybe disgruntled parents.
Well, the church compound
is heavily fortified,
and they have locked gates,
barbed wire fences,
and they have security cameras
all over the place.
The up side
of being paranoid nut jobs.
Sunday was my day off.
I would say it's an inside job,
'cause they have a
pretty extensive security system.
Uh, and how many members
in this cult?
Well, a thousand
at least.
I embrace in situ
experimentation
as much as any
physicist,
but next time you make
the aqueous odyssey.
Well, it'll work next time.
A scientist
is never
as diligent as when he himself is the experimental subject.
Hey, I was diligent!
Right now,
I'm calculating possible concentration-temperature
coefficients...
All right...
Charlie, come on,
please, focus?
Certainly.
On what?
There was
a mass murder attempt
at a cult church
this morning.
Attempt?
DON:
Yeah, arsenic.
Although, fortunately,
since 9/11
we've been stockpiling
the antidote.
Dimercaprol.
We saved most of them,
although, actually,
they tried to stop us.
Faith healers?
And I was
telling him
unless we have a thousand
psychopaths,
the poisoner's motives
and/or actions should
be easily detectable
according to normal
social dynamics,
whatever those are.
Social network analysis--
Bayesian network analysis--
will help me uncover
hidden dynamics
and covert architecture of this cult.
Well, I wouldn't
so readily discount the
"thousand psychopaths" theory.
I mean, what kind
of mindless cretins
"Creh-tins"...?
...would blind themselves
to the gifts of science?
How else would a Creator
reveal himself but through his creation;
and to deny
the mind of that creation
is to deny the mind of God!
Isn't it "cree-tins"?
Did you know that Don's
favorite movie is
is a Preston Sturges comedy?
It's not Heat?
I know, right?
CRAIG:
What do you call this?!
REVEREND:
You're the one who
crossed the line.
Be angry with me for
getting medical help,
but don't shirk responsibility
for your sexual misconduct.
I'm 18! I'm an adult!
I can do what I want!
Hey, guys, keep it
in your own corners.
He thinks he can
just control me
like he always has.
Things are going
to change.
What kind of things?
I spent the night
with my girlfriend.
I love Audrey and I'm done.
I'm done sneaking around.
I know how the government
regards us, Agent Granger,
but we are a church,
not a cult.
This was a hate crime.
We were attacked
because of our faith.
The kind of faith
where everyone
turns over power of attorney
to their leader?
We live in Lucifer's time,
forced to contend
with schemes that he
disguises as laws.
My flock looks to
me for guidance.
Well, they weren't so happy
with your decision
to let the paramedics
save their lives.
Sadly, there is a tradition at Patmos
of misinterpreting scripture on faith-
based healing.
Now, I've been working with
the Council of Elders
to change that.
Well, we're going to
need to take a look
at some church files--
records, history.
Sister Susan Doran will give
you everything you need.
I'll instruct her
to be cooperative.
Boy, that's the fourth
security camera we've passed
since they buzzed us
through the gate.
Extremist in Orwellian
paranoia
as well as stunted
religious beliefs.
Hey, so,
did you see anything
on that surveillance footage?
No outsiders got in,
and the coffee urns were
placed strategically
nowhere near all
those cameras,
so the enemy lies within.
Well, isn't it always so?
Uh, what do you think these
people are so afraid of?
Anybody not them.
They feel privy
to sacred information
that they're morally obligated to defend.
Ideologues tend
to demonize anyone who opposes them.
Mrs. Doran,
I'm Special
Agent Reeves.
These are Doctors
Fleinhardt and Eppes.
We're here to go through
your church records.
Yeah, we're just here
to help.
You've already put our souls
in jeopardy.
How are our people supposed
to meet the Father
with your noxious medicine
flowing through their veins?
Without
said "noxious medicines,"
you would have dozens now dead
instead of just the two.
Or has your zealotry
blinded you to that?
Hitler adopted
the cult of science.
Do you align with him?
Oh, those are
my choices here?
Hitler's science
or your religion?
Oh, my God in Heaven.
Do not take
His name in vain!
What is vain is
my appeal to Him
to grace you with some small
glimmer of rational thought.
Hey, that's enough.
Maybe you should
take a walk.
Yes, exactly.
So...
MEGAN:
Mrs. Doran, we respect
your religious freedom--
you can believe anything that you like--
We're just here to go through the church records,
that's all.
We're neutral, you know?
Just scientists.
You're bricklayers,
paving the path to hell
with good intentions.
Coming?
I'll be right back.
Hey.
Audrey will
help you find the files you need.
Thanks, Audrey.
Wow, that's an awful lot
of cash.
Safer here
than under the eyes and hands
of Lucifer's moneylenders.
My father, Reverend
Richard Doran, founded Patmos.
We've been custodians
of the church's finances
and records
since the early days.
It's only a matter
of time
before Reverend Ezra
and his deceitful son
put an end to that
tradition, as well.
Mother... Craig is
a good person.
You never lied to me
until you met him.
My father passed away
last summer.
The church
is in a period of transition.
I'm sorry to hear that.
How did your father die?
Heart attack.
And then Reverend Ezra took over
the church?
Yes.
But he and Craig joined us
almost three years ago.
Heart attack...
Arsenic poisoning can sometimes
be misread as heart failure.
We're going to
want to exhume your husband's body.
Absolutely not.
His body, in life or in death,
is sacred.
Ezra agreed to the
exhumation on the condition
that he be present
to protect the sanctity
of Richard Doran's body.
Hm. Let's see
what we turn up.
Everyone present?
All done with the cutting.
I don't understand.
We all have normal levels
of heavy metal like arsenic
or mercury in our bodies.
Hair shows abnormal dosages.
Even a year later?
Well, they dug up Napoleon
and it worked on him,
so, yeah,
I think we still
got a window here.
Atomic absorption
spectrometry.
This bad boy zaps it all the way
from a liquid into free atoms,
measuring the concentration
of the arsenic.
Now, a normal person's hair
would read 10 to 20 PPB--
parts per billion.
And what about
a murder victim?
Above 10,000
will be fatal.
You did this.
Susan, we need to know
whether or not Richard...
We don't need
anything from them.
You're desecrating
my husband,
just like you
destroyed my church.
DAVID:
Mrs. Doran, please.
What does that mean?
your husband was murdered
？？
I was in Alaska on
a mission before he died.
Returned home to perform
his service, in fact.
And jumped
Susan Doran's place in line.
She wants to stand still
30 years in the past,
when Patmos consisted
of 11 people in tents
in an orange grove.
So everyone just follows a guy
who's been around
less than three years?
The council
isainfully aware of the prejudices against us--
prejudices that begin with the government
classifying us as a cult.
They believe
that I can move us forward,
see that our traditions
are recognized and respected.
Your tradition against
the Devil.
Don't you fight against him
every day?
Isn't that why this room exists?
All right, top-level
priorities-- Reverend Ezra.
This is the percentage
for info in.
AMITA:
Oh, I thought that
was info out.
No, I've got information
moving out from Reverend Ezra.
Okay, so I need to rework
my equation for info out.
I hate to break this up,
but I was about to pass out
from the marker fumes.
Ah, yes,
that would be the lemon.
I told you
it was too much.
I like it.
It smells like a urinal cake.
Statement from Reverend Ezra.
Looks like there was infighting
for control of the cult.
Okay, that's excellent,
because it's that kind of concealed dynamic
that will help
uncover the motive
for poisoning the entire church.
Uh, in social
network analysis,
we examine the
differences
between the perception
of a group's structure
and its actual structure--
the hidden architecture.
In an apartment building,
hidden behind the walls,
under the floors,
are complex systems--
plumbing, electricity,
phone lines.
While we may endow
the penthouse
as being the most powerful
location in the building,
the nerve center
is actually in the basement.
So using three variables--
connectivity, access,
and information--
we can map the way
in which Patmos functions.
And who's being left
in the dark.
Susan Doran... isn't this the
woman that you threw down with?
I... didn't say
"threw down."
You know, I was taken aback
by t intensity
of her intolerance, yes.
Aren't you the one
that told me
never to try to teach anybody
who doesn't want to learn?
My dad used to say,
"Don't talk religion unless
you're looking for a fight."
Your dad makes a good point.
ROBIN:
I found something interesting.
Yeah, what's that?
in Patmos' latest appeal
for legal recognition,
Reverend Ezra added a list of nine practices
that he's changing,
including no more
prohibitions
against people seeking
medical help.
So what?
I mean, you think
he's going legit?
And trying
to make a ton of dough.
In property taxes alone,
they're paying
over six figures.
Members pay 75% of their
income to the church,
and Ezra controls
all of it.
If they go legit
and get tax-exempt status,
he gets millions more
to play with.
Goes to motive.
Right, but he
was in Alaska
for the other
reverend's murder.
Yeah, but he's still good
for the recent attacks.
Dose the congregation,
show them modern medicine
ain't so bad.
So, what, maybe, like, two
of them did the poisoning?
I know it doesn't seem likely,
but I don't have a lot to go on
in this "cockeyed caravan."
Wow, Preston Sturges,
Sullivan's Travels.
I did my Don Eppes homework.
Opposition research, my friend--
you should try it.
All right.
Hey.
So we've been studying the
hidden dynamics of your cult.
Not a cult much longer,
if Ezra can help it.
You know, that fits the pattern.
You see, overtly,
Reverend Ezra
is the leader
with a council and
members below him.
Yeah, we mapped out
more covert social networks--
power relationships,
financial status, marriages.
In the past, Susan Doran
was the connecting node--
the gatekeeper,
controlling the
flow of information
amongst all the
subnetworks.
Right, she had the safe
with all the records.
Yeah, she's been
the hidden power behind Patmos for 30 years.
CHARLIE:
However, we've noticed
that she's had less
and less influence
over the past
few years,
since her husband
and Reverend Ezra
began going on
missions together.
Ezra usurped her position.
Yeah, left her disconnected.
What, are you saying
she killed him for power?
Yeah, but it doesn't work, so
she loses status even faster.
Now she's got to reveal Ezra
as an impostor
by creating a situation
where he goes against church law
and has to use medicine
to save his son.
That's right-- so if she
mixed this poison at home,
you're going to find
trace amounts of arsenic.
ALAN:
You know what the best part
about being
a student is?
If I don't pass
a reflective surface,
I'm convinced
that I'm 25 years old
and I'm, uh, about
to conquer the world.
Well, I surrendered all
my dreams of conquest
when I realized all I'd
have to show for it is...
the world.
Hey, hey, Larry,
what's eating you?
A particularly repugnant woman
who somehow manages
to link all science
with Hitler and the Devil.
Oh, come on, Larry.
It's not worth getting upset
about every crazy out there.
I know this!
I live in a monastery,
I meditate.
I-I believe in peace
and, and compassion
and tolerance,
but still
this woman, she triggered
such outrage in me.
I think that
people like that,
like this woman, they're just
looking for something--
they're looking for answers,
you know, maybe even some
of the answers that you are,
but just by, uh,
different means.
You cannot begin to justify this
woman's spewing of her venom.
N-N-N-No,I'm not, I'm not.
It's just that, um,
not everyone has the emotional
and intellectual resource
to search for God in a
supercollider.
People look for answers
in what's available to them,
and when they're
particularly desperate,
they latch on to the closest
answer that's available.
I mean,it may make them wrong
but not necessarily evil.
Yeah.
Listen, I know you're right.
All my life I have attempted
to find just that perfect point
of beauty and balance
between science
and spirituality,
where they
not only coexist,
they complete each other.
And I saw in this woman's...
rage and her ignorance
a complete caricature of my faith,
and yes,I did match her bigotry
with my own.
God will rain His
justice on your heads.
I can live with that,
Mrs. Doran.
You're a faithless
charlatan!
You've spit on everything
we sacrificed our lives for!
You can't hide
in the church!
He will find you there!
We' positive
for arsenic residue in the
laundry room.
Okay, how conclusive
is this?
Heavy concentrations.
We're going to find it
all through the house.
Why would anyone want
to harm us?
It's indicative
of someone mixing water
and arsenic in a container,
not someone trying
to kill you.
Are... Are you accusing me?
Actually, Mrs. Doran,
I am arresting you.
Please...
This is Your test.
I can see that now.
Let me be strong enough...
Audrey!Hold on, I'm going to get you
out of there--
back up!
Craig, give me your hand.
You okay?
Can you walk?
Father--
in the kitchen.
Reverend Ezra!
(coughing):
Reverend!
Reverend Ezra!
Audrey.
My father?
Craig, we weren't able
to get to your father.
Hey, so, anyone else?
Just Reverend Ezra.
Craig Ezra, Audrey Doran,
they were shaken up a bit,
but they're going
to be just fine.
And you guys
are all right?
Yeah, I was going
to wait
for the fire department
to get here,
but Granger made me look bad
by running in there.
Ah, heroes.
Right, the
reluctant hero.
Hey, at least you got
to carry a girl.
So any idea
what caused it?
No, we don't know yet,
but the kitchen's hot
for arsenic dust.
It was clear yesterday.
Susan Doran?
She was cuffed and
in our custody.
But she could've
set a trap.
Well, maybe a kid.
Craig says he and Audrey
were here to meet with his dad.
Their alibi for the coffee
poisoning is weak.
I mean, the hotel has them
checking in and out,
but it doesn't mean
they were there.
DAVID:
So what do you think?
Kill Dad, put Mom in jail,
then they get married,
take over the church,
but that'd mean he
drank his own poison
and he sat on
his own bomb.
Right, so it makes him stupid
or a hardcore.
LARRY (over radio):
You know, it's really
your dad's insight
that led to the epiphany read my
egregious behavior.
Goggles.
LARRY:
Okay.
Version 17...
No reaction.
Let's try intentional ignition.
All right, where was I,
by the way?
Uh, "epiphany"
and, uh...
Oh, yeah,
yeah, yeah...
"egregious
behavior."
There I was, I mean,
so self-righteously
attacking Susan Doran
but never realizing
that I was just projecting
my doubts onto her.
Doubts about, uh...
about what?
Well, about my
faith, you know.
I have to wonder, all these
questions I'm asking--
are they an expression
of my belief,
or are they just a failure
to surrender myself to it?
Larry, does it have to be
an "either-or"?
Hey, there's one
to grapple with.
LARRY:
You know, the monks say
there are no enemies,
just the unresolved within us.
Hey.
Hey, so... so we think heat accelerated arsenic dust
to create this fire.
There was a similar
dust explosion
at a sugar factory in Georgia.
Wasn't that an accident?
LARRY:
Set off by sparking
heavy machinery.
Yeah. We've been
attempting to recreate the accidental combustion
all morning,
using kitchen appliances,
but nothing's
exploded yet.
Yeah, but that won't explain
what the arsenic was doing
there in the first place.
Which is why our next test
will be to determine if the
explosion occurred by design.
Uh, confidence is high
this wasn't an accident.
What does that do
to your network analysis?
Well, network analysis
was an analytic sledgehammer.
With the additional murder,
we've graduated to a scalpel--
affinity analysis.
Beer and diapers.
Oh, it's a
classic story,
most likely apocryphal,
all about a grocery store
that wanted to know
what items sold
most often with diapers.
They discovered it was beer.
Now, from this they inferred
that the wives
had delegated the diaper-buying
to their husbands,
who consolidated this duty
into their weekend beer runs.
They started
stocking the diapers
next to the beer coolers,
and increased their sales.
So, using
affinity analysis
and association
rule mining,
we determined that this
crime must have been
committed by
a partnership.
So we reexamined
the relationships
and behaviors of,
of your varied suspects
and it keeps leading us
back to Audrey.
MEGAN:
Susan's daughter?!
Okay, so Charlie says to
reinterview the suspects.
I think I could
have told you that.
But Audrey is the one
with no motive.
Not if she's helping
her boyfriend.
Or her mother.
I see the thinking.
I say she's a wedge.
That's our only move.
Thanks, Peter.
Oh, and Don?
Quit browbeating
my assistant
for personal
information on me.
You gave me up?
I know where my
paycheck comes from.
Now, what
makes you think
that he would have
something juicy on me?
I'm thorough.
Oh, yeah?
What do ya got?
We'll see.
I'm still compiling.
Nothing.
You got nothing, Eppes.
And what about the hotel?
Was Audrey there with
you the whole time?
No. Not the whole time.
She left for an hour
for dawn prayers
with her mother,
but she came right back.
So she had time
to poison the coffee?
Audrey?
COLBY:
She was the only one
who didn't have an alibi
for all three of the crimes--
the fire, the poisonings
and the death of your father.
But she handed me the coffee.
The morning of the poisonings?
Yeah, first thing.
I mean...
she poured me a cup.
Right.
But she didn't have any herself?
No.
Oh, God...
What?
Well, before
the church exploded,
she called us over,
Father and me.
Audrey's the only person
in the entire church
who doesn't have an alibi for
all three of the incidents.
Why would she need an alibi?
Because we have
a statement
implicating her
in the poisoning.
What?
MEGAN:
Your daughter
set you up, Susan.
She killed your husband.
Is she working with Craig?
No.
Is she working
with you?
I know I am being tested.
We found arsenic
all over your house.
If it wasn't you, it was Audrey.
She had nothing to do with it.
I did it.
I did it all.
What did you do?
Poisoned the coffee.
Poisoned my husband.
Huh. This is wrong.
She's the wrong person.
It's not the outcome
we expected,
but they've got
their confession.
You know something?
I think you need to
arrest Craig Ezra.
Well, how you
figure that?
What we may have here
is the test of Solomon.
Now, if so,
Susan Doran just now
sacrificed herself
for her daughter.
Okay? You tried
to cut her baby in half.
e wouldn't let you,
no matter how much the cost to herself.
And then Craig fed her to the wolves.
That's it.
CHARLIE:
However, it's pretty
counter-intuitive
that he would put himself
in harm's way twice.
And still he survives.
Hold on.A Bible story's not
gonna trump a confession.
No, I mean, obviously,
with real stories of faith,
you know, they don't
have easy answers,
but this story does give
us a place to find them.
All right,
you know what?
Given the results
of the interviews,
why don't... why don't
you give us some time
to revisit
our affinity analysis?
All right, good.
Go for it.
CHARLIE:
All right, so,
well, this isn't working.
Craig-slash-Audrey
and Craig-slash-Susan
have low support values.
Craig alone has
a low predictive value.
I'm thinking we circle back,
try a K-optimal
pattern discovery.
Charles...
What are we missing here?
Aside from a positive result?
Reverend Ezra.
I'm put in mind
of one Abimelech,
who slays his clan
in order to rule his
family and his kingdom.
Slay your clan,
poison your church.
After murdering
his own people,
God condemns and
kills Abimelech,
but not for his sins
against his people.
No, it was for dishonoring
his father, Gideon...
who was already dead.
Wow. I really don't
understand the Bible.
Well, the point
I'm making here
is that a father's influence
over his son can define him,
and maybe even drive him.
So Ezra-... slash-Craig.
That's a relationship we
haven't been focusing on.
DAVID:
Before 1998,
a Joseph and Emily Ezra lived in Bangor, Maine,
They went to work,
went to school,
they paid taxes...
and then... nothing.
Now, between 1998 and 2005,
the Ezras did not exist.
No credit cards, no drivers'
license, no taxes--nada.
Then Joseph and Craig Ezra
showed up at Patmos.
So what happened in 1998?
I think the real Joseph
and Emily Ezra, they died.
A car crash.
The bodies were burned
beyond recognition,
no match to dental records,
the identities went unknown.
1998.
Portland, Maine.
I know you got more than this.
Yes, I do.
Before the Ezras went missing...
they had a foster child.
MEGAN:
That would be Craig.
Craig?
Hey, Craig, we're gonna
need to speak to you
for a second.
What for?
Just want to talk to you.
About Audrey?
Me?
This is Eppes.
You need to run
California plates:
four, David, ocean,
queen, six, seven, eight.
You all right, Colb?
Yeah. Yeah.
？？
And we got no bites
on the APB.
DAVID:
William Boone.
Bunko has a long rap sheet on this guy;
he's got
short cons, fraud, scams,
been in and out of jail.
He drops off
the radar in 2005.
COLBY:
William Boone and Craig set up
shop at the Church
as father and son,
Joseph and Craig Ezra,
working a long con.
Life con.
You don't get into the tax-exempt business
looking for a quick buck.
Boone had
a retirement plan.
Okay.
DAVID:
Craig kills reverend Doran while
Ezra-slash-Boone is away.
And Boone poisons the coffee
while Craig's away.
This way, they both alibi out
for the other murder.
And I think church poisoning
was meant to be minimal.
You know, just enough
to sicken people
and give Patmos the option of accepting
medical treatment.
DAVID:
They drop controversial
beliefs,
including the mandatory
faith-based healing.
They fall off the cult list,
get recognized
as a real church,
get the tax-exempt status.
So what are you thinking?
Boone gets greedy
and uses more poison than planned?
Yeah, Craig drinks it
'cause he thinks it's going to be mild,
ends up almost dying.
So, to pay Boone back,
he decides to blow him up.
And these guys go to war against each other,
but at the same time,
they keep pointing the finger
at Susan Doran.
MEGAN:
So Craig's got three years
invested in this scam.
Now he's out in the cold,
he has nothing.
And that church has
a safe full of money.
I bet he's just
obsessing about it.
Sure. All right, he knows
better, but he's a con artist,
so he's always going to be
thinking about that score.
Audrey?
If she agrees,
we can run a sting on Craig.
Sure.
And if I don't agree?
Then he gets away
with killing your father
and destroying
your mother.
Audrey, he gave us
enough testimony
to get you the death penalty.
He literally
threw you at us.
He was scared.
He was scared he'd get nailed
for blowing up that church,
killing his dad,
and trying to kill you.
He never tried to kill me.
Audrey...
he left you
in a burning building.
He loves me.
There's somebody that loves you,
it is just not Craig.
MEAGAN:
If it wasn't you,
it was Audrey.
SUSAN:
She had nothing to do with it.
I did it.
I did it all.
You did what?
Poisoned the coffee.
Poisoned my husband.
Oh, dear.
You all right? Here.
Let me give you a hand.
I got it.
Thanks.
There you go.
Oh, I think this cappuccino
is a vanished dream.
Have the regular stuff.
Hey, nice turnaround
on Susan Doran.
Well, it's no easy thing.
I'll tell you-- separating the ugliness
of her dogma
from the sincerity
of her faith.
Yeah, I agree.
You know, with your job,
there's so many horrific things
that you hear people say or do.
How do you
shrug that off?
Alcohol.
(chuckles)
No, look, I-I try to remember
the job's more
important than me.
Well, we all pray at our own
unique altars, don't we?
Well...
you know, I think
of religion as a...
a really good police force,
you know?
It keeps 90% of
the people honest
and then we worry
about the other ten.
That's religion.How about belief?
Well, look,
you know we weren't a big
"God house."
I just always figured
one exists, but...
that's pretty much
the extent of it.
Pascal's Wager.
One lives as if God exists.
If He does,
your gain is infinite.
If He doesn't, well,
you've lost nothing.
Think Vegas gives odds on that?
You don't feel any...
any emptins in this?
Ah, well, hence the alcohol.
Well...
They let my mom go an hour ago.
I think they're
going to arrest me.
CRAIG (on phone):
The church has been tainted by outsiders.
We have to rebuild it.
How?
We need the money.
It's the right thing to do.
I mean, you know
the combination.
To start again, we need a lot.
As much as you can take.
Okay.
Okay, yes.
Where should I meet you?
Union Station in an hour,
main entrance.
Audrey, I love you.
I love you, too.
All right, there he is.
We moving in?
No, let him take the bag.
What if he wants to take her with him?
Don't worry,
not this guy.
I wasn't sure.
I didn't think think you were
going to make it.
How much did you get?
I don't know, a lot.
Okay, look, go back to Patmos,
and, um...I'll call you as soon
as I find a safe place.
Craig...
Trust me, Audrey.
This is for the best.
Bitch!
Move!
Audrey, come with me.
Not sure where
you're going, buddy.
DAVID:
I'm pretty sure the top of this
tower doesn't come out in Mexico.
Clear the bottom!
DAVID:
Come on, Craig!
We know who you really are.
You're not
the jumping type!
COLBY:
Freeze!
DON:
Don't move!Freeze!
Take it easy.
Nice and easy.
That's it.
Now get your hands
on your head.Get them up!
She told me to do it.
Everything.
"She"?Which one?
Audrey.
Audrey told me to do everything.
DAVID:
Seriously?
I bet Colby 20 he'd blame Susan.
WOMAN (on TV):
...stay out of town.
MAN (on TV):
Thanks.
I know 50 times as much about trouble
as you ever will.
Besides, you owe it to me.
You sort of belong to me,
when you're a hobo.
I found you.
Careful.Careful,
I tell you it's absolutely out
of the question.
You know every line?
Not on purpose.
Yes?
Thanks for not making me
watch Heat.
Oh, I forgot.
For you.
Chocolates?
You know what,
not a big fan.
I don't know anyone who
doesn't like chocolate.
Mm, I expected better investigative prowess
from you, Agent Eppes.
I see-- so that's it? You're not
even going to open them?
Okay.
It's watermelon?
Aha.
That's my favorite.
Ha, ha, ha.
How did you know?
No one knows.
Ball's in your court, kid.
Yes, I'll follow you
and I'll holler,
"This guy's a phony,
ladies and gentlemen.
"This is Sullivan, the big
director from Hollywood.
A phonus-balonus,
a faker, a heel..."
MAN 2:
If I man join
in the controversy, sir...
Emergency retrieval
equipment?
Check.
Drying mechanism, check.
Okay, have we
thought of everything?
Only one way
to find out.
Break.
I don't know,
it kind of looks like it did the
other day but...
Um, all righty, wish me luck.
Oh, wait, wait,
Charlie, you forgot to take your shoes off.
No, I didn't.
Okay, who's next?
破烂熊字幕组
-==Http://Www.Ragbear.Com==-
欢迎加入