[Driver] So what's the difference
between East L.A. and L.A.?
[Man] It's a whole
different country.
Hope it works out better
for you here than in Vegas.
It's got to.
It's home.
[Man] You're not gonna get anything
like this in Las Vegas.
You got that right. I been
dreamin'about these for 18 months.
- No, mi hijo. Como siempre.
- Gracias. Eighteen months.
Say hello to your mother.
And stay outta trouble!
Orale.
Hey, hey!
¡ Cuidado, mi hijo!
Jesse! I'm gonna need
a trim, homes. ¿Cuando?
- Manana a las once.
- Orale.
[Remembering] Miklo, tell those wetbacks
to step on it, or they ain't gonna get paid.
- Did you hear what I said?
- I heard you!
Get their asses movin'.
I got two more trucks on the way.
I'm already humpin'
and you ordered too much.
That's 1,500 bucks of mud. Tell them to
get it down, or they can pay for it.
Your mistake.
Tell 'em yourself.
Don't ever take the side of the Mexican
over your father! Just tell 'em!
- Fuck you!
- You ungrateful little punk!
I'm the one that
kept you out ofjail!
You love 'em so much, you can get
the same thing they're gettin' paid.
- I'll get a man to run this group.
- You son-of-a-bitch!
[Miklo Remembering]
Find yourself another slave, Dad!
- You're through!
- I'm goin'home!
You're fired! I'm telling
your probation officer!
[Laughing] I wish I could have
seen your father's face.
[Laughing]
You beat him up.
Ay, Dios mio.
Ay, Miklo, he'll kill me
if he finds you here!
Don't worry, Mama. He ain't never
gonna touch you again.
- Not after what I done.
- I know that cabron. He'll turn you in.
Miklo, come.
Help do me up.
You know, if the judge finds out
you're here, he's gonna stop my check.
I need that money.
Whoo, baby, cold hands!
Oye, mami. En seis días, just six
little days, bingo, I'm home free.
Ay, bingo. What's this bingo? What
are you gonna be doing in six days?
Mi cumpleanos.
June 28th.
My birthday, remember?
I'll be off probation.
A birthday.
Ooh, eighteen.
Que macho.
Mami, mami, mami.
But to me you're always gonna be
my little chavalito, huh?
[Car Horn Honking]
Oye, I'm late.
Beto hates to wait.
Hey, Miklo. You can stay with
your Aunt Dolores, huh?
Come on.
We'll drop you.
♪ [Spanish Music On Radio]
Shh, shh, shh.
Hola, Luisa. Shh.
¿Dolores?
¡Dolores!
¡Ay, nino! Oh,
so good to see you!
Ay, Paco.
Paco, venga aqui.
¡Ooi, ya cha-chai,
ya cha-chai!
You're so tall!
- How long are you here?
- Uh, I'm back for good.
- Your probation is over?
- No, no. Uh, he's got a birthday coming up.
Look, um,
I gotta go.
Dolores, Miklo's gonna stay
with you for a while, okay?
- Why?
- Because you have so much more room.
- [Sighs]
- I love you, nino, huh?
Lupe, you may be my sister, but I'm
tired of taking care of you. Grow up!
[Lupe] Look, I have tried to
be like you. I can't.
- Your life would drive me crazy!
- Ooh, orale.
- The Pillsbury doughboy's back in town.
- Back for good, homes.
- ¿Que tal?
- What's happening, man?
Thought you was never
coming back, eh.
Hey, you know me. I always find my way
back to East Los, homes.
You couldn't hang with your
white boy daddy or what?
Paco, Miklo's gonna be staying with us
for a while, huh? Make room for him.
Ain't no one share my bed
and TV but a woman.
- This puto's staying in the garage, eh.
- Oh, yeah?
You're not the rooster here,
huh? This is my house.
Miklo's your cousin.
Take this electric bill over to Mano and
tell him it has to be paid this afternoon.
♪ [Radio, Spanish]
Better keep the blankets
over your head, pendejo,
so your fluorescent skin don't keep me
awake all night. Come on.
Hey, check out this
fucking "3 P", ese.
Since when do we let Tres Puntos
get away with that shit, homes?
Big badass vato.
3 P ain't nothin'...
but a bunch of fuckin' paint sniffers
who sneak in here at night.
- They ain't about shit, ese.
- They are shit, ese.
Why the fuck do you come
all the way back here?
'Cause you owe me five bucks, ese,
and I came back to collect with this!
Fuck you! I'm gonna
kick your ass, milkweed!
Come on,
Jolly Green Giant!
I'm gonna kick
your ass, milkweed!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Orale, mi hijo,
this is Quetzalcoatl,
the great Aztec
poet king.
He ruled
the kingdom of Aztlan...
that was from Mexico
all the way up here to Califas.
Sexy mamacita.
Pay attention, pelao. I'm gonna
teach you all about Aztlan.
'Cause this vato's coming back some day
to reclaim the raza's kingdom.
- Huacha! Eee!
- Ah, parece, pero...
why do you put
my initials on?
Because you help me, ese.
We did it together, carnalito.
- [Rooster Crowing]
- Hijo.
[Mock Rooster Crow]
- Hey, Paco, what's up?
- Chale, ese, you can't sneak up on us,
not with Luis's
feathered watchdogs on duty.
- [Rooster Crows]
- Oye, el gallo negro looks pretty mean, ese.
I'd put some feria on him.
- ¡Orale! ¡Huacha!
- [Miklo] Cruzito!
El Miklo.
El Miklo Velka.
[Cruz] What's happening, ese?
When'd you parachute in, milkweed?
Today, from Vegas.
High roller, ¿o que?
Mira, papa.
- Miklo.
- ¡Hola, Tio Mano!
- Miklo! What are you doing here?
- Nada.
- How's your father?
- Oh, he's, he's okay.
- ¿Ytu jefita?
- My mom wants you to pay that.
No te tucha.
When you gonna pay
your share?
Chale.
I'm on the K-Mart
pay as you can plan, eh.
- [Laughing]
- [Rooster Crows]
You done anything
about the Corps?
I talked to the recruiter, Bentley.
He's waiting for you.
And take orders from
a jarhead like you?
Forget it. I ain't
with that party.
[Paco] You may be my stepfather,
but you ain't my commanding officer.
You eat and you
sleep in my house,
and as long as you do,
don't you talk to me like that!
Si.
[Mano] Venga, hijo.
I wanna stay
with Cruz.
- Have you done your homework?
- Yeah.
In the truck.
Hey, take it easy on Mano, homes.
He just wants you to work.
Hey, he's your dad, not mine.
Let him tell you what to do, eh.
I'm just telling you, ese.
You don't have to mad-dog me.
- Chale, it's a customer's ride. We can't use it.
- That's bullshit.
Where do you want
to go, Vegas vato?
- [Horn Honking]
- Hey, Cruz!
Chale, I told you,
we can't take that ride.
- [Chuckles]
- [Speaking In Spanish]
- Don't cry.
- [Rooster Crowing]
All right, but this time we gotta
go down Brooklyn and Whittier, ese.
[Speaking In Spanish]
Just like the old days, man. Remember
when you were living at Paco's mom's house?
This dude
was rotten, Holmes.
- He threw some mean bombs.
- Chale, that's bullshit, ese.
No, really. You woke up all the babies
in the barrio, ese.
Chickens couldn't
lay eggs for a month.
You're the one throwing bombs.
Elephant farts.
- Hey, do that baby on acid face that you do, man.
- Oh, that's stupid.
- Just do it, ese.
- All right.
[Making Baby Sounds]
[Car Door Closing]
That tree
is East Los to me.
It's good to be home.
[Cruz] ¿Que no? Hey,
¿sabes que, ese?
My paintings
made it to the finals.
- ¿De veras, man? You really made it?
- Simon.
In all of Califas,
I'm still in.
- Orale.
- Te aventaste.
They'll give the prize
to you. You're the best.
- Not bad for a Chicano, eh?
- [Paco] ¿Que no?
- Oye, Cruzito.
- ¿Que pasa?
- You still have your quills and inks?
- Simon. ¿Por que?
Get down, James Brown.
Put the needle in, huh?
[Miklo] I want
my V.L. Tattoo.
Hey, take a look
in the mirror, guero.
[Paco] Does it snow in L.A.?
Does a white boy get
a V.L. placazo?
No, he don't!
I'd have my placa now if the judge
hadn't thrown me outta East Los.
Chale, you wouldn't
have shit, milkweed.
It's some serious shit, homes.
It don't wash off.
First sign of trouble, you'll be running
back to your white boy daddy in Las Vegas.
Oye, vato, dejalo.
Oye, Miklo.
Just wait 'til your number's called,
ese. You'll get one.
...Folsom and Indiana,
possible vehicle violation.
Fuck, man.
I'm on probation, man.
- No te tucha.
- Pinche jura. Always fuckin' with us.
- Cool it, ese!
- [Cop] I got it.
Hello, officer.
What seems to be
the problem, sir?
Bumper clearance has gotta
be at least ten inches.
- Oh, really?
- You, in the car.
Registration,
license?
You do this to people
in Beverly Hills, eh?
Take off the glasses,
please.
You look familiar.
You got a record?
Yes, sir, he's got a record.
He's got a great record.
"The Black Rooster."
Thirteen K.O.'s.
He's got a great
right uppercut.
You, uh, used to train at
the Boys' Club, didn't you?
Two years, second division Golden
Gloves, 'til, 'til he broke his wrist.
- Oh, yeah, I remember.
- See? Orale, vato.
- This your car?
- Well, I just painted it, sir. What do you think?
It looks nice.
Listen, uh, just raise up
the bumper a few inches, okay?
Like your
uppercut, huh?
[Laughs]
Thank you, officer. We will, sir.
Ah, it's all right, Joe. Let's go.
Hey, you know who the kid was?
Pinche culero. Didn't have that fuckin' badge
between us, we'd see who hassles who, eh.
- Shut the fuck up, ese.
- Don't be using my boxing anymore, eh.
- Oh...
- Don't be stupid. He's just trying to save our asses.
I let you put my hat
off my head once,
but you better keep your fuckin' face outta
my business before I put you down, milkweed.
Ya. Ya, vato. Come on,
let's get this ranfla back.
[Hissing]
You know it.
- [Cruz] Hungry, Miklo?
- [Miklo] I got the munchies, man.
- We get back to the canton, we'll get some refino.
- [Rooster Crows]
See if Mama Dolores
made some...
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Cruz] Even a white boy
should like chocolate.
- Hey.
- Pull it up on your end.
Come here.
¿Que paso?
Check it out, homies.
- Who is it?
- Tres Puntos, ese.
Right in our own
fuckin' alley, homes!
¡Chingada!
Tres Puntos, ese.
- But those fuckers crossed the line, eh.
- Into dead man's land, ese.
Chale, just my dick in my pants.
Don't fuck around, ese!
- We gotta do something, man!
- Oh, we gotta do something?
Well, do something then, rooster.
You're listo. You're ready.
Chale... Why do you
always wanna fight raza?
Hey, shut
the fuck up, eh.
You want your placazo so bad? Do
something. Let me see the color inside you.
- Leave it alone, ese.
- Come on!
- What the fuck's wrong with you?
- That's what I thought.
- Leave it alone, carnal.
- Watch me, Jolly Green Giant!
Hey, fuckin' kamikaze!
Miklo, wait!
Hey, pinche loco man!
This ain't no pinche
card game, ese.
Hey, life's a risk,
carnal.
What the fuck is
he doin', ese?
[Cruz] He's locote, homes.
- ¡Huacha! ¡Huacha!
- Milkweed's got some balls, ese. Don't fuck him up, ese.
[Cruz] Oh, he's gonna start
some pedo, homes.
[Spray Can Hissing]
Hey, hurry up, ese!
What are you in a hurry for?
You got a date or something?
Let the homeboy get down.
Fuck these punks! I'll come in here day
or night. I'm taking over this barrio.
Get down, Demon. Throw that
puto sign on these punks.
[Gang Leader] They can't bust
a grape, can't kick no dust. Shit!
Oh, no! Shit!
- ¡Chingao!
- ¡Viva Vatos Locos!
I'm gonna fuck you up, you
bastard! Lucky motherfucker!
Get in the car, Demon!
You crazy shit, you!
- Javier!
- ¡Ahi vienen! ¡Ahi vienen!
- [Tires Screeching]
- [Cruz] Shit!
Fuck you, putos, ese!
[Paco] You oughta be ridin'
a tricycle, Spider!
Spider, puto, you paint
our wall, we'll paint your ass!
Why you wanna bust up
our ride around, punk?
[Spider] Fuck you, Candelaria!
We're taking over this barrio!
- Try it, Spider!
- [Paco] Now get outta here, punk!
[Man] Ladies and gentlemen,
it gives me great pleasure...
to announce the winners of the Los Angeles
City Schools Annual Art Competition.
And the first one is from
Lincoln High School, Cruz Candelaria.
- [Cheering]
- Come up here, Cruz.
- Cruz!
So, Cruz, here's your plaque.
Your award of honor.
And much more important
than this plaque, however,
I want to give you this,
which is your scholarship...
from the Los Angeles
College of Design.
May you have tremendous success
in the future.
Ow! Cruz!
Gracias.
I, uh...
I first started painting
when I used to draw...
little cards for my mom
when she was sick in the hospital.
Those little cards
made her happy,
and she told me then,
"Mijo, tu eres un artista."
You are an artist.
I guess she was right.
I just wish that she
was here to see it.
I want to thank especial mi...
especially mi abuelito,
my grandfather, my father, my stepmom,
Dolores, who I love very much,
y Los Vatos Locos.
Whoo!
Viva Los Vatos Locos!
[Gang Member #1]
Poke him deeper, ese. Make it last.
[Gang Member #2]
You want me to hold you down, eh?
Miralo.
Como crying!
♪ Ay, ay, ay, ay ♪♪
Hey, Cruzito, you almost done, man?
I need you to stitch my khakis.
This afternoon I got my prize, ese,
and now you get yours.
[Gang Member] ¡Orale!
- Hey, your blue eyes are turning brown, ese.
- [Laughter]
Caquita brown.
Orale, carnal.
This is it, ese.
No more going back
to Fantasyland...
and believing the cat
never catches Tweety Bird.
Chale. Not here, ese.
Now you home with us,
and defend the barrio.
- ¡Dale!
- ¡Dale, guero!
- [Gang Member] Lleguele, cabron.
- Vatos Locos forever.
- Forever!
- Forever.
- Whoo!
- Orale.
Hey, baptize him.
- Listen...
- No, no, no, no!
- [Indistinct Shouting]
- Just calm down. It don't hurt.
- Ah. ¡Ay!
- Looks good, eh.
- Yeah, homes.
- Echale. Echale.
[Screams]
Another one,
another one.
Hey, that was cool what you did,
jackin' up those jokers, eh.
Cool, eh.
Orale.
...que me empinque la vida.
- Come and watch cartoons. It's really funny.
Mira.
- [Mano] Have some respect.
- Ow! ¡Huacha!
[Cruz] Not bad for a loco
from the barrio, eh?
Can you imagine? Nobody
ever went to City Hall...
except to pay fines
or bail somebody out!
Si. Cruzito, you are
a lone stallion among mules.
You're gonna become a legend,
like Pancho Villa orJoaquin Murrieta!
To Cruz!
- Salud.
[Man] ¡Arriba, arriba, arriba!
- Ow!
- Ay.
♪ [Stereo]
♪ Who's that lady
- Beautiful lady
- Who's that lady
- Lovely lady
- Oh you're fine, lady
- Who's that lady
♪ Oh you can look, girl
but don't touch, baby
Huachalo, huachalo.
Huacha, Chuey. Huacha, Chuey.
Huachalo Chuey.
- Ow!
Go on, Chuey!
- Beautiful lady
- Who's that lady
- Oh you're fine, lady
Hey, Frankie, let me borrow
the keys to your brother's GTO.
Hey, what do you
think I am, a pendejo?
Oh, culero, see how
you are, ese?
See who paints that portrait
of your girl like you wanted me to.
Oh, pinche Indian giver.
Hey, you promised, eh!
- Chale, chale, ese.
- You're an Indian giver, ese.
Me la rayo, vato. I'll paint your
ruca firme like that, all naked y todo.
- Put some gas in it, ese.
- Hey, don't be putting stains on Frankie's backseat, homes!
[Frankie] Or the front seat
or anywhere else, vato.
- Yes I am
- Searchin', searchin'for my baby
[Paco] ¡Orale, Cruzito!
♪ Searchin, searchin'
for my love
Mira. Huacha,
huacha, huacha, Cruz.
- Orame. No!
- Ooh!
Hey. ¿Que paso, mi hija?
Thought you said you was
gonna be at this thing.
- Huh? Guess what? I got Frankie's brother's GT.
- Oh, you did?
Yeah, you know it,
mi hija.
So what's up? I thought you was
gonna be at this thing...
- and then you didn't show up.
- You didn't tell me what time.
Oh, well,
let's dance, ruca.
Baila, bebe.
[Together]
¡Orale, Cruz! No te pincha.
[Indistinct Spanish]
[People Cheering]
♪ For my dream girl
For my dream girl
♪ I'll never, never
never have no peace
- Let's get outta here.
- No, no, no, no, no
- Hey, where's Cruz going? Hey, come here, homes!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
No, wait, homes.
Where you goin'?
- Cruz's gonna open a present now, eh.
- ¿Que?
Oh, si, baboso.
Like you don't know.
- Come on.
- Orale, I'm gonna take you out with a knockout, homes.
- Horale, Juanito. Put up your dukes, eh.
- What do you think I'm doin'?
- [Paco] Guard yourself.
- Hit him with a right!
- Oooh! - Oooh! -
You gotta finish him!
But Bobby Chacon rises and dusts
Chucho Castillo.
Pa-pa-pa pow-pow.
Picks him up...
- Come on, let me go!
- Spins him around!
- [Car Radio]
- [Indistinct Talking]
[Cruz] Your skin's
so soft, mi hijita.
Tus labios,
tus ojos.
[Sighing]
Ooh.
Will you paint my picture?
Te voy a pintar, m'hija.
I'm gonna paint you
like an Aztec princess.
Tocame, suavecito.
- [Laughs, Moans]
- Hold me, hold me
- Hold me - I want
you... - [Click]
Ooh, looky, looky.
Can I have some?
- I like mine rare.
- [Laughing]
Ye-pa, ye-pa, ye-pa!
What door
do I pick?
Chingalos, putos.
This ain't your turf, ese!
Get him out!
Get him out, guero!
¡Dejalo! ¡No!
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Screaming]
[Spider] Let's give this
Vato Loco a joyride!
[Shouting Indistinct Spanish]
We gotta teach these putos a lesson!
They ain't gonna fuck with us no more!
I'm taking his V.L. placa!
It's mine forever, ese!
- [Screaming]
- [Man] What are you kids doin' up there?
[Spider] Get your old man ass back inside
now, punk, before I put you to sleep!
Let's get the fuck
outta here! Let's party!
[Spider] Tres Puntos own
this barrio now!
[Screaming]
¡Ay! My back, my back!
[Doctor] He's still under
the anesthetic. I gotta go back in.
Your son has multiple contusions. The
thoracic vertebrae in his back is broken.
- It's very serious.
- When will we know if he'll be okay?
His spleen is injured, so I gotta
go back in and stop the bleeding.
If he gets an abdominal infection,
he might be in for a prolonged stay.
I'm sorry. That's all
I gotta say right now.
- ¿Que paso?
- We got the vatos here.
Vamonos.
- Orale, vatos, that rocho...
- Get the door!
- [Indistinct Chatter]
- Tres Puntos are gonna pay big time, homes!
- Big time!
- [Paco] Shut up!
Shut up! We ain't gonna
be hitting 'em tonight, eh.
They're gonna be waiting for us tonight.
We're gonna get 'em tomorrow morning.
In the daylight?
It's Sunday, ese.
They ain't gonna be going
to Mass, pendejo.
Gimme that! You don't think I want
'em, eh? You don't think I want 'em?
I got some poison for a spider,
eh, but for tomorrow.
- [Indistinct Shouting]
- Paco! Paco!
Hey, hey,
cool it, ese!
- What are you doing?
- [Paco] We can't let those punks come into our barrio...
- Get out, all of you! Just get out of here!
- Start pushing us around.
- Who are you fighting?
- Tres Puntos!
- Chuey, who are you fighting, pendejos? Yourselves!
- What are you doing?
- Don't talk to him like that.
- Just fighting yourselves!
- Those are mi carnales. They're my family.
- I'm your family!
We should be taking care of each other,
not fighting on the street!
Hey, we do nothing
and we are nothing!
- Fuck that! Come on!
- Yeah, homes, chale!
- Paco! Paco, mi hijo!
- [Indistinct Shouting]
- No, Miklo.
- I'm sorry, Tia.
Ooh! [Chuckles]
I like the country, ese!
Hey, Kool-Aid, put that little jalapeno
back in your pants, ese.
- [Laughing]
- Hey, homey,
I was just marking
our new territory!
[Spider] That's right. We're the new
landlords. Vato Locos are finished.
Check out
the new view, homies!
I'm gonna build myself
a righteous pad here.
Swimming pool, white
picket fence and shit.
Hey, Joker, you got
a fine mamacita, homes! Mwa!
- Save me some.
- Come here, baby.
- Don't, they're watching.
- Come here. Gimme some.
- No.
- [Spider] Woo-hoo-hoo-hooey! Yeah!
- [Laughing]
- [Car Horn Honking]
[Honking]
Hey.
Check it out, Spider.
[Honking]
♪ I don't know why
you treat me so bad
♪ And of all the things
we could have had
♪ Love and emotion
I can't forget
♪ My sweet 16
now I'll never regret
- It's that punk from the alley.
- Hey, Spider!
Vato loco must be on
medication to come here.
You cut my carnal!
I'm here to jack you up, puto!
- [Car Radio]
- [Miklo Shouting, Indistinct]
[Miklo] Hey, Spider!
[Chuey] Hey, let's cut
the motherfucker!
[Girl Shouting Indistinct Spanish]
- What do you vatos wanna do, ese?
- Cale, homies.
You gotta pay your dues
to me, pinche mamon.
You wanna throw down, puto?
Come and get some?
- Chale, motherfucker!
- Hey, fuck you!
You want another placazo, badass!
Come and get it, motherfucker!
¡Chinga tu madre! I'm gonna cut
your fuckin' eye out, punk,
- and kill you!
- Fuck these other vatos, ese!
Get up, Chuckie!
Get up!
You fuck with my familia, eh, you gotta
answer to me here and now.
Come on, toe to toe.
- [Whistles]
- Let's go, motherfucker!
[Paco] Let's see what kind of man
you are in daylight!
What's the matter, Spider,
you a-scared of me?
I'm gonna catch you
on the fuckin' rebound, punk!
I'm gonna squash you like the pinche bug
you are. Come on, motherfucker!
¡Vamonos!
Fuck!
Die, motherfucker!
Where you goin'?
Get up.
- My rib's broken.
- You ain't talkin' so bad now, ese.
- Oh, my rib!
- You wanna know how it feels like?
You wanna know how it feels like
to get stuck, puto? Come on, get up.
- Get up!
- Fuckin' punk!
What are you
runnin' for, bitch?
You should not have done that
to my brother Cruzito, ese.
You know what I mean,
jellybean?
- Fuck!
- You wanna dance?
I know a tune that's called
"Stick and cut."
- [Screams]
- You like that shit, stick and cut, ese?
- Aaah!
- Puto.
Miklo, hold him down!
[Indistinct Shouting]
¡Ay!
¡Cabron! Aaah!
Property of Vatos Locos.
In case the dogcatcher
wants to know.
- [Spider] Motherfucker!
- Let him up, milkweed!
Hey, Jorge. We got him for Cruzito,
ese! He's marked for life!
- [Paco] ¡Hijo de la chingada!
- Paco, no!
Cruz is alive, ese! Besides, when a dog
goes belly up, he's finished. ¡Chale!
Yeah, look at him.
The dog is belly up!
- Whoo! ¡Viva Los Vatos Locos!
- ¡Viva Vatos Locos!
Ah-ha-ha-hi-hi!
Yeah!
¡Viva Los Vatos Locos!
Let's go, homes!
Die, pinche puto!
No!
[Miklo] He's dead!
- Come on, let's go, homes!
- No!
[Frankie] Shit! Where's he hit,
man? Where's he hit?
Chuey, get his
shirt off, homes!
[Frankie] Take it easy, Miklo!
There's blood everywhere!
He's hurt bad.
[Frankie] What the fuck are you
doing, pendejo? Watch the corner!
You're gonna kill us!
You're gonna kill us, Paco!
Shut up, Frankie! I gotta
get him to the hospital, homes!
No, I don't wanna go to no
hospital! People die there!
Man, you're shot! What are you worried
about, ese? I'm taking you to County!
No! Let me out!
- I ain't going to no hospital!
- Get your ass back in here!
Watch the van!
[Siren Blaring]
- Let's get outta here, Paco!
- [Chuey] Step on it, Paco!
Oh, shit!
[Frankie] Watch it, Paco!
Oh, hang on!
¡Hijole! He's
still there, vato!
Ya, ya, ese.
You cry, we die! Shut up, homes!
[Chuey] Come on, homes!
Step on it, man!
He's gaining on us!
¡No van a chingar!
They ain't gonna do shit,
vato! ¡Huacha!
[Screaming]
[Siren Blaring]
Huacha, homes, huacha!
¡Hijo de puta!
Chicano U-turn, homey!
- Puro ricochet!
- There's no fucking jura in this town, ese,
- can do a Chicano U-turn!
- De veras.
Right on, carnal!
Hey, you just
hang on tight, Miklo.
You're gonna be as free
as a bird, vato.
[Shouting, Crowing]
- [Siren Blaring]
- They're down on Floral!
- This is your papi's shotgun, homes!
- Throw it out the pinche window!
Relax, homes! Es mi barrio. Those are the
pinche tourists! They ain't gonna get nobody!
[Speaking In Spanish]
...right down here
on Indiana Street, homes.
Me la pelan, tourists!
[Laughing]
- Look out!
- [Screaming]
[Indistinct Shouting]
Go!
Come on, Miklo!
We gotta go, homes!
- Come on, eh!
- Paco, come on!
- Run, carnal, run!
- Vatos Locos forever, carnal. Let's go!
Come on!
Shit!
Freeze!
Show me
your hands!
- My cousin is shot, homes.
- Put 'em up!
- Get against the car! Get against the car!
- You gotta help my cousin, homes.
- He's hurt.
- Get 'em up!
My cousin's
been shot, homes.
Get up against
the car! Go, move!
- Cuff him!
- Hey! Hey, help out my cousin.
- He's been sh...
- Shut up and get against the car!
Pac... Ah! Paco!
Paco!
[Groaning]
Another fish tank
in from L.A.
Two down
and one to go.
Feel the pain, man. Come on,
keep it going. Keep it going. Come on.
Some fresh meat
just come in, carnal.
[Inmate] Come on, Ryder,
one more time, man.
Come on, man.
Come on, Ryder.
[Ryder] What the fuck
we got here?
Fuckin' fresh fish, man.
Can you believe that shit?
58-271.
- [Guard] Okay, come on. Pick it
up. Let's go! - Velka, B69-345.
Pick it up. What you strollin' for?
Move it along. Let's go!
Hey, baby, long time since I had a West Texas
ballroom bitch. How 'bout you bein'my lady?
Say, you, black baby. This bull
been corralled up for a long time.
I got what you need.
Put that punk in a cell with me.
Orale, blue eyes. Mamacita, look
over here. I got something for you.
You don't listen to anybody but me.
Do you understand that?
I'm The Man. I'm the boss.
Do you understand?
Now, walk!
Go to the door.
White sign over the door.
Your chains will come off. You'll drop
your drawers and you'll be home.
Welcome to San Quentin.
...515, you got visitors.
- Name?
Carney.
- What's your number?
- Um, I don't remember, sir.
[Guard] Learn it.
Sweeney, B56-212.
Robinson, B28-398.
[Indistinct Shout]
[Guard] Move it out.
Let's go.
What the fuck
you lookin' at?
[Inmate] Hey, smells like fish!
Come on.
Get it in.
I'm the interior officer. You got
any problems, you gotta see me.
[Dolores Speaking Indistinctly]
- Do what you wanna do.
- [Dolores] Look who's there.
Hey, Cruz, look what
Grandpa got you.
- Juanito, doesn't he look good?
- Yeah, homes.
How you doing?
El palo del abuelito. Mira.
Hey, homes, that operation you got?
It makes you look good as new, homes.
Wait 'til you see
your surprise.
- Simon. - Surprise? -
Just around the corner.
[Whistles]
Huacha, eh?
[Dolores] Can you believe this?
[Mano] The Corps is making
a man of him.
- Hey, carnal.
- Qu'iubo, champ.
I'll walk from here.
[Dolores]
Oh, no, no. Cruz, no.
- Mi hijo, do you think you should?
- Oh, yeah, I'm...
- Ama. ¿Me hacen un favor?
- Si.
- Let me and Paco walk by ourselves to the car.
- Si, si. That's fine.
- Can I go with you guys?
- We'll go.
- Can I go with you?
- I'll see you in a minute, mocoso. Go with mama.
[Mano] We'll get the car.
Vengan, niños. Dolores.
- Bye, mi hijo.
- [Juanito] Hey, Cruzito, see you at the car, huh?
- [Dolores] Andale, andale, Juanito.
- Later, homey.
[Alicia] He doesn't
look so good.
Look at me.
Look it.
You all right, man?
¡Ay! Pinche
pierna, homes.
Let me get 'em.
More, more.
- There we go.
- Those help you?
They don't do shit.
Morphine's the ticket, though.
Can't run,
can't sleep.
Can't play
the accordion.
- Hope I can still paint, carnal.
- You will, carnal, you will.
Mira, vato.
A fuckin' Marine, ese.
- Chingao.
- It was either this or jail, right?
But after boot camp, I ain't so sure
it was such a good deal.
A lot better
than Miklo, homes.
Pobre milkweed.
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Laughing]
Wanna buy
some cigarettes?
What's happenin'?
How are you?
- Hey, baby.
- Hola, pretty.
Are you blond
all over?
Get your hands
off of me, faggot!
Ooh, how his blue eyes just
light right up when he get mad.
Leave me alone, man!
I'll kill you, bitch!
Oh! You will?
[Laughs]
Where the fuck you get that
placa, Little Bo Peep?
Hey, Cinderella,
go find yourself a fella.
You're on the clock, bitch,
and midnight is comin'.
You got the wrong man.
¿Como te llamas?
- Miklo Velka.
- [Speaking In Spanish]
¡Orale, vato!
There's some vatos
you should meet.
Most of these cons don't clique.
They just fill in space, doin' time.
It's the gangs
that run this place.
See a black dude
with a comb over there?
[Popeye] That's Bonafide.
He runs the B.G.A.,
the Black Guerilla Army.
Don't take nothin' from him, or you'll end
up with a Black Power comb through your heart.
- What's your problem, man?
- Hey, I got no problem, brother.
[Speaking In Spanish]
That's a fuckin'
fine comb you got.
- You should give it to one of my bitches.
- Watch your mouth, sucker.
- Put your spear down.
- Don't you know this comb has power?
- Black power.
- [Together] Yeah.
- [Prisoner] Right on.
- Power to give a fool like you nightmares,
- but see, you wouldn't understand that.
- Ain't nothing to me, ese.
Yeah, I know it.
Those polar bears over in the corner,
that's Aryan Vanguard,
the AV-ers.
Those white boys control the dope trade,
do free-lance killings, anything...
- for the right price.
- I'm about finished waitin' for my money, punk.
Hey, why not take it out in trade? You
always liked Tinkerbell. She's fine.
You bet cash, you lose cash,
you pay cash, pimpmobile.
Soon, or I'll have to hire
Red Ryder here and his A. V. Boys...
to cut some fat off
that tongue of yours!
Or maybe you'd like to swap for
some of that tender white meat.
You can pay
your bets with that.
Suave, Al.
I'll pay you what I owe, but don't try
scaring me with your A.V. Insurance policy...
'cause remember, I got
a policy with Ryder too.
He knows better than to mess
with a good customer.
Since business
is so good,
I suppose I'm gonna have to raise
the rents on both you lame-ass fucks!
[AV-ers Laugh]
What's the matter?
You never heard of rent control?
- Easy on the threats, Ryder.
- [Whistles]
You got the vatos back there.
You don't want to do anything in public.
- [Whistles]
- [Man Shouting In Spanish]
We're talking
business here.
[Chuckling]
Fuck him.
Just tuvo, Beto.
It's over.
¿Ese pues que
chinga trae?
Why the fuck you let these putos
disrespect you like that for?
- Take it easy, carnal.
- You're wrecking it for the rest of the homeboys.
I'm just showing
this homeboy around, okay?
It's Miklo,
from el barrio.
You're the sucker
that dusted Spider?
Well, if a rep is what
you're lookin' for, killer...
then I'm the man you want.
Mira. Tres Puntos,
like Spider.
- [Snarls] Ooh! I'm the bogeyman!
- He pissed in his pants.
[Laughter]
- [Inmate] ¡Pinche Vato Loco!
- Come on, carnal.
Get the fuck outta here
before I make you my bitch.
- He's Tres Puntos, ese.
- Hey!
That's
street bullshit, ese.
It's different
in the joint.
We clique together.
Power, to protect ourselves.
So Tres Puntos or anybody strong enough
to stand with La Onda is okay.
- What's La Onda?
- Some questions you don't ask.
Escort!
Move it over!
- [Speaks In Spanish]
- Dead man walking.
Back up!
Back it up.
Escort!
Back it up!
Death row's over there.
For all of California.
[Guard] Escort!
- Got some smokes for you.
- I don't smoke cigarettes.
Got a little
something else.
- Some juju weed.
- I smoke that now, vato.
You don't mind if I keep you
under my wing for a little while?
- I mean, I gotta take care of you, huh?
- Okay, vato.
- Hey, we homeboys, right?
- Fuckin' A. East Los rules, vato.
- Gracias, carnal, okay?
- Orale. Simon.
All right, you white bitch.
Gimme some chon-chon!
- Get away from me.
- You get nothing for free in here, punk.
- ¡Chinga tu madre!
- Ah?
- Okay.
That's right, give it up.
Oh, shit! Yii!
¡Pinche puta!
You want me to take it? Huh?
You want me to rape you, eh, puto?
- Aaah!
- Let's see the color of your blood, gabacho.
I'm gonna cut that fucking placa
off of you. You ain't no Vato Loco!
[Shouting In Spanish]
Keep your business
off this tier.
- Simon.
- Ese, Pepe don't belong in La Onda.
It's low class.
We're better than that.
Chale. My business has
nothing to do with La Onda.
- ¡Madera! You're part of the clica.
- I was Onda before you were.
[Montana] Keep your whores
in the rec room.
Keep that fuckin' thing
in there!
Orale, carnales.
Popeye's getting
on my nerves.
[Al] Come on,
you debutantes!
Got a once-a-year
special on pork chops!
Sweet thing! This shit
will make a man impotent,
but you ain't goin'
to no prom soon.
[Cackling]
Eat up, folks, eat up.
Shit, man, ain't nothin' but fat
on that bone. Gimme another chop.
Hate like hell to disappoint
your gods, bro,
- but unless you got a carton of smokes, no seconds.
- Motherfucker!
Our Lord is blushing!
- I ain't no Moslem, man.
- All right.
- How about a little wager on this weekend's game?
- Your odds stink...
and I ain't movin'
'til I get another chop.
Move on, nigger, before I
carpet my cell with your black skin.
- Hey, mother...
- All right, what's the holdup?
Johnson, move it.
Punk-ass motherfucker!
All right, all the rest of you hungry
bunnies, get 'em while we got 'em.
There's your chop.
You happy now?
All right, now for
my brown brothers.
Sorry, no tortilla.
Wait a minute.
There's a ray of sunshine in
all that darkness down there.
Come up here,
sweetness.
[Inmate] Come on, muevete.
You're keepin' all these
hungry beaners waitin', baby.
- Move on down!
- What are you doin'? What's the holdup?
It's okay, Sarge. He was outta line.
He was in here before.
Gimme your tray, homes.
You're catchin' a ride
on the wrong train.
You oughta be at the front of the line,
ahead of those jungle bunnies.
I don't take no free tickets
on no one's train!
Now you take a ticket,
or you get run over.
It's better to ride up front, first
class, and eat with the white folks.
Know what I mean?
- Flirt on your own time, Albert.
- Ooh-hoo-hoo, she's jealous!
- Hey, where's my chop?
- That was the last one.
- I want my fuckin' chop, puerco.
- Please be courteous to the help. We've run out.
We only get pork once a year.
I know you got more back there.
Only for the kitchen detail.
Perhaps one of them might sell you one.
- I ain't buyin' what's mine!
- You know the fuckin' trip. No freebies.
- Your mama was a freebie!
- ¡Calmala!
Hey, tough guy.
You want a write-up?
Maybe you wanna go
to lockup, huh?
Calmala, carnal.
Move it! Come on, we got
ten minutes here. Let's eat.
You sold our meat, Al. You been
gettin' by with that shit too long.
We ran out. It happens. Now move on,
flycatcher. Got hungry men behind ya.
I'm gonna fold your bluffing hand
some day, you chicken-shit motherfucker.
In your dreams, Pedro.
In your dreams.
- A la chingadita.
- Chale. Calmala.
Where the fuck do you think
you're trespassing into?
Orale, calmala.
Calmala.
- Clavate.
- What do you want?
- I thought you wanted it.
- What?
My chop.
I don't want his pork chop.
I want his life.
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Distant Screaming]
- ¿Que quieres, vato?
- [Speaking Spanish]
Oye, why don't you go play
with the polar bears...
or the mayates?
- What's Toluca?
- That's the Aztec ball court.
Where you lose...
you die.
- [Indistinct Shout]
- I'm gonna drop you, white boy!
Go ahead, drop me. I ain't
afraid to die. Come on!
Come on!
Hey, boy. That shit wouldn't happen
if you're up here with Daddy.
Fuckin'...
Vamonos.
Andale, andale.
You speak Spanish, guero.
So do parrots.
I'm in here for
backing up a carnal.
I killed a Tres Puntos 'cause he was
gonna take out my partner. Soy chicano.
Chicanos killing Chicanos
is what they want.
Blacks and Chicanos killing
each other is what they want.
That's how they
run this place.
Once we get together,
they don't run shit.
You got a lot to learn
about being Chicano, guero.
I'm no lightweight, and the color
of my skin shouldn't keep me out.
White is the enemy.
White's the system.
You're stuck
in the middle.
All my fuckin' life
I've been kept out.
You know what that
feels like?
Knowing you're a Chicano and no one
accepts you 'cause your skin came out white?
My mom's as brown
as you are,
and my white dad tried to beat
every ounce of her outta me.
But you know what?
He couldn't do it.
Chicano's not a color. It's the way
you think and the way you live.
And if you're willing to give
your life up for a carnal.
I'm here to do that.
Use me. Use this.
¿Como?
You said it. Everything's
based on color, right?
I can get places you can't
'cause my skin's white on the outside.
But I'm brown on the inside.
To the bones.
The only way into La Onda is
to take down one of our enemies.
In your case, it would
have to be somebody big.
Someone we can't hit without
losing a lot of carnales.
- Chale.
- Gimme a chance!
Trust me.
Just one chance!
Estoy listo.
Respect is everything, guero.
You ready to die for it?
Vamos a ver.
Blood in, blood out.
- Entiendes?
- Todo.
[Al] We start cookin'
breakfast at 4:30 a.m.
Start dinner at 2:00. I'm startin' you
on pots and pans, with the niggers.
Thanks for nothin'.
I'll take whatever I can get, Al.
- Whatever you say.
- That's right, baby-cake.
I knew you'd
wise up, sunshine.
That greaser pimp can't do
half what I can do for you.
- Sounds nice.
- Hey, Gil. Tell Red Ryder I got that protein powder he wanted.
See that? You learn to treat me
right and you get it all.
Food, coffee,
sex, drugs.
Hell, the works.
Come on over here.
Hey, clear outta here.
It's off-limits to everybody
but me and the staff.
Go on in.
Hey... you like that?
Oh, that's nice.
Yeah, so's this.
So this is where you
keep all the goodies, huh?
Some of'em.
- Pinto beans?
- No pintos for you, baby.
Nothin' but
Texas barbecue.
How 'bout it,
sweet teeth?
Just remember, Al.
I fuck who I want,
when I want.
All right. It's all right.
Take it easy. It's all right.
You treat me right, everything's
gonna be all crimson and clover.
Popeye tried to take it.
Almost cut his dick off!
Well, I can wait, baby.
That spic's a pig.
Got no class.
Just don't make Daddy
wait too long.
Come on, now.
Come on.
- You wild little bitch.
- This is just a sample.
- I'm gonna fuck your brains out!
- When I'm ready, Al.
When I'm ready.
♪ [Jazz]
[Dolores] ¡Ay, mi hijo!
The prices, they're so high.
[Cruz] The prices don't mean nothing
unless they sell that much.
Cruz, I've been looking
everywhere for you.
- I'm saying good-bye to my family.
- We were just leaving.
Hey, Cruz, can you buy me
a low-rider when you get rich?
- ¿Que low-rider? ¡Andale! Usted tambien,
senorita. - I wanna stay with Cruz.
- Bye, Alicia.
- Come with me, Cruz.
[Woman] People want to meet you. You've
got to circulate. You're the artist.
- Janis!
- Oh, God.
- Janis, what a find.
- Cruz, say hello to Lois and Jared Levinson.
Cruz Candelaria.
Mucho gusto.
[Chuckles]
You, uh, make them look so noble.
So, uh... fuerte.
I paint what I see.
So you really like it, huh?
- [Woman] Oh, yes.
- I'm sorry, but I've gotta take him to a press photo.
- We'll bring him back in a few minutes.
- All right.
Janis, what are
you doing?
- They were gonna buy something.
- Oh, they're looky-loos.
- Window-shoppers.
- How do you know that, Janis?
I thought we agreed to keep
tonight strictly business.
Yeah. So?
They went in.
How come they went in?
We both have
a lot at stake, Cruz.
Don't let them
blow it.
¿Comprende?
Gentlemen, your names
are not on the list,
and if you don't have an invitation,
you can't come in here.
Look, we don't need our names
on the list, ruca.
You see that face
up there? That's me.
[Woman] Whether that's you
or not, it doesn't matter.
Miss Weinstock needs to say
that it's okay for you to come in.
Orale. Have yourselves a good time. Enjoy
yourselves. There, there's my invitation.
- [Chuey] Okay? Gracias.
- [Whistling]
Hey, hey, hey. It's okay, Belinda.
It's all right.
- [Together] It's okay, Belinda.
- ¿Que paso, locos?
Hey, Cruzito.
Congratulations.
Orale, Gilbert.
In a minute, homes.
[Gilbert] Come check out
the carrucha, carnal.
- Orale.
- Orale, Cruzito.
"Cruz Candelaria," vato.
This is big time, homes.
Oye, it's too bright
in here, ese. Too much white.
Hey, Cruzito, homes.
What happened to
our invitation?
What, are you
ashamed of Frankie?
- Are you ashamed of me?
- Si, babosos. I'm glad you came.
But why'd you have to
bring Gilbert, that culero.
You know Gilbert can smell money
from across town, homes.
- No shit.
- He came to help you spend that plata.
Oh, shit, I can't
pay him now, ese.
No mas tengo diez bolas.
I've only got ten bucks to my name.
- What, with those prices?
- Hey, shit, I ain't sold nothing, ese.
Well, maybe if we jack up
a few of these maricones, vato.
I got the guy
in the bell-bottoms.
- And I'll take everyone without a bra, vato.
- Be cool, ese.
- I'm trying to hold it together.
- Gilbert wants his full payback...
- before he's gonna give me some new credit.
- Shh. Quiet.
- No, you fu...
- Shh. Calmate, vato. Relax.
Here, have some pisto.
I'll see what I can do,
all right?
- He says he'll take this price.
- Tell him I'm not negotiating.
- [Janis] The price is so low now, it's a steal.
- He'll probably pass.
That'll be his loss.
Listen, Janis, I need a cash advance.
Can you help me?
I've already given you
three advances.
I need some money, Janis. What good is it
to have a show if I don't sell anything?
Cruz, most of your paintings are already
spoken for by important collectors.
- What?
- You'll be completely sold out by the end of the night.
Sold out? All of it?
Then why can't I get
some money tonight?
It doesn't work that way. The checks
go to the accountant to be processed.
No, I need some money now!
Do you understand me? Tonight.
Come on. I sold out,
so I deserve some, right?
You've got a brilliant career
ahead of you, Cruz.
But all that talent can
go right in the garbage.
Think about that when you're getting
high with your friends tonight.
Please, no Baptist sermons, okay,
Janis? Strictly business, remember?
Thank you.
[Tires Screeching]
[Chattering In Spanish]
You know, he really
is a genius, though.
- And the amazing thing... he's never even been...
- [Laughing]
- Hey, Belinda, Belinda.
Here's my ticket.
[Laughing]
Belinda, you're too uptight.
Come on, this is my show.
Hey, hey.
[Speaking In Spanish]
I want to
present you my friends.
- This is Lois and Jerry.
- Jared.
- You had a good time tonight, huh?
- [Laughing]
Hey, Cruzito!
Cruzito!
Cruz!
Hey, homes, homes.
Hey, you made me look
like a cholo, ese.
- [Speaking In Spanish]
- [Laughing]
[Continues Speaking In Spanish]
- Daniel.
- Mm-hmm.
Get them on their feet
and out the door.
Artists, folks.
Just artists being artists.
Drink up, enjoy yourselves.
We got art on the walls, on the floor.
This is a happening. We are going to
read about this tomorrow in the paper.
Let's celebrate
artistic freedom.
You had all this planned, didn't you?
It's part of the exhibit.
[Ryder] I got a hot tip, Al.
How's my credit?
[Al] Ryder, your credit's
as tight and firm as...
Oh, come on.
Don't be that-a-way.
Nothin' like poppin'
a cherry, huh, Al?
Red Ryder, your mouth,
your mouth.
- [Laughs]
- Lakers won in overtime, Al.
Oh! Give him a green one.
No, the other green one.
Why do you keep bettin' on them
L.A. Teams, Lightning?
You just keep payin' up, Al, and
everything's gonna be just fine.
She looks a little
bowlegged to me, Al.
You're gonna always
be runner-up, punk.
I'm still gonna cut that
V.L. placa off of you, sissy.
Hey, Pancho, don't be a sore loser.
Get the fuck outta here.
I don't want that greaser pimp
even talkin' to you. Understand me?
[Montana]
Tomorrow is your day, guero.
Tonight, you must read
the black book.
These are
the killing points.
The arrows show
where a man can be killed.
Hit a man here or here,
and he dies slowly
and painfully.
Hit a man here... or here,
and he dies instantly.
[Magic] When you get
to the kitchen in the morning,
look in
the largest stock pot.
Geronimo will be watching.
If you're successful tomorrow,
you'll become one of us.
If you fail, you die.
Hey, no,
I got that, Howie.
- Let a real man do the job.
- It's all yours.
All right, you slaves! I want them
things clean in one hour. Now move it!
You, get to work.
[Inmate] Now you heard the man.
Let's do it.
[Screaming, Indistinct Shouting]
That stuff's burnin'
my back! Oh!
- [Inmate] It hurts!
- [Guard] I know it hurts. I can't do nothin'!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Hey! What the fuck
are you doing in here?
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
I didn't know.
- What are you doing in here?
- I didn't do anything!
- This room is off-limits.
- You shouldn't be in here, baby-cakes.
- What do you want?
- I'm sorry, I just wanted some more steel wool.
You are fuckin' up, Al,
lettin' this kid in here.
- It's okay, Bob, he's cool.
- Bullshit! Nobody else is supposed to know...
- I won't say anything. - Shut
up! - It's all right, Sergeant.
- He does what I say.
- I am not risking everything for some piece of ass!
Just a goddamn minute. You get paid
plenty for your risk, right? Am I right?
Shh!
- Yeah, right.
- Well, all right, then. Now get movin'.
We got plenty of trips
for you to make.
[Al] Remember, I got a receipt for
every dollar you got in that money belt.
Hey, what the fuck
you lookin' at?
Get your ass right there
and stand there and don't move!
Bob, cover that money up! How long will it
take you to get back here from the parking lot?
- Fifteen minutes.
- All right, I expect you back here in ten.
- Keep this damn door closed.
- [Al] Don't give me orders!
Just make sure nobody
sees you leaving here.
Goddamn you,
you little bastard!
Don't you ever do that again or I'll
kill you! Now get the fuck outta here!
You little prick tease! I'm tired of you
swingin'your precious little ass around...
like you own
the joint!
- You haven't put out worth shit!
- I'm sorry, Al.
I fucked up.
I know.
Forgive me.
I thought you were alone.
- Get out!
- Please don't hold it against me.
- Shut up!
- Please?
Let me
make it up to you.
I know I've held back, but I'm not
gonna do it anymore.
We don't have a lotta time!
Come on.
Let's get to it.
Hurry up!
I'm gonna lick you clean.
- Do it, bitch.
- Lay back and enjoy it.
[Indistinct Shout]
- I'm all right, I'm tellin' you. It was an accident.
- Shit!
- Hey, I'm tellin' you...
- Let's cut the shit.
You're affiliated with
La Onda, aren't you?
Lieutenant, I don't know
what you're talking about.
You tryin' to insult my intelligence?
You're Onda, he's B.G.A.
Look, I know you're the gang coordinator,
but you side on the wolf ticket.
- Shit!
- [Lieutenant] Don't bullshit me.
[Geronimo] I wanna get outta here.
I can make something of my life.
Hell, I told you
to keep the door...
Fuckin' little shit!
[Lieutenant] Okay, gentlemen,
it was just an accident.
Get back to work.
You got breakfast to make.
[Whistle Blowing]
Man down! Let's go! Storage room!
Man down! Let's go!
[Whistle]
[Lieutenant] Goddamn it!
You all wanna fuck with me?
Sergeant, I want you
to shake this place down!
I want the I.D. And background
on every man in here.
[Bob] All right, I wanna
know who did it.
Somebody in here gets 25 years
or you're all dead. Take your pick.
You shut up!
I wanna know who did it!
Everybody in here
goes into lock-down!
No exercise, no rec room,
no sunshine!
Get outta there! No nothin'
until I get some answers!
And until I do, you're not
gonna see the light of day!
[Lieutenant] Sergeant Devereaux!
Sergeant Devereaux, I want you
to strip-search these men.
Everyone here
is gonna do time in the hole.
- Hey, big fella!
- You'll get it.
- Sarge, where's the food?
- You'll get it. It's on its way.
Come on with
the damn food, man!
If I don't get that damn book and money back,
you're not gonna walk off this cell block alive!
- You understand what I'm saying?
- Your name's in that book, Bob.
If I don't stay real healthy, the warden's
gonna find it in the suggestion box.
- Hey, Bob.
- What?
Can I get
an extra dessert tomorrow?
[Inmate] Just push this cart
over here! Let's move, man!
I'm gettin'hungry
up here!
Shut the fuck up!
- [Boy] Whose are they?
- They're a friend of my brother's, homes.
But he won't say shit.
He's asleep anyway.
- You're gonna get in trouble if he wakes up.
- Nah, fuck that.
All right, eh!
See you later, homes.
- He's gonna get pissed at you.
- Nah, I'll kick his ass.
♪ [Stereo]
[Door Opening]
- Hey, Cruz! I thought Chuey...
- Hey, man. This ain't no playground.
- Damn!
- Oye, pendejo, you don't know how to knock?
I'm sorry, eh. But it's cool.
I know what's up.
Chale, it ain't cool,
and you don't know what's up.
But ¿sabes que, homes? You better learn,
or else you can't come here no more.
- You understand?
- I'm sorry.
Your place is great,
and I wanna come back.
Okay, carnalito, but be cool. You can't
just barge in anywhere you want.
- All right.
- Go upstairs and watch TV until Mom comes.
Simon. [Whispering]
I took his shoes and threw them.
[Chuckles]
Pendejo. Go on.
Go upstairs and practice so you can
be a badass like Bobby Chacon.
- Simon, eh.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Tell Mom that my back was hurting,
so I had to take a nap, all right?
- Yeah.
- Ya, lepe.
Oye, baboso.
What the fuck's wrong with you?
You can't fuckin'be sonando yourself
when my carnalito's around.
- It's cool, homes.
- It ain't cool, homes.
Come on, Cruzito.
[Sniffles]
Come on, eh.
Come on down.
This will cure
your back pain, homes.
[Cruz] Oh! Painting those
22 masks is a drag, homes.
I'm tired of this
assembly-line shit!
It's money in
the bank, Cruzito.
♪ [Stereo]
♪ It's all right
She said it's all right
- Take anything you want...
- Take the pain away.
Hey, paint some
rucas naked.
- Oh, man!
- Ese, I don't wanna spend the rest of my life...
decorating rich people's
fucking living rooms.
[Sighs] I wanna do
something different, ese.
¿Tu sabes?
You know, the way that
I see it, Cruzito...
You know, homes, you take the money
and you run, vato.
- ¿Que no?
- Yeah.
I'll peddle
for you, eh.
- Fuck 'em, man. I'll paint what I feel.
- Hmm.
♪ Fly on, little wing
[Montana] This is your
bautismo, guero.
We created La Onda,
the seven of us.
This is the inner circle.
Every one is a capitan
and commands his own soldiers.
We all have an equal vote,
but I am the elected spokesman.
This is the last time
you will ever sit in the circle.
You've proven yourself, so we're
admitting you into Onda.
It's a commitment
for life.
As a soldier, you will answer to this council
and carry out our orders without question.
Failure to do so
is death.
[Speaking In Spanish]
Blood in...
blood out.
Hijo,
te traje la...
¡Ay, no!
¡Ay, Dios mio, no!
¡Ay, mi hijo!
Please, somebody!
Juanito? No!
God!
Help!
Somebody, please, help!
¡Juanito!
¡Por favor, Juanito!
- ¡Ay, mi hijo!
- Mom, ¿que paso?
Don't touch him!
Don't touch him! Leave him alone!
¡Oh, mi hijo!
Oh! Stop it! You...
You did this, you bastard!
- We gotta get outta here, Cruzito!
- Juanito!
- There's nothing
left! - Cruz! - ¡Chale!
Please bring
my baby back. Please.
There's nothing we can do! If we don't
get outta here, we're fucked!
Okay?
Come on, please.
- Juanito!
- Come on!
¡Ama!
Please get up. You can do it.
Get up, Juanito. Get up!
Oh, God, no!
[Priest] The Lord is my shepherd,
There is nothing I shall want.
Fresh and green are the pastures
where He gives me repose,:
Near restful waters He leads me
to revive my drooping spirit.
Surely goodness and kindness shall
follow me all the days of my life,
and in the Lord's own house
shall I dwell.
Let us begin. In the name of the Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
Apa.
- [Priest] This is a reading from the first letter ofJohn.
- Forgive me.
Perdoname, apa.
Not now!
Not ever!
You are dead to me,
likeJuanito.
Let us pray.
LordJesus Christ, by Your own
three days in the tomb,
You allowed the graves of all
who believe in You to be made holy,
so You made the grave a sign
of hope that promises resurrection,
even as it claims
our mortal bodies.
Grant that our brother, Juanito,
may sleep here in peace...
until You awaken him
to glory.
Then he will see You
face to face,
and in Your light,
we shall see life...
and know
the splendor of God,
for You live
forever and ever. Amen.
It's okay, jefito.
[Paco] You can cry if you want.
[Mano Cries]
The Aryan Vanguard's
been insulted.
You spics knew Big Al had
an insurance policy with the A.V.
So when your little lamb strays from
the flock... I'm gonna kill the boy!
I heard that.
[Montana] Al deserved to die.
Besides, your AV-ers owed him
more money than anybody else.
So you made out fine.
He still dies.
The council has authorized me
to make a substantial cash offer...
to assure nothing happens
to Miklo.
I'm listenin'.
Half of Al's cash.
$8,000.
[Montana] We're now open
for business.
We'll give you personally 25% of every
bet we collect from one of your members.
You don't give me squat!
You don't even do business
unless I say you can.
You understand?
So?
So, what are you givin'
on the Lakers-76ers?
Give the puto four
on 76.
The 76ers... and four points.
Gimme the Lakers
for a hundred.
I'll take some of
that action myself.
[Montana] Miklo, if Onda's going
into business, carnal,
people have to know
they can trust us.
So treat everybody
the same.
The AV-ers control the dope and the
BGA-ers are trying to move in on them.
Let 'em fight it out
while we build our bank account.
We'll do business
with both of them.
Money knows no color, carnal.
Everybody likes to gamble.
[Miklo] All right, all you little old
ladies! It's the milkman!
Come on. It's time to collect
all that milk money!
[Miklo] It's all I can do.
I'll give you a half a point.
- That's the point spread. Gotta be cool, bro.
- Be cool.
Jefe, here's some produce, freshly
picked right outta the fields.
¡Ay! Christmastime! Pancho Villa,
Virgen de Guadalupe, gracias.
Huacha, from now on I want 40% of
everything we make set aside for legal fees.
We gotta start helping
our gente get outta here.
Use 20% for Christmas presents
for the carnales.
You should be ashamed!
Quit looking at boobs.
Look at a boob tube, compliments
from El Mero Mero.
My B.G.A. Brothers! Pockets!
Gotta get rid of that natural look.
Go back
to processing.
- Look like me, vato, huh?
- Hey, how 'about those Raiders, chump?
Heh-heh!
B.G.A. Is always right.
[Miklo] Got a special sale for tomorrow
night's fight. It's gonna be two-for-one, bro.
Two for me
and one for you!
Hey, man, don't talk to me about credit.
I got debts as thick as a phone book.
[Montana] Now that Mosca and Flaco
are getting transferred to Chino,
we'll have a base close
to the courts in Los Angeles.
Give 'em some money so they can set up
a legal fund, recruit some soldiers.
[Miklo] You got it, Jefe.
Hey, milkweed.
My plan to join our business
and share profits, I like it, ese.
- I don't.
- Where you goin', ese?
Hey, hey, hey, homes.
Hey, I'm sorry.
Hey, hey, mira. Look, uh, it's about
that little debt, you know?
- Not so little.
- Hey, I'm booking next week, homes.
I got my parole, you know?
I need my cash for the streets.
- It's hard to get set up out there, you know?
- Gotta pay part of it.
I can do better than that.
Put you on the council.
You could be one of the seven.
Motada's been wenting you in.
He needs my vote.
Erase my debt, and you're in.
Okay, Popeye.
There'll be a blank space
next to your name in my book.
I'll keep it up here
in my memory.
Orale, carnales. You'll be tied in good when
you get out. Whatever you want, just ask.
[Popeye] Come on. This is
my parole picture.
Hey, you only get
paroled once.
Magic, something
to remember you by.
All right, okay.
Here we are now.
All right, vato,
take a picture.
Oh, come on.
Hey, I got people waiting.
- Ready?
- Andale.
Uno, dos, tres.
[Man] You know, I grew up
about ten blocks from here,
but this place
blows my mind, Carmen.
Looks like
Hawaii, man.
My father planted this
40 years ago.
Created the whole
Yucatan right here.
Carmen's the best chef
in all of East Los.
- That right?
- Uh-huh.
Suck on this
licorice stick.
It's been dipped 20 times
to make you hump all night long, Paco.
With you two around, I ain't gonna need
no marriage counselor. ¿Que no?
[Young Woman]
I like your style, Paquito.
I'll check it out. I know this shit is
good, 'cause like the last batch you made,
was dynamite, man.
But the only trip is, I'm wondering if you
could supply the quantity that I'll need.
- See, um...
- First the money...
then the honey.
All right, look.
You see my homey out there?
You got nine more grand.
Now show me yours.
Get him a caja.
- Okay.
- Make sure not to shake the baby food.
PCP is very explosive.
Boom!
I'd hate to lose
such a handsome customer.
Ooh, mami.
That feels good.
I might need it
for later.
- So did you really make this stuff? You a chemist?
- [Carmen Laughs]
I worked in
a medical lab. Simon.
Hey, baby... have you
ever had a threesome?
Hey, baby, let's take care
of the deal first, okay?
What's the matter?
Too much for you?
No, I just like business
before pleasure.
- He's a fucking cop!
- Rollie, get in here now!
Get him!
You son-of-a-bitch!
No!
[Carmen] No!
- ¡Pinche perro!
- Aaah!
You killed my baby!
My baby!
- [Rollie] It's PCP! Don't breathe!
- [Paco] Get this shit off me!
Oh, shit! We gotta get you
to the hospital! No, no, no!
Get me a hose! We're gonna wash
this stuff off! Don't breathe!
- [Police Radio, Indistinct]
- It's a bust, ese.
Goddamn it! We lost the fuckin' lab
and Clavo's money!
[Popeye] That pinche
loan shark's gonna shit!
How we gonna
pay him back now?
- We lost everything.
- ¡Mira, mira! There's Carmen, eh.
Come on, man,
turn around.
Who's that? Hey, she's
signalling someone, man!
[Rollie] Paco, come back here!
We gotta wash that stuff off you!
- Draw in the perimeter!
- Wilson, call it in!
Police!
Stop the car!
Pull over
the fucking car!
Stop the car!
Put your hands on the steering wheel!
Get your hands up!
Let's go.
Outta the car.
Careful, careful,
we're taxpayers, Officer McCann.
- You turn around.
- You two, outta the car!
Orale, that's a nice placa
you got there, ese.
You should be riding with me,
not fucking with me, carnal.
Don't you call me carnal, you
piece of shit. I'm not your brother.
[Paco] Scumbags like you
are killing off our kids.
You should get some clothes on, officer,
before you get arrested for indecent exposure.
- What an example to set for the kids.
- Listen, motherfuckin' rat punk.
I'm gonna put you and your rat clica
back in the joint. You keep talkin'!
All right, all right,
Paco, let's go.
- Check the trunk.
- Put some clothes on.
- You got a warrant?
- Check that trunk!
- What do you think you are, bulletproof? Check the trunk.
- Goddamn it, check it, Rollie.
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Man] So? You think I never
seen an O.D. Before?
What's the matter?
You don't recognize your own son?
Hey, fuck you.
That ain't Hector.
No, Hector's only 11.
That boy's 13.
If your boss Savedra keeps manufacturing
that shit, it'll put Hector in a cemetery too.
¿Sabes que, homes? You may grow that
long hair and try to act like a vato,
- [Sniffing] but you still smell like chorizo, pig!
- This pig...
is the only thing standing
between you and them,
but you ain't gonna
get through me, punk.
- Smokey, don't say nothing!
- Get him out of here, Rollie!
[Shouting, Indistinct]
Your boss is a punk. He's gonna throw
you out with yesterday's coffee grounds.
- I ain't no rata.
- Yeah, you're a rat.
Get up! Go!
[Miklo] Ladies and gentlemen,
I believe my time here in this institution
has turned me completely around,
and I'm very grateful.
Now I think I can make it as
a productive member of society.
Mr. Velka, isn't it true
that you clique with La Onda,
a group whose motto is:
"Blood in, blood out,"
meaning you have to kill someone
in order to become a member?
I hung out with a group who are
my friends from my old neighborhood.
Our reputation grew out of defense of each
other. That's a... That's it, nothing more.
[Miklo] They didn't even listen!
They fucked me!
Stop feeling sorry for yourself, Miklo,
and make something of your life.
I don't ever wanna see you
in here again. ¿Me entiendes?
This is my daughter.
Look at her.
Look at her! She was only
six months old when I came here.
She grew up without me.
I don't even know her.
- That ain't right, carnal.
- No, it's not, but it's that way for too many of us.
That's why your parole
is so important.
You've gotta prove
there's another way.
You got a chance
to do it, I don't.
Right on, carnal.
Right on.
Thank you.
[Montana] You gotta start acting like
somebody who deserves parole, carnal.
Put it on the record.
Earn your freedom on paper, ese.
All they got in front of them
is yourjacket.
You are yourjacket, 'cause to them,
you're just a number.
Everyone who enters the joint thinks he's
a man, but you know what he really is?
A number,
worth 30 grand a year.
They want us
to come back.
And what's worse, they have us
lining up to get in, ese.
We gotta turn
the system around.
We gotta
outthink them.
Now concentrate.
Why do you deserve parole, Mr. Velka?
Sir, I been in prison
almost a third of my life.
I've grown up here. I've
learned to read and write here.
I earned my G.E.D.
Mr. Velka,
this board's only concern...
is to find evidence
of your rehabilitation.
- That's all.
- Sir, with all due respect,
look at my record.
I've worked hard to prove I deserve another
chance. It's in there in black and white.
Please give me
another chance.
- ¿Que paso?
- I got it! I got my parole!
- Magic! [Laughs]
- [Growls]
They're gonna throw
a parade for me in Hollywood.
Hey, vato, the only parade they're
gonna throw for you is on Halloween.
[Chattering, Laughing]
[Dog Barking]
¡Simon que si!
Damn, ese, they're
not that good, homes.
That's the best thing I've
tasted in nine years, vato loco.
[Laughing]
Orale.
- Good to be home, carnal.
- Right on, cacheton. Right on.
Cuidado, Cruzito.
That rose won't bloom
in the spring.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. No
Baptist sermons, okay, homey?
Takes away the pain
in my back.
The Lord can't.
I tried praying.
- You better still be painting.
- You know it, homes. You know it.
But it's different
than before.
More real.
[Cruz] No, hombre.
Famous apartments?
They ain't famous
no more, ese.
Orale, come stay with me, homes.
I got a studio.
Nah, I gotta stay here.
Frank got me a place.
And besides, the parole board
checks my address.
- Simon.
- Thanks, Cruzito.
Anytime, carnal,
tu sabes.
You don't know how good
it is to see you, vato.
Vato Loco forever, carnal.
[Man, Woman Arguing In Spanish]
[Man] Nobody home!
[Knocking]
What the fuck's
up with you?
- Oh, milkweed.
- I made it.
Entra.
[Laughing]
Hey, welcome to
the barrio, homes.
[Laughing]
Hey, Smokey!
Apache!
Mudo!
Hey, homes.
Yeah, Carlos. Yeah, he told me
to tell your mom to send more coffee.
And make sure
it's, um, T.C.
Shit, she never
sent me nothin'.
Chata, some coffee!
Ay.
She's fucked up.
We had a party last night, ese.
[Coughs]
[Coughing]
So, uh, you got a place
for me in this building, huh?
[Popeye] Uh...
[Coughing]
Hey, you know, that
didn't work out, homes.
This whole fuckin' building
is filled up.
So what am I gonna tell
my parole officer?
Hey... tell him
to suck his pipi.
[Laughter]
Simon, ese.
[Popeye] You can stay here, ese.
It's the same address.
- I even got you a good job.
- You're supposed to have an apartment for me!
Hey, just a fuckin' minute,
Your Majesty!
This ain't the joint
with three hots and a cot!
This is the streets, homey.
You got no choice!
The parole board calls the shots here! This
is your address for at least three months!
¡Chinga! La Onda
could do better than this!
Yeah, Rico and Luis
split after a month, man.
I'm just hanging
for my old lady and my kid.
- What about Popeye?
- Popeye's docking me for a third of my check, man.
Everybody's getting clipped,
man, to pay that loan shark, Clavo.
That's the dude that fronted the bread
for the PCPIab.
That's not the way
it's supposed to be!
♪ [Radio, Spanish]
Son las once treinta y siete
y seguimos escuchando...
Io mas romantico
de nuestra musica.
- I burnt you on that one.
- Truck's loaded. Can I get my check?
No, Larry. No, no.
Don't be that way.
Larry, pettiness
is an ugly thing.
Won't be able to cash that 'til Monday.
Company'll do it for ten bucks.
- All right.
- So, Larry,
what do you give me
on the Lakers and Golden State?
Three points?
Come on, Larry.
Kareem is crippled.
Gimme six points
and Golden State. Come on.
- [Knocking]
- What?
Barry's hand's hurt.
He's Golden State's whole offense.
Hang on, Larry.
So?
Kareem is injured.
So's Nixon.
Lakers got lots of firepower, but
without Barry, Golden State's nothin'.
Six points
ain't enough.
Listen.
Six points or no bet.
Sorry, Larry.
All right.
Who made you the expert?
Put me down
for 1,200.
Yeah, 1,200, Larry.
[Chuckles]
[Miklo] Chingao, East Los
has gotten really crowded.
[Cruz] It is, man. Illegals
pouring in from everywhere, homes.
Guatemala, El Salvador, Ecuador, Panama.
Donde sea, homes.
Crossroads of the world, ese.
A Latino world.
- Simon, ese.
- You seen Paco?
- What?
No, not since
Juanito died.
They don't wanna keep the wound
open, man. They don't want me around.
That's cold-blooded,
carnal.
Paco's a narc, homes.
Probably bust my ass someday.
Man, that's fucked up!
- [Intercom Buzzes]
- Detective Aguilar.
Detective! Big time!
- ¿Qu'iubo, champ?
- Miklo?
- Good guess.
- Oh, man, are you out?
- Yeah, two weeks.
- Well, why didn't you let me know, man?
Hey, after nine years in the joint,
it ain't easy to call a cop, ese.
Listen. It's not me I'm calling
about anyway. It's Cruz.
He's hurtin', man.
He needs his familia.
- He has no family.
- That ain't right, Paco. Vatos Locos forever, remember?
No, you know what I remember? The day they
lowered my little brother into the ground.
That changed me forever.
Every time I see a junkie
on the street...
it reminds me how Cruzito pissed
away his life and his talent.
- Yeah, well, think about it. I gotta get back to work.
- Hey, hey, carnal.
How you doing, man?
Anything I can do to help?
Nah. If I'm gonna make it outta here,
it's gonna be me who does it.
And I really want to, carnal. There's lots
of chances to go the other way, believe me.
- But I'm gonna make it, Paco.
- Well, that's great, carnal. That's... That's great.
I need the keys
to move the trucks.
Wait a minute. Make sure all the tires
are out of'em and they're washed down.
[Chuckling]
So you know your hoops.
[Old Woman]
Oye, cholos, alla arriba.
Eh, cortense sus pedos
alla arriba.
¡Oye, tu! Dile a tus camaradas
que llamare a la policia.
What the fuck?
[Indistinct Chatter]
Hey, guero.
Fuck the world.
[Laughter]
Would you please get outta my bed?
I gotta go to sleep.
Later, ese.
Get the fuck outta my bed! I gotta
go to work in the morning, man!
- What the fuck you on, ese?
- Hey, relax!
- What's up with you?
- That's my space, man! That's all I have!
Aaah!
You pinche mamon!
[Miklo] Hey, Gil, there's been some
sorta mistake on my check.
I'm $150 short. I worked 20 hours
overtime last week.
That's right. I'm gonna do you a favor
and take 150 out seven more times...
'til you pay back
the money you stole.
What? I been totally straight with
you, man. What are you talkin' about?
[Sighs] You know, I try
to give you cons a break.
You see money and you
can't resist stealing it.
That's a lie, man! I never stole
from you, Gil! It wasn't me!
You had the keys.
You knew where the money was.
What?
I didn't...
I didn't do anything.
Wait a minute.
150 times eight is 1,200.
Right?
You use my money to pay back
your gambling debts? Huh?
That's a cute story.
Tell you what.
I'm gonna call the cops.
I'll tell 'em my version, and
you can tell 'em yours, convict.
Hey. I'll get you
some extra overtime.
Yeah, right.
So much for the straight world!
Fucker's got me by the balls!
He can call my parole officer
anytime and get me revoked.
No Ilores, vato. This is just
to get you on your feet, ese.
- You know, later on you'll get something better, tu sabes.
- Yeah, right.
Maybe I can join the priesthood and get
some of that tax-free Sunday money, huh?
Ah, I was doin' better
than this in the joint.
- This just ain't worth it, ese.
- Don't bother, milkweed.
There's no respect.
Oye, open up!
- [Man] ¿Quien es?
- Ronald Reagan, asshole. Open up.
- Who the fuck are you, pendejo?
- Who the fuck are you? I live here, pinche huey!
My house!
[Popeye] Hey, hey, hey, it's cool,
it's cool. He's crashing here.
- Entrale. Tu tambien.
- [Indistinct Spanish]
Oye, Popeye. I told you
no artillery in this place.
- You wanna get these people outta here now?
- Go change a tire, guero.
We're talking some
heavy business here.
You ain't gonna make no deals in this
place. You're gonna fuck up my parole.
- Come on, let's go.
- No, Cruzito, this is my house, damn it!
Cruzito.
Hey, Cruz.
Where you been, ese?
Hey, Clavo.
¿Que paso, homes?
Man, you a tough mama
to find.
Where are those little four G's
that you owe me?
Oh, look, homes. I just gotta sell
a couple of my paintings, ese.
Paintings, that's right. At least you
gave me some paintings, ese.
This baboso still hasn't given me dick.
Can you believe that?
What about the 30% you been cutting out
of the carnales checks at the retread shop?
That's not what Onda's about.
I ain't payin' you shit!
Shut the fuck up, guero!
I represent Onda here!
You represent yourself.
You always did.
Hey, Popeye,
you been collecting?
- What about our share, homes?
- Fuck, Popi, me too!
- You told me you were broke.
- You told me you were fuckin' broke!
I don't come here to listen to you
chumps whine about nickels and dimes.
[Clavo] I'm talkin'about coppin'
a hundred grand.
In Nueva York, I mean, shit,
that wakes people up.
Anybody got
a problem with that?
- Heh-heh, no, no. We got no problem with
that, ese. - Then what's the bullshit?
I'll do it.
We'll do it.
I got... I got Mudo out on the street
right now. He's coppin' some wheels.
And, uh... and, uh,
we got the muscle.
You just give us the plan.
You got the muscle
to jack yourself off.
- That's it.
- [Laughter]
You better watch your back,
Mr. Retread Man!
I'm gonna put you in
fuckin' high heels again!
Go ahead and make your move, motherfucker!
I'll send you to hell with Big Al!
Ah... I ain't got
no time to waste on you.
Wolf ticket's chump.
You're right, kid.
This chump can't even
change his socks.
He can't,
but I can.
Hey, Clavo.
Hey, hey, wait a second.
- What's the scam?
- [Groans]
I need a triggerman, white boy,
not someone who just punches a clock.
- You wanna see who I am? Huh?
- ¡Calmala!
- ¡Calmala, calmala!
- I don't give warning shots, cabron!
We can do the money truck,
or we can off each other.
M- M-Miklo,
don't fuck around, ese.
Realthing.
Miklo, this vato's big trouble!
- ¡Callate!
- You bluff in this game, gabacho, you better be holding five aces.
In the joint, I was hustling more money
than that punk ever dreamed of.
He was punchin' my time clock
every day. What's the gig?
- ¡Aguila! ¡Aguila!
- The armored truck at the Zody's Saturday night. Lotta cash.
Popeye cleans his debt
and gets ten percent.
¡Chale! Armored truck's a dumb deal.
It's too dangerous.
Not this one,
smart boy.
The driver's in on it.
He's a customer.
Okay, we'll do it.
But it's fifty-fifty, and
you wipe out Cruz's debt.
¡Chale, homes! Don't get fucked up in
this bullshit! Stay straight, pendejo!
No sermons, ese,
remember?
This is who I am.
So, do we gift wrap this sucker for you,
or do you walk away empty-handed?
Sixty-forty. Realthing
handles the cash.
You come up with the guns and the car.
Apache's drivin'.
Me and Smokes will
back up Realthing.
- Okay. I can deal with that.
- You're gonna have to.
Hey, hey, hey!
What about me, fucker?
You're out of it,
asshole!
It's payback time,
Popeye.
I'm gonna take back
my rent money, with interest.
Orale. Let's have
a drink, ese.
Detective Aguilar?
Delivery from El Tepeyac?
- I got you, man. I got you.
- No way.
- Once... I did. I did so.
- No way, man. I knew it was you.
Check this out. Check this out.
"Manuel's Special."
Is this a nuclear accident
burrito or what?
- Something to tide us over 'til lunch.
- Us? You mean you. Two of you.
- Hey, I'm an undercover cop, all right?
- [Phone Buzzes]
- I'm working on my character look.
- You're a fat undercover cop.
Does this look real or fake?
Real, right? McCann.
Oye, narco. You like
busting dope dealers?
Oye, pendejo.
This is my lunch hour.
- Big deal going down tomorrow, the Zody's on Whittier.
- Who is this?
Look for a blue Econoline van
with 20 kis of coke inside.
You'll be on
the six o'clock news.
Oh, yeah.
Who is this?
[Paco] All I gotta say is,
shit goes down...
and we're sittin'here without backup,
we're gonna be two sorry assholes.
[Rollie] How many times we done this
and nothing's happened, huh?
A lot. Relax.
H- Have a doughnut.
I already have one.
Have another doughnut.
Look at these.
What a dick.
Dick and asshole.
That's all you call me.
What is my name?
Dick Asshole?
[Paco] Hey, hey.
Blue Econoline van.
- Is that your guy?
- I don't know.
- Do you see a connection anywhere?
- No.
[Rollie] Looks like
two Latino males in front.
Some more in back.
I don't know how many.
[Paco] That's a lot of people
for a dope deal.
Wait a minute.
Shit! They're rippin'off the connection!
They're gonna take the money and the dope!
[Paco] No, there's
an armored truck!
This ain't a buy.
This is a heist! Call it in!
- 211 in progress, Zody's on Whittier.
- Look up!
[Paco] Look up!
Come on!
[Miklo] Smokey, I got you covered!
Let's go!
Shit! Apache, cover me!
- Apache, wait!
- [Gunfire]
Shit!
They're headin' south on Whittier!
There's two of'em!
- Call it in!
- Roger!
- It's me, carnal!
- Miklo? What the fuck are you doing, man?
- Gimme the gun, carnal.
- No fuckin' way, ese!
Miklo, I can help you.
Gimme the fuckin' gun!
I ain't goin' back, Paco!
You owe me this one, vato loco!
No! Miklo, wait!
I can't!
- Stop! Police!
- Fuck you, detective!
Stop or I'll shoot!
♪ [Jazz]
Hey... Cruz, man.
When you gonna finish
messin' with that shit, homes?
Huh? You painted it
about 20 times. [Sniffling]
Hey, come on,
tecato.
- Let's ride the horse.
- Chale, Chuey. We got an intruder.
Oh, shit, homes.
It's John Wayne.
[Chuckles]
[Imitating John Wayne] Uh, well, you're
just a bunch of little chavalas...
and I can whip the whole bunch
of ya chicanos.
So what you want, man?
Not much, carnalito.
Uh, "Hey, how are you?
How you doin'?"
- You know, things people usually say who care about each other.
- Oh, si.
After seven years
of nothing, man?
Not even
a fucking greeting card.
You want hospitality, homes?
Hey, pues...
There's a can of
chinga tu madre...
on the table, man.
- Why don't you help yourself.
- [Laughs] Hey, homes?
Did you say "Hey, homes" to Miklo,
homes, before you shot him?
- Hey, chill out, Chuey!
- He was a shooter in a robbery. I was doing my job.
Nobody has the right
to kill innocent people.
[Chuey] No, you're a pinche
vato vendido, puto!
- [Spits] Fucker!
- Hey! ¡Calmala!
- Hey, fuckin' relax!
- Ow! Ow! Ow!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, wimp!
Hey, homes, you can't come here anymore
unless you're gonna bust me!
Who the fuck gave you permission to use
my little brother in your paintings?
I don't need permission from you.
He's my carnalito too!
Don't you useJuanito as an excuse to
wreck your life. You don't have that right!
Si, culero.
I don't have the right, huh?
Fuckin' right I don't.
You're fuckin' right
I don't have the right.
I don't... I don't have
that fuckin'right.
You want him outta my painting, joto?
All right.
All right. There he is!
¡Ahi esta! ¡Toma!
Take it, man!
Come on!
Juanito always loved me
more than you, homes.
¡Tu te creias muy chingon! You were always
too much of a badass to love the little vato!
Just like you are now. So much of a
fucking badass you kill your own people!
No!
Don't you ever say that to me again,
Cruzito. I let you say that once...
¿Que, puto?
What the fuck?
You gonna kick my ass?
Well, ¡caiga! Let's get down.
- Come on! You the badass!
- I don't wanna fight with you, little brother.
To what, bust me? Well, come on,
gabacho. You the law. Do your job.
Do your fucking job!
Look at this.
Look at that.
Must be
from Quentin, huh?
- Hey. Hey, he's the guy...
- PCP bust. That's Popeye Savedra.
Miklo's connected to him.
"La Onda a toda madre
o un desmadre."
What's "Onda"?
No, La Onda.
It's your destiny, man.
It's... It's like a wave
nothing can stop.
Uh, "madre" means mother.
So...
No, no, it's a lot more
complicated than that.
This is some heavy shit,
all right? "A toda madre".
Everything is perfect.
It's like...
your mother's love.
And "un desmadre"...
is like you have no mother.
It's absolute hatred.
Complete destruction.
In other words, you win it all
or lose everything.
Sweet bunch of guys.
This big fat pig, Popeye, right here in
the center? He's gotta be their leader.
- Hey, Aguilar?
- Look at the way they're all grouped around him.
Hey, Aguilar, that con you
blasted just got outta surgery.
He's gonna be a whole lot
easier to catch from now on.
Nurse, could you
give me a minute, please?
Nurse?
Por la Virgen, Miklo,
I did not know that it would...
Don't talk to me about the Virgen.
Vatos Locos forever.
That all died when you
pulled the trigger.
How did everything
get so fucked up, man?
The pinche badge, ese.
You owe me, vendido!
Who's the sellout?
You're tellin' me you're
workin' hard, goin' straight.
The next thing I know,
you're pointin' a.357 at me...
and there's two guys
dead on the ground.
I would have given you
anything, Miklo.
But you can't just
take away what I am.
You chose
the wrong side, ese.
There's too many of us.
You're gonna lose.
No, uh-uh. I don't forget
where I come from or who I am.
That's what keeps me goin'
every day.
- You don't wanna hear the truth, Paco.
- What truth?
This? La Onda.
Is this your truth?
Two-bit punks like Popeye Savedra
with their PCPIabs?
Or you, robbing Zody's
and killing innocent people?
If that's your truth, then you're
right. I don't wanna hear it.
Get out, puto!
You're not my blood!
I'm cutting you off
like they did my leg.
You don't exist
for me anymore.
[Inmate] Miklo!
Orale, carnalito. What's up, ese?
You're looking good,
homey.
[Inmates Whistling,
Shouting Indistinctly]
- [Banging]
- Hey, Hopalong!
You better tell Carlos he better
stop fucking with my business!
Pockets,
not in public!
[Pockets] I ain't gonna let
no junkie rip-off my customers!
[Guard] Velka, time to lock up!
Mira, mira.
It's the Bionic Man.
[Miklo] Hey, Carlos,
what's with the B.G.A.?
Pay no mind to cheap conversation.
They're just sore losers, ese.
- They're just flapping their crow wings.
- Pockets is on the warpath.
I can't help it if the customers
know where the quality is.
He's been selling 'em
baby powder.
I don't have all day, man.
Let's take it in.
Hey, Majito.
Gonna be cellies, huh?
- Orale.
- [Guard] Move over here. Let me get these cuffs.
¡Orale! That's
a badass pano, homeboy.
You been burnin'
them quills, huh?
- You're getting good.
- It's yours.
My "Home Sweet Home"
picture, huh?
At least this bum leg
got me something.
I get to work
at the law library.
What's all that mad-dogging
between Carlos and the B.G.A.?
The vato's got one
sweet cocaine connection.
Hmm. And he's moving in
on Pockets' customers.
How did he connect?
Nobody knows. But it's dynamite shit.
Pure Bolivian flake.
And Montana, he just stood by
and watched Carlos jump in?
Plata talks.
Carlos is recruiting
lots of soldiers...
and buying influence on the council
to try to neutralize Montana.
Says it's his own personal trip,
not Onda's!
That's bullshit! Personal trips
is what's fucking Onda up!
[Groaning]
I saw that out on the streets.
We're cutting
our own throats.
It's too soon
to be walking on it.
It's a long way up.
But there's no way they're gonna stick
me down there on the first tier without...
ah, my carnales.
Ah!
Your own cousin did that.
- We should put a hit on that puto.
- No, he's mine.
His payback's
gonna take time.
I'm gonna make him sorry
he ever fucked with my business.
Hey, puto.
What the fuck do you think
you're doing, chorizo?
Trying to jump-start
your memory, punk.
Turn your ass around.
Where the fuck is Popeye Savedra?
I ain't seen the vato.
He took off.
Yeah? Right after
Zody's, right?
You were in on that too,
weren't you, Smokey?
- How 'bout these putos? You know 'em, don't you?
- No. No way.
La Onda? Isn't that what
that snake tattoo means?
Isn't that what
I don't know what the fuck
you're talkin' about, ese.
I'll tell you what
I'm talking about, pendejo.
You're a two-time loser, Smokey. One
more, they're gonna lock you up for good.
So you better tell me about Onda, or
I'm gonna strap you down with a bitch.
You'll never see
the streets again!
If I say anything, I'm dead meat.
I ain't gonna tell you shit, ese!
[Grunts]
It's baby powder, baboso!
You write down
every word I say.
Anything you don't understand, you ask.
I will answer just once, so write it down.
Precedents for habeas corpus,
cruel and unusual punishment here.
You're also allowed to help
on Durham decree.
How much can you
charge for this?
You gotta know what you're
talkin' about first.
You do your homework,
jailhouse lawyer...
can make as much as
any mid-level attorney on the street.
I'm gonna live
in here.
- Jerry, I don't mean to be nosy, but I...
- Then don't be.
All right, what?
What is it?
I'm just
wonderin', uh...
You own all those
hardware stores.
How come
you're in here?
Eleven tons of Colombian weed,
twelve keys of heroin...
and a pilot that turned
state's evidence.
¡Chingao! Big time.
- Hey, Jer, I just want you to handle my ca...
- Hurry up, Jerry.
Charlie. I didn't see your jacket here.
You got an appointment?
The name's Carlos. Remember, I'm
paying you lot of feria, ese.
- Make an appointment, Charlie.
- You should be working on my case overtime.
Charlie, cool out or get out.
George? Table.
Oye, Miklo. You could take your leg off and
hook down some of the books from up top, ese.
Hey, I'm just kidding, ese.
Come here. Oye, come here, man.
Hey, relax. I got the medicine
to make you well, vato. Mira.
If you're ever in any pain, homey, you
just come talk to me. ¿Me entiendes?
- You should talk to El Mero Mero.
- Chale.
Think about the future, not the past.
Montana's not God.
[Carlos] Tomorrow at the council I'm giving
Onda a chance to move into the driver's seat.
Don't be
left behind, eh?
Mira. I cut a sweet deal
with the AV-ers.
They'll supply me
with all the dope I can move...
just as long as I sell
only to the blacks and the browns.
What do you have to give
in return to the polar bears?
I gotta plug up
the B.G.A. Pipeline.
Take 'em outta
the dope business.
It's simple. Me and my soldados
can take care of Pockets in here.
My brother Smokey can take out Cheap
Times, their main supply joint in L.A.
All I need from the council
is backup.
- In return, I'm prepared to give Onda a third of my profit.
- It's a sucker's deal, ese.
The only thing the Aryans want is
to start a war between black and brown.
Chale. We've got
a truce with the B.G.A.
Why do you wanna play
the chimp with these mayates?
The market is there.
Cocaine is America's
cup of coffee.
Oye, check it out.
I'm making so much feria
right now,
it's making Miklo's gambling book
look like bubble gum change!
We don't start wars
to become dope pushers.
You even addicted some of
our own soldados to coca.
We're supposed to protect
our people, not destroy them.
Look at his arms. He loves
that shit more than he loves us.
- He'll destroy La Onda.
- ¡Ya! Enough words.
We've come all this way. You wanna
go back to bumming cigarettes, ese?
- Oye, you wanna shine shoes?
- Ese, La Onda don't shine shoes.
That's right, but that's what's gonna
happen if we don't make our move now.
I wanna own the whole fuckin' store!
Now are you with me?
I say chale.
You're not the leader here.
I say Onda's
not with you.
You do what you
have to do without us.
'Cause I ain't goin' back.
I don't need Onda for this.
Money buys my backup.
I'll get the polar bears
to back my play.
- Oye, ¿adonde vas, Jose?
- I split, eh.
- Hey, carnal.
- No, ese.
Carlos, come back!
Jefe, we can't let him go.
We can't let him
split up Onda. Carlos!
[Jerry] Can't you see Montana's
stupid for letting Charlie walk?
- Onda's committing suicide.
- Fuck you, Jerry!
Fine. I thought you wanted
to learn something.
Listen, Charlie's
a businessman.
He broke some serious
business rules.
Not only did he get strung out
on his own shit,
but he moved on B.G.A. Clients
when he didn't have to.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, that's right.
I see the jackets of most
of the cons that come in here.
Eighty percent of them...
eighty percent of them are drug cases.
You know why?
Because everybody out there's doin' it.
Doctors, lawyers,
housewives.
Cocaine is
America's cup of coffee.
You were Carlos' connection.
He said the same "cup of coffee"line
exactly. You were supplying him.
You're pissed 'cause he's
doing business with AV-ers now.
Last year, California passed
a flat-time law for drug offenders.
You know what that means? That means
they have it worse than anybody...
murderers, rapists,
anybody.
There's no parole,
no good time.
That's a lot of guys that are gonna be
here for a real long time, all drug users.
Can you see
the potential?
- Can you?
- Yeah.
Anyone who can accommodate
that appetite...
can control this joint
and every other joint.
Dwell on it.
[Lightning] Drive it.
Drive it, Ryder.
Here's your pill briefs.
Jerry said it will take at least
three months for the court to respond.
Well, well, well,
Lightning.
Our favorite spic lover has come home.
I knew he'd be back.
Here's your file. Magic said to remind you
about Lightning's account. It's overdue.
You hear that, Lightning? The cripple
here wants to collect your gambling debts.
Yeah, well, I might think about it,
if he'll show me his falsie.
Come on, cripple,
show me your stump.
[Ryder] Little white Mexican boy...
came all the way back
just to show us his stump.
- Hold his fuckin' leg! Come on. Stand still.
- Get off me, motherfuckers!
Too many britches on.
Stay still, goddamn it, I said!
You gotta be crazy to pull
this shit, Lightning!
Ooh, I'm scared, punk.
I'll bet you didn't fight so hard when
Big Al used to do this, did you?
He must be laughin'
in his grave, cripple.
Get off, you fuck...
No, leave it alone!
Stay still,
goddamn it.
- Oh! There she is.
- Fucking puto!
You ever heard that old saying,
"Put your foot in your mouth"?
Spit-shine that shoe, boy.
- You fuckin' polar bears are gonna pay, believe me!
- [Ryder Spits]
Look around you, half-breed.
Onda's finished!
Carlos works for us now,
and every day he brings
more Onda soldiers with him.
You greasers better wise up.
It's a white world.
The coloreds are here
to serve us.
From now on, you're gonna be
my personal errand boy.
- You motherfucker!
- Fuckin' punk!
Go out for a pass, cripple.
Come on, go deep.
[Laughter]
Now you're back to
your true nature, boy.
- Crawling on your belly like a worm.
- [Laughter]
They put it in my face!
You have to understand. Your leg is gone,
Miklo. You can no longer be a soldier.
That's why I put you
in the library.
It's not what they did to me.
They got no respect for Onda.
We should never have
given up Carlos.
You think I wanted to?
Carlos fucked up, bad!
I'm not saying he didn't,
but he was right about the drugs.
Whoever controls them
controls everything.
You ever seen an old drug dealer,
Miklo? They don't exist.
Look, all we have
to do is wait.
In five years, Chicanos are gonna be the
majority in the pintas in the Southwest.
This is now,
not five years from now!
What good is it if we're a bunch of fuckin'
slaves workin' for the B.G.A. And AV-ers?
We gotta attack now!
We gotta take power!
All we ever been doing is fighting
each other! And for what?
The best of us ending up
in pools of blood...
for a pinche pack of smokes
and a snort of coca!
¡Chale!
I don't know where
you're comin' from, bro.
¿Que es eso?
A Chicana from Cal State got them
to publish my essay on prison reform.
They want me to write a book
on the Chicano in prison.
You better lift your eyes
outta this book, Jefe.
You better see what's
goin' on around us now.
Wind it up, gentlemen. Take it
to your houses. Let's go, move it.
[Magic] Hey, Bonafide! When's
the B.G.A. Gonna take care of its tab?
No can do, carnal.
Quarter of the bill
I can take care of, maybe.
Indugu. You forgot
your comb, man.
Maybe.
Thinks he's getting away with something.
He's holding on to a fairy tale.
- ¡Pinche mayate!
- Hey, Magic.
Help me out.
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Inmate] You mad-dog me,
you better watch your back, homes!
Now the fuckin' AV-ers
won't pay on their bets either.
Why pay? They were testing us
with Carlos and we folded.
Now they're gonna take us
apart piece by piece.
Whether we like it or not, the dope
business is where it's at, Magic.
If the AV-ers and the BGA-ers control
it, they control everything, including us.
Fuckin' A, ese.
Carlitos was right.
No, he was stupid...
for sellin' out to the AV-ers.
Onda should take the money left
in the gambling book and make a buy.
Yeah.
I know a connection.
- But the council won't approve it.
- We should do it anyway.
- You wanna die, ese?
- If I have to, I will!
I lost my fucking leg,
my family back home.
This is all I got left.
If we don't do something now,
Onda dies. Do you want that?
Magic.
I love Montana too.
But I'm not gonna stand by
and watch them destroy us.
Will you stand with me,
carnal?
[Miklo] Right now there's
only two of us,
so we gotta lay back
and wait for an opening.
The Aryan Vanguard's gonna force Carlos
to make his move soon on the B.G.A.
His first target
will be Pockets.
I told you to stop
branchin', punk!
Better watch your back
'cause I'm gonna ride you.
Orale, ese. You're right.
I don't want any trouble.
I've changed my ways.
Now I'm takin'
all your customers.
Say anything
and you're dead!
[Miklo] At the same time
he hits Pockets,
his brother Smokey will move on Cheap
Times, the B.G.A. 's drugstore down in L.A.
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey
♪ She's a super freak
Super freak
- She's su...
- [Indistinct Shout]
Brought you monkeys
some coconuts...
from Quentin!
[Screaming, Shouting]
[Miklo] The only problem is,
Carlos is so strung out...
he can't see the wolf
in the henhouse.
If I know Red Ryder, as soon
as Carlos does the AV-ers'dirty work,
they'll pull
his protection,
and it'll be open season
on Carlos Zuniga.
[Geronimo] Carlos!
No!
[Indistinct Shouting]
- [Whistles Blowing]
- [Miklo] If I'm right,
all hell's
gonna break loose.
That's our chance, Magic.
Where there's war,
there's opportunity.
What we gotta do is wake Montana up
and move Onda into power.
No, listen! Before we fuck up everything we
built, I have to have a meeting with the B.G.A.
- ¡Vamos ahorita!
- ¡Chingao!
We're making a horrible mistake.
Can't you understand that?
- Are you blind or what?
- Wait a minute! I said I want you ready!
I'm not gonna waste the lives
of our soldados for nothing!
First we talk.
We fight only if we have to!
- The time to strike is now! We wait, they'll destroy us!
- No, Magic!
We gotta back El Mero Mero. If he says
meet with the B.G.A., we gotta do it.
What are you talkin' about? If we stand by,
we're gonna watch Onda go down in flames!
Magic!
I want you to hit Smokey.
I want him dead by tomorrow.
- Orale.
- And you set up a meeting with Bonafide.
- Simon, Jefe.
- [Montana] Geronimo, dile a tus soldados que se calmen.
Yo.
Thought I was off
your list, ese.
No, Smokes.
We straight.
That heist was
the huevo's fuckup.
- So, what do you want?
- Think you can move 300?
Easy as mantequilla
on a hot tortilla.
Mira.
Go make yourself
some planta.
Orale.
Gracias, carnal.
Por nada.
I owe you.
[Groans]
Motherfucker!
[Shouts In Spanish]
Get him around the park!
Three more California prison inmates
have been killed in gang violence,
bringing the tally of fatalities
this week to eleven.
Aguilar!
Aguilar.
Hey, chorizo. You still
want Popeye Savedra?
- Zuniga?
- They got a hit on me.
I need protection
or I'm dead.
Listen, Smokey. If you want protection,
you're gonna have to give me more than Popeye.
I want everything on Onda.
Who they are and where they are.
Hey, no way.
Forget about it.
Hey, don't talk shit, Smokey. You stay out
there alone, you're dead. You said so yourself.
All right. All right!
I'll give it to you.
The whole layout.
Capitanes, soldados.
- But I gotta be outta state first.
- We'll talk about it.
- Where can we meet?
- St. Mary's Church, Fourth and Chicago.
- I know it.
- Be there in 15 minutes, chorizo, or forget about it.
I'll be there.
[Door Opening]
[Children Giggling, Whispering]
[Captain] Aguilar?
This is Lieutenant Ivan Burnett.
He's from San Quentin.
- Detective Paco Aguilar. How ya doin'? Yeah.
- This the victim?
Paco, we just heard
from Sacramento.
We are to "cooperate"
with Corrections on this.
That means Burnett's
bringing down his entire team.
- What does that mean? I'm out of it?
- You heard me.
Well, this is bullshit, Captain. Come on,
I've been working on this case for months.
This vato was about to give
me the full lowdown on Onda.
What do you know
about Onda?
I had a run-in with a couple of
these guys here.
- The whole council. Captain, I'll need this picture.
- Fine.
- My chief investigator will debrief him tomorrow.
- [Paco] Wait a minute, man.
That's my evidence.
This is an East L.A. Case.
Look, I appreciate your interest,
but this is much bigger than East L.A.
Things are poppin' up
all over the state.
You hear about
the grenade...
that was thrown into the Cheap Times
Social Club in Wilmington last night?
I'm betting that Zuniga here
was the quarterback.
Part of a plot started by his brother
in Quentin. It all comes outta Q.
All right, all right,
Lieutenant. Let's get inside.
This is happening here,
not in San Quentin.
It's all tied up to prison gangs now.
It's very complicated.
That's why
we're takin' over.
Do you speak Spanish?
You ever been in a street gang?
No, but my warden has
and he's Chicano.
Well, is your warden related
to someone on the Onda council?
Miklo Velka is my...
is my cousin.
I am related to him
by blood and by this.
Look, Lieutenant,
I don't mean any disrespect,
but I think I can get further
on this thing than you can.
All I'm asking is
that I'm involved.
Thank you.
There is no war here, Bonafide. This was a
personal thing between Carlos and Pockets.
Carlos and Pockets were loose cannons.
That was business.
But what you all did in L.A.
Night before last was bullshit.
There's gonna be more blood
on blades than broken bones...
'cause we ain't lettin' y'all
hit us in the back no more.
You wanna powwow?
You wanna talk? Go ahead, talk.
Onda had nothing to do
with Cheap Times.
Carlos' brother, Smokey,
acted on his orders, not Onda's,
and he's paid the price
with his life.
Cheap Times make for
cheap lives. Lots of'em.
You want a war? We're ready.
Believe me, we'll win.
We've got more soldiers and they'll go all
the way... to the death if they have to.
I got soldiers. My soldiers are
ready to die. We can prove that.
Is that what you want? I guarantee
that's what the Aryans want.
We can stop the killing now,
you and me, right here.
Now your word means something here.
What about Folsom and Chino?
- I speak for them too.
- Uh-uh.
Maybe for Soto at Folsom, but your word
ain't reachin' to Chino right now.
Mosca Lopez is crazy. I done
lost three people down there.
I can ask the warden
for a temporary transfer.
- He might agree if you guarantee peace while I'm gone.
- Fuck a truce!
- We cannot...
- [Indistinct Remark]
[Murmuring]
Man, you got five days.
[Bonafide] I'm gonna hold
my side up for five days, man.
Five days.
Miklo will coordinate
Onda business in my absence.
You can trust he'll make sure
nothing happens while I'm away.
So do we have
a truce?
- Right on.
- Well, well, well.
Wetbacks and Bonafide
porch monkeys holdin' hands.
[AV-ers Laugh]
You now have
a combined I.Q. Of two.
You're a dead man,
Wonder Bread!
Why don't you kiss my enriched
white ass, motherfucker?
This here's my coon dog.
Get them coons, boy.
[Barking]
Hey, Ryder!
What's goin' on?
Don't ask me what's goin' on! Ask,
"What are we doin' here? Is there a war?"
[Ryder] Run 'em outta the goddamn
banks! Save the taxpayers some money!
All right, gentlemen,
let's clear the yard!
[Ryder] It's between
the niggers and the spics!
We're white, white,
white, you motherfuckers!
[Miklo] Jefe, will Bonafide
listen to me?
Magic and the others
are warriors.
If I put one of them in charge,
Bonafide would never trust me.
You're a jailhouse lawyer,
a counselor.
- He knows you'll follow my wishes.
- But what if he's lying?
What if the B.G.A.
Doesn't want peace?
Nobody in here knows what peace is.
They've never had it.
I'm talking
about power, carnal.
The only way for us to gain real power
is for black and brown to come together.
¿Me entiendes?
[Paco] Huh. And I thought Popeye
Savedra was the leader of Onda.
It's hard to buy it's
that little guy down there.
You better believe it.
He's got what you
call "charisma."
You really think he can do something
to stop the violence?
Montana's got something that makes you
wanna listen to him. He's got a lot of heart.
If anybody can stop
this war, it's him.
I can always bring in the guns,
but I'd rather it be him.
I don't like you
traveling alone.
I don't trust the administration.
I don't trust anybody.
Don't worry. The warden's
guaranteeing my passage.
Top secret route.
Oye.
I made a deal
with the vato.
I get to spend the night in Delano,
see my daughter.
After 14 years.
Can you believe it?
Come on, Segura.
Move it.
Jefe.
Huacha. You tell
those vatos...
to find some shade and chill out
'til I get back, eh?
You got it.
[Montana] What time's
my daughter coming?
She'll be here
about 7:00 sharp.
- We'll rack you at 6:00 tomorrow for a shower.
- I'll be waiting.
- Psst! Name's Wallace.
- Montana.
Say, amigo, you ain't got
no street smokes, do ya?
This state tobacco, man,
it'll kill ya.
I don't smoke.
You don't smoke, huh?
Man, I can't wait for these
son-of-a-bitches to let me outta here...
so I can find me
a field crew.
Do me some pickin' so I can send my old
lady some money back in Louisiana.
- Yeah, I used to pick a little when I was a kid.
- Huh.
Me, I been followin'
this crop all my life.
If it ain't that,
I takes me a little drink.
If it ain't that, they got me
behind bars tryin'to dry out.
You ever pick
any grapes, Wallace?
[Laughing]
No, I ain't never picked no grapes.
But I done cut me a bunch.
Yeah.
- Here.
- Oh, man, thank you.
Is it... Say, amigo, d-do you mind
any if I have two?
- Ah, keep the pack. They're only for trade.
- Oh, man.
[Guard] Lights out.
You know, when I was a kid,
I used to love to pick.
Nothing like fresh vegetables
and fruit right from the vine.
Yeah.
Hmm.
Okay, the escort's on his way.
You'll have one hour with your father.
- Let's go.
- I'd like a couple of seconds to straighten up.
I don't care who you are in San Quentin.
You're nobody here in Kern County.
Look, officer. I haven't seen
my daughter in 14 years.
Could I just take a couple of seconds
to straighten up?
Please?
I'm gonna put your daughter in the
visiting room. You've got one hour.
The clock is ticking.
One hour. Be right back.
Mornin', Montana.
Morning, Wallace.
See they botherin' with ya
early in the mornin', huh?
No. It's a good day.
I'm not gonna let
anything ruin it.
Aaah! Ooh, them damn
short-handle holes!
Yeah, I used to
feel those myself.
Oh... Oh!
Here, amigo.
Why don't you use this?
Yeah, well,
I'll hold it for you.
Thank you.
Yeah, chingo de tiempo
since I felt this good.
My daughter's coming today.
Mi hijita.
- Oh, man, today is gonna be such a good day for you.
- Yeah.
Your daughter's
gonna be so proud of you.
- There.
- [Grunts]
- Uh-huh.
- [Gasps]
Now this is what they call
"a change of plans."
For Cheap Times!
- [Gasping]
- Son-of-a-bitch!
Motherfucker, think you can
blow up my brother! Uh-uh!
- Daaah!
- You can go join your maker now.
For what falls
to the floor is his.
[Groaning]
Don't forget your smokes.
[Gasping]
[Guttural Cry]
[Indistinct Shouting]
- You want a war? I'll give you a fuckin' war!
- No! Stop him!
No! They're waiting for us
to run in blind!
They'll cut us down!
We gotta think like Mero Mero.
- You're not Mero Mero!
- No, I'm not! But I'm alive!
And I'm gonna stay that way! And I
want mi familia to stay that way too!
We gotta plan like men,
not get shot down like dogs!
Wait and be ready,
Magic!
Again. How'd you know
he was in Delano?
How'd you know the head
of La Onda was there?
Man, I do not give
a good goddamn...
who that taco-eatin'
motherfucker was.
Oh, who that taco-eatin'
motherfucker was!
- Do you know who you killed, asshole?
- Your mama!
- We're gonna stay here all day until you...
- [Warden] He won't crack.
Nope. He's been in
for 30 years.
He's as tough
as three-inch steel.
- [Knocking]
- When I get back, I'm gonna bust your ass.
I'll be here.
Come in here.
Yeah, that's the man. That's the one
who ordered it. Bring him in here.
- Tell him what you told me.
- I didn't order no hit on nobody.
That'd be like throwin'
gasoline on fire right now.
Don't bullshit me, man.
I ain't no sucker.
He's B.G.A.
He made the hit. He's your man.
I ain't tryin' to play you
for no sucker, brother.
I'm just tellin' you, if I wanted to hit
Montana, I'd have used a free-lancer.
An AV-er, so it
couldn't be traced.
I'm not
a stupid man, sir.
[Warden] That's enough.
Come on over here with me.
- [Warden] Is that your man?
- [Bonafide] Yeah, that's him.
- Why don't you let me talk to him?
- No way!
He ain't gonna
tell you nothin'.
You wanna get to the bottom of this
problem? You wanna deal with it?
Now, I know
he'll talk to me.
Your call.
[Speaking Arabic]
- Goddamn. The Man got you down here too?
- Yeah.
Look here.
Why you hit Montana?
Oh, I dig. The Man got
his eyes and ears in the wall.
Don't sweat, brother.
I'm gonna maintain.
Who ordered the hit?
You did.
Come here.
[Screaming]
Oh!
[Indistinct Remark]
You did, man!
- You did. I got your kite, man.
- I didn't send you nothin'.
- Ow! Ow! Fuck!
- Who ordered it?
You did, man. You did.
I got your comb.
- I know your design.
- You got my comb?
Yeah, I got your comb. I opened it up.
I read the message, I burned it.
It was your comb, man!
[Paco] Listen, man,
we've got five minutes.
The warden let me come in here
to talk to you about Montana's murder.
Who the fuck are you
to come here like this?
Montana's none of
your fucking business!
You gotta listen to me, Miklo.
Bonafide says somebody
counterfeited his comb...
and put a phony message
in it to hit Montana.
- The B.G.A. Didn't do it.
- That's bullshit!
We know the fuckin' B.G.A.
Killed him.
Yeah? Well, the administration doesn't
think so. And what if they're right?
You wanna be responsible for starting a
fucking war against the wrong people? Huh?
Listen, man,
I know you hate me.
I shot your leg off, and that's something I'm
gonna have to live with for the rest of my life.
But you're still my blood, and I'm not gonna
stand here and watch you destroy yourself.
If you start this war, you and
your vatos will be committing suicide.
Now look over there.
You see the warden?
He's got all the firepower he needs, and
he ain't afraid to use it, believe me.
Do you want that?
Oh, you're The Man now,
aren't you?
Look, Montana left you
in charge, right?
Be a real leader, man.
Protect your people.
Meet with Bonafide.
What do you got to lose?
I'll meet him in the yard.
[Miklo] One lieutenant each.
No guards around.
[Warden] That's far enough.
Let 'em go on their own.
I swear to you,
it wasn't the B.G.A.
Montana was a stand-up dude.
We were set up!
That old man was no jive-ass punk.
He was hard-core B.G.A.
That's right. That's why
it don't make no sense.
I take out Montana with my own man?
That's suicide.
Now you do what you wanna do,
but think about this:
Who you think stands to gain
if B.G.A. And Onda war?
The fuckin' A.V.!
Oh, yeah, they want us
to take each other out.
Then they step in and take over
everything. We go back to bein' slaves.
The AV-ers.
They're the only ones who could've gotten
Montana's route from the white guards. Right?
I work with Lightning
in the wood shop.
He gets my comb, he counterfeits it,
he sends it to Wallace.
- It's possible.
- And now that motherfucker Red Ryder...
sittin' in a front-row seat just waitin'
on us to take each other out.
- So what do you propose?
- I say whip those motherfuckers together.
We do to them
what they tryin' to do to us.
[Miklo] You see those
pinche vultures?
They're watchin' us with
a magnifying glass right now.
So for the next six months,
we'll practice a good-neighbor policy.
So we got a deal?
We join forces?
Yeah.
And we'll celebrate a big
Mexican holiday together.
Now which one
you talkin' about?
Dia de los muertos.
That means what now?
Day of the Dead.
- All right.
- [Chuckles] Right.
In six months.
My man.
They're shakin' hands.
We got a truce.
We won't congratulate ourselves
too soon. We'll wait and see.
[Cyclone]
I don't trust that dude.
No, no, no.
This boy's in way over his head.
He ain't got no choice
but to go with us right now.
We help them take out the AV-ers,
we're making the mayates stronger, ese.
It's okay, carnal.
When you expect nothing and you get
everything, that's destiny.
The B.G.A. Wants to help us take out
the AV-ers? All right.
We'll throw a little
white meat to the dogs.
Then we'll rob
the house.
¡Orale!
Gracias, carnal.
You were right.
You did the right
thing, Miklo.
Tell your mom
I love her, okay?
- Take care of yourself, all right?
- Yeah.
♪ [Drumbeats]
♪ [Cruz Singing In Spanish]
Juanito, Juanito.
Hey, homes, if anybody
messes with you, ese.
[Sobbing]
I'm sorry, ama.
¡Perdoname!
- I loved Juanito.
- I know, mi hijo.
[Cruz] I loved him, ama.
[Sobbing]
...carnalito, familia.
I'm sorry.
[Sobbing]
I missed you.
Mi familia.
♪ [Drumbeats, Chanting]
...she put the handcuffs on,
two days later, I come back.
She's got eye hooks drilled
in the door. She's got thongs.
I swear to God, she absolutely
loved it! She became or...
♪ [Drumbeats]
♪ [Chanting In Indian Tongue]
- [Grunting]
- You got it. One more.
- Come on, one more.
- [Gasps, Screams]
Hey, hey, hey.
No more. No more, man.
I'm through, okay?
That's it.
[Ryder] Ten cents
a fuckin'hour.
That spic warden ain't gettin'
a nickel's worth of overtime outta me.
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey!
What the fuck is wrong with you
goddamn people! Are you...
Goddamn it! You stupid fuckin'
asshole! You got it in my eyes!
Lousy...
Aaah!
Now everybody keeps their mouth shut,
you understand me?
This way, won't be no problem
with nobody when the shit go down.
The plan's
gonna work, Bonafide.
I'm telling you, man,
we keep our stake together.
- That way we control the whole joint, right?
- All right.
You want some of this?
[Groans]
[Warden] Who do these punks
think they are? Look at this!
It's unbelievable.
Every hit was strategic.
First they knocked off
most of the A.V. Leadership,
and then they
finished off the B.G.A.
I don't like being lied to.
I want the Onda council broken up.
Use interstate compact. I want 'em outta here.
Get 'em outta here before the end of the week.
[Rollie Whistles] Taxpayers
just saved another three million bucks.
Everything's a fuckin'joke to
you, man. What's your problem?
- What's my problem? You got a problem!
- No, you don't understand, man.
That little bastard's up there playing
God and he's got an army to back him up.
Yeah, I don't understand, right?
I don't ever understand, right?
Well, as long as he's doing it behind bars,
it's not gonna affect you or me, is it?
- Is it?
- Oh, it's not gonna affect us?
Won't affect
any of us, will it?
You used me.
I tried to save your life and you
used me to set up the B.G.A.
They would've come after us
if we hadn't got them first.
- I did what I had to for my brothers to survive.
- Your brothers?
And what am I, Miklo?
Man, you grew up with me.
You slept in my room.
You wore my fuckin' clothes!
How could you use your own flesh and
blood to help massacre all those people?
I didn't wanna hurt you, Paco.
In here, you use what you've got.
Without your help,
a lot of carnales would've died.
- Gracias...
- Don't you thank me.
I hate what you did.
I hate what
you stand for.
You know, Paquito,
for a long time I hated you.
I blamed you for everything.
But then I realized something
that changed my life.
Everything you did...
even shooting my leg off...
forced me into my destiny.
Made me discover myself.
Find my real family,
my home.
Here.
Inside these walls,
I found the strength of La Raza.
You got no fuckin' idea
what La Raza means.
It's about our people out there, working,
surviving, with pride and dignity. That's raza.
Not lying and murdering.
All you got is
your white father's hate.
Still hung up on my
fluorescent skin, vato? Hmm?
He wasn't my real father.
Montana was.
He taught me about respect.
You gotta be willing
to die for it.
Like you. Like you not deserting me
after the car crash at El Pino.
That was real respect
for a brother.
And I'll always
love you for it, carnal.
Miklo, it's not about drive-bys
and gang fights anymore.
- It's about...
- Let's stop fighting, carnal! We're family.
We should help each other,
not cut each other's throats.
Let's be brothers again.
[Sighs]
Just because you're a cop and I'm a con
doesn't mean we can't cooperate.
I can give you tips from inside that
could really help you out on the street.
You got a lot of power
out there, man.
Your guidance and advice
would be invaluable to me.
What are you asking me?
To be a member of your gang?
Are you outta
your fuckin' mind?
Do you remember how we
took out Spider for Cruz?
Together, Paco.
We're unbeatable.
Your Onda's not my onda,
and it never will be.
Paco!
I'll always be
your brother, vato loco.
Never.
- Orale, Chivito.
- Tucha, carnal. They're watching, homes.
I know they are.
Let 'em watch.
[Miklo] The show's just beginning
and they don't even know it.
This will probably be our last
meeting together, carnales.
They're trying to break Onda up.
But you know what?
They're only
helping us grow.
They're using
the interstate compact...
to exchange each of you who's from
out of state for cons from Califas.
So, Chivo, they're
sending you back to Arizona.
- ¿Como dices?
- Hey, man, we can't do nothin' about it.
You gotta go. But at least
you'll be back to your mom, man.
She needs anything, let me know.
I'll take care of her.
Orale, homes.
Simon que si.
Geronimo goes back
to Texas.
- You straighten your son out, ¿que no?
- Simon.
They're trying
to break up La Onda!
But we're gonna
turn it on 'em!
And you know how
we're gonna do that?
Each of you is gonna establish
your own chapters.
La Onda has $15,000 for each of you
so you can start things out strong.
We're gonna spread La Onda
gospel Billy Graham style!
Yeah.
Say it, homey.
El Mero Mero
had a dream.
We are that dream.
We're gonna multiply
in numbers undreamed of.
In every pinta,
every barrio.
Every southwestern state.
La Onda
has a destiny...
and no one can stop us.
¡Eso!
¡Orale!
¡Viva La Onda!
- Tocale, carnal. Orale.
- Viva.
What about me, carnal?
Where do I go?
You stay with me, carnal.
You're the eyes
behind my back.
The leg I don't have.
The other half
of mi corazon.
You ordered me
to destroy this mold.
But I kept it for protection...
from you.
Now I want you
to destroy it.
- I loved him.
- We both loved him.
But we did what we
had to do for Onda!
You were right.
I give my life to you.
¡Jefe!
Simon.
- [Paco] What are we doing here?
- No Ilores, vato.
No mas ven.
- Come on, man.
- Man, you got me outta bed to come down here?
Think you lost more
than your hair, vato.
Ha! Don't believe all that
shit you hear about Samson, ese.
I'm just strippin' myself
down to the bone, homes.
- What if I said I wouldn't come?
- Shit, I knew you would come.
Shee... Huacha.
Come look at yourself
in the mirror, ese.
Oh, man.
It's not all
marked up, man.
It's a sign
of respect.
For ten years, man, I've been
Star Trekking in the Twilight Zone.
Thought if I came and looked at this,
I might find my way back, ¿que no?
[Cruz] Damn!
We were all innocent, eh.
That's all gone, Cruzito.
It ain't like that anymore.
What, not even a little carnalismo
left in there, ese?
What, you think you use brotherhood up
like a shot of tequila?
[Cruz] You just drink it down,
it burns, makes you feel good, ya?
And you're left with a hangover
the rest of your life?
Look, man, you showed me
your mural.
You're a good artist.
I think you're the best.
Now come on. Let's go.
Just 'cause you wear sunglasses
don't mean you're blind, ese.
Oh, shit! You wanna know
what I see up there?
A fantasy, man.
A dream.
Three vatos looking for
something that wasn't there.
Loco, we stood by each other.
We trusted each other.
¡Orale! That's
worth believing in!
Shit, we were familia,
homes.
And never again, Cruzito.
Miklo and I are finished, man.
He ain't my family!
I hate that fuckin' puto!
You oughta scrape his ass
off the wall like dirt.
Chale, vato. No matter how much hate there is
between you and him, you're still connected.
You got the same blood pumping
through both your hearts, ese.
That's a bond
you can never break.
Neither can Miklo.
He's still just trying
to be like you!
- That's bullshit!
- ¡Simon, ese! Come on!
¡El Gallo Negro!
The baddest Chicano in the barrio!
Yeah, well, that ain't me!
Not anymore.
You ain't changed
a bit, ese.
Oh, so what?
What are you saying?
It's all my fault the way
everything turned out?
Oh, I see.
Orale.
What, you think you got
so much fucking power, huh?
You control everybody's
destiny? Chale.
- No, you're right, man. I set Miklo up.
- No, I'm not.
I made him go after Spider.
I started the whole fuckin' thing.
Relax, ese.
- Your back wouldn't be all fucked up.
- [Sighs]
- Miklo wouldn't be in prison. He'd still have his leg.
- Hey, I forgive you, ese.
I don't want
your forgiveness, man!
You know, that's your fuckin' problem,
ese. You can't forgive yourself.
You need that guilt.
It's what keeps you going.
Hey, I know, bro. I fed mine
through a needle for ten years.
And that guero up there, hating
his own fuckin' white skin?
Shit, he's got it worse
than both of us.
You gotta cut it loose, carnal.
It's fucking poison!
That's who we are.
Three vatos locos
full of carnalismo,
trying to survive
in a fuckin' war zone.
But what I know now, bro, is that I need
my familia to do it. We all do.
Even you, ¡pinche jura!
Badass cop.
Hey, don't back away,
vato.
Life's a risk, carnal.
Remember? You said it yourself.
¡Pues orale!
Step into the ring and throw down, ese.
You a badass?
Take care of business, homes.
¡Caiga, puto!
'Cause we're
from East Los, ese!
We come out chased
by hounds! Huh?
Round and round we go,
wearing a pinche rabbit's foot for luck.
Just ahead of the fuckin'
hounds. ¡Qu'iubo!
- Ow!
- Yeah!
¡Que vida es!
Que loca vida, homes.
¿Pero sabes que, ese?
- [Sniffling]
- Hey.
We got something better
than a rabbit's foot, homes.
We've got familia!
Raza, huey.
Hmm? You know
what I'm saying, ese?
Crees mucho,
Gallo Negro.
You may be bad, but you
can't dance like Smooth Cruz.
¡Orale!
Yo y tu, ese.
Oh, I see now.
I remember you, vato.
- ¡Ah! ¡Ay, ay, ay!
- El Gallo Negro, vato.
- I'm a lover, not a fighter, man.
- Oh, si.
Simon. El merengue
at the Tender Trap '72.
- Rucas got their hearts broke and I kicked your ass. Pow! Pow!
- Shit!
Shit, man, I was breakin'
hearts and faces, vato.
[Cruz] ¡Oh, si! Bullshit!
You still can't dance, ese!
You still can't dance.
¿Yque, loco?
Yeah, but you can learn, ese.
I'll teach you. Simon.
'Cause it ain't ever over,
homes. Never!
Bailamos hasta que
nos morimos, ese.
Ow! Ow!