[Airplane landing]
[Wheels touching down]
[Chattering]
[Footsteps]
[Loudspeaker, people chattering]
- You okay?
- I'm fine, mate. Don't worry about it.
You all right?
Enjoy L.A.
[Speaks French]
[Men yelling in Spanish]
He did it.
[Silence]
- [Man] Everything's always about you.
- [Woman] It's not.
That gearhead was being sarcastic
and you know it.
- I just didn't see it that way.
- Bullshit.
What about the dig
about the makeover?
What do you want me to do?
I work with him, for chrissake.
You're capable of taking care
of your own shit.
You know something? Last time I checked,
you were sleeping with me.
So unless you want to start fucking him,
I suggest...
[both speaking Spanish]
Hey, pal. Where can I catch a shuttle
to the airport around here?
- Right there.
- Thanks.
It was him in that gold Lexus
with the cell phone.
Are they still asking for
a change of venue?
He's enhanceable because
of priors in the early '80s.
- Where to?
- Downtown. 312 North Spring Street.
Downtown.
Look, the transcriptions need to be done
by 7 a.m., period, okay?
Hold on. Take Sepulveda
to Slauson to La Brea.
Take La Brea north to 6th,
into downtown.
So what? You'll be up late.
I'm pulling an all-nighter too,
so save the tears.
- I'll take 105 east to the 110. It's faster.
- What?
The 105 to the 110
will get you there quicker.
The 110 turns into a parking lot
around USC.
But once you get to La Brea
north of Santa Monica, it's jammed.
The 110 north of the 10, you get people
driving to Pasadena and they drive slow.
Yeah, they do, but what I do is
I get off on Grand and then I...
Surface roads is what you want,
that's what we'll do.
Are we taking bets?
- Are we?
- And what if you're wrong?
I don't think I'll be wrong,
but if I am...
...your ride's free.
Okay, you got yourself a deal.
- Go ahead, say it.
- Say what?
- Go ahead.
- I got lucky with the lights.
You weren't lucky.
What you were was right.
I was wrong...
...Max.
You mind turning that up?
You like the classics.
- I do. I used to play in high school.
- Let me guess. Woodwinds.
No. Strings. Never had the lungs
for wind instruments.
Could've fooled me the way you were
unloading on that cell phone.
[Woman] Different instrument.
If you had just listened to me, we'd be
all bogged down in traffic right now,
and you would've made
an extra five bucks.
Yeah, well, you keep that 5 bucks.
Buy you something special. Go wild.
Really, it's not a big deal.
Nothing big here.
How many cabbies do you know get you
into an argument to save you money?
There were two of us.
I had to kill the other one.
I don't like competition.
Take pride in being good
at what you do?
What, this?
No, this is part-time.
This is a fill-in job.
Pay the bills.
But I will be the best at what I do.
But that's something else.
- What else?
- Just shaping up some things.
Like...?
Tell me.
Limo company I'm putting together.
Island Limos.
It'll be like a island on wheels.
A cool groove, like a club experience.
When you get to the airport,
you won't want to get out of my limo.
So I do this part-time
to get my Benz off leases...
staff up, get the right client list.
You know, things like that.
How do you like being a lawyer?
- What are you, psychic?
- Little bit.
There's the dark pinstripe suit.
Elegant, not too flashy.
That rules out advertising.
Plus a top-drawer briefcase
that you live out of.
And the purse. A Bottega.
Anyway, a man gets in my cab with
a sword, I figure he's a sushi chef.
- [Laughing]
- You?
Clarence Darrow.
Well, no, not quite. He worked defense.
I'm a prosecutor.
- Big case?
- Yeah.
[Sighs]
- Got us here fast.
- Of course.
But you didn't answer my question.
You like what you do?
Yeah.
But not today.
No, I do. Like, I can't wait.
I love standing in that courtroom.
At the same time, I get this...
...clenched up thing
the night before the first days.
Clenched up? How?
I think I'm going to lose.
I think the case sucks,
my exhibits aren't in order,
I'm not prepared enough, people will
find out I don't know what I'm doing
and I've been running a charade
all these years.
I represent the Department of Justice,
and my opening statement will fall flat
at the most important point
and the jury will laugh at me.
And then I cry.
I don't throw up.
A lot of people throw up.
I have a strong stomach.
And then I pull myself together,
I rewrite my opening statement...
work my exhibits and that's what I do
for the rest of the night.
That's my routine.
In the morning it starts and I'm fine.
You need a vacation.
I just had a vacation
on the Harbor Freeway.
Not in a cab.
You need to get your head straight.
Get your unified self up.
Get harmonic, you know...
- When did you last take a break?
- I go on vacation all the time.
- How often?
- A dozen times a day.
My favorite spot:
Maldives Islands.
It's my own private getaway.
Things get heavy for me, I take
five minutes out and I just go there.
And I just concentrate
on absolutely nothing.
- Here. Take it.
- I couldn't do that.
Take it because you need it
a lot more than I do.
And it'll help you.
I guarantee it.
Thanks, Max.
Go get 'em.
[Tapping]
Hey.
I don't know...
In case you ever want to investigate
a Fortune 500 company, or...
...argue cab routes.
- [Electronic beep]
- [Unlocking]
[Electronic beep]
Hey.
Come on, man, I'm sorry.
I didn't hear you, man. Come on.
I'll take you.
- Where to?
- 1039 South Union Street.
Gotcha.
- [Man] How long you think this'll take?
- [Max] Seven minutes.
Seven. Not eight? Not six?
Two minutes from the 110 to Normandie.
Normandie to Venice, three minutes.
Over to Union is one,
plus one for "shit happens."
- Okay if I time you?
- Knock yourself out.
What do I get if you're wrong?
A free ride?
An apology.
Already offered my free ride today.
- To who?
- Some girl.
Did you get a date with her?
First time in L.A.?
No. Tell you the truth, whenever
I'm here I can't wait to leave.
It's too sprawled out, disconnected.
You know? That's me.
- You like it?
- It's my home.
17 million people.
It's the fifth biggest economy in the world
and nobody knows each other.
I read about this guy
gets on the MTA here, dies.
[Max] Oh.
Six hours he rides the subway
before anyone notices his corpse
doing laps around L.A.,
people on and off sitting next to him.
Nobody notices.
[Man] This is the cleanest cab
I've ever been in.
[Man] Regular ride?
Yeah, I share it
with the day shift guy.
[Man] You prefer nights?
People are more relaxed.
Less stress, less traffic, better tips.
- [Man] How are the benefits?
- It's not that kind of job.
I'm not in this for the long haul.
Just filling in.
Temporary while I get
some things shaped up.
This is just temporary.
- How long you been driving?
- 12 years.
Really?
What other things you putting together?
Um...
You know, I don't want to talk about it.
Just a little business plan.
- No offense. I just...
- None taken.
You're one of these guys that do
instead of talk.
That's cool.
Seven minutes.
Man, you're good.
- I got lucky with the lights.
- Yeah, sure.
You probably know
the light schedules too.
Listen, I'm in town on a real estate deal,
close in one night.
I got five stops to make.
Collect signatures, see some friends,
and then I got a 6 a.m. Out of LAX.
- Why don't you hang with me?
- The car's not for hire. Against regs.
[Scoffing] Regulations?
They don't pay you sick leave.
How much you pull down a shift?
- How much?
- 350, 400.
Well, let me tell you what,
I'll make it 600.
Man, I don't know.
An extra 100 you get me to LAX
and I don't run for the plane.
- I don't know about this.
- Yeah, you do.
- I don't know, man.
- 600...
- Cool. We got a deal.
Now, here's 300 down.
What's your name?
- Max.
- Max, I'm Vincent.
[Max] All right.
I can't stay double-parked here.
I'll meet you in the alley
behind the building.
Definitely not from around here.
[Baby crying]
[Max] There you go.
[Speaking Spanish on television]
[Crashing]
Oh, no! Shit!
What the hell?!
Damn it!
My man, you all right?
[Panting] Oh, shit. Fuck.
He fell on the cab.
He fell from up there
on the motherfucking cab.
Shit. I think he's dead.
Good guess.
You killed him?
No, I shot him.
Bullets and the fall killed him.
Fuck this, man.
- Red light, Max.
- Hold on.
Put your hands down.
- Put your hands down.
- OK.
- Help me out. Pop the trunk.
- What?
Pop the trunk.
- Come on, man.
- Move.
Come on. What you doing?
We're going to roll him off the roof.
Can't leave him here, so unless
you want him up front with you,
- but given the hygiene.
- Oh, shit.
It's only a dead guy.
Grab his hands.
- I can't do this.
- Grab his wrists.
- You got it?
- He's twitching and shit.
[Max grunting]
Okay. That's good enough.
Let's go.
Why don't you just take the cab?
- Take the cab?
- You take it.
I'll chill.
I'll just chill.
They don't know who drives
these half the time.
They never check.
Okay, so just take it.
You, me...
- You promise not to tell anybody, right?
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Promise.
Get in the fucking car.
Get in the car.
[Tires squeal]
Ramone?
[Speaks Spanish]
Fuck.
- Rampart Watch Commander.
- This is Detective Fanning, Narcotics.
Send two black-and-whites and
a night detective to 1039 South Union.
And contact SID. I got a crime scene.
Roger. 1039 South Union.
[Cars honking]
- What are you doing?
- I got to clean up. This is a mess.
Lady Macbeth, we're sitting here
and the light's green. Leave the seats.
[Man] Asshole!
You no longer have the cleanest cab
in La-La Land.
You got to live with that.
You focus on the job. Drive.
7565 Fountain. You know it?
- West Hollywood.
- How long you figure?
I don't know, 17 minutes.
Why?
Oh, no. Hold on, man.
- I told you we had other stops tonight.
- You said you had to visit friends.
They're somebody's friends.
You drive a cab, I make my rounds.
You might make it through the night,
come out 700 bucks ahead.
I'm not trying to piss you off,
but I can't drive you around
while you kill people. It ain't my job.
Tonight it is.
Look, you don't get it.
I mean it.
[Stammering] I... I'm not up for this.
- [Vincent] You're stressed.
- Yes, I am.
[Vincent] You're stressed.
I understand that.
Now, you just keep breathing
and stay calm.
- Are you breathing?
- Shit.
- Are you breathing? Okay, good.
- Yes.
Here's the deal.
You were going to drive me tonight
and never be the wiser,
but el gordo got in front
of a window, did his high dive...
We're into plan B.
You still breathing?
We gotta make the best of it.
Improvise. Adapt to the environment.
Darwin. Shit happens. I Ching.
Whatever. We got to roll with it.
"I Ching"? You threw a man
out of a window.
I didn't throw him. He fell.
- [Max] Well, what did he do to you?
- What?
- [Max] What did he do to you?
- Nothing. I only met him tonight.
You just met him once and you kill him?
I should only kill people
after I get to know them?
- No, man.
- Six billion people on the planet,
and you're bent out of shape
because of one fat guy.
- Who was he?
- What do you care?
- Have you ever heard of Rwanda?
- Yes, I know Rwanda.
Tens of thousands killed
before sundown.
Nobody's killed people that fast
since Nagasaki and Hiroshima.
- Did you bat an eye, Max?
- What?
Did you join Amnesty International
or Oxfam?
Save the Whale, Greenpeace
or something? No.
I off one fat Angeleno
and you throw a hissy fit.
I don't know any Rwandans.
You don't know the guy
in that trunk either.
Man.
If it makes you feel better,
he was a criminal
involved in a continuing
criminal enterprise.
What, you just taking out the garbage?
- Something like that.
- [Siren]
- [officer] Pull over to the right.
- Shit.
- [Vincent] Get rid of them.
- How?
[Vincent] You're a cabby.
Talk yourself out of a ticket.
- Please, don't do anything.
- Then don't let me get cornered.
- You don't have trunk space.
- I can't believe this.
- Believe it.
- Don't. I'll talk to them.
[Radio] A domestic disturbance.
No additional units needed.
He's probably married.
The other one has kids.
Probably his wife's pregnant.
- [Tapping]
- I'll take care of it. I got it.
Just a second.
How you doing? My partner's going
to help you out on that side.
- License, registration.
- Uh, yeah.
I'm pulling you over
because your windshield's smashed.
- All this current?
- Yes, officer.
You have a food fight in here?
Yeah. I'll just clean it up.
Is this blood up here
on your windshield?
Yeah, uh...
Yeah, uh, I...
- I hit a deer.
- You hit a deer?
Yeah, over on...
- I was on Slauson.
- A South Central deer?
They out there. It ran right in front
of the car and I couldn't avoid it.
Why you still carrying a passenger?
I'm on my way to the depot and I could
just drop him. His drop is on my way.
Your cab's unsafe to drive
and we have to impound it.
We got to do a vehicle inventory.
Pop the trunk and step out the vehicle.
Sir, you'll have to call another cab.
Is that necessary?
I'm half a mile from here.
I'm afraid it is. Step out the vehicle.
You too. Come on.
- If you open that trunk, they go inside.
- You know what, it's been a long night.
Plus, the barn is right up there.
Just give me a break.
This is my first fare.
Get out the cab.
Open the trunk.
Step out.
You too, sir. Please.
[Radio] This is Rampart Division dispatch.
Shots fired at 83rd and Hoover.
All available Precinct 26 units respond.
Over.
- Partner, we got to roll.
- Roger. En route.
Go straight to the garage.
Have a nice night.
Stop here.
- Hands on the wheel, at 10 and 2.
- Why?
Because I say so.
[Radio] Max. You out there,
you son of a bitch?
Who is that?
That's Lenny. Just dispatch.
[Lenny] I know you're there.
Answer the call.
- What happens if you don't?
- He just keeps calling.
[Lenny] Max, answer.
Don't blow it.
- Lenny, what's up? It's me.
- Just got off the phone with the cops.
Desk sergeant called to check
if you brought the cab in.
Yeah, so?
So aside from
I hate talking to cops,
they tell me you crashed
the goddamn cab?
No. No, I got crashed into. I didn't...
Do I care what, where, why?
You're paying.
It was an accident.
You're not liable.
I'm not liable.
I'm making you liable.
It's coming out of your pocket.
Tell him to stick this cab
up his fat ass.
- I can't. That's my boss.
- So?
- I need my job.
- No, you don't.
[Lenny] You still there?
I'm talking to you.
He's not paying you
a damn thing.
[Lenny] Who the hell is this?
Albert Riccardo, Asst. U.S. Attorney.
A passenger in this cab
and I'm reporting you to the DMV.
[Lenny] Let's not get excited.
How do I not get excited, listening to you
try to extort a working man?
You know goddamn well
your collision policy
and liability umbrella
will cover the damages.
What are you trying to pull,
you sarcastic prick?
- [Lenny] I was just...
- Tell it to him.
Here, tell him he's an asshole.
Go ahead.
You're an asshole.
Tell him he pulls this shit again,
you'll stick this yellow cab up his fat ass.
And next time you pull any shit...
I'll have to stick this yellow cab
up your fat ass.
Crazy.
Shit!
[Phone ringing]
[On TV]... where a man wants his wife
back or a boyfriend-girlfriend thing.
We hear, "Get your protective order."
[Man] A protective order's
a tool we use,
but often times it's just
a piece of paper to the stalker.
- [man] Mr. Clarke, there's a notary here.
- Did he identify himself as a notary?
Yes, he did.
All right, sure, send him up.
[Woman on TV] Or shoots them?
That happens too often.
[Man on TV] But we use it as a tool.
I say a lot of times,
in this situation
strangers may write or call.
But how often, in fact, are stalkers
people that the recipient
of those affections knows?
[Honking]
[Max] Hey, I'm in the cab!
Hey!
Shit. Down here in the alley!
Shit.
[Honking]
Hey, hold up.
Oh, man, yeah.
Yeah, right there.
I'm in the cab, man, I'm stuck.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hey, look, I got to get out of here.
What's up? What's going on?
This guy tied me up,
but he's in this building,
doing wild shit.
- I need to get out of here.
- You all tied up in there, huh?
- Get me out so we can call the cops.
- Give me your wallet.
- Are you kidding me?
- Do I look like I'm kidding you?
Listen, don't you see that my hands
are tied to the steering wheel?
I don't care what they're tied to.
I'll fuck you up.
- Don't shoot, man.
- Then get your ass up.
Fuck.
What the fuck else you got in here?
Jackpot.
Thanks, for real. Bop!
Yo, homey.
- That my briefcase?
- This yours?
Yeah, it is.
Why, you want it back?
How about your wallet?
What else you got for me, huh?
Fuck!
Where's the button?
Under the dash?
Mind getting it?
You attract attention, you're going to
get people killed who didn't need to be.
You understand?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
But, hey, new news...
We're ahead of schedule.
- Like jazz?
- Sorry. What?
Jazz. You like jazz?
Not that much.
Guy told me about this place
off Crenshaw.
Leimert Park.
All the West Coast greats played there.
Dexter Gordon, Charlie Mingus,
Chet Baker. Like that.
Come on, finish up.
I'll buy you a drink.
- [Indistinct chatter]
- [Helicopter overhead]
What's your informant's name? Ramone?
Ramone Ayala. Supposed to meet him
in Bellflower last night.
He doesn't show up,
I roll here, find this.
- How long you been working this guy?
- Four months. He's a low-level player.
Part of a distribution network
that hooks up to Felix.
Felix Reyes-Torrena?
Feds are all over him,
don't want us anywhere near it.
Since when's LAPD
working for the Feeb?
They'll just take our stuff,
build their case, take the credit.
- What's the point?
- The point is my guy flew out a window.
So if my CI flies out a window,
he's got Felix's handprints on his ass.
That makes it mine.
Is there a crime here? A homicide?
You got a body?
- Just a bunch of broken glass.
- And blood.
Down here, in the glass.
Here's some more.
And there's some spatter patterns
over there and over here.
- [woman] Richard?
- Yeah, it's me.
Ramone went through that window...
splat.
Glass here, then tires rolled over it.
Maybe he jumped.
Sure. He's depressed so he jumps four
stories out of a window onto his head.
"That feels better."
Picks himself up.
"Now I think I'll go on
with the rest of my day."
- Come on, man.
- Hey, Ray!
Catch.
- Recent?
- You can still smell the cordite.
Old guy across the alley watching TV
says he saw a cab earlier tonight
- with two guys walking around the hood.
- Description? He see anything?
Kind of saw. Guy's got glasses
like Coke bottles.
There are 4,000 taxicabs in L.A. County.
You got anything else?
That's it.
Okay. Keep knocking.
Let's keep knocking.
Remember that Bay Area deal? Oakland?
Cabby drove around all night,
killed three people,
- then put the gun to his head.
- He flipped out. So what?
So that Oakland detective
never bought it.
Cabby had no criminal record
or history of mental illness.
Pops three people, then himself?
Anyway, that detective always thought
there was someone else in that cab.
[Jazz music plays]
I never learned to listen to jazz.
It's off melody. Behind the notes.
Not what's expected.
- Improvising, like tonight.
- Like tonight?
Most people, ten years from now,
same job, place, routine.
Everything the same.
Just keeping it safe over and over.
Ten years from now.
Man, you don't know where you'll be
ten minutes from now.
Do you?
Who is that on the trumpet?
[Woman] That's Daniel, baby,
he's the owner.
He's terrific. Would you be so kind
as to invite him over after his set?
- I got to buy him a drink.
- Sure thing, darling.
[Daniel] Now see, I was about 19,
bussing tables right here.
The money wasn't shit,
but that wasn't the point.
It was about being around the music.
And I was.
Take this one night. July 22nd, 1964.
Who you think walks through that door?
[Woman] Bye, baby.
- Miles Davis. That's right.
- In the flesh?
I'm talking about through those doors,
the coolest man on the planet.
Jesus.
Anyway, he had been recording a session
up at Columbia, up on Vine.
So Miles comes through that door.
Before you know it, he's up on
the bandstand, jamming with the band.
I mean, it had to be...
Oh, it was scary.
I mean, the dude was so focused, man.
Plus, he was kind of
a scary cat anyway.
Everybody and their mama knew you don't
just come up and talk to Miles Davis.
I mean, he may have looked like
he was chilling, but he was absorbed.
This one young, hip couple, one of them
tried to shake his hand one day.
And the guy says,
"Hi, my name is..."
Miles said, "Get out of my face,
you jive motherfucker.
Take your silly bitch with you."
[Both laugh]
You know? That was Miles, man.
That's the way he was when he was
in his musical headspace. Fierce.
- But did you get to talk to him?
- Better than that.
I played for about 20 minutes.
[Vincent] Unbelievable.
- How'd you do?
- How'd I do?
You really ain't shit
playing next to Miles Davis.
But he carried my ass.
[Vincent] What'd he say?
He said one word: Cool.
Cool?
- That's it?
- Yeah.
That meant, "Good, but not ready."
It meant, "Look me up when you are."
Did you?
No. I got drafted
and got into some other things.
And by the time I got back to music,
season had passed.
You know, I was born in 1945,
but that night was the moment
of my conception.
- Right here in this room.
- Crowd's not here now.
Well, jazz ain't the draw
that it used to be.
What a great story.
I got to tell the people in Culiacan
and Cartagena that story.
You know the folks
in Culiacan and Cartagena?
Afraid so.
Just when I thought
you were a cool guy.
I am a cool guy with a job
I contracted to do.
- Come on, give the dude a pass.
- I'm working here.
You're the one talking
about improvisation.
You like the guy, how he plays.
Let's just play a little jazz.
Improvi...
That's funny coming from you.
How's this?
- I'll ask a question.
- [Daniel] What question?
A jazz question.
Now, you get it right, we roll.
You disappear tonight.
If I walk out of here tonight,
I will go so far away,
it'll be just like I was dead.
And one more thing: These people
and their rep here, Felix...
Well, you tell them I'm sorry.
You tell them I had to.
They laid a grant of immunity on me.
It was either play ball
or go back inside.
And I'm not going back inside.
Yeah.
Lay it on me.
Where did Miles learn music?
- I know everything about Miles.
- Then let's have it.
Music school.
He got into music school, right?
His father was a dentist,
east St. Louis.
Invested in agriculture,
made plenty of money.
He sent Miles to Juilliard School
of Music, New York, 1945.
Man.
Dropped out in less than a year, tracked
down Charlie Parker on 52nd Street
who mentored him
for the next three years.
Hey.
- No, I'm done. Find you another cab.
- Max.
Leave me alone.
I'm collateral, anyway.
[Grunting]
[Max panting]
I am not playing.
You played him, man.
He got the answer right...
...would you have let him go?
[Lenny on radio] 102. Max.
What is it with this guy?
- You hassling my driver again?
- Who are you?
The same guy you talked to last time.
Max's mother's driving me crazy.
Put him on the line, please.
Hang on.
Carefully.
Yeah?
Your mother's calling.
"Why didn't you show?
- Are you all right? Where are you?"
- [Vincent] Show for what?
Tell her I can't make it tonight.
I'm not related to you.
Tell her yourself.
Show up for what?
She's in the hospital.
- You visit every night?
- Yeah. What's the difference?
- You don't show up, it breaks routine.
- So?
So people start looking for you, this cab.
That's not good.
I'm not taking you to see my mother.
Since when was any of this negotiable.
Two paces ahead, one to the left.
Flowers?
It's a waste of money.
Won't mean a thing to her.
She carried you in her womb
for nine months.
People buy flowers. Buy flowers.
Excuse me.
Keep the change.
[Bell rings]
[Man] Hold that elevator, please.
- Floor?
- Five. Thanks.
- Having a good night?
- Mezzo mezzo.
You?
Excuse me.
Hey, Ma.
I've been calling and calling.
- I got caught up at work.
- Why couldn't you call me?
I'm lying here wondering if something
terrible happened to you.
- I brought you flowers.
- What am I gonna do with flowers?
- Cheer up.
- How?
By worrying that you spend money
on stuff that's just going to wilt and die?
See what I mean?
I didn't buy you the flowers. He did.
Who?
Why didn't you tell me we had company?
What's your name?
Sorry my son is rude.
No harm done, ma'am.
You paid for my flowers?
They're beautiful.
Well, Max?
Mother, this is Vincent.
Vincent, this is my mother, Ida.
I am very happy to meet you,
Mrs. Durocher.
[Chuckling] Oh, just call me Ida.
Ida. I was with Max
when he got the call.
- [Lda] You came here to see me?
- [Vincent] It's nothing, ma'am.
Tell my son.
You have to hold a gun to his head
to make him do anything.
You must be one of
Max's important clients.
Client? You know, I like to think
of myself as his friend.
[Lda] Max never had many friends.
Always talking to himself in the mirror.
It's unhealthy.
How many times I got to ask
don't do that?
Do what?
Don't talk about me like
I'm not right here in the room here.
What's he saying?
[Vincent] He says he's standing
right here in the room here.
Yes, you are.
He's sensitive.
I know. But I'm sure
you're very proud of him.
Of course I'm proud.
He started with nothing, you know?
Look at him today.
Here, Vegas...
Mom, he is not interested in hearing
about all that, okay?
I came to see you, I saw you,
you look good, let's go.
I am very interested, Ida. Please.
- Limousine companies.
- Is that right?
He drives famous people around.
Famous people. Limousine companies.
Now, that's quite an achievement.
- [Lda] What did you say your name was?
- My name's Vincent, ma'am.
Visit again?
[Vincent] No, I'm just in town tonight.
- [Lda] When you come back.
- [Vincent] Sure.
Max!
Don't!
[Max screams]
All my prep was in there.
You are screwing with my work.
[Ragged breathing]
Let's see what else you can do.
[Max groans]
Well, I've had four come in tonight.
Maybe one's your guy.
No, not Ramone. Let's see this one.
No, next.
There's something funny
about this, though.
These three all came in within
half an hour of each other, right?
The kid and that last guy,
both done by the same shooter, I think.
Why do you say that?
Wound pattern.
Two in the sternum, one in the head.
This guy is shooting tight groups too,
all right? Check this out.
Double taps are
a couple millimeters apart.
Let's see this one.
See what I mean?
Holy shit.
Can I use your phone?
Come on, come on, wake up.
[Ringing]
Hello.
It's Fanning. I'm still down here
at the morgue at Sisters of Charity.
John Does didn't pan out, but you'll
never guess who's in the meat locker.
Who?
Sylvester Clarke, criminal attorney
turned lawyer criminal.
[Fanning] Including Ramone,
who he represented, who's still missing.
Both are in
the exotic substances business together.
There's something going on,
and I don't think the feds know about it.
Stay on your cell phone.
I got the ASAC's phone.
I'll hook up with you in 30 minutes.
Good.
Going to a place called El Rodeo.
It's on Washington Boulevard, Pico Rivera.
- Where at on Washington?
- Look it up.
Limos, huh?
Don't start.
I'm not the one lying to my mother.
She hears what she wants to hear.
I don't disillusion her.
Right. Maybe she hears
what you tell her.
Whatever I tell her's never good enough.
It's always been that way.
So, what's at El Rodeo?
Just drive.
They project onto you their flaws.
What they don't like about themselves,
their lives, whatever.
They rank on you instead.
How do you know?
I had a father like that.
- Mothers are worse.
- Wouldn't know.
My mother died
before I remember her.
What happened to your father?
Hated everything I did.
Got drunk, beat me up, foster homes.
Went back with him. Like that.
Then what?
I killed him.
I was 12.
[Laughing]
I'm kidding.
He died of liver disease.
Well, I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
So, what is this "driving a cab temporarily."
It's all bullshit?
It is not bullshit.
[Vincent] 12 years isn't temporary.
Got to get the cash together.
Insurance, bonds, maintenance, tires.
Got to staff up,
get the right client list.
It's not just get the car
and put asses in the seats.
Why not?
Because Island Limos
is more than just a ride.
It's like a club experience.
Cool groove.
Don't want it to end.
It's got to be perfect.
Perfect.
It's up here. Turn right.
Give me your wallet. Come on.
Give you my wallet. For what?
I'll hold it for you
in case the people inside search you.
- Who's searching?
- The people inside.
Go in, ask for Felix.
He's expecting you.
- Felix. What does he look like?
- I don't know, I never met him.
Who is he?
He's connected to the guys
who hired me.
I don't get it.
You destroyed my work-ups.
Number four is due.
What'd you think, night's over?
Called on account of rain?
Go in there, say you're me.
Score the backups.
- They'll be on flash drive or CD.
- How come you don't...
I don't meet people. Anonymity.
I protect mine.
You're not going to screw that up.
Contract's with their bosses.
These guys don't meet me,
or know what I look like.
If I don't pull it off, then...
They will kill you.
You got 10 minutes.
At 10:01, I execute your mother
on my way out of town.
- Don't pretend indifference.
- I can't do this.
- I can't.
- Sure you can. Come on. Hey, hey.
If I do this, I'm just going to end up
getting people killed.
Out of options. Take comfort in knowing
you never had a choice.
- How long you been doing this?
- Why?
Just in case they ask me.
- Private sector? Six years.
- Okay. All right. Six years.
You get benefits?
Or, you know, insurance? Pension?
No. No paid sick leave.
Quit stalling, get out of the cab.
[Max sighing]
[Indistinct chatter, music]
Hold on, man.
Who's this?
Mark the time.
All right, he's clean.
What's up, Holmes?
I'm here to see Felix.
He has something for me.
Don't know no Felix.
Tell him...
Say it's Vincent.
I'm Vincent.
[Speaks Spanish]
[Indistinct, on walkie-talkie]
Copy.
Let him in. Let him in right now.
[Door clattering open]
Detective Richard Weidner, LAPD,
Major Narcotics Division.
- Detective Ray Fanning...
- OK, how are you? Agent Frank Pedrosa.
- Thanks for seeing us.
- How can I help?
Why do you want to know
about our case?
- Any unusual activity tonight?
- Like what?
That relates to a series of murders
in Wilshire Central or West Hollywood?
All quiet on the western front.
Various people are asleep.
Various people are not.
They come and go in cars,
pickups, taxis.
Other than that, we watch air move.
- Your interest in our case?
- We got a situation. Two bodies.
Could be a coincidence,
could not be a coincidence.
It doesn't look like one.
We got an attorney and his client...
Roof's all beat to shit.
- Can you zoom in on this?
- On what?
On that.
- [Fanning] Look at that right there.
- [Weidner] What is it?
Yeah.
5-queen-4-9-9-7-4.
5Q49974.
[Jazzy Latin music plays]