[distant gunfire]
[birdsong]
There are over 550,000,000 firearms
in worldwide circulation.
That's one firearm
for every twelve people on the planet.
The only question is...
...how do we arm the other eleven?
/# Buffalo Springfield:
For What It's Worth]
# There's somethin' happenin' here
# But what it is ain't exactly clear
# There's a man with a gun over there
# Tellin' me I got to beware
# I think it's time we
Stop, children, what's that sound?
# Everybody look what's goin' down
[chatter]
# There's battle lines bein' drawn
# And nobody's right
If everybody's wrong
# Young people speakin' their minds
# Are gettin' so much resistance
From behind
# It's time we stop, hey,
What's that sound?
# Everybody look what's goin' down
# What a field-day for the heat
# A thousand people in the street
# Singin' songs
And they're carryin' signs
# Mostly say "hooray for our side"
# It's time we stop, hey
What's that sound?
# Everybody look what's goin' down
# Paranoia strikes deep
# Into your life it will creep
# It starts when you're always afraid
# You step outta line
The man come and take you away
# You better stop, children
What's that sound?
# Everybody look what's goin' down
# There's battle lines bein' drawn
# Nobody's right if everybody's wrong
# Young people speakin' their minds
# Are gettin' so much resistance
From behind
# It's time we stop, hey
What's that sound?
# Everybody look what's goin' down #
[man] You don't have to worry.
I'm not gonna tell you a pack of lies
to make me look good.
I'm just gonna tell you what happened.
My name is Yuri Orlov.
When I was a boy,
my family came to America.
But not all the way.
Like most Ukrainians,
we congregated in Brighton Beach.
It reminded us of the Black Sea.
I soon realised we'd just
swapped one hell for another.
Even in hell, an angel
sometimes makes an appearance.
I'd worshipped Ava Fontaine
since I was ten years old.
Of course, she didn't know I existed.
I was startin' to think
she had a point.
For the first 20-odd years of my life,
Little Odessa was to me
what it is to the Q train:
the end of the line.
Oh, I did lie about my name.
It's not really Yuri Orlov.
There've been few occasions
in the 20th century
when it's been an advantage
to be a Jew, but in the '70s,
to escape the Soviet Union,
our family pretended to be Jewish.
Little about my life
has been kosher ever since.
- How's it goin', brother?
- It's not.
That's Vitaly, my younger brother.
He was as lost as me,
he just didn't know it yet.
Yuri. [Russian]
You late.
My father took
his assumed identity to heart.
He was more Jewish
than most Jews,
which drove my Catholic mother crazy.
How many times?
I can't eat shellfish. It's treyf.
- You're not Jewish.
- I like it.
I like the hat. It remind us
there is something above us.
I like that.
I'm going to temple.
You're not going to temple.
You go more than the rabbi.
[Russian]
[mother speaks Russian]
Yuri. Don't forget to check
the specials at The Palace.
Growing up in Little Odessa,
murder was an everyday part of life.
Russian mobsters had also migrated
from the Soviet Union,
and, when they came to America,
their baggage came with them.
[tyres screeching]
Gangsters were always
getting whacked in my neighbourhood,
but I'd never seen it
with my own eyes.
I had this knack of showing up
five minutes before,
or five minutes after.
Not that day.
[# plaintive violin]
It hit me. It couldn't have hit me
harder if I was the one who'd been shot.
You go into the restaurant business
because people
are always going to have to eat.
That was the day I realised
my destiny lay in fulfilling
another basic human need.
The next Sabbath,
I went to temple with my father.
However, it wasn't God
I was tryin' to get close to.
[father] Eli, my elder son, Yuri.
My contact at synagogue landed me my
first Israeli-made Uzi sub-machine guns.
The first time you sell a gun is a lot
like the first time you have sex.
You have no idea what you're doing,
but it is exciting,
and, one way or another,
it's over way too fast.
Gentlemen.
The new Uzi machine pistol,
big firepower in a small package.
This baby uses 9-mm hollow points,
twenty 25-round extendable mags.
Rear flip adjustable sights.
Excellent recoil reduction.
Muzzle jump reduced 40%.
60% improved noise suppression.
You could pump a mag
into me right now
and never wake the guy
in the next room.
Of course, that would eliminate
your opportunity for repeat business.
I did have a natural instinct
for smuggling contraband.
Fortunately, back then,
a video camera was as big as a bazooka.
[sigh of relief]
I'd been running away
from violence my whole life,
and I should have been
running towards it.
It's in our nature.
The earliest human skeletons
had spearheads in their ribcages.
/# David Bowie: Young Americans]
[father] Where have you been?
What if we had a customer?
God bless America.
[cash register rings]
- Mm. Mm-hm.
- Yeah?
- [choking noises]
- [Vitaly speaks Russian]
"Beware of the dog"? You don't have
a dog. Are you tryin' to scare people?
Nah, it's to scare me. Remind me
to beware of the dog in me.
The dog that wants to fuck everything,
to fight and kill weaker dogs.
I guess it's, uh, to remind me
to be more human.
Isn't bein' a dog part of bein' human?
What if that's the best part of you,
the dog part?
What if you're really
just a two-legged dog?
You need to see somebody.
It stinks in here.
I'd always wanted to do
something big with my life,
I just didn't know what.
Anyhow, I figured,
if I was going into the gun trade,
I was goin' to aim high.
[Yuri] Vitaly, stop fuckin' around,
I wanna talk to you.
[seagulls]
You read the newspapers, Vit?
Newspaper? [scoffs]
It's always the same.
You're right. Every day there's people
shootin' each other.
Know what I do
when I see that?
I look to see what guns they're using,
and I think "Why not my guns?"
You opening a gun shop?
Already more of those
in America than McDonald's.
Even with all the gangsters here,
the margins are too low.
- You've worked out the margins?
- Sure.
Forget gang wars.
The real money's in actual wars.
Between countries.
Yuri, what the fuck
do you know about guns?
I know which end I'd rather be on.
I made the first sale.
We're already in business.
Whoa... We?
I need a partner.
I don't know.
I don't know, Yuri. I don't know.
Vitaly, I've tasted your borscht,
you're no chef.
I can eat in the restaurant for free,
and I still don't.
- Fuck you.
- We're doing nothing with our lives.
I mean...
This is shit. This is shit.
That's true,
but maybe doin' nothing's
better than doin' this.
I need you.
[Russian]
/# Wagner: Ride of the Valkyries]
[man] Sir, sir,
may I interest you in the shoulder-fired
SA-7 surface-to-air missiles?
The older model, not so effective
against modern military aircraft
but deadly if used against a commercial
airliner. I'm giving them away at 850.
It was the '80s,
and the Cold War was far from thawed.
Most deals
were government-to-government.
It was a mostly private club,
with a lifetime club president.
- That's him.
- Oh, the big shot?
Simeon Weisz.
Angola, Mozambique.
Those Exocet missiles in the Falklands.
He was selling guns
before there was gunpowder.
I'll be right back.
Mr Weisz? Mr Weisz?
It's OK, they're talking.
- May I help?
- Yes. A mutual friend,
Eli Kurtzman, from Brighton Beach,
said to contact you.
I have a business proposal.
Perhaps we could discuss it.
I don't think you and l
are in the same business. [laughs]
You think I just sell guns, don't you?
I don't. I take sides.
But in the lran/lraq war,
you sold guns to both sides.
Did you ever consider
that I wanted both sides to lose?
Bullets change governments
far surer than votes.
You're in the wrong place,
my young friend.
This is no place for amateurs.
[Russian]
Curious how you revert to your native
tongue in moments of extreme anger.
And ecstasy.
[man and woman groaning]
[Russian]
[laughter, groaning]
[Vitaly] Oh, you are beautiful.
What's your name again?
[television in German]
The only option for Vitaly and me
was under-the-counter gunrunning.
I got my first break in Lebanon,
after the suicide bombing.
But I wasn't the only
local kid making good.
[distant gunfire]
When the United States
leaves a war zone,
they generally don't take
their munitions.
It costs more to bring it back
than to buy new stock.
[Yuri] So.
We sell by the kilo.
They're second-hand weapons,
but they're still OK.
- How many kilos would you like?
- 5,000.
I had a flair for languages,
but I soon discovered
that what talks best
is dollars, dinars, drachmas, roubles,
rupees and pounds fuckin' sterling.
Of course, the US Army
got a piece of the action.
Army salaries were no better
in the '80s than they are today.
Some of the brass,
like Lieutenant Colonel Southern,
needed to raise money
for their own private wars.
Good to make your acquaintance.
This is bullshit money, Vit.
This is small fucking potatoes.
- What, you wanna go more legit?
- No, more illegal.
What I would give right now
for a plate of cabbage and potatoes.
[gunfire]
It's not our fight.
Vit, come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Selling guns
is like selling vacuum cleaners:
you make calls,
pound the pavement, take orders.
I was an equal-opportunity
merchant of death.
I supplied every army
but the Salvation Army.
I sold Israeli-made Uzis to Muslims.
/# Flying Lizards:
Money (That's What I Want)]
I sold communist-made bullets
to fascists.
[Asian language]
I even shipped cargo to Afghanistan when
they were fighting my fellow Soviets.
I never sold to Osama bin Laden
Not on any moral grounds. Back then,
he was always bouncing cheques.
[gunfire]
By the mid-'80s,
my weapons were represented
in eight of the world's
top ten war zones.
[ringing of cash register]
There's no problem
leading a double life.
It's the triple and quadruple lives
that'll get you.
Back then I carried a French, British,
Israeli and Ukrainian passport,
and a student visa for the US,
but that's another story.
I also packed six different briefcases
depending on who I was that day
and the region of the world
I was visiting.
Without operations like mine,
it would be impossible for certain
countries to conduct a respectable war.
I was able to navigate around those
inconvenient little arms embargoes.
There are three
basic types of arms deal:
white, being legal;
black, being illegal;
and my personal
favourite colour, grey.
Sometimes I made
the deal so convoluted
it was hard for me to work out
if they were on the level.
To fool authorities,
I often spoke in code.
Rocket-launchers were "mothers",
rockets "children",
the AK-47 assault rifle
was the "Angel King".
It's Yuri. [laughs]
Yeah. Well, yeah, Raoul.
Raoul, the Angel King
will arrive tomorrow. [laughs]
Hallelujah to you too. All right.
The point is, if I've done my job right,
an arms embargo should be
- practically impossible to enforce.
- [telephone]
What?
OK, just slow the fuck down.
I can't understand you. What?
What do you mean, "tipped off'?
They know where we are?
Where are they?
Well, how long have I got?
"Not long"?
What does that mean? Shit.
- Do we try to lose them?
- On this?
- Yuri, we have to get off.
- No one's going anywhere.
Slow. Dead slow. Buy me time.
[bell rings]
Yeah, it's Yuri.
Get that fuckin' rag down!
I need another handle for this tub.
Something in our weight class.
You! Over the side.
We're changing the name. Now!
Yes, it's gotta check out!
The way I look at it,
what's in a name?
You got a shorter name?
I'd often changed the registration
of a ship or plane,
but never at such short notice.
Damn. They're hauling.
What? "Kono"? How do you spell that?
K-O-N-O. OK, well, that's good.
"Kono". K-O-N-O.
What do we fly? Dutch? Got it.
Vit, get me a Dutch flag, will you?
- Faster, or I'll send your arse in!
- Yuri, I don't have Dutch!
- What?
- I've got Belgium.
What use is that? He's painting a name
registered in the fucking Netherlands.
- I've got a French flag.
- So?
Turn it sideways, it's Dutch.
[Yuri laughs]
That's why you're my brother.
[Yuri] Good.
Everybody look innocent now.
They say every man has his price,
but not every man gets it.
Interpol agent Jack Valentine
couldn't be bought,
at least not with money.
For Jack, glory was the prize.
Yeah, it's the Kono,
it's not the Kristol.
Kono, K-O-N-O.
- [man] It's clean,sir.
- Clean? It sure doesn't look clean.
I'm gonna go aboard.
Phone in a sighting
of the Kristol south of Aruba.
Even when I was up
against an overzealous agent,
I had a number of methods
for discouraging a search.
I routinely mislabelled
my arms shipments "farm machinery",
and I've yet to meet
the customs official
who will open a container
marked "radioactive waste"
to verify its contents.
But my favourite is the unique
combination of week-old potatoes
and tropical heat.
It smells.
Sir, a sighting of the Kristol,
due north.
Most importantly, I kept a number
of intelligence people on the payroll
to supply their colleagues
with counter-intelligence.
Let's go.
The second rule of gunrunning is,
always ensure you have
a foolproof way to get paid,
preferably in advance,
ideally to an off-shore account.
That's why I chose customers carefully.
Say what you like
about warlords and dictators,
they have a highly developed
sense of order.
They always pay their bills on time.
[Spanish]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- What are you doing?
- Fuck you!
Fuck you!
Ah, ah... No, Vit!
[Yuri] Shit.
The first and most
important rule of gunrunning
is never get shot
with your own merchandise.
You OK?
[sighs] I think so.
- So what do we do now?
- Let's celebrate.
/# Eric Clapton: Cocaine]
Aah!
[yelps]
That narco-guerrilla
had his facts right.
After shipping it stateside,
the return netted me a healthy profit.
It would've been even better,
except one kilo never made it back.
Vitaly? Vit?
To this day, I don't know
what Vitaly was running away from.
Maybe just from Vitaly.
I found him 12 days,
2000 miles and 1 50 grams later
in a Bolivian boarding house.
Of course, my dream girl
had gotten there before me.
Vit?
[Yuri] C'mon!
[knocking]
Ah, Yuri. It's my brother, Yuri.
He's my big brother.
- What the fuck is that?
- Ukraine.
I was young, but I remember.
Look. I...I start in Odessa, right,
and then l... [gulps]
I work my way to the Crimean...
You're gonna be dead before Kiev.
We're goin' home.
- Come on.
- You fuck! You...fucking fuck!
You fucking fuck!
What the fuck is your problem?
[Vitaly grunts]
[Yuri] Come on, Vit.
- [Vitaly] It's so nice to be home.
- Yeah, we're gonna get you home. C'mon.
[Yuri exhales deeply]
Get out of the car.
Vitaly, I need you
to get out of the car.
I promised our parents.
- Please.
- You're gonna have a great time.
It's a top place. Two Ford Models
checked in last week,
that cute weathergirl's
been here since July...
Please.
Please, Yuri.
You're a good brother.
- You're a good brother, Yuri.
- OK. All right.
- Good brother.
- All right, get out of the car.
OK. Get out of the car.
From then on,
I was a one-man operation.
I never understood what separated the
recreation drug-user from the habitual,
but, for the grace of God,
it could have been me
snorting lines
as long as the Belt Parkway.
However, I wasn't entirely free
of the grip of addiction myself.
There she was again,
Ava Fontaine.
In my neighbourhood,
they say the good get out.
In our own ways,
we'd both conquered the world.
/# Grace Jones: La Vie en Rose]
You can't force someone to fall in love
with you, but you can improve your odds.
It cost me 20 grand to book her
for a fake photo-shoot,
another 12 to buy out the hotel.
It's a popular hotel, huh?
- Ava Fontaine.
- Yuri Orlov.
- What brings you to St Barts?
- Photo-shoot.
At least that was the plan. Guess
the photographer got stuck in Miami.
Hurricane,
though there's nothing on the news.
Those things can come out of nowhere.
So the job's been cancelled, and
there's no flight back until Tuesday.
You can hitch a ride with me
if you like. I'm leaving tomorrow.
Meanwhile,
why don't I take your picture?
In my experience,
some of the most successful
relationships are based on lies.
Since that's where they usually end up,
it's a logical place to start.
Right there, right there.
Hold it. Oh, my God.
I nearly went broke
convincing her I was anything but.
I knew Ava was not a woman to be
seduced by a ride in a private jet,
unless you owned the jet.
- This is your plane?
- That is my name.
Course I was lying.
The plane was a rental, like the car
and even the suit I was standing in.
At the last minute,
I bribed the crew for the paint job.
Luckily, by he time we landed, Ava
wasn't looking anywhere but in my eyes.
I had no idea.
I'm sorry I didn't recognise you.
Don't apologise.
I put clothes on for a living.
At least you're not taking them off.
I would be if half the photographers
had their way. What about you?
I'm in transport.
International air freight, mostly.
Business is good.
Where are you from?
I was born in Ukraine,
but grew up in Brooklyn.
- No.
- What, you too?
Williamsburg.
Well, here's to a hurricane.
Without it, I never would have met you.
This is no accident, is it, Yuri?
It feels like...fate.
I don't believe in fate.
What do you believe in?
- Is that a view, or is that a view?
- That's a view.
[applause]
[Yuri] Thank you. Thank you all.
[murmuring voices, music]
- [father] Mazel tov.
- Congratulations.
Thanks.
Always remember, son.
There is something above you.
Sure, Dad.
A $40,000 crystal chandelier.
Make yourselves at home. Go.
- Go!
- [all laugh]
/# Louis Armstrong:
A Kiss To Build A Dream On]
I'm sorry. Today must be tough.
Be nice to have a couple more guests
from my side of the family.
- I'm sure they're watching right now.
- Thank you.
But you don't believe that, Yuri.
Remember?
I know you, Yuri.
I know you're not everything you seem.
Don't worry,
I won't ask a lot of questions.
I don't wanna hear you lie.
You take risks. Just...
...promise me you won't risk us.
That's the trouble
with falling in love with a dream girl.
They have a habit of becoming real.
I've never been so glad to see Vitaly.
You're fuckin' beautiful!
Brother, brother, thank you so much
for giving me such a...beautiful sister.
He was out of rehab,
and out of his mind.
Dance, dance, we have to dance!
- All right.
- It's a celebration. To Yuri!
But for once, he rescued me.
I was still living way beyond my means,
mortgaged to the hilt,
using one credit card
to pay off another,
anything to keep Ava
in the style to which she had,
thanks largely to me,
become accustomed.
- Ava. Ava, this is too much.
- Yuri likes to spoil you.
Then suddenly,
all my Christmases came at once.
[Ava] Nicki, you did it! Good boy!
[laughs]
That's my grandson!
Yuri, come see
what your son is doing!
Whoever said it's better
to give than receive
never got a Christmas present
like the one I got in 1991
- from Mikhail Gorbachev.
- What the hell's the matter?
- It's over!
- What's over?
The Cold fuckin' War!
The Soviet fuckin' Union.
Mikhail's saying "no mas"!
He's thrown in the towel!
It's over!
- Your son is walking.
- That's incredible, honey.
At least they'll get religious freedom.
Hm. Let's hope so.
I think I'll go back for a visit.
You stay in touch with Uncle Dmitri?
I'm not a fool, Yuri.
I don't think you're going
there just to sell Pepsi-Cola.
Is this how you want to be remembered?
I don't want to be remembered at all.
If I'm remembered, it means I'm dead.
[door opening]
Merry fuckin' Christmas!
[giggling]
- Who is this, Vitaly?
- [woman laughs]
- I'm Angel.
- Her name really is Angel.
She's a fairy.
Let's put her on top
of the Christmas tree! C'mon.
[Vitaly] Whoa! C'mon.
- [Vitaly] I love you.
- [Yuri] C'mon.
- I love you all.
- [Nicki crying]
Take this.
I'm going back to Ukraine.
I miss Odessa.
- I miss you.
[kisses him]
Be careful, Yuri.
Those things you sell kill. [sighs]
Inside.
You're high.
That's true.
Hello, Christian.
/# military band music]
During the Cold War,
the Red Army stationed
nearly one million troops in Ukraine
because of its strategic
military importance.
The day after the Wall came down,
the pay cheques stopped.
[Russian]
There's nothing better
for an arms dealer
than the combination of disgruntled
soldiers and warehouses of weapons.
I was hoping Maj. Gen. Dmitri Volkoff
would open a lot of armoury doors
in a lot of military bases.
For a start, he was family,
a highly decorated
hero of the Red Army,
and he was almost
permanently shit-faced.
I can't just sell you
government property, Yuri.
- I have to report.
- Report to who? Moscow?
As of last week,
Moscow's in a foreign country.
- New flag, new boss.
- There is no new boss yet.
They're too busy squabbling
over who gets the presidential
holiday home at the Black Sea.
It's beautiful.
The ones who know don't care any more,
and the ones who care don't know.
[Yuri] Mm. Show me your inventory.
Those 45 years of mutual hatred
between the East and the West
had generated the highest
weapons build-up in history.
The Soviets had guns
coming out of the demon hole.
Huge stockpiles,
and now no enemy.
How many Kalashnikovs do you have?
40,000.
Is that a four? It doesn't look like
a four to me. It looks more like a one.
No, it's a four.
It's whatever we say it is, because
no one else will know the difference.
[sighs] Ten thousand
Kalashnikovs for a battalion.
Your stocks
are dangerously depleted, Dmitri.
You should order more from the factory.
Someone will work it out.
- What happens then?
- We'll cut them in.
The end of the Cold War
was the beginning
of the hottest time in arms dealing.
The arms bazaar was open.
Guided missiles, unguided missiles.
Mortars, mines,
armoured personnel carriers.
Whole tank divisions.
[Russian]
I even landed a squadron
of helicopter gunships.
The most sophisticated
fighting machines,
built for a war with America
that never happened.
[Russian]
Thanks to me, they'd finally
get to fire a shot in anger.
I have a feeling it wasn't exactly
what Comrade Lenin had in mind
when he advocated
the redistribution of wealth.
But I wasn't the only one
offering a crash course in capitalism.
I had rivals.
Inform your commanding officer
that Simeon Weisz is here to meet him.
You don't know who I am, do you?
[Russian]
[speaks Russian]
You're late.
So it appears.
[# Russian folk music]
You look a little lost, Simeon.
Is the world changing too fast?
- I'm here, aren't l?
- Not all of you, I think.
You've gotten so rich
selling for the ClA,
you can't get that ideology
out of your head.
Oh, the Cold War had its uses.
Kept the tensions frozen.
Now it's harder to determine...
which side one's on.
Things have become
more...complicated.
No, it's gotten simpler.
There's no place in gunrunning
for politics any more.
I sell to leftists and rightists.
I'd sell to pacifists, but they're not
the most regular of customers.
You're not an internationalist
until you've supplied weapons
to kill your own countrymen.
This current state of chaos
won't last forever.
There'll have to be order.
Instead of cutting
each other's throats, it...
...may be beneficial if we work
together. What do you think?
What do I think?
I think you are the amateur now,
and I think you should go with your
instincts, with your first instinct.
I'm the same man who was
not good enough for you before, and...
...I'm just not good enough for you now.
The problem
with gunrunners going to war...
...is that there's no shortage
of ammunition.
This was the chaos
that the old guard had always feared.
As far as they were concerned,
I was giving arms dealers a bad name.
But then, they could hardly report me
to the Better Business Bureau.
And Ukraine wasn't the only former state
with an unpaid army
and stockpiles of guns.
There was Bulgaria,
Hungary, Poland, Belarus.
All there for the taking.
/# T chaikovsky: Swan Lake]
Of all the weapons
in the vast Soviet arsenal,
nothing was more profitable
than Avtomat Kalashnikova,
model of 1 947,
more commonly known as the AK-47,
or Kalashnikov.
It's the world's
most popular assault rifle,
a weapon all fighters love.
An elegantly simple 9-pound amalgamation
of forged steel and plywood.
It doesn't break, jam or overheat.
It will shoot whether it's covered
in mud or filled with sand.
It's so easy, even a child can use it,
and they do.
The Soviets put the gun on a coin.
Mozambique put it on their flag.
Since the end of the Cold War, it has
become the Russians' greatest export.
After that comes vodka,
caviar and suicidal novelists.
One thing's for sure:
no one was lining up to buy their cars.
[seagulls]
[Russian]
I thought you were watching out
for them.
How can l?
You keep selling my helicopters!
You are too greedy, Yuri.
I can't hold him forever!
- I've got paperwork.
- Not for the gunships.
You know the penalty
for sanction-busting?
Selling the military helicopter
is a major violation.
Military helicopter.
It's not a military helicopter.
It's a rescue helicopter.
Get to work, son.
The law's on our side.
[Valentine] All right,
let me see your papers.
No, no, put that away.
Let me see your papers.
Yuri Orlov.
Always in the wrong place
at the right time.
We've met before.
Off the coast of Colombia?
What was the name of that freighter?
Was it the Kono or the Kristol?
The crew called that vessel a lot
of names, none of them repeatable.
- [gun cocked]
- Answer the question.
The new MP-5.
- Would you like a silencer for that?
- I need to see your papers.
Dmitri.
The end user certificate for this
aircraft states "Burkina Fasou".
Nice. Very nice.
Did you type this up yourself?
The helicopter's
for humanitarian missions.
- Oh, so you're a humanitarian?
- Oh, absolutely.
- [scoffs] This is a military aircraft.
- Not any more.
Listen to the nephew.
What can they do with military hardware
but convert it to civilian use?
The only way you could die from this
baby now is if a food drop hits you.
And this stuff?
Is that going to Burkina Faso as well?
To a different client
at a different address.
It's just a coincidence? Do you
take me for a complete fucking fool?
Not complete, sir. And while
I hesitate to tell you your job,
I must point out
that when shipped separately,
the weapons and the aircraft both
comply with lnterpol trade standards.
We both know
that is an obscene bureaucratic loophole
that's gonna be closed
any goddamned day.
But it's not closed.
And while some might
interpret this cargo as suspicious,
we live in a world where suspicion alone
does not constitute a crime,
and where men like you
respect the rule of law.
[sighs]
I was as guilty as sin,
but Valentine couldn't prove it.
He was the rarest breed
of law-enforcement officer:
he knew I was breaking the law,
but wouldn't break it
himself to bust me.
He wasn't the only one
trying to put me out of business.
My uncle had turned down
rival arms dealers,
sometimes with better offers,
but to Dmitri,
you couldn't put a price on loyalty.
[speaks Russian]
- What was he doing?
- Hoping to beat your offer.
I told him to go
have intercourse with himself.
- But Yuri...
- You need to make more pay-offs.
- Too many know.
- Don't worry.
There are more VCRs, cigarettes.
I left them in your new car.
Even your enemy
was admiring that car.
- [laughs] I'm the luckiest man alive.
- You are.
[telephone]
- Hello?
- Ava?
Hi, baby.
- You forgot what time it is?
- Sorry, l...
How was that... Your audition?
They're going in another direction.
The direction of someone who can act.
They don't deserve you.
Where are you?
Is everything OK?
- It was a rough day at the office.
- Come home.
- Soon. How's Nicki?
- He misses you. We both do.
It's lonely without you here.
You know I don't like nights.
Ever since my parents...
[gunfire]
- Yuri, what's that?
- A party.
I'd better go. I just wanted to call
and hear your voice. Kiss Nicki for me.
- I love you.
- [dial tone]
The pillaging didn't die with my uncle.
After the Wall came down,
32 billion dollars' worth of arms were
stolen and resold from Ukraine alone.
One of the greatest heists
of the 20th century.
[distant voice]
The primary market was Africa.
1 1 major conflicts involving
32 countries in less than a decade.
A gunrunner's wet dream.
At the time,
the West couldn't care less.
They had a white war
in what was left of Yugoslavia.
I did the bulk of my business
in Liberia, "Land of the Free".
Established as a homeland
for freed American slaves,
it's been enslaved by one dictator
or another ever since.
The latest was American-educated,
self-declared president Andre Baptiste.
[# rap music]
- [revving]
- Mr Yuri!
Andre Baptiste Jr.
- My father would like to meet you.
- What an honour.
[revving]
Thank him.
Unfortunately I have other business.
It's a shame.
It's...It's a very busy schedule.
[revving]
It is not,
as they say,
optional.
My father is easily offended.
My schedule just freed up.
President Baptiste was my best customer,
but I was in no hurry to meet him.
He's gotten a reputation for hacking off
the limbs of those who opposed him.
His seven-year civil war
has been described as
"a relentless campaign
of sadistic, wanton violence. "
That kind of sums up Andy for me.
The Glock is interesting.
It's made of a polymer composite.
Many feel they can get through airport
security without setting off bells.
I do not recommend that.
On the other hand, if you are looking
for a traditional wheel gun,
there's no substitute for the six inches
of muzzle energy of the.357 Magnum.
And, of course, it will never jam.
- Why'd you do that?
- What did you say?
Now you're gonna have to buy it.
It's a used gun.
How can I sell a used gun?
[snorts]
"A used gun."
"A used gun"?
That's a good one.
You know, there is no discipline
with the youth today.
I try to set an example,
but it is difficult, huh?
- Personally, I blame MTV.
- [distant gunfire]
"A used gun."
I think, you and l,
we can do business.
If I thought I was scared
of Andre Senior,
I knew I was scared
of Andre Junior.
Like father, like son.
The guava doesn't fall
too far from the tree.
He was also a cannibal.
They say he would eat
a victim's heart while it was beating,
to give him superhuman strength.
[gunfire]
Monrovia itself
was like being on another planet.
Planet Monrovia.
From the temperature, it was obviously
a planet close to the sun.
I rarely saw another white man,
and I never left town alone.
Outside town was the edge of hell.
I didn't wanna even gaze into it.
[Andre Jr] This is your hotel.
Two stars.
Can you bring me the gun of Rambo?
- Part one, two or three?
- I've only seen part one.
The M-60. Would you like
the armour-piercing bullets?
Please.
My father left a welcoming present
in your room.
Enjoy. [laughs]
[distant gunfire]
[French]
My God.
She nearly got her head cut off.