Guard: ONE CON UNDER ESCORT.
OPEN GATE 5!
[GATE UNLOCKS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
Guard: MAN WALKING!
OPEN GATE 2!
[KEYS JANGLE]
[GATE UNLOCKS]
[INMATES TALKING]
Guard: LET'S GO!
FACE THE WALL!
GOT ONE UNDER ESCORT!
[GATE UNLOCKS]
[INMATES' TALKING FADES]
Woman: GOOD MORNING.
GOOD MORNING.
PLEASE STATE YOUR NAME
FOR THE RECORD.
DANIEL OCEAN.
THANK YOU.
MR. OCEAN,
THE PURPOSE OF THIS HEARING
IS TO DETERMINE
WHETHER, IF RELEASED,
YOU ARE LIKELY
TO BREAK THE LAW AGAIN.
WHILE THIS WAS
YOUR FIRST CONVICTION,
YOU HAVE BEEN IMPLICATED,
THOUGH NEVER CHARGED,
IN OVER A DOZEN OTHER
CONFIDENCE SCHEMES AND FRAUDS.
WHAT CAN YOU
TELL US ABOUT THIS?
AS YOU SAY, MA'AM,
I WAS NEVER CHARGED.
Man: MR. OCEAN, WHAT
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND OUT IS
WAS THERE A REASON
YOU CHOSE TO COMMIT THIS CRIME,
OR WAS THERE A REASON
YOU SIMPLY GOT CAUGHT THIS TIME?
MY WIFE LEFT ME.
I WAS UPSET.
I GOT INTO
A SELF-DESTRUCTIVE PATTERN.
Second woman: IF RELEASED,
IS IT LIKELY YOU'D FALL BACK
INTO A SIMILAR PATTERN?
SHE ALREADY LEFT ME ONCE.
I DON'T THINK SHE'D DO IT
AGAIN JUST FOR KICKS.
First woman: MR. OCEAN,
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU WOULD DO IF RELEASED?
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CHIPS, PLEASE.
SURE.
CHANGE 150. WOULD YOU LIKE
QUARTERS OR NICKELS?
QUARTERS ARE FINE.
OK.
GOOD LUCK.
THANK YOU.
20. DEALER HAS 19.
FINE.
GOOD START.
ALL RIGHT.
GOIN' ON BREAK NOW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
YOU HAVE A GOOD ONE.
HOW ARE YOU, SIR?
HELLO, FRANK.
I BEG YOUR PARDON, SIR?
YOU MUST HAVE ME
CONFUSED WITH SOMEONE ELSE.
MY NAME IS RAMON,
AS YOU CAN SEE RIGHT HERE.
IT'S MY MISTAKE.
NO PROBLEM, SIR.
TABLE'S COLD ANYWAY.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TRY
THE LOUNGE AT THE CAESAR'S.
IT GETS BUSY AFTER 1:00.
1:00?
YES, SIR.
THANKS, RAMON.
THANK YOU.
CHECKIN' UP
ON CURRENT EVENTS?
RAMON?
GLAD TO MEET YOU.
FRANK CATTON CAN'T GET
PAST THE GAMING BOARD.
JUST GOT OUT?
THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU SEEN HIM?
LAST I HEARD, HE WAS
TEACHING MOVIE STARS
HOW TO PLAY CARDS.
WHY?
YOU HAVE A PLAN
ALREADY?
ARE YOU KIDDING? I JUST
BECAME A CITIZEN AGAIN.
OFFICER BROOKS,
THIS IS DANNY OCEAN.
I WAS TOLD TO CONTACT YOU
WITHIN 24 HOURS.
NO, SIR, I HAVEN'T
BEEN GETTING IN ANY TROUBLE.
NO, SIR,
I HAVEN'T BEEN DRINKING.
NO, SIR. I WOULDN'T EVEN THINK
ABOUT LEAVING THE STATE.
Man: HEY, RUSS! RUSTY!
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION, MAN.
ARE YOU INCORPORATED?
[SCOFFS]
WELL, OK. IF YOU'RE NOT, YOU
SHOULD REALLY THINK ABOUT IT,
'CAUSE I WAS TALKING
TO MY MANAGER LAST NIGHT.
BERNIE.
NO, NOT BERNIE.
MY BUSINESS MANAGER.
ACTUALLY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
THEY'RE BOTH NAMED BERNIE.
ANYWAY, HE WAS TELLING ME
THAT BECAUSE OF WHAT WE DO
CAN BE CONSIDERED,
LIKE, RESEARCH
FOR LIKE A FUTURE GIG
OR WHATEVER,
I COULD TOTALLY MAKE IT
A TAX WRITE-OFF.
THE ONE THING IS, AND THIS IS,
LIKE, JUSTHISTHING--
AND IT'S STUPID--BUT,
I'D HAVE TO PAY YOU BY CHECK.
WHAT--
OR WE COULD
JUST STICK TO CASH.
YEAH, LET'S--YEAH,
LET'S JUST STICK TO CASH.
[MUSIC PLAYING,
PEOPLE TALKING]
ALL RIGHT. WE'RE GONNA
BEGIN WITH 5-CARD DRAW.
EVERYONE REMEMBER
5-CARD DRAW?
HELL, YEAH.
OH, YEAH.
WHO WANTS TO
START US OUT? JOSH?
YEAH.
JOSH.
YEAH?
TO THE LEFT.
DEAL TO YOUR LEFT. SHANE?
HIT ME.
IT'S NOT BLACKJACK.
DUDE!
[OTHERS LAUGH]
LOOKIN' AT 'EM DOESN'T CHANGE
'EM. YOU KNOW WHAT YOU HAVE.
OK. LET'S DO IT.
JOSH.
LEFT, LEFT.
I'LL GET IT.
LADY BETS.
LET'S KEEP IT MOVIN'.
BLUE.
THAT'S A 50.
I WILL CALL YOU.
OK.
ALL RIGHT.
SHANE'S CALLING, 50.
THERE IT IS.
WHAT THE HELL, IT'S ONLY
POCKET CHANGE, RIGHT?
HA HA HA!
HOW YOU BET
IS YOUR BUSINESS.
YOU WANT TO MAKE THEM THINK
YOU'RE BETTING FOR A REASON.
YEAH. THANKS, MAN.
OK.
RIGHT, RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, HOW MANY?
4.
YOU DON'T WANT 4.
YOU WANT TO FOLD.
I WANT TO FOLD?
FOLD.
IS THAT GOOD?
JUST LIKE THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
YOU'RE DONE.
AND...DEALER
WILL TAKE 3.
YOU'RE DONE.
SHANE,
YOU GOT 3 PAIRS.
YEAH.
YOU CAN'T HAVE
3 PAIRS.
YOU CAN'T
HAVE 6 CARDS
IN A 5-CARD GAME.
MAYBE ONE WAS--
JOSH.
DON'T LOOK AT ME--
FELLAS, FELLAS!
ALL REDS.
HA HA HA!
YEAH!
YOU THE BIG GUY!
ALL RIGHT!
WHAT UP, DOG?
MAN, I HATE YOU!
[OVERLAPPING TALKING]
OH, I'M GONNA LOVE
SPENDING YOUR MONEY.
I'M GONNA
GET MY CAR WASHED.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HOW'S
THE GAME GOIN'?
LONGEST HOUR OF MY LIFE.
WHAT?
I'M RUNNING AWAY
WITH YOUR WIFE.
GREAT.
Ocean: THAT'S
HARD TO DO, ISN'T IT,
CROSSING OVER
FROM TELEVISION TO FILM?
Man: NOT FOR ME, DUDE.
[OTHERS LAUGH]
OH, HEY, RUSS,
WE GOT ANOTHER PLAYER,
IF THAT'S COOL WITH YOU.
MR. OCEAN, WHAT DO YOU
DO FOR A LIVING,
IF YOU DON'T
MIND ME ASKING?
WHY WOULD I
MIND YOU ASKING?
2 CARDS.
I JUST GOT
OUT OF PRISON.
REALLY?
WELL, WHY WERE
YOU IN PRISON?
I STOLE THINGS.
YOU STOLE THINGS?
LIKE, UH, JEWELS?
INCAN MATRIMONIAL
HEAD MASKS.
ANY MONEY IN THOSE
INCAN MATRIMONIAL--
HEAD MASKS.
THERE'S SOME.
DON'T LET HIM FOOL YOU.
THERE'S BOATLOADS,
IF YOU CAN MOVE 'EM.
TAKE ONE.
BUT YOU CAN'T.
MY FENCE SEEMED
CONFIDENT ENOUGH.
IF YOU'RE DEALING IN CASH,
YOU DON'T NEED A FENCE.
SOME PEOPLE LACK VISION.
PROBABLY EVERYBODY
IN CELL BLOCK E.
THAT'S $500.
GUYS, WHAT'S THE FIRST
LESSON IN POKER?
NEVER BET ON THE--
NO.
LEAVE EMOTION
AT THE DOOR.
THAT'S RIGHT, TOPHER.
TODAY'S LESSON--
HOW TO DRAW OUT THE BLUFF.
THAT MUCH MONEY
THIS EARLY IN THE GAME,
I'M SAYING HE'S HOLDING
NOTHING BETTER THAN
A PAIR OF FACE CARDS.
BARR?
[SIGHS] ALL RIGHT.
EH, I FOLD.
JOSH?
NO. I'M GAME.
I WILL SEE YOUR 500,
AND I WILL RAISE YOU
ANOTHER 500 OF MY OWN.
THAT'S A VERY
HANDSOME BET, JOSH,
BUT BE CAREFUL.
WE DON'T WANT TO PUSH HIM
TOO HIGH TOO FAST.
WANT TO KEEP HIM
ON THE LEASH.
HOLLY?
CALL.
CALL?
AND I'LL CALL.
Ocean:
I'LL SEE YOU 500,
RAISE YOU 2,000.
[WHISTLES]
GUYS, YOU'RE FREE
TO DO WHAT YOU LIKE.
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY,
BUT I'M STAYING IN.
HE'S TRYING TO BUY
HIS WAY OUT OF HIS BLUFF.
JOSH?
2.
[GROANS]
THAT A GIRL. CALL.
CALL.
LET'S SEE 'EM.
I'M NOT SURE
WHAT THE FOUR 9s DOES,
BUT THE ACE, I THINK,
IS PRETTY HIGH.
DUDE! THANKS FOR THE TIP
ON CALLING OUT THE BLUFF.
[ALL TALKING]
GOD, I'M BORED.
YOU LOOK BORED.
I AM BORED.
[SIGHS]
SO, HOW WAS THE CLINK?
DID YOU GET THE COOKIES I SENT?
WHY DO YOU THINK
I CAME TO SEE YOU FIRST?
SO, TELL ME.
IT'S TRICKY. IT'S
NEVER BEEN DONE BEFORE.
IT'S GONNA NEED PLANNING
AND A LARGE CREW.
GUNS?
NOT EXACTLY.
A LOT OF SECURITY,
BUT THE TAKE--
WHAT'S THE TARGET?
8 FIGURES EACH.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU WERE IN VEGAS?
WHAT? YOU WANT TO
KNOCK OVER A CASINO?
OH! HO HO.
Ocean: THE VAULT
AT THE BELLAGIO.
Rusty: MMM.
OOF!
WELL?
IF I'M READING
THIS RIGHT,
AND I'D LIKE TO
THINK THAT I AM,
THIS IS PROBABLY
THE LEAST ACCESSIBLE
VAULT EVER DESIGNED.
YEP.
YOU SAID 3 CASINOS?
THESE FEED INTO THE CAGES
AT THE MIRAGE,
THE MGM GRAND, BUT
EVERY DIME ENDS UP THERE.
THE BELLAGIO
AND THE MIRAGE.
THESE ARE TERRY
BENEDICT'S PLACES.
YES, THEY ARE.
DO YOU THINK
HE'LL MIND?
MORE THAN SOMEWHAT. YOU'D
NEED AT LEAST A DOZEN GUYS
DOING A COMBINATION OF CONS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
OFF THE TOP OF MY HEAD,
I'D SAY YOU'RE LOOKING
AT A BOESKY, A JIM BROWN,
A MISS DAISY,
2 JETHROS,
AND A LEON SPINKS,
NOT TO MENTION THE BIGGEST
ELLA FITZGERALD EVER.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN GET
THE MONEY TO BACK THIS?
IF WE'RE HITTING
THESE 3 CASINOS,
WE'LL GET
OUR BANKROLL.
BENEDICT'S GOT
A LONG LIST OF ENEMIES.
YEAH, BUT ENEMIES WITH
LOOSE CASH, NOTHING TO LOSE?
AH! REUBEN.
REUBEN?
Security guard: HEY!
JESUS! OSCAR, LOWER IT
A BIT, WOULD YOU?
SORRY. YOU GUYS
DONE UP HERE?
FIND WHAT YOU WANT?
YEAH. WE JUST WANT TO TAKE
THESE HOME FOR THE NIGHT
AND MAKE SOME COPIES,
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT.
Oscar:
WHATEVER YOU NEED.
APPRECIATE IT.
WHAT?
WHA--
I NEED THE REASON.
DON'T SAY MONEY.
WHY DO THIS?
WHY NOT DO IT?
BECAUSE YESTERDAY,
I WALKED
OUT OF THE JOINT
AFTER LOSING
4 YEARS OF MY LIFE,
AND YOU'RE COLD-DECKING
TEEN BEATCOVER BOYS.
BECAUSE THE HOUSE
ALWAYS WINS.
PLAY LONG ENOUGH,
YOU NEVER
CHANGE THE STAKES,
THE HOUSE TAKES YOU
UNLESS...
WHEN THAT PERFECT
HAND COMES ALONG,
YOU BET BIG,
AND THEN
YOU TAKE THE HOUSE.
YOU'VE BEEN PRACTICING
THIS SPEECH, HAVEN'T YOU?
A LITTLE BIT. DID I RUSH?
IT FELT LIKE I RUSHED IT.
NO. IT WAS GOOD. I LIKED IT.
TEEN BEATTHING WAS HARSH.
I WONDER WHAT
REUBEN'LL SAY.
YOU'RE OUT OF
YOUR GODDAMN MINDS!
ARE YOU LISTENING TO ME?
YOU'RE, BOTH OF YOU, NUTS.
I KNOW MORE
ABOUT CASINO SECURITY
THAN ANY MAN ALIVE.
I INVENTED IT,
AND IT CANNOT BE BEATEN.
THEY GOT CAMERAS, THEY GOT
WATCHERS, THEY GOT LOCKS,
THEY GOT TIMERS,
THEY GOT VAULTS.
THEY GOT ENOUGH ARMED
PERSONNEL TO OCCUPY PARIS.
OK, BAD EXAMPLE.
IT'S NEVER BEEN TRIED.
HO HO!
IT'S BEEN TRIED.
A FEW GUYS EVEN CAME CLOSE.
YOU KNOW THE
3 MOST SUCCESSFUL ROBBERIES
IN THE HISTORY OF VEGAS?
NUMBER 3--THE BRONZE MEDAL.
PENCILNECK GRABS A LOCK BOX
AT THE HORSESHOE.
Man: HEY, HEY!
GET THAT GUY--BROWN SUIT!
HE GOT 2 STEPS
CLOSER TO THE DOOR
THAN ANY LIVING SOUL
BEFORE HIM.
HEY! LEAVE
THE MONEY!
SECOND MOST SUCCESSFUL
ROBBERY--
THE FLAMINGO IN '71.
THIS GUY ACTUALLY
TASTED FRESH OXYGEN
BEFORE THEY GRABBED HIM.
UHH!
OF COURSE, HE WAS
BREATHING OUT OF A HOSE
FOR THE NEXT 3 WEEKS.
GODDAMN HIPPIE.
AND THE CLOSEST
ANY MAN HAS EVER COME
TO ROBBING
A LAS VEGAS CASINO
WAS OUTSIDE OF CAESAR'S
IN '87.
HE CAME, HE GRABBED,
THEY CONQUERED.
dd TAKE MY BREATH AWAY dd
BUT WHAT AM I SAYING?
YOU GUYS ARE PROS--
THE BEST!
I'M SURE YOU CAN MAKE IT
OUT OF THE CASINO.
OF COURSE, LEST WE FORGET,
ONCE YOU'RE
OUT THE FRONT DOOR,
YOU'RE STILL IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE FUCKIN' DESERT!
YOU'RE RIGHT.
HE'S RIGHT.
REUBEN, YOU'RE RIGHT.
OUR EYES ARE BIGGER
THAN OUR STOMACHS.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT IT IS--PURE EGO.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
BLAH, BLAH, BLAH.
THANK YOU FOR LUNCH.
BE SWELL.
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
SORRY WE
BOTHERED YOU.
LOOK, WE ALL GO WAY BACK,
AND, UH, I OWE YOU
FROM THE THING
WITH THE GUY IN THE PLACE,
AND I'LL NEVER FORGET IT.
THAT WAS
OUR PLEASURE.
I'D NEVER BEEN
TO BELIZE.
GIVE DOMINIC YOUR ADDRESSES.
I GOT SOME
REMAINDERED FURNITURE
I WANT TO SEND YOU.
LOOK, JUST OUT OF CURIOSITY,
WHICH CASINOS DID YOU
GENIUSES PICK TO ROB?
[QUIETLY]
THE BELLAGIO--
THE BELLAGIO,
THE MIRAGE,
AND THE MGM GRAND.
[SILVERWARE CLATTERS]
THOSE ARE
TERRY BENEDICT'S CASINOS.
IS THAT RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU GUYS...
WHAT DO YOU GOT
AGAINST TERRY BENEDICT?
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
AGAINST HIM?
THAT'S
THE QUESTION.
HE TORPEDOED MY CASINO,
MUSCLED ME OUT.
NOW HE'S GONNA
BLOW IT UP NEXT MONTH
TO MAKE WAY FOR SOME
GAUDY MONSTROSITY.
DON'T THINK I DON'T SEE
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
WHAT ARE WE
DOING, REUBEN?
IF YOU'RE GONNA STEAL
FROM TERRY BENEDICT,
YOU BETTER GODDAMN KNOW.
THIS SORT OF THING
USED TO BE CIVILIZED--
YOU'D HIT A GUY,
HE'D WHACK YOU, DONE.
BUT WITH BENEDICT,
AT THE END OF THIS,
HE BETTER NOT KNOW
YOU'RE INVOLVED,
NOT KNOW YOUR NAMES,
OR THINK YOU'RE DEAD,
BECAUSE HE'LL KILL YOU,
AND THEN HE'LL GO
TO WORK ON YOU.
THAT'S WHY WE'D HAVE
TO BE VERY CAREFUL,
VERY PRECISE.
HMM. WELL-FUNDED.
YEAH. YOU GOTTA
BE NUTS, TOO.
AND YOU'RE GONNA NEED
A CREW AS NUTS AS YOU ARE.
WHO DO YOU GOT IN MIND?
Ocean: ALL RIGHT,
WHO'S IN?
FRANK C. IS IN.
[COUGHS]
FRANK C. HAS DEVELOPED
A BAD CASE OF BRONCHITIS
AND IS PUTTING IN
FOR A TRANSFER
TO WARMER CLIMATES.
Ocean:
WHAT ABOUT DRIVERS?
Rusty: TALKED
TO THE MALLOYS YESTERDAY.
THE MORMON TWINS?
MMM.
THEY'RE BOTH
IN SALT LAKE CITY,
6 MONTHS OFF THE JOB.
GOT THE SENSE THEY'RE HAVING
TROUBLE FILLING THE HOURS.
WAITING, SWEETHEART,
JUST WAITING.
GOOD. GO.
WAITING FOR YOU.
TO DO WHAT?
GO, LITTLE GIRL!
YOU'RE LIKE
A LITTLE GIRL!
RELAX. I'VE BEEN
DOING THIS ALL DAY.
I'M GONNA
GET OUT OF THE CAR,
AND I'M
GONNA DROP YOU
LIKE THIRD PERIOD
FRENCH, OK?
SO, RELAX!
GO!
[ENGINE HUMMING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[CRUNCH]
[CACKLING]
Ocean: ELECTRONICS?
Rusty: LIVINGSTON DELL.
LIVINGSTON'S BEEN DOING
FREELANCE SURVEILLANCE WORK
OF LATE
FOR THE FBI MOB SQUAD.
Ocean:
HOW ARE HIS NERVES?
Rusty: OK. NOT SO BAD
YOU'D NOTICE.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN MOVE IN
A LITTLE BIT ON THIS ONE.
D-D--DON'T--DON'T--
DON'T--DON'T TOUCH THAT.
WHY NOT?
DO YOU SEE ME GRABBING
THE GUN OUT OF YOUR HOLSTER
AND JUST WAVING IT AROUND?
HEY, RADIO SHACK. RELAX.
HEADS UP!
UHH!
SORRY!
OH! AH!
MUNITIONS.
PHIL TURRENTINE.
DEAD.
NO SHIT.
ON THE JOB?
SKIN CANCER.
YOU SEND FLOWERS?
DATED HIS WIFE
FOR A WHILE.
THE BASHER'S
IN TOWN.
THERE MIGHT BE AN ISSUE
WITH AVAILABILITY.
ALL RIGHT, CHAPS.
HANG ON TO YOUR KNICKERS.
[CLICK]
[EXPLOSIONS]
[ALARM SOUNDS]
OH, LEAVE IT OUT!
YOU TOSSERS!
YOU HAD ONE JOB TO DO!
[POLICE RADIO CHATTER]
[SIREN]
Policeman: THAT'S ALL YOU
USED IN THE EVENT, RIGHT?
NOTHING ELSE?
HANG ON.
ARE YOU ACCUSING ME
OF BOOBYTRAPPING?
WELL, HOW ABOUT IT?
BOOBYTRAPS AREN'T
MR. TORRES' STYLE.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT,
BASHER?
PECK, ATF.
LET ME VENTURE A GUESS.
SIMPLE G-FORM MAINLINER,
BACK-WOUND QUICK FUSE
WITH A DRAG
UNDER 20 FEET?
YEAH. LET ME ASK YOU
SOMETHING ELSE.
DID YOU
SEARCH THIS SCUMBAG
FOR BOOBYTRAPS
ON HIS PERSON?
I MEAN, REALLY SEARCH--
NOT JUST FOR WEAPONS.
STAND BACK.
OY! HERE WE GO.
GO FIND GRIGGS. TELL HIM
I NEED TO SEE HIM.
WHO?
JUST FIND HIM, WILL YA?
HEY, BASH.
HEY, RUSS.
HOW FAST CAN YOU PUT
SOMETHING TOGETHER
FROM WHAT
I JUST SLIPPED YOU?
IT'S DONE.
HEY, IS
DANNY ABOUT?
YEAH, HE'S WAITIN'
AROUND THE CORNER.
OH, THAT'S TERRIFIC!
IT WILL BE NICE WORKING
WITH PROPER VILLAINS AGAIN.
Policeman:
EVERYBODY DOWN!
[EXPLOSIONS]
HA HA HA! THEY WEREN'T
EXPECTING THAT SHIT!
HA HA HA HA HA!
NICE WORK.
OH, THANK YOU!
[BELLS JINGLING]
[CLAP] HO!
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
WHICH ONE'S
THE AMAZING YEN?
THE LITTLE
CHINESE GUY.
WHO ELSE
IS ON THE LIST?
HEISTHE LIST.
[SPEAKS CHINESE]
[SIGHS]
I DON'T KNOW. DOESN'T
SEEM ALL THAT DIFF--
WE GOT A GREASEMAN.
FABULOUS.
WE NEED SAUL.
HE WON'T DO IT. GOT OUT
OF THE GAME A YEAR AGO.
GET RELIGION?
ULCERS.
YOU COULD ASK HIM.
HEY, I COULD
ASK HIM.
[ENGINE STARTS]
I SAW YOU
AT THE PADDOCK
BEFORE THE SECOND RACE
OUTSIDE THE MEN'S ROOM
WHEN I PLACED MY BET.
I SAW YOU BEFORE YOU
EVEN GOT UP THIS MORNING.
HOW YOU BEEN, SAUL?
NEVER BETTER.
WHAT'S
WITH THE ORANGE?
MY DOCTOR SAYS
I NEED VITAMINS.
SO WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE VITAMINS?
YOU COME HERE
TO GIVE ME A PHYSICAL?
BOX SEATS. COME ON.
SO, YOU GONNA TELL ME,
OR SHOULD I JUST SAY NO
AND GET IT OVER WITH?
SAUL, YOU'RE
THE BEST THERE IS.
YOU'RE IN
COOPERSTOWN.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
NOTHIN'.
I GOT A DUPLEX NOW.
I GOT WALL-TO-WALL
AND A GOLDFISH.
I'M SEEING A NICE LADY
WHO WORKS THE UNMENTIONABLES
COUNTER AT MACY'S.
I'VE CHANGED.
[HORN BLOWS]
GUYS LIKE US
DON'T CHANGE, SAUL.
WE STAY SHARP
OR WE GET SLOPPY.
WE DON'T CHANGE.
QUIT CONNIN' ME.
IS THAT YOUR HOUND
WAY IN THE REAR THERE?
HE BREAKS LATE.
EVERYONE KNOWS THIS.
SO YOU GONNA TREAT ME
LIKE A GROWNUP AT LEAST,
TELL ME WHAT THE SCAM IS?
[WHISPERING]
OH.
TV: EXHIBIT "C,"
THE BELT
HE'S FLAUNTING AS KING
OF THE HEAVYWEIGHT CROWN.
LENNOX LEWIS...
[INDISTINCT]
SAUL MAKES 10.
10 OUGHTA DO IT,
DON'T YOU THINK?
DO YOU THINK
WE NEED ONE MORE?
YOU THINK WE NEED
ONE MORE.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL GET ONE MORE.
HELLO, LINUS.
WHOSE IS THIS?
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M A FRIEND
OF BOBBY CALDWELL'S.
YOU'RE EITHER IN
OR YOU'RE OUT. RIGHT NOW.
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S A PLANE TICKET.
A JOB OFFER.
YOU'RE PRETTY TRUSTING
PRETTY FAST.
BOBBY HAS A LOT
OF FAITH IN YOU.
FATHERS ARE LIKE THAT.
OH, HE DIDN'T TELL YOU.
HE DIDN'T WANT ME
TRADING ON HIS NAME.
IF YOU DO THIS JOB,
HE'LL BE TRADING ON YOURS.
IF YOU DON'T,
WE'LL FIND SOMEBODY ELSE
WHO WON'T BE QUITE AS GOOD,
AND YOU CAN GO BACK
TO FEELING UP STOCKBROKERS.
CAN YOU GET THE CHECK,
PLEASE?
THAT'S THE BEST LIFT
I'VE SEEN YOU MAKE YET.
LAS VEGAS, HUH?
AMERICA'S PLAYGROUND.
Elvis Presley:
dd A LITTLE LESS CONVERSATION dd
dd AND A LITTLE MORE
ACTION, PLEASE dd
dd ALL THIS AGGRAVATION
AIN'T SATISFACTIONING ME dd
dd A LITTLE MORE BITE,
A LITTLE LESS BARK dd
dd A LITTLE LESS FIGHT
AND A LITTLE MORE SPARK dd
dd CLOSE YOUR MOUTH
AND OPEN UP YOUR HEART dd
dd AND, BABY, SATISFY ME dd
dd SATISFY ME, BABY dd
dd BABY, CLOSE YOUR EYES
AND LISTEN TO THE MUSIC dd
dd DRIFT
THROUGH A SUMMER BREEZE dd
dd IT'S A GROOVY NIGHT dd
dd AND I CAN SHOW YOU
HOW TO USE IT dd
dd COME ALONG WITH ME
AND PUT YOUR MIND AT EASE dd
dd HEY, A LITTLE LESS
CONVERSATION dd
dd A LITTLE MORE ACTION,
PLEASE dd
WHAT, DID YOU GUYS
GET A GROUP RATE
OR SOMETHING?
SO DO YOU MAKE IT
OUT TO UTAH MUCH?
NOT AS OFTEN
AS I'D LIKE.
THINK YOU SHOULD
CHECK IT OUT.
THINK YOU'D DIG PROVO.
I THINK YOU COULD DO
VERY WELL THERE.
I'LL LOOK INTO IT.
GENTLEMEN,
WELCOME TO LAS VEGAS.
EXACTLY.
EVERYBODY EATEN?
GOOD.
EVERYBODY SOBER?
CLOSE ENOUGH. ALL RIGHT,
BEFORE WE GET STARTED,
NOBODY'S
ON THE LINE HERE YET.
WHAT I'M ABOUT
TO PROPOSE TO YOU
IS BOTH HIGHLY LUCRATIVE
AND HIGHLY DANGEROUS.
IF THAT DOESN'T SEEM LIKE
YOUR PARTICULAR BRAND OF VODKA,
HELP YOURSELF TO AS MUCH
FOOD AS YOU LIKE
AND HAVE A SAFE JOURNEY.
NO HARD FEELINGS.
OTHERWISE, COME WITH ME.
YOU'RE BOBBY CALDWELL'S
KID, HUH?
FROM CHICAGO?
YEAH.
IT'S NICE THERE.
DO YOU LIKE IT?
YEAH.
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
GET IN THE GODDAMN HOUSE.
GENTLEMEN, THE 3000 BLOCK
OF LAS VEGAS BOULEVARD,
OTHERWISE KNOWN AS
THE BELLAGIO, THE MIRAGE,
AND THE MGM GRAND.
TOGETHER, THEY'RE 3
OF THE MOST PROFITABLE CASINOS
IN LAS VEGAS.
LET ME SEE.
[CHANGES SLIDES]
THIS IS THE VAULT
AT THE BELLAGIO.
IT'S LOCATED BELOW THE STRIP
BENEATH 200 FEET OF SOLID EARTH.
IT SAFEGUARDS EVERY DIME
THAT PASSES THROUGH
EACH OF THE 3 CASINOS
ABOVE IT...
AND WE'RE GONNA ROB IT.
SMASH-AND-GRAB JOB,
HUH?
SLIGHTLY
MORE COMPLICATED
THAN THAT.
WELL, YEAH.
THIS IS COURTESY
OF FRANK CATTON,
NEW BLACKJACK DEALER
AT THE BELLAGIO.
OK, BAD NEWS FIRST.
THIS PLACE HOUSES
A SECURITY SYSTEM
THAT RIVALS MOST
NUCLEAR MISSILE SILOS.
FIRST WE HAVE TO GET
WITHIN THE CASINO CAGES,
WHICH ANYBODY'LL TELL YOU
TAKES MORE THAN A SMILE.
NEXT, THROUGH THESE DOORS,
EACH OF WHICH REQUIRES
A DIFFERENT 6-DIGIT CODE
CHANGED EVERY 12 HOURS.
PAST THOSE
LIES THE ELEVATOR.
THIS IS WHERE
IT GETS TRICKY.
THE ELEVATOR WON'T MOVE
WITHOUT AUTHORIZED
FINGERPRINT IDENTIFICATION--
WHICH WE CAN'T FAKE.
AND VOCAL CONFIRMATION
FROM BOTH THE SECURITY SYSTEM
WITHIN THE BELLAGIO
AND THE VAULT BELOW.
WHICH WE WON'T GET.
FURTHERMORE,
THE ELEVATOR SHAFT
IS RIGGED
WITH MOTION DETECTORS.
MEANING IF WE WERE TO
MANUALLY OVERRIDE THE LIFT,
THE SHAFT'S EXIT WOULD
LOCK DOWN AUTOMATICALLY,
AND WE'D BE TRAPPED.
ONCE WE GET DOWN
THE SHAFT, THOUGH,
THEN IT'S
A PIECE OF CAKE.
JUST...2 MORE GUARDS
WITH UZIs
AND THE MOST ELABORATE
VAULT DOOR
EVER CONCEIVED BY MAN.
ANY QUESTIONS?
[SPEAKS CHINESE]
NO, TUNNELING'S OUT.
THERE ARE SENSORS
MONITORING THE GROUND
A HUNDRED YARDS
IN EVERY DIRECTION.
IF A GROUNDHOG WERE TO NEST
THERE, THEY'D KNOW ABOUT IT.
Ocean: ANYONE ELSE?
YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT GOOD NEWS?
YEAH. THE NEVADA
GAMING COMMISSION
STIPULATES THAT A CASINO
MUST HOLD IN RESERVE
ENOUGH CASH TO COVER
EVERY CHIP AT PLAY ON ITS FLOOR.
THAT MEANS,
ON A WEEKDAY, BY LAW,
IT HAS TO CARRY ANYWHERE
BETWEEN 60 AND $70 MILLION
IN CASH AND COIN.
ON THE WEEKEND,
BETWEEN 80 AND 90 MILLION.
ON A FIGHT NIGHT, LIKE THE ONE
2 WEEKS FROM TONIGHT,
THE NIGHT
THAT WE'RE GONNA ROB IT...
150 MILLION
WITHOUT BREAKING A SWEAT.
NOW, THERE ARE 11 OF US,
EACH WITH AN EQUAL SHARE.
YOU DO THE MATH.
[WHISTLES]
EXACTLY.
I HAVE A QUESTION.
Ocean: MM-HMM?
SAY WE GET INTO THE CAGE
AND THROUGH
THE SECURITY DOORS THERE
AND DOWN THE ELEVATOR
WE CAN'T MOVE
AND PAST THE GUARDS
WITH THE GUNS
AND INTO THE VAULT
WE CAN'T OPEN--
WITHOUT BEING SEEN
BY THE CAMERAS.
OH, YEAH, SORRY.
I FORGOT TO MENTION THAT.
YEAH, WELL,
SAY WE DO ALL THAT.
WE'RE JUST SUPPOSED
TO WALK OUTTA THERE
WITH $150 MILLION
IN CASH ON US
WITHOUT
GETTING STOPPED?
YEAH.
OH.
OK.
Ocean: ALL RIGHT,
HERE'S HOW WE'LL BEGIN.
FIRST TASK: RECONNAISSANCE.
I WANNA KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT'S GOING ON IN ALL 3 CASINOS
FROM THE ROTATION
OF THE DEALERS
TO THE PATH
OF EVERY CASH CART.
I WANNA KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT EVERY GUARD,
EVERY WATCHER,
ANYONE WITH A SECURITY PASS.
...THIS GIRL
CHARMAINE.
I WANNA KNOW
WHERE THEY'RE FROM,
WHAT THEIR NICKNAMES ARE,
HOW THEY TAKE THEIR COFFEE.
SHE'S A DANCER
AT THE CRAZY HORSE TOO.
SHE'S PUTTING HER WAY
THROUGH MEDICAL SCHOOL.
I THINK
SHE REALLY LIKES ME.
Ocean: MOST OF ALL,
I WANT YOU GUYS
TO KNOW THESE CASINOS,
THEY'RE BUILT AS LABYRINTHS
TO KEEP PEOPLE IN.
I WANT YOU GUYS TO KNOW
THE QUICK ROUTES OUT.
HE WENT THROUGH AT 10:44.
10:46--GET A WATCH
THAT WORKS.
[MUTTERING]
Ocean: SECOND TASK--POWER.
ON THE NIGHT OF THE FIGHT,
WE'RE GONNA THROW THE SWITCH
ON SIN CITY.
BASHER, IT'S YOUR SHOW.
Basher: YOU WANT BROKE,
BLIND, OR BEDLAM?
Ocean: HOW ABOUT ALL 3?
RIGHT. IT'S DONE.
THIRD TASK--SURVEILLANCE.
CASINO SECURITY HAS AN EYE
AND AN EAR ON EVERYTHING,
SO WE WANT AN EYE
AND AN EAR ON THEM.
LIVINGSTON?
WELL, IT'S NOT THE LEAST
ACCESSIBLE SYSTEM
I'VE SEEN,
BUT IT'S CLOSE.
I DON'T SUPPOSE THEY HAVE
A CLOSED CIRCUIT FEED
I COULD TAP INTO?
NO.
THEN IT'S DEFINITELY
A BLACK-BAG JOB.
DO THEY EMPLOY AN
IN-HOUSE TECHNICIAN?
2, AND ONE OF THEM'S
LONELY.
THANKS, CHARMAINE.
I'LL HAVE THIS BACK
IN AN HOUR.
SAY HI TO YOUR MOM
FOR ME.
SAY IT YOURSELF. SHE'LL
BE ONSTAGE IN 5 MINUTES.
WATCH IT, BUD!
WHO YOU
CALLING BUD, PAL?!
WHO YOU CALLING
PAL, FRIEND?!
WHO YOU CALLING FRIEND,
JACKASS?!
DON'T CALL ME
A JACKASS.
I JUST DID CALL YOU
433, WE HAVE
A VISUAL IMPAIRMENT
ON THE NORTHWEST 0-5-2
EXIT DOOR CAMERA.
COPY THAT. I SEE THEM.
IT'S, LIKE, A WORD?
"OBSEQUIOUS" IS A WORD.
SIR!
I'M NOT IN YOUR FACE!
YOU WERE
IN MY FACE!
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU GOT IN MY WAY!
I'M JUST TRYING
TO DELIVER MY BALLOONS.
GENTLEMEN!
[LAUGHS]
HE'S A BALLOON BOY!
BALLOON BOY!
YEAH, BALLOON BOY?!
YOU'RE SPITTING
IN MY FACE!
Rusty: AND WE'RE
UP AND RUNNING.
WHY DO THEY ALWAYS PAINT
HALLWAYS THAT COLOR?
THEY SAY TAUPE
IS VERY SOOTHING.
HMM.
HI.
FINE, THANKS.
I'M GONNA NEED YOU
TO MOVE THOSE BALLOONS.
YOU WANT ME TO MOVE
THOSE BALLOONS?!
YOU KNOW WHY
I'LL MOVE THOSE, SIR?
'CAUSE I HAVE A VERY IMPORTANT
CLIENT WAITING FOR THESE,
AND I DON'T HAVE TIME
TO FOOL AROUND WITH YOU TWO...
CIRCUS ANIMALS.
UH-OH.
HEY, HOLD UP
A MINUTE.
EXCUSE ME!
HEY! EXCUSE ME!
HEY. YOU DROPPED THIS.
OH, THANK YOU.
HOW'S RECEPTION
ON THOSE THINGS?
EXCELLENT.
TAKE CARE.
OOH!
WELL.
YEAH.
Ocean: FOURTH TASK--
CONSTRUCTION.
WE NEED TO BUILD
AN EXACT WORKING REPLICA
OF THE BELLAGIO VAULT.
Rusty: FOR PRACTICE?
Ocean: SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
FIFTH TASK--INTELLIGENCE.
WE NEED THOSE CODES,
LINUS,
FROM THE ONLY GUY
WHO HAS ALL 3.
WHO? BENEDICT?
LEARN TO LOVE HIS SHADOW.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
ALL I GET TO DO
IS WATCH THE GUY?
YOU GOTTA WALK
BEFORE YOU CAN CRAWL.
REVERSE THAT.
Ocean:
SIXTH TASK--TRANSPORT.
WELL, I AM SORRY,
BUT 18,500 APIECE
IS THE BEST OFFER
I CAN MAKE.
WELL, I UNDERSTAND.
AND THEY ARE SOME GREAT-LOOKIN'
VANS YOU GOT THERE.
YES, SIR.
TOP OF THE LINE.
OK, THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME,
MISTER, UH...
DENIM--BILLY TIM DENIM.
YES, DENIM LIKE A JEAN.
YES, THAT'S IT.
JUST LIKE THE JEANS.
MAN, YOU'VE GOT
SOME LOVELY HANDS HERE.
DO YOU MOISTURIZE?
I'M SORRY?
I TRIED ALL SORTS OF BRAND
OF LOTION.
I EVEN WENT FRAGRANCE-FREE
FOR A WHOLE YEAR.
NOW, MY SISTER,
SHE USES, UH, UH, UH...
ALOE VERA WITH A LITTLE
SUNSCREEN IN IT.
YEAH, AND IDEALLY SPEAKING,
YOU ALMOST SHOULD WEAR GLOVES
WHEN YOU GOING TO BED.
BUT I FOUND OUT
THAT THERE WOULD BE
A LITTLE INTERFERENCE
IN MY...SOCIAL AGENDA,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
OH, YES.
PLUS I CAN GET A REACTION
FROM THE CAMPHOR,
SO I REALLY DON'T GET
INTO THE TRADITIONAL REMEDIES.
I SEE. YEAH.
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING,
IF YOU WERE WILLING
TO PAY CASH--
YEAH?
I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO DROP THAT DOWN
TO, SAY,
17--16 EACH.
NO?
YES, SIR.
YOU'D DO THAT?
WELL, YES, SIR.
THEN THAT'D BE LOVELY.
THEY TOLD ME
TO COME SEE YOU.
OH, DID THEY? WELL,
I'M SURE GLAD THEY DID.
THEY TOLD ME.
OK, WELL, LET ME GO
GET THE PAPERWORK.
AND--AND
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
JUST WAIT HERE
AT THE TABLE, OK?
YOU DO THAT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THIS IS
VERY NICE MATERIAL.
Ocean: IT'S
IMPORTED SILK, SAUL.
YEAH. VERY NICE.
GENTLEMEN,
WOULD YOU EXCUSE US
JUST FOR A SECOND?
THANKS.
SAUL, YOU SURE
YOU'RE READY TO DO THIS?
[SIGHS]
IF YOU EVER ASK ME
THAT QUESTION AGAIN, DANIEL,
YOU WILL NOT WAKE UP
THE FOLLOWING MORNING.
[WHISPERS]
He's ready.
MY NAME IS...LYMAN.
ZERGA.
MY NAME IS LYMAN ZERGA.
[DEEPER]
MY NAME...
IS LYMAN ZERGA.
OK, TELL ME
ABOUT BENEDICT.
THAT GUY'S A MACHINE.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
MR. BENEDICT.
HE ARRIVES AT THE BELLAGIO
EVERY DAY AT 2 P.M.,
SAME CAR, SAME DRIVER.
HOW ARE YA, TOMMY?
HOW'S THE BABY?
VERY WELL,
THANK YOU.
HE REMEMBERS EVERY VALET'S
NAME ON THE WAY IN.
NOT BAD FOR A GUY
WORTH 3/4 OF A BILLION.
OFFICES ARE UPSTAIRS.
HE WORKS HARD,
HITS THE LOBBY FLOOR
AT 7:00 ON THE NOSE.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
HOW ARE YA, FRANK?
HOW'S THE FAMILY?
SPENDS 3 MINUTES ON THE FLOOR
WITH HIS CASINO MANAGER.
WHAT DO THEY
TALK ABOUT?
ALL BUSINESS. BENEDICT
LIKES TO KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON
IN HIS CASINOS,
LIKES TO BE IN CONTROL.
THERE'S RARELY AN INCIDENT
HE DOESN'T KNOW ABOUT
OR HANDLE PERSONALLY.
OH, BeeNE.
COME STA?
BeeNE. BeeNE.
SPENDS A FEW MINUTES
GLAD-HANDING THE HIGH ROLLERS.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
HE'S FLUENT IN SPANISH,
GERMAN, AND ITALIAN,
AND HE'S TAKING
JAPANESE LESSONS.
HE'S GETTIN' PRETTY GOOD
AT IT.
[SPEAKS JAPANESE]
HE'S OUT BY 7:30
WHEN AN ASSISTANT HANDS HIM
A BLACK PORTFOLIO.
CONTENTS: THE DAY'S TAKE
AND NEW SECURITY CODES.
THEN HE HEADS
TO THE RESTAURANT.
LIKE I SAID...
A MACHINE.
THAT PORTFOLIO
CONTAINS THE CODES
TO ALL
THE CAGE DOORS?
MM-HMM. AND 2 MINUTES
AFTER THEY'VE BEEN CHANGED,
HE'S GOT 'EM IN HIS HAND.
I TELL YOU, YOU GUYS
REALLY CAN PICK 'EM.
THIS GUY IS AS SMART
AS HE IS RUTHLESS.
THE LAST GUY THEY CAUGHT
CHEATING IN HERE,
HE NOT ONLY SENT HIM UP
FOR 10 YEARS,
BUT HE HAD THE BANK
SEIZE HIS HOUSE,
AND THEN
HE BANKRUPTED--
HIS BROTHER-IN-LAW'S
TRACTOR DEALERSHIP. I HEARD.
HE DOESN'T JUST
TAKE OUT YOUR KNEES.
THE GUY GOES AFTER
YOUR LIVELIHOOD
AND THE LIVELIHOOD
OF ANYBODY YOU EVER MET.
YOU SCARED?
YOU SUICIDAL?
ONLY IN THE MORNING.
NOW WHAT?
NOW COMES A GIRL.
SHE COMES DOWN AFTER HIM
IF THEY'RE IN A SNIT.
WHERE'S SHE
COME FROM?
MUSEUM UP THERE.
SHE'S A CURATOR.
OH. HERE SHE IS.
THIS IS JUST
THE BEST PART OF MY DAY.
I STILL DON'T KNOW
IF WE CAN USE HER YET.
ACTUALLY, I HAVEN'T
EVEN CAUGHT HER NAME.
TESS.
HUH?
HER NAME IS TESS.
WE HAVE TO TALK.
OK.
NOW.
TELL ME
THIS IS NOT ABOUT HER,
OR I AM WALKING.
I AM WALKING
OFF THIS JOB RIGHT NOW.
WHO?
TESS. TERRY BENEDICT.
TELL ME
THIS IS NOT ABOUT
SCREWING THE GUY THAT'S
SCREWING YOUR WIFE.
EX-WIFE.
TELL ME.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THAT.
IT'S NOT ENTIRELY
ABOUT THAT.
RUSS, DO YOU REMEMBER WHEN WE
FIRST GOT INTO THIS BUSINESS?
WE SAID WE WERE
GONNA PLAY THE GAME
LIKE WE HAD NOTHING TO LOSE.
WELL, I LOST SOMETHING.
I LOST SOMEONE.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
[EXHALES]
OK, HERE'S THE PROBLEM.
NOW WE'RE
STEALING 2 THINGS.
AND WHEN
PUSH COMES TO SHOVE,
IF YOU CAN'T HAVE BOTH,
WHICH ARE YOU GONNA CHOOSE?
AND REMEMBER,
TESS DOES NOT SPLIT 11 WAYS.
IF EVERYTHING GOES TO PLAN,
THEN I WON'T BE THE ONE
THAT HAS TO MAKE THAT CHOICE.
HOW'D SHE LOOK?
SHE LOOKED GOOD.
THANKS.
[INAUDIBLE]
YOU LIKE IT?
I LIKE THAT
YOU LIKE IT.
I'LL SEE YOU TONIGHT?
OK.
IN MY HOTELS,
THERE'S ALWAYS
SOMEBODY WATCHING.
I'LL SEE YOU TONIGHT.
Man: A WEAK STOMACH,
MR. ZERGA?
I DON'T BELIEVE
IN WEAKNESS.
IT COSTS TOO MUCH.
I DON'T BELIEVE
IN QUESTIONS, EITHER.
OH, REALLY?
WELL, LET ME
GIVE YOU A TIP.
I WOULDN'T GET
INTO TERRY BENEDICT
FOR TOO MUCH MONEY.
HE DOESN'T FOOL
AROUND.
MORNING,
EDDIE.
MORNING, SIR.
ANYTHING FOR ME?
MR. ZERGA, LYMAN ZERGA,
IN THE THIRD POSITION,
WANTS TO SPEAK TO YOU
PRIVATELY.
WHO IS HE?
BUSINESSMAN OF SOME KIND,
WORKING MOSTLY IN EUROPE.
VERY VAGUE.
BUT I ASKED AROUND.
WORD IS HE DEALS
PRIMARILY IN ARMS--
ONE OF THE BIGGEST.
ZERGA.
YES, SIR.
NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
THAT'S WHY
I DON'T DOUBT IT.
HE STAYING HERE?
CHECKED IN 2 NIGHTS AGO.
HE'S IN THE MIRADOR SUITE.
HOW'S HE DOING?
UP. ALMOST 200.
GOOD FOR HIM.
YOU'RE 30 SECONDS LATE.
I WAS ABOUT TO SEND OUT
A SEARCH--
HELLO, TESS.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I'M OUT.
YOU'RE OUT.
OF PRISON.
YOU REMEMBER THE DAY
THAT I WENT FOR CIGARETTES
AND I DIDN'T COME BACK?
YOU MUST HAVE NOTICED.
I DON'T SMOKE.
DON'T SIT.
AHH. NOW, THEY TELL ME
THAT I PAID MY DEBT TO SOCIETY.
FUNNY,
I NEVER GOT A CHECK.
YOU'RE NOT WEARING
YOUR RING.
I SOLD IT. I DON'T
HAVE A HUSBAND,
OR DIDN'T YOU
GET THE PAPERS?
MY LAST DAY INSIDE.
I TOLD YOU I'D WRITE.
DANNY...GO NOW, BEFORE--
WHAT? BENEDICT?
HOW YOU DOING?
WHISKEY,
AND A WHISKEY.
DANNY--
TESS, YOU'RE
DOING A GREAT JOB
CURATING THE MUSEUM.
THE VERMEER IS QUITE GOOD.
IT'S SIMPLE, VIBRANT,
ALTHOUGH HIS WORK DEFINITELY
FELL OFF AS HE GOT OLDER.
REMIND YOU
OF ANYONE?
AND I ALWAYS CONFUSE
MONET AND MANET.
NOW, WHICH ONE
MARRIED HIS MISTRESS?
MONET.
RIGHT. AND THEN
MANET HAD SYPHILIS.
THEY ALSO PAINTED
OCCASIONALLY.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL MAKE THIS QUICK.
I CAME HERE FOR YOU.
I WANNA
GET ON WITH MY LIFE.
I WANT YOU WITH ME.
YOU'RE A THIEF
AND A LIAR.
I ONLY LIED
ABOUT BEING A THIEF.
I DON'T DO THAT
ANYMORE.
STEAL?
LIE.
I'M WITH SOMEONE NOW
WHO DOESN'T HAVE TO MAKE
THAT KIND OF DISTINCTION.
NO, HE'S
VERY CLEAR ON BOTH.
YOU KNOW WHAT
YOUR PROBLEM IS?
I ONLY HAVE ONE?
YOU'VE MET TOO MANY
PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
I'M WITH TERRY NOW.
DOES HE MAKE YOU LAUGH?
HE DOESN'T
MAKE ME CRY.
Saul: MR. BENEDICT,
THE FIGHT IS SATURDAY
NIGHT, IS IT NOT?
YES. WOULD YOU
LIKE SOME TICKETS?
NO. HAND-TO-HAND COMBAT
DOES NOT INTEREST ME.
I HAVE A PACKAGE
ARRIVING HERE THAT EVENING,
BLACK BRIEFCASE,
STANDARD SIZE,
THE CONTENTS OF WHICH
IS VERY VALUABLE TO ME.
I'LL PUT IT
IN THE HOUSE SAFE FOR YOU.
THE HOUSE SAFE
IS FOR BRANDY
AND GRANDMOTHERS'
PEARLS.
I NEED SOMETHING
MORE SECURE.
MR. ZERGA,
I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT OUR HOUSE SAFE--
AND I CAN ASSURE YOU,
MR. BENEDICT,
THAT YOUR GENEROSITY
IN THIS MANNER
WILL NOT
GO OVERLOOKED.
NOW...WHAT CAN YOU
OFFER ME
BESIDES THE SAFE?
SEE, THE PEOPLE
YOU STEAL THINGS FROM?
THEY HAVE INSURANCE
TO COMPENSATE THEM.
THEY GET
MADE WHOLE AGAIN.
I HAD TO LEAVE NEW YORK
TO GET AWAY FROM WHAT HAPPENED.
HOW AM I GONNA GET
MY 5 YEARS BACK, DANNY?
YOU CAN'T.
BUT WHAT YOU CAN DO IS
NOT THROW AWAY ANOTHER--
OH, YOU DON'T KNOW ANY--
TESS, ALL RIGHT.
YOU DON'T LOVE ME
ANYMORE.
YOU WANT TO MAKE A LIFE
WITH SOMEONE ELSE, FINE.
I'M GONNA HAVE
TO LIVE WITH THAT.
BUT NOT HIM.
SPOKEN LIKE
A TRUE EX-HUSBAND.
I'M NOT JOKING, TESS.
I'M NOT LAUGHING, DANNY.
YOU HAVE TO ADMIT THERE IS
A BIT OF CONFLICT OF INTEREST
WHEN YOU GIVE ME ADVICE
ABOUT MY LOVE LIFE.
YES, BUT THAT DOESN'T
MEAN THAT I'M WRONG.
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT I SAID
TO YOU WHEN WE FIRST MET?
YOU SAID THAT I BETTER
KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
DO YOU? YEAH?
BECAUSE, TRULY, YOU SHOULD
WALK OUT THE DOOR IF YOU DON'T.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
Benedict:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
JUST CATCHING UP.
TERRY,
MEET MY EX-HUSBAND.
DANNY OCEAN.
MR. OCEAN.
I'M IN YOUR SEAT.
FORGIVE ME
FOR BEING LATE.
A GUEST REQUIRED
MY ATTENTION.
THAT'S FINE.
DANNY WAS WALKING
THROUGH THE RESTAURANT
AND SPOTTED ME.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YEAH.
IMAGINE
THE ODDS.
"OF ALL THE GIN JOINTS
IN ALL THE WORLD."
YOU RECENTLY WERE RELEASED
FROM PRISON, IS THAT CORRECT?
Ocean: THAT'S RIGHT.
Benedict: HOW DOES IT
FEEL TO BE OUT?
Ocean: ABOUT THE SAME.
DANNY WAS
JUST ABOUT TO--
I JUST STOPPED BY
TO SAY HI TO TESS
FOR OLD TIMES' SAKE.
STAY AND HAVE A DRINK.
I CAN'T.
HE CAN'T.
Benedict: WELL, THEN...
I DON'T IMAGINE WE'LL BE SEEING
MR. OCEAN ANYTIME SOON, RIGHT?
Ocean: YOU NEVER KNOW.
AH, I KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT'S HAPPENING IN MY HOTELS.
Ocean: SO I SHOULD
PUT THOSE TOWELS BACK?
NO, THE TOWELS YOU CAN KEEP.
GOOD TO SEE YOU, TESS.
TAKE CARE, DANNY.
TERRY.
DANNY.
[INAUDIBLE SPEECH]
OH.
STINKIN'...
TOMORROW, THE DAY IS YOURS.
DO WITH IT WHAT YOU LIKE.
CALL IS AT 5:30--
MAKEUP AND COSTUME.
SAUL'S PACKAGE
ARRIVES AT 7:05.
LINUS GRABS OUR CODES.
ALL GOES WELL,
WE'RE A GO.
7:30, YEN GETS LOCKED IN.
WE'RE COMMITTED.
FROM THIS POINT WE HAVE
30 MINUTES TO BLOW THE POWER
OR HE SUFFOCATES.
Rusty: ONCE
THE ELECTRICITY GOES,
ALL ACCESS POINTS
TO THE VAULT AND ITS ELEVATOR
WILL AUTOMATICALLY SHUT DOWN
FOR 2 MINUTES.
THAT'S WHEN
WE MAKE OUR MOVE.
OK, IT PUTS YOU
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE ROOM,
10 FEET FROM EVERYTHING.
YOU HAVE TO GET
FROM THERE TO THE DOOR
WITHOUT TOUCHING THE FLOOR.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
10 SAYS HE SHORTS IT.
20.
HMM.
WINDOW OR AISLE, BOYS?
YEAH,
WE'RE IN DEEP SHIT.
THAT POXY DEMO CREW
HAVEN'T USED A COAXIAL
TO BATTEN THE MAIN LINE,
HAVE THEY?
THEY'VE ONLY NOSED UP
THE MAINFRAME COUPLET.
NOSED IT RIGHT UP!
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
ANY OF THIS?
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
LISTEN, THEY'RE SO PONIED
THAT THEY'VE GONE AND BLOWN
THE BACKUP GRID
ONE BY ONE LIKE DOMINOES.
Ocean: BASHER,
WHAT HAPPENED?
Basher: THEY DID THE SAME
WHAT I WOULD HAVE DONE,
ONLY THEY DID IT
BY ACCIDENT.
PROBLEM IS NOW THEY KNOW
THEIR WEAKNESS
AND THEY'RE SORTING IT OUT.
THEY'RE FIXING IT.
Ocean: SO--
SO UNLESS WE INTEND
TO DO THIS JOB IN RENO,
WE'RE IN BARNEY.
BARNEY RUBBLE--
TROUBLE!
MM-HMM.
WE COULD
ALWAYS--
BY TOMORROW?
HANG ON A MINUTE.
HANG ON.
WE COULD USE A PINCH.
WHAT'S A "PINCH"?
A PINCH IS A DEVICE
WHICH CREATES,
LIKE, A CARDIAC ARREST
FOR ANY BROADBAND
ELECTRICAL CIRCUITRY.
OR BETTER YET,
A PINCH IS A BOMB,
NOW, BUT WITHOUT THE BOMB.
SEE, WHEN A NUCLEAR WEAPON
DETONATES,
IT UNLEASHES
AN ELECTROMAGNETIC PULSE
WHICH SHUTS DOWN
ANY POWER SOURCE
WITHIN ITS BLAST RADIUS.
NOW, THAT TENDS
NOT TO MATTER IN MOST CASES
BECAUSE THE NUCLEAR WEAPON
USUALLY DESTROYS EVERYTHING
YOU MIGHT NEED POWER
FOR ANYWAY,
BUT, SEE, A PINCH CREATES
A SIMILAR
ELECTROMAGNETIC PULSE
BUT WITHOUT THE FUSS OF
MASS DESTRUCTION AND DEATH.
SO INSTEAD OF HIROSHIMA,
YOU'D BE GETTING
THE 17th CENTURY.
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 30 SECONDS.
COULD A PINCH KNOCK OUT
THE POWER OF AN ENTIRE CITY?
LIKE FOR INSTANCE--
LAS VEGAS?
YEAH, I THINK IT MIGHT.
BUT THERE'S ONLY
ONE PINCH IN THE WORLD
BIG ENOUGH TO MANAGE IT.
Ocean: WHERE?
Ocean: LET'S GO!
BASHER, COME ON.
WHOA! WHERE YOU GOING?
I'M COMING WITH YOU.
NO.
UH, NO. NO!
DON'T LEAVE ME
WITH THESE GUYS!
OH, FOR THE--
I'LL START.
OK, GO AHEAD.
I GOT ONE.
ARE YOU GONNA THINK
OF ONE OR--
NO, I'VE ALREADY
THOUGHT OF ONE.
I'M NOT GOING
TO THINK--
ALL RIGHT, SO YOU'RE
THINKING OF ONE RIGHT NOW?
NO, I'M DONE
THINKING ABOUT IT.
I HAVE IT IN MY HEAD.
ARE YOU A MAN?
YES. 19.
ARE YOU ALIVE?
YES. 18.
EVEL KNIEVEL.
SHIT!
I'M NOT TOUCHING YOU.
TAKE YOUR HAND
OUT OF MY FACE.
MY HAND'S NOT IN YOUR--
AM I TOUCHING YOU?
YOUR HAND'S RIGHT
IN FRONT OF MY FACE.
I'M NOT TOUCHING YOU.
I DIDN'T TOUCH YOU.
YOU JUST TOUCHED ME.
NO.
YOU MADE ME TOUCH YOU.
NO, NO, NO.
THIS IS YOUR SIDE.
[BOTH ARGUING AT ONCE]
[FIGHTING]
Basher: ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA NEED A SCORE
OF CAR BATTERIES,
ALONG WITH
A COUPLE WIRE--
WHERE'S LINUS?
WHAT?
WHERE'S LINUS?!
[BRAKES SQUEAL]
Ocean: THERE HE IS.
OH, WOULD YOU LOOK
AT THE STONER?
[YEN SPEAKING CHINESE]
SHOULDN'T SOMEBODY
HELP HIM?
OH, NOW, THAT'S
A GREAT IDEA, RABBIT.
LET'S HOP OUT OF THE VAN
AND WE CAN ALL GET NICKED.
[WINDOW SHATTERING]
BACK IT UP!
LET HIM IN.
Basher:
YOU STUPID BASTARD!
AAH!
JESUS!
I SAY STAY IN THE VAN,
YOU STAY IN THE VAN.
YOU GOT IT?!
GOT IT!
LOSE FOCUS IN THIS GAME
FOR ONE SECOND--
I SAID I GOT IT!
I GOT IT.
[SPEAKS CHINESE]
WHERE ARE THEY?
THAT'S
WHAT I WANNA KNOW.
WHERE THE HELL
ARE THEY?!
Saul: THEY WILL BE HERE.
[MOCKING]
THEY WILL BE HERE.
SCHMUCK.
Rusty: YOU BOYS
HAVE A NICE TRIP?
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
YOU'VE BEEN RED-FLAGGED.
IT MEANS THE MOMENT
YOU SET FOOT
ON THAT CASINO FLOOR,
THEY'LL BE
WATCHING YOU...
LIKE HAWKS--
HAWKS
WITH VIDEO CAMERAS.
THAT'S A PROBLEM.
Rusty: SAUL,
TURN THAT OFF, WILL YOU?
I'LL TURN IT OFF
WHEN I'M READY TO TURN IT--
SAUL!
IT'S OFF. IT'S OFF.
ANY IDEA
HOW THIS HAPPENED?
NO.
OH, COME ON.
HE'S BEEN CHASING
BENEDICT'S GIRL.
THE TWO OF THEM GOT IN
AN ARGUMENT 2 NIGHTS AGO.
I WAS TAILING YOU.
AND WHO TOLD YOU
TO DO THAT?
I DID. I WAS CONCERNED
YOU COULDN'T
LEAVE TESS ALONE.
WHO'S TESS?
MY WIFE.
Rusty: EX-WIFE.
TESS IS HERE?
I'M SORRY. I DIDN'T KNOW
IF IT WOULD STING YOU,
BUT IT DID.
YOU'RE OUT, DANNY.
HE'S OUT?!
IT'S EITHER THAT OR WE
CALL THE WHOLE THING OFF.
HIS INVOLVEMENT
PUTS US ALL AT RISK.
THIS IS NOT YOUR CALL.
OH, YOU MADE IT MY CALL.
WHEN YOU PUT HER BEFORE US,
YOU MADE IT MINE.
THIS IS MY JOB.
NOT ANYMORE.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HE CAN'T JUST BE OUT.
WHO'S GONNA TRIGGER
THE VAULT?!
KID, YOU UP FOR IT?
I CAN DO IT.
Rusty: DONE.
LOCATE THE OTHERS.
LET THEM KNOW
THE CHANGE IN PLAN.
CURTAIN GOES UP
AT 7:00.
Saul: TESS IS
WITH BENEDICT NOW?
SHE'S TOO TALL
FOR HIM.
Benedict: YES.
NO.
VERY MUCH NO.
WELL, THEN
INFORM MR. LEVIN
THAT HE'LL BE BETTER OFF
WATCHING THE FIGHT
IN FRONT OF
HIS TELEVISION AT HOME,
'CAUSE SURELY
HE MUST HAVE HBO.
THAT'S IT.
[CELL PHONE BEEPS OFF]
HI.
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING ABOUT?
YOU.
Rusty: WHERE YOU
GONNA PUT YOUR HANDS?
NO GOOD.
DON'T TOUCH YOUR TIE.
LOOK AT ME.
OK, I ASK YOU
A QUESTION.
YOU HAVE TO THINK
OF THE ANSWER.
WHERE DO YOU LOOK?
NO GOOD.
YOU LOOK DOWN,
THEY KNOW YOU'RE LYING.
AND UP, THEY KNOW YOU
DON'T KNOW THE TRUTH.
DON'T USE 7 WORDS
WHEN 4 WILL DO.
DON'T SHIFT YOUR WEIGHT.
LOOK ALWAYS AT YOUR MARK,
BUT DON'T STARE.
BE SPECIFIC,
BUT NOT MEMORABLE.
BE FUNNY, BUT
DON'T MAKE HIM LAUGH.
HE'S GOTTA LIKE YOU
AND THEN FORGET YOU
THE MOMENT
YOU'VE LEFT HIS SIGHT.
AND FOR GOD'S SAKE,
WHATEVER YOU DO,
DON'T, UNDER
ANY CIRCUMSTANCES--
RUSS!
YEAH?
CAN YOU TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS?
Rusty: SURE.
SAUL?
IT'S TIME.
YEAH.
OK.
LET'S DO IT.
Jim Lampley: ON A PERFECTLY
CLEAR NIGHT IN LAS VEGAS
AND WITH THE EXPECTED CROWD
OF CELEBRITIES
AND EAGER SPORTS FANS
PILING INTO THE MGM GRAND
GARDEN ARENA.
THE 2 BEST HEAVYWEIGHTS
IN THE WORLD
PREPARE TO MEET
AFTER AN 8-MONTH DANCE
AROUND AND TOWARD
EACH OTHER.
MR. ZERGA.
MR. BENEDICT.
IT'S A VERY BUSY NIGHT FOR ME.
ARE WE ON SCHEDULE?
I HAVE NO REASON
TO SUSPECT OTHERWISE.
MY COURIER SHOULD
BE HERE MOMENTARILY.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
18. BLACKJACK!
FIND MR. WALSH.
TELL HIM MR. OCEAN'S
IN THE WEST SLOTS.
I'M AFRAID I CAN'T HAVE ANY
PRIVATE SECURITY PERSONNEL
IN THE CASINO CAGES.
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SAUL! SAUL BLOOM,
IS THAT YOU?
SAUL! SAUL, IT'S ME!
BUCKY BUCHANAN, REMEMBER?
FROM SARATOGA.
MIKHAIL, VLADIMIR.
HEY! HEY! SAUL! SAUL!
HEY!
MR. BENEDICT, PLEASE.
I HAVE NEVER ENJOYED
THE TOUCH OF STEEL
TO MY SKIN.
LIFT THEM UP, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, MR. ZERGA,
I ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT YOUR BRIEFCASE
DOES NOT CONTAIN
ANY DANGEROUS
OR ILLICIT MATERIAL,
AND I FURTHER AGREE TO TAKE
CUSTODY OF SAID BRIEFCASE
AND STORE IT
IN MY SECURED VAULT
FOR A PERIOD OF 24 HOURS.
NOW, I CANNOT
ACTUALLY ALLOW YOU
TO ACCOMPANY THE BRIEFCASE
INTO THE VAULT.
WHY NOT?
INSURANCE FOR ONE,
SECURITY ANOTHER,
BUT MOST OF ALL,
I JUST DON'T TRUST YOU.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
EXCUSE ME.
2 PLAINCLOTHES ON OCEAN.
HE'S IN THE KENO BAR NOW.
MR. ZERGA, THIS IS
MY CASINO MANAGER MR. WALSH.
NOW, IF YOU WILL ALLOW HIM,
HE WILL ARRANGE
FOR YOUR BRIEFCASE TO BE
STORED INSIDE OUR VAULT
WHILE YOU WATCH
ON A SECURITY MONITOR.
THOSE ARE MY TERMS.
YES OR NO?
YOU LEAVE ME
NO CHOICE.
GOOD.
PLEASE DON'T DO THAT.
Livingston on radio:
DEEP BREATHS. YOU'LL DO FINE.
THANK YOU.
NO SWEAT.
YOU'RE A NATURAL,
BUT DON'T SCREW UP.
WHO GETS THE PENNE?
RIGHT HERE.
YOU READY?
THIS IS OUR SECURITY CENTER
WHERE WE OVERSEE ALL GAMING IN
THE CASINO AS WELL AS OUR VAULT.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO MONITOR
YOUR BRIEFCASE RIGHT FROM HERE.
DON'T LET ME KEEP YOU.
MR. ZERGA.
MR. BENEDICT.
LINUS, YOU'RE UP.
GOT HIM.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
MR. BENEDICT.
HI, SHELDON WILLIS,
NEVADA GAMING COMMISSION.
I'M AFRAID I NEED
2 MINUTES OF YOUR TIME.
ANYTHING FOR THE NGC.
THANK YOU.
WILL YOU ACCOMPANY ME
TO PIT 5, PLEASE?
Rusty: OK, WHEN DO YOU
MAKE THE DEPOSIT?
UH, WHEN WE
GET YOUR SIGNAL.
DUDE, WHAT DO WE LOOK LIKE?
A COUPLE OF PECKERWOOD
JACKASSES OR SOMETHING?
AMAZING.
HOW'S THAT FEEL?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YOU WANT SOMETHING
TO READ? MAGAZINE?
ALL RIGHT.
COUNTING DOWN.
30 MINUTES OF
BREATHING TIME STARTS...
NOW.
THIS JUST CAME TO OUR
ATTENTION THIS MORNING.
APPARENTLY HE'S GOT
A RECORD LONGER THAN MY...
WELL, IT'S LONG.
IF HE IS
WHO YOU SAY HE IS.
YOU BEEN
AT THE COMMISSION LONG?
ABOUT 18 MONTHS.
YOU KNOW HAL LINDY OVER THERE?
WORK WITH HIM AT ALL?
NOT SINCE HE DIED
LAST YEAR.
RAMON ESCALANTE?
YES.
SHELDON WILLIS,
NEVADA GAMING COMMISSION.
WHAT'S--
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT'S COME TO OUR ATTENTION
THAT WHEN YOU APPLIED--
I THINK IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF WE SPEAK OFF THE FLOOR.
CHARLIE.
THANK YOU.
NO, DANNY.
TESS--
NO, I WANT YOU
OUT OF HERE.
I JUST NEED YOU
FOR ONE MOMENT.
I'VE HAD IT WITH THIS.
COME HERE.
TESS, COME HERE.
HEY!
YOU ARE UP TO SOMETHING,
DANNY. WHAT?
AND DON'T SAY
YOU CAME HERE FOR ME.
YOU'RE PULLING A JOB,
AREN'T YOU?
WELL, KNOW THIS.
NO MATTER WHAT IT IS,
YOU WON'T WIN ME BACK.
TESS, I JUST CAME
TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
GOOD-BYE.
YOU BE GOOD.
MR. OCEAN.
MR. BENEDICT WOULD
LIKE TO SEE YOU.
I THOUGHT HE MIGHT.
AFTERNOON,
MR. ESCALANTE.
OR SHOULD I CALL YOU
MR. CATTON?
YOU ARE FRANK CATTON
FORMERLY
OF THE TROPICANA,
THE DESERT INN,
AND THE NEW YORK STATE
PENITENTIARY SYSTEM,
ARE YOU NOT?
TAKE IT FROM YOUR SILENCE
THAT YOU'RE
NOT GONNA REFUTE THAT.
MR. BENEDICT, I'M AFRAID YOU'VE
BEEN EMPLOYING AN EX-CONVICT.
AS YOU KNOW, THE NGC--
GODDAMN CRACKER.
EXCUSE ME?
YOU HEARD WHAT I SAID.
BLACK MAN CAN'T EARN
A DECENT WAGE IN THIS STATE.
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY--
YOU GONNA TRY TO THROW ME
OUT ON THE STREET.
THAT'S RIGHT. I'M TRYING
TO DO MY JOB, SIR.
WHAT YOU WANT FROM ME, MAN?
WANT ME TO GET ON THE TABLE
AND DANCE?
LIKE ME TO SHINE YOUR SHOES?
WANT ME TO SMILE AT YOU?
'CAUSE YOU DEFINITELY
WON'T LET ME DEAL THE CARDS.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
CALL IT WHITEJACK.
GO ON!
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY TO THAT.
THAT'S--SORRY,
MR. BENEDICT,
I JUST RESENT
THE IMPLICATION
THAT RACE HAS ANYTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
YEAH, RIGHT.
HORRIBLE THING TO SAY.
YOU, SIR, OF ALL PEOPLE,
KNOW THAT WE AT THE NGC
HAVE ALWAYS SUPPORTED
THE HIRING OF COLORED--
NO! NO! I DIDN'T
MEAN IT! I DIDN'T.
OK, OK.
COME ON. SIT DOWN.
SIT DOWN.
YOU BETTER TALK TO HIM.
HE'S GOT IT.
Benedict: SIT DOWN.
VIRGIL, TURK,
DELIVER THE PACKAGE.
Linus on video:
I'M SORRY.
HI.
WHERE'S YOUR CARD?
OH, GOD! I THINK
I LOST MY CARD.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?!
OH, JESUS,
I'M SO SORRY.
YOU ARE SO STUPID,
YOU KNOW THAT?!
YOU'RE A NINCOMPOOP!
GUYS! HEY, DON'T--
HEY, DON'T--
[ALL SHOUTING AT ONCE]
HEY!
KEEP IT DOWN.
SORRY. SORRY.
HEY, WHERE--JUST TELL ME
WHERE DID THIS--
HIGH ROLLERS' ROOM.
THIS IS MR. BENEDICT'S
STUFF IN HERE.
IT'S HIS STUFF.
ALL RIGHT, JOE.
TAKE THIS INSIDE.
TO THE COUNT ROOM?
NO! TO THE, UH, VAULT.
BENEDICT'S MONEY GOES
IN THE VAULT. YOU KNOW THAT.
I'M SORRY.
HEY!
NEXT TIME,
JUST REMEMBER THE CARD.
WE WON'T
RUN INTO THIS AGAIN.
STUPID.
YO! HOLD THAT, PLEASE.
Walsh: THERE. THERE'S
YOUR BRIEFCASE NOW, MR. ZERGA.
WO-WONDERFUL.
THAT'S MY CUE.
GIVE BASH
THE GO.
BASH, WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
Livingston: BASH!
EASY, EASY. NO NEED
TO SHOUT, GUV'NOR.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
YEAH, I'M NEARLY THERE.
Benedict: COME ON,
COME ON.
MR. WALSH...
SHOW THIS MAN
OFF THE PREMISES.
DON'T EVER SET FOOT
IN MY CASINO AGAIN.
SIR?
CRACKER!
OH, DEAR GOD!
OH.
OH, I--I FORGOT
MY PAGER.
I LEFT IT. SORRY.
[SIGHS]
YOU KNOW
YOUR WAY BACK?
Linus: I DO.
GOOD.
OK, ENJOY THE FIGHT.
SORRY.
Ocean: SO HOW MUCH LONGER
YOU FIGURE
MR. BENEDICT'S GONNA BE?
HMM.
NO CAMERAS
IN THIS ROOM, HUH?
YEAH.
DON'T WANT ANYBODY SEEIN'
WHAT GOES ON IN HERE.
HE'S NOT COMIN', IS HE?
[THUMP THUMP THUMP]
Man: WE'RE GONNA
STEP OUTSIDE NOW,
LEAVE YOU TWO ALONE
TO TALK THINGS OVER.
THE WEDDING'S
IN 3 WEEKS.
IT'S ALL "I LOVE YOU.
YOU LOVE ME.
I CHOOSE YOU.
YOU CHOOSE ME."
AND I'M HOPIN' IT'S...
I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW,
BUT, UH...
YOU KNOW IT'S PART
OF IT, YOU KNOW.
1 P.M., SHE'S
EXPECTING ME AT 11 A.M.
SO NEEDLESS TO SAY,
IT'S GONNA BE CRAZY.
I SAID, "WHAT THE HECK
"DO YOU EXPECT?
WE'RE UP AT THECASA.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK THOSE ARE?"
IT'S ALL CHOIR
PRACTICE, REALLY.
GOTTA DO IT.
OH, SHIT.
Walsh: THERE, DOES THAT
SATISFY YOU, MR. ZERGA?
I AM VERY SATISFIED.
ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT, SIR?
I'M FINE. I'M FINE.
ALL RIGHT.
AAH! AAH.
JESUS.
BRUISER,
NOT UNTIL LATER.
SORRY, DANNY.
I--I FORGOT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HOW'S YOUR WIFE?
PREGNANT AGAIN.
WELL, THAT HAPPENS.
LET'S GET STARTED.
COME HERE. UNH!
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
YOU'RE ALMOST THERE, LINUS.
WHO'S THAT GUY?
A-31, I GOT A BOGIE
IN THE WEST CORRIDOR.
UNH!
Walsh: MR. ZERGA.
[BELL RINGS]
CALL A DOCTOR!
SIR, PUT THIS
UNDERNEATH HIS HEAD.
GOING TO VIDEO...
Man: WE NEED A DOCTOR.
NOW.
THE EYE IN THE SKY, ASAP.
WE HAVE A MAN DOWN, AND HE
APPEARS TO BE UNCONSCIOUS.
OH, JESUS!
NOW YOU REALLY
DIDN'T THINK
I WAS GONNA SIT
THIS ONE OUT, DID YA?
WHAT, YOU
DIDN'T TRUST ME?
[SNAPS FINGERS]
I DO NOW.
UNH!
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
DID SOMEONE CALL
FOR A DOCTOR?
AND HOW DID
YOU GET HERE?
IF YOU GIVE A FRIEND
A COUPLE MILLION...
YEAH, BUT WHAT ABOUT RUSTY,
THE WHOLE ARGUMENT, YOU KNOW?
WHAT WAS THAT ABOUT?
WELL...
AW, COME ON.
YOU KNOW, WHY DON'T YOU
JUST TELL ME?
WHY--WHY DO YOU HAVE
TO PUT ME THROUGH ALL THIS?
WHERE'S THE FUN
IN THAT?
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET GOIN'.
Rusty: UNH!
COME ON, MAN, BREATHE!
BREATHE, DAMN IT!
BREATHE!
I'M SORRY.
WE'VE LOST HIM.
Medic: DUDE,
I TOLD YOU TO HURRY.
Second medic: DON'T DO THAT.
JUST DON'T DO THAT.
I DIDN'T
TELL YOU TO HURRY?
Bruiser: UNH! UNH!
COME ON, GET UP! GET UP!
UNH! AAH!
[GROANS]
HAD ENOUGH YET?
AAH! [CRASH]
Linus: THESE THINGS
ARE GONNA HOLD US, RIGHT?
Ocean: THEY SHOULD.
[SIGHS] HA HA.
OOH.
LIVINGSTON, WE'RE SET.
BASHER, WE'RE SET.
HANG ON A MINUTE, CHIEF.
Livingston: LOOK,
WE DON'T HAVE A MINUTE.
YEN'S GONNA SUFFOCATE.
WELL, THEN, YOU'D BETTER
LEAVE OFF BOTHERIN' ME,
DON'T YOU THINK?
[BELL CLANGS]
Ocean: ALL RIGHT,
CRACK 'EM.
GO.
AAH!
SHIT.
CUT IT.
UNH.
UNH!
AAH.
[CROWD BOOS]
[BELL CLANGS]
HEY!
UNH!
SECURITY AT 10-33.
PIT 6, TABLE 5.
DEALER'S
COMPROMISED.
...BEEN BREACHED.
TABLES 3, 5, 6, AND 10.
[ALL SCREAM]
UNH!
GET YOUR COAT.
THIS IS CRAZY.
[BEEPS]
[THUD]
NO, NOT YET,
BUDDY.
[THUD]
GOT IT.
YOU THINK
YEN MADE IT OUT OK?
I'M SURE
HE'LL BE FINE.
HOW WE DOIN'?
OK...
I GUESS.
[SIGHS]
JESUS.
THERE'S A 95-POUND
CHINESE MAN
WITH $160 MILLION
BEHIND THIS DOOR.
LET'S GET HIM OUT.
YEAH.
[THUMP THUMP THUMP]
10 SAYS
HE SHORTS IT.
NO BET.
TRY HIM AGAIN.
[THUMP THUMP]
[SIGHS]
[YEN POUNDS]
OK.
HEY. WHERE WE AT, BOYS?
PINS AND
FLOOR SENSORS NOW.
BLINDER.
[SIGHS]
HERE WE GO.
AH! [GRUNTS]
COUNTING DOWN
FROM 20...NOW.
20...
[GRUNTS]
DO NOT BLOW THE DOOR.
LINUS, CAN YOU READ ME?
10, 9, 8...
MAYBE THE PINCH
BLEW OUT HIS EARPIECE.
LINUS, CAN YOU READ ME?
DO NOT BLOW THE DOOR.
Ocean: 2, 1...
Linus: WHAT'S WRONG?
SOMETHIN'.
[SIGHS]
AH.
DID YOU CHECK
THE BATTERIES?
YOU KNOW...
IF YOU LOSE FOCUS IN
THIS GAME FOR ONE SECOND...
I KNOW.
SOMEBODY GETS HURT.
YOU DON'T HEAR
YEN COMPLAINING.
[BEEP, CRASH]
AAH!
YEN?
[THUD]
WHERE THE FUCK YOU BEEN?
SORRY. [SIGHS]
THAT IS THE SEXIEST THING
I HAVE EVER SEEN.
RUSTY, YOU'RE UP.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
[RING]
YOU GONNA ANSWER THAT?
I DON'T HAVE
A CELL PHONE.
[RING]
THIS ISN'T MINE.
SEE WHO IT IS.
HELLO?
Rusty: MAY I HAVE A WORD
WITH MR. BENEDICT?
IT'S FOR YOU.
WHO THE HELL
IS THIS?
Rusty: THE MAN
WHO'S ROBBING YOU.
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON IN THE VAULT?
UH, NOTHING, SIR.
IT'S ALL NORMAL.
SHOW ME.
Benedict: I'M AFRAID
YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
Rusty: YOU WATCHING
YOUR MONITORS?
OK, KEEP WATCHING.
IN THIS TOWN, YOUR LUCK
CAN CHANGE JUST THAT QUICKLY.
FIND OUT HOW MUCH MONEY
WE HAVE DOWN THERE.
YES, SIR.
TESS.
PERHAPS
YOU SHOULD...
PERHAPS I SHOULD WHAT?
IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF YOU WEREN'T
AROUND HERE FOR THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU PROVED YOUR POINT.
YOU BROKE INTO MY VAULT.
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU'RE A DEAD MAN.
Rusty: MAYBE.
MAYBE? MAY I ASK HOW
YOU EXPECT TO LEAVE?
DO YOU BELIEVE
I'M GONNA ALLOW YOU
TO PARADE BAGS
FULL OF MY MONEY
OUT OF
MY CASINO DOORS?
NO, YOU'RE GONNA
CARRY IT OUT FOR US.
AND WHY WOULD I DO THAT?
TAKE A CLOSER LOOK
AT YOUR MONITOR.
AS YOUR MANAGER'S PROBABLY
REPORTING TO YOU NOW,
YOU HAVE A LITTLE
OVER $160 MILLION
IN YOUR VAULT TONIGHT.
YOU MAY NOTICE WE'RE ONLY
PACKING UP ABOUT HALF OF THAT.
THE OTHER HALF, WE'RE
LEAVING IN YOUR VAULT,
BOOBYTRAPPED
AS A HOSTAGE.
YOU LET
OUR 80 MILLION GO,
AND YOU GET
TO KEEP YOURS.
THAT'S THE DEAL.
IF YOU TRY AND STOP US,
WE'LL BLOW
BOTH CASH AMOUNTS.
MR. BENEDICT,
YOU CAN LOSE $80 MILLION
TONIGHT SECRETLY
OR YOU CAN LOSE
$160 MILLION PUBLICLY.
IT'S YOUR DECISION. HI.
MAKE THE CALL.
Man: 911 EMERGENCY RESPONSE.
WHERE'S DANNY?
DANNY'S FINE.
HE'S IN GOOD FORM.
HE REQUESTS THAT YOU GO
UPSTAIRS AND WATCH TV.
HE DOES?
WE HAVE 3 MEN
WITH EXPLOSIVES
WHO HAVE TAKEN CONTROL
OF OUR VAULT.
OK...
IT'S ALL RIGHT, TESS.
Benedict: YOU HAVE A DEAL.
I PROMISE. FANTASTIC.
HERE'S WHAT YOU DO.
Rusty: THE GUYS
IN THE VAULT
WILL DEPOSIT 6 BAGS
INTO THE VAULT ELEVATOR.
THE ELEVATOR WILL RISE
TO YOUR CAGES.
3 OF YOUR GUARDS
WILL PICK UP THE BAGS
AND CARRY THEM
OUT INTO THE CASINO.
NOW, IF THEY TAKE MORE
THAN 20 SECONDS
TO REACH THE CASINO FLOOR,
OR IF THERE'S ANY INDICATION
A SWITCH HAS BEEN MADE,
WE'LL BLOW
THE MONEY IN THE BAGS
AND THE MONEY IN THE VAULT.
HE'S IN THE CASINO
BY THE SLOTS.
Rusty: OF COURSE
I'M IN THE CASINO.
IN FACT, I'M STAYING
IN YOUR HOTEL.
I HAVE 2 WORDS FOR YOU:
MINI BAR.
Rusty: AS SOON AS YOUR GUARDS
HIT THE CASINO FLOOR,
A WHITE, UNMARKED VAN
IS GOING TO PULL UP
IN YOUR VALET STATION.
YOUR GUARDS WILL LOAD THE BAGS
INTO THE VAN'S REAR.
IF ANYONE SO MUCH AS APPROACHES
THE DRIVER'S DOOR,
WE'LL BLOW EVERYTHING.
WHEN I GET WORD
THE VAN IS AWAY
AND THE MONEY IS SECURE,
MY MEN
WILL EXIT THE BUILDING,
AND ONCE THEIR SAFETY
IS CONFIRMED,
YOU WILL GET
YOUR VAULT BACK.
S.W.A.T. TEAM
IS HERE.
ALL RIGHT. NOW...
I HAVE COMPLIED WITH
YOUR EVERY REQUEST,
WOULD YOU AGREE?
Rusty: I WOULD.
GOOD, 'CAUSE NOW
I HAVE ONE OF MY OWN.
RUN AND HIDE, ASSHOLE.
RUN AND HIDE.
IF YOU SHOULD
BE PICKED UP NEXT WEEK
BUYING A $100,000 SPORTS CAR
IN NEWPORT BEACH,
I AM GONNA BE SUPREMELY
DISAPPOINTED
BECAUSE I WANT
MY PEOPLE TO FIND YOU,
AND WHEN THEY DO,
REST ASSURED
WE'RE NOT GONNA HAND
YOU OVER TO THE POLICE,
SO MY ADVICE
TO YOU AGAIN IS THIS--
RUN AND HIDE.
NOW THAT'S
ALL THAT I ASK.
MR. BENEDICT,
OUR GUYS SAY
THAT VAN IS HEADED
TOWARD McCARRAN AIRPORT.
GET EVERYBODY
IN POSITION.
I WANT MY VAULT BACK
BEFORE THAT VAN
HITS THE TARMAC.
NIGHT GOGGLES ON.
PREPARE TO CUT POWER.
READY.
CUTTING POWER NOW.
Benedict: DO IT.
Man: BREACHING
ELEVATOR DOORS NOW.
WE HAVE 2 GUARDS,
BOUND, UNCONSCIOUS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
Man: GUYS! GUYS!
SOMEONE'S HERE! SOMEONE'S HERE!
TAKE HIM DOWN NOW!
I GOT HIM!
[GUNFIRE]
[CRASH, GLASS BREAKS]
Man: LIGHTS! LIGHTS!
WE NEED POWER NOW!
GIVE IT TO 'EM.
RELAX. RELAX,
ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT, TAKE IT EASY.
[ALL TALKING]
Benedict: WHAT'S GOING ON?
TALK TO ME.
Man: IT APPEARS A HIGH
EXPLOSIVE INCENDIARY DEVICE
HAS BEEN DETONATED.
I REPEAT,
CONTINUING
SEARCH FOR SURVIVORS.
TELL 'EM TO TAKE THE VAN.
I'M GOIN' DOWN THERE.
AND FIND OUT HOW
THEY HOOKED INTO MY SYSTEM!
YES, SIR.
GET OUT OF THE VAN NOW!
NOW!
TIRES. TIRES.
Man: SIR, OUR SEARCH
YIELDED NO SUSPECTS,
NOR WERE WE ABLE
TO DETERMINE AT THIS TIME
HOW THEY ENTERED
OR EXITED THE PREMISES.
TAKE YOUR MEN OUT.
SIR, MAY I SUGGEST
YOU STAND OUTSIDE
UNTIL THE BOMB SQUAD--
NOW.
IT'S YOUR VAULT.
BLUE TEAM, MOVE IT OUT!
[BEEPS]
WALSH, WHERE ARE WE
WITH THE VAN?
Man: OK,
I JUST WANNA
TRY SOMETHING HERE
FOR A SECOND.
THERE'S NOBODY INSIDE.
OOPS. OH,
I'M SORRY. OOP.
OH, NO,
YOU'RE GOING--
ENOUGH MONKEY BUSINESS.
DO IT ALREADY.
Walsh: MR. BENEDICT,
WE TOOK THE VAN, SIR.
Benedict: AND?
I'M AFRAID THAT
THERE WAS NO MONEY
IN THE BAGS, SIR.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
THERE'S NO MONEY IN THE BAGS?
THEY SAY THE BAGS WERE
FILLED WITH FLYERS, SIR,
FOR HOOKERS.
[BEEPS] WALSH.
CUE UP THE TAPE
TO THE ROBBERY.
[BEEPS]
YES, SIR. I'M LOOKING
AT THE TAPE NOW.
Benedict: DOES IT SAY "BELLAGIO"
ON THE VAULT FLOOR?
Walsh: NO, IT DOESN'T.
UH, I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
[BEEPS]
WE HAD IT INSTALLED
ON TUESDAY.
THE IMAGES WE SAW OF THOSE MEN
ROBBING US WAS A TAPE.
Walsh: WHAT?
IT WAS STAGED.
SOMEBODY MADE
A DUPLICATE OF MY VAULT,
AND WHAT WE SAW
ON THE MONITOR
WASN'T ACTUALLY HAPPENING.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO ALL THAT MONEY?
MAKE THE CALL.
911 EMERGENCY RESPONSE.
OY VEY.
NIGHT GOGGLES ON.
CHECK.
BETTER STEP OUT.
BREACHING
ELEVATOR DOORS NOW.
WE HAVE 2 GUARDS,
BOUND, UNCONSCIOUS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
ALL RIGHT! GUYS,
SOMEONE'S HERE! SOMEONE'S HERE!
TAKE HIM DOWN!
NOW!
I GOT HIM!
[GUNFIRE]
OPEN THE DOOR.
UNH!
UHH!
HEY, YA, BENEDICT.
HOW'S THE
OTHER FIGHT GOING?
PICK HIM UP.
[GROANS]
DID YOU HAVE A HAND
IN THIS?
DID I HAVE
MY HAND IN WHAT?
I'M GONNA ASK YOU
ONE MORE TIME.
DID YOU HAVE
A HAND IN THIS?
BENEDICT, I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
OK.
YOU'RE FREE TO GO.
SHOW HIM OUT.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO?
Livingston:
TURN TO CHANNEL 88.
WHO IS THIS?
Ocean: WHAT HAPPENED, BENEDICT?
YOU GET ROBBED OR SOMETHING?
Benedict: STOP.
Benedict: I'M GONNA GIVE YOU
ONE LAST CHANCE.
WHERE IS MY MONEY?
WHAT IF I TOLD YOU
I COULD GET YOUR MONEY BACK?
YOU GIVE UP TESS.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY?
I WOULD SAY YES.
ALL RIGHT.
I KNOW A GUY.
WE WERE
IN THE JOINT TOGETHER.
ANYBODY PULLS ANY JOB
IN THE WESTERN
UNITED STATES,
HE KNOWS ABOUT IT.
YOU GIVE ME 72 HOURS,
I'LL FIND OUT
WHO TOOK YOUR MONEY.
YOU KNOW A GUY.
SHOW MR. OCEAN THE EXIT
AND CONTACT THE POLICE.
I'M SURE HE'S IN
VIOLATION OF HIS PAROLE.
Guard: YES, SIR.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
TESS.
YOU OF ALL PEOPLE
SHOULD KNOW, TERRY.
IN YOUR HOTEL,
THERE'S ALWAYS
SOMEONE WATCHING.
WAIT!
THAT'S MY HUSBAND.
DANNY.
TESS, I TOLD YOU,
I KNEW WHAT I WAS DOING.
I DIDN'T.
Policeman:
ALL RIGHT. LET'S GO.
HOW LONG
WILL YOU BE?
ABOUT 3 TO 6 MONTHS,
I GUESS.
UHH.
I HOPE
YOU WERE THE GROOM.
TED NUGENT CALLED.
HE WANTS HIS SHIRT BACK.
13 MILLION,
AND YOU DRIVE
THIS PIECE OF SHIT
ACROSS THE COUNTRY
TO PICK ME UP?
BLEW IT ALL ON THE SUIT.
WHERE ARE THEY?
BACK ROW. SILVER SEDAN.
10 O'CLOCK.
I STOPPED AND PICKED UP
YOUR PERSONAL EFFECTS.
HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
I'M NOT SURE
THESE BELONG TO ME.
HI.
WE NEED TO GET
RUSTY A GIRL.
THERE'S A WOMEN'S PRISON
DOWN THE ROAD.
YOU SAID
THAT YOU SOLD THIS.
I SAID THAT.
LIAR.
THIEF.