[MUSIC]
[PHONE RINGING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Harry, answer that.
[RINGING STOPS]
So, what do you wanna
hack for, Bickle?
I can't sleep nights.
There's porno theaters for that.
Yeah, I know. I tried that.
So, what do you do now?
Now? Ride around nights mostly.
Subways, buses.
Figure, you know, I'm gonna do that,
I might as well get paid for it.
You wanna work uptown nights?
South Bronx, Harlem?
I'll work anytime, anywhere.
Will you work Jewish holidays?
Anytime, anywhere.
All right. Let me see
your chauffeur's license.
How's your driving record?
It's clean.
It's real clean,
like my conscience.
You gonna break my chops? I got enough trouble with
guys like you coming in here to break my chops.
If you're gonna break my chops, you can take
it on the arches right now, you understand?
Sorry, sir, I didn't mean that.
Physical?
Clean.
Age?
Twenty-six.
Education?
Some.
Here, there, you know.
Military record?
Honorable discharge.
May 1973.
Were you in the Army?
Marines.
I was in the Marines too.
So, what is it?
You need an extra job?
Are you moonlighting?
Well, I...
I just wanna work long hours.
What's moonlighting?
Look, just fill out these forms
and check back tomorrow
when the shift breaks.
O'Brien, please step up.
Take the car out
through 58th Street, please.
Because it's crowded on 57th.
MAN:
Hey, Rodriguez!
[MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
All right, all right,
I'm coming down there.
[MUSIC]
[WOMAN SHOUTING IN ITALIAN]
[BABY CRYING]
BICKLE:
May 10th.
Thank God for the rain,
which has helped wash away
the garbage and the trash
off the sidewalks.
I'm working long hours now.
Six in the afternoon to 6 in the morning,
sometimes even 8 in the morning.
Six days a week,
sometimes seven days a week.
It's a long hustle,
but it keeps me real busy.
I can take in $300, $350 a week.
Sometimes even more
when I do it off the meter.
All the animals come out at night.
Whores, skunk-pussies, buggers,
queens, fairies, dopers, junkies.
Sick, venal.
Someday a real rain'll come and
wash all this scum off the streets.
I go all over. I take people to the Bronx, Brooklyn.
I take them to Harlem.
I don't care.
Don't make no difference to me.
It does to some.
Some won't even take spooks.
Don't make no difference to me.
MAN:
Driver, 48th and 6th, please.
Man, you are gorgeous!
Beautiful little girl.
[MAN AND WOMAN LAUGHING]
I can't afford
to get stopped anywhere.
Oh, no. We wouldn't
want that to happen.
MAN: There'll be a big tip in it
for you, you do the right things.
You got a way.
Yeah.
Now you're talking!
Driver, hurry up, will you?
Yeah.
[KIDS SHOUTING]
[MUSIC]
BICKLE: Each night when I
return the cab to the garage,
I have to clean the come
off the back seat.
Some nights, I clean off the blood.
Can I help you?
Yeah, what's your name?
My name is Travis.
That's nice.
What can I do for you?
I'd like to know what your
name is. What's your name?
Give me a break.
Look, you can tell me what your name is.
I'm not gonna do anything.
Do you want me to call the manager?
You don't have to call the manager.
Troy!
All right. Okay, I mean...
Okay. Can I have a Chuckles there?
And do you have any Jujubes? They last longer.
I'd like to get some Jujubes.
What you see is what we got.
A Clark.
I'll take these.
Coca-Cola.
We don't have Coca-Cola.
Royal Crown Cola is all we got.
A dollar eighty-five.
[WOMAN PANTING
AND MOANING ON FILM]
BICKLE: Twelve hours of work
and I still can't sleep.
Damn.
The days go on and on.
And they don't end.
All my life needed was
a sense of some place to go.
I don't believe that one should devote
his life to morbid self-attention.
I believe that someone should
become a person like other people.
[MUSIC]
I first saw her at Palantine campaign
headquarters at 63rd and Broadway.
She was wearing a white dress.
She appeared like an angel
out of this filthy mass.
She is alone.
They...
cannot...
touch...
her.
Yes. Well, you delivered
two boxes.
I think it's a total
of 5000 campaign buttons.
Now, all the ones we had
before and our slogan is:
"We are the people,"
and "are" is underlined.
These new buttons
have "we" underlined.
That reads, "We are the people."
Well, I think there's a difference.
"We are the people" is not
the same as "We are the people."
Let's not fight.
Look, we'll make it
real simple.
We don't pay for the buttons.
We throw the buttons away, all right?
BETSY: Tom, come here a minute.
What?
What is it?
This canvass report
is about ready to go.
Check it out with Andy and if he okays it, have
a copy sent to headquarters in every county.
Okay, I gotta get that New
York Times article xeroxed.
Don't forget the new photos.
I didn't forget it.
Now, look, we have to emphasize
the mandatory welfare programme.
That's the issue
that should be pushed.
First push the man,
then the issue.
Senator Palantine is a dynamic man.
An intelligent, interesting,
fresh, fascinating man.
You forgot sexy.
Man, I did not forget sexy.
Listen to what you're saying.
You sound like you're selling mouthwash.
We are selling mouthwash.
Are we authorized to do that?
Very funny.
You can get in trouble selling
pharmaceuticals in a campaign office.
My uncle's in jail because of that.
Well, it's not really jail. Of course, living
with his wife, anything would be jail.
Look over there.
I love you.
Notice anything?
No.
Well, put your glasses on.
Okay, just a minute.
All right.
That taxi driver's
been staring at us.
What taxi driver?
That one,
the one that's sitting there.
How long has he been there?
I don't know. lt feels like a long time.
Does he bother you?
No.
You really mean yes,
and you're being sarcastic.
Oh, you're quick.
You're really quick.
Well, I try to be real quick.
I'll tell you what.
I'll play the male in this relationship...
Good luck.
... and tell him to move.
And I don't need good luck. Thank you.
Oh, yes, you do.
You just think you don't.
Say, you're blocking our doorway.
You think you might wanna move your cab?
[TYRES SCREECHING]
[MUSIC]
WIZARD:
You know, eye shadow, mascara,
lipstick, rouge.
DOUGHBOY:
Not rouge. Blush-on, they call it.
WIZARD: The kind with the brush.
DOUGHBOY: Yeah, it's Blush-on.
WIZARD:
Travis.
Hey, Wiz.
That's Blush-on. My wife uses it.
Ask Travis.
He's a ladies' man.
A cup of coffee, please.
Anyway, whatever the fuck it is,
she uses a lot of it, you know?
And then perfume.
The spray kind.
And then, get this.
In the middle of the Triborough Bridge...
And this woman is beautiful.
... she changes her pantyhose.
No.
Oh, yeah.
What'd you do?
I throw the meter, you know,
and I jump in the back seat and I whip it out.
I said, "You know what this is?"
She says, "It's love." You know,
I'm gonna fuck her brains out.
She goes wild, you know,
and she said,
"That's the greatest
single experience of my life."
Then she gave me a $200 tip
and her phone number in Acapulco.
Travis, you know
Doughboy, Charlie T.?
Hey, Travis.
Got change for a nickel?
We call him Doughboy because
he'll do anything for a buck.
So, uh...
So how's it hanging?
What's that?
Well, I turn on the radio.
Some fleet driver from Bell just got all cut up.
Stickup?
No, he got cut up by some crazy fucker.
Cut half his ear off.
Where?
It was at 122nd Street.
Fucking Mau Mau land.
DOUGHBOY: You run all over
town, don't you, Travis?
Travis?
Travis.
You run all over town, don't you?
Yeah.
I mean, you handle some
pretty rough customers, huh?
Yeah, I have.
You carry a piece?
No.
You need one?
DOUGHBOY: You ever need one, I know a
fella who can get you a real nice deal.
There's lots of shit around.
WIZARD: I never use mine.
I'm conservative, you know.
But it's a good thing to have
just as a threat.
DOUGHBOY:
I'm gonna go dig my dirt.
Travis.
Look.
Piece of Errol Flynn's bathtub.
Dig the symbols.
F-4-0-5-4-3-4.
And the watermark.
There's one person,
there's two persons,
and there's three persons.
I got this at his estate,
The Pines.
Look, why don't you take it,
and if you can sell it,
you give me half of what you got.
I don't want to.
Well... Hey, I'm gonna get
in my cab and boogie.
Oh, I'm so terribly sorry.
What? Well...
Nothing.
That's very cute. Thank you.
Hey, you wanna see something?
Wait, I just typed,
"You wanna see something?"
What?
If you had
these three fingers
missing on this hand
and that hand missing
on that hand,
how would you light the match?
I wouldn't light a match.
Go ahead.
Give it a try.
Well, I don't think I could do it.
No?
It's gonna be difficult.
I'll give it a try.
Oh.
I got my thumb back for a second.
Thank God.
Just a minute.
I can't do it.
Well, the guy at the
newsstand can do it.
Well, I don't work
at a newsstand.
Anyway, he's probably Italian.
No.
You're sure he's not Italian?
He's black.
Well, if he had been Italian, he might've been a thief.
They do that, the mob does that.
If a thief screws up on the job,
you know, they'll blow his fingers off.
I'll tell you something else.
This sounds like a joke, but it's true.
If they kill a stool pigeon,
they leave a canary on the body.
Apparently it's symbolic.
Why not a pigeon instead of a canary?
I don't know why not
a pigeon. Wait a minute.
You gotta catch a pigeon. A canary, you can walk
right into a pet store, as long as you pay for it,
boom, kill it right there.
Put it on anyone you want. Doesn't matter.
Hi. I'd like to volunteer.
Great. I'll take you right over here.
That's all right. I'd rather
volunteer to her, if you don't mind.
Why do you feel that you
have to volunteer to me?
Because I think that you are the most
beautiful woman I have ever seen.
Thanks.
But what do you think
of Palantine?
Well, l...
Charles Palantine, the man you're
volunteering to help elect president.
Well, I'm sure he'll make
a good president.
I don't know exactly what his policies
are, but I'm sure he'll make a good one.
You wanna canvass?
Yeah, I'll canvass.
How do you feel about the
senator's stand on welfare?
I don't really know the senator's stand on
welfare, but I'm sure it's a good stand.
You're sure of that?
Yeah.
Well, we all work together
here full-time, day and night,
so if you would just like to step over there,
I'm sure the gentlemen will sign you up.
The thing is, I drive a taxi at night,
so it's kind of hard for me
to work in the day.
So, uh...
Then what exactly do you want?
Would you like to come have
some coffee and pie with me?
Why?
Why? I'll tell you why.
Yeah.
I think you're a lonely person.
I drive by this place a lot,
and I see you here.
I see a lot of people
around you
and I see these phones
and all this stuff on your desk
that means nothing.
And when I came inside
and I met you,
I saw in your eyes, and I saw
the way you carried yourself,
that you're not a happy person.
And I think you need something.
And if you wanna call it a friend,
you can call it a friend.
You're gonna be my friend?
Yeah.
What do you say?
It's a little hard standing here
and asking you, so...
Five minutes, that's all.
Just outside. Right around here.
I'm there to protect you.
[LAUGHS]
Come on.
Just take a little break.
I have a break at 4:00.
And if you're here...
4:00 today?
Yes.
I'll be here.
I'm sure you will.
All right, 4 p.m.
Right.
Outside in the front?
Yes.
Okay.
Oh, my name is Travis.
Betsy?
Travis.
I appreciate this, Betsy.
[MUSIC]
BICKLE:
May 26th, 4:00 p.m.
I took Betsy to Charles' Coffee Shop
on Columbus Circle.
I had black coffee and apple pie
with a slice of melted yellow cheese.
I think that was a good selection.
Betsy had coffee
and a fruit salad dish.
She could've had
anything she wanted.
Fifteen thousand volunteers
in New York alone's not bad.
But, Christ,
the organizational problems.
Mm-hm.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I got the same problems.
I gotta get organized. You know, little
things, like my apartment, my possessions.
I should get one of those signs that says, "One
of these days, I'm gonna get organiz-ized."
You mean "organized"?
Organiz-ized.
It's a joke.
O-R-G-A-N-E-Z-I-E-Z-D.
You mean "organiz-ize." Like those little
signs in offices that say, "Thimk."
Do you like the place
you work in?
We've got some good people working for us.
And I think Palantine's got a good chance.
You know you have beautiful eyes?
Do you like the guy you work with?
He's okay.
Yeah, I know.
But do you like him?
Well, he's funny, and he's very good at his job.
He's okay. Though he does have a few problems.
I would say
he has quite a few problems.
His energy seems to go
in the wrong places.
When I walked in and I saw
you two sitting there,
I could just tell by the way you were both
relating that there was no connection whatsoever.
And I felt when I walked in,
there was something between us.
There was an impulse
that we were both following.
So that gave me the right
to come in and talk to you.
Otherwise, I never would've felt that I had the
right to talk to you or say anything to you.
I never would've had
the courage to talk to you.
And with him, I felt there was
nothing and I could sense it.
And when I walked in, I knew
I was right. Did you feel that way?
I wouldn't be here if I didn't.
Where are you from?
Upstate.
That fellow you work with,
I don't like him.
Not that I don't like him,
I just think he's silly.
I don't think he respects you.
I don't believe I've ever met
anyone quite like you.
You wanna go to...
a movie with me?
I have to go back to work now.
I don't mean now.
I mean, like,
another time, though?
Sure. You know what
you remind me of?
What?
That song...
by Kris Kristofferson.
Who's that?
The songwriter.
"He's a prophet...
He's a prophet and a pusher,
partly truth, partly fiction,
a walking contradiction."
You saying that about me?
Who else would I be
talking about?
I'm no pusher.
I never have pushed.
No, no, just the part
about the contradictions.
You are that.
[MUSIC]
BICKLE: I called Betsy again at her office, and
she said maybe we'd go to a movie together
after she gets off work
tomorrow. That's my day off.
At first she hesitated, but I called
her again and then she agreed.
Betsy, Betsy. Oh, no.
Betsy what?
I forgot to ask her last name again.
Damn! I gotta remember
stuff like that.
MAN 1 : I don't think we have to worry
about anybody here committing themselves
until things start coming in
from California.
Listen, this is just making me nervous.
I think we should've waited for the limo.
MAN 2:
I don't mind taking a cab, but I mind
going out to California without the right preparation.
That's gonna get us in trouble.
Are you Charles Palantine,
the candidate?
Yes, I am.
I'm one of your
biggest supporters.
I tell everybody that comes in this
taxi that they have to vote for you.
Why, thank you...
Travis.
I'm sure you're gonna win, sir.
Everybody I know's gonna vote for you.
You know, in fact, I was gonna put
one of your stickers in my taxi,
but the company said it was against their policy.
But they don't know anything.
They're a bunch of jerks.
Let me tell you something, I
have learned more about America
from riding in taxicabs than in
all the limos in the country.
Oh, yeah?
PALANTINE: That's true.
Can I ask you something,
Travis?
Sure.
What is the one thing about this
country that bugs you the most?
Well, I don't know. I don't follow political
issues that closely, sir. I don't know.
PALANTINE:
Oh, well, there must be something.
Well, whatever it is, he should
clean up this city here,
because this city here is like an open sewer.
It's full of filth and scum.
Sometimes I can hardly take it.
Whatever ever becomes
the president should just...
[HORN HONKS]
really clean it up.
Know what I mean?
Sometimes I go out and I smell it.
I get headaches, it's so bad.
And they just like... They just
never go away, you know?
I think that the
president should just
clean up this mess here.
He should flush it right down the fucking toilet.
Well, uh...
I think I know
what you mean, Travis.
But it's not gonna be easy.
We'll have to make radical changes.
Damn straight.
MAN 1 : Here you go, Travis.
Keep the change.
Thank you.
Nice talking to you, Travis.
Nice talking to you, sir.
You're a good man.
I know you're gonna win.
Thank you.
Drive safe.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
Come on, man.
Get me out of here, all right?
Come on!
MAN: Come on, baby.
This is a real drag.
Now, come on!
Come on, don't make no scene.
You wanna get busted?
Now, bitch, be cool!
Don't start no trouble.
Cabbie, just forget
about this. It's nothing.
Be cool, bitch!
[MUSIC]
IRIS: Stop!
SPORT: Wanna hear something?
What's the matter, baby?
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN:
Get your ass out of here!
[MUSIC]
Hi there.
Hi.
Have a nice day today?
Not particularly.
I got a present for you.
Oh!
[DRUMMING]
Now back to Gene Krupa's
syncopated style shortly.
Why'd you do that?
What else am I gonna do
with my money?
I wish you'd have
listened to this.
Well, I would have, except my
record player doesn't work now.
Your stereo's broken?
Yeah.
How can you stand it?
I couldn't live without music.
I don't follow music too much, but I
would really like to. I really would.
So then you haven't played
this record yet?
No.
But I was thinking maybe we could
listen to it on your record player.
Now, going back to
40 years of Chick Webb.
You gotta be kidding.
What?
This is a dirty movie.
No, no. This is a movie
that a lot of couples come to.
All kinds of couples go here.
You sure about that?
Yeah. Yeah, I see them
all the time.
Come on.
[MAN SPEAKING IN SWEDISH
ON FILM]
[SPEAKING IN SWEDISH]
[MAN SPEAKING IN SWEDISH
ON FILM]
BETSY:
Excuse me.
MAN:
Shut the fuck up.
Where are you going?
I have to leave now.
Why?
I don't know why I came in here.
I don't like these movies.
Well, I mean...
I didn't know you'd feel
that way about this movie.
If I had known...
These the only movies you go to?
Yeah, I mean I come and...
This is not so bad.
Taking me to a place like this is about as
exciting to me as saying, "Let's fuck."
Uh, there are other places
I can take you.
I don't know much about them,
but I can take you other places.
We're just different.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
I have to go.
I've gotta go now.
Wait.
Wait a second, I wanna talk to you.
Look, I have to go.
Taxi!
Can I talk to you at least?
Won't you at least talk to me? I didn't know you'd...
Look, won't you take
the record?
I've already got it.
But, please.
I bought it for you, Betsy.
Thanks, now I've got two. Let's go.
Can I call you?
Jesus Christ, I got a taxi.
Hello, Betsy.
Hi, it's Travis.
How you doing? Listen,
I'm sorry about the other night.
I didn't know that was
the way you felt about it.
Well, I didn't know that was the way you felt.
If I... I would have taken you somewhere else.
Are you feeling better or...?
Maybe you had a virus or something.
A 24-hour virus, you know.
It can happen. Yeah.
You, uh...
You've been working hard,
huh? Yeah.
Would you like to have
some dinner with me
in the next few days
or something?
How about just a cup of coffee?
I could come by the headquarters
or something, and we could...
Okay, okay.
Did you get my flowers
in the...?
You didn't get them?
But I sent some flowers.
Yeah. Well...
Okay, okay.
Can I call you again?
Tomorrow or the next day?
Okay.
No, I'm gonna...
Okay, yeah, sure. Okay.
So long.
[MUSIC]
BICKLE:
l tried several times to call her,
but after the first call, she wouldn't
come to the phone any longer.
l also sent flowers,
but with no luck.
The smell of the flowers
only made me sicker.
The headaches got worse.
I think I got stomach cancer.
I shouldn't complain, though.
You're only as healthy...
You're only as healthy as you feel.
You're only...
as healthy...
as...
you...
feel.
Let's not have any trouble, okay?
Why won't you talk to me?
Why don't you answer my calls?
You think I don't know you're here?
Let's not have any trouble.
You think I don't know?
Would you please leave?
Take your hands off!
I just want you to know
that I know...
Please, just leave.
This is no place to do this.
Take your hands off me.
Take your hands off!
Okay, then just leave.
Take them off!
All right, just leave, then. Come on.
I'm gonna tell you, you're in a hell!
And you're gonna die in hell like the rest of them.
There's a cop across the street.
You're like the rest of them.
Look, I'm calling
the cop. Officer!
Officer!
Look, don't come around here,
because I'll call the police!
BICKLE: I realize now how much she's
just like the others, cold and distant.
And many people are like that.
Women for sure.
They're like a union.
MAN:
Yo, cab!
[MUSIC]
MAN: Okay, pull over to the curb over there.
Right over to the curb. Over there.
No, no, don't... Don't...
Don't... Whoa, whoa!
The fucking meter.
What are you doing?
What are you doing
with the meter?
Did I tell you to put...?
Did I tell you to do that with the meter?
Put the meter back.
Let the numbers go on.
I don't care what I have to pay.
I'm not getting out.
Put the meter back on.
Put it down.
Put it... That's right.
Put it... Put it down!
That's right.
Why are you writing?
Don't write!
Put the thing down. Just sit.
I didn't tell you to write.
I just said, "Pull over to the curb."
We pulled over to the curb.
We're gonna sit here.
We're gonna sit.
Cabbie, you see that light
up there? The window?
The light? The window
up there in the second floor.
The one that's closest
to the edge of the building.
The light up in the window.
Second story.
What are you, blind?
Do you see the light?
BICKLE: Yeah.
Yeah, you see it. Good.
You see the woman
in the window?
Do you see the woman
Yeah.
You see the woman. Good.
I want you to see that woman
because that's my wife.
But that's not my apartment.
It's not my apartment.
You know who lives there, huh?
No, I mean, you wouldn't know who lives there.
I'm just saying. But you know who lives there?
A nigger lives there.
How do you like that?
And I'm g... I'm gonna kill her.
There's nothing else.
I'm gonna kill her.
Well, what do you
think of that? Hm?
I said, what do you
think of that?
Don't answer.
You don't have to answer
everything.
I'm gonna kill her
with a .44 Magnum pistol.
I have a .44 Magnum pistol.
I'm gonna kill her with that gun.
Did you ever see what a.
44 Magnum pistol can do to a woman's face?
I mean, it'd fucking destroy it.
Just blow it right apart.
That's what it can
do to her face.
Now, did you ever see what it can do to a woman's pussy?
Now, that you should see.
That you should see. What a.
44 Magnum's gonna do to a woman's pussy you should see.
What's that?
I know you must think
that I'm, you know...
You must think I'm pretty sick or something.
You must think I'm pretty sick.
Right? You must think
I'm pretty sick?
[CHUCKLES]
Right? I bet you really think I'm sick, right?
You think I'm sick?
[LAUGHING]
You don't have to answer. I'm paying for the ride.
You don't have to answer.
WIZARD:
I picked up this midget, you know.
He's very well-dressed,
Italian suit,
good-looking,
with a beautiful tall blond.
Was it a lady midget?
No, the guy was a midget.
The blond was a lady.
Oh, I got you.
Those midgets are funny.
Sometimes I like to hold a midget.
Yeah?
They're funny. They always
wanna sit in the front seat.
WIZARD: Then I pick up these two fags.
They're going downtown.
[BUZZES]
They're wearing these
rhinestone T-shirts.
They start arguing,
they start yelling.
The other one says, "You bitch,"
and starts beating him on the head.
I say, "Look, I don't care
what you do in the privacy
of your own home,
behind closed doors.
This is an American
free country.
We got a pursuit of happiness thing.
You're consenting, you're adult.
But, you know, in my fucking cab,
don't go busting heads.
God loves you, do what you want."
Tell them to go to California.
Because out in California, when two fags split
up, one's gotta pay the other one alimony.
Not bad. They're way ahead
out there, you know? California.
So I tell them to get out
of the fucking cab.
MAN: One time, I saw a cop
chase this guy with one leg.
He was on crutches, you know.
WIZARD: The cop?
No, no, the dude he was chasing.
Fucking cops, they chase anything.
WIZARD: Hey, Travis.
Hey, you got that 5 you owe me?
My man is loaded. Loaded.
I'd be broke tonight if I hadn't caught
me some people from Ohio out at Kennedy.
I took them into Manhattan by way
of Long Beach, tipped me $5.
WIZARD:
What's the action around?
It's pretty slow.
I'm shoving on.
Hey, Wiz, wait.
Can I talk to you for a second?
CHARLIE T.: Bye, Killer.
[IMITATES GUNSHOT]
MAN:
Thank you. Night.
You put it down.
You can have them all you want!
Hey, don't be hitting my man!
You better take
your ass out, boy!
Yeah?
I know you and I ain't talked
too much, you know.
But I figure you've been
around a lot, so you could...
Shoot, that's why
they call me the Wizard.
I got...
It's just that I got a... I got a...
Things got you down?
Yeah, happens to the best of them.
Yeah, they got me real down.
Real...
I just wanna go out
and you know, like, really...
Really... Really do something.
Taxi life, you mean?
Yeah, well...
No, it's...
I don't know.
I just wanna go out...
I really...
I really wanna...
I got some bad ideas in my head.
I just...
Look. Look at it this way.
A man...
A man takes a job, you know.
And that job...
I mean, like, that...
You know,
that becomes what he is.
You know, like...
You do a thing,
and that's what you are.
I've been a cabbie for 17 years.
Ten years at night.
And I still don't own my
own cab, you know. Why?
Because I don't want to.
That must be what I want.
You know, to be on the night shift,
driving somebody else's cab.
You understand?
You get a job,
you become the job.
One guy lives in Brooklyn,
one guy lives in Sutton Place.
You get a lawyer,
another guy's a doctor.
Another guy dies,
another guy gets well,
and people are born.
I envy you, your youth.
Go out and get laid.
Get drunk. You know, do anything.
You got no choice, anyway.
I mean, we're all fucked.
More or less, you know?
I don't know. That's about
the dumbest thing I ever heard.
It's not Bertrand Russell, but
what do you want? I'm a cabbie.
What do I know?
I don't even know what the fuck
you're talking about.
I don't know.
Maybe I don't know either.
Don't worry so much. Relax,
Killer, you're gonna be all right.
I know.
I've seen a lot of people...
and I know.
Okay.
Thanks, man.
I'll see you.
I guess...
Yeah, you know. You're all right.
You're all right.
[MUSIC]
What do you think of your opponent
Goodwin's chances in the upcoming primary?
Well, Mr. Goodman
is a fine man.
I would certainly,
if it came to it, prefer him
to our opponent
in the other party.
I think that my programs
are better defined than his.
They're more imaginative than his.
And moreover, I have a better chance of winning.
It's academic, though. He's not
gonna win the primary. I am.
HOST:
I see.
Well, one more thing
I'd like to ask you.
How is your campaign going?
How do you feel it's going?
When we came up with our slogan
"We are the people,"
when I said
"Let the people rule,"
I felt I was being
somewhat overly optimistic.
I must tell you that I am more
optimistic now than ever before.
The people are rising to the demands
that I have made on them.
The people are beginning to rule.
I feel it is a groundswell.
I know
it will continue through the primary.
I know it will continue at Miami.
And I know it will rise
to an unprecedented swell
in November.
[MUSIC]
[TYRES SCREECHING]
[HORN HONKS]
[GIRL GASPS]
[TYRES SCREECH]
MAN: That bitch, goddamn!
I'll blow her brains out!
I'll kill her, goddamn it! I'm gonna
get my hands on her, I'll kill her!
Shoot, goddamn it! Fucker!
I swear if I get my hands on her,
I'll kill that fucking bitch!
Hey, Sport.
MAN:
I'll kill her! Damn it!
That guy keeps following us.
Don't look at him.
Hey, guys.
You wanna take a walk?
MAN: Yeah.
[MUSIC]
BICKLE: Loneliness has followed
me my whole life, everywhere.
ln bars, in cars,
sidewalks, stores, everywhere.
There's no escape.
I'm God's lonely man.
June 8th.
My life has taken
another turn again.
The days move along
with regularity, over and over,
one day indistinguishable
from the next.
A long, continuous chain.
And then suddenly,
there is a change.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Travis, this here's Easy Andy.
He's a traveling salesman.
How you doing, Travis?
You got a .44 Magnum?
It's an expensive weapon.
That's all right.
I got money.
It's a real monster.
Stop a car at 100 yards, put a round
right through the engine block.
Here you go.
It's a premium,
high-resale weapon.
Look at that.
Look at that. That's a beauty.
I could sell this gun to some
jungle bunny in Harlem for $500.
But I just deal high-quality goods
to the right people.
[GUN CLICKS]
How about that?
This might be a little too big
for practical purposes.
In which case,
for you, I'd recommend
.38 snub-nosed.
Look at this.
Look at that.
That's a beautiful little gun.
It's nickel-plated
with a snub-nose,
otherwise the same
as a service revolver.
That'll stop anything
that moves.
The Magnum, they use that
in Africa for killing elephants.
That .38,
that's a funny gun.
Some of these guns
are like toys.
That .38, you go out and
hammer nails with it all day,
come back and it'll cut
dead center on target every time.
It's got a really nice action to it
and a heck of a wallop.
You interested in an automatic?
It's a Colt .25 automatic.
It's a nice little gun.
It's a beautiful little gun.
Holds six shots in the clip,
one shot in the chamber.
If you're dumb enough
to put a round in the chamber.
[GUN CLICKS]
Here. Look at this.
.380 Walther.
Holds eight shots in the clip.
That's a nice gun.
That's a beautiful little gun.
Look at that.
During World War II, they used
this gun to replace the P 38.
Just given out to officers.
Ain't that a little honey?
How much for everything?
All together?
Well, only a jackass would carry
that cannon in the streets like that.
Here.
Here's a beautiful handmade
holster I had made in Mexico.
Forty dollars.
Three-fifty for the Magnum,
250 for the .38,
one and a quarter for the .25,
1 50 for the .380.
You take this and wait here.
I'll walk down with you.
How about dope?
Grass? Hash? Coke?
Mescaline? Downers? Nembutal?
Tuinal? Chloral hydrates?
How about uppers, amphetamines?
No, I'm not interested in that stuff.
I can get you crystal meth,
nitrous oxide.
How about a Cadillac?
A brand-new Cadillac,
with the pink slip,
for 2 grand.
[MUSIC]
BICKLE:
June 29th.
I gotta get in shape now.
Too much sitting has ruined my body.
Too much abuse has gone on
for too long.
From now on, it'll be
50 pushups each morning.
Fifty pull-ups.
There will be no more pills.
There will be no more bad food,
no more destroyers of my body.
From now on, it'll be total organization.
Every muscle must be tight.
WOMAN [ON FILM]:
Wow.
Look at the size of that.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Oh, it looks so good.
[WOMAN MOANING ON FILM]
It's getting harder and harder,
and it's throbbing now.
BICKLE: The idea had been growing
in my brain for some time.
True force.
All the king's men cannot
put it back together again.
Where do we get more of these?
Where do you think? At headquarters.
All the way back there?
Come on.
They'll work.
Maybe it's these speakers.
I've done this 100 times.
You've done this before?
I've done this before, don't worry.
When was the last time you did this?
I've never done this before.
Betsy!
What?!
TOM:
Betsy. Come here, come here.
Hey.
Hey, you're a Secret Service man,
aren't you?
Huh?
Just waiting for the senator.
You're waiting for the senator?
Oh...
That's a very good answer.
Shit, man.
I'm waiting for the sun
to shine.
Yeah.
No, the reason I asked if you
were a Secret Service man...
I won't say anything.
... is because I...
I saw some suspicious-looking
people over there.
You did?
Yeah, they were right over there.
They were just here.
They were very, very...
Suspicious.
Yeah.
Where'd he go?
Is it hard to get to be in
the Secret Service?
Why?
Well, I was just curious,
because I think I'd be good at it.
I'm very observant.
I was in the Marine Corps,
you know.
I'm good with crowds.
I noticed your little pin there.
That's like a signal, isn't it?
Sort of.
A signal. A secret signal
for a Secret Service.
Hey, what kind of guns
you guys carry?
.38s? .45s? .357 Magnums?
Something bigger, maybe?
Look, if you're really interested, if
you give me your name and address,
we'll send you all the information
on how to apply. How's that?
You will?
Sure.
Okay.
Why not?
My name is Henry...
Krinkle. K-R-l-N-K-L-E.
154 Hopper Avenue.
"Hopper"?
Yeah.
You know, like a rabbit?
Hip, hop.
Fair Lawn, New Jersey.
Is there a zip code?
Yeah, 6-1-0-4-5-2.
Okay?
That's six digits. 6, 1...
Oh, well, 6-1-0-4-5.
Okay.
I was thinking of
my telephone number.
Well, I've got it all.
Henry, we'll get all the
stuff right out to you.
Thanks a lot. Hey, great.
Thanks a lot. Hell. Jesus.
Be careful today.
Right. Will do.
You have to be careful around
a place like this. Bye.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Damn it!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Yeah.
Huh?
Huh? Huh?
I'm faster than you,
you fucking sick...
I saw you coming, you fuck.
Shitheel.
I'm standing here.
You make the move.
It's your move.
Don't try it, you fuck.
You talking to me?
Well, then who the hell else are
you talking to? You talking to me?
Well, I'm the only one here.
Who the fuck do you
think you're talking to?
Oh, yeah? Huh?
Okay.
Huh?
[MUSIC]
BICKLE: Listen, you
fuckers, you screwheads.
Here is a man who would not
take it anymore.
Who would not let...
Listen, you fuckers,
you screwheads.
Here is a man who would not
take it anymore.
A man who stood up
against the scum,
the cunts, the dogs,
the filth, the shit.
Here is someone who stood up.
Here is...
Huh?
You're dead.
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[SIRENS WAILING]
Hey, Travis.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Hi, Melio.
[MAN AND WOMAN
SPEAKING IN SPANISH ON TV]
MELIO:
Yeah, man?
MAN: Okay, shut your fucking mouth and give
me the cash out the drawer. Come on! Come on!
Let's go. Give me the damn cash.
MELIO: Don't shoot.
MAN:
Stop taking so long. Come on!
Let me have it.
Give me the bread.
This all you got?
MELIO: That's it.
I don't have
any more money, man.
That's all I got!
MAN: You got more.
MELIO:
I tell you, I got no money!
Reach in your sock.
You got more bread.
Give me the rest of the bread.
Hey. Hey.
Did you get him?
Yeah, I got him.
Shit, man.
Is he dead?
I don't know. His eyes are moving.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
I ain't got a permit for this thing.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Don't worry about it, man.
I'll take care of it.
Can I give you some money?
No, man, just get out of here.
No, man. I'll take care of it.
Go ahead.
The fifth motherfucker
this year!
[JACKSON BROWNE'S "LATE FOR
THE SKY" PLAYING ON TV]
PALANTINE [OVER PA]: Walt Whitman,
that great American poet,
spoke for all of us when he said,
"I am the man. I suffered.
I was there."
Today I say to you:
We are the people. We suffered.
We were there.
[CROWD APPLAUDING
AND CHEERING]
We, the people,
suffered in Vietnam.
We, the people, suffered.
We still suffer
from unemployment, inflation,
crime and corruption.
BICKLE:
Dear Father and Mother,
July is the month I remember
which brings not only
your wedding anniversary,
but also Father's Day
and Mother's birthday.
I'm sorry I can't remember
the exact dates,
but I hope this card
will take care of them all.
I'm sorry, again, I cannot
send you my address
like I promised to last year.
But the sensitive nature of my work
for the government
demands utmost secrecy.
I know you will understand.
[MUSIC]
I am healthy and well
and making lots of money.
I have been going with a girl
for several months,
and I know you would be proud
if you could see her.
Her name is Betsy, but I can tell
you no more than that.
Hey, cabbie, you can't park here.
Come on! Come on, let's go!
Let's go! Move it!
PALANTINE [OVER PA]:... bear the
burden of suffering for the few.
No more will we fight the wars
of the few
through the heart of the many.
BICKLE: I hope this card finds
you all well, as it does me.
I hope no one has died.
Don't worry about me.
One day there will be a knock
on the door and it'll be me.
Love, Travis.
Don't you have some idea?
I'm not the one who
wants to talk.
WOMAN: But you must know that the
reason that I didn't marry him
is because I couldn't stand
to be a cause of divorce.
Now he's getting
a divorce anyway.
Phillip wants to
marry me, Brock.
I do love him.
What about us, June?
Our marriage?
You gotta know that our
marriage wasn't legal.
In the eyes of God,
we are married.
Brock, please
don't do this to me.
I love him so...
[MUSIC]
Damn.
Goddamn!
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
They trying to get
in the picture.
You looking for some action?
Yeah.
You see that guy over there?
You go talk to him.
His name is Matthew.
I'll be over there waiting for you.
Okay.
[SPORT SINGING]
Your name Matthew?
I want some action.
Officer.
I swear I'm clean. I'm just
waiting here for a friend.
You gonna bust me
for nothing, man?
I'm not a cop.
I ain't a...
Then why are you
asking me for action?
Because she sent me over.
I suppose that ain't a .38
you've got in your sock.
A .38?
I'm clean, man.
Shit, you're a real cowboy?
Yeah.
That's nice, man.
All right. That's all right.
Fifteen dollars, 15 minutes.
Twenty-five dollars, half an hour.
Shit.
A cowboy, huh?
I once had a horse.
In Coney Island.
She got hit by a car.
Well, take it or leave it.
If you wanna save yourself
some money, don't fuck her.
Because you'll be back
here every night for more.
She's 12 and a half years old.
You ain't never had no pussy like that.
Do anything you want.
Come on her,
fuck her in the mouth,
in the ass. Come on her face.
She'll get your cock so hard,
she'll make it explode.
But no rough stuff.
All right?
All right, I'll take it.
Hey, man! Don't take out
no money over here.
You wanna fuck me?
You ain't gonna fuck me.
You're gonna fuck her, you give her the money.
Catch you later, copper.
What'd you say?
I'll see you later, copper.
I'm no cop, man.
Well, if you are,
it's entrapment already.
Huh?
I'm hip.
Funny, you don't look hip.
Go ahead. Have yourself
a good time. Go ahead, man.
[LAUGHS]
You're a funny guy.
But looks aren't everything.
Go ahead, man.
Have a good time.
You're a funny guy.
[SIRENS WAILING NEARBY]
Hey.
The room'll cost you 10 bucks.
I'm timing you too.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on.
Are you really 12 and a half?
Listen, mister, it's your time.
Fifteen minutes ain't long.
When that cigarette
burns out, your time is up.
How old are you?
You won't tell me?
What's your name?
Easy.
That's not any kind of name.
It's easy to remember.
Yeah, but what's
your real name?
I don't like my real name.
But what's your real name?
Iris.
Well, what's wrong with that?
That's a nice name.
That's what you think.
No, don't do that. Don't do that.
Don't you remember me?
Remember when you got into
a taxi? lt was a checkered taxi.
You got in and that guy
Matthew came by
and he said he wanted
to take you away.
He pulled you away.
I don't remember that.
You don't remember any of that?
No.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Listen, we better make it
or Sport'll get mad.
How do you wanna make it?
I don't wanna make it. Who's Sport?
That's Matthew.
I call him Sport.
Wanna make it like this?
[UNZIPS]
Listen, l...
Can't you understand something?
You're the one that came into my cab.
You're the one that wanted to get out of here.
Well, I must've been stoned.
Why? They drug you?
Oh, come off it, man.
What are you doing?
Don't you wanna make it?
No, I don't wanna make it.
I wanna help you.
Well, I could help you.
[UNZIPS]
Damn, man!
Goddamn it!
Shit, man. What the hell's
the matter with you?
We don't have to make it,
mister.
Goddamn it! Don't you
wanna get out of here?
Can't you understand
why I came here?
I think I understand.
I tried to get into your cab
one night,
and now you wanna
come and take me away.
Is that it?
Yeah, but don't you wanna go?
I can leave any time I want to.
Then what about that one night?
Look, I was stoned.
That's why they stopped me.
When I'm not stoned
I got no place else to go.
So they just, uh,
protect me from myself.
Well...
I don't know.
I don't know. Okay, I tried.
Hey, look, I understand.
And it means something, really.
Yeah, well...
Well, look,
can I see you again?
That's not hard to do.
I don't mean like that.
I mean, you know, regularly.
This is nothing for a person to do.
All right, how about
breakfast tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
I get up at about 1:00.
One o'clock?
One o'clock.
Well, I got a thing.
I don't know...
Come on, do you want to or not?
Yeah, I want...
Okay, all right.
Okay, 1:00.
One o'clock.
Okay. See you tomorrow.
Oh, Iris.
My name is Travis.
Thanks a lot, Travis.
So long, Iris.
See you tomorrow.
Sweet Iris.
[MUSIC]
This is yours.
Spend it right.
Come back anytime, cowboy.
I will.
Why do you want me
to go back to my parents?
I mean, they hate me.
Why do you think I split in the first place?
There ain't nothing there.
Yeah, but you can't live
like this. It's a hell.
A girl should live at home.
Didn't you ever hear
of women's lib?
What do you mean,
"women's lib"?
You're a young girl.
You should be at home now.
You should be dressed up,
going out with boys.
You should be going to school.
You know, that kind of stuff.
Oh, God, are you square.
Hey, I'm not square.
You're the one that's square.
You're full of shit, man.
What are you talking about?
You walk out with those
fucking creeps and lowlifes
and degenerates out on the street,
and you sell your little
pussy for nothing, man?
For some lowlife pimp?
Stands in a hall.
I'm the... ? I'm square? You're
the one that's square, man.
I don't go screw and fuck with a bunch
of killers and junkies the way you do.
You call that being hip?
What world you from?
Who's a killer?
That guy Sport's a killer.
Sport never killed nobody.
He killed...
He's a Libra.
He's a what?
I'm a Libra too. That's why
we get along so well.
He looks like a killer to me.
I think that Cancers
make the best lovers,
but, God, my whole family
are air signs.
He's also a dope-shooter.
So, what makes you so high
and mighty? Will you tell me that?
Didn't you ever try looking at
your own eyeballs in the mirror?
So, what are you gonna do about
Sport and that old bastard?
When?
When you leave.
I'll just leave them.
Just leave?
They got other girls.
You just can't do that.
What are you gonna do?
Want me to call the cops?
The cops don't do nothing.
You know that.
Look, Sport never treated me bad.
He didn't beat me up once.
But you can't allow him to do
the same to other girls.
You can't allow him to do that.
He is the lowest kind
of person in the world.
Somebody's got to do
something to him.
He's the scum of the earth.
He's the worst...
sucking scum
I have ever, ever seen.
You know what
he told me about you?
He called you names. He called
you a little piece of chicken.
He does... He...
He doesn't mean it.
I'll move up to one of them
communes in Vermont.
I never seen a commune
before, but I don't know.
I saw some pictures once in a magazine.
It didn't look very clean.
Why don't you come
to the commune with me?
What? Come to the commune
with you? No, no.
Why not?
I don't go to places like that.
Oh, come on, why not?
I don't get along with
people like that.
Are you a Scorpion?
What?
That's it. You're a Scorpion.
I can tell every time.
Besides, I gotta stay here.
Come on. Why?
I got something very important to do.
So, what's so important?
I'm doing something
for the government.
The cab thing
is just part-time.
Are you a narc?
Do I look like a narc?
Yeah.
I am a narc.
[LAUGHS]
God! I don't know who's
weirder, you or me.
Sure you don't wanna come with me?
I'll give you the money to go.
You don't have to do that.
No, no. I want you to take it.
I don't want you to take
anything from them.
And I wanna do it.
I don't have anything better
to do with my money.
I might be going away
for a while.
[DISPATCHER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
You're just a little tense,
that's all.
I don't like what
I'm doing, Sport.
Baby, I never wanted you
to like what you're doing.
If you ever liked what you were
doing, you wouldn't be my woman.
You never spend any time
with me anymore.
Well, I got to attend
to business, baby.
You miss your man, don't you?
I don't like to be away
from you either.
You know how I feel about you.
I depend on you.
I'd be lost without you.
Don't you ever forget that.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING
ON RECORD]
How much I need you.
Come to me, baby.
Let me hold you.
When you're close to me
like this, I feel so good.
I only wish every man could know
what it's like to be loved by you.
That every woman, everywhere,
had a man who loves her
like I love you.
God, it's good so close.
You know, at times like this,
I know I'm a lucky man.
Touching a woman who
wants me and needs me.
It's only you
that keeps me together.
[MUSIC]
BICKLE: Now I see it clearly.
My whole life has pointed
in one direction. I see that now.
There never has been
any choice for me.
[CROWD APPLAUDING
AND CHEERING]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next president of the United
States, Senator Charles Palantine.
[ALL APPLAUDING
AND CHEERING]
Thank you, Tom.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are met today at a crossroads,
Columbus Circle.
This is no ordinary place.
It is a place where many roads
and many lives intersect.
It is appropriate that
we meet here today,
because these
are not ordinary times.
We meet at a crossroads
in history.
For far too long, the wrong roads
have been taken.
The wrong roads have led us
into war, into poverty,
into unemployment and inflation.
Today I say to you,
we have reached the turning point.
No longer will we, the people,
suffer for the few.
Now, I would lie to you if I told you
the new roads would be easy.
They will not be easy.
Nothing that is right and good
has ever been easy.
We, the people, know that.
And we, the people,
know the right roads and the good.
Today I say to you,
we are the people, you and I.
And it is time to let the people rule!
Thank you.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
All right, let him
through. Pull back.
MAN 1 :
Palantine.
PALANTINE:
Thank you. Thank you.
[MUSIC]
Over there. Get that man.
MAN 2:
Give him some air!
Give him some air, will you?
AGENT 1 : I never saw him.
AGENT 2: I saw him run.
I saw him.
AGENT 3: Where was he?
What's happening?
Got the money?
Iris in her room?
Yeah.
Okay.
Hey, Sport, how you doing?
Okay, okay, my man.
How...?
Where do I know you from, man?
I don't know.
How's everything in the
pimp business? Huh?
Do I know you?
No.
Get out of here.
Come on, get lost.
Do I know you?
How's Iris?
You know Iris.
No, I don't know
nobody named Iris.
Iris? Come on,
get out of here, man.
You don't know anybody named Iris?
I don't know nobody named Iris.
No?
Get back to your fucking tribe
before you get hurt.
I don't want no trouble,
huh, okay?
You got a gun?
Get the fuck out of here, man.
Get out of here.
Suck on this.
[GRUNTING]
Hey!
[GUNSHOT]
[SCREAMING]
You crazy son of a bitch!
Fucking son of a bitch!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
I'll kill you!
I'll fucking kill you!
Crazy son of a bitch!
I'll kill you!
[IRIS SCREAMS]
MAN:
Crazy son of a bitch!
You fucking bastard!
I'll kill you!
You crazy son of a bitch!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
IRIS:
Stop!
[MAN GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
IRIS:
No! Don't shoot him!
[SOBBING]
[GUN CLICKING]
[MUSIC]
[IMITATING GUNSHOTS]
MAN:
Dear Mr. Bickle:
I can't say how happy
Mrs. Steensma and I were
to hear that you are
well and recuperating.
We tried to visit you at the hospital
when we were in New York
to pick up Iris,
but you were still in a coma.
There is no way we can repay you
for returning our Iris to us.
We thought we had lost her,
and now our lives are full again.
Needless to say,
you are something of a hero
around this household.
I'm sure you want
to know about Iris.
She's back in school
and working hard.
The transition has been
very hard for her,
as you can well imagine.
But we have taken steps to see
she has never cause
to run away again.
ln conclusion,
Mrs. Steensma and I
would like to again thank you
from the bottom of our hearts.
Unfortunately, we cannot afford
to come to New York again
to thank you in person,
or we surely would.
But if you should ever
come to Pittsburgh,
you would find yourself
a most welcome guest in our home.
Our deepest thanks,
Burt and Ivy Steensma.
WIZARD: Eddie, the owner-operator, comes
up, he says, "Hey, I wanna swap tires."
I say, "These are new tires.
Why don't you throw in
something else, like your wife?"
His wife was
Miss New Jersey of 1957.
That's why the fleet
has no spares.
Doughboy, Wizard, Killer.
Hey.
Charlie T.
CHARLIE T.: What's happening?
Hey, Travis, you got a fare.
Shit.
Well, see you later.
See you, Travis.
BETSY:
Hello, Travis.
Hello.
[MUSIC]
I hear Palantine
got the nomination.
Yeah, won't be long now.
Seventeen days.
Well, I hope he wins.
I read about you in the papers.
How are you?
Oh, it was nothing, really.
I got over that.
The papers always
blow these things up.
Mm-hm.
Just a little stiffness.
That's all.
Travis.
How much was it?
So long.