Mr. Akins received
this from a man
who claims his
daughter worked here.
"Deviant freak"?
Control over my own trust.
Let me prove that I can do this.
Alright.
Your father's full name?
Daniel Andrews.
And you said he was a veterinarian.
That's news to me.
How long before
you tell the truth?
I'm trying to tell
a new story here.
If you are interested. I could
manage to be much less distant.
I got demoted today
because of you.
Well then, stay the hell
away from me, Vera.
Mom?
Father told me you were dead.
Come on.
- It was a a nice cafe.
- Yes it was!
Surprise!
This is for you.
Happy wedding.
He'll make a honest
woman out of you.
Are you surprised?
I'll say.
And who do we have here?
This is my mom.
Your mom?
Sync & corrections by Alice
www.addic7ed.com
That's another drink for
the future Mrs. Ivan Buchinsky!
I don't mind.
I want a word with his
soon-to-be mother-in-law anyway.
Kate, isn't this amazing,
your mom being here after all
this time thinking she pasted.
Yeah.
C'mon, shower-girl
needs a breather.
Let's go again!
I read in the engagement notice
that your husband's a vet.
Vernon?
Oh no, he was a pacifist.
Now, Mother, stop teasing
Mrs. Corbett!
It's our old family joke,
"What d'you call a vet
who's never served?
A veterinarian!"
Plenty to be smile about now,
don't you, Mrs. Andrews?
Yes.
There's a spot in the game,
Mrs. C!
No no no no.
You... you--
Let's sit in here.
It's like basketball.
If I'd known I'd cause
such a commotion.
Don't worry about it
I'm only glad to see you.
You were hard to find.
Wasn't that the idea?
I know, but I'd reason
to trouble the waters.
Marion, I had a call from
a police detective.
What did he want?
To finish a conversation you'd had
about the night your father died.
He thinks it was foul play.
And he wants the truth about
your father's death.
Relax, Lore, it's just
a blood drive.
And guess who'll be there?
I tell you, I can't
quite get my head around
how they can draw
out your blood now
and just save it
for someone else.
Guess I don't care much for
doctors making advances,
however you square it.
Well, if we have boys leaking
blood all over the African sands,
we're damn lucky they found ways
to fill them back up again.
Suddenly you're a big
believer in modern medicine.
Patel says he can improve
these legs:
Exercises, electricity
on the muscles...
That "doctor" is selling
you snake-oil,
trading on your hopes
to nab our girl.
You can't rewrite thirty years.
Oh I'd say we can.
You okay, Mrs. Corbett?
I can't believe they go in there and
draw out half the blood God gave you.
We only take ten percent, Mom.
You joining the line or
just holding it up?
I'm busy corralling the workers.
Now I know why it's
called a blood drive.
That's quite the system.
Well, with nearly nine
thousand wounded allies
in that North African
desert, we need it.
To think our blood will be winging it
across the Atlantic and within 48 hours,
pumping through
the veins of our boys.
Visclovski, McRae, and Perrault?
Your turn to donate blood.
Mine too, Mrs. Corbett.
Didn't you give already?
Oh, I'd remember if I did.
Oh dear, I'm really
dropping the ball.
You're juggling a lot.
Boy, with this
Operation Supercharge,
Montgomery's throwing
everything he can at 'em.
Three years,
Rommel's gone undefeated.
Well, we got 'em on the run now.
You watch, the ole Desert Fox'll
be chewing on sand in no time.
Might want to look away.
There, you're done.
Mr. Parry.
Now there's something
I can set eyes on.
Count to sixty
before you get up.
Wish you'd been here earlier.
One look from you and the blood
drains right out of me.
Aren't you a card.
It's my low blood-pressure.
What's your game now,
Mr. Parry?
None left to play.
My stint here is winding up.
What, the war ended
and nobody told me?
I'll be assigned
another job elsewhere.
I'd hope by now you can trust me
to know where to send a postcard.
C'est la guerre.
Easy, you haven't
waited your minute.
I'm stronger than I look.
"Cheerio."
After work.
Testing field.
You'll have a glimpse of
what I've been all about.
Can't wait.
Boy, look at all that.
You'll want it on ice quick.
Could be going to my brother,
he's RAF, flying over the
Sahara right now.
Sinking fuel-ships and cutting
supplies from Nazi tanks.
You know a thing or two.
I met a few RCAF.
What's your brother's name?
We call him Twill.
Twill?
Yeah.
You don't forget a
name like that.
Glad to hear he's
still kicking.
What's your name?
Vera Burr.
Twill wrote about you.
He said there's no gal better
at bucking up a soldier.
Is that what he called it.
Oh hey, I meant it
as a compliment!
Ivan.
Apparently I gotta go have the life
drained outa me. Kiss for good luck?
I need to tell you something before one
of the other girls starts spilling.
Uh-oh. You get into trouble
at your shower last night?
Ivan, I haven't been
entirely honest.
It's my mother.
She's alive.
What?
I just found out yesterday.
How can she be,
not dead all of a sudden?
My father wasn't a good
man. He lied, Ivan,
and told me that my mother died.
When it was all to cover his pride
that she'd gone and left him.
What kind of man
lies about that?
It's hard to explain.
Try.
I hate to tell you this way.
But, see, my name's not Kate.
Miss Andrews!
I got a gent waiting to see you.
Detective.
Detective?
Come on.
What are you doing now?
Looking for a good vein.
And how do you know
when it's good?
Best ones are in the
antecubital fossa.
Visible, well supported
and with a large lumen.
What's a lumen?
Mother?
You're right, I don't
want to know.
But they're sure this is safe?
If you don't want to help out,
there's plenty of other
people who can.
I'm doing this,
Sheila, and I'm here.
Just get it over with.
You're good.
Top of nursing school,
I bet.
Turning all kinds of heads.
Teachers, doctors.
I've turned Narendra's head.
That's good enough for me.
I didn't mean...
You're still hoping that
I'll do better.
You should know that
I've quit looking.
You don't worry you'll get hurt?
I'm not going to stop seeing
a man, just because
he's one of the things out
there that scares you.
Fresh air and stout,
does the trick.
What's it going to like
in there for me now?
As far as VicMu is concerned,
your gravest sin was
missing a day's work.
Thank you.
When I say to you
"Don't mention it".
You mean, don't mention it.
A man I know once said,
there's nothing more exhilarating
than to be shot at and missed.
You got yourself another
chance, Mr. Moretti.
Make it count.
I hear congratulations
are in order.
I'm getting married, yes.
If I hadn't seen your
picture in the paper
with this new name of yours,
I'd've never found you.
I would have been in touch
if I thought I could help.
Your father's injuries
tell us he fell backwards.
Any ideas how?
Must have lost his balance.
Our tests show he
wasn't a drinking man.
Never touched the stuff.
So what happened?
Sir, none of us likes it
when a man dies alone,
but when my father went?
It was just him and his Maker.
Yes.
Except your father was
covered with a canvas tarp
like a sleeping baby.
He didn't die alone.
Someone was with him.
Someone who wanted
to cover it all up.
You've gone a bit pale.
I gave blood today.
Oh.
No please, come in.
Thank you, Miss Rowley.
Miss Rowley, I know
where you are now.
You didn't know her
real name either.
"Real" name?
Lot of girls come from other
places, reinvent themselves.
So long as they do their work,
don't cause trouble...
Marion Rowley is the daughter
of a street preacher
who died under suspicious
circumstances.
Kate's a good girl,
Detective Brodie.
What a sight.
Before the war, who'd have thought
women could work like this.
We've proved we're
as capable as men.
Yes.
I'm starting to think you're
capable of just about anything.
Blood drive's over for
today, come back tomorrow.
I'm here to see you, Vera.
Well I'm not here for
you, Marco. Not anymore.
You nearly sunk us both.
The guys you fell in with,
that guy Frankie?
Is in jail. And I'm
done with that.
It's over. I promise.
Now please, let me
make it up to you.
What'd you have in mind?
Figured I'd pop by tonight.
Did you?
Yeah.
Say eleven-thirty?
Can I say no to that?
Why yes I can. I don't
need a Midnight Man.
Oh why? 'Cause you found a
Midnight Pipsqueak?
That half-pint soldier
you were chatting up?
Life's more than a parade
of randy service men.
You need a better gambit than
leading a girl to nowhere
and ruining her shoes while
you play Man of Mystery.
I can't tell you
where I'm going...
but I can show you
why I've been here.
Is this one of my
father's tins?
Patience and I
will show you.
Show me what? A blob
of plasticine?
Not quite. That's dangerous.
Well I'm tired of your secrets,
Clifford.
Give it to me!
Not till you start
shooting straight.
What are you doing
get off me!
Did somebody just bomb us?
Yes. You did.
What on earth...?
Cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine.
In English, please?
RDX.
Research Department Explosive.
Uses a fraction of the materials
and packs twice the punch.
Hitler won't know what hit him.
I know I didn't.
We're using it in the
Sahara right now.
And we advanced this in our lab?
Yes. I'd hoped my
demonstration here would
be somewhat more, controlled.
And the tin, my father's design.
So Operatives can carry it
discreetly behind enemy lines.
Why show me this?
And I hate the thought
of leaving without you
knowing what we are all about.
Well, next time you're looking
to turn a girl's head...
make sure she doesn't
nearly blow it off first.
Here it is.
Elizabeth McRae
"Betty McRae...
Deviant freak. Seduced my
daughter, Marion Rowley."
Lorna? What are you doing?
What have you got there?
Easy going, Ivan.
You're down a pint of blood.
That's one way to
save money on beer.
I know I threw a lot at you.
Do I call you "Marion" now?
No!
Ivan, I'm still Kate
to anyone who matters.
And the cop?
Why's he think your dad's
death was suspicious?
I don't know.
Honest.
Was your dad even
a veterinarian?
Was he?
You saw the scars on my back.
He was supposed to
be a man of God.
And I'm ashamed, Ivan...
of everything that I come from.
And if you knew you
wouldn't blame me.
I'm still the same girl.
You'll be a Buchinsky soon.
I just want our life to start.
So we take the train
to Winnipeg.
What, and get married there?
New job,
new home... it's a lot
cheaper out there.
Run away?
It's not running away
if you're going home.
Let's do it.
Everything will be better
once we're out there.
Glady, here I am entertaining
at your hotel.
You'd asked for more
of your winter clothes.
Did Mother bring my coats?
I was feeling a chill
on the way home from work,
A nip of brandy will
warm those bones.
Come on in.
I'll have a bellman bring up
your luggage up from the car.
What are you doing
entertaining at The Hedley?
I'm here with some military associates
who depart soon for overseas.
We're celebrating
a job well done.
Clifford Parry, is he here?
How well do you know him?
A few dust-ups on factory turf,
nothing to speak of.
Gladys, dear, I was just
waxing on about you.
You know Clifford Parry.
Miss Witham. Nice to see you
out of the factory.
Mr. Parry was just telling me how he held
back Churchill against Lord Halifax.
Imagine the pickle we'd be in if our
British Bulldog hadn't prevailed.
No doubt we have you to thank
for the defence of the free world.
Your father was lending us a great
help in our latest round.
Something about the container,
that's all they'll tell us gals!
I'm proud of you, Daddy.
I have an inspiring force in
you, my dear.
If this country had more
women like your daughter...
the danger she faces
on a daily basis?
Mr. Parry, I'll faint in your
arms if you're not careful.
Perhaps, she could pursue your
line of work, Mr. Parry.
What's so funny
about that Daddy?
Not to worry, Gladys is
hardly intelligence material.
What she has in moxie,
she lacks in judgment.
You do know I'm standing
right next to you.
I'm only saying, your parents
have nothing to worry about.
I'm sure coming from a virtual
stranger, that's a great relief.
Come, Mr. Parry,
let's freshen your drink
and go speak to the Major.
It was a pleasure, Miss Witham.
I'll give him moxie.
He's lucky he's
leaving the country.
Now, now.
Mr. Parry told me he thought
you quite liked him.
Something about an explosive
afternoon at work?
Mr. Akins caught me red-handed.
Looking at a girl's
employee records.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Except now he's gone and
taken what he found
in those files and
given it to the police.
Damn it.
Why didn't I just go and burn
the letter the first time,
when I had the chance?
It'll just shine a little
light into the dark.
And who knows what'll
come crawling out?
This could do your
girl some help.
This preacher who wrote it sounds
like one hell of a lunatic.
This detective won't
see it that way.
You don't know that, Lorna.
We women, the jobs we do,
he thinks it perverts a girl.
He's a man who hates us.
I need to talk sense
into that detective.
Seems a lot for a
lady to carry alone.
It's just a mix-up.
Bellhop brought it here
instead of my room.
Nothing a fifty-cent
tip won't cure.
Oh fifty cents?
Well, I am between jobs now.
It's a good time to
improve your discretion,
learn how to talk to a girl.
Gladys, let's be
nice to our friends.
I'm sorry mother.
Must have been a
residual belch of moxie.
You want nice?
I'll give nice.
Let's go, Jeeves.
Until we meet again, Mr. Parry.
You sure
like your steak.
I need it.
I donated blood today.
So, what else did your
brother say about me?
That thinking of you gets
him through the dark,
knowing there's girls like you
back home helps him fight.
Well, that's sweet.
You cutting his meat there,
Vera?
This ain't your party.
You're just doing this
to get me going.
Don't flatter yourself.
I'm going to have to
ask you to leave.
Is that right?
Enough. Quincy, if he
doesn't shove off, we will.
Let's go have some dessert.
"My daughter has been
corrupted by your factory
and your employees,
namely one Betty McRae."
This man, he's a twisted soul.
He was a pious, God-fearing man.
And every father has the right to
protect and correct his daughter.
She sings for the
soldiers at the hospital.
Two perfect angels.
They may have made mistakes.
Like what they did
to Vernon Rowley.
Why are you dogging
them like this?
Because I hate it when
people lie to me.
You know what,
I can always tell.
Anything else you
want to say to me?
Tip for services rendered?
You want a tip, Clifford?
Stop swanning around here like a
class-act with a plum in your mouth.
I was attempting to
protect your career.
By belittling me to my parents?
They already think
little enough.
I need to keep it that way,
if you're to move forward.
What is your big plan here?
Your job's only beginning.
What does that mean?
What are you...
Let go!
My dress.
- I didn't mean to, I'm sorry.
- Oh, God.
Take it off.
You heard me.
Take off your dress.
I'll fix it.
Boy, when you said dessert,
I wasn't thinking a
plate of cookies.
Sweetie, that's your
sugar ration and some.
Never seen so many dresses.
The coral one's
my favourite.
It's my best colour.
Have you never been in a
girl's room before?
No.
And I'm figuring I'm only here
so's to make that fellow jealous.
Yeah, he's one man who's
never coming back in here.
Why's that?
Well...
let me tell you
about girls, Quincy.
It's like your brother
flying over the Sahara.
You need to know what
you're gunning for.
You have to like her for her.
Not just because she's
available.
And you let her know
she's the special one,
because if you don't?
She moves on.
Good night, Quincy.
You run, Marion,
You'll get chased.
I got myself free last time.
You'll look guilty.
I am guilty, Mom.
I was there on his last night.
He flew off in
one of his rages.
I thought he was
going to kill me.
And he fell.
He fell from a height
and landed hard...
and he died.
I was afraid to say.
Oh, Marion.
And I should have come forward,
I know.
And now it's too late.
I'd rather take my
chances with Ivan.
Okay, I understand.
Impressive.
I was a journalist,
then a soldier.
You learn a thing or two.
Thank you.
You've a rare gift,
you can navigate
different worlds.
Your intelligence,
your patriotism,
it hasn't darkened your spirit
the way it has some men.
Half my job is
hiding what I feel.
The shell never cracks.
But I'm fighting for a time
when I won't need secrets.
I only hope,
I'll remember how to
live without them.
You can turn around.
You take care of my daughter,
you hear?
I'll be out to Winnipeg to check
up on you soon.
Yes, Ma'am.
She's a special girl,
I'll take good care of her.
We should get moving.
I love you, Mom.
I doubt anyone's
travelling tonight.
I need to ask you a
few questions.
My friend Betty's expecting us.
Oh, Miss McRae is already
at the station.
She doesn't have to go with you.
Then I'll come back
with a warrant.
A warrant? For what?
I'll go, whatever you want.
A warrant for what?!
For her arrest in connection with
the death of her father, Vernon Rowley.
Kate?
- I had nothing to do with it.
- I'm coming too.
You stay here, get
the boy a paper bag.
We'll leave tomorrow, okay?
I don't even know you.
- It's his asthma, he needs help!
- C'mon!
You being here is making
it worse. Come on.
Wait. Stop! You can't do this!
Mom?  Mom!
Mom! Call an ambulance!
Where were you the night
of February 13th?
The night he died?
I went to some "do" at a
friend's, then I went home.
And before the party?
I worked. Check my time-sheet.
I hadn't seen her for months.
I've a patrolman who identified you in a
fight with the man the night he died.
It must've been another girl.
The last time she saw my father?
The night he came to
the rooming house.
They shook hands...
And I wished them all the best.
- He'd scream every day on that corner.
- He scream at you?
I needed correction.
Saw her scars?
You feel Miss Rowley
was trapped?
Kate's a grown woman!
I could've left if I wanted to.
And the letter?
What letter?
You loved her.
She was your obsession.
But Daddy stood in your way.
You had a grudge.
And here's a girl who you knew
would do your dirty-work.
What kind of monsters
do you think we are?
Women hold our moral centre.
Only what's been asked
of you in this war,
is stripping all
of that away.
You can't prove a thing.
Watch me.
So both of them? In jail?
All night with the police.
And capped it off
with a warrant.
Just like that?
I hate to trouble you,
but there was nobody else I...
It's no trouble.
My daughter's in jail,
Mrs. Corbett.
I can't lose her again.
Please.
For the sake of
appearances, you go in first.
Meet me in my office at
lunch. I've a proposition.
Miss Witham. I need your help.
This is the wrong way.
Not today.
Betty and Kate,
they're in terrible trouble.
And I don't know how to fix it.
Still can't believe I went
and fell asleep on you.
What a lightweight.
Beer has that effect
on the best of them.
Once we load out tomorrow,
that'll be it for
the blood drive.
Till the next one.
By then, I'll be over there.
Yeah?
Well, keep your head low,
and say hi to Twill for me.
Incoming...
Woops,
left a little axel grease.
Keep it.
It'll earn you some
respect from the boys.
I'll never forget you,
Vera Burr.
Elizabeth McRae
and Marion Rowley
are charged with murder
in the second degree.
Accused of violently ending
the life of Vernon Rowley.
Given that Miss Rowley has been
living under a false identity,
can we assume there's
a high risk of flight?
Yes.
What does the Crown recommend?
That bail be denied,
Your Worship.
We didn't kill anybody, honest.
This is a bail hearing,
not a trial.
With grave charges.
Bail is set in the
amount of $7,000 each.
Until such time as
bail can be met,
the defendants will be
remanded into custody.
Your Honour?
"Your Worship."
Yes.
Well, I will offer a surety.
Gladys?
You are in possession of
fourteen thousand dollars?
Yes, sir.
My name is Gladys Witham.
And your father?
Does he know you're involved
in this sordid business?
It's not my father's money.
As a surety,
it's your responsibility that the
accused adhere to the terms of bail,
report to bail officers,
and attend all hearings.
If not, you lose every dime.
I understand.
So ask yourself,
how much do you trust
in these girls?
Your Worship, I believe
in these women.
Bail is granted. Miss Witham,
settle with the court office.
And you, young women,
do not fail your friend.
Gladys.
I've got to go to the office.
Gladys, thank you.
I'm so sorry I did this.
I said my first prayer in
I don't know how long,
thanking God for you here.
You had your secrets.
I understand.
Go see your mom.
I should have just destroyed
the letter when I had the chance.
It's okay.
I could have done
better by you.
Look, I'm sorry. Both of you.
This won't be
an easy fight.
We'll work up a defence.
It doesn't work,
fixing each other's lives.
Some things just
have to play out.
Betty, this is not over.
Princess? I can't owe you more.
This just in.
"I'm advancing without cover.
Jewel Box, 8pm."
A coral dress.
Quincy...
Dividends from the
blood-drive?
I saw that solider
chatting you up.
You know, Carol?
They say the tide is turning,
that the battles we're fighting
might finally end different.
You ask me.
Isn't it time,
we change things here, too?
Is he nice, your soldier?
Yes.
He's very nice.
But I can't do this anymore.
I tell you, these asthma
cigarettes never seem to help.
Excuse me, excuse me.
They let you out.
Gladys put up bail, but
we can't leave the city, yet.
I'm so sorry Ivan.
We're not going anywhere, Kate.
The wedding's off.
You don't mean that.
I changed my life for you.
And when you had the
chance to come clean,
you only lied more.
I don't even know
what to call you!
Kate!
You call me Kate.
I gave you my heart.
Nurse?
Just go.
Nurse!
Kate, just go and
I'll be better.
Waiting for someone?
Yeah.
Nice dress?
Well he's a nice soldier.
So, why's it in the box?
If you must know,
I'm not taking it.
Why is that?
It's your favourite colour.
How would you know
what colour it is?
You're the one
who bought this dress?
I know a thing or
two about you, Vera.
But all I've been able
to see lately is
the mess I've let this
war make of my life.
I've been either too blind or
too stupid to tell,
that all this time, Vera,
I'm looking at the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I've got this... thick porterhouse
steak for two on order.
Hey.
You're not out of
the doghouse yet.
I know.
Ivan won't see me.
He says I'm no good.
He'll come 'round.
Why should he?
He's right, I'm a liar.
We didn't kill your dad.
It was an accident.
They're after us hard, Betty.
And there's no way to play this
where we come out looking good.
I should've never
asked you to stay.
You wanted to leave when he died
and I wouldn't let you.
I'm sorry.
Growing up in that
awful caravan,
I never thought that
I'd have a future.
But in the last year, I've lived
more than I ever dreamt.
I found a real home.
And I met a man who
was good to me.
And I found a friend, Betty.
A real friend.
Who loved me.
Allied tanks, planes, and infantry
continue to dispense sledge-hammer blows
to the fleeing, beleagured
German and Italian divisions
forcing them back toward
the Libyan border.
That's a tide turning,
right there.
Feels like it's the first time
that's happened this war
That's because it is.
Mom, what's that smell?
It's lentils.
Lentils? What kind
of dinner is lentils?
Welcome.
Narendra?
Well.
I invited him for supper.
You did?
Thank you for having me.
You're welcome.
Some things have to play out.
Well, come in, Doctor.
Take a seat.
- How go your exercises, Mr. Corbett?
- Very well--
Good morning.
Honey. You should
eat something.
I'm done running, Mom.
I'm going to tell the truth.
What's this?
Something that Betty left you.
"You're safe here now."
Marion what happened?
I've gotta stop her.
You're up early.
What are you doing?
Figuring out how to convince
my father I'm no fool.
He'll think I just threw
away my trust fund.
I can hear him now:
"You hardly know these girls."
Father doesn't see
what I see.
The courage, shrewdness,
creative thinking.
They don't look good
on a Rosedale Girl.
Then get out of Rosedale.
Easy for you to say,
you're leaving.
There's a place we
call "the farm,"
a good drive out of town.
Allied operatives from around
the world train there,
and carry out missions.
No volunteers.
Only recruits.
Sounds like a dime-store novel.
We'll help win this war.
New codes, new technologies.
RDX is only the beginning.
You're telling me this now, why?
Because I want you in.
Of course, you'd be subject
to the Official Secrets Act.
Family, friends,
they can never know.
You have what it takes, Gladys.
Are you up for the job?
Betty?
Betty! Betty!
You were saying.
I went to see the preacher,
to tell him to stop
harassing me at work.
He got mad.
Go on.
He attacked me,
had me on the run.
I went into this alleyway,
up a fire-escape.
He was right behind me,
grabbing me, hitting me.
And then what?
He fell.
And your friend Marion?
My friend Marion was not there.
I'll swear to it.
They say with El Alamein,
the tide is turning.
Girls, they're lucky
they have you here.
Otherwise, who knows what
might happen to them?
You have something for me?
The turning tide.
How did Churchill put it?
"Now this,
is not the end."
"It is not even the
beginning of the end."
"But it is, perhaps..."
"...the end of the beginning."
Sync & corrections by Alice
www.addic7ed.com