We here already.
Hey. Wake up March.
We're back in the war boy.
Hey, this isn't the town. It's a hospital.
Give me an egg special.
C'mon. sit down. You won't
find a real nurse at this hospital.
They're real.
Yeah.
They're real alright.
Real real.
3 of them.
And there's probably more inside.
It's a real hospital.
That's what it says.
325th evacuation
Hey March. Come back here.
Come on. Get back in that truck.
Kirb, you come with me.
Pull it up. Pull over there. Wait for us.
Honey?
I, Andy
He's cracked sarge. He's cracked.
Come on. Let's get him.
What's the matter with you?
Leave me alone, will ya?
Boy, that's an officer
you're messing around with.
I'm sorry Lieut. Just that,
he hasn't been gettin much sleep
I'm alright. I'm alright. This is my wife.
This your wife?
Yeah.
Oh honey. This is the sarge,
and that's Kirby, my best buddy.
Well uh, congratulations, uh.
Huh, ha. Pleased to meet you Sir, uh, Miss.
What are you supposed to call..
Mrs. March? I don't know.
Lieutenant March.
Lieut. March. What's happening here?
This is Andy, my husband, Doctor. He, uh
And these men?
I'm Sergeant Saunders, 361st.
We're in a convoy headed forward, uh.
Corporal March just found
out his wife is stationed here, Sir.
Sir, you see uh
Perhaps you'd better hold
your reunion outside Lieut.
These other men aren't feeling quite that chipper.
I'm sorry Doc.
Go ahead. You're relieved of
duty until your husband's convoy leaves.
Thank you, Sir.
This is a real bedside manner for you.
Walk, er. Let's go outside.
Come on, honey.
Ah, He's got one.
He's got a nurse.
Andy, please.
Let 'em look.
Andy, not here. It isn't fair.
Been such a long time, honey.
I, I was asleep and I heard the
guys talking, and then I heard hospital
and then 325th, and I just knew it.
Couldn't believe it, but I knew it.
How've you been. Your letters haven't
caught up with me for over a month now.
I just can't believe you're here.
I'm here.
Excuse me Lieut.
We have to move out.
The convoy's already moved out.
Aw, come on sarge. I haven't seen her since
The Sergeant can't help that.
We have to move out March. Sorry.
Look, Sarge. Once we cross
the river we're gonna be moving fast.
I may not get a chance to
see her till after the war.
What are you talking about. You're
better off than the rest of us right now.
You stay out of this Kirby. What do
you know about it. You're not married.
You don't gotta be married..
I'll talk to Lieut. Hanley.
Maybe we can swing a couple of days for you.
You're kidding.
Really?
I, I'd give my right arm for 48 hours.
Did you hear that honey.
I said I'd ask. I can't promise anything.
A fat chance you got of getting
a pass in the middle of the war, March.
You really think it might be possible Sergeant'
I'll do my best Lieut.
Let's go Kirby. March, 2 minutes.
Nice to have met you.
Yeah. Any friend of Andy's is a friend of mine.
Howcome he can do that?
It's his wife, numbskull.
His wife?
Yeah. His wife.
They're married. That means
they got, uh, privileges.
March. We're moving out.
I didn't know your husband was over here. Nice.
Have them take him right
over to the surgery tent.
Well, has, has he gone?
Yes. He's gone.
It's a shame you didn't have more time.
His Sgt. gonna try to get him a pass.
He's not sure if he can, but he's going to try.
Well, I'll be damned. Oh uh.
We have an abdominal in half an hour.
Would you like uh, some coffee, maybe?
There's a lispodite down there if
you have to fill up your canteen.
Hey March.
You and me. We're buddies, right.
Sure Kirb. You know that.
How's come you never
told me that you was married.
I don't know, I
I started to a lot of times, but
The way you talk about women.
All the different ones, I mean.
I, I just love her.
very much.
I guess I just
didn't want to share her, not even talking.
How long you been married?
Two days. Not counting the 8 months we been apart.
8 months?
That means, you got hitched in England, right?
Yeah. That's where I met her. Hah.
Boy, you should've seen the chain of command
we had to go through to get permission. Hoho.
Huh, well how does Company deal with
somebody's only been together 2 days, though.
Omaha Beach.
Do you think the sarge can
really swing that pass for me.
Aw, forget it. Look, you believe in Santa Claus.
Take you an Act of Congress to get.
What happened to you Saunders? Breakdown.
No, not quite. It was Corporal March.
He ran into his wife.
Sergeant. I asked you what happened.
You see, she's a nurse and she
was stationed at a hospital that we passed.
And it took some doing, prying them apart.
We're lucky you got here this fast.
March is with you, isn't he?
Oh yes. He's up in the truck there.
Lieutenant, about March.
You know what they're talking about right now?
About whether to give March a
pass so he can go see his wife.
Aah, it's the truth. We saw him kiss her.
C'mon Kirby. Get to the end of the line.
Eh. Put me there.
I'll put you on top of the moon
Hey. Come on. Back in the line.
That's enough.
Forget it.
Come on Kirby. Move.
Hey Billy. Did he kiss her
right out in front of everybody.
Oho, I'll say.
Hey, she's an officer.
So what. She's a girl, isn't she.
Well yeah, but I mean..kissing an
officer. What if she pulls rank on him.
Billy, have you ever been married?
Nooo
Well, have you ever had
a girl? I mean, a real girl.
You guys make me sick.
What's eating him?
Bonjour.
Hey March.
Yes sarge.
It's in the works. The Lieut's gonna
make a request from Cpt. Harper.
Hey sarge, if uh, if you can do
this for me, you're gonna have the
workingest, neatest, finest soldier you ever saw.
Yeah.
I won't forget it sarge.
It's alright.
Je ne pas parle anglais.
Je nes parle vous.
Je ne comprend pas.
Hey.  You think you can
pull back out here in a minute.
Kirby.
Come on.
How's that for a weekend pass, huh.
You just forget it.
Yeah. You forget it sarge, Okay.
She's not for you Kirby. Not your type.
What are you talking about.
I don't see any off limits sign on her.
Hey, why don't you just
calm down till we get to Paris
I need, just get a name.
I know her name.
It's trouble.
Now, come on. Get in the truck. Let's go.
Hey Kirb.
The Lieut.'s gonna send my
request for a pass on to
Someone's ready.
Hat trick.
Okay.
Got a little straight.
Hey Kirby. Don Juan.
C'mon get your feet wet. It'll cool you off.
You know Kirby doesn't care about money.
Come on. Let's play cards.
That's right.
Kirby cares about just one thing.
What's that?
Kirby.
Hey sarge. The Lieut. wants to see you right away.
Hey sarge. Maybe that's about my pass.
Hope so, March.
Hey Crowne. Why don't you grab a seat.
Yeah. Yeah, Not me. I've got
better ways to spend my money.
Okay. A pair of Queens bets.
You alright.
Hey uh. You get a good look at March's wife.
Uh huh.
Pretty?
Yeah. huh.
He seemed like not much of
a ladies man to me. Did he to you?
You want to see a real good looking thing.
Are you kidding?
I got one I'm gonna see tonight.
Now, if you wanna tag along,
maybe she's got a friend.
Kirby. You slip a gear.
You just tag along and find out.
How far you figure that last village.
Kirby. You can't go in there after dark.
I'll see.
Hey. Hey sarge. Did it come through.
Not yet March. It's in the works.
Hey, what the Lieut. want sarge.
We're to lay wire to the
combat outpost tomorrow, daybreak.
Oh, no.
Who goes?
Littlejohn and Billy. Packard, Caje, you and I cover.
Who rides shotgun for Billy and me.
Uh.
Well, March. It's his turn.
Wait, wait a minute. What if his pass comes up?
Yeah.
Let somebody else ride shotgun.
Awright now. Wait, wait, wait a minute.
I was up last trip.
Naw, he's right.
That is, unless you wanna
volunteer for your buddy.
What do you...
You don't really think that pass
is gonna come through, do you?
Yeah. So does the Lieut.
Okay. Who's gonna stand in the
path of romance. I'll ride shotgun.
Thanks Kirb.
I'll make it up to you, I promise.
I'll ride 3 in a row when I get back.
Thanks a million Kirb.
Okay.
Oh, what was it.
Queen.
Fifty cents.
Alright.
You're not really going into town Kirby.
Yeah, I'm really going into town Kirby.
Now you gonna stay here or you coming with me.
Help me out you really got a girl.
Coming or not.
When we get caught, we've had it.
Don't wait up for me.
Didn't I tell you. It's a cinch. Come on.
Seized up, huh.
That was a big reception.
Got a favorite that goes here.
Just sit down will ya. shift over.
Hey. Is there any table service. Servir. Service
Oh, no, no, no Monsieur.Ah look ah
Well, we'll have a bottle of cognac.
Out of cognac. Ce mon javais.
Oh, uh
Wine, ca vais. Wine, wine.
That's good, that's good.
Here comes it.
Uh, my name is Kirby, Kirby.
Kirrbee.
Kirrbee, what's your name?
Claire.
Eh, Claire. Hey listen Claire, I came
Claire, Monsieur, does not understand english.
Perhaps I can help you.
Oh, look. Thanks friend.
You tell her that I'm the
guy she smiled at this afternoon.
I think, uh, you're mistaken.
Heh. You mean I don't know
when a girls coming on to me.
Hehe. You ask her what time
she gets through, would you please.
When she gets through Monsieur
she goes home.
She's bethrothed to my brother.
You see, he fights with the,
how do you say, the Resistance.
Well, I don't know anything about that, but, uh
she seems big enough to think for
herself, so let's just let her decide, alright.
I speak for my brother. I speak for Claire.
Look Claire, uh. When you get finished,
when you close up here, I'm gonna meet
I'm gonna meet you outside
Ecouter moi bien, Monsieur.
You come here to drink
then drink.
Because if you look for something
else, you're going to find trouble.
Hey, uh. I think he's got a
point there eh. All of them.
Wait. Wait just a minute.
Hey, come on Kirb. Let's go.
No no. Go on if you want to.
I'm not leaving here until she tells me to go.
Awright. I'm going.
HUH! Thanks a lot.
Hey. Look.
You smiled at me, and I smiled
back at you, so, I come see you.
I tell you, Monsieur. Leave her alone.
Don't put your hands on me, friend.
C'est pardon. Col a fairez chaud.
Il pol a baques.
(French)
(Caje shouts in surprise)
What was that?
What's going on?
Kirby. Come on.
Kirby.
Crowne.
Come on. Come on. Get up.
What?
Get up. C'mone.
Where's Kirby?
I said Where's Kirby?
Didn't he get back yet?
Get back? From where?
What?
Now where's Kirby. You answer me.
I, I don't know Sgt.
Back from where Crowne. Don't lie to me.
I want to know where Kirby went.
What're you asking me for?
Where's Kirby? Now you answer me.
We went into town. I came
back alone. I guess he's still there.
What do you mean, you guess.
He was with that french girl.
At least, he was trying.
Looked like trouble to me, so I came back.
I guess he did alright after all.
He did alright.
He's liable to be tried for missing a patrol.
Now you get over there to the Lieut. and
make out a full report on the both of you.
Sgt. I came back.
Get over there.
Come on. Come on.
Oh sarge. Did it, did it come through.
No, not yet, but you're gonna
have to ride shotgun with us after all.
What happened to Kirby. I thought he was gonna.
Ah, your buddy went over the hill.
Kirby went over the hill?
We're moving out in 15 minutes.
Maybe your pass will be
ready by the time we get back.
Go on.
Well, we were only there
for a few minutes Sir.
At least I was.
Kirby was really hooked on that girl.
Why did you leave?
Because it looked like trouble in it.
I tried to get him to go with me.
(phone ringing)
Stand at attention soldier.
King 2. Lieut. Hanley.
Yes Sir. I'm looking into it now Captain.
How is he.
That's a break Sir.
Yes Sir. I'll get my report
in right away. King 2 out.
Thank you Sir.
For what?
For not mentioning me to the captain, Sir.
Private Crowne. You were absent
from the Bivouac area without
permission. Is that not correct.
Yes Sir.
That is absent without leave. Is that correct?
Well Sir. Yes Sir, but I did come back.
You're going on my report to Captain Harper.
You'll be punished along with Kirby as
soon as he gets out of the hospital. Dismissed.
Got a dandy for you Lieut.
What is it. Bullet wounds or shrapnel.
Just whiskey bottles and hard toed shoes.
Aaagh!
Take it easy, will you Doc.
What's his name and outfit.
Kirby, King Company, 361st infantry.
361st
Nurse.
Yeah. First things first, Lieut.
Put him in that open bed over there.
Sure thing Lieut.
(groaning)
Aah.
How did this happen?
He got beat up.
Good old fashioned alley fight.
Why? Do you know him, Lieut.
He's a friend of my husband.
He was here yesterday.
Is his Company still in this area?
I don't know. You'll have to ask him Lieut.
All we do is scrape them up, and deliver them.
(kapow)
(BANG)
Take cover.
Take cover. Artillery's gonna
start coming on our ass.
March.
Let it go.
BLAM
(Oompf)
Cut it off.
Oh come on. Hey, it hurts.
Any way to talk to an officer.
What?
Oh. Um. uh, sorry Lieut.
Forgot where I was.
Uh. Oh. It's a hospital.
Feel better.
Hey. You're March's wife, aren't you.
I met you early this morning.
Yesterday.
Oh, yesterday.
Now ain't that something.
Too bad old March didn't
get beat up by those guys, huh.
Yeah,. I mean, uh, then he'd be here
with you right now instead of me.
How is he?
Oh, March is doing great, uh
Far as I know the Lieut. is trying
to rustle up a pass for him
So's you two can finish up your honeymoon.
Well, Kirby.
It's refreshing to have someone like you in here.
Reminds me of the old
days at L.A. County General.
Knifings, beatings, smashups. How you feeling?
Terrible.
Well, Im not surprised.
You got a nice concussion there.
And two badly sprained,
if not broken, fingers.
and uh, How many stitches were there?
36 stitches in your head.
Plus that black eye.
Oh, Lieut. Willows.
Would you take over here please.
Yes Sir.
Lieut. March. I'd like to see you for a moment.
Alright, doctor.
Well?
Well, what?
Did he get the pass?
Is he gonna be here for awhile?
I don't know.
(crying)
Lieut. The guys got back.
What happened?
Artillery, heading back.
I don't know how bad it is, but it's pretty bad.
Where's Doc.
Back at Company CP. They had some trouble.
Put him in the jeep. It's only a few
miles back to the EVAC hospital.
And his wife. Alright. Come on.
Put him in that jeep.
I'd like to take him back Lieut.
Sure. Who do you want to go with you?
Kirby.
Oh, he's there already.
He's what?
Take Crowne. He'll explain on the way.
Alright. You get in that jeep.
I guess it doesn't matter much now, but
his pass came through.
Maybe Kirby can use it.
How you feeling, pal.
Oh, I hurt, aah.
Well, you got nothing to
worry about. I heard them talking.
You'll be out of here tomorrow.
That's what I'm worried about, huh.
I got a feeling I'm gonna be
digging trenches all the way to Berlin.
What'd you do. Get in a fight with a non-com?
Um I, had a little skirmish with
the entire French Underground.
Just that, I wasn't where I
was supposed to be at the time.
AWOL huh. Well, don't worry about it.
They could call it desertion and just shoot you.
Heh, thanks a lot pal.
How do you feel?
Oh, worse. Hey Lieut.
Did you hear anything from my outfit yet.
They know you're here.
Well, that's something at least.
I'm not under arrest or anything am I?
Why should you be under arrest?
I can think of a couple of reasons.
Did you hear anything
from March? I mean, Andy.
Not yet.
You will. I betcha he comes barreling
through that door any minute now.
How well do you know Andy.
Andy and me's best buddies.
He sure kept you a secret though.
I have to admit that of course.
If you was a wife of mine, I'd have
your picture plastered up all over the place.
I'd even be talking about you to total strangers.
Maybe Andy doesn't know me
well enough to talk about me.
You see, we haven't known
each other for very long.
Hmph, well. I knew old March had
something going for him though cause
he's always sneaking off by himself writing letters.
You must have got one every day.
Almost.
Hey, that's some dame, huh.
You bet.
To look at her you'd think she was just about
the sweetest, purest girl ever, wouldn't you.
What's that supposed to mean?
She's married to your friend, isn't she?
Yeah, that's right. What about it?
Well she's holding hands with the good doctor.
Are you kidding?
Well I been here for 3 weeks.
I might have a couple pounds of
kraut lead in me, but I'm not blind.
I don't believe you.
What evers the make, she's not your wife.
Give us a hand, will you.
Bring a stretcher.
Some of the splints are pretty bad.
Take him in there.
I'll get Doctor Anders.
Well hey. Hey sarge. Over here.
Okay, I give up. Arrest me,
but get me outta here, will ya.
I put him in the ready ward doctor.
In case you want to operate.
This is the Sergeant that brought him in.
I see. Lieut March. Get the information
from the sergeant. I'll go and have a look at him.
Hey Captain.
You're Andy's sergeant, aren't you.
Uh, Yes. Yes ma'am.
No.
Please God, don't let it...
What happened.
It's old March, huh.
Did uh...
Did, did he get hurt bad?
Well, what're you trying to do?
Blame the whole thing on me.
Sgt. now look. He, he was up for that patrol in
the first place. I was just doing him a favor by
Okay sarge. Look. I didn't mean to duck anything.
Sarge.
Sarge, I got myself beat up now
You know I wouldn't do that on purpose.
Well come on. Say something will ya.
Got nothing to say.
Lew?
Yes?
Is it very bad?
I don't know. It could be.
Some of the metal penetrated the skull.
How much or how far I won't know until I go in.
He's got to live.
He's just got to live.
Amelia, I'm gonna do the best I can.
I know how important it is for all three of us.
Cause if he died
we
They're going to release you tomorrow molrning.
Did they tell you?
Good. Maybe I'll give old
March this bed. It's a dandy.
You can see everything from here.
Doctor Anders is going to operate now.
He's really very badly wounded.
Doctor Anders, huh.
Now that's, cozy.
I don't understand what you're talking about.
Oh yes, you do. Lieutenant Miss March.
You understand alright.
You're in enough trouble now, Kirby. Don't press it.
Well you tell me why she's not mad
at me for ducking out on that that patrol
So's that her husband could
go get himself blown up.
I'll tell you why.
cause she got the guilts right up to there.
All the time old Andy was
in the mud just scrounging around
trying to fight this lousy war she was in
there playing patty-cake with her doctor.
Now you shut up Kirby.
You hear me. You just shut up.
I'm sorry Lieut.
Kirby
I'm gonna see to it they throw the book at you.
For what? Just telling the truth.
You ask him.,he'll tell you.
I don't have to ask anybody.
It's none of my business.
And it's none of your business.
You got it. You just shut up.
Only one thing is your business one thing and
that's all and that is being a soldier and doing
your job and that is the one thing you didn't do.
And now I'm gonna tell you something else.
You wanna know the reason why she didn't
get burned at you for sending March on that detail.
Cause she didn't know. Wanna
know why. Cause I didn't tell
her because that's none of her business.
And now I want you to do some deep
thinking about who's up to where with the guilts.
And while you're at it you just give
a little thought to your best buddy
March who's out there being operated on.
Cause he might not make it.
And if he doesn't pull through
I'm not gonna forget it.
(Chuckling)
Now there's what I call a tough
Shut up.
Would you like some coffee Sergeant.
Yeah. Thanks.
Thank you.
We don't have any milk.
Oh black coffee is fine.
Would you like to sit down.
No thanks.
How long do these things
usually, usually take.
It depends.
He was telling the truth.
I am in love with Doctor Anders.
After the war I'm gonna leave Andy.
Look Lieut. Your personal life is your own.
I want to tell you.
Cause if he dies
Doctor Anders and I could never
It would always be between us.
Do you understand Sergeant.
I'm trying to.
It's not as bad as it sounds.
I'm trying to be honest.
I fell in love with this man.
I didn't try to, didn't want to.
I just did.
Thanks for the coffee Lieut.
What would you do?
Please Sergeant.
Look Lieut. Everybody's got a problem.
Everybody. You, Kirby, March.
There's no time for it.
There just isn't enough time.
Only thing I can do is try to hold onto my men.
Keep them alive.
You know.
that boy.
has just about the toughest
skull I ever run across.
Thank god. Thank God.
Now take it easy.
There's nothing to really worry about.
Uh, Captain?
If Kirby's ready for release we can take him back.
Oh. Certainly Sergeant. Kirby can go anytime.
Oh. Lieut. March. Would you
prepare Private Kirby for checkout.
Your husband's gonna be alright.
Of course Doctor.
Whoa.
Now you keep warm and
come back and see us soon.
Honey, Sir. Where I'm going they got bars
balls and chains and no girls of any kind.
That's for sure. Hah.
You think you're gonna sit this war out
in some soft stockade, you just forget it.
Like I said. Enjoy the war. Bye.
Alright. Get em down.
I still think she gave old March a rotten deal.
So a quick war marriage doesn't work.
What are we supposed to do.
Write our Congressman.
Besides if March's head is as
hard as the doctor said it was
maybe he won't let her go.
Subtitles by
Jack T