This is flight deck. Prepare the cabin
for Combat Descent into Kandahar.
Excuse me, Dr. Gordon.
I strongly urge you to get
into your seat for landing.
I can't right now,
I'll be out in... 2 minutes.
We're about to do a combat landing, ma'am.
We'll be flying an evasive pattern
so we don't draw fire.
I know what a combat landing is.
I read the manual.
Yes, ma'am. Did the manual say anything
about passengers throwing up?
Don't worry about me, I'll be fine.
- Ok.
- Commencing combat descend.
Sync by YYeTs.net
Corrected by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
B.P. 100 over 80.
When did you eat last?
Any drugs you're taking?
Any allergies to medication?
Where are we? Am I gonna die?
You're at the Role 3 Hospital
at Kandahar Airfield,
and you're gonna be fine.
Excuse me. Ma'am?
I'm looking for the Role 3 Multinatio--
Multinational Medical Unit. Yeah. Me, too.
Hi, I'm Bobby Trang.
Nice to meet you. Rebecca Gordon.
Hi, Rebecca.
So one of us is walking the wrong way.
Uh, I just got directions,
and apparently, it is this way.
I'm sorry. I'm not familiar
with Canadian ranks.
I'm a major and trauma surgeon. You?
Brand-new captain and a brand-new doctor.
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me. Can you--
Lewis, take point!
That was weird.
So you're a major?
Is that you?
You get reception out here?
Damn it. Yeah, I got nothing--
no bars, no messages, nada.
You're not even gonna read them?
No. They're from my ex.
He's turned into a stalker.
Excuse me for asking, but
are you feeling okay?
I'm fine.
I'm just tired.
I don't sleep well on planes.
It's nothing that a solid eight
hours of sleep won't cure.
How's it going, Simon?
Piece of cake, Colonel.
Any sign of our fresh meat?
Nice way to refer to
your future colleagues.
Let's see how long they last.
We have to find them first.
They're lost in transit.
Well, if they knew what was
coming, they'd stay lost.
We need the manpower, Simon.
Really? I'd say we need more women.
Actually-- one of them is.
Oh, really? Now you're talking.
Well, I don't know what I was picturing,
but-- it wasn't this.
No. That's for sure.
I hope they have air conditioning.
Yeah, right?
Whew.
Outpatient clinic is closed.
Just take a seat.
We'll see you as soon as we can.
Oh, no. We're not sick.
We're reporting for duty.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's just that you looked a little--
You know what? Never mind. We can use you.
We just had a rush.
We're about to have another one.
Okay, listen, clean the blood off the floor
so that no one slips, okay?
Oh, you don't understand.
Um, we're doctors.
What?
Does that mean we have to show
you how to mop the floor?
No, no. I know how to mop a floor.
Great. I just think that may--
I'm going to reload these.
I guess we mop the floor.
I guess so.
Okay, who left their damn bags
right in the middle of the floor?
Sorry, sir. We just got in.
Uh-huh. Captain Trang.
Yes, Major Gordon.
We were expecting you yesterday.
I got stuck in Dubai. I got stuck in Kabul.
Any updates?
Dust-off 1-7's five minutes out, sir.
Dust-off 2-2 is right behind
them with four on board,
no details, TOC's only getting
every second word, sir.
Who are they?
This is Major Gordon, Captain Trang, sir,
reporting for duty.
We were expecting you yesterday.
Sorry, sir. We both, uh, got--
Don't tell me. Dubai.
You feeling all right?
Absolutely, sir.
Yeah. I'm good to go.
All right. Follow me.
All right.
Now we got recovery and I.C.U. here.
Sorry we gotta put you to
work the minute you get here,
but, you'll find this place
very unlike anything--
you ever experienced before.
Now we go three O.R.s here.
The main ward's down the hall at the end.
Uh, actually, Colonel, um,
I trained at both Detroit receiving
and Miami General, and we could see,
four, five, -- I don't doubt it.
Even six-- we got mental health right here.
Down here's the central hallway.
And here--the U.S. Army
used to call this the ready room.
I haven't been able to
come up with another name.
The unready room, I call it.
Hey.
Well, hello.
This is Dr. Hill, our neurosurgeon.
Please, call me Simon.
I'm Rebecca.
Hey, man. I'm Bobby.
Hello, Bobby.
You can change into your scrubs in there.
Just the shirt.
Now you can store your firearms
in these lockers if you want to.
I wear mine because I'm
always going in and out.
And besides, I like the constant reminder
that we're in a war zone.
Sir, two minutes out.
New details?
Yes, sir.
So did they, uh, did they
try to hand you a mop?
They didn't just try. They succeeded.
Oh, they tried that with me.
They didn't get very far.
Let me tell you.
Yes, sir.
Sir.
You have emergency
medicine training, right?
Yes, sir, but just the standard 3-month--
Good. You're trauma team
leader, bay 4, all right?
Ready, sir.
Let's go. You, too, Simon.
Right behind you, Colonel.
To be honest with you, sir, I've
never been a T.T.L. before.
I like to think I'm a good diagnostician,
but you know your ABC's, don't you?
Airway, breathing, circulation.
So you'll be fine.
Uh, I have tons of T.T.L. experience.
No, I want to leave you free for surgery.
Until then, stand by the red line
in case someone needs your help.
All right. They're here. Let's go!
Bird landing any second!
All right. Trauma bay 4, doctor. This way.
All right, everyone.
I'd like you to meet Dr. Bobby Trang.
This is Captain Pam Everwood, your nurse.
These are your med techs,
Larry Alexander and Christine Ezrin.
You okay?
Yeah.
Don't worry about it. They got your back.
You're gonna need this.
Okay, everyone, let's go!
G.C.S. 9, B.P. 100 over 40. Pulse 102.
Labored breathing. I.E.D.
blast 5-0 minutes ago.
G.C.S. 9--should, uh,
should we tube him?
Your call, Doctor.
Shallow breathing.
I'm getting nothing on the right side.
Let's try some adrenaline. B.P. falling.
Okay. We'll tube him.
Can I get a-- B.P. falling. 75 over 20.
20 of etimodate and 100 of sux.
Given.
Can I get a smaller tube?
Do you want more blood, Doctor?
Yeah.
O neg. O-2 sat 93% and falling.
Damn it. Get in there.
Blood pressure's dropping fast, doctor.
Get in there.
Want some help with that airway, doctor?
Yes, please, sir.
Stylet out.
It's in the right place.
Bag him.
Shallow on the left.
Still nothing on the right.
Chest tube.
That got it. I'm getting
bilateral breath sounds now.
O-2 sat 95% and rising.
Do you want to get him to the O.R., sir?
Doctor, what would you like?
Whatever you say, sir.
No, don't get up just yet, son.
I'm Commander Royal, your nurse.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Do I--
Yeah, you've got your arms and your legs,
and everything you had yesterday,
including some ugly looking plastic tubes
sticking out of your chest,
which we gotta keep in for a few more days.
Mm. Yeah, your ribs are gonna
be sore for a bit, so--
you in any pain at all?
No, sir. Not really.
Well, you speak up if there's
anything that you need.
Anything at all.
Welcome back, soldier.
I'm Dr. Marks.
You missed your C.O. by half an hour.
He left you a purple heart.
Your unit chaplain's got a satellite
phone so you could call home.
Your buddies are in the waiting room.
Thank you, sirs, both of you.
You don't have to thank us.
We're just the guys that get
to give you the good news.
Aha. There you are.
I have your orientation packets.
They have your room
assignments and your keys.
I also had your bags sent over already.
You are to wear these at all times.
The code 9-1-1 means drop
whatever it is you're doing
and get here quick.
Beepers in 2006?
Old-fashioned, but reliable.
Which reminds me, Major, you
got a personal e-mail message
sent via the D.N.D. in Ottawa.
You'll notice that you have your own
individual e-mail addresses
in your folders.
If you could ask your friend to
use that one in the future--
Uh, if he does it again,
Just please tell him to eat crap and die.
"Eat crap and die."
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, got 'em all sorted out?
Yes, sir. Fine additions
to the team they are,
if I may say so myself, sir.
You may. I couldn't agree more.
Walk with me.
Did somebody die without telling me?
No, sir.
No, nobody died.
When he came into your trauma
bay, he was dying, no question,
but he went out alive.
And there he is-- P.F.C.
George Lowen, 19, from Dayton, Ohio,
and he's about to make a
call to his mom and dad.
All right?
I couldn't think, sir.
I-I couldn't even fit the tube in.
Well, that kid had the biggest
damn uvula I've ever seen.
You didn't have any trouble with it.
I've been doing it for 25 years.
You know what the most
important thing-- oh.
Sorry if I scared you.
You didn't scare me. You startled me.
Ah. Well, I stand corrected.
That's a nice, uh, tattoo you got there.
Yes, sir.
Oh, come on. No, I mean it sincerely.
A sincere compliment.
Simon, you mind if I cut in?
Yes, of course, Colonel.
I will be in the unready
room, getting unready.
You did a very good job
with the chest tube today.
Thank you, sir.
How well do you know Bobby Trang?
Uh, we only just met.
So you've got nothing against him?
No, of course not.
Well, you completely undermined his
confidence by stepping in like that.
Me? Sir, I didn't do
anything before you did.
No, I asked permission. You took over.
There's a big difference.
- You didn't see that line of red tape
on the floor? - Yes, sir.
You know what it means?
No one crosses the red line.
Unless?
Unless instructed by the trauma team leader.
Exactly.
Sir, the patient was tanking--
No, he'd would've survived another minute,
And by then, Bobby would've
ordered a chest tube.
Let me spell it out to you
in--in words of one syllable.
I need you both.
Now I got eight trauma
bays and only three O.R.s,
and if I had to pick one of
you, I need a confident,
top-of-his-game trauma team leader
more than I need a hotshot trauma surgeon.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, sir.
Good. Other than that,
you did very well today.
Oh, I almost forgot.
That thing about the mop--
Don't believe Simon.
It's not some fraternity hazing ritual.
Blood is slippery.
We don't want anybody falling.
Now the nurses and the med techs,
they know where everything is,
what needs to be restocked.
Doctors don't.
So-- doctors mop the floors.
Really nice of you to show us to our rooms.
You being sarcastic?
Huh?
Don't worry.
Right, Bobby, you are up here.
Okay, that's Max, your roommate.
Lieutenant Colonel, U.S. Air Force.
He's a nice fellow, but no one
really wants to room with him.
You can hear why. He could play
the tuba, it wouldn't bother me.
I'm gonna be asleep in about ten seconds.
What I wouldn't give to be able
to fall asleep in ten seconds.
With my luck, I will be up all day.
Oh, really? You need something for sleep?
Yes. Why, you have something?
I have everything.
Now step into my office. I will fix you up.
Wow.
Now I don't know if you know
anything about oriental rugs,
but these are the real thing.
I paid, uh, $3,000 for this one here.
I could sell this in London
tomorrow for 40,000 pounds.
Uh, the wow was for your view.
Oh, yeah, that.
Well, one wants to have a touch of home.
Well, what do you have to
do to get a room like this?
Wait. Don't tell me.
A privilege of being a civilian.
Yes, and I don't have
to share with anyone...
Plus, they pay me an obscene
amount of--are you vibrating?
Yes, damn it.
Oh, it's rather good luck your
phone's even working here at all.
Not in this case.
Ah, unwanted attention.
Ex-husband?
Recent?
Very.
Can I offer you a drink?
Biohazard?
Well, it's only hazardous if
you're allergic to fine vodka.
No, thanks.
All right. Suit yourself.
Mmm.
Now did you leave him at the
altar and go off to war?
No.
Oh. Oh.
So he left you. Well, what an idiot.
Now it's a case of what on
his part--regret, remorse?
I don't know. I don't care.
And I don't want to talk about it.
You don't want to talk about it.
Well, I don't blame you.
Certainly explains why you can't
sleep, but you're exhausted.
Now would you like one
of the benzodiazepines?
I have several.
What you need to do is,
you need to inhibit the reuptake
of dopamine and serotonin
and trigger the release of
oxytocin and vasopressin.
Of course, sex is the
natural way of doing it,
but-- there is a place for
the pharmaceutical approach.
Such as now.
Shame.
Well, in that case, I suggest
a 2 milligram dose of--
9-1-1.
Come on!
Hot one! Hot one, sir.
E.H.V.I. with through-and-through G.S.W.S,
right thorax and lower left quadrant.
Take him to 1.
Roger that, sir.
E.H.V.I. with entrance
wounds here and here.
Corresponding exit wounds in back.
We sealed the sucking chest.
We gave him fluids and ox.
And he's got 6 milligrams
of morphine on board.
E.H.V.I.?
Enemy High-Value lndividual. He's Taliban.
Later, people. We got work to do.
Give him 100 of propofol. We'll tube him.
Plug in a large-bore I.V.
Flood him with o negative and saline
until we find a crossmatch.
Given.
Thank you. I think the bullet
crossed the mediastinum.
I need chest tubes on the left and right.
Find the Colonel.
Tell him this one goes straight to O.R.
Yes, sir.
Stylet out.
Strong breath sounds on the left side.
I'll move on to the right side.
What's going on?
These guys are A.N.A.--
Afghan National Army. They're on our side.
They're afraid the Taliban
guy is going to escape.
Well, tell 'em he's not going anywhere.
They don't believe me.
They think he's faking.
Faking?
Yes.
Tell them to watch this.
Oh, dude.
Do they still think he's faking it?
All right.
Nice. That's it. Two. Three.
You got the needle?
That was so badass,
how you just stabbed him like that.
Have you met Vans yet?
He's one of our terps.
It's nice to meet you, Vans.
But I-I didn't stab him.
I just--I made an incision.
Whatever. You made the point.
I can't get in this vein.
Let's try somewhere else.
What have we got here, Doctor?
Adult male, history unknown,
presenting with G.S.W.s
to the mid thorax and lower left quadrant.
We sedated, intubated,
placed bilateral chest
tubes for decompression.
He's had 3 liters each of saline
and packed red blood cells,
but he's losing volume as
fast as we can give it.
Recommend immediate laporotomy and
thorocotomy to control the bleeding.
No C.T. scan?
No, sir. In my opinion, the
risk of fatal hypovolemia
far outweigh the benefits of imaging.
Very good, Doctor. Will.
Uh, this guy goes straight to O.R. 3,
without passing go,
without collecting $200.
Yes, sir. Dr. Gordon
is gonna be the surgeon.
I'll assist.
Very good job.
They taught you well at Miami General.
Thank you, sir.
Actually, sir.
I was the youngest chief surgical resident
in Miami General's history--
Don't anybody move.
Just hold very still.
Could I have a fresh glove, please?
It's okay, Graham.
We're fine. Just had a snake.
Can't have snakes in the O.R., sir.
Don't throw it away. Put it on ice--
to show our friend at Vickerdale.
Right you are, sir.
Dr. Gordon, you okay?
Fine, sir.
Uh, it's just that, uh,
that wasn't in the manual.
♪ I'm sending out a telegram ♪
♪ I'm sure you're wondering
where I've been ♪
♪ How can I be scared of home? ♪
♪ It's nothing that I've ever known ♪
♪ I'm falling asleep ♪
Oh, well, hello.
You must be Rebecca.
I'm Major Pedersen, your, uh, roommate.
Oh, pleased to meet you.
And I'm delighted to see you
awake and dressed and ready.
I thought you'd be too tired.
Too tired for what?
The Colonel didn't tell you?
We do a women's clinic off the base.
Afghan women don't come
to the hospital, you see.
They--they're afraid they'd be dishonored
if they're seen by men
outside their family.
So the women from the
hospital, we go to them.
Actually, I am kinda tired.
Well, I mean, it's strictly volunteer,
but I was hoping.
You see, we do get a lot
of physical problems
as well as the emotional ones.
In fact, most of the women we
see are physically sick, so--
Well, it stands to reason,
you'd see a lot of sick people in a clinic.
But I'm a psychiatrist, so--
but no worries.
If you're really too tired, I--
No. I'm not too tired. Of course I'll come.
Great.
Tape, some syringes--
Help you find something?
Uh, um, do we stock pregnancy test kits?
I never saw any. Why?
Well--
Don't some of the women
who come to the clinic
want to know if they're pregnant?
I've never had an Afghan woman ask me that.
Well, suppose someone on the base
thought she might be pregnant.
Well, I suppose we would just
send a urine sample to the lab.
But what if she wanted it confidential?
They'd all want it to be confidential.
Sexual relations on the base
are against regulations.
If they were military, they'd be
sent home on the first plane.
Why do you ask?
Just a general question.
Uh, Rebecca Gordon,
This is Captain Mary Ann
Reith, our pharmacist.
Nice to meet you, but I didn't
see you, and you didn't see me.
I'm gonna get a coffee.
Lock up when you leave.
Uh, what was that about?
This is one of those gray areas.
The top brass like it that
we run our women's clinic--
hearts and minds and all--
But there's not exactly
a budget for supplies.
Wait. A-are you saying that they
want us to run a women's clinic,
but we have to steal the supplies?
Oh, not stealing, exactly.
The Colonel calls it
"Requisitioning without paperwork."
A nice way to put it, don't you think?
Major Samizay to see you, sir.
Okay.
Thank you for seeing me at once, Colonel.
Of course. What's the matter?
I believe the base is going to be attacked.
Fahran Nawabi-- the Taliban
we operated on just now?
Not just any Taliban.
He is the number three Taliban
in all South Afghanistan.
It is all over Sky News.
There are rumors everywhere.
That is why no women would
show up to the clinic today.
The Taliban must know he is
being taken to this hospital.
They will lose respect if
they do not attack the base.
Graham.
Sir. Make sure TOC sends
this report up the chain, marked "Urgent."
Already done, sir.
Of course.
That was fast. Okay.
Graham, you know what to do.
Yes, sir.
This is an attack warning. Take cover.
Put your flak jacket on.
Come on, soldier. Move it!
Let's go! To the bunker!
Double time! Let's go! Move it!
Look, if he doesn't hold still,
I'm gonna have to sedate him.
Dude, gross!
Tell him to count backwards from ten.
He says to have sex with a--
With a what?
He didn't finish.
And then the Captain says,
"No, sir. It was only spaghetti."
Conrad.
What's so funny?
You had to be there, ma'am.
I guess. Listen, you guys are
gonna have to go to the bunker.
Oh, come on, ma'am.
We have our frag vests on.
We have our helmets. Sorry.
If my Colonel catches you
here during an attack,
there'd be hell to pay.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll see you guys later.
All right, man. See you later.
See you, man.
Where were you?
I'm not allowed to pee?
How's our prisoner?
Did you hear that he's famous?
Yeah, I heard.
Number three top Taliban in Kandahar.
There might be a vacancy.
He's turning septic, and there's why.
Oh, holy crap.
How could I have missed that?
I was practically right there.
He's gotta go back into the O.R.
When the Colonel sees this,
he's gonna ream my ass out good.
What am I reaming your ass about?
That esophageal injury. I just--
I didn't know how I could've missed it.
Well, they're easy to miss.
I missed it, too, remember?
So you're fine. No reaming today.
You want to take him or are you too tired?
You've both been going since you got here.
No, I'm fine, and, um, I'd like
to take him if that's okay.
Good. O.R. 1 is prepped and ready.
You can take him there.
Bobby, you want to scrub in with her?
Happy to, sir.
Good.
Not too tired for surgery?
I am never too tired for surgery.
Okay.
A little more retraction
on the pulmonary hilum.
Okay. How's that?
Good. B.P. is holding.
It can be a little nerve-racking.
They want you to take another one.
Oh, gosh. Battery.
Anyone got another camera?
My battery is dead.
Oh, holy crap.
I nicked the friggin' artery.
Clamp it.
Little slow on the uptake there.
You're welcome?
I'm sorry, Bobby.
Thank you.
New suture, please.
How much volume did we lose?
Can't have been much. B.P. is holding.
Thank God. That was a close one.
Nice shirt, man. I was there.
What? You saw the warped tour?
Yeah. Which one?
Last one--
Asbury Park, New Jersey, summer '05, baby.
My Chemical Romance? The Offspring?
Oh, The Offspring was sick, dude.
Oh, they had to cancel?
No, no. Sick.
Oh, sick, like awesome.
Wicked cool, you know?
You know what?
Don't teach him any more slang.
We can barely understand him as it is.
- With all respect, pay no attention
to Commander Royal. - Oh.
Conrad, who else did you see?
Avenged Sevenfold?
No, no, no.
We saw the Dropkick Murphys, yeah.
Hey, what is that, son?
Oh. Uh, it's-- it's nothing, sir.
Um, the frag vest absorbed the impact.
Didn't even break the skin.
Still, get it looked at.
Sure, sir, but really, it's nothing.
Yes, sir.
All clear. The attack is over.
The attack is over. Over.
♪ Oh, the milky way ♪
♪ Has gone a little sour ♪
♪ The leaves dried ♪
♪ And the flower fell away ♪
♪ I've been sitting ♪
♪ Waiting for a sign ♪
♪ inhuman beings ♪
♪ Taking up all of my time ♪
♪ Wanna leave but I've got to stay ♪
♪ And I'm wondering more every day ♪
♪ Montreal to Hong Kong ♪
♪ Where have all the good people gone? ♪
♪ Traffic jam but I'm on the shoulder ♪
♪ Took ten cops ♪
I don't think I'll make it to my room.
I might just crash on the couch in here.
All right. We're gonna try
to discuss that next time,
but--oh, just in time
for the end of rounds.
Commander.
All right. I'd like everyone
to take a look at this.
This is a fresh shrapnel hole.
You've seen these around
the building before.
In spite of the fact
that we are surrounded by
blast walls and containers--
In case you haven't noticed,
we are in a plywood and canvas building.
Yet there are still people
who are slow getting into--
their helmets and flak jackets.
Unacceptable.
Now I don't want to single
anyone out, but, Simon,
what are you waiting for,
an engraved invitation?
Well, I'll, uh, make sure I'm
quicker next time, Colonel.
You do that.
Now for the rest of it,
I was fairly satisfied.
Preoperative diagnosis as
revealed by the C.T. imaging
determined indications of an
upper anterior mediastinal--
Okay. Moving on.
Oh, hi.
Sorry. I'll come back.
No, no, hey. Come here.
Rounds are over.
All right. Everyone get some sleep.
We had a snake in the O.R. last night.
Snakes in the operating room?
That's ridiculous.
Yeah? Graham. Get the snake.
Yes, sir.
And while he's getting the snake,
I want to talk about the dust.
Dust? I--
Hey, I was, um, I was wondering
if you wouldn't mind running a test for me.
The thing is, I don't have any paperwork.
Oh, that's no problem, doc.
What do you need?
Just a basic pregnancy panel.
It's for a friend.
She's military and doesn't
want to get sent home, so--
Rest your mind, doc.
Nothing from here ever
goes outside the Role 3
unless you say.
So you're feeling better?
They won't give me a card,
but your mom called.
I think he's good to go to iso.
Want to double-check?
No, if you're happy, I'm happy.
All right. Ready?
I'd say a real nice shaving cream.
You the surgeon?
Who wants to know? Dr. Trang?
Yeah.
Dr. Trang?
Who are you, and where are the M.P.s?
We took over. When can he be moved?
When he's well enough.
When will that be, miss?
It's Doctor or Major, not miss,
and he's well enough when I say so.
Rebecca, you got a sec?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Any more questions?
No?
Then excuse me.
This is Dr. Gordon.
She's the one who saved your life.
Uh, no, it wasn't me. I just assisted.
Thank him.
Well, what can I say, except, uh--
Don't look at me. It was her.
I just--I just--I'm so-- Dr. Trang
was your trauma team leader.
So if you want to thank
somebody, thank him. Thank her.
Well, uh, both of you, thank you.
I'm--I'm really--
Conrad!
Oh, man. What's wrong?
No, back up.
I need Diazepam, 5 plus 5 I.M.,
then 1 gram phytoin over 20 minutes.
How close was he to the explosion?
Next to me, but he wasn't hurt.
Was he unconscious at any point?
Only for a minute.
What's going on?
Okay, we got blood in the belly, and lots.
Splenic rupture. We've got a blown pupil.
We need Dr. Hill.
All right, he needs a C.T. scan right now.
Call Dr. Hill!
We gotta get him on a gurney.
What's happening?
He's been bleeding internally.
But he was fine. He was fine.
More F.F.P.
Can we pull the curtain, please?
Cardiac arrest. Starting C.P.R.
One one thousand. Two one thousand.
Three one thousand. Four one thousand.
Five one thousand. Six one thousand.
Seven one thousand--
I don't think this brain
damage is survivable.
He's not clotting at all either.
O-2 sat 93% and falling.
Does anyone think there's
anything else we can do?
17 one thousand. 18 one thousand.
19 one thousand. 20 one thousand.
21 one thousand.
Okay. 22 one thousand. 23 one thousand.
Stop C.P.R. 24--
17 local time, Kandahar.
Let's take a moment.
But I was the one that was hurt.
Okay?
Not him. He was fine.
He wasn't, I'm sorry to say.
He thought he was, but he wasn't.
Maybe if we had gotten to him sooner--
I don't know.
We're very sorry.
I'm sure you did everything you could.
What the hell?
Attention!
Hut. Salute.
Colonel--
The Taliban prisoner's gone missing.
I heard.
No, he hasn't gone missing. He was taken.
Why aren't you pissed off?
I'm pissed off for the
same reason you are--
that we lost that young soldier.
I take it personally when we lose one.
I see that you do, too.
But what about--
That's my problem, not yours.
I'm on it.
Get some sleep.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Hey.
I have completely lost track.
How long has it been?
Since we've been here?
Yeah.
Let's see, it was night,
then day, then night--
Mm-hmm. I don't know. I've lost track, too.
Well, finally, we get to sleep.
Actually, there's one more thing.
You're kidding me.
No.
I don't really know what to do
except just to hand it to you.
The lab guy gave this to you?
To give to you, yes.
Look, he was trying to get your attention,
but you were so focused
on finding the Colonel--
Anyway, he didn't mean anything by it,
you know, since it was for your friend.
You read it, naturally.
It wasn't exactly in a sealed envelope.
Well, you're the diagnostician.
And as I'm sure you've already figured out,
I thought that I might be pregnant,
and according to this, I am not.
I have never missed my period.
Okay, it could be one of
a few things or nothing.
A blood test will tell us.
Can you stay awake for another half-hour?
Honestly? No.
This is what I was worried about.
If it is anything else, I can wait.
The only thing that I care
about right now is sleep.
Yeah.
There!
Done! Over and out.
Remind me never to get on your wrong side.
Oh, don't worry. I will. Night.
Night.
9-1-1.
Oh, for the love of God!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
We have five ambulances at the main gate!
You were right.
Nothing prepared me for this place.
Yeah. Me neither.
What can I say? Welcome to Kandahar.
Sync by YYeTs
Correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net