- Hurry up, girls.
- Nearly ready.
You have too much
metal on you.
It's not so much.
I'm a magistrate,
not King of Asia.
Give one
to your sister.
Give one to your sister!
Will you stop fussing
and put that veil on, please?
We're going to be late.
Patron, I kiss you.
Mabinio, you honor me.
What do you want?
I um... well, I'll go
straight at it then.
My piss pots were all broken
this past nine day.
- Oh?
- Soldiers, naming no legions,
thought it funny to tip them
out over the heads of honest citizens.
Now now, who's to say
it were soldiers?
Might have been
gladiators simulating.
I know soldiers
when I see 'em...
not as I'm prejudiced.
Most soldiers are
good men like yourself.
But there's a lot of a foreign
element these days...
- It won't happen again.
- I should hope not.
Roman citizens that
need and deserve respect
are getting drenched
in piss instead!
There's not
a drop left!
How am I to make
cloth without piss?
- How am I supposed to make...
- It won't happen again.
Thank you, Patron.
Minerva keep you.
Brother Mascius.
Ah, Brother Vorenus.
Big man now, eh?
You're not so small.
Ah... these
Roman bitches.
I've done nothing but fuck
and eat and fuck since I got here.
We're not under
goatskin now, brother.
No disrespect
to your women, huh?
I am pleased to speak
with you more, Mascius,
but I must see
to my clients first.
And they are upset if not
received in their proper order.
Of course, of course.
Excuse my crude
soldier's ways.
What brings you here,
Mascius?
Oh, just seeing
how you do...
which is good,
looks like.
But where's that
old Titus Pullo?
I don't know.
I haven't seen him.
Gerrae!
You and Pullo were
like Castor and Pollux.
Pullo's dead to me.
Well, I'm glad to see
you're doing so good.
- How's our old chief then, eh?
- He is well.
Good good.
I'll not lie,
your brothers are unhappy,
very unhappy.
They feel the old chief's
forgot who brung him here.
They cannot have more coin.
There is an agreement.
Ay, there is.
There is.
And it's adequate coin.
Got his picture on it
now I see.
A coiner may depict
what he likes.
Fact is, our brothers
need more than just money
if they're to lead honorable
and peaceful lives.
Money runs out one day,
then what do they do?
What?
They need to take up
a trade maybe?
It's unlikely.
What are they to do?
Do not pose questions
at me, brother. Speak directly.
We want land in Italy.
Caesar will give all
veterans land when he can
as he promised he would,
but not in Italy.
Caesar gave you
land in Italy.
I am a magistrate,
and he must have an income.
But I am one man,
not legions.
Must be lovely.
I haven't seen it yet.
I'm too busy.
Of course.
Busy busy.
- We don't want to be unreasonable...
- Then don't be.
We have an agreement.
Talk it over
with your man.
- Mars and Bellona keep you.
- And you.
Cavi, Chief.
Salve, Pullo.
How goes it?
Want some mouse?
You should.
They do 'em savory here.
Best mouse
in the city.
So... do you have
some work for me?
Always somebody
needs mortality.
Give me a name.
Trouble is, my honey,
you want discretion.
This last job?
You ran that poor scurra
up and down the Aventine
like Justice
chasing chickens.
Might as well have
done it in the Forum.
- I'll go quiet next time.
- I don't know.
I've my reputation
to think of.
People come to me
for their mortality work
- because they know my men are reliable.
- That's right.
Reliable men.
I'll be quiet
as death next time.
Come back tomorrow,
same time.
Urbo will take you
to your man.
Give me some money
on spec.
Not here.
This is a respectable place
for decent citizens.
What would they have me do?
I cannot make farmland.
Certainly you can.
It's called eviction.
- And who shall I evict?
- Your enemies.
- Enemies? I have enemies still?
- Strange to say.
I shall make friends
of them in time.
And make enemies of your veterans...
unless something is done.
Is it possible
they turn on me?
They would never
fight against you,
but if they're
not satisfied
they will turn
to banditry and raiding.
In your name.
Not good.
Tell Mascius
I respect his honesty.
Tell him my veterans
are as sons to me,
and to all loyal veterans
I shall give good lands in...
Pannonia.
Good fertile bottomlands.
- Pannonia?
- Speak freely.
It's hard country,
Pannonia, and far away.
Mascius will refuse it.
Does Mascius have
the men's full trust?
Can he sway them
either way?
He can sway the 10th men, and what
the 10th men do will sway other legions.
Make him
a personal offer then.
- To what limit?
- You be judge of that.
Oh, Magistrate Vorenus...
my niece is holding
a symposium next market day
and I should like you and your wife
to come as my guests.
We are honored, sir.
You look troubled.
My wife and I
are simple people, sir.
No matter. You shall get
used to good society.
How is it?
Much more comfortable.
I don't think my back could take
another of Cicero's eulogies.
No, he praises you
so long and high,
one might think
he was being sincere.
- Salve, Magistrate.
- Salve, citizen.
My husband is home.
It was so good
of you to visit.
Oh. Not at all,
I'm sure.
Please come again. I'd be
so happy to receive you.
Thank you.
Desist
that now.
Receive us,
she says.
- I would...
- Ladies.
Magistrate, sir.
- Husband...
- What are these now?
Leased, and at
very good rates too.
And don't they
look impressive?
Put some more
cloth on 'em.
You look tired.
Why don't you
lie down?
I wish I could.
"By claim of the Senate
and people,
our beloved Father,
Gaius Julius Caesar,
has been declared
Dictator for life.
Furthermore,
the fifth month is
henceforth name
July in his honor."
Erase that.
Cassius.
It will do no good. The image
is on every wall, on every hill.
Don't worry about
those scribbles.
King Caesar knows
you're his loyal friend.
Oh, I'm not worried
about that.
No, it's just,
do I truly look like that?
It's near.
- Well, how tragic.
- Hmm.
But an image
cannot catch your vim,
your noble vitality.
I speak only what's true.
You have that grace in action
they say your noble ancestor had.
That's why plebs
put you on the walls.
- They see him in you.
- They see my wretched name, that's all.
Simpletons. Let us
speak of something else.
There's weight in names,
isn't there?
You may call a cat a fish,
but it will not swim.
The plebs love liberty.
In your name they...
They would not pluck
a hair for liberty.
Plebs like to see
their betters fight.
It's cheaper than theater
and the blood is real.
Come, come here
with me.
Look now.
Look at that.
It is a chair.
What of it?
Chair?
It's a throne!
I believe thrones are
generally more decorative.
That is decidedly plain
and chairlike.
- Are you blind?
- Do not become hysterical.
Your mother said you were
a coward. I begin to believe her.
My mother is very unhappy.
Forgive me.
I spoke in anger.
I am no coward,
nor am I blind.
I know what Caesar is.
I can see.
But I have pledged
myself his friend...
no, I am his friend.
So for friendship
you would let
the Republic die?
I am just a man.
The life or death
of the Republic
is not in my hands!
You are precisely wrong.
The Republic is
in your hands.
The people will not
accept a tyrant's death
unless a Brutus
holds the knife.
Now you have
gone too far.
He has to die.
You know him. You know
he'd never accept exile.
He has to die.
Wait, friend.
Wait!
Shh.
How's that
Gaulish cunny then?
Greasy I bet.
Don't talk
unless I tell you.
There, in the middle.
Aufidius.
Murderer! Murderer!
Murderer!
He killed Aufidiu!
Aufidiu. He killed Aufidiu!
Murderer!
Murderer! He killed Aufidiu!
Pannonia?
Pannonia is
900 miles away.
More like 600.
In Germania practically.
It's not even provinced.
Soil's black
and deep they say.
Tall forests,
full of game.
Full of Teuton raiders and
Dacian bandits and who knows who?
Our brothers don't want
any more fighting.
They won't have it.
If our brothers
accept Pannonia,
Caesar will be
extremely grateful to you.
- How so?
- 5,000 denarii.
- I don't understand you.
- I think you do.
I have been true to my brothers
since I first spilled blood.
You think I would betray them now
for 5,000 denarii?
- Seven then.
- It might be 20,000.
I am not
so greedy as some.
Not so greedy as who?
I merely say that my honor
is not for sale so cheap.
In favoring Pannonia, you would not
betray our brothers.
If they will not have Pannonia,
they will have nothing.
- Men with swords never starve.
- But they still die,
captains first.
- 15.
- 10.
12.
I'll be away then,
brother.
Good to see you.
And you.
- Has that man gone?
- He has.
- Is this all right?
- You look beautiful.
I'm so scared
I can hardly breathe.
It will be fine.
My dear girl, I have enough
to worry about.
I will not be fearful
of graffiti.
I'm telling you, the scribblers
are not wrong.
Brutus will betray you.
You seem very sure.
His mother
will compel him.
She will not rest
until you are dead.
I well imagine poor Servilia
is not very fond of me,
but really,
wants me dead?
Atia, you're
a dramatist.
Well, I've warned you.
I'll say no more.
I've warned him.
You're far away.
Somewhere pleasant,
I hope.
- It's all one.
- So they tell me.
I need your help.
Your mother is a vicious
and heartless creature,
but I find I am
wretched without her.
I have done my best
to sway her,
but still she shuns me
like a leper.
Refuses even
to speak to me.
Will you talk
to her for me?
Let her know how
pitiful I have become?
There's no need.
Her disdain for you
is an act.
She is entirely
infatuated with you.
That is a wicked,
foolish lie!
Atia, you let me
speak with you...
Daughter, that creature over there
by the door, who is she?
The beauty
in the vulgar dress?
She's with
Lucius Vorenus.
His wife I expect.
It's so beautiful.
They've even painted
the ceiling.
She has a wonderful tang
of the street about her.
Let me introduce you.
- Maybe we should walk around.
- No, we should wait.
- They're coming towards us.
- Calm calm.
Magistrate,
my niece would like
- to meet your lovely wife.
- Honored.
Niobe, Atia.
How did a grim thing like you
win such a flower?
I found her when she
was still young and foolish.
Perhaps you will
entertain Niobe
while I speak with
her fortunate husband?
Delighted.
Now, tell me,
who on Gaia's earth
- made this astonishing dress?
- I did.
- You didn't.
So... what does
Mascius say?
He will accept
Pannonia for 12.
Very good.
I did not think he would
sell himself so cheap.
I must send you to negotiate
all my corruptions.
I would rather not, sir.
I spoke in jest.
I understand.
Please.
You have corrupted
one man
and saved thousands
from banditry.
I often wish I were
back in Gaul.
There is something pleasingly
simple about warfare.
- Vorenus...
- Magistrate Vorenus, if you please.
He outranks you now,
my boy.
Excuse me,
Magistrate Vorenus.
I hear rumor
among the servants
that Titus Pullo
is in the dungeons
awaiting trial for murder.
Is it true?
It is.
He has been hiring himself out
as a knifeman.
He killed a man
in broad daylight.
We must do
something for him.
We must do nothing.
- Nothing?
- The man he killed
was Aufidius Dento,
Deputy Chief of
the Caelian Nailmaker's Association.
Popular man, apparently,
and a vocal critic of my leadership.
People will suspect
I ordered his death.
I must not confirm
those suspicions by helping Pullo.
And did you...
order his death?
I did not know he existed
until he didn't.
I have no notion
why he was killed.
Public man like that,
might be many reasons.
I can't appear to be
sending out my soldiers
to murder anyone
who opposes me.
I would lose support
of the plebeians...
Perhaps Vorenus and I
might be able to...
...nor can anyone
associated with me help him.
Has he any friends?
Who will help him find
a lawyer to defend him?
He is guilty.
People must see
justice done.
Soldiers have to learn
they're not above law.
I'm sorry, Vorenus.
I know he is brother to you,
but there is no choice.
It's all true.
I think we can
go now unless you...
Can we? This is
very nice, but...
I know.
Castor...
in the morning,
bring Timon
the Jew here.
Good night, Mother.
Good night, my love.
I don't see
what's wrong with it.
Oh, Moses,
you need law?
Number one justice
right here! Right here!
Take me, boss! Top lawyer!
Top lawyer!
- You're good are you?
- Good?
I could have Medea acquitted. What's your
case?
Man, name of
Titus Pullo...
- On your way, Jew.
- You don't want the case?
I'd rather suck
Pluto's thorny cock.
Anyone?
Anyone want work?
It would go
much easier for you
if you said who it was
that paid you.
It-it shows penitence.
I can't help you.
Sorry.
I gave my word.
Perhaps you need the money
to help your sick mother
or a friend in need?
Something like that
would help.
I needed money for wine.
Have... have you any friends
that would speak for you?
There must be someone.
Good bread, this.
Have you got any more?
Titus Pullo, soldier,
13th Gallic Legion;
Accused of homicide
re citizen Aufidius Dento,
Caelian Hill,
tribe of Falerna;
Brought to trial
by his friends.
We begin.
Who speaks
for the corpse
of Aufidius Dento?
I... Maius Nigidius.
Who speaks
for Titus Pullo?
I- I...
Priscus Maevius.
Accusator, proceed.
Citizens,
friends...
when I was told
of the death of Aufidiu,
I was deeply saddened.
A good man, stabbed!
Butchered!
Hacked to death in daylight
on a public street!
I was deeply saddened.
But I was not surprised.
These horrors
have become commonplace.
Wretched specimens
like this
are common as rats.
I will not take your time with
lengthy proof of his guilt.
Look at him!
It's not open to question.
We all know he's guilty.
When I find a rat
in my cellar,
I don't ask questions, I have
a slave squash him underfoot...
Salve, brother.
And to you, brother.
Not good, eh?
What are you doing here? I thought
Pullo was dead to you?
Dead to all soon.
Hard as adamant, you.
Well, you might
be wrong, though.
Many's the slip
'tween knife and altar.
- What?
- Pullo is not alone.
We'll not let any brother
be damned by this dirty mob.
These dogs will be
yelping louder soon.
When they bring him
down off there,
we'll go in swinging
and have him away.
- Call them off!
- Eh? Why?
Do you not understand
what is at stake here?
- Brother Pullo's life.
- Politically.
What is at stake
politically.
Politically. I fuck politically
in her fat ass.
If Pullo is rescued
by Caesar's men,
people will assume that he
ordered Dento's killing
and Caesar will
be held responsible.
And so? Caesar can
do as he likes.
He is trying to
re-establish law and order.
That won't work
if his soldiers are seen
to be killing citizens
without consequence.
Still. I can't call
the boys off now.
- Why not?
- Because it makes me look bad.
You could look
far worse.
You will tell them?
I will if I have to.
Look at us, brother.
How has it come
to this?
It is for the good
of the Republic.
It's a worthy cause then.
Just call them off.
To add insult to injury,
this soldier,
this brute, this barbarian
from who knows where,
refuses to name
his paymaster!
Caesar! Caesar!
We name no names, Citizen.
We cannot know.
We might guess.
We might
very well guess,
but we cannot know.
Which makes his crime
even worse.
Is there punishment enough
for monsters such as this?
I think not.
But perhaps
my learned friend
can tell us otherwise.
Priscus Maevius speaks.
This-this man...
is nothing
but a helpless servant.
A tool, a puppet.
We should feel pity,
not anger.
Pity for his...
pity for
his degradation.
Wait. Do you
claim him innocent?
No, I'm simply
saying that...
Well if you do not deny his guilt,
then we're done with it.
- Do you deny his guilt?
- No, I do not sir.
Very well.
Titus Pullo
condemned to death
in the arena.
You know that I have always
looked on you as my son.
Oh dear, one of
those conversations.
Hmm, good move.
I have a favor
to ask of you, father to son.
Oh?
I need someone
to take over Macedonia
from that idiot Valerius.
I would like
to appoint you.
I govern Macedonia?
If you will accept.
Why by three Furies would
you want me to govern Macedonia?
You are the right man
for the job.
I can think of
few men less right.
Brutus, you've always underestimated
yourself.
You might achieve great
things if you would but try.
In Macedonia?
I think not.
I would ask you
to reconsider.
I need someone
I can trust.
- You need me out of Rome?
- Not at all.
I need your help.
Someone you can trust?
Am I wrong to do so?
- You have doubts, do you?
- I did not say that.
Speak plain,
I beg you.
Have I given you
reason for doubt?
Since you ask, you have
as you well know.
You speak of years ago.
Old betrayals
do not signify?
I betrayed nothing.
Had you told me
you were to march on Rome
and asked me
for my allegiance,
I would have given it.
I would have
judged you insane...
but I would have given
you my allegiance
because I look on you
as my father.
- Brutus...
- But you did not ask for my allegiance.
You demanded it
at swordpoint.
I betrayed nothing!
Forgive me,
I spoke too hot.
You have never betrayed me.
- So why do you not trust me now?
- I trust you completely.
So much so that you
would send me
from Rome
to govern Macedonia?
Well, thank you.
I am honored,
but I will not go.
It is in my legal power
to insist that you do go.
As my father,
as my father
I looked on you...
For a year or so,
no more.
Until the city
is stable.
Forgive me.
I feel unwell.
Perhaps we can finish
this game another time...
Be reasonable!
You're on every wall
with a knife at my throat!
I would be foolish
to ignore it.
Only tyrants
need worry about
tyrant killers.
And you are no tyrant.
Haven't you told me
so many times?
You may go.
Janus, Gaia and Dis...
I humbly beg
you accept this creature
as my offering,
and if it pleases you...
I ask you to give
Eirene long life.
And same for my friend
Lucius Vorenus and his family,
if it's not too much.
And let Eirene know
that I am sorry
for what I did.
Come on, soldier, up!
Cavi with this one...
soldier.
Come on, coward!
Fight!
Stand up and fight.
I don't want to.
That's not how it works.
You're supposed to resist.
Not if I don't want to.
I just want to die,
all right?
So come ahead and kill me
and be done with it.
Bollocks. Move!
What's wrong with you?
Where's your dignity?
Get up and fight!
Hey, soldier.
Wake up!
Why don't you come here
and suck my cock?
Look, just hold
your sword.
Just stand up and hold it,
that's all.
You don't have to
run about or anything.
You're naught
but a bloody mollie.
You and the whole 13th!
Naught but bloody mollies.
Don't talk of the 13th.
Oh, eh?
I piss on the 13th!
Pig spawn,
all of em.
Why don't you and
the 13th all line up and suck my cock...
13!
Heya!
Pullo! Pullo! Pullo...
- In autumn, they disappear.
- Who?
Eels, they all
disappear.
- That so?
- Where?
- Where what?
- Well, where do they go?
- The eels?
- That's what I'm saying.
Nobody knows.
It's a mystery.
Was expecting you time ago.
If we employ you again,
next time,
best not use veterans.
Mother?
I owe Caesar
no more friendship.
I must do my duty.
I'll speak to Cassius.
See what can be done.