Rome - Season 2 - Episode 06
"Philippi"
Where are the grain
provisioning figures?
This can't be right.
I've been talking with the men.
They had no idea
greece was so large.
And they're sick of the endless
marching you put us through.
Were plotting our revenge.
We must find good ground.
They're quite an amiable lot,
really, when you get to know them.
Ravening potbellied whorescum.
Let's hope they fight
as well as eat.
If you will bury your nose
in quartermaster's accounts,
You must expect to be gloomy.
Look up, Cassius. Look around.
Is it not wonderful?
I see only 100,000 mouths to feed.
You have no poetry in you, Cassius.
We ride with these men
to save the republic.
Yeah, well, sorry to be prosaic.
Before we do any saving of republics,
we have Octavian to defeat.
Indeed.  Ha!
if we play this right,
We can take Brutus
and Cassius by surprise.
They will be expecting to face
only you and your troops.
So when both our armies
arrive in greece
They will be trapped.
And there will be no time
for them to flee.
Do you understand what I'm saying,
or shall I speak more slowly?
No, making use of strategic
surprise is obvious.
To that end, there is a list
of the most prominent friends
And supporters of Brutus
and Cassius left in Rome.
We should kill them
Before they learn
what we're about.
You are a ferocious little cunt...
with a pen.
These are among the finest men in Rome,
Some of them my good friends.
Their money will be
useful as well.
General Antony, tell them.
Cicero is the cleverest
bastard of them all,
And he has the largest network of spies.
He must die first.
There are one or two names
I'd like to add myself.
I shall start back to Rome.
I'll muster my troops and
let it be known I intend
To go east to confront
Brutus and Cassius alone.
Lepidus, you will remain
behind with a small force.
Keep the peace in Rome
after we've left.
I'm pledged
to agree with you.
But I must say,
these killings...
send the list ahead
to Lucius Vorenus
At the aventine collegium.
Add instructions telling him
to divide the names
Among the gangs.
I have a name while you're at it.
Not Servilia.
We cannot kill women.
- Rufus tranquillus.
- Who?
Isn't he father
to Octavia's frienjocasta?
Why do you
want him dead?
I don't like the girl.
She's a bad influence.
This is not a game, mother.
Her father is
immensely rich.
True.
Stone quarries.
Woe unto
rufus tranquillus then.
Make sure Vorenus knows
that he and titus Pullo
Should deal
with Cicero personally.
All right.
Tell them
To cut off his hands
And nail them
to the Senate door.
I told the old fool I'd do it if
he ever crossed me again.
Nobody can possibly say
that I don't keep my word.
Goodbye, my love.
I shall miss you.
We're forever saying goodbye.
It's becoming tiresome.
One little campaign in Greece
and we shall never be parted again.
- Do you mean that?
- Of course.
That would make me
very happy.
When you return you must bring me
Brutus' head as a wedding present.
Yes, a wedding.
Yes, we must think
about that when I return.
Now don't keep your
darling boy waiting.
It's a long way back to Rome.
And you be careful
with Octavian.
Of course.
I know how to handle him.
That's what
I'm afraid of.
There, see?
Brings out your eyes.
What are you doing?
Wash that off at once.
Yes, father.
What's the problem?
A little blush.
Paint yourself
as you wish.
You stay away
from my daughter.
Mascius, tell the collegia
captains we meet here today.
Tell them it'll be in their interest
to attend.
- Will do.
- Thanks.
Eh?
Standing up for me
like that.
Shut up.  He's captain.
She's his daughter.
He says don't paint her.
Don't fucking paint her.
Spoken like a true
third man.
I like you.
You know I do.
But be careful, slave.
I have my limits.
Each of you has been given a list.
On it are 10 of
the richest men in Rome.
You've been given
license to kill them
And are to take of theirs what
you and your men can carry.
Licensed by who, you?
By order
of Octavian Caesar.
What gives you the right
to decide who gets what?
The list has been equally divided.
Yoall get your fair share.
I've only got two senators.
- Try to keep him out of the mud.
- I will, father.
- Cotta here's got six.
- Right!
You got more equestrians.
It balances out.
It's the principle!
Lucius, Lucius, stop right now.
Lucius, get out
of the mud.  Lucius!
Lucius, stop right now.
I swear I'll smack you so hard.
Lucius, stop! Stop it!
That's the one.
Lucius!
Excuse me, lady.
Is this the way to the temple of...
Vai! Vai. You don't talk.
Vai.
There's more than enough
here for everyone-
Close on 80
of the richest,
Noblest patricians for you to murder
and then rob.
Which of you has ever seen
so much money for the taking?
What shall we do
with all this wealth?
I'm serious. How shall we spend
this blood money?
Slaves?
Wine?
Whores for the boys?
We can assume
you have a better idea.
The feast of pomona
is coming soon.
It used to be that each
collegium would distribute
Fish and bread
to the people.
- Why?
- As an offering to pomona
And as a gesture
of goodwill to the people.
Yes, but why?
The people eat fish.
Then what?
Then the people will begin
to see the collegia
As more than purveyors
of violence and fear.
But that is what we are.
It used to be different.
It used to be
People would come
to the collegia for help,
For justice, for money
For a marriage or a funeral
When they needed it,
extra grain when the dole was short.
What, we're gonna be priests
of ceres now?
Thank you for the history lesson,
but that was the old days.
Nothing but war
and turmoil since then.
- Things change, brother.
- They do, brother.
They are changing now.
Whoever wins
in greece wins Rome.
- Some kind of peace will follow.
- Suppose it does.
Peace is no friend to men like us,
Men that thrive on blood
and anarchy.
The collegia must change
Or they'll die.
Suppose we don't want
to change.
to waste good money
On fish for beggars.
I cannot force any of you
to be generous.
However, the aventine will be honoring
pomona with fish and bread.
You can spend your money
as you wish.
Oh, I see.
I see!
Play the big man
and make us look bad.
For that, you need
no help from me.
Vorenus, you're right.
You're right.
It's a splendid idea.
We shall be charitable. We shall be
large. Let us feed the people.
By all means,
goodwill.
So speak, brother.
Why'd you back him?
He's a man of vision, cotta,
a man of vision.
It's our duty
as romans to back him.
- And?
- It's done.
I don't trust
that Memmio.
- Too smooth by half.
- He bears watching.
You'll take care
of Cicero, eh?
He's at his villa
in tusculum.
They want it done quick.
- I'll get my kit and be off then.
- No looting on this one.
We'll show some respect.
Right.
Off out are you?
Ooh, sharp.
Don't touch that.
- Where are you going?
- Not your business.
Just trying
to be friendly.
Look, love,
I know your game.
I don't want any part
of it.
Too bad.
It's a good game.
Go find yourself some
other fool to play with.
If you ever change
your mind...
don't flatter yourself.
We're done.
What she want?
Huh?
Oh, nothing.
- You know her.
- Yes, I know her.
Where are you going?
Bit of work,
only for the day.
Why don't you
come along?
It's lovely country
where I'm going.
Vorenus,
why don't we all go?
Don't go.
I'll be back
before you know it.
Save me some
of that chicken, girls,
Or I'm eating Lucius
when I get back.
- Good luck.
- Ha, it's my middle name.
Dominus.
Speak, man,
what news?
I've just spoken
to someone in Antony's camp.
And?
I think your secrets will be safe
with hector. Out with it.
"My dear Brutus, I write
in haste with urgent news.
Octavian and Antony
have reconciled.
Their two armies
are united.
They plan to descend on greece
and take you by surprise
With an overwhelming
force."
Dominus, armed men
are at the door!
"You must retreat to asia
before the trap is sprung."
- You must run.
- No.
Too late for that.
On your life, you must get
this letter to Brutus. Understand?
- On your life.
- Yes, sir.
Master, you must
save yourself.
Show him the back way.
Be quick!
So you Cicero then?
What is your name,
young man?
Titus Pullo, sir.
Late of the 13th.
Ah, the famous
Titus Pullo.
I am honored.
Likewise, honored.
Talk about famous,
everyone's heard of Cicero.
Yes.
I daresay
Your work today will
earn you immortality.
- How's that?
- I will be in all the history books.
My killer's name,
no doubt, will live on also.
Ah, my name.
Thought you meant me.
Good peaches.
Yes,
just getting ripe.
There's no way...
I can dissuade you
from your task, I suppose?
I have a great deal
of money.
No, sorry.
Normally, I'd be tempted,
but you're far too important.
Imagine the fuss--
I get back and I haven't done my job.
Go away!
- Leave him alone.
- Give over.
- Put your weapon down.
- Never.
Don't mess about.
I haven't got all day.
Do as he says, Tyro.
But, Dominus.
Really, old friend,
If you could see
how absurd you look,
You would not protest.
Do as he says.
Thank you.
No, not yet.
Please...
give me
a few moments.
Whenever you're ready.
Mind if I pick some peaches?
What?
Oh, yes,
Take what you want.
Thank you.
Nice present
for the wife.
All right.
Now.
Stop this at once!
Resume your hideous
wailing when I'm gone.
Everything will
be all right.
You've been freed
in my will.
Take care of my people.
Yes, master.
Goodbye.
Easiest if you kneel.
You might not want
to watch this.
- Such a beautiful girl.
- She is.
I mean no disrespect,
But it seems a shame she'll never have
a family of her own.
It is.
It is a shame.
But she could marry,
If you would let her.
I know Niobe
would want it so.
Niobe would only want her
married to a decent man.
And no decent
man would have her.
We might try
and find her one.
What kind of man would
marry a prostitute?
No man that she deserves.
- Lucius, stop!
- If she can't have a good man--
Lucius.
Take better care of your brats, peasant.
I could have killed him!
You stupid bastard,
you were riding too fast.
Fuck you and your fucking mongrels.
Get out of my way.
Vorenus, no!
The children.
Go.
Go, get out of my sight.
Get back to your game.
And you, stay out
of this road.
Anyone want some peaches?
- Good day, was it?
- Very nice.  Yours?
No problem.
He's not a bad fellow,
that Cicero.
Not stuck up,
like you might think.
Give one to your sister.
More names
from Mark Antony.
- More?
- Antony has many enemies.
It takes time
to remember them all.
Surely we have
killed enough.
Close on 1000 men.
The troops need paying.
We have to get the money from somewhere.
Agppa has a point.
We should proceed
more slowly.
We do not want
to appear butchers.
Certainly not.
Excuse me.
I need some air.
- Long day?
- Very long.
It's tiring work, I imagine,
Killing people,
Even defenseless ones.
Most of them we shall
let escape into exile.
They will only lose
money and land.
Just ruined?
That's all right then.
It's not pleasant work,
but it's necessary.
For the good
of the republic.
Exactly.
- If you'll excuse me.
- No, wait.
You've been avoiding me.
- I thought it best.
- Why?
To avoid
any awkwardness.
Awkwardness.
I see.
I was right then.
How so?
I think if you did actually
love me as you said,
You wouldn't mind any
amount of awkwardness.
No no, I'm glad
to know the truth.
Please do not toy
with me.
You cannot have mistaken
my sincerity.
But to avoid
awkwardness?
I have not spoken to you because
I am aware that my feelings
for you are hopeless.
But that's for me
to say, isn't it?
No.
No, it's not.
My father was a nobody.
His father was a slave.
I have not a drop
of good blood in me.
So you have risen
purely by merit.
Surely that is commendable,
in its way.
You are sister
to Gaius Octavian Caesar.
You'll not be married
to the commendable son
of a nobody.
I'll marry who I like.
No, no you won't.
You'll marry some useful nobleman of
your brother's choosing.
- Octavia--
- Just leave me alone.
I'm sorry.
I've been torturing myself
these last months.
I cannot--
- I cannot bear to--
- Don't.
Oh, hello, Octavia.
Maecenas, I came
to see my brother.
I'm sure he'll be
very happy to see you.
Agrippa, we can't find
the wretched blasted figures
- For the blasted tax projections.
- Uh, yes.
Lovely to see you again.
It is no small sum
We are asked to give.
What guarantee is
there that our money
Buys the influence
we seek?
It is herod's own agent
who makes this request of us.
If our money can ensure
That Rome recognizes him
As king of judea,
herod will be in our debt.
He acknowledges this
himself.
But who exactly does
he intend to bribe?
Who knows who will
be master of Rome
next month,
Leave alone next year?
We will not disburse
the money
Until the conflict
is settled.
How has it come
to this?
In this holy place
You conspire
in bribery
So that idolaters can
rule over your own people.
Who do you think
you are?
Sit down, Moses.
Would you have
the seleucids rule judea?
Or the ptolemys?
Better one we know,
one we can work with.
Why let any of them rule?
This is our land.
You are traitors
to your own kind.
May ha-Shem have mercy
on all of you.
Name yourselves.
We are the sons
of arod,
From the families
of manasseh.
We are the wrath
of Israel.
Oh, tevye.
What joy it is
To have your strength
at my side.
I don't get it. Roughing up the elders,
no problem.
But where's the point
in something like that?
Zion is the point, brother. We're
redeeming the kingdom of zion.
Remember, friends.
Remember who we are.
We are the chosen people.
Not slaves, not animals.
The chosen people.
Make way.
Make way there!
Thank you.
- Everybody eats today.
- Bless you, Vorenus.
See?  Orderly
as you like.
Yes, very nice.
- Octavian leaving today?
- Uh-Huh.
Winner takes all,
you reckon?
I reckon.
Shame not to be there.
Those days are
behind us, brother.
We've other concerns here. There'll be
peace soon, one way or another.
A good thing, I suppose.
But?
You know how it goes
with me in peacetime.
Violence is
the only trade I know.
Peace comes, and the collegia change
as you say they must,
I'll be on my ass again,
won't I?  Jobless,
Telling war stories
to the rest of the drunkards.
No, it's different now.
You and me,
we can do big things here.
You will.
You'll do big things.
It's good to see you so happy
and full of purpose again.
It is.
But me,
I don't know.
You're second man
in the aventine.
Second man.
I can see it
on my tombstone now.
"Second man
on the aventine.
He handed out
many fish."
Nothing wrong
with handing out fish.
No no no.
Canny business, no doubt.
But it's not soldier's
work, is it?
I'm a soldier.
Least I used to be.
Second hour.
We should go.
Third hour.
Gods, that can't
be right.
- They're always right.
- Third hour.
Blind bawdy house slaves.
Always.
You're familiar with the species,
are you?
I'm an unchaste
and sinful woman.
I thought you
liked that about me.
I'm sorry.  I have no right
to be possessive.
No, I like that
about you.
Are you sure
you're all right?
I'll be fine.
Once you're gone,
I'm sure I shall be fine.
I really should go.
I'm very late.
Then go.
- I don't want to leave you like this.
- Go!
Octavian, please, if only for my sake,
be good to Antony.
I am pledged to it,
mother.
He's an arrogant shit, I know,
but he's a good and honest man.
You need him.
You need each other.
- I'm aware, mother.
- Listen--
Troops are assembling
on the field of Mars.
- We must be away soon.
- Where is Agrippa?
I don't know. Saying goodbye
to some woman, I expect.
- Oh?
- He attendsto several whores.
Or one lover.
I don't know which.
Be a friend to Antony.
Don't be cold and superior.  It will
only provoke him.
It provokes everybody.
We all know how clever you are.
- No one needs reminding.
- Yes, mother.
I'm so sorry.
Hot from a brothel bed
on such a day?
Shame on you, Agrippa.
I assure you,
nothing of the sort.
I'm teasing you.
It's fine.  We should go.
Goodbye, mother.
Juno, bless you.
Oh, thank the gods
you haven't gone already.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Women's troubles--
Had to go to the temple.
Place was a madhouse.
I'm so glad
I didn't miss you.
Give me a kiss, sister.
The men are waiting.
Forward!
So now you can tell me
all about Agrippa.
What about him?
How long have you
two been lovers?
It's not true.
Oh, please. Don't lie to your mother.
You know it's futile.
How did you know?
I didn't until now.
You mustn't--
You mustn't tell Octavian.
- Please.
- It's harmless enough, I suppose.
Both you and Agrippa have
good reason to be discreet.
- You may as well enjoy yourself.
- Thank you.
Just so long as you keep
your wits about you.
Don't be thinking you can
go off and marry him someday
- Because it's not
gonna happen.
- I know.
But I love him,
mother.
I love him.
Soft as cheese.
What am I gonna do
with you?
Help me!
Gods, help me!
Please help me!
I beg you to help me.
Jocasta, what's wrong?
What's happened to you?
Men came in the night.
All my family are dead.
They killed them
and took me away.
- They have dishonored me.
- You're safe now.
Isn't she, mother?
We'll keep her safe.
Of course.
We'll protect you.
- Hey.
Whole place stinks
of fish, doesn't it?
I don't mind.
Reminds me of home.
Oh, right.
Like fish, did they,
your lot?
I didn't know that.
We had a big lake.
Deep.
A lot of fish.
What is the helmet for?
Nothing.
Just thinking of old days,
that's all.
Old days.
Not today.
- Soldiers leaving.
- You mean me,
Leaving with them?
No.
Well, it had crossed
my mind, obviously.
I'm in with the chiefs,
aren't I?
If I was to go back
in now,
I'd probably be first spear, at least.
Legate even.
Think about that:
wife of a legate.
Talk about respect
and money.
Probably buy a lake.
It'll be
a short campaign.
Everyone says so.
Sons of dis,
I was only talking.
No call for blubbery.
I'm "preglant."
What?
I'm "preglant!"
- "Preglant!"
- Pregnant?
Whatever you call it.
What is that
you've got there?
You've been mooning
over it the last hour.
This is my father's
signet ring.
I received it
from my mother.
I remember it on his hand
when I was a boy.
It's a good fit.
Sir, word from the scouts.
The enemy is sighted.
- At last.
- It's not just Octavian, sir.
Mark Antony is with him.
- That's impossible.
- The heron standard was seen.
- How many legions?
- 19, it seems.
To our 14.
The worm turns.
- How far away are they?
- A day's march.
Muster the men.
We must break camp and begin
the retreat immediately.
No, wait.  Stop.
Do nothing.
We will not retreat.
- Old friend, this is--
- No.
No more running.
We will meet them
here tomorrow.
If we win...
all the more glory for us.
And if we are to die,
This is as good
a place as any.
'Tis in the hands
of the gods now.
We have the upper ground.
As he says.
Heavens,
I entirely forgot.
Today is your birthday,
isn't it?
Is it?
I believe you're right.
Happy birthday.
Sorry there's no cake.
Next year, eh? You can bake me
an extra big one.
I shan't forget.
No cinnamon--
Makes me sneeze.
If you need to urinate,
now would be the time.
I'm fine,
thank you.
You sure?
Let us begin then.
Watch closely, boy.
This is how history
is made.
Now, let's have
some fun.
Advance!
Sorry, rude of me.
Would you like the honor?
No no,
you do it by all means.
Thank you.
Advance!
What is happening?
Do you know?
No idea.
On my command,
follow me.
Where are you going?
When in doubt...
attack!
Standard on Antony!
Go.
Thank you.
You two, on me.
Yes, sir.
Sir, Antony's forces
have broken the line.
Our right flank is gone.
- Halt!
- Our right flank is gone.
Send in
the reserve cohort.
Testudo!
Teombure!
Forward!
Down.
Cassius?
What happened?
Not sure,
to be honest.
Hell of a birthday.
Don't despair.
The day's not done yet.
Sir, our center is routed.
We must fall back.
We must fall back
immediately.
I see.
All right.
Come, old friend,
we have to move.
Sir, we must go.
Cassius?
We must go.
Sir.
It has been an honor
and a pleasure leading you.
I am sorry we could not
do better.
But you must look
to yourselves now.
Save your ins.
Sir...
give my best to my mother.
Tell her...
tell her
something suitable.
Cohort halt!
Keep searching.
Throw the dead on the pyre.
Breathe deep, boy.
The smell of victory.
Smoke, shit
and rotting flesh.
Beautiful,
isn't it?
What report, Agrippa?
The body of Cassius
has been found.
We're still searching
for Brutus.
Excellent.
Have the head
packed in salt
For transportation
back to Rome.
People appreciate
the little touches, I find.
SynchroFix :
YST
-=Tlf sub team=-