Episode 1x08 :
Caesarion*
* "Little Caesar".
He'll be Ptolemy XV
and the last Greek pharaoh.
(cf. note line 311).
"A fine reward is offered
for the return of a slave woman
stolen
or absconded
from the house
of Claudius Appius.
The following noblemen
returning from Greece
have received pardon of
Caesar and must not be harmed:
Publius Servilius Casca*,
* One of Caesar's murderers.
Marcus Tullius Cicero,
Gaius Cassius Longinus*
* He'll be though one of the leading
conspirators in the plot for murdering Caesar.
and Marcus Junius Brutus*.
* One of Caesar's murderers.
The traitor Pompey
has fled to Egypt.
Glorious Caesar follows."
Shoulder arms !
Forward !
Forward face !
Forward march !
Behold Ptolemy,
he of the two ladies,
he of sedge and bee*.
* The sedge and the bee are symbols
of Upper and Lower Egypt.
Behold Ptolemy,
son of Ra,
Ptolemy the divine.
Greetings...
How long may we hope for the
blessing of your presence ?
Not long.
We are desolated.
If His Glorious Honor cares
to divulge His purpose here,
the servants of the Mighty Lion
would be ecstatic
to help you
in any way whatsoever.
That is most kind of you.
How goes your
preparation for war ?
War ?
We have no war prepared.
I'm misinformed then.
I was told the sister
of the Mighty Lion
disputes his right
to the throne.
Do not speak of her.
I piss on her !
I shit on her !
It is true
our beloved princess
has listened to ill counsel
and raised some absurd claim.
But...
she has no support,
None but traitors
and barbarians.
What was that name ?
Deilogos of Pergamum.
He can raise ten legions.
Deilogos of Pergamum
Can raise
ten legions for her.
A petty bandit.
I assure you, you have no problem,
no fears at all
about Cleopatra.
Where is she ?
Well, nobody knows.
Somewhere in the South,
we believe.
He lies.
They have her.
This dispute between
you both must end.
Rome desires Egypt
to be at peace.
Your grain ships
must keep sailing.
We are in absolute
control of the country,
from the lighthouse
to the cataracts.
Good, in that case
you should have no trouble
in handing over Pompey Magnus.
I do not like his tone.
He can go.
Master,
do you remember
what we spoke of before ?
Of crocodile and fox ?
Let us show him our surprise !
All right, go on.
Show him.
We have a gift for you,
Glorious Excellency,
that we think you will
be very pleased with.
We were going to
make him a body,
moving arms and legs,
and do a mime show
with real animals and everything...
Silence !
Shame on the house of Ptolemies
for such barbarity.
Shame.
But...
you are enemies.
He was a consul of Rome !
A consul of Rome.
To die in this sordid way...
Quartered
like some low thief...
Shame !
Where is the rest of him ?
Eh, um, he has been
cremated...
with all proper
funeral rites, of course.
With all decorum.
I shall return tomorrow,
at which time
you will give me the man
that took Pompey's life.
Captain says the wind is fair.
- Good.
- We can leave
whenever you like.
You will take half the men,
return to Rome immediately.
You shall have the honor
of announcing Pompey's death.
I shall follow you...
when I've settled things here.
Settled things ?
Settled what things ?
Civil war is in the air.
It must be prevented.
Why ?
Let the wretches
fight it out.
War will disrupt
the grain supply.
Without Egyptian grain,
Rome goes hungry.
It would be...
unwise not to intervene.
And how will you intervene
with only half a legion ?
I do not intend to fight.
I shall merely arbitrate
the various factions.
You make it
sound so easy.
Those various factions are united
only by their hatred of Rome.
He's right.
Ptolemy might use you to rouse
the people against a common enemy.
I have conquered Gaul.
I have defeated Pompey Magnus.
I think I can handle
a small boy and a eunuch.
A small boy with 100,000 men.
I am aware of that !
He's still a boy nonetheless.
You seem to forget that
that our war is not over yet.
Cato and Scipio
are still at large.
Given time, they will
raise another army.
And when they do
I shall crush them.
I'm glad
you're so confident.
Some would call it hubris*.
* hubris or hybris.
Greek word often translated by "immoderation",
used to refer to the pride feeling
that lead a man to think he's like a god.
That unforgivable sin is often one
of the motivating forces in Greek tragedies.
It's only hubris
if I fail.
Remember she is a princess
of ancient blood.
When you find her you will treat her
with the utmost respect.
You must obey her in all things,
within reason.
Understood, sir.
I'm counting on you, Vorenus.
You have something to say ?
Regarding Pompey Magnus,
sir, I wish to apologize.
It was my actions
that brought him
here to this end.
- If I had done my duty...
- Indeed.
Dismissed.
Pompey's murderer.
Alas, he has run away.
Find him.
In the meantime...
these instruments
tabulate the money
that was borrowed
by His Majesty's illustrious father,
Ptolemy XII.
In the name of the republic,
I have come to collect.
17 thousand thousand drachma.
17 ?
Absurd !
Four, perhaps.
The tabulation includes all monies
borrowed from Pompée
and other agents of the republic
now unable to collect.
That is not just !
Post-mortem interests
of this type are legally
entailed
to the presiding consul,
i.e.* Gaius Julius Caesar.
* i.e. = id est = that is to say
- It's law.
- Roman law.
Is there some
other form of law*,
* Egypt is not yet a Roman province (30 b.C.)
but in 63 b.C. Ptolemy XII makes allegiance
to Pompey, and in 59 b.C. is called
by Caesar consul
amicus et socius populi Romani,
("friend and ally of the people of Rome"),
that is to say vassal.
you wretched woman ?
A thousand apologies.
Forgive us.
There !
There's for your payment.
So sorry...
His Majesty forgets
He is a vassal to Rome.
Vassal ?
I am no vassal !
I am king !
I am...
Sit down !
Thank you.
When can I expect payment ?
Your Honor, we have little enough
ready coin for our own needs.
Our tax farmers
have not been working
as they should because...
Because ?
Cleopatra's foolishness has stirred
unrest in some parts.
Nothing serious.
Well, I do not wish
to appear unreasonable.
I will accept
10 thousand thousand drachma.
Even that amount will
take many days to collect.
In that case,
I shall have
ample time to adjudicate
Your dispute with
princess Cleopatra.
Excellent notion.
But alas, who knows where
princess Cleopatra is ?
Do not worry about that.
I shall find her.
Blood and fire !
It's as hot as Vulcan*'s dick !
* Vulcan is the god of the fire
and of the blacksmiths.
His forge is believed to be
underneath the Aetna.
What a dump !
Gyppo gods must be right wasters
to make a place like this.
Don't speak ill of the gods
in their own country.
Gerrae*.
* = Bullshit.
I've seen their gods.
Titus Pullo isn't scared
of any bastard
with a dog's head on him.
More fool you.
These gods are old
and powerful.
Egypt was a great nation
long before Rome.
Was it ?
Mumped it up now,
then, haven't they ?
Why are we here, anyhow ?
Waiting.
Yeah, I know we're waiting,
but for who ?
I'll know
when I see them.
Be like that.
"Vassal," he says !
Barbarian scum !
It's simple extortion.
If we do not pay him,
he will put Cleopatra on the throne.
If...
If he could find her.
He is a resourceful man.
He will find her.
She should have died
when we first caught her.
Now it must be done.
She must die.
I agree.
My men could be
with her by nightfall.
Tell him "wait."
Cleopatra.
Queen majesty ?
Hutto asks to
speak with you.
Slap me.
- Night or day ?
- Night.
He may enter.
Majesty...
Fresh word has come
from Alexandria.
Speak, worm !
I am most deeply
sorry to say
Majesty must prepare Herself
for Her journey to the afterlife.
When ?
Now.
Say your words.
Hello, ladies.
Attack Caesar ?
Are you serious ?
Why not ?
He only has
a few hundred men with him.
How many men could you rally ?
You would be
the liberator of Egypt.
Your name would
live forever.
My mortal flesh should
be less fortunate.
Rome does not
forget an injury.
Forget Rome !
Rome is doomed.
Her people tear at
their flesh like mad dogs.
In ten years the city will be
a forgotten ruin.
Maybe so, but what
of next year ?
Perhaps you're right.
Ergo*,
caution is best, yes.
* = therefore
Perhaps...
you don't have enough influence
among the people.
Caesar has so few men.
I could raise the whole city
with a word.
Think on it.
Do you think I could
borrow Septimius
for a little while ?
I'd be most grateful.
Of course.
Messenger from Ptolemy XIII
begs entry, sir.
"Ptolemy the Water Bringer,
he of the two ladies,
he of sedge and bee,
king of kings, son of Ra,
informs His Most Grand Honor,
et cetera,
that him who bears this message
is him that killed Pompey."
He's handsome enough.
Good, strong chin.
Looks like a mean
old man to me.
More.
Divinity's mortal flesh
turns green.
Give it here.
She will look like a reptile
when she arrives at Alexandria.
Weak, I call it.
Weak, am I ?
She knows how to beat
her slaves well enough,
but she cannot
throw away that pipe,
- and she knows it.
- Insolent dwarf.
You know nothing.
Throw it out.
Throw... it out.
Weak, am I ?
That Gyppo princess,
now that's good cunny.
Her father's people
rode with Alexander*.
* Vorenus talks about Ptolemy Ist Sôter
(367-283 av. J.C.). Lagos' son, the
historian Pausanias wrote he'd be an
illegitimate son of Philip II of Macedon
(therefore Alexander's the Great
half-brother). He grew with Alexander
and was one of his lieutenants. When
Alexander (323 b.C.), he made
several conquest around Egypt that he
had received, and started the Lagid
dynasty from which are descended
the brother-husband and the sister-wife
Ptolemy XIII and Cleopatra VII.
You can't speak of her like that.
She is, though,
and she wants me badly.
Should've seen her
when I done that Nubian.
Wet as October !
Pullo, look at me.
She is a princess
of royal blood.
You touch her,
you die.
I'm not stupid.
I'm just saying she wants me.
Lovely.
Lovely !
Nothing like cold,
stinking sweat to seduce a man.
Caesar will think himself
on Olympus with Aphrodite*.
* Greek counterpart of Venus,
goddess of the beauty and love.
Hush, piglet !
What do you know of seduction ?
As long as Caesar is a man,
I will have him.
She seems very sure of herself.
I have him...
or I die.
So I will have him.
May it be so, Isis.
I only wish
he were here today.
My womb is between the flood.
A child would come
as sure as spring.
Come.
You, come.
So red !
Your Highness,
how can I be of service ?
Leather.
Olives.
Not so bad.
- He will do.
- Majesty commands
you will enter her.
I do not understand.
You have coitus with her.
You have it wrong.
"Coitus" means to make babies.
Exact !
So,
make babies.
Don't be scared.
I'm not scared,
I just cannot do what you ask !
It is not...
It is not in our custom.
Roman men are not used
by women in this way.
Come,
you will enjoy it.
My queen is an excellent lover.
What is he waiting for ?
He must do as he is told !
- Let me give you a hand.
- Get off !
I must ask forgiveness of Your Majesty,
but I cannot comply !
I am no slave
to be commanded so !
- With all respect.
- He refuses ?
This...
insect refuses me ?!
You dare refuse
the daughter of a sun god ?
Pullo ! Report immediately
to princess Cleopatra
and do as she says !
- Eh ?
- You heard !
- What's going on ?
- Just go.
Legionary Titus Pullo
reporting for duty, ma'am.
- Gods, that was something, I can tell you.
- I don't want to know.
If you value your life,
you won't speak of it again.
Why ?
I was only obeying orders.
Bloody good orders, too.
What do you think Caesar will do
if he hears of it ?
I'm not stupid.
I promised the princess.
I shall not speak of it.
You can't keep a secret
to save your life.
You've got a mouth like a drain.
Princess Cleopatra, sir.
Daughter of
the two rams,
mistress of sedge and bee !
Well done, Majesty.
Thank you.
Is something wrong,
little husband ?
How funny you look
in father's chair.
I never wanted to harm you.
Of course you did not.
It was your gelding
led you astray, no doubt.
- Mistress...
- It must not speak.
It must die !
It was him...
Not me.
He led him astray,
not me.
It was him !
Get in formation !
And you, Pullo.
Calpurnia...
She's your third wife ?
She is.
Has she given you a son ?
She has not.
How sad.
A man without sons is
a man without a future.
I never thought
of it that way.
Sad.
Never mind.
Have you secured
the upriver ports ?
You must do so immediately.
Whoever controls
the ports controls Egypt.
Good advice, no doubt,
- if I wanted to control Egypt.
- Of course you do.
Why else are you here ?
And why save me
so heroically from death...
if not to use me
as your...
puppet queen ?
Do you dislike the notion ?
My wishes
are immaterial.
You redeemed me
from captivity.
I am your slave.
Testudo* !
* = the turtle.
A Roman military tactic: soldiers close up
all gaps between each other and grab
their shields at the sides and above
their heads so that the formation seems
to have a shell.
Are you well ?
Well enough
though I do not sleep.
I write very bad poetry
through the night
and in the morning
I give it to the cook
to stoke the kitchen fire.
It's a form of magic.
My ill conscience
is transformed into
roast birds and pastries.
You should have
no ill conscience.
We only did what
we had to do.
No doubt Saturn* said something
of the sort after eating his children.
* Saturn is the father of Jupiter,
Juno, Neptun, Pluto, Hestia et Ceres.
As he feared to be dethroned by one
his children, he ate them, except
Jupiter, saved by his mother, who
grew up and made Saturn regurgitate
his brothers and sisters.
The question is...
If Caesar does not
return from Egypt ?
Caesar has escaped
tighter traps than this.
He has been besieged in Alexandria
the better part of a year.
Perhaps his luck
has run out.
Well, what fools
we shall look
if we have kissed
the feet of a dead man.
With Caesar dead,
that bastard Marc Antony
will be unleashed
to do as he wants.
Very likely,
but it isn't a concern of mine.
I am done with politics.
Self-pity is all very well.
I'm not unashamed myself.
But we are still senators.
We have responsibilities.
I remind you we swore
an oath of loyalty.
To Caesar,
not to Antony.
Cato and Scipio have
raised an army in Numidia.
If we were to
communicate with them,
we might...
If it isn't Cicero ?
How strange !
I was just now thinking of you.
I've received some happy news,
and my first thought was
to come and tell you two.
And here you are.
What a coincidence !
It's amusing how often
that happens, eh ?
So I was walking
across the forum
and thinking of
this particular woman,
who should arrive
right in front of me
But the thing herself.
Savage little
Spanish creature.
Hair down to her ass.
Everyone misjudges me, you know.
I'm a merciful man.
I know that's not
my reputation, but
I am.
Now, everyone's entitled
to a few mistakes.
Gods know, I made
one or two myself.
I've done things...
things I'm
ashamed to think of.
We are, all of us,
imperfect in our way.
Exactly.
We are, all of us,
imperfect.
Give me your hands,
brother Cicero.
With all my heart...
I forgive you.
I don't know
what you mean.
Nothing escapes me.
If a pigeon dies on the Aventine*,
* One of the seven hills surrounding Rome.
I hear of it.
So be assured, brother,
if I ever,
again,
hear your name
connected
with murmurs of treachery...
I will cut off
these soft, pink hands,
and nail them
to the Senate door.
Antony ?
You said you had
happy news to tell us.
Yes.
Of course.
A courier came from Alexandria.
Caesar has lifted the siege
And massacred
the armies of Ptolemy.
He is safe and sound,
and master of all Egypt.
The man is
a damn prodigy, eh ?
Atten-hut* !
Hail Caesar !