Miss, you one of them volunteer
nurses? Could you soothe my brow?
I'm feeling a bit feverish.
You look fine to me.
Back in line, you.
Oh, are you one of us?
I didn't see you on the boat.
I didn't feel very well.
Oh, quite a few girls didn't.
I'm Flora, by the way.
Katherine.
Can you believe we're finally here?
Everyone at home is thrilled,
even though they wept buckets
when I left.
Did your family weep buckets
when they said goodbye?
Yes. Buckets.
The others went in here.
Hello again.
Where are the others going?
Shouldn't we be following?
They were led off,
I was told to wait and not move.
Finally. The stragglers.
What do you think this is, a Sunday
afternoon stroll in England?
Follow me.
Keep your papers with
you at all times.
Do not put down your luggage.
Do not let go of anything you value,
you'll never see it again.
Your transport.
But where are we going?
Hospital 25A.
Not far from the Front.
I hope you like it lively.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
I'll write to his mother.
Yes, Matron.
End bed, please.
Can you change his dressings? Matron.
You... get my boots.
I want my boots.
Why do you want your boots,
Private Molloy?
I'm leaving here.
I can't walk out on my bare feet.
I need my boots.
Will you fetch my boots?
I'll bring them in a little while.
He won't see out the day.
I'd like it if he could
have as much peace as possible.
I'll go to him next.
I need an experienced nurse
to special Molloy.
There's other men needing that.
Men who joined up for noble reasons, not because
they thought they could escape the law.
All men deserve the same
when they're dying,
no matter what they're
said to have done.
I'm not sure who we can spare.
Help is coming.
Help?
Girls, with a few months' training?
Our nurses feel
the insult most keenly.
Did you know that military
nurses are forbidden to marry?
Isn't that just awful?
It's like being a nun!
Do either of you two have chaps or
fiances in khaki?
You're very daring.
Might I have one? Flora.
All the actresses do it. There are
photographs in my magazine.
You're not an actress.
Just... It gives an impression.
The Voluntary Aid Detachment.
I think it's a splendid idea.
Impressionable young women, newly
arrived in a strange place,
getting lost, having to ask the
dashing captain where everything is.
I'll be sure to tell them.
You're not dashing. I'm dashing.
You're in mate.
I want a full report!
Thank you.
Not till it's been checked, sir.
One Royal No.10 portable typewriter
with five ribbons.
Counted and checked by me, Captain
Gillan. Me, the Quartermaster, sir.
And I will get to you in
good time, sir.
Here at last.
Sister Quayle.
Let's get you settled. Follow me.
I imagine it's a little
different from what you're used to.
I love camping.
Do you know what we'll be doing
first, Sister?
It's just, I'm ever so much
better at some things than others.
Let's hope they're the right things.
Sister, where are
the... erm... conveniences?
There are chamber pots under
the beds.
Please hurry and change.
Matron is expecting to see
you in uniform.
Thanks.
Permission to run, Matron? Granted.
Bastard! Bastard.
I'm so sorry, Matron.
Get him off me!
Get off of him!
Don't you stick that bastard
thing in me, you bitch.
Ah, you bitch!
Bitch! You whore! You bitch!
I'll kill her.
See to the Padre, Nurse.
Hot sweet tea and a quiet place to
sit down. Yes, Matron.
Take Molloy back to his bed,
please, Corporal.
Get him ready for examination.
Bitch. Bitch...
Was it the noise?
Do you want to come with me?
Come on. Come on.
Yes?
Ah. Do come in, Prentiss.
Why does it help?
I don't know. But it does.
I'll put him on the list.
I think that's the right thing
to do, Colonel.
Have you shown the young
ladies the ropes yet?
Not yet.
I expect them to be welcomed.
It's difficult for my nurses.
Civilian girls, on the wards.
It's extra pairs of hands and feet
and God knows we need them.
And I don't want any
silliness from your nurses,
giving the volunteers a bad time.
We're the friendly face of the Army.
Of course, Colonel.
Matron.
Why did you attack the Padre?
He was trying to help.
Bastard was making me
ready for the box.
You keep him away from me.
I don't want no cross on my head,
I'm not dying.
I can special him, Matron.
Sit with him. He doesn't bother me.
It's a nurse's job, Corporal,
and you have other work to do.
Matron... Suit yourself.
..the volunteers are waiting.
The youngest was immediately
overfamiliar with the patients.
Shall we go together?
If you think I can be useful.
Margaret...
The promotion was
just as much of a shock for me.
It was right it was you,
and I couldn't be more proud.
My protegee.
And I know you will
rise to the challenge.
Give us all
confidence in your leadership,
and show these girls
what's expected.
At ease, Prentiss.
Blighty ticket.
I don't know how long they'll give
you, but I'm sending you home.
Oh, there... There, there.
What is that?
It's a cake, Matron. A fruit cake.
Mrs Bartlett, she's our cook, she
made it. She makes wonderful cakes.
Would you care for a piece?
Put it down.
Flora Marshall.
Yes, Matron.
Rosalie Berwick. Yes, Matron.
Katherine Trevelyan.
Matron. There are supposed to be
four of you. Where is Joan Livesey?
There was only three of us
at the meeting point, Matron.
So, Miss Livesey will arrive
if and when she feels like it.
Marshall, how old are you?
Oh, I'm nearly 24, Matron.
No, you're not.
I am. I just look very
young for my age. I always have.
Even when I was a baby
I looked young for my age.
You're wearing scent.
I'm not, Matron.
It's just rose-water.
Were you not taught the rules
concerning conduct and deportment?
Yes, Matron, of course. But you
don't think they apply to you?
No, Matron, of course they do.
I'm speaking to Marshall.
Of course they do, Matron.
Wash it off, please.
The soap is there for a reason.
It looks ever so... drying, Matron,
and I'm rather prone to rashes.
The rules are clear.
No scent,
powder or paint is to be worn.
No fancy stockings, boots,
shoes, belts. No trivialities.
Nothing that might invite, provoke
or inflame masculine attention.
But perhaps, Marshall,
you ARE a trivial young lady
and masculine attention is what
you're hoping for?
It was only a splash of
rose-water, Matron.
Matron, we all understand the rules,
and will abide by them utterly.
Nursing the men to the very
best of our ability
is what we're ready to do.
I'll be the judge of that.
That one's going to be trouble.
A well-made bed is essential to
a well-run hospital.
Sister Quayle is showing exactly
how it should be done.
And now you. You have two minutes.
I'm more than happy
to deal with this.
As I said, I'll be the judge.
Come on, girls.
Go on, Ginger, that's it!
Five, four...
Straight on to the quilt!
That's it. Tuck it all under!
..three, two...
Come on, quickly. Go on! ..one.
That's it now.
Time's up.
Your uniform is incorrect, Marshall.
Good God.
Berwick and Trevelyan,
you will make every bed
in the next three tents,
I will be checking every
single one of them.
Marshall, you can't make beds.
It's not my best thing, Matron -
but I'm ever so good at bandaging.
Look...
Lady Cavistock herself commended
my bandaging.
And my dressings and fomentations.
If you could just read...
And who is Lady Cavistock
that she is such an expert?
Oh, she runs the
Women's Guild in Worthing.
And who did you
practise your bandaging on?
The Scouts. Well, anyone who'd
let me. Even Daddy occasionally.
I'm really very good. I excel.
Lady Cavistock says so.
Please read her commendation.
With me, Marshall.
On with your work.
Sir, might I have a moment?
Ah, Sister Quayle, I was
intending to speak to you.
I know you would
have expected to be Matron.
You know how much I value
your experience on the wards,
and I wanted you to stay where
you're doing so much good.
Colonel,
thank you for the compliment,
and for clearing that up for me.
Any decision of yours has
my full support.
Boiled, dried, rolled.
Since you excel
in bandages and dressings.
Colonel Purbright is here.
Oh, Christ.
Sir.
All ready then. As you see.
Well, don't let them languish.
If they can walk and shoot,
then back up they go.
Matron Carter. How are you
settling in to the new job?
Very well, thank you, sir.
I thought you would have
chosen the other one.
What the bloody hell is that smell?
Oh, um, Sloan's Liniment.
I have a cold.
Well, don't give it to me.
Do you get called anything for short?
Kate? Katy?
Nope.
Well, then, Katherine.
I feel I must speak to you
about something rather important.
Might you turn around, please?
The rules are there for a reason.
We've all come here to do our duty,
and that's not to question
and be difficult, but rather to do
what's required of us.
They don't want us here.
We're being tested. Just as Britain
is being tested, and...
you really are being
rather selfish.
Muttering under your breath
when Matron's speaking to you,
being defiant and impertinent -
well, it reflects on all of us.
Not only Flora and myself,
but on every volunteer.
You wouldn't want to give us all
a bad name, would you?
God forbid.
I knew you'd see sense.
So best foot forward, and let's put
this behind us and be friends.
I didn't come here to make friends.
Especially not with a hypocrite.
I'm not a hypocrite.
What are you? 30?
The embarrassing unmarried daughter.
A drain, a weight to be endured.
Getting in the way, gathering dust.
But thank Christ for the war.
At last, function.
Purpose. Meaning.
You didn't volunteer out of duty.
You volunteered to escape.
Got a spare one, Nurse? I'm gasping.
It's a very sad thing
when a man's heart beats with such
ardour for a machine.
You're jealous
because you haven't got one.
Yes, because what I've always
dreamed of is a typewriter.
Were any of them pretty?
The volunteers. Come on!
Tell me, what were they like?
I didn't notice.
I despair of you, Tom.
You're a bitter disappointment to me.
Oh, and speaking of bitter
disappointment, despair
and other malaise - brass hat alert.
That lickspittle Purbright demands
our presence tout-bloody-suite.
I'm busy. Exactly.
Let him stew in his minor
public school juice.
We are surgeons, and
no-one clicks their fingers at us.
This is ridiculous. How can
all these men have venereal disease?
Can you be sure?
Yes, we're sure.
Well, symptoms
are being manufactured.
Chancres are being simulated,
Needle dipped in paraffin wax
applied to the old chap to
create a blister.
General's Office has even
heard of condensed milk being used
to simulate discharge.
I'm sorry, do you find that amusing?
Shocking waste of supplies, sir.
My staff know the difference
between condensed milk
and a genuine
presentation of syphilis.
They can't all have the bloody pox!
What do you do with those cases
that aren't genuine?
Well, they go back up the line.
Right.
In future they'll be reported.
And those men that HAVE got
themselves riddled will be put on
half pay, and their families
informed as to the reason why.
All but the Colonel
and Matron are dismissed.
I want to review your Blighty cases.
You're not permitted
to be on the wards.
But there's... toes...
Don't run in uniform. She'll
have your guts. What's in there?
Toes. Three toes.
They fell out of a bandage.
What you going to do with them?
Dunk 'em in your tea?
No, I'm going to
ask Matron what to do with them.
No, you're not. Come with me.
The majority are amputees.
Thank you, I can read.
A burst eardrum?
It's affecting the man's balance.
Right, we'll keep him here
for a week then send him back up.
With respect, sir,
a week isn't enough.
What about this man? Prentiss.
No details of any injury.
All his limbs are intact.
And HIS eardrums are A-1.
Why are you sending him home?
Neurological damage. Nerves.
Sudden noise, sudden movement,
any disturbance triggers
paroxysms, seizures...
An hysteric. No, he...
So what is wrong with him?
I don't know.
And I don't know how to treat him.
It says here that you've found
that music helps.
Yes. I don't know why, but it does.
I have some recordings
for my gramophone
and quite by chance,
Matron and I discovered that
if Prentiss listened to them,
something was released,
he was able to weep
and so avoided seizure and fitting.
So let me be clear about this.
He's young, fit, no physical
injury, there's no medical reasons
FOR these fits, and he cries
when he hears music.
Sounds to me
like he's putting it on,
sounds to me like funkiness.
Not at all.
Well, let's put it to him.
Run along and fetch him here.
When I want Matron's opinions,
I'll ask for them.
See you put a leash on her.
Corporal Prentiss,
could you come with me, please?
Enjoy the game.
On your way home then, Prentiss.
Sir.
Neurological damage.
Hold your hands out for me,
there's a good chap.
Walk a straight line for me.
Look at that.
Neuve Chapelle. Lose many chums?
Sir.
Tough times for everyone.
Are you lead-swinging, Prentiss?
No, sir. Are you a coward?
No, sir.
Are you aware of the penalty
FOR cowardice?
Yes, sir.
Are you a homosexual, Prentiss?
No, sir.
So if you're not a lead-swinger,
and you're not a coward
and you're not a homosexual,
you must be a soldier.
Sir.
Good man, Prentiss. Right answer.
Sir...
You may go back up the line
and rejoin your regiment.
Dismissed.
Get another bar for that medal, eh?
Make your country proud.
He needs a rest. He's had a rest.
Do you think the enemy are sending
their men home because they're tired?
We MUST have men at the Front
or we will lose.
It's that simple.
The bits go in here.
Bits?
Big bits - legs, arms. Small bits -
hands, feet, fingers, toes,
ears sometimes. There's always bits,
and they all go in here.
But whose ARE they?
Well, aren't we going to say
anything? A prayer, or...?
They're rotten.
Neither use nor ornament.
Chuck them in, and get back to what
you're doing. Sharpish.
Go on.
There. Now you know what to do.
Isn't what you expected, is it?
You'll get used to it.
What if I don't?
Then you don't.
But no-one's got the time
to nanny you through it.
You disobeyed an order.
You were told to make
the beds in the new ward tents.
I needed some fresh air.
You disobeyed an order.
For a moment, yes. But the soldier
asked me for a cigarette.
You should have
asked an orderly to help him
and returned immediately to
the task you were given.
I thought it more important
to help the soldier.
You thought that was
more important than my order?
Yes, Matron, I did.
Then you will be reprimanded
in the strongest possible terms.
For helping a man to
smoke a cigarette?
He asked me for help,
was I supposed to walk away?
Why are you here, Miss Trevelyan?
You seem incapable of respecting
the most simple of necessary rules.
Was it necessary to be quite so
vindictive towards Miss Marshall?
To humiliate her so publicly?
Is that in the rules?
Or was it more about proving
a point to Sister Quayle?
Your marching orders, Miss Trevelyan.
I have no use for you.
The convoy leaves
with the Blighty cases at 8:00,
you will leave with them. Now,
get out of my sight. With pleasure.
Ask one of the nurses to direct
you to the sluice room,
tell them you are on my orders
and are to scour every single bedpan
till they gleam. Yes, Matron.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
You'll keep checking him regularly.
I don't want him
in any pain at the end.
Yes, Matron.
Sister? I'm hemming!
Nurse! We have a haemorrhage
over here.
Very slowly, we don't want him
bleeding out.
Got another one for Blighty.
That's it. Off you go.
Lucky bastards.
Haemorrhage.
You're needed in theatre, sir.
With me, Sister. Matter of urgency.
The Blighty convoy is
about to leave.
I want you to find Corporal
Prentiss, and give him that.
I thought it had been
rescinded, sir.
This is my bloody hospital.
I want Prentiss on that convoy.
So hurry, please. Of course, sir.
Rosalie?
Rosalie, I'm about to leave,
but I have to say something first.
Oh! Sorry, I thought you
were someone else.
You try and get away,
you breathe one word...
I'll cut your whore's throat.
I've done it before. And I'll do it
again like it's nothing.
Nothing like a gusher to brighten up
a dull afternoon, eh, lads?
Shit.
What do you want?
You're going to keep me alive.
Molloy?
Molloy? Is that you?
They're looking for you. They're
the ones that can help you. I can't.
No, they'll tell him where I am.
Who?
He wants me.
That's why I need you -
to help me hold on.
He's coming for me.
All the things I've done,
he's coming.
There's something coming out
of my mouth.
Wipe it.
Show me.
You bitch.
You said you would keep me alive!
No, I didn't. I didn't. No, I...
They can, they can.
You said that, but I can't.
I'll take you with me.
You're a lying bitch.
I've got nothing else to lose!
Well, go on, then - stop
talking about it and do it.
I've got nothing left to lose
either, so really, go ahead.
What are you waiting for?
No. No...
You should be begging for your life.
Come on, beg.
Beg. Beg for your life!
I'm not begging you for anything.
I'm dying.
I won't leave you.
I'll stay with you.
Come on, let's get you into bed.
Blighty convoy just left, Matron.
Thank you.
The convoy's left,
why aren't you on it? Ssh.
Who's that?
No-one to be scared of. Sssh...
From the mouth.
Two minutes.
When I killed her...
..it weren't deliberate.
Will you tell her?
You tell her I didn't mean it.
You tell her I'm sorry.
Of course I will.
No harm done.
In his paybook you will find an
address for his mother in Aberdeen.
As you were the special,
you will write to Mrs Molloy.
You will say that her son
died peacefully and without pain.
You always tell the families that
the death was peaceful
and without pain,
even when it is not.
Is that rule
reasonable enough for you?
Yes, Matron.
What was the matter with him?
Gas gangrene. Liver and lungs.
How he had the strength to lift
himself out of his bed is beyond me.
You disobeyed another order.
I thought this was more important...
Matron.
He will need laying out.
I've been trained in how to do that.
I'll send someone to make sure
you do it properly.
You also never talk about
a dying man's last words.
No matter what they confess to.
It won't go any further.
Probationary period, Trevelyan.
I will not be so lenient again.
Matron.
Strip the linen. Yes, Matron.
Private Molloy's body
is in the new ward tent.
Corporal Foley, you will assist the
volunteer in laying him out.
He had these.
It could all have been
very different.
Thank you, Matron.
Your uniform is incorrect.
Sorry, Matron.
Are you waiting for me, sir?
I think it's you that's
been waiting for me.
I can't apologise enough
for being late. Joan... Livesey.
How's the first day been then,
Volunteer?
My esteemed colleague was lying.
He said none of you were pretty.
He must be blind.
Shy. How sweet.
I apologise for my friend,
he er... he thinks he's dashing.
Leave her alone, Miles.
Do you know what
they call the VADs?
The Very Adorable Darlings. And
I think that suits you perfectly.
My father gave me
a piece of advice about women,
shall I tell you what it is?
He said, never marry a woman who
holds your look for too long,
she's bound to be trouble.
And you take your father's
advice for everything, do you?
Well, usually,
but not in matters of the heart.
Of course you do.
You're the sort that does
exactly as he's told.
She will be eating out of my hand
within the week.
Sister Quayle? No running!
Oh. Sorry.
Sister Quayle? I was wondering
if I could have my cake?
I shared it out among the men.
I thought that was what
you intended. I am sorry.
No, please - I'm glad you did that.
It's much better.
Did they like it?
They enjoyed it very much.
Oh, good. I shall tell Mrs Bartlett.
She'll be so pleased.
Thank you, Sister. Goodnight.
Don't forget to say your prayers.
Oh, of course. I always do.
I realised I'd missed the lorry
so thought I'd get here
under me own steam.
Bought the bike in Boulogne.
Got the coat, goggles, everything
for an absolute song.
You can buy anything in Boulogne.
I could have turned up
in full evening wear with two
Pekingese dogs if I'd have wanted
to. Margaret, this is Joan Livesey.
The missing volunteer.
No, a civilian Sister. A reservist.
From the Royal Infirmary, Liverpool.
How do you do?
A Sister? We thought...
We were sent four names,
so naturally we assumed...
I completely understand,
wires get crossed.
You've been billeted with the volunteers, but
you will have your own private quarters.
You wouldn't mind showing the way,
would you?
Don't trouble yourselves.
I can find my way.
If I get lost, I'll ask someone.
Goodnight.
A proper, qualified,
highly-qualified civilian nurse.
I may have a brandy to celebrate.
She's rather young
to have made Sister.
Is she all right parked there?
Can you point me in the general
direction of the sleeping quarters?
Follow the signs.
Thank you.
I would never dream of cutting
my hair, but I do think yours
looks smashing. Well, thank you.
This is Joan. That's Katherine.
Hello.
It's Kitty.
I get called Kitty for short.
Are you married?
Flora! That's far too personal!
We're off duty! And civilian nurses
can get married. So, are you?
Or engaged? Is there a Mr Joan?
When would I have time for a man?
Well, never mind.
You have a motorcycle. And I'd
absolutely die to ride a motorcycle.
Maybe I'll teach you.
Oh, I'd love that!
That's the boys leaving!
We should wave them goodbye.
You're in your nightclothes!
They're going to the Front.
What I said was unforgivably cruel.
I'm sure we'll all get used
to each other.
Come and see this!
You have to see this!
Right marker!
Get a move on, you lot!
Squad will move to the
right in fours.
Form... fours!
Right.
By the left. Quick march!
Left, right,
left, right, left, right...
What I wouldn't give
to be you, lads!
Give the Hun hell from me!
For King and country,
give 'em hell, lads.
Left, right,
left, right, left, right...
Good luck, boys. Good luck!
Stay alive for me.
Stay alive.
Where's my husband?
I didn't think you'd be
so close to the sea.
You shouldn't have come.
I'm not prepared for this.
No woman is a blank sheet of paper,
we all have histories.
And I will not give up
until I see a smile.
I really believe
I was meant for this.
I've got grit!
Where? In your shoe?
Are you going to put them all
in the laundry,
out of sight, out of mind?
It's just bloody-minded.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.