["Fast and the Furious" by Ja Rule]
_
[choking sounds]
[British accent] Bearing 0-4-5.
- [Rapid beeping]
- Steady 10 knots.
I can't see. [Coughs]
[Coughing]
Sir? Sir?
Holding course, steady.
- Depth... sonar?
- Captain?
Bearing 0-4-5...
[Chokes]
Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.
Captain?
Oh, God.
Oh, God. [Whispers] Oh, God.
What the hell is going on, Sean?
Everyone's dead but us.
We lost the captain. We're all alone.
There's no answer from the base at Faslane.
How we gonna get home?
Sean!
We'll get home, Bruv.
How do you know?
Because I do.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Speaking indistinctly]
Rachel: Hope.
Such a rarified concept these days.
High in demand... [sighs]
And short in supply.
I'm enjoying recording
these logs again.
Until recently, I
had given up on them.
With no connection
to the outside world,
they were serving as little
more than just a diary.
But now with the satellite
network up and running,
they have become my trusty carrier pigeons.
I am happy to report that
the cure has landed safely
in labs across the country and in Europe,
and I am on my way to you, Dr. Hunter,
my friend, my mentor.
We'll be stopping first in Savannah
to set up a lab there,
before heading down to you
in Florida with the cure.
As promised,
I am uploading my data
to the secured satellite,
and I would love for you to take
a look at the work we've done,
and get your thoughts on
faster methods for replication.
Because time, as you well
know, is of the essence,
and millions still
continue to live at risk.
So take of yourself, old friend,
and I'll be seeing you shortly.
The door to the autoclave still won't shut,
and we're nearly out of ethanol.
I know. We've been running
the equipment at full capacity.
And with what those troopers
did to us in Baltimore,
it's a wonder that
anything is working at all.
Excuse me, ma'am. You need to see this.
Hospital ship U.S.N.S. Solace
departed naval station Norfolk
two weeks ago bearing south-southeast.
- Destination?
- That's just it, sir.
The harbor master log doesn't show one.
So it headed out to sea
to avoid the pandemic,
maybe create a safe hospital offshore.
That's what I thought, sir,
but then I checked the ship's manifest,
and aside from a skeleton crew from
the military sealift
command to run the ship,
there were only 15 doctors on board.
I mean, that's well below
reduced operating status.
With the plague, maybe
that's all that's left.
Even so, Master Chief,
the Solace was
especially retrofitted
before going underway...
Negative pressure equipment,
incubators, thermocyclers.
Precisely the tools one
needs to make a biolab.
Chandler: 15 doctors, all that equipment...
Think that's the missing lab from Norfolk?
It has to be. Put on a
ship and moved offshore.
[Radio chatter]
- Let's call 'em.
- Aye, sir.
They brought enough equipment
on that hospital ship
to build a lab three
times the size of ours.
With the cure, they can produce
tens of thousands of doses a day
and get them directly to
the people who need it.
South America, Europe.
We're gettin' another ship.
[Exhales]
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.Addic7ed.Com -
[Nishioka speaks indistinctly]
Gentlemen.
Now I know how much all of
you like carrying a load,
but the truth is we
could use a little help.
So I want to introduce you to
two of our new team members.
Both of these sailors were part of
the Navy's special warfare
joint operation training program
in Norfolk
when shit hit the rotors
about three months ago.
They volunteered to join
us on our mission south.
Senior Chief Taylor, Royal Australian Navy.
[Australian accent] You can call me Wolf.
He is the real deal.
A diver, E.O.D. expert,
and all-around operator.
- Proud to join the team.
- Welcome aboard.
- Hey, Wolf. Tex.
- Hey.
And this is lieutenant Ravit Bivas.
Israeli defense forces...
- Expert diver and intelligence operator.
- Hey.
Wow. We are a regular
coalition of the living.
That's right. Now let's make
our new friends feel welcome,
show 'em the ropes.
That is all.
- Hey, man.
- Lieutenant Burk, Carlton.
Yeah, sounds great.
You know, when I was deployed in the Gulf,
I spent some time outside Tel Aviv,
a town called Gi-Va-Tayim.
[Israeli accent] - Givatayim.
- Right.
Congratulations.
Miller: Hey, Wolf, let
me ask you a question.
Do you think them Navy
regs on fraternization
apply to foreigners?
You better check the rule book.
I'm just being hospitable.
- Uh-huh.
- Mm-hmm.
[Both laugh]
I say again, this is
U.S.S. Nathan James
hailing U.S.N.S. Solace
T-AH21 in the green
on sat-hi-com. How do you copy? Over.
[Static crackling]
Still nothing, sir.
Sir, I'm assuming that if
they took the lab from Norfolk,
they brought their call sign with them.
You try hailing them on
Navy Red or Fleet Tac?
Yes, sir. No joy.
Nothing on their Mars
station frequencies either.
Gator, hospital ships still
use their beacons don't they?
To announce their
presence as noncombatants?
Yes, sir. Prerecorded voice
broadcasts once per hour,
that's the rule, but the
range is over the horizon,
and we're not picking anything up.
Well, they couldn't have gone too far.
[Rings]
Bridge, this is the captain.
Come to course 1-7-5,
all engines ahead full.
Harbor master log said they
went south by southeast.
- Let's find 'em.
- Aye, sir.
[Radio chatter]
Hospital ship's nearly
twice the size of ours.
It's a 70-foot climb from
the water up to the o2 deck,
- [grunts]
- There you go.
Steam powered, one screw.
Yeah, but no guns.
I'll take a smallboy any day.
Hell, yeah. Built to fight, just like us.
- Hoo-yah.
- [Grunts]
That's nice. Keep that left hand up.
- I know.
- Yeah, yeah, you know.
Come on! You punch like a girl.
[Grunts]
Nice. Nice.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Panting]
Caught you slipping, buddy.
Come on, Tex.
[Grunting]
They're just friends, by the way.
Had a little convo with Wolf.
All right, not that you're interested.
Whoa, hey, hey. What'd he say?
He says she's like a sister to him.
Yeah?
Just don't break her heart.
You don't wanna tangle
with the big brother.
[Grunting]
Ooh.
Woman: The United States
hospital ship Solace
transmitting in the
clear without encryption
or secret codes as
required by article 34
of the second Geneva convention
for the amelioration
of the condition of
the wounded, sick, and
shipwrecked members
of the armed forces at
sea. United States...
[Door closes]
[Indistinct conversations]
It's a diagram of the grace,
sister ship of Solace.
From what I understand,
they're practically identical.
They most likely
constructed their labs here,
two levels below the o2 machine.
Best place for negative
pressure and ventilation.
You'll want to check... excuse me.
Sir, we picked up Solace's beacon.
O.O.D. reports they are in
range of bridge-to-bridge,
but they're not answering
our hails on any channel.
They still moving?
It appears not, sir.
Why does this story sound familiar?
This bloody virus...
Well, at the very least,
we'll be able to salvage their lab, right?
That'll be our mission.
Once we get the ship secured,
you can jump on board and take stock.
Then off to Florida and Georgia.
The labs are waiting for us.
I'll alert the team, bring
you right up alongside.
Master Chief.
[Door closes]
They put themselves out to sea,
waiting for us.
And we were late.
So, Wolf. Badass name. Who gave you that?
My mother.
All right, cool.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, you're probably
used to your Tavor rifle.
Mp7's better for close in fighting,
but could be a little tricky.
[Clicking]
Yeah, guess you got it.
Wolf: Just didn't see it coming.
I was working joint operations
down in little creek.
Yeah, things got bad real fast.
I mean, one day, they're talking
about a few isolated cases
of this crazy flu.
The next thing,
there's general havoc and
the airports are closed.
We went from setting up hospitals
to enforcing quarantines
to running for our bloody lives.
Nobody knew which way was up.
I always wondered how
it all went down here.
Yeah, most of the big cities in Australia
were hit pretty hard, too.
Never managed to call home.
My brothers, my sister.
This place isn't exactly home, but...
You've got a family here.
Appreciate that, Miller, really.
Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
CIWS is down,
but we'll have S.C.A.T. teams ready for you
if you need support.
All right, well, we'll be ready.
- Yeah.
- Mm.
I, uh, saw your new team members.
[Scoffs] Come on. Jealousy
is a useless emotion.
I agree. I'm just saying all
the girls are talking about
the man from down under.
- [Imitates Australian accent] G'day.
- G'day.
Jeter: This is united
states warship 1-5-1
on your starboard bow,
hailing you over channel 1-6, over.
- Port and starboard lookout watches set, sir.
- Very well.
O.O.D. starboard R.H.I.B. is away.
Woman: Very well.
Jeter: United States
hospital ship Solace,
this is United States warship 1-5-1
on your starboard bow...
Man: I hold Solace at all stop
with slight bearing drift to port.
[Engine whirring]
Man: O.O.D. recommends
steady course 1-8-0
maintaining 600 yards C.P.A.
Very well, helmsman.
Steady course 1-8-0.
1-8-0, all engines ahead
1/3 for 3 knots, aye.
All right, Tiger Team... Tex, Ravit, Burk.
Start aft and starboard,
clear your way to the lab.
The rest of you on me.
We go port and forward.
You come across anyone still alive,
save who you can with the
doses you are carrying.
- Am I clear?
- On it, sir.
- Man: Aye, sir.
- Burk: This way.
Tex: Let's find that lab, Tiger Team.
Nathan James, this is Vulture Team.
Radio check.
Reading you loud and clear.
Expect radio drop-off once we
get in the skin of the ship.
Next check in five mics.
Roger that. Good luck.
[Metal clanks]
So the vaccine your doctor
gave me, you sure it works?
Oh, yeah.
I wouldn't be here if it didn't.
Amazing.
Burk, what do you see?
A whole lot of nothin', sir.
Same here.
No sign of life.
Or death.
Where the hell did everyone go?
Sir? It's been five minutes, sir.
Vulture Team, this is the bridge,
radio check. Radio check.
[Crackling] Bridge, vul... team.
Hey, no... life.
Vulture Team, say again.
Your last was garbled.
Bridge, Vulture Team, I say again,
- no sign of...
- [Crackling]
Vulture Team, say again.
[Static]
[Grunts]
Man: What's going on in here?
For me? [Laughs]
Sir, you hear that?
Over there.
[Man speaking indistinctly]
Perhaps the best birthday...  Woman:
Hey, Stella, you know what?
Inside the cake is ice cream, too.
Chocolate mint.
[Girl speaking indistinctly]
You do or you don't?
Boy and girl: Do.
[Child speaks indistinctly]
Okay, say good-bye.
Children: Bye.
Found a body.
- Virus?
- I don't think so.
Two shots to the back, one to the head,
high-powered weapon.
Blood's still wet.
More blood over here.
Nathan James, vulture
team, this is Tiger, do you copy?
[Crackling] Do you copy?
[Beep]
Commo, bridge. I need a better signal.
- [Crackling]
- Slattery: Vulture Team.
Nathan James, Nathan James.
Holy mother.
They were lined up and executed.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
U.S. Navy. What's going on here?
- Be careful.
- [Switch clicks]
They're still on the ship.
Tiger Team, be advised,
hostiles operating on board
this ship. Location unknown.
Do you copy?
- [Crackling]
- Burk: I... we... we got...
12 Solace crew, K.I.A.
- [Crackling]
- Danny: Burk... read me.
Vulture Team, we got a
dozen Solace crew down.
Believe hostiles may still be on board.
I say again, hostiles may be on board.
[Static] Vulture Team, do you copy?
- [Crackling]
- Danny: Team, be advised...
Ship. Again, hostiles
operating on board this ship.
Set general quarters.
- [Bell clanging]
- General quarters. General quarters.
All hands, man your battlestations.
- General quarters is up and forward to the starboard side.
- [Siren wailing]
Down and aft to the port side.
The reason for general quarters
is hostile activity on board south.
Tex, Burk, do you read me?
Sir, they boarded about 20 minutes ago.
How many? At least a dozen.
Now we figured, pirates,
locals from the islands
desperate for food, medicine.
Now we've had those before, but these guys,
these guys came out shooting.
They think we have the cure.
[Indistinct conversations]
They were going after the wrong ship.
That was you?
The folks Secnav was talking about?
That was us.
[Sighs] I'm Chief Mate Gonzalez.
They killed our ship's master.
We held down as long as we could.
I'm so sorry.
No, sir. I'm sorry.
- [Ring]
- C.I.C., bridge,
hostiles operating aboard Solace.
I need a 360 surface search.
They didn't come from nowhere.
- Find me a ship.
- [Receiver clatters]
Get us in there closer.
Prepare the weapons.
Aye, sir. Helmsmen, left 15 degrees rudder,
all engines ahead two-thirds.
Everybody, listen. Let's stay together.
- We're getting out of here, all right?
- Doctor, we gotta move you.
I'm... I'm not going anywhere,
this man's chest is filling with blood.
We can't move until I get a tube in him.
Just... give us a minute.
Scalpel 36 French.
Nurse, stat!
Where's this lab you built for the cure?
It's down a level back
aft in a converted I.C.U.,
but the pirates went there first.
Burk, secure the lab,
level three back aft I.C.U.
- I say again, secure the lab.
- [Static]
Roger that. Let's move.
- And where are these pirates now?
- I have no idea.
But we heard some shooting,
like, 10 minutes ago,
up by comms.
Wolf, Miller, let's probe our way aft.
When we exit, break right.
Take starboard, we'll go port.
- Flush out contacts.
- Aye, sir.
Cruz, get everyone in here
secured, then join the fight.
- Aye, sir.
- Officer Gonzalez.
Sir. Look like you did prior service
before becoming a merchant mariner.
20 years. Surface warfare.
Firing on an unarmed
hospital ship's a war crime.
You know this ship better than anyone.
- Let's make 'em pay.
- Aye, sir.
[Gun clicks]
Anything on surface search?
No, ma'am. Nothin'.
Let's check underwater.
- Mason.
- Ma'am?
I need you to run sonar.
You passed the murder board.
I need a 360 degree sonar search.
- You can do this.
- Aye, ma'am.
I'm going to man the starboard Mark 38.
Fastest way to comms is through here.
Hey! Freeze!
Hold it right there. U.S.
Navy! Toss out your weapon!
[Rapid gunfire continues]
[Panting] Jesus. Did you see that gun?
These are not pirates.
[Door closes in distance]
[Indistinct conversations]
You ever been shot before, Miller?
Can't say I have.
My advice? Avoid it.
On my six.
Now.
- [Men shouting indistinctly]
- [Woman screams]
[Wolf shouts indistinctly]
[All grunting]
- [Gunshots]
- Uhh!
[Groans]
Miller.
[Panting]
- Vitals holding. He's stable.
- Not a minute too soon.
Hm2 dulac. Secure the
occlusive dressing on the chest.
Everyone, back behind the equipment
and turn out the lights.
Don't open this door for anyone but Navy.
Understood.
I'll be back.
[Switch clicks]
This is it. This is the lab.
We got company. I can't tell how many.
[Men speaking indistinctly]
[Men continue speaking indistinctly]
I got eyes on three.
Fine. Make sure they're clean head shots.
We wanna preserve the lab.
On my count.
Copy that. Ravit?
Ravit?
- [Door opens]
- Hey, hey. What are you doing here?
Looking for the cure? I'll give it to you.
Good shoot.
[Gun clicks]
Nice move.
Yeah, but we're too late.
Damn.
Vulture leader, Burk.
They destroyed the lab
looking for the cure.
I say again, the lab is destroyed.
Not sure what we can salvage. Sorry, sir.
Chandler: Well, get out of there.
But be advised hostiles are
heavily armed and well-trained.
Burk: Roger that.
[British accent] Come on, Ned.
The bloody U.S. Navy's all about the ship.
We got what we came for.
Let's get out of here.
Gracias. [British accent]
And miss all the fun?
Ding-dong! Hey, U.S. Navy,
it's bad luck for you
happening on this ship,
but this is the end of the line for you.
Because we know how to
fight better than you do.
And if it's a fight you want,
it's a fight you're gonna get.
Chandler: Whoa! Hold your fire.
Sir, doctors are secure.
About a dozen more M.S.C.S
holed up in the engine room.
Your boys took out
three hostiles with
ropes and wrenches. Nice.
All right, well, we can't
fit everybody on that R.H.I.B.
And there's no clear way down.
We can everyone out on the tender boats.
O2 level, starboard side.
Okay. On my order, get 'em there.
Captain, thank you.
Don't thank me yet.
First, we clear a path,
and then I'm going after
the man behind that voice.
Ned: Come on, keep up.
No word from Giovanni or
the others. We're losin' men.
We should give the order and jump ship.
Not until we kill every last one of them.
That wasn't the plan, Ned.
Your brother said we sh...
Don't you every bring up my brother to me!
I know what he wants!
I am the only one that
knows what my brother wants.
So let's just do what needs doing, yeah?
And then we can go.
You're lucky I won't tell Sean
how you cocked up the job today.
[Gun clicks]
We got gunfire. Topside.
- Foster?
- No target.
Sir, if we get any
closer, we could collide.
Chance we have to take. Bring us in closer.
- Find me something to shoot!
- Aye, sir.
Uhh!
- Nice shooting, Miller.
- Thanks, Wolfman.
Hey, Wolfman. I like it.
[Men speaking indistinctly]
[Whispers] Ambush.
They don't ambush us.
We ambush them.
Nathan James, what's your whiskey?
Comin' up your starboard side,
400 yards, lookin' for a target.
Well, I'll give you one. Flight deck.
We flush three hostiles
topside, you light 'em up.
Roger that. Batteries released.
Aye, sir.
[Whirring]
Starboard Mark 38 hot.
[Men shouting indistinctly]
On your count.
[Rapid gunfire continues]
Chandler: Three...
Two...
- One!
- [Click]
Lost 'em in smoke.
[Canister hissing]
- Chandler: You got one.
- Roger that.
- These guys are good.
- Too good.
Look for a military ship, a helo.
There could be more where they came from.
- Looking.
- [Ring]
Sonar, bridge, anything
on that subsurface search?
Nothing in the water, sir.
There could be a ship
hiding out in the deep blue.
[Receiver clatters]
Vulture Team, Vulture
Team, no R.H.I.B.s, no helo.
These guys didn't just swim here.
How's the patient, doc? He's still stable.
Glad to hear.
Okay, we found the others.
A dozen more survivors.
Oh, thank God.
Okay, everyone, we are
getting you all off the ship.
Cruz: Let's go. This way.
Let's get the hell out of here.
- Let's go, let's go, let's go.
- I'm gonna jump on the stretcher.
[Grunts]
Vest.
[Groaning]
Guys?
They're gonna blow the ship.
- [Static]
- Vulture Team,
hostiles have rigged the ship to blow up.
I say again, hostiles have explosives.
All hands, all hands,
abandon ship towards
the Lee, starboard side.
- Get to those tender boats.
- We need to get out of here.
- No.
- No?
We lost the lab. We're gonna lose the ship.
Okay... does anybody know how
to diffuse a bomb like this?
- [Whirring]
- Nathan James, we got about 18 doctors and crew,
one of them hurt.
We're about to load them into the tenders.
- Did he say doctors?
- Mm-hmm.
We're gonna need cover,
though, starboard amidships.
Slattery: Roger that.
[Sonar pinging]
I've got something on sonar.
Possible submarine in the bounce.
Are you sure?
- [Pinging stops]
- I...
It's gone.
Man: Bridge, Tao, possible
subsurface contact,
bearing 0-5-0 relative.
Request bearing, clear or foul.
[Tanks clanking]
How you looking, lieutenant?
Don't talk.
Cruz: Let's go, let's go, move
it. Let's go. Right in here.
[Men shouting indistinctly]
Move it.
- Everyone accounted for?
- Yes, sir.
Man: All right, guys, come on, steady.
Let's go, let's go, move it! Load 'em in.
Come on. Get on that boat!
[Ravit gasps]
Uh-oh.
I hope that's Hebrew for "a-okay."
Now that is an oxygen tank we can't move.
Let's go, let's go!
- Get 'em into the rear!
- [Gunshot]
- [Screaming]
- Chandler: Down! Get down!
[Screaming continues]
[Bullets ricochet]
Get 'em back to the
James! Do not wait for me!
- Let's go. Move. Move it!
- Let's go!
Come on, get up. Go, go, go, go!
Taylor, you all right?
Yeah, through and through.
[Gonzalez groaning]
Oh, this bullet hit the
carotid. I'm with you. All right.
There's a remote
detonator. Contact trigger.
If I pull it, it will go off.
Well, how do you stop it?
- Ravit?
- I'm thinking.
I need to keep contact on the metal.
Captain, we got a little
hitch in our plan here.
We've taken care of the first bomb.
There's another one
with a remote detonator.
And oh, boy, it's a big one. I
don't think we can diffuse it.
Get your asses off the ship.
Doc, let's go!
- It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
- [Speaks indistinctly]
- I'm with you. I'm with you. It's okay.
- [Gagging]
[Groans]
Doc, I'm sorry. We gotta
get you on the boat.
[Breathing heavily]
Man: Get out of here!
[Bullet ricochets]
[Ravit clears throat]
Man: Come on. We gotta go.
Cruz: That's everybody. We gotta go.
Well, lower the boat.
[Rapid gunfire]
You got two on top.
[Rapid gunfire continues]
Good shot, ma1.
- [Groans]
- Ian: I'm blocked off. Where are you, mate?
Juan Carlos?
_
get off the ship, man!
Whatever you do, don't let 'em catch you.
_
[groans] _
[exhales, inhales sharply]
- You got it?
- You guys need to get out of here.
No, we're not leaving...
No, you don't understand.
The detonator is inside. It
needs to be metal to metal.
It... the pressure release, I can't do it!
Aw, hell. Step away.
- Burk: What the hell are you doin'?
- I got an idea.
It has to stay in contact
with the metal, right?
- Go on, skedaddle.
- No. [Speaks Hebrew]
- What does that mean?
- [Speaks Hebrew]
[Grunts, panting]
[Speaks Hebrew]
Tex, are... you know what you're doing?
Make a hole.
End of the road.
You'd like to shoot me.
That'd be nice, wouldn't it?
Just a word of warning...
I let go of this button,
and this whole ship gets
blown to kingdom come,
including you
and all the little people
that you're trying to help.
You may blow up this ship,
but I promise I will take you with me.
Well...
- [Explosion]
- [Screaming]
Shit. Shit. [Groans]
[Panting]
Aah! Aah!
[Door opens]
[Indistinct conversations]
Captain's in combat.
Nishioka: Sir, no air or
surface contacts on radar.
Man: Negative E.S. in the area.
Slattery: We spotted
at least eight hostiles
diving into the water.
Aside from the one we clipped
who's sitting in our medical bay,
the others never came up for air.
There were no other boats
around Solace,
no R.H.I.B.S, no rafts.
Ah, Cruz said he found some
wet suits with the hostages.
My guess is they came
in on 2-man subs, S.D.V.
Agreed. They're military.
Any indication whose flag they're flying?
They weren't nice enough to wear uniforms.
Mercenaries, then.
Hunting the cure for the higher bidder.
Hospital ship was a natural target.
Mason, are you sure
you saw a sub out there?
Sir, I'm sure of it.
Hidden out there in the seabed...
It was a sub.
Well, keep searching the water.
The minute you find anything, I wanna know.
- Aye-aye, sir.
- Yes, sir.
- [Click]
- Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
Good as gold. Thanks.
Hey, Wolfman.
I'll never play the fiddle again.
Never say never.
You'll regret that.
Doctor Milowsky,
I'm so sorry that you all got
caught in the middle of this.
[Sighs deeply] We left
behind family, friends,
all of us working in isolation.
Solace was our last hope.
[Scoffs] You have the cure,
and they destroyed my lab.
It's a great loss for us all.
Chief Mate Gonzalez saved our lives.
I just wish I could've saved his.
So what happens to us now?
Well, your ship is seaworthy,
you have enough crew to
get you and your associates
back to Norfolk. We have people there.
You'll be needed and greatly appreciated.
We'll send you back with
doses of the cure, obviously.
I wanna stay here with you all.
I'm an expert in vaccine manufacturing
and genetic engineering.
If you're spreading the cure,
I'd like to be a part of it.
I'm sure we could use the help.
It would be an honor to have you.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah, it'd take, uh, more
than a bullet to knock me out.
I'm just glad we all got back
in one piece, more or less.
You, uh... did real good out there today.
I'm glad to have you on the team.
[Chuckles]
What?
I like you guys.
You're crazy.
[Chuckles]
It's a miracle he survived.
The lord works in mysterious ways, Deacon.
No doubt about that.
While he was conscious,
he was muttering what sounded like Spanish,
but you said your guy had a British accent.
An international band of thieves.
How'd they get their hands on a sub?
Well, if this man ever
wakes up, we'll find out.
[Engine whirring]
[Sonar pinging]
[Whistles]
So, you guys, is someone
gonna explain to me
where we're going in the
middle of the night here?
I told ya. There's someone
who wants to meet ya.
Was there a problem?
You didn't find the ship?
Oh, yeah, we found it.
So great news. You see? I
told you. Right? I was right?
Standard protocol for
emergency preparedness,
all hospital ships go offshore.
Niels, he said they found it.
He didn't say nothin' about good news.
What was the problem? You
didn't find what I told you?
No, we found the United States Navy...
A ship.
You found the Navy?
Yeah, it's like they knew we were comin'.
[Pinging speeds up]
You guys, that's them. That's them.
That's captain Chandler and Rachel...
That, um, Dr. Scott. I
mean, they have the cure.
Did you catch them?
[Pinging speeds up]
You think I had something to do with that?
You guys, I assure you, the
last time I saw that ship,
we were, like, a few miles
from Jamaica. I swear.
- If you suspect that I somehow set you up...
- [Shifts gear]
- [Engine slowing down]
- I categorically deny any involvement in any kind of...
Do us a favor, Niels. Stop talkin'.
You can save your bellyaching for the boss.
[Pinging rapidly]
The boss?
Let's go.
[Pinging continues]
[Pinging stops]
The boss.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.Addic7ed.Com -