Come in. Anyone? Anybody out there?
[Crying]
We're sick.
I'm broadcasting in the blind.
Mama?
- Mama?
- In the blind!
- [Coughing]
- Mama, please don't fall asleep.
Sam: Mama, we're
gonna get you help.
- [Coughs]
- Wake up, mama, please!
Jed: Anyone, please? Anyone out there?
Anyone... damn it! [Coughing]
Mama, please don't fall asleep!
Wake up, mama!
[Echoes] Mama!
[Click]
[Clicks]
What's your name?
[Click, beep]
[Clicks]
You sure you have enough
for the whole crew?
And 50 or 60 more.
When we get home,
we can use this as a vaccine and a cure?
The uninfected will be immunized, and...
The sick can be cured,
providing they're not too far gone.
After all the failures
and the false starts,
I just feel so...
Happy?
[Exhales sharply]
I can't truly remember the last time
that I felt that emotion.
Still so much to do.
We have to mass produce it,
we have to distribute it.
- Thank God...
- Rachel...
You did it.
Let's enjoy the moment.
Sync & Corrections by Darcade
- Addic7ed.com -
I told her how I feel.
I mean... [exhales]
Basically spilled my guts to her.
I mean, sure, I'm spiking
a 104-degree fever,
but still.
"You make me wanna love again."
I actually said that.
And what does she give me? Zip.
What I understand about women,
you fit in a shot glass.
I don't need to tell you.
[Whines]
[Indistinct conversations]
Hey, how are you feeling?
I don't get seasick, so...
[Exhales]
I've never seen morning sickness
on a D.D.G. before.
[Exhales] Have you seen a nursery?
[Chuckles] No.
- [Door opens]
- Form up.
[Sighs]
Okay, here's the deal.
We are presently attempting to make contact
with the infectious disease lab
at Fort Detrick,
as it has just the facility
Dr. Scott requires
for mass producing the cure.
So far we've had no joy.
I'll be honest...
Knowing how deadly this plague
is and how fast it spreads,
I don't have any confidence
that there's gonna be any survivors, so...
That being said,
there's a reason they call it a fort.
And if anyone can hold their own,
it's our friends in the U.S. army.
Master Chief.
Thank you, sir.
I want to address the issue
that's on all of our minds.
On our way up the coast,
our ship will be passing
right by Norfolk... by home.
And our comms team tells us
we could pick up
some orphan signals from random cell towers
or servers still online.
You may even get a phone call
if they've restored power on land.
It's unlikely, but I just
wanna prepare you.
We don't know what to expect
when we get back to the states.
The only way to help the people we love
is to deliver Dr. Scott and the cure
to a secure and workable lab.
Detrick's our best bet,
so that's our mission.
All: Aye, sir.
Carry on.
Any station in this net vicinity
of Fort Detrick U.S.A.M.R.I.I.D.,
this is U.S.S. Nathan James, over.
Aye, sir.
Captain, S.S.E.S. reports
that the keyhole satellite
will be flying over
our whiskey in 50 seconds.
Unable to steer,
but they did manage to break
the uplink/downlink encryption.
Bringing up the feed now.
[Beeping]
- [Exhales deeply] It's traveling fast.
- Too fast, sir.
There's no one left at home to control it.
When it gets over the area,
we'll have less than a minute
to capture the images we can.
We just need enough to chart a clear route
from the land to the lab.
We've tapped into one of
the air force's spy satellites
to check the traffic to Fort Detrick.
Well, why not send
your helicopter or drone?
No more fuel.
They spent it all looking for me.
Kara: Satellite passing over us.
[Static]
Mason: Any station...
Come on, give us something.
There it is.
[Beeps]
Home.
That's interstate 70.
If it's clear, it'll get us
all the way to detrick.
There'll be some image blur,
but I'll get you closer, sir.
[Clicks]
That's a mass evacuation.
- Take us north a mile.
- Aye, sir.
[Typing]
Any station this net vicinity of
Fort Detrick U.S.A.M.R.I.I.D.,
this is U.S.S. Nathan James...
That red "X"... Some sort of quarantine?
More like a warning sign to stay away.
Looks like people took it seriously.
Sir, the satellite's approaching
Fort Detrick.
I say again,
anyone at Fort Detrick, please respond.
The laboratory building's
in the center of campus.
Roger that, ma'am. Zooming in.
[Whispers] Oh, my God.
[Normal voice] It's been
completely destroyed.
The lab, the containment areas,
the equipment, everything.
Nothing else on the base was burned.
That lab was targeted.
Who would've done that?
Slow down! Slow down!
Stop the car.
Where you goin'?
My family's sick. They need help.
Can't go this way. Turn around.
Please. Please, we're just trying...
- Trying to get to Olympia.
- Olympia can't help you.
Go back where you came from, old man.
[Window whirs]
Get down.
- [Shifts gear]
- [Gasps]
[Engine revs, tires screech]
- [Children scream]
- [Gunshots]
[Machine gunfire in distance]
[Engine revs, tires screech]
[Man shouts indistinctly]
Should we go after 'em?
No. They'll be dead soon.
Sir! Sir!
Take a breath. What is it?
I caught a new broadcast.
It's another loop.
But this one was updated today.
And there's something you need to hear.
Woman: Winds are coming out
of the southwest,
and temperatures will reach
50 degrees in Baltimore...
How come we're just hearing this now?
Probably a weak F.M. transmitter, sir.
It must've just come into range.
There are reports of a fresh
outbreak of the red flu
- in sector 9.
- "Red flu."
Is that what they're calling it?
Doesn't do it justice somehow.
It's looping around. Here it comes.
U.S.S. Nathan James,
we are aware of your mission
and we have secured
the facility you may require.
If you are within range of this signal,
we urge you to reply over channel 1-6.
I repeat, U.S.S. Nathan James,
if you are still out there,
please reply on V.H.F. channel 1-6.
- Get them on the line.
- Yes, sir.
This is U.S. naval warship Nathan James
hailing you on channel 1-6.
We have heard your call, over.
This is U.S. naval warship Nathan James
hailing you on channel 1-6.
We have heard your call, over.
Baltimore. We should set a
course in that direction.
Agreed.
- [Door closes]
- We may still be too far out.
You let me know as soon as you find out.
Good work, son.
- [Door alert dinging]
- Schools have reopened in sector 3,
and some city services are set to resume.
[Coughs]
Attention, attention,
this call goes out to the crew
of the U.S.S. Nathan James.
We are aware of your mission
and we have secured
the facility you may require.
If you are in range of the signal,
we urge you to reply over channel 1-6.
I repeat... U.S.S. Nathan James,
- if you are still out there...
- Jed?
Did you hear that, Darien?
Tom's still out there.
People are waiting for him.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
You're gonna make it. You hang in there.
[Keys jangle]
[Engine sputters, turns over]
- Quincy: I had to do what was best...
- [Door opens]
- Kelly: Best for whom?
- Please listen to that.
Rachel: Ava?
Kelly: We have been through it.
They're at it again.
Quincy: You know that I love you.
Events... they just happen
on a mind of their own...
I know that things are better now.
But...
I don't think they'll be the same again.
Hello, Kelly.
Hi. Ava, darling, shall we go
and find something to eat?
All right.
I'll see you later.
I'll see you later. Bye.
She can't forgive me
for what I put them through.
To be honest, I don't blame her.
Well, when the Captain
finds the right place
for us to put ashore,
maybe you can all start again
on more solid ground.
Captain, I've got Baltimore.
A Mrs. Granderson is on the line.
Did you say Granderson?
- Yes, sir.
- Well, put her through.
They're trying to use the vidcom,
but so far it can only get audio, sir.
- Go ahead, sir.
- This is Tom Chandler,
commanding officer of
the U.S.S. Nathan James, over.
Captain Chandler.
You have no idea how good it is
to hear your voice.
We thought you were lost at sea.
No, ma'am, we're alive and well.
- Oh! There you are.
- I got it.
You must be nearby. I'm Amy Granderson.
And I suppose an explanation is in order.
As vice-chair of
the President's defense policy board,
I was briefed on your
mission to the Arctic.
I knew the risks of the coming pandemic,
and I had my daughter
transferred to your ship.
You must forgive me.
No apology needed, ma'am.
Your daughter's been an incredible asset.
Pleased to hear from you.
We had no word
from the presidential bunker.
President Geller invited me underground.
I declined. I-I felt the risk was too big
to have so much of our civilian
and military command
in one confined space.
Unfortunately, I was right.
So the government is gone.
For the most part, yes.
Since the bunker went silent,
there has been a breakdown
of infrastructure,
general panic, and, of course,
a tremendous loss of life.
I have tried to execute a contingency plan
working with the state and local police
to create safe zones.
We have been hanging on as best we can.
And I have been praying
every day for your return.
Ma'am, we can be in Baltimore
in the matter of hours.
In the meantime,
I'm sure there is someone
you'd like to speak with.
Mom?
Alisha!
Mom, I don't... I don't understand...
What are you doing? Where are you?
I'm here, darling.
Oh, I knew you were out there.
I just knew it.
- Thorwald.
- [Water splashing]
We've intercepted a transmission.
A U.S. Navy ship is due to make
port in a matter of hours
in Baltimore harbor.
- What kind of ship?
- I don't know, sir.
Well, is it a tug? A destroyer?
A 5,000-sailor aircraft carrier?
The signal was spotty.
All we know is the name.
Nathan James.
It's the ship
they've been hailing for weeks.
Granderson's sending out a greeting party.
Well, if they're having a party...
Then let's party.
Man: We are cleared, Baltimore.
[Speaks indistinctly]
The port distance 1,000 yards.
No threats, no contact.
Man: All commands reporting...
Man: V.B.S.S. on the way
to designated meeting point.
Kara: E.W. reports negative
rackets of interest.
Nothing moving on surface plot.
Clean picture.
Bridge? C.I.C.
A.T.T.W.O. reports S.C.A.T.
team manned and ready
at all crew-served weapon
stations port and starboard.
Jeter: All right, let's move.
- Fan out.
- Aye, sir.
Secure a perimeter.
Dennis and Rowler, left flank.
Cruz, you take right.
Keep your hands on the swivel, fellas.
[Man speaks indistinctly]
Man: Perimeter secure.
Man: Keep eyes on upper structures.
Copy.
Slattery: Here they come.
[Men speaking indistinctly]
Hi! Hey.
I'm Lieutenant Pete Norris
of the Maryland state police.
Inside my vehicles are
my assistant barrack commander,
my criminal section supervisor,
and a few surviving state troopers.
You don't need the masks. We're not sick.
I'm Lieutenant Green,
this is Lieutenant Burk.
It's a pleasure to make your
acquaintance, Lieutenant.
Bridge, Burk. The pier is secure.
- All clear, over.
- [Radio static]
Understand. All clear on the beach.
- Landing party underway.
- [Radio chirps]
- Welcome to Baltimore. [Laughs]
- Hey, it's great to be here.
Looks like the troopers just got themselves
a couple hundred U.S. sailors.
A few dozen tomahawks, too.
Looks like a landing party arriving.
Thorwald: Including the Captain.
You must be Lieutenant Norris.
Tom Chandler, C.O., Nathan James.
Pleasure to meet you.
This is Lieutenant Landau.
Ma'am. Sir.
Hey. How y'all doin'?
Just fine, now that you're here.
We can escort you guys back to our H.Q.
Thorwald: Here comes another van.
Man: Cobra 1 in place.
All clear on the beach.
[Engine turns off, doors close]
Holy shit.
What?
- [Voice breaking]
- Mom?
I had to come see for myself.
Oh, my baby girl.
It's her. It's Granderson.
She came out herself.
I am so glad to have you back.
Captain Chandler, thank you.
Thank you for returning my daughter to me.
Privilege, ma'am.
We wouldn't be here without her.
Take the shot.
Mrs. Granderson,
we really need to get you
back in the vehicle.
She's blocked.
Come. Everyone's eager to meet you.
I can take out the fat man.
No! You only have one shot.
- I want her.
- Danny: Nathan James,
looks like we're having
a bit of a family reunion here.
We're headed out with the group.
Sending Lieutenant Norris back
with the V.B.S.S.
To update you on the situation
on the ground, sir.
Roger that.
We'll arrange a welcome
for Lieutenant Norris.
Oh, and say "hi" to Mom for us.
Damn it!
I lost her.
Talk to your friends on the inside.
Find out what they're doing here.
[Click]
- Man: Let's go!
- [Dog barking in distance]
[Doors close]
We were fortunate to find this building.
There's only one coal-fired
plant still operational,
and we have a direct line.
Plus, strategically we're
far enough from the city
to avoid infection.
You'll be safe here.
Come.
Mom, this is amazing.
Oh, yes, but it's been a battle.
And who's the enemy?
Warlords, they call themselves.
And recently, they've killed
more people than the actual virus.
Do you know they raided
the National Archives?
They actually tried to steal
original copies of the Constitution.
As if that could take away
who we are as a people.
Captain.
I didn't want to broadcast about the virus
over an open radio feed, but...
The President told me
that you had the materials
to produce a vaccine.
Is that true?
Yes, ma'am.
We've actually made a little
more progress than that,
Mrs. Granderson.
[Inhales sharply]
We have the cure.
Fort Detrick was our first option, too.
They had the lab and all, but, uh,
- Thorwald got there first.
- Thorwald.
Former Baltimore P.D. turned
self-proclaimed leader
of the Warlords.
Been a real pain in our ass
since this whole thing started.
I shouldn't complain. [Chuckles]
I imagine you've been through
a hell of a time yourselves.
Listen, Lieutenant,
last I talked to my wife,
she said was taking
the family to Deer Park.
Safe zone. Heard of it.
You know if it's still there?
There was fighting,
but there are survivors.
I can get you there as soon
as we get you off the ship.
- [Click, hiss]
- Ooh! Thanks, Doc.
You have no idea how good that felt.
Well, I have some idea.
- Yeah.
- [Click]
Man: What were the results of the test...
[Speaks indistinctly]
See, these results are consistent...
Now this is the main reason
we chose this building.
[Speaking indistinctly]
We've worked for months
trying to develop a cure.
But now you're here.
[Exhales] It's heavenly.
[Clapping]
- [Door opens]
- You're not gonna like this, boss.
My guy inside Granderson's said
the ship came back with a cure.
It could be bullshit.
We've heard this before.
Not from the U.S. Navy.
If that's true, Granderson will spread out,
go anywhere she wants.
We will lose the city.
We need to get our hands on the cure.
It's probably locked away
somewhere on the ship.
The only way is to take
Granderson on directly.
We have to take her lab.
Rachel: Extraordinary.
- Look at her.
- [Speaks indistinctly]
She's in love with a toaster.
You still haven't made your move yet?
Oh, I've been making my move since Gitmo.
She ain't buying what I'm selling.
I thought once she saved the world,
- she'd let loose a little.
- [Chuckles]
Jeter: Nathan James, this is
Vulture One. Do you copy?
[Lowered voice] This is her letting loose.
I repeat...  Nathan James,
this is Vulture One.
Do you copy? I can't get through, sir.
You won't get a signal here, Master Chief.
The Warlords are jamming
the local frequencies.
They have a radio room, sir.
I let the X.O. know where we are.
Ma'am, uh, if that radio room
is still available,
I'd like to get word to my family,
see if they're still out there.
I think it's time you thought of yourself.
Meanwhile, we can work with your team
to arrange safe transit here
for your ship's crew.
- Due to warlord activity...
- This is Tom Chandler,
listening on a spread spectrum,
looking for Jed Chandler
in Clearwater, Virginia,
- or parts nearby, over.
- Citizens are advised
to avoid these areas until further notice.
This is Tom Chandler, listening
on a spread spectrum,
looking for Jed Chandler
in Clearwater, Virginia,
or parts nearby, over.
And some city services are set to resume.
This is Tom Chandler,
looking for Jed Chandler
in Clearwater, Virginia, over.
[Static]
[Clicks]
This is Tom Chandler,
looking for Jed Chandler
in Clearwater, Virginia, over. [Clicks]
[Sighs deeply]
Howdy.
Tex.
Hey, listen, just wanted to let you know
that I'm heading off.
- Heading off?
- Mm-hmm.
[Huffs] What are you talking about?
I'm moving on.
By yourself?
But it's chaos out there.
I've seen worse.
And thanks to you, I can
travel wherever I like.
Where will you go?
I, uh, got things to take care of.
The young girl whose picture
that you keep in your locket.
Among other things, yeah.
Anyway, you seem to have things
plenty well in hand here.
Right then.
[Chuckles, breathes sharply]
Oh, you're a special woman, you know that?
You take care now.
[Mutters] What the hell.
[Door closes]
[Exhales]
This is Tom Chandler,
looking for Jed Chandler
in Clearwater, Virginia, over.
- [Static crackling]
- [Sighs]
This is Tom Chandler, U.S. Navy,
looking for Jed Chandler
in Clearwater, Virginia, over.
- Tom?
- Dad?
Dad? Are you there?
It's me. It's Tom. I'm back!
- Tom?
- I'm here, Dad.
- Tommy? [Coughing]
- [Sighs]
[Static crackling]
Are you at the cabin?
- We're going to... [Coughs] Baltimore.
- Baltimore?!
Are you with the kids?! Darien?!
[Pants] We're sick.
We had to leave the cabin.
[Coughing] Going to Olympia.
It's our only hope for a cure...
Come quick. We're sick!
Tell me exactly where you are.
What do you see?
- Onyx truck stop.
- Truck stop?
- What happened? Are you on the road?
- Onyx truck stop.
- It's a tire shop downtown.
- We can get you there.
Listen to me. Stay put. I'm coming for you.
Put these jackets on.
You'll blend in better.
We're in and out, gentlemen.
[Tires screeching]
Dad!
Dad?
- Burk: Let's get eyes. 360.
- Darien?
[Men speaking indistinctly]
Dad?!
Darien?!
- Where did you get this radio?
- [Coughs]
- Where did you get this radio?! Answer me!
- It's mine now.
The man you took this radio
from, where did he go?!
Man, everybody's going to the same place...
Where did he go?!
- The arena!
- Where?! What arena?!
- Olympia! [Coughs]
- Olympia.
Come on! Let's go!
- Can't do that, sir.
- What do you mean?
Olympia's off-limits. It's for sick people.
But we're immune. You got the shots, too.
Get back in the car.
We're going back to base.
- We're going to Olympia.
- You don't give the orders, Captain.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Get back in the cars!
- Whoa!
- Drop your weapons!
- Get back in the car!
You don't want to do this, trooper!
We're on the same side!
- Everybody calm down!
- [Gun cocks]
Aah!
Master Chief!
I'm all right! I'm okay.
Nathan James, this is Vulture Two. Come in!
- Damn it, still can't get through!
- [Tires screech]
Take the truck, get the Master Chief
back to the ship.
- And tell the X.O. what's going on!
- What is going on?!
Find a way to get the
others back to the ship.
We're getting out of Baltimore.
- [Engine starts]
- You okay?
What about us?
We're going to Olympia.
You'll inform the others then?
Very good.
- [Hangs up telephone]
- Everything okay?
Yeah. All good.
I want to try and look for Sarah.
I-if you survived, there's a chance
that maybe she's still okay.
Alisha...
Your friend lived in Wisconsin.
There's no way to get there now.
[Pouring coffee]
- Soon, maybe.
- But if we make...
Soon.
Now...
Tell me this...
What kind of man is Captain Chandler?
He's amazing.
Without him, we wouldn't have
gotten through any of this.
So he hasn't the let
the power go to his head?
I'm not sure I understand the question.
I'm asking if he will still follow orders.
Follow orders from whom?
Mother, what's going on?
Michael, have you seen these protocols?
Of course. Why?
Well, Dr. Hamada claims that his treatment
prolongs the lives of the infected.
But his whole assumption about the virus
seems to be wrong.
[Huffs] I'm just a statistician,
but the data he's given me suggests
- the treatment's working.
- No, that's impossible.
- Is something wrong?
- Dr. Hamada,
you're using ribavirin to introduce
higher error rates to
the virus' D.N.A. replication.
In a chemical cocktail, yes.
Yes, but the pandemic virus is error-free.
Your treatment wouldn't have
any positive effect whatsoever.
In fact, these dose levels
are highly toxic.
Um...
[Indistinct chatter over P.A.]
[Turnstiles clacking]
Man: Go through the turnstile
and wait for assessment.
[Indistinct conversations,
chatter over P.A. continues]
[Child crying in distance]
[Indistinct conversations]
Daddy?
- Daddy!
- Ashley!
- Daddy! [Sobbing]
- Oh, my God.
- [Crying]
- Sammy... Sammy...
Daddy... Daddy... We're sick.
I know, baby. I know.
Daddy's gonna make it better, okay?
- [Panting]
- [Crying]
Where's mommy?
- [Panting]
- Tommy...
- Where's your mother?
- [Crying]
[Gasps, whines]
- Tommy...
- Dad, why didn't you wait for me?
- [Crying]
- Sam, a little pinch.
A little pinch. This is
gonna make you feel better.
- Ahh! [Whines]
- Tommy...
Where is she?
Son, I'm sorry.
Dad, where's Darien?!
She's gone, son.
She's gone.
[Crying]
I tried to do everything
I could to save her.
I tried. I tried.
I know you did, Pop. I know you did.
But right now I gotta give you this.
[Gasps]
[Sobbing]
Slattery: You stack the cases
by the hangar door,
we'll put 'em on a pallet
and unload 'em dockside
as soon as we make port.
I'm not sure exactly
when that's gonna be...
Oh, hey, Norris, answer
a question for us if you could.
Yes, sir.
- Hey!
- Whoa! Whoa!
Commander. Commander!
I want you to get on the horn
and give the order to drop anchor.
You muster your entire crew
on the flight deck
and you open up the door to the helo bay
where you're storing the cure.
I'm not giving you a goddamn
thing, you son of a bitch.
I don't know what
your plan is here,
- but this is my ship!
- You'll do exactly what I say,
or I'll pick off your entire
crew one-by-one.
My troopers are everywhere.
This ship is mine now.
- Please, he needs help.
- Hey...
- Call Doc Rios!
- Nobody moves!
- [Shouting indistinctly]
Put down that weapon!
Everyone heard that gunshot.
- They're gonna come running.
- You don't think I'll do it, X.O.?!
- Put down that weapon!
- You think I won't do it, X.O.?
Just try me!
- [Gunshot]
- Ahh!
- No!
- Ahh! Ahh!
Ahh! Ahh!
I'm not gonna tell you again, Commander.
Muster your crew.
- [Exhales]
- [Door opens]
Doctor.
My troopers say they
experienced no side effects
from the cure.
It's amazing what you've created.
I wish I could say the same in return.
I understand you have some questions
about the way we've been treating the sick.
What you are giving the sick
is anything but a treatment...
Of that I am sure.
Doctor...
You know this.
In the 14th century, the Black Death
wiped out 60% of the European population.
The plague killed indiscriminately...
The artists, scientists, thinkers,
so few and precious to begin with,
were wiped out.
It upended the social order
and prolonged the dark ages 150 years.
I cannot let that happen here.
[Breathing erratically]
Granderson: I understand
your allegiance to your friends.
You've gone through so much together.
But you've seen nothing
of the chaos here at home.
The hysteria,
the cruelty, the savagery.
You must try to see the situation
from our point of view.
There are people out there
who would use this crisis
to take what does not belong to them.
They are the barbarians at the gate
who would send us into a new dark age.
We have the power to stop them,
to keep them in their place.
It is my duty
to help the right people first,
the people whose survival will ensure
the future of our entire society...
And all that we hold dear.
So you gather your elite few
within these walls.
And the rest...
What happens to them?
The virus doesn't discriminate.
That unfortunate task falls to me.
[Indistinct chatter over P.A.]
[Man coughs in distance]
[Clicks]
Pl... [Breathing erratically]
Plea... plea...
Please...
[Whimpering]
[Gasping]
Hey, what are you doing? You can't be here!
You're killing them.
Get the hell back behind the curtain!
- You're killing them!
- Stay back!
- You sick bastards!
- Man: Hey, you can't be here!
[Gunfire]
Captain, we gotta move!
Man: Security breach in section 12.
Repeat... security breach in section 12.
[Truck engine revving]
I don't... I don't... I don't get it.
They're burning 'em.
They're burning the bodies
to power the city.
- [Clicks]
- I know it's hard to understand.
You've been away so long.
But in time, Rachel,
you'll see it's the only way.
She was trying to run.
Dr. Scott, I swear I had
no idea this was happening.
- I swear...
- Hush, dear.
You can't replicate my work
with the doses that I've given you.
Everything that you need
is locked up on that ship.
And the Captain will never give it up.
You let me worry about the Captain.
Daddy...
We have to go.
- [Radio static]
- Nathan James, come in. Do you read me?
[Radio static crackling]
Nathan James, come in. Do you read me?
Nathan James, this is the Captain.
Come in. Do you read me?
[Whirring]
Chandler: Nathan James, come in.
Do you read me?
Nathan James, this is the Captain.
Come in. Do you read me?
Nathan James, where are you?