[ Man Narrating ]
Prevlously on The Bible .
[ Man ]
In the beginning...
God created the heavens
and the earth.
Adam and Eve disobeyed God
and ate the forbldden frult.
Since then,
since Cain killed Abel...
God has seen too much evi
in human hearts.
God warned me.
He told me to build a boat.
[ Male Voice ]
Abraham.
God has spoken to me.
He will lead us
to a new home.
He has promised descendants
as numerous as the stars.
- You will have a chil
- I can't.
It's too late for me.
Abraham, there just isn't enough land.
There are too many of us.
It's time we go
our separate ways.
- What happened?
- There were so many of them.
- And Lot?
- Alive. But taken prisoner.
[ Abraham ] How can I lead a people
when I can't even lead my own family ?
Trust in God!
Abraham,
we're carrying on to Sodom.
You're going to destroy it.
The whole city?
[ Abraham ] Will you destroy
the good men along wlth the evil ones?
Abraham, where is your wife?
[ Male Voice ] Though she is barren,
Sarah will have a son.
You will hame him Isaac.
[ Abraham ]
God wants a sacrlfice.
Have I not shown you
enough faith?
[ Male Voice ]
Abraham!
[ Bleating ]
[ Abraham Sobbing ]
[ Narrator ]
Nearly 400 years after Abraham...
famine has forced the Israelites
from the promised land to Egypt.
Here they've been
enslaved by Pharaoh.
Abraham and God have
become a distant memory.
- [ Man Shouts ]
- [ Whip Cracks ]
All his people reduced
to beasts of burden...
except one.
[ Woman ]
Moses.
- You're not going to fight again.
- I can't refuse.
He's Pharaoh's son,
Mother.
The fighting between them
has to stop.
Moses doesn't want to fight.
It's your son who forces him
into it and keeps losing.
[ Chuckles ]
You may be
my sister's favorite...
but I will be pharaoh.
I will be god!
[ Shouts ]
- Please.
- Fight me! I order you!
[ Grunting, Shouting ]
[ Pharaoh ]
Moses.
Enough!
Ahh!
[ Groans ]
-He needs to learn his place.
-You were the one that started-
I will be pharaoh!
Then you better start
behaving like one.
This is your faul
You should never have let her keep him.
[ Pharaoh ]
Silence.
You're not one of us.
- [ Pharaoh ] Silence, I said!
- What's he talking about?
[ Whimpering ]
You'd better tell him now.
You!
Come with me!
Mother, tell me what?
What?
Moses, I love you
like a son.
But you're not my blood.
You were born a slave.
Take them all !
- [ People Shouting ]
- [ Baby Crying ]
[ Mother ]
Father killed so many children.
[ Crying ]
[ Mother ]
He feared a rebelllon.
Your people were too many.
My... people ?
I saved you.
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Shushing Softl ]
Your people are out there,
Moses.
[ Mother ]
Our slaves.
The Israelites.
[ Groans ]
You had a brother-Aaron.
And a sister- Mirlam.
But they are not like us.
- Come on! You! Move along!
- [ Cries ]
Come on!
You'll get more!
They worshlp
the God of A braham.
And he has deserted them.
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Grunting ]
[ Groaning, Screaming ]
- Get up!
- [ Groans ] Stop.
[ Egyptian ]
Israelite scum!
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Groans ]
No, please!
Please, I beg of you!
[ Groaning Continues ]
- Dog!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Yells ]
[ Man ]
Run. Run.
I will hide the body.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
My lord,
the amulet of Moses.
- Shall we hunt him down?
- No.
Let him go.
He's no threat now.
Welcome to
your new life, Moses!
You are nothing now!
Nothing.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Spits, Grunts ]
[ Yells ]
[ Mother ]
Your people are out there, Moses.
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Ramses ] You're not one of us.
[ Mother ]
They worshlp the God of A braham.
[ Ramses ]
You should never have let her keep him .
[ Mother ]
And he has deserted them.
[ Ramses ]
I will be pharaoh!
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Weather Calms ]
[ Flame Bursts ]
[ Male Voice ]
Moses.
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Male Voice ]
Moses.
[ Ragged Breathing ]
I am here.
I am the God of A braham,
of Isaac and Jacob.
- You are real
-I am.
I have seen the misery
of my people .
I am sending you to Pharaoh
to bring them out of Egypt.
But how can I set them free?
I'm not a prince now.
I'm nothing.
I will be wlth you.
[ Panting ]
With your power...
I will set my people free.
[ Narrator ] In Egypt,
there is a new man on the throne.
Moses'old rivaI
is now Pharaoh.
Thank you, Father.
One day you will have
an army of them. ReaI ones.
[ Men Chattering,
Shouting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Grunting, Gasping ]
- [ Man ] Come on!
- [ Man #2 ] Come on!
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Moses ]
Nothing has changed.
- So much suffering.
- [ Man Groaning ] Please!
[ Whip Cracking ]
Hey, you! Hey, you!
[ Groans ]
Back to work!
Go on! Move it!
[ Groans ]
Wait. Wait.
Please.
I'll take care of him,
master.
[ Whip Cracking ]
What are you doing?
Trying to get us all a beating?
Who are you?
- What are you doing here?
- My name is Moses.
[ Chuckles ]
Moses.
You are Moses?
I need to see your elders.
Come with me.
[ Chattering ]
This man says
he's Moses.
[ Man ]
The runaway prince.
You're wanted for murder.
If you're who you say you are,
why would you return?
God has sent me.
I am here...
to set you free.
[ Chuckles ]
God has sent you.
Yes. God...
sent me to speak to you.
Have you forgotten God?
Even if you have...
he has not forgotten you.
In case you had forgotten...
Pharaoh is the onl god
we have to fear.
And you think he's just
going to let us go?
Who created the earth...
the sea...
the sky?
Who created you?
Pharaoh...
or God?
- You're demented.
- [ Man ] No.
He isn't.
[ Exhales ]
He's my brother.
Aaron.
Moses!
[ Laughs ]
God sent me a dream...
to say you would return.
This is Miriam,
your sister.
Brother.
My children.
[ Moses ]
My famil .
My people .
Our people .
- God's people !
Old P haraoh may have
been fond of you...
but it's his son you'll
have to deaI with now.
Why would P haraoh
even see you?
Oh.
He'll want to see me.
You have a son?
An heir.
Our dynasty
will last forever.
Why are you here, Moses?
Have you come to ask
for forgiveness?
No.
God saved me
for a purpose.
Yes?
I come to demand that
you release his people from slavery.
Demand?
Let my people go.
[ Chuckles ]
You always were a fighter,
Moses.
But you never knew
when you were beaten.
If you defy God...
you will be punished.
You return after all these years
to threaten me?
Tell me. Is it your invisible God
that's going to punish me?
The one who abandons
his people ?
The one who runs
from his responsibilities?
From his past?
From his famil ?
- Teach them who God is.
- [ Groans ]
I am God.
I am God!
Moses.
You've made Pharaoh angry.
He will punish us. Don't make it worse.
God has spoken to me.
He will force Pharaoh to free us.
If he has to.
- What should we do?
- Sister, Brother...
all of you...
trust in God.
Pharaoh is over there.
If he didn't listen to you when you were
six feet away, why would he hear you now?
You will see.
[ Whispering ]
Put your staff to the water.
[ Gasps ]
Come, master!
Come out of the water!
It's blood!
[ Shouting ]
It's blood everywhere!
- [ All Shouting ]
- The whole river!
- Master!
- [ Whimpering ]
[ Shouting Continues
In Distance ]
You are not a god.
You are just a man.
And you will
set my people free.
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Growls ]
Move away!
Master.
Moses!
[ Laughs ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Miriam Laughs ]
Do you doubt, Joshua?
All my life,
I have been Pharaoh's.
I will never be a slave again.
God is with us.
- [ Croaking ]
- [ Moses ] This is just the beginning.
Our Lord is sending 1 0 plagues
to change Pharaoh's mind.
Let my people go.
No!
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Buzzing ]
Locusts.
- [ Woman ] Come away! Master!
- [ Man Shouts ]
No!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ People Chattering ]
[ All Chattering ]
Moses, what is Pharaoh's answer?
Surel he will see sense now.
No.
- He refuses.
- Again?
Give up, Moses,
before it's too late.
God will keep on doing this
untiI Pharaoh breaks.
What's wrong?
Soon there will be
a finaI plague.
The AngeI of Death is coming.
Every firstborn son will die.
No.
But not us.
Why would he punish us?
Death is coming for us all .
- [ People Gasping ]
- [ Man ] No!
[ People Muttering ]
Why us?
[ Chattering, Exclaiming ]
Friends!
We can be spared
God's vengeance...
but onl if we do
exactl as he tells us.
- [ All Chattering ]
- [ Bleats ]
Don't spill .
Every single house
must be marked with blood.
[ Narrator ] The Israelites paint
lamb's blood on their doorways...
ldentifying them
as God's people .
God will
watch over us.
We promised God woul
free our people .
But now he sends us death.
We must trust in him.
[ Joshua ]
It's coming.
- [ Boy ] Will we be safe?
- Don't be afraid, my son.
- [ Boy ] Father, I'm -
- God have mercy.
[ Joshua ]
Pharaoh has not listened.
Whatever happens to his people
is now on his head.
Once I counted them
as my people , Joshua.
Our freedom
comes at a price.
[ Wind Rushing ]
[ Narrator ]
The Angel of Death...
finds every Israelite house
painted wlth blood...
and passes over.
[ Moans ]
[ Panting ]
[ Ramses ]
Why?
Why should Israelite slaves
have life...
when my son is dead?
Get up.
Go! And leave my land!
And take your wretched God
with you!
[ Sobs ]
Pack up.
Get ready.
Come on.
Good.
[ Aaron ]
Moses!
- [ Miriam ] Moses! Moses!
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- [ Cheering Continues ]
- You won!
[ Shouts ]
[ Man Shouts ]
Moses!
They did it!
[ Cheering Continues ]
We are going to fulfill
Abraham's covenant with God.
We're going to live
in the promised land...
with descendants as
numerous as the stars.
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Man Chanting, Low ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
My son.
How could slaves do this?
I vow to you,
here and now...
that I will bring
the Israelites back...
and make them build you the greatest tomb
the world has ever seen.
Moses' body...
shall be buried
in its foundations.
I still can't believe
Pharaoh just let us leave.
- But he did.
-It's what God demanded.
Onl a madman would defy God
again after what he's done.
[ Aaron ]
Brother, what now?
Brother?
God will provide a way.
Moses, why have you
brought us here?
God brought us here.
And what does God say
about getting across?
- [ Men Shouting ]
- [ Hoofbeats Galloping ]
[ Man ]
Egyptians. On the hill .
[ Soldiers Shouting ]
Where is your God now,
Moses?
We have them!
They're trapped!
There!
Moses!
Chariots!
They're here.
The Egyptians.
[ Clamoring, Screaming ]
Fool! What do we do now?
Was it because there were no graves
in Egypt that you brought us here to die?
Because that is
what you've done.
[ Man ] They're coming!
What do we do? Where shall we go?
[ Man ]
Well ?
Moses.
[ Driver Shouting ]
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
[ Man ]
Get everything into the carts!
[ Woman ]
My children!
[ People Shouting ]
Moses! Moses! Moses!
Wait!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Lord, I cannot believe
this is the end you planned for us.
[ Shouting ]
[ Wind Howling ]
We have watched you
bring terror on our enemies.
There!
You kept death
from our door.
[ People Shouting ]
Moses! Moses! Moses!
[ Soldiers Shouting ]
Lord!
[ Water Roaring ]
[ All Muttering ]
God is with us!
Follow me!
[ Shouts ]
- God is with us!
- We're gonna go straight through there.
Get your men together!
- Hurry! Hurry!
- We have to leave now!
Light torches! Quickl !
[ Crowd Shouting ]
[ Man ]
Let's go! Move it! Let's go!
Quickl ! Hurry!
Come on!
[ Moses ]
Have faith!
Come on!
Keep moving!
Hurry!
[ Groaning ]
[ Joshua ]
Don't be afraid! Have faith!
Come on!
Keep going!
Wait!
After them!
[ Shouting ]
Now!
Bring me Moses!
Run!
- [ Woman ] Moses!
- Come on!
Keep moving!
Hurry!
[ Soldiers Shouting ]
I see their torches!
Come on!
Keep moving!
[ Shouting ]
[ Woman Screams ]
On!
[ Shouting ]
[ Moses ]
They're coming.
They're coming!
Hurry!
[ Shouting ]
Run!
Hurry!
We're there!
Come on!
Come on, old man!
[ Shouting ]
[ People Shouting,
Chattering ]
Hurry!
We're here!
They're still coming!
There!
Up there!
[ Soldier ]
We've got them!
You are not a god, Pharaoh.
[ Moses ]
There is onl one God.
And he is here...
with us.
[ Mouthing Word ]
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
No!
Moses.
Moses!
[ Laughing ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Freedom!
[ Crowd Exclaiming,
Chattering ]
[ Boy Laughing ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing, Shouting ]
[ Crowd Chattering, Cheering ]
My friends!
My... people .
God has delivered us
from slavery.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
We are free.
You have come a long way,
I know.
But our journey
is just beginning.
We must trust in God.
We must follow his path.
[ Narrator ] Moses leads the Israelites
to Mount Sinal...
where God first spoke to him
in the burning bush.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Narrator ]
God gives laws to Moses...
wrltten in stone.
The Ten Commandments.
Joshua.
God has...
[ Panting ]
renewed the promise
he made to Abraham.
We have new laws
preparing us for the promised land.
If we are true to God,
he will keep his promise.
Abraham's dream.
Our future.
You are our people 's future, Joshua.
You must take the land
promised to Abraham...
and all of his descendants...
as numerous as the stars.
[ Narrator ]
Next time on The Bible .
[ Joshua ]
The Lord brought us out from Egypt.
He promised us this land.
Soon, it will be ours.
We must take Jericho.
Just find me a way in .
Joshua!
The people melt in fear
because they know he is with us.
God is with us.
[ Angel
The Lord parted the waters for Moses.
For you, he will split rock.
[ Cheering ]
Jericho is ours!
[ Shouting ]
[ Joshua ]
If we obey the Lord...
anything is possible !
Israel!
Israel! Israel!
God will give you a son.
Your strength
comes from God.
Samson...
your duty is to drive
the Philistines away.
[ Samson ]
What would you have me do?
Reject the woman I fell in love wlth
just because she's a Philistine?
We need to send these Israelites
a message. They cannot take our women.
[ Screaming ]
For my wife.
[ Neck Snaps ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Screaming ]
-[ Samson Shouts ]
-[ Woman Gasps ]
What is your name?
My name is Delilah.
Why are you so strong?
[ Shouts ]
[ Samson ]
God is wlth me, Delilah.
He makes me strong.
If I cut my hair...
my God will take away
all my strength.
What have you done!
[ Man ]
Everyone has their price.
Your God has deserted you...
and taken your strength
wlth him .
No. He wants me
to destroy you all !
^^ [ Woman Vocalizing ]