^^ [ Woman Vocalizing ]
[ Man Narrating ]
Prevlously on The Bible .
[ Explosion ]
In the beginning...
God created heaven and earth.
Then human failings led him
to destroy his creatlon.
Wrong choices, wrong decisions.
After Noah, a new beginning...
and a promise for Abraham.
God has spoken to me.
[ Abraham ]
He will lead us to a new home.
He has promised descendants
as numerous as the stars.
[ Narrator ] But enslaved by Egypt,
Abraham's descendants suffered-
[ Men Groaning, Screaming ]
until a new leader emerged...
who would become Israells greatest hero.
- [ Groans ]
- Who are you?
My name is Moses.
God has sent me... to set you free.
Freedom? They're free to choose-
slavery or death!
[ Man ]
All my life, I have been Pharaoh's.
I will never be a slave again.
Joshua, God is with us.
- Ride!
- [ Wind Howling ]
Lord!
Follow me!
[ Shouting ]
[ Moses ]
God has delivered us from slavery.
We're going to live in the promised land.
[ Joshua ]
Abraham's dream is our future.
You are our future now, Joshua.
You must take the land
promised to Abraham.
[ Narrator ]
Moses has led the Israelites...
to the edge of the promised land.
Under Joshua, they must conquer lt.
[ People Chattering ]
[ Joshua ]
Lord, I was with Moses...
when he handed down these commandments.
I was witness to the covenant...
the promise of a hol nation.
Help me to forge that nation...
to lead your people to inherit their land.
[ Man ]
Joshua!
- The Lord brought us out from Egypt.
- [ Men ] Right!
He promised us this land.
That's right!
And soon...
it will be ours.
[ Men Exclaiming ]
Come.
- Are you ready?
- We'll search the whole city.
Just find me a way in.
We must take Jericho.
It's all that stands between us
and the promised land.
[ Clanks ]
[ Dogs Barking In Distance ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Man ] Hey. Hey!
You can onl collect water in daylight.
Go home now. Go. Go.
Stay indoors.
The Israelites can attack at any time.
Rahab, my little whore.
[ Grunts ]
What are you doing out, hmm?
You know it's not safe.
Safe enough.
- [ Grunts ]
- No one is safe.
I can look after myself .
[ Groaning ]
[ Exhales, Kisses ]
Go home.
[ Laughing ]
Shh.
What are you doing here? Israelites!
Go. Go.
Israelites! Help !
[ Man ]
Israelites!
[ Panting ]
Brother.
For Israel!
For Israel
[ Men Groaning, Screaming ]
[ Man Shouts ]
Quick.
Over here! Get more men!
[ Whispering ]
We've got to get inside. Look out.
[ Door Clatters ]
[ Man ]
They must not escape.
Go door to door.
In here.
[ Man ]
Everyone, return to your homes.
[ Man Shouts, Muffled ]
- [ Whimpers ]
- [ Rahab ] Hello?
[ Man Shouting Outside ]
- [ Muffled Whimpering ]
- Shh.
Keep quiet,
and I promise I won't hurt him.
Swear.
Mmm.
- You're Israelites.
- You've heard about us?
You have a god who commands the winds
and parts the seas.
He saved us from slavery.
We are his chosen.
This whole city is terrified of you.
How can we fight a people
whose god can do that?
- [ Pounding On Door ]
- [ Man ] Open up! Open up!
- Back inside.
- Open the door!
- [ Pounding Continues ]
- [ Women Screaming ]
Can we get out that way?
Help us, and we will help you.
Go.
I'll stall them if I can.
[ Man ]
Open the door!
Come with us.
I can't. My famil .
When our army comes,
hang this on your door...
so they will know not to harm you.
You'll be passed over.
[ Pounding Continues ]
Stay here.
[ Grunts ]
Joshua!
Tell me, did you find a way in?
Is there a weakness?
Not in the walls-
[ Panting ]
but... in their hearts.
Joshua, we met a woman.
She thinks God has taken the city already.
The people melt in fear
because they know he is with us.
God is with us.
But we've still to find a way in.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Moses...
my old friend...
what would you do?
[ Wind Rushes ]
[ Sharp Inhale ]
Lord, when I was a slave...
you showed me your love and your power.
You have given me new life.
Would you have us turn back?
Who-
Who are you?
I pray you are with us...
and not with our enemies.
I am with God.
Commander of the Lord's army.
What does he ask of us?
The Lord parted the waters for Moses.
For you-
[ Rumbling, Crackling ]
he will split rock.
This is what you must do.
March around the clty once a day
wlth all the armed men.
Do this for six days.
Carry the Ark wlth you.
It contains God's commandments,
and he is wlth you.
Then, on the seventh day...
march around the city seven times.
Then the prlests should make a long blast
wlth a ram's horn.
As soon as you hear
the sound of the trumpet-
^^ [ Deep Tone ]
all the people shall shout a great shout.
[ Israelites Shouting ]
[ Thunderclap ]
- [ Shouting Continues ]
- ^^ [ Horn Continues ]
[ Screams ]
It's happening!
[ Angel
Glory will come.
- [ People Screaming ]
- [ Deep Rumbling ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Explosions ]
He trul is the shaper of the world
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Israelites Continue Shouting ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Wailing ]
We give this city to the Lord!
Jericho is ours!
[ All Shouting ]
Onl Rahab the prostitute
and her famil may be spared...
for God said she must be spared...
-for the help she gave us.
- ...for the help she gave us.
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Man Groans ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Groans ]
[ Men Shouting In Distance ]
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Shouting, Screaming Continue ]
God...
has kept his promise.
If we obey the Lord...
- anything is possible !
- [ Cheering ]
[ Chanting With Crowd ]
Israel! Israel!
Israel Israel
[ Chanting Fades ]
[ Sheep Bleating ]
[ Narrator ]
A hundred years after Joshua...
the 1 2 tribes of IsraeI
have spread out across the promised land.
Hyah!
But hostile neighbors surround them.
Hyah! Hyah!
Better armed and better trained...
the Philistines are the deadliest threat.
[ Woman Screams ]
Wlthout great leaders like Moses
or Joshua to unlte them...
the Israelites must rely
on local heroes called judges-
people like Samson.
- [ Shouts ]
- [ Horse Whinnies ]
Mother, come.
[ Shouting ]
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Whinnying ]
[ Crowd Shouting, Screaming ]
[ Panting ]
When will this all stop?
I don't know.
You must fight them.
It's what God wants you to do, Samson.
It's why God created you.
Remember what his messenger told me.
- [ Gasps ]
- Don't be afraid.
Though you are barren,
God will give you a son.
[ Sharp Inhale ]
[ Stammers ]
Thank you.
Listen carefully.
There are conditions.
See to it that you drink no alcohol ..
and eat nothing unclean.
And when your son is born...
his hair must never be cut.
This will be the sign
that the boy is a Nazarite.
He is given to God-
from his birth to his death.
He will begin to deliver IsraeI
from the Philistines.
Your strength comes from God.
Your duty is to drive
the Philistines away.
- ^^ [ Drums Beating ]
- [ Cheering ]
[ Narrator ]
Instead of fighting the Philistines...
Samson falls in love... and marrles one.
[ Samson Laughing ]
- Let me talk to her.
- Of course.
Mmm.
Mother...
does love not come from God?
What would you have me do-
reject the woman I fell in love with...
just because she's a Philistine?
Will your love protect us from them?
[ Guests ] Samson! Samson! Samson!
Samson! Samson! Samson!
[ Chanting Continues ]
We need to send
these Israelites a message...
make it clear to them
they cannot take our women.
[ Samson Laughing ]
Our people should never mix.
[ Man #2 ]
How are we going to get to him?
We're not going to get... to him.
- [ Pounding On Door ]
- [ Man ] Open up!
- Where is Samson?
-I-I don't know.
- [ Shouting ] Where is he?
- He's not here.
[ Woman ]
Father! Father! No!
- [ Shouting ]
- Father! No!
No!
- Do it.
- Please, no.
You are a disgrace to our people .
- Oh, please. Please.
- [ Man ] Please, I beg you!
- [ Shouting ]
- Don't hurt her.
- [ Groans ]
- Father! No!
[ Sobbing ]
No. No.
[ Gasps ]
No. No!
Please.
Please, I'm begging you no.
Please, no.
[ Screaming ]
No!
No! No!
[ Echoing ]
No!
For my wife.
[ Neck Snaps ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Shouts, Groans ]
[ Grunting, Groaning ]
Philistines!
- [ Men Shouting ]
- [ Roars ]
- Over here!
- Help us.
[ Shouting Continues ]
Help us!
- Free us. Free us!
- [ Roaring ]
[ Man ]
Stop the Israelite!
- [ Grunting, Groaning ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Man Shouts ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Exhales ]
One man did this.
Where is he? His people must know.
You!
You will bring Samson to me...
and you will do it quickl .
And for every day I do not see him,
one of you will die-
starting now.
[ Man ]
No, no. No, no, please.
Please, no!
- [ Crowd Gasps ]
- [ Woman Screams ]
[ Man ]
Samson!
[ Mother ]
Samson.
[ Birds Calling ]
[ Man ]
Samson?
Samson.
Are you there?
[ Samson ]
Mother.
I wasn't expecting you. Forgive me.
- We have come to reason with you, Samson.
- Reason?
You must stop the killing.
Please.
For every Philistine you kill ...
two more appear, seeking revenge.
As they did to me, so I have done to them.
The Philistines are our rulers now.
Everyone must do what they think is right.
No, Samson.
You must do what is right for your people .
For God.
Not for yourself .
You must give yourself up, Samson.
Mother, is this what God wants?
[ Exhales ]
I'm not sure.
Sometimes God leads us
in ways we cannot see.
God will guide your choices.
[ Mother Whimpers ]
Come.
[ Man ]
Stand aside.
[ Man #2 ]
Stand back.
Get back.
Stay back.
You have your prize.
All I see is a common murderer.
No worse than you.
[ Wind Whistling ]
Why did you kill my wife?
[ Chuckles ]
To teach you...
and your people a lesson.
I gave myself up to save my people .
Will you leave them alone now?
If I had more men, I'd drive you all ...
back into the wilderness where you belong.
I'd happil kill all of you.
Kill him.
[ Mother's Voice ]
Your duty is to drive the Philistines away.
God will gulde your choices.
[ Wind Rushing ]
My Lord God of Israel, is that you?
[ Grunts ]
[ Crowd Clamoring ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting, Groaning ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Roaring Continues ]
Lord...
is this what you want from me?
Guide me, please.
- [ Snarls ]
- [ Gasps ]
Come.
Come!
[ Panting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Dogs Barking In Distance ]
Thank you.
What is your name?
My name is Delilah.
Dagon...
god and creator, lord of our land...
deliver into our hands...
our enemy, Samson...
destroyer of our nation.
We have news of Samson.
He's got a new woman.
A Philistine woman.
Another one?
What's her name?
Delilah.
I know her.
Bring her to me.
[ Man Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
Delilah...
thank you for coming.
[ Man Cackling ]
As beguiling as ever.
What do you want?
Well , let's just have a little talk -
about Samson.
An interesting choice.
Not one of us, of course.
Why are you with him?
Why do you want to know?
Don't tell me you care about him.
Is he in love with you?
Ask him yourself .
He's butchered hundreds of our people .
He's changed.
He's a different man since he's met me.
You really believe that?
He will go on killing
untiI we find a way to stop him for good.
Where does he get his strength?
What's his secret?
I don't know. He won't tell me.
Try to convince him.
Have you seen what he's capable of?
Maybe this will help .
- [ Coins Jingle ]
- Call it danger money.
It's all for you.
Uh-uh. Not now.
Not untiI we know his secret.
Why are you so strong?
God is with me, Delilah.
He makes me strong.
[ Whispering ]
What do you mean...
God is with you?
How does he make you strong?
My mother was barren.
God brought her a child- me.
But there are things I must not do.
Such as?
I have never cut my hair.
I am forbidden.
A sign of my devotion.
If I cut my hair, I
What, my love?
What if you cut your hair?
My God will take away all my strength.
I will be as weak as everyone else.
You don't believe me?
No, Samson...
I do.
[ Sighs ]
[ Kisses ]
[ Door Opens ]
Samson!
Wha- Huh?
- Take him.
- [ Samson Grunts ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
What-
Wha- What have you done?
[ Men Laughing ]
[ Hinges Squeak ]
[ Coins Jingling ]
Don't feeI bad.
Everyone has their price.
Delilah.
Take a good look...
and remember the day
you first met the lovel Delilah.
You will never see her again.
- [ Delilah Gasps, Whimpers ]
- [ Samson Screams ]
- [ Samson Whimpers ]
- [ Cries ]
Take him away.
- [ Crowd Shouting, Jeering ]
- Move. Move!
Quickl .
Bring him through.
[ Shouting, Jeering Continue ]
[ Man Laughing ]
Blind Israelite!
[ Crowd Clamoring, Jeering ]
I am weak.
Stand me against something.
Lord-
Quiet!
Lord...
if I am yours, remember me now.
Strengthen me once more.
Your god has abandoned you, Samson.
You are the man who took away my eyes.
[ Exhales ]
I am glad of it...
for the darkness helps me think.
Your god has deserted you...
and taken your strength with him.
No.
I can see him more clearl than ever.
He wants me to destroy you all !
- [ Crowd Laughs ]
- [ Grunts, Roars ]
It's over, Samson.
[ Roaring ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Pillars Rumbling ]
Stop him!
- Kill him!
- [ Roars ]
- Now!
- [ Roaring ]
[ Screams ]
[ Rumbling Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Crowd Clamoring ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
^^ [ Singing Lament ]
[ Sobs ]
^^ [ Continues ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Narrator ]
Samson's sacrlfice kills thousands...
but he could never defeat
the Philistines on his own.
The prophet Samuel has urged the people
to unlte in God's name.
There is no one like the Lord.
But after decades of struggle ...
he, too, has failed
to halt the Philistines.
[ Man ]
Prophet, we await you.
And the people 's patlence is wearing thin .
[ Chattering ]
- [ Men Fall Silent ]
- [ Man Coughs ]
So what is it that troubles you?
We are grateful, prophet.
You have led us for many years.
God has led us.
Samuel ..
you are not as young as you were.
We are worried.
Who will speak to the Lord after you?
Who will lead us against the Philistines?
My sons will inherit my place.
Your sons are corrupt.
My sons have been brought up
to trust in God and obey his laws.
Everything I have done for you
I have done because I walk in God's ways.
We know that they take bribes.
Everyone knows it.
They shame your good name.
So...
when you are gone...
and the Philistines return...
and we look to your sons to call on God...
will God answer?
No. He will not.
Then what do you want?
A king.
As other nations have.
But look what other nations' kings do.
They become tyrants.
They make slaves of their people .
Not if they are chosen by God...
anointed by his righteous prophet-
by you.
You would reject our God?
God promised us this land.
This is God's kingdom.
He is our onl king.
You have the ear of the Lord, Samuel
You must ask him to choose a king for us.
Leave me alone. All of you.
[ SamueI ]
I have given everything.
Now they have rejected me...
and you, God.
But if you say
I should give them a king...
then of course I will .
But who should it be?
[ Wind Rushing ]
[ Whinnying ]
I see...
that could never be me.
But I will still be your prophet.
I can guide your king.
[ Crowd Shouting ]
Saul! Saul! Saul!
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Chanting ]
Saul! Saul! Saul!
[ Chanting Continues ]
Saul
May you reign justl and wisel ...
and according to God's law.
I anoint you the first king of Israel
May I, as God's prophet...
help you in any way I can.
[ Narrator ] A new era
in Israelite history is beginning-
- [ Chanting ] Saul! Saul!
- the perlod of prophets and kings.
They must work together
to secure the promised land.
[ Crowd Chanting ]
Saul! Saul! Saul!
Next time on The Bible .
- [ Horse Whinnies ]
- [ SauI ] Are the men ready?
They're ready.
We must make a sacrifice before we attack.
[ SamueI ]
May God forgive you!
Be a king. Leave the job of priest to me.
You are our prophet, but I am your king!
What the Lord gives, he can take away.
God is with me!
Are you with him, Lord, really?
You disobeyed the Lord.
He has torn your kingdom from you
and given lt to Davld .
When you have my crown, will you not
kill my descendants, bury my name?
[ David ]
Jerusalem, our new home.
[ Men Shouting ]
[ Man ]
A king is never above his god.
You abused your power.
You took everything
from your most loyal servant.
You took his wife, then you took his life.
You think God doesn't see everything?
I am his chosen one.
Davld , he will bring disaster
on your house.
We shall see.
^^ [ Woman Vocalizing ]