( Clock ticking )
Man's voice: Scenario 37...
agent-to-agent transfer.
( chatter )
Pharaoh, please.
I don't know which is colder,
the wind or the winter.
And weary winter comin' fast
and cozy here
beneath the blast.
( laughing )
You there.
What's the price
for one of those?
I'm afraid these
are not for sale.
Agreement with the commissary.
Oi, you turn your back on me?
It's one measly egg.
And I've the balsam to pay.
So how's about you
quit acting a lout
'fore I shove one of these
bumnuts down your throat?
( Grunts )
( eggs crack )
Oh, look at what you done now.
Hey, what's this?
( Grunting )
( gunshot )
Mm.
Traitor. Traitor.
I killed the traitor.
( Coughing )
Try, try again.
♪ Hush, hush
♪ There's snakes
in the garden ♪
♪ Soul for sale
♪ Blood on the rise
♪ Hush, hush
- ♪ I can't wait anymore
- ♪ Soul for sale
♪ I can't wait anymore
♪ Hush, hush...
Soldier: Shoulder firelocks!
Soldier ♪2: The prisoner exchange was
carried through this morning, Excellency.
Washington: And what is the
condition of our returned?
Very poor, sir.
Some are unable to walk
owing to starvation.
It confirms
Captain Gamble's account...
the enemy treat
our captured with brutality
while we protect theirs
according to protocol.
"To Lord Howe."
I am sorry
to trouble Your Lordship
with a letter
almost wholly on the subject
of the barbaric treatment
our officers received
"on board your prison ship
in New York Harbor."
Prepare a copy of
Captain Gamble's account.
- I want it enclosed.
- Yes, sir.
"I call upon
Your Lordship to say"
if our treatment of your men
"had merited so severe
a retaliation..."
Absent without leave, falsifying
intelligence, insubordination...
I want you to know, Captain, I plan
to leave nothing out of my report.
I wouldn't expect you to, sir.
Though you should know, I already
told the commander everything I did.
Well, then likely your
punishment's been decided
and we've merely been called
here to see it carried out.
( Bell tolling )
The accused, John Herring,
having been convicted
of breaking into the house
of Mr. Prince Howland
and robbing him
of several spoons,
silver dollars,
and wearing apparel,
has been sentenced
to suffer death.
His Excellency,
the commander in chief,
approves this sentence
as an example made
to deter the boldest and
most hardened offenders.
- ( choking )
- ( rope creaking )
( choking continues )
Shall we?
( Rope creaking )
This is Mr. Nathaniel Sackett
of the Committee
to Detect and Defeat
Conspiracies against America.
Sir, the presence of a civilian at
court-martial is highly irregular.
Yes, I agree, Charles.
Now, would you be so kind
as to brief the room
on the intelligence
uncovered at Trenton?
- Brief the room?
- Myself included.
Ahem.
An examination of orders
discovered in the desk
of Colonel Rall
suggests that the garrison
we took from the Hessians
was much more
than a winter camp.
Trenton was being prepared
as a launch point
for an attack on Philadelphia.
I know what Howe wants.
But how will Howe take it?
By land...
by sea...
or will he lunge north
to join forces with Burgoyne
so as to decapitate New England
from the rest of our colonies?
We have until the snow melts
before their forces
in New York begin to move.
New York.
Which remains dark to us.
Sir, I have just dispatched new
scouts to observe the enemy.
I grow weary
of contradictory accounts
that merely guess at
the intent of the enemy.
This letter written by
your man on Long Island...
That letter was not received
through the proper channels.
Which is why I paid it no mind.
It was a lone report
and unconfirmed
until our victories at Trenton and
Princeton proved it accurate.
More accurate than any
piece of intelligence
we've received
thus far, at least.
Gentlemen, I've asked
you here today
to determine
if this was a fluke
and, perhaps more importantly,
if this fluke can be repeated.
( grunting )
Mornin'.
What's your business
in New York?
Feeding your officers.
These hogs I have here are bound for
Colonel Cook of the commissary.
- Papers?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
- You often travel alone?
- Uh, usually I do, yeah.
Is that... is that a problem?
- Not for me.
- Great.
Thought you might have
trouble closer to the city.
They're still jumpy
from the fire.
And after
the rebels' victories,
they see lone
arsonists everywhere.
Mm.
You look like you might
give them real trouble.
( Both chuckle )
Safe travels, Mr. Woodhull.
Thanks.
( Clicks tongue ) Go.
Ben: I can assure you, sir, you
will be perfectly convinced
of my friend's
integrity and loyalty.
Well, according to you, he took an
oath of loyalty to King George.
Only to get closer to the
enemy, to learn their secrets.
Traditional military
reconnaissance
is a proven discipline.
Multiple scouts
produce multiple reports
which may be cross-referenced
to ensure verification.
In addition, soldiers
are trained to recognize...
Actually, soldiers
make terrible spies.
All that discipline
drilled into their movements
makes them easy to spot,
unlike us civilians.
Excuse me, sir, but why
exactly are you in this room?
I've been invited here
by your commander in chief
to opine on
the business at hand.
Mr. Sackett came to us
by way of William Duer,
who recommended him as a person
of intrigue and secrecy.
And I must say,
I find this young man's
chain of agents
very intriguing.
I want this chain notion
explored
and a unified recommendation
presented upon my return.
Any questions?
- I...
- Well, yes, Your Excellency.
The letter that I transcribed
regarding the Hessians
and Trenton.
It was unsigned.
I mean to ask, how did you come
by the name Abraham Woodhull?
Excellent question.
Any for you, Mr. Sackett?
Plenty, but not for you, sir.
Very well.
( Footsteps receding )
( door closes )
Singing "Johnny's Gone
For A Soldier"
♪ He'll not come back
for many a day ♪
♪ Johnny's gone
for a soldier... ♪
Hey.
( Explosions )
Can you hit 'em
with your rifle?
I think it came
from over here somewhere.
- ( Gun cocks )
- Soldier: Don't worry...
I got ya.
♪ He'll not come
back for many a day ♪
♪ Johnny's gone
for a soldier... ♪
( Snorting )
♪ With pipe and drum
he marched away...♪
( crackling )
- ♪ He would not heed...
- ( explosion )
Andre: Are you nearly finished?
We have important company
arriving, Abigail.
We must show them
a respectable welcome.
Now, let's have a look.
( laughs ) Oh, dear.
I'm afraid this is all wrong.
I'm sorry, sir.
I just arranged it how my
mistress had taught me.
I don't expect you to
anticipate my preferences.
Then again...
it is never too late to learn.
Have a seat.
Please have a seat.
Show me how
your former mistress
would cut up and eat her meat.
Ah, ah.
It is the European custom,
and most appropriate,
to switch and feed oneself
with the dominant hand.
The time it takes to transfer
prevents us from
descending into gluttony.
( Chuckles )
You must think us mad
to devote such attention
to trivialities, don't you?
I know I certainly did when I
was first made to learn it all.
If I ask you your opinion, you
need not be afraid to give it.
I want you to feel safe here
and perhaps
find reason to smile.
- ( Bell rings )
- Ah!
And here they are.
( Clapping )
Happy return, gentlemen.
You should all feel free to relax
and get some rest tonight.
Tomorrow, I shall
interview each of you
regarding your time
in captivity.
Abigail will show you
to your rooms.
( laughter, chatter )
Look at this.
Liberty never smelled
so sweet, hey, snowball?
( laughs )
I smell his tackle
on your breath.
You gonna pick it up?
Listen to the pickaninny.
We be Queen's Rangers, son.
Back to your digging.
Did you say
the Queen's Monkeys?
There's your monkey.
You wanna play?
Come on. Huh?
( Grunting )
( clatters )
- ( grunting )
- ( stick clatters )
( whistles )
No eyes on him.
I am sorry to keep you waiting,
but, you see, I've been
looking for someone.
I've been tracking a man
who killed one of my boys.
And it's been four months...
just one of them, four months...
so, you see, if you hurt
a Ranger, you pay a price.
Now, it's nothing personal.
That's just the rules.
Do what you will.
Oh, yeah, I will.
But before all that,
I just wanna ask ya,
where the hell did you learn
how to use staves like this?
I have seen all manner
of lethality,
but you showed me
something new today.
I'm Maasai.
We train with fimbos
for initiation.
Fimbos? ( laughs )
Go on, then. Show me.
Only warriors are initiated.
I have been a warrior
for 30 years, boy.
( Chuckles )
Let me put him down, Major.
Drop your iron.
I'll make you my meat.
While you dream, snowball.
We'll have a fair fight, then.
The lads'll make a little coin,
and you and he will get the
answer you're looking for, eh?
So she then hangs a black
petticoat on a drying line
to signal to my courier when
the intelligence is ready.
- Not bad.
- And she hangs napkins
to signify which cove
is safe for the rendezvous.
Wait, wait. Rendezvous?
Don't tell me your agent meets
your courier in person?
Oh, well, of course.
Failure. Death.
No, no, no. Courier and agent
are never in the same
place at the same time.
Well, then how do you expect
for them to make the transfer?
( Sighs ) You
predetermine the location
to drop, id est, hide
the lettre confidentielle
in question
and then arrange
a later time for retrieval.
A dead drop...
to ensure your agents
don't drop dead
from being caught
in flagrante delicto.
Which demonstrates
the folly of this scheme.
If a single link is broken, the
entire chain is rendered useless.
Which is why
we use encryption, sir.
To shield the men,
not the message.
( Chuckles )
Captain, which
enciphering method
have you been using thus far?
Rossignol? Trithemius?
Personally, I prefer Dumas.
Please tell me
you're using encryption.
My God.
I was told you were
a graduate of Yale.
Yes, sir. Class of '73.
Hmm.
One supposes you've studied
Greek, Latin, Hebrew?
Nai. Certe. Chen-adon.
And I am a quick
study, Mr. Sackett.
Then at least we have
somewhere to start.
Commit this to memory.
Scott: We don't
have time for this.
The commander expects
results, not wordplay.
But we're ahead of the game,
thanks to Captain Tallmadge here.
Typically, I have
to concoct a legend
for the agents I wish to
embed into enemy territory.
A poultry trader,
fishmonger, schoolteacher.
Requires wardrobe,
documentation, training.
The brilliance of Mr. Woodhull
is his life is his legend.
There's no reason
to invent a false one.
He's already living it.
- Who pays for it?
- Hmm?
Well, if the farmer's not farming,
who provides for his expenses?
His food, his lodging?
His money to bribe sources?
- ( Cracks nut )
- We do, of course.
The Congress will never
approve intelligencer salaries
while we cobble together
bounties for our regulars.
Congress needn't know about it.
We'll draw from a secret fund
authorized by Washington to
be used at our discretion.
General, please.
We've been asked to explore how
a chain of agents might work.
Some debate is to be expected.
Explore whatever you want,
Tallmadge.
As the head of intelligence,
I will never approve this.
It's time that you learned how
the chain of command works.
- ( Door slams shut )
- Hmm.
That was predictable.
Ah.
( Gasps )
Man singing: ♪ I sold my
flax, I sold my wheel ♪
♪ To buy my love
a sword of steel ♪
♪ So it in battle
he might wield ♪
♪ Johnny's gone
for a soldier... ♪
Listen, you.
You've made a mistake.
You're shivering, Mr. Woodhull.
Here.
This'll warm you up.
No, no, no.
I am the son
of a Tory magistrate.
I'm a loyal subject
of the Crown.
You've gotta listen to me.
You've gotta listen.
- ( Grunts )
- Little Tory boy.
( Coughing )
I'm with the 19th
Continentals under Sullivan.
I've been out here
five months...
the last man of my unit...
ambushing their dispatch
riders, hitting supply lines,
all while looking for a way to
get back to the regiment proper.
Only reason
you're still breathing
is I got more questions
need answering
about who you sell to
and where, at what price,
anything they'll ask
at the checkpoints.
( Shivering ) You plan to
pass yourself off as me?
But that coat and that pin
is as much a disguise
for me as it is for you.
I'm under direct orders
to infiltrate the city
and gather intelligence
for the Continental Army.
- I swear.
- Oh, I see.
So...
you're a spy.
Benjamin Tallmadge, Second
Continental Light Dragoons.
He will confirm my loyalty and
he will verify my mission.
Your mission?
( Sighs )
You're gonna tell me
what I need to know
or they'll find your body
liberated of its skin.
What, you know them all,
trust them all?
We all grew up together.
Childhood friends. Fascinating.
Wouldn't have thought
to try that.
Well, it wasn't
exactly planned.
( Quietly )
Don't tell anyone that.
Don't tell anyone else
Mr. Woodhull's name.
Time to gift
Mr. Woodhull an alias.
One by which the other
agents will know him.
I'm sorry, the other agents?
Hmm, I've plans
for your farmer.
Need him to nurture the seeds
I've planted over
the last year and a half.
One of them
is sprouting right now,
right under the enemy's nose.
I... no, I'm sorry,
but I'm afraid that's
not how this is going to work.
You see, Abe,
he's a very cautious man.
He won't meet with anybody
he doesn't already know.
- He'll have to.
- No, he'll quit is what he'll do.
I thought he was your friend.
Yes, which is exactly why
he trusts me to protect him.
Only that which
is concealed is protected.
You can't even
conceal his name.
Luckily for you, I am a master
at the art of concealment.
Thank you, Lieutenant Terrence.
I have an uncle
in the Coldstream Guard,
so he'll be glad we've
reclaimed one of his own.
I remember the motto...
"Nulli Secundam."
Second to none.
Good evening, sir. Have a seat.
- Name and rank.
- Captain John Graves Simcoe.
And where was your post?
A town called Setauket.
Setauket, Long Island?
Ambush, was it not?
Where are my manners. Drink?
( Rings )
And how did you
find it there in Setauket?
May I have some more ink,
please, Abigail?
This is for military record?
Oh, my own personal curiosity.
It's a pit
run by a man who I'd say...
well, best not
to talk out of turn.
Hewlett?
"The Oyster Major," as he's
referred to in these parts.
( Chuckles )
If you'd like, I could see
to arranging a transfer.
Please, Major,
not on my account.
There's someone whom I
left far too abruptly.
A local woman, perhaps?
In any case, I should very
much like to return to her.
By all means.
Tell me about her.
Well, I'm all packed up.
Tell me what I need to know
or I kill that fire 'fore I go.
No? Have it your way, then.
( Mumbling ) My... my
father's Richard Woodhull.
His deal is with Colonel Cook
for seven pounds per pound.
Now, was that so hard?
Tell me true...
if you're such a Patriot,
why didn't you enlist
with the militia
and fight for your
country like a man?
Because you can't win.
Look at you.
Look at your...
your fort here.
You're one man.
You're alone in the woods...
surrounded by an army
on an island
surrounded by a navy.
That... that is
the Continental Army.
That is what you're
running back to.
So I should be like you, then?
Swear allegiance to the king with
my fingers crossed behind me?
What's your family
think of you?
( Scoffs )
What I do, I do for my son.
He know you're a liar?
He's a year old.
I want to be there for him
when he grows up.
Man: If I had a son,
I'd have him know
I fought and died
for my beliefs
so he could rise to avenge me.
I'd want my son
to choose for himself...
rather than have
his father choose for him.
But then our...
views on liberty...
true liberty... may differ.
You say you need this suit,
this pin, and this paper.
I'll do you a deal.
Fight me for them.
Come on!
I don't want to fight you.
Oh, don't worry. I'll
let you warm up first.
You think you
deserve this more?
- Prove it.
- We're on the same side.
Prove you're worth more.
- No, I won't.
- You fight me.
- I'm not worth more.
( Grunting )
( yells )
Wanna kill me? Wanna kill me?
That's what a man does.
- ( Horse whinnying )
- ( gasps )
Soldier: Mr. Woodhull's cart.
( Grunts )
( grunts )
Soldier: Come around
to the left, men!
No, he's the captive!
There he is!
Surrender! You are
alone and outnumbered.
Man: You were right,
Mr. Woodhull.
You Tory bastard!
( yells )
It's over now. You're safe.
Tough nut, that one.
( laughing )
Oh, it's a long story.
Too long.
- Do tell, tell.
- Soldier: Tell, tell.
( Soldiers tapping )
Very well, very well.
You see, I, too,
was once taken prisoner.
Not long after
I arrived in America
during the defense
of Fort Saint-Jean.
I took it upon myself to write
down everything that I saw...
troop movements,
gun placements.
I even drew a detailed map
of the territory.
You must be quite the artist.
I dabble.
My reports were sent
to General Howe
and, impressed
with my initiative,
he assigned me to a new post.
So you see, I understand
the value of men in chains.
Thus it falls to me
to interrogate our returned.
Though I do prefer
to compare multiple accounts.
That way, if something
is suspect...
it's easier to spot.
As an artist, I've learned that
it's not always the big picture,
but the little details
that effectively sell the tale.
Another line of the old
author, Lieutenant Terrence?
Lieutenant Terrence here
is a Coldstream man.
I propose a toast for
one of Colonel Mathew's finest.
Nulli Secundam.
Secundus.
What the hell have you done?
This man's a liar.
Coldstream lieutenant
not knowing
his regiment's motto.
He was likely sent
back to us as a spy.
I know that!
You pale fool.
I had planned on
turning him double,
the opportunity of which
I have now been robbed.
I apologize, Major.
I just thought...
You didn't think.
You acted upon the assumption
that you were the only one
who could spot
a mouse in the cupboard.
Has it really been that
long since your last kill
or was violence
your natural inclination?
Go back to Setauket, Captain.
I pray that woman can
settle your savage side.
General, have we
come to a consensus?
Your Excellency, we believe
traditional reconnaissance
is the way forward
as it depends on as little
variable as possible
and would be carried out by men who
could be trusted to follow orders.
Captain, what say you?
I...
I concur with the general, sir.
( Scoffs )
The chain of agents approach
would require trust
and in that resource,
I'm afraid we find
ourselves lacking.
You're speaking now
of your men on Long Island.
No, sir, I'm speaking
of the men in this room.
Sir, for a conspiracy
like this one to function,
we would need to be
keeping secrets
from the enemy, from Congress,
even from our own army.
This would require
absolute trust
amongst the secret-keepers,
and yet General Scott here
does not trust me
or my judgment.
Mr. Sackett here
mistrusts my experience,
much as I mistrust his attitude
toward the lives
of the agents in the field.
And you, sir...
you know the name
Abraham Woodhull
and yet you will not
disclose to me
the source of your knowing.
Apparently, you do not
trust me either.
Therefore, I cannot
trust the success
of any chain that we
might build here today.
I would like to speak with
Captain Tallmadge alone.
( Cheering )
( crowd stomping )
( cheering continues )
( grunting )
( cheering )
( grunts )
( cheering continues )
- ( yells )
- Hold!
Shut your gobs!
( Crowd quiets )
You still gonna kill me?
Well, Rangers don't kill
their own initiates.
( Chuckles )
( exhales )
( speaking Abenaki )
Samuel Tallmadge.
Samuel.
Mr. Sackett tells me
that you prefer
an alias for Woodhull.
I must say, I concur.
Forgive me, sir, but I
thought that we had agreed
that the best way forward...
You were right
in your prescription.
We require an amendment
in the name of trust.
Following our retreat
from Brooklyn Heights,
I tasked a native to
reconnoiter enemy encampments
around Long Island and seek out
contacts friendly to our side.
His name was Nathan Hale,
and he was captured while
he was on a mission for me.
He was hanged as a spy.
Fortunately,
his best friend at Yale,
a certain Benjamin Tallmadge,
spoke often of his
hometown friends...
a whaler named Brewster
and a farmer named Woodhull.
I wrote those three names
down on a report,
a report I looked back on
when an unsigned letter
sent by an anonymous
farmer proved correct.
Captain Hale died without
friends to support him.
We cannot let that happen
to Mr. Culpepper.
Mr. Culpepper?
We'll never use
the name Woodhull again.
Why was he
wearing your clothes?
His aim was to pose as me,
escape into the city,
I suppose.
Right, and that proves
the general's anxieties.
Can't take any more
lone men into New York.
What do you... you mean
I can't continue on?
Not alone.
( Sighs )
He tell you his name?
No.
Please don't think that I
condone such barbarism.
Just...
miss my boy, is all.
You have a son?
His birthday's comin' round.
Well, then, we must
send him something.
If you think of a gift,
I'll make arrangements
to have it sent
by special courier.
Well, there's that smile.
That's good. Good, good.
Washington: You are an
invaluable asset to me,
and so, General Scott,
I feel it better
to apply your acumen where it
is most needed... on the front.
But, sir, a captain can't
run the intelligence branch.
That's why I have
promoted him to major.
I wish you the best of
luck, Your Excellency.
He is a fine general.
Thank you
for this promotion, sir.
- I pray I do you proud.
- As do I.
Your first duty is to come up
with a given name
for our Mr. Culpepper.
Samuel.
In honor of your brother,
I presume?
Yes, sir.
And might I ask, what is the
meaning of "Culpepper"?
Excellent question.