This film documents the Vietnam War
in the words of Americans
who served there.
it features home movies
and rare
archival footage
collected during a worldwide search
and now presented in high definition
Many scenes are graphic in nature
and your discretion is advised.
What do we want Equiality?
I was in Word War II,
fella,
and I served for years.
I know it's about.
I have a son that's gonna
go into the army.
Over Ten Years
Over 2.5 million americans
served in vietnam.
It's not the war you know.
It's the war they fought.
Search & Destroy
1966 - 1967
===========
VC right across the river.
Roger, okay.
JANUARY 1966
The US victory over
the north Vietnamese
in the Ia Drang Valley,
measured by a kill ratio of 12 to 1,
convinces US commanders to
implement a new strategy,
Search ans Destroy.
The plan is brutaly simple.
Search out the enemy in South Vietnam,
and then destroy them
in numbers so high,
they will no longer be able
to continue fighting.
For the firt time in modern
US military history,
victory in war wil be measured
not by territory taken,
but by body count.
But as US and South Vietnamese forces
battle through the vast
countryside and winding rivers,
they quickly discover that the
enemy has a plan of their own.
The VC have meticulously planted
tens of thounsas of
mines and booby traps.
They have dug hundreds of miles of tunnels
to move soldiers and weapons,
and launch suprise attacks.
And perhaps worst of all,
they hide in plain sight,
indistinguishable from the 17 million civilians.
If they are to win the war,
US leaders realize
they need an enormous number
of boots on the ground
1966 becomes the year of escalation.
JANUARY 1966
180.000 US TROOPS ARE IN VIETNAM.
MAY 1966
280.000 TROPS.
Go faster! Run faster!
JULY 1966
300.000 TROOPS.
SEPTEMBER 1966
325.000 TROPS.
JANUARY 1976
389.000 US TROOPS ARE IN VIETNAM.
ONE THIRD ARE VOLUNTEERS.
When we graduated,
one of the commencement speakers
quote President Kennedy,
saying we should: "Ask not what
our country can do for us,
but ask what we can do for our country".
Well, the more I hear about Vietnam,
the more I think I'm finally
starting to understand
what those words mean.
In san Bernadino, California,
Barry Romo is feeling the
effects of the growing war.
And this sorts of led me to tinking about,
well, if I believe in the war then I have to
actully join the military and go and fight.
Really put my principles into action.
When I told my father
I was going to enlist,
he said: "I dont't want you to go".
And I said: "Well, you served".
He said:"But your brother
and I went to war to fight
people who were putting
other human beings in ovens.
All you're gonna do is go
fight some poor farmer
that doesn't want to
be bothered with you,
and I don't want you to die".
But he doesn't know
what he's talking abut.
We're in Vietnam to save those
farmers from the communist.
That's what this war is about.
Everybody knows that,
and everybody's behind it.
So I tell him,
"Sorry, Pops, regarless of what you think,
I'm enlisting in the army,
and I'm volunteering to go to Vietnam".
As Romo undergoes
his 12 months of training,
he has no idea what
Vietnam will really be like.
No more than 28 year old Chales Brown has,
even after serving 8 years in the peacetime army.
A few months ago, I didn't even
know any of these men existed.
Now we're headed into combat together,
and we're gonna have to depend
on each other to survive.
TAY NINH PROVINCE
May 1967.
Well, back when I was at fort benning,
training up young men
that was going to Vietnam,
one of my favorites slogans was:
"I'm gonna go to Vietnam.
I'm gonna kil some Viet Cong. Ha!".
Well, this take effect on you.
Remember now, I'd been drilled
for a good 8 years whit nothing
but talking about combat.
No that I wanted to experience,
but it had became a way of life,
there're certain things
you do and how you do it,
and actually combat is the only
way this is gonna be tested.
Brown is now second in
command to a platoon of 30 men
with the 173rd airbone brigade
sweeping through Tay Ninh Province,
a know Viet Cong stronghold.
A lot of my guys are from
places like New York and Chicago.
Boys that barely been
out of the city, let alone
been out in the middles
of a jungle like this.
No matter how much training they got,
Vietnam is a whole different world to them.
Summer daytime temperature overage
over 100 degrees Fahrenheit,
while a 100% humidity is like
bein in a stema bath 24/7.
Then men must cut their way
thoungh 8 foot tall razor
sharp elephan grass
and bamboo covered
in thick, thorny vines.
But this is only part of the problem.
THe countryside is also
infested with thounsand
of poisonius insectes and snakes,
including one of the deadliest in the world,
known as the "two step snake"
for the number of step a bite
victim can take before dropping dead.
Brown and his men must navigate
this treacheruous terrain
under the constant threat
of ambushes and booby traps,
looking for any signs of the elusive Viet Cong.
Couple of hooches up ahead.
I tell my radio man  to call
back to camp and tell:
"em we're gonna
search it fast" fore nighfall.
Couple of my guys start bitching,
waiting to know why the
hell we can't just skip it,
but I tell "This is a job," so they better
bucke down and get it done.
As Brown and his men enter
the area, they quickly realize
it's an abandoned
Viet Cong encampment.
The VC have a sophisticated
network of scouts
and sympathizers who alert
them the American's presence
allowing them to choose when
and where they want fight.
The best the americans can do now
is destroy any hidden enemy
weapons or supplies they can find.
I always tell these guys you got to go slow,
you got to take your time
going through these things,
but none of them listen to me.
All they want to do is get
done and get back to camp.
This one guy,
he thinks he's been out here so long,
he knows everything there is to know.
So what does he do?
Instead of him going
down into the rice slowly
to see if anything was in it,
he tilt the rice, immediately seeing
what we could call a
pressure realese booby trap.
The booby trap blast Brown and
two of his men with shrapnel.
Within minutes, a medevac chopper is on route
to take them to one of the 18
military hospitals in Vietnam.
The emergeny call indicated
that there are three injured, wounded G.I.'s.
We're on our way flying above
what has to be considered
insecure, hostile territory.
Nearly one million patients are airlifted
in medivac choppers during the vietnam war.
The average time from battlefield
to hospital is one hour.
Okay, we've go our three
wounded G.I.'s on board.
At least one of them is hit pretty bad.
We took a little fire on the
way out of this.. pickup area.
Romo: We had hear about
search and destroy missions
and ambushes and even practices them
in officer candidate school and other places.
But the reality of actually going out...
is a totally different thing.
It's not like the movies
where you go out in the field,
and that evening you're back in a base camp,
drinking beer or smoking dope.
We would go out
30, 35, 40 days at a time.
24/7.
In july of 1967,
19 years old second lieutenant
Barry Romo arrives in Vietnam.
He replaces a platoon leader
who was critically wounded
by a landmine during a search
and destroy operation.
Now Romo is in Quang Nam province,
300 miles north of where
Charles Brown was wounded,
leading his platoon of approximately 30 men
on a similiar mission, whit similar dangers.
Get Down! Take cover!
Get Down!
It's the not knowing that gets to you.
The feeling that you're never safe
anywhere, at any time.
All clear! Let's move it!
Suddenly mortars and gunfire
are flying in from everywhere.
No one knows what the hell's going on
or where the enemy's even at.
I start screaming at my men to get down
and form adefensive perimeter...
but everyone's yelling and shooting.
And then I realize one of my squads
got stuck between us and the enemy.
They're caught in the crossfire,
getting hit from both directions.
I gotta do something.
So I yell for cover,
and I run forward as fast
as I can to my squad.
They are all injured.
And every man was badly wounded.
And two of my men were dead.
And one of my men had
been thrown 100 feet,
maybe by a concussion,
and his insides were jellified,
and I saw that I had to
get them out there...
out of there or more
people are gonna die.
Medevac doesn't want to land be
cause we're taking too much fire.
But I scream into the radio and I tell them
"¡I 'm gonna stand up in the
middle of this damn field
and you better get in here
and get my men out!".
When it's finally over and
we get back to the platoon,
my company commander said,
"I'm going to put you in for a bronce star".
In my mind I could only picture a
bronce star for my dead men,
and it didn't seem worth it.
it didn't seem fair
that people should die
for me to get a medal.
During the first nine
months of 1967
6.990 americans are killed in Vietnam.
More than the total killed in
the previous five years combined.
As U.S. losses begin to mount,
president johnson reminds
the american people
that the war is not only about
stopping the spread of communism.
There is an even greater cause
worth fighting for in Vietnam.
Johnson: Every American
must know exactly
what it is that we are
trying to do in Vietnam.
Our greatest resource,
really, in this conflict,
is your understanding.
Hall: By the summer of 1967,
the united states is sending more
than $500 million in aid to SV.
More than 1.5 million children
are attending hundreds of new schools.
And for the first time
hundreds of thousands
of poverty stricken civilians
are receiving modern medical care.
Johnson: It is a goal that's worthy
of the deeds of our brave men.
The people of Asia do matter...
and I pledge to all those
that are counting on us,
you can depend upon us...
because all americans will do our part.
BOONVILLE, MISSOURI
Summer 1967.
PURCELL HOME MOVIES
Purcell: As long as ben
and I have been married,
our lives have been run by the army...
but I guess that's the price you
pay for falling in love with a military man.
Hall: Anne Purcell married Ben,
a carrer military officer, in 1951.
After 16 years of marriage,
five children, and mnay moves,
thery are living in Boonville, Missouri,
where he is stationed as a colonel.
Ben and I both know he'll be going
to Vietnam sooner or later,
so we figure if he
volunteeted to go to Vietnam,
the family had a choice as to where they
stayed, and we would stay in Boonville,
because it was already like home,
having lived there four years.
I dreaded seeing him go,
but I knew that was his duty,
and so I just accepted it that way.
Right Before we leave to see Ben off,
he surprises me with a pair of audio recorders.
He's going to take one to Vienam with him,
and I'll keep the other so we can record tapes
and mail them back and forth.
When we get to the airport, I give Ben last kiss,
and tell him he better try out
that recorder as soon as he gets there,
and let me know that everything's okay.
But the war colonel Purcell is
about to join is not going as planned.
Although U.S. forces conduct
hundreds of search and destroy operations,
including massive sweeps involving
up to 30.000 soldiers at a time,
the NV and VC are elusive,
refusing to engage in locked down,
drawn out combat.
Finally, near the end of October 1967,
U.S. forces locate 6.000 NV soldiers
massing near the american base
at Dak To in Kon Tum province.
More than 6.500 u.s and
south vietnamese soldiers,
along with attack helicopters, fighter bombers,
and the mightiest aircraft
in the u.s arsenal,
the B-25 bomber,
are deployed to the region.
On november 3, 1967,
shortly adter midmorning,
The first group of three B-25's
prepares to unleash nearly
six tons of high explosives,
before the ground troops move in...
the largest clash with the NVA
since the Ia Drang Valley begins.
All morning long, bombers
have been coming in overhead.
You can feel the ground shaking like Jell-o.
Sergeant Charles Brown
has recovered from his wounds
and is back with the 173rd Airbone Brigade
on his way to relieve American units
engaged in heavy combat outsie of Dak To.
We can hear the gunfire as we get closer.
The sound of M-16's and
AK-47's rip through the jungle.
The sound of trees splintering.
Men screaming.
A few paces ahead,
the recon team radios back.
They've walked right into an ambush.
And now they're stuck out there
only a few meters ahead of us,
screaming for help.
We got to do something
fast before they al get killed.
C.O jumps on the radio and tells:
'em to hit the ground and stay down.
Then he turns to me and instructs me
to take the rest of the platoon in
to see what was going on.
knowing that my men in there was down,
we went in firing from the waist up.
just spraying the whole area.
Brown, Charles, J., staff sergeant E-6,
awarded Bronze star medal
with first oak leaf cluster with V device.
"Reason: for heroism in
connection with military operation
against a hostile force...
near Dak To, Republic of vietnam".
OUTSIDE DAK TO
November 15, 1967.
After three weeks of fighting,
u.s and south vietnamese
forces have stopped the NVA
from destroying the
american base at Dak To.
But of the 6000 enemy
soldiers spotted in the area,
only an estimated 600 were killed.
The remaining 5400 are
making a strategic retreat
towards Laos an cambodia.
Diplomatoc policy prohibits
u.s ground troops
from crossing the border.
Hoping to stop the NVA
before they escape...
the americans give chase.
On november 19, 1967,
u.s soldiers pin down 2000 NVA
on an 875 meter high hill,
know as Hill 875...
just six kilometers from Cambodia.
Do you have any idea what
kind of fire we have on this?
They are immediately
ordered to take the hill.
EN ROUTE TO HILL 875
Ain't no such thing as rest for the weary.
2000 NVA are on Hill 875
and command want us
to go hunt 'em all down.
During WWII an infantryman averaged
10 days of combat in one year.
In Vietnam an infantryman averaged
240 days of combat in one year.
Hours into the assault,
sargeant charles brown and his battalion
are helicoptered to hill 875 to join the fight.
They are dropped in a safe zone
just out of range of enemy fire.
The entire place already looks
like hell from all the fighting.
Trees are splintered and broken.
Smoke billows in the distance.
You can see this is a
completely destroyed area.
Trees gone, nothing to hide on, just a whole...
Unbelievable how it had been destroyed.
As brown and his men make their
way towards the american units,
they have no idea of horros that lay ahead.
The NVA have transformed Hill 875
into a heavily fortified stronghold,
brimming with prebuilt bunkers
and carefully carved put escape routes.
It's a cunning trap that the
americans are waking right into.
As we head into the twilight,
we can hear the mortar and artillery shells
exploding a few miles out in front of us.
Up ahead, men start whispering back
whenever they come across a dead body.
Pretty soons, seems like all you hear is:
"¡Body! ¡Body! ¡Body!".
OUTSIDE TAM KY
300 miles to the north.
Five hours ago, we were out
there in the middle of the bush.
Now I'm cracking open a warm
beer while ckick shakes her butt.
300 miles to the north,
second lieutenant Barry
Romo and his platoon
are on a 2 day breack
after being in the field
for 30 straight days
of search and destroy.
I guess this is one of the
crazy things about Vietnam.
One minute you're out there,
freaking out about tripe
wires and booby traps...
and the next thing you know,
they fly you into a rear area,
where they take away our weapons
and our hand grenades,
and they would plop us on a beach
like in apocalypse now
and have a big barbecue,
and you would drink and they
would bring in tons of alcohol.
And then after two days,
they would pour you
back into the helicopters
and give you your weapons back
and fly you to an area for another operation,
for another 30 days.
It's so bizarre.
All anyone knows is that no one has
any idea what will happen next.
I had an officer in training that once said:
"The viet cong guerrillas are the
fish in the sea of the people,
and our jobs is to dry up that sea".
I thought he was crazy for saying that...
but now that I've been
out here for a few months,
I'm starting to see what he meant.
Second lieutenant Barry
romo is back in the field
seraching a south vietnamese village.
Civilians sympathetic to the viet cong
hide weapons and supllies,
while those who side with the americans
stay silent for fear of
brutal communist reprisals.
As result, the americans
cannot tell friend from foe...
leaving the villagers caught in the middle.
We're told the VC threaten
these people with their lives
unless they help them.
So you got to figure
it's not really their fault.
But at the same time,
when you find a bunch of AK-47s
hidden in some villager's chicken pen,
you can't help but feel like they'r
the reason your buddies are dead.
I mean, these are supposed to be
the people we're here to help.
Only it seems like don't give
a shit about helping us.
I've never once had a Vietnamese say:
"Don't go down this trail,
because there's a mine" ...
or, "Don't go over to this area
because the north Vietnamese
are gonna ambush you".
You morality wears down.
Your patience wears down.
After a while,
people started blaming the
Vietnamese for our casualties.
All of the Vietnamese,
and there's a genuine
dehumanization of the people
we were supposedly there to help.
This isn't like my dad's war.
We aren't fighting uniformed
nazis on our way to Berlin.
Out here,
we've got to figure things
out every days as it's gappening.
So given a choice between your buddy living,
and one of those villagers living,
you know who you're gonna pick.
'Cause that's just the way it is,
and all any of us want to do
is get out of here
and get back home alive.
HILL 875
Day three of Battle.
Every time one of these birds tries
to come in with supplies,
NVA shoots 'em up.
We already got two birds shot down.
Sargeant Charles Brown
and the 173rd airbone brigade
are pinned down on the side of hill 875.
Over the past 48 hours,
u.s and south vietnameses forces
have made several attempts to take the hill.
So far, all they have to show for their efforts
are mounting numbers of dead and wounded.
The north Veitnamese
are dug in, and dug in deep.
We were gonna have to burn them out.
Each platoon was ordered
to send a man forward
to our little rear camp to learn
or be familiar with the
operations of a flamethower.
And I ordered one of my replacements,
Billy Cupid, he was kind of
stocky black kid from Chicago,
and I told him:
"Get familiar whith the flamethower".
With flamethowers in hand,
u.s forces prepare for
their final push up hill 875.
I order my men to get into position.
All of a sudden,
mortars and rocket fire
start coming downs on us.
105's are screaming overhead,
and men are shouting and firing.
Smoke start clogging my lungs
and the sounds of small arms
and machine gun fire rips through the air.
As we charged the hill with
the flamethower on his back,
that pressure tank was hit
with a piece of shrapnel...
and the concussion of hit killed billy.
For a moment,
I am frozen with the
unbelievable sight of a man dying
right in front of me.
Soldier: Take the first two lines!
But then the incoming fire snap me out of it.
Soldier: Go! Go! Go!
It's constant and
coming from everywhere.
There seems little strategy
left other than move forward
and kil anything in front of you.
HILL 875
Day Five of Battle.
Only a couple choppers have
landed since we took the hill.
And all they've brought
is the bare necessities...
ammo, water, rations, and body bags.
Lots of 'em.
On november 23, 1967,
after five days of harrowing,
close-quarters combat,
u.s forces, including sergeant
charles brown an his company,
finally take hill 875.
115 americans have been killed,
and another 253 wounded.
Combined with the casulities from
the previous three weeks,
Brown's 173rd brigade
has lost nearly one-fifth of
its total fighting strength.
Medics are making their
way to wounded troopers,
giving 'em sips of water or shots of morphine.
You got to admire them.
Lot of these boys ain't no
more than 18, 19 years old,
but they fought better and harder
than anything I could have ever hoped for.
They fought like the well disciplined,
professional soldiers they were trained to be.
Just like the soldiers I had trained them to be.
Despit their succes in
courageously taking the hill,
the American soldieres are
unable to achieve the primary goal,
killing all of the enemy
soldiers in Kon Tum Povince.
Of the 6000 north vietnamese originally spotted,
only some 1400 were killed.
The rest escaped into Laos and Cambodia
the night before the final assault.
Six days after spilling so much blood to take it,
u.s forces leave hill 875.
In the strategy of search and destroy,
victory is mesured by
enemy bodies, not territory.
Hill 875 is now considered worthless.
It didn't take us long to realize
there ain't no iwo jimas in Vietnam.
We don't get to plant
our flag and claim victory.
But we know we've done what
we was assigned to do.
We knew we were superior.
We knew we has killed all that was up there.
We didn't know at that time
that some of them had left.
That was one of the myths of vietnam.
Each time you take a
piece of ground, we left it,
and they returned to
that same piece of ground.
But we left the hill as heroes.
We finally captured Hil 875.
That's the way we left it.
We were heroes.
Lost some buddies, lost some men, yes,
but we defeated the enemy on hill 875.
DECEMBER 1967
16.250 americans have
been killed in vietnam.
An estimated 186.000 enemy
troops have been killed.
Faced with only the cold
hard numbers of body count,
the american public has a difficult time
seeing measurable progress in vietnam.
In two years, public support
for the war has dropped
from 80% in 1965 t only 46%.
But with nearly half a
million soldiers overseas,
president Johnson and
his generals are convinced
that they have turned the corner.
They launch a massive campaign
designed to reinvigorate
public support for the war
and demostrate that
victory is on the horizon,
so long as the american
public doesn't give up
so close to the finish line.
I could quote a number
of meaningful statistics
such as the roads that are being opened.
The numbered of weapons being captured...
and other statidtical information
that suggests we are making
progress and we are winning.
Today, I can tell you that military progress
in the past 12 months has
exceeded our expectations.
And so I report to you
that we are going to continue
to press forward.
We will provide all that our
brave men require
to do the job that must be done.
Let the world know that
the keepers of peace
will endure through every trial
and that with the full backing
of their countrymen...
they are going to prevail.
----