Previously on "Vikings":
Bishop Swithern: We will
catch you and crucify you.
An apostate is the vilest
of all creatures
in the eyes of God!
Raise an army,
observe the size
of the raiding party
and their intention.
This land is rich,
but here...
Is the real treasure.
Earth.
We want to make peace
with the king,
so we don't have to kill
any more of you.
You're my wife,
you should be at my side.
Lagertha:
Agh!
Bjorn: Why would you
allow him to do that?
It will never happen again.
If it does, I will kill him.
In order to punish those
who have insulted me,
I will seek vengeance
against Ragnar Lothbrok.
We will seize all his land
and I will repay his brother's
treachery with the axe.
Old warrior: Rollo, your first duty
is to save the sons of Ragnar.
♪
♪ More, give me more ♪
♪ give me more ♪
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I... ♪
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(Thunder rumbles, rain patters)
(Footsteps splash)
♪
(Exhales)
Rollo:
We'll stay here!
Aslaug:
No, stop!
I'm not staying there!
It looks disgusting.
Rollo: Princess, it will
be winter soon enough.
If we have nowhere to live,
no roof over our heads,
no hearth fire to warm us,
we will all perish.
Surely we can find
some Earl's hall -
somewhere more inviting
and comfortable.
(Sighs)
For my children.
And if we are to find
such a place,
it would only take a few days
before someone took
the news to Jarl Borg.
(Baby cries)
(Clucks tongue) (Sighs heavily)
Siggy:
We will survive this.
Believe me,
you and I can survive this.
It will make you stronger.
It will make your sons
stronger, also.
Jarl Borg:
People of Kattegat -
I am Jarl Borg of Gotaland,
your new ruler.
I promise you I only came here
to seek justice.
Earl Ragnar broke
his sacred promise he made to me
and therefore, by our laws,
he forfeited the right to rule.
Townspeople:
(Murmurs of concern)
In me, you will find
a fair ruler;
Kattegat is an important
trading station
and I mean to see it flourish.
Townspeople: (Murmur)
Man: Of course.
Seer:
(Low groan)
There will be no protest
against my rule
and there will be no law here
except mine.
Oever will deliver me
the whereabouts
of Ragnar's wife,
his children, and his brother,
will be paid
his or her own weight
in silver and gold.
From now on, only criminals
will talk of Ragnar Lothbrok.
To all intents and purposes,
Ragnar Lothbrok is dead.
(Door opens)
(Door creaks closed)
Why have you come?
I've come to ask you
some questions.
Seer:
Not too many.
I have no time
to answer too many.
Then tell me this, wise one:
Did you foresee
what has happened here?
And, if so,
did you warn the people?
I see what the gods
allow me to see,
and say what
they allow me to say.
Then you saw nothing,
or you said nothing?
Do you have
any other questions?
I'd like to know
what will happen to me,
if, that is,
the gods will allow you to say.
Yes, I can see...
And I see an eagle.
I see that an eagle
hovers over you.
But I also see that you yourself
are the eagle.
Jarl Borg:
An eagle is a good sign.
Always in the sagas,
a good sign.
An eagle, a soaring bird.
A good sign from the gods.
Is it not true, old man?
Seer:
Yes, I see an eagle,
and the eagle is your destiny,
Jarl Borg.
(Door creaks open and closes)
(Bones rattle)
(Goats bleat,
metallic clanking)
Bishop Edmund: Sire, if we
continue to do nothing,
their depredations
will only spread.
They've not removed themselves,
nor yet sailed away,
as we all prayed.
Ealdorman Werferth: Your army is
collected, sire, and awaits your orders.
They expressed
the desire to talk,
so, first, we should talk.
Bishop Edmund: How are we
to trust men like these
who kill without conscience,
who desecrate and pollute
sacred places?
Ecbert:
No, we cannot trust them.
Therefore, there will be
an exchange of hostages
before we begin.
Man:
Hmm, wise.
Ealdorman Werferth: And who are we
to deliver into their tender care?
Ecbert:
My son, Aethelwulf.
Father?!
A hostage of the highest value
is the safest hostage.
But I will not deliver you
to them
until they have first
delivered to me
a hostage of equal value
to themselves.
Bishop Edmund: They are
savages, heathens!
They do not put a value
on any life.
Ecbert:
Oh, I... I doubt that.
We are christians,
but not so long ago
we were also pagans.
And, when we were pagans,
do you think we cared nothing
for our families,
our children?
But I swear to you, my son,
I would never surrender you
without your blessing
and agreement.
Father, you know the answer
to that:
I place myself in your hands.
I am at your disposal.
Man:
Well said, young man.
(Wind blows fiercely,
rain patters)
(Goat bleats)
(Baby wails, chickens cluck,
people chatter quietly)
- Ubbe: I said, get down!
- Aslaug: Boys!
- Ubbe: Move it.
- Hvitserk: Stop! Want to sit!
- Aslaug: Stop it!
- Ubbe: I'm not going to stop!
- Aslaug: Boys! Ubbe!
- Hvitserk: Stop it!
Leave your bother alone!
- Aslaug: Ubbe! Stop it!
- Siggy: Come on, let's go.
- Aslaug: Hvitserk!
Siggy:
Here, give me the baby.
- Ubbe: (Laughs)
- Hvitserk: Ubbe!
- Shh, shh, shh...
- Oh! Off him!
Everything is so dirty here.
You are safe here,
and your children
are safe here.
Aslaug:
Safe?
They will all die
of some disease.
Look at the boys,
already so thin, so sickly.
I can't stay here!
You have to stay here.
Look, I know this is not
what you are used to,
but you will get used to it.
(Baby fusses, settles)
Many of our people
live like this.
Life is not a walk
across an open field!
(Frustrated sigh)
Say what you want, Siggy.
We won't stay here.
♪
(Horse whinnies)
(Hooves clop)
♪
(Horse whinnies and snorts)
(Gate thuds shut)
(Rooster crows outside)
(Footsteps crunch on gravel,
horse whinnies nearby)
(Birds chirp)
(Footsteps echo slightly)
Ragnar:
Who made all of these things?
Ealdorman Werferth:
Nobody knows.
Some say a race of giants
once lived on this island.
Giants?
(Door creaks open)
Ealdorman Werferth: Sire, may I
present Earl Ragnar Lothbrok.
(Water ripples)
Ecbert:
You may leave us.
All of you.
(Footsteps retreat)
(Door creaks closed)
Will you not join me,
Ragnar Lothbrok?
The water is very temperate.
(Clothing rustles)
(Splashes water absently)
(Leather vest thuds on floor)
(Clothing rustles)
(Footstep splashes)
(Water rippling)
Ecbert:
Now we are equal.
We can talk together honestly,
man to man.
May I ask you a question,
Ragnar Lothbrok?
Why do you not go home?
After the sack
of the minster at Winchester,
you surely have
enough treasure.
And by staying,
you've given me time
to raise a large army.
I don't care about treasure.
I am a very uh...
Curious man.
I want to see your lands,
and I want to see
how you farm them.
You see...
I am really a farmer.
Are you saying that
if I offer you some land,
we could make a deal?
It's possible.
But I would want something
in return.
You see, Ragnar Lothbrok,
I am an ambitious man.
I have great plans.
And you and your warriors
could help me to fulfill them.
(Horses snort, birds chirp)
Horik: What else did this
King of Wessex have to say?
Ragnar:
That he might offer us land.
Horik:
And you believed him?
Can you trust him,
this Christian?
Ragnar: He wants
something in return.
What does he want in return?
(Horn bellows in the distance)
(Horn bellows)
Horik:
It's one of mine.
It's Thorvard!
Warriors:
(Curious chatter)
Thorvard!
(Laughs delightedly)
Captain:
There!
Warrior:
Here!
Thorvard, welcome.
Thorvard:
Thank you, my lord.
I bring grave news
for Ragnar Lothbrok.
Your lands are lost,
invaded by Jarl Borg.
Your family is fled,
only the gods know where.
Now Jarl Borg lives
in your great hall
and rules in your place.
(bird cries)
(Frantic panting)
- You're leaving?
- Of course I am.
I must find my family.
Are you not coming?
I'm minded to stay here,
Ragnar,
to speak with this
King Ecbert further.
I think he is afraid of us
and will make some deal
to our advantage.
Ragnar: You can't even
speak their language.
How will you communicate?
Horik: If you will permit this
man, Athelstan, to remain with me,
he can do the talking.
Ragnar:
Athelstan is a free man.
It is his choice.
Athelstan: If I can be
of help to King Horik
then I am happy to stay.
I am surprised to hear
you say that...
For you know my family
better than anyone.
You've always said how important
these contacts are
for the future and prosperity
of all your people.
So is it not more important
for me to remain here?
Are you sure
you want to do this?
Then so be it.
Prepare the ships!
If you change your mind,
your friends will be leaving
at first light.
Horik: May Thor fill your sails,
to the place of vengeance!
♪
(Water churns)
(Hooves thunder)
Yah! Come on!
Bjorn: Jarl Borg has invaded his
lands while ragnar has been away.
He killed all who resisted.
Rollo, Princess Aslaug, Siggy,
Princess Alsaug's children,
they've all fled Kattegat.
Lagertha:
I cannot believe it.
What are the gods thinking?
Bjorn:
Ragnar will come back.
He will come back
to fight for his lands
and we must help him.
We can't.
But you used to-it's not
Earl Sigvard's quarrel.
Why should he fight
to restore Ragnar's lands?
Bjorn:
You could ask him!
(Sighs angrily)
(Hooves thunder)
Rollo: There are several
farming families
who are willing to fight with us
against Jarl Borg.
How many?
Twenty...
Thirty warriors.
That's not enough.
No, not enough,
at least to do battle.
But perhaps enough to torment.
We have to make sure
that Jarl Borg
never feels secure
in his inheritance.
We can mount raids
on his outposts,
disrupt his supplies.
Sooner or later,
my brother will return,
and, in the meantime,
our task is to keep
his memory alive.
Why are you smiling?
(Sighs happily)
I am smiling because...
A year ago, you would not
have spoken like this.
My brother forgave me,
something I thought impossible.
When I searched my heart,
I discovered that
I always loved him.
That I'd grown to hate myself.
(Fire crackles)
(Goats bleat)
I'm sorry, you're tired.
You must want to sleep.
I don't want to sleep.
(Rollo gasps)
I want to feel alive.
(Lively music plays nearby,
low hum of chatter)
(Door bangs open)
You're still a handsome woman,
Lagertha.
I'll say that for you.
There's something
I want to talk to you about.
As long as...
It has nothing to do
with ragnar Lothbrok,
then talk away.
Of course it has to do
with ragnar.
Then I'm not interested.
(Belt clatters on floor)
Come into bed.
Lagertha:
No. Not until we have talked.
I told you, woman,
I don't want to talk about
your ex-husband.
He used to own your body,
but now I own it.
So, come to bed.
It would be in your interest
to intervene in this affair.
How so?
Jarl Borg will bring
his relations,
his family, his people,
from Gotaland
and place them
on your doorstep!
On our doorstep, wife!
After ragnar, you will be next,
don't you understand?
Forget ragnar!
Don't!
I am your husband!
Lagertha:
(Struggling grunts)
(Muffled struggling grunts)
(Whimper of protest)
Earl Sigvard:
Agghhhh!
Lagertha:
(Hard punch)
(Choked grunts,
Bjorn unsheathes dagger)
Don't ever treat me
like your whore!
I am your wife.
I am not your whore.
Do you understand?
(Panting)
(Grunting)
(Footsteps approach,
door unlatches)
He's asleep.
Go to bed.
But he-
I said, go to bed.
He will not harm me.
But thank you.
Men: ♪ up onto the overturned keel ♪
♪ we clamber
with hearts of steel ♪
♪ cold is the ocean's spray,
your death is on its way! ♪
Nun 1: (Terrified cries)
Let me go!
Men: ♪ be strong though rain beats down... ♪
Nun: I beg you!
Upon your balding crown
- Men: ♪ with maidens you had your way... ♪
- Warrior: Get her!
Nun: (Tortured screams) (Empty line)
Men: ♪ and each must die someday ♪
Horik's men: (Laughing)
Nun: (Sobbing)
Horik:
Priest!
(Nuns scream in terror)
Nun: (Wailing) On no!
Mercy! Oh, mercy!
(Horik's men laugh)
Athelstan:
(Sighs heavily)
Warrior: (Grunts) Milk her!
Nun: (Screams)
(Screams of terror)
(Sadistic laughter,
jumble of chatter)
Warrior:
...What I was going to say!
(Nun screams)
(Nun sobs, thunder rolls)
Nun: No! Help me!
(Protests become distorted)
(Screaming and pleading)
No, please, no!
(Screams of terror)
Athelstan:
(Frightened gasps)
(Floor creaks,
footsteps approach)
Ecbert:
What is it?
Ealdorman Werferth:
Their forces have divided.
Four of their ships
have sailed away.
(Holy water sloshes)
Honest prayers
are always answered,
ealdorman Werferth.
(Wet, squishy, tearing sounds)
Aslaug: Ubbe, Hvitserk...
Come away.
But we want to watch.
♪
(Sniffles)
(Leaves rustle in the wind)
(Water splashes)
Captain: Lower it! Pull it!
Ragnar:
Are my family here?
Helga:
No, but I know where they are.
Siggy sent a boy to tell me,
a farmer's son.
Take me there.
Tomorrow.
After you have slept.
I shan't sleep.
Jorl Borg has taken away
my sleep.
Unload!
Helga:
What happened?
Thor was angry with us.
He beat his anvil
and the waves grew ever taller,
soaked the boats,
and one went down,
heavy with water.
We saw it,
and heard the cries of the men
hauled down into the deep.
And then, at first light,
we saw another had vanished,
storm wrecked,
the men all drowned.
Thank the gods you're alive.
(Inhales forcefully)
♪
(Birds chirp)
__
(Wings beat loudly)
Man 1: There!
Warriors:
Oh no! Ugh!
Man 1: You were too late again!
Man 2: You couldn't hit a ship.
(Laughing)
Man 2: There'll be more!
Man 1: Yes, they're everywhere!
(Men laugh)
(Foliage rustles underfoot)
(Wings beat furiously)
Man 1: Oh! There he is!
(Arrow whistles) Ungh!
Dying man: (Gasps in pain)
Man 1: Where he is?!
Man 1: Go! Run this way!
Man 2: Go! Go!
Man 3:
Keep up! Save him! Save him!
Athelstan: (Pants and grunts)
Men: (Scream out in pain)
(Arrows strike) Agghhh!
Man:
Keep low! Over here!
(Grunting and panting)
Man:
Agh!
(Groans in pain) Ungh!
(Grunting and panting)
(Splashing footsteps,
churning water)
(Foliage rustles underfoot)
(Thunder rumbles, wind blows)
(Pain patters)
(Birds chirping)
(Arrows striking,
Athelstan gasps in fright)
Soldier:
(Speaking Anglo-Saxon)
Athelstan:
Saxon soldier: (In Anglo-Saxon)
He speaks our language.
Saxon soldier 2: (In
Anglo-Saxon) Dirty heathen!
(Speaking Anglo-Saxon)
Saxon soldier: (In
Anglo-Saxon) Bring him!
(Rain patters heavily)
(Running footsteps)
(Milk squirts, goat bleats)
They're inside.
(Unlatching door)
Man:
Ragnar!
Ubbe:
Father!
- Ragnar: Little man.
- Hvitserk: Father!
Ragnar: Hello, son.
Oh, I've missed you.
Thank the gods!
Ragnar: You still have it.
Ubbe: Yes.
Aslaug:
I knew you were coming back.
I saw you down in the field
three days ago.
(Baby coos)
What did you call him?
His name is sigurd
snake-in-the-eye.
I warned you, my love.
You questioned my prophecy,
but here's proof of it.
In your child's eye
is the serpent
my father killed.
It is not a curse,
it is a blessing.
♪
I was afraid that
I would never see them again.
I always knew
you would find us.
(Gasp of pleasure)
(Sigh)
No, we cannot have sex.
Not for three days.
Ragnar:
No more prophecies.
Just want to feel
the warmth of it,
the heat of it.
(Footsteps approach)
Siggy:
Rollo is back.
Rollo:
Hello, brother.
Welcome to this shithole
we call home.
Ragnar:
Shall we talk?
(Latch rattles)
Ragnar: I want to attack Kattegat.
Now!
I want to destroy jarl Borg,
I want to make him suffer
as he has made
my family suffer.
I want to kill that Madr
Strodinn with my bare hands.
Then I must be Frank
with you, brother.
I know you lost boats
in the storm,
but it's a pity you didn't
return with more men.
As it is, we have no chance
of defeating jarl Borg,
or regaining Kattegat.
Then we find more men.
There are no more to find!
Believe me, I've tried.
And what's more...
Is that news of your arrival
has only made our discovery
more certain.
Jarl Borg has placed
a fortune on your head.
(Angry sigh)
(People chatter, goats bleat) Woman: The
sheepskins are over in the shed over there.
(Hooves thunder)
Woman: Can you help here? Can
you help me lift this up?
(People chatter, goats bleat)
Jarl Borg: I am happy that
ragnar Lothbrok has returned.
It will be a pleasure
to fight him.
Surely the gods
will reward handsomely
anyone strong enough
to defeat him.
After all,
they have never taken kindly
on those who seek to join them,
pretending in their vanity
to be gods themselves.
Ragnar Lothbrok is one such,
and his vanity will kill him.
No, not his vanity.
I will kill him!
Men: (Boisterous cheering) Yeah!
(Distant metallic clanking)
♪
Athelstan: No, no, no,
no, (Screaming) Noooooo!
(Anguished screams)
♪
Saxons:
(Shouting and cheering)
Bishop Edmund: Here is
your destiny, apostate!
You are being crucified
in the name of our Savior,
Jesus Christ.
Amen.
Crowd:
Athelstan: (Shuddering in
pain) In manus tuas...
(Shuddering)
Domine commendo spiritum meum.
(Hooves thud)
Athelstan:
Please... please...
Ecbert:
Wait!
Man: It's the king!
Man and woman: Your majesty!
(Shuddering in pain)
Crowd: Your highness. Sire.
Your highness.
Must we really kill this man?
Bishop Edmund:
He is an apostate.
He has denied our Savior
Jesus Christ
and returned to pagan
and evil ways.
He has murdered
good christians.
I say he should die.
I say he should be crucified.
What do you all say?
Crowd: Crucify him! Crucify him!
Kill him!
Cut him down.
(Shuddering in pain)
Ecbert:
I said, cut him down!
(Gasping in pain)
(Hooves thud)
Floki:
Ragnar, they're here!
Floki: Ragnar, they're coming!
Helga: Who's coming?
Floki: Who do you think?
Jarl Borg and his men.
They've come to finish us off!
(Hooves thunder
in the distance)
♪
(Bird cries)
(Hooves thunder)
(Hooves clop, horse whinnies)
It has been a long time.
Hello, ragnar.
I heard of your troubles.
I have brought these warriors
to help you.
- Ragnar: And you are?
- Bjorn: I'm your s...
(emotional) Father!
I always knew in my heart
that I would see you again.
But I never guessed
it would be in
such circumstances.
Bjorn: Who can guess the
plans and ways of the gods?
But now they have contrived
to bring us back together
and I for one am glad for it.
Ha!
I do not need to ask
if you have been fed well.
You have grown so tall.
When this is over,
we shall have many stories
to tell.
You and I, father, are bound
both by ties of memory
and blood.
It seems your moth
and I have produced a son
that is both strong and wise.
And if my sister had lived,
she would have been the same.
Yes. And you are right
to carry her memory,
as do I.
For a long time, father,
I feel I have carried
nothing else but memories.
But now, here, in this place,
with you, and with my mother,
I feel... reborn.
As if I have a life to lead.
(Affectionate slaps)
Ragnar:
Far too long.
♪
(Warrior clucks his tongue,
hooves clop)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com