Memo, son, are you coming?!
Easy, easy...
Mum would not let you...
No, no... my sweet baby...
This is gonna burn, Memo!
Go and get some water.
Come on, dear! And bring some
bread. Dad will be coming soon.
Let us put the plates...
let us put...
don't, my honey,
don't my sweetheart...
Memo, get going, aren't you
listening to what I say!
Look, look...
Eh, why don't you go and get it?
- Ok.
Ok?!
- Ok, I'll go now.
No, my honey, no, my baby...
baby mine...
Where are you going?
What's up?
- Nothing much...
Leave that!
But you are going to show me?
- I will, once you come back.
You'll show me how to assemble
and dismantle it, all!
Come on, take care.
They are shelling like hell today.
Honey, come to me, honey!
- Come on, hold her for a minute.
Come on, sweetheart... Come on,
it's high time for you to go!
Take care, Memo!
Hey, boy...
Where is the video recorder?
- I'll get it to you!
What do you mean by that?
I'll pay for it.
What about the washing machine?
- I'll get that as well...
What about the spare part?
Fuck it...
Good afternoon, how are you!
- Good afternoon!
U want to get out?
- Later.
Halo!
- What is it?
Sniper...
- Let me go!
Hey, boy, has your dad
come from the trenches?
Tell him to come to Ahmo's.
They should introduce
the shifts... 24-48.
So that, when you come home...
you come home.
When I come home,
I have not time
to get the water warmed up
let alone use it all.
I mean it, trust me.
Leave the gun!
Look, there is Memo!
Where have you been, chap? What is up?
Listen! The guy with bread
will come now.
Here is a cigarette for you,
go and get us some bread, please
I want the gun!
- See Memo the merchant...
Come on, here are two for you,
I am left with one now...
Come on, get one loaf
for the two of us.
And what did your wife say?
Nothing, she told me to go to
the logistics... What did you play?
Come on, folks, go to the shelter.
They have started shelling again.
We have to eat!
Come on, you... why do you
always have to make trouble!
Don't get in!
Let me go!