This is just an automatic translation
of the Hungarian Subs...
... thats why it also still has so
many Hungarian words in it
since I do not speak Hungarian.
Maybe someone with some time
and a dictionary can correct the rest?
But better than nothing, so thank Zeph for the Hungarian Subs.
Have fun. - André
TIZENKETTÕ
Juror lords
...az delegated away bûncselekmény for his weight
megfelelõen
...a opposite a defendant can be imposed
the highest
...a opposite a defendant charges
Juror lords, Ön may have caught it the
bûncselekmény his weight
If they agree with the point of view of the charge,
the decision has to be taken:
bûnös, or not
The Russian folk made a lot because of that, that
let him unite it on this wide area
...amennyiben solid doubt
arises
...a büntetõ statute book relevant
in the sense of his section
Idõben you are not limited.
...visszavonul onto the discussion, where
You have to decide it the defendant
bûnösségét illetõen
...hogy for leaning them against monotone one
is needed to be.
I repeat it once more
for monotone one.
The highest punishment which can be imposed
...az opposite a convict applicable
highest punishment the relevant
in the sense of measures
...hogy for their decision anyway
...ennek the man's fate
...határozatot it has to be brought
...bûnös
...minden, the substance which is connected to the case
In case of their claim promptly
...amennyiben arises
Mom! Mother, speak in Russian! Mom!
Speak in Russian.
Speak in Russian, mother.
Mom!
Until the making of the jurors' decision
I order a pause.
I am asking it, let them be set up!
Being audible
Father, you are hungry?
Egyelõre is everything properly. Yes.
Says it I am asking it, the photographs, that the judge
showed, I may take it in?
I donot know.
- Do I have to stay here?
- Yes.
- But back I told everything already.
- Then, this order.
- With a word, juror lords
- This is a phantasm.
...kérem, let them delegate now.
Let them be struggling along, I am asking it, we have to get there the
until a twenty minutes break.
- Until a what kind of pause?
- Everything is found out immediately.
Let them not fall behind. After me, after me.
Here, I am asking it!
Let's go.
It is seen, the renovation yet not
fejezõdött in.
That room was not able to be finished yet,
where they should hold a meeting. Here, here!
After me.
The renovation, naturally good thing, but
he makes the work difficult.
This does not affect themselves, clear the case,
egyszerû their thing.
They decide under cca. 20 minutes, this here
actually an egyszerû thing.
Here more carefully, we go over now an
into an adjacent room.
A school put it at our disposal.
Court beside the school, rather much
he entails a problem.
Imagine only away:
Spring, is, the windows open,
a ball is flying in, directly the witness
into his forehead and ready - loses his consciousness.
An idõs nõ.
Not, the holiday was good on his time, splendid,
dared in the classes
Children! Children!
My god is sweet! Children! Children!
Children, I beg for it!
Let us withdraw here onto a side, a side.
Let everybody come here.
It is seen, between what kind of circumstances is needed
to work?
This only temporary, does not last until a lot.
If the renovation is finished, the court
egyszerûen will be magnificent.
Be going already. Faster!
Indulgence, this only egyszerû formality, but
all of the mobile telephones have to be passed.
This is in this manner unfortunately.
I withdraw it SIM card, a lot important
there is information on him.
- Being audible, Vaszja
- Persze-persze, onto the god's love.
...másfél onto a clock turn off.
Tell it Margarita Jakovlenának, that
I am on social work. Õ wanted this.
That is it.
I will be here throughout. If he would be need onto me,
from an any kind of reason,
this apparatus is here, with this may indicate.
This it I Know-How-m.
With a word, my invention.
From my son is, from the child railroad.
- It is not known, that mûködik?
- No.
Let everybody be listening
This button is pressed.
This will be at themselves.
If the smallest need is onto me, immediately
call in,
I will be here promptly, and I bring anything,
what they need only.
They will hold a meeting here. All conditions
given Kérem Ön.
Please.
Hands!
We this, we will hold a meeting in a gym?
I said it already, a renovation is going on there.
Somebody does not know it, how much idõ may be
to get out onto Kurszki állomásra?
So idõben.
At least one and a half clocks, but rather
an forty.
Go!
Let us come, throw it here!
- Are you sure?
- Get rid of it only, get rid of it!
- Since this
- Szpartak - the champion!
- Na, catch it!
- What was that?
- Himself was asking it.
This not too football ball, but
medicine-ball, it is not possible to play with this.
Does he talk about the lamp?
Anyway at us in the school
just like this is.
- You see that?
- Totally.
- Does not know it, where WC is here?
What there is now, in will be here closed?
These rules.
He is needed in this manner!
Look at it, already!
This why it was made with him?
- Sure, that let the children not ruin it.
- You are translated.
You are translated, in case the children
let them be wounded because of it.
He may drop behind.
Somehow not really lucky, that
there is a court beside the school.
He does not drop behind.
There is even a upright piano behind the grid,
and on the bench.
WC is here.
That is good.
Why it is abstained from, does not buy something?
Visibly mindannyiunknak set.
For us? Not shop,?
- Have bought! There is tea here with lemon.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
My business lunch will be today in Puskin.
Egyszerûen do not want elõre to be replete.
Next this does not last until so much,?
I do not believe it, this not that case.
I believe it in that manner.
It is a totally other case.
Mmm a curio. What gyönyörûség.
Dugi was on place. Let him imagine it,
I forgot it, was not idõm to change.
Annoying.
Principle collection pfuj!
My lords, let us set about it!
Let them be listening, elvtársak-pfuj-urak,
really his time to start.
Very little it idõnk.
- Does he hurry so much possibly?
- Not expressing.
My train leaves after a clock Nyizsnij-in,
next guest performance on Volga River.
He attains it certainly.
There is at most an a hour's work here.
- That toilet?
- Not, this here the boy WC, it there the
VIP.
Somebody can say a rhyme Júlia onto a word?
Júlia - fury.
But not, what kind of fury.
Júlia is a beautiful young girl.
Júlia? Tessék:
Pulja, sells it,
- Plots against it
- He digs it.
- No
- His school
- His school?
His school, his party, his mom, dad
Oh, my God!
- Today tizenkettedike is?
- That is right.
- The televí where the TV is?
- There he is.
- There?
An interview will be today with my mum!
Who is his own mum? Politician? Színésznõ?
- We it, not mûködik, or we?
- No.
We it, that not mûködik?
Not mûködik! Mum.
We have a family TV company, LTV his name.
Were they not audible from him?
My mum I am the president, me the
general manager, I help him.
With a word, a producer.
Na, caught this.
- Nahát, saw this?
- I apologise!
One like this was seen already?!
And yet only pupil!
- Aj-jaj-jaj.
The food is good sure.
I saw one like this only one times in my life.
Pupil at a girl?
Come on. Where thinks!
It is for my mother-in-law similar.
Was.
Not, 3 of his months I buried it.
This is a yes!
Little boys and little girls
- Let it be looked at, what I found!
- The reason stops!
Blow the song some people,
browse others.
Akceleráció!
Excuse me.
Sorry.
I lost it because of this monstrosity
my elder brother.
On 36 year ones!
So much szörnyûséget I saw it already.
Back, because of this.
Sorry.
Juror lords, let us make something already, that
let the ice be broken finally.
Let somebody guide it already down the parade!
- There are a yes, truth, let us begin it.
- Let us come, we start it already.
We have to assign it anyway, really an
levezetõ president.
THE zsûrinkben.
Everything comparing, himself experienced
looks like a man, let him be himself the vezetõnk.
- Telephone?
- Á, it gets it with the boiler room only together.
I asked already.
- If there is nobody against it, then
- No, No, No.
- ...én with pleasure.
It is known, that
We do not stain errõl to vote,?
- No, No.
- No.
With a word, it is known, that for our decision
has to be definitive will be definitive.
And an appeal will not be eligible.
And because of this I ask for attention!
Because of this kötelezõen is needed monotonously
to vote.
This all clear, we bring it only already
finally operatively our monotone decision.
We may be going next.
- Guest performance on Volga River.
- Everybody
Everybody may relate his opinion in a row,
next vote.
- No, No. Vote
- Afterwards? I
- Vote now immediately.
...véleményt to say.
- That is nobody protests?
- No, No.
- Not, we start it.
With a word to vote, generally,
may be with a show of hands,
or onto sheets of paper
- But not.
- We do it in this manner.
- Let him be a show of hands.
- Good.
- Vote.
- That is, this means it, with a hand vote?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yes, with a hand naturally.
I am asking it let him put up his hand, who beside it.
There is one single question, the beside it
beside what it is.
Meaning?
The reports it beside it, that bûnös,
or it, that innocent.
Naturally it, that bûnös.
I I believed it, the beside it
he is besides us starting the vote.
We will vote for it now, that already
vote.
I this egyszerûen I do not understand it.
- Already vote.
- I donot understand. I donot understand.
In that direction, that bûnös.
- I donot understand.
- I this
Let their hand be put down, this my mistake.
This vote invalid, this my mistake.
My mistake, I apologise.
So let their hand be put down.
We vote for it with a word, that the defendant
bûnös.
- Yes.
The elevated hand means it bûnös?
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Not, I wanted to correct it only, that
let us not make a mistake.
Lift it up then your hand and you do not make a mistake.
The underground at themselves, were altogether
gyûlések?
Of course! Steadily!
- Na, let us come, vote already!
- Come on!
Why vote elõször in that direction, that bûnös?
What is the difference?
- Not, but
- What is the difference?
That not likes.
It may be this disturbs himself?
Not, totally all the same. I believed it only,
is in this direction some kind of rule.
Not, there is an any kind of rule here.
May be in this manner, reversely.
Is not needed reversely, let us come already.
Only vote already egyszerûen.
Let us vote for it let it be finished! Vote
in that direction, that the defendant bûnös.
- Yes.
- I am asking it to put the hands up.
Monotone! This much, I am going.
Not, not, let him stop!
But my lords, I am asking it, there are rules because of that.
A kindergarten is clear.
Let him sit down, I am asking it.
Let them lower their hand.
Let it be made already down finally their hand
And now, who votes for it, that the defendant
Let us observe the rules.
...ártatlan.
I am asking it let their hand be raised.
Donot
So, 11 May I?
Eleven in that direction, that "bûnös",
and an in that direction, that not bûnös".
- This is a yes!
- Then we now mirõl voted?
Oh! Let it be looked at now
This man was confused totally.
We voted on it, that this the stinking
Chechen bastard bûnös, the nevelõapja,
against the Russian army's officer
he delegated away in a murder.
You donot get it, do you?
The comrade did not understand it. We have to vote it
once more.
- Somehow
- Everybody
No. Not, not, not, I
No. I corrected it. I am against it.
Against the charge.
We it, that against it?
Themselves voted a yes, I though against it.
Why?
Well developed in that manner, that eleven
Beside it, an though against it.
But why?
How come why?
Why voted in this manner?
If I would have voted a yes, then
tizenkettõ would be beside it and
an neither against it.
And we could all go home.
But back this good.
Why does he vote against it then?
Let him vote for it and we go home.
I De, this somehow too fast.
Understand? Express, somehow.
Why express? Be listening, until three days
we listened to this woman.
Do you call this an express?
No Yeah, but
but I got frightened, somehow
We put up our hand somehow, suddenly.
This is too fast somehow. Is it understood?
But back it the good, if express.
Everything clear, proven on all of them.
We heard all of the testimonies,
we saw the evidences.
Yeah, but
But any kind of,
it is only a man after all there.
We somehow, hand up and and his end.
After all, what wants actually?
Want
at least to talk about him at least.
To talk about him.
Let him speak.
Sorry. This American jury
his formula:
The deficiency of a solid doubt.
Egyszerûen I studied at Harvard only
management and I kept silent an short
course from the right.
The sense of the talk would be then,
if the deficiency of a doubt would not be solid.
Was it heard? A doubt is solid!
We do not have doubts.
What kind of doubts?
Destroyed it - this fact.
A retired position cruelly
murders his foster son something
because of a ridiculous sum!
- Yeah!
- Then mirõl we speak?!
Let them be listening, this man on Harvard
completed and there is nothing for him his doubt.
He is not for the others.
Himself
- Let him say it already.
- Let them forgive I am asking it, understand.
It had me, of course, Harvard
Himself, goes away to buy melon onto the market.
Me?
No, No, No. Me.
I go to buy melon onto the market.
The vendor very much meggyõzõen says it, that
the melon ripened and beautiful, but
till then, you do not take it home and up not
you kill it, very heavy to judge, how.
However here, here not an dinnyérõl
there is a word!
The melon who may be végülis to get rid of
into the garbage.
Since Tud, this man
a punishment lasting for life threatens it,
we now all of them we elect it and
õt it is imprisoned forever.
And never comes out from there.
It is understood altogether?! Never.
Let them reflect on him only into this word!
So-ha does not come out from there.
And is in this manner properly.
Why would he be needed some other way? Killer!
We should send it onto Thailand possibly to be on holiday?
Let him be glad that there is not death penalty already.
He learns it then in the prison.
Good.
Be
I do not want to steal their time,
vote once more.
If I am left alone again, than it elõbb,
I stain likewise to vote, than the others.
And let a boy fare for this
shape,
végülis I will know it, that at least
I tried to make something for him.
A step is interesting! So practically himself
makes the same one, than the others,
while he believes it rightfully, that the himself
his hand is clear. Did he believe it in this manner?
Yes.
In that manner tûnik, in this manner.
Only that request of mine, that the vote
let him be secret.
But why?
Õszintén? I pull it it idõt.
It is necessary to catch the paper, the feather, throughout
it is necessary to believe it - this means minutes.
Besides very often vote in that manner,
that let them not stick out from the row.
I ask him it in exchange for this to be the vote
secret.
Secret, open - the result then
obvious.
Well, back a proposal arrived secret
onto vote.
- Do they agree?
- Yes.
- Then
- With these,?
Yes, yes, the paper, the pencil are caught,
the feathers are here.
If may vote, we look at it then only
Is there everybody on his place? Immediately
As if somebody is missing.
That lord went out onto WC, I saw.
I saw, onto my word of honour.
Not, back what let us be waiting?
Vote!
- Old man already
- We start it, good?
It already true, while he finds it,
pí-pí, his prostate, adenoma
...aztán to pack
the equipment.
Instead of a urn, onto vote.
Vote!
I look at it in that manner, this all for himself
not novelty.
Old, not to be a pensioner boring
I sit in the holiday house, I paint water-colours.
Na I hold a meeting on the court sometimes.
Mûvész,?
What kind of mûvész. I paint water-colours,
only in that manner mûkedvelõként.
Did everybody pass his paper?
- Everybody voted?
- Not, we waited for himself.
My grandfather says it:
With peeing and the labour -
it is not possible to wait for it.
Let them not be worried, I will be fast.
Practically revival.
Thank you.
- Apology, apology.
- No problem.
Back we reckon it up then.
Bûnös
Innocent
Then back, according to ten "bûnös",
an against it.
Kettõ.
According to Kettõ innocent.
That kettõ? Wait a minute.
It cannot be!
He gives the sheets.
Ellenõrizzük only down
No. Is not needed nothing ellenõrizni.
I was it, who in that manner voted, that the
a young man is innocent.
That-how?
Five of his minutes voted for it yet,
that the kid bûnös.
Elsõre in that manner tûnt, that the question egyértelmû.
And what there is now, not egyértelmû?
Not, I may not say it, that not
egyértelmû,
but this man called, that let me buy it
onto myself the felelõsséget it õ for his decision.
And it is known, I reflected.
Mirõl?
Let him not be angry, but himself did not have me.
This is some kind of Jewish logic.
He is in this manner perfectly.
I am Jewish.
A hundred are Jews in a percentage.
For all men,
I have many deficiencies,
but I have a virtue, and it is known,
this a Jewish characteristic was born,
...elgondolkodni.
I hold a high opinion of this.
I reflected, and I went away onto WC.
To think.
And it is known, to doubt I started.
Why?
The lawyer.
What is there with the lawyer?
He was bored.
Would have been Mitõl jókedvû?
This Chechen monster killed his father.
It was my impression, that altogether
he did not protect the defendant.
And correct, how did not protect it, what
was not why to protect.
Exactly. Exactly.
Was not why. The boy is penniless.
The lawyer's eyes empty,
his face is bloated.
He was not able to work altogether.
Himself did not like the lawyer,
because not Jew?
Alcoholic, but honest - did not leave it,
that let the killer come out from the loop.
For himself suddenly in that manner tûnt
Let him cross himself, if something in that manner tûnik.
Ten felnõtt for a man not tûnt up nothing,
for himself suddenly, from one of the moments
onto the other one, yes.
- In the loo.
- Punctually, in the loo tûnt in that manner.
I can be thinking well there.
Everybody can be thinking well there.
Why is he agitated?
Let him not be agitated.
Themselves are on ten here, we only
two people. We should be agitated.
I am nervous though.
Knows it, I am agitated.
And I am not top notch not to be agitated.
Because I see it, himself the Jew
gets this tangled up with his tricks the totally
clear case.
Himself did not like the lawyer already.
There is something, modifies it immediately
his opinion.
Since this typical
typically Jew.
Na enough! I my own opinion not
I modified it, I am Jewish half though.
There are not Jews half.
This now good, you are bad?
For you countryman certainly
he is not doing well.
An, kettõ, three, four, five
Watch the boy being glad about your gift.
Umarik!
Umarik, come to dine,
Vologya arrived uncle.
All right. Let them listen, they agreed now
a good, neat, naive man,
...akit onto their own side claimed.
We the curl rhymes with a word?
- What?
- Curl, hair, rhyme.
Let him leave this now.
Curl - treasure.
Perfectly am gyõzõdve from that direction,
that who we can be acting uniform
opinion.
It pulls it only idõt and say yet
some example tale from that direction, how is needed
to select the melon.
You are now just how is needed
to buy fresh fish.
True, I do not understand it we from an aim.
Let him impose us on new one to repeat
all that, that already 3 of his days we keep silent
on the court,
all 100%-os evidence for this the
for a villain the bûnösségérõl,
what he cannot disprove, what
irrefutable.
So what?
It idõs a lord goes away once more the
onto a loo and thinks through it once more,
it modifies his decision
onto one single correct one.
Let it be believed, will be in this manner.
In no way some other way.
I do not understand it only, we he makes sense
for this it idõhúzásnak?
Let us start revising the testimonies again?
Himself is not a blind deaf-mute.
Since sat in the conference room there,
he saw that bastard on his prisoner have dock.
Says it: We talk it over, back then
we speak it.
On him, we talk it over.
What kind of words may say to this brute
in his protection, onto which is not and not too
may be any kind of excuse?
A what kind of excuse this may have the
for a monster, who raised a hand, the
nevelõapjára, onto a retired position?
And not only egyszerûen raised his hand against him,
but slaughters it, than a lamb.
Understand? Killed that man, who
ensured him, cipõt, bought dresses
for him, raised it.
Killed the man who nothing is
he did not do bad for him!
Not only that nothing, but just
ellenkezõleg, adopted it as a son, saved it!
And does not count, why destroyed it, the
for his cheap pension, or an shouted
for an insult.
This is uninteresting for me.
I do not know it how they are with him, but for me this
he does not fit into my head.
I would not be able to say one single word to this
onto the excuse of the garbage.
For this garbage!
I believe it in that manner nobody would be top notch here,
themselves would not be top notch.
Why was needed then into this whole one
to start it? I
Sorry.
I had a wife
We leave the wives késõbbre.
He was three for me.
Wait! Wait!
Was my wife and I loved very much õt.
Ate a piece of meat - destroyed it because of this.
- Yes. Yes. Yes.
- Vegetarian.
Wait! Wait!
I loved very much õt.
Csertanovoban was a change of our room,
practically without furniture.
We had to dine on the floor yet, because
was not ebédlõasztalunk.
Kezdõ I was a scientific colleague it
in one physical Tudományos Kutató Intézet
and I drew up an own idea.
My wife was obliged because of this three
to work on a workplace, that
let us be successful somehow.
Shortly, I invented it a new tunnel-diódát.
This would be complicated to explain what should do.
In the institute praise, gave 50 rubles
premium, and it was recommended, deal
with something else.
In this manner back I leaded home my three-year work
his result, the 50 rubles.
My wife looked at me with a look like that,
One of the big western firms offered it,
that buys my patent,
for a huge sum.
But I - not! I wanted it, that it here,
at us mûködjön.
I went onto the other one from one of the offices,
I offered it, it was called me:
This nagyszerû"
Nobody needs him!
For nobody!
I started drinking. Awfully.
I lost my work, leafed the
my wife, for me was nothing
it is important apart from drinking.
In the morning, in daytime, in the evening.
Reggeltõl until a night terribly drunk
was! He was Szörnyû.
I felt in that manner once, that soon
I die.
And it is known, I was glad about this yet
for the thought.
Altogether not alarmed.
I wanted only one - mielõbb.
And I started looking for the death.
Onto my word of honour, was in this manner.
I started looking for the death.
I fought the rendõrökkel, I found fault with it
into the peoples, the neighbours.
Beat, knife.
I worked the night in doorways, in hospitals
I tossed!
Beat, onto bloody one beaten!
It doesnot matter. I climbed out.
At home, than an házõrzõ dog,
I lick away at my wounds,
and I struggle out again.
An valamitõl I am concerned about it - to jump in front of a train
and to spring out from the window. Ettõl somehow
I am concerned about it. I donot know why.
I am concerned about it.
I traveled by the train once, terribly
drunk, dirtily, stinkingly.
He was stuffed with peoples.
I found fault with the peoples again.
I was yelling, I swore!
And it is known, I was watching myself kívülrõl
and I rejoiced.
On my own obscenity - I rejoiced!
I dreamed about only a thing, that
let there be at least a man,
who would catch and would throw out from the train
during procession.
In that manner, that my head crush on the rails.
Onto pieces.
Not, everybody was sitting only and kept silent.
Their head was turned away, but they were sitting
and they kept silent.
An nõ with his exception, who is an one around five years
he traveled with a little girl.
I heard it, the little girl said it:
Mom, the uncle õrült, I am afraid tõle".
The nõ though it responded:
Not, õ not õrült,
he is very badly only.
I sold my technology an western
for a firm.
This mûködik practically on all of them the second
in a mobile telephone.
I though - I am for this company the
képviselõje. But not this the important.
It the nõ, now my wife,
the little girl - my daughter.
We have even a boy.
Four are year.
Did he finish it?
No, not yet.
May be, that for that boy the
he has to die in a prison.
May be, who knows that this is his fate.
Since for me under the fence
I should have died.
But I did not die.
A man dared Egyetlen!
...figyelmesebb was to me,
than all the others.
And did not allow it, that in outrage and
let me stay in solitude.
I finished it now.
Well
this is the moving story of a rescue.
But this his own story.
And himself destroyed nobody.
This though here - the story of a murder,
with one-hundred-percent evidences the boy
bûnösségét illetõen.
His old testimony from the lower flat,
who heard the quarreling and
the boy's shouting: I will kill you!.
The boy says that he did not destroy it
the nevelõapját.
Why, what should say?
Did I destroy it?
Back we would not ride it here then.
For me õszintének tûnnek his words.
Since knows it hardly even in Russian
to express.
Enough! What?!
Mirõl they speak?!
Here let them keep silent! Embe! Totally!
I spit on the fact that he speaks in Russian!
Already indulgence, but themselves all felnõtt
peoples, they are not ashame of themselves,
let them be watching already circle!
Since this already not too our city!
Everything was occupied!
Everything. The markets, the casinos,
the hotels. Everything is theirs!
I tried to drive it over yesterday with my Volga River
on Teatralnij keresztutcán
Eight are lanes! Eight lanes - and all stuffed!
The Bentley-jeik, Mercedes-eik, it is understood,
it is not possible to go over!
There some wedding party was kept -
you sing, they danced,
just only not lõttek the levegõbe
with the Kalasnyikov reason!
And all this three! Under the three minute roads
Ljubjankától!
This is not Moscow already! This anything -
Baku nought, anything, but not Moscow!
And I, I, was born Moscow, here, the
myself find it strange in my own city!
Myself feel it in that manner, as if in company
would be!
But back for that boy we his alley to this?
What boy? What is there already with the boy?
Tries to protect it,?
Imagine only away, let him remember him,
was a word from that direction, that elõzõleg
did he fall out with his father?
Let us imagine a Russian kid. What
makes in this case a Russian kid?
May be, that to bully tooth, megsértõdik,
na and finally, I do not know it, escapes possibly
from home!
But does not take a knife in his hand!
That savage, his own barbarian boy,
that animal, conceals his offence, because of that,
that let him recur and cuts his throat off.
Embarks the knife!
Back it is known, this because of that after all exaggeration!
Barbarians.
After all the XXI. we live in a hundred.
Next it would not be necessary to exaggerate it in this manner
the things.
We, anyway, we make very big work.
Who it the themselves? Who are you? Who?
Who are you?
Democratic erõk.
That how?
How erõk?
I agree on the other hand.
Not, I not from that direction in connection with Az
Scum these! Scum.
In private - normal, but if in more
are old-old-old
This train is here, I travel, freedom.
Four beasts, one aim a knife at me
rob, kettõ holds my hand down,
the fourth rummages in my pockets.
Not from that direction there is a word, that scared
I got frightened.
That psychopath called off with the gas.
I came to myself - Simferopol.
Na, next Lovustban,
kettõt in the bazaar
Yeah. - I say it.
Recognize, they came for me directly,
my thongs started being licked away at.
Ours összegyûltek, it was fenced in.
Repelled, I caught it, in this manner,
I save it, I leaded away
And I kicked into an ass, in this manner na!
My foot was strained, I was top notch hardly
to go home.
My loin hurts. I
Is himself a doctor?
I am a surgeon.
Thank you.
Not, surgeon egyelõre is not needed,
then kenõccsel I am smearing it.
Scum these! Scum.
If he did not commit a murder once, not all the same,
how speaks in Russian,
respected juror lords?
Right.
You like that?
I love it.
Look at it, how beautiful.
Thank you.
Umar! Umar!
Come on!
I said it, come home!
Do not be angry, my father calls lesson to make.
Do not be worried, my son, even you get even your share of him ebbõl
from the war.
Hé, my friend, it do not teach it at a school
to fight.
What you said my friend? Törõdj the own
with your thing
We are at home, we are successful somehow
because of our seed.
Come home, Umar!
Wolf-cub, be added to me.
Let's go.
Who his head behind a woman's skirt
hides it, elsõként will lose it.
...egy, kettõ, three, four, five
Anyway, I demanded it in order for it to be brought here
the knife, with which the murder was committed.
Why?
Dared only on the court steadily it
it was stressed that this is some kind
extraordinary knife, special.
And that
I say thank you for it thankfully.
And that, supposedly only for that boy
he was like this.
Let them remember.
On the court whole idõ it was said,
that this some kind of unique knife.
Egyszerûen is special.
That is it.
Let it be allowed only!
A special knife is a yes, this.
Single special rendeltetésû
subunits he may be systematized.
Emerson with an American sample is similar féle
"CQC7 close combat onto a knife.
Old, with a name provided.
The kid Csecsenföldrõl may have brought it
this knife.
It is possible to obtain it on the black market yet there.
It is not possible to buy a knife like this in Moscow.
This knife terrible pervasive erõvel
he takes action.
OH! Not nothing!
FATHER
MOTHER
The situation it, that
...a special unit õrnagya was.
His subunit just on that area
he fought where the defendant lived.
Picked the boy up, adopted it next.
- Did he lose something possibly?
- No
- And what there is if these are the armed men,
...katonák, just õk it was murdered the
a boy's parents?
This is a motive. Motive to the murder.
Yes, yes, of course, but the situation it, that
the nevelõapja knew it since five of his year ages
the boy.
He was good at a friendship with his parents.
Not, I in connection with the knife.
Who does he belong to?
It is known, the drop caps are there.
And these the kezdõbetûk they do not pass
one szereplõhöz neither.
Rare knife, it was kept in the house and
the kid dragged it along with himself always.
His companions saw the knife, this at him declared
on the court.
Yes, you talk about it steadily, that this
an exceptionally rare knife. Special.
Look at it, a what kind of picture starts taking shape.
- What is he looking for?
- I find it in no way
Did I not lose it only?
Was walking with a word, was walking, was walking, once
somebody goes there to it only and says it:
Be listening boy, you do not know it accidentally
where is it possible to get a so good knife here?
In this direction õ: Back I would know it sure!
Is for me, good knife this, rare, special.
Sold it, chance purchase, yes.
The boy sold the knife, the man bought it,
he went away to kill his father next.
Curly is crystal clear.
- What?
- Nonsense, nonsense.
Stand, stand, stand.
But back money was found in his pocket - 7 thousand.
7 thousand - so exactly so much, than it
a father's pension, which he obtained same day,.
But what kind sold? What kind of knife?
Destroyed it and robbed it.
To keep silent the defendant kid's little tales -
a thing is meaningless.
- Other knife like this egyszerûen impossible
here to obtain, children.
- I found it!
Thank God. It is known, small the key
and I believed it lost.
He hid in my pocket though.
I thought that the knife is unique,
special.
And, that may have been at that boy only.
Let it be looked at only.
Here.
Oops!
An it in one.
There is even an account from him.
It was said that it is this only,
special and that was for the boy only
so.
It was on Extrém piacon -
totally freely.
So what?
What does this prove? That it on the suckle
did he not kill his father?
Not, this proves nothing.
Is it allowed to smoke here?
- Why not? We are locked
- Give I am asking it a thread.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- This proves nothing.
- Na is well, is well,
- My task was totally other.
...találta this knife.
- Not, I bought it.
- Good, bought it, bought it. What is the difference?
I believe it - bought it. Nowadays anything may be
for money to have bought, even rocket rack.
Yes! Tells me it, how proves it
this it, that the person who bought it from the boy
the knife,
is it the killer just?
May I? This in no way
This does not prove it, only dot
interrupted.
Thank you.
I wanted to say it, that for this knife
the charge was his individuality fõ his argument.
Let them remember only.
It lightens up though now - it is possible to buy one like this
egyszerûen.
So what? What doe that mean?
This means it, that the investigation not too
it was conducted conscientiously.
- It may be him then that the others are a fact
- The lawyer.
The lawyer. Was not what to say.
A shape is frivolous. He was not able to save.
And what there is what there is if it is who
bought the knife - it destroyed it.
Oh, my God!
Countryman, mitõl your brain is on his place
is a cheese melted?
Who bought it Valaki destroyed it. You yourself
what is what you say for you at least?
Five of his minutes are not yet, that a book-keeping
drew here for us.
Who killed it yet and robbed it.
But for who for something else, than for that hybrid,
in his stood interest to kill the retired
õrnagyot for his pension?
Knows it, I would listen to it in his own place
the "Metróépítõ"- and a colleague's opinion.
- Knows it, himself is thinking in that manner
- Than a Jew?
Why, would like me thinking in that manner,
than former Jasser Arafat?
- All right. Not, but, let him be waiting, let him be waiting
- This is good!
All right. Good, this worker man said
some folly, but why himself needs him
to support?
Knows it, does not say a folly.
A back knows it, these tricks
jellemzõek.
If Jew did not say the folly -
is properly, if though Jew - then
already not folly.
All right. The knife - tallies, punctually
just like that - I agree.
But the man, who bought this knife,,
the abbot destroyed it with him next - it we,
is a coincidence chance likewise?
Are two chance after each other? Na this already
impossible, so is not.
So may not turn elõ never.
Knows it, I a time of his I believe it in that manner, that it
everything is possible in a life.
Absolutely on all of them, even it,
what is impossible.
My father
he was in a ghetto under the war.
- Does himself want to tell a story to us about the holocaust?
- Not, from my father.
Lithuanian SS was stationed there just
one are his subunits.
Was a position there, for who an gyönyörû
his wife was Lithuanian.
My father skinny man
Am I seen? - You would eat trebly worse.
Indulgence, külsõleg it himself resembles his father?
Not, onto my mother. My mother was not likewise
a beauty, but at my father because of that more beautiful.
And back my father, onto his ruin, fell in love with it.
I do not know it, what was biting him, but
he fell in love with this Lithuanian beauty.
And õ, õ too fell in love with my father,
than a girlie.
It can be imagined, what would have been with them,
if ours, it do not come Russians?
It SS-es escaped the Reich-in,
his wife was left with my father.
Oh, my God.
Mindkettõjüket számûzték into Siberia,
into compulsion camps, long idõre.
They broke out in 1953, it was found
each other and they got married.
They settled down in a little village, somewhere
Near Vilnius and it was started excitedly
to produce the children.
Eleven men.
This elõtt of course my father, garbage on a manner,
he left my mother.
But I understand it õt.
Elõször, I saw his photograph.
I saw his photograph.
Secondly though
my mother was not likewise an fõnyeremény.
His mother - not fõnyeremény.
Touching story.
If somebody would tell this story to me,
I would believe him it in no way.
But this occurred with my father.
Everything possible.
Everything.
Stand, stand. Stop!
Not dubious, that everybody has him the
his story is own.
Everybody digs his garden on his own manner.
And holds the shovel on his own manner.
Well Na, back
Back, if themselves would know it
I have a uncle, a relative.
In a small town beside an edge, Voronyezs,
lakatos-vízvezetékszerelõ.
He has a golden hand! Ready, neat
All of the city with a word with him
Back, in that manner. Õ was sipping, of course.
But not malicious. Not it, that
Every now and then.
Is there in the centre
there is a space.
It was set up there the, establishment
With a word, to play with it it
with an automaton, for money.
"Testvér-nek it is called. Sibling.
Na, Kolja a uncle was playing never, now
here the payment, drank of course, next there.
There. With a word, lost, lost everything
it last kopejkáig.
How I am going now home, - believed it -
Ljubához, to my wife, how I say it
for him, that I lost all of the money.
How? Egyszerûbb, if he hangs himself.
Good peoples told it in confidence-is here not far
an office, it is possible to put on money for a credit there.
In this direction õ there. It is said there - our trump.
But onto only a year, an interest.
And less, than 50 thousand, may not give.
Catch it if he is needed it fifty, if not,
go into the hell.
Õ, Nincs what to do, it catches it
50 thousand and direction again the sibling.
And lost everything! All 50 thousand.
Now next we be
For him now even
The office is bright daytime, a direction.
The fõnök says it:
Are a thousand 50? We it, went crazy?
Went crazy?! Na be waiting only! -
home, weapon, small shot
And back. The fõnök by that time somewhere
he escaped.
The book-keeping is a direction. There all nõ.
Hármójukat takes it hostage,
he becomes terrorist.
Forces it egyikõjüket to put out an
bucket onto the porch with a tag.
There his claim: 57 thousand rubles, flat
in the élite quarter, fõmérnöki arrangement,
and an repülõ an tetszõlegesen granted
onto a dot.
Why he needs him fõmérnöki arrangement, if
does he want to fly away once?
Na, but this not important.
This is not important.
The women - Kolja uncle, what you do,
look at it
Õ like that ajajaj,
cannot sound nothing.
The women caught it, the safe was opened,
800 rubles were withdrawn,
one ran away for vodka, brought for,
is afraid with a chest, ice-cream
There already the rendõrség, marksmen!
Aim the terrorist, nothing, tûz!
In this direction the rendõr commander - Stop!
Onto no case! Le with the weapons!
Then I, personally
This is the man though!
Went there, alone, unarmed
Kolja a uncle aims the weapon at his stomach
- I destroy you. In this direction õ - do not kill.
I destroy you.
Do not kill.
It again - I destroy you.
Why?
Because I am the commander -
the commander said it.
Kolja a uncle threw away the weapon.
They sat down beside the chest and they drank.
They were crying.
No court, no investigation.
Apology, why told it actually
away for us all this?
Back, that Ha
In a normal case,
it would have been necessary to send it into a prison, on a brain
would have been needed lõni. Terrorist!
The rendõr commander
What is a man! This is the man though!
...nem nothing.
Kolja a uncle works, his debt
he paid it off. I helped a small one for him.
The rendõr commander elõléptették,
he was a businessman.
The sibling t kindled it.
Somebody else, not Kolja uncle.
Not, this nagyszerû, only quasi,
we everything has something to do with our case?
If Hogyha
I am beside the good one.
Igeeen! You next quickly blew out,
sibling.
This is not needed, is not needed, for me here not
there is a melted cheese.
The neat one has to help it, the bad one
Hells!
Vote - the Chechen child not bûnös.
Let him write it down. Thank you.
Back, knows it this elképesztõ!
From what kind of jurisdiction may be here
to speak?
The locksmith Kolja is running around on a Bács drunk
in the city!
The rendõrfõnök, Ljosa uncle vodkázik with him!
The urban prosecutor, Vaszja uncle, eye
he naps above all these.
The bûnözõ is left at large!
And all this like that idõkben, when it is whole
civilized world already since centuries
he lives according to laws!
The Russian man never stains in the life
to live according to the laws.
Why?
He is boring for him according to the law.
The law - dead person.
There is nothing personal in him.
The Russian man, personal contacts
- useless.
Neither to steal, neither õrizni.
Since this terrible!
And who said that this is good?
Let this pipe, this horror be looked at.
Since this pornography!
Real pornography in Moscow's centre,
in a school incidentally, where children
they study.
It believes them építõknek, who
make forget fûtéscsöveket to build
to an apartment house,
when you go to themselves, was doing here already
the school it would be necessary to tear their hand, their foot out.
Into a prison to close. All of them.
According to this law. But they are here the
personal contacts. Human. Russians.
It was talked over with the school, that
temporarily on a terrible manner like this
this pipe is fixed.
Temporarily. It, that all this how
szörnyû has an effect on the pupils,
already because of their childhood
The bra was left because of this possibly
in WC.
...nem excites nobody!
Na and how the law comes here?
The human contacts.
Tessék, let them take delight!
Inventory number 721799
Eaglet úttörõtábor, 1967.
I was not born yet.
Well?! How about this? What?
40 years passed. 40 are years!
We we cannot come out hitherto
from the coma.
Into the sack the eternal champions of running.
Over. The train left.
The others left, I I stayed here.
And vote - the Chechen child not bûnös.
Let him write it down. And dot.
The good
Their good sweet mommy!
We this what there is with themselves, what mûvelnek?
- I, anyway, I join likewise!
- This is a circus!
Writes it only down!
- On him, let us join all of them!
- Very interesting.
I believe it in that manner, that the boy not bûnös!
Yes. And for me, anyway, solid
I have doubts.
Explains it to us if he destroyed it and
cleaned it out the nevelõapját,
why recurred with this money the
bûncselekmény onto his site?
Really.
A vulgar killer does not make one like this.
Let him listen, let him listen
Na is well
But back himself, himself a normal man,
is it a dean that he may speak one like this?
We it, that vulgar killer does not do
one like this? Yes, an vulgar is not going
back, but this yes.
Because this an stupid, mûveletlen savage.
Who climbed down yesterday from the tree only.
What is wanted, that õ it finds it out
"Azazel"- t?
But back themselves know it, that for these the
the comprehension of games like that, than
that of a canary.
Do not be angry already, I am asking you, but in no way
I do not understand it, who himself calls a savage?
- I came from Caucasus for example.
- Knows that this does not mean it
And Shota Rustaveli? Is Õ a savage?
- Is Piroszmanisvili a savage?
- How comes here?
Szergej Paradzsanov, Danelija?
- Who does himself call a savage?
- I not Shota Rustavelirõl I speak.
- I talk about that bastard, who
he killed his father!
- I, I I talk about myself.
Because I came from Caucasus. Here,
I did it in Moscow the fõiskolát,
after all everybody "tuskó-nak faithful.
I am not a trunk though,
but surgeon.
I am a doctor, I have an own clinic.
Understood? Yes.
- Not kétlem, that own.
- Yes.
Does not stain of course, apparently already
as a local doctor to work in the hospital.
Understand? This not thing like that, than to travel here
from Caucasus, to buy a degree.
Who? Who bought it?
I bought it?!
- I bought it?!
- I do not talk about himself.
- Be waiting, only, I asked you!
- Not from himself
- Be waiting only, I talk to you! I in that manner
I bought my degree, yes?!
Me. Never. Nothing! And senkitõl I did not buy it!
Do you understand?!
Altogether, that dares?!
How may allow one like this to himself, we?!
Only negyedszerre raise the Moscow
Fõiskolára is medical science!
And those four years, I got in,
I worked as a nurse throughout the urban
In 1. No. hospital, yes!
The mentõknél I worked, the sürgõsségin!
And I finished a golden degree! Is that clear?
Eh, with a red degree, na.
Na what there is, I do not speak too well in Russian,
na and? What is there then?
I made a mistake, I told it,
I apologised already.
I am a good doctor on the other hand! Is that clear?
- I do not dispute it. Himself is a good doctor.
- Yeah!
- A doctor is good!
I do not understand it only, that himself, an good
doctor, why votes for it, that bûnös?
If there at themselves, in Caucasus for everybody
he has a golden degree and all like that mûveltek.
Why?
Just because of that vote in this manner, because unprecedented
onto the single Caucasus number of an evil deed,
if somebody raises a hand it idõsebbre.
Particularly then, if it illetõ called
into his own house, his own family.
My friends, my friends, my friends.
But my lords
Comrades I do not know it
na, let us come onto a man's manner, so help me God, na
This already yet an.
Not bûnös, bûnös.
Let us come, onto a man's manner.
Let us all come everything elõröl,
let us vote for new one, calmness.
Everything jegyzõkönyvezünk, that
let him be clear.
We start it, good? That vote?
With a show of hands?
- Yes, let us come.
- Yes, with a hand.
- Then tessék.
Who there is beside it, that the defendant not bûnös?
- An, kettõ
- What? How?
- Not bûnös.
Let him be more attentive. Not bûnös.
An, kettõ,
three,
four,
five.
Who there is beside it, that the defendant bûnös?
An, kettõ, three, four, five, six.
Woe, seven.
Seven beside it
Five beside it, that not bûnös",
seven, that "bûnös".
This will be here the this will be the borderline,
here, yes.
We test everything with a word tükörszerûen
to develop.
- Says it I am asking it, himself
- Yeah?
...ezt found out the whole one because of that,
that betûrõl-betûre let him recall it
the bygones?
Come on. Betûrõl-betûre.
How could he be?
They are above each other.
We test it tükörszerûen to develop,
for the draft megfelelõen.
Much or little punctually.
Here let him keep silent, the old man, the lower neighbour
heard it, when the little boy it howled:
I will kill you!
Heard the sound of the falling body next and
seeing, the little boy escapes.
It is said, I am asking it, was from among themselves somebody
on the site of the murder?
Of course not.
It is known, I went there it elsõ negotiation
after a day. Myself caught it and I went there.
Because I wanted to look at it, what kind of house it,
where the inhabitants stayed in only two flats there.
The murder happens in one, the
the eyewitness of the murder lives in other one.
- And nobody else.
- Na and what there is then?
We this has something to do with our case?
The situation it, that beside the house
building operations leak.
A élite house is being built. Very many machines
gyûlt there together.
The building operations are continued day and night.
So what? Day and night.
With a word, it can be imagined how large a noise there is
on a building operation, which it is according to a word,
does he leak under their window?
And why says all this?
The old man claims that the boy heard it
his cry: I will kill you! and something heavy
the fall of a thing.
And recognized the boy's sound resolutely
he said it in this manner in his testimony.
Heard it, yes!
So what? What is there then?
It is, that all of my respect the witness's,
but I cannot believe this.
Let us wait for a moment, wants it with a word
to say that the old man is an oath on the court
, lied deliberately?
Communist, old school, neither word,
neither speech defamed it innocent
Chechen boy.
You are a back if somebody lied under an oath
without it, then they dot the communists.
They lied above and beneath, egytõl until one.
It elõjogok for his mood, the mood of the power
you are only in that manner, from habit.
I am asking it, we leave this now at least.
They were all kinds of peoples.
My father onto Területi Bizottság secret
he was Uralban.
Mirõl themselves speak?
What kind of elõjogok?
We did not see it until years at home. Fifty-year-old
onto his age his heart was used up.
When it was pensioned off though,
he perished under three months.
It was spat out, than an chewed
piece of paper! Mirõl they speak
What kind of elõjogok.
Says it I am asking it, how we are doing here, successful?
- In that manner tûnik, is similar.
Well, we worked up two alike flats.
His images for each other.
I say it, that these under each other
are, because of this with an alike type.
The old man claimed it in his statements,
that the "bûncselekmény in his moment
lay in the room on a sofa
Not, I do not see nothing.
We speak immediately.
What is this how? Electric train.
I call you back then.
- Called in?
- Could not be Gyújt light be
kind, we read the testimonies.
- We make an experiment.
- Since is in the evening already.
Is well, I turn it on immediately.
Let him be light.
Csubajsz the bûnös!
- This it
- Thank you.
The old man lay here, on the sofa.
And the murder happened here.
The old man said it, that his room
is under that room punctually,
where the bûncselekmény happened.
Somebody observed it, how it went out
to make an old testimony?
Splendid, I remember it well well,
was going, his knees were bending hardly,
the little old man went slowly.
Because he was his arthritis.
According to the draft, is here the rooms, the
the floor-space of corridors, we tested it the
lehetõ the most punctually to reconstruct.
So to it, that let him notice it, up was needed
to get up from the sofa,
to cover 35 metres, to open the door
and to notice somebody.
Somebody can tell it, how much
is a pedestrian his average speed?
- Let somebody know it?
- One and a half are a metre, a seconds. He calculates it.
- One and a half metres, a second, so
- Yes, for a healthy man.
- So 10 seconds, it 15 metres.
- 10 seconds, it 15 metres.
Cca. 25 seconds are 35 metres, them.
It is noticed immediately, which vein elõbb
to the entrance door.
But let him not be going with his own district.
My lords, apology, I would be able to measure it it idõt.
- Good.
- It is necessary to measure it it idõt.
- Thank you very much.
- Me too.
- Thank you.
With a word himself the old man, lies on the sofa.
I am me the bûnözõ. Himself needs some
let a second put it on with it in order for him to get up
his slippers and let him start.
- Of course.
- Let him start the counting onto my command.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Ready.
- Let us start it.
- I will kill you!
What is going on?
Stop! Stop!
- Apology, but disturbance.
- He disturbs us now.
- Go away. We work now.
No trouble, I say thank you for it, here now an
an experiment is going on.
Sorry.
It is okay. One more.
To zero a stopwatch.
Zero.
- Ready?
- Yes.
Attention
Let us start it.
I will kill you!
- To get up, to get up!
- I am on my way.
- He heard the cry.
- Knife! Knife!
Fingerprints. Let us come, let us come old man!
Up, up, up!
You heard the cry.
Something happens there.
No, No, No. Wait!
Le has to delete the fingerprints.
Not to dust off, but to wipe it
fingerprints.
Is going, is going, is going, is going.
Let us come old man, let us come, let us come!
Come on, come on!
Wipe the fingerprints.
Tessék, wipe.
In this manner, ni.
The money, has to take away the money!
He has to find it!
Let us come old man, let us come, let us come!
Is going, is going, is going, is going.
Come on, come on, come on!
If the boy would have destroyed it, õ would have known it
where the money.
- What villains!
- I am looking for the money
- ...ordibálnak nightly.
- I believe it this much idõ already
I would have found that money.
He has to get dressed yet!
Let him not forget to get dressed.
Come on! Something happened there!
Let us come old man, let us come, let us come!
Go!
Parasites!
Button
- I am going.
- Come on, come on!
I go over. I am in the other room already.
I open the door.
I open this.
It elõszobában am.
I open the door.
The lépcsõn am.
The lépcsõház - seven lépcsõfok.
Three steps the lépcsõfordulóban.
An, kettõ, three, four, five, six, seven.
An, kettõ, three, four, seven.
An, kettõ, three - his old flat.
An, kettõ.
Clear.
I save it!
Õ reached now to the door only.
And let 5 seconds be added to him yet,
while he opens the lock.
53 are a second, my lords.
53 are seconds.
So what?
It may be him that he was in this manner,
may be, that not.
The examination believed the old man it, that
what he saw.
I though believe for the examination.
The old man saw the kid running away.
You are somebody somebody else.
Who?
The person for who he was not sietõs.
The person who wanted it to be noticed.
Well
I believe it in that manner, that
- Thank you.
...ez the old man, who
elõrehaladott because of rheumatic arthritis
suffers,
would never be able to do this distance
Under 10 seconds.
This, than doctor I say it.
To vote want.
I vote for it,
that the boy
not bûnös.
Six-six.
And
I.
Seven-five.
- What do you want?
- It is cold.
You cold? Everybody is cold, tootsie.
Lám, you install a double grid for himself
and is cold after all.
Tûrjél, tootsie.
Where a birch tree, where sorb
The branch of broom above water
What there is mûvészkém, your band without you
did he go away onto deployment?
This is said in that manner at us, to barnstorm.
- Where you hit home yet
- You act here at least.
"...nyugalmat.
- True, free.
It is said in that manner for greasy bread.
Loved on eternal one szülõföldem
Why did you change sides?
- Where you hit home yet nyugtot.
- It is called in that manner - Punch.
Get him!
Be listening, do not be angry, I
I did not want it. I believed it you catch it.
Let him be listening
Let him be listening Figyel
Himself why quiver himself I steadily?
- But since I apologised
- Now not the bocsánatkérésrõl there is a word.
Why call you?
- You I
- We it
- ...együtt we played football?
Vodkáztunk? Or what?
Did we play the field?
What is this? I do not understand this.
And why you guffaw steadily, we?
- Who guffaws?
- You - you guffaw. You guffaw, you guffaw.
- Why do you guffaw?
- Who?
- Back, you, steadily.
- You guffaw steadily and you guffaw.
- But back who guffaws?!
- For what I would guffaw. Five of his clocks we are sitting here.
- You guffaw, I say it.
You found a clown for yourself possibly,
or we?
Am I a clown according to you? Clown?
A cheap clown?!
Is a clown cheap?
I am till now the nevetésedtõl!
Believes already all of them turned blue, than it
hanged man, from his own flashy.
Would he like to laugh?
For himself ridiculous.
He is laughing everywhere! Always! On everybody!
Did not come into the hall yet, his vocal cords
he prepared it for the guffawing already.
Everything is ridiculous absolutely for himself!
Life! Death! Cunami! Earthquake -
himself guffaws only!
Ha-ha-ha.
Half of the country froze - Ha-ha-ha.
An rendõr - committed a murder - ha-ha-ha.
Five a million children without supervision -
Ha! Ha! Ha!
After all, why is laughing?
Why this the - Ha, if, if?
Back because of that, because the serious things
onto his own number terrible.
Recently, here in Moscow, an gyûlésen
I absolve it and I started speaking sincerely
to the audience.
Az életemrõl, az õ életükrõl,
errõl, in that manner generally.
Everybody laughed at.
It was believed, this some prank.
I believed it, it would be necessary to spit one
onto the audience, it elsõ one after the other. In this manner, ni!
But back they will be laughing then.
Nothing, it are understood it is believed - this an
a prank is like this.
Did you find a clown for yourself?
I am not a back clown!
From truth I deserved only a smile.
Altogether one single smile.
When now here, that old man
I was left often alone in my childhood
with my ill grandma.
Five, you are six I may have been year
Yes, six.
Was badly only once, to die
started, I understood it immediately.
I tempted it the mentõt, but was nowhere.
The medicine,
I am concerned about it awfully.
But I was sorry for it, since after all the
my grandma.
I believed it in that manner I cheer it up, to parody
I started ismerõsöket.
Szima old lady, Klavdija Petrovnát, the felsõ
neighbour, who the barátnõje was.
They were very amusing.
The grandma had big pains, but
I saw that he smiled.
Yet when it was taken away, dead, then
I saw the smile on his face.
This all
laugh.
and smile.
This Chechen boy,
...az old man.
Now egyszerûen I feel it in my bones
the rémisztõ fear
and the solitude.
Likewise, than when with the grandma
I was left over.
With the dying man.
Back that only smile was this, that
from truth I deserved it.
Good, that there is a swear at least
I did not beat it up my back.
What an Russian story.
Yes. Here somehow generally on all of them
very Russian-like.
Not Harvard.
Not, it sure.
Upset it,?
Here let them keep silent, make yet an
experiment.
- What?
- Since themselves did one already.
Not, egyszerûen only ellenõrizni
I would like a thing.
Imagine only away
Is their fantasy?
Me?
Well, I do not complain. His part for my trade.
Of course.
Well, yeah.
Imagine now away:
Késõ returns home in the evening.
- Me?
- Yes.
- Himself nõs?
- Yeah, sure.
- Catches it, I am asking it.
- All right.
- Does he have a child?
- Yes. A little girl.
- A what kind of car does he have?
- AUDI is 8.
Let him imagine it with a word:
Késõ returns home in the evening.
He lives on a good neighbourhood, in élite house.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
On all of them, is needed - doorkeeper,
video-observing, car park,
safety õrök, barrier.
Barrier.
Safety õr.
I have remote control. Bip-bip.
Yes, Kolja, it õr.
True, really Koljának it is called.
Yes. The janitor, Petya is a uncle.
- Valera is a uncle.
Valerocska uncle, pleasant holidays.
Mindegyikõjüket you know it, everybody knows,
you are not afraid so késõn to return home
- Naturally, I am not afraid.
...hiszen this your house.
- Yes
This an very well õrzött house.
You, generally, on the usual place
you park your vehicle,
and suddenly, from the pole of your eye you notice it,
that there is not something properly.
What is there not?
There is light in the windows.
Light.
But back õk in this it idõben generally already
they sleep.
Why would they sleep? They wait for me, that
Of course, is in that manner, egyszerûen only
you returning home wanted to be being waited for.
But within, something in that direction forces, that
ask it: Valera uncle, in all order?
- Is Valera a uncle, everything properly?
- There are a yes, that of all reasons, everything properly.
You drive to the entrance, the doorkeeper,
Polja an old lady smiles.
- Good, good.
- Listen
Not, pay attention to me.
You go to the elevator, the elevator - shhhs.
Elevator. You enter. Do you live on the 5. floor?
- That is right. How do you know?
- Wait.
It is my lodge on 5 really.
- Of course, that it on 5. Right?
- Yes.
It is the best floor. Is not neither too high,
neither too low and good the view.
You know?
They do not sleep because of something only.
They do not sleep for something. But immediately,
you find it out immediately, what kind of surprise
prepared for you.
It is 5. floor here.
5. floor
Not, an nõi a sound says it:
Fifth is floor.
Fifth is floor. And here the 5. floor.
It is on 5.
Ej, the rogues, they do not sleep, it is waited for it
their daddy.
- Door.
- In that manner.
Something was prepared for him.
I open the door.
Wipe his foot.
Wiped?
- And there is silence!
- What?
The silence is big in the flat.
He is not silence like this.
And the light. The lights are on everywhere.
The things flung about.
Child slippers. One. His pair nowhere.
An big fürdõlepedõ, white törölközõ
on the floor of the corridor. You take everything already.
You summon it õket. They would answer only already.
I beg for it, let them answer only already!
But õk they keep silent.
The telephone the safety õrökhöz it
elõszobában, right
- On the left side.
- Apology, gone astray. On the left side.
The cable torn out, the handset
trampling on the floor.
You are reversed slowly, and
There he is!
- What?
- There!
- Pool of blood from under the door.
The door opens slowly.
Hangs down from the chandelier
a panda.
Panda. A huge plush panda. -
your little girl is his favourite game.
The blood though, - not too blood, but
wine poured out it shattered üvegbõl.
Is not yet on all of them disappearing, you run the
into net, and here Over.
The bedroom is your daughter on his doorstep.
Like that, as if would live, no blood.
It was strangled.
You open the bedroom, and there
the megerõszakolt and cut up
your wife!
This end.
You want to shout, but do not endure.
You want to run, but do not endure.
You stand only, than a pillar of salt,
above your wife's and your daughter's corpse.
Be waiting, be waiting, he does not come to an end with this yet!
Your lounge, somebody goes behind your back!
Who may it be? It though just it on the suckle,
who you want to save the börtöntõl.
Just with this knife.
And õ translates onto a stomach slowly, skilfully
on the floor,
tightens your head and with this it sharp,
with a cold blade
fültõl to an ear kills it!
- And you, the Harvard-oddal
- Please!
...a you will crawl in your own pool of blood,
- But I am asking it!
You think about not having called the mum.
And you do not take it only yet, there döglõdve,
why he made this!
Made it because of that õ this, because we for them
only prey are!
We are not peoples! Prey!
I modify my decision
the killer - bûnös.
A kid is good.
And your mum.
What raised a kid - clever, active,
is képzelõereje.
A man is true.
Back we are doing in this manner.
Six - six.
Very interesting.
Why do they look at me now?
I donot know sensitive.
This man is badly.
Would it not be necessary to call here the court usher?
Let us listen to the doctor
Well, here this not food poisoning, that
This is on a neural basis. Water he needs him
to give, that
- Apology, that
- I am well, I am well, I say thank you for it.
Yes, yes, yes.
Gaudy wolves 2,7. class,
befejezõ part.
Really. I was watching.
Every day, hétfõtõl, until a Thursday
21:at the time of 35.
I am glad that he looks at our channel.
Thank you.
To stop!
Cease fire! Everybody down!
Cease fire! Quiet!
Quiet.
The car! Bring the car.
- Somebody there?
- Not, there is nobody.
Umarik. Umarcsik.
Is that you?
I am it, Vologya uncle.
Do not be afraid.
Be set up, be set up Umarcsik.
I am it, Vologya uncle!
Stand up.
Take it easy. Donot be afraid.
Donot be afraid.
Umarcsik.
Umarcsik. Umarcsik.
Na calm down, calm down.
It is gratitude for a god that I found you.
He will be in all order already now.
You will stay with me, in Moscow.
Let them not be afraid, I am it.
Oh, my God!
It is known, new here the lighting, the
an indicator board is old on the other hand.
- Yeah.
- It is freezing now on the street outside.
Next so for a long time nobody to which accustomed was not got
to sit here.
- Back yes.
- He is not tough.
- I put this lamp here.
- Yeah.
- Let them not be worried, immediately
- Thank you.
- I find something out immediately.
Good.
- Na, tessék!
- What happened?
I believe it, now already everything clear.
His old title.
When he made a testimony on the court,
he granted a home address.
That is the title of that house, where the
a murder happened.
Now already, here on the court, an
he granted an other title.
His daughter's title.
Yes, said it.
Ow! Excuse me.
Said it, that after the murder with a day
traveled to his daughter, into Moscow's other end.
- Yes yes.
- He stayed there.
- And now there Most lives there?
- Is in that manner, is in that manner.
Said it, that onto his daughter's birthday
he traveled.
Yes! The escape of the murder and the neighbour
he happened in November.
Yes.
His daughter's birthday though
he is in a March.
Light, let him be kind.
Tessék, tessék.
What does all this mean?
- Woe
- Light.
I explain it immediately.
I proposed to our court usher, that
let him dig elõ some information it
in connection with building operations,
what leaks beside the house.
Let me be believed it - this an huge
building operations, a new élite house are being built.
The square metre price -
at at least 4 thousand kezdõdik.
All are a flat sold.
On the place of that house though, where the
a murder happened, for this the cool expensive
one of his wings would stand for elite house.
It building határidõket punctually
it is necessary to keep it.
So what?
Now imagine only away:
It is necessary to hand over the house, where flat
you pay more million dollars.
And something because of two of my bars, who do not ripen
an kopejkát neither, it is not possible to start it it
building operations.
The single magisterial house,
Catches it, I am asking it.
...a in a city's centre.
The thrived an officer did not move out,
since it was his of service flat.
Nothing was his right onto him.
The military authority was not top notch to ensure
into an exchange any kind of other flat.
And the resolute former party worker, who
did not move out, because There it is!
...egyenértékû it required a flat new
because of power, likewise in the centre.
The cases like this are handled individualwise.
Thank you.
The jurists, immovable agents come
Or may enter sporting event themselves it is wanted.
Tersely, these egyszerûen robbers.
These peoples hit the soldier,
who battled against them,
the was for a party worker, who did not understand it,
who were added to it.
And begins here an very much
szakszerû manõver.
Watch is set up.
The relations are found out.
Who, how, who is in contact with.
The situation improves.
The final result: One - dead person,
the other, who naturally does not stitch
nobody, gets into a prison,
the third, escapes headlong
Into Moscow's suburb, to his daughter,
and registers inside some days
onto one to be stood to it.
This a yes szakszerû manõver.
So wants to say it, that this an
deliberate and elõre planned murder?
In that manner tûnik.
But back this szörnyû!
Back, knows it
when a million from dollars there is a word
the separating lane the "meggyõzni" and the
To kill between solutions
insignificant.
From where himself is top notch ezekrõl?
I asked it - from where is top notch ezekrõl?
It was told.
Hands over the candle, I am asking it.
Here, the candle.
Well told all this to us now,
And what there is now?
Meggyõzõdésem, that the little boy did not kill it
his stepfather.
Vote - not bûnös.
Oh, man!
Again, seven - five.
Apology, I accept it an so, quasi,
wild version lehetõségét,
but it was forgotten that he is yet an
eyewitness from the neighbouring house.
It õ his windows are in an eye punctually
with the windows of that room, where the
a murder happened.
Õ it declared, that with his own eye
seeing, the father
The father for something face the boy was struck by him,
snatched up the knife on the suckle though next and
sticked, directly into the officer's breast.
For him nothing his interest not fûzõdött to it,
that falsely bear witness.
It õ nobody wanted to break down his house.
That is, why not we would take it for him?
That woman, not only saw it, but yet
too showed it pricked, fentrõl downwards.
- Yes, showed it.
- That is right.
- Yes.
Mielõtt raise it would be medical science
fõiskolára, I worked as a nurse the
on accident surgery.
Much knife gallop like this I saw a wound.
How this boy was capable, who, it is known,
with at least a head lower at his father,
how knew it with a word fentrõl downwards
to prick with the knife?
We are in an Indian cinema possibly now,
or we?
Here let them keep silent, since this bosh!
But since bosh! Bosh!
What themselves wear here together?
What are dreamed up?
I cannot understand it Indian cinema
Since this bosh! Bosh.
How believes it I was not a bar
nurse on the accident surgery.
Let me show it how may be an with a head
to stab a lower man in a breast
fentrõl downwards?
We it, let me show it?
Let me show it?!
Let him show it if he knows it.
- Let me show it?
- Let him show it.
All right. Look!
No
Come here.
I teach you immediately,
how he did it.
Come here.
In that manner.
No
Come here.
No.
How did it
Immediately.
Come here.
Immediately, immediately.
Immediately.
Come, come.
Come on.
Here.
Stop.
Now lower termetû am.
With a head.
Na, lower?
- Come back.
- Yes.
- Lower?
So I am lower with a head.
You say it - Indian cinema?
How was he able to make this?
I show it immediately.
I teach you, how knew this
to do.
Struck it õt. His father.
He humiliated it. He struck it!
It held the knife.
What was that?
It is blood?
Small bird.
Laid.
Does he allow it?
Knows it, the boy on country like that nõtt up,
where the essence of the knife is understood.
Anybody, for who he was at least one times already,
his alley to a knife, knows it, that with a knife from below
it is necessary to prick.
This always incalculable, always
dangerous and always heavy to prevent.
For example
Next into the neck!
- Onto a throat!
- What
Next to it, that let the knife reach it the
heart, the doctor szakértõk it is said,
an very much erõs it is necessary to make a hit,
that let him break through the chest.
For example
In this manner!
What is wrong with you?! Since, you
You you are a surgeon.
Surgeon, surgeon.
Did you not notice it possibly?
Knife the knife, than any thrusting weapons,
particularly in Caucasus,
the culture is his part likewise.
Hûha! Yes!
Sorry. Ablabari I am a child.
Sorry.
Very interesting.
Then, I modify my decision.
God, went blind.
I cannot talk right now.
I cannot speak now, for you?
They hold a meeting yet.
Imagine it now.
Since a yes, a morning, imagine only away.
There were overzealous ones like this.
I am me maybe the wrong because of this?
Since the indicator board got ruined finally,
in this manner
This is everything, which I can recommend,.
It is this was left of the school discotheque here.
And the there is nothing?
I take the lamp, it away.
They would have worked properly, already for a long time at home
could be,
and they would not jump about in the discotheque
until a morning, all neat men.
The pupils come soon
I suggest it, vote!
The architect there is absolute truth for a lord.
A system is very accurate.
I am beside it, that the kid
not bûnös.
Let him raise his hand, according to who the defendant
bûnös.
An,
kettõ,
three.
Let him raise his hand, according to who not bûnös.
An, kettõ, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight.
Apology, and you?
Sorry.
...És you?
- What?
- That votes?
- In a what kind of sense?
But a back said that he modifies it the
his opinion. For what?
Wait a minute.
Let him not be angry, I am asking it, does not remember it,
how did I vote it recently?
- Ja, when for himself
- Yes, yes, yes.
Was beside it, that bûnös.
I voted it in that manner "bûnös".
Yeah, I I modify it really the
my opinion and I vote for it, that the
defendant not bûnös.
Does not change his opinion already,
? May I write it down?
But back mirõl speaks. Come on.
This is my definitive decision.
It is conceptual question.
Dot because of the so conceptual peoples
one we will wake up to it in the morning,
that in our country Green Berets
order is done.
A foreign country speech is all around us.
I do not understand it, we his reason for this
for the reproach?
Himself changed its opinion,
just like I.
But not, my friend, not in that manner, than you.
This man just told a story now away an
perfectly clear scheme and it,
this mûködik.
But back this an unique bûnügyi special.
This not unique and not bûnügyi,
this scheme mûködik everywhere.
What kind is a scheme?
When the big ones do not think
onto the small ones
the small ones obliged to live in that manner,
they are top notch.
Own törvényeiktõl his guiding principle.
And this is in this manner everywhere.
On the building operations, in the hospital,
yet the temetõben too.
I do not understand it, how comes here the temetõ?
Himself buried already away somebody? Once?
That I?
I buried it.
With two years ezelõtt, in London.
Matilda.
Who is Õ?
Rottweiler.
This not surname, this an dog.
Well, I do not know it in London that
the dogs are buried,
I can talk about it only, how
the peoples are accompanied on the last journey at us.
I am eight of his year already headmaster an
temetõben.
Let it be imagined to be in front of themselves the következõ picture:
A close relative is buried.
Well, song, funeral ceremony, -
on all of them, is needed.
They arrive the temetõhöz, there the grave
in that manner that
What are you doing? What kind is a grave?
Believes this mum of mine.
Sorry.
This is my mum.
My mum.
Shortly, végsõ farewell, relatives
Some totally strange old lady, beside us,
looks into the grave and starts lamenting:
Oh, my God. How my poor little thing stains there
to lie?
The relatives - Mirõl there is a word? What happened?
They look into the grave, the water is a knee deep there.
Na, now we be?
We do?
An approximate man is not caught apparently
into the marsh to strangle.
The old lady into their ear whispers - gives advices.
The cryings start vezetõjéhez.
But õ is there beside them already.
It is said: Let him look at it, my respected lord,
the water is a knee deep there, it would be necessary to make something.
In this direction õ mumbles something the underground
vizekrõl,
with his shovel starts it to scoop the
from a grave the muddy water and jolts.
The relatives catch a shock.
During this the old lady catching somebody at his finger
yanks and shows it, direct beside it
With a word, a totally dry grave.
He dug freshly.
And comes now the most interesting.
The relatives turn to the gravedigger.
It is said: Let him be listening, could be
somehow
...szóval, to substitute?
That imagine, they lost its mind?!
Immediately, after 15 minutes bring for an
to bury a man!
How? May not be, -
the documents are ready already.
Õk they fall on a knee, they are wet with tears.
My respected lord, let him help already. We pay it.
Tells it how much.
Long already egyszerû -
it is surveyed külsõ on his basis.
Automatically - two green hasú"- t ask for.
Automatically - five hundred.
If the man penniless, into a word
they are doing with him.
And the method: The board is exchanged,
the thrives it is put into the dry grave,
the relatives, direction the thorax,
for the old lady though 500 into the pocket,
ruble naturally.
The foil covered early is dragged out
and the grave after 15 minutes dry.
Na, fighters, let us come new wet grave
to make.
This is going in this manner.
Good, that the mother-in-law in a crematorium
I had it cremated.
Very interesting.
Why do they look at me in this manner now?
Huh?
Is he some other way possibly at themselves?
All of them we live encage. Everybody.
Only everybody the sajátjában.
Is in this manner, countryman?
Rolex?
Back yes.
Expensive?
Temetõi pénzbõl?
Temetõi pénzbõl.
Yes, temetõi pénzbõl. I take nothing away.
However ebbõl the pénzbõl yet the chapel
too I had it restored and I feed it steadily
the homeless.
Who the temetõhöz vetõdtek.
They have to devour it somewhere.
I had even a school built up in the village,
where felnõttem, 850 km because of Moscow.
Even the sports hall is there Jön
away to look at, so szörnyûség and horror
he is not there.
At me the csõ runs under the land, is needed.
Számítógépterem LCD with monitors.
Teachers from the city, all with good payment.
I started a bus, that the
gyerkõcöket brings it in the környékrõl it
into a school and of course back.
That let him not be their time to snuff.
And if the peoples are asked in this the
in a village:
Actually how pénzbõl too was being built
is it a school?
They spit on him, that how pénzbõl recovered
the school.
The essence it, that let the school be at a standstill
and mûködjön.
So that I help the dead persons' money
it élõknek.
If nobody else does this already.
The essence - on the suckle not bûnös.
After all, it is explained already for me, an
almost for a healthy man, that this it
egyszerû woman, for who
nothing his interest not fûzõdik to it
Why declared on the court it, that
it destroyed it with the knife on the suckle Vologyát,
the Russian position.
I know.
May shout at me, or may laugh at me.
But I know it.
- Jealousy.
- We, we?
A back knows it!
- It is
- This jealousy.
May not have heard it certainly, the boy it
shouted it: I will kill you!, what the opposite
he resides in house.
And may not have seen it.
Since lives opposite the house and
he was in the evening just then.
In the best case only shades
may have seen, bar it valószínû.
He did not see it.
Was sure that this was the boy
and nobody else.
Because he wanted it very much, and was ready in the boy
to see the worst one.
Why?
Jealousy.
Szörnyû, meaningless, feminine jealousy.
Is here, let these photographs be looked at.
Showed it on the court õket.
Here.
Onto understanding got it, how knew the victim.
There is a photograph here where they are together
on some feast.
Õ, it is victim and his wife.
Is it seen?
And this photo is here, Here.
...ahol the nõ, the man and somebody's hand.
This is the wife's hand.
What it was necessary to pick up and to enlarge
just that part, where only õ and it
victim shows.
Cut off the wife.
This photograph - it õ his dream.
If we carry on this theory,
takes shape an egyszerû picture.
Single nõ, who is an own normal family
he dreams about his formation. Childless.
Who likes the man from the opposite house.
There is only a trouble - the man nõs.
Writes a letter for him onto Csecsenföld, writes it,
that his wife cheats on it.
- Apology, I may look at it?
- Of course, tessék.
And, that is sorry for it very much, but not
may keep silent errõl.
Not to be top notch, it is you whether this was in this manner neither,
but fact, how sent a letter to him.
This is jealousy.
The nõ provoked it, that separate the
feleségétõl.
Clear. There are not more obstacles.
Only õ and the man, on this photograph.
It is necessary to wait it out only already while he recurs.
The beloved man's recurrence.
Arrives next, but not alone.
On a nerve, game, in Russian badly beszélõ,
dirty, hostile Asian kid.
They remember that he complained, when
asked the man, what plans
now to do?
Õ though egyszerûen answered it, that with this
will live with the boy in two one, törõdni wants
with his fate.
The end of everything!
All of his hopes - everything collapsed!
But õ does not give it up
Let them remember only told it that
invited the neighbour into company, the
together with a boy.
Onto a name-day.
Set, bought sweets,
some kind of book.
Noticed it suddenly next, that eltûnt
his money.
What lay beside that place,
where a poor boy was sitting.
And how rehearsed it meggyõzni õt, that
he gives back his money.
Anyway the money késõbb elõkerült.
Õ himself related that he forgot it,
but somebody else sorted it out apparently.
But the nõ the seriously injured position
elõtt the money brought it up eltûnését.
Had to know it certainly on all of them, what stains
to happen. And this occurred of course.
The man hears it, that the boy, who õ
as his own son rears, thief!
In this direction õ lost his self-control apparently.
Face the little boy was struck by him, but the nõ only
he keeps silent.
When his nose started bleeding on the other hand,
the boy rose to his protection and said it, that
Not free, the boy not bûnös".
More punctually, that Ha wrong, not free
Vern.
Since õ weaker, child yet.
It is not allowed to hurt it.
Oh, my God.
The nõ did not lie, wanted it very much only.
He decided that the killer may be the boy only.
This is the little boy and nobody else.
Jealousy.
Meaningless, cruel, blind, vehement,
jealousy is feminine.
That is it.
Késõbb the money turned up.
This the nõ himself erõsítette.
I inhabit it with my son. Õ now 20 year, then
He was 1991,6.
My wife leafed on 90 of his ends
it escaped into states with somebody.
A back leafed if he leafed, francba with him.
The kid suffered of course, but I
I explained it to him,
that his mother egyszerûen off, long
idõre, and that will see it certainly yet.
My mother looked him after.
In it it idõben full erõvel taxiztam.
I did not think of the family somehow.
Fõleg, that the chicks did not report
problem, and
a chick sat down once, we talked,
we were warming to it
Was not a beauty
I fetched it several times the munkahelyérõl.
He moved to us next.
I was not waiting tõle a lot - be zaba,
let him do the laundry of us, let him take the kid into the school.
In that manner tûnt, õ too deals with him kindly.
Petted: Kolja-Nyikolasa.
If kill neither I remember him, that
kezdõdött this all.
All kinds started talking about my son.
So where did not make something,
where did trouble.
I beckoned to it and I asked: Was he in this manner?
Õ looks at me only, smiles and says it:
Was in this manner, father.
The garbage only bakes.
Back I punished it.
Once infuriated something,
I do not remember already, what it was
said something about him, that felbõszített.
Something tore in me
fog fell on my eye.
I burst in at night into the bedroom,
I pulled it off from the bed and with a fist,
with a fist for him
The nõ keeps silent only.
The kid's nose started bleeding suddenly next.
In this direction started yelling
Killer! Killer! What mûvelsz?!
You kill the child!
And said it only
I it is struck by me long
Sees blood - bellows.
All degenerated with a word, somehow.
The fiacskám, as if waited for it already somehow
would be this whole one.
He was not crying already. Flickers only steadily
and smiles.
Sûrûn winks, and what is the essence - is not crying.
He is not crying! I the face of a pitfall, it all blood,
õ flickers and smiles.
Flickers and smiles.
Once with some aroused night
My lounge, that the fürdõszobában the water flows,
I go in, I see it is washing it the lepedõjét.
In brief behugy urinated in his dream.
A boy child.
The lepedõt pressed it to his breast and the
he hid into a heel. Looks at me and smiles.
He smiles.
Flickers and smiles.
Behaves the way I go home as if
already from the beginning bûnös would be.
Is watching and that smile, like that
Is watching and
Apparently true is, but my soul on deep one's,
from within somehow
As if somebody for my own son's hangman
would have appointed.
And a child of his was then.
Likewise boy.
Four may have been year possibly, when
once dot my eye elõtt made something
badness and I easily onto his bottom
I hit it.
And then knocked the crash!
The lord looked me after possibly! Slightly bent down,
in this manner the iron onto only a centimetre tõlem driven
into the wall.
That the
The sajátomat pitfall, but to his
I imply it, almost stitches.
Caught the small one then and they left
Tambovba to the relatives.
My night call was once
I took the road from home already, but something
he was heading back somehow.
As if they would have sticked to a neck only.
I am reversed - direction home.
I see it, there is light in the window.
I burst in into the flat, here and there, is nowhere.
3 clocks are nights.
My lounge - swishing in the cupboard.
I open the cupboard, õ is there,
in the cupboard, is sitting, smiles and looks at me.
And flickers only. Flickers, sûrûn flickers.
In this direction I ask what do: Are my small son, we with you?
I pulled it out the szekrénybõl, to myself
I hurried, õ snuggled up to me tightly,
looks at me, smiles, flickers, and the right
his back hides his hand behind it.
I ask it: My small son, we it there? and
I take his hand, his hand
He was a loop in him.
Loop the own övembõl.
I do not know it what showed on my face,
only caught, embraced, snuggled up to me
and said it whispering it:
Father, not, father. Father, not.
Not and repeated it without an end
Not, father, not.
And smiles, smiles.
Father, not.
With a word I in that manner vote, that
the kid not bûnös.
Let him note it.
A back knows it, this really very much meggyõzõ was.
I agree - the boy not bûnös.
- Vote.
- Is well, then vote.
Who votes for it, that the defendant not bûnös?
I ask for the hands to assume.
- Let him live, let him live. Made.
- Gratitude for a god made!
- That is it. Thank you.
- And his end.
- With a monotone decision.
- Let them be waiting, let them be waiting
- Thank you.
Let them be waiting, let me write it down.
- More, than seven clocks.
- Yes, I am asking it
- Let them be waiting, let them be waiting!
- What? What?
- Wait.
- What?
- What is there yet?
- I did not vote it yet.
- I hope for it himself joins us.
- Of course.
No.
I believe it in that manner, that bûnös.
Eleven innocent and an "bûnös".
- Back you next
- I explain it.
- Why
I explain it.
- The festõ was sitting only till now, because
- Very interesting.
- I explain it.
- I do not understand it
Back, is not what to do
It, that õ innocent, kezdettõl caught
I was top notch.
From my trade adódóan this egyszerû.
I agree with all arguments, that here
he was over.
And the old man was scared really, this showed.
And now the nõ. It was forgotten, that
myopic, wears glasses.
Megerõsítette, that slept already, when
the thing happened.
To it, that let him see everything, up was needed
to get up, had to put on the glasses and
to go to the window.
This egyszerûen valószínûtlen.
What the boy deserves
It is known well, that õ Caucasus and, that õk
entirely some other kind of peoples.
I was ordered repeatedly into Caucasus
and I know these peoples.
Will never shout it, that
I destroy you, but catches it and destroys it.
And will not guess all kinds of bosh,
õ finds something in which nobody hits home out
mistake.
The others are obvious though.
Obvious, that all of this all thing
arranged.
Those peoples directed it in this manner, for who
was very important, that the boy in a prison
let him be sitting.
Is that right? We understood this.
We proved it, that not bûnös.
Right?
But, if this is in this manner, then
we come to this decision and õt freely
it is allowed.
- Back sure! Of course.
- Nagyszerû.
- And gratitude for a god.
Yes, gratitude for a god, that not killer,
this is true.
But then why votes in that manner, that
bûnös?
I egyszerûen they is worthless.
I do not take it finally already now.
How when finally himself
They is worthless altogether already!
It is known, on this already all of them too are!
I am here for example was like this!
And when when already everybody
Then himself De back we this?!
Exactly. Huge, sweaty, heavy
we made work.
We found out the truth! Himself
I may claim one surely, in the prison
will live long, than freely.
Very interesting.
Let it be understood, if õ is about the street now,
will not go into the pub, you are a homeland,
to the relatives.
There are nothing and nobody.
Is it understood?
Is going and looks those who destroyed it up
his father.
Besides, if we now felmentõ judgement
bring for,
with this egyidõben automatically new procedure
he runs in the case of the unexplored murder.
And the peoples who killed his father,
they will be nervous and the boy will be looked for.
Õ will be looking for it õket, õk it will be being looked for õt.
But õ does not know it, that õk where they are,
õk it is known on the other hand, where is õ.
We though with our current decision, instead of it,
that into a prison we would send the boy,
we sign his death sentence.
It will be destroyed, stupidly, terribly,
than a dog in the doorway an dikics
with a knife.
Nobody will look for this boy.
Themselves know this well.
Then with 8 months késõbb it is found
somewhere in a channel, or an
in a cesspit, and ready.
Let it be understood, in the hall now peoples like that
who accompany it with attention are sitting how
végzõdik this lawsuit.
I have a good nose to this. I feel it.
This is a vocational instinct.
- Is it understood?
- Mûvészi instinct, true?
- What?
- Mûvészi is an instinct.
Mûvészi.
- And if there, in the prison
- Onto the god's love!
...felakasztja himself?
- Let him not point himself out.
From where we know it what may happen to him there?
How will behave - from where we know it?
Then, this it õ his fate
if hangs himself there.
But I claim one certainly - in the prison
will live long, than freely.
Na is well, but what suggests then
in this case?
Suggests it, that an innocent man
let him sit in a prison, the bûnözõk though
let them be left freely?
- Yes.
- Back this it.
I did not suggest one like this.
If we conceal the boy in the prison
Is not where to do.
He does not have a home - it was broken down.
Is not where to live.
We hire lawyers, gyûjtünk onto him
money, I believe it.
We go away onto the public prosecutor's department, we look it up
the leghozzáértõbbeket and we tell it to them
our arguments.
Those peoples press it to a wall then
these killers.
And when they will be in the prison already,
it is possible to let out the boy.
He will be securely outside already then.
At least in this look.
Apology, it is sold already away, these lawyers,
these the hozzáértõ peoples, this public prosecutor's department,
this
Who will deal with this?
This interests me.
- Who
- Whether who?
Back we ourselves! Who else?
What?
Back who needs this the penniless,
in Russian beszélõ onto a Chechen boy,
who the nevelõapja with murdering him accuse?
Who will deal with him? Who are more important to
õ, if not for us? Who?
I am a cab driver, not investigating.
I have to drive it
I understand it, of course, but
I donot know.
I do not know it, they were my contacts it
at a public prosecutor's department, but for this already a hundred of his years,
it is my father on his time yet.
For me for example onto a half-year into Japan is needed
to travel.
This is a very complicated work.
Let it be understood, not only from me there is a word.
I am responsible for 850 workers yet and the
for their family.
But back, that imagine this?
Let me work in that manner there,
that I know it meanwhile, an innocent man is sitting
in the prison, who does not know it, what do?
Na, pél for example for me the jövõ on seven
four mûtétem is.
On 21, 23 and 24 immediately kettõ.
What I should make now, let me cancel all of them?
But back that? How I could make it?!
Is well, my lords, let us put it up, quasi
On a totally theoretical basis, let us put it up, that
I would be able to deal with him, but how?
Is needed sincerely very much with this
to deal, to this much idõ necessary.
A reality show just starts now at me,
I am there day and night.
That title of the show: The planet of a good turn.
It is
Totally clear, everybody would be top notch, but when?
Three are monthly guest performances on Volga River.
This much, I was late in this manner already, needs
to ripen the team.
Let them listen, kind!
We executed a big thing!
We set an innocent man free!
An, anyway for us strange man.
- Doubtless.
- We accomplished the jurors' duties!
The others - already other power organs' thing.
Rather already ebbõl the fejetlenségbõl.
Since exists, végülis, the law!
What is there with themselves? Their E flat are
altogether, we?!
Segítõ-úttörõk, how it is believed,
do they want to stick to a TA here until a morning?
What there is with themselves, let them come to their senses already!
A clock falls after forty minutes the
my machine Seremetyevo-ra.
Arrives now Dubai-ból my darling.
Julecska.
21 are year. Two of his months I did not see.
Does my life want to be ruined?
They lost its mind, or we?
I started going regularly to fitness, than an
old idiotic.
Three and a half are the sizes of his melons.
Two of his months I did not see õt.
Two are his months!
I was amorous, possibly elõször!
1.83 are tall. His buds are chocs like this.
Like this, ni!
His lips, than Angelina Jolie-é,
his eye is green.
The fenekérõl I cannot speak
it is a commissioner because he holds out.
All guffaws temetõ! Yet poems
too I started writing on my workplace.
Julia you kind, you sweet.
Throw the chains of the sense of shame down.
I find everything in you only.
The day, the levegõt
- Water.
- And the water.
It is necessary to tear it off half-hourly.
For what did I have to go away onto this fitness?
21 are year! I cannot sleep calmly,
do you understand it?
His third day I have an ejaculation.
Than an for fifteen year kids!
When was your ejaculation last?
Television. You know?
We with this the gyûléssel, vazze!
Let us come, let us do something already.
- Let's go.
- Relax.
- Donot touch me!
Let us come something let us decide already,
my lord is respected.
- Let him drink
- Drink it, you may eat the glass.
Do not touch me.
Let us come, let us do something.
Mitõl he has merriment like this?
That pipe, sees it?
- How comes here the csõ?
- But not, na, sees it?
- How many of his years are already here?
- Forty.
- And till when will be yet?
- So much.
So much.
- So what? What we?
- Everything is going in this manner.
Everything.
It was looked at, it was discussed, you contemplate,
they gave a dismissive wave of the hand, they lighted up and this much.
And everything is going in this manner.
A proposal of mine is shortly, for me.
We do it righteously, felnõttek onto his manner.
If now, despite my arguments,
everybody in that manner votes, that the boy innocent,
I join.
Will he be properly in this manner?
Stop.
Himself is sure that he elects it,
if we all of them
I gave my word.
Na, knows it, an festõ his word
Is well, if does not like the festõ his word,
I give the word of a position then.
Visible a volt of his position.
A volt of his Russian position
Vote.
Who there is beside it, that the boy not bûnös?
I ask for the hands to assume.
- Do we vote for the innocent one?
- Yes.
1,2,3,4, 5,6,7,8, 9,10,11.
Tizenkettõ.
Innocent.
This is the best place after all.
Not, the end of the case is not yet.
Then késõbb we speak.
Do not start without me.
Being audible, mother
Would you recognize those who they were in the flat?
Of course, I never forget it õket.
We find it õket.
We find it anyway.
I promise it to you.
How was your father called?
Ruszlan.
- And the nevelõapádat?
- Vologya is a uncle.
I am called Nyikolaj.
May call in Nyikolaj for a uncle.
If you want.
You will stay with me.
Let's get out of here.
Let us be going, let us be going.
With a word: If you want to fly - fly,
a fly is free.
If you want to be left over - be left over.
The essence that you yourself should decide.
Nobody does this instead of you.
He was my fortune!
The law above everything, but we be, if
the mercy on a law proves
B.Toszja