25.000
1 +1
CTC TV Station
Makilida TV Station
Produce.
1988 Afghanistan war
has continued for 9 years.
Krasnoyarsk, Siberia, 1988, Day 1
Don't cry, please.
Two years.
It's only two years.
Vorobyov ! Yes
Chugainov ! Yes.
Ok, go now
Is Ryabokon here? Here he goes.
He's over there.
The enemies won't pass!
Mama
Well?
It's time to say goodbye.
This is for you.
Brothers, the frontier is locked
And the key's  in the pocket.
Come on ! Go! Quick
Put your stuff on the table ! Quick !
Bags here !
Beer, vodka and other booze on the table !
Is she your girlfriend?
Have you fucked her at least for one last time?
What?
Hasn't she given you?
Alright. Don't worry.
Everything will be all right.
There are many nice boys out there.
They'll take care of her
What's this?
- Paint.
Warrior, what are you going to
Draw there?Wheel of a tank?
Have you brought the easel, painter?
Gioconda
Next.
You thought she's gonna wait for you?
She's gonna fuck in two holes while
you write her love letters
What do you want from me
What have l done to you?
Oh, you can talk ! So maybe
you wanna punch me in the face? Come on.
Come on. Bitch.
Relax, son. I'm gonna  make you
a real soldier.
Do you know the first rule
in the army?
Soldier should  firmly
endure toughness and difficulties
of the army life.
Say, why you wear a suit?
You think it's a party here?
I have no other clothes.
Let's switch.
I'll give you mine, plus cigarettes.
You don't need it anymore, right? And l need
go out to the city, disco and girls
Can you understand?
Yes, nice service you got.
You bet.
It's like a beautiful dream
which you don't wanna wake up from.
So, deal?
Of course.
- That's my boy.
Take the sheet away,
Sure.
Beautiful dream, you say
Yeah
Hold it motherfuckers!
Hold it, l said !
Relax, son.
What you said there about enduring
toughness and difficulties, huh?
Let go of me,
Let go.
Remember?.
Can you remember?
Finish your hairdo yourself
Guys, is this the 6th unit?
And where you think you going?!
Fucking Rambo, piss off
Chill out, Chugun.
What?
Nothing.
What's the name?
Volodya Vorobyov
Lutayev Oleg, for short: Lutyi (Furious)
This is Ruslan, Gioconda
Stas ,Seryi
It's good to see you.
Volodya
Ryaba( Pocky), Chugun (Pig-iron), that's it.
Move, mate
Sit, Vorobey (Sparrow)
Continue, Ryaba
In short, I wake up in the morning
My head exploding
Open my eyes with fingers
Look around...
Whatta hell's this house?
How the hell did I get here?
There's a girl sitting next to me.
Smiling
Naked!
Woo-hoo.
And her father .
Stands above me
Like above a dead man.
He says, dude , you real fucked up.
The girl is under18.
So decide
Either registry office.
Or police.
And the slut covered her tits with the
blanket. And looks innocently
Like nothing happened.
And ugly....
Like a bulldog.
But l said no, papa
I would rather lie
under tank wheels.
than with her.
Grabbed my feet and start running.
Hoping  I get here first
before him getting
to police station.
And l got
married yesterday.
The wedding and the send off at once.
What? Congratulations.
Pretty boy.
Alright,she said,now l am
yours. Come on,
we can do it now.
She thinks l am a fool.
l open the door and be out for 2 years,
while she sprees here.
She yelled all night long.
How come l didn't touch her.
But l said,  when l get back.
I will check it
And if it ain't there - l'll kill you bitch
Left it as is.
That's him. That one.
Wearing a suit.
What's wrong with you, sucker?
Who are you pointing at?
Quiet, quiet.
Go have a rest.
I'll crop your dumb head myself now.These are
Afghan - Units, dickhead.
Come on , bitch.
Ahh... Oh...
Fergana, Uzbekistan, Day 3
Where are you from?
I am from Grozny.
Where?
Grozny
From Grozny.
So you'll be called Pinochet now
- What?
- Pinochet.
Why Pinochet?
I don't know. Why not?
Is him coming for us?
Whatta face.
Where are you from, clowns?
We are from Siberia,
Mr. Commander.
I am lieutenant  Dygalo
What?
Are you hard of hearing?
Come on, get up.
Get up quickly.
Stand in a line quickly.
Put your hats on
Attention.
I don't think there's any blinds here.
That's our mountain there.
Beyond it
is Afghan.
And for you not to die.
The first day you get there
I will train you for 3 months
twenty four hours a day.
From this minute on.
Any questions?
No questions.
Turn right.
Follow me to our camp.
Run...
When l order to run.
You should bend your arms.
Go.
Name?
Private Ryabokon
Name,
Private Chugainov
Soldier's straps is not
for holding the balls, warrior.
Name,
Private Bekbulatov.
N...
Private Stasenko
Private Petrovsky
It's you, our painter.
It's me, Comrade lieutenant.
What are you doing here, son?
Should stay home.
To draw them naked women or
flowers in jardinieres.
You see, comrade lieutenant.
Accordingly to dr. Freud
Any painting is a sublimation of
subconscious instincts.
Including the instinct of violence.
But you can disagree with this.
Because Soviet science does
not recognize the bourgeois doctrine
of doctor Freud.
Very clever.
Sorry, l'll fix it,
With your help, comrade lieutenant.
Rule No.1
Paratroopers should be always
ready for a sudden attack.
Very good. Name.
Private Lutayev
Rule No.2.
Brighter than a lieutenant
ls only the first lieutenant
Forget who you were and what you knew.
Remember, clowns.
You ain't good and ain't bad here.
No bright nor stupid,
Not even a painter. You are nothing.
You are not even humans.
Here you are shit.
I'm the one who
will make humans of you.
Using these very hands.
Clear?
Yes, sir!
I did not hear it.
Yes, sir.
Louder.
Yes sir!
Get the equipment, fill it.
Comrade lieutenant , how come the first unit
runs with light equipment.
Take your girl to the bushes.
with light equipment.
Here,The more ammo you bring,
the more chances to survive.
The mission is,
Beat off the armed enemy.
Take the height, confirm
your position and report me
the situation.
Comrade lieutenant . The second
unit is ready.
The preparation of
the mission is done.
Stand up.
Run, forward.
Forward, forward.
Forward.
The mission failed
You are all corps.
You, you and you.
Cargo 200
in the black tulip.
Piece of shit
in a zinc coffin.
The convoy that will go here
encounter the enemy's ambush
You know what's the
meaning of one machine-gun?
Up there, on the height.
Huh!
Do you know?
Get up, dead men.
Put on your helmets. Run down.
I said, run, run.
I wish to get to
Afghanistan already.
Sparrow.
Whatcha want?
Take my dick to piss
so tired, can't get up
Him?! Nah...
He'll overstrain himself.
Look, Snow White comes.
Come over here.
Snow White.
Snow White, come over here, sit with us.
Snow White, come here.
Come over here. Don't be afraid.
Dammit, now it'll stand till next morning.
Who's this?
Were you born yesterday?
This is Snow White, the
paramedic's daughter .
Half of Afghanistan have fucked her
They say she's hot
Not you her,
but she fucks you.
There's such a disease
How you call it?
Get outa here, scholar.
Can you try to arrange it with her?
Why to try?
She's non-refusable, just
like Kalashnikov gun.
Grab and go
How we gonna get her through two sentinels?
No, Guys. I think it's a bullshit.
The previous call up
leaving in couple of days.
And we will stay here
for three months.
If you get caught - it's your end.
Listen, Lutyi. Would you
sleep with her after
them fourty men been with her?
No.
Me neither. It's better
to die than
eat from garbage cans.
Yeah?
and l ate. I ate.
Have you ever been
starving so bad ,
that you even can't sleep?
So shut the fuck up your hole!
Our dinner was three spoons
of carpenters glue.
After eating that, we were
wandering around the city
Looking how you and your bitch
sit there in a restaurant.
Hoping to get your leftovers after!
Dig it?
And the bitches l had were all like her
l can't have something else, fuckface
Guys, stop it.
Shut up whelp ! First smell a woman.
Then talk.
Quiet, quiet.
How to quiet? You don't touch
mine
and l won't touch yours
Pick from the lgarbage cans...
Maybe she's better
than all of your rich sluts.
You bastard, one more word from you
and you'll eat shit. Got it?
Who is Soviet paratrooper?
Soviet paratrooper
Is the glory ,
power and pride of the military forces
Who is Soviet paratrooper?
Sovie paratrooper is the assurance
of all units and people.
Who the hell are you?
We are the shame of all
units and you personally.
Iisten.
Iisten, he is an idiot.
Nah. He's cool
l don't get only one thing.
Why the first unit is
always in the front?
Run with light equipment.
And  have
an hour to sit and smoke.
While we eat shit here.
We have done nothing bad.
Should be by turns. One time
for them, one time for us.
Yes, it because
their lieutenant is sane.
And ours Dygalo is an idiot
Making his ranks on us, bitch
No, he was hurt badly.
In the head
He lost all of his men
in Afghanistan
He's the only one who survived.
He's been reassigned here
But he writes letters to the minister ,
wants to come back
But with his head injury
Who needs him there?
So he's going mad on us.
We are in the deep shit guys.
Company get up !
Put on your uniform
Stand in line
Why you move like pregnant
l don't get it!
What's taking so long?
You are not soldiers,
but pregnant cockroaches!
What's the matter girls,
is it heavy?
Is't because of your skirts?
What a hell is this line ?
Dismissed
Come on, help our dystrophycs!
Get up
How you think to fight like this?
Go back, clowns
Take Chugainov up
Run
Go!
Dismissed
Lower, lower!
Keep your ass lower, dammit!
Stand up
Lower, Lower
Raising your head like this
is a gift for sniper
And your mothers get obituaries then!
I said faster!
Faster!
Dismissed
Turn back
You screwed soldier,
after dismissed come
to my office
Get up,
Run
Hold up your weapon
Quick
Second squad, come back
Run back
Lutaev, Ryabokon, pick up the soldier
Remember
never leave your soldiers behind
Forward, l said forward
10 minutes, rest
Take it
Shithead
Tell me Sparrow,
l need to care you like this
every time?
I got enough shit of my own
So, kill me, come on,
kill me
Sod off
I can't stand it anymore
Then fuck off,
step forward and tell everyone,
the ceremony is tomorrow
Yeah, l will tell !
What?! You despise me?!
I don't give a shit,
I don't care.
Olya's waiting there for you,
she can't wait anymore
Tomorrow l quit too, guys
Got a letter from my mom
It's been a while already,
she is sick
If l die,
then she has no one
Didn't want to quit first,
like some scum-sucker
Ok, guys,
is there anyone else?
I herad from the first call up
In Afghanistan you make one week out
Two at the base
And here Dygalo will finish you even before
you get to war.
He'll destroy you.
What do you say, Ryaba?
Sparrow, then we decided, yeah?
We quit together, ok?
Eyes to the center, attention !
Comrade colonel ,
The regiment is ready.
- Hello, comrades paratroopers
- Salut, comrade colonel
At ease
Everyone of you, voluntarily
Made a decision to serve in Afghanistan
Now l must ask you one question
Is there anyone who has changed his mind?
I don't ask why
Your will be merely
reassigned to another division
Who doesn't want to go to Afghanistan?
Thanks for your service
For the Soviet Union
Harder
It ain't no girl, but iron gun
Kill him
Don't fear, kill, don't fear
You only have one strike
to save your ass
Crush the ribs, rip the guts
Take 'em down
Give it to me, like this, look
Like this
Right, kill him
Come, soldier, kill him
Kill
Vorobyov
Yes
Come here
Yes, Sir
Stasenko
Come, take off your weapon,
put down your bag
Come on
Soldiers
Take the stuff away
Beat him,
punch him in the face
You are going to war,
come on, son
That's how you're gonna pet your girlfriend
Punch his mug!
Full contact , quick ! Both of you
Sparrow,
Hit first
Yeah, that's it
Come on Sparrow
Don't back off, don't fear
One more try
Get up
Come on Sparrow, hold on
Come on, come on
Come on, more
Get up, warrior, punch him!
Finish him, Stas
Get up, when he falls down,
you must finish him
Only dead man won't
shoot you in the back
Sorry, Sparrow, forgive me
Sparrow, good done
Let's continue
Looks like a plasticine
Everybody touch it
Touch it, feel it
You see, it's soft
It can take any form
looks like a harmless toy,
that everyone of you had
Every one of you molded,
squirrels, rabbits
But in a fact ,in your hands
you hold a powerful weapon
Plastic explosive
Stas!
It has its chemical formula
But we do not need to know this
Plastid is irreplaceable
It's a necessary item
in equipment of every paratrooper
The question, why
First, in this condition
It's absolutely safe, easy to store
and always available
As they say, in the hand
But in war
It is very efficient
and has enormous destructive power
But you've got to be skilled,
for using it
Warrior...
There are two simple rules
First ,the more you squeeze it,
the more it blows
Number two,
don't stick it everywhere!
But by itself this thing won't work
For it to blow we need what?
Detonator
Exactly
We need to insert detonator
Your name soldier?
Private Petrovsky
You screwed, soldier
l've got to report to your commander
Come in
Comrade lieutenant, private Petrovsky
Well molded, quite realistic
Can you paint?
I  learned painting
A portrait, kinds of big
I could
I'm here...,
The girl's writing...
We met before the war
She wants my photo
What am l gonna do?
Send it with this?
Can you , like...
Without it...
more handsome?
Yes, just need some  time,
couple of days
I certainly won't go to
see her after war
Just let her write for the meanwhile
Attention!
Go!
Goddam tractorists...
Eat this
Look
Pissed his pants
You laugh? My bed
is under Sparrow's bed
So what , birdy, do l need
to sleep with umbrella now?
I don't get it, soldier
Did you see something?
Nothing, Sir
And you?
I misunderstood, sir
Then tell me what's it all about !
I also wanna share you joy
You can swallow your snots
Can call your mama
Piss your pants, but your mission
Must be accomplished,
Die but do it , and he did
Turn back
Basic knowledge of your
communication with locals
You can get from this
But
The first thing, you should rember
when you cross the border
That you're in
a muslim state
Islam it's not merely
another religion
It's another world which
has its own laws
Another approach to life and death
Muslim doesn't afraid to die
fighting the infidel, in other words - us
If he gets killed he goes straight
to heaven
Where all he was missing in this life
awaiting him there
Water
The fruits in the garden,
beautiful maids
How Muslims treat women
it's another topic
The most important holy
thing for muslim is his house, Harram
From which derived the word Harem
The second meaning of it - "forbidden", "prohibited"
Looking at the muslim women is Harram
Everything regarding
sexual intercourse is Harram
Harram to show a muslim indecent gestures
Those you all are so used to them
For this you can get a bullet
even from a common peasant
Another important thing,
Muslim will never profane
his house with blood
That means when you enter
their village, you are
their guests
To kill a guest
even an infidel - harram
So, you must remember
this one
As long as you're in the village,
you are safe.
But after you crossed
the borderline of the village
The same man,
who drinked tea with you 5 minutes ago
May shoot you in the back
Because it is a glory to kill
an infidel
It is a staircase to heaven.
I'm telling it for you, soldier
Ah...
After all, Afghanistan is a
multinational country.
Over 20 nations live there.
Tajiks Turkmen,
Uzbeks
Pushtuns live along the Pakistani border
In the north, live
Khazars and Mongoloids
The word khazar means
thousand in Turkic languages.
Am I boring you, soldier?
Comrade captain, Does it matter
who you shoot?
During the whole history
No one ever succeded to conquer Afghanistan
No one, ever
Squad, Get up
What are we doing
in Afghanistan?
Fulfilling our
international incumbency,
and help our Afghan brothers
to resist the aggression
of imperialism.
Fire!
Private Ryabokon, done!
Private Chugainov, done!
Right down
You pull the trigger too sharp
Very dense, but too high
Breath slowly.
OK
Have you ever shot before?
No sir, I'm a painter,
l have a very accurate eye
Over here.
Ok
Give him.
Private, Vorobyov
Yes
Put down the gun and
come here.
Yes, sir!
Here. Put it there.
Run!
Oh, cool, Gioconda
Cool!
Listen, Gioconda, tell me honestly.
Why did you come
to Afghanistan?
You could sit at the headquarters and draw.
They even offered you.
You won't understand
So make it simple
Simple?
Do you see the
tank over there?
Beautiful, isn't it?
What a power!
and nothing otiose,not a bit
Weapons are
the most beautiful!
The most beautiful thing the mankind created
So what?
There was an artist named
Michelangelo in the renaissance
One day, someone asked him how
he sculpts his works.
He said, very simple,
l just take a rock and get rid of the otiose parts
Understand? Beauty is
something without anything otiose,
Without any crap.
In the war,
there is only life
and death, nonting otiose
War itself is a beauty.
Listen, Gioconda, l don't
understand you
Are you a fool or what?
What is so beautiful?
When the guts are
twisted around the tank tracks?
You think it's a kids play?
I said you won't understand
Fuck you, freak!
Guys,  letters.
Calm down!
Stasenko,
it is mine.
What day is today?
Wednesday. Third!
Sparrow,
mine
Lutaev,
Suvorov,
me!
Ryabokon
That's it
That's it?
My friends asked me out to disco.
But l will not go without you
because l love you!
Give it to me!
But tonight l found two nice boys...
You fucking got tough, bitch, motherfucker
Come on! Come on!
Come on, sparrow!
Ah...
Attention, soldiers!
Stand at attention! You screwed soldiers!
You two come to me later.
Very good!
Very good, man.
Stand at attention!
Turn back and march!
March!
Ok, guys. Listen carefully!
March steady. Don't fan out.
To the top of this rock.
Sparrow, Stas and Ryaba, you guys
hold their legs and push them over.
I don't give a fuck how, even bite 'em
Pinochet, Chugun, Gioconda,
you guys come with me.
All come with me!
March!
Be steady!
Hooray
All squads, stand up!
Stand up, l said!
Come out, lie down!
All down on the floor.
Creep, l order you!
Creep quickly! All! What?
What did you say?
I don't understand.
Stand up
I don't understand
what someone said.
Who said? Who?
Who said?
I don't know.
Who?
It is you?
I don't know who said.
Who said?
I don't know.
Go there, you!
Do you want to tell me?
Tell me. Tell me what you know
Tell to my ears!
Whisper, l will forgive you.
All of you!
Come on, l'm alone
Come on , you and me.
No one will know
Are here some normal people?
Or just  fucking freaks?
Was it a bad dream?
Aha! Maybe
dreamed something.
Looks like an aggravation
Wait! I heard that he wrote
a request again
to the headquarters.
He wanted to go to
Afghanistan with us.
He was refused
Hold on .
Who's there?
What are you doing?
Stay where you are!
Come on, quickly! Slient!
Hold this.
Is there any pot left?
Hush!
Heh! She sings again!
Did you see it !
she comes like a machine gun
Guys, Dygalo won't be looking for us?
Nope!
Why?
Because...
Lutyi ,
l thought l smelled something good!
Something left?
Take..
I'm gonna fuck tonight so hard, that it
won't rise for the next year and a half
Man, let's smoke some more
Ah, Sparrow, bird!
You know how we used to smoke
in orphan house?
Like Gypsies
One joint for all
Wanna see?
Show me
Look, what they doing!
Hey, guys, you are so good
l love y'all
Bird had enough ! Don't give him more
Otherwise we'll need to cary him again
Alright
I'm going
Tell me, you a man ?
No really, tell me,
are you a man or what?
Let's not , Oleg
What?
I have a girl, Olya,
you know how she is.
Ah, Olya
So love your Olya
Everyone has his Olya,
We all have ,
but do you remember
what you were?
Now you became a real man,
and there's last test left
You must, bird,
You gotta!
It's not a resort we going to
maybe this your last chance
You can't go a virgin to war
it's a men thing, understand?
Come on, Sparrow,
go for it, come on
Maybe she don't want me
Are you fool ?!!!
she likes you the most
Really? You kidding me
I swear, ask the boys
l am not kidding
C'mon c'mon , go!
She has seen you many times at the camp
But you paid no attention,
she felt hurt
No, l can't do this before you all
Well, drink in the meantime,
l'll be back
Are you so special?
Better than others,
l don't get it!
Shut up,
I'll explain you later
You need help Sparrow?
Want me to hold your legs
Sparrow, just go
Go fight !
Take the sword out !
If l don't come back
Say, he died bravely
Warriors, forward
Stas, what's the matter?
Why are you so sad?
I miss my family,
toss me one
It's scary a little , isn't it?
If to be honest,
without any bullshit
Scary
Not all die...
If it happens fast,
It's not that scary
The worst thing if you get crippled
When l was in Tashkent, l went to
that hospital, and some
soldiers were there
The whole ward
Each one occupies only half a bed ...
I knew a guy who came from
the battlefield
He is good,
only his bladder is cut by splinter.
He got a pipe coming from his stomach,
and a bag tied to a leg.
They call him bagpipes...
What's up with Sparrow
ls he sleeping there or reading books?
Wait, l'm going to see
You are bruts!
Understand, animals!
You all are like animals,
don't care with whom and where
I can't do like this,
You all are animals
I wanted it to be good...
What are you looking at?
Have anyone told you
that you are very beautiful?
Are you in love with me?
so marry me,
and they will come visit us
You must know it,
you are so beautiful
Are you an idiot?
Artist
Cyprida (Aphrodite)
Cyprida, coming from a sea
Cyprida
Goddess of beauty
The sea washes away
all the sins
Eternal purity
Goddess
Everyone worship her!
On your knees, you freaks
Guys, l love you
Rank
Comrade lei...At ease.
we'll......
Turn left
Run towards the plane, move
Krasnoyarsk
Is there someone from Krasnoyarsk?
I am
Where are you from?
Kraza
And l'm from Yershovka , my countryman!
Just stay cool
Ok
I got back, you'll come back too
Here, this is amulet
Take this
4 over-periods, 28 missions,
and not a scratch
Wear this, don't take it off,
do you understand
Yes
Countryman, don't take it off
Then pass it to others when you come back,
just wear it
Aye
What's your name
Oleg, and you ?
Kolya
Look there, guys
Commander, from the right
No brakes
Keep it steady
Help me
Melkumov, yes
Sitroylov, yes
Ryabokon, yes
Vanifatiev, yes
Demchenko, yes
Bekbulatov, yes
Go to the fourth company,
follow me
Bye, guys
Take care, bye
So long, man, bye
So what's your story,
junkies, alcoholics and sex maniacs.
Yor are in the 9th company
Follow me
Oh, a fresh meat is coming
Get hanged, ghosts
Attention
Stand at attention
Warriors, congratulations for
coming to the valiant 9th company
I don't get it,
Warriors
Welcome
To
The ninth
Company
Hooray, hooray, hooray
Fuck it Hohol
Take them outside and wank them there
I am lieutenant Pogrebnyak,
Forget all you've known
Here you ain't bad and ain't good
Here, you're nothing
Yes, brothers, we've  already heard
it in some other place
I plan to deal with you day and night,
until you become a good soldiers
Is it clear?
Yes, comrade lieutenat
Huh?
That's good
Private Chugainov
Why is it so gnawed?
This machine gun is Samyilin's,
He heroically died
He killed 8 ghosts by it
And got a medal
It's scratched a bit,
because he died of grenade
It's not such a big deal,
Glue it
The barrel is skewed,
How am I gonna shoot?
You are very lucky, dumbass
This gun is special
You should feel proud,
instead you're bitching here
Comr...
Solder! Sign here!
Turn left, move
Who was your former commander?
1st lieutenant Dygalo
Sashka...
I thought he retired
He slept there
Been screaming all night long,
going to a combat ,no one could sleep
Then they took him to the hospital
To Tashkent l guess
Aha
Was a good guy, joyful,
Used to laugh a lot
He had some illness,
hey doc, how'd you call it?
It is called contusion
I thought you'd say something clever
what a dickhead
Oh , shut up!
Is that snow white
girl still there?
Snow white's there
Say, painter
Is this good?
More or less
Some boy here made it by memory
Listen, Hohol
Pomidor - this son of a bitch,
gave him broken Samylin's gun
And the new one probably sold...
What? He trades weapons ?
Some die at war, and some make profits of it
Sir, l heard that we'll
go to combat in two or
three days, is that right?
Not a combat, but we go out, our mission
is occupying a height
Hold the line of defence,
protecting our convoys
Is this all?
Yes, what you thought
it's Stalingrad here?
He's so monumental,
l'd make him a statue of bronze
Kagraman
What?
Kag - ra - man
Dushmans call him so
It means angry giant
Our commander is the only one
in the whole Afghanistan
He's been nominated for hero three times
But each time he returns from a combat
He beats shit out of some brass hat
They don't take him
to the martial court, though
But he ain't getting his star .
Afanasyi, who are them?
These are the Green
Afghanistani army,
Darned Allies
There is nothing worse
than working with them
When it gets tough a little, they run
While you think they
cover your flank,
they're far behind
Three kilometers away
We got surrounded once because of them assholes
Where the Dushman
territory begins?
After the block station
There they are
They say - Russians are our friends and brothers
But when the night falls
dig out their guns
And go Allah Akbar,
and shit.
So do not haste to
join this war,kids
You'll get it anyway
You probably already made
a bet who kills a ghost first
Of course
Bet on what?
Marlboro pack
I add another one
Who was the first then, lieutenant?
Samylin,
He killed the first ghost
He also left first, in the zinc,
What remained of him,
The pieces we could gather
There they are ,savages
The frontier guard
We'll drop some ammo and food and go on