Man: The court
is open.
Yes, sir.
Captain Leland,
this court has carefully
considered your case
and has reached its conclusions
based solely upon the evidence
introduced in open court
while you were present.
At the close of the evidence,
the court was closed,
and by secret written ballot
in which at least 2/3 of the
members of the court concurred,
the court has reached
its findings,
which are, of all specifications
and of all charges, guilty.
And again by
secret written ballot
in which at least
2/3 of the members
of the court concurred,
the court has decided upon
your punishment,
which is that you be
sentenced to dismissal
from the United States army
and to forfeit all pay
and allowances
now due or to become due,
this subject to the approval
of the reviewing authority.
Any further business
before the court?
Man: No, sir.
Do I hear a motion
for adjournment?
Man: I move that
the court adjourn.
Second man:
I second the motion.
Any objections?
Apparently not.
Court is adjourned to meet
at the call of the president.
How about a game?
All right, Hansen,
but you and me
against Greer and Parsons.
Man: I'll take a cue.
Well, captain...
Anything bothering you?
There used to be a custom
in the British army
when a man disgraced
his uniform.
Too bad we can't do it.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Well, Rick...
An officer shouldn't
associate with one
who's been
dishonorably dismissed.
The regulations say so.
The adjutant gave
his permission.
In spite of the evidence,
I just can't believe.
Or if you did do it,
you must have had a reason--
well, one that you thought
was important.
Tell me.
I'm your friend.
It's all in the testimony.
Rick, I could have loaned you
the money, or part of it,
and there were others
who would have been glad.
Oh, I just can't believe.
You, of everybody I know.
Well, I guess nobody ever
really knows anybody.
What are you going to do, Rick?
I'll probably go up to Canada.
They need artillerymen there.
But, Rick...
Well, anyway, good luck.
Thanks.
Good-bye.
[Band playing march]
Man: Sit down.
I see you're an
artilleryman, Mr. Leland.
Now what exactly
is your experience,
and with what type of ordnance?
All types and calibers
of both fixed and mobile
coastal guns,
including one year
in an antiaircraft battery.
Now, where were you stationed?
Two years at fort MacArthur,
one year and 8 months
Fort Totten,
one year and two months
fort Kamehameha,
4 years in the
Panama canal zone.
Your full name?
Richard Lomas Leland.
Richard Leland?
That's right, sir.
Why, I'm sorry,
Mr. Leland,
but I believe at this time
we have a full complement
of coast artillery
officers of all ranks.
I thought the Canadian army
needed men of experience.
Oh, regardless of
his qualifications,
no one man is indispensable.
Maybe Chiang Kai-Shek
won't be so particular.
I'm aware neither of
the exact desperation
of the generalissimo's needs
nor how good are his
sources of information.
Good day, Mr. Leland.
Man: Your baggage checks,
miss Marlow.
The ship sails from pier 19.
Sailing time will be midnight,
but passengers be aboard
by 11:00, please.
Marlow: Thank you.
What was that boat
you were talking about?
The Genoa Maru, sailing
tonight for Yokohama
by way of New York, the
Panama canal, and Honolulu.
It's for me.
Excuse, please?
How much?
To port of final
destination, $212.80.
Excuse, please.
I cannot promise passage
on the Genoa Maru
unless we have cancellation.
However, there is possibility.
If you will leave
name and address,
I shall inform you in time
before sailing.
When is the next sailing?
Next Wednesday.
The Nakamura Maru bigger,
more passenger space.
Same fare.
Try to make it Genoa mar...
I'll be packed and waiting.
We trust we can be
satisfactorily of
service, Mr. Leland.
[Speaking Japanese]
Man: Good night,
Mr. Leland.
Night.
This is Mr. Leland
speaking.
The N.Y.K. Steamship
office call me?
You're sure?
Oh, thanks.
[Telephone ringing]
Yes?
Yeah.
Yeah, speaking.
Oh, the Genoa Maru it is, eh?
OK. You send
the tickets over,
and I'll pay the messenger.
Right.
[Bell ringing]
[Speaking Japanese]
Passenger?
Yes.
Bags, sir, shoulda be.
What time do we sail?
Soon. 10 minutes
or half-hour, shoulda be.
It should.
Leland Richard.
No, Richard Leland.
Shoulda be.
Bed hard?
It's very hard.
Shoulda be.
My name Sugi.
Uh, I think I'll call you
"shoulda be,"
if you don't mind.
Shoulda be.
For drink.
Wash hand.
Fan.
For read.
Anything else?
[Bell ringing]
[Whistle blowing]
[Clears throat]
We're going to know
each other eventually,
so why not now?
That seems reasonable enough.
I'm Alberta Marlow.
My name's Rick Leland.
Would you mind
stepping into the light?
Please.
Oh, and a jap freighter, too.
You'd better pinch me.
I don't think
I know you that well.
Pretty girl on a boat
with no college boys,
no handsome officers,
no eligible men
of any description...
Why, it's wonderful.
You've traveled a lot.
Some, but never so luxuriously.
This is my first time
on a big ship.
Well, this is not a ship.
This is a boat.
In medicine hat,
we wouldn't know
about such things.
That where you come from?
How far you going?
Through the Panama canal
to Los Angeles
and then back home by train.
Vacation?
Mm-hmm.
I'll try to make the trip
as pleasant as possible.
Thank you.
Good night, Mr. Leland.
Oh, no. Don't go.
Let's go into
the salon and talk.
Sorry. Hope I'll see you
around again soon.
Oh, we'll probably
bump into each other.
Good night.
Thick night out.
Yes, sir.
You can't open the liquor
till you get outside
the 12-mile limit, can you?
That is so.
Silly rule, huh?
Yes, sir.
Excuse, please.
Yes.
I presume you're Mr. Leland.
That's right.
I'm Dr. Lorenz. Not
much chance of mistaking
one's fellow voyagers
on this passage.
Not much.
May I inquire where
you're bound for?
Across the pacific--
the orient.
Excellent. I, too.
The Philippines, that is.
I hold the chair
of sociology at
the university there.
[Speaking Japanese]
My man. He doesn't
speak English.
That would be "T. Oki"
of the passenger list?
I take him everywhere.
The Japanese make
great servants.
Will this be your first trip
to the orient, Mr. Leland?
Never been further than Hawaii.
Indeed? I have
lived and worked
in the far east
going on 30 years.
That's a long time.
The oriental way of life
holds a great appeal for me.
I'm going to take a turn
about deck before retiring.
Would you care to join me?
That's a good idea.
You're an American,
are you not, Mr. Leland?
Yes.
You probably don't share my
enthusiasm for the Japanese.
Oh, I don't know. I never
thought much about them.
Wonderful little
people, wonderful.
Greatly misunderstood,
believe me.
To know them--that is,
to really know them
is to feel the deepest
affection toward them.
I understand we have
a charming young lady
passenger aboard.
Yes, a creature of
rare loveliness, doctor.
She walks in beauty.
I'm a very, very
happy man--but very.
Usually, on a freighter--
I know, but not this one.
A fellow couldn't do
half as well
on a transatlantic liner.
I have no objection
to your discussing me,
but would you mind doing
it a little farther off?
I'm trying to sleep.
You're fortunate--
fortunate and young.
Occasionally, I wish
I were young again.
Ha ha! Good night.
Good night, sir.
[Lorenz chuckles]
[Bell ringing]
[Man speaking Japanese]
Good morning.
Ah, Mr. Leland.
I hope and trust
you had a good night.
I don't remember,
so I must have.
You missed something
by sleeping so late.
We dropped the pilot
a little while ago.
No. What I came to see,
I didn't miss.
Are your legs always blue?
They're not blue.
Oh, shoulda be, give me
that blanket, will you?
I don't want a blanket.
I want the sunshine.
Your teeth are chattering
like a crap game.
This is November,
and it's winter sunshine.
Thank you.
Pure selfishness on my part.
If you catch pneumonia,
what will happen to our romance?
What will happen to it
anyway if you don't shave.
I shall enjoy
listening to you two,
if you'll permit me.
You can referee.
Relationships between
modern young Americans
seem most peculiar
to a man of my years.
You give your lovemaking
an assault-and-battery twist.
Living so long in the far east
has perhaps given me
a more or less
oriental view of things.
We were discussing
Philippine economics
when we were so
rudely interrupted.
My own field.
Miss Marlow was kind enough
to listen to me.
They're going to be free
in 1946, aren't they?
They are, provided
America doesn't insist
on fighting a war with Japan.
It's my opinion, however,
that that contingency
is going to keep the Philippines
from ever being free.
Won't Japan gobble them up?
No offense, but Japan
or Canada or anybody else
can have the Philippines,
as far as I'm concerned.
It's hot in Manila.
Might be even hotter
before long.
Hot enough to go
around in shorts?
Ah, there's a Canadian for you.
Let them take their clothes off,
and they're happy.
Look, an American warship.
Oh, yes--
a 1918 flush Decker.
44-inch .50 caliber guns,
one 3-inch .23 caliber
antiaircraft gun.
Not very formidable.
Don't you find, Mr. Leland,
that the United States
is inclined to forget
that most of the world
is at war already
with more war to come,
perhaps in the pacific?
Well, if it comes, it'll
have to do without me.
Indeed, Mr. Leland?
You seem about the right age.
I'll see you later.
A very interesting young man.
Very.
[Speaking Japanese]
Lorenz: I don't
believe our captain
will mind my
explaining his words.
What he just said
means in English,
"permit me to take."
Something like saying
grace before a meal.
It also expresses
his thankfulness
to his ancestors.
That is right.
Excuse, please.
I like that.
I come from a long
line of grace Sayers.
Excuse, please.
Miss Marlow, Mr. Leland,
chief engineer Mitsuko.
How do you do?
[Speaks Japanese]
Excuse, please.
Chief engineer has no English.
Chief engineer has a good grip.
Ha ha! Some joke.
I think I'll skip
the bread pudding.
Just bring me some coffee.
I hope you're a good sailor,
miss Marlow.
The Genoa Maru has her
moments when a blow comes on.
I wonder if it will
really get rough.
This is rough.
Not nearly rough enough.
I want to go through something
I can talk about afterwards.
You probably will,
but you may not want
to talk about it.
I think there's something
elemental in a storm.
It appeals more
to women than to men.
They're more
elemental--
than what?
Than women--men.
I hope so, honey.
I'm your friend.
Ha ha ha.
Ha! Some joke.
I suppose I shouldn't smoke
my cigar right now.
No. Let her be happy
for a little while...
A little while.
Do you know what I'd like to do?
I'd like to go up in the bow
if I had a man to hang on to.
I'm your man anyplace, even
the crow's-nest. Let's go.
Marlow: Excuse me,
gentlemen.
Leland: Mmm.
Better bring your coat.
Gentlemen.
[Speaking Japanese]
Whoo!
This is wonderful!
What a figurehead you'd make.
Look at the stern, the way
it goes up and down.
It goes down so far you'd think
it would never come up again.
And look at the way
the masts are going.
Don't look too long.
Keep your eyes off
the water below.
Oh, I feel wonderful.
You are wonderful.
I wish I had a better suit.
It doesn't matter
about the suit.
You have a kind face.
You think so?
Yes, I do, Rick.
That's the first time
you ever called me Rick.
Is it?
Yes.
What's the matter?
Look, I didn't mean that.
I did. Why didn't you?
A fella with a suit like mine
shouldn't go around
kissing girls.
See, I--
are you getting sick?
I don't know.
How do girls usually act
when you kiss them?
They don't turn green.
Then I'm sick.
Get me out of here.
Everything was going
so beautifully.
Why did you have to eat
that bread pudding?
Oh, shoulda be,
the lady's been stabbed
by a bread pudding.
Do what you can for her.
Bread pudding?
Too bad.
Shoulda be.
Ah, Mr. Leland.
Beating it?
Patience is a game one
only plays out of boredom,
which condition of mind
it does nothing to relieve.
Will you have a drink with me?
Thanks. I will.
Have another.
I shouldn't.
I'm strapped.
Sorry to hear that,
Mr. Leland,
but what possible
bearing can that have?
If the fella I'm
counting on in New York
doesn't kick through,
I won't be able
to buy you a drink.
That doesn't alarm me greatly.
Miss Marlow dying.
Want to see Rick.
Excuse me.
I'll be right back.
I understand you're dying.
Yes.
You want to be buried at sea?
They have a very nice service.
They stitch you up in a bag,
and you wouldn't like that.
I'll have shoulda be
put you on ice.
Very amusing.
A woman suffering.
Stop being such a baby.
Even if I do live,
I'll never be the same again.
It happens to everybody
that eats bread pudding
and looks at a mast.
The mistake I made
was in kissing you.
I was all right till then.
I resent that.
I'll never let you
kiss me again.
We won't argue.
You're not well,
and you don't know
what you're saying.
I do too.
Stop that!
Don't tell me you're the kind
that goes to bed
with your shoes on.
I need them on for suddenly
have to run down the hall.
All right, darling.
I'll humor you.
Humor me?! Ha!
When you're sitting
at the table tonight
eating your head off,
think of the girl whose
happiness you wrecked.
Yes, darling.
I pity the woman you ever marry.
I'll never get married.
The kind of a lover I am,
it wouldn't be fair.
Any wife of mine would spend
her life running down hallways.
You aren't married,
are you, Rick?
No. Does that
make you feel better?
You make me sick.
And if you stay here
one minute longer,
I'll prove it to you.
I take it our lovely
traveling companion
has a touch of mal de mer.
It was only a matter of time.
She speeded things up
by looking at the mast.
What a pity.
Yes. She doesn't look too
well with a green face.
From certain remarks
you dropped on deck
this morning,
Mr. Leland,
I gather you're
quite well-informed
in matters pertaining to
the United States Navy.
Yes, I know
a little bit about it.
You were perhaps in the Navy?
No, coast artillery.
Army.
How interesting.
Not so interesting.
Were you ever
stationed in Panama?
Part of the time.
I hope you don't think
I am too inquisitive.
Not at all.
You're furnishing the liquor.
It's hardly an excuse
for asking a man his history.
I haven't got any history.
I was in the army.
I got kicked out.
I went up to Canada
and tried to enlist,
and they wouldn't have me.
I can't understand that.
It's perfectly simple.
They don't want men that--
have been kicked out
of another army.
You're Frank, anyhow.
I admire that quality.
Why shouldn't I be?
So-called facts.
I'm known on every army post
in this hemisphere.
I understand how you feel,
but you can't afford
to be bitter
against your own countrymen,
particularly in
these troubled times.
Can't I?
How do you know
what I can afford?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to intrude
an unwanted opinion.
OK, doc.
I'll hire out to whoever
will pay for my services.
Chiang Kai-shek,
Hirohito...
Anybody that will pay.
I can't tell you how
I sympathize with you.
Were you stationed long
in the canal zone?
Quite a while.
I served at Fort Amador
and fort Sherman.
I was attached to staff.
Amador guards the pacific
approach, doesn't it?
Yeah.
I think I've had
too much to drink.
Have you?
Can I help you,
Mr. Leland?
Sick. Need help.
Go away.
Tea? Hold head?
Beat it.
Too much whiskey.
Very sick. Shoulda be.
Beat it.
Ha ha ha ha!
This is the happiest
moment of my life.
My prayers have been answered.
Close the door when you leave.
They have a nice burial at sea.
Go away, will you?
I want to die alone,
without a friend.
You will. Is there
anything I can do--
something to make you sicker?
Just hang around.
Keep your shoes on.
I hope you'll need them.
Ha ha ha ha!
Rick, before I get off
the gangplank,
are there any stray
hayseeds in my hair?
Now, look, angel, I've got
to see a friend of mine.
I think I can borrow some money.
You wait here for me.
Only be a few minutes.
Ok.
Man: Here you are, folks,
the collected ingenuity
of the 4 corners of
the earth for a quarter.
25 cents apiece.
Each and every article is
unconditionally guaranteed.
If you get them home
and they don't work,
bring them back.
I won't be here.
Here's something nice.
Take it home
to scare your friends.
You won't have many friends.
What's the matter, Buddy?
You taking root there?
Step right up, folks.
25 cents. 1/4 of a dollar.
It amuses the kiddies.
It amazes the old folks...
Eighth floor.
Eight, please.
[Telephone rings]
Atlas finance company.
One moment, please. Yes, sir?
I'd like to see
Mr. hart.
May I have your name, please?
Leland.
He's expecting you.
Go right in. Yes.
Well, glad to see you,
captain Leland.
Colonel hart.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Say, I had to duck a fellow
on the way up here--
white man, tall, thin,
wore a long black
overcoat, derby hat.
I think I know the man.
We may soon pay him a visit.
How did it go up north?
Everything went
about as expected,
but I must say
that their rejection
of my army application
was just a little bit
on the insulting side.
By the way, how did you manage
to get me on the boat?
Your story was told
in the right quarters.
Dr. Lorenz was
well informed about you
before you even came aboard.
Now, there's a girl--
yes, I know. We've been
checking on her,
but from what I hear, I
don't think she's the type.
Would she be there
if she weren't?
Possibly, but I doubt it,
however, that's up
to you to find out.
What's she like, captain?
Well, uh...
Remember the girl you
used to dream about
when you were 19?
Why, very well.
This is her in the flesh.
I see.
How are you
and the genial doctor
getting along?
Famously, I'd say.
Well, don't take
too much for granted.
Lorenz is no chump,
or he wouldn't
have lasted so long.
He may be just
giving you enough rope.
Another thing, captain,
remember, on shipboard,
anything
can happen to a man--
a box drops on your skull,
a wave washes you overboard.
I'll be careful.
You're going to have
a new shipmate tonight.
Getting aboard is a young man
by the name of Totsuiko,
Joe Totsuiko,
a member of the
Kokuryu-Kai, and tough.
A jap gunsel,
so watch out
if you bump into him.
Yeah, I'll do that.
There's one other item.
The details of your disgrace
have been widely circulated
in Panama and
across the pacific,
so you won't be
welcomed, exactly,
with open arms.
I'll be on my own down there?
Smith is expecting you.
No one else knows.
Some big things
are brewing, captain.
We have reason to believe
they'll boil over soon.
We don't know how soon
or what side of the pot,
but they're sure
to involve the canal,
and that's where you come in
because Lorenz may or
may not be the key man.
It's up to you to find out.
Success.
Thank you.
I hope you and the girl
I wanted to marry when I was 19
have a nice lunch together.
Good-bye, sir.
Good-bye.
Who's your friend?
I don't know.
I hate to complain, but
he's been pretty nasty.
Yeah? About what?
The usual thing.
Do you want to meet this lady?
No.
She was under the impression
you wanted to talk to her.
Not me. I guess I was just
reciting something to myself.
Why don't you recite
something to me?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I got to get going.
It's not polite to walk out
on a lady like that.
First you say you're sorry,
then
you say good-bye.
I beg your pardon, lady.
I guess I mistook you
for a girl who
used to come in here
and sit all the time.
It won't happen again.
Why didn't you really hit him?
Were you afraid of him?
No. He had my number.
Did you get your money?
Yeah. More than I expected.
Did I talk fast!
In that case, you're going
to get yourself a new suit.
This has been
some day for a girl
from medicine hat.
Is that a gag, or do you really
come from a place
called medicine hat?
What's wrong with medicine hat
it's hot in summer
and cold in winter,
nothing ever happens there.
You happened there.
That's good enough for me.
By any chance, are you
a woman of means,
by any chance, I hope?
My father's a farmer.
I work in a 10-cent store.
I sell peanut brittle.
Oh, I see, you whipped up
the gaudy garments you wear
on the family sewing machine.
I suppose I'm on
your blacklist now.
Oh, no. I'm used
to bad luck.
It'll probably end up
with captain higoto
marrying us on the boat.
Oh, no. I want
a church wedding
and a groom who has
more than two suits.
How long were you
in Panama, Rick?
About 4 years.
Did you ever hear of a man
by the name of Morton--
Dan Morton?
Yeah. Yeah. He's
a planter, isn't he?
Lot of dough. Why?
He's related to some
friends of mine.
You'd better look him up.
He might take a fancy to you
and leave you all his money.
I'm not so obsessed with
money as you seem to be.
I can do without it.
You stick around with me,
and you're going to get
plenty of practice.
We can walk to the pier.
You ought to
save your money.
This is no time to
be a pinchpenny.
I'm wooing a girl.
Pier 16.
Someone should tell
our little friend
that tight overcoats
and guns
don't go together.
He's liable to get
picked up by a cop.
Pier 16.
If we'd known
he was coming here,
we could have given him a lift.
What's up, Rick?
You stay here.
You can't dump me
like this. Something's
going to happen.
Now, go back. Don't be
an innocent bystander.
They always get hurt.
You all right, doc?
Yes.
You know him?
I don't think so.
At any rate, he isn't
a close friend.
OK, then, we better
send for the police.
If you don't mind,
I'd prefer that you
didn't. Miyuma.
[Speaking Japanese]
If the police were
called in, there might
be an investigation.
Might not be able to sail.
It's none of
my business what
you do with him.
He wasn't shooting at me.
I can never
thank you enough,
Mr. Leland.
Oh, skip it, doctor.
I was just coming on board
and practically
stumbled over the guy.
How you doing, angel?
I think I got pushed
in the face by somebody.
My lipstick smeared.
Aw, you look cute.
And now if you'll excuse me,
I'll go to my cabin...
And faint.
I hope no more of
your homicidal friends
are on the pier.
Standing so close to you
might be bad luck.
First officer miyuma
is taking care of that.
[Gunshot]
You weren't kidding.
I suppose you're wondering
about this
little incident,
Mr. Leland.
No, not particularly.
As you know,
I'm a resident of
the Philippines.
In fact, I consider
myself a Philippine
national.
And what do the Filipinos
consider you?
It's unfortunate
that some of
my fellow citizens
resent my
realistic attitude
toward Japan.
A few of them
even go so far as
to call me traitor.
That misguided
little man in
the long overcoat
undoubtedly believed
he was acting on
patriotic principles.
Whatever he believed,
he believed pretty strongly.
If I were you,
just from a health
standpoint,
I think I'd give up the japs.
I'm afraid my ties with
the Japanese are rather
too close for that:
Financially, spiritually,
ideologically,
and otherwise.
If those ties involve
some personal danger,
I don't mind,
considering the ultimate reward.
Well, then,
if you don't mind,
I shouldn't mind either.
I'm being Frank with
you, Mr. Leland, because
you saved my life.
Naturally, anything I say
is in confidence.
Naturally.
All that worries me
is that I came
on this trip
for my health and pleasure,
but I seem
to have come to
the wrong place.
I never saw such
a gunned-up boat
in my life.
Really?
Yes. Your little
Filipino friend
had a gun.
Sugi's got a gun,
and that wasn't
an apple
the first officer
was holding
in his pocket.
You got a gun?
Even I, Mr. Leland.
Mine's bigger than yours.
I usually like
to keep this locked
up in my suitcase,
but with all these
guns around, what's
a fella going to do?
I wouldn't worry
about it if I were you.
In fact, I wouldn't even
think about it.
Thanks for the tip.
Did you and miss Marlow
have a good time in New York?
Wonderful.
Saw your man, got your money?
I got it. Miss Marlow
made me spend it
on a new suit.
It's very handsome.
Yes. She seemed to think
it made some improvement.
Well, I'll be hitting the hay.
If anybody else
starts throwing
slugs at you, doc,
don't forget to duck.
I believe I'll be
a little better
prepared. Thank you.
Good night.
Hey.
Am I nuts, or did I
hear some shooting
a few minutes ago?
Did I miss anything?
Firecrackers.
Chinese new year's.
Maybe I am nuts,
but it sounded to me
like those firecrackers
were shot from a muzzle.
My name's Joe Totsuiko.
Rick Leland.
I'm sure glad
there's someone around
that speaks my language.
I'm rooming with
that dope named T. Oki.
He's got his lip
buttoned up for good
as far as I can figure out.
Where you bound for?
The orient.
Me, too. My old man's
sending me down there
to work for one of my uncles.
Say, I wonder if those
Panamanian mamas are all
they're cracked up to be.
Terrific, Joe, simply terrific.
Well, I'll see you
around, Ricky.
Yeah. Take it
easy, Joe.
Without knocking.
Where's your modesty?
What's going on on this boat?
Nothing's going on on this boat.
Shh! Not so loud.
Well, that is, nothing
except an attempted
assassination.
But why get so excited
about a little thing
like that?
Who are you after?
Are you a g-man
or something?
What if I was?
I just wondered.
Look, I'm just
a private citizen,
and I happened
to be passing a room
where one guy was trying
to bump off another guy,
which, as you know,
happens to be
against the law.
Happened to be passing.
You followed
our little friend
in the tight overcoat,
and then you lied to
Dr. Lorenz about happening
to stumble over him,
you can't do that to me.
If it'll make you happy,
I'm J. Edgar hoover.
Here's my badge.
Some joke. Mr. Leland,
I believe that a man
should tell the woman
he's going to marry
everything.
Oh, in that case,
I'll come clean.
[Bell ringing]
I look old,
but that's because
I've worried a lot.
Actually, I haven't
yet reached the age
of legal consent,
and if you don't
get out of here, I'm
going to yell for help.
All right.
You can get yourself
another heiress.
Powder, angel, and when
you go, stop thinking
and keep your mouth shut.
I never saw anybody
like you--you never
have any clothes on.
Well, if anybody
heard you complaining
about it,
they'd put you in
the psychopathic ward.
[Bell tolling]
[Reading in Japanese]
"You birds
of passage,
do not fight
but help each other
in your flight."
The Japanese build
their poetry like
they do their houses.
Read some more, Joe.
You better turn over.
This side's done.
[Reading in Japanese]
"Cherry blossoms
at the well
in danger are.
See
drunken man."
I think I'll get drunk.
Your occidental poet
is wont to describe
grand passions
and heroic events,
not so with the Japanese.
Their emotions are stirred
by some tiny fragment of life
possessing the quality of beauty.
This he would
extract, reduce,
distill, as it were,
down to its purest essence.
Then they do
have emotions,
I mean, like us.
I mean, you're
always so calm. You
never show anything.
We are taught not to.
It is our way of life.
We must not show too much
sadness or too much joy.
If you praise what we have,
we say it is nothing.
If you admire our sons,
we must say they are unworthy.
You're most
eloquent today,
captain higoto.
Yes.
The nisei aren't
quite so calm.
Take me for instance, kid.
I'm a live wire.
What are nisei?
Second-generation
Japanese, those born
in the good old U.S.A.
They represent a
very small fraction,
fortunately.
Hope there's nothing
personal in that, doc.
Oh, no.
[Bell tolling]
Excuse, please.
Anybody want
to play shuffleboard?
Leland: Not me, Joe.
I'm sleepy.
How about you, doc?
Shuffleboard?
Hardly.
However, a game of
gin rummy, perhaps.
Boy, let me at them pasteboards.
At last, we're alone.
Now, listen, bright eyes--
no romance.
There's something
very interesting
over there, Ricky.
Where?
What do you mean?
T. Oki.
That's not the same oki
that came down from
Halifax with us.
That's another man.
The heat's
getting you, angel.
They all look alike.
No, they don't either,
not if you examine
them closely.
Did you ever notice
how the first oki stood?
He stood with
his head bowed
and his shoulders bent.
This man
stands up straight
with his shoulders back.
The first oki
never put his hands
in his pockets.
This man keeps his
in his coat pockets
all the time.
Take it easy, angel.
Take it easy.
You're on your way
to being a first-class
detective,
but I wouldn't see
too much all at once, or it
might be your last case.
What do you mean?
You're getting
a bad burn, you know it?
I don't feel like I am.
If I were you, I'd go
inside and put stuff on.
Oh, it's all right.
Remember the bread pudding.
Stick them up.
Boom.
Oh, I was only
kidding, oki.
Don't get sore.
Some joke, huh?
[Nervous laughter]
[Knock on door]
Mr. Leland,
may I come in?
Yeah, come ahead.
Who won the gin rummy?
As Mr. Totsuiko put it,
I was skunked 4 times.
Have a drink, doc?
Thank you.
Amusing fellow--
Joe.
Quite.
A little of him goes a long way.
[Bell tolling]
Your health.
No. To yours.
Younger men always
have more to live for.
That is if they're lucky.
In my experience,
one has to be smart
to be lucky.
I hope I'll be smart.
I'm interested
in you, Mr. Leland,
especially since
you saved my life.
Ah.
You're too modest.
Look, if you
feel that calls
for some dough...
That isn't exactly my
idea, though it might
be worth some help.
Such as?
One night you told me
about your troubles
in the army.
I'd like to hear more
about that.
I got in a jam with a dame.
Yes?
I needed some dough,
had access to
the regimental funds,
so I borrowed it,
intending to put it
back, of course.
Of course.
They found out first.
The brass hats could've
given me a chance
if they'd wanted to,
but they didn't.
They tied me up
with pink ribbons
and threw me to the wolves.
You can write your own finish.
Whatever that
is to be, you'll
need some money.
You can have more
when you want it,
within reason, of course.
What's my part of the deal?
I never discuss being
a traitor with a man.
You'll find it easier
if you don't think
about that part of it.
Go ahead.
Very well.
In a day or two,
you'll talk to me
about certain installations
in the vicinity of both
balboa and Cristobal,
with particular reference
to antiaircraft emplacements,
railway guns,
and ammunition dumps.
All you have to do is
to remember accurately.
That ought to be worth
quite a lot.
You'll find me quite generous.
You're not only
interesting to me now,
you're also valuable.
That shouldn't cause you
any anxiety.
You mind if it does?
If, uh...If you
were to apply
for life insurance
stating all the facts,
the company's actuaries
might decide
there were certain
imponderables existent
in your position--
for instance, having
committed yourself,
I wouldn't want you
to change your mind.
It might turn out
to be most unfortunate.
All right.
Remember what I said,
Mr. Leland,
that it would be easier
not to entertain
certain thoughts?
Miss Marlow burning up.
She say
please come quick,
put out fire.
Shoulda be.
Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Ooh.
You certainly are
a girl of many colors.
First your legs get blue,
then your face
turns green, and now
you're red all over.
I never knew what
suffering was until I
came on this pleasure trip.
Your trouble is
you always know
all the answers
till the results are posted.
I knew you couldn't
resist at least one
"I told you so."
[Whistling]
It's true. Seeing me
in pain does give you
pleasure.
Oh, no, precious, it isn't that.
Well, then, what are you
so happy about?
Well, I just got some
money from Dr. Lorenz
for saving his life.
Rick, you didn't
actually take money
for saving a man's life?
Is there any other
reason you know of
why I should
take money
from Dr. Lorenz?
But, Rick...
Oh, Rick, you're not much
account, are you?
I think I'll make
a career out of
saving lives.
Listen, precious,
if that bothers you
so much,
you're in for
a real shock when
we get to Panama.
How?
Well, you're
going to hear
some things about me
that aren't very nice.
What kind of things?
I believe I'll leave that
to the people
who'll get fun
out of telling you.
Will what they tell me be true?
Yes.
Then I won't listen.
Now I know you didn't
come from medicine hat.
Ha!
[Speaking Japanese]
What's all that about?
Judo is more
than a mere contest.
Its devotees form a brotherhood,
similar in many respects
to our western freemasonry.
It, too, has its degrees
and its secrets
as well as its
religious--
or should I say
philosophical
background.
Leland: Come again?
It's an oriental concept
that destructive force
acts upon itself,
and there you have
the principle of jujitsu--
to turn the power
of one's antagonist
upon himself
and by so doing, vanquish him.
That's the art of the thing.
How would all that
stack up against
a right cross?
Throw one at me, Rick.
What?
Go ahead.
Throw one at me.
[Chuckles]
You mean that, Joe?
Sure, I mean it.
Sock me one.
All right.
You asked for it.
You better get rid
of those glasses.
Oh!
Marlow: Oh, Rick.
No hard feelings.
[Bell ringing]
[Speaking Japanese]
Unfortunate, most unfortunate.
Something wrong, doctor?
Seems the canal
is being put into repairs
so far as ship's flying
the Japanese colors
are concerned.
This ship can't go through?
Precisely. It will have
to sail around the horn.
We shall be forced
to get off at Cristobal
and await another boat,
unless we are prepared
to add another 60 or 90
days to our voyage,
which I most certainly am not.
So sorry to cause you
this inconvenience.
Excuse, please.
Money will be refunded,
of course.
Where will you stay
in Panama, Mr. Leland?
The panamerican.
Very quiet and respectable.
That ain't for me.
Where are you going, beautiful?
Someplace where they have
a bath in the hall
and 40-cent lunch.
I know the guy who
owns the panamerican.
He'll give you a rate.
Perhaps I'll try
the panamerican.
Well, I hate
to recommend places.
In this case,
I'm sure our tastes
will be similar.
Well, I see
I ain't got any
folks to meet me.
Can I give you
some directions, Joe?
No, thanks, Rick.
I'll find my way.
It's been nice knowing
you kids. I'll be seeing
you one of these days.
Keep your Dukes up.
[Speaking Japanese]
Sayonara, captain.
Good-bye, captain.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
[All speaking]
Too much.
$5.00
shoulda be.
Forget it.
I'm a rich man.
Good-bye, captain.
I do not know,
but I think I might
have saved Dr. Lorenz
some trouble on my boat.
I think him will have
very bad luck with you.
Everybody has bad luck
with me. Good-bye.
Good-bye.
Hello, Leland.
What are you doing back here?
You ought to have
more sense than to
come back here again.
Free country, isn't it?
It sure is, for guys like you.
Sam, this is miss Marlow
and Dr. Lorenz.
Very nice you come here.
Panamerican need beauty.
Sam, this lady is very poor.
You don't mind my
parading your poverty?
Not if it does the trick.
I told her that I had
a pull with you.
Can you take care of her cheap?
Can do.
[Speaking foreign language]
I would like a room
with a northern
exposure,
if you please.
All the same floor,
all close together.
Your room not quite ready.
Maybe so have tea while wait.
Maybe so.
I'll be right along.
Office.
What's the matter you, Rick?
What's the matter you
"what's the matter" me?
All the time people
say you're no good.
Big smell from up north.
What's the matter you come back?
Too much army here.
Everyone know.
You're through with Panama.
Panama through with you.
Well, Sam, maybe
I won't be here long.
Maybe so you need money
go other place.
No, Sam.
I don't need money.
You no need money?
Sam smell big fish.
Sam keep nose clean,
Sam no smell fish.
No catchee trouble.
All the time you like trouble.
Maybe so
Dr. Lorenz trouble?
Maybe so.
Girl, too?
I don't know, Sam.
I hope she's all right.
She got your bad.
Much trouble--
all the time, much trouble.
Sam...
You can help me.
People tell you things.
People tell me
because I don't tell.
I tell, they don't
tell me anymore.
Ok, Sam, if you don't
want to help me,
you don't have to.
Can do.
I knew you would,
Sam. Thanks.
Be careful.
If I get any more careful,
I won't be any good.
Much trouble.
All the time, much trouble.
[Door closes]
Key, sir.
Room 24.
Thanks. Hey!
Thanks, seor.
Mr. Leland,
may I pay you a visit?
Yeah, sure.
Come on in.
Hot.
Very.
Ice water.
Room 24, please.
Well, doc, what's on your mind?
Now that we're in Panama,
I think it's time you began
to earn your money.
Ah, hot!
Ok, doc, where do we begin?
Pedro Miguel locks
will be a good place
for a starter.
How many batteries are there?
What are their caliber?
Antiaircraft or heavy stuff?
Begin with
the 16-inch guns.
Now, let's see.
The last time I was
down here 2 years ago,
there were double railway guns
east and west,
two twin concrete
embrasures half a mile
to the north,
one 4-gun turret of
shore-mounted navies
back of hill 14.
But what's the idea?
You know all that already.
Testing me, eh?
You examined the money
I gave you?
That's right.
Do we go on?
We go on.
What specific knowledge have you
of the military plane patrol
over the canal area?
Well...2 years ago--
what happened 2 years ago
doesn't interest me.
What I want is the current
schedule of the patrol planes.
When the flights take off,
exactly what areas they cover,
what altitude they conduct
their reconnaissance,
and the precise time
of their return.
[Knock on door]
Ice water, sir.
That's going
to take some getting.
I'll pay generously for it.
How much?
Shall we say $500?
Shall we say $1,500?
I said I'll pay generously,
not foolishly.
Now, just a minute.
The only place I can
get that information
is air force headquarters,
and that won't be easy.
It may take almost
a week of trying
before things begin
to break just right.
I'll make you a deal--
1,500 if you get it
by 5:00 today.
5:00? Why all the rush?
There's no rush.
Just $1,000 worth, eh?
Remember, Mr. Leland,
it's your place to answer
questions, not to ask them.
Sorry. I--I'm
a little new
at this game.
Of course, of course.
Oh, and by the way,
don't get the ingenious
idea of selling me out
to the American authorities.
It wouldn't pay...
In the long run.
Marlow: Wait a minute!
Who is it?
It's me.
How you doing?
All right.
You happy?
Very.
What's the program?
I'm free as a bird.
I've got a couple of
things to attend to.
I'll meet you at
the international bar
at 1:00.
How do I get there?
Tell any cab driver.
Come as you are.
What can I do for you, sir?
I want to open an account.
Sit down, please.
Thank you.
Savings or checking?
Savings.
And, uh, what is the name?
Leland.
Richard Leland.
Will you sign there, please?
Mm-hmm.
There you are.
How much did you wish
to deposit?
$1,241.00
no one can get close
enough to hear us
without our seeing them.
Go ahead with your report,
captain Leland.
Lorenz is hooked.
I'm on his payroll--
$350 worth.
He must think
you're very valuable.
What have you got?
Not much.
Lorenz seems to be head man.
They switched his valet
in New York.
The new T. Oki could
be a naval officer.
He is.
Have you any idea
what Lorenz is up to?
No, but I've got a hunch
that whatever is going to happen
will happen soon.
He offered me the family jewels
for the canal patrol
flight schedule,
and he wants it quick.
Well, we could
hardly afford--
I think it's worth the gamble
to keep his confidence.
Hmm. We could make up
a fake schedule.
Yes, we could,
but all he'd have to do
would be to get
a pair of binoculars
and a watch to find out
he'd been tricked.
No. I think we'd better
give him the real dope.
I'll phone you if things
get to looking dirty,
and you can always
change the schedule.
Very well.
Under the circumstances,
I suppose it wouldn't be
too dangerous.
We hardly think
they'd keep those two men
in Washington
I they intended
to pull a fast one.
Shoulda be.
I beg your pardon?
Now, about the schedule.
Oh, yes. I'll have
a copy of the schedule
at your hotel this afternoon.
Any more dope about the
girl from medicine hat?
Yes. She never
lived there.
She's a new yorker,
a buyer for Rogers fifth Avenue.
She's made 8 trips abroad
in the last 2 years.
Of course, that could
be part of her work.
Hmm.
Well...
I guess that slams
the door on miss Marlow.
Funny thing, though.
She pointed out
the oki switch to me.
Sometimes the best way
to gain a confidence
is to give one.
What have you got
on a fella
named Dan Morton?
Owns a plantation here
called "bountiful."
Morton.
Age: 55 to 60.
Came here in '31.
Heavy drinker.
Bit of a dipsomaniac.
May be a little cracked.
His plantation
has been profitable.
Has substantial accounts
in 3 banks.
Apparently no entanglements,
either political or feminine.
Seems all right.
Why do you ask?
She asked me about him.
Said some people in Halifax
told her to look him up.
Personally, I don't
believe that anyone
with as much money as Dan Morton
would bother with the small
profit that treason pays,
and he's hardly the type
to go in for the excitement.
However, you never can tell.
And now I think you've
been here long enough, captain.
I'll check with you later.
You send a schedule over
to my hotel at 5:00.
Of course you'll phone me
at the first suspicion
that they're making use of it.
And, uh, your book, captain.
Of course.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Smith.
Good day, sir.
I'm sorry to be late,
angel. I was held up.
I like waiting for you, Ricky.
Wouldn't I make a splendid wife?
What'll it be?
Something cool and long.
How about a couple
of planter's punches?
Fine.
Si, seor.
Rick, I had
the funniest feeling
coming over here.
I felt as though
I were being followed.
A cab stayed right behind mine
all the way over from the hotel.
I may be imagining things,
but I don't think so.
Who do you think
would be following you?
I wouldn't know.
Would you?
All that funny business
on the boat.
What did it mean, Rick?
Who is Dr. Lorenz,
and what is he up to?
You're good, angel.
You're very, very good.
Don't you think it's about time
we got together on a few things?
Such as?
Who we are and what we are.
I've told you
everything about me.
Now, look, angel,
we can play this dumb,
or we can play it smart.
I'm in this for what
I can get out of it,
and I don't think
I'm getting half enough,
and we can really make
Lorenz pay off plenty
if we throw in together.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Come off it, angel.
I don't know how you got
in with Lorenz's crowd,
but you're in it up
to your beautiful neck.
I didn't know Lorenz
had a crowd.
Oh, yes. I forgot.
You're the little lady
from medicine hat.
It was your twin sister
who was the buyer for
Rogers fifth Avenue.
Couldn't be that
she held that job
so that she could conveniently
take trips abroad, could it?
Let's see.
How many did she make
2 years ago?
3, wasn't it?
You must have gone
to a lot of trouble
to find out all this.
Sometimes it pays to go
to a lot of trouble.
Rick, I don't know
what you're thinking,
but whatever it is,
you're mistaken.
Yes? In what way
am I mistaken?
All right, Rick.
I'll tell you.
Well, well, well.
Look who's here--
the happiness kids.
Hello, Joe.
Pull up a chair, Joe.
Thanks, I will.
What's that you're knocking
yourselves out with?
Hey, waiter! I'll have
one of those.
Well, how are we doing?
All right until this moment.
Waiter:
Miss Marlow?
I'm miss Marlow.
A telephone call.
That's funny.
Who could it be?
It's easy enough to find out.
This way, please.
You know what
I think I'll do, Rick?
I think I'll take
the train into Panama City,
and catch a coastline freighter.
The next boat through here
is 3 or 4 days from now.
It's a Chinese boat,
and I'm not so keen
on taking a Chinese boat.
So I figure I'll be saving
time in the long run
if I catch a coastline freighter
to Los Angeles or San Francisco
and make new connections there.
What do you figure on doing?
Me? I--I
don't know yet.
Why don't you string
along with me?
We could share a cabin.
That's not
a bad idea, except--
oh, I get it--
the little lady.
Can't say that I blame you.
She sure is a swell dish.
It's too bad about
the Genoa Maru
not being let through.
She wasn't a bad ship,
even though you did grab
the only dame on board.
I got to hand it to you, Rick.
You sure are a fast worker,
if there ever was one.
Miss Marlow--
did she go?
Si, seor.
Just now.
The party that called--
any name?
No, seor.
Anything the matter?
No, not a thing.
Where did she go?
Oh, I get it.
Do me a favor.
If she comes back within
the next 10 minutes,
ask her to phone the hotel.
Let me know where she'll be.
You take care of the check.
Sure thing, Rick.
Mr. Leland.
Has miss Marlow come back?
No. There's
something for you.
Dr. Lorenz?
Upstairs.
Any calls for him?
No call.
Hey, Sam. Give me
a passkey, will you?
Can do.
When she gets back,
ring twice, her room.
Will do.
Sorry to disturb you,
Mr. Leland.
Oh, that's all right.
Has your search
revealed anything?
Yes.
You'd be surprised
how little
girls wear these days.
I was shocked.
It's 5:05,
Mr. Leland.
I believe
you said 5:00.
You're a little fast.
But anyway.
I would consider it
prudent of you,
Mr. Leland,
if you would cease
your attentions to miss Marlow.
Why so, doc?
Your interest in her
is unqualifiedly
romantic, is it not?
Between the two of us,
I'm nuts about the lady.
I suggest that you find
a safer romance,
something more permanent.
And now, Mr. Leland,
the schedule.
Look, doc--
that is it in the envelope,
isn't it,
Mr. Leland?
Oh, yes. That's it,
all right.
1,500.
Now, hold on.
I know I said 1,500,
but it cost me that much.
Almost, anyways.
I'll only get
a few bucks out of it.
That's your business.
My business is
to take care of myself.
How much more do you want?
Let's say 500.
Very well.
But bear in mind,
Mr. Leland,
that such
extraordinary procedure
doesn't dispose me
towards further dealings
with you.
You got me all wrong, doc.
It isn't that I don't
want to play ball.
I do, but for all I know,
you'll hand me the 1,500
and wave good-bye.
I'll be left out in the cold
with nothing to show for it.
If I were
on the inside--
I shall have to make out a check
for the 500,
Mr. Leland.
Then it is a kiss-off.
For the moment, yes.
Perhaps in time to come--
look, doc, I've got
another proposition--
sorry. Not interested.
No checks, doc.
I'm a cash-and-carry man.
But, Mr. Leland,
it's after 5:00.
The banks are closed.
I'll never be able
to get any such sum.
Well, then, it's no dice.
As you say, sir.
Uh-uh!
Remember, mine's
bigger than yours.
You overestimate
your value to us,
Mr. Leland.
Actually, we have on file
any information you can give us.
Merely that we like to check
and recheck such data.
In other words,
your services were
never at any time
indispensable.
Ah, come off it, doc.
You doubt me,
Mr. Leland?
No offense.
Hmm.
I'm checking out.
Have my bill ready, please.
Send up a boy for the bags.
You're leaving, doc?
I must continue my journey.
Good-bye and good luck,
in spite of our little
difference.
By Jove, I think you mean it.
Mean what?
What you said about
not needing this.
Dispose of it as you
will, Mr. Leland.
Ok, doc, you win.
I was only bluffing.
Let's see the color
of your money.
But I was not bluffing.
The deal is off.
Don't be that way, doc.
After all, I did save
your life once.
You'll never know
how fortunately
that circumstance
has operated for you.
Aw, give me a break, doc.
How much?
1,500.
1,000 it is.
I guess I deserve it.
[Knocking on door]
Lorenz: Who is it?
Bell boy, seor.
Come in.
[Airplanes approaching]
[Speaking faintly]
Hello.
Get me colon 893.
Hello? Can I talk
to Mr. Smith?
Smith? This is Leland.
Yes, Mr. Leland,
what is it?
I was unable to contact you.
I've been out all evening.
Now, listen.
Our plans must be changed.
Understand?
You take care of that.
I shall take care
of it immediately.
Thank you very much.
[Gunshot]
Operator: Number, please.
Number, please.
[Speaking Japanese]
What's the matter you, Rick?
Where you been? How you
get your head bump trouble?
My pal, Dr. Lorenz.
Pretty, eh, Sam?
[Tongue clucking]
Dr. Lorenz go 5:15
in private car.
The license number no good.
Stolen plate.
What about miss Marlow?
She no come back.
Much trouble.
You said it, Sam.
You like movie show maybe?
Go ewa theater.
Buy ticket. 10:00.
What's up, Sam?
Much trouble.
You got a gun?
Can do.
Order automobile for front.
Much trouble.
Thanks, Sam.
Much trouble all the time.
Stick around.
Yeah.
[Soundtrack in Japanese]
[Baby crying]
[Audience laughing]
[Laughter]
[Baby crying]
Bountiful plantation.
Go bountiful plantation.
Fat man there.
Go quick.
Bountiful plantation.
[Audience laughing]
[Woman screaming]
Let's get away from here fast!
How much further to the house?
2 or 3 miles.
You better turn your lights off.
Si.
You keep your lights off
till you get a mile
or 2 back down the road.
Si.
[Clanking]
[Speaking Japanese]
Don't move!
Up hands!
Come on!
Rick.
[Lorenz speaking Japanese]
[Speaking Japanese]
Ah, Mr. Leland,
I am surprised.
Indeed, I am.
But that's the way with you.
You're always
furnishing surprises.
Come in, sir.
Join our little family.
Hello, Rick.
Hi, Joe.
Some joke, eh?
Have a seat.
[Speaking Japanese]
Astounding recuperative
powers you possess,
Mr. Leland.
Or should I say captain Leland?
Amazing animal energy.
The average man,
given the punishment
you received,
would be flat on his back
for at least a week.
That comes from living
a clean life, doc.
[Chuckles]
I hope you saw what
you came to see, sir.
Yeah. Looks like
you boys
are planning
to knock over the canal.
You said it, brother.
When those
8-foot torpedoes
hit the Gatun locks,
it'll make the johnstown flood
look like something
that happened in a bathroom.
Don't be too sure, Joe.
Maybe your plane will
never reach the locks.
Maybe you overlooked something.
Could you suggest anything, sir,
that we might have overlooked?
What about your getaway?
We have a rendezvous
with an undersea boat.
I think you'll discover,
captain, that nothing--
absolutely nothing--
has been left to chance.
[Thump]
Maybe you're right, doc.
It seems you are.
Would you mind telling me
how you got the plane
and torpedo parts
into the canal-zone area?
Not at all--
piece by piece
and bit by bit.
We brought them in cases
of otherwise-innocent
farm equipment,
addressed to "D. Morton,
bountiful plantation."
D. Morton?
Mr. Marlow,
alias D. Morton.
Her father.
Where do you figure in all this?
I don't, Rick.
I never did.
I told you that, remember?
I didn't know what
was going on down here.
I felt that something was wrong.
His letters were so strange.
I wrote him that
I would come down.
He said that I shouldn't,
that I might be followed.
Then I got a telegram
to go to Halifax
and take the Genoa mar...
I was going to tell you
this afternoon
when I got the telephone call.
It was father.
He said to come quickly
and to make sure
that I wasn't followed.
That's why I left the way I did.
Nice timing, doc.
I take my hat off to you.
Thank you, sir.
Americans are famous
for good sportsmanship.
Tell me, captain,
would your attitude
remain the same--
impersonal, objective--
were you to know that Smith,
Mr. a.V. Smith,
was unable to act
on your last words?
Stay put, Rick.
I see the knowledge
does affect you.
[Airplane engines starting]
It's nothing, captain.
Nothing at all.
They're only tuning up
the motors.
We have a few minutes yet.
You better sit down, Rick.
What do you want?
I want--
pathetic, is he not, sir?
There's a rugged individual.
Look at him!
Eyes without focus.
Flesh without feeling.
Lips with no tongue.
Utter decay.
He stinks.
Mr. Marlow is a thief--
a lazy, comfortable,
drunken thief.
He absconded with
his company's funds,
escaped to Panama with his loot,
assumed another identity,
felt conscience-stricken.
Mr. Marlow's dipsomania
enabled us
to introduce our nationals
into his employ
under the guise of workers
and servants.
In due time,
he became a prisoner on
rather than the master
of this plantation.
[Speaking Japanese]
Get up!
[Officer speaking Japanese]
[Speaking Japanese]
Lorenz: His
imperial highness
the prince Gazuo
Takemitsu Inoue.
Yeah. We've met before.
You the pilot, oki?
His highness asked permission
from the emperor himself
to perform this mission.
As you see, captain Leland,
I, too, was only kidding.
[Speaking Japanese]
They have no wish to kill you,
captain Leland, unless...
Ok, doc, I'll be good.
Lorenz: Joe!
[Speaking Japanese]
You can sit down now, folks.
Nobody's going anywhere.
You guys been looking
for a war, haven't you?
That's right, Rick.
That's why we're starting it.
You may start it, Joe,
but we'll finish it.
We'll see, Rick.
[Airplane engines]
Don't get nervous, Rick.
I might lose control of this.
You know something, angel?
Miss Marlow: What?
Wish you'd stayed
in medicine hat.
Rick!
Sayonara!
[Speaking Japanese]
Rick!
Now, take it easy, angel.
Have you seen Lorenz?
Yes. He was running
toward the house.
[Speaking Japanese]
Go ahead.
What's the matter, doc.
Haven't you got the nerve?
You're a soldier, sir.
I appeal to you.
Bullet. Here.
Some other time.
I ask you again.
Do me the honor.
No, I can't do it.
You got a date with
army intelligence.
Come on, doc.
You know, you're
a great disappointment to me
after that big speech you made
about weakness and decay.
Right on time, eh, doc?
Any of your friends in Tokyo
have trouble
committing hara-kiri,
those boys will be glad
to help them out.
Right down there.
Well, angel?