On the Centenary of Russian Cinema
With the support of the
Russian Ministry of Culture
Channel One
Film Direction
I checked in the studio photo records.
It's definitely her.
Dago Film Productions
Present
Konstantin Khabensky
The wife on an enemy of the revolution.
Where am I going to find a face like that?
Elizabeta Boyarskaya
Sergei Bezrukov
In a film by
Andrei Kravchuk
ADMIRAL
Baltic Sea, Pillau Region.
German Waters. 1916
Look sharp. Mines at least
seven meters from the surface!
82 feet under the keel
85 feet under the keel
- Officers on deck.
- At ease!
- Well?
- It's foggy.
No signals from the "Sentry"
or the "Hunter" for a while.
Try signaling them again.
I'll be with the Commander.
- May I come in?
- Yes. So?
Everything's calm,
Alexander Vasilievich.
- Will you have some tea?
- Thank you.
That's the Kazan Mother of God,
if I'm not mistaken?
Sofia Fyodorovna gave it to me,
before our marriage.
Anna Vasilievna gave me this.
As a memento. Look...
Beautiful.
- Yes?
- May I come in?
Gentlemen. Your presence on the
bridge is needed at once.
The Germans, gentlemen.
The Germans...
Their 210 mm cannons
against our 45s.
- The "Friedrich Karl".
- So much for your "Sentry"...
Thank God they're quiet.
They've missed us.
All hands to battle stations!
All to fighting stations!
Battle stations! Attention!
- Full speed ahead!
Helmsman, full speed ahead.
Battle! Cut the ropes!
Hold her steady!
- Why have we slowed down?
- Engine room!
Why have we slowed down?
What's happening?
A shell got the pipes
in the engine room!
- How long to fix it?
- Half an hour.
You have 15 minutes.
In 15 minutes they'll
turn us into a sieve.
Yes, we're a sitting duck!
Why have you stopped firing:
Midshipman!
Are you alive?
Alexander Vasilievich!
Should we get the orderlies?
Get on the tower.
Gurov, you alive?
Man the guns!
To arms!
To arms, I said:
Lads!
Fire!
- Yes!
- We got them on the running tower!
They're off us now.
The Germans' bridge is damaged!
Relieve the gunners!
Third gunners to the main guns,
Good thing we dropped the mines:
- What?
- I'm sorry.
Good that we dropped the mines,
if not:
Your Excellency, they've
repaired the pipes.
- The main bridge can't be mended in an hour.
- Put on the reserve one.
We need to get out of here,
while there's still time.
Mines, mines
Full speed ahead!
- Steer course for Pillau!
- But that's our minefield!
Assemble the officers
on the starboard deck.
At attention!
Gentlemen!
There's a German squadron behind us.
The "Friedrich Karl" is in front.
There's no way back to base.
So I see no way out except
to lure the Germans onto our mines.
Steer course for Pillau.
Onto our minefield. Questions?
I have a question.
One meter from the mines!
We won't make it.
Our own mines. We're
digging our own graves.
Calm down, midshipman.
We're going onto the mines.
Gold help us!
Let us pray.
Remove your headwear.
All powerful God
Lord our Saviour
Pardon Your faithful servants
hear and protect us
- Mine at port side!
- Stop engines.
Ready to reverse.
- Mine at port side!
Calm down, gentlemen.
God have mercy...
The Germans are opening sights.
Right, now they're all together.
Reverse.
We've missed the mine.
- That's the end...
- Goodbye, my friends.
They're going to get us.
What a shame, gentlemen...
Give the order for battle.
Stop! Into battle.
Slow ahead!
Previous course.
We're past the minefield.
Head home, gentlemen.
Champagne for the captain.
Podgorsky, come back here.
- You've already completed your dare.
- No!
I promised to stay until
the end of the game.
Russian naval base.
Helsingfors, Finland.
What should the dare be?
A new uniform!
Down a glass of cognac
for our victory.
That'll be a pleasure for him.
But something more challenging!
Make him kiss someone.
The first person to come
through the door.
Yes! Passionately.
And with feeling.
That's your dare,
Alexander Vasilievich.
- Quite a situation...
- Gentlemen, this is not funny.
The first through the door will be
the sailor I sent for champagne.
- Have you no conscience?
- That's how it is in war time:
Rear Admiral Kolchak
kissing a common sailor.
Until he comes in,
I suggest we continue.
What should this dare be?
Vladimir, we're waiting.
Attention!
And here's the sailor.
I was just looking for you.
I've been summoned to headquarters urgently.
Afraid I won't be back tonight.
Will you see my wife home?
If I don't have the time,
as a friend...
This is Anna Vasilievevna.
My wife.
I ask you...
What's going on here,
gentlemen?
Alexander Vasilievich just
took on a dare.
To kiss the first person
to come through the door.
That is, your wife.
So off you go to your watch.
Alexander Vasilievich.
We implore you...
You ought to honour it!
Rules of the game -
Like service regulations!
Come on Annushka, the dare!
You really should obey!
Dares are more serious
than debts at cards.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Your attention please!
- Slavushka, run off and play.
- All right, papa.
- Volodya, see what a
ship I have!
I'm starting to believe in fate,
Anna Vasilievna.
Today, when I came to
Helsingfors,
For some reason
I was sure
- that I would meet you.
- Really?
Yes, indeed.
Sonechka, do you remember
when we left Moscow so suddenly?
Your father had the bad luck
to fall in love.
Why are you telling me this?
Your neighbour is just
too beautiful.
Sasha is prone to infatuation.
But it doesn't normally last long.
Yes, and I wanted to ask,
There'll be a ball at the
Podorgskys tomorrow. Are you coming?
Kirill Fyodorovich,
come over here!
Attention, ladies and gentlemen.
Why on earth do you have
to entangle all these balls of yarn?
How did the Tsars
choose their brides?
The brides would untangle a yarn.
The Tsar watched through the keyhole.
If a girl fidgeted, or lost her temper,
that was it.
Out you go, lazybones!
Because the Tsar's wife
must have patience,
and self-restraint.
That's how my grandmother
prepared me to be a bride.
Interesting:
And why did your grandmother
call you a Shelkova cossack?
Because I am a Shelkova woman.
Our Cossacks married Turkish women.
I have Turkish blood too.
So, let's drink to the Turks!
With pleasure.
- Mama, is father an Admiral?
- A rear-Admiral.
Better if he'd stayed a captain.
I like him as a captain better.
Rear-Admiral is hard to say.
Better if you got some sleep.
Go to sleep, my dear.
Or you won't go swimming
again with father.
So what did you find out?
It turns out, these
Turkish ladies, from the harems
Would not give anyone anything!
A traveler comes along,
and asks for a glass of water.
What does the lady of the house reply?
"When Ivan comes, he will
give it to you, traveler."
Slander! Slander and calumny!
I for one would never
turn you down.
I fear, Anna Vasilievna, you
would have your hands full.
I'm very partial to drinking.
I understand you perfectly.
Generally speaking, it seems to me that
water and war are the only
loves in your life.
It seems to me you know
perfectly well -
that's not how it is.
Well:
It's getting late:
We had a nice walk,
and now it's time to go our separate ways.
Who knows, Anna Vasilievna -
whether we'll ever have such a
good time as we did today?
Thank you: Dear
Alexander Vasilievich.
Go now: Go.
This is the light signal of a sinking ship,
Anna Vasilievna.
Good night.
I was thinking that something had happened:
Sasha:
Is everything all right between us?
Not exactly.
Have you fallen in love?
Tell me if this is -
but...
Are you sure this is serious?
I don't know:
I have no intention of getting in your way,
Slavushka, Mother and
I will leave. For Petersburg.
Sonya, I:
You don't need to go anywhere.
Everything will be all right. I promise.
You are my wife and I am your husband.
That's the way it will always be.
How is Slavushka?
His temperature is nearly normal.
Shall I wait for you at lunch?
No, I'll be dining at the Assembly.
Alexander Vasilievich, congratulations
on your new assignment!
What a brilliant career!
No, I understand well that you can't force
someone to love or hate
against his or her will.
- But we took vows before God
- So what?
You swore before God,
to love me and remain faithful.
You understand perfectly well that:
Remain faithful - what do you mean?
Not go to bed with someone else?
If that's what you mean, I haven't
been unfaithful to you.
God, you're still such a child...
I don't understand.
What on earth are you doing here?
Nikolai Alexandrovich, tell headquarters
that the mining operation is
complete and there are no losses.
We're heading back to base.
Thanks for your service, gentlemen.
Alexander Vasilievich, please submit
my report to Naval Command.
- What is this report?
- I request to be transferred to another ship.
Have we let you down somehow,
Sergei Nikolaevich?
Rear-Admiral, Sir,
a radio message from the coast.
From Prince Melikov. To all at sea.
Ragotsem Cape, Gulf of Riga, 1916
- We're heading towards a communications buoy.
- Stop engines.
- Engines stopped.
- Drop anchor!
Your Excellency.
We received a radiogram
- "I arrived with the"Glory"." Kolchak.
- Go.
The cable is connected.
The communication is established.
Alexander Vasilievich, we're
connected with the coast.
Man the starboard battle stations.
Man the battle stations.
Hurry!
This is the commander of cruiser the "Glory",
Rear-Admiral Kolchak.
The situation is critical. The Germans
are squeezing us on the right flank.
I will coordinate  your
firing operation myself.
Grid thirty. Coordinates:
Three thousand five hundred.
Two thousand two hundred.
Battle stations! Man the guns!
Sight eighteen.
Deflection forty three. Fire!
Twenty more to the left. Three higher...
The Germans are turning their guns!!
Hello! Hello!
Hello!? I can't hear you.
Man the guns! In place!
The Germans have opened fire on us.
- So?
- We're a sitting duck now
- We need to head out to sea.
- Then how do I adjust the line of fire?!
We're staying in place.
Check the communication!
Are you wounded?
Let me help: This is not the time
or place, Sergei Nikolaevich:
But as a military officer you surprised
me with your report.
To leave your comrades with whom
you have served so long:
Given the situation that has arisen between
the two of us. A personal situation
What situation?
The only situation now is war -
fighting the enemy
and doing your duty to the homeland. Yes!
Rear-Admiral Kolchak. What are your
new firing coordinates?
Ten to the left and five higher!
Open fire!
Mates! Attack! Hurray!
Stop! Stop!
Here is a letter in Morse code.
I did my best with a textbook at home.
Thank you. But today is the
last time we shall see each other.
We can't meet again.
What happened?
Did we do something wrong:?
Anna Vasilievna:
We didn't even dance.
Why Alexander Vasilievich?
Because I love you.
Farewell!
Alexander Vasilievich.
Give me the letter.
My darling Annushka! You're all wet.
Be careful or you'll fall ill.
- I'm very tired.
Sure Annushka, I:
Mogilev, 1916 the Emperor's
General Headquarters
The Emperor will see you here in the park.
- I wish you health, Your Majesty.
- Greetings.
I have been told of your bravery.
Of the courage you showed
on the Baltic Sea.
I acted according to the call
of duty, Your Majesty.
I invited you here to inform
you of my decision.
You have been assigned
the rank of Vice-Admiral,
and become the Commander-in-Chief
of the Black Sea fleet.
Thank you for your trust,
Your Majesty.
Take this, and may the icon
of the long-suffering Job
give you strength.
Thank you.
I wish you good luck!
Allow me to take my leave,
Your Majesty.
Godspeed, admiral.
"I must know that you're alive".
Driver!
To the train station on the double!
Faster, please...
Gentlemen.
Alexander Vasilievich needs
protection from the sun!
- It's a resort area.
- There's more sun in Sevastopol...
When are you going there,
Sophia Fyodorovna?
Tea, gentlemen.
This is your fleet!
Yesterday I was walking
by Mikhailovsky castle
when I heard children arguing:
"Mine, give it me", "No"...
Then all of a sudden it
became crystal clear to me
"Everything will come in due time.
It already has come".
There is no more mine or yours.
Every morning I open my eyes
and smile... I'm alive...
I am waiting... This is a reward,
not a punishment.
Because against all the laws
of physics you give,
the more you give
the more you receive.
Just imagine,
I can feel in the palms of my hand
a big and unbelievably
shiny ball.
This is Grace.
A gift...
Happiness... That's the
way it is.
Don't laugh. I know.
I stand on the edge
of a vast unseen world.
And although we see the future
unclearly, as the Apostle said:
"Through a glass darkly...
And now abideth faith,
hope and love.
But the greatest of these is love".
Alexander Vasilievich,
I heard that you
will be in Petrograd...
How soon? March or April?
For some reason it seems
to me that it won't be long.
May I come in? Your Excellency,
a wireless message just came in.
On March 2nd the Emperor Nicholas
the Second abdicated the throne.
Power is with
the Provisional Government...
The monarchy has fallen.
A Provisional Government...
What does that mean?
I don't think it bodes
at all well for Russia.
I think you're right.
Anna Vasilievna, unfortunately...
KRONSTADT, 1917
The revolution has eclipsed our future.
The darkness is moving in.
- Where are you taking us?
- Wherever...
Gentlemen, are we just
a herd of animals?
- We should do something!
- Hands off, sailor!
Please, obey.
It's treason.
- Listen to my command.
- My God!
We're at war. Come to your senses!
What are you doing?
- Sort out the Admiral.
- Fear the Lord.
Gentlemen! Save yourselves,
that's an order!
- Run!
- Shoot them...
Kolya!
May God be with you!
SEVASTOPOL
Annushka, good you're
home. Pack your bags.
- What happened, Serezha?
- Admiral Nepenin has been killed!
- How did he die?
- I said he was killed!
He was clubbed with rifle butts
and stabbed with bayonets. Brutes!
Serezha, I can't understand
what's happening.
God! What on earth
is happening?
Serezhenka, calm down, explain.
Podgursky has also been killed.
He died in my arms.
Out of the way!
- What's the matter?
- The first order...
of the Petrograd Soviet
is for all officers
to hand over weapons.
To prevent a counter-revolutionary
conspiracy.
Turn in your weapon, Admiral.
- We're leaving for Petrograd...
- Why are we leaving?
- I was able to take some leave...
- Hold on now!
What are you waiting for?
Pack your bags...
Admiral, follow
this order immediately.
- Get out of here!
- Listen here, Admiral...
Get out!
All right men,
we'll figure this out on deck.
Officer of the watch, tell everyone
to line up on deck.
Wait, Serezha, how can I...
how can I go...
All letters come to this address.
I'm waiting...
At least close your suitcase?
Anya. Anya,
Anechka, please my dear.
I'm begging you.
The boat leaves in half an hour.
We're finished
if we don't make it on time.
Arms!
As you were!
Attention! Order revoked!
Fall in!
Who are you obeying?
- You afraid, lads!
- Fall in!
Quick.
Officers, gentlemen.
- Weapons up.
- I'm sorry!
At ease.
To avoid bloodshed,
I order the officers
to turn over their weapons.
Admiral, sir, your weapon...
Sir.
PETROGRAD (ST. PETERSBURG)
To the meeting?
Kerensky will be there himself.
Come with us, lady... Let's go!
You weren't home today.
I got the mail and there is a
letter for you.
From Sevastopol.
It's strange that mail
still arrives.
I'm feeling tired today.
In three days I'll be in Petrograd.
Seeing you is all
I'm dreaming of.
SEVASTOPOL
Hearing your voice.
- Kerensky has summoned me.
- It's dangerous in Petrograd...
the sailors and workers
have rebelled.
Admiral Nepenin was stabbed
to death with a bayonet.
- Can I see you to the station?
- Sonya, I...
Rostislav is waiting for you.
Go to him.
- Will you come back?
- Of course.
What silly thoughts.
Petrograd
Kerensky wants to offer you
the post of war minister...
Let's see. I wish he would
see me on time.
But he is late.
Today...
at the Mikhailovsky Castle...
I can see we have a different
view of the war...
By condoning anarchy
you have broken up the army
- and destroyed the Russian navy.
- Don't forget, Admiral...
Unless I have authority
to impose strict order
your proposals
are unacceptable to me.
Former procedures in the army
are not acceptable to us.
I was the first to swear allegiance
and I'll be the first
to leave the Navy.
In this way,
I will make a public statement
that the current state of affairs
is ruinous for Russia.
I accept your resignation.
I am honoured.
You should be arrested for your
counter-revolutionary leanings.
But given your merits,
I offer you to go to America.
I'm giving you the chance to
continue the war against Germany.
Are you exiling me from Russia?
The Americans need an expert who can
conduct a landing
and seize Constantinople.
My family is still in Sevastopol.
I'll take care of them.
I'll ask the allies to have
them brought to you overseas.
Thank you.
Dear...
My darling, Anna Vasilievna.
You are my happiness;
I can't live without you...
What?
Their times are over!
I'm leaving Russia.
Why?
What tired eyes you have.
I love you.
And I always will.
Forgive me.
Farewell,
Alexander Vasilievich.
I know that you are alive.
SEVASTOPOL
Is it ready?
At least let me pray.
You can pray if you want to.
Listen, bring the rope.
Let's go while he draws the
Sailors away!
Stop!
Quick, let's go...
we can't wait for him here. A
Stop!
Mrs. Kolchak! Open the
door, Mrs. Kolchak!
Document check!
Break it down!
Break the windows!
It's time, the British ship
sets sail in an hour.
TRANS-SIBERIA RAILWAY
AUTUMN 1918
I think I'm doing it better.
Take your place.
What a good shot!
Let's drink to our wishes.
Even the ones that don't come true?
Does that make them
any less wishes.
- Excuse me, Madam.
- Yes, of course.
- Mikhail Ivanovich.
- Anna Vasilievna!
- My God!
- What a surprise!
I haven't seen you for a year...
What brings you here?
Sergei Nikolaevich has been
sent to the Far East.
He's on a mission to
disarm the Pacific fleet.
Sergei Nikolaevich?
...So he's in power now?
- A red commissar.
- I have no right to judge him.
At a time like this.
It's the same time for everyone.
- Where are you going?
- To Omsk.
But the Soviets are in
power there too?
No. Kolchak is there.
But I thought Alexander
Vasilievich was abroad?
Kerensky did send him abroad:
But after the Bolshevik coup
he returned to Russia
to fight the Bolsheviks.
I'm sorry, Anna Vasilievna,
I must go.
Goodbye.
Serezha:
Aha... yes... yes, Anya!
What is it?
Kolchak is in Omsk
gathering an army.
Anya, if this is a rebuke,
you know I agreed to collaborate
with the authorities because
they allowed us
to go far away from
this fratricidal madness...
To Japan, China...
It's all for your sake, Anechka.
I don't blame you for anything.
But I love Alexander
Vasilievich, Serezha.
And now I need to be with him...
I realize that these are harsh words,
but I have never
stopped loving him.
I see! ...Stop, stop...
Let me help.
So there it is. A time of wars
and revolutions.
Anything goes.
The time has nothing
to do with it.
When I fell asleep I
was your husband.
I wake up and I am
no longer your husband:
I know it's hard for you
but you've got to be strong.
You'll forget me before long.
Let me be the one
to decide that.
Siberia, Eastern Front.
November 1918
I pledge and swear
before Almighty God,
His Holy Gospel
and the Life-Giving Cross:
To be faithful and ever true.
To the Russian state
as my Homeland.
I pledge and swear
to serve it
as the Supreme Ruler of Russia,
without regard for my life,
family ties or friendship,
enmity, or gain,
and mindful only of the revival
and success of the Russian state.
Hereby I make the sign
of the cross,
and kiss the words and
Cross of my Saviour.
Amen.
OMSK.
Hello, my lady!
Who are you looking for?
You, I think.
How can I help you?
I'm the one who would
like to help you.
My dear
sweet Alexander Vasilievich,
I have realized that I simply
can no longer wait!
Do you remember how I dreamed
to be on the deck of your ship?
Just to see you.
You would not even notice me,
I would not disturb you;
all I need is to stand nearby:
And now it seems that I will
experience this happiness.