"The victor will never be asked
if he told truth"
Adolf Hitler
Since the mid-20th century,
the world has ever heard of
an incredible story,
the story of a boy from an ordinary
family whose ambition it was
to became an artist, but who
instead became a drifter.
His destiny however was not to drift
into the awaiting oblivion,
but to rise to the greaest heights
of power, eventually to become
one of the most influential men
who ever lived.
Now for the first time, here is
the true and fctual account
of a story many believe to be...
The Greatest Story NEVER Told!
The Untold Story of Adolf Hitler
ADOLF HITLER
THE GREATEST STORY NEVER TOLD!
April 20, 1889
Braunau am Inn, Austria
The story began here in the
Austrian town of Braunau,
with a child born in
this house, Adolf Hitler.
At his peak, the most
popular ruler in Europe.
The child born here in Braunau,
belonged to that handful of human
beings,
who have clearly and decisively
changed the history of the 20th
century.
Linz, Austria, the site of the
only memorial to the Hitler family.
The grave of Hitler's parents.
Nothing about his
parents or Adolf's early life,
gave any hint of the extra
ordinary career that was to come.
His father Alois
was a stern short tempered
custom's official
who beat his son.
His mother Klara
tried to protect him.
When she died young
Adolf was broken by grief.
He kept her portrait with
him for the rest of his life.
The infant Adolf was baptized
and brought up as a Catholic.
At the age of 6 he entered the
monastery school at Lambach.
Soon he was top of his class.
Hitler was a chorister at the
Great Abby Church of Lumbach.
I used he said,
"to intoxicate myself with the solemn
splendor of the services."
Every day when he sang in the choir,
he saw the memorial to an earlier abbot.
Above it was an emblem,
which a quarter of a century later,
Hitler was to adopt for the
Nazi Party, the Swastika.
In his teens Hitler became
a moody adolescent.
At secondary school in Linz,
he lost interest in most of
his work.
His ambition was to go to Vienna
and become an Artist or Architect.
Once there he produced architectural
drawings and water colors like these.
Competent, but not good enough
to win the place he longed for
at the Viennese Academy Of Fine Arts.
Vienna, Austria
Little by little all Hitlers early
ambitions in Vienna turned sour.
After the shock of
being turned down twice
by the Academy of Fine Arts,
he became a drifter.
Hitler later called his period in Vienna
the most miserable time of my life.
Vienna 1913
Three of those miserable years,
were spent here in a Viennese
back street
at this hostile for homeless men.
In this depressing hostile, the future
Führer passed much of the day
sitting with other inmates churning
out drawings of water colors
which earned him
a modest income.
When he drifted from
Vienna to Germany in 1913,
he was still dreaming of becoming
a great Artist or famous Architect.
Munich, the first of August 1914.
A cheering crowd welcomes the
outbreak of the First World War.
On the right is a photographer,
and among the crowd he's
photographing,
is the 25 year old Adolf Hitler.
Adolf Hitler - THE WAR HERO
If you look at the tenacity of his
service, I mean he's a fanatic.
And he petitioned King
Ludwig III of Bavaria,
to enlist in what is referred to
as the King's own regiment.
That's an elite Bavarian unit.
He was accepted, but put in the
16th Bavarian reserve infantry.
And World War One is a
major influence on Hitler's life.
Now he served his basic
training without complaining.
But he was always willing to
offer his fellow comrades help.
He spoke about the evil of tobacco
and alcohol to his fellow soldiers,
and they liked him because of
his drawings that he did for them.
He would do
sketches for them.
Remember he sketched and did a
variety of things you know in his youth,
as he was trying to
get into Art school.
So he really got along
with his fellow soldiers.
At one point during the trench
duties, in between 1914- 1918,
he will have a dog, somebody
going to steal from him.
During World War
One Adolf Hitler
repeatedly, repeatedly
volunteered for hazardous duty.
His first combat was
October the 29th, 1914.
Hitler's unit lost 3.000 of its
3.600 men,
after making 5 assaults on the
enemy position.
Now Hitler had one
of his sleeves shot off.
He walked out of a tent where
he'd been talking with some men,
and a couple of seconds later a shell
hits and blows it to kingdom come.
And for his
fighting in this unit,
he was awarded the Iron Cross, 2nd
Class for Bravery, Bravery Under Fire.
And he was
promoted to Corporal.
So this is a well
deserved award.
Later, he became a runner,
which meant he moved messages
from the rear to the front,
and it's a very
high mortality job.
And he liked it, he
always liked that job.
Then in December, of 1914, when
you have the famous Christmas truce,
on December the 25th, Hitler
wouldn't leave his trench.
And his comment was, "such a
thing should not happen in War time".
Then he told his buddies
that participated, that they were
wrong to get involved.
So no fun, while the war goes
on, those are your enemies.
Now between 1914- 1916, in the final
stages of the Battle Of The Somme,
Adolf Hitler was wounded in
the leg by a shell fragment.
This sent him back to
Germany to recover.
And he's there for about 5 months.
Hitler could have stayed back
in Germany, on light duty
because of his wound,
but demanded to be
sent back to the front.
So this...
he's no shirker.
You've got to give the guy some
due here for not being a chicken.
A lot of people, you know, look
for a way to get out of there.
Then you have Hitler
back again on trench duty,
and then he shows up again during
the of course German offensives.
Now, during the
Ludendorff offensives,
he was armed with a pistol and
he captured five French soldiers.
And for that he received
the Iron Cross 1st Class.
You didn't get those at any
time in the war for free.
You can't dismiss
his decorations.
He wins the Iron Cross 2nd
Class in 1914, 1st Class in 1918,
and then in mid October he got
another battle field decoration.
But he's never promoted because he
had a Captain, Captain Fritz Wiedemann,
said he lacked the
capacity for leadership.
You just can't make
these statements.
As the war turned against Germany,
he believed that the pacifists
and the shirkers, which were people
trying to get out of duty,
were losing the war.
And the thing that enraged
him even worse is what is
referred to as "defeatism" in the ranks.
They're actually non-commissioned officers,
who said it was stupid to keep fighting.
He beat one up.
So we have a Corporal beating
up a non-commissioned officer,
and he doesn't get into
trouble for it. He's a fanatic.
The end of the war Hitler was gassed by
the British forces advancing their Ypres
in mid October 1918.
It bloated his face up,
in particular his eyelids.
Constantly watering eyes,
had a hoarse voice.
He then had this terrible pain, he referred
to it "piercing pain in my eye socket".
He hated leaving the
front to go to the hospital.
He considered it the
happiest chapter in his life.
Being there, being something,
being with people,
you know he had friends, and he had
comrades while he was in the war.
He was not a loner.
He had the respect of
his fellow soldiers.
He had purpose.
By early November Hitler's spirits
had come back, and it's very common
for people who had been
gassed to plunge into depression,
because they're concerned about
being blind the rest of their lives.
On November the 9th, this is
two days before the Armistice,
a local Pastor came to the hospital
and told the patients that
on November the 8th,
that the Kaiser had abdicated,
and Germany was now a Republic.
And he told them
that the war was lost.
Defeat was followed by a
humiliating peace at Versailles.
The injustice of Versailles rankled with
most Germans for the next 20 years.
Unable to accept that the
German army had lost the war,
Hitler convinced himself that the
soldiers had been stabbed in the back
by Communist revolutionaries
and parliamentary Politicians.
The stab in the back he believed was
part of a great Jewish conspiracy.
Suddenly Hitler discovered the greatest
talent he possessed,
the gift of public speaking.
He joined the small group of
fanatical Nationalists in Munich.
They became the National Socialist
German Workers Party, or Nazis.
In 1921, Hitler
became their leader.
Munich 1921
The word "Nazi" was used by the Allies
as a derogaory term,
popularised by the international media
for propaganda purposes.
After World War One,
Germany was in serious danger of
a Communist takeover,
with 6 million German Communist Party
members in the country.
Adolf Hitler was only the 55th member
of the NSDAP, and although membership
rapidly grew under his leadership,
the early meetings
were often held under
threats of violence.
Vastly outnumbered, the National
Sociolist would often find
their meetings infiltrated, where
brawls would inevitably break out.
The first film of the apprentice
Führer campaigning
shows him as still a
rather awkward figure.
Not yet certain of his roll
as Germany's Messiah.
In 1923, Hitler felt strong enough
to try and seize power in Munich.
Emil Klein, the only stormtrooper
still alive who marched with Hitler,
now retraces their steps.
Everything went well
until the marchers found armed Police
blocking their exit from a narrow street.
"We were still singing as
we marched down the street.
Suddenly, we heard shots
being fired all around us.
Procession started.
We were speechless, we
couldn't explain what had happened,
until word came from the front of
the march saying Hitler was dead.
I saw men with
tears in their eyes,
and I myself was very moved to,
and had great difficulty keeping
myself under control.
Though Hitler in fact
survived the hail of bullets,
he was arrested and locked
in a cell in Landsberg prison.
At first he was so depressed,
he refused to eat.
Then his confidence returned,
as he discovered that the failed
uprising had made him a local hero.
At the trial Hitler
rounded on his accusers.
He told the Judges, who
gave him a prison sentence,
"history will tear to tatters
the verdict of this court!"
You have been accused of 'High Treason'
and called 'An Enemy Of The State'!
"If I am guilty of anything,
then I am guilty of fighting to defend
the rights to the German people."
Herr Hitler, the court
finds you Guilty of Treason.
You are hereby sentenced
to a fine of 200 Gold Marks,
and 5 years in Landsberg prison.
You will... you will be eligible
for parole in 9 months.
Adolf Hitler will serve next
12 moths in Landsberg prison
To be continued
Part 2
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
After the propaganda
triumph at his trial,
Hitler set out to write the
Bible of National Socialism.
He dictated much of the text here
in his cell to his faithful follower,
Rudolph Hoess.
On Saturday evenings, the
other prisoners sat around
as Hitler read out the
completed chapters to them.
The book as a whole, dwells on the great
obsessions which had come to dominate
Hitler's political thought; the Jews, racism,
living space for the German people,
the evils of communism and
parliamentary democracy.
But it also includes
Hitler's views on a variety
of other topics ranging
from boxing to syphilis.
Mein kampf
Mein Kampf will become one of the
best-selling books of al time,
despite being banned in many
countriesfter the war.
The amasing apeal, Hitler was
lated to exercise
but he is mastering a spoken word.
After prison, the Leader, or Führer
as he now called himself,
had a new political strategy.
Instead of planning another coup,
he aimed to win power at the polls.
What was to win him millions
of votes, was instead,
his vision of a great national revival.
Hitler's election opportunity came
with the onset of the depression.
In a few years, 1 in 3 of the
labor force was out of work.
Ilsa Vemple, was a church social
worker during the depression
among the unemployed
in the Berlin slums.
"The despair was so
terrible as I can't describe it.
You had everywhere beggars, wherever
you went in Berlin, you had beggars."
The democratic political
parties offered no solution.
To millions of Germans, the
only hope was Adolf Hitler.
Have you been to
the marketplace?
Do you know how much it costs
for a loaf of bread these days?
$500.000 marks.
$500.000 marks!
The wheelbarrows aren't big
enough to carry the money in!
He's afraid I'll stir things up.
You tell Commissar Kahr,
this is not a time for silence.
"I supported Hitler because he,
after having seen all that depravity,
all that poverty here,
was the only one who could do
social justice to the people here."
"He had that ability,
the ability derived from his
readiness
to throw himself totally open
to... to appear as it were,
bare and naked before his audience,
to tear open his heart
and display it, to throw
on a few extra generators
and suddenly become
absolutely charged with energy."
Presidential Elections
26 April 1925
Nur
Paul von Hindenburg
Reichstag, Berlin
Nazi Party: 3 seats
April 1925
Election Campaign
It wasn't as though
he was using words,
it's as though the emotions
came direct without words almost.
There was a rawness
about Hitler's power.
Reichstag Election
Nazi Party: 107 seats
Six and a half Million
votes. 107 seats.
The biggest party
in the Reichstag.
Get me Hitler.
Reich Chancellary, Berlin
30 September 1933
Nobody has ever had this
power to move audiences so easily.
What he says...
it's the way he says it!
Hitler comes to power,
not as he had hoped through
outright victory at the polls,
but as head of a
coalition government.
As this withering glance suggests,
Hitler despises his coalition partners.
He quickly out maneuvers them,
and establishes his own dictatorship.
A month after he
comes to power,
the Reichstag building, the parliament
building, in Berlin is set on fire.
This happens to come
The Reichstag Fire 1933
at the time when he is constantly
insisting
that there is a communist plot
to overthrow the new government,
and to scary out a revolution.
And the Reichstag fire goes up
in flames which everybody can see.
Before that night was over,
he had got a set of decrees
drawn up,
which transformed
the situation politically.
All the guarantees, in which
people in any democratic state,
the freedom of speech and so on,
freedom from arrest, all of this
is swept away.
In the 1920s, Berlin was known as
the center of sexual perversion,
drugs and depravity.
Once in power Hitler ordered the sity
ceansed of these elements.
Obscene books, pornography
and Communist literature
were all burned by the National
Socialist.
The clampdown will fore Jews,
promiscuous liberals and gays such as
Marlene Dietrich - a known bisexual -
to leave for the US.
1933 BERLIN
The burning of pornography
and Communist literature
A majority of Germans tolerate
the burning of books,
the banning of other political parties,
and the setting up of a police state,
because Hitler offers a way out
of the depression.
If he's doing things which are
not so good, which happened,
then we said, "well, you have to
take the rough with the smooth."
Dictatorship seemed to be the
only way to get out of the mess,
and so, I thought that was
a good thing
that they cut away all this
nonsense and rather
did something, really did
something, and that's what Hitler did.
He eliminated the crushing
unemployment that Germany suffered.
And he gave millions of people
new confidence, and indeed, welfare.
They were doing better;
much better.
When Hitler assumed power
in 1933,
there were 7 million unemployed
Germans,
the highest per capita unemployment
rate in Europe, at the time.
In only is first year in office,
an unprecedented 3.374.000
were helped back to work.
Hitler's brilliant and innovative ideas
included building motorways
the lenght and breadth of the country,
with housing units provided for workers.
The worker's familes would then eagerly
spend the newly earned wages,
contributing to a fast-growing
economy.
Priority was given to the health
and fitness of the nation,
especialy for the youth.
Free healthcare and generous financial
support were provided for expectant mothers.
The world's first anti-smoking
campaigns are also introduced.
In addition, it was now government
policy
to protect the environment
and wildlife.
Crime was virtually eliminated,
with city streets made safe
to walk again.
Workers, subsidised by the government,
would take holidays abroad.
Hitler is the first in Europe to
introduce the 40-hour work week,
with extra pay for overtime.
Factories are now required to provide
workers with restrooms and a cafeteria.
The NSDAP leadership looked upon
the charging of interest on loans as immoral,
and by forsing banks to abolish
the practice of usury,
millions were freed from slavery
of debt.
It was a spectacular financial recovery
not witnessed before or since,
and often reffered to as the
greatest economic miracle of all time.
Meanwhile, most Western countries were
still mired in the Great Depression.
THE NUREMBERG RALLIES
The annual celebration of Nacional Socialism
They came in the tens of thousands,
full of youthful idealism to worship
the Führer,
the awesome surroundings
of the Nuremberg stadium.
Among the worshipers in the
Hitler Youth
was Alfons Heck, now a writer
of the Nazi period.
The decisive turning point in my
life occurred at the age of ten.
From that moment on, I would
remain beholden to Adolf Hitler,
long until after our defeat.
I was one of 82.000 members of the
Hitler Youth lined up in Zeppelin's Field.
I stood in the first row.
And when Hitler began to speak,
we were just tingling with nervousness,
filing to see our God.
Then he appeared
on the podium.
I was afraid to
look at my neighbor,
because I didn't want him
to see the tears in my eyes,
my knees were shaking.
Then Hitler beamed down on us,
he calmed us down by lifting
his hands,
both hands several times.
When he began to speak it was
in a very conversational tone,
man to boy, father to son.
Then he said how fortunate
we were to live in this new age.
And he said from now on you,
no longer have to fear any class
distinction, you're all one.
But the essence, and the emphasis
occurred in the final sentences.
He leaned over the podium,
and I know he looked straight
into my eyes.
And he said, "You, my boys, the
young of Germany,
live in a fortunate time,
because you are the standard
bearers of the movement.
You will inherit what we
have so far created."
And from that moment on,
without any doubt,
I was bound to Adolf Hitler.
Long until after our defeat.
Before us lies Germany
within us Germany is stirring
behind us all Germany is following!
The mid 1930s were the
halcyon years of Hitler's Germany.
Germany was at peace, her prosperity
restored, her national pride recovered.
To those prepared to ignore or justify,
the police state,
it seemed a beautiful Germany.
A host of distinguished foreign visitors,
many with impeccable democratic
credentials,
came to call on the Führer at
his mountain retreat, the Berghof.
Among them, was the former British
Prime Minister, David Lloyd George.
With LG, was his
secretary Albert Sylvester.
BERCHTESGADEN
4t SEPTEMBER 1936
Hitler run down
the flight of stairs
to welcome LG as
he got out of his car.
Shook hands with him most warmly,
and conducted us into the inside
of the Berghof.
This massive room, the
only light of which came
from a massive window, which was
terrific, I'd never seen such a window.
Lloyd George said, "You have
done great things for Germany.
You have restored her honor,
and you have gained for her
equal rights."
To be continued
Part 3
Adolf Hitler - The Greatest Story NEVER Told
I've met a few.
Arm chair Politicians.
Care more about their money,
than they do their own country.
Yes, but surely as your
Parties propaganda leader,
you must know, that in
order to defend their money
they'll spend it.
A good deal of it.
That is if someone they trust
tells them that it is a safe bet.
That's where I come in.
Herr Hitler, I can make you very popular.
Far more popular than him.
But you have to admit,
the color catches the eye.
Unlike the Soviets with their hammer
and sickle, the Nacional Socialist
had no such flag or amblem.
Hitler not only wanted a simbol to
represent the NSDPA,
but one powerful enough
to strikefear into the Communists.
The once failed art student would
now set about to design
the most recognised flag
in history.
After 1945, the NSDAP flag will be
banned and portrayed by the
media as a symbol of hate.
It also be hijacked by extreme
political group,
and others such as motocycle gangs,
who have no concept
of its oriinal anti-Communist design.
THE BLUTFAHNE SWASTIKA
The Blutfahne displayed at the attempted
Beer Hall Putsch in Munich in 1923
ended up covered in the blood
of National Socialist members
either wounded or killed
by munich police.
It was thereafter treated as a sacred object,
used at the Nuremberg Rallies
by Adolf Hitler to "sanctify" new flags.
This most treasured of all NSDAP artefacts
was last seen on 18 October 1944.
To this day its whereabouts
remain unkown.
On the morning of the
12th of March 1938,
German soldiers crossed the
border into neighboring Austria.
They were greeted not with bullets
and guns,
but with roses and carnations.
So much so, that the action became
known as the "Blumenkrieg",
the "War of Flowers".
Most of the Austrian people,
envying what they saw as the
economic success and prestige,
that Hitler had brought to Germany,
now welcomed their German
neighbors.
One People, One Reich,
One Leader.
In a demonstration of how central
he was personally
to this whole system,
Hitler traveled across
Austria on a campaign tour.
In the future I want to be nothing other
than what I have been in the past:
alerter of my people,
teacher of my people,
and the Führer of my people.
As German troops cross the border
of Austria,
Austrian troops simultaneously enter
the German cities of Munich,
Dresden and Berlin, a sign to the
rest of world
of a peaceful reunification.
An overhelming 99,7% of Austrian
citizens
will deocratically vote to
reunite with Germany.
... and this people...
... do not come to the Reich...
... with hat in hand.
I myself...
... bring you home!
I think the thing...
some period
around the end of '37- '38,
Hitler feels well this is fine,
but I didn't come to power
just to restore German self
confidence and solve this more,
he changed his gear I think.
And then getting rid of a number
of the old guard, and the army,
and the foreign office, and so on.
And he becomes more aggressive.
It was the 12th of March 1938.
Austria was showered with Swastika's.
March 12, 1938
He crossed the border near
his birth place at Braunau.
People rejoiced him, the "Anschluss",
which they saw as the fulfillment of
an old dream of the German nation.
An emphatic display
of self determination.
A right denied to the German
people of the Versailles Treaty,
whose terms were generally considered
unjust.
Visibly moved he entered Vienna.
The city that had seen his early
failures, now gave him a hero's reception.
Homage was being
paid to the man
who had achieved the
unification of the German people.
The welcome here was
the most tumultuous yet.
Heil Adolf Hitler!
While in Leonding, Hitler visits
the grave of his parents
situated across the street from
his childhood home.
THE BERGHOF - THE BAVARIAN ALPS
It was here, far from the millions
of his followers,
that Hitler felt most able to relax.
The inner circle
at the "Berghof",
saw a quite different man from the
charismatic Führer of the party rallies.
Life at Hitler's retreat, was
both reassuring and agreeable.
And their was an entertaining
side to the off duty Führer
as Ribbentrop's private
secretary discovered.
"I was overwhelmed by the possibility
to meet the Führer personally.
And for instance, for the beginning,
he was a sort of a Messiah for me.
He was a man
who liked to joke.
He could laugh a lot. He
didn't accept two sort of jokes.
Dirty jokes and political
jokes, they were bad.
But all the other jokes
he enjoyed terribly."
Hitler had no close friends in whom
to confide his inner most feelings.
He could never admit
human weakness to anyone.
But the inner circle discovered
one secret of his private life,
which was unknown
to ordinary Germans.
"When Hitler was talking for hours and
I was standing near to the wall, waiting,
until they want some
papers or something?
And the curtain opened,
Eva Braun appeared and says,
"Adolf, we must to have lunch now."
And she didn't bother him
with political questions.
And he didn't want
to give her influence.
And he thought that as
long as he is a bachelor,
he has the love of
the German women.
Because if he's married,
the impression is not the
same on the other women.
And she gave him a little bit...
a home of bourgeois,
a quality with tea, with cake,
and I think with sex."
You think it was a
sexual relationship?
"Certainly."
In 1919. the Allies at Versailles formed
a new country called Czechosovakia.
The population will now consists of...
6.7 million Czechs
3.1 million Germans
2.0 million Slovacs
700.000 Hungarians
460.000 Ukrainians
With Czech violence against ethnic
German minorities on the rise,
Sudeten Germans are forced to call
for the reunification with Germany.
Czech President Edvard Benes will
instead order martial law
imposed on the Sudeten provinces,
forcing a furious Adolf Hitler
to demand their return.
26 Sept 1938
I have put an offer to Herr Benes...
an offer that is nothing other
than reaisation of his promises.
The decision is his now!
Be it war or peace?
He can either accept my offer
and give the Germans their freedom,
or we Germans will go get
it ourselves!
4 POWER CONFERENCE CALLED BY
HITLER; AVERTS CZECH INVASION
28 Sept 1938, British Prime Minister
Neville Chamberlain departs for Germany
The Munich Peace Conference
"IT IS PEACE WITH HONOUR"
SAYS CHAMBERLAIN
A wave of relief and gratitude
for the Führer swept Germany.
His iron nerve had freed the Germans
in Czechoslovakia,
and yet averted war.
You secured us victory...
now you secure us peace.
Heil Hitler! Sieg heil!
Sieg heil! Sieg heil!
To be continued
Part 4
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
The US state department
in its 3-volume report on the origins of
Communism in Russia, published in 1931,
reveals how Jewish controlled German
banks
under the leadership of Max Warburg
conspired as early as 1914 to send
large payments to Lenin, Trotsky,
and others in their attempts
to bring down the Tsar.
When the White Russian patriots
heroically attempted to regain
their freedom from the Jews,
the Judaica says compact Jewish
masses were utilized by the Bolsheviks
to suppress such counter revolution.
Clearly Jews and native Russians
were engaged in a death struggle
over the destiny of Russia.
Unfortunately, the Jewish masses won...
the Jewish masses won... the Jewish...
"We will survive",
that's what they tell us.
What they mean is,
"THEY will survive!"
We surrendered in November,
at a time when we were perched
on the edge of victory,
betrayed by the cowards
and the traitors within our ranks.
"Lousy Communist pigs!"
How do we fight them?
We unite! We must join together,
for a greater Germany!
We will hang the profiteers,
crush the Communists,
we will disinfect our country
of the Jewish vermin!
We will sacrifice,
we will struggle yes,
but only then will we triumph.
And we will triumph!
We will triumph! We will triumph!
- We will triumph! We will triumph!
We will triumph!
We will triumph...
What exactly was the "great stab
in the back"
that Hitler had always talked about?
In 1961, former Zionist Benjamin
Freedman gave a speech
at the Willard Hotel in Washington, D.C.
on the World War One betrayal
of the German people.
WORLD WAR ONE
1914 was the year in which
World War I broke out.
Within two years,
Germany had won that war.
The German submarines,
which were a surprise to the world,
had swept all the convoys
from the Atlantic Ocean,
and Great Britain stood there
without ammunition for her soldiers,
stood there with one week's food
supply and after that, starvation.
At that time the French
army had mutinied;
they lost 600.000 of the
flower of the French youth.
The Russian army was defecting;
they didn't like the Tsar,
and the Italian Army had collapsed.
Not a shot had been fired
on the German soil.
Not an enemy solider had crossed
the border
into Germany and yet,
here was Germany offering England
peace terms.
Well, England in the summer of
1916 was considering that, seriously,
they had no choice.
While that was going on,
the Zionists in Germany
went to the British war cabinet,
"Look here, you can win this war,
if the United States will come
in as your Ally.
The price you must pay us,
is Palestine after you have
won the war
and defeated Germany,
Austria-Hungary, and Turkey."
They made that promise
in October of 1916.
Now, that is something that the people in
the United States have never been told.
They never knew why
we went into World War I.
After we got into the war,
Lord Balfour
the Zionists went to Great Britain
and they said,
"Let's have something in writing
that shows that you are
going to keep your bargain
and give us Palestine
after you win the war."
And that was called
"The Balfour Declaration".
The Balfour Declaration was merely
Great Britain's promise to pay the Zionists
what they had agreed upon
as a consideration for getting
the United States into the war.
That is where all
the trouble started."
WAR DECLARED BY UNITED STATES
Resolution passed by both houses of legislature
Army of 2.000.000.
Munich, Germany
April 1919
Down with the Kaiser!
Death to the Kaiser!
The Treaty of Versailles on
28 June 1919
and the Treaty of Saint-Germain
on 20 September
of the same year ensured that German
people would be thoroughly humiliated.
With millions unemployed, revolucionary
Jewish Communist leaders
Karl Liebknecht and Rosa Luxemburg
will atempt a "red" revolution.
British Prime Minister Lloyd George
wrote:
"The international bankers swept statesman,
politicians and journalists all to one side
and issued their orders with the
imperiousness of absolute monarchs."
The Daily Mail reported 10 July 1933:
"The German Nation was rapily falling
under control of alien elemens.
In the last days of the pre-Hitler regime
there were twenty times more
Jewish gouverment officials in Germany
as had existed before the war."
Jews of internationl attachments-
and with Communist persuasions-
had successfully insinuated into
the German administrative sistem.
In 1933, as the new National Socialist
government is removing these Jews
from influential positions, the worldwide
Jewish boycott
of German goods begins.
The German boycott of Jewish business
concerns came in April 1933,
only after the Jewish declaration of war
was announced earlier in March.
JUDEA DECLARES WAR ON GERMANY
Above all,
we must remove the Jews.
They run our banks,
they lost us the war.
They alone are responsible for
the economic disaster we're in.
"When you ask, what have
the Germans done to the Jews,
you must always ask, what have
done the Jews to the Germans.
Since 1850, when the Jews became
got all the political rights in Germany,
the German Reich; they have done
3 things which are really dramatic.
Number 1: They were a small
minority of 2% of the population.
At the time when Hitler came to power,
500.000 within 60 million German people.
500.000 among 60 million.
They were a small minority.
This small minority managed to
control of about 50% of the media;
to give about 70% of all judges;
to have a tremendous influence
in movie, and in theater,
and in literature, they
were over-represented.
This is one thing, they were
absolutely overrepresented
as today in England, in
France, and in United States.
Second, Jews were
at the origin of a lot of
catastrophic financial bank crashes
in Germany between 1870 and 1920.
In that time, they made a
lot of crashes, which have...
This is all documented, it's not Nazi
propaganda,
or anti-Semitic, or Arab propaganda.
It's a lot of books have been published,
even by Jewish-Germans,
about this problem.
They have millions of
German fathers have lost
their uh, their uh, their incomes
their uh their fortune, their savings,
because of these Jewish gangsters,
bank gangsters and speculation people.
Then the third point which was
psychologically
the most dangerous of all,
they have introduced into German
art and culture and theater and movie:
decadence - immorality.
The first homosexual theaters, plays
were made in Berlin in the 1920s.
The first adultery theater plays
were made in the 1880s and the 1890s,
a hundred years ago,
by Jewish authors, adultery,
then sexual perversions of all sorts:
sadism, masochism, lot of
homosexuality all these things and
then the decadent art you know,
an art which is absolutely ridiculous,
so called modern art, it was
all pushed by Jewish intellectuals
and this created among the
German people, a big, uh, a big revolt.
And they also, they wrote books,
ridiculing Christianity, ridiculing Jesus.
And there were furious reactions
in Germany.
And this is why Adolf Hitler
came to power.
And you see then Hitler in
two years, from '33 to '35,
he brought six million unemployed
Germans back into their jobs.
He created 6 million jobs.
It's incredible."
KRISTALLNACHT
9-10 november 1938
The November 1938 assassinion of te
German diplomat Ernst von Rath in Paris
by te Jew Herschel Grynszpan was
the pretext for the progoms
agaist the German Jews that followed.
At the time, Joseph Goebbels
was negotiating
to overturn te international Jewish
trade embargo.
He moved quicky to halt the vioence,
fearing it would derail the talks.
NAZIS SMASH, LOOT AND BURN JEWISH
SHOPS AND TEMPLES
UNTIL GOEBBELS CALLS HALT
THE TRANSFER AGREEMENT
Secret negotiations between the
Nazis and the Zionists in 1933,
22 April 1984- Channel 5 News
which allowed German Jews and
their assets to go to Palestine.
The Transfer Agreement
The Dramatic Sory of the Pact Between
the Third Reich and Jewish Palestine
A group of Zionists,
at the same time,
was quietly negotiating an
agreement with the Nazis,
to allow the immigration
of German Jews
and the transfer of their assets
to Palestine.
That deal, reported in August 1933,
was the Transfer Agreement.
Palestine, sparsely
settled by Jews at the time,
was radically changed as a result.
I lived in Palestine
from 1933 to 1936.
And uh, we saw, every week,
passports of German Jews,
coming to settle in Palestine.
German-Jewish settlement of Palestine
was, for a time, official Nazi policy.
These photos, of Jewish life
in Palestine,
along with a lengthy text,
appeared in 1934,
in the Berlin paper,
Der Angriff, the publisher,
Hitler's propaganda
minister Joseph Goebbels.
"A Nazi Visits Palestine", was
the title of the multi-part series.
A medal was struck by
Goebbels in commemoration.
On one side the Swastika,
on the other, The Star Of David.
Hitler demanded one concession
for the transfer agreement.
That the call for a Boycott of the Reich,
raised by Jews here and elsewhere,
be rejected by the Zionists.
The Zionists made that concession.
London, England
Judea declares war on Germany
BOYCOTT ALL GERMAN GOODS
THE TRANSFER AGREEMENT
The Transfer Agreement was a pact
that allowed Jews to emigrate
from Germany to Palestine
with their wealt intact.
This is contrary to all anti-Hitler
propaganda.
The agreement was concluded
in August 1933,
following talks between German
officials
and the Palestine Center of the
World Zionist Organisation.
Each Jew bound for Palestine deposited
money into a special account in Germany.
The funds were used to purchase
German goods
which were exported to Palestine
and sold there
by the Jewish-owned Haavara
company in Tel Aviv.
Profits from the sales were then given
to the Jewish emigrant upon his arrival,
an amount corresponding to the
initial deposit in Germany.
Thus, the agreement served the Zionist
aim of bringing Jewish settlers
and development capital to Palestine,
whilst simultaneously advancing
the German goal
of freeing the country of an
unwanted alien group.
As a result, Hitler's government vigorously
supported the emigration
of Jews to Palestine from 1933
until 1940-41,
when the Second World War
prevented futher collaboration.
HITLER'S JEWISH SOLDIERS
Approximately 150.000 soldiers with
Jewish blood would eventually fight
for the armed forces on the
Third Reich.
These included:
2 Field Marrshals
15 Generals
8 Lieutenant Generals
5 Major Generals
Together they commanded up
to 100.000 troops.
20 Jews would also win the Reich's
highest military honour,
the Knight's Cross.
1/2 Jew Werner Goldberg
1/2 Jew Horst Geitner
Received Iron Cross 2nd Class
and The Silver Wound Badge
1/2 Jew Johannes Zukertort
1/2 Jew Colonel
Walter H. Hollaender
Emil Maurice was a personal friend
of Hitler's,
and his one-time chauffer
and bodyguard.
He was also an early member
of the NSDAP
and one of the founders
of the SS.
The Führer stood by his old friend
when Maurice's Jewish ancestry
was discovered,
declaring him an "Honorary Aryan".
He was allowed to remain
in the SS...
To be continued
Part 5
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
On 28 June 1914 Serbian radical
Gavrilo Princip assassinated
Austrian Archduke Franc Ferdinand
in Sarajevo.
One month later on 28 July 1914
Austria declared war on Serbia,
initiating World War One.
Munich, Germany
May 1914
Come closer!
Let me speak!
England, France and Russia are
joining forces against our ally Austria.
We must stand with her,
united, ready to sacrifice.
Eventually the victorious Allies
would hold Germany alone
for World War One.
The next twenty years would see
the German population suffer terribly
from the consequences of the
Treaty of Versailles.
To understand the causes of World
War Two,
we must first studi the aftermath
of World War One.
The allied leaders were arguing
their way
over the whole future
of the German people.
Under their hands the map of
Europe was drawn,
and re-drawn again.
At last, after more than
three months of discussion,
they presented the terms of
their treaty to the Germans.
Germany lost land in the
East, the West, and the North.
In the East, the most important of those
losses was the wide strip of territory
given to the newly independent
Poland,
separating East Prussia
from the rest of Germany.
While on the West, France took back
the provinces of Alsace and Lorraine.
And was also given the
right to mine coal in the Saar,
an area placed under League
of Nations control for 15 years.
To protect France, Germany was forbidden
to station soldiers in the Rhineland,
an area which was to be
occupied by Allied troops until 1935.
It was not only the loss of
territory which Germany resented,
but also the fact that Czechoslovakia
and Poland,
now contained large numbers
of Germans.
And as if to add insult to injury,
the treaty forbade German
speaking Austria
to unite with Germany.
Her fortifications were to be
destroyed.
Her army was to be
reduced to a 100.000 men.
No Air Force.
No submarines.
And to accept blame for starting
the War and pay reparations.
So, in the high summer of 1919,
the German delegates were brought
to the great
Hall of Mirrors of Versailles
to sign the peace treaty.
It was a compromised peace
that satisfied not even one
single Allied leader,
and predictably the
Germans loathed it.
The Germans argued that
the Germany,
to which they were returning
had suffered poverty
and unemployment in
the years since the war,
and couldn't afford the vast
sums demanded by the Allies.
But these arguments
didn't impress the Allies,
who fixed the sum of 6.600.000.000
pounds for the Germans to pay.
That sum would have to be
paid in goods as well as money.
Most would come from here
in the Ruhr,
the industrial heart of Germany.
But at the end of 1922, the Germans
fell behind with their payments,
and Raymond Poincare,
the new French Prime Minister,
decided to act.
If Germany wouldn't pay in full
and on the nail,
then France would help herself.
So, on the 11th of January, 1923,
French and Belgian troops entered
the Ruhr
to force the Germans to pay up.
There was of course, after Versailles,
no German army big enough to stop them.
At first, the French believed that they
could make the Germans work for them.
But suddenly, German politicians and
people were united in a common cause;
hatred of the French.
And huge protest meetings
were held all over Germany.
Their attitude towards the
Germans in the Ruhr began to harden.
They tried to cut off the Ruhr
off from the rest of the country.
German visitors were searched as
if they were entering a foreign land.
1923 was disastrous for Germany.
In that year, the great
German inflation reached its peak.
For some time the value of
the Mark had been dropping.
As the value of the notes decreased,
so the amounts of notes needed
to buy things grew.
Banks became more
and more hard pressed,
to meet the ever-increasing
demand for paper money.
Closed
For their customers,
suitcases replaced wallets.
As Germany slipped towards disaster,
Gustav Stresemann was appointed
Chancellor.
The loss of production in the
Ruhr was making inflation even worse,
and Stresemann realized that the only
way to help the economy back to normal,
was to call off resistance there,
and get production going again.
The government also announced
that Germany would resume
the payment of reparations;
it was the only possible
way of getting the French out.
But to the nationalists,
it looked like again another pathetic
surrender to Germany's enemies.
General Ludendorff, who had never
accepted
that Germany had ever been
defeated,
gave his support to Adolf Hitler,
the leader of the new National
Socialist party.
1939 THE POLISH CONFLICT
Problems had arisen in Poland
over access
to the German territory of East Prussia
and coastal city of Danzig.
Hitler on several occasions presented
proposals to try
and resolve both situations peaceably,
but the Poles refused to seriously
negotiate.
Now in Poland, just like in Czechoslovakia,
the safety of ethnic Germans
was again becoming a concern
for Hitler.
DANZIG
Until 1934, conflicts between
Germany and Poland smoldered.
Danzig, next to East Prussia,
had been completely cut off
from the Reich.
Warsaw continued to try to rest
total control
over this strategically important
harbor city.
In West Prussia, the
situation was similar.
East Prussia was now completely
cut off from the German Reich.
Bolstered by English and
French guarantees of war support,
Poland has no further incentive to
negotiate in good faith with Germany,
and in the meantime in Warsaw,
maps are suddenly starting to circulate
which contain a new Western-Polish
border,
extending to just West of Berlin.
All across Poland, the so-called
pogroms against the minorities begin.
Night after night, polish border
officials shot at the fleeing Germans.
Shortly before the official outbreak
of war,
there were already 80.000
ethnic Germans in refugee camps
in both Danzig and the German Reich.
The misery of the
minority Germans in Poland
had now developed the third and most
pressing reason
that would lead to the outbreak
of war.
"The democratic states should not be
vain as to think
this state of affairs will last forever."
Adolf Hitler 1939
THE DANZIG MASSACRES
Hitler now has a problem that Britain
and France will declare war on them.
At this point, Poland is actually
committing,
pretty bad atrocities against the
German minority in West Prussia,
in the German part of Poland
at that time.
And so given that Poles
are committing atrocities
against the German minority in Poland,
Hitler is now at a
very tough situation.
Basically it's like, alright
if I don't declare war on
Poland, if I don't go in and
help these Germans out,
well then, the German minorities are
just going to keep getting slaughtered.
And it's not an insignificant amount of
Germans in that area who are being killed,
it was pretty bad what was going on,
what the Poles were doing in that area.
And so, he was basically
saying well, if we don't go in,
then those Germans are just
going to keep getting slaughtered.
If we go in, we're going to find
ourselves at war with Poland,
France, and Britain, and
possibly the Soviet Union.
But in a move of brilliant cunning,
he astonished the world in the summer
of 1939, by doing a deal with Stalin.
With Stalin on his side,
Hitler was sure nobody else would
interfere, when he attacked the Poles.
German Foreign Minister
Joachim von Ribbentrop
Whilst the military commissions
of the Western powers
are still negotiating in Moscow
with a view of enlisting Russia
in their front against Germany,
Reich Foreign Minister Von Ribbentrop
flies to the Soviet capital to
sign a pact of non-aggression
and consultation with Mr. Stalin
and Foreign Commissar Molatov.
1 SEPTEMBER 1939
Applause greets the Führer
who has just arrived
at the Kroll Opera House
to address the Reichstag,
which has been called
in an extraordinary session.
"Danzig was and is a German city.
to have only Germany to thank
for their cultural development.
I told the Polish ambassador
three weeks ago,
that if the situation continued
as it was,
if Danzig was persecuted, and if it
were attempted by Poland
to ruin Danzig economically,
the situation could
not be tolerated."
"We interrupt this broadcast of Adolf
Hitler's speech just moments early,
to report a dispatch from Paris, which
says that Premier Daladier of France,
has now called the French Council of
Ministers for an emergency meeting."
Polish troops are mobilised
"I, therefore, resolve
to speak to Poland
in the same language in which Poland
has addressed us for such a long time."
Danzig is liberated the same day
"Once again we interrupt very briefly.
This talk by Chancellor Hitler,
to announce that, in London,
Parliament has been
summoned to meet at 6 pm in London."
"Poland, for the first time, this evening,
has shot at regular soldiers upon our territory.
From now on, bomb will be met
by bomb."
Poland had greatly underestimate the
German armed forces.
The tactic of attacking the enemy
with great speed
known as Blitzkrieg, or "lightning war",
is utterly devstating.
The plight of the German minorities
had become clear.
During the last weeks before
the outbreak of war,
racial propaganda in the Polish press
played a major role
in the persecution of Germans
already hounded and harrassed.
Acts of violence against the Germans
continue,
and would eventually include a total
of 58.000 slaughtered.
The worst massacres will take place
between 31August and 6 September.
The climax came on 3 September in Bromberg,
in what is known as "Bloody Sunday".
The mass murders would only end on
18 September
with the arrival of German
troops near Lowitsch.
Those found guilty of taking part
in the brutal killings
now faced dead by firing squad.
LONDON, ENGLAND
3 SEPTEMBER 1939
"I am speaking to you,
from the Cabinet Room,
at 10 Downing Street.
This morning, the British ambassador
in Berlin,
handed the German government,
a final note,
stating that unless we heard from them
by 11 o'clock,
that they were prepared at once,
to withdraw their troops
from Poland,
a state of war would exist
between us.
I have to tell you now,
that no such undertaking
has been received,
and that, consequently, this
country is at war with Germany."
To be continued
Part 6
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
Within two days, the issues involving
the human rights of German minorities,
as well as the disputies over Danzig
and isolated East Prussia,
would turn into World War Tho.
From the beginning the civilian population
feels the jmpact of the invasion.
As casualties mount Polish civilians,
with the full support of their military,
hunt down any Germans still
in Poland.
Following the invasion, there is a wave
of house searches;
ethnic Germans are beaten and raped,
with at last 5.000 murdered.
The massacres, especially in the sity
of Bromberg, will be hidden
from the history books.
They will eventually emerge as one
of the most henious of crimes
to be inflicted upon a
civil population.
DANZIG
16 SEPTEMBER 1939
As a soldier in the World War
who only fought in the West...
I never had the opportunity to
witness such deeds...
the thousands of slaughtered
Volksgennossen...
the brutally butchered women
and children...
the countless German soldiers and
officers who fell, wounded...
in the hands of the enemy and who
were massacred
and bestially mutilated with their
eyes gouged out...
and worse yet, the Polish government
has
openly admitted this in a
radio broadcast...
the Lufttwaffe soldiers, thet were
forced to parachute,
were to be killed in a cowardly fashion.
THE GERMAN-SOVIET
NON-AGGRESSION PACT
In securing the Molotov-Ribbentrop
Pact with the Soviets
and offering Stalin the Eastern
half of Poland,
Hitler hopes that the Russian presence
there will prevent Britain and France
from declaring war.
This would now allow Hitler to protect
the German minorities,
and at same time reclaim the teritories
lost at Versailles.
Although both Germany and Soviets
invade Poland,
war by the Allies is only
declared on Germany.
On 17 September 1939, Stalin invades
Poland and claims
the Eastern teritory as agreed.
Meanwhile, Hitler on three separate
occasions, offers the opportunity
of uncondicional surrender to
the Polish commander in Warsaw.
Poland refuses all ultimatums und
the German assault begins.
Warsaw capitulates in just 24 hours
at the cost of 40.000 dead or injured.
The war with Poland last
just 29 days.
Hitler didn't want a
general war, what he wanted,
and I have no doubt about this,
he wanted a war to destroy Poland.
That he was prepared for.
For a moment, he was disconcerted
to find that he might be involved in war
with Britain and France, because,
this had never been his plan.
He had always regarded
Britain as his natural allien.
But, in the end, he accepted.
'Look, I have a
Nazi-Soviet pact,
which guarantees that this will
not develop into a general war.
I shall be able to knock Poland out in
three weeks, which he more or less did.
After that, the West isn't
going to start up a war again.
PLANS FOR A LONG WAR
CHURCHILL IS NEW NAVY CHIEF
MAY 1940
In theirs quests to prevent Germany
from reclaiminig territory
lost under the Treaty of Versailles,
Britain and France refuse any offers of peace.
In reality, they are worried about
Germany's rapid economic growth,
and will not suffer futher
German advancement.
At stake are the British and French
empires,
with the British alone ruling
over 480 million people.
French Empire 1919- 1939
British Empire 1919- 1939
10 May 1940
With French troops mobilising and
more British troops arriving
on the mainland by the day,
Germany has no alternative
but to go on the offensive.
The British Establishment replaced
Nevil Chamberlain as Prime Minister,
shoosing Winston Churchill instead.
The same day Hitler invades
France trough Belgium.
The armies of Britain and France
are no much for this
new German war machine.
There will be no World War One
trench warfare,
as the tactic of the Blitzkrieg once
again proves devastating.
In a matter of weeks the Germans seize
vital territory and resources in Europe,
and eventually outtlank and trap
the Allies on the coast of France.
With their backs against the
English Channel,
both the world's leading colonial
armies face total annihilation.
Hitler delays the attack for two days,
leaving the British time
for chaotic evacuation
from the Port of Dunkirk.
Althout most histrians see this
as a gesture of peace,
others still insist it was
a military blunder.
Humiliated, the British Empire now has
to rely on civilian sailing vessels
and merchant fishing boats to help
ferry troops back
across the English Channel.
With all their heavy artillery, tenks
and armoured vehicles
left on the shores of France,
they are a spent force,
but will look for other means
of continuing the war.
Six weeks of German
Blitzkrieg defeats France.
Paris is Hitler's.
Hitler will have the French authorities
surrender at Compiegne
using the very same carriage in
which the Germans had been compelled
to ask for an armistice in
World War One.
Carriage No. 2149D was rolled out
of its protective building
to the precise spot it
occupied on 11 Nov 1919.
1940 FRANCE
France asked
Hitler for an armistice.
Shortly before 3 o'clock, on
the afternoon of June 21st, 1940,
he arrived in the
forest of Compiegne.
Hitler himself took the seat
where Marshall Foch had sat.
The French delegation led by General
Huntziger followed closely behind.
When the French
delegation entered the carriage,
Hitler could fully relish
the peak of his career.
Long ago on entering politics,
he had sworn never to rest until the shame
of November 1918 had been wiped out.
Now, he had done it.
But the dream of his lifetime,
he said, had been fulfilled.
1940 BERLIN
Berlin greeted him
with flowers of jubilation.
Hitler's triumphal return to Berlin,
sent a flood of respect and adulation.
"The church
bells rang all day,
and the mood of elation really
penetrated throughout the country."
"My feelings towards Hitler were such
as if he were some super human being
between man and a
God, sent by Providence."
This was the man who had obliterated
the humiliation of The First World War.
The same day in a speech at the Reichstag
Hitler presented Britain
with yet another offer
of peace.
LONDON, ENGLAND
Secret government documents reveal
that a British received
over a dozen offers of peace
between 1939 and 1941,
despite their desperate military
straits after the evacuation at Dunkirk.
Prime Minister Winston Churchill however
would have none of it.
Because he is aware Britain cannot
defeat Germany alone,
he will do his utmost to drag
the US into the war.
It will however mean the eventual
loss of the British Empire.
1940 BRITAIN
Germany was absolutely in a
position to direct the course of the war.
All we had to defeat now,
we believed, was Britain.
The German fighter
ace, Adolf Galland,
also thinks the next
priority is the Battle of Britain,
but when he meets Hitler, he discovers
that the Führer's priorities are different.
Galland: "I told him that our good time
would come, and we could bomb London
and the fighters could... the
English fighters couldn't take off.
He said "No, no,
no, no... stop this.
I don't like this.
I really don't like the
fight against England.
The English people are so
similar people to the Germans,
and I have the highest respect for
the English building up an empire.
So, you must understand,
I'm forced to fight this fight
against England, but I don't like it."
I think that he himself had not
got any great wish to engage
on an invasion of Britain, because
all the time by now we know,
he was already beginning to get
itchy, and wanting to turn eastwards,
after defeating France.
But Göring insisted
that with the Luftwaffe, with the Air
Force alone, he could knock Britain out.
So he gave him his head
to try.
Initially, Hitler had insisted that only
military installations were to be bombed.
However, on 4 Sept 1940, he explained
in a speech to the Reichstag,
way after months of British targeting
German civilians in nightly bombing raids,
he now has no choice but to
retaliate in kind.
"While the German planes fly over
English land day by day
no Englishman has managed to so much
as cross the North Sea by daylight.
That is way they come at night
and drop their bombs,
you know it well, indiscriminately
and on civilian residents,
farms and villages.
Wherever they see a light,
they drop a bomb.
I did not answer for three months
because I was of an opinion
they would stop this nonsense.
Mr. Churchill perceived this as a sign
of our weakness.
You will surely understand that we are
now giving our answers night after night,
and this at an increasing rate."
To be continued
Part 7
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
Hello America, this is Edward
Murrow speaking from London.
There were more German planes
over the coast of Britain today
than at any time
since the war begun.
Despite the British Empire's vast
resources, and vast the millions of
men at her disposal, including...
1 million Australians
2 million Indians
1 million Canadians
... Churchill and Roosevelt will push
for the US to enter the war.
However, polls consistently show
that ordinary Americans have no
wish to be involved in what to
them is yet another Europian civil war.
In spite on this, Roosevelt will now
force laws through Congress
making a mockery of the US's
supposed neutrality.
in favor of one-sided supply of arms
to Germany's enemies.
The same year, Roosevelt freezes all
assets of defeated European countries,
refusing to recognise their
recognise their new governments.
The "Destroyers for US Bases" agreement
is passed, whereby 50 reconditioned
US Navy destroyers are transfered to
the Royal Navy
in exchange for British bases
in the Caribbean.
Roosevelt will persuade congress to
pass the Lend-Lease Act
which officially ends his pretense
of being neutral.
He will also allow American citizens
to enter the British Air Force.
Roosevelt freezes all German assets in the US,
a violation of international law.
The US announces an oil embargo
against "aggressor" nations.
$ 1 billion dollars in Lend-Lease aid
is sent to Britain.
The US will eventually ship a total of
$ 31.4 billion worth of supplies,
the equivalent of $ 445 billion
in today's money.
The loans will take Britain 61 years
to repay,
with the last installment made
in 2006.
By an overwhelming majority congress
passed Lend-Lease... bill number 1776.
I've asked this congress
for authority and for funds,
sufficient to manufacture additional
munitions and war supplies of many kinds,
to be turned over to those
nations which are now in actual war,
with aggressor nations.
Our most useful
and immediate roll,
is to act as an arsenal for
them as well as for ourselves.
We shall send in ever increasing
numbers: ships, planes, tanks, guns.
That is our purpose
and our pledge.
The enormous amount of US funds,
along with the covert US operations
in the Atlantic
help Britain sustain the war
against Germany.
The quick knockout blow Göring
had hoped for now seemed unlikely,
and the Battle of Britain will shortly
give way to a more important fight.
Hitler will now concentrate on the battle
he believes will eventually
the outcome of World War Two.
On 11 December 1941, he gives a speech
describing the growing Soviet menace.
"Already in 1940 it became increasingly
clear from month to month
that the plans of the Kremlin
were aimed at the domination,
and thus the destruction of Europe.
Only a blind person could fail to see
that a military build-up of
unique world-historical proportions
was being carried out."
Clearly the Soviet Union had
been expanding West.
30 November 1939- Finland is atacked.
21 February 1940- Sweden is bombed.
18 June 1940- Estonia, Latvia, Lithuaia
are invaded.
27 June 1940- Romania is forced by Stalin
to surrender Bessarabia.
Hitler feels that not only is Germany
in grave danger,
but indeed the whole of Europe.
He knows the horrors the
Bolsheviks will bring.
Rather than wait, after meeting with
his generals, Hitler will now plan
a pre-emptive strike against the
Soviet Union,
in what will be known as
Operation Barbarossa.
To understand Hitler's fears for Europe,
we must first look at
the Bolshevik regime and Stalin,
the man President Roosevelt
would affectionately call "Uncle Joe".
STALIN
Stalin came to power
on the death of Lenin,
and ruled the Soviet
Union by fear and torture
for nearly the next 30 years.
During that time,
he was responsible for some
40 million deaths.
Stalin spent his first years in
power consolidating his position.
He managed to sideline Trotsky,
whom he perceived as his major rival.
In 1929 Stalin implemented a
policy known as collectivization.
Lenin's experiment in nationalizing
the land had remained half finished,
and Russian peasants were
still working their own land
and selling their own
produce in the markets.
By means of collectivization,
Stalin meant to complete Lenin's
initiative,
and to take away all of the peasants
lands and produce in the name of the state.
In 1930, peasant's produce
began to be collected up.
The Red Army one-by-one seized
the produce from every single field.
Some peasants managed to hide
their goods rather than give them up,
but communist party officials
searched every nook and cranny
eventually discovering
the hiding places.
The officials also seized the
peasant's agricultural equipment.
The peasants were left with nothing to
eat, and nothing to work the soil with.
Eventually, that catastrophe that
Lenin had described
as the most useful for communism
raised its head again... famine.
In Ukraine alone, 6 million people
starved over the next few years.
2 million died in Kazakhstan and
1 million in northern Caucasus.
Children reduced to skin
and bone died in agony.
There was another ghastly result of the
famine inspired by Stalin - cannibalism.
Peasants maddened by
hunger began to eat corpses.
Then an even
worse horror emerged,
some peasants had kidnapped
children and eaten them.
In front of these two Russian
peasants caught eating human flesh,
lay the remains of the
children they had snatched.
Stalin's regime had turned
human beings into savage animals
just as communism had intended.
Everyone who opposed Stalin's
collectivization policy paid with his life.
Tens of thousands of Kulaks
were detained and shot.
In actual fact,
the regime branded everyone it saw
as opposed to its ideology as Kulaks.
Large numbers of priests and even
members of their congregations,
who attended church
frequently were arrested as Kulaks.
Some were executed.
Others were sent to the labor camps,
where a slow lingering death
awaited them.
These camps were
set up all over Russia
and were simply another
of Stalin's killing machines.
Millions of people regarded as enemies
of the state were worked to death in them
under the most
terrible conditions.
Some were put to work laboring
on canals in the blazing heat,
others were sent off to break
rocks in the freezing cold of Siberia.
These people, forced to perform hard
labor under the worst possible conditions,
soon turned into living skeletons.
The great majority
never left the camps alive.
The Soviet Union, like every communist
country, was an economic basket case.
It could not produce
enough to survive.
And so, every communist / socialist
state has been dependent upon aid from
the capitalist producing states.
So, Russia was desperate for our aid,
both in terms of direct government aid,
but also in terms of opening up the
spigots for private capital markets,
particularly New York bankers and corpor-
ations to move into Russia in a big way.
In 1933 the Roosevelt administration invited
a Soviet representative to Washington
to negotiate terms of
diplomatic recognition.
Number of Deaths in Ukraine
1941 POLAND
Hans Frank is appointed
governor-general of Poland
and the country disappears from
the headlines of the world press.
Jews must wear the Star of David
on their arm,
not carry it in their pocket.
In Warsaw there is a
streetcar exclusively for Jews.
A district a mile and a half
square is transformed into a ghetto.
There is condemnation from the Allies
over the Jewish ghetto,
and yet it bears no comparison to
the many black ghettos in Amerika,
a country where Negroes were still
being lynched, and hanged from trees.
Britain's record on the "human rights"
of the subjects in her many colonies
is likewise cruel and racist.
Winston Churchill served in the Boer War
when thousends of women and children
were left to starve in British
concentration camps.
No one was ever brought to account for
the many crimes against humanity in...
India
Africa
Australia
... or for the mass drugging of the
population of China in the Opium Wars.
MEXICAN REPATRIATION ACT
In the US, the years between 1929
and 1939 saw the forced deportation
of 2 million Mexicans, as first
authorised by Presdent Herbert Hoover.
Of those, 1.2 million were born
American citizens.
The final US Army massacre of the "Indians"
occurs, at Wounded Knee, South Dakota.
By 1924, they are almost completely
wiped out.
Children that survive are sent to
boarding schools for re-education,
where teachers are instructed to...
"kill the Indian in them"
AMERICAN RACISM
Throughout World War Two and up
until the 1960's,
a majority of American States
enforced segregation
trough the use of "Jim Crow" laws.
States could impose legal punishment
on those
consorting with members of
different race.
The most common types of laws
forbade intermarriage,
and mandated that businesses and
public institutions
segregate blacks and whites.
Here is just a sampling of the
various State laws:
ARIZONA
Intermarriage:
The marriage of a person with Caucasian
blood with a Negro, Mongolian, Malaysian,
or Hindu shall be null and void.
FLORIDA
Cohabitation:
Any Negroes or White person who are
not married to each other,
and occupy the nighttime in the
same room, shell be
punished by imprisonment or fine.
MISSOURI
Intermarriage:
All marriages between... White persons
and Negroes or Mongolians
are prohibited and declared
absolutely void.
President Franklin D. Roosevelt had time
and time again resisted any
Republican Party efforts to pass
a Federal law prohibiting lynching.
In 1922, future President Harry Truman
joined the Ku Klux Klan.
1936 BERLIN
THE MYTH OF THE OLYMPIC GAMES
Anti-Germn propaganda in the US
claim that a furious Hitler
had ignored four-time Olympic gold
medalist Jesse Owens.
In his 1970 autobiography Owens
wrote:
"When I passed the Chancellor he arose,
waved his hand at me,
and I waved back at him.
I think the writers shoved
bad taste in criticism the man
of the hour in Germany."
On his return to the US, Owens will
not be invited to the White House.
He later said, "Hitler didn't snub me -
it was FDR who snubbed me.
The President didn't even send
me a telegram.
The Olympic champion later had to
make a living by racing horses.
In 1960, almost a quarter of a century
later, a young Casius Clay
threw his Olympic gold medal into
the Ohio river
after a waitress in a resturant
told him...
"We don't serve Niggers here."
To be continued
Part 8
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
Italy, which had allied with Germany
in 1940, was now fighting
the British in Greece and in
the Middle East.
War had broken out in the Balkans,
where the worst atrocites
of World War Two would
soon take place.
Before Germany could invade
the Soviet Union,
Hitler would first have to send
the Vehrmacht
to help secure these regions.
Within six weeks, the British would
be forced
to retreat from both Greece
and the Middle East.
In Yugoslavia, the British-backed
government is quickly overthrown.
Croatia is now independent for the
first time in 900 years.
To this day, many Croats honour
Adolf Hitler as a liberator.
THE JAPANESE CONFLICT
Troughout the 1930's Japan has been
at war with China.
When Japan allied with Germany and
Italy in 1940,
the new Vichy French government
consented to the
Japanese occupation of France's
Indochina colonies.
The British Empire however, which also
had colonies in the region,
together with the US froze Japan's
assets in July 1941.
NEW YORK TIMES, 26 JULY 1941
"The measures, in effect, bring all financial
and import and export trade transactions
in which Japanese inerests are involved
under the kontrol of the US government."
On 1 August 1941, Roosevelt -
still looking for a way to enter the war -
forced an oil embrgo on Japan,
an intentional act of hostility.
Both these actions were taken before
fateful December 7 Pearl Harbour attack.
The results:
Japan lost access to 75 % of her
oversaes trade
and 88 % of her imported oil.
Soon there be insufficient resources
to continue war with China.
To try and resolve this the Japanese
entered into negotiations with US officias,
who demanded that Japan first withdraw
from China before the embargoes would end.
The Japanese would never permit themselves
to be humbled in such a way...
... a fact which Roosevelt must
have known.
In his book "Icebreaker", Russian historian
Victor Suvorov gives compelling proff
that Hitler was forced into a reluctant
pre-emptive strike
against massive Soviet military
machine
poised to invade whole of
Western Europe.
Suvorov quotes top secret Soviet
documents which make it crystal clear
that Soviet military was being built
as an offensive force.
The collateral damage inflicted on the
eleven Europaan countries
involved in Hitler's defensive measures
against Britain and France
had created an unprecedented situation
where their armies,
governments, and political parties
had been destryed.
Now with Europe totaly exposed,
Stalin is hoping Germany will
expand the war by sending
troops to Britain.
Instead, he is caught completely off
guard as 3 million soldiers
prepare to invade the atheisti Soviet
Union wearing
belt buckles engraved with the words...
Gott Mit Uns
From the Balic to the Black Sea
three million German soldiers,
are moving into position
22 JUNE 1941
OPERATION BARBAROSSA
to launch Operation
Barbarossa.
It's the most brutal conflict
between two nations in recorded history,
is about to begin.
On the first day of Barbarossa
alone, 1.200 Soviet aircraft
are destroyed in a single strike.
Panzer units sweeping East, are
already deep inside Soviet territory.
Chaos multiplies the catastrophe.
Without orders from the Kremlin,
Red Army field Commanders lose
control of their units.
Dazed, cut off, surrounded,
thousands of Soviet soldiers surrender.
And at the height of the
Wehrmacht's furious onslaught,
Stalin disappears completely.
He has every reason
to hide from his people.
Captured German news real
footage,
shows Soviet frontier troops
overwhelmed.
A retreat under fire in total confusion.
Whole formations surrendering.
Hundreds of thousands of men
entangled with fleeing civilians
in scenes of Biblical disorder.
Yet, there are some Soviet
citizens who welcome the invader.
To many in the Ukraine,
the arrival of the Germans
is a heaven sent opportunity
to throw off Stalin's yoke.
Local women bless the
Germans as they pass.
Their men folk destroy reminders of
a man who has terrorized them for years.
Stalin is above all stunned by the
shear speed of the German advance.
Still the Germans drive East.
They're at the outskirts of Kiev,
Smolensk, and Leningrad.
Yet fierce pockets of Red Army
resistance fight on behind enemy lines.
The fortress city of Brisk.
The besieged Red Army
garrison fights on and on,
for more than a month until they
are finally compelled to surrender.
Hitler is so impressed by the
tenacity of the Russian troops,
that he exercises rare clemency.
Only one survivor is shot.
The Political Officer at
the fortress Mikhail Fomin.
The Führer sights the defense
of Brest as an heroic effort.
An example to his own soldiers.
And he visits the fortress
with Mussolini,
to acknowledge a hard earned victory.
But for Stalin, the defenders
of Brest are not heroes.
Years later, after they're
released from German capture,
he will send
survivors to the Gulag.
The Wehrmacht's rapid relentless
advance seems unstoppable.
Traveling at up
to 50 miles a day,
Panzer divisions are already
approaching the heart of Stalin's empire.
And in the middle of July,
Stalin is forced to consider offering
the Germans a negotiated peace.
While Stalin contemplates
a way out of the war,
he is drawing up plans to punish
his own troops if they surrender.
In a desperate attempt to halt
the route, he issues order No. 270.
All officers and Political Officials
taken prisoner at the front,
are to be considered traitors.
If ever they return to the Soviet
Union,
they will be arrested and executed.
But the barbarity of order
270 does not stop there.
The wives of captured troops also
face imprisonment in the Gulag.
Hitler now forms the Einsatzgruppen
units for the necessry removal
of the die-hard Bolshevik leadership
and NKVD,
from all Soviet towns and cities.
However, on hearing of the German
invasion, many civilians
refuse to wait and take immediate
revenge on their Communist oppressors
and associated collaborators.
Meanwhile, Roosevelt extends the Land-Lease
Act, and sends more financial
and military aid to the Soviet Union
to help keep the Communist regime
in the war.
Stalin is now rumored to have
suffered a breakdown.
Now with Moscow in
range of the Luftwaffe,
Stalin's own citadel of power
comes directly under attack.
German Armies race for the Capital.
Elsewhere, army group
North heads for Leningrad.
Army group Center makes a
pincer movement towards Smolensk.
Army group South strikes
towards Kiev and the Ukraine.
The suburbs of Kiev,
the beginning of August.
In a fast pincer movement, German army
group South, threatens to encircle the city.
During August and the first
two weeks of September,
the Wehrmacht encircles a vast
area crammed with Red Army troops.
Four Soviet Armies parish.
On the 18th of
September the city falls.
The Führer is now lord
of all he surveys.
It seems as if he is on
course to meet his objective.
To crush Stalin's Russia
before winter sets in.
Leningrad lies ahead of the
Wehrmacht, defenseless.
As September draws to a close,
Leningrad is totally cut off with no
land link left to the Soviet Union.
At the end of September,
the Führer launches Operation
Typhoon,
the final drive alone the road
to Moscow.
14 German tank and 74 infantry
divisions,
a total of 1.8 million officers and men,
take part in the offensive.
Stalin has good cause for panic now.
Facing a disaster that might
sweep away the whole Soviet Union,
they have one last hope, that
the weather will save them.
Sleet is turning to snow.
The ground frozen at night is
now a quagmire during the day,
paralyzing Hitler's
overstretched war machine.
On the 2nd of December, German
units reach Krasnaya Polyana,
17 miles from the
center of Moscow.
As the weather intensifies
and temperatures plummet,
the bleak truth is time
turns decisively against them.
5 DAYS LATER...
AND AFTER 5 MONTHS OF US SANCTIONS...
PEARL HARBOUR, HAWAII
7 DECEMBER 1941
Two Army Privates running
the Opana radar station,
are suddenly startled
by blips on the screen.
Fifty planes headed for Owahu.
Immediately they report the sightings
to the Army Operations Center.
They're dismissed as US planes
coming from the mainland.
Aircraft designated for the
second wave of the attack take off.
Messenger boy Tadao Fuchikami,
picks up General Marshall's urgent
cable for delivery to General Short.
Commander Fuchida's first
wave armada is on course.
Sleepy-eyed sailors and Marines,
their breakfast getting cold,
mistake the attack for some
crazy kind of air raid drill.
They think the
planes are American.
At 7:55 AM, dive bombers
hit Hickam and near airfields.
Two minutes later, torpedo planes
start their bomb on battleship row.
Three minutes later,
Zero's strafe other airbases.
It's Fuchida's first wave of aircraft that
hits the Arizona; she erupts like a volcano.
Flames burst 500 feet in the air.
Fuchida's deadly first waves
sinks the West Virginia.
Now, the Oklahoma,
a battle wagon moored outboard of the
US Maryland shutters with torpedo hits.
She begins listing...
and capsizes.
More torpedo's rip into the
battleships California and Nevada.
After the last bomb is dropped
the United States of America
virtually has a Pacific Fleet...
no longer.
Japan Attacks Pearl Harbor
And Then Declares War on U.S.
Yesterday,
December 7th, 1941,
A date which will live in infamy,
the United States of America
was suddenly and deliberately attacked
by Naval and Air Forces
of the Empire of Japan.
On 8 December 1941, the US declares
war on Japan
and officially enters World War Two.
Britain will declare war the
same day.
Was the attack really such a suprise?
JAPAN MAY STRIKE OVER WEEKEND
KURUSU BLUNTLY WARNED NATION
READY FOR BATTLE
To be continued
Part 9
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
1941 THE UKRAINE
We knew there was a war on.
By that time,
what was left of us was herded into
the cattle trains and shipped to Siberia.
That was literally a matter of
hours if not minutes until our turn.
And we were already sitting at the
railroad station - this was September 1941
when the German Army
overran the Ukraine,
and stopped the exiling; stopped
the trains. They stopped the trains.
And it was to us as if the
Lord had sent us the angels.
Here were people who stopped the
terror that had been upon us for 25 years.
Who came and opened
the churches for us
and said: "You can have
all the services you want".
It was like heaven.
My mother, to the day she
died, never stopped talking
about the wonderful 2 years that she
had when the German Army came.
They took over the
houses - we gave them gladly!
It was magnificent!
And we were absolutely convinced
that the Germans had come
to save us from Communism.
And never was there any reason for us
to change our minds - why should we?
The Germans were
heroes in our eyes.
We absolutely believed in Adolf Hitler,
we believed in the, in the nature of his
struggle, in the merits of his struggle.
We had these magnificent
German soldiers protecting us,
so the beginning was
not at all unpleasant.
But then it became grim,
then the winter came.
On 11 December 1941, four days after the
Japanese attack on Pearl Harbour,
Hitler spoke to the Reichstag in Berlin
and dealt at lenght
with President Roosevelt hostile
policies toward Germany.
He detailed the increasingly belligernt
actions of Roosevelt's government,
and dramatically announced Germany
was now
joining Japan in the war
against the US.
Italy and Croatia would soon
follow suit.
The Independent State of Croatia,
commonly reffered to us the NDH,
is created 10 April 1941.
Led by Ante Paveliæ,
several hundred Ustae militia will
travel from training camps
in Italy to form the new government.
They will govern most of modern day
Croatia including Bosnia and Herzegovina,
and will seek to clear out ethnic
Serbs, Jews and Romany gypsies.
However, one third of all ethnic Serbs
will be spared death or deportation
by converting from Serbian Orthodox
to Roman Cathoic.
This is not dissimilar to what English
Protestants offered
the Catholics during the Middle Ages.
In Jerusalem, Hitler will ally with the
Grand Mufti Muhammad Haj Amin al-Husseini,
and together Croat and Muslim in
Bosnia form
the 13th Waffen Mountain Division of
the SS Handschar.
Few historians have ever asked
way so many foreigners
supported a supposedly "racist" Hitler.
The Arabs and the Japanese would
not be
the only non-Whites to fight
on the side of the Third Reich.
Africans, Slavs, Asians, Hindus, Arabs
and numerous other nationalities
all fought shoulder-to-shoulder
with Germans.
Hitler's Wehrmacht and Waffen SS
were in reality the most culturally,
ethnicaly and religiously diverse
military forces in Western history.
Ustae
With uncompromising hatred, fanatical
nationalism and die-hard religious beliefs
all in play, the horrors about to occur
in the Balkans are unparalleled.
Yugoslavia will become a war zone
of competing political interests
and disparate ideologies, including Socialism,
Fascism, Commuism, Monarchism,
and Serbian and Croatian nationalism.
It is well-documented and undeniable
that the fiercely nationalistic and fanatical
Croatian Ustae persecuted Jews.
Communists are perceived enemies
of the state,
holding them in camps such as
those at Jasenovac.
The Croats had been victims themselves
however, having suffered terriby
at the hands of the Serbs and
Bolshevik partisans.
Indeed, the Ustae's elite unit-
the Black Legion -
was formed on 3 Sptember 1941
by the Croat and Muslim survivors
who had fled Sarajevo after seeing
their families
butchred by Serbs and Chetniks.
They eventually earned a reputation
as the most brutal and ruthless
of Ustae units with a motto of...
"No quarter asked, none given."
Their finest hour came in the defence
of the town Kupres where,
although heavily outnumbered, they
and other Ustae units
successfully defended the civilian
population against
four Communist partisan regiments,
preventing their certain death.
When the war ends, after successfuly
escaping the Communists,
hundreds of thousands of Croat soldiers
throw down their weapons
and surrender to the Western Allies
at the Austrian border town of Bleiburg.
However, the British Army will trick
the unarmed POWs and their families
into boarding trains supposedly
heading West.
The trains will instead trasport them
East, over the border to Yugoslavia,
and towards certain death at the hands
of the victorious partisans
led by Marshal Josip Tito.
On arrival, they are dragged from
the tranis and the men shot.
The women and children are forced
on foot to prison camps where,
along the way, many are raped,
beaten or murdered.
Hidden from the history books,
it is the worst massacre
of 20th century Europe, and became
known in Croatia as:
"The Bleiburg Massacre"
THE BATTLE OF MOSCOW
In the dark days of Autumn 1941,
the Summers' defeats have
decimated the Red Army,
and Hitler's artillery could
strike Moscow itself.
Soviet Union seems on
the brink of total defeat.
But Stalin has his back
to the wall
and he will stop at nothing
to protect his power base.
Hitler and the Allies, expect the
fall of Moscow at any moment.
In the capital, an agitated Stalin
entrusts the defense to general
Zhukov.
And it is his suggestion
at the end of November,
of a counter-attack against
the German pincers
that triggers hurried planning for a
massive Soviet counter-offensive.
It is a plan made possible by the seemingly
limitless depth of Red Army reserves.
His agent in Tokyo, Richard Sorge,
has sent word that Japan will
not as feared,
attack the USSR from Manchuria.
And for once, crucially, Stalin
trusts the advice of a minion.
He authorizes the transfer West
of more than half
the Soviet strength in the Far East.
17 fresh divisions, trained regulars
with full armored and artillery support,
that will form the heart
of the counter-attack.
The first days of December
are an agony of anticipation,
but on the 5th Zhukov unleashes
his armies.
Within 48 hours the Soviet
thrusts are fully underway.
Hitler's furious order to hold
advanced positions is meaningless.
The Red Army's new T-34 tanks are
rugged, powerful fighting machines
designed to perform unfailingly in
the bitter cold of deepest Winter.
And swarms of specialist ski troops
are too fast for the ill-clad Wehrmacht.
German troops can only fall
back in astonished disarray.
As army groups enter, the juggernaut that
was to crush Moscow, is smashed apart.
After 6 months of catastrophic
defeats,
the Red Army's hard-fought victory
is undeniable.
And as the year closes,
Soviet towns and villages
west of the capital
are being freed from
their brief Nazi occupation.
There will be more sweeping Soviet
victories,
but none will burn more brightly
than this first astounding
recovery from the brink of defeat.
Convinced now that Germany
is on the brink of collapse,
Stalin demands attack after attack.
Every remaining reserve
is thrown into the fray
as he seeks to drive the
invader from Soviet territory.
But it is impossible.
Their superhuman effort has taken
its toll,
and the armies are exhausted.
Dissipated by Stalin's
overreaching ambition,
the offensives make only trivial
gains and at a dreadful cost.
And by the time its attacks
peter out in February,
the Red Army has lost almost a
million troops in the battle for Moscow.
That grim statistic will be hidden from
the Soviet people for half a century.
The majority of Wehrmacht units
may have escaped encirclement,
but they could not
save their equipment.
Now it lies abandoned everywhere;
a gigantic German scrapyard.
It is a fitting sight to show
British foreign minister Eden
when he arrives to
survey the battlefields.
For neither Britain nor Stalin's
new ally the United States
believed that Moscow could
survive the German onslaught.
But if the Western Allies are amazed,
this one victory has revealed to Stalin
a mirage of complete triumph and he
is totally committed to further attack.
But he has miscalculated.
The Wehrmacht is not yet beaten
and a furious Hitler is planning
massive new offensives.
His folly will again compel the Red
Army to fight in desperate defense.
And so the Soviet
people must struggle on.
It will be a long, painful journey
and many will not survive
to its conclusion.
RUSSIAN COSSACKS IN THE BALKANS
After the 1917 Russian Revolution,
the Communist Bolshevik regime brought
nothing but death and misery
to much of the population,
especially ethnic minorities.
One such oppresed group was
to rise up
and fight alongside the Germans.
With their reputation for toughness,
mobility and fearles fighting,
they are well-suited for the rugged
terrain of the Balkans.
Allocated to clear the region of
Communist partisans,
they are led by charismatic
German officer...
General Helmuth von Pannwitz
During oprations in Serbia and Croatia,
there occured a number of atrocities
against the civilian popuation, including
mass rapes and executions.
But an order by General von Panwitz
dated 20 October 1943
made it absolutey clear to all
under his command
that any crimes of such a nature
were to be punished by death.
On 11 May 1945, General von Pannwitz
surrender to the British Army
in allied-administred Austria,
after the Germans were assured
they would remain in the custody
of Western powers.
By mid-May it was becoming clear
that the Cossacks would be
sent back to the Soviet Union to face
execution of the Gulag prison camps.
This action will forever become
known as...
"The Betrayal of the Cossacks"
As a German national under the proection
of the Geneva Conventios,
General von Pannwitz was not subject
to banishmet to the Soviet Union.
Knowing full well the consequences,
he refused to abandon his Cossacks
comrades, stating:
"I was with the Cossacks in good times
and I will stay with them in bad times."
On 26 May, he was relieved of his
command and placed under arrest.
The British Army then set about
Cossacks onto railway trucks
by beating them with baseball
bats and rifle butts.
The fighting lasted for several days.
Eventually the British would deliver
to the Red Army around 40.000 Cossacks,
and with them their women and children.
Many are not even Soviet citizens,
and those who were not sent
to the Gulag are subequently executed.
General Helmuth von Pannwitz
was executed in Moscow on 16 January 1947.
He is to this day known by
the Cossacks as...
"The Last Knight of Europe"
"Betrayal of the Cossacks"
To be continued
Part 10
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
THE SOVIET UNION 1942
As the spring campaigning
season opens,
the Red Army's victories
of late 1941
seem suddenly meaningless.
A hasty Soviet attack in
the south against Kharkov
is swallowed up by a
German counteroffensive.
For Soviet soldiers, this
could so easily be the end.
Even Stalin's son
has been captured.
And his image on propaganda leaflets
Yakov Dzhugashvili
adds credence to German
claims of imminent victory.
And on the brink of catastrophe,
he resorts as always, to terror.
Stalin's secret order number 227,
issued under his signature in late July 1942.
This notorious document makes any
unauthorized retreat punishable by death.
Not one step back.
Stalin means it literally.
And this unique footage shows NKVD
troops putting his edict into practice.
They're known
as blocking units.
Deployed just behind the troops,
they pass instant sentence
on any who disobey order 227.
Enforcing the supreme commander's
will without hesitation or mercy.
Stalin will reject exchanging German
prisoners for the return of his son,
reportedly stating,
"I have no son named Yakov"
Yakov died in German captivity,
although the circumstances are unclear.
One account says he ran into
an electric fence
surrounding his POW camp.
Another, that he was shot
whilst trying to ecape.
The Führer is confident now,
certain that the Wehrmacht can seize
the vital oil centers of Grozny and Baku.
Two smaller German armies
have been advancing slowly east
towards the industrial
city of Stalingrad.
He sees a chance to cut all links
between Moscow and the Caucasus.
The city on the Volga
becomes his new prime target.
JAPAN AT WAR
After the bombing of Pearl Harbour,
the Japanese will now seek
to rid from the region the
domineering
Western powers of Britain
and United States.
On Christmas Day 1941, they capture
Hong Kong from British.
The Phiippines, Burma and
British Malaya
all fall in quick succession.
However, their greatest prize will be
the taking of the British
stronghold of Singpore.
Vastly outnumbered, 30.000 Japanese
troops force over 100.000 British,
Australian and Indian soldiers
to surrender.
It will be one of the most humiliating
defeats ever for the British Empire.
Winston Churchill describe the fall
of Singapore as...
"The worst disaster and largest
capitulation in British history."
Later, historians will point the
finger at Churchill himself
and blunder he made in
underestimating the Japanese.
Hours after surrendering to the
Japanese,
Austrlian-born Lieutenant General
Gordon Bennett and several of his officers
deserted their men and
absconded to Australia.
He was never given a major
position of command again.
SINGAPORE SURRENDERS
Fighting Ceased at 10 P.M. Sunday
HONGKONG SURRENDERS!
ANEMY ASKS FOR ARMISTICE AT
5:50 P.M. THURSDAY
BRITISH ASIA FLEET SMASHED
Japanese Land at Guam:
Nippon Losses Insignificant
In 1942, at the height of its power,
the Japanese Empire ruled over an
area spanning 2.847.000 squre miles.
It was one of the largest maritime
empires in history.
JULY 1942
The Wehrmacht are at the gates
of Stalingrad.
An order from Stalin will prevent
civilians, even women and children,
from leaving the city.
His reasoning is that their presence
will encourage
greater resisance from the
city's defenders.
Stalingrad seems there
for the taking.
But this is Stalin's city, the very
symbol of his personal prestige.
And that is something even women
and children are expected to defend.
THE BATTLE OF STALINGRAD
23 AUGUST 1942
But when the thunder finally
abates, 50.000 lay dead.
Now, the Wehrmacht is moving
in to claim the rubble for its own.
As they inch through the suburbs,
German troops surely
expect a rapid conquest.
Instead, they are entering a savage
killing ground, for a duel to the death
that will rank among the most
terrible in human experience.
For at their approach the
ruins spring to furious life.
Soviet soldiers and citizens do
not even contemplate surrender.
A thousand desperate
battles erupt on the streets.
And a wild labyrinth of constantly
shifting front lines swamps the city.
The front line might be a house,
an alley, a tram line or a wall.
And every street is a minefield,
virtually impassible for tanks
or big guns.
So that soldiers, denied air
and artillery support,
must fight eyeball to eyeball,
lives hanging on their wits, their
battle skills and their cunning.
General Chuikov, in command
of the 62nd Army,
mounts a skillful campaign,
but his outnumbered troops
cannot hope to stop the Wehrmacht.
And by early November it has
cut a swath across Stalingrad,
splitting the 62nd Army in two.
In a last desperate gesture,
Chuikov mounts assault after assault
on the Mamayev ground,
a vital patch of high ground,
the very hub of the battle zone.
The hill changes hands
no less than eight times,
as Chuikov throws
everything into the fray.
And from the USA's Alaskan airfields,
fighter aircraft fly into Siberia
to aid a Red Army almost
ready to launch its counterstrike.
And on the
19th of November,
a huge artillery barrage by the
southwest front pierces the front.
And Yeryomenko's southern wing
surges forward on the next day.
The Wehrmacht, taken utterly
by surprise, cannot stop them.
And as its allies
collapse on the flanks,
there are no reserves to
stem the resurgent Red tide.
Within 3 days the Southwest
Front has taken Kalach,
some 80 kilometers
West of Stalingrad.
And on the 23rd of November,
a few miles southwest of Kalach,
its advanced units meet up
with Yeryomenko's forces.
Suddenly the German's Sixth
Army and the Fourth Panzer Army,
perhaps 300.000 of Hitler's finest
troops,
are surrounded inside Stalingrad.
The hunter has been
captured by his prey.
An astonished Hitler summons
Manstein, his troubleshooter, to Stalingrad.
Two Soviet armies, the
51st and Second guards,
are rushed to meet Manstein's relief
force and stop it dead in its tracks.
The guards pay a high
price for stopping Manstein.
Almost two-thirds of the
army is killed or wounded.
There will be no relief now
for German troops in Stalingrad.
The Luftwaffe tries,
but the Red Army brings up
extra AA batteries.
And the lumbering German transports
are blown out of the sky
in their hundreds.
Yet, like Soviet troops before them,
they entertain no thought
of surrender.
For ordinary
soldiers on both sides,
this is the ghastly climax
to a long, dark journey.
In the heart of the cauldron,
Hitler's gladiators know now
that they are doomed.
They evacuate a few casualties
on the last plane out of Stalingrad.
And with it go their last words
to families, lovers, friends.
But though they fight on,
the bullets are running out,
and the Red Army is still coming
at them.
Finally, after five long months,
a battle that began
almost by accident is over.
2 Feb 1943
Field Marshal Friedrich Paulus
surrenders to the Soviets.
300.000 German, Croatian, Hungarian,
Romanian and Italian soldiers,
including 35.000 Soviet volunteers
fighting the Communists,
had been surrouded.
Over 11.000 would refuse to lay
down their arms at the official surrender,
preferring instead a fight to
the death with the Bolsheviks.
By early March all pockets of
resistance had been wiped out.
Of those who remained, many will
freeze to death
on the forced marches East.
Others die from disease or mistreatmet,
or are worked to death
in the Gulag concenration camps.
Later, historians would confirm
that of the 11.237 letters sent by
soldiers in Stalingrad to their families,
almoust all expresed a willingess
to fight Communism
and die for National Socialism and
the Führer Adolf Hitler.
Field Marshal Friedrich Paulus was
held prisoner in the Soviet Union until 1952,
when he settled in Dresden,
East Germany.
He would spend the remainder of
his days
defending his actions at Stalingrad.
Later he would be quoted as saying...
Communism was the best hope
for postwar Europe.
In 1955, only 6.000 of an estimated
90.000 prisoners or more
would return home.
Stlingrad would prove to be
a turning point in the war.
To be continued
Part 11
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
From early February,
Stalin orders new offensives
all along the southern fronts.
Though they have fought and
survived the Battle of Stalingrad,
their commanders can
permit them no rest.
Instead they must struggle on
through the late winter blizzards,
instruments of their supreme
commander's lust for glory.
The Red Army drives deep into Nazi
held territories fighting exhaustion,
cold, mud. Inch by inch
the infantry advances.
The Führer knows that if his
stretched forces
are to defeat the Red Army
in 1943,
they must attack quickly
before it can recover
from the losses of the winter.
Hitler's strategy is simple
and optimistic.
In a two-pronged attack,
he plans to destroy the Soviet
position around Kursk.
On the map, a great bulge 130
miles long and 100 miles deep
at the center of the eastern front.
And so now, two gigantic
armies are converging.
The greatest tank battle
of all time is about to begin.
THE BATTLE OF KURSK
The great barrage of Katyusha rockets
and artillery
announces counteroffensives
by 4 more Soviet armies
sweeping around the rear
of the battered German divisions.
German offensive operations
are halted.
The Wehrmacht can only retreat.
It leaves behind the
mangled debris of war.
Battle zones littered with
charred and broken tanks,
and the bodies of hundreds
of thousands of men.
For survivors of this savage
inferno, shattered, shell-shocked,
stunned by the horrors they have
witnessed, there can be no joy.
The Battle of Kursk
5 July 1943- 23 August 1943
Outnumbered by more that two to one,
the Germans suffer casualties of
around 203.000. whilst Communist losses
amount to some 803.000.
The Germans however failed
to achieve their goal.
With the US opening a new front
in Italy, after the batle of Kursk,
never again will Germany regain
the initiative.
The Germans will now fight a rearguard
action in freezing weather conditions,
and at the same time offer much-needed
protection to refugees fleeing
the rampaging Communists.
"1943 the story changed and
the Germans were pushed back.
And in the pushback they moved
us with them, and we went willingly.
There was no moving at gunpoint.
Had we stayed back
the Communists would have
taken us and executed us
or shipped us to Siberia.
So we very willingly retreated
with the Germans.
Food was getting short.
The horses were getting sick.
The road was getting narrow.
It was extremely cold.
When I think of the war, I do not
think of hunger so much as of cold.
It was always, always cold.
And then of course once the winter
came, it became harder and harder.
We had to often stay
overnight in strange houses.
The army would confiscate houses,
would put the refugees there.
The army protected
us to the end.
The army never, ever let us down.
NEVER let us down, to the very end."
¶ And the snow fell,
covering the dreams and ideals.
freezing the blood and the wheels.
¶ And the snow fell,
they had to keep warm for survival.
and defeated the beast's only rival.
¶ They took the old roads that
Napoleon had taken before.
¶ They fought as the forces of light
against the darkness in a holy war.
¶ One day they were looking around
at the sun shining on the cold flowers.
¶ The next day they were freezing to death
in the snow and the ice cold showers.
¶ And the snow fell,
covering the dreams and ideals.
freezing the blood and the wheels.
¶ And the snow fell,
they had to keep warm for survival.
and defeated the beast's only rival."
PARTISANS - THE RED TEROR
This secret partisan report
declassified for this program
complains that amongst
one large partisan division.
Drunkenness, robbery, beatings
and rape are universal occurrences.
The widespread terror
wrought by the partisans
was not a story the Communists
wished to tell after the war.
This rare archive shows a
woman hanged by the partisans
and displayed to the rest of
the population as a warning.
These film rushes, never shown
to the German public during the war,
reveal Soviet mutilation
of German prisoners.
Actions like these only served to
escalate the level of the German reprisal.
During our retreat we found
20 soldiers...
... murderer in the most bestial
manner
Their ears were cut off, their eyes
gouged out, their genitals cut off
Naturaly, we felt enormous rage
The partisans became a growing
problem for the German occupiers.
If the Germans suspected a village
had been used as a partisan base,
then it was common practice
to burn it to the ground.
"And we burned the houses.
On the one hand I
didn't regret it too much
because I knew what was
is worth a Russian house?
They are so primitive anyhow.
Not comparable to a German house or an
English house or French house, or so on.
Not at all. But all in all, there's not
much value in it, in such a house.
They would survive.
That was my feeling."
In Britain, they have forged
a sword,
a gift to the victor of Stalingrad
from King George.
Earlier, in 1943,
at Katyn forest near Smolensk,
German occupying authorities
had unearthed the mass graves
of 20.000 Polish officers.
International observers were
invited to support Berlin's claim
that the murders were
carried out by the NKVD.
But Stalin had reacted furiously,
denying any link with the massacres.
But when Allied leaders meet
in Teheran,
Churchill and Roosevelt back their
most important ally
in the face of outraged protest
from exiled Poles.
His sword is presented,
and Stalin stands as an undisputed
world leader.
THE KATYN MASSACRE
In March 1940, in a forest near
Katyn village,
eight huge pits were dug.
Heavy trucks brought in people.
They were Polish Army
Reservists, Doctors, Engineers.
The Soviets carried out massacres
on a regular basis.
Riga, Tartu, Lviv, Minsk.
Relatives could not identify
many of the corpses.
Horrific torture had
made them unrecognizable.
The Soviet Union meanwhile
had become an Allied power.
The Soviet officers who pulled
out fingernails, cut tongues,
and perforated the skulls
of their victims with nails...
WERE PAID WITH WESTERN AID!
The British War Crimes Act gives them
immunity from prosecution in Britain,
because war crimes by definition
were committed only by the Germans.
According to the
1991 BRITISH WAR CRIMECAST
War crimes by definition were commited
ONLY by the Germans.
In 2012 the World Press reported their
recent findings on the Katun Massacre.
According to documets published Sepember
2012 by US National Archives
and Records Administration, the US
received coded reports in 1943
from two of its officers taken by
they German captors to the Katyn Forest.
Though the messeges of the US
officers reached Washigton,
they disappeared soon thereafter.
It has long been suspected that President
Roosevelt and Prime Minister Winston Churchill
knew that Soviet leader Joseph Stalin
has ordered the massacre.
One thing the World Press forgot
to mention...
Adolf Hitler is now officially exonerated
of Katyn Massacre.
To be continued
Part 12
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
On 25 July 1943, Italien leader Benito
Mussolini is overthrown and imprisoned.
Over the next few weeks he will be held
in several top secret locations
on the orders of the new
Italien government.
A hand-picked SS squadron, along with
members of Luftwaffe,
are given the task of finding and
rescuing him
before he can be handed
over to the US.
Hitler had personally interviewed three
men to led squadron.
The men he chose was...
Captain Otto Skorzeny.
With time runing out, Mussolini's whereabouts
are finaly discovered at Campo Imperatore
high in the Apennine Mountains
of Italy.
The plan is to land the commando unit
there and assault it.
German military expert warn Hitler
of the high probability of failure
and to expect an 80 % casaulty rate.
The codename for the mission is
Operation Oak.
The 12th of September
1943, central Italy.
High above Mount Gran Sasso.
The most daring and spectacular raid
of World War Two was completed
in just 12 minutes without a
single shot being fired.
Captain Skorzeny greeted Mussolini
with now immortal words...
"Duce, the Furer has sent me
to set you free!"
To which Mussolini replied...
"I knew that my friend would not
forsake me!"
On his return, Captain Skorzeny was
promoted by Hitler to the rank of Major
and awarded the Knight's Cross of the
Iron Cross with Oak Leaves,
the highest order a German military
officer could obtain.
Mussolini awarded him the
Order of 100 Musketeers.
The Allies would come to know Skorzeny
as the most dangerous man in Europe.
At the Nuremberg Trials, Skorzeny was
accused of war crimes but acquitted.
Whilst awaiting a further trial,
he escaped to Spain.
He then moved to Argentina but return
to establish a successful
construction company that would
make him a multi-millionaire.
Otto Skorzeny finally succumbed to
cancer on 5 July 1975, aged 67 in Madrid.
His ashes were later flown to Viena,
Austria to be interred
in the Skorzeny family plot at
Döblinger Friedhof.
OTTO SKORZENY
The most dangerous man in Europe.
1943 OPERATION GOMORRAH
On Saturday, July 24th, 792 RAF bombers
readied for a night attack on Hamburg.
Each loaded with tons of high
explosives and incendiary bombs.
It was the first of a series of attacks
that would continue for an entire week,
codenamed
Operation Gomorrah.
By 1943, the US had finally rearmed
the British.
Now the countries of Capitalism and
Communism and those they dominate,
will combine to seek the total annihilation
one of most advanced civilisation
the world had ever seen.
Under National Socialism,
Germany in a few short years
had arisen
from financial ruin and social
degradation,
to lead Europe in science, technology
art and literature.
It will now be surrounded.
The Germany wil eventually be attacked
by over 50 countries
led by the Soviet Union, Britain
and the US.
Over Hamburg, the Americans will
strategically bomb
industrial plants during the day,
whilst the British will purposely
target civilians at night, aiming at
the tighty-knit houses
of the working class communities.
In what was a heious and barbaric
war crime of epic proportions,
insigned by Churchill and RAF Commander
Arthur "Bomber" Harris,
over 50.000 will be incinerated in the
ensuing firestorm
that will become known as
Germany's "Hiroshima".
The Allies exepect the war
to be over by Christmas,
confident that the firebombing
of other cities will force the Germans
to turn over Adolf Hitler
and the Third Reich.
Yet, no matter how many bombs
Allies drop on German cities,
there will never be a hint of
an upraising against Führer.
"People were sitting there
in the cellar trembling,
and we saw the walls shivering.
As it was, but trembling,
and...
those nights we can never
forget in our lives.
I cannot forget it ever.
We asked ourselves, why are
they doing this to our Führer?
And we were told by everyone,
because they hated the Führer.
Because the Führer wanted
to create a better world.
Maybe Churchill and Roosevelt
thought they could demoralize
the German people with bombing?
And make them surrender?
But he reached the opposite of it."
In the aftermath of the firestorm,
almost a million refugees
fled Hamburg
and took with them stories
of the most terrible
horror that they'd witnessed.
This caused a panic across Germany,
which was unlike anything that
they'd ever experienced before.
In the aftermath of the Hamburg attacks,
the American and British commanders
remained committed to their
sharply divergent strategies.
Eaker continued to press precision
attacks on industrial targets.
Major General
Ira C. Eaker
Harris championed the bombing of cities.
Air Chief Marshal Arthur "Bomber" Harris
And the city he was
focused on - Berlin.
OPERATION "THUNDERCLAP"
the total devastation of the
center of Berlin
THE RED TERROR MOVES WEST
Stalin's military troikas come in
the wake of the resurgent Red Army.
They tour a land scorched
by the departing Germans,
convening kangaroo courts
to purge partisan units
of nationalists, anti-Communists.
There is no hiding place for
Nazi collaborators.
The white card of betrayal hangs
round their necks
as they pay the price of treason.
There is no pity for the young boys
who flocked in innocence
to join the Hitler Youth.
His desperate plea for clemency
will be in vain.
THE FLIGHT FROM COMMUNISM
As the Communists begin to recapture
territories formerly occupied by the Germans,
more and more refugees flee West
in a desperate bid to rich safety.
However, the exodus bring with it
poverly, over-crowding and malnutrition.
These conditions are the perfect breedig
ground for what has become known
over the centuries as the
"war disease"... typhus.
A typhus epidemic had already
broken out
during the summer of 1942
at the Auschwitz-Birkenau POW camp,
when between 1-19 August, over
4.000 deaths were registered,
at an average of 216
prisoers a day.
The Germans managed to save
thousands during the outbreak
using pesticide Zyklon B,
but the disease is so deadly
that the victim's clothing had to
be removed after death
and burned to destroy the
typhus-bearing lice.
In 1943, potentially devastating epidemics
in Sicily and throughout Italy
were only averted by cocerted American
delousing campaign
using the recenty-invented compound
called DDT.
"Germany at that time already
was besieged by 51 countries,
they were struggling for their lives.
And they took us in.
We were all put into what
looked like a great big bathroom.
And what happened eventually is
that they rained soap and water on us.
And the reason for that was
that we had to be deloused.
We were so full of lice.
So, when I hear about the shower heads
in the Holocaust, and all of that,
I know exactly what it was.
That was soap and water
raining down on us to delouse us.
To wash us down like dogs.
The same for the cutting of hair.
I mean we were all shorn
bald in order to stop the lice.
Everybody had lice in the war,
and this was just common
knowledge.
We considered ourselves lucky
if we could ride those cattle cars.
And yes, they were crammed full of
people, and yes it was very difficult,
you know, to travel like that.
You couldn't...
often you could not sit,
you had to stand because
they were crammed full.
This is how it was
in those years.
People were hanging
on those cattle cars.
When you see those pictures,
that could have been us.
We were like that.
The same when you
see the bunk beds.
My goodness, we were lucky if we had
bunk beds where you could sleep at night.
It meant we did not have to
sleep outside in the snow."
To be continued
Part 13
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
BATTLE FOR SICILY ENDS
Order Non-Resident From British
Coastal Areas Today
ITALY DECLERES WAR ON HITLER
ALLIED ARMIES LAND IN FRANCE
IN THE HAVRE-CHERBOURG AREA;
GREAT INVASION IS UNDER WAY
SKY TROOPS POUR INTO FRANCE
On June 5th, 1944,
as the greatest armada
ever assembled left southern England,
bound for the coast of France,
history remembers it as D-Day.
As the ships head towards France,
the men, many of whom will die,
take care of some
last-minute chores.
This Hitler impersonator took the
men's mind off the task at hand,
at least for a few moments.
The time for fun ends as the
coast of France comes into view.
The next day on the
morning of June 6th,
a tremendous barrage strikes
Hitler's fortifications at Normandy
softening it up for the men
who will soon be in the beaches.
The night before,
23.000 airborne troops
parachuted behind enemy lines to
secure the flanks of the landing.
At Gold, Juno, Sword, Utah and
Omaha beaches, 130.000 Allied troops
would now attack five heavily
defended areas
of Hitler's Atlantic wall.
Both Roosevelt and Churchill, after
years of providing
the Soviet Union with financial
and military aid,
finaly send in troops to fight
and die for Stalin
and murderous Bolshevik regime.
The ideologies of Capitalism and
Communism will now combine
to annihilate not only Germany
and her people,
but the very notion of
Nacional Socialism itself.
JUNE 6, 1944
DOG GREEN SECTOR
OMAHA BEACH
THE BETRAYAL OF POLAND
The first overt signal that Stalin comes
not as liberator but as conqueror
is seen in late July,
as General Rokossovsky takes
the eastern Polish city of Lublin.
Within hours of the red flag's
appearance over the city,
Stalin has installed a puppet Communist
government: The Lublin Committee.
Loud denunciations by
nationalist Poles in London
bring little response from
the Allied corridors of power.
And the London Polish government
is power-less to prevent this theft
of its constituency.
But its cries will not
long go unheeded.
"Uncle" Joe Stalin is about
to drop his mask
and show his true face
to the world.
On the 29th of July,
Soviet Radio issues a general plea
to the Polish resistance movement,
"The Home Army".
The carefully worded broadcast calls for
active resistance to the occupying forces.
It gives the impression
without ever directly saying so
that the Red Army is about
to storm the city.
But the Red Army does not move
from its positions just east of the city.
And Stalin, oblivious to mounting
pressure from Western leaders,
grimly rejects Churchill's request
for the use of Soviet airfields for RAF
planes dropping supplies.
Without help, the Poles are doomed.
The battle for the city rages all
through August and into September.
But gradually, inevitably, the Polish
resistance movement is decimated.
Stalin bows to international
criticism only in September,
when an increase in Soviet aid
comes too late.
Last Home Army survivors
surrender in early October.
British Prime Minister Churchill
visits Moscow,
and he has come to discuss
the fate of Eastern Europe.
And he knows that there is little
that Britain
or even the United States can do
to stop a man whose ambitions are
backed by Red Army occupation.
And so, the two leaders
reach a pragmatic agreement.
Jotted down on a piece of
scrap paper,
he concedes Soviet control
over Bulgaria,
Hungary and Romania,
in return for Stalin's guarantee
of nonintervention in Greek politics.
The future of Yugoslavia
is left open.
And Stalin refuses even to
discuss Poland.
THE ENEMY WITHIN
Although Allied propaganda would
have us believe otherwise,
Adolf Hitler was one of the
most popular leader
the world had ever seen.
However, as in the case of
Julius Caesar,
the danger to the Führer
would come from withim.
Hitler had always doubted the loyalty
of some officers from the aristocracy,
and in 1944 he will be proven
right.
Only assassination could snap
the bonds of loyalty
which still bound millions
to Hitler.
The only plotters with access to
the Führer were army officers.
The officer who came closest
to killing Hitler
was Colonel Claus von Stauffenberg.
Claus von Stauffenberg.
He had his opportunity at a
briefing on the 20th of July, 1944.
"This was the time precisely
when we were at a very...
precarious military situation.
And the only man who could possibly
stave off disaster was Adolf Hitler.
That opinion was shared
by many Germans,
Germans who did not belong
to the Party."
ERICH FELLGIEBEL
EXECUTED 4 SEPTEMBER 1944
DR. CARL GOERDELER
2 FEBRUARY 1945
ERWIN VON WITZLEBEN
EXECUTED 8 AUGUST 1944
At the Wolfschanze,
Hitler's headquarters in East Prussia,
Claus von Stauffenberg and fellow
conspirators
fail in their attempt on Hitler's
life
and the coup d'etet they
wished to effect.
On 21 July 1944, at 12:30 A.M.,
Stauffenberg is executed by firing squad.
The other conspirators are
rounded up - judged to be traitors -
either shot by firing squad
or hung.
Fearful and deluded, they had tried
to negotiate a separate peace treaty
with Roosevelt and Churchill,
in the futile hope
of preventing Stalin from
invading Germany.
To be continued
WARNING
contains graphic images that
some viewers may find disturbing.
Part 14
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
"MY HONOUR IS MY LOYALITY"
The following footage features
the translated words of Léon Degrelle,
one of the most famous of
the Waffen SS.
Born in Belgium, he joined
as a private
and earned all stripes from
corporal to general
for exceptional bravery in combat
and was the recipient of
the highest honours.
the Ritterkreuz
the Oak Leaves
the Gold German Cross
... and numerous other decorations
for outstanding vaour under
enemy fire.
One of the last to fight on
the Eastern Front,
he was engaged in 75 heavy
hand-to-hand combat actions
and was wounded on several
occasions.
Léon Degrelle escaped unconditional
surrender
by flying 1500 miles across Europe,
surviving constant fire along
the way
and managing to crash land
on the beach
of San Sebastian in Spain,
critically wounded.
Against all odds, he survived
and lived out the rest of
his life in Spain
where he eventually died
at the age of 87.
Adolf Hitler once told him,
"If I had a son, I would want him
to be just like you."
General Léon Degrelle
Young men who joined the SS were
trained like no other army in the world.
Military and academic instructions
were intensive.
But it was the physical
training that was most rigorous.
They practiced sports
with excellence.
Each of them could have performed
with distinction at the Olympic Games.
The extraordinary physical endurance
of the SS on the Russian front,
which so amazed the world, was
due to their intensive training.
The most striking feature
of the Waffen SS
was that it was composed of volunteers
from some 30 different countries.
What cause gathered them,
and why did they volunteer
their lives?
Was it a German phenomenon?
At the beginning, yes.
In addition to Germans
from Germany,
northwestern Europeans, descendants of
Germans from all across Europe, enlisted.
Then in 1941, during the great clash
with the Soviet Union,
rose the European Waffen SS.
It was on the front lines that the
results of the SS physical training
could really be noticed.
An SS officer had the same
rigorous training as the soldiers.
A relationship of the equality and mutual
respect between soldiers and officers
was always present.
Half of all division commanders
were killed in action - half!
There is not an army in the
world where this happened.
The SS officer always
led his troops into battle.
To them, Hitler was the most
exceptional man ever seen.
Hitler understood them,
and had the remarkable idea
to open the doors to the SS.
The response to Hitler's
offer was overwhelming.
Legions from Norway, Denmark,
Holland and Flanders were formed.
Hitler welcomed them home.
German racialism has been
deliberately distorted.
It was concerned with making the German
race strong and healthy in every way.
Hitler was not interested in
having millions of degenerates.
Today one finds rampant alcohol
and drug addiction everywhere.
Hitler cared that German
families be healthy,
cared that they raised healthy children
for the renewal of a healthy nation.
German racialism meant rediscovering
the creative values of their own race,
rediscovering their culture.
It was a search for excellence,
a noble idea.
National Socialist racialism
was not against the other races.
It aimed at defending
and improving its race,
and wished that all other races
did the same for themselves.
That was demonstrated
when the Waffen SS
enlarged its rank to include
60.000 Islamic SS.
The Waffen SS respected their
way of life,
their customs and their religious
beliefs.
Each Islamic SS battalion
had an imam.
Each company had a mullah.
It was our common wish that their
qualities found their highest expression.
This was our racialism.
I was present when each
of my Islamic comrades
received a personal gift from
Hitler during the new year.
It was a pendant
with a small Koran.
Hitler was honoring them
with this small symbolic gift.
He was honoring
them with what was
the most important aspect
of their lives and their history.
National Socialist racialism
was loyal to the German race
and totally respected
all other races.
The young European volunteers
had observed two things.
First, that Hitler was the only leader
who was capable of building Europe,
and secondly that Hitler,
and Hitler alone, could defeat
the world threat of Communism.
The Communists never aimed at
serving the interests of Russia.
Communism does not limit itself
to acquire chunks of territories,
but aims at total world domination.
Alone among all the leaders
of the world,
Hitler saw this concept as
an equal threat to all nations.
Right through the war the
Waffen SS never retreated.
They would rather
die than retreat.
One cannot forget the figures.
During the 1941 winter the Waffen SS
lost 43.000 men in front of Moscow.
The regiment "Der Führer" fought
almost literally to the last man.
Only 35 men survived out
of the entire regiment.
The Der Führer men stood fast,
and no Soviet troops got through.
And that is what Hitler
admired most of all: guts.
For him it was not enough to have
intelligent or clever associates.
These people can often fall
to pieces,
as we will see during the following
winter at the Battle of Stalingrad,
with General Paulus.
The defeat there was decided
by a man without courage.
He was not capable to face
danger with determination.
To say, "I will not surrender.
I will stand fast until I win."
But he was morally and
physically gutless, and he lost.
Without their heroism,
Germany would have been annihilated
by December 1941.
The Roosevelts and the Churchills sold
out Europe in Teheran, Yalta and Potsdam.
Not since the great religious
orders of the middle ages
had there been such
selfless idealism and heroism.
In this century of materialism,
the SS stand out as shining light
of spirituality.
"Greatness in adversity'" is
the distinction of the SS.
THE HOLY OATH OF THE WAFFEN SS
"I swear to thee Adolf Hitler as Führer
and Chancellor of the German Reih
loyality and bravery.
I vow to thee and to the superiors
whom thou shall appoint obedience
until dead so help me God."
STALIN'S PURGES
With the return of the Soviet forces
in 1944, the mountain peoples,
Ingushe, Balkars, and above all,
Chechens,
are rounded up in dawn raids
of new horror.
Mobile NKVD units
are sent into the hills.
Whole peoples,
uncomprehending of their guilt,
are marked down for
punitive deportation.
It is the tragedy of a small nation in
the hands of a vast and ruthless state.
They're dragged from their homes,
their lifestyle destroyed,
leaving whole areas empty
of any inhabitants.
And when German troops are
driven from the Crimea in May,
Stalin is convinced the Tartar people had
been guilty of collaboration with the enemy.
He immediately dissolves the Muslim
autonomous republic
of the Crimean Tartars,
and punitively deports 400.000
people, men, women and children.
And beyond the misery of
shocked and frightened people,
the disregard for military needs.
This is a time when the Soviet forces
need all the transport they can get.
THE GENOCIDE OF GERMANY
EAST PRUSSIA 1944
East Prussia, with
its forests and lakes,
was the first part of prewar German
territory the Red Army entered.
It is estimated that as many as 2
million German women were raped
by Red Army soldiers.
"From 1944 to 1947
what occurred to Germany,
in the last year of the war
and the immediate postwar
years was a crime so terrible;
and the world has never
experienced such a crime like this.
And the fact that it remains a secret
doesn't mean it is any less of a crime,
but it probably was the largest,
the darkest and the bloodiest, uh...
secret in world history.
The massacres, the rapes,
the starvation,
the deliberate attempt to
destroy a nation entirely. Entirely!
Now I'm not talking about
leaving something left.
Basically, that was the uh...
uh that's what they were,
the Allies were traveling under
in the last year of the war and
the immediate postwar years.
This nightmarish attempt
to destroy Germany.
A terror bombing toward
the late stages of the war.
A terror bombing:
there's no other...
There's no other phrase that says
it quite as well as "terror bombing".
Long after all military objects
had been blown to bits / splinters,
the American and British Air Forces
continued to blast German cities,
blasting the rubble to even
more rubble.
A lot of folks are still, to this very
day, their bones are still buried
underneath the rubble in Germany;
that was built over of course,
after the war.
What it was like for...
a woman?
Let us say a... let's say a 45
year old something woman,
a German who was in a village
when the Russians finally came,
when they finally burst through
and the fighting had past.
And then comes the second
echelon of Russian troops,
for the most part Asiatics and Mongolians
from the Rusk Russian eastern republics.
And the rapes began... and
what does a woman do?
How do you deal with rape?
And I'm not talking
about just one soldier
perhaps dragging you
into a room and raping you.
I'm talking about 5 maybe 10
at a time;
for days, for weeks, this goes on.
Some women, I mean again we're talking
in the words of the people themselves
They did all sorts of
things to avoid rapes.
They become almost indifferent to it...
indifferent to it after a while; almost.
Some of them lost their minds.
But some women, who were
actually good looking prior to the rapes,
actually started trying to
make themselves look uglier.
They would feign illnesses
and act like they were cripples.
And it still didn't work.
The madness for the uh...
among the Russian soldiers
for rape was incredible,
and sometimes women were raped 10,
20 times a night, a 100 times a week.
Sometimes they were raped
to death;
and then they were raped
some more.
And of course mothers with
children
were frantic to try to protect
their little ones.
They'd do anything they could.
Of course they would give their
bodies gladly;
if they could protect their children.
Mostly it didn't work though.
There was an old saying,
"from 8 to 88".
That was the time... that was
the age frame for rapes,
if you can believe that.
Even grandmothers were
taken and raped repeatedly.
Even people that were sick and women who
were on their periods; nothing was sacred.
And just very nearly extinguished
the German people altogether."
"Use force and break the racial
pride of these German women.
Take them as your lawful booty.
Kill! As you storm onward.
Kill, you gallant soldiers of
the Red Army!"
Jewish Soviet Commisar
Ilya Ehrenburg
FYODOR KHROPATIY
27th Soviet Army
What if you found one of your
fellow soldiers had raped someone?
Nobody took any notice
on the conrary, soldiers
told each other everything
it was almost considered to be
heroic or couageous
... to sleep with a women -
or several
Even if someone was murdered -
well, it was war
So it was no big deal if a soldier
slept with a women or girl.
Our valint troops continue
their march to the west
But there were those who had
been glad to see the Red Army.
First, the population of the
occupied parts of the Soviet Union,
and now the Soviet prisoners
of war.
Tatyana Naneva, who had served
in the Red Army as a nurse,
was one of more than a
million Soviet prisoners of war,
who had been transported to camps
within the greater German Reich.
She was overjoyed when
the Red Army arrived,
a feeling that was not reciprocated.
Nearly 2 million Soviet prisoners of
war were liberated by the Red Army.
All were to suffer at
the hands of Stalin.
For many, like Tatyana Naneva,
their suffering began here in a
filtration camp run by the secret police.
Their problem was that Stalin
maintained that the Soviet Union
had no prisoners of war,
only traitors.
For the crime of being captured
by the Germans,
volunteer nurse Tatyana Naneva
was sentenced to six years
in the gulag
and lifetime exile in Siberia.
To be continued
Part 15
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
On 7 July 1944, around 57.000
German prisoners
were marched through the
streets of Moscow
to be loaded onto cattle trains
and transported to the other
regions of Siberia.
After the march ended the streets
were
symbolicaly disifected of
"fashist" footsteps...
Between 1939 and 1945, around
7 million German and Axis POWs
were sent to the Soviet Gulags,
with estimated German deaths
alone over3 million.
The majority of prisoners sent here
will never see
their home and families again.
However, one German soldier
marching in Moscow
would defy all odds to see
his family again.
Sentenced to 25 years hard labour
in the mines
of the barren eastern reaches of
Siberia, he will eventually escape.
It will take him 3 years to cross
almost 9.000 miles,
enduring the most inhospitable
conditions on earth.
His name was Cornelius Rost,
but to avoid retribution from the KGB
he would be forced to use
the alias of "Clemens Forell".
His book will be translated into
15 laguages,
selling over 12 million copies
worldwide.
It was the basis for an
award-winning film in 2002.
October 1949
Christmas 1952
DECEMBER 1944
Setbacks for Germany und the Axis
coutriees accelerated during 1944,
but in December the same year,
Hitler devised a brilliant plan
which would take the Allies
completely by suprise
and almost turn the war
on its head.
Fought in the densely forested
Ardennes mountain region of Belgium,
devastating German offensive
would become known as...
THE BATTLE OF THE BULGE
In December 1944,
American forces were pummeled by German
Panzer divisions in the Ardennes forest.
It was a decisive moment in
World War Two.
Hitler would either succeed in pushing
back the approaching Allied Armies,
if he can drive the American's
and the British
all the way back to the
coast line,
he may be able to force
them into a negotiated peace?
Late in October, the Germans
begin secretly moving their units
to points East of the Ardennes,
without arousing Allied suspicions.
A quarter million Germans roll
towards the Western Front.
But officers in Allied
intelligence refuse to believe it.
They all agree the Germans don't have
the military strength for such an attack.
Early morning on December 16th,
a shattering barrage of German
artillery and rocket fire, lights the skies.
Gloomy weather for
the next several days,
provides effective cover for the German
might, that churns over the roads.
Panzer units slash through.
In the center, the Germans gouge a 12 mile
corridor to the approaches of Bastogne.
They are ordered to surround
and bypass this town,
then drive for the Meuse river.
There is all out confusion.
Communications are sketchy.
American troops discover
Germans in front and behind them.
Panzers under
cover of fog and rain,
slip into American armored columns,
then blast the Americans off the road.
More than 7.000 soldiers of the 106th
destroy their weapons and give up.
Next to Bataan, this is the largest
mass surrender in military history.
Elsewhere, with
communications shattered,
other Americans fight isolated
holding actions.
Gradually, small scattered units
slow the German advance.
Especially around St. Vith.
The 5th Panzer Army, had good success,
in the Southern part of the invasion.
However, the effects were not
what the Germans had wanted.
They were trying to race to
the Meuse river in two days.
On the third day, General
Dwight Eisenhower,
orders General Patton's third Army
to attack the German flank
and relieve Bastogne.
December 20th, the Battle
of the Bulge, is in its fifth day.
American forces are reeling under the
impact of the mighty German offensive.
General Patton and his third Army, are driving
North toward Bastogne, to counter attack.
December 21st, a wintery snow
falls throughout the Ardennes.
St. Vith is taken by the Germans.
Now the center route across
the Ardennes is wide open.
The Germans flow around Bastogne
on all sides,
encircling the American forces there.
They thought the Germans were
beaten, after the race across France.
The Germans were not beaten.
December 22nd: the situation in Bastogne,
grows desperate; ammunition is short.
McAuliffe's artillery battalions are down
to 10 rounds per gun; and it's still snowing.
The cold causes more casualties.
Frostbite is rampant
among the troops.
The Germans send an emissary
to Bastogne, with an ultimatum.
Since the Americans
are surrounded
and there is only one possibility to save
them from death: an honorable surrender.
General McAuliffe's reply
is short and to the point.
McAuliffe's bravado is based on
the expectation of the third Army.
General Patton's time table is
a critical factor.
If the German's move on Bastogne,
they could easily take it at this point.
The surrounded and
undermanned US Army watches
and waits anxiously
for reinforcements.
The freezing cold conditions
don't make it easier for either side.
The next day, December 23rd, dawns
bright and sunny; perfect flying weather.
American's in Bastogne cheer
as Allied planes fly overhead
to bomb and strafe the enemy.
To drop supplies,
not all that's needed,
but enough to enable
the American's to hang on.
On Christmas day, news reaches
Bastogne that the Western spearhead
of the German 2nd Panzer division has
been stopped, just short of the Meuse.
When Hitler is told by his Generals,
he orders the expected all out attack.
The Wehrmacht advances on Bastogne
with 9 divisions, 4 of them armored.
A great part of this effort is aimed at
closing the American corridor to the South.
On January 3rd, the Allies
launch a 3 pronged counter attack.
By January 16th, patrols from the 1st
and 3rd Armies meet North of Bastogne.
By early February, the German's have
been pushed back to where they started.
By the end of the Battle of the
Bulge, they knew they couldn't win.
And from that time on,
the remains of the Panzer
Wehr division,
are sent to the Eastern front,
where it was eventually destroyed.
It became clear the German Army no
longer could fight on the Western Front.
Due to the Soviet taking the
oilfields in the east,
lack of fuel prevented the new
German Tiger tanks
from reaching the Meuse river.
The Battle of the Bulge was the
bloodiest battle
US forces fought in World
WarTwo.
It resulted in:
19.000 dead
47.000 wounded
23.000 captured
These figures were not surpassed
those of any other battle.
With official German losses
at 84.834,
the last of the reserves were
now exhausted.
The lack of fuel would eventually leave
the Luftwaffe permanently grounded.
The remaining German forces
would be bombed incessantly
in their retreat to Berlin.
To be continued
Part 16
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
While the Western Allies were
held up in the Ardennes,
fighting the Battle of the Bulge,
on the Eastern Front, the Red
Army was making good progress.
They entered Warsaw on
the 17th of January, 1945.
The locals cheered as the Polish
units in the Red Army passed by.
They did not know that some of
the Officers they applauded
were from the Soviet Union,
and were only pretending
to be Poles.
Stalin hadn't just created
new Polish Officers,
he'd created an entire
new Polish government.
Unlike the Polish government in exile,
this group of tame Poles would
do just what Stalin told them to.
The Red Army continued to push
forward further into Eastern Europe.
Capturing Budapest, the Capital
of Hungary, in February, 1945.
Budapest
The Hungarians had been Allies
of the Nazi's.
Together with the German's they had
fought fiercely against the Red Army.
Now they would pay for it.
Report by the Direcors of the
Hungarien General Credit Bank
They opened every safe
and strong box.
They took away 113
Million Pengoe in cash.
As well as about 800 suitcases and
other containers deposited by clients.
And emptied 1.400 safety
deposit boxes.
Nearby, other Soviets took paintings and
other works of Art worth Millions of pounds.
Including works by Renoir,
El Greco, and Goya.
An estimated 99% of these
artworks have never been recovered.
As well as the wealth
of the city,
the population was also at the
mercy of the Soviet occupiers.
But what happened to them in the
aftermath of the Soviet victory in Budapest,
was to become infamous.
So bad was the situation
in Hungary,
that a group of Hungarian Communists
in Kobanya,
sent a letter of complaint
to the Soviet authorities.
In January, when the
Red Army arrived,
they committed a series of sexual
crimes in an outbreak of savage hatred.
Drunken soldiers raped mothers in
front of their children and husbands.
Girls as young as 12, were dragged
from their fathers and mothers
and raped in succession
by 10 to 15 soldiers.
From whom many of them caught
venereal diseases.
THE YALTA AGREEMENT
In February 1945,
Stalin traveled here
to Yalta, on the Black Sea, in
the South of the Soviet Union,
to attend what would become
the most famous meeting of the war.
But the pressures of the war
had clearly taken their toll
on one of the leaders
of the Alliance.
Churchill looked at Roosevelt
so very solicitously.
Churchill, I suppose,
had no surprise,
as I had, and anyone else who
had seen Roosevelt previously,
to see this corked very thin figure.
His face was waxened, to sort of yellow
and waxened, and very drawn, very thin.
And a lot of the time
he was sort of sitting
sitting there with his mouth
open, sort of staring ahead.
So that was quite a shock
to see him in that state.
The Allies also decided on the formation
of the United Nations after the war.
The news reel coverage
was decidedly optimistic.
This meeting crystallizes the
alive resolve
that Germany shall be beaten
unconditionally,
and that lasting peace shall
prevail throughout the world.
The optimism didn't last long.
Here in Poland, on
the 28th of March, 1945,
just a few weeks after signing
the Yalta Agreement,
the Soviets showed how sincere they
really were
about Polish political independence.
Sixteen leading independent political
and military figures in Poland,
arrived for what they had been told was
to be a lunch, with senior Soviet officials.
We will be meeting for lunch.
It's not far away, nine
kilometers from here.
It's more comfortable then these
primitive conditions.
They weren't just going on a short journey,
and they weren't just going for lunch.
In fact they were all transported
over 700 miles to here,
the Butyrka prison in Moscow.
The Polish leaders had made
a big mistake.
They'd trusted the
Soviet authorities.
Each of them was imprisoned
and interrogated.
And then they waited to see the
final fate Stalin had in store for them.
Roosevelt was more relaxed
about the whole dispute with Stalin.
Just before Yalta, he'd even remarked that
apart from matters concerning Germany,
he wanted to stay out disputes
in Europe, as far as possible.
He wrote to Churchill
in early April, that...
"I would minimize the general Soviet problem
as much as possible, because these problems,
in one form or another,
seem to arise every day,
and most of them straighten out."
Roosevelt was still keen
to get on with Stalin.
Partly because the Soviet leader
had offered to help with what
was happening here,
in the far East, in the
war against Japan.
American's made up the
bulk of the Allied forces
who were engaged in the Pacific in
what was known as "Island Hopping",
the struggle to wrest each
island from the Japanese.
It was a brutal and bloody war.
Just 8 days after
the Yalta Agreement,
the Americans had launched
one of their fiercest assaults here,
on the Island of Iwo Jima,
750 miles South of Tokyo.
Just after 9 o'clock in the morning,
on the 19th of February, 1945,
the first wave of US
Marines landed on the island.
But the battle for this piece of volcanic rock,
less than 8 miles square, would be horrific
for both sides.
Of the 21.000 Japanese defenders,
20.000 would die in the struggle.
The total American causalities on Iwo Jima,
including wounded, were over 25.000,
more than the Allies suffered
on D-day.
"The injured are
carried to the rear."
So Roosevelt was intensely grateful
that Stalin had promised the Soviet
Union would help the Western Allies,
and lend to the war against
Japan, once Germany was defeated.
"The wreckage along the beach was only a
small part of the cost of 26 days of fighting."
As for the 16 independent Poles tricked
into meeting the Soviet authorities
by an offer of lunch,
they were all put on trial.
The court investigation exposed
the full extent of the criminal
activities of the Polish separatist.
They were acting on the orders
of the Polish government-in-exile
in London.
as enemies of democracy, of peace
and of the Polish nation.
Of the 16, 13 were sentenced
to various terms in Soviet prisons.
The US will now change their
strategy
of bombing German industrial
and military targets.
Insteed, the Americans will join
the British in the bombing of civilians.
THE DESTRUCTION OF BERLIN
Reversing years of
American strategic policy,
would be a massive
air assault on Berlin.
Over 6 months,
the head of Bomber Command, sent his
planes on 19 mass attacks on the Nazi capital.
As many as 800 bombers
on a single mission.
Nearly 11.000 bombing sorties.
This attack on Berlin would have
significance far beyond causality numbers.
With this raid, the 8th Air
Force crosses a moral threshold.
And that moral threshold is, we
will not deliberately bomb civilians.
Usually the moral divide
for historians
is the Tokyo raid, which took place
the next month,
where we incinerate the city
and kill almost 100.000 people.
And, but I think,
once we crossed the moral
divide in Berlin, it made everything else,
including the Atomic Bomb,
a little bit easier.
The world must understand that
this state will never surrender
... the German Reich may
encounter setbacks...
... but never will it stray
from its chosen path
The German leadership shares
the hardship endured by its people...
... but never will it surrender
in the face of hardship
By spring 1945, the situation had
become all but hopeless for the Germans.
The Red Army had reached
the river Oder,
the last great natural obstacle
before Berlin.
12 April 1945, US President Franklin
D. Roosevelt dies from a brain hemorrhage.
ROOSEVELT IS DEAD!
Crowds are lining Constitution
Avenue, from here to the White House.
All the soldiers and service men in
the crowd, stand firmly at attention.
And now the caisson will start its solemn
sorrowful procession through Washington.
His Vice-President Henry A. Wallace,
a known Communist,
had been quickly and quietly
removed from office
once it was known Roosevelt's
condition was terminal.
He is replaced by Harry S. Truman.
28 April 1945, Guilino di Mezzegra,
Italy
Italian Communist partisans, capure
Mussolini and his lover Clara Pettacci
along with several of their
comrades in Northern Italy.
After a sweeping trial
they were quickly executed.
However, recent forensic medicine
findings,
supported by modern digital tehology,
contradict the official version
of Mussolini's death.
Photographs and films shot in
April 1945 in Piazzale Loreto
and examinated at the Institut of
Forensic Medicine, Milan
conducted that the dictator was
undressed prior to being killed.
It has long been suspected that
during their 24 hours of captivity
Mussolini was tortured
and that Clara Pettacci was raped
several times.
Their bodies will be brought
to Milan the next day
where before being hanged
upside down
in a heinous public display,
a baying crowd will stamp,
spit and urinate on them.
Adolf Hitler will hear of Musolini's death
whilst in his Berlin bunker.
By his side is the ever faitful
Eva Braun.
He has been there since
16 January 1945,
surronded by his High Command.
To be contiued
Part 17
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
The sky is literally falling in
on the people of Germany.
Massive fleets of British and
American heavy bombers,
pound cities to rubble;
Germany is surrounded.
From every frontier enemies are
marching on the heart of the Fatherland.
They are twice as many men
as the Wehrmacht,
four times as many tanks.
Hitler knows he is surrounded.
Old men, women and children
prepare for a desperate fight
against hopeless odds.
Yet, at the same time,
a people who remain astonishingly
loyal in the face of certain defeat.
Boys of the Hitler youth
ready themselves for battle.
Ordinary people still
cheer Hitler's armies.
These troops are all that stand
between Germany and Armageddon.
Stalin claims he has 6 Million men,
against less than a million
armed remnants of every unit
the Reich can muster.
On the 19th of April, Soviet
troops reach the Berlin suburbs.
Now it is street fighting,
house by house.
Everyone a natural redoubt
for desperate defenders.
Casualties mount.
Resistance stiffens, but the Soviet
Armies cannot be halted now.
Hitler's Reich has been pierced
to the heart.
On the 25th of April,
southern units of Konev's front
make contact with the United
States forces at the Elbe.
No hint of future
tensions here.
Now as Soviet forces converge
on the center of Berlin,
the fighting embraces everything
and everyone in the battle field.
Adolf Hitler Square
But even now, Hitler
has one guardian angel.
HANNA REITSCH
Fighter Pilot Hanna Reitsch.
The only woman to receive an Iron
Cross in the Second World War,
she is utterly devoted to the Führer.
On the 29th of April, she pilots her
light aircraft into the heart of Berlin.
Touching down on the
Unter den Linden,
she makes the perilous journey through
the mayhem of battle, to Hitler's bunker,
where he waits the end;
accompanied by a few
treasured possessions.
Hanna Reitsch is Hitler's last chance
to escape, but he will not leave.
He chooses to meet
his destiny in Berlin.
REICHSKANZLEIBUNKER, BERLIN
His grand chancellery
now severely damaged,
he admitted for the
first time that all was lost.
He then stepped into the passage where
Eva and the secretaries were waiting.
"All of a sudden the door
was opened, Hitler came out.
He said everything is lost.
Pack your things and go,
you have to leave, and within an hour
the last plane will bring you out.
After a moment of silence, Eva
Braun stepped forward, went to him,
took his hand and said,
"but you know I stay with you".
He smiled, I mean he tried to
smile, and he kissed her on the lips.
At this moment we all said,
"we're staying too".
She came towards me, embraced me,
and said,
"try to go home, try to get out
of here.
And if you are successful, if
you come to Bavaria back
give my regards to everybody."
And she was very sad and I think she
tried to be very brave in this moment.
He knew what happened to
Mussolini, he saw the pictures.
And he was very very frightened
to have the same fate,
if he would be captured."
The last known phoograph of
Adolf Hitler
Excerpt from Adolf Hitler's
LAST WILL AND TESTAMENT
After 6 years of struggle, which in spite
of all reversals will go down in history
as the most glorious and most courageous
manifestation of a people's will to live.
I cannot separate myself from
the city,
which is the capital of this Reich.
Because our forces are too few
to permit any further resistance
against the enemies assaults,
I desire to share the fate
that millions of others have taken
upon themselves.
Except I shall remain in this city.
Furthermore, I do not want to fall
into the hands of enemies
who for the delectation of
the hate-riddled masses
require a new spectacle promoted
by the Jews.
I have therefore resolved
to remain in Berlin
and there to choose death
of my own will
at the very moment when,
as I believe,
the seat of the Führer / Chancellor
can no longer be defended.
I die with a joyful heart
in the awareness the immeasurable
deeds and achievements
of our soldiers at the front,
of our women at home, the
achievements of our workers,
of the contribution, unique in history,
of our youth, which bears my name.
It goes without saying,
that I thank them all from
the bottom of my heart.
Defiant to the end, Hitler denounced
Field Marshal Hermann Göring
and SS chief Heinrich Himmler
as traitors for attempting to negotiate
with the Allies without his
knowledge.
Stripping them of their positions,
he hands over
the leadership of the Third Reich
to navy commander Karl Dönitz.
The Final Days
On April the 29th, Hitler decided
to marry his mistress Eva Braun.
After the bridal couple had confirmed
they were of true Aryan decent,
the ceremony was concluded with
Goebbels and Bormann as the witnesses.
Hitler signed the wedding certificate,
but when it came to Eva's turn,
she began to write her
surname as "Braun"
before crossing out the letter
"B", and writing Eva Hitler.
Arm in arm, Adolf Hitler led his bride
to the study for the wedding reception.
Traudl Junge:
"As a gesture of gratitude for her
love, for her royalty, for her fidelity,
and I think he wanted to
compensate her for
to get the figure of history
as his wife."
30 APRIL 1945, BERLIN
Less than 2 days after the
wedding on April the 30th,
Hitler and his bride
retired to his study. Traudl Junge:
"And there he stood, very quite,
very tired, and then he turned and I,
I felt somehow's like
frozen, because I knew now
that this decisive moment where we
were going to see soon he'd end his life."
They sat on the couch.
Opposite them was a portrait
of Hitler's mother.
Eva now took a cyanide capsule
and popped it into her mouth.
She died instantly.
Then Hitler picked up his gun,
put it to his right temple,
and fired.
Acting in accordance with Hitler's
instructions,
members of his staff wrapped both
the bodies in blankets,
and carried them up to
the surface.
During a pause in
the Russian shelling,
they doused the bodies with what
petrol they had managed to collect,
and set them alight.
The strugle between the people
and hatred between them...
... is being nurtured by very
specific interested parties.
It is a small rootless international
clique
that is turning people against
each other...
... that does not want them
to have peace!
It is a people who are at home
nowhere and everywhere!
Who do not have anywhere a soil
on which they have grown up...
... but who live in Berlin today...
... Brussels tomorrow, Paris the day after,
then Prag, Viena or London...
... and who feel at home everywhere!
They are the ones who can really
be regarded as international elements...
... because they conduct their
business everywhere!
"At the very end of his life,
to be sure, his back had become bent,
but his mind remained as clear
as a flash of lightning.
When has history ever vitnessed
so enormous
a tragedy brought to its end
with such iron self-control?
General Léon Degrelle
To be continued
Part 18
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
In 73 A.D. a huge Roman army lay
siege to 1000 rebel Jews
and their families,
in the mountain hideaway
of Masada.
On the eve of the batlle, and fearing
the rape of their women
an enslavement of their children,
the men to avoid surrender
drew straws to decide
which of them would kill
their loves ones.
Once the killigs were completed
the men commited suicide,
leaving the Romans to find not
a single survivor the following day.
Today in Israel, they are remembered
as heroic martyrs.
CENTRAL BERLIN 1945
April 1945 inside the Reichskanzleibunker,
Joseph Goebbels loyal to the end,
is fully aware that the Bolsheviks
are raining death
and destruction on the
population outside.
With him is his wife Magda
and their six children.
And although they are safe
for now,
with the Soviets just hundreds
of yards away,
he knows that time is
running out.
They too, will choose death for
themselves and their six children
rather than risk escaping
brutality of the Commuists.
Under such circumstances, Magda
cannot trust anyone else
with the responsibility of
her children's lives.
Now she must steel herself
for what must be every mother's
worst nightmare.
Not once but six times over.
On 1 May 1945, Joseph and Magda
Goebbels will commit suicide.
The history books will not
treat them as kindly,
nor view them as herically,
as the Masada martyrs.
Magda especially, will be portrayed
by the media
and in future Hollywood movies
as a sinister perpetrator
of evil.
"A mothers love for her child
is like nothing else in the world.
It knows no law, it knows no pity.
It dares all things
and crushes down remorselessly
all that stands in its path."
GERMANY IS DEFEATED
On 7 May 1945, Germany officially
surrenders.
Fighting continues in the Balkans
where German soldiers and Croat fighers,
many with their families, continue
their battle
against pursuing Communist partisans
in a strugge to reach the Austrian border
and surrender to the Western
Allies.
Berlin has Fallen.
Marshall Stalin has just announced
the complete capture of
the capital of Germany.
There are some reports that
Hitler died;
result of a stroke suffered
several days ago.
There are other reports that
Hitler was not in Berlin at all.
That he's been hiding out,
and that he may still be alive.
That the German story of his death is
only a rouse to permit him to escape.
Many today believe that Hitler
escaped
THE AUSTRIAN BORDER 1945
THE BLEIBURG MASSACRE
If people are told the truth,
about where they're going,
Capt. Nigel Nicolson - British 8th Army
and they refuse to go,
because they will be killed,
the only way to get them
onto the trains,
is to lie to them about their
destination.
And of course if they'd learned
the truth,
that they were going back to Yugoslavia
where they didn't expect to survive,
none of them would have
consented to mount the railway tracks.
Now, I remember asking for...
advice from the division.
Are we to send the civilians
as well?
And the answer came back...
Yes.
WAR CRIME
There were women and children,
and old men, and sometimes babies,
who were in these convoys,
which we organized.
But did you hear the machine guns?
- Yes.
Capt. Colin Gunner - British 8th Army
On the Yugoslav side of the border?
Oh for Christ sake!
Do you think I like to talk about
fucking kids being shot down?!
At Yalta, Churchill, Roosevelt
and Stalin had agreed
to forced repatriation of
enemy POWs and refugees.
Although the US signed international
agreemets opposing forced repatriation,
they inserted fine print
expecting from the ban
all those who originated from nations
given over to the Soviets
at the end of the war.
While claiming to "make the world safe
for Democracy", Roosevelt and Churchill
condemned millions to slave
labour camps and certain death.
The Allies even kept secret from
the world fact
that Stalin was holding over
5.000 Allied soldiers as hostages
to ensure that the West complied
with his demands for repatriation.
"And then for the next 5 days,
we organized trainloads of Croats
to go to Yugoslavia.
But ah, as they trusted us, when
we were telling them the truth,
there wasn't much trouble
about loading them on."
OPERATION KEELHAUL
Whilst searching through US
military archives
for the Cogressional investigation of
the State Department cover-up
of Soviet involvement in the
Katyn Forest massacre,
researcher Julius Epstein discovered
evidence
of a top secret program of forced
repatriation known as
Operation Keelhaul.
US and British troops had to beat,
drug and drive at gunpoint
millions of civilians back
to the Communists.
In spite of this, Stalin never did
release the American and British POWs.
It is suspected they perished
in the Gulags, as the US still
refuses to open the archives
revealing their fate.
THE ALLIES MISTREATMENT OF
GERMAN PRISONERS
Unlike the Soviets, the Allies
had signed on
to the Geneva Convention of 1929.
But by reclassifaing the German
POWs as "disarmed enemy forces",
they had now found a way
of cicumventing the rules.
The British, French and Americans
will now block any attempt
by the International Red Cross
from checking that the prisoners
are treated according to
international law
in Allied camps across Germany.
Eisenhower's mistreatment of prisoners
in the Rhine Meadow concentration camps,
where they held under appalling
conditions,
have only recently come to
light.
It is now estimated that at
least 1.5 million soldiers
and civilian POWs died whilst
in Allied captivity.
"This is Deanna Spingola.
Today I'm going to share some
details about World War 2,
that many of you might
not have heard before.
I base this information on the hundreds
of hours of research that I have done.
Eisenhower's Death Camps.
In a letter to his wife Eisenhower
said,
and this is the quote,
"God I hate the Germans!
Why? Because the
German is a beast", unquote.
He suggested a new class of
prisoner, Disarmed Enemy Forces,
prisoners the army would not feed.
Get that? They would not feed!
after Germany's surrender.
Food, water and shelter,
basic human necessities,
were unavailable in the camps;
per Eisenhower's orders!
Excuse me.
On April 22nd, 1945,
the US had in Europe,
50 days worth of 4.000 calorie
rations to feed 5 million people
for an additional 50 days!
They had the food,
they just chose not to give it!
On April 26th, 1945, the combined
Chiefs Of Staff in Washington,
cabled Eisenhower their approval of
the Disarmed Enemy Forces status,
for ALL German citizens!
Everybody was considered an enemy!
By April 30th 1945, there was
an additional 2.062,865
of these CIVILIAN prisoners.
Author Giles Macdonogh wrote,
that at least 1.5 million Germans
died in those camps due to
their ill-treatment and starvation.
In contrast in 1945 the American Red
Cross said that "99% of the US POWs
held in German camps had survived
and were soon returning home."
I was a US Army Guard at a
German Prison Camp in Andernach.
And I was uh silent
for 45 years because uh
I was warned
it would be futile
to say anything,
and that I would be in
serious trouble if I did.
To be continued
Part 19
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
LONDON, ENGLAND
8 MAY 1945
Victory in Europe.
V- E Day.
We may allow ourselves
a brief period of rejoice.
But let us not forget for
a moment
the toils and efforts that
lie ahead.
Japan with all her treachery
and greed remains unsubdued.
In Asia and the Pacific
the war still raged.
HIROSHIMA, JAPAN
6 AUGUST 1945
BERLIN, GERMANY
In the wake of its unconditional
surrender on the 7th of May, 1945,
Germany lay vanquished.
Millions had died.
Those that survived had
suffered terribly during the conflict,
both in combat and
on the home front.
Intensive Allied bombing raids
and the ground battle for Germany,
had forced millions of Germans
from their homes.
On the 5th of June, 1945,
the Allies announced they would govern
Germany through 4 occupation zones.
One for each of the 4 powers.
The Soviet Union, Britain, the
United States, and France.
Following the war, hundreds of
thousands of former soldiers,
Nazi party members,
were held in POW camps.
Thousands of officers and members
of the Nazi party remained imprisoned.
Their fate a trial
for war crimes.
THE ALLIED LIBERATION OF
POW CAMPS
BUCHENWALD, GERMANY
The US army forced the local population
to file through the camp
to view the horrors they had
ecountered upon arrival.
The sight and stench of thousands of
emaciated and naked corpes
will also be experienced by the
British at the Bergen-Belsen camp
and others across Europe.
Only months before, the Bolsheviks had
claimed they had discovered
homicidal gas chambers i camps
across eatern Europe.
This, as the Germans are purposely
led around camps shocked,
dazed and bewildered, will mark
the beginning
of what will become known as
de-Nazifiction.
The Americans claim they have
even more evidence of atrocities.
A lampshade made from human
skin, two shrunken Polish prisoer's heads
and pieces of tattooed skin
are displayed
for an already sickening crowd.
There will soon be sories of humans
used for soap,
and even more homocidal gas
chambers discovered,
this time in the camps
iberated by the Allies.
THE DACHAU MASSACRES
Within the first hour of the
liberaion
of the Dachau POW camp
Northwest of Munich,
122 SS guards are shot after
surrendering to the US 45th Division.
Another 40 SS are beaten to
death by inmates.
A further 358 SS men will be
rounded up
and herded into an encosed
coal yard.
Initially, 12 are machine-gunned.
The rest are executed shoortly
thereafter.
In total, 560 SS men who had
surrendered
were murdered during the
liberation of Dachau.
The only punishment for the
US soldiers involved in the executions
was the threat of a court-martial.
Despit claims from prisoners
and the US soldiers who liberated them,
a sign at Dachau will later
begrudgingly read...
No gassing ever took place.
THE NUREMBERG TRIAL
Admiral Karl Dönitz and the NSDAP
leaders are arrested
and placed on trial for alleged
war crimes.
It is an event unprecendendted
in history.
For the first time ever, members
of a government defeated in war
will now stand trial for
their lives.
In the court room will be four
judges, one each from the
US, Britain, France and the
Soviet Union.
Admiral Karl Dönitz
The wer crimes of Stalin are
covered up,
and will only come to light
when the Soviet Union colapses
over half a century later.
Roosevelt and Churchill deliberate
bombing of German civilians
in Dresden, Hamburg and Berlin
are never recognised as war crimes.
You can light a
fag on any of those.
Bombs doors open.
Bombs away.
There goes the cookie.
There go the incendiaries.
The Allies will use hanging as
a method of execution, a practice
usually associated with a common
criminal or murderer
and not a military tribunal.
Head of the SS Heinrich Himmler
will escape the hangman
by swallowing cyanide after
his arrest.
A capsule is also discovered
on Herman Göring.
He will stand trial however,
and his commanding presence
will dominate the proceedings.
What struck you when you
first met him, was his bearing.
He was a commanding
personality; you were impressed.
You knew that somebody
important was there.
Whenever the prisoners
where in their cells
H. Göering
they were constantly under
observation; every minute of it.
As expected, the majority of verdicts
are announced as guilty,
and the leading National Socialist
receive either the death penalty
or long prison sentences.
After being accused a request for
a "soldier's death" by firing squad,
Hermann Göering hours away from
his execution,
will also cheat the hangman.
To this day, it is a mistery
how he was able
to obtain the required cyanide.
The ethnic cleansig of National Socialist
will now commence with a witch-hunt
against German military leaders,
political officials, industrialist and financiers.
Many of the hangings go
so horribly wrong,
with some deaths taking
between 20-30 minutes,
that the British Army will request
the services
of Britain's top criminal hangman
Albert Pierrepoint.
Pierrepiont, good
to see you again.
We've had the gallows constructed
to home office specifications,
as you've requested.
And here's the list of tomorrow's
condemned prisoners.
13 in one day.
No Sir. I'm not
with you Sir.
I thought we had a
week to do this job?
Well yes, but there are
different batches each day.
Well, how many
others are there, Sir?
47 in total.
47?
That's just this week.
I'm afraid you'll find
them coming thicker fast,
now that the courts have
delivered their verdicts.
Jolly good.
196 pounds.
Irma Grese.
Keiner unterhaltung.
Uh... 5' 3"
You do the Jews work for them.
Stehen bleiben.
113 pounds
That's the last of them.
Time for a break?
No, we don't want to fall behind.
To be continued
Part 20
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
CONFESSION BY TORTURE
Recently released documents disprove
decades of denial, and show
that the Germans suffered horribly
whilst in British captivity.
Thousands of Germans passed through
the unit known as the London Cage,
run by Lieutenant Colonel
Aexander Scotland.
The London Cage was just one
of a series of nine cages in Britain
where the torture of Germans
took place.
At Nuremberg in 1946, the Allie's
"star witness" was Rudof Höss,
former commandant at Auschwitz,
who they claimed had confessed
to exterminaing over
3 million Jews.
Film of emaciated bodies used as
evidence of German atrocities
is intentionally misleading.
The Allies know that most of
the inmates perished from typhus...
Zyklon B dropped into the death
chamber from a small opening.
It took from 3 to 15 minutes.
15 DE ABRIL DE 1946
We knew when the people were
dead because their screaming stopped.
After the bodies were removed our
special commandos took off the rings
and extracted the gold
from the teeth of the corpses.
Jesus
Children of tender years
were invariably exterminated
since by reason of their
youth they were unable to work.
Is that all true and correct
witness?
Yes.
It was the British who obtained
by torture
the confession of Rudolf Hoess,
Commandant of Auschwitz, before
turning him over to Soviets and Poles.
This has been confirmed in a book
published in 1983
titled "Legions of Death",
which contains the recollections
of British sergeant Bernard Clark,
who brags about having tortured
Hoess,
to get a confession out of him,
and of threatening his family.
It was here that Hoess was hanged.
Auschwitz
Modern science will ultimately
determine the horrific claims
from Buchenwald and Bergen-Belson
to be Allied propaganda.
To this day, many believe them
to be true.
DNA testing proves that the
Dachau lampshade are goatskin.
And the two shrunken heads?
They conveniently disappeared
before they could be tested.
And though other stories -
such as articles made from
"human tattooed skin" -
are equally false,
they remain embedded in
Holocaust mythology.
Only in Eastern Europian camps,
where no invesigation ever occured
or where alowed, is it
still claimed
that millions of Jews entered
the gas chambers.
Perhaps the most dubios piece
of evidence at Nuremberg
was the story of
"human made into soap".
Deborah Lipstadt, a cosultant for
the Hoocaust Memorial museum,
eventually wrote an article confirming
that this was also fabricaion.
Nazi Soap Rumor During
World War Two
... The fact is that the Nazis never
used the bodies of Jews,
or for that matter anyone else,
for the production of soap.
The soap rumor was prevalent both
during and after the war.
It may have...
I rather wished that the Führer
hadn't stood by his followers,
and taken the responsibility
for his command.
Think of his position.
Oh sure. His position as
Chief war criminal, right?
He was our sovereign.
It would be intolerable for me to
have him standing before a foreign court.
You men knew the Führer.
He would be the first
one to stand up and say,
"I gave the orders and I
shall take full responsibility!"
And I would rather
die 10 deaths
than have the sovereign
subjected to such humiliation.
GERMAN WAR REPARATION
Germany finally cleared its
World War One dept in Ocober 2010.
It amounted to a total of
£22 billion.
Germany, in 2013, still paying reparation
for World War Two.
The once-proud nation even has
pending court cases
at the United Nations for further
reparations concerning Italy and Greece.
Guilty verdics by the court will
most likely open
the floodgates for other countries
to follow suit.
Jews who survived the conceration
camp are known as Holocaust survivors.
However, other Jews can also
qualify.
According to AMCHA in Israel,
a Holocaust survivor is any Jew who...
in 1933... resided anywhere under...
A Nazi regime
Nazi occupation
The regime of Nazi collaborators
This qualifies any Jew who left
Europe in 1933 for America or elsewhere
and lived in comfort and safety
whilst the war raget on.
In 2013, Germany will provide compension
payments to a new category of vicims:
some 80.000 Jews who fled the German
Army and who eventually resettled
in former Soviet Union.
They are eligible for a one-of
payment of $ 3.253
along whit a monthy Holocaust
pension.
Despite the seizure by the Allies
of millions of documents
at the end of the war
not one single document showing
Adolf Hitler ordered
systematic exterminatios of the Jews
has ever been found.
With no photographs, video footage
or even a single report
of a gassed victim,
we have had to trust the Soviets
at testimonies of former inmates,
none of whom were cross-examinated
at Nuremberg.
However, some inmates tell a
conflicting story
of their treatment in the Eastern
concentration camps.
We also had an orchestra where
some of the musicians stands us together
and one musician was so good
that he had the instruments
playing and he wrote the notes,
and later on we had a band
show who played over the weekend.
And that was of course helping us,
you know we also did plays and stuff.
Were there any cultural
activities happening in Auschwitz?
Yes. I told you we
had a piano, put into,
not just a piano, a grand
piano, was brought into block one.
Once that was built, that new block,
the downstairs room was assigned
for theater.
They said they're going
to build a movie in the camp.
The prisoners sat down and
, "you must be crazy,
you cannot make a movie
for us in the camp?"
But really it happened.
They made a movie in the camp.
Yeah, and we...
we went in barracks
after work we... we could
go to see a movie sometimes,
they brought movies in see.
...in the evenings, and...
What kind of movies
would they show?
German movies.
Once I came to
the main camp,
we were allowed twice
a month to write home.
Once a postcard and once a letter.
They gave you the materials?
Yeah, they gave us the letter
and the materials... the cost.
You had money?
Yeah, we got my ways??...still
got my w??...money we got through the
Jewish community from
they know who send us...
everybody some money.
And in the camp you could
have currency?
Yeah, we could have money,
because there was in camp loads
of what they called a "Cantina",
and not many times, but once in
a while they sold a few cigarettes,
or they sold something...
whatever they had.
So if you had money you
could buy, at the Cantina there.
Redeemable in... in that
Cantina if they had something.
So, that was their... their
way of distributing money.
To everybody, everyone got
this money.
Soccer teams...
were organized very well.
the event is held in the former
barrack's courtyard
And one of these uh
enlisted, top enlisted SS men,
decided he wants to play
for the Polish team.
So... we say okay,
you can play.
And then the Commandant...
Commandant... SS Commandant,
he was uh like...
like a Captain,
he decided he wanted to
play for the German team.
So he went in the field. But that's
happened, so... but it was 1944, see?
Is what you're saying then that um...
the closer the end
of the war came, uh...
pressure was let up rather than ah...
- Definitely.
becoming more cruel or...?
Freddie Hirsch called me...
to the children's barracks,
he was heading then,
and uh... he asked me if I could paint
something on the wall for the children?
And I said, "well, if you
can get the materials?"
He said,
"I'll get the materials."
And I said, "Okay".
And then a very handsome
young blonde man
from the man's camp
came over one day,
and Freddie Hirsch called
me to come and meet him.
And he asked me what I need?
So, I said, "well, if I
can get any wall paints,
so I mean tempera paints,
I would like those,
if you get me some?"
And he said, "Yes, anything you want."
So I made a painting of Dopey
standing on another dwarfs head,
with a cloak around him
so he looked like a tall guy.
So he would be as tall
as Snow White.
Theresienstadt Concentration Camp
I now understand that
there was another painter,
who continued something
painting on the walls after I'd left.
What did it do,
not only for... for you,
but for the...
for the children?
On, on an emotional level?
Well it did several things,
not just emotional,
but the children then wrote a play,
which was a satire of Snow
White and the Seven Dwarfs.
The play was very successful.
Because the little girl,
who was playing Snow White,
had an incredible voice.
A gorgeous soprano,
just like the one that you
hear in the movie.
Apart from ameniutes we know
of that included...
An orchesra, movies, camp money,
canteen, postcards, letters,
theater, musical plays and a
football team...
Facilities at the Auschwitz "death
camp" also featured...
A hospial, a library and an
Olimpic size swimming pool
complete with several diving
boards.
... AND COMPARED TO STALIN'S GULAGS?
STALIN'S GULAGS
Look down, look down,
you'll always be a slave
You're standing in your grave
Look down, look down,
you'll always be a slave
You're standing in your grave
To be continued
Part 21
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
In1992, a brilliant young Jewish
revisionist named David Cole,
made a groundbreaking documentary
about the Holocaust.
This is an edited version of
his work.
The complete documentary "Cole in
Auschwitz" can be viewed on the internet.
I know from years of my own
research and the research of others
that proofs of the Holocaust
are few.
Literally, all there is
are the "eyewitness" testimonies
and postwar confessions.
There's no picture, plan
or wartime document
dealing with homicidal gas
chambers,
or a plan to exterminate
the Jews.
And we can't use the excuse that
the Nazis destroyed all the evidence
because after we had
broken the German code,
we were able to intercept
their secret transmissions
including those that came
from Auschwitz.
The key to understanding
the Holocaust story
is understanding the true nature
of the things
passed off as "proofs".
Everything that is used as
evidence of the Holocaust
also can be said to have a
perfectly normal explanation.
For example,
these exhibits are said to be
the material "proofs" of exterminations.
There's the piles of human hair.
But what does that prove?
It's acknowledged that each inmate
had his or her head shaved
because of the lice problem.
That's not denied,
so why wouldn't there be
piles of human hair?
What about the piles of shoes
and clothing; is that a proof?
It's a fact that the prisoners
were issued a uniform upon arrival,
including shoes.
So why wouldn't there be piles
of inmates' shoes and clothing?
It doesn't prove anybody
was killed.
What about the canisters
of gas?
No one denies that Zyklon B was used
to disinfect clothes and also buildings.
Zyklon B was one of the premier pest
control agents in Europe at that time.
It was present in most of the
concentration camps including those
that are not said to have had
homicidal gas chambers in them.
The typhus epidemic that spread
throughout Europe during the war
and also spread through the camps
called for stringent lice control
procedures.
So what other proofs are offered?
Well, there's the usual
pictures of sick inmates
which proves the ground-breaking
thesis that people got sick in the camp.
Once again I'll add that nobody
denies the typhus epidemic
which resulted in many deaths.
Then there's the artwork
and the pictures of children.
But at this point it's looking pretty bad
for somebody looking for objective proofs
of the gas chamber.
And some of the proofs they present
actually work against the concept.
For example, they have one
of several aerial photographs
taken at Auschwitz by
the Allies during the war.
They don't mention, however,
that when blown up,
these photos don't show people
being gassed or bodies being burned,
even though they were taken during the
time killings were said to be going on
almost non-stop.
Once inside, we can see why revisionists
have had such a field day with this building:
Obvious marks on the walls
and floors,
where apparently walls had been
knocked down.
Equally obvious holes in the floor
where bathroom facilities had been.
We maintain that,
unlike the large hollow chamber
we now see,
this room had once been 5
rooms including a bathroom.
Yet the building does have what appears
to be evidence of criminal usage;
4 holes in the ceiling,
which lead to the roof where
4 little chimneys stand.
It is said that through these 4 holes,
Zyklon B crystals were dropped.
And indeed, there seems to be
no other explanation for them.
Do these holes prove
homicidal gassings?
Revisionists have claimed in the past
that these holes were added
after the camp's liberation,
and that the inside walls were knocked
down and the bathroom facilities removed
to make the room look
like a big gas chamber.
Let's start again talking about
this building here. Um this...
This is a crematorium
/ gas chamber.
But this is a reconstruction?
It is in original state.
- Original? -Original state.
It is an original part. Original.
Oh, it is original?
Original, in through this
chimney was thrown Zyklon B.
Later, a senior official would confirm
that the holes in the roof
had been built after
the war.
Are those the original
holes in the ceiling?
No.
They've been rebuilt?
- Yes.
Okay. After the war?
- After the war, yes.
Dr. Franciszek Piper, the senior curator
and director or of archives
at the Auschwitz State Museum,
admitted on camera to David Cole
that "Krema 1", the alleged
"homocidal gas chamber" at the
Auschwitz main camp was,
in fact, fabricated after the war
by the Soviet Union,
under direct orders of Stalin.
This includes the fake chimney, that
is not even connected with crematorium.
This is Auschwitz-Birkenau in an Allied
aerial photo from September 1944.
The train that would come up,
carrying the doomed inmates,
you would have thousands of
inmates being marched off the trains
into one of these two gas chambers
in full view of the entire camp.
This was a spectacle that nobody
in the camp could miss;
they would see thousands
of people
marching into those buildings
and nobody coming out.
These were "gas chambers" that
were not isolated from anyone
and indeed, when these aerial photo-
graphs were released in the late 70's,
they contradicted many
supposed eyewitness claims
about how the Nazis had tried to
camouflage the gas chambers at Birkenau.
Another question that should
be asked:
Is there any Zyklon B
residue in the gas chamber,
knowing that cyanide gas would,
in fact, leave a residue?
conducted forensic examinations
on the gas chambers at Auschwitz
to answer that question.
He took samples from the
4 gas chambers at Birkenau,
the one at the main camp
and the control sample
from one of the disinfestation chambers
that we know did use Zyklon B.
Now, the gas chamber samples
showed almost no appreciable traces
whereas the dis-infestation sample
literally went right off the scale.
In 1990, the Institute of
Forensic Research in Krakow
decided to conduct
their own forensic tests
to see if they could refute
Fred Leuchter's findings,
and their own tests got
back the same results.
In Canada in 1988, Ernst Zündel
faced charges
for Holocaust denial in
a second trial.
He hired American Frederick A.
Leuchter,
a court-certified expert
in gas execution technology.
After secrely conducing scientific
experiments
in camps such as Auschwitz
in Poland,
on his return he pubished his
findings in the "Leucher Report".
I told Mr. Zundel and his
defense team prior to my going,
that if I did in fact find facilities
that could have supported executions,
not only whether they did,
did support the executions,
but only whether or not they could
have sustained gas executions,
I would make that
very clear in my report.
And that is what I would testify
to, when I testified in court.
What aside from the samples
convinced you
that these facilities could not
have been used
then or now as execution facilities?
You must have gasketed
doors, no windows.
Means of getting the gas in,
means of getting the gas out.
If those persons operating the
facilities didn't gas themselves to death
at the same time that
the executies died,
they certainly would have
been blown to bits,
when the gas exploded from a
switch, the heat of a light bulb,
or the gas approaching and
getting in to the crematory furnace.
We're talking about brick and
mortar buildings, without heat,
with non explosion proof
lighting, without gasketed doors.
In some cases without doors
at all.
And with crematories that opened
very close or adjacent to the facility.
I mean it's just
ludicrous to consider
that these facilities could have
been used as gas chambers.
There's no such a thing
as an "eye witness".
I have never seen a report that
was written,
by anyone, who had a valid description
of what could of happened
at a gassing.
So, the long and the short of it
is, there are no eye witnesses,
because there were no gassings.
I think it's necessary to put
this matter
in its proper historical perspective.
You see, we live in a time now
when the old Soviet Union
has fallen apart
and it's now okay for both liberals
and conservatives,
as well as everybody else,
to speak ill of the
departed communist state.
But it was not always that way.
During World War 2, the Soviets
were more than just a military ally;
their anti-Nazi propaganda was
readily accepted by the other Allies
because it served all of
their purposes.
The point is, that,
as the victors,
the Soviets got to commit their
propaganda to the history books as fact.
With the 20-20 hindsight
we now have,
the knowledge of Stalin's despotism,
and the KGB's history of
misinformation and deception,
as well as the other camps in Poland;
Majdanek. Belzec, Chelmno, Treblinka
and Sobibor,
we've had to rely on the Soviets
for most of our information.
THE RISE AND FALL OF THE
AUSCHWITZ DEATH TOLL
In Krakov, the trial of the principal
culprits
for the Auschwitz concentration
camp
came to an end before a Polish court.
1945- 300.000 dead.
Altogether nearly 300.000 people
from the most different nations
died in the Auschwitz concentration
camp.
FOUR MILLION
PEOPLE SUFERED
AND DIED HERE
AT THE HANDS
OF THE NAZI
MURDERERS
BETWEEN THE YEARS
1940 AND 1945
1948- 4 Million
1989- 1.5 Million
ABOUT ONE AND A HALF
MILLION
MEN, WOMEN, AND CHILDREN,
MAINLY JEWS
FROM VARIOUS COUNTRIES
OF EUROPE.
AUSCHWITZ - BIRKENAU
1940-1945
Deaths at Auschwitz drop by a
huge 2.5 million,
but still the total 6.000.000 deaths
remains the same.
THE MEDIA HISTORY OF THE "SIX MILLION"
1915- 2013
... Six million Jews...
Six Million Souls...
6.000,000
... the 6.000.000 Jews...
... 6.000.000 IN...
SIX MILLION JEWS
... "the Europiean holocaust."
... A depressing picture of 6.000.000...
PIERS MORGAN
TONIGHT 2013
CNN - 2013
I believe in the inarguable fact,
that 6 million Jews were killed
in the war by Adolf Hitler Nazis.
I'm merely asking you,
as a President of Iran,
and as a scholar,
do you believe 6 million Jews
were killed by the Nazis,
or do you think that is
not true?
In a 2005 speech, Iran's former
president, Mahmoud Ahmadinejad,
caused an international uproar
by describing the Holocaust
as a fabricated legend
promoted to protect Israel.
David Cole disappires after his 1994
appearance on the Phil Donahue show
after receiving several death threats
from Jewish extremists.
He recently emerged from hiding
in 2013.
In Canada in 1988, Ernst Zündel was
convicted
and sentenced to a nine-month
jail term
after the court dismissed Leucher's
testimony.
Later, Ernst Zündel will spent 2 years
in solitary confinement in a Canadian jail
before being deported to Germany
to stand trial.
Fred Leuchter asked for a joint
scientific investigation into the Holocust.
It never happened.
Insteed he was targeted by Jewish
extremists and his career ruined.
Since its publication the Leuchter
Report has earned
legendary status in the world
of Hoocaust Revisionism.
Denying the Holocaust is a
criminal offence
and carries a custodial sentence
in several European counries.
The Holocaust is the ONLY event
in history to be enforced by law.
Notable Political Prisoers:
1998.
Jürgen Graf, Swiss Court
15 months imprisonment
1998.
Gerhard Förster, Swiss Court
12 months imprisonment
2000.
Gaston-Armand Amaudruz, Swiss Court
1 year imprisonment.
2006.
David Irving, Austrian court.
1 year imprisonment.
2006.
Germar Rudolf, German court.
21/2 years imprisonment.
2007.
Ernst Zündel, German court.
5 years imprisonment.
2008.
Wolfgang Fröhlich, Austrian court.
6 years imprisonment.
2008.
Sylvia Stolz, German court.
31/2 years imprisonment.
2009.
Horst Mahler, German court.
5 years imprisonment.
2009.
Dirk Zimmerman, German court.
9 months imprisonment.
But I don't think 6 million
Jews were gassed.
Now be... be careful,
I beg of you.
This is against the law in Germany.
If there was a German, or
somebody with the German state,
you could have me thrown in
prison, before I leave Germany.
I hope that's not your intention.
2009.
Bishop Richard Williamson, German court
 12.000 fine
To be continued
Part 22
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
9 August 1945, Nagasaki, Japan
10 days earlier
THE OCEAN OF DEATH
After delivering the first atomic bomb
for the drop over Hiroshima,
the USS Indianapolis is hit by
two torpedoes
fired from a Japanese submarine.
The ship with a crew of 1197
sank in only 12 minues.
It is estimated that 300 sailors
initially perished.
They were the lucky ones.
DAY ONE
DAY TWO
DAY 3
The terrified sailors are cold,
hungry and thirsty.
Many are unable to resist
drinking sea water,
which will not only cause them
to vomit and hallucinate,
but will eventually be fatal
in less then six hours
The USS Indianapolis is now
long overdue
and US officials are still unaware
of the plight of the crew.
The tragedy will be the largest
maritime disaster in US naval history.
DAY FOUR
Out of the almost 900 that survived
the initial torpedo attack
only 317 are rescued from the
shark-infested waters.
Captain Charles B. McVay survived
the disaster,
but was later court-martialed
and find guilty
of endangering the ship in a
government cover-up in November 1945.
After years of being plagued by
abusive phone calls
from family members of the crow,
he commited suicide in 1968.
He was exoerated of all charges
by the United States Congress
in October 2000.
Six days after the bombing of Nagasaki,
hostilities between the US and Japan cease.
World War Two finaly ends.
From the Mediterranean to the Baltic,
the victors were shaping Europe
in their own image.
Poland, the invader's route
to Russia, obsessed Stalin.
Eastern Poland had been
annexed by the Soviet Union.
As compensation the Allies
shifted the whole country westward,
giving Poland the eastern
territories of Germany.
The Germans were expelled.
Soviet zone
From all over Europe
some 12 million Germans
were expelled from lands
they had lived in for centuries.
Today it's called ethnic cleansing.
Then, the Allies called
it population transfer.
And the British helped to
move the Germans out.
The Allies will now strip
factories of machinery
and plunder German inventions
50 years or more ahead
of their time.
In just 12 jears under Adolf Hitler
and National Socialism,
Germany had become the world
leader in the fields
of medicine, science and techology.
It is the greatest theft of nation's
intellect ever,
with 1554 tons of patented documents
worth billions,
collected and sent back
to the US alone.
The Allies had decided that Germany
should compensate them for war damage.
The German population was forced to help
the Russians seize industrial resources.
Not just machines,
thousands of craftsmen and scientists
were kidnapped
and taken to the Soviet Union.
THE WONDER OF GERMAN SCIENCE
AND TECHNOLOGY
This part of the story
is an amazing one.
And few people even
today know about it.
Werner von Braun - Leading
German rocket scientist
Watch it Chuck,
keep your eyes open.
There's a break at 11, break at 11.
Planes 9 o'clock coming around.
Fire at 10:30.
Coming around.
10:30 upper or lower?
B-17 out of control at 3 o'clock.
Come on you guys, get
out of that plane. Bail out.
There's one, he come out
of the bomb bay.
What was that?
What the hell was that?
It went by like we
were standing still.
Blue leader to grouping.
Get on the air.
Going by at 2 o'clock.
What the hell is it?
It was the Messerschmidt 262, the
world's first operational jet fighter.
It flies a 150 miles an hour
faster than our fastest fighter.
On becoming airborne, the
undercarriage was jettisoned,
and the aircraft demonstrated
an amazing rate of climb.
Later, Dittmar was towed to altitude
to conserve fuel when he achieved
623 miles per hour,
easily breaking the
existing world speed record.
Hanna Reitsch also test
flew one of the early models,
from the Messerschmidt
airfield in Lechfeld.
And she later flew a
more powerful version,
now named Komet, which
made a great impression on her.
"And I can only tell you,
it was like thundering
through the skies
sitting on a cannonball."
OPERATION PAPERCLIP
The US hunt for Hirler's scientists
By mid-June 1945,
1000 ex-Nazi scientists
from various German weapons
programs
had been hastily moved to the
safety of the American zone.
There they could be kept away from
anyone who might prosecute them.
Russia's leader Joseph Stalin
was outraged.
"We defeated the Nazis.
We occupied Berlin and Peenemunde.
But the Americans got
the rocket engineers.
How could this happen?"
What's more, over a 100 V-2's
were making their way to America
under Special Mission V-2.
The Americans had stolen
the V-2 team
and much of its equipment
from under the Russians' noses.
TO THE VICTOR THE SPOILS...
... AND WITH DEFEAT RETRIBUTION
Even though the war has ended,
most of Europe is still a violent
and dangerous place.
Many will seek revenge on Axis
soldiers, ethnic Germans
and especially any known
"Nazi" collaborators.
Central Europe was
reverting to the Dark Ages.
FRANCE
This was a space without
law, shelter or mercy.
CZECHOSLOVAKIA
In Czechoslovakia German soldiers
are beaten to death
and their bodies spat on
To be contiued
Part 23
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
Of the Soviet's 7 million World War
Two captives,
more than half were German.
In 1953, an article in The Pittsburg
Press admitted
2.8 million German POWs capures by
the Soviet Union had died,
and that another 700.000
were in slavery.
Only around 20.000 German POWs
held in the Soviet Union
would be repariated to Germany.
The last survivors were not
relesed until 1955.
Thus, an esimated 3.480.000
German POWs
perished whilst in Soviet
captivity.
11/4 Million German POWs
Vanish in Russia
1955 WOCHENSHAU, GERMANY
Wochenschau
Oktobar 1955
Heinz Krüger
Their war was over, but POWs
return to an occupied,
divided and de-Nazified Germany.
The Allies had learned their lesson
well after World War One.
The NSDAP, along with its official
insignia the Swastika,
had be banned.
School teachers would be replaced,
and National Socialist books and
documents burned or taken away.
Meanwhile, the war trials had served
their intended purpose
of demonising the NS leadership
and dehumanising the German people.
This time there was to be
no peace treaty.
Germany would instead remain occupied,
with the history of World War Two
to be dictated by the victorious Alien.
Former Natioal Socialists will be
portrayed as "Evil Nazis"
with the help of the media,
future television documentaries
and Hollywood movies.
In Germany, Adolf Hitler's name is
not to be spoken of.
I will be instead replaced by those
who still secretly admire the Führer
with the ironic code word "USA".
Unser Seeliger Adolf
This was confirmed by Winifred
Wagner, daugher-in-law
of German composer Richard Wagner.
"We old national socialists found
a new pseudonym after the war
because you couldn't talk about
him in public...
... if you wanted to talk about him,
we called him USA.
In German this stands
for "Our Blessed Adolf".
On 8 May 1945, the High Command of
the German Armed forces,
General Alfred Jodl, signed a
Deed of Surrender.
It was not however signed by
the appointed head of the
Third Reich, Admiral Karl Dönitz.
Therefore legally, Germany,
as a country
did not surrender after
World War Two.
This means that the Federal Republic
of Germany, installed by the Soviets,
as well as the Democratic Republic
of Germany as estabished by West,
were both illegal under
international law,
as each had been constructed
over an existing sovereign State.
In 1961 after years of tension
between the Soviet Union and West,
Soviet-controlled Eastern Europe
will close its border,
inflicting more misery on
the people of Berlin.
1961 BERLIN
Freedom to travel to the West
for millions now living
under Commuist occupation is
forbidden.
These restrictions and others
become known as the
"Iron Curtain".
The pupppet government of East Germany
will build the Berlin Wall,
subsequently cutting off 19 million
Germans from family and friends.
Many risk their lives in a desperate
bid to reach West Berlin.
In 1989, as Communism is collapsing
in Soviet Union,
many in Eastern Europe will seek
refuge in Western embassies.
After 28 years of divison,
presure now mount
on East German authorities
to open their border.
Astonishing news from East Germany,
where the East German authorities
have said
in essence that the Berlin Wall
doesn't mean anything anymore.
9 NOVEMBER 1989
The wall that the East Germans
put up in 1961 to keep its people in
will now be breached by
anybody who wants to leave.
It is perhaps the most
important announcement made in
Central Europe since the end
of World War 2 certainly...
THE GREAT ALLIED
"EAST GERMAN" DECEPTION
Most outside Germany believe that
the country is once again whole,
when in fact it was only central
Germany
that was reunified on
3 Oct 1990.
The Eastern territories,
as defined by the Allies at the
Postdam Conference in 1945
still remain under Polish and
Russian control.
On 23 May 1949, the Western Allies
ratified a new German constitution
known as the Basic Law
However, two days prior,
a secret state treaty
was also signed.
It granted complete Allied control
over education and all licensed media
until the year 2099.
This was cofirmed by Major-General
Gerd-Helmut Komossa,
former head of German Millitary
Intelligence in his book
"Die Deutsche Karte"
On 19 September 2000, a limited
liability company was formed
to organise the financial affairs
for the Federal Republic of Germany.
It was called the:
"Bundesrepublik Deutschland
Finanzagentur GmbH"
The German GmbH is an economic
branch of the huge Jewish
financial conglomerates that incude
Rothschild, Goldman Sachs
and Federal Reserve.
These forces of Inernational Jewry
are the very same
about Adolf Hitler tried to
forewarn the German people.
All of Germany's gold reserves are
now held
in the US Federal Reserve Bank
of New York.
Now as then, the German people find
themselves in the same state of
economic servitude the Führer
sought to correct.
THE DECEPTION CONTINUES
On the 70th anniversary of the
invasion of Poland in 2009,
German Chancellor Angela Merkel
apologised
and publicly blamed Germany
alone for starting World War Two.
"Seventy years ago today,
with Germany's attack on Poland,
began the most tragic chapter
in the history of Europe.
This war instigated by Germany
brought immeasurable suffering
on many peoples,
years of disenfranchisement,
humiliation, and destruction.
I commemorate the many millions of
people who lost their lives in that war,
and in resistance to Germany.
I commemorate those 60 million
who died in this war,
instigated by Germany."
Was she speaking as the
Chancellor of Germany?
Or on behalf of a private
non-government Zionist organisation?
Germany today is still an occupied
country, with 100.000 foreign troops
stationed on her soil.
After 68 years there still has
been no peace treaty
concluded with any of the
Allied powers.
Boundary of training area
of the US forces
WARNING
Entry at own risk
The community commander
To be continued
Part 24
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
CENTRAL BANK
So, what is a central bank?
A central bank is an institution
that produces the currency
of an entire nation.
Based on historical precedent,
two specific powers are inherent
in central banking practice.
The control of interest rates,
INTEREST RATES
INFLATION (MONEY SUPPLY)
and the control of the money
supply or inflation.
The central bank does not simply supply
a government's economy with money,
it loans it to them at interest!
Then through the use of increasing
and decreasing the supply of money,
the central bank regulates the
value of the currency being issued.
It is critical to understand
the entire structure
of this system can only produce
one thing in the long run: debt.
DEBT!
It doesn't take a lot of
ingenuity to figure this scam out.
For every single dollar produced by
the central bank is loaned at interest.
That means every single dollar
produced is actually the dollar plus
a certain percent of
debt based on that dollar.
And since the central
bank has a monopoly
of the production of the
currency for the entire country,
and they loan each dollar out
with immediate debt attached to it,
where does the money to
pay for the debt come from?
It can only come from
the central bank again.
Which means the central bank has to
perpetually increase its money supply
to temporarily cover the outstanding
debt created, which in turn,
since that new money is loaned out
at interest as well,
creates even more debt.
MORE DEBT
The end result of this
system without fail,
is slavery.
DEBT = SLAVERY
For it is impossible for the
government, and thus the public,
to ever come out of the
self-generating debt.
Now, the control of the economy
and the perpetual robbery of wealth
is only one side of the Rubik's
cube the bankers hold in their hands.
The next tool for profit
and control is war.
WAR!
It's important to understand
that the most lucrative thing
that could happen with
international bankers is war,
for it forces the country to
borrow even more money
from the Federal Reserve Bank
at interest... at interest... at interest...
HITLER'S ECONOMIC MIRACLE
The real reason for World War Two?
"Germany is too strong.
We must destroy her."
- Winston Churchill Nov 1936
When Hitler came to power,
Germany was hopelessly bankrupt.
For years, the Allies had demanded
crushing reparation payments,
and private currecy speculators
would now cause
the German Mark to plummet.
It was a total destruction of
national curency
and wiped out savings and
businesses,
leaving ordinary Germans
to starve.
Hitler devised a national credit
program
which included the construction
of new roads,
bridges, canals and port facilities.
Jews at this point were removed
from prominent financial positions
and instead of borrowing from
the banks at interest,
the government issued bills of
exchange called...
Labour Treasury Certificates.
This issuance of currency was backed
by the productivity
and economic of Germany's
labour force,
and it came on the authority -
not of some privately-owned central bank-
but that of the National Socialist
government itself.
Germany even succeeded in exporting
goods
abroad despite the 1933 international
Jewish boycott,
using a barter system that again
cut out the banks competely.
As a result, Germany - despite
the worldwide depression - became
the most powerful and prosperous
state in Europe in only 5 years.
According to the 1978 book
"Which Way Western Man?"
by
William Gayey Simpson
"The German peasant, who had been
on the verge of utter ruin,
was given an honored status as the
source of the nation's food supply,
his land was released from the
grip of the Jewish usurer and measures
taken to ensure that it should,
remain permanently in the possession
of one family,
handed down from father to son."
The Jews could not let continue
as they knew it would spell the death
of their dept-driven monetary system.
World War Tho starts in earnest
that year.
It was not war between Germany
and the Allies,
it was a war between Germany
and Jewish powers
who controled the Allied governmens
and their media,
using both to propagandize the
Allied populace
into fearing and hating
German people.
In the end, it took the entire Capitalist
and Communist world
to destroy the German revolution,
and bring Europe back
under the heel of the bankers,
where it remains to this day.
"If Hitler had not come
to Germany in 1933?
Germany had 270.000
suicides the year before.
Germany was, in Berlin,
the sin capital of the world,
thanks to largely Jewish entrepreneurs,
who ran the smut films
and the cabarets and so on.
Germany was
dope capital for Europe.
German industry was virtually dead.
Without Adolf Hitler, Germany would
have
died with a whimper in 1934
or 1935.
Adolf Hitler saved Germany.
At least he gave the Germans 12
years of liberation and freedom...
liberation and freedom... liberation
and freedom... liberation and freedom..."
MEDIA VENGEANCE
With the Hollywood movie industry
and majority of US television networks,
newspapers and publishing houses
Jewish-owned,
for nearly 70 years the demonization
of Adolf Hitler
has been almost relentless.
HITLER
The rise of evil
You made a fool out of me!
Tried to humiliate me!
You must learn to sit down!
Learn to...
- That's enough.
Of the many hundreds of anti-"Nazi"
films released since 1945,
one film more than any other
has influenced
how millions perceive Germany's
role in World War Two.
Filmed in black and white for a
claim to authenticity,
it was then sold to the public
as a true story.
Despite the scenes of nudity and
violence
it was shown to children in schools
in the US and Europe as mandatory viewing.
Schindler's List
First of all, the film is
based upon this book,
Schindler's List, which won the
L.A. Times book award for FICTION.
SCHINDLER'S LIST
Tomas Keneally
Here we have a film that's being
shown to our schoolchildren as truth,
when it's based on the book
that says this is a work of fiction.
In other words, it's not true.
"Names, characers, places and
incidents
are either product of the author's
imagination
or are used ficiously".
THESE SCENES ARE BASED ON
A BOOK OF FICTION
7 OSCARS WINNER
WHAT IF GERMANY HAD WON?
A war-torn Europe would have been
spectaculary rebuilt,
supervised by Hitler's architect
Abert Speer.
Berlin, now renamed Germania,
would be the capital of Europe.
All Europeans would have benefied
from the German "Economic Miracle".
No USSR and thus no Cold War
or "Iron Curtain".
No Red China and the subsequent
killing of 40-60 million Chinese.
No Communism anywhere.
The end of the political ideology
known as Zionism.
A Palestine free from Israeli and the
relocation of Jews to Madagascar.
Greater stability in a Middle East
without Israel.
No fictious "War of Terror".
A ban on usury and privately-owned
central banks.
Abolishment of Freemasonry.
No depraved Hollywood movie
industry.
No "political correctness".
An emphasis on traditional
family values.
No Cultural Marxism or Liberalism
and their devastating consequences:
Drugs
Abortion
Pornography
Open homosexuality
Radical feminist movement
No multiculturalism and present Jewish
policy of forced Third World,
non-Western immigration
to the West.
Jews Unite Behind
Push for Immigration Reform
"It's in our strategic interest."
"It has gotten so bad
in this sick world we
live in,
that now some leaders
of nations are
openly promoting genocide
of the European people.
Sarkozy went on to say that...
"I think there's a resurgence
of anti-Semitism
because at this point in time
Europe has not yet learned
how to be multicultural.
And I think we are going to
be part of the throes of that...
of that transformation
which must take place.
Europe is not going to be the
monolithic
societies that they once were in
the last century.
Jews are going to be
at the center of that.
It's a huge transformation
for Europe to make.
They are now going
into a multicultural mode.
And Jews will be resented
because of our leading role.
But without that leading role,
and without that transformation,
Europe will not survive.
jewish world
"Isamization of Europe a good thing"
"It's nature to want to be
with your own."
Muhammad Ali
And I'm sure no intelligent
white person watching this show,
or no intelligent white man
in his or her right white mind,
want black boys and black girls
marrying their white sons and daughters,
and in return introducing their
grandchildren as half brown
kinky haired black people.
I wouldn't...
- And I am sure...
I wouldn't object to that.
Well you wouldn't but
a lot of them would.
Well, I will tell you you're
sad... that it's... it is sad
It ain't sad cause I want
my child to look like me.
Every intelligent person
wants his child to look like him.
I'm sad because I want to blot out my
race and lose my beautiful identity?
You can do what you want!
But it's nature to want
to be with your own.
I want to be with my own...
UTOPIA LOST?
WELCOME TO HELL
Just Married!
To be continued
Part 25
Adolf Hitler - The Gretest Story NEVER Told!
General Otto Ernst Remer - in Conversation
with Adolf Hitler
In 1944, General Otto Ernst Remer
commander in charge of the defence
of the Wolfsschanze
aseked the Führer if he could have
waited before invading Poland?
Hitler replied:
"You are mistaken.
I knew as early as March 1939
that Roosevelt had determined
to bring about a world war, and I knew
that British were cooperating in this,
and Churchill was involved.
God knows that I certainly did not want
a world war.
That's why I sought to solve the
Polish problem in my own way
with a kind of punishment expedition,
without a deklaration of war.
After all, there had been thousend
of murders of ethnic Germans
and 1.2 million ethnic German refugees.
What should I have done?
I had to act. And for that reason,
four weeks after this campain,
I made the most generous offer
of peace that any victorious leader
could ever have made.
Unfortunately, it wasn't successful...
If I had ot acted as I did with regard
to the Polish question,
to prevent a second world war,
by the end of 1942 at latest
we would have experiecing what
we are now experieced in 1944."
WE DEFEATED THE WRONG ENEMY
After the war, General George S. Patton,
commander of the US Third Army,
openly admitted that the Allies had
fought the wrong people.
He said about Soviets:
"Let's not give them time to build up
their supplies.
If we do, then... we have had a victory
over the Germans, and disarmed them,
but we have failed in the liberation
of Europe; we have lost the war!"
He wrote to is wife:
"If we have to fight them,
now is the time.
From now on we will get weaker
and they stronger."
The media would now begin a campaign
to discredit General Patton.
Patton, on 22 September 1945:
"There is a very apparent Semitic
influence in the press.
They are traying to do two things:
first, implement Communism.
And second, see that all businessmen
of German ancestry
an non-Jewish entcendents are
thrown out of their jobs...
... in my opinion and most
nonpolitical officers,
it is vitally necessary for us
to build Germany up now
as a buffer state against Russia.
In fact, I am afraid we have waited
too long."
And in a letter later that night
to his wife:
"I can't tell them the truth that unless
we restore Germany
we will ensure that Communism
takes America."
George S. Patton Jnr. died in a
Heidelberg,
Germany hospital 21 December 1945,
do to complications from a broeken neck
he sustained eleven days earlier
in a minor automobile accident.
No official report was made of the incident,
and there was to be no autopsy.
The postmortem findings remain
classified to this day.
Patton's prophetic warnings
ultimately went unheeded.
General George S. Patton
1885- 1945
WE FOUGHT TO SAVE EUROPE
A group of German Wor War Two
veterans explain to a Dutch journalist
how they fought to save from te wrath
of the Bolsheviks
not only Germany, but all of Europe.
We didn't fight againt you.
- Just against the Russians?
To be exact, not against the Russians,
but against bolshevism.
They were people like you and I.
- Against Stalinist bolshevism.
We defended our country against it,
and more importantly, all of Europe.
If we hadn't stopped it, it would have
reached your country and France too.
Right up to the Channel.
Tht was their plan.
We also had to fight the Americans
when they landed...
in France, Italy and Africa.
In the end the Russians sometimes
outnumbred us by twelwe to one.
And we still tried to keep them away
from the borders of the Reich.
To defend our people.
The French Charlemagne SS were the last
defenders of Hitler's bunker, fighting until
2 May to prevent the Bolscheviks from
capturing it on May Day.
Reduced from over 7.000 to approximately
30 able men, most of those who made it
back to France were denounced and
sent to Allied prison camps.
French General Philippe Leclerc was presented
with a defiant group of 12 captured
Charlemagne SS men.
The General immediatrely asked them
way they wore a German uniform,
to which one of them replied by asking
the General way he wore an American one?
The 12 French Charlemagne SS men were
later executed without any form of
due process.
Henri Joseph Fenet, one of the last
recipiens of the Knight's Cross,
was sentenced to 20 years hard labour.
He was released in 1959.
We didn't think of death at all.
Henry Frenet, French volonteer
Not at all.
Only on fighting, keeping on fighting.
We lived and fought only to fight.
Loyal to the end.
More French soldiers died fighting
for Germany than for France aiding Communism.
Many more volunters travelled from
around the world to stand
alongside the Germans in the
defence of Europe.
Those captured faced either execution,
enslavement or imprisonment.
Some would starveand die alongside
the Germans in Eisenhower's death camps.
Volunteers from the following countries
would fight for the Third Reich:
ALBANIA
ARGENTINA
BELGIUM
BRAZIL
BOSNIA-HERCEGOVINA
CHILE
CROATIA
DENMARK
EIRE
ESTONIA
FINLAND
GREECE
HUNGARY
INDIA
IRAN
IRAQ
ITALY
LATVIA
LITHUANIA
LUXEMBURG
NETHERLANDS
NORWAY
POLAND
ROMANIA
SERBIA and MONTENEGRO
SLOVAKIA
SPAIN
SOVIET UNION
SWEDEN
SWITZERLAND
UNITED KINGDOM
USA
"Now, I have only one regret...
... I wished an earlier involvement"
Henri Joseph Fenet
The Freikorps Oberland was a unit in
the early years of Weimar Republic,
known for their street battles against
Communist and Polish insurgens.
Fridolin von Spaun, the last living
member, describes meeting
Adolf Hitler for the first time.
He was indeed observing me.
And that was one of the most
curious moment of my life.
I had the feeling that he was
searching somehow-
the gaze which at first rested
competely on me
suddenly went straight through me
and into an unknown distance.
It was so strange.
And the long gaze which
he had given me
convinced me completely
that he was a man of
honourable intentions.
I can only say I am glad
that I saw Hitler's most
beautiful side.
Surely there must have been
dark sides,
but I saw his wonderful side.
And nobody can take that
away from me.
"Lord God, give us the strength that we
may retain our liberty for our children
and our children's children, not only
for ourselves, but also
for the other peoples opf Europe,
for thi is a war which we all wage,
this time, not for our German people alone,
it is a war for all of Europe and with it
in the long run, for all of
mankind."... Adolf Hitler 1942
THE END
The consequences of Germany's defeat
are still being felt today.
In the decades since the end
of World War Two,
the German birth rate has fallen below
the repacement level.
Millions of racially and culturally alien
migrants have been welcomed as settlers
in Germany.
The number of children of mixed ethnicity
has sharply increased.
As a result, the ethnic and cultural
character of much of the country
has been drastically altered.
Germany remains occupied.
Joseph Stalin
Real name:
Josif Vissarionovich Dzhgashvili
Died 5 March 1953, aged 74.
Stalin had collapsed amids rumours
he had been poisoned.
After the fall of Communism, document
No. 103202/06, signed by
Soviet Chief of Staff Kirill Mereskov on
18 September, 1940
revealed that Stalin was preparing
to invade western Europe on
10 July, 1941
in a massive military offensive
operation code-named
OPERATION THUNDER
Germany had invaded the Soviet Union
to only 3 weeks to spare.
Franklin D. Roosevelt
Died April 12, 1945 aged 63
from a brain hemorrhage.
Despite funding one of history's most
murderous regimes,
and despite his knowledge that US
had broken Japanese code
prior to the strike on Pearl Harbor,
FDR remains one of
America's most popular president.
Winston Churchill
Died 24 January 1965, aged 90 after
suffering a stroke.
Although he is regarded as Britain's
greatest statesman,
Winston Churchill has never been forgiven
by the Welsh for sending the British Army
to break up the 1910 Miners'
strike in South Wales.
The result was the death of two miners
and a bayonet charge on an unarmed crowd.
In 1965, the Welsh Valleys celebrated
upon hearing of Churchill's death.
Harry S. Truman
Died on 26 December 1972, aged 88
after a complexity of organ failures.
He will be remembered most for
ending the worst war in history
by the heinous act of dropping
the atomic bomb
on civilian targets without
warning... twice.
According to official reports and
eyewitness testimonies:
Adolf Hitler
Died 30 April 1945, aged 56,
defending his beloved Germany.
"Adolf Hitler, son of the Catholic Church,
died while defending Christianity.
It is therefore understandable that
words cannot be found
to lament over his death, when so
many were found to exalt his life.
Over his mortal remains stands his
victorious figure.
With the palm of the martyr, God
gives Hitler the laurels of Victory."
Francisco Franco
Head of Spain
3 May 1945
"It is necessary that I should die
for my people;
but my spirit will rise from the grave
and the world will knowthat I was right."
Adolf Hitler 1945
In memory of the many thousands
massacred at Bleiburg...
... and the millions who fought
for a better world.
Since the making of this documentary,
in 2012 the headstone overlooking
the grave of Adolf Hitlers's parents
Alois and Klara was removed.
No one knows what it's like
To be the bad man
To be the sad man
Behind blue eyes
No one knows
What it's like to be hated
To be faded to telling only lies
But my dreams they aren't as empty
As my conscious seems to be
I have hours, only lonely
My love is vengeance
That's never free
No one knows what it's like
To feel these feelings
Like I do, and I blame you!
No one bites back as hard
On their anger
None of my pain woe
Can show through
But my dreams they aren't as empty
As my conscious seems to be
I have hours, only lonely
My love is vengeance
That's never free
No one knows what it's like
To be the bad man
To be the sad man
Behind blue eyes
No one knows
What it's like to feel these feelings
Like I do, and I blame you!
But my dreams
They aren't as empty
As my conscience seems to be
I have hours, only lonely
My love is vengeance
That's never free
Without the miracle of the internet
this documentary could not
have been possible.
... And the women was arrayed in
purple and scarlet colour,
and decked with gold and precious
stones and pearls,
having a golden cup in fer hand
full of abominations and filthiness
of her fornication:
And upon her forehead was a name
written, Mystery, Babylon The Great,
The Mother Of Hurlots
And Abominations Of The Earth.
Book of Revelation
Chapter 17
During the1920's, Berlin became known
as the cesspit of Europe,
a city where any and every depraved
sexual acivity
could be had at a price.
With drugs, prostitution, peadophilia
and homosexuality
and even bestiaity rampant, it was
a place dangerous and unfit
for any self-respecting German
family to reside.
Against all odds, in 1933 one man
would drive the "Whore of Babyon" from Berlin
and out of Germany, restoring
family morals once again.
BABYLON BEFORE HITLER
After the armistice, the guns
went silent across Europe,
but not in Berlin, where
Germans were fighting Germans.
News of the loss by the Fatherland,
had come as a shock to Berliners,
and now the old order was gone.
In its place came chaos.
The streets of what was once
a quiet conservative town,
became free fire zones.
The Nationalists in the extreme right,
battling it out with the Communists
of the extreme left.
And out of this struggle,
emerged a new democratic state,
the Weimar Republic.
In the 20th century,
after the First World War,
the world's great metropolis
of vice was Berlin.
Berlin in the 1920s was
the sex capital of Europe.
If you knew what to look for
you could find anything,
anything known to man
David Clay Large - Author
in the sexual world was
available on the streets of Berlin.
On any given night,
as many as a 100.000 prostitutes
walked the streets,
or worked the sex
clubs across the city.
There were all different whores
with, um...
different kinds of make-up
on the street.
For instance, one
was called "Munzi".
Munzis, who were prostitutes who hung
out on just one street, munzstrasse,
and these were
pregnant prostitutes.
There were prostitutes who looked
horrible,
who had massive scared faces
or hunched backs or
were lame or crippled, these
were called "grasshoppers".
You had mother and daughter teams
on one street, that dressed exactly alike.
Here in Berlin,
sex for sale offered every
sort of perversion
or fetishism imaginable.
There was not a sexual appetite
that could not be satisfied;
in the city.
There were clubs where lesbians
liked to whip school boys
and you'd find military officers sitting
there with children sitting on their laps.
So a lot of it was play acting.
Ean Wood - Author
But there were quite a lot of people
who also indulged in it.
Berlin in the 1920s was
the sex capital of Europe.
Its very name became synonymous
with perversion,
debauchery, and creativity.
Places that you hadn't noticed
would turn into outrageous strip clubs.
The basements of the restaurants
would be homosexual or lesbian
romper rooms and sex clubs.
Every intellectual was Leftish.
The whole political right wing,
which basically came from Munich,
did not play any
roll in the beginning.
The whole town was in
the hands of Leftist ideas.
But outside Berlin,
the right wing Nationalist movement
was attracting scores of
disillusioned Germans,
including one obscure Austrian
Corporal
by the name of Adolf Hitler.
Hitler, like many of the right
wingers, hated this new Berlin.
A city bursting with Bolsheviks,
socialists, revolutionaries, and Jews.
But in the early 1920s,
Berliners
had more immediate concerns.
By 1922, inflation was
spiraling wildly out of control.
People would be paid in the
morning,
and have suitcase fulls of bank
notes.
And they would have to then
run to the shops,
because in the time between
being paid,
and the time when they bought
their goods, their food,
the prices would have risen.
Anton Gill - Author
Berlin was in a state of total,
total chaos.
Hundreds of thousands of
dispossessed starving in the streets
and at the same time,
you had very rich people.
You got on the one hand,
the poor eating turnip soup,
the Butchers selling
crows, squirrels, even rats.
And on the other side,
people who could afford it,
eating the most sumptuous meals,
like they never paused for thought.
With virtually every currency in the world
more valuable than the German mark,
foreign tourists flocked into
the city
to take advance of the cheapest
sex on the continent.
$10 dollars in American money,
could buy you anything you wanted.
Every possible sexual
taste was catered for.
House Fraus became harlots,
teenagers turned tricks,
and Papa became a pimp.
When you have unemployed,
you also have an increase
in sex workers.
But it wasn't just Berliners.
It was tens and maybe hundreds of
thousands of young boys and young girls,
who were coming to Berlin
to participate
in this hard currency sex traffic.
It was a city that was
filled with lesbian life.
There was the idea that every where
you went,
you didn't have to hide what
you were.
Marlene
DIETRICH
When it came to sex Marlene
Dietrich could be omnivorous.
As long as she found them
attractive,
she couldn't care less if her
lover was a man or a women.
Dietrich was an omnipotent
sexual figure.
She was an icon for gay women
around the world
at a time when there was no
one else.
With this new anything goes
attitude,
Berlin over night replaced Paris
as the center of Hedonism.
That's why people saw Berlin
as the Babylon of the 20s.
Things that had been considered
to be immoral amoral whatever,
were became irrelevant
and anything went.
Drugs were readily
available in Berlin.
Every variety of drug.
Morphine, cocaine, opium.
The morphine and cocaine you could
probably get prescribed
by your local doctor or pharmacist.
Opium was widely available,
and also drugs were used in
sexual science.
Sexual scientists were very
interested in the effects of for instance
morphine would have on the
orgasmic rate of a lesbian.
So there was a
complete scientific culture.
Berlin had become the center
of sexual experimentation.
It also became the center of
scientific research into sex,
led by a pioneering doctor.
von Dr. Magnus Hirschfeld
And this was a very funny character
called Papa or the Einstein of sex.
In Berlin, it was Magnus Hirshfeld.
Hirshfeld was queer Jewish Social
democrat,
who really defined the Liberal spirit
of Berlin.
The crusading doctor for sexual freedom
was also the founder of the world's
first institute
devoted to the
scientific study of sex.
You could go and look at various
fetish items,
for example he had these trousers.
Now if you wore a trench coat
you could walk around Berlin,
and look like you had pants on,
because the lower parts of
the trousers were there.
But then you had nothing on above
them, and you could flash this way.
This was thought to be
very tidily very amusing.
So it was this sort of thing, you could
see in the institute for sexual research.
Unlike his fellow doctor
in Vienna, Sigmund Freud,
Hirshfeld advocated the radical
notion
that human sexuality could be
studied,
without imposing moral judgements.
Hirshfeld's also credited with operations
and surgeries of sex change
and sexual rejuvenation.
He had a clinic for people to be
consoled about sexual problems.
But Berlin's reputation as a
hotbed for the new and risque,
was not just limited to
its bars and bedrooms.
They also streamed into the
city streets and clubs of Berlin.
From all across Europe, artists,
writers, and intellectuals
with homosexual leanings
were drawn to this metropolis.
Berlin was unquestioningly the
most open gay city in the world.
It attracted first W. H. Auden,
the great British poet,
and then his friend, Christopher
Isherwood.
Auden came first,
was interested in the gay scene there,
and talked about Berlin being
a bugger's paradise.
Christopher Isherwood,
fed up with Cambridge,
and an England openly hostile to
homosexuals,
chose to move to Berlin.
His novels about the wild side of
life in the city and its cabarets,
were eventually turned into a hugely
successful stage play and movie.
There were about a 160 completely
different
lesbian and gay male night clubs
and lounges.
Unlike most cities, with
their one red light district,
Berlin's erotic clubs were scattered
throughout the vast metropolis.
Bizarre sexual fantasies of domination,
were turned into works of art.
While they would indulge in a wide
variety of strange sexual experiments
involving violence and death;
all in the name of art.
In 1928, a Nazi propaganda sheet,
denounced Berlin as a melting
pot of everything that is evil.
When Goebbels got off the
train in 1926,
to take over the city,
he found the Nazis could scrape
together maybe 200 members.
And the Communists at
that point had about 250.000.
And they didn't particularly take to a
group of people who came in from outside
and said that everything
that the city had stood for
was all of a sudden to be abandoned
or to be considered decadent
or to be pushed aside.
Hitler had personally
appointed him to go to Berlin.
It looked at the time like
an impossible mission.
He was a good choice for the Nazis
because he understood the city.
It was he who was designated to turn
the city from a bastion of Communism,
a red city, into a brown
one, a bastion of the Nazi's.
This was a difficult proposition.
Berlin to them was
foreign territory.
They shared the typical provincial,
conservative German's notion
about Berlin as a decadent place.
It was too avant-garde,
they hated the place.
Berlin was in an upheaval.
Street fights were common.
Unemployment was worsening.
And then on January 30th, 1933,
Hitler was appointed Chancellor
of Germany.
He made it clear what
his plans for the city were.
"What is ugly in Berlin,
we shall remove."
What happened in '33, especially,
was that the gay Berlin dime bars
started to be raided.
Those things were allowed to kind
of exist under the radar,
for, up until 1933 really.
The Nazi police started paying
attention to the dime bars.
They were harassing the customers,
they were closing them down;
you might get arrested.
The Eldorado, home for some of the
most famous transvestites in the city,
was taken over and turned
into Nazi headquarters.
Goebbels sang out the name
of every book
as it was consigned to the flames,
legend has it.
The exodus was almost immediate.
Bertolt Brecht, Kurt Weill, George Grosz,
Albert Einstein, Marlene Dietrich,
just a small number of the
thousands
who were driven into exile.
Berlin for a short 14 years,
had been a crucible of history.
Brimming with a volatile mix
of sex, arts, and politics,
laced with disillusionment,
and spiked with decadence.
The Babylon of the river
supreme was no more.