[Arguing and commotion]
Man: Gentlemen,
gentlemen, please.
Now, if we start
the encirclement
in this sector
and maneuver the enemy's troops
out of the central
defense lines,
why, the counterattack
must be successful.
Second man:
That stinks!
I beg your pardon.
Walter Winchell
said last night--
will you listen to me?
Now, here are the Nazis.
So what have they got, tanks?
So what's a tank?
In '29,
they used 'em in Chicago.
Armored cars.
You're living in the past.
The layout's a cinch.
Remember how Willie's mob
mowed down those West Side boys?
I'll never forget it!
That's how the British
should do it.
Now...
The fleet muscles in
at this spot,
we hijack their ammunition,
the R.A.F.
Spits on Berlin,
and we catch them
with their panzers down.
[Laughter]
The way you're doing it,
we'll lose the war.
What?
You're backing us right
into another Dunkirk.
Smart guy, where'd you
learn to be a general,
in the Bronx?
I've served some of
the greatest authorities
of our times, to wit:
Gunther, Kaltenborn,
Raymond, Graham, swing.
Listen, four-eyes,
if you don't keep
quiet, I'll serve you
with a blackout.
20 years.
Take those glasses off
and I'll pop you in the nose.
Oh, yeah? Don't let
that stop you.
I don't need the glasses.
Where's everybody?
[Laughter]
Where are you, fellas?
Wait a minute, sunshine.
I think
the general's
got a point.
What point?!
When you take into consideration
the carastan
on the tagabrue
with dive bombers--
I told you
that the fleet
muscles in here,
the R.A.F.--
what did you say?
I said the Carastan
on the tagabrue is
a very serious problem.
To say nothing of
the larrisanc Faye.
Cut out the double talk,
and don't camouflage
your ignorance.
Listen, we know just as much
about doping out
this war as you do,
ignoramus.
Ignoramus? I'll shove
a tank down your throat.
I'll stab you
with this--
man: Here comes the boss.
Hey, what's going on here?
Man: Hello, boss.
How are you?
I could hear you boys
clear down to 42nd street.
Hey, what is all this?
A few things
I picked up at
the five-and-ten.
Second childhood, huh?
This character
thinks he's an expert
on the international situation.
Just showing the boys
how England can win
the war, Gloves.
I'll arrange
a conference between
you and Churchill.
Now let's get down
to serious business.
Serious business?
This is serious business,
Gloves.
Don't you think it's time
you got your mind
out of the sports section
and onto the front page?
I can't be bothered.
That's Washington's racket.
Let them handle it.
Now, will the ambassador
from Belmont park
kindly give me a report
on the racing situation?
I clocked sweet dream
this morning at 1:40.
Yeah? What's
the morning line?
3 to 1.
5 grand on the schnoz.
Caught kid O'Brien's
workout this morning.
How's his left?
Like a machine gun.
10 grand he wins in 3 rounds.
10 grand on O'Brien?
What's the matter with O'Brien?
Nothing.
I like him.
I also like my mother,
but she can't fight, either.
Bring me my coffee
and cheesecake, Louie.
Yes, Mr. Donahue.
Right away, sir.
Cheesecake
for Mr. Donahue.
We have a problem.
No cheesecake?
Plenty, but not from
Miller's bakery.
What are we going to do?
He only likes it
from Miller's bakery.
Give him the
national cheesecake.
It's a reasonable facsimile.
I wouldn't advise it.
You wouldn't know
the difference.
Sunshine:
Incidentally,
Samson is
twirling for the
tigers today.
Incidentally, Samson's
got a glass arm.
Here you are,
Mr. Donahue.
Put 5 yards on the yanks.
5 yards
on the yanks.
OK, boss.
You better get those bets down.
Man: Hi, boys!
Hi, fellas.
Hiya, Barney.
Hello, coach.
I got the money from Callahan.
Did he give easy?
Just like extracting a molar.
Any message?
Should I leave out
the curse words?
No message.
Dry cleaner--
what'd he say?
He says he ain't no welsher,
but in his opinion
the taxi bet was a frame.
He says 4 even license numbers
in a row just don't happen
to come along.
Hey, there's a miracle
on 48th street.
He's got a nerve,
accusing us of bribery.
Ain't he, though?
Here, pay off those hackies,
and tell 'em it was nice timing.
After that, coach,
can I beat it?
No, you got to drive us
out to the ballpark.
Can't I skip the ball game?
I got a date with a doll.
Bring her along.
We got something planned.
Anything you're going to do
you can do at the ballpark.
I don't think so.
Hey, Louie.
Yes, Mr. Donahue.
When I order cheesecake,
I don't expect to get mucilage.
I'm sorry,
Mr. Donahue, but--
this is not Miller's cheesecake.
He didn't come today
yet...Today.
Why not?
We don't know.
There's a new invention
called the telephone.
You could've used it.
Let me get you
something else maybe.
A nice French doughnut
oozin' with jelly?
You tell Charlie
to take his cheesecake
from Miller's only...
Or else.
Wait a minute,
Mr. Donahue.
Can't you--
cut out the arguments.
Can't you read?
Who's smokin'?
Flowers?
Oh, hello, Herman.
Hello, gents,
you are not leaving?
I got a business engagement
at Yankee stadium.
But you didn't have
your cheesecake yet.
I haven't got time for that now.
I'll have two
for supper tonight.
What happened to you?
Oh, nothing, nothing.
I got a little pain in my back.
Aw, that's too bad.
See Dr. Lachelle and
tell him I sent you.
Oh, say, you going
to see my old lady?
Naturally.
Well, here, give her this.
Tell her if I make
out good at the game
she's got herself a new sable.
Here you are, Lottie.
Thank you.
Here, buy yourself a yacht.
Thanks, Gloves.
You done a good job, boys.
Hey, Gloves,
won't you please
reconsider my request?
This date is personally
important to me.
See the dame tomorrow.
But I'm aging fast!
I want to take
advantage of my youth.
Whoa.
Woman: Mr. Miller.
Hello, Mrs. Donahue.
Did you see my son?
Yes.
How is he?
Fine, fine!
Any circles under his eyes?
I didn't see any.
For you.
For me?
Oh, no! Ain't that
sweet of him?
I'll be down in a few minutes.
Thank you, Mrs. Helen.
Come again.
Good day.
Hello, Anna.
Oh, it's good you came back.
I promised Mrs. Schulz
this birthday cake
for half-past 2:00.
Anna.
Yes?
There's somebody here to see me?
No. Do you
expect anybody?
No, no. I was
just asking.
Herman, what's the matter?
Is anything wrong?
No, no. You go
deliver the cake.
I will talk to you
when you come back.
There's something
I have to tell you.
Herman?
Don't worry.
[Man humming]
Thank you.
[Resumes humming]
Hello, papa Miller,
how is everything?
[Sharply]
Hello.
[Mimicking]
You're not very polite today.
You didn't ask me how I am.
Look!
The candies I like.
I'll have a few.
You don't mind?
Have some popcorn?
No.
No? No.
See, papa Miller,
you have been a very
busy man lately.
I've been watching
for you all morning.
Deliveries.
A man must make a living.
Of course.
But I must make a living, too.
Excuse me, I have
some work to do.
[Man begins humming]
Tell me, papa Miller,
were you down at the pier
this morning?
You know I go to
the pier every morning.
Then you got
the information
from Schiller?
No.
Oh, you didn't?
No. I won't do this
kind of work anymore.
You won't?
Perhaps you need
a little encouragement.
You don't frighten me.
Frighten you?
I didn't want to frighten you.
I merely wanted to warn you.
You see, tonight's job
is very, very important.
I don't care.
I won't do it.
I thought it over.
You are criminals,
murderers. I won't
have any part--
perhaps now you'll
change your mind.
No. You can beat me.
You can do whatever
you want,
but I won't do it,
and I won't let
you do it.
I'll stop all of you.
I will tell the police.
I will tell everybody.
No!
This is very exasperating.
A man on first,
a man on second,
a man on third,
2 out, 3 balls and 2 strikes,
and we have to leave the game.
Why?
Yeah, why?
I don't know,
but my old lady
says it's urgent...
In unison: And when she says
it's urgent, it's urgent.
You gonna be long, coach?
What do you care?
Somebody's waitin' for me.
And that's urgent, too.
Hello, mom.
What's the trouble?
Hello, son,
I am glad you're here.
I got here as quick as I could.
I hated to call you
from the ball game,
but he isn't here.
Who isn't here?
Mr. Miller.
I just saw him
a little while ago
downtown.
I know! It's just as
if the earth opened up
and swallowed him.
Yeah?
Where's Mrs. Miller?
She's inside.
Come on.
You boys wait out here.
[Woman crying]
Hello, Mrs. Miller.
Now, now, Mrs. Miller,
stop crying.
We'll find Herman for you.
There's nothing to worry about.
That's what I told her.
No, no.
Something's happened.
I'm sure of it.
Maybe he just took a walk
around the block.
No, no!
When did you last see him?
Just after lunch.
Yes, just after lunch.
Mrs. Miller went out
for a few minutes,
and I come down
to get the flowers
you'd sent me,
and he was gone.
Anybody see him leave?
No! Johnny
was standing
right out there
by his popcorn stand
the whole time.
And he never saw him come out.
And the back door was locked
from the inside.
Did he say anything
or do anything
to make you think he
might be in trouble?
Oh, well...
No!
Why would he be in trouble?
Sure he never
harmed a person--
mom, will you
let Mrs. Miller
answer my questions, please?
Well, he did say
there was something
he wanted to tell me
when I got back.
People don't
just disappear
for no reason.
Well, I don't know.
Now, now,
Mrs. Miller,
don't you cry.
We'll find him for you.
Anybody search the place?
Why, sure we've looked around.
We didn't see a sign of him.
Come on, we'll search the joint.
Sure, we got time to burn.
Let's go up the attic,
down in the basement.
We'll start
in the basement
and work our way up.
Maybe we can find a clue.
You'll see, Mrs. Miller,
my boy'll find him.
I'm a promoter, mom.
I'm not J. Edgar hoover.
I hope nothing's
happened to him.
Oh.
What do you make of it?
I had an uncle once
who used to disappear
like this,
and every time they'd
find him in Atlantic city
with a dame named Clarissa.
You know I'm only
doing this to satisfy
my old lady.
Your old lady.
All I know is every
time we get settled
at the race track,
the ball game,
or the prize fight,
she has to call up
and disturb us.
Why don't you
get her a penthouse
on park Avenue
and isolate her?
I tried that once,
but she likes
the old neighborhood.
All her pals are down here.
There's nothing here.
Let's go.
[Metal clanging]
[Cat meows]
What's the matter, pussy?
That's a nice cat.
Come here, pussy.
How about that?
[Woman screams]
Herman!
I can't figure it.
A nice old gent like Miller.
Who would want to knock him off?
I hope this isn't a clue...
Because I just swallowed it.
...waiting here
a whole hour.
Say, chief, can't I get away
just long enough
to give my girl
a quick hello?
Stick around, will you?
What are you
so nervous about?
She'll keep.
That's what you think.
I can't take a chance.
The fleet's in,
and she's defense-minded.
Come on, Romeo, get out of here.
Well, mom,
how's Mrs. Miller?
Oh, how can she be?
We've got to find out
who did this.
Why, he never harmed
a person in his life.
There, now, now,
this won't do any good.
You'll make yourself sick.
We'll let the cops handle this.
That's their business.
Woman: Excuse me.
I'd...I'd like to see
Mr. Miller, please.
I'm sorry, sister.
He--he ain't here.
Oh. Do you know where
I can find him?
What do you want
to see him about?
Well, it--it's personal.
You're too late.
He was found dead
a half an hour ago.
Dead?
Murdered.
Oh, Gloves.
I want to talk to you.
Just a minute.
What the...
Officer:
Not so fast, Donahue.
Just where do you
think you're going?
I was just standing
here talking to a dame,
and I turned around,
and she's gone.
Even with a murderer
around you have to
talk to dames.
Don't tell me there's
a new city ordinance
against that.
You just be available.
The D.A. Will want
to know your version
of this.
Hey, what are you trying to do,
get me mixed up in this?
Miller was a friend of mine.
I've been eating
his cheesecake
for 10 years.
I'm just up here
trying to help
the community.
Just make sure
you don't leave
the community.
How about that?
Don't forget
the policeman's ball
ain't so far off.
Son, did you notice
anything peculiar
about that girl?
Peculiar?
She does a great vanishing act,
if that's what you mean.
Yes, why did she
run away like that?
Maybe she was scared.
The puss on that
lieutenant's enough
to scare anybody.
No. I've seen her
here before talking
to Mr. Miller.
So what?
That girl knows something.
Aw, now, ma,
you can't suspect
everybody
that comes into
the bakery to buy
a loaf a bread.
Yes, but there's
something--
sunshine: What do you want
him to do, Mrs. Donahue,
spend the rest of his
life trying to find out
who killed cock Robbin?
No! But as sure as--
I know how you feel,
but let's be sensible
about this.
Let the cops handle it.
You go on home
and buy yourself
a new hat.
And here's a couple
of hundred bucks
for Mrs. Miller.
If she needs any more,
let me know.
So long, mom.
Good-bye, son.
Gloves:
All right, Barney,
drive me home.
Say, Johnny, did you see
a girl come out of here
a few minutes ago?
Excuse me, boss.
Hey, Saratoga.
Yes, sir.
Isn't that my tie you got on?
And my shirt?
Yes, sir.
What are you doing with my belt?
You don't
want your pants
to fall down,
do you, boss?
I'll talk to you later.
Yes, sir.
Hey, where's Barney?
I don't know.
He took a run
out after we
left the bakery.
I think
he's got ants
in his romance.
Get him for me, will you?
Sunshine: Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sunshine...
I got something hot
at the end of the wire.
Yeah?
Cowboys from Wyoming?
All right, all right.
How much have they got
in traveler's checks?
20 grand, at least.
Listen, tell Gloves
this is the opportunity
of a lifetime.
It's their first trip
to New York.
The sky's the limit,
and they're raring to go.
OK, Spats, keep 'em on ice.
Your apartment in an hour.
I just staked a claim
to a gold mine.
Spats dug up a couple
of Wyoming types in town
on a convention.
They would like
to spend a nice,
sociable evening
playing tiddlywinks.
I hope they're good losers.
I'll make sure.
I'll bring my deck.
[Telephone rings]
For whom do the bells toll now?
Yeah?
Hello, let me talk to Gloves.
This is Marty Callahan.
Callahan?
What do you want?
Just a minute.
Mr. Callahan would like
to converse with you.
Yeah, what is it, obnoxious?
Hello, Gloves, say,
what are you trying to do,
put me out of business?
I run
an ultra-high-class
joint here,
and if you think
you can drag me into
some murder rap--
what? Wait a minute,
translate that into
English, will you?
What? Who?
Your old lady.
Your mother.
She's down here
crabbing my whole
setup with some beef
about some guy named
Miller, some bakery,
some murder rap.
Now, look,
if you don't come down
and get her out of here,
I ain't gonna be
responsible, see?
OK, OK. Don't have
a nervous breakdown.
I'll be right over.
Here, get me out of this.
Yes, sir.
What's up, I'm afraid?
We're going to the duchess club.
This is no time
for a rumba lesson.
It isn't a rumba,
it's my mother.
Your mother?
What's she doing there?
Maybe if we're lucky,
she's dug up another dead body.
[Knock on door]
Hiya, coach.
I did it, I did it.
Annabelle and me
just got married.
I'm the happiest man
in the world.
Congratulations.
Come on.
But, coach, I and the bride
want to go on a short honeymoon.
Next month, Casanova.
Sorry, miss.
I'm sorry, honey.
Excuse me, sunshine.
Good-bye, honey.
Come on, come on!
See ya' later, kid.
Married 20 minutes
and already I'm a widow.
Don't worry, miss,
things ain't always as
black as they looks.
Mrs. Donahue:
I can stay here
if I want to,
and I want to stay here!
Callahan: You're
getting all my customers
conscience-stricken,
and you're busting up my show.
Take it easy, Marty,
this glamour girl
you're pushing around
happens to be my mother.
Ain't I got enough
trouble with you?
Do I have to have your mother?
I'm warning you,
don't start up
with my son.
I'm telling you
and your son both
I don't know any guy
named Miller.
I don't know nothin'
about any murder,
and stop upsettin'
my Prima Donna.
Be sweet, will you?
Will you scram?
All right, Marty, all right.
Gee, ma, what are
you doing down here
at this time of the night?
Don't be angry with me, son.
But that girl's here.
What girl?
The one who came to the bakery.
My star performer
don't go in no
cheap bakeries.
That's what you think.
Now, if you talk
to her, you'll find out
who killed Miller.
I told you a thousand times
she don't
know any guy
named Miller.
Don't go to pieces, Marty.
What makes you think
she knows anything
about it?
Son, I've got a feeling.
And you know when--
[everybody]
You've got a feeling,
you've got a feeling.
You've got a feeling?
Who is this dame?
Her name is Leda Hamilton.
She sings here.
Songs.
Foreign-type
songs.
Now will you take
your old lady home?
My customers
start thinking
about
home and mother,
I'm a dead duck.
And you know it.
Now get her out of here!
That big blow-hard.
I'd like to--
all right, mom,
where is this dame?
Here.
Woman:
* Cheri, Cheri, my own *
* Cheri... *
that's her.
Are you sure it's the same girl?
Why, of course.
Take a good look at her.
* oh, I could play you
a thousand ways *
* I'll say it all
in that old sweet way... *
she's not bad.
What's that?
I said it's a sad song.
Maitre d':
Table, sir?
No, not just yet.
OK, mom, I'll have
a talk with her.
You do that, son.
Ask her what she knows.
Oh, sure. I'll find
out everything.
Including address,
telephone number,
and open dates.
Sunshine, put
my mother in a cab,
and have Starchy take her home.
It'll be a pleasure.
Good night, mom.
I'll give you
a full report
in the morning.
You do that, son.
Good night, and go to bed early.
Oh, yes, I'll go to bed early.
* I love you *
* love you *
* that's what I... *
hey, Joe.
What's he doing here?
Him and his old lady's
been driving me nuts.
If he wants a table,
tell him we're all
filled up.
If he starts cracking,
heave him out.
I'll do it in reverse.
I'll make him feel
like a fish peddler.
We're all sold out,
Mr. Donahue.
Hello, Joe.
What do ya' know?
Don't say that to me.
Look, Donahue,
our prices are
too high for you.
You'd look much better
carrying your own tray.
Besides, we only cater
to the smart set.
One of your off nights, eh?
I'm only going to be
here a few minutes.
What time is it?
You done that on purpose.
Now, don't get
me mad, Donahue,
I got a bad temper.
You also got a bad memory.
3 months in a plaster cast
the last time you
tangled with me.
Thanks for reminding me.
That's still one
I got to pay off.
Back to your
smart set, Reginald.
Fish peddler.
* that's what I mean *
* when I whisper Cheri *
* my own *
thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
And now I would like to do
a number that I first sang
in Paris at the belle tableau.
[Orchestra begins]
* all through the night *
* you are mine *
* deep in
a star-spangled dream *
* you are mine *
* all through the dream,
violins sing to me *
* and all through the song,
I feel you cling to me *
* all through the day,
I'm alone *
* I know that twilight
will make you my own *
* who cares if dreams
never come true? *
* I share them all
through the night with you *
Gloves: Miss Hamilton.
Yes?
Remember me?
Gloves Donahue.
Well, I...
I know, you meet so many people.
That's it.
Miller's bakery this afternoon.
I'd like to have
a little conference
with you.
I, uh...
Suppose we step over to the bar.
We'll have a drink.
All right.
What'll you have?
Sherry, please.
Sherry for the lady
and a double Martini
for me.
Yes, sir.
Now, miss Hamilton,
I don't mind telling
you,
you can certainly
sling those
obbligtatos around.
Thanks.
Woman: Hello, Gloves.
Hi, uh...
Nice kid.
I met her at the junior prom.
Now, what was it
you wanted to talk
to me about?
Well, I don't know
exactly how to begin
this beguine.
My old lady had
a feeling that
you might be able
to tell me something
about Miller's death.
Said she
and the neighbors
used to see you
down at the place quite often.
Well, of course.
I--I was a customer.
I seem to remember
you were saying
this afternoon
that it was something personal.
Did I?
Yeah.
I can't remember anything
I said. I was so upset.
Well, that makes sense.
I'm sorry I bothered
you, miss Hamilton.
Not at all.
See, my old lady
was pretty upset.
The Millers were
good friends of ours.
Yes, I know.
Huh?
If there's anything
I could do for his family,
I...
I never met Mrs. Miller.
But he certainly was
one of the nicest men
I've ever known.
Yes, he was OK.
My only complaint
is that he didn't
tell me about you.
Well, that's too bad.
He told me all
about you, though.
No fooling?
No fooling.
He knew you ever
since you went to
public school 139.
Your real name
is Alfred, but you
keep it a secret.
Yeah, and don't you
give it away.
What else?
You gave him a dozen
ties for Christmas.
You eat
his cheesecake
3 times a day
and make
every restaurant
on Broadway buy it,
or else.
Oh, now,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Miller never gave you
that "or else" business.
No. Mr. Callahan.
And he intimated
that you were
a no-good,
double-crossing,
chiseling--
which one do you
want to believe?
I'll tell you some other time.
OK.
[Glasses clink]
Leda: I'm sorry,
Mr. Donahue.
But I couldn't
possibly leave
Mr. Callahan right now.
Oh, hello, Pepi.
Pepi, this is
Mr. Donahue.
Mr. Donahue,
this is Pepi,
my accompanist.
Hiya.
Mr. Donahue is
opening a new club
in a few weeks.
Oh, is he?
Yes, and he's asked me
to work for him.
Oh, he did?
Yeah, it's
a brand-new idea.
I was thinking
miss Hamilton here
is quite an attraction.
Isn't she?
But we are perfectly happy here,
are we not?
Of course.
And, now, Mr. Donahue,
if you will excuse us.
I'd like to finish
my drink, please.
But we have to rehearse.
Didn't you hear her?
The lady said she'd like
to finish her drink.
And I said we have no time.
I wouldn't advise
you to do that.
Do what?
Listen, weasel,
back to your piano.
Please,
Mr. Donahue.
I don't like
the way he's
pushing you around.
It isn't important.
Please don't interfere.
Come on.
Let her alone.
Take your hands off me.
Just a minute,
Mr. Donahue.
We don't want
any disturbance
here.
I warned you when you came in.
Oh, he's just trying
to persuade her
to quit
Mr. Callahan.
Oh, chiseling again, huh?
I'm afraid we'll have to ask you
to leave,
Mr. Donahue.
Lightly and politely.
Why don't you shut up?
I'm getting hoarse
listening to you.
Good night,
Mr. Donahue.
Miss Hamilton--
now would you leave?
Or do you want a sample
of our Southern hospitality.
OK, Reginald.
Spread a carpet for him
on his way out.
Better talk to that dame.
[Man and woman
arguing in German]
[Gunshot]
[Woman screams]
Good night.
And you'd better not come back.
Thanks for the tip.
Can we go now, coach?
I've been waiting here so long
the mayor offered
me a job as
a fireplug.
For all the good I'm doing here,
I might as well be one, too.
You know, I'm worried
about that canary.
She's in some kind of a jam.
May I remind you we
have a rendezvous with
a couple of cowboys?
That can wait.
Be back in a minute.
Well, we're here
for the duration.
I don't get it.
I marry Annabelle,
and I spend my
honeymoon with you.
Well, I can cook.
[Engine revving]
[Big band music]
Now, don't start anything,
Joe, I'm going to talk
to this Hamilton dame.
Joe.
Joe, what's the matter?
The dame.
They got the dame.
What are you talking about?
Who got the dame?
What are you trying
to tell me, Joe?
Hey, which way did that cab go?
What cab?
The diamond cab
that just popped
out of the alley.
I didn't see no cab.
What's up, coach?
What's the matter?
Somebody just
bumped off
Joe denning
and grabbed the dame.
What?
Drive me down
to the diamond
garage.
I gotta trace that cab.
Here we go again, boys.
Got any idea who bumped Joe off?
No. He died before
he could tell me.
All he did was hold up
his hand like this.
What for?
Maybe he wanted
to leave the room.
Shut up.
The guy is dead.
I'm reasonably sorry.
Pat? Smitty.
Did you pick up a fare
at the stage entrance
of the duchess club
about 8:30?
If you see Frankie Cole,
tell him to call in.
What about it?
No soap yet, Gloves.
But we'll trace it
sooner or later.
You're sure it was
one of our cabs?
Positive. It almost
flattened me.
We'll find out as soon
as Frankie calls in.
The duchess club's his beat.
When are you gonna
let me scram, coach?
Annabelle's waiting for me.
Quiet down, will ya', Barney?
After all, I'm a married man.
I got obligations.
All right!
Send her flowers.
That wasn't my idea.
Radio announcer:
We interrupt our regular program
to bring you this
latest new bulletin.
Joe Denning, well-known
night club operator
and partner of Marty Callahan,
owner of the duchess club,
was found dead tonight with
a bullet hole in his back.
A glove found near the body
was identified as the property
of Gloves Donahue,
man-about-town,
and well-known figure
in the sporting world.
Callahan accuses Donahue
of the murder.
Police are now searching
for Donahue,
who was last seen driving
a long, black car,
license number 2-2-o-o-7-7.
All citizens are asked
to report sight of the car...
Murder! How about that?
Blasting my good name
all over the air.
You'd think Callahan
would know me better
than that.
I suggest we visit
the D.A.'S office
and deny everything ipso facto.
Yeah, that's good.
That's all I gotta do
is walk in there,
and I'll never get out.
He's been trying to hang
something on me for years.
There's no use
denying it. We're
practically outlaws.
Poor Annabelle,
married to an accessory
before the fact.
Listen, Smitty,
I've gotta find
that dame now.
I'm doing my best.
[Telephone rings]
Maybe this is Frankie now.
Hello.
Listen, Frankie...
Did you make a haul
from the duchess bar
about 8:30 tonight?
Yeah?
Where to?
Uh-huh.
OK. You're
in luck, Gloves.
Frankie picked up this customer
and took him
to a warehouse at
733 east 61st street.
Lend me a cab,
will you?
My car is hot.
Sure. Go ahead.
Thanks. And if
anybody asks you,
you ain't seen us.
You know me.
How many years
do you get if they
give you life?
Nice, cheerful
little neighborhood.
Friend of mine
got his skull crushed
down here last week.
For what?
For nothing.
"I.J. Madison,
importers and
exporters."
Now, this can't be the place.
That's the address
Smitty gave us--
733 east 61st street.
Maybe he got
his numbers mixed up.
I'll ring
the bell and ask
the landlady.
Wait a minute.
Maybe the landlady
won't like us.
You douse the lights
and wait here.
Alone, Gloves?
Yeah. Come with me,
sunshine.
How long you gonna
be gone, fellas?
What do you care?
You got your
insurance paid.
That friend of yours, how is he?
Fine. He's dead.
What are you gonna do now?
Try to figure out
a way to get in here.
Well, allow me.
I suddenly
remember something
from my youth.
Good evening, officer.
How are you?
This your cab?
Yes, sir.
Better get it out of here
before somebody
takes it away
from you.
I can't.
I'm waiting
for a fare.
Stick around.
You'll get one.
There ain't a night passes
we don't pick
a stiff or two
out of the river.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
[Both laugh]
Oh...
Personally, I'd feel
more comfortable
if I had a rod.
Here lies sunshine
under the sod.
That's not odd, he had no rod.
You know,
there are times when
I wonder about you.
What would a sweetheart
like that Hamilton dame
be doing in a dump like this?
Maybe she still believes
in Santie Claus.
[Toy xylophone plays]
Quiet!
I must have slipped.
You must have slipped.
All right, dig yourself
out of there and let's go.
This is not
my idea how to spend
a pleasant evening.
Right now I could
be dealing myself
a straight flush.
If I could only figure out what
Joe meant when he
held up his hand.
I know he must've
been trying to tell
me something
or show me something.
[Clattering]
You are the noisiest guy.
I wonder what's up there.
You know, I think
we ought to--
hey, sunshine.
Sunshine!
Hey, sunshine!
[Motor whirring]
[Gunshot]
Hey, Barney!
What happened to you?
You look like
you've been rolled.
I had a little trouble
with a guy inside.
Where'd you get that?
Same place. Say,
you seen sunshine?
No, coach, he's with you.
Coach, he ain't with you!
Somebody yanked
him on an elevator
and took him up to
the third floor,
and I followed him.
When I got there,
I couldn't find a thing.
No sunshine?
No sunshine and no third floor.
But you just
said you got to
the third floor.
I did, I did.
It's all clear to me, ain't it?
Wait a minute, I got an idea.
This building must
connect with one
on the next street.
That's right. They
both come together.
Come on. Drive me
around the corner.
You better brush up.
You look terrible.
Drive slow.
It oughta be just
about in the middle
of the block.
There. Stop in front
of that auction shop.
Maybe it's a front.
Gloves: Continental
art galleries.
High-class joint.
Yeah. Hey,
how do I look?
Oh, fine.
OK, let's go.
Auctioneer: And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
we offer you a most
extraordinary piece,
this George I
secretary bookcase.
As you can see, it is
in excellent condition.
An original piece of the period,
it was for many years a part of
the famous holbrook collection.
Now surely there's someone here
who would appreciate the beauty
of this magnificent piece.
Looks like
an old-fashioned
revival meeting.
Shh.
Will somebody say $3,000
for this superb secretary?
Woman: 1,250.
1,250. I'm offered 1,250.
Can I hear 1,500? $1,500?
1,500.
I am bid 1,500.
Can I hear 2,500? $2,500?
2,250.
Thank you, madame.
And now, please, I have 2,250.
May I hear $2,500? $2,500?
May I help you?
No. I'm just
looking around.
Is there anything
in particular you're
interested in?
Yeah, but nothing
around here seems
to catch my fancy.
Perhaps if you
could tell me what
you're looking for.
What you got in there,
in that room?
Oh, that's the cashier's office.
Oh. Well, I'll
just stick around.
Something might strike my eye.
You ain't kidding, neither.
Auctioneer: $2,500,
once, twice, and sold
to that very charming lady
in the second row.
This way, madame, please.
I think I better
have a look in there.
Woman: You'll find
the cashier in here.
Auctioneer: And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
for the next item to be offered,
I have here this exquisite...
Madame.
The man in
the second row
on the aisle,
that's Donahue.
Tell Ebbing.
Ebbing: But ladies
and gentlemen,
$500 is ridiculous.
Once marshal Ney
sat at this desk,
and Napoleon, too.
Do I hear more?
One grand.
Ebbing: I believe
that's $1,000, isn't it?
Gloves: Check.
I have $1,000.
May I hear 1,500?
May I hear
$1,500? $1,500?
1,500.
Ebbing: 1,500.
I'm offered 1,500.
Do I hear more?
Gloves: Two gs.
Two gs!
Um, that's $2,000?
You got it.
You're gonna pay
2 grand for that
broken-down table?
Relax. I know
what I'm doing.
I'm offered $2,000.
May I have $2,500?
$2,500, please?
2,500.
I'll see the lady
and raise her 5.
That's $3,000, I believe.
That's right, brother.
Ebbing: $3,000,
I have $3,000.
Do I hear more?
Save your breath, lady,
it won't do you any good.
Ebbing: $3,000, once, twice,
and sold to that very
distinguished gentleman.
And may I congratulate you.
Wait here.
Excuse me, I'll have
the cashier come out here
for your convenience.
There's no inconvenience at all.
But I'm sure you'd
find it more profitable
to remain.
There are so many
wonderful items
for a collector.
I've got all I want
out here, sister.
Substitute auctioneer:
And now ladies and gentlemen,
we are going to offer
you a magnificent set
of rockingham China...
How do you do, sir?
I will attend
to this gentleman
personally.
Won't you sit down?
Oh, thanks.
Nice show you put on out there.
Thank you.
How would you like to pay?
Got a blank check?
Certainly.
Here we are.
Got a pen?
Of course.
Aw, it broke.
Oh.
Another antique, eh?
Try this one, sir.
Fascinating idea, a blank check,
if you ever stop
to think about it.
Yes, very fascinating.
This is a nice
layout you got here.
Full of stuff
to tempt the eyes,
as they say.
Perhaps we could tempt
you with something
to go with a desk?
Oh, no. No, thanks.
Oh, you wouldn't happen to have
anything
in the toy line,
would you?
Toys?
No antique toys.
No, modern.
When my nephew gets
through with them,
they'll be antique.
Ha ha ha!
That's very charming.
There you are.
[Elevator starts]
What's that?
The ventilating system.
Yeah? Well, somebody
took a shot at me
in that ventilating
system of yours
and hijacked a pal of mine.
Keep your hands in front of you.
I beg your pardon?
Now, listen, Buddy,
I don't know what
your racket is.
And I'm trying not to move in.
But I gotta know one thing.
Where's miss Hamilton?
Miss Hamilton?
Yeah.
I'm afraid you have us
confused with the bureau
of missing persons.
Madame, will you show
this gentleman the door?
Certainly.
I'd advise you
to butt out, madame.
You know, you're not
a bad-looking character.
I'd hate to see that
fine nose of yours
smeared all over your pan.
I gotta know,
where's miss Hamilton?
Oh, hello, baby.
I don't know what
these monkeys are
trying to do to you,
but you got nothing
to worry about now.
I'm here.
I wouldn't advise
you to do that.
The little lady
and I are going out.
Don't bother me now.
I'm busy.
You say Donahue
followed you here
from the club?
That's right.
Who was with him?
Two of his friends.
One we got in a warehouse.
The other is downstairs
in the auction room.
Did they find out anything?
I don't think so.
This man, Leda,
is he a friend
of yours?
No. I met
him tonight for
the first time.
What were they doing
at the club?
Oh, talking.
But very intimately.
What about?
He offered me a job.
He's opening a new club.
What does he do, Pepi?
Oh, he's a Broadway big shot.
Very belligerent personality.
[Intercom buzzes]
Yes?
Man on intercom:
Fleischer's here.
Send him in.
Schroeder
and Holzmeir
will be late.
The plane has
been forced down
at Harrisburg.
Bad weather.
Tell them they must
get here as quickly
as possible.
They must take a chance.
Come in, Fleischer.
Did you bring the drawings?
I couldn't do it.
It wasn't possible.
You had your instructions.
If those drawings disappear,
I'll be held responsible.
As foreman of the plant,
the police
would come
to see me first.
I can't do it.
I must keep my job.
And the next time,
I break your neck.
Ebbing: Now get me
those drawings.
We must have them tonight.
I'm sure he'll bring them now.
Pepi, you'd better
look after Donahue.
Arrange to have a truck
take him and his friend
to New Jersey.
Madame, get rid of
the other one downstairs.
What about this girl?
We will discuss it later.
Later? Why not now?
I said we will discuss it later.
But Pepi hasn't told you
all about her.
This afternoon, she--
madame, I know my duty.
I hope you know yours.
What about the meeting?
Are you still holding it here?
Why not?
Isn't it dangerous
after what's happened?
It will take more
than Mr. Donahue
to disrupt my schedule.
I told you
what to do.
Do it.
Get Steinem on the phone.
Wait in my study, Leda.
The meeting
will be held at 3:00.
Tell everybody to use
the warehouse entrance.
Auctioneer:
I am offered 750.
750 once, 750 twice,
sold to Mr. marlin for 750.
We'll charge that
to your account, sir.
And that, ladies and gentlemen,
concludes our session
for tonight.
Next week we are
offering the contents
of a Southampton estate.
I hope to see you all then.
Good night,
and thank you for coming.
Good night.
Are you waiting for someone?
Yes, ma'am,
I'm waiting
for my friend.
He's kind of a tall,
dark, handsome-like
gentleman.
I don't seem to remember him.
Yes, you do. He's
the one that bought
the fancy desk.
Paid quite
a lot of scratch
for it, too.
Oh, yes.
The Louis xv with
the gilt ormolu.
No, ma'am.
Just a desk.
But that was some time ago.
He paid for it...
And left.
No. He wouldn't
leave without me.
I'm just like his right hand.
We was kids together
down on the east side.
I'm sorry I haven't
time to listen to
your biography.
We're closing now.
I must ask you to go.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I ain't moving
a budge without
my friend.
Then I shall insist.
Look it, lady,
when we started out tonight
there was 3 of us.
20 minutes later
there was only 2.
Now there's only one.
One of us ain't enough
to leave here alone.
I'll go and see it myself.
Hello.
Will you show this gentleman
to the door, Anton?
Careful, Buddy,
I got a very
nasty temper.
You don't intimidate me.
I'm warning you.
I'll tell the police.
I'll tell them he's here.
Why don't you?
I understand they, too,
are looking for Mr. Donahue.
Oh.
Good night.
Good night, ma'am.
I'm going.
I said good night, didn't I?
What are you doing here?
Ebbing asked me to wait for him.
Where is he?
In the office.
You can see him there.
He asked me to wait
for him here.
Madame, there is
no reason for you
to dislike me.
I not only
dislike you,
I distrust you.
But I'm sure you
know that if ever
you attempted to betray us,
your father
will be the first
to hear of it
and the first to pay for it.
And if you have any idea
that your friend
Mr. Donahue
could help you,
you can give that up, too.
Pepi will take care of him.
Hey.
That you, sunshine?
If it ain't, I've been
doing a lot of suffering
for the wrong party.
Quiet.
These knots must've been tied
by the number one boy scout.
Untie me, will you?
Glad to be of service.
How do them seals
get around so fast?
What happened to you?
A gentleman persuaded me
to look at his etchings.
What persuaded you?
That dame.
The dame?
Yeah.
That makes the evening perfect.
Wait'll the boys
at Charlie's
hear about this.
Yeah. Couple of
smart guys we are.
Speak for yourself.
You and that cheesecake
started all this.
Why couldn't you--
aw, lay off, will you?
[Door opens]
There's a door...
The end of the hall.
It leads to the docks.
I don't figure you, sister.
First you slug me,
now you're trying
to help me.
Who killed Joe denning?
The same man who killed Miller.
That doesn't add up,
Miller and Joe knocked off
by the same party.
I can't untie these.
Skip that.
Try my hands.
Now listen, sister,
I've been tagged
for Joe's murder.
The cops are looking
for me all over town.
I've got to clear myself.
Who killed Joe Denning?
I can't tell you.
[Approaching footsteps]
I've got to leave.
Gloves:
Now, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
There's a cigarette
lighter in this pocket
here. Give it to me.
Good luck.
How can you trust this girl?
Why are you so blind about her?
If you don't mind,
I will handle this.
Call me the moment
Schroeder arrives.
Sit down, Leda.
I have neglected you,
my little Hansel, yes.
But now we are
going to play.
Here you are. Hup.
And now let's go on, Leda.
Pepi tells me
you went to see
Miller today.
I was in the shop,
if that's what you mean.
Why?
I've been
buying things there
for quite some time.
Uh-huh.
Madame seems to think
you went for some other reason.
Madame has
a fabulous imagination.
Ask her if she
and Miller weren't
working against us.
That isn't true.
Then why did you
bring Donahue here?
I didn't bring him here.
I accidentally met him.
If he followed me,
it wasn't my fault.
I tried my best
to discourage him.
How did he find you?
I don't know.
But he could have
shot his way out
of here tonight.
And he would, if I
hadn't stopped him.
I think that is your answer.
Does that satisfy you?
Apparently it satisfies you.
It does.
If anything goes wrong tonight,
it will be your fault.
The responsibility
rests with you.
I am glad
you recognize
my position.
I hope you don't forget it.
Come on, Willie,
put them in those crates.
And now, gentlemen,
you are going on
a nice little trip.
Unfortunately,
you won't see much
of the scenery.
You weren't thinking
of putting us in those
crates, are you?
Oh, certainly.
Sunshine: Are we goin'
parcel post or C.O.D.?
Don't you worry
about that.
You'll arrive.
Come. Hurry up,
Willie.
I hope you'll enjoy New Jersey.
Bon voyage.
[Pepi humming]
[Hammering]
[Workers speaking German]
[Thud]
Quiet those dogs
of yours, will ya'?
What kind of a place is this?
I don't know,
but nobody's gonna
tie me up again.
Quiet.
I got some Indian blood in me.
What are you gonna do?
"Principal airways."
"Arterial highways."
Looks like public school 167.
I got expelled from there.
"Crude oil."
Get a load of
the spelling.
Steel. Ah, things
are looking up.
What kind of a radio is that?
That's a shortwave outfit.
What goes on here?
I don't know.
I don't get it.
Hold on.
Aha!
Mm-hmm.
Schicklgruber,
the house painter.
Yeah. I recognize
the face, but I don't
know where to put it.
Hey, there's more here
than meets the F.B.I.
Say...
Do you know something?
We've been playing
tag with a bunch
of fifth columnists.
Wait a minute.
What's the matter,
you don't like
the manicure?
5. Fivers.
That's what Joe was
trying to tell me!
How about that?
A bunch of
fifth columnists
on 61st street,
2 blocks off fifth Avenue.
How about that?
I told you it was time
you got your mind out
of the sports section
and onto the front
page, didn't I?
Shh.
[Man speaking German]
Sure.
Herr Ebbing?
[Thud, body hits floor]
Very good. Joe DiMaggio
couldn't have done better.
I used to bat .320
at reform school.
Put that guy in the closet.
How about getting out of here
and having a little
talk with the cops?
Better take a few souvenirs.
The police are
frequently skeptical.
[Desk drawer banging]
Do you remember anything
else from your youth?
Yeah, but they gave me
3 years to forget it.
You and the elephants, huh?
What's that?
I don't know.
Looks like a who's who.
Hey. Hey,
get a load of this.
Miller was one of this outfit.
You mean cheesecake Miller?
Yeah. Take a look.
Remember that fire
on the Brooklyn docks?
Yeah.
This outfit.
Holy smoke.
These guys have
really been busy.
Hey, boss,
I don't want to
blast your romance,
but your big moment,
miss Leda Hamilton,
is one of these
bund babies, too.
"Leda Hamilton,
"uda hammel,
father in d-a-c-h-a-u."
Dachau. Where's that?
Never heard of it.
Must be one of those
towns across the drink.
What's the difference.
It says there he's dead,
anyway.
But this don't make any sense.
If she's one of this mob,
why did she help us?
This is no time for
"information, please".
C'mon, let's get out of here.
I think I'll take this along.
It might come in handy.
I'm gonna take
a look around.
Come on.
Take a peek down there.
If you hear a blowout,
you'll know I bumped into Gary.
[Voices]
...discontent and confusion.
Do you ever look at the faces
of these Americans
as they read the headlines?
Already we have split them
into angry little groups
flying at each other,
unconscious they
are doing our work.
You will see...In a year,
perhaps less than a year,
they will all be taking
their orders from us.
First, brother rat,
you take a few orders from me.
Get 'em up.
We're gonna let the cops in
on some of your bright ideas.
Thank you.
But for the present
I would rather keep
my ideas to myself.
Listen, buster,
you ain't got no
secrets from me.
I just took
a quick tour through
your tunnel of love.
Looks like the
number one office of
Hitler and company.
You're comin' along,
too, sister.
You realize
you will never
get out of here.
Every entrance is guarded.
Aw, don't try that line
on me, Jack.
This is Broadway, not Berlin.
It's a great pity,
Mr. Donahue,
that you and I should
oppose each other.
We have so much in common.
Yeah? How's that?
You are a man of action.
You take what you want,
and so do we.
You have no respect
for democracy.
Neither do we.
It's clear we should be allies.
It's clear you are screwy.
I been a registered democrat
ever since I could vote.
I may not be
model citizen
number one,
but I pay my taxes,
wait for traffic lights,
and buy
24 tickets regular
to the policeman's ball.
Brother, don't get me
mixed up in no league
that rubs out innocent
little bakers and--
[gunshot]
Excellent.
Did you learn that
in one of your gang wars?
No, that's a little
trick I picked up
from Benny's
shooting gallery
in coney island.
And if you don't quit stalling,
I'll show you some other tricks
I learned in Brooklyn.
Well, Leda,
it's useless to argue
with such determination.
Gloves: Hey,
where you going, buster?
For my hat, if you don't object.
You make another
false start like that,
you won't have a head
to put it on.
Get those hands up.
A smart character, ain't you?
All right, go ahead.
Get your hat.
Thank you.
[Speaking German]
[Alarm rings]
What's that?
There'll be a dozen men
up here in a moment.
You'll never get out.
You think so?
Come on!
Please, Gloves, listen to me!
Please let me explain!
You can't talk your way
out of this one, sister.
I know all about you now.
Sunshine! Sunshine!
Hey, Gloves!
In here!
[Gunshots]
This place will be
a shooting gallery
in 2 minutes.
Yeah, and we'll be
the Clay pigeons.
[Speaking German]
Where do you think
you're going, baby?
Gloves, please let me go.
I helped you before, didn't I?
Now you've got to help me.
Get out of here,
but let me stay,
please--
get out of my way.
Listen, sister, I don't
know what you're up to,
but out there,
the cops are waiting for me
with a one-way ticket
to the hot seat.
You know who killed
Joe Denning, and you know
who killed Miller,
and you know what's
going on around here.
You're exhibit "a,"
and you're coming with me.
Hey, Gloves...
This way out!
Hey, Barney!
Barney!
Where have you been?
You don't know what
I been going through!
We're coming down!
This is no time for
foolish questions,
but how?
Down that latticework
over there.
All right,
start climbing, sister.
No, Gloves, I won't do it.
Now, you're getting
to be an awful nuisance.
Give her
the old one-two.
I hate to do this.
Ha ha!
Glass jaw.
Be careful, now.
Watch your step!
[Speaking German]
That's too slow for me.
Why don't you stay
in your own backyard?
Hey! Who is this?
My alibi.
How do you do?
Hey, drive me to
the 47th street
precinct.
That's a police station!
I know it.
Hey! Wait for Tarzan!
Hey! What'll I do?
Let go, you dope!
[Speaking German]
I don't often slug a lady,
but you gave me the cue.
I shouldn't have
expected any better.
If you only had
kept out of this.
You've messed up everything.
Yeah, I'm ashamed of myself.
[Speaking German]
Hey! Them weenies
are tagging us.
Hit it up, Barney.
I'm racing now.
Well, cut through the park.
Right.
[Speaking German]
Gloves: Stall them
as long as you can.
Ebbing!
Come on, sister.
Ha ha!
Hey, no, wait--
Ebbing! Ebbing!
Ebbing!
Leda: Ebbing!
[Speaking German]
Say, what are
you trying to do,
break your neck?
I suppose you're sorry I didn't.
If you try that
again, then maybe
I'll do it for you.
Come on.
Get on your feet.
Pepi!
What are you standing here for?
Oh, we'll never find them.
They are gone.
We must find them.
I can't go any further.
Oh, yes, you can.
Some night you're
giving me, sister.
I start out the evening
with a nice poker game
in view
and wind up in central park
playing cowboys and Indians.
I don't know where I am.
How about that?
Me, in the middle
of New York City,
lost in the woods.
Well, come on.
Sit down in there
and keep quiet.
Will you please try and listen?
You start talking
about Joe Denning
and Miller
and that bunch
of fancy killers
you run around with,
and I'll listen.
Otherwise, shut up.
But you don't understand.
I hate them
just as much as you do.
You think I work for them
because I want to?
It's because I have to.
Oh, don't give me that.
This is a free country.
Nobody has to do
anything they don't
want to do.
Please let me explain.
Listen, sister, I'm a busy man.
If I can get out
of this blitzkrieg,
I'm going to turn
you over to the cops
and you can do
all your explaining
to them.
You can't do that.
Someone's life
depends on it.
You said it,
sister--mine.
No. My father's.
Your father?
What's he got to do with it?
They're holding him
in a concentration camp
in Germany.
Unless I keep on
working with Ebbing,
they'll kill him.
Wait a minute...
Where's this place,
d-a-c-h-a-u?
Dachau--that's where
they're holding him.
What do you know about it?
[Branches rustle]
[Click]
Stay over there.
Gloves. You're looking
for me, I suppose.
Yeah.
I thought you'd run out on me.
There's no need for that now.
Tough luck, kid.
I'll do whatever you say.
OK.
Sit down here, kid.
[Ring ring]
Hello,
Westmore hotel--
oh, good evening.
Give me a room, curly.
With or without?
It don't make any difference.
Any kind.
Boy.
For me and the lady.
And who might that be?
My mother.
Have you got
any baggage?
No.
Well, I'm sorry, but
I can't give you a room
without baggage. I--
give me that key.
Call up the cops
and tell them you got
Gloves Donahue
up in room 214.
Who?
Gloves Donahue!
I'm a murderer, a killer.
There's my picture--
one of my best.
Come on, kid.
There's a 10 grand
reward out for me.
You'll never have
another chance like this
till you pick the winner
in the Irish sweepstakes.
We'll walk.
Operator, give me
the police, quick!
This ain't
exactly in my line,
playing nursemaid.
Feeling better?
Thanks.
Aw, now, come on.
Cut that out, now.
Here. Here,
have a cigarette.
Sorry about tonight, kid.
Sorry you had to go
through all this.
It wasn't your fault, Gloves.
Well, I wish you
could have found out
about your old man
in some easier way.
Quite a shock, wasn't it?
It's all right.
Just as well.
It's better for him this way.
Sure it is.
It's better
for you, too.
At least they can't
kick you around
any longer.
How'd you ever get
tied up with them
in the first place?
I came here 2 years ago.
Ebbing found out
I was in New York
and gave me the choice--
my services or my father's life.
Nice characters.
What were you supposed to do?
Meet important people,
try and get information.
That's why I was at the club.
I knew you was OK
the first time
I talked to you tonight.
Like my old lady says,
"I had a feeling."
Then, as the evening wore on,
I got a little mixed up.
When I caught that
conversation between
you and the head man,
well, I...I guess
I blew my topper.
Now, you were saying
that Miller and Joe
were bumped off
by the same guy.
Who was it?
Pepi.
Pepi? That squirt?
What'd he have against Miller?
They were
working together,
weren't they?
No. Miller was working
under pressure, too.
They must have asked him
to do something,
and he refused.
Oh, I see. Well,
we'll get that Pepi.
We got a special little gadget
up in sing sing that'll
just melt him away.
It isn't only Pepi, Gloves.
There are hundreds
of them in New York,
in every city of the country.
They get around, don't they.
I was glancing
through this book.
What's in there is nothing
compared to what they're
going to do tonight.
They're planning something
much more serious
than anything they've
ever done before.
Yeah?
That's what Miller
wanted to talk to me about,
and that's what I was trying
to find out from Ebbing
when you came into the room.
Holy smoke.
Haven't you got any idea
what it's all about?
No, but I do know that
there's a meeting
at 3:00
at the antique shop,
and they're expecting
2 munition experts
from Detroit.
How about that?
Munition experts, huh?
You say their meeting's
at 3:00?
Yes.
Well, we'll
bust that up.
[Knock on door]
Man: Open up!
Police.
All right, you tell the cops
everything you told me.
That'll even up the score
for both of us.
Come in, boys.
Am I glad to see you.
All right, kitty,
get your coat on.
We're getting out of here
with an escort.
Ebbing:
Good evening.
To quote you, Mr. Donahue,
"get them up."
You're like a bad penny.
Are you all right, Leda?
Yes.
Good. He won't annoy you
any longer.
Can I go now?
Yes.
Yes...I know.
I'm sorry, but your father was
an enemy of the state.
That's no excuse for murder.
I'm afraid you will be
of no further use to us.
Take them both.
If you please, Mr. Donahue.
Ok, buster. It looks
like it's your pot.
Mm-hmm.
You mind if I check out?
Keep quiet.
[Sirens approach]
Hiya, boys!
Now I want you to meet
some friends of mine.
You're just in time, boys.
I got a little
something for you.
Good evening, officer.
Mr. Donahue
tried to escape,
but we managed
to keep him.
Good night.
Thanks, Buddy--
hey, you!
Come back here!
Don't let them
get away with that!
They're spies!
They're fifth columnists!
Yeah, and I'm Hitler.
But I'm telling you,
you dope, don't let them
get away with it!
Gloves: Remember
that explosion
in the powder plant last week
and that fire in
the shipyard a month ago?
This outfit's back of all that,
and that antique
joint's the front
for the whole works.
You take my breath away.
Now, why don't
you start your story
with "once upon a time"...
Now, stop kidding around,
will you, Forbes?
I'm giving it to you straight.
It's all down in that book
I was telling you about.
Oh, yes, the book.
We mustn't forget the book.
He's right,
lieutenant. You've
got to believe us.
All I want to know is
who killed Joe Denning?
A goggle-eyed
little rat named Pepi,
and he's the guy
that got Miller, too.
You're making a very naughty boy
out of this Pepi.
What I don't understand is,
what is the connection
between Joe Denning and Miller?
I told you 50 times.
I don't grasp it.
Maybe I'm not big
enough mentally.
Listen, if you don't quit
munching that sandwich
and throw that
feeble brain of yours
into high gear,
those guys are
going to hijack
the statue of Liberty.
Come on, will you, Forbes?
I'll show you their hangout.
Ok, I'm no prude.
I'd like to see
this den of bogeymen.
Now, don't let anyone
take that sandwich.
And that goes for you, too.
What are you going
in this way for?
They got a trick entrance
around in the back
through the warehouse.
I like to be conventional.
Let's go in the front way.
You might just as well
have phoned and told him
you were coming.
Listen, Gloves,
I'm a simple man.
I can only digest
one hunk of bunk
at a time.
Yeah, well, you'll
change your mind
when you get inside.
It's possible
I could be convinced.
Well, here we go.
Well?
Open up.
What do you want?
What do I want?
What do I look like?
Open up.
Yes, sir.
Don't worry, boys.
They told me there'd
be nights like this.
All right.
The main office is
right down this hall.
This'll open up your eyes.
You're scaring me.
Sounds like the next
installment of superman.
My kids will enjoy this.
How about this?
Very convincing.
Yeah, but...
I don't get it.
There was a bunch
of desks in here,
and a lot of maps
on the wall, and--
and a shortwave
radio over there,
and a picture of
what's-his-name,
and--
maybe they're still here.
Maybe we just can't see them.
Aw, why don't you
quit being funny.
I saw them with my own eyes.
Great evidence.
An invisible office.
Hey, you...
What became
of all the stuff
that was in here?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
This has been a storeroom
as long as I've been here.
What are you trying to
tell me? I was in here
only an hour ago and I--
don't get excited, Gloves.
Take it easy.
Yeah, but this guy's
one of them, too.
How long you been working here?
Oh, 5 or 6 years.
He's lying.
I've never seen
him here before.
Anything been moved
out of this room tonight?
Not that I know of.
The gentleman must have
another place in mind.
No, I haven't got any
other place in mind--
now, Gloves, the good little
fairy won't like it.
Gloves,
the elevator--
they must have
moved all the stuff
into the warehouse.
The elevator, that's it.
I forgot all about that.
Come on, boys.
Right over here
behind this wall.
How do you get in there, baby?
There's a switch over here.
Now, you fellas
better stand back.
It opens out that way.
Gloves,
it's gone.
What?
There was a button
releasing a spring.
I think I have a clue, folks.
Aladdin dropped in
with his lamp,
gave it a couple of rubs,
and the whole thing disappeared.
Now, you got to listen
to me, Forbes--
I've been listening
to you. Now you
listen to me.
I'll tell you what we'll do.
We'll all get
on our magic carpet
and get back to the station.
We'll let the D.A.
Unravel this
in the morning.
But tomorrow morning
will be too late.
We've got to find them tonight.
He's telling you
the truth, lieutenant.
We've got to stop them tonight.
I'm sorry, miss Hamilton.
You're acting
your part fine, but
I'm a bad audience.
Now, I'm booking you
for murder, Gloves,
and holding
your girlfriend for
further questioning.
I'm telling you
that behind that wall
there's an elevator
that leads to a warehouse
in the next block.
I've had
enough of that--
elevators, radios,
secret panels!
I'm tired chasing butterflies!
Ok, baby, I guess it's no dice.
The lieutenant
is losing his temper.
I surrender, dear.
Come on.
Wait.
What is it now?
Leda...
That curtain.
Oh, the curtain!
Of course!
You gonna start that again?
No...I think that's
what I been looking for.
What do you see?
Nothing.
See you later, baby!
Forbes: Come back
here, Gloves!
Don't let him
get away, boys!
Go get him!
You can't get away
with this, Gloves!
[Gunshots]
[Pounding on door]
Come back, Gloves,
or I'll shoot.
Sunshine:
Hello, hello? Yeah.
Let me talk to Benny.
Here you are, sunshine.
Hello, Benny?
You seen anything
of Gloves tonight?
Yeah, we know the cops
are looking for him.
Keeps your lamps open,
and if you see him,
we're waiting at Spats' place.
Can I use the phone, please?
Go away.
What about yip's place?
I called him.
No soap. I'll try
the golden rule.
Can't I please phone Annabelle?
Hey, what's eating you?
I'm worried about my honeymoon.
I just got
married tonight.
So what?
Gloves might be lying
in an alley with a knife
in his back.
You ought to be
worrying about him,
not your honeymoon.
Can't I worry about them both?
Ah, the line's busy.
Can I use the phone,
please, can I, huh?
All right, call her,
but make it a quickie.
Well, what do we do now?
The best thing
for Gloves to do
is to get on a plane
and go as far as it'll take him.
What kind of a mouthpiece
are you?
You're making
a convict out of him
before they convict him!
Hey, don't you
start complaining.
You're the guy that
got him mixed up in this
thing from the first.
Who me?
Yeah, you!
I told you, we were
at the ball game
this afternoon
when his old lady called up
and told us about that
Miller's cheesecake--
if I hear that story again,
I'll go nuts.
Wait a minute.
Hey, fellas, please.
I'm trying
to converse
with Annabelle.
Converse, converse!
Don't get
sore, Annabelle.
I can't help it.
I'm lonesome, too.
I'm doing the very best I can.
I'm only human, after all.
I'm at Spats' place,
honest I am!
I'm waiting here for Gloves!
Tell her, will you, fellas?
Forget her!
I'll get you another dame.
Annabelle, I don't
want another dame.
No, I don't love Gloves
more than I love you.
Please tell her,
will you, fellas--
hang up, stupid!
No, Annabelle--
Anna--
all right, she hung up.
Now you see what you've done?
She's going to divorce me
and name Gloves as corespondent.
Don't worry, junior.
You need the experience.
But I haven't had
any experience!
Sunshine:
Hey, Spats!
What's the matter?
Quick!
Give a look!
Sunshine: Callahan
and his boys are downstairs.
Uh-oh.
We're wasting our time, boys.
Gloves will never pass
through that picket line.
He'll show.
I'll sign an affidavit.
Hey, fellas, what
about these cowboys?
I can't hold on
to them much longer.
If I have to listen
to that song once more,
I'll shoot them both.
And I'll bury them.
Do me a favor.
Let them go.
What about the poker game?
Forget it.
What?
Forget 20 grand?
Gloves is in a jam,
and that dough will buy
a lot of writs
of surceasement
and habeas corpuses,
ipso facto.
Hey, that's good.
You take them over.
I'm running out
of double-talk.
All right, come on.
Cowboys: * home,
home on the range *
there they are.
* where the deer and
the antelope play *
how you doing, boys?
I'll tell you, partner,
I'm getting mighty weary
waiting for this here
Mr. Donahue.
Me, too! I'm all
for hitting the trail
back to the motel.
Come on!
Now, now, now...
Wait a minute, buck.
It's like I told you.
Mr. Donahue's delayed,
but he'll be up here
any minute now,
right, Starchy?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Keep your spurs on.
After all,
you can't expect
pyramid aldatia for
Benson all the time.
Lay off that gab, will you?
Come on,
come on there, Barney.
Cheer up the boys.
Let's whoop it up, wranglers!
All: * home,
home on the range *
[knock on door]
* where the deer
and the antelope play *
come right in.
Come right in.
Hello, Barney.
Mrs. Donahue,
what are you doing here?
Well, I been looking for Gloves,
and I can't find him.
I been to his apartment
and down to his office,
and I thought maybe
he might be here.
He just stepped out
for a little air.
He'll be right back.
Oh.
Why don't you come on in?
Sit down.
There's a nice chair.
You know the boys, don't you?
Good evening,
mother!
Hello, ma.
How are you,
Mrs. Donahue?
Barney, I'm that worried
about Gloves.
It says here in the paper
that he killed somebody.
Oh, they're just
trying to build up
circulation.
Exactly!
Well, I don't
understand it.
Now, when I come in here
a little while ago,
there was Callahan
and his boys downstairs,
and they tried to search me!
What?!
They can't do that
without a search
warrant.
Say, mother, how about
a little drink, huh?
Fix you a nice
little glass
of Sherry.
Oh, no, thank you, Barney,
but I wouldn't mind
a little bit of bicarbonate.
Oh, yes.
Bicarbonate.
I'll get it.
[All talking]
[Rustle, thud]
Gloves! Hey, fellas,
it's Gloves!
It's Gloves, fellas,
Hey, Marty.
Now, don't start shooting.
Let me get my mitts
on him first.
Gloves: So I do
a beautiful swan dive...
Quiet.
Into the east river.
They don't follow
because they figure
I'm at the bottom.
And that's the story up to now.
What's the idea,
Callahan?
Shut up!
You've got no right
to break in here
like this, you big--
keep out of this, Spats!
This is illegal entry!
Gloves has got a date
with the hot seat,
and I'm going to see
that he keeps it.
Son!
It's ok, mom.
Marty, you got me
figured all wrong.
I didn't kill Joe,
but I know who did--
Pepi, your piano player.
Don't try
to tell me--
that grease ball
is part of a mob
that makes you and me
look like little Bo-peep,
and they been using
your joint to do
their finagling in.
When did you dream that up?
Sunshine:
That's no dream.
Gloves is referring
to certain parties
from across the pond.
Yeah. Tracking down
this Hamilton doll,
I uncovered a nest
of fifth columnists,
fivers, spies to you.
Pepi was one of them.
That's what Joe found out,
and that's why
Pepi knocked him off.
Well, if that's on
the level, what are
you telling me for?
Why don't you spill
it to the cops?
I tried to, but no soap.
Now, listen, Marty.
I know you're no mental giant,
but try to juggle this,
all of you.
I got a firsthand report
tonight on what it's like
on the other side,
from that Hamilton babe,
and brother, I'm telling you,
we got to watch our steps.
Those babies are
strictly no good
from way down deep.
They're no bunch
of petty racketeers
trying to muscle in
on some small territory.
They want to move in wholesale,
take over the whole country.
So what?
It don't make
no difference to me
who runs the country
as long as they stay
out of my way.
That's just it.
They're not going to
stay out of your way.
Oh, yes, they will.
Aw, now, listen, big shot,
they'll tell you
what time you get up
in the morning
and what time
you go to bed at night.
They'll tell you what you eat,
what kind of clothes
you can wear,
what you drink.
They'll even tell you
the morning paper
you can read.
They can't do that.
It's against the law.
Yes, it's unconstitutional.
How do we know
you ain't making
this up?
Why don't you read the papers?
It's on the front page
every day.
Every order that Berlin
dishes out, these babies
follow through.
Up to now, we've had
only the preliminaries,
but tonight's the main bout.
We got to
find out what it is
and stop it quick,
and I need your help.
What do you say?
Ok, count us in.
Good.
Give me that coat.
Cowboy: I'll help you
track down them coyotes,
partner.
I tackled them in 1918,
and I ain't afraid
to tackle them now.
Me, too. They going
to make a warmonger
out of me yet.
The first one of
those guys I tag,
I'm going to kick him
right in the swastika.
Callahan:
Where do we go?
That's what I got to find out.
Spats, you round up
everybody we know.
Barney and sunshine,
you come with me.
I'll call you back
in a few minutes.
Mrs. Donahue:
Be careful, son!
Where are we
going to look for
these lugs, coach?
You said the antique joint
was cleared out.
That's right,
but the kid will know.
They got her in
the 47th street police station.
They'll grab you
if you get within a mile
of a police station.
Don't you worry about that.
Sunshine's doing
all the interviewing.
Annabelle!
Barney!
Darling!
I haven't seen you for so long,
I didn't know you--
good-bye.
Where are you going now?
Please try to understand, dear.
It's a national emergency.
It can't wait!
Well, neither can I!
Miss Hamilton?
Yes?
Ok, sister, get your things.
You're leaving us.
Leaving?
Yeah, you been sprung.
A friend of yours
just bailed you out.
Oh. Mr. Donahue?
I don't know, lady.
I just work here.
Come on.
Get your coat.
All right, miss Hamilton,
you can go now, but understand
you must stay
within the jurisdiction
of the court and be
available when called.
Yes, sir.
Your friends are
waiting outside.
Thank you.
Make it quick, sunshine.
Keep the motor hot.
Hello, beautiful.
Jail is no place for
a nice girl like you.
Hey, Gloves! They got
the dame in that car.
What are you talking about?
They sprung her, the fivers.
Get in. Let's go.
They've went like magic.
Maybe they ducked
around the corner.
No, they didn't have time.
We were too close behind them.
They're somewheres
in this block.
Look. "Kassler rippchen
eisbein saurbraten mit--"
what does that mean, coach?
It means we're in
the right neighborhood.
Oh.
Wouldn't it be better
if we just sent
an anonymous letter
to the g-men, huh?
Hey, wait a minute.
Coach...Look.
Where have I seen
that face before?
"Madison novelty
company."
Doesn't that ring a bell?
Yeah. "I.J. Madison
and company" on the sign
at the warehouse.
Boys, we're on the right track.
Hey, wait a minute.
There's the car.
That's it, all right.
Yeah, that's the car,
but where are the people?
[Vehicle approaches]
Say, this might be a lead.
Duck out of sight.
I wish I was at 42nd street.
Why 42nd street?
So I could catch a subway home.
Quiet.
Hey, Barney,
tell Marty and Spats
to hotfoot it down here
with the interference.
What about you fellas?
You can't impersonate
them two guys.
We can try.
Go on. Beat it.
Good luck.
Don't forget us.
Heil Hitler.
Heil.
Your cards.
Cards?
Identification.
Welcome to New York.
This way, gentlemen.
Schroeder und holzmeir.
[Crowd murmuring]
[Rap rap]
Ebbing: Quiet!
We were forced to meet here
because of an indiscretion
of one of our agents.
Nevertheless, we will proceed
with our operations
according to plan.
I cannot impress upon you
too strongly
the importance
of tonight's task.
Our success depends
upon the precision
with which each man
carries out his assignment.
What we have done up to now
is only the beginning
of our campaign.
We have laid the groundwork
for their disruption
and disintegration,
but now we must
destroy their confidence.
And we can only accomplish
this by an action
as daring and as bold
as the one planned for tonight.
We must not fail.
All: Sieg heil!
Sieg heil.
Now...The vessel
will sail at 4:27.
It will proceed
from the Brooklyn Navy yard,
at a speed of 4 knots,
to a point in the narrows
opposite fort Henry.
What vessel
is he talking about?
Quiet.
At this point,
the speed increases
from 4 to 9 knots.
And according to our plan,
the vessel will reach
the minefield
at approximately 5:15.
Excuse me, Herr Ebbing.
Yes, doctor?
5:21, to be exact.
Based on the coast
guard tide reports,
it is a mathematical
certainty that,
barring unforeseen events,
we can hardly be a second off.
Thank you, doctor.
So the vessel will reach
the minefield at 5:21 exactly.
Steindorff, check the reports.
I'll be back in a minute.
What's up?
I don't know, but I got an idea
that somewheres
off there,
we'll find the kid.
Quiet!
Quiet, please.
Lichdich.
Hier.
Your report please,
Herr Lichdich.
Arrangements have
been made to control
any interference
from harbor traffic
on the Staten island side.
5 men will be on the dock,
one man in each car
on the ferry.
And 3 sailors have
already been stationed
in 3 various positions.
Very good.
Holzmeir.
Herr Holzmeir.
Herr holzmeir.
[Whispering]
What do we do now?
Once this guy Holzmeir
starts talking,
we'll duck
out that door.
Ok.
Holzmeir!
Biller.
Yes?
Did Schroeder
and Holzmeir arrive?
Yes, they were admitted.
[All murmuring]
Herr Holzmeir.
Hey, that's you.
What? Oh.
Ja?
Are you Holzmeir?
Ja.
Didn't you hear me
call your name?
Well, yeah...
I'm sorry.
I was talking
to my friend, uh...
Schroeder.
Herr Schroeder.
Did Schiller take you
to the docks tonight?
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Sure, he took us
to the docks.
Good. Schroeder and Holzmeir
have flown in
from Detroit to help us.
Your report, please.
My report?
Well, all I can say is
it's a great pleasure
to be here
tonight to find out
what you mugs--uh--
gentlemen have
been doing in this
part of the country.
It's very enlightening,
to say the least...
Which reminds me of a story.
Uh, many years ago--
we have no time for stories.
Your report, please.
The report. Well,
if you don't mind,
I'd rather wait
till Ebbing gets back.
[Speaking German]
I don't get you.
Well, if that's the way
you feel about it, ok.
What did you have reference to?
Come forward, please.
Uh-oh.
[All murmuring]
You and Schroeder
are munition experts,
are you not?
Yeah, we--we know a little
something about it.
I was told you inspected
the mines tonight.
Oh, yes, yeah.
We gave the mines
the once-over.
And what's your opinion?
My opinion?
Yes.
Up here, please.
Now speak up.
Speak up.
Well, uh...
At the moment,
things don't look so good.
What do you mean?
Well...These things
take a little time
to figure out.
Have you got any ideas,
Herr Schroeder?
Who, me?
Well, the way
I figure it is, uh...
Oh, yeah. The stratavan
is on the paratoot
right next to
the mockters prockters.
That is correct, Herr Schroeder.
The stratavan is definitely
on the paratoot
right next to
the mockters prockters
and 100 feet deep.
But according
to my calculations,
if we can just keep this up,
we'll be ok, right?
[Speaking mock German]
And we must not fail!
Heil!
All: Sieg heil!
I'm sorry,
but all this seems
rather confusing.
Would you try
to speak a little
more distinctly?
I said the stratavan
is larasang tatavan
Brooklyn Navy yard.
Apparently this gentleman
does not understand
the technical terms
used in our report.
Never mind that.
What about
the mines?
Oh, the mines?
Oh, yes...
Uh...Uh, the mines.
Uh...Uh,
what about the mines,
Herr Schroeder?
The mines? Well,
what about the mines?
Well, didn't you
check the mines?
Who, me?
Well, uh...
Oh, yeah! The kansanon
is on the prossapoo,
and the senapot will
equalize the poopanick
if the gradastan
is on the altar.
And we will win!
Heil!
All: Sieg heil!
I'm sure you gentlemen know
what you're talking about,
but I must ask you
to repeat the whole
thing again,
and this time, very slowly.
The--the whole thing?
Yes.
He wants the whole thing.
Well, I--I don't
think that's going
to be necessary.
I think we have here
what we have been
looking for.
It seems like we got
a control station
at rockaway point.
Looks like we got
another one on the bridge
between Brooklyn and rockaway.
Not only looks like it,
we--we got one.
And it looks like
we got a little problem
up here with the coast guard.
Oh, we got a battleship
in Brooklyn.
Looks like we're
planning to sink
a United States battleship.
[Speaking German]
Gloves: Yeah, yeah,
I know that.
I just want to make sure.
Ebbing: Did you tell
the police there was
a meeting here tonight?
No.
You are lying!
I--I told them
there was a meeting,
but I didn't know where.
Did Miller tell you
about this place?
No.
She's still lying.
I told you
she and Miller were
working against us,
but you wouldn't listen to me.
[Speaking German]
What is it?
"What is it?"
Your friend Donahue
is downstairs.
Donahue?
How did he get in?
Well, how should
I know? Why don't
you ask beautiful?
He's not only here,
he's on a platform,
speaking,
and he knows everything.
Madame: You fool.
You've let a pretty little face
destroy everything
you've worked for.
You silly, stupid,
blundering old--
keep her here.
Barney: Hey!
Come on! Come on!
[All talking]
Barney:
It's locked.
Is there a lock-picker
in the crowd?
Callahan: Get in here!
We'll go around it. Come on!
Well...That's...That's
about all I got to say.
Everything's all set,
and if things go
according to plan...
We can't miss.
Ebbing: Thank you,
Mr. Donahue.
You caused me
a great deal of trouble.
This time I'll
attend to you myself.
Bring him upstairs.
This one, too.
Hey, take it easy,
will you, fellas?
I'm all run down.
I'm taking pills right now.
Here we are, Gloves!
Ok, Barney!
Heil!
Heil.
Ok.
Heil?
Heil.
Uh-huh.
Now sing!
What do you want me to sing?
God bless America!
Heil!
Fine.
[Speaking German]
What do you mean?
They have broken up the meeting.
Broke up the meeting?
Who?
Leda: I'll tell you--
the people.
The people you despise so much.
The people you said
you would split
into angry little groups.
You can't beat them, Ebbing.
You think not?
Never.
You're finished!
You stay here!
Ebbing: They haven't
beaten me yet.
Pepi, you come with me.
But where are you going?
We'll do it ourselves.
What, the two of us alone, huh?
Yes!
But that's silly!
I'm not going.
What did you say?
Suicide is not for me.
Schweinhund.
Leda! Leda, baby.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Oh, that's fine.
Now, listen, kid.
We got them on the run.
They won't bother you
anymore. Where's Ebbing?
I don't know.
He was here a few minutes ago.
Madame:
I can tell you.
You'll find him at the docks
near the warehouse.
Thanks for the tip, lady.
I'll put in a plug for you.
Coach! How'd it go?
Coach! Everything
all right?
Yeah. Take Leda
over to my joint
and turn this dame
over to the cops.
With pleasure.
So long, kid.
[Motor idling]
[Footsteps]
I hope you find it
interesting,
Mr. Donahue.
Drop your gun.
Did you hear me?
Drop it.
Get your hands up.
Pardon my curiosity,
but what is all this?
Explosives.
High explosives,
Mr. Donahue,
for the newest
American battleship.
Looks like a little bit
of flash Gordon, to me.
You don't think you can
sink one of them big boats
all by yourself, do you?
Why not? One man,
if he's inspired,
can change the world.
Get into the boat.
What for?
Since you have been kind
enough to follow me,
I shall take advantage
of your services.
Get in.
I could very easily
kill you, Mr. Donahue.
Don't tempt me.
Take the wheel.
And now you will see,
Mr. Donahue,
what kind of man
the new order breeds.
Get underway.
You don't think
I'm going to sit here
and drive this canoe
into one of our
battle wagons, do you?
If you make one false move,
I'll kill you
and take the wheel myself,
so you might as well
do as I say.
Them boats ain't made
out of tissue paper.
Are you sure this stuff
is going to work?
Not even the steel plates
of your battleships
can withstand
these new explosives.
What do we do,
dump this stuff
over the side and run?
There will be no time for that.
What do you mean?
We'll strike the ship
the moment the explosion
occurs.
Yes, Mr. Donahue.
In a few minutes,
you and I and Hansel
will die.
You're not afraid
to die, are you?
I don't mind dying,
but I hate
to be divided up
into small pieces.
There she is.
Now bear toward
the center of the ship.
Now faster!
Brother,
I hate to tell you,
but you're nuts.
You fool--it's our
destiny to conquer,
and no one can stop us.
Go on!
Faster now! Faster!
Faster! Go on!
Faster!
Yes, Mr. mayor.
Yes, sir.
Donahue's in my office
right now. He's ok.
That motorboat
smashed into a barge
loaded with lumber,
made toothpicks out of it.
Yes, sir.
Absolutely.
Whatever you say,
Mr. mayor.
Yes, sir, you're right.
That's what I been
saying for years.
We got to wake up.
Yes, sir.
I'll tell him right away.
Yes, sir!
What's up, Forbes?
Yes, how about the D.A.?
What's he going to say
about this?
Take it easy, boys.
Take it easy.
Come on. Break it up.
Break it up.
I've got a message
for you, Mr. Donahue.
Ok, sweetheart, spill it.
The D.A. Says
the charges against you
and your girlfriend
are dropped.
The chief says
you're a free man.
And the mayor says
as soon as he can
find his fire helmet,
he'll meet you at the city hall.
Well, how about that.
Looks like
you're national hero
number one, Gloves.
Reporter: What's
the next stop,
Mr. Donahue?
Are you invited
to the white house?
Second reporter:
I hear you're going
to work for the F.B.I.?
Well, I'll tell you,
boys--
how do you feel about
this, miss Hamilton?
Yes, let's hear your story.
Well, I feel a little
like the Princess
who's been
rescued from the dragon
by the white knight.
Aw, that's you, Gloves.
You're the white knight.
Now, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Anybody that prints that
can expect the usual trouble.
What else?
Go ahead.
Well, I also feel
it's about time
someone knocked
the axis back
on its heels.
Excuse me, baby.
What she means is,
it's about time somebody
knocked those heels
back on their axis.
See you later,
chief. Mom!
Hello, son.
Are you all right?
Sure, I'm ok.
Oh, something
terrible's happened.
Yeah?
What is it now?
5 will get you 10
the milkman disappeared.
How'd you know?
Didn't I tell you?
It's true.
He didn't come
home last night,
and I'm afraid
something's
happened to him.
Oh, what makes you think that?
Well, son,
I've got a feeling--
all: And when
you've got a feeling,
you've got a feeling.
Captioning made possible by
Warner bros.
Captioned by the national
captioning institute
--www.Ncicap.Org--