I think we can begin.
The first parole request
for Carter ''Doc'' McCoy.
Is legal counsel present?
''Carter McCoy, one to ten year sentence
for armed robbery.
''Wanted by the state of Ohio
for assault with a deadly weapon...
''...and armed robbery. ''
The State of Ohio has waived jurisdiction,
Mr. Chairman.
Mr. McCoy is no longer wanted
in that case.
Mr. McCoy has served
four years of his sentence.
Applied for parole
on September fifth of this year.
Remarks?
l would only, once again,
like to point out to the committee...
-Notice is taken.
-Thank you, sir.
Have you reached a decision regarding
Mr. McCoy's request for parole?
Request for parole is denied.
Open the gate.
Eight hole colored.
One hole.
Eight hole.
Thirty.
Come on.
-Fifteen.
-Thirty.
Hogfield, you go to the left
and start rounding up on that brush pile.
Time to go.
Round this pile up and get it burning.
Oh, man, that's just a game.
Look out, McCoy.
Get your axe and come on up here
and pitch in.
Go to work. Go to work.
De Leon, get the fire going.
That Mexican there--
Get up all this little stuff
and put it on this pile.
Thirty.
Eight hole.
l want it tight to where it'll burn.
Get these stumps down under the ground.
Bob Field...
...round up that pile.
Get it to burn.
Kirk Shaw, over on the ground....
Keep that line straight.
Hello, Doc.
l'm sorry.
Get to Beynon.
Tell him l'm for sale. His price.
Hello, Mrs. McCoy.
l'd like to see Jack Beynon.
Class. ls she a regular?
Jeez, is that Carol Ainsley?
Shut up!
How are you, Mrs. McCoy?
Ready to talk about my husband,
Mr. Beynon.
So the good doctor comes up again.
Why?
Can l help?
How about a drink?
Yeah, l could use one.
Come on over.
You'll be back, Doc.
-Hi, Doc.
-Hi.
Feel okay?
l'm a lot better off now
than l was an hour ago.
-You want to drive?
-My driver's license has expired.
-You feel good?
-Yeah.
You okay?
Pretty good.
Made a trip to Oregon
to see my brother and his kids.
l figured it'd be
the last time l'd see them...
Fatter.
You know, some things never change.
Yeah, that's right.
That's not all of it.
lt's been a long time, Doc.
Did you go out much?
Four years, and now
the question comes up.
l couldn't handle it inside.
lt does something to you, you know.
lt does something to you.
Really?
Really.
Let me make you feel good, Doctor.
lt's been so long.
Fantastic.
Hey, l was gonna fix you breakfast.
You were sleeping.
A little ketchup.
And then we have a little....
-For what?
-For getting me out.
lt was a pleasure.
Thank you, ma'am.
Hey, Claude. Here's your boy.
You have to be kidding.
Not at all.
Just a pleasant way to have lunch.
Sit down.
lt's good to see you
in them civilian clothes.
lt just takes a long arm, Beynon.
You know, it's hard to say
how those things happen.
The parole board almost never
changes their decision.
lt must be because l'm a model prisoner.
Any business with me...
Back with your own people, now.
l'll get my own men, Beynon.
You run the job, but l run the show.
And don't forget it.
You've got two weeks to set it up.
lt's not a big bank, but it handles
the cash deposits for an oil company.
Over half a million dollars.
lt's a family bank.
...is on the board of directors
at Con-Sol Oil in Beacon City.
Rudy Butler, Frank Jackson.
Yeah, l've heard of you.
You work with Miller?
You're out of touch, Doc.
Miller got blown up.
Where?
Fort Lauderdale.
-Were you with him?
-Yeah.
You?
l was backup man on a payroll job.
l'd hit some liquor stores. l drive good.
l drive.
l want Mexican visas and passports.
They'll be ready.
You boys just do your job.
He's early.
You got a flashlight, some light batteries.
A-hooks, pliers, wire cutters....
What do you want all this stuff for?
Well...okay.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
especially you gentlemen....
We very proudly present
the pride andjoy of Beacon City.
Our own high-stepping and high-kicking...
...Southwest Texas Ropers.
Following the strutters...
representing the Ladies' Auxiliary of...
...the Volunteer Fire Brigade.
We have the first beautiful float...
...which consists of the Constitution
in the history of the Lone Star State.
l'd like an application
for a checking account, please.
He goes here, follows down here.
Now, this is the spot you're looking for.
Here. Yeah.
-Thanks a lot.
-You're welcome.
Change for a $50, please.
$20, $30...
...$40, $45, $50.
The diversionary explosions are spaced
20 seconds apart.
That gives you...
You've got a bank president,
you have three tellers.
And you've got a bank guard.
Usually on the right as you come in.
Pin him right away.
Shouldn't be anywhere near the vicinity
when we make our hit.
Traffic is usually light at that hour.
...and then there's the alley.
Will you put that away and pay attention!
Now the guard carries a .38.
The cops carry 357*-magnums.
You know what this is.
l've been working ten years without one.
What about the vault?
lt's a Chambers Reilly.
No, one-inch stuff
on a three number combination.
That's me.
No, no. l'll handle the fine stuff.
You're backup all the way.
Whatever you need, brother.
Right.
You keep going over this.
l don't want anybody lost.
lf we're clean,
Gollie will take us across at Laredo.
Aren't we going a little bit hard?
A piece of cake.
You don't have to be Dillinger for that one.
Dillinger got killed.
Not in the bank.
Take it with you.
Expenses.
And his people better be there.
All of them.
l understand.
Beynon's to be alone at the drop.
Only one car in the garage
at the ranch and that's it.
Now, l'm not gonna have the money.
-He understands.
-Good, good.
Make sure everybody does. Okay?
Good morning.
Good morning, Mr. Morgan. How are you?
Fine, thank you.
Hold it.
Come on, move it!
Relax.
Superior technology, my ass.
Mr. President? Up!
Everybody, out this way.
Come on, come on! Hurry it up! Move it!
Now just relax.
Face down!
Move it. Move it, honey.
They're on their way. Just relax.
Ninety seconds.
Seventy-five.
Sixty-five.
Fifty, brother.
No!
Stupid bastard!
Take the wheel.
How did it go?
Come on, come on.
Shit.
Where's Jackson?
He didn't make it.
Neither did you.
...was held up this morning
shortly after opening.
...who forced the employees....
Hey, there's only $500,000 here.
Doc?
l see it. Take it easy.
Okay, drive on.
l'll kill him.
l'll kill that mother!
He's on.
l'm here.
Yeah?
Tell me about Beynon's ranch.
l've never been there.
When we met, it was at his office.
lf we make a mistake, he's gonna burn us.
l don't want to go there.
Let's do it my way.
l'll wrap it up as quick as l can.
News said two people killed.
Three. Rudy got ambitious.
And you got him.
That's right.
What about your wife?
Let's cut up the money, Beynon.
She told me no one would get killed.
You still don't get the picture, do you?
And l've always heard
what a smart-ass operator you was.
No applause.
One. An extremely attractive woman.
And there's the woman's husband.
A man who can easily get a parole
for a convict.
Why should he?
A simple reason, McCoy.
Let's get down to it.
Radio's rapping about $7*50,000.
There's a half a million, here.
A little more was taken out before.
You see, my brother's
the director of that bank.
We had a few problems we had to iron out.
Okay. We covered you....
You surely did, Doc.
My old lady must've made you
a lot of promises.
Close.
Stupid!
Why didn't you tell me?
What the hell do you want anyway?
Something's wrong.
What's the damage?
Your collarbone's broken
but it's not shattered.
There's no infection, yet.
lt's okay.
We...we can't leave here.
That's not possible.
l mean, we have all of this.
ls that possible, Mrs. Clinton?
Just tell us what you want.
What kind of a car do you drive?
A Ford. We have a Ford.
That's good.
You run on out and gas up the Ford.
You do what he says, Harold.
You. Get a cloth.
You're gonna wash me.
What about El Paso?
He's a friend of Laughlin.
We've got to get somebody down there.
Either Rudy or...
...McCoy's got a half a million bucks.
Just dump him down a dry well,
if you can find one.
No, he ought to be buried proper.
You just do what l tell you.
Thank you, ma'am.
Wendy, sit down.
Kind of tricky, isn't it?
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Come over here.
l'll do anything you want.
Really.
l will.
Okay.
l don't like it.
And get rid of that, too.
What is that?
No, l'm afraid not.
l'd like another one.
Me, neither.
There's about 12 people in the state who
aren't Mormons, and l'm one of them.
l guess that makes you kind of special.
Hey, baby.
You wouldn't be taking the train
to Salt Lake, would you?
No, l'm afraid not!
That's just my luck.
Where's the bag?
lt's in the locker. l've got the key.
How long ago?
Fifteen minutes ago.
lt's the oldest con game in the world.
He switched keys with you.
He'll figure you for more time.
He's probably still in the station.
Find him.
Your attention please. The Lone Star Flyer
for...and El Paso now boarding.
The Lone Star Flyer for...
-There you are, ma'am.
-Thank you.
You have coach number six.
You've got coach number four.
You have coach number two.
-My aunt forgot her bag.
-Yes, sir.
Coach number six.
-l'm gonna see somebody off.
-All right.
Last call for the Lone Star Flyer
now leaving at track site.
That's awfully heavy. To save my life,
l can't possibly lift it up there.
Thank you.
That's coach number one.
That's coach three.
Car number three, right over there.
Tickets, please.
Tickets please.
Two. End of the line.
l'll get you.
Stick 'em up!
l said, ''Stick 'em up or l'll shoot you.''
Now, listen...
...l know you're a good kid.
Now, get back there with your mother.
Your attention, please.
Next stop: Alpine, Texas.
Talk it up a little, Harold.
lt'd be good for you.
Something ought to loosen him up.
l'm looking for a suitcase.
Yes, sir, all the time.
Congratulations.
Sign right there.
That'll be $5 in advance.
Junior...
...show this gentleman to his room.
Checking-out time is 1 :00 p.m.
No girls allowed in the rooms.
House rules.
Call the conductor.
Mama, Mama, Mama....
Your attention, please.
Shuttle train from Alpine
now arriving at track site.
You're all right.
How did you get it back?
Texas is a big state.
-l can handle it.
-Yeah, l bet you can.
You. Get a cloth.
You're gonna wash me.
What about El Paso?
He's a friend of Laughlin.
We've got to get somebody down there.
Either Rudy or...
...McCoy's got a half a million bucks.
Just dump him down a dry well,
if you can find one.
No, he ought to be buried proper.
You just do what l tell you.
Thank you, ma'am.
Wendy, sit down.
Kind of tricky, isn't it?
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Come over here.
l'll do anything you want.
Really.
l will.
Okay.
l don't like it.
And get rid of that, too.
What is that?
No, l'm afraid not.
l'd like another one.
Me, neither.
There's about 12 people in the state who
aren't Mormons, and l'm one of them.
l guess that makes you kind of special.
Hey, baby.
You wouldn't be taking the train
to Salt Lake, would you?
No, l'm afraid not!
That's just my luck.
Where's the bag?
lt's in the locker. l've got the key.
How long ago?
Fifteen minutes ago.
lt's the oldest con game in the world.
He switched keys with you.
He'll figure you for more time.
He's probably still in the station.
Find him.
Your attention please. The Lone Star Flyer
for...and El Paso now boarding.
The Lone Star Flyer for...
-There you are, ma'am.
-Thank you.
You have coach number six.
You've got coach number four.
You have coach number two.
-My aunt forgot her bag.
-Yes, sir.
Coach number six.
-l'm gonna see somebody off.
-All right.
Last call for the Lone Star Flyer
now leaving at track site.
That's awfully heavy. To save my life,
l can't possibly lift it up there.
Thank you.
That's coach number one.
That's coach three.
Car number three, right over there.
Tickets, please.
Tickets please.
Two. End of the line.
l'll get you.
Stick 'em up!
l said, ''Stick 'em up or l'll shoot you.''
Now, listen...
...l know you're a good kid.
Now, get back there with your mother.
Your attention, please.
Next stop: Alpine, Texas.
Talk it up a little, Harold.
lt'd be good for you.
Something ought to loosen him up.
l'm looking for a suitcase.
Yes, sir, all the time.
Congratulations.
Sign right there.
That'll be $5 in advance.
Junior...
...show this gentleman to his room.
Checking-out time is 1 :00 p.m.
No girls allowed in the rooms.
House rules.
Call the conductor.
Mama, Mama, Mama....
Your attention, please.
Shuttle train from Alpine
now arriving at track site.
You're all right.
How did you get it back?
Texas is a big state.
-l can handle it.
-Yeah, l bet you can.
You. Get a cloth.
You're gonna wash me.
What about El Paso?
He's a friend of Laughlin.
We've got to get somebody down there.
Either Rudy or...
...McCoy's got a half a million bucks.
Just dump him down a dry well,
if you can find one.
No, he ought to be buried proper.
You just do what l tell you.
Thank you, ma'am.
Wendy, sit down.
Kind of tricky, isn't it?
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Come over here.
l'll do anything you want.
Really.
l will.
Okay.
l don't like it.
And get rid of that, too.
What is that?
No, l'm afraid not.
l'd like another one.
Me, neither.
d.
Me, 5either.
6051  X1:232 Xthing  X1:30557:04,765  X1:077 X2:64290
d.
Me, 6either.36 X2:462 Y1:457216 d.
He swi:04,765  X1:077 X2:64290
d.
Me, 7either.43:20,444  X1:07n bucX1:208 Xt be taking the train
to36:23,09
d.0:56:128either.4lems we had t,445  53:03,973 Y1:450 Y2:487
Junior...to hiy come n9
00205:22,845  X1:205 X2:51.
bucks.
me n9
d.6 X2:4d41,60 Y2:490
N:492
l480 Y2:492
Just 480 2:487
That
Me,92
Next stop: Al,402  : Alp! ,402
Rea49 5
01:06:54,5334:168
00:59:02,851  X1:063 X2:65?
1:45Star t?
1:40 Y!9
45Star
Me,93
Rea49 569 X2:530 Y1:49X2:5434key.
0X2:475 Y1:450 Y2:4D7:36
2Y2:40  X1: line.
N:4
Rea49 501:09:05,253 .38.,133  X1:0219
l'm here.
00:56.38.,1u can.
3 guard did you :183 X2:8X1:220 X2:499 Y1:450 me00:53:523
0:56:14
l'm h8of that, too.
29Eith
00:560  t?ate.
275lease
00:58:31,49:53,692  X1:224 X2:495S X1: isn343
01:0756
00:5505
01:06:23,0135is.
352566  X1:2n advance.
01::49348
298:06:25,6885:56,769  X1:307 X2:0Y1:450you.
a> 01:04:?
f't want 5Y1:450 51:07:3oth.
275le2:48Y2:492
the s585 00:58:23,808  X1:0:219 X Y1:a n:05, qui Y2plac00:56:1n2:450 51:03.9:06:23,0135is45,581 Y1:4501:08:1793 X2:476 Y1:450 Y2:49
F 00:49:58,928  X1:297 X2
00:555?
30501:074oth.
275le295
06:25,6885:56,71450 Y2:487
You. Get
287hihere.0:58:c:07:31,858
00:56.38l'll can.
3 ...
00:5
for a convict.
00:5 ...
00:53:2 ...2,207  X1:56
00:269115 X2:604 Y1:450 Y2nd of the Y2:ry,62 Y1:coo31
00431,8587
00:5 ...801:06:23,013517:06,99 attention ple1 00:58:23,808  X1:0:lody0 Y2:4a 31sonal ques.McC00:555?8
00:5 ..00:46:13,482  51Y2:4927
l'm 03 Y1:450 Y2:492
S'm gonna
Fifte5:08:53oth.
Mam7e key.
2:642 Y18t like it.
00:56kid:450rn th00:555.
He s56
0126:13,482  51Y2rld.
He s266  X1  X1:194 X2:524 Y1: X2:4l
01:075e you f51e over here.
n year X2:539 Y1Take it easy.
2178:14,amant.
6:22, Y2:4878:32,60519 Y19:06:23,013517g6d265key.
2:642 Y18t like it.
l uitc, Haron
00:5ahe bag?5X1:063 ambers8oth.
3itious.
2is tha243  X1:113 X2:605Kid:424  X1:if8,207 , Harol2:492to3:3 ui,at l 7 , Harol2:492 bag?5X4:063 amb50ver here.
n y1894anything
01:eriahe bag?5X
00:56.00:569:06:23,0135208:53:26,933 's me.
00:271:166 X2:kn Y2:492illed.
bit1:3f487 Y1:to3:3 ui, Y2:4878600:56.00:42
00:46:47,5u're 5
00:56:54
01:05:19,493 89
00:527  X192
Yoa2plac0ther sed.
:07: X1:090X1:X1:1492
SoY2:4878700:56.00: We have a Fo58
0134:34,255  X1:183 X2:535 Y1:450 Y22 X2:bout 50rn thcase.
l'ye:07:31,8550 Y2:45hat a3:06:23,01352027rgot her ba
00:269115 X2:604 Y1:45
34n ple afraid am
owave co
N34 Y1:47:57,50
00:46:47,5u'7,596:575 Y1:450 Y2:92  X1:224 X2:495Say Y2:492650 Y2:48:00,1fraid not.8:0032
Tell meh me.
3Y1:450 Y2:490
Me,48,290 ,  X1:247 X
00:35:56see som8:00325 have a Fo580:53:08:51,564:492
2846or the 52 Y174oth.
2752 X2:5-> 00:56:44:40,766  X1:220 X2
w
00:53:18,6at's aw52 X2
Where's th52 X448Y2:492
Find him.
0a. Mo''Stick6962  X1t gonn20,444  X1:t go,50,924  X
2:642 Y18t like it.
29lhankkon:31,533$13 343
0160:50,055on bu1:06:23,0135nds.67
House et's c5,522  X1:153 X2:5Suppo
You1:00>0 X2$ase
50 Yis 1 :00 prutentio50 Y23:18,6a650,055on
00:56:553w, get back th
00:53:03,973 -0 Y2:523seriou23:18,6a750,055on 3
01:01:09,95ed pro.
He sw450 Y2:47
Come over here.
53:42,664:04,4454l.
0,444  X1:t15 Y12Y2:487
F8305
0X2:475 Y1:45492
C31,533$2se
503:18,6:492
T5,77e gonna wash 5,746  a little,4 X1:232 X2:487 Y1:X1:237 1:00:, he ou,00:56:1t down
3426450 Y2:5,74325 have a Fo54 want.
28Y1:450 Y2:492
You still dPrbone55,493 h7 Y1
01:54 w9,5onna wash 5,70 Y2:450 Y2:6
0 Y2:20,892  X1:247 walk1:3n
And y:38,37bord
One.490
6'6m up 5,744 gonna wash 5,7s
234 X2:484 Y637m up 5,75001:06:54,53350 Y1:3 X1:237 X183 X2:536 Y1:450 Y2:492 Y1:4cld upy523
Ju3:18,6::04,4454l54,5onna wash 5,750 Y
00:57: get rid of that, toons.
01:09:06,8536as.
5Star 297
00:57:5Sta8,691  X1:26
05:450 Y2:492
653 n450 thcby SOFTlTLER:450