"Bad memories: be yet welcomed...
you are my distant youth..."
Army in the Shadows
October 20, 1942
- Do you mind if we stop for a while?
- Not at all.
It won't take too long.
Just some shopping.
You have to sort it out for yourself
these days.
It's very understandable.
You will be alright in this camp.
The best camp in France!
This camp was for Germans.
I'm not sure I understand.
At the beginning of the war, we were
expecting a lot of german prisoners.
But of course there were none.
However, this camp is very useful now.
What good luck!
You said it!
Always the same; don't know who they
are, or how to treat them.
Some of them arrive without being charged
and stay forever.
Some, who committed crimes,
get out very quickly and become influential...
in the department,
or in the Vichy government.
Philippe Gerbier, 41 years old.
Engineer.
Vivid and independent mind.
Distant and ironic.
To subdue.
Seems to be influential.
To be treated gently.
Suspected of Gaullist thinking.
To subdue.
Set free by lack of evidence:
influential, to be treated gently.
The room you are going to
was for german officers.
I'm honored.
Certainly to be treated gently...
and certainly with caution.
Philippe Gerbier
Colonel Jarret Du Plessis
I don't know why you are here
but I'll tell you why I was arrested.
I said in a café that
Admiral Darlant was a bastard.
And Marechal Petain is a bastard also,
whose treatment of soldiers is reprehensible.
You, Colonel, have the chance
to suffer for your opinions.
Aubert, a druggist.
Do you know, Sir,
what a Mallert Shell is?
No.
It's a component of a
certain chemical reaction.
I am a chemist and I had to keep
a Mallert Shell.
I was censured for shell possession,
and no one would listen to any explications.
Octave Bonnafous.
Business man.
I unfortunately stumbled into
a Gaullist meeting...
No more laws!
Only bastards!
They took my pension away!
Where should I settle in?
As the room leader, allow me
to assign you this free mattress.
I am Legrain, communist.
Here's Armel, teacher and catholic.
Is he sleeping?
No, he's very sick.
No infirmary?
Already full.
Do you play dominos?
I'm afraid not.
We'll teach you.
Thank you, but I would rather not.
Excuse us then, but we must finish playing
before they turn off the light.
The Commandant is not as stupid as he looks.
He put me in with three idiots
and two lost children.
Going for a walk?
I'm working in the power station.
Well done!
I don't get paid,
but I like it and wish to practice.
See you later, comrade!
Are you communist?
No, but we're comrades all the same.
There are people here
from every country.
Russians.
Poles.
Algerians.
Jews from all over,
Gypsies.
Yugoslavians.
Romanian, Czech.
Germans against Nazism,
Italians against Fascism.
Spanish against Franco,
And some others,
arrested for smuggling.
You alright?
I managed the installation
of powerlines in Savoie.
You're an electrician?
- Just like you.
- Surely you're more qualified than I.
Maybe we could talk about it sometime.
Of course.
With pleasure.
The young teacher died one night,
silently.
The Algerians carried his body away.
I never heard him speak.
I'm not sad.
He's in a better place.
All debts will be paid one day.
Mister Gerbier.
I wish to speak with you tonight.
There are two obstacles to escape;
barbed wire and guards.
We can pass under the barbed wire,
and I can blind the guards
by turning off all the lights.
Why haven't you escaped yet?
I didn't want to escape alone,
and leave Armelle.
But I trust you.
Why are you telling me this?
I think you're needed on the outside.
Turn off the light and go to sleep.
Good night.
Secretly, between us,
the escape plan was taking shape.
Little by little.
Gerbier, come here.
Get ready.
Hurry please.
Please salute Legrain for me.
- There are the bastards.
- But...
Farewell, Sir.
Allow me, please.
Thanks.
There's just one chance.
I'll ask the soldier for something,
and then you'll cross the two gates.
Good luck.
Excuse me sir, do you have a cigarette?
What do you want?
I'd like a shave.
Marechal has said... Marechal has accomplished...
Marechal keeps his promises.
There you go.
I'll get your change.
- No wait...
- Wait for your change.
Take this.
Not very much, but it's all I have.
Thank you.
Paul Dounat received orders
from his organization.
He had to be in front of
the Marseilles courts
at noon, and wait there
for a friend he knew.
Police. Papers please.
All right.
But follow me anyway.
For a simple check.
Dirty job.
Felix, put on your hat.
No need in the car.
This is the guy who betrayed you.
I don't think there's any need to question you.
We should have refused him.
It's my fault.
So much to do,
and such little help.
Bison, faster please.
They'll notice us.
I'm also in a hurry.
I have to repair a radio,
and a young agent's bicycle.
And prepare tonight's reception.
Do you have the fake papers?
Yes, do you want them now?
The car must stay here.
It might be noticed.
- We'll take a walk.
- I'll come with you.
Not necessary.
Indeed.
I suppose not.
I'll pick you up later tonight.
One false move, and I shoot you.
Hell, when we rented this house,
the other one was empty!
Let's go anyway.
This way.
Is he the traitor that we're supposed to...
Yes, he is.
And are you the boss?
He is Claude LeMasque.
He's asked for harder assignments.
I came one hour earlier
to get everything ready...
and noticed that
some neighbors had arrived.
There was nobody yesterday!
I called immediately,
but you had already left.
It'll be alright.
We can begin the interrogating.
I prepared chairs, desk, paper...
This is not a trial.
Here's what it's about.
No way!
The neighbors will hear everything!
Listen...
The walls are paper-thin.
The English didn't deliver on
the silenced guns we requested.
Let's look for a better place.
How could you do it?
There's no better place.
The cellar won't work.
And neither will the attic.
We will need a good knife.
Bison has one.
A knife? Are you kidding?
I can't let you do that.
Felix! Go look for something
in the kitchen.
Please don't do this.
It's murder!
We are here to kill, regardless.
That's true, but not like this.
I know what you mean.
I swear I am not scared,
but this is my first time ...
This is our first time also,
can't you see?
I didn't find anything.
Maybe we could wait for Bison?
No, out of the question.
We must finish it now.
Bloody hell!
We can't just smash his head in, can we?
Gag him.
We must strangle him.
With our bare hands?
No.
There's a towel in the kitchen.
Enough!
You came here for this!
You wanted a harder assignment?
Here it is, so don't complain.
Make him sit down.
Felix, go behind.
I will hold his hands
and Masque will grab his legs.
I promise you won't suffer.
We're leaving.
I'm coming.
I could not imagine
this was possible.
Neither could I.
Get some cyanide pills.
And if you're arrested, eat them.
I will.
A glass of rum.
- Jean François!
- Felix!
It's been a long time.
Still young and handsome.
What are you doing in Marseilles?
I moved my workshop here from Paris.
And you?
Nothing special.
I have to go.
Can you walk a bit with me?
Alright, let's go.
Can you wait five minutes?
Five minutes.
Not my whole life.
Always lucky!
A bit risky to wear a pilot's jacket?
Fuck them.
- And then?
- And then what?
Just fuck them?
What else? Fight?
I know some more exciting things.
Really exciting?
Yes.
You'll have to get up early,
sleep on the train, on the road,
without reasons or explanations.
I'm interested.
Come and see me tomorrow,
here's my address.
No, don't write it down.
Just remember it.
And never tell a soul.
Of course.
Everyone says that...
but even a girlfriend...
I don't have one.
The girl in the bar?
I told her 5 minutes...
she'll have to wait a few more.
Parents you like to talk with...
They all died.
Just one brother,
who stayed in Paris.
I love him.
But would never confide in him.
Theater and Music Center.
Do you have an appointment?
With Mr. Russel.
This way, please.
I came as quickly as I could.
It's very urgent indeed.
How many people to board
for Gibraltar?
Two canadian officers,
from Dieppe commando,
three aviators from R.A.F.,
and also two Belgians
sentenced to death by Germans.
Eight including me.
Where will they wait for the submarine?
The doctor's clinic is under surveillance.
Couldn't we send them outside,
a few at a time?
No, too dangerous.
A Canadian officer will want to go into a café
and talk, forgetting his accent.
We will be informed of the submarine
arrival just one day in advance.
Everyone must go to the Viella farm.
Everyone?
It's not very safe...
We are not an insurance company.
On the contrary, indeed!
You must choose a real trustworthy man
to supervise everything.
I have this man.
You don't know him.
He did a very good job
on several recent missions.
He is now in Paris.
To deliver a new radio to Matilda.
- When will he be back?
- Tomorrow morning.
Contact him immediately.
Everything must be ready by tomorrow night.
I'll be there at the last second.
And take a break.
When you will be gone.
No, now.
There'll be no time after that.
The luggages will be checked
inside the station.
Need some help?
Goodbye.
Open your case.
No smuggled goods?
No.
What is this?
Just a radio.
Okay, you can go.
Madam, please, luggage check.
Any trouble?
Not really. Stopped twice.
Tell Felix we need a new quartz.
The frequency has changed.
Alright. May I help you?
Certainly not.
The second radio is in the case.
Okay. Want something to eat?
No, thanks. I'm going to surprise someone...
Hello, Saint-Luc!
Ah, little Jean!
Still so many books around...
And the music instruments...
Nothing's changed.
The temperature has changed!
So I bought this,
in order to avoid freezing.
I stay there when I work at night
or when I eat.
But how did you get here?
Hope you have a permit.
Oh! Saint-Luc is back to earth.
He knows about the permit!
Of course I've got one.
And even...
...and I'm even very hungry.
We're going to eat.
Marie.
Yes, Mr. Luc.
What do we have on today's menu?
Some rutabaga like yesterday.
And?
Some unticketed cheese.
A little butter, but no bread.
I have tickets for bread,
and I can give all of them to you.
You're not resourceful.
You're still greedy.
So I am, but what can I do?
What about smuggling?
Marie is afraid of cops...
And I...
And you also...
It's becoming warmer.
I felt very warm this morning.
Twice.
So many people on the train or the metro...
I was wondering if Matilda,
that I knew only a little bit...
was not closer to me than you,
my brother,
who I have so much love for,
but with whom I share so few things.
I went back to Marseilles the same day,
but today I had a very strange feeling.
Hello Mrs. Vialla.
Your home has become an hotel!
Hello!
- Hello!
- Good evening sir.
The fishing boat will await you
after midnight.
Maybe you can all sail together.
Mrs. Vialla's daughter
will lead you there, surreptitiously.
Perfect.
Am I leaving?
No. There's one more passenger.
Unexpected.
The big boss.
But he will not sail with us.
We're full.
You will board with him.
Somewhere else.
Bison will bring him.
You'll wait for my light signal.
Three short and one long.
Got it.
Madame, we will leave.
How much do I owe you?
You can pay later.
You already told me that before.
Yet you came back,
so you must like the welcome.
You will walk in single file.
Not too near,
but always keeping watch over each other.
Not a sound, not a word.
Keep quiet, I have a gun!
- What are you doing here at night?
- And you?
I'm Mrs. Vialla's brother-in-law.
The nurse?
I'm verifying that everything is alright.
And then?
It's okay, a police patrol has just departed.
Germans are too few and get lost.
So they trust the customs.
And the customs?
The customs? But I am the customs!
I am the only one in charge
in this area.
No kidding!
Get on board!
Good luck, boss.
So strange to think the big boss
looks like any other man.
Here in this boat, where base and
tip of the pyramid meet.
Strange.
I'll have to talk with Saint-Luc
about it after the war.
Watch your steps sir.
I'm so happy to be travelling with you.
I feel the same.
I cannot deliver you all the weapons
you asked me for.
The English don't believe too much in
the efficiency of the French resistance.
They want to keep as many planes
as possible to bomb Germany.
But we will improve
your transmission equipment.
So we'll send you some radio operators,
and we'll help your agents
to improve the landing place
that we will really need for later.