Missak Manouchian.
Died for France.
Joseph Boczov.
- Olga Bancic.
- Died for France.
- Thomas Elek.
- Emeric Glasz.
- Died for France.
- Maurice Fingercwajg.
- Jonas Geduldig.
- Died for France.
- Léon Goldberg.
- Szlama Grzywacz.
- Died for France.
Stanislas Kubacki.
Died for France.
- Marcel Rayman.
- Died for France.
- Willy Szapiro.
- Wolf Wasjbrot.
- Died for France.
- Robert Witchitz.
- Roger Rouxel.
- Died for France.
- Arpente Avitian.
- Georges Cloarec.
- Died for France.
- Spartaco Fontano.
- Rino Della Negra.
- Died for France.
- Cesare Luccarini.
- Alfonso Celebatano.
- Died for France.
THE ARMY OF CRIME
- Antonio Salvadori.
- Died for France.
Think there's a bomb in the pram?
You're thinking of Dolores?
Yes. She's with her father.
You see,
Petra was right to split us up.
Remember, your daughter
will never know war.
You'll miss your train, Mrs. Bancic.
Dolores isn't Romanian.
No, a Spanish War heroine.
Hurry up! We're going to be late.
Where's Alexandre?
Out by the stable.
Mummy will be back soon, dear.
Alexandre!
We'll miss our train.
Will we see her again one day?
Don't say that!
Don't say it.
Yes!
I don't want you doing that
here again. It's the last time.
We've done no harm.
Monique, spare me trouble
with your parents.
As for you, Marcel...
You should be ashamed.
Sorry, Dad, but I'm not ashamed.
Shame is poisoning us all.
Enough of your fancy speeches!
Get to work.
I'll leave you all.
Come outside, Simon.
- His deliveries...
- We'll go together.
- You should tell Marcel.
- What?
About that green paper
from the police.
What green paper?
I know what you'll say.
What's going on?
He's been summoned
to assess his situation.
Don't go!
Don't shout!
I'll go and then I'll be in order.
- What if it's a trap?
- You see traps everywhere.
They know my address.
They can come any time.
- Where is it?
- In my pocket.
Want to search me?
You all piss me off!
Krazu!
Krasucki!
Coming!
Erase that, you filthy Yid!
Then you can lick my boots, you ape.
Calm down!
- Where's Mum?
- What's wrong?
Mum!
Thomas?
I was called a filthy Yid!
I'm not having that!
I'll kill him next time!
Ignore provocation.
Hold your head high.
Head high...
This is France.
Nothing can happen to us here.
It's the land of human rights.
Besides,
all our papers are in order.
Why am I circumcised?
It's more hygienic.
Don't worry.
Dad knows people at the city hall.
Paris-soir, ladies and gentlemen!
Germany invades Russia!
The end of the German-Soviet pact!
German troops invade Russia!
Get Paris-soir!
Germany is winning on all fronts
The police, Mrs. Manouchian!
Get away fast!
What's this?
What is it, scum?
They're pamphlets
denouncing bastards.
What bastards?
Tell us, wop.
Let's have a laugh!
What's going on?
My neighbor.
Go, this doesn't concern you.
I want to know.
Want us to take you in too?
Let's go!
Move it!
"His eyes knew broad horizons
"He was used to mountains
"And had pierced
the mystery of their grandeur
"The animals and birds, trees
and flowers, plants and the earth
"Had taught him the secret of love"
Missak?
Come in.
What's wrong?
They took him to the Gestapo.
You can move in here.
Remember the day I nearly drowned?
I remember.
I must have had cramp.
You were all in the sun.
We'd just had a picnic.
Missak jumped in fully dressed
to save you.
We laughed so much that day...
We'll laugh together again.
It's my turn to save him now.
Thomas Elek.
- You were born in Budapest?
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Principal.
Yes, Mr. Principal.
And... is your family Jewish?
I'm a Communist, Mr. Principal.
- And your parents?
- Their French is good.
I'm asking you what do they do.
Mother has a restaurant.
- And your father?
- He reads all day.
The Talmud?
No, he prefers Dostoyevsky.
Do you know Dostoyevsky?
"Crime and Punishment"...
All right.
Reading isn't a trade.
What would you like to be later on?
A physicist, Mr. Principal.
You're doing well
in science subjects.
But you're spoiling everything.
Why keep drawing
the communist emblem?
- To become a martyr?
- Yes, Mr. Principal.
Don't talk nonsense!
You have a bright future.
I'll be frank.
I despise the boy who insulted you
and condemn all political activity
here. Is that clear?
This place is neutral!
No one can be neutral now.
Just make an effort.
We'll forget this matter.
But I know people
will hold it against me.
Meaning they aren't neutral,
Mr. Principal.
Two kilos, please.
Listen to this...
"This film contains
a host of kike mugs.
"The ghetto
and its mass of filthy Jews,
"bearded, hairy and gesticulating,
"with their huge, lewd noses
"above their fleshy lips
"are replaced, via a cinematic ploy,
with a host of rats
"that flood over the screen
in a sickening tide..."
What's a cinematic ploy?
We'll never part, huh?
Say we'll never part!
Let go, you're hurting me!
I'm Dupont.
Yesterday's prisoners
are at the fort in Romainville.
- Thank you.
- What?
Do nothing. Wait for orders.
With Russia invaded,
they'll pursue Communists here.
- You understand?
- I understand.
Where are you staying?
At the Aznavourians' for now.
Bad. Very bad.
You'll "indanger" them.
We must protect our comrades.
Very bad. You understand?
Mélinée...
We all love Manouchian.
For a long time.
What does that mean?
That he's already dead?
Not here.
The Jewish affairs office.
First floor, staircase F.
I'm here about my husband.
He has been arrested.
Thank you.
That's her.
Inspector Mathelin. Come with me.
You know your husband's on file?
You want to end up in a camp too?
He's not here anymore.
He was moved to Cormeilles.
An old fort used by the Germans
as a prison camp.
That's all I know.
Thank you.
I'm sorry,
but I have no choice.
Because of my colleagues.
I have to play it safe.
Mélinée!
Wait!
Let's take a break!
- Aren't you thirsty?
- No.
They'll never agree to this.
He has to eat to keep going.
Be careful.
Chow.
For my husband, Missak Manouchian.
You understand "chow"?
Madam, I understand above all
that you're very brave
or completely mad.
Prisoner's wives
never dare to come here.
I love my husband.
He's a lucky man then.
He's an important Armenian poet.
Intellectuals share the same cells.
The French police arrested them.
- As Communists.
- Missak isn't political.
He has to prove it.
- What now?
- We'll give it to your husband.
May I see him?
I'll say goodbye.
We're enemies, madam.
Comrades, finish the pâté.
I'm full.
Finish your share!
You must eat, Missak.
After roots and worms,
you can do without a lot.
The Turks raided my village
every day.
They would fire at random,
just to kill Armenians.
So I fled with my brother Karapet.
We walked with no precise goal.
We should have died 100 times.
Then, one day,
we woke in a Syrian orphanage.
Here, this is my big brother.
Well, this was him.
I couldn't utter a word.
Writing poems got me speaking again.
Two tenths faster!
Bravo, Rougemont!
You're making great progress!
- Two tenths isn't bad.
- I don't realize.
Believe me, it's not bad.
I'll show you how to swim.
What's so funny?
Rougemont...
I can't get used to it.
- It sounds like someone else.
- It is.
You're ashamed of Rayman,
of being Jewish?
- Shut up, silly.
- I can't shut up.
- Let's go.
- Have I upset you?
No, I have to fetch Simon.
Leave your brother be.
You stifle him.
When he's with me, I know he's safe.
Go and get dressed.
Know why I love you?
You never know why.
I know.
Really?
You know everything.
Because you're a liar.
Do you really
play harmonica in a band?
Who told you that?
People.
- You're a good musician...
- What people?
Don't listen to what people say!
They talk rubbish.
You're no fun.
Well?
Krazu!
Come on!
We're leaving?
Do you really
play harmonica in a band?
I'm a good musician.
But that password is six months old.
Monique just asked me that.
Monique?
If she knows, everyone does.
Be more serious,
this isn't some damn game!
People of France!
Hoping for the victory of England
and the USSR is not enough.
You must play an active role in it.
Hello, gentlemen. Sit down.
Mr. Rottée, congratulations
on your nomination
as head of intelligence.
Prefect Bard called me
to sing your praises.
We hold Admiral Bard in high esteem.
He's very...
Energisch.
What's the word in French?
Energetic.
Energetic!
Superintendent David,
our nations are made to get along.
Prefect Bard
is stepping up
the anti-communist effort.
Superintendent David
will head the special unit.
Six lorries destroyed
on Avenue Parmentier.
The attacks
are increasingly frequent.
Attacks on garages, derailments...
They even slash our lorries' tires!
I know, Obersturmführer.
Knowing is not enough!
This requires action.
We've managed to keep it quiet
until now.
We have the press under control.
You know our orders.
10 Communists shot
for each German murdered.
You have to sign.
No, I won't sign it.
Stay alive to keep fighting for us.
I won't sign it, I said.
You look upset.
Dupont told me Hadj, Boitel
and Pitard were shot two days ago.
Don't know them.
- They're in Manouche's cell.
- Shit!
Hello, Cristina.
Hurry up, Mélinée.
I have my opera audition in an hour.
Workers,
sabotage German production.
Each minute of work lost
Will save a life.
A faulty machine, a loose bolt,
or a pinhole in a can
will hasten the German defeat.
I write to him every evening.
We'd know if they'd shot him.
Dupont told me he was alive.
- Henri, are you listening?
- Of course.
You're hiding something.
Mélinée, if I knew anything at all,
you know I'd tell you.
Asshole...
Don't you find him cute?
Go ahead,
tell him you want to have a Kraut!
Jealousy always makes men stupid.
- What's wrong?
- Bad news.
They arrested all the Jews
who came with the green paper.
Your father's interned
in Beaune-la-Rolande.
- Where's that?
- Near Orléans.
- A German camp?
- No, French.
That's ok.
It's not. The gendarmes open fire
on anyone who approaches.
There's barbed wire and...
What?
My contact says they'll be deported.
He doesn't know where
but we won't see them again.
I'm sorry, Marcel.
What's wrong?
His father.
Henri. Henri Krasucki.
What did he say?
He wants us to play football.
Very pretty.
Tomorrow,
you won't have a head, comrade.
- Where are you going?
- To tell Mum to stop waiting!
Just wait for orders, ok.
We'll avenge your father.
I know what I need to do.
Here we are in Beaune-la-Rolande.
The Jews seethe here
in less space than in Pithiviers.
In the French countryside,
will they begin to sense
what their race has always lacked,
a love of land and hard labor?
Unfortunately, one doubts that.
If they cannot understand
the great and simple example
of France's granary,
of this land's
rough and ready inhabitants,
at least they have rid Paris
of their undesirable presence.
Mum!
What's this?
- How was your day?
- What is it?
They came earlier, one in uniform.
Germans?
No, Tommy, French. All young.
That has to go on the door
to avoid trouble.
- Why did you obey?
- To get peace.
That's all you talk about.
But we're at war!
They'll be back, Thomas.
Fine, I'll be waiting.
With a gun.
You're mad.
That's nothing new.
I say he's right.
Can I borrow Karl Marx?
"Das Kapital"? What for?
It's a Gothic-script edition!
Thanks, Dad.
Thomas!
I'll have to scarper.
Stay nearby and hide,
keep your eyes and ears open.
Watch everything.
Then go home and wait.
When I get back,
tell me everything, every detail.
You understand?
General Béla Kun!
Still no news, but you've taught me
never to give up hope.
I know you're alive.
That's the main thing.
In the meantime, I seal envelopes
the way we did together.
My tongue is like
a cheese-grater now!
A swollen one too!
Don't...
I'm too dirty.
You escaped?
No.
I signed a document
declaring I'm not a Communist.
I heard about the others.
I'm ashamed that I'm still alive.
You've no idea how ashamed.
I love you.
Sleep, my little orphan.
Thomas!
Been following me long?
Two weeks or so.
Ever since I realized
you had something planned.
How did you know?
I went round to your hide.
I just blew up "Das Kapital"
in that filthy bookshop!
- You're proud?
- It's a fine gesture.
What if they'd checked your bag
at the door?
- I took that risk.
- Of being caught. And after?
- What?
- Torture.
- I'll never talk.
- Cut it out!
Petra is right.
You're a danger for us all.
Listen carefully.
Go home now.
I forbid you to return to your hide.
You hear me? I forbid it!
How are Charles' songs going?
He won another contest
the other day.
The kid's bringing in money!
I'll cut some sausage.
Rhymes with bridge.
Bad rhyme.
Where's the "sausidge" from?
Laversine, a village west of Paris.
I go for eggs every two weeks.
I got two rabbits this time.
Life is beautiful.
At first, they shot 10 of us
for every German killed.
When I left the camp, it was 20.
They're making room
for new arrivals.
It makes you think.
Think too much and you do nothing.
She's right.
- What will you do now?
- Go mad soon.
I'm waiting for a signal.
All day long.
Why sever all contact with you?
They've put me in quarantine.
It's fishy when you get out alive.
They think you're a rat
or bait for the cops
who manage to break
a lot of comrades.
Let's do that too.
Isn't Monique here?
She's at the grocer's.
What do you want now?
- I have a book for her.
- What book?
"Les Misérables".
We're getting enough misery.
She doesn't need to read
"Les Misérables"!
We always need to read.
Henri Krasucki told me that.
That Commie?
Part of the bad company you keep!
Leave Monique alone!
She'll only end up in trouble!
I pity your poor mother...
Her husband arrested....
Deported...
And eliminated.
Don't say that.
You don't really know.
They need workers in Germany.
Your father will be back one day.
Bravo, Olga!
Thomas, drink with us!
Come on, Mrs. Elek!
Six months ago to the day,
after escaping
from the Argelès camp,
I arrived here
without a penny to my name.
I was starving
and, right away,
you fed me, Mrs. Elek.
And you said...
I'll always remember this...
"If you came to us,
there's a reason.
"A good one no doubt,
but none of my business."
And it still isn't now!
- Consider this your home.
- To you and your family.
- A speech, Mrs. Elek!
- No...
A quick one.
No, I'm a good cook
but a terrible speaker.
Mum! Go on!
Come on...
When we left Budapest
to flee the Fascists,
we left many dear ones behind.
So it's natural
to create a new family.
And our family is you.
With you, we keep warm.
With you, we don't need coal!
May I kiss you?
- May he?
- Yes!
Mrs. Elek!
And Mr. Elek!
Tell us about Avenue Parmentier.
No, Tommy, please!
We know it by heart!
So what? Come on!
Patriciu is right. Relating his
exploits will make my poet senile.
Senile? Me? Never!
The boy should know.
Good evening, Petra.
- Are you well?
- Yes.
Dupont was right.
You can be heard a mile away!
Come on, Petra.
Have a drink with us.
You're totally reckless.
You came to lecture us?
Shut your mouth, Boczov!
The fact you fought in Spain
doesn't make you smarter than us.
What do you mean exactly?
Stop committing isolated acts.
They're no use
and put us all at risk.
What we want
is to form a real army with chiefs
and soldiers who obey them.
I'm not against that.
Then you and Olga must part.
It isn't good,
you two always being together.
Wasn't leaving Dolores
in the country enough?
No, it's not enough.
You mustn't be seen together.
Is that clear?
You can always find girls
if you want to get laid!
My wife's a whore?
How can you say that about Olga?
I'll kill you!
Stop!
When I carried grenades
in Dolores' pram,
you all thought that was good.
I did it 20 times at least!
To thank us, you sent her away.
And we obeyed like dogs!
I was 16 when I married Alexandre!
Don't get divorced.
Just don't be seen together.
Know what a partisan fights for?
He fights for life.
For life,
against those fighting for death.
And Olga is my life.
And Dolores is my life.
Never forget that, Petra.
We kill people
but we're on the side of life.
All right?
We're entrusting you
with new responsibilities.
You've worked with Immigrant Labour.
The Armenians trust you.
You're brave.
People must talk
about the Resistance now.
We must demoralize the Germans
and scare the collaborators.
We have to be organized like an army
with discipline and rules,
with orders and chiefs like you,
you understand?
- Nothing to say?
- Petra already lectured me.
What do you say?
I couldn't shoot a German soldier.
You can learn fast.
No, comrade.
I won't kill anyone.
It's a matter of ethics.
Ethics? What the hell are ethics?
My personal code.
It's nothing to do
with bravery or cowardice.
I don't understand.
We have a meeting on March 8th.
Memorize the address and raze this.
Burn it, Dupont, you burn paper.
Think of your mother dying
of hunger and grief in your arms!
Of your father.
And of your big brother Karapet!
His lungs rotted away!
And you talk about ethics?
Shame on you!
Leave my family out of this.
Refuse
and we'll dump you and your wife.
You have until March 8th to decide.
Ethics!
The Special Brigade's key targets
are foreign terrorists,
notably those
of the Immigrant Labour Movement.
Any questions?
- Inspector David?
- And the Jews?
Let's get this clear.
Jews only concern us
if they commit terrorist acts
like other foreigners,
Italians or Spaniards,
refugees in France.
The question allows me
to stress something...
The close collaboration
of our force with the German army
is our main asset.
They're soldiers, we're policemen.
They don't know the streets
or how to tail someone.
We must use that to lead the fight
against Bolshevism!
Remember the Popular Front.
It was a close call.
I would like you
to realize
that our mission of repression
is a highly
patriotic mission.
- Hello, officer.
- Madam...
I'm Mrs. Boulin, janitor,
17, Rue Voltaire.
I'm not the type
to disparage my tenants, inspector.
The gentleman pays his rent on time.
But the other day...
there was an odd smell at his door.
What kind of smell?
I don't know.
A smell like sulfur.
You're saying he's the devil?
Not at all.
But nip it in the bud, I say.
With all these wops
and all these attacks.
You're right, Mrs. Boulin.
- What will you do?
- We'll watch your building.
I don't want trouble.
Don't worry,
the police protects true patriots.
Inspector Pujol, 11th district.
Superintendent David, please.
Hello, Mr. Forestier.
Have you seen?
It's going to rain.
Goodbye.
Have a good day!
So that's the devil?
The comrades are expecting you.
- Am I late?
- No, they're always early.
Sit down, Missak.
Were you followed?
Only by my shadow,
but it doesn't scare me.
A bowl of chicory?
- Boczov isn't here?
- Boczov isn't on the agenda.
That's a pity.
Let's not "squibble" about it.
- What's so funny?
- Nothing. You're right.
Missak,
we asked you to form a combat unit.
Do you have any suggestions?
- I have a list.
- On you? You're mad!
Just joking.
I know you like to joke
but these are serious matters.
Fine, I'll be serious too.
The first name is Feri Boczov.
Are you provoking us?
Not at all, comrade.
It's common sense.
He's a proven fighter
and is ready to join my group.
Next?
Young Thomas Elek.
Boczov will supervise him.
- No.
- Yes.
No! He's too foolhardy!
Petra's right,
he has a partisan complex.
What's that?
He feels invulnerable
and puts us all at risk.
I know Tommy well.
He just wants to learn.
Just trust Boczov.
Fine. And the others?
Former members
of the International Brigades.
It's good, they have experience.
And young Armenian refugees too.
I already work with them.
And the Italians.
Take Olga Bancic too.
You and your husband
work separately.
All right.
And Mélinée?
You aren't going to split us up.
That's non-negotiable.
Take Marcel Rayman too.
He'll teach you to shoot.
I don't need to know that
to head a combat unit!
You're wrong, Missak.
You don't have to kill.
Just learn to shoot.
- Comrade...
- That's non-negotiable too.
Your little brother?
His name's Simon. Wait here.
I didn't ask you to bring him.
I asked him along.
You're late.
Metro trouble.
Another German soldier was shot.
Anything to do with you?
I'm teaching you to shoot?
With you, Pétain will live
to a ripe old age! Watch...
If you use one hand like a cowboy,
your aim is wild.
And you tremble. A gun's heavy.
So use both hands,
spread your legs, get stable,
extend your arms to the target
and you aim better.
Try it again.
Can I try?
Haven't you got a book to read?
Good, you're making progress.
And you?
- What about me?
- Can you follow orders?
Talking about Simon?
I told Petra:
I won't be parted from him.
If he's with me, he's safe.
I hear you swim. You're training
for a competition, is that right?
The Seine championship.
What of it?
Keep a lower profile!
I'm not competing, Rougemont is!
- Michel Rougemont!
- Bullshit!
You do gymnastics every morning.
I need to swim.
And you always need a gun,
even when you swim?
- It stays in my bag.
- Someone might search it.
I go with Simon, Monique
or Krazu.
One of them stays with my bag.
Is the interrogation over?
You want to join my group
but you don't want to obey me.
Not always.
But you're the chief, you decide.
I decide.
Can't you sleep?
What's on your mind?
I love you, Mélinée.
And that's keeping you awake?
"A charming young child
"Spent all night dreaming
"That the sweet purple dawn
"Will bring bouquets of roses."
That was my first poem in French.
Paris is so peaceful.
We've had news from Drancy.
There are 3 convoys a week
to Auschwitz,
a concentration camp in Poland.
I heard German soldiers
have a new weapon,
a new nerve gas.
I even heard they're testing it
on deported Jews.
Can you believe that?
Daddy's making money in Germany!
- A pineapple and two pieces?
- No, only one.
Shit!
It's what they gave me.
A new automatic,
straight from the factory.
If I'd known...
It's not your fault.
We'll manage.
How's Alexandre?
You're sweet. He's well.
One piece.
Good job I still have mine.
I just need a grenade.
Call it off.
It's too risky, Narek.
- Missak...
- What?
It'd be a shame to call it off now.
Marcel can cover me.
I'll back you both up then.
Let's go.
- What's wrong?
- Give me the grenade.
Are you deaf?
Hand it over and back us up!
He's insane!
Let him go. This is unbelievable.
Throw it...
Has something bad happened?
You know, Mélinée,
I always felt revenge
was an awful idea.
Changed your mind?
I don't know.
I've become a real fighter.
It's my first act
but won't be my last.
Once you've started,
you can't back down.
You can't turn back anymore.
I know what awaits me.
Missak! Missak!
Today is the anniversary
of Soviet Armenia.
I remember my father
killed by Turkish soldiers,
my mother who died of grief
and the brother I loved so much.
I'm an orphan
like all the other Armenian victims.
But I'm lucky
because you're all here.
Because you have become my family.
A family of fighters
to confront the occupier!
Long live France!
Long live Armenia!
Long live the ILO!
Good evening. Come in.
What's this meeting?
An Armenian wedding.
- Who's the bride?
- I am!
You can find love at any age!
Can't you, officer?
Have a drink!
- We'll bring our bikes in.
- They're safe here.
Don't worry.
Go ahead, please.
What would you like?
That white wine there
will fit the bill.
Glad you're back, Manouche.
Me too, Narek.
We'll work well together.
Cheers! To your good health!
Enough orders
from London and Moscow.
They never set foot here
and they think we're useless!
What can we do?
They supply our weapons.
A few at a time, as if we were kids!
We'll follow you,
but not the Hungarian.
Which Hungarian? Petra?
- No names, please.
- I know.
But I agree with him.
I won't obey a Stalinist.
- Go on, drink!
- I am drinking!
To the Marshal!
When a train derails
or locomotives are destroyed,
that isn't one train less
for the Germans,
it means the French will go without.
When a power station or a dam
is bombed,
when saboteurs blow up a transformer
or cut power cables,
French workers go idle,
French housewives lack electricity,
French craftsmen
have to down tools...
- Wait a second.
- What?
I'll check we weren't followed.
Hello, Mrs. Elek.
This is Mélinée, my wife.
Missak talks a lot about you!
- Is that lie true?
- I never lie, unfortunately.
- Can I give you a kiss?
- Of course!
- Is Thomas here?
- I'll fetch him. Sit down.
Thomas!
Hello. You want to see me?
I think I'll get
her stuffed chicken recipe.
Sit down.
Was that a password?
No. I need to talk to you alone.
- Did you mention me?
- Yes.
As group chief, I want you with me.
But it wasn't easy.
Thank you.
My only worry is your parents.
They're not a worry.
Are you sure?
They don't want to know.
I told them
you were teaching me chess.
You and Missak make a lovely couple.
I'd like to meet your husband.
He's a real bear.
He reads all day long.
He's read Missak's poems.
He found them moving.
Meet Boczov tomorrow afternoon
at 5 sharp,
at the corner
of Rues Ternaux and Oberkampf.
Don't wait more than five minutes.
Ever.
If he doesn't show,
go back the next day at 5.
If he still isn't there,
he's been arrested.
- Got that?
- Yes.
Watch carefully.
The knight is protected
by two pawns. We work in threes.
One acts, the other two defend him.
I hope this war won't last.
What do you think?
We must fight to end it one day.
You sound like Tommy.
I know why Missak
has come to see him.
I prefer it this way.
On his own,
he'll do something really stupid.
I'm glad he's being taken in hand.
But don't tell him that.
He has to think
we have our heads in the clouds.
See the car?
That's Saas.
You know Patriciu.
He was at the restaurant.
The one on the bike is Cristea.
I led them all in Spain
against the Francists.
There's a Sten under the vegetables.
I know that one.
An English submachine gun.
Every morning, a Wehrmacht unit
relieves the guards at Renault.
- Olga scouted it out.
- A motorbike opens the way?
From time to time with a sidecar,
never on Monday.
If it's there, I step in as back-up.
Here's the bus...
It's like clockwork.
He moves the old lady.
No innocent victims...
And we avoid any unnecessary risks.
We must be precise.
We have to stay alive, Thomas.
Thomas?
Yes...
Why are you up so late?
I told you to wear a scarf.
I forgot. You aren't in bed?
I was waiting up for you.
If you're here, it went well.
I can't say.
I'm not asking.
I'm with you, that's all.
Is Dad too?
He's afraid for you.
No sense in worrying him even more.
Go to bed, son.
Here we go.
Soldiers from the barracks
come here to drink, sing
and get laid. There are at least
20 or 30 in there.
- Only Krauts?
- A mix, but a stinking mix.
Rayman, you're with me
as second back-up.
Narek, first back-up,
at the bottom of the steps.
Celestino, go in, toss the pineapple
and come back out.
- Don't I have time to get laid?
- Or to talk crap! Go.
What's he up to?
Go on...
Why isn't it going off?
What the hell has he done?
- I couldn't do it.
- Why not?
The place is full of women.
I can't do it.
One wasn't even 18,
as pretty as a picture...
She had this dress...
and a lovely smile.
Sorry.
What's going on?
- I'll do it!
- Pull out. That's an order!
I'm disobeying.
You can dump me now!
Marcel, come back!
- He'll pay for this.
- Maybe right away.
Where's the goddam pin?
I'm getting cramp.
You a pain, Rayman!
Some things you can't do!
Like I said.
Very bad work. Very bad...
There were innocent girls.
We can't do that!
Sure, we'll talk about it later.
Hurry, I can't hold it!
What are you doing in my sewing box?
I need a safety pin, a needle,
anything...
Hello, Mélinée.
Come over here!
Don't move.
Let go. Slowly...
Good evening, ma'am.
It's true, she had a lovely smile.
Listen to him!
What happened
to the bloodthirsty killer?
Know what time it is?
I can tell the time!
I'm waiting for your father
because there's no sense
in waiting for you.
You only do as you please.
You stink of drink!
- Where have you been?
- At a brothel.
Stop saying such nasty things.
Stop it!
- Is Simon asleep?
- Of course!
I don't want you waking him up.
Go to bed, Mum.
And stop waiting for Dad.
He'll never come back.
You want to kill me too, is that it?
No, I want you to live.
As long as possible.
Near Chalon-sur-Saône, 18 dead
and 32 wounded in an attack.
In Grenoble, a terrific explosion
causes 1,500 casualties.
In Bourg-en-Bresse, pillaging
during General Dobenet's funeral.
This is the work of foreign
terrorists, nearly all Jews,
Armenians, Polish Jews,
Red Spaniards...
We shall answer violence
with fair but merciless repression.
Good morning.
It won't rain today!
- Goodbye.
- Have a good day!
Police!
Hands up!
This is good.
It's very good, Pujol.
Quite a haul thanks to you.
Their forged papers are a good lead.
We searched that Forestier's place.
We found this.
Not flour, it's potassium chlorate.
Well, I'm delighted
to have been of service.
Tell me, Pujol...
Do you like the 11th?
It's humdrum.
You deserve better.
Would you like to join my unit?
My chief may not agree.
Hennequin?
A good man for the municipal police
but lacking vision.
I'll see the Interior Minister.
A rapid promotion for you.
I'm a chief superintendent at 34!
Beat that.
Here's what I tell
my hunting dogs...
You'll get shot
more often than congratulated.
It's your choice.
I'll think it over.
Don't take too long.
Let me show you the basement.
The basement?
I want you to meet
Daime and Barrachin.
Concerning your district...
from June 7th, in occupied France,
all Jews over the age of six
must wear the yellow star.
They must report to the police.
You have better things to do.
Such as the big clean
planned for July.
We'll talk about that later.
Boys, meet Inspector Pujol.
He helped catch these bastards.
- Congratulations!
- Bravo!
Hold him tight.
- Where are we at?
- Nowhere.
This scum faints every five minutes.
It's slowing us down.
Listen carefully, swine.
We'll strip you,
lie you between two tables
and crush your balls.
You understand French?
The other two?
Resting. We'll get back to them
in an hour.
- I have to go, sir.
- You know the way.
Strip him!
Hold him tight.
Look...
This the secondary track
from the Gare du Nord to Verneuil.
The Germans reopened
six months ago.
We get here at 8:30 p.m.,
we hide...
and we don't move until midnight
when we unwrap our gear.
Cops patrol the area.
Expecting someone?
No. Don't move.
Who is it?
Missak.
Come in.
- What's wrong?
- Don't keep a gun here, I said.
What's the problem?
They got your pals,
Patriciu, Sass and Cristea.
No...
That's impossible!
Pack, we have to hide.
Seine Swimming Championship
On your marks!
Go, Michel!
- Go, Michel!
- That's good!
We won!
Brilliant!
Michel Rougemont!
Lane 5, Seine champion!
- Mr. Rougemont, how old are you?
- 19.
You're a prime example of athletic
and determined French youth.
The Marshal would be proud.
Any comment?
I've broken my own record
and I hope to go further.
Bravo and keep going, young man.
Bravo. Really.
- Do you think Mum...
- Shut up!
Mum!
Speak, say something.
- I'm so ashamed...
- Stop it.
I was at the grocer's
when they came.
Mrs. Lavet hid me in her cellar.
We mustn't stay here.
Where on earth can we go?
Let things cool down.
When the escapees
resume their lives,
we'll serve them a second helping.
Look at those two.
They don't have stars.
What does that prove?
You're right, nothing.
Hold your nose
and check their dicks.
No, I'm worn out.
We have our quota of Yids.
6,000 in Drancy,
7,000 at the stadium.
It's a fine score.
First, stay away
from your old street.
Second, we've rented you a place
on Boulevard Soult, at number 83a.
Move there
with your mother and Simon.
Third, stop screwing up.
And that's an order.
What did I do?
A German soldier yesterday.
A policeman two days ago.
- He was doing an ID check.
- Listen.
Obey or we cut you loose.
You're not Jewish...
Know what Hitler said
in a Reichstag speech in 1936?
He said,
"Who remembers the Armenians now?"
My family vanished a long time ago.
Sorry.
We'll change the mail drop
next week.
Money for the month
and bread stamps too.
How much do you make?
1,600 francs like you. A married man
needs children to earn more.
There's no future in the Resistance.
What are you reading?
"Les Misérables".
- You live on this yard?
- Yes. Over there.
Why don't you go in?
You'll catch a chill.
I'm afraid alone at home.
Where are your parents?
In Drancy.
I haven't heard from them for weeks.
- Take off the star.
- I can't.
It's obligatory for Jews.
There are always exceptions.
- But the police...
- I am the police.
My name's Pujol.
Inspector René Pujol.
You stitched it on well!
- It's ages since I had lemonade.
- Good.
Listen, I'll try to find out
about your parents.
- What's your name?
- Stern.
Monique Stern.
Monique... That's a pretty name.
Pretty like you.
Why don't you arrest me
so I can be with my parents?
You'll see them again.
Obersturmführer Raffenbach,
I'm sorry they wouldn't say a word.
Not even their names.
I know your methods, superintendent.
I know you did the maximum.
The SS could learn from you.
- Don't exaggerate.
- I'm not.
I'm impressed.
Our collaboration exceeds our hopes.
Your Police Minister, René Bousquet,
has demanded
something Himmler never dared ask
your troops.
The stadium round-up
is a fine success for France.
Not one German took part.
Allow me to invite you to dinner,
my dear Fernand.
Clitch blew his brains out
to avoid arrest.
He was a good man.
We must be even more vigilant.
You don't sound convinced.
- The comrades are exhausted.
- And you?
Me?
I'm eating soup with the woman
I love. I can't complain.
I have good news.
- Is it true?
- Of course it's true.
They're well, the food's good and
you can write to them through me.
You can even send parcels. I know
an officer who'll get them in.
Thank you, Mr. Pujol!
You can call me René.
You can even give me a kiss too.
Thank you!
Know how you could thank me?
It's very simple.
We're not getting enough press,
I'm telling you.
- The command is "mispleased".
- Displeased.
We've thought hard.
To keep your command,
we need spectacular results
in the coming weeks.
Spectacular how?
People
aren't talking about us enough.
So the Germans don't shoot
enough hostages after each attack?
I mean the press.
The Resistance
has to make headlines!
The Paris-Cherbourg train
will have 1,500 German soldiers
on it when we derail it.
Come up with something better
or you're out!
I knew you'd be here.
The yellow star's gone?
Yes.
For good.
You hit the jackpot?
You could say that.
I've met someone.
Who?
A friend.
What does he do?
He's in business.
- Shady business?
- Not at all.
I don't really know.
He does as he wants.
- Sleeping with him?
- He's a friend!
He knows people.
I can write to my parents.
- Your parents?
- I even sent a parcel today.
To Auschwitz?
What are you saying?
Your parents left Drancy long ago.
For Poland. In cattle wagons.
Your friend's taking you for a ride.
You're so evil.
I came to tell you I still love you
and you...
- You have to forget her.
- You know about girls now?
- How are your parents?
- They're living in a cellar.
Dad planned it
without telling anyone.
He's fine with his books.
It's less fun for Mum.
- And Marthe and Béla?
- They read all day.
And you?
I'm ok. I manage on my own.
- 45 Germans down on Quai de Valmy.
- I wasn't alone.
Narek told me
you shot two Krauts who were
chasing you on the elevated metro.
That takes guts.
You'd have done the same.
- For confession?
- Yes, for this gentleman.
Father! I was here first!
What's on your mind?
I have to meet someone.
Who?
We've hardly talked.
It's better that way.
I'm just good for making love?
I didn't say that.
Why don't you trust me?
I don't trust anyone these days.
I want to fight with you.
What do you mean?
I'm not stupid.
I want to avenge my parents
with the Communist Youth.
Nothing to do with me.
Ask Krazu.
I last saw him before the round-up.
Everyone's avoiding me.
I'll set up a meeting.
I promise.
Still seeing your protector?
No.
You were right, he's a bastard.
You want to screw her?
She's very cute.
Jewish girls freeze me up.
You wouldn't turn your nose up
at her if she was in your bed!
Ask my wife what she thinks.
General Julius Ritter
is a prime target.
Last year, he sent
600,000 French workers to Germany.
What's he like?
A big general with his petty habits.
Every morning,
his chauffeur picks him up at 8:45.
We could attack then
or in the Bois de Boulogne.
He rides there every Sunday.
The Bois.
I'll get him at the polo ground.
And I look on?
No, you're back-up.
- Which one shoots best?
- Don't start!
It's my decision.
We have to split up now.
We leave at three-minute intervals.
Marcel, go first.
Marcel says
you want to work with us?
How about a hello?
Some other time.
Not very nice...
It's the times we live in.
- Marcel's wrong to be sweet on you.
- You're jealous?
I have to go.
I came here for nothing?
Where did you get the earrings?
And the fur?
- You've met someone.
- I've stopped seeing him.
You're a whore?
He was too good for me.
Get him to buy you dinner.
Why?
Before we decide,
we need to know who you see.
Come back tomorrow
at the same time.
We've got him. Henri Krasucki.
They all come from the same street.
A hive of terrorists,
a real shtetl, Jews and Commies.
All lying low since the round-up.
Want us to arrest this Krasucki?
No, don't.
One suspect leads to another.
That's how we trace the network.
Go slowly, chief inspector.
Chief inspector?
I promised you swift promotion.
You have it.
They're doubling our numbers.
Rottée has transferred you.
Get L'Œuvre!
General Ritter killed by terrorists!
Germany in mourning!
Get L'Œuvre! General Ritter...
L'Œuvre, sir!
"A day of national mourning
throughout Germany.
"Himmler asks Oberg to annihilate
all terrorists.
"The army of the shadows
steps into the light." Happy now?
Well done, Missak.
But you must be a lot more cautious
from now on.
Here's the payroll.
Violence, pillage and murder
are not French words.
Those who have stayed here
have retained a better idea
of French values than the immigrants
who sell themselves
and auction off their country.
Over to you, Pujol.
You have a free hand.
But keep it secret.
Walls have ears, even at police HQ.
Pull him out.
Pujol, one of your colleagues.
Mathelin...
A good cop, a good father,
well on his way to promotion.
But working for Bolshevik partisans
for two years now.
You have leads?
Pujol...
We've been tailing a certain
Marcel Rayman, a Polish Jew,
and he's likely to...
I want proof and results!
All right, we'll make arrests.
We won't disappoint General Oberg.
General Oberg demands
a large scale round-up!
We'll hold a show trial.
We must terrorize the terrorists!
Forget the others.
But you promised to save Marcel.
You can't just leave.
Stay a while longer...
my honey.
You said if I slept with you,
Marcel would be safe.
We've done that.
Did you like it?
If you want more, take care of him.
Mrs. Frydman?
Are you Marcel Rayman's aunt?
- A cup of chicory?
- No, thank you.
Mrs. Frydman, your nephews
are about to be arrested.
I don't know where they are
but hurry and tell them to hide.
There's no time to lose.
You understand? The partisans
are dropping like flies.
Marcel has to hide or he's had it.
Thank you, inspector.
You're going?
Certainly not.
It reeks of a trap.
You're sure?
Why would he want to save Marcel?
Whatever for?
It doesn't seem right.
Run, Simon!
Run!
Wait...
My name is... Petra.
There we are.
I knew we had found
someone important
and sensitive.
Get him a glass of water.
Mr. Petra...
Here are a few photos.
We know this one is Marcel Rayman,
isn't he?
Yes.
General Ritter's killer, right?
You see, Pujol,
there's no need to rush.
Raffenbach and Oberg
will be pleased.
This one is known as Gilles Estain.
Colonel Gilles.
The top commander
with the partisans.
His real name
is Joseph Epstein.
And this one?
Missak Manouchian.
The head of the group.
- No one followed you?
- No.
- You're sure?
- Yes.
I saw two men in the café.
I think they've left.
- Got the package?
- Yes. Here.
Leave it on.
Go and stay with Cristina.
Come back tomorrow.
If this rag's still here,
run and drop everything.
- And you?
- I'm meeting someone.
Tell me who you're seeing for once.
Colonel Gilles.
He's here. He's waiting up there.
Hands up!
"My whole soul is on my lips
"And I cannot communicate
with those I love
"Countless duties
jostle and assail me
"I don't know which one to pursue
"I'm thirsty for science,
"Thirsty for art
"Thirsty for love,
thirsty for life"
You still won't talk?
Nothing to say?
No.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Sure?
Has anyone talked?
No.
Here, have a seat.
Be nice to us, we'll be nice to you.
I'll be right back.
I know him...
Shut up. Nobody knows anyone here.
I'm Marcel Rayman's brother.
You're Simon? How old are you?
Fifteen soon.
Can you let me in?
I've been thinking of you,
Mrs. Mélinée.
Thank you, Mrs. Viard.
It's Mélinée, Mrs. Elek.
Hello, Mélinée.
Come in.
Don't get up, Mr. Elek.
If I don't move, I'll get rusty.
Any news?
Mr. Darnand, congratulations!
General Oberg is expecting us.
What we want is a trial
that will cause a stir,
to mark public opinion.
French patriots need to know
that the Jews and Communists
who led their country to war
are dangerous terrorists
in the pay of England and the USSR.
Minister Darnand
has designed a brochure.
We'll call it "The Army of Crime"
and distribute it all over France.
Excellent!
The trial will be held in February
and they will be executed
immediately after at Mont-Valérien.
My dear Simon,
I'm counting on you
to do all I can't.
Take care. I love you.
I'm pleased.
Be happy. Make mother happy.
I would have if I had lived.
Live the beautiful and happy life
you'll all have.
Sorry this letter is so crazy
but I can't stay serious.
Marcel.
Members of the press,
this is the full Manouchian group.
Take a look at these characters!
Polish, Hungarian and Romanian Jews.
Spanish and Italian Communists too,
with the leader of their gang,
an Armenian!
They claim to be liberators
but this is the army of crime,
vengeance and hatred.
Generals Raffenbach and Oberg want
posters displayed all over France
showing
these terrorists' countenances.
There.
I'll leave you to do your work
with the sample that we've selected.
Hold onto that gun.
You'll need it
when the FFI cut off your balls.
Shut your mouth, filthy Yid!
Antoine Salvadori, Amadeo Issiglio,
Cesare Luccarini, Rino Della Negra,
Spartaco Fontano, Georges Cloarec,
Arpente Avitian, Roger Rouxel,
Robert Witchitz, Wolf Wajsbrot,
Celestino Alfonso, Willy Szapiro,
Marcel Rayman, Stanislas Kubacki,
Szlama Grzywacz, Léon Goldberg,
Jonas Geduldig, Maurice Fingercwajg,
Emeric Glasz, Thomas Elek,
Olga Bancic, Feri Boczov,
Missak Manouchian.
"Mélinée,
"my beloved little orphan,
"In a few hours, I shall be gone.
"We are to be shot
this afternoon at 3.
"It's like one of life's accidents.
"I don't believe it but I know
I'll never see you again.
"What can I write?
"Everything is vague yet clear.
"I joined the Army of Liberation
as a volunteer
"and I'm dying
with victory in sight.
"Joy to those who survive us
to savor sweet freedom
"and the coming peace.
"As I go to my death,
"I feel no hatred for the German
people, nor for anyone else.
"The German people and all others
will live in peace
"after this war
that will soon be over.
"I wish I'd had a child with you
as you wanted.
"And so I beg you to marry
after the war
"and to have a child
to fulfill my last wish.
"Joy to you all.
"Your Missak.
"Post scriptum:
"I have 15,000 francs in my suitcase
at Rue Louvois. Pay off my debts."
Mrs. Rayman was gassed
on arriving in Birkenau.
In Auschwitz, Henri Krasucki
took care of Simon Rayman.
The Allies freed them in 1945.
Mélinée never remarried.
To relate the commitment
of foreigners
in the French resistance,
I have had to alter
certain events.
That was necessary
to recount this modern legend,
to help us live here and now.
Subtitles: Ian Burley
Subtitling: C.M.C.