ARSENAL The revolution epic story
Screenplay by, director - Oleksandr Dovzhenko
Cinematography by D. Demutskyi
Production design by: Y. Shpinel, V. Miuller
Cast:
Tymish - S. Svashenko
Red Army man - G. Kharkov
Bespectacled German soldier - A. Buchma
German officer - D. Erdman
German soldier - S. Petrov
Nationalist - Mikhaylovskiy
Nikolay II - A. Yevdakov
PRODUCTION of the All-Ukrainian Administration
of Photography and Cinematography (VUFKU)
Oh, a mother had three sons
There was a war
The mother doesn't have three sons
September, 12. I killed a crow.
The weather is nice.
Niki.
You've missed your aim, Ivan.
There exist gases that amuse a human soul.
Where is the enemy?
- Everything rushed and
buzzed along Ukrainian paths.
Give back, foe, our Ukrainian boots!
- For three hundred years I was
tortured by the damned Katsap.
Is it about me?
Arrived at the post,
at "Volynskyi".
- I can't go further, comrades. Here is a slope.
The breaks broke.
You drive? - No.
You drive?
- Calm down, lads,
we'll fix the breaks by ourselves.
- By the name of the Ukrainian
People's Republic, lay down the weapons!
By the name of the Ukrainian nation?
Who said that?
How to steer the train?
Move, Havrylo!
Hey, move, Havrylo!
Hey, move, move up, Havrylo!
Turn the piston!
I will become an engine operator.
Who?
- Demobilized soldier from the Arsenal,
I have an honour to come back.
Ukrainian?
Deserter?
Go back, Timish, to the barracks.
The time will come and revolution
committee will call you.
Let us pray to God for our God-saved free
mother-Ukraine...
Orthodox people!
Gymnasia pupils!
Students!
Teachers!
Co-operators!
Actors!
Long live!
Let, let it be!
Let! Let! Let it be!
For three hundred years we were...
The Christ will rise from the dead!
The Christ has risen from the dead!
Do you know who Bohdan Khmelnytskyi was?
One of the Khokhol's generals.
Soldiers! The Central Council calls upon you!
- I wonder, can we kill bourgeois
and officers on a street if we meet them?
And you are Ukrainian?
Yes, a worker.
- We have the congress here as good people do
- the first Pan-Ukrainian one.
- This is that Ukrainian presidium,
which the teacher told us about.
- The representative of the Bolsheviks
is taking the floor.
- We, workers, we support Ukraine too,
but we demand factories, land...
The Soviet power!
Let us see how you will commit
the self-justice
over unarmed representatives
of workers and peasants!
- Well, good, you say that the
power is Ukrainian, than whom land belongs?
And land belongs to lords or peasants?
- The floor is taken by general
ataman Symon Petliura.
- Gentlemen, we have received the
greeting from the Black Sea Fleet.
Do not lie to our brothers and sons,
because they'll see soon your
reality and you will be cursed
by all Ukraine's sons.
Do not rely on the Black Sea Fleet,
because we will be the first ones who will aim
twenty-inch guns at you.
Gentlemen, this is mistake...
I'm voting, gentlemen.
Who is for to considerthis a mistake?
Who is against?
Dreadnought Maria!
Three apostles!
Donbas! Poltava!
Bohunians!
Taraschanians!
Arsenal was listening.
Strike.
The proletariat is cancelling trains.
Arsenal.
Well, lads, let us start working!
Come on!
It seems they are shooting already.
I bow low...
I bow down to the raw earth for you...
And what is the address?
Whom should the letter be addressed to?
He bowed down to the raw earth for you...
And asked everybody
of you whether one can kill
bourgeoises and officers
outdoors if one meets them.
Yes you can!
Bakhmach and Nizhyn are flooded with blood.
Hey you, my brothers, comrades in arms...
Served for four years and was in four wars...
And one year as a civil, brothers...
Petliura wounded me by a bullet,
and I feel my heroic death.
Bury me at home for a half an hour.
I have not seen it for nine years.
Hurry up, brothers, Arsenal is dying.
Hey, you, our battle horses!
Hurry up to bury our friend...
The dead fighter of the revolution!
We hear...
We hear, our masters!
We are rushing on our 24 legs!
- Take, mother, we have no time to explain.
Our life and death are revolutionary.
Armoured vehicle "Vilna Ukraina"
("Free Ukraine").
You toppled over our "Free Ukraine".
- Stand with your face to the wall
so I could kill you in your back.
Can you if I look into your eyes?
And why can I?
Seventy second hour.
What weather will we have tomorrow?
We stopped...
I think that tomorrow we will be done.
We moved and then stopped.
Shells!
Where is the father?
Where is the husband?
Where is the son?
- Where is metalworker?
- We do not have one.
- Where is the smith?
Freeze! Name yourself!
A Ukrainian worker. Shoot at me!
- Down! Down...
You are wearing an armour, or what?
The film was restored
on the "MOSFILM" studio in 1972
Music, conductor - V. Ovchinnikov
The End