ASHES AND DIAMONDS
SCREENPLAY BY
STARRING
CINEMATOGRAPHY BY
DIRECTED BY
Who's this guy again? I forgot.
Szczuka.
And what is he?
Secretary of the
District Workers' Party.
Excuse me, sir.
Scram, kid.
Could you open
the chapel door for me, please?
You see? It's locked.
Get out of here.
Maciek.
- What is it?
- They're coming.
Maciek!
It's okay.
I've waited for bigger things.
Hurry up!
Goddamn ants!
Get out of here! Go!
Quick, they're coming!
The car's coming! Quick!
Get his papers!
He doesn't have any!
Jesus and Mary!
Let's get out of here!
Wait, you stupid ass!
Where do you think you're going?
Wait!
What happened?
Two of our men were killed.
That's what happened.
Smolarski,
from the cement factory council.
- And him?
- Gawlik, also from the cement plant.
Young kid, not even 20 years old.
Just came back from forced labor
in Germany a week ago.
Came back to meet his death.
So that's where
the bastards were shooting.
Hey, call the police.
If I get my hands on them...
I think it was you and I
who were supposed to be lying there.
- You think so?
- Of course.
But that's not important.
Excuse me, comrade.
My name is Szczuka.
So you're the party secretary
who was coming here?
That's right.
I wanted to ask you something.
Not just me, but all of us.
Can you tell us how long
people will have to die like this?
This isn't the first time.
- And it won't be the last.
Does that scare you?
- Everyone wants to live!
We've lost a lot of our people.
Did you know Smolarski lost two sons?
One was shot by the Germans in 1939,
the other in 1943.
And now he lies there too.
And for what?
Who shot him?
Poles?
Tell us!
How long is this going to go on?
I'd be a bad communist, comrades,
if I were to reassure you
like a bunch of naïve kids.
The end of the war
isn't the end of our fight.
The fight for Poland
and what kind of country
it's to become has only just begun.
Today or tomorrow
or the day after,
any one of us could die.
Fine. We understand that.
But what do we tell his wife?
What should we tell her?
It's hard for me to talk about this,
since I know very well
those bullets were meant for me
and not those two.
Now pull yourselves together.
Each has to do his duty
while he's still alive.
That's the important thing.
This is a special announcement.
Today, May 8th,
in the ruins of Berlin,
the German High Command signed
an unconditional act of surrender.
On behalf of the German High Command,
the unconditional act of surrender
was signed
by Keitel, Friedeburg and Stump.
On behalf of the Red Army
High Command,
by the marshal
of the Soviet Union, Zhukov.
So, what's with him?
You know, him.
I have no idea.
He should be here.
Where does he get his information?
From his boss.
And who's his boss?
The mayor.
This idiot is the mayor's secretary.
So he works for both sides?
I despise that.
Is he reliable?
- Is anyone?
- Look. Those tanks aren't bad.
Polish tanks are ready to fight.
- Here he comes.
- Look! Look!
Hello, gentlemen.
- You're late. Any complications?
- No, I had to change clothes.
You getting married?
No, I'm in charge
of organizing a banquet.
- Give me that thing.
- Can't see much. Too much light.
Listen, Andrzej, don't ask me
for this type of thing anymore.
- Fine. Don't worry about it.
- Information, fine. But not this.
That's enough.
- What?
- Let's go.
- Where?
- We've been invited to a banquet.
Stop joking.
Don't worry.
I know what I'm doing.
- Don't take risks.
- Stop being a pain.
See ya.
My respects, sir.
Look who's here!
My respects.
What brings you here?
Duty, Mr. Kotowicz.
I understand. The banquet, right?
You're looking for Mr. Slomka.
- That's right.
He's in there, arranging the banquet.
A masterpiece!
Take it from me.
Good evening. How are things?
I hope the mayor will be pleased.
The mayor is particularly anxious
about tonight's banquet, Mr. Slomka.
I understand.
It's the end of the war.
An extraordinary moment.
A separate entrance to the bathroom.
Very convenient.
How's everything, Mrs. Jurgeluszka?
Thank you, director.
It's pretty quiet.
Doesn't look bad at first glance.
I guarantee you, sir,
it'll look even better when you taste it.
Come on. Let's go.
- Did you see the pretty girl?
- Forget it.
Let's have a drink.
Good evening.
What can we get to drink?
Starovin or Jarzebiak.
Two small vodkas.
Miss Krystyna.
What is it, sir?
That's a beautiful name, Krystyna.
- Stop fooling around.
- I'm not.
Drink up and let's go.
Two tall ones and two chasers.
Very nice bar, isn't it, miss?
How late are you open?
We close at 3:00.
- Do you like violets?
- Very much.
Me too!
Maciek!
- Did you see that?
- What?
Like Warsaw girls.
Makes me want to stay.
- Then stay.
- Easy for you to say.
As far as I know,
no one's waiting for you.
That's just it.
Why stay if no one's waiting?
- I don't follow.
- Neither do I.
It's probably the master.
Let me take that.
Yes, this is Mrs. Staniewicz.
I'll put him on right away.
- Major?
- Yes?
This is Andrzej speaking.
Andrzej.
I wanted to inform you
that the matter's been taken care of.
Everything's fine. Yes.
No complications.
Yes.
Good evening.
Do you have a room
for Comrade Szczuka?
The Town Committee
called in a reservation.
Of course.
Everything's taken care of.
Number 18, second floor.
At your service, sir.
Just a moment.
What's going on?
Did you go for a walk or something?
Hold on. I don't understand.
So it wasn't carried out.
Yes, it's clear now.
Too bad.
All right, come here at once.
- Thank you.
- Do you have any cigarettes?
American? Hungarian?
American will do.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Wait for me at the bar.
Fine. I've waited for bigger things.
- Do you know the Staniewicz family?
- Of course, sir.
Do they still live
where they did before the war?
Yes, not far from here.
They have a telephone.
Shall I connect you?
Allow me.
Thank you.
Their number is 12-14.
And here's your key, sir.
What time is this banquet again?
11:00?
Yes. The car will wait for us.
Can I help you, sir?
For now, a pack of cigarettes, please.
- American or Hungarian?
- Hungarian. They're stronger.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- I'll get your change.
- No, that's okay. It's nothing.
Will you have a smoke?
No, thank you.
They're too strong for me.
At my age, the cough, you know...
- Your age? How old are you?
- Sixty.
- You don't look a day over 50.
- Very kind of you, sir.
Are you here alone?
- For now.
A blonde?
You could say that.
You know, we're always short
of double rooms...
That's okay. A single's fine.
The more intimate, the better.
- Are you by any chance from Warsaw?
- Where else?
So am I.
I used to work at the Savoy Hotel.
- On New World Street?
- Yes.
Just two months short of 25 years.
That's a long time.
- So you were there for the uprising.
- Of course.
Downtown until the last day.
How about you?
Here and there. First in the Old Town,
then downtown.
You know, without our old Warsaw,
things just aren't the same.
It's like losing an arm.
The chestnuts would be blooming
about now in the boulevards and parks.
Blooming, you say? Blooming...
I was going to give you
a room on the fourth floor,
but the place is full of bugs.
Take room 17, on the second floor.
- Thank you.
You deserve it.
We Warsovians have to stick together.
Do you have any luggage?
- Just this.
- That's not much.
- I've had less.
Here are my papers.
- Ah, occupant issued, I see.
Chelmicki, Maciej.
- That's right.
Born in Warsaw in 1921.
Occupation... worker?
That's just to fool the Germans.
I'm actually a student.
Thank you.
What are you bawling about?
Did the kitchen staff
say something to you?
Don't be stupid.
They're jealous of you!
Well?
They killed Stasiek!
The bastards shot him!
Who's Stasiek? Who shot him?
My fiancé, Stasiek Gawlik.
O Lord, let the bastards die
a painful death!
Sit down.
Why would they want to kill him?
- How should I know?
- It's probably not true.
- Not true?
Jeziorek just stopped by.
- The cop?
He probably just wanted some vodka
and got it all wrong.
No, it's no mistake.
He said two people
from the cement plant were shot.
I got a bad feeling
and asked who'd been shot.
He said Smolarski and Stasiek Gawlik.
God, I thought I'd die right there.
I felt this spasm inside me.
Killed on the spot, he said.
They apparently meant
to kill someone else.
Those two died by mistake.
Drink. It's a shame,
but you can't undo it now.
And stop crying.
I'll give you some stockings.
You pretend to be nice,
but you only want one thing from a woman!
What's with you?
It seems innocent people
died needlessly.
An attack of conscience.
You think that's out of place, Major?
Do you know who was killed?
Workers from the cement factory.
The situation is very clear.
There was a mistake,
and it must be corrected.
- Major, I have a question.
- Yes?
Is it really necessary to kill Szczuka?
Lieutenant, you're too experienced
a solder not to realize
that as your superior officer
I have the right to ignore that question.
I just thought...
I don't care what you thought.
I'm waiting for your answer.
Yes.
I'm glad we're of the same opinion.
Nevertheless,
I'll answer your question.
I understand your doubts.
What's more,
I'd be surprised if you had none.
It's a very complicated situation,
but the war years have taught us
that we must approach
these complicated situations unequivocally.
No compromises,
one way or the other.
When did you join the Resistance?
1941.
And what did you fight for?
Freedom for Poland?
Well, is this the Poland you imagined?
Lieutenant, you must be aware
that the only option left to you
in a Poland such as this is to fight.
Where will you go
with your past history?
All doors in this country
are closed to you
except one... prison.
I know.
Now, about this man
who's been giving us trouble.
Who is Szczuka?
An intellectual, an engineer,
a communist and an excellent organizer.
A man who knows what he wants.
He's just come back from Russia
after several years away,
and now he's been named
to the Party's Regional Committee.
You're surely aware of the power
he'll have as first secretary.
The skillful removal of such a man
should make a favorable impression.
It would resonate at the level
of both politics and propaganda.
Particularly now that
the situation in our sector
just became much more complicated.
I just received a report
that Captain Wilk's detachment
was surrounded by the army
and security police last night.
They suffered heavy losses.
Only a few managed to get away.
That's unfortunate.
But if I know Captain Wilk,
he'll manage.
Unfortunately,
the captain was killed.
We must admit, dear friends,
the colonel's wife
puts us at ease here.
I can forget
about the ugliness out there.
- I'm so glad, Count.
- Please, no titles tonight.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
- How's our business going?
- Coming along nicely.
Are you certain, my dear?
I see you've forgotten that in times
like these, nothing is certain.
What a pessimist.
Our friends will always remain
our friends.
That's why we place our fate
in your lovely hands.
I'm sure you mean my husband's hands.
He's going to spare no effort
to get us out of this country quickly.
Then I propose...
since it's getting late...
that we drink to the colonel's health
at the Monopol.
- Mr. Szczuka has arrived, madam.
- Who did you say?
Mr. Szczuka.
Forgive me, but I must
leave you for a moment.
I have to see to some
rather boring business.
I know what you mean.
Business is always so boring.
And yet it's become impossible
to live without it.
The allies will strike
with lightning speed.
I agree.
How are you, Katarzyna?
You do recognize me, don't you?
What is it?
You know I returned from abroad
only a month ago.
I know. I received your letter.
I wrote three.
I had no news to convey.
I still don't.
Listen, Katarzyna.
Towards the end of 1941,
friends notified me
that Maria had died
and that you had taken Marek.
You think I should have sent him
to an orphanage?
I wrote then that I didn't want you
bringing up my son.
I gave you the names of friends of mine.
Did you get that letter?
- No.
I never got that letter.
But I can assure you
that even if I had,
Marek would still have stayed with us.
You seem to forget
that Maria was my sister, after all.
Where is he?
I don't know.
I wrote you that the last time
he was in this apartment
was in October,
right after the uprising.
- And you've had no news of him since?
- No.
And that's all
you can tell me about my son?
Listen, Katarzyna, he's only 17.
I know.
Nowadays, boys of 17 are grown men.
Who is he now?
What kind of man
did you raise him to be?
A good Pole, I can assure you.
I can imagine,
with your type of patriotism.
It's not at all hard to guess
what kind of man
you raised my son to be.
But too bad.
What's done is done.
But he's only 17.
And I assure you that if he's alive,
sooner or later
he'll be my son again.
It was nothing important.
Wait a moment.
This apartment isn't safe anymore.
- In a hurry?
- No, I'm meeting someone.
- A woman?
- Happy?
- Who?
- You.
Me?
What do I care who you're meeting?
- You don't care about anything.
- I should hope so.
- I don't believe you.
Suit yourself.
Then I don't believe you.
Do you have to stay late?
- Until we close.
Really? All by yourself?
- A friend comes in to help at 10:00.
- You see?
I see nothing.
When it gets busy,
the two of us can barely handle it.
Here comes the woman you're meeting.
I see you remember him.
- Of course, he's very handsome.
- Indeed.
- Let's go.
- Well?
- Let's go somewhere quieter.
- What did he say?
- Come on.
- Are you crazy? It's quiet in here.
Well, don't you like this little table?
It's a dream.
Not bad, eh?
It'll do.
Are you going away?
Are you crazy?
I thought you were going to Warsaw.
What happened?
Did Florian call it off?
On the contrary.
Then what do you take me for?
Think I'm the type
to leave a job unfinished?
Guess who's staying in Room 17
of the famous Monopol Hotel,
next to you-know-who.
All right, Maciek.
Who's that idiot, for God's sake?
- Who?
- That guy.
- He's got a stupid back.
- His front's stupid too.
Good evening.
- Your usual vodka and vermouth?
- No, cognac for a special day.
You must have done some business today.
Artistic business.
Thank you.
- How's your show doing, Mr. Kotowicz?
Splendidly.
Right this way, Countess.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we begin our artistic program.
Today we are celebrating a great day.
The war has ended!
And what better way to celebrate
than with the incomparable
Hanka Lewicka?
Do you see those ruins on the hilltop
There your foe hides like a rat
You must, you must, you must
Grab him and cast him from the cliffs
And they went, heedless of danger
They went, to kill and avenge
They went, determined as ever
As always, for freedom, to fight
- You remember?
- What?
Drinks at Red's?
No.
You don't remember?
When was that?
You remember.
Stop fooling around!
- No?
- I don't remember!
No?
Haneczka.
Wilga.
Kossobudzki.
Red.
Kajtek.
We're still alive.
Still, those were the days, Andrzej.
You really think so?
What a life... and in such company.
What a great crowd.
So what?
They're almost all dead.
Maybe so, but life was better.
- We were different.
- Younger.
Not just that.
We knew what we wanted.
- Perhaps.
And what they wanted of us.
Now you said it.
It's simple!
What do you think they wanted?
They wanted our lives,
and they still do!
But that's all right.
We can afford it!
Enough theatrics.
It's easy to die.
- Depends on how.
- It's all we're good for.
- Is that so little?
It's hopelessly little.
You're exaggerating.
You're exaggerating, Andrzej.
No need to take things so seriously.
The main thing is
to find a way through this mess
without being tricked or getting bored.
What else is there?
Perhaps.
Years will pass and ages will roll by
But traces of bygone days will remain
And all the poppies on Monte Cassino
Will be redder
from growing in Polish blood
Listen, Maciek,
I've got to talk to you seriously.
God, these animals make so much noise!
How will you handle our friend?
Don't worry. I'll manage.
Listen, I'm responsible to Florian.
That's all right.
I'm responsible to you.
Everyone's got to be
responsible to somebody.
There's just one other complication.
Don't worry.
The order will be carried out.
What's the complication?
First, Florian doesn't want me
directly involved in this job.
And?
And, I have to leave, quickly.
This is all news to me.
- I'm taking Wilk's place.
- Why? What's wrong with him?
I'm taking his place.
So, another one.
Listen, a while ago you said
no one was waiting for me.
That's true.
Will you take me with you?
Are you serious?
Serious?
Nothing in this country
is serious anymore.
But I've gotten used to it.
If you'll take me, I'll go with you.
When do you leave?
- Early.
4:30 in the morning.
So you see, you have
precious little time to finish him off.
Little time?
Let's see,
this wake will start around 11:00,
and it'll probably last about...
Three hours.
It's easy. He'll have
to go to his room to sleep.
All right, Maciek.
I'll see you later.
Don't party too hard.
See you.
Alone now?
Unfortunately.
- When's your friend coming? At 10:00?
- Yes.
So you could probably
get out by 10:30, right?
You could tell them you've got a headache,
don't feel so well, something like that.
- Miss Krystyna.
- They can wait.
I'd like to pay.
They can wait.
The bill, please.
Will you be able to get away?
Suppose I could? Then what?
I'm staying at the Monopol.
Really? Good for you.
Second floor, room 17.
- Are you sure?
- It's easy to check.
- Unfortunately, I only check my bills.
- Is that all?
Yes, and they never tally anyway.
You really only check your bills?
Seriously, you can check for yourself.
This will tally, I assure you.
Well?
I swear, these violets
smell better and better.
Room 17.
Second floor.
10:30.
I'll be waiting. I swear.
Miss Krystyna!
There you are, sir.
- Excuse me?
- Your bill.
Just a minute, Miss Krystyna.
Miss Krystyna.
Just a moment.
Well, look who's here!
Enjoying yourself?
Forgive me,
but I'm on duty at the moment.
Oh, I see the illustrious Town Council
is displeased with the press.
I know nothing about that.
You didn't send me
an invitation to this banquet.
Excuse me, sir,
but Mr. Pawlicki received an invitation.
Oh, Pawlicki!
I guess Mr. Pieniazek doesn't count.
I'm sorry, but the mayor himself
made up the guest list.
Precisely.
My friend Swiecki.
No! Mayor Swiecki. The mayor.
What?
Why do you stare like that?
No reason.
Though something
did just occur to me
that you might find of some interest.
Me? No.
What is it?
It's just a little tiny problem.
If my friend, Swiecki...
Excuse me, sir.
All right, if you insist:
If my former friend, Swiecki,
should go to Warsaw,
will he or won't he be taking
his present secretary along?
What? Do you know something?
Pieniazek...
knows everything!
Miss Krystyna,
two tall ones.
What about...
Two tall ones.
Let's have a drink.
No, I'm on duty,
and if the mayor should...
But that's great.
We should drink to the minister's health,
especially if on duty!
So you mean it's true?
What ministry did he get?
- National health.
- Not bad.
Damn, I wish it had been foreign affairs.
Yes, he'd have preferred that too.
Here's to foreign affairs!
You think he'll take me with him?
Of course he will.
Shit always floats to the top.
You'll see where I'll be in five years.
You bet I will.
Here's to the five-year plan.
How are you today, Mr. Slomka?
I'm always well, Mr. Mayor.
See, gentlemen?
Finally a citizen who's not complaining.
Please forgive me, Mayor.
I know the editor,
but not the other gentleman.
- Mr. Kalicki.
- Exactly.
I'm not sure what position...
- What are you getting at?
But since you attach
such importance to titles,
then you may from now on
address me as...
As what, Mayor?
Mr. Minister, I'm afraid,
my dear, Mr. Slomka.
Careful there.
Gentlemen.
Well done, Mr. Slomka.
But where's Mr. Drewnowski?
Has he been here?
Yes, Mayor.
I beg your pardon... Minister.
Mr. Drewnowski
kept an eye on everything
and, if I may say so,
expressed his satisfaction.
Where the hell is he?
He should be here.
You want an appetizer?
No?
No matter. But tell me:
What exactly do you want?
Everything!
Lots of money.
- You'll have that.
- Sure!
I'm fed up with being poor.
Miss?
Miss, two more.
- Who is it?
- It's me.
Were you sure I'd come?
Yes.
And do you know why I came?
It's simple.
I could never fall in love with you.
What?
You don't want to fall in love?
- With you?
- In general.
- I'd rather not.
- On principle?
- Why complicate life?
It complicates itself.
So why add more complications?
What?
Tell me something about yourself.
Why?
On second thought, I will.
I lived in the country,
on my parents' estate.
- Before the war?
- Yes, near Poznan.
- And then?
- Then we moved to Warsaw.
- We?
- Mother and I.
Father was arrested
by the Germans right at the start.
- Did he die?
- Yes. At Dachau.
That's about all there is to tell.
- Is your mother alive?
- No.
She died in the uprising.
Any other family?
Fortunately, no.
- Fortunately?
- Less people to lose.
You're right.
What about you? No family?
None whatsoever.
Are you going to stay here long?
I don't know.
I suppose I will, for now.
- And after that?
- I never think that far ahead.
You know, I wasn't sure you'd come.
You don't even know me.
You don't know me either.
Come on, let's go.
Did you invite me or didn't you?
Are you the minister's secretary
or aren't you?
I invited you, but not on that side.
Both sides are good.
From today on,
there's only one correct side.
Rubbish!
You can go from one side to the other.
Both sides are good!
- Will you take Drewnowski with you?
- Of course.
Evening, comrade.
He's a great guy.
Climbing the ladder.
I'll make a man out of him.
- Will I be a director one day?
- Of course you will.
You'll be a director!
I'm gonna be a director...
This way, please.
Mrs. Jurgeluszka!
Poland has blown up!
It's blown up!
Where are the directors going now?
To the banquet!
I'll lead you to a bright future!
What's the meaning of this?
Where have you been?
What's this scoundrel doing here?
Well, actually,
it just kind of happened.
I just thought, Mr. Mayor...
Sorry. I mean Mr. Minister.
I thought the press...
What's this nonsense?
What's wrong with you?
Congratulations, Mr. Minister.
On behalf of the democratic press,
hip, hip, hurrah!
This is a scandal, Mr. Drewnowski!
A happy day indeed.
Congratulations.
Best wishes.
Let me introduce Comrade Szczuka.
Comrade Wrona, head of security.
I can't even look you in the eye
after what happened this morning.
I thought it would go differently
in the forest.
At least we're out of the forest now.
Welcome, comrade.
Please come in.
Good evening.
- Out of my way.
- You won't leave?
No! Is this a democracy or not?
Please be seated.
Please.
You won't leave? Just wait!
Are you threatening me?
And who brownnosed before the war?
- Shut your foul mouth!
You didn't kiss Sanacja's ass?
Tell me you didn't!
- Did you?
- Yes, I did.
Poland has blown up in our faces.
- I'm a director.
- You'll be a director.
- There are still too few of us.
- We need to pull more people together.
- Yeah, but who?
- What do you mean "who"? The nation.
You've been drinking already, haven't you?
Of course, I have.
And you should be drinking too.
Enough now. Hush.
I hate these affairs.
They're for the bourgeoisie.
- You don't like them?
- No.
Don't worry.
One day you'll like them!
Quiet!
Mr. Swiecki,
the minister.
My dear comrades and citizens...
today, May 8th, 1945,
is a great day for liberated Poland.
How are things, Mrs. Jurgeluszka?
They're giving speeches.
The minister himself is speaking.
Anyone been sick yet?
- No! It's too early for that!
Everything at its proper time.
First, the speeches.
Then people come running here.
- I think you'll do well today.
- I think so too.
It's probably somebody's birthday.
What are you talking about?
It's nobody's birthday.
An anniversary, then.
What are you babbling about?
It's all for Poland!
You know what just occurred to me?
We only met a few hours ago,
but I feel like we've known
each other much longer.
Tell me.
What?
What are you really like?
What do you mean?
You seem different than before.
Is that bad?
God, I don't think it matters.
It doesn't matter at all?
- Are you cold?
- A bit.
- Okay now?
- Better, anyway.
Why do you always wear
those dark glasses?
A souvenir of unrequited love
for my homeland.
It's nothing, really.
I spent too much time
in the sewers during the uprising.
You know?
No.
Why not?
I don't want to.
There's no point.
Why?
Don't you understand?
You're leaving.
I don't want
any good-byes or memories
to leave behind when this is over.
Not even happy memories?
Not if they're only
going to be memories.
You have your life, and I have mine.
We met by chance, and that's nice.
What more can we ask for?
What is it?
Nothing.
I think our neighbor is back.
It's awful how you can hear
everything here.
Awful.
Hold me.
Do you have any cigarettes?
Of course.
American or Hungarian?
Hungarian, please.
Here you are.
Thanks.
What are you doing tomorrow?
Today. It's today already.
Let's spend the day together.
What do you say?
You already know the answer.
- Where were you captured?
- In the forest.
- Wilk's gang?
- Captain Wilk's detachment.
What's your name?
- Krzysztof.
- Is that it?
Krzysztof Zawadzki.
Your name?
Turn around.
How old are you?
- A hundred.
A hundred and one.
You have to go.
I should. Lili will kill me.
Bye.
Could you give me a light?
Certainly.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Stay with me for, say, half an hour.
All right?
All right.
It's started to rain.
Here.
What are you thinking about?
Don't want to say?
I was just thinking...
about something I shouldn't think about.
But I'm done now.
Don't look at me so reproachfully.
- It's not reproach.
Then what?
You still don't know?
It'll start pouring soon.
- You want to go back?
No.
God! Life can be
so beautiful sometimes.
Knock on wood!
- It was just a wish.
- Knock on wood anyway!
We're marching to fight
for our homeland
Life is dangerous.
Come on!
Let's hide in there.
This way!
Aren't you cold?
Look. An old crypt.
An inscription.
"So often
are you as a blazing torch
with flakes of burning hemp
falling about you.
Flaming, you know not if flames
freedom bring or death,
consuming all that you most cherish.
Will only ashes remain, and chaos,
whirling into the void..."
The letters are blurred.
I can't read it.
It's by Norwid.
"Or will the ashes
hold the glory of a starlike diamond,
the Morning Star of everlasting triumph."
That's beautiful.
"Or will the ashes hold the glory
of a starlike diamond..."
And what are we?
You...
are definitely a diamond.
Listen.
I have to tell you something.
- Nothing sad, I hope.
- No.
Actually, I'm not sure.
I don't know.
I'd like to change some things
and arrange my life differently.
It's really hard to talk about this.
You don't have to. I can guess.
- Really?
- Is it so difficult?
You know...
until now I haven't thought
about many things.
Life always managed
to work itself out somehow,
and the point was simply to survive.
You understand?
- Yes.
I just want a normal life,
to take up my studies.
I graduated from high school. Maybe
I could go to the technical institute.
What about you?
You weren't supposed
to talk about sad things.
Was that sad?
Should I knock on wood?
God, if I had known yesterday
what I know now...
I probably wouldn't
have come to you then.
You know...
until now,
I didn't know what love was.
I really didn't.
My heel.
Where?
Don't worry.
I've fixed bigger things.
What's this?
Who the hell are you?
What are you doing there?
The lady's had some trouble. You expect me
to find a shoemaker at this time of night?
Shame on you! And you too!
This is how young people act these days!
They can't even respect the dead.
- What?
- Don't you see?
You act all happy,
while two people murdered today
lie there next to you.
Maciek, what are you doing?
Come in.
Where have I heard this?
You don't remember?
I got really drunk that night.
This wine's pretty dangerous.
Alba Seta.
Our first days in Spain.
Grabowski died in the forest,
and Rubacki in France in 1944.
You remember
there were 36 of us at first?
And who's left now?
Those were good times.
And these will be good times too.
I don't know what to think anymore.
If it was up to me,
I'd do something about them quickly.
That mob down there
doesn't represent all of Poland.
I know,
but that doesn't make it any easier.
I don't know how to govern.
Don't even try to learn how, Franek.
Listen to me.
There is so much suffering and injustice,
so many tears in this country.
Everyone carries his own burden.
Learn to understand.
What's there to understand?
German.
Did you find them?
No, but we will.
Some of these are English too.
At close range,
there's not the slightest difference.
Let's get some sleep.
We'll deal with all this tomorrow.
It's going to be a nice day.
The rain stopped.
See you tomorrow.
When are you leaving?
Probably tomorrow.
But perhaps I could still
change everything.
Change what?
Certain things.
Could you?
Perhaps.
Were you buying yourself
some flowers?
Listen, I need to talk to you, seriously.
I think we've already spoken seriously.
Well?
You know I'm not a coward.
So?
Try to understand, Andrzej.
I can't go on killing and hiding.
I just want to live.
You've gotta understand.
I don't have to do anything.
Are you speaking
as a soldier or a friend?
- I don't understand.
- You mean you don't want to.
I can only speak to you on this matter
as your superior officer.
You took this on yourself.
Nobody forced you.
- You're my only friend.
- Drop the melodrama.
You fell in love.
That's your business.
But to put your personal affairs
before our cause...
You know what they call that.
- I've never been a deserter!
- And what would you be now?
You wanted this job.
You took it on yourself.
Don't you understand people can change?
I'm not running away.
But you want to.
You want me to say,
"Fine. You're in love.
Do as you like."
How many times have we been
in action together?
What if you had fallen in love then?
Would you have come to me then?
How about during the uprising?
- That was different.
- No, my friend.
You keep forgetting you're one of us.
And that's what counts.
Now you've done it.
You can say good-bye to your career.
Beat it!
You'll be singing a different tune
tomorrow. The minister will ruin you.
I don't care.
The bastard's going to ruin me?
Life's like a house of cards.
Have a drink, sir.
No. I'll do it myself.
Recklessly?
Don't worry. I want to live.
I'll be waiting for you in the morning.
Remember: 4:30.
No.
Well, then,
I guess this is where we part.
I doubt we'll ever meet again.
Only one of us will be proven right.
See you.
Do you believe in all this?
Me? That's of no importance.
Please buy some violets, sir.
Zoska, go home.
It's good when everything's quiet.
Come in.
Forgive me, Comrade Szczuka.
I have an important message
from Major Wrona.
Do you have a son, comrade?
Marek. He's 17.
- Bad news.
- What's wrong?
He was a part of Wilk's group.
We've got him in custody.
Major Wrona's sending a car.
The porter will tell you when it's here.
Very well. I'll wait.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Do you know the name Wilk?
No.
What did you do during the uprising?
I shot... at Germans.
But now you shoot Poles.
And you shoot sparrows.
- Porter?
- Yes.
A car will arrive soon.
Tell Comrade Szczuka
to come down when it does.
Szczuka? Ah, in Room 18.
Very well.
Our patience has been rewarded.
Here's to Warsaw.
It's a beautiful night.
Time for a walk before my trip.
Are you leaving already?
I'm afraid I have a jealous wife.
Stop it! You're hurting my ears!
Gentlemen, it's time to go home.
Just a moment, gentlemen.
Music! I want to dance!
Are you artists, or are you not?
At this time of night?
Director, please.
Time should be irrelevant to an artist.
I demand absolute obedience.
- It's no use.
- We've never played that before.
No, I'll accept no excuses.
Give me an A-major, young man.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the last dance... in A-major!
What happened?
Nothing. I have to leave.
Now?
My train's at 4:30.
You weren't able to change things?
No.
All right then. Not another word.
No more excuses.
Don't say another word.
Just go.
Wonderful! Fantastic!
And now, a great discovery!
A salute to the new day!
A brilliant idea.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's have a polonaise!
In pairs, please.
Anyone opposed? No one.
I proclaim universal agreement.
Quite the happy bunch.
If we could only celebrate
a Warsaw not in ruins.
Well, as long as I'm here,
you can count on getting a nice room.
Thank you. Good-bye.
Sir!
Give my regards to Ujazdowska Parkway.
How's it going?
Come here.
Give me that.
So you've changed your mind!
- What's this for?
- You don't know?
You only came because you got fired!
Trying to be a hero now?
What for?
Maciek, stop!
What are you, crazy?
He's got a gun!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Careful! He's armed!
- Where is he?
- Come on!
- He couldn't have gotten far.
- I saw him!
This way!
THE END