Who the hell
is he trying to kid?
Hello? Hello, Abbeville?
What? But if you cannot
place them, advise Paris.
I'm at my winds end,
but carry on.
Reinforcements, sir?
Why don't you cut out
the clowning?
- Me, sir? What have I done?
- Don't ever let me see you...
doing a victory roll
over my airfield again.
I thought it would buck up
the civilians.
For God's sake, Jamie,
give your brain a chance.
Corporal,
refuel them immediately!
Yes, sir.
So anyway, he hit me
and made me nose bleed...
Corporal, I don't mean
with your blood.
I gave him a couple of socks...
And re-arm them.
Yes, sir!
Hello, Harvey. Where's Jumbo?
Posted missing last night.
You acting C.O.?
Oh, yeah. Of what?
Five serviceable aircraft.
No spares. No contact.
First we knew the bastards
would overrun us...
was when we tried to land.
But yes, I hear you very well.
Eh? What?
Are you sure?
They are at Sedan?
For the benefit
of the uneducated among us...
I shall translate.
Archam can't believe
that Sedan's fallen. I can.
It's no use. They'll be here
in half an hour.
We must leave immediately.
Yes, let's get
the hell out of it.
Where to, sir?
Why don't you follow me
and find out? Come on, idiots.
After you.
Unless they've got there
before us.
Get that buzzard out of here!
We'll go with what we've got!
All right.
Forget your kit. Let's move.
Get all the transport you can
and get the men out of here.
All N.C.O. S report to me
immediately!
You know what to do
with the lame ducks?
Yes, sir.
Bombs away.
All the yanks, over here!
Load 'em up!
Over the wing.
Flood the cowling.
Plenty of it.
Right! Stand clear!
Into the trucks!
Come on!
We haven't got all day!
"To the permanent
Secretary of State for air...
"Sir, I have the honor to refer
to the very serious calls...
"which have recently been
made upon fighter command...
"in an attempt to stem
the German invasion...
"of the continent.
"I hope and believe that our
armies may yet be victorious...
"in France and Belgium...
"but we have to face
the possibility...
"that they may be defeated.
In this case...
I presume that there is no one
who would deny...
"that England
should fight on...
"even though the remainder
of the continent of Europe...
"is dominated by the Germans.
"I must therefore request...
"That not one more fighter
be sent across the channel.
"If the home defense
is drained away...
"in desperate attempts to remedy
the situation in France...
"defeat in France will involve
the final, complete...
"and irremediable defeat
of this country.
"I have the honor to be, sir...
"your obedient servant,
H.C.T. Dowding."
Air Chief Marshal Dowding, sir.
You do realize, Dowding,
the position this puts us in?
I realize that the French have
been promised this squadron.
By Churchill personally.
He's given the French
prime minister his word.
You do appreciate, Dowding...
that Churchill
will have to see this?
That's why I wrote it.
This is the BBC home service.
Here is the news.
In the House of Commons
this afternoon...
the prime minister,
Mr. Churchill, said...
"What General de Gaulle called
the Battle of France is over.
The battle of Britain
is about to begin."
Eyes right!
I welcome you in the name of
the Second Luftwaffe, General.
Thank you, thank you,
Kesselring.
- My dear Fink.
- General.
Everything all right?
We are ready, General.
We can start.
Very well, gentlemen,
then forward.
Attention!
Eyes right!
Call out the guard!
Attention!
If I have to inspect
one more bomber...
I won't recommend you for
a Field Marshal, Kesselring.
Please, may I finish
the inspection?
Certainly.
Sir.
Pleasant return journey.
The English are not ordained
by fate to be our enemies.
You heard it yourself,
Jeschonnek.
This time he's wrong.
They are completely
finished... done for.
We'll never have a chance
like this again.
Absolute nonsense!
Nonsense, do you call it?
It's a pure catastrophe.
Herr Baron von Richter.
The Fuehrer
will speak to you now.
My dear Max!
How lovely to see you
back in Switzerland so soon.
I came straight from Berlin
an hour ago.
The ambassador
will see you now, sir.
Thank you. Excuse me, please.
Sir David,
I'm again instructed...
to emphasize that
the Fuehrer wishes...
to avoid further bloodshed.
England is not
our natural enemy...
and he offers guarantees
for the British empire...
if you give Germany
a free hand in Europe.
Goering and his Luftwaffe
would like to flatten London...
as a prelude to invasion.
It's two lumps you take,
isn't it?
What's left of your army...
abandoned its weapons
at Dunkirk.
You're defenseless
and just playing for time.
We know of the moves
you're making in Washington.
We know the Americans
won't be drawn in.
Their embassy in London
gives you two weeks.
So what's stopping you?
Look, David. The Fuehrer
is being very reasonable.
He offers guarantees.
Experience shows the Fuehrer's
guarantees guarantee nothing.
What about Churchill?
After our last appeal,
what do we hear?
"We will fight them
on the beaches."
With what?
Winston gets
carried away sometimes.
With liquid courage.
That's what they tell me.
Clearly, you don't know him.
David, we are not
asking for anything.
Europe is ours.
We can walk into Britain
whenever we like.
If you think
we're going to gamble...
on Herr Hitler's guarantees,
you're making a grave mistake.
All those years in England seem
to have left you none the wiser.
We're not easily frightened.
Also, we know how hard it is for
an army to cross the channel.
The last little corporal
to try it came a cropper.
So don't threaten
or dictate to us...
until you're
marching up Whitehall!
And even then we won't listen.
Heil Hitler.
It's unforgivable.
I lost my temper.
The maddening thing
is that he's right.
We're not ready.
We're on our own.
We've been playing for time.
And it's running out.
Silly bitch!
He's calling you
names again, Harold.
I spent half a week settling her
and the kids in the country...
and now,
"I'm bored," she says!
One of your elite
trying to land without wheels.
Boomps-a-daisy.
It's enough to make you weep.
And welcome home, sir.
Undercarriage lever
a bit sticky, was it, sir?
Yes, as a matter of fact,
it was.
Well, I wouldn't tell the C.O.
That, sir, not if I were you.
You can teach...
monkeys to fly
better than that!
I'm terribly sorry
about that, sir.
- It won't happen again.
- Keep your jacket on, boy.
How many hours have you done
in spits, Simon?
On spits, sir? 10 1/2.
We'll make it eleven before
Jerry has you for breakfast.
Spring chicken to shite hawk
in one easy lesson.
Attack, attack, attack...
This is Rabbit Leader.
Are you receiving me?
Hello, Rabbit Leader.
Red-3 on 3.
Receiving you loud and clear.
Right. I'll try
and get on your tail...
and I want you to take
evasive action. Understood?
Hello, Rabbit Leader.
Red-3 on 3. Understood.
Attack, attack, attack,
attack, attack, attack...
Hello, Rabbit Leader.
I thought you might
come in from the sun.
Don't think. Don't just glance.
Look! Search for the bastards!
And never fly in a straight
line, or you're a dead duck.
- Sir.
- Now, let's try it again.
Or, in other words,
beware of the Hun in the sun...
who, for reasons best
known to himself...
has confined his recent attacks
to our channel convoys.
However,
this won't last forever.
But it has given us a chance
to pull ourselves together...
and to train people like you.
As fighter controllers, you'll
be joining an organization...
which, thank the good Lord...
was not rushed up
hastily yesterday.
It'll be a pain in the neck
to the enemy when he comes.
It's the joker up our sleeves.
Now, the R.A.F. Chain
shows us where they are.
The information
is passed to group...
group scrambles
the necessary squadrons...
and you, at sector level...
guide our chaps
to the interception.
It's been tried and tested.
It works.
So don't blame the system
if you're no good.
Now, clearly, 11 Group here...
will bear the brunt
of the battle...
as those of you
who are posted there...
will find out
to your discomfort.
12 Group is our second line
of defense...
and covers the industrial
midlands and the north.
13 Group, Scotland
and the northeast...
and 10 Group,
the west of England.
More than half
the fighter-command squadrons...
are stationed here
at 11 Group...
near the coast where we
expect the invasion...
and also able
to protect London...
which is as far as the bombers
can get with fighter escort.
But I think
we can leave strategy...
to those with egg
on their hats.
Attention!
Please, gentlemen, the Inspector
General has just arrived.
Here.
Thank you, Captain.
Ah, my dear Foehn.
You are well?
- Yes, thank you, General.
- And Falke?
Yes, thank you, General.
May I introduce
my brother Hans, sir?
Another fighter ace perhaps?
When I get the chance
to fight, General.
General.
We have borrowed this.
- Dover?
- Dover.
Those masts are their
radio direction finders?
Yes. Their secret weapon.
Which we captured at Dunkirk.
Our Stukas can deal with them.
Excuse me, General, but why?
If they know we're coming,
so much the better.
We don't have to look for them.
The pilots are in excellent
spirits, General.
I have eyes in my head,
Osterkamp.
I merely wanted to say,
General...
we shouldn't wait too long.
It may happen sooner
than you think.
Please, gentlemen.
Come, Falke.
Thank you, General.
This delay is an incredible
piece of luck.
I mean, they roll up France
and then stop.
They could've come right on.
You know,
our latest intelligence...
is that Herr Hitler
is sightseeing in France.
'Tis rather pleasant weather.
Oh, no, I mean it.
He's on holiday.
I'm not complaining, Minister.
No, no, no,
seriously, Dowding...
the morale factor is vital.
I saw Beaverbrook on Monday.
Now, he's going
to be able to deliver...
as many as
a hundred fighters a week.
Well, after seeing you...
I want to be able to go
back to the cabinet...
and tell them you're
as confident as I am.
Damn it, man,
we've got 650 planes.
And they have 2,500 aircraft,
haven't they?
They won't all come over
at once, and we have radar.
Churchill puts great faith
in radar.
It's vital, but it won't
shoot down aircraft.
I must say, you don't exactly
exude a spirit of optimism.
God willing,
we will hold out, Minister.
I see. So I tell
the cabinet...
that you're trusting in radar
and praying to God... right?
More accurate
the other way around.
I'm trusting in God
and praying for radar.
But the essential arithmetic
is that our young men...
will have to shoot down
their young men...
at the rate of four to one
if we're to keep pace at all.
It's the oil pressure, sir,
but the gauge is being checked.
- All right, Charlie. Carry on.
- Thank you, sir.
Never give up,
do you, Charlie?
Instrument check, sir.
I hope your new C.O.
Believes you.
He's going to be
one of your headaches now.
They know the orders...
don't tangle unnecessarily.
So it's "May I do
an engine check, sir?
"Or an undercarriage
check or a radio?"
Any excuse
to get at the Jerries.
At least it shows they're keen.
Yeah, they're a good bunch.
God knows what I'll find
in Scotland.
A lot of kids with down
on their cheeks.
Yeah, training them
to be fighter pilots...
is a damn sight more dodgy
than fighting Germans.
Well, you've got to earn
that new stripe somehow.
At least I got
three days in town.
Give my regards to your wife.
Thanks.
May I have a word, sir?
Send us back a haggis.
If you want permission
for a test flight...
the answer is no.
Large scotch, please.
You with that lot
down the road, sir?
No.
One and six, please.
- Thank you.
Have you applied
for that post in Scotland?
- Darling, I can't.
- You can't.
You know I can't.
- You mean you don't want to.
- Can't. I've got a job.
What have we got?
What the hell is this?
Is it a marriage or a flaming
air force committee?
For God's sake, Colin,
don't start that all over again.
I knew this would happen.
I never wanted you
to join up... never.
Colin, please, try to behave
as if I were a human being.
You look more like a
parade-ground suffragette to me.
I'm just not cut out to wave
a wet hankie on sooty stations.
For God's sake,
who's asking you to?
We'll be
in Scotland together.
I never could stand
marching women.
You couldn't care less,
could you?
I cared enough
to come here fifty miles.
I didn't measure it.
I did.
I even booked a room.
Three days.
It would be marvelous.
Are you going to apply
for that posting or not?
Left, right, left.
Right, left, right, left, right.
Squad, halt!
Right turn!
Order arms!
Now, wait for it.
Squad...
dismissed!
Come on, Albert,
you're not dead yet.
- It's his turn.
- You'll be lucky.
Twelve pints, please, Fred.
One for the sarge.
Let him get his own.
No, sir, it's not Charlie.
It's some Hurricane
out of juice very likely.
Right. Call me directly
you hear anything.
Well, somebody
must have spotted him.
He can't just disappear.
All right, I'll hang on.
Sir, it's
Air Vice Marshal Park.
That's all we need now.
Jamie, hang onto this.
Good afternoon, sir.
Tell your men to relax.
How are they making out,
Canfield?
Half the squadron
are new pilots, sir.
That's why you were sent here,
to lick them into shape.
They get less warning here
than any other station...
so they must learn
to get up from standby...
in two minutes flat if they're
to intercept the enemy.
Hello. Dispersal.
Right.
Stand down, "A" flight.
Yours?
Yes, sir.
The chaps spoil her.
All right, Canfield, what's up?
You have a pilot missing.
Yes, sir.
Over the channel.
Is he much overdue?
Over two hours, sir.
I thought I'd made it clear
we're too near the enemy...
for pilots to go
swanning around on their own.
We can't afford
to lose them this way.
What's the excuse this time,
undercarriage check?
Instruments, sir.
We've all done it,
but that's no excuse.
What's his name?
Pilot officer Lambert, sir.
Gerhardt, my bath!
Yes, certainly, Major.
Do me a favor. Not now, Papa.
These are the day's instructions
for the Luftwaffe...
- and they must go off today.
- All right, if I must.
I know, you have just found it.
That doesn't concern you.
Hurry up, old man...
because my evening meal
will not wait for you.
In exactly five minutes,
we drive to Boulogne, OK?
Hans, look after Major Foehn.
Good evening, sir.
May I lead the way?
Certainly, my boy. Lead on.
Don't let him
near the wine cellar!
What's the best way to evade
a Spitfire, Major, shallow dive?
And curving in
at the same time.
But excuse me, Major,
my brother says...
a Spitfire
can outmaneuver a 109.
When we are in England,
let him take up a Spitfire...
and prove it to me in my 109.
Done! But don't forget
your life jacket!
I said look after our guest,
Hans, not drown him.
Major Foehn doesn't think much
of the shot-method.
If you would teach your boys
to shoot a little sharper...
the problem wouldn't arise.
Excuse me, Jafu II.
You are to report to Wissant.
- What, now, Papa?
- Immediately.
And Major Foehn also.
I think I know why we've been
asked to go to Wissant.
This is it.
Gentlemen... Eagle Day!
The destruction of the Royal
Air Force on the ground.
Zero hour for takeoff 7:15 A.M.
Our targets today
in southern England...
are the following airfields.
Manston, Biggin, Kenley...
Dover, Hawkinge.
It is our task to destroy
the R.A.F. On the ground.
There'll be nothing left for us.
Don't worry, gentlemen...
our omnibus drivers won't
be able to destroy everything.
Some Spitfires
will remain, anyway.
Even for you, Bruno.
Therefore, gentlemen...
fly in at maximum height
and make good use of it.
And try not to land
in the Channel.
Especially use your eyes
and watch your petrol gauges.
Remember, you've only got
thirty minutes over there.
Come on, chaps.
Away, I'm here.
Hostile 2-3.
Morning, all.
Bearing 1-8-6,
range thirty miles.
Twenty plus.
Height, six thousand.
Yes, Danmoor, I confirm.
No I.F.F.
Hostile 2-9, now thirty plus.
Yes, Danmoor, I confirm.
Recheck I.F.F., please,
Bentmarle.
Sorry to call you in, sir,
but something's building.
2-8 now forty plus.
Convoys?
None due through
until tonight, sir.
Hostile 3-1 forty plus, 1-6.
Better bring
more squadrons to standby.
Right, sir. Get me Beacon Hill.
Reconfirm Hostile 2-3.
Hostile 2-3, 1-8-0.
Getting interference
again, sir.
Not now, corporal, not now.
That's better.
Five miles.
I'm afraid the raid is entering
my ground range, Danmoor.
Stukas.
Get them up.
43 Squadron,
intercept Hostile 2-1.
That was Danmoor, sir.
Ventnar radar out of action.
Who's covering Dover?
54 Squadron, sir.
6th Squadron's airborne, sir.
Too slow. Some of them
took six and seven minutes.
They'll have to do it in two.
Tallyho, Velvet Leader!
Down there on the left.
Stukas!
Roger. Here we go.
Attacking now.
Yellow section, keep your eyes
peeled for the escort.
Spitfire!
Easier to hit than a barn door.
It's like shooting rats
in a barrel.
You'll be in a barrel...
if you don't watch out
for the fighters.
What's the matter?
Can you hear me?
Ventnar, and now Dover's
out of action.
- Our plots are drying up.
- Then we're blind.
So now we've only got
the observer corps.
This is only the beginning.
They won't stop now.
Heinkels.
Make it a hundred plus.
Hello? Hello?
Heinkels, hundred plus.
Yes, Center. Still going north.
Height?
Twelve thousand.
Dispersal.
2 Section, scramble!
Look alive!
Engine trouble!
Lookout.
Right.
Muck and filth everywhere,
Mr. Warrick. It's like a pigsty!
The cooks don't come on
till 6:00.
Well, you've got some
defaulters. Put them onto it.
Come on you lots, move!
You'd be there fast enough
if it was real!
At the double!
Oh, my God.
Section Officer Harvey!
Sir.
I've noticed
that some of your girls...
are now using the men's trenches
during air raid practice.
- It's got to stop.
- Sir.
And another thing...
gas mask cases...
they're for gas masks.
They're not handbags.
I do realize, of course,
that female requirements...
differ somewhat from the male.
Nevertheless,
that's no excuse to...
God's teeth!
Take cover!
Bastards.
At least we know
what Jerry's going for.
All our airfields,
unfortunately.
It's a squadron scramble, sir.
Don't be wet.
Get me the duty controller.
We've only just come down.
We're still refueling.
Don't just stand there!
Get one up!
Corporal Johnson!
Engine blocks away!
Rest of you men,
in the trenches!
Talk about a hairy takeoff.
- I saw Jimmy buy it.
- Did Archie get off?
Oh, I'm with you old boy,
but I've left my stomach behind.
Ah, shut up, will you!
Rabbit Leader
to Cowslip Control.
Do you read me? Over.
For Christ's sake, Cowslip,
wake up, will you?
Rabbit Squadron airborne.
Close up, Red-2!
Stick to me like glue, Simon.
Rabbit Leader, sorry about that.
This is Cowslip.
About time, too.
Where'd they go?
Bandits now twenty miles
east of you heading southeast.
Sector 1-2-0
and make Angels 2-0.
We'll go, Cowslip.
Rabbit's turning port... now.
Come in, Red-2.
Where the hell are you?
Where the hell are you, Simon?
You, lads, pull
yourselves together!
Get moving!
Get another shovel!
Bates, pull yourself together.
Stay with them, Seymour.
It's all right. I'll see to it.
How about two hands
over here, Officer?
Run the hoses out over here!
Put that cigarette out!
The mains have gone!
Can't you smell gas?
Don't you yell at me,
Mr. Warrick!
Here, you men!
Don't stand there looking
at it, you idle shover!
You! Get me some stretchers
and the orderly.
- Ma'am.
- Fast!
You can stand some of the girls
down now, Corporal.
Jones, Whitman,
clear up that mess.
Then you can take five minutes.
43, stand down.
1-1-1 released.
5-0-1 are down at Tangbear.
They couldn't get in
at Big Wing.
Few more days like this...
and we won't be able
to get them down anywhere.
I suppose we could always
pull them all back...
north of the Thames,
out of range.
That is precisely what
they want us to do.
This is the BBC home service.
Here is the 9:00 news.
Large formations
of enemy aircraft...
today attacked targets
in southern England...
but the enemy's aerial armada
came in for heavy punishment.
Over forty-seven German planes
were destroyed...
with a loss of only fifteen
of our own aircraft.
Six of these pilots were saved.
Several R.A.F. Aerodromes
were also attacked...
and some casualties
were sustained...
but they were light.
Colonel.
Good. Very good.
The weather is constant.
We have a stabilized
high pressure zone...
and we'll make use of it.
The proof, gentlemen.
We are destroying...
as many planes on the ground
as in the air.
Thank you, Schmidt.
On the desk, please.
Reichsmarschall Goering
will certainly be interested...
in my report.
To date, almost 300 planes
have been destroyed.
Almost half the entire British
fighter force, gentlemen.
The Colonel can report
what he pleases.
The fact remains...
that our bombers continue
to be intercepted.
Because the English are now
bringing in their reserves.
As from tomorrow, we'll increase
our attacks on these airfields.
And five Luftwaffes will attack
the north and north-east.
But that is outside the range
of our fighters, Colonel.
Also outside the range
of the English fighters.
Not even a Spitfire can be
in the north and the south...
at the same time.
How far are we from the coast?
Everybody, Action Stations.
Tomato Heinz to all.
Another ten minutes to target.
All ready at Fighter Stations.
Another ten minutes
to target. End.
Look! Spitfire!
Help yourself, everybody.
There's no fighter escort.
There! Right behind us!
Soapbox Leader, break it off.
Home and tea.
For once you deserve it.
Well done, everybody.