Seventeen ninety-seven...
...the year of the mutinies
of the fleet at Spithead and at the Nore...
...and of the continuing war
with republican France.
August the 16th, His Majesty's
frigate, Avenger, on a wartime cruise...
...with orders to reinforce
the British squadron off the coast of Spain.
John Claggart, master-at-arms,
royal navy.
Edwin Fairfax Vere,
post captain, royal navy.
The Dansker, sailmaker.
Philip Seymour, first lieutenant.
Julian Ratcliffe, second lieutenant.
Steven Wyatt, gunnery officer.
Enoch Jenkins, maintopman.
Squeak, assistant to Mr. Claggart.
Alan Payne, maintopman.
William O'Daniel, maintopman.
Arnold Talbot, maintopman.
Neil Kincaid, maintopman.
Alfred Hallam, captain of marines.
On the same day, at the same hour...
...the merchant ship, Rights of Man,
out of Dundee...
...bound for the West Indies
with a cargo of manufactured goods.
Nathaniel Graveling, ship's master.
Amos Leonard, first mate.
Charles Mathews, merchant seaman.
Billy Budd, merchant seaman.
- Down a little.
- Down a little, sir.
Weren't it better to heave to, sir?
She's a man-of-war.
Not an enemy, is she?
No, sir, she's British.
Her name's the Rights of Man, sir.
It's a dangerous name for a vessel
in this day and age.
- Is she heaving to?
- No, sir.
Aye. It's worse than any enemy.
If she's British, I'll not heave to.
If she's French,
she only wants to sink us.
Every seaman leads his life
in the expectation of being sunk.
If she's British, she'll want to take my best
men from me, and I'll not stand for that.
Hoist the topgallants.
Hoist the topgallants!
Hey, Budd.
Billy Budd, give us a song.
They calls me Hanging Johnny
Away, boys, away
They says I hangs for money
All hang, boys, hang
At first I hanged my Sally
Away, boys, away
And then I hanged my family
She's hoisting more canvas.
- They appear to be singing, sir.
- Yes.
Are they so ignorant
they cannot understand our purpose?
Oh, I doubt that it's ignorance
which motivates their actions, Mr. Ratcliffe.
Captain Hallam.
- Sir?
- We all envy your word of command.
Tell them to heave to, if you will,
with my compliments.
Ta.
Away, boys, away
Captain's compliments...
...will you heave to?
- Captain, they're ordering us to heave to.
There can be no mistaking
their meaning now.
That don't prevent me
being a bit hard of hearing, do it?
- Fall off.
- Fall off, sir.
I'll get the best I can out of her.
She appears to be falling off
to make a fair wind of it, sir.
You sure she's not a Frenchman
in disguise, sir?
Nothing so adventurous,
I'm afraid, Ratcliffe.
Her refusal to heave to
proves she's one of ours.
But I will be obeyed.
Send a shot across her bows.
We're at war, Mr. Seymour.
Fire the bow chaser!
Well, I can't pretend
to be blind too, can I?
Back the main yard, Mr. Mate.
Backing the main yard, sir?
There's no avoiding it, man.
Get up on the focs'le.
If I spit now,
I'd get him fair and square, man.
Why do you waste it on him?
He's not so bad.
There's no difference
between any of them.
Cast off forward.
And what do you want, then?
Down oars.
All together.
All hands on deck.
All hands right over to the focs'le.
Budd. Billy Budd. Get up aloft again.
Maybe they won't see you.
Men lined up already, captain?
There's no doubt about your intentions.
Is that why you failed
to obey our order?
I never thought I'd see the day when
I'd pray for a French sail on the horizon.
A French sail? Why?
Then the royal navy
could do its duty for a change...
...protect our merchant ships
instead of preying on them.
You have ideas of your own, captain.
I'm not alone in that.
What's this man's record?
- Good.
- He looks a likely man.
What, with the whole of the Nore
and the mutiny?
Who's the likely man now, lieutenant?
Aye, there was officers killed and all.
Where did you hear this?
Aye, it's common knowledge.
We're not long out of port.
The mainland's buzzing with it.
Read the newspapers. They're talking
about reforms in the House of Commons.
You know what that means.
It means the reforms
are nearly a century overdue.
- Who is that?
- Billy. Billy Budd.
According to the rights of war...
...a man-of-war can impress a seaman
from any other vessel.
- Do you understand that, Billy?
- Aye, captain.
You also understand
there's nothing I can do?
Aye, captain.
You understand too much too well.
Are you at least sorry to be leaving?
Aye, that I am, captain.
It's a good ship, this.
You helped make it good.
A man-of-war, you'll find, is different.
- Different, sir?
- Aye, Billy.
Do your work well, keep your mouth shut,
except at meal times.
It's not as it is here.
Now, there's a good lad.
Go forward and get your gear.
Aye, captain.
My compliments to your captain.
Tell him I regret
I do not command a faster ship.
Cast off forward.
Take that oar.
Up together.
God go with you, Billy Budd...
...for it's a fact that you go with God.
Goodbye to you all.
- Goodbye to you too, old Rights of Man.
- What do you mean by that, boy?
Nothing, sir.
- All that trouble for only one man.
- Must be a reason, sir.
Oh, yes, I can imagine the reason...
...knowing the temper
of that vessel's master.
- Well, Seymour, our choice better be good.
- Get a rope down.
Do you swear to abide
by the Articles of War, to obey orders...
...and, if need be, to lay down your life
for king and country?
Aye, sir.
Like that?
- Say ''I swear.''
- I swear.
- Age?
- I don't know, sir.
- You don't know your age?
- That is, sir, I'm not quite sure.
I think 17, 19, or...
Or...
Eighteen?
Or 15 or 14?
- Place of birth?
- Please, sir, I don't know that either.
You don't know your age
or where you were born?
I was found one morning
in a silk-lined basket...
...hanging on the knocker
of a man's door in Bristol.
Silk-lined?
I take it then you're...
- A bastard, sir?
- Aye.
Aye.
Sign.
Master-at-arms.
Claggart, our new recruit, William Budd.
I suppose that is your name?
Aye, sir.
You look sturdy enough.
What was your station aboard?
I was a merchant seaman, sir.
We took turns at doing everything.
You'll have a station here.
Maintop, Jenkins' watch.
Squeak, take him below,
assign him a hammock...
...show him where to stow his gear.
- Aye, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
Well, life's full of surprises,
I always say.
And the better for it, Captain Hallam.
Here, mate.
- Back here?
- Yeah.
This is your hammock.
All hands on deck
to witness ship's punishment.
Best put down your bag, Budd.
It'll only be a matter of minutes.
Dansker, look after Budd.
Boatswain...
...do your duty.
Very well, boatswain.
Release the man.
Mr. Ferriman...
...you will see him to sick berth.
Ship's company, dismiss.
Away there, mate.
What was his crime?
God only knows, young man.
You mean you don't know what he did?
Flogging...
...is the only solution to every problem.
I warrant even the culprit himself
doesn't know.
It was just his turn.
What is it, Budd?
Did they not indulge in flogging
on the Rights of Man?
No, sir.
All right, Budd.
You'll keep your hammock
properly lashed in this manner.
Never get caught
with your bag out of order.
You wouldn't be wanting
to find yourself on ship's report.
Like the lad who was flogged.
- Why was he flogged?
- It could've been for one of many reasons.
You mean you don't know?
It's not for the likes of us to know,
just to witness, see?
- Hungry?
- Aye.
Well, this is the captain
of the maintop, Jenkins.
Right, Budd, this is your table.
Make room for him.
All events, you're welcome here, lad.
Here, boy, take my seat.
Here's a plate.
His first day
aboard our happy ship.
What was the ship
they impressed you off?
I couldn't read it at that distance.
You can't read at any distance.
Don't take offense,
you're in good company.
I can't read either.
She was called the Rights of Man.
You come off a ship called that?
Rights of Man?
My name's William.
Billy, if you like.
Oh, this is Payne, Kincaid,
Jenkins, O'Daniel, and I'm Talbot.
Oh, and that...
That old tar there's called Dansker.
He's Danish. Or he thinks he is.
Dansker, have you ever had a real name?
Not for many years.
Why don't you spit in the stew?
It can't taste no worse.
Nobody's making you eat it.
You can wash your feet in it if you like.
It seems the cook already has.
There's a splinter in it anyway.
That's enough of laughing
at my deformity.
Do you ever bring yourself
to eat this dirt?
I can't cook, you know that.
They only gave me this employment
because I'm unfit for active service.
You ought to be ashamed of yourselves.
Well, Billy,
there's the royal navy for you.
Can you cook?
I can make a stew.
From now on,
I'll be praying that you lose a leg.
Like it, Billy? Taste good?
It's hot, and there's a lot of it.
I like everything about it
except the flavor.
And how do you like the company,
Billy boy?
Not quite what you're used to?
Ever seen so much ignorance
all dumped together in one place?
Ever heard such a din
as these gentlemen eating?
Let the lad be, Jenkins.
Baby has to learn.
There'll be others to teach him
soon enough.
He's in my watch.
Would you have him learn lashed to the
grating with his lesson written on his back?
Why was that man flogged?
He may have spat against the wind...
...or mumbled in his beard.
It may have been a prayer.
To them, it was a protest.
You don't know why.
It's wrong to flog a man.
I...
It's against his being a man.
Aye.
Aye, lad, it is that.
Why do you stammer, boy?
Because I sometimes
can't find the words...
...for what I feel.
Our young bastard's stammering
because he's scared.
Leave him alone.
Come on, ba... Ba... Baby.
T... Talk back, why don't you?
- Is it a fight you want, then?
- Aye...
...for your own good,
and my satisfaction.
I want to baptize you
in the ways of our world.
There was a lad on the Rights of Man
who used to like a friendly fight.
Name of Mathews.
- Come on, Jenkins, do something.
- Go on.
- Go on, have a go.
Well, you asked for it, didn't you?
Ba... Ba... Baby.
I'll get you in a minute.
- Come on.
Come on.
- Hang on.
- Come on, Billy.
- Hold him down.
Steady.
Jenkins.
- Jenkins. Easy.
- Hold on, Billy.
Turn your head, Billy. Turn your head.
All right, I'll let you off this time...
...but don't do it again, boy-o.
I'm warning you.
- Will you shake hands, mate?
- Shake hands, is it?
- You're a hell of a peacemaker, Billy.
- Well, you beat me fair.
That's the first time
I ever hear him eat his words.
And what a terrible diet that is.
Worse than the stew.
Don't you be getting any wrong ideas.
I'm warning you.
- I'm more than a match for you, boy-o.
- Aye.
- I took you off your guard.
You make friends quickly, Master Budd.
Come here, boy.
What was the fight about?
Well, I...
Nothing to say.
And the rest of you?
Mr. Claggart.
Watch what you're doing.
Don't you ever touch me.
- I swear...
- You swear.
What?
None of you have anything to say?
It was nothing, master-at-arms.
A test of strength.
You'll need your strength
for the fighting to come, boy.
Aye, Budd.
You do indeed make friends quickly.
That's a good quality to have.
Billy...
...be careful of the master-at-arms.
Careful? Why?
He had a pleasant smile for me.
That's why.
Make eight bells!
- First watch aboard a man-of-war, Billy?
- Hey, don't fall.
Or jump.
Come on, get up there.
Aye, he's quite a hand for jokes.
Always cheerful too.
Always smiling, waving at people.
Lovely little character. Always...
Afternoon, sir.
Wind seems to be freshening a little.
With your permission, sir.
''Freshening'' did you say,
master-at-arms?
Yes, it is indeed,
master-at-arms. Indeed.
Our young newcomer
seems to feel quite at home.
Aye, sir. Indeed he does.
Yes.
He's even melted
old starry Vere's stone heart.
He'll make the old Avenger
a merchantman yet.
The trouble is I just can't find
the distances like I used to.
I'll take your turn tomorrow
while you stay below decks.
Who's there?
Well, what's up, then, Squeak?
Routine inspection, Jenkins.
What's the matter? Sick, are you?
My health does not concern you.
No need to be uncivil, Jenkins.
Is this sickness something
master-at-arms should know about?
He'll know
when I want him to know, boy-o.
Well, I hope it's nothing serious.
- Evening.
- Good evening.
Oh, it's on a petty report
you are again, Budd.
Well, I mean, look at it.
It's a pity you will not learn.
I don't understand.
That's the second time
it's happened like this.
Well, next time,
sew yourself up in it...
...and then you'll be sure to know
if somebody meddles with it.
Oh, Dansker?
What?
Reading?
How many times
must you be on ship's report...
...before they tie you to the gratings
and flog you?
That's a matter he decides.
He?
Aye...
...the master-at-arms, Mr. Claggart.
Go on. That's all you're gonna get.
Fish.
They're serving fish.
I can't think why.
It's Wednesday.
However, I hope it's better
than that horsemeat we've been getting.
Maybe it's a seahorse.
Here, Jenkins,
aren't you eating anything?
Well, you've got to eat something,
you know, or go sick.
Well, at least come in out of the sun.
Handsomely done, lad.
But then handsome is
as handsome does.
Clean up that mess.
I thought that I said,
''Clean up that mess.''
That's the mess boy's job.
It's yours when I order it so.
I'll clean it up.
After all, sir, it was I who spilled it.
Stand back, boy.
Might as well clean that up too.
- Sir, he's sick.
- Sick?
I'm sorry to hear that.
Is that what you'd like to do, Jenkins?
Perhaps you'd do it...
...if you weren't so...
So sick.
You others feel well enough, I hope.
Here I am, unarmed.
Now's the time.
To make it easier...
...l'll turn my back on you.
You lack fiber, men.
Or have you some more
devious plan for me?
- Some night when there's no moon.
- Don't be a fool.
That's a very good plan indeed.
A plan worthy of pigs like you.
You'll soon feel better, Jenkins.
Just keep your hate for me alive
until that time.
Damn his flaming soul.
I can't stand it no more.
What are you gonna do about it, mate?
Stick him. Stick him
one of these nights like he said.
He's waiting for it.
Don't do nothing foolish, mate. You can
get hung for no more than an angry look.
Oh, I'm sick of the taste of blood, boy-o.
Why is he so friendly to me?
It was I who spilled the food.
Don't you believe it.
It was him lurched into you. I saw it.
I'll ask him why.
No, you don't, Billy.
Not a word, you hear?
Just thank your stars he's still
smiling at you, lad, and leave it at that.
He never did smile at me. Never.
Not even the first day.
It's all right for you to give advice,
you've had your food. I'm hungry.
That don't mean much.
I ate mine, I'm hungry too.
I'll ask him when I get a chance.
I will.
You recommend Budd
for a post of more responsibility...
...yet here's his name
on ship's report again.
These are just misdemeanors.
Nothing serious.
An infraction of any rule is serious.
- Mr. Ratcliffe.
- Sir.
You took him off that merchant ship.
When he cried out:
''Goodbye, old Rights of Man,''
what did you take it he meant?
At the time, sir, I wasn't sure.
Now I'm sure he meant nothing.
He knew of the shameful mutinies
at the Nore and at Spithead.
It was common gossip
aboard that merchantman.
I charged him to keep
the knowledge to himself.
As far as I can ascertain,
he's kept his secret well.
- Must be a hard one to keep.
- Yes.
He was the only man I dared impress,
if you remember, sir.
The boy has a quality of trust.
Thank you, Ratcliffe, that'll be all.
- Claggart. What does he recommend?
- I've not discussed it with him, sir.
- Well, why not, pray? The boy has sworn...
- With your permission, sir.
In this matter,
I didn't think it necessary.
What do you know about Claggart?
Before he came aboard this ship,
I mean.
Not much, sir. Nobody does.
- There are rumors.
- Rumors?
- But then there always are in any ship.
- What rumors?
That he was once arraigned
at the King's Bench...
...on some mysterious charge...
...then volunteered with the king's navy
as payment.
How flattering for us.
Too much of the navy
is made up of debtors...
...murderers and drunkards without
the steady legs to escape impressment.
If it were not true in his case...
...then why would a man of his intellect
have accepted life aboard ship...
...on such a lowly station?
- Aye. Aye.
He's a good master-at-arms, mark you.
He's the best I've ever sailed with.
The ship is yours, sir.
- The choice of men to man her too.
- Choice.
What master-at-arms
is ever loved by the crew?
Loved?
They hate him, sir.
That may be better than indifference,
Seymour. Who knows?
The fact that I command
does not relieve me from doubts.
On the contrary, it magnifies them.
A man-of-war does not come to life
until it's in action.
Will we acquit ourselves well...
...or badly?
What kind of a weapon
have we forged?
Or when the time comes,
will I know how to use it?
Claggart is a force for order, Mr. Seymour.
A force for order I must have.
Sir...
...if he should be opposed
to Budd's promotion...
You know, Seymour, there are some men
who cannot stand too much perfection.
They see it as a disease...
...which must be stamped out
at its first rash showing.
I will think over
the matter of Budd's promotion.
- What's the matter with him?
- What is it, mate?
Oh, it's no good, boy-o. I feel sick.
Sick and dizzy.
- Come on, let's get aloft.
- No, wait.
Get him down below.
Where are you taking him?
Sick berth.
This sickness
begins to grow tedious, Jenkins.
How does it strike you?
In the head?
In the limbs?
Maybe in the gut.
Does it exist at all?
- Can't you see?
- We're undermanned.
- Get aloft.
- You can't let a sick man...
...hang from a spar like that.
He'll fall, sure.
We're in French waters.
Orders are a man on every spar.
Now, get aloft.
- You think I'm shirking?
- Yes, I do.
Then be damned to you.
I'll stand my watch.
- At least let the ship's doctor...
- I said I'll stand my watch.
French waters...
...undermanned.
That's not why you're sending me aloft,
Mr. Claggart.
A sail one mile off the starboard bow.
A Frenchman. Beat to quarters.
Clear for action.
Beat to quarters! Clear for action!
Mr. Seymour, sir.
Here, get ahold of that!
Go on, you lazy landlubbers there!
Go on, get ahold of this.
- Move on there, move on.
- Keep moving!
Battle stations fully manned, sir.
- Set more sail and give chase.
- We'll never catch her, sir.
- She may not have seen us.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Set more sail, Mr. Leverett.
- Set more sail, Mr. Seymour.
- Steer close to the wind, sir?
- Aye.
- Quartermaster, steer by the wind.
- By the wind it is, sir.
Why is that man leaving his post?
Who is it?
- Budd, sir.
- Budd?
For the love of God, Billy...
...look to yourself.
Claggart!
Damn your bloody eyes!
The man is dead, Mr. Ratcliffe.
- Take the body below.
- Aye, sir.
You, you. Thompson, Ridley.
Bear him below.
- The Frenchman's drawing ahead, sir.
- Commence firing, Mr. Seymour.
- But, sir, it's hopeless. It's out of range.
- Yes, Mr. Seymour.
- We can attract other enemy ships...
- I know your objection.
We can't sink the Frenchman. All I can do
is to lessen the tension aboard my ship.
Commence firing, Mr. Seymour.
- Starboard battery, open fire!
- Open fire, sir.
- Fire at will.
- Fire at will!
Fire at will.
- What are we firing at?
Don't question the commands,
obey them! Fire!
Look out!
- Mr. Seymour.
- Sir.
Officers will wear swords all the time
from now on.
We've lost her, sir.
- Give up the chase, Mr. Seymour.
- Aye, aye, sir.
What else do you expect me
to tell you?
Hand in your arms.
Oh, Kincaid.
You're under ship's arrest.
Take him below.
Hand in your arms.
What's the matter, master-at-arms?
These dogs are out of temper, sir.
- Why?
- I don't know, sir.
What is this about?
You will come to attention
when I address you!
May I remind you
that this ship is at war?
This is a wartime cruise.
We sail under the Articles of War.
Volunteer or impressed man,
veteran, seaman, or recruit...
...you are no longer civilians but sailors.
A crew that I shall mold into a weapon.
One lawless act...
...one spurt of rebel temper
from any one of you...
...high or low...
...I shall pay you out
in coin you know of.
You have only two duties here:
To fight and to obey.
And I will bend
each contumacious spirit...
...each stiff-neck,
prideful soul of you...
...or crush you...
...if I must.
Abide by the Articles of War
and my commands...
...or they will cut you down.
Now choose.
Kincaid, you shouted. Why?
Why did Jenkins fall, sir?
Master-at-arms, that accident, the man
who fell upon the deck from the yardarm...
...do you know how this occurred?
- I do not, sir.
You were his messmates.
Does any man here
know how this occurred?
You?
No, sir.
Boy, you left your post. Why?
I knew that Jenkins was sick, sir.
I saw him sway.
You knew he was sick?
Mr. Claggart,
did you send a sick man aloft?
He said he was.
But when I questioned him,
he changed his mind...
...and went to stand his watch.
But that's not the way it happened,
Mr. Claggart. Don't you remember?
That is the way it happened, sir.
I see.
Hand in your arms.
Take him below.
We therefore commit his body
to the deep...
...to be turned into corruption.
Looking for the resurrection
of the body...
...when the sea shall give up her dead.
- The sea shall give up her dead.
- And the corruptible bodies...
...of those who sleep in him...
...shall be changed...
...and...
...and made like unto his glorious body...
...according to the mighty working...
...whereby he is able...
...to subdue all things...
...unto himself.
- Amen.
Ship's company, dismiss!
Well, that's the end of Enoch Jenkins.
Over the side he goes
and his mates soon forget him.
They'll not forget him so soon,
I'm thinking.
Whatever's happened to Jenkins,
he ain't worried none.
He's got a hundred fathoms
between him...
...and the troubles of this life.
I'd rather be buried at sea
than on the shore...
...when I come to die.
Will you stand by the plank, mates...
...so I can shake a friendly hand
before I sink?
Budd...
...Captain Vere wishes to see you.
Come in.
Seaman Budd, sir.
- You sent for me, sir?
- Yes, Budd.
Your divisional officer recommends you
for a post of more responsibility.
He thinks you can perform duties
of a higher station, and so do I.
The spirit you showed last night
warrants it.
From now on,
you're captain of the foretop.
Yes, that's a real honor
for a man so new aboard.
You can trust me, sir.
I do.
Very well. That's all.
Aye, aye, sir. Thanks.
Captain Vere, sir...
...with your permission.
- Yes?
You must be aware, sir,
that Budd is...
Well...
It's unlike you to falter, Mr. Claggart.
He has been aboard such a short time.
Long enough to prove himself to me.
He left his station last night.
In a good cause no doubt, master-at-arms.
He showed initiative.
The captaincy of the foretop is his reward.
With your permission, sir.
Will there not be some dissatisfaction
among those...
...who've been aboard
much longer than Budd?
Oh, master-at-arms,
I concern myself with these matters.
They're really none of your function.
Until such a time as the senior topmen
formally object to Budd for incapacity...
...and for no other reason whatsoever...
...he is captain of the foretop.
Make it so on the bill.
- Captain Vere, sir, with your permission.
- What?
In the matter of Kincaid,
the man who shouted from the mast.
It was a serious breach of ship's discipline
while engaging the enemy.
What punishment do you recommend?
Ten lashes.
It was while engaging the enemy.
- Mr. Claggart.
- Aye, sir.
Do you consider the sentence just?
May I speak freely, sir?
I do not ask questions
in order to get insincere answers.
Ten lashes would seem to me
a mild sentence...
...under peacetime conditions.
A hundred would, to my mind,
be appropriate.
A hundred?
We must serve the law, sir...
...or give up the right
and privilege of service.
It is only within that law that we may
use our discretions according to our rank.
You are so lucid and so intelligent
for the rank you hold, master-at-arms.
I thank you, sir.
Yes. That's no flattery, Mr. Claggart,
it's a melancholy fact.
It's sad to see such qualities of mind
bent to such a sorry purpose.
What's the reason for it?
I am what I am, sir...
...and what the world has made me.
- The world?
The world demands
that behind every peacemaker...
...there be the gun,
the gallows, the jail.
Do you think it will always be so?
- I have no reason not to, sir.
- You live without hope.
I live.
But remember, Mr. Claggart...
...that even the man
who wields the whip...
...cannot defy the code we must obey...
...and not be broken by it.
- That'll be all.
- Aye, sir.
With your permission, sir.
Is it still to be 10 lashes?
It is.
One...
...two...
...three...
...four...
...five...
...six...
...seven...
...eight...
...nine...
...10.
Release the prisoner.
Dismiss ship's company, please,
Mr. Seymour.
Ship's company, dismiss.
I expect the French will be putting us
to our stations any hour now.
Aye.
In the question of Jenkins...
...Budd was telling the truth.
- I know, sir.
What are you going to do
about Claggart?
What can I do but watch and wait?
No court-martial would do more than
strip him of his rank for such misconduct.
And then what? As a rating,
he'd be slaughtered by the other men.
And who would replace him?
Would the French refrain from attacking us
while we settled our petty differences?
No, l...
I must give him his head until some act
puts him squarely counter to the law...
...and then let the law consume him.
What would you do
if you were captain of this ship?
I'm not captain of this ship, sir.
One day you may be, Philip.
And then?
Remember.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
Will it be all right if I stay topside a bit
to watch the water?
I suppose the handsome sailor may do
many things forbidden to his messmates.
The sea's calm by night, isn't it?
Calm and peaceful.
You've made a good impression
on the captain, Billy Budd.
You have a pleasant way with you.
Thank you, sir.
If you wish to make a good impression
on me too, however...
...you will need to curb your tongue.
- Now, sir?
Not now.
Can it be that you really don't
understand my words?
Is it ignorance or irony...
...that makes you speak so simply?
It must be ignorance, sir...
...because I don't understand
the other word.
Let us see which it is.
Tell me, without fear, if you can...
...what do you think of me?
I never met a man like you before.
You blame me for Jenkins' death.
You must have had a reason
for doing what you did.
If you thought I had a reason...
...why did you contradict my words
before the captain?
In my ignorance, sir,
I could not guess the reason.
I only knew the truth and told it.
The sea is calm, you said...
...peaceful.
Calm above...
...but below,
a world of gliding monsters...
...preying on their fellows.
Murderers, all of them.
Only the strongest teeth survive.
And who's to tell me it's any different
here onboard, or yonder...
...on dry land?
You knew my reputation...
...and yet you dared to speak
what you call the truth. Why?
I know some of the men
are fearful of you, hate you...
...but I told them,
you can't be as they think you are.
Why not, pray?
No man can take pleasure in cruelty.
No?
Tell me, do you fear the lash?
Aye.
And will you speak the truth again?
I'm on my honor, sir,
if the captain asks.
Why are you laughing, boy?
Laughter's good, sir.
And it's good to hear you laugh.
Laughter's good?
Even the laughter of fools,
aimed at nothing?
No, sir. You didn't laugh at nothing.
What did I laugh at, then?
I don't know, sir...
...but I think you were laughing
at yourself.
Why should I laugh at myself?
There's times when all men do,
men as you can call men.
They make mistakes...
...behave like fools.
- They do?
Tell me in all ignorance,
do you dare understand me, then?
I think so, sir.
Why did Jenkins die?
- You did not wish his death.
- No, I did not.
You didn't even hate him.
I think that sometimes
you hate yourself.
I was thinking, sir...
...the nights are lonely.
Perhaps I could talk to you
between watches...
...when you've nothing else to do.
Loneliness.
What do you know of loneliness?
Them's alone as want to be.
Nights are long...
...conversation helps pass the time.
Can I talk to you again, then?
It would mean a lot to me.
Perhaps to me too.
Oh, no.
You would charm me too, huh?
Get away.
Sir?
Master-at-arms.
Mr. Claggart, sir?
What's the ''Get thee behind me'' for?
Which of us is Satan, then?
Why, I'm not ambitious.
Well?
I can't find nothing wrong
with Budd's gear.
All stowed perfect.
Well, disarrange it, man.
You've done it before.
I was nearly caught.
Two of his mates woke up.
Be more careful.
I want him on report,
now more than ever.
- Do as you wish.
- Well, it's not easy.
How's your gear, Squeak?
All stowed perfect?
Moon's in and out tonight.
There's a storm somewhere.
Aye, old man.
Well...
...I have my watch to do.
Billy.
Slip into the lee forechains.
There's something in the wind.
- What you...?
- No, no, no. Don't speak here.
I'll meet you there.
We'll have to talk quickish, Billy.
The dawn'll be on us
before you can say ''mutiny.''
What is it you want? It's cold it is
and against the rules to be up here.
I saw you and Claggart talking.
I don't know what was said, not liking
to listen to other folks' conversations...
...but if it's buttering him up you are,
beware.
I tried that.
I was frightened of him.
Well, that's how I began, see?
I talked to him one night,
and after that, I was his slave.
I amused him, see?
Something about me amuses him.
There's nothing I can do about it.
Anyway, I started spying on people
for him and the like.
Only to escape the lash.
Well, a man can't help
being frightened, can he?
I mean, it's human in some of us.
Every time he laughs at me,
I know I'm safe.
Until the next time, that is.
It's only old Dansker
passing away his watch.
Hey. You know when you kept
finding yourself on report?
Well, that was my doing.
Yeah, but I was only obeying orders.
His orders, Claggart's.
Claggart's?
- I thought it was you, out of spite.
- Me?
But I got no spite in me.
Now, take tonight. I'm supposed to
get you on report again, see?
I was sent by Claggart
to steal your kit while you was asleep.
Instead, I woke you up.
My conscience
wouldn't permit me to obey...
...whatever the consequences.
I said to myself:
''You can't do this to Billy. Not this.''
I ought to thank you, then,
didn't I?
No. No, no, I'm a human being,
that's all. Same as the next man.
I want no thanks.
I can't help being a coward though.
That's my trouble.
I hate Claggart.
That's what he don't realize.
I hate him.
- You hate him?
- Yes, I do.
Don't you?
No.
- You don't?
- No.
You must do.
Why has the old man stopped singing?
Get away, old man.
Aye, I'll leave you in the dark, Kincaid...
...but think again.
Well, even though
you don't hate him, Billy...
...there's many as does,
and they need your help.
They came to me and they said,
''Do you think Billy'll help us? ''
I said, ''Well, I've never known him
not to help them in need.''
What do you want me to do?
Tomorrow night...
...talk to Claggart as you did tonight,
with his back to the deck.
Now, that's important.
- The lads will do the rest.
- The rest?
That's a lovely knife you got there.
What...?
Damn. I don't know what you mean.
Forget I even talked to you.
- You better go back where you belong.
- Yeah, I'm going.
If you don't start,
I'll toss you back over the rail.
I never said nothing.
- Well?
- Well, what?
I heard you muttering with him
down by the forechains.
I tried something new,
something you once suggested.
I told him some of the lads was out
to kill you and tried to get him to join in.
- And?
- He wouldn't do it.
Fool. Blithering idiot.
You didn't tempt him right.
You made mistakes.
- No.
- You were too obvious.
- Weren't you?
- No, I did as you suggested.
I tried to be subtle.
I told him
how much I hated you.
He didn't let forth one hint
that he agreed with you?
No, sir. No, master-at-arms.
Not one word.
Mr. Claggart, we done enough to him.
He's a good lad, sir.
Couldn't it be someone else?
Kincaid, maybe?
So he's softened your heart too, huh?
I'll see your back laid raw
with the flogging whip.
- No. No.
- Quiet.
Yeah.
He hates you, does Billy Budd.
He wants your life
like the rest of them.
You swear it?
I swear it...
...on my oath.
I knew it.
Why don't you go to Mr. Seymour...
...or to the captain?
Then I'd be an informer.
No, no, Dansker, I can't.
It's Kincaid.
Leave him be.
- No.
- Leave him be, Billy Budd.
Kincaid.
What are you doing topside?
You're after Mr. Claggart.
- Well?
- It's wrong, Kincaid. He knows.
- He's waiting for you.
- No more than I'm waiting for him.
Get out of my way, lad,
and let me do it.
No, I won't let you hang yourself.
I don't give a fiddler's damn
what happens to me.
Out of my way, lad.
Give me that knife.
Billy, you're a nice boy,
but I'm not playing.
This is no game for boys.
Damn me, I won't let you hang yourself.
The moon's under now.
Sweet mother of God,
will you let me go?
No.
Oh, my back.
Explain this.
It was nothing, sir.
- An argument.
- An argument?
- Whose knife is this?
- Mine, sir.
Truth, boy.
Truth.
Isn't that the course
by which you steer?
Or am I wrong?
That's not the way it happened.
That's what you told captain
when Jenkins slipped from carelessness.
There are many ways to lie,
Mr. Claggart.
But there is only one way
to tell the truth.
Jenkins was unfit.
Unfit?
Well, here's another one that's unfit.
Up man. On your feet.
I've been expecting you, Kincaid.
Why did you try to stop him?
Why should I want you...?
Killed?
''Why should I want you killed? ''
What's the disturbance there?
You there, forward.
- Master-at-arms reports all in order, sir.
- Stand where you are.
Say nothing to this officer.
Come on, up. On your feet.
What's the matter, master-at-arms?
It's an odd hour for stargazing.
A slight matter, sir.
I found these men together here on deck,
contrary to captain's orders.
I was sending them below
when you called out.
Surely there's more to it than that.
The story's lame, man. What occurred?
Your knife, master-at-arms?
William Budd's, sir, I believe.
Return it to him.
You reported all in order, master-at-arms.
I'll take your word for it.
Consequently, I do not wish to see
either of their names...
...on ship's report tomorrow.
- Sir...
...I feel that l...
- Either all is in order or it is not.
If it is not,
I wish to know about it now.
There is no reason for these men's names
to be on ship's report, sir.
Good.
Thank you. Good night.
Get below.
Both of you.
- More sail please, Mr. Ratcliffe.
- The glass is falling, sir.
Our mission is to join the fleet.
More sail, Mr. Ratcliffe.
- Aye, sir.
- Morning, master-at-arms.
- Battle stations fully manned.
- Carry on.
With your permission, sir, I would
like to speak to you in private.
If this is not a matter
of grave concern...
...l'd rather...
- It is of grave concern, sir.
Set the topgallants!
Very well.
- I'll be in my cabin, Mr. Wyatt.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Well, master-at-arms, be brief
if you will. I'm required on deck.
Last night, when on my rounds...
...discovering Budd's hammock
was unused...
...I combed the ship and found him
in conclave with several growlers.
Men who, like himself, spread unrest
and rebellion among the crew.
- Budd spreads rebellion?
- Aye, sir.
- An accusation, I take it.
Ratcliffe.
- Oh, Captain Hallam.
- Sir.
Would you bring Budd,
the captain of the foretop?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
They were collected here,
near the lee forechains...
...and when I ordered them below,
young Budd and others threatened me...
...and swore they'd drop me
and officers they hate overboard...
...on some misty night.
Should you desire substantial proof, sir,
it is not far.
Weigh what you speak.
There is the rope and the yardarm
for false witness, in peace as in war.
- I understand, sir.
- I am glad to hear it.
- Budd, sir.
- Bring him in.
Very good, sir.
Come in, Budd.
Captain, see that we're not disturbed,
if you will.
- Very good, sir.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Tell this man to his face
what you told me.
Certainly, sir.
I said this man, this William Budd...
...acting so out of angry resentment against
impressment and against his officers...
...against this ship,
this service, and the king...
...heads in the crew a spirit of rebellion
against the officers, the mates and me.
And urges them
to the outrage of mutiny.
This very night,
I surprised him in the forechain...
...and both saw and heard him
conspire with known malingerers...
...and men who continually growl
about unfair pay...
...mistreatment, the lack of shore leave,
and similar complaints.
I have the names of the others involved
in this sinister plot. The man Kincaid...
...the old sailor
who goes by the name of Dansker...
...and regrettably,
my own hitherto trusted corporal.
But there is no doubt in my mind...
...that Budd is their ringleader.
I say this man
threatened his officers with murder...
...and was bent tonight in urging
other men to act concertedly in mutiny.
I have nothing further to say
at this time, sir.
Speak, Budd.
- Defend yourself, Budd.
- I'm...
Take your time.
Take your time, there's no hurry.
May I add, sir...
...I am as surprised as you seem to be
at Budd's complicity in this...
...as I'd hitherto shared
your high opinion of him.
Give the lad his chance.
You've made your accusation.
It's up to him to defend himself.
- With all due respect, sir...
- Mr. Claggart.
- I don't think he can.
It's not so much
that he can't find the words...
...as that there are no words to find.
- Mr. Claggart, I told you...!
Ca... Captain.
Seymour?
Go in there until I call you.
- Captain Hallam.
- Yes, sir?
Forgive me for imposing
upon you again.
Do you think you could
call the surgeon to come?
The surgeon, sir?
- I do hope, sir, that you are not...
- No, no.
- Nothing.
- Very good, sir.
Good morning, sir.
I trust I find you in good health.
How is it with this man?
Is it so, then?
I thought it.
- Verify it.
- The man is dead, sir.
- But is that possible? One blow?
- Temple.
I've known the largest men
to have thin skulls.
This might have happened at any time
and for any reason.
Ratcliffe.
What?
Why the drumhead court-martial?
Couldn't the prisoner be guarded?
The matter referred to the Admiralty
when we reach port?
When we reach port? We do not
sail to port, we sail into battle...
...and battle makes a mockery of justice.
No, we must cling to what
vestiges of order we can.
- It must be done quickly.
- Quickly?
Since when is justice
compatible with speed?
You realize that we were spared mutiny
aboard this ship...
...simply because we were not in port.
But the men know. They know.
Rumors fly over the empty sea
and with them...
...the temper of the times we live in.
And so we are afraid?
Justice must be not only quick
but also expedient.
What did you say?
I apologize, sir, for the manner,
not for the matter.
Claggart would've hung for false witness
if Billy hadn't killed him.
Yes, he would have done,
but by fair process of law.
Budd has prevented that,
and he's turned the law against himself.
You can't condemn the boy for answering
with his arm for lack of words.
He was tempted beyond endurance.
- The motive was clearly justified.
- Aye, but was the act?
This master-at-arms,
you know him for a liar, a vicious dog.
A dog's obeyed in office.
Claggart was authority.
Seymour, a trial there must be.
And you cannot make the dead
stand trial.
So the living must stand trial
for a dead man's crimes.
It's more than any man
can have to answer for, captain...
...to his God, or even to his king.
Come in!
You all know why
you've been summoned here?
Aye, sir, in a general sort of way.
- Ratcliffe.
- You took all precautions, gentlemen?
No man aboard knows
why you are here?
No, sir.
Oh, Captain Hallam, the body?
It still lies
in the compartment below, sir.
Nobody saw the men
who put it there?
No, sir, I made sure of that.
Thank you, captain.
I've never seen him so disturbed.
Aye.
I give him cause.
Very well, Mr. Seymour.
You may proceed.
Gentlemen.
You are appointed members
of a court-martial...
...convened by Captain Vere
in extraordinary circumstances.
I am senior member...
...and I declare these proceedings open.
As you know...
...the master-at-arms has been killed
by the foretopman, Budd.
Whether by accident or by design...
...and whether the act
shall carry the penalty of death or no...
...you are to decide.
- Sentry.
- Sir.
Bring the prisoner in.
There is only one witness,
Captain Vere.
I shall call on him to give his deposition
as soon as the sentry brings in the prisoner.
- Sentry, stand outside.
- Sir.
You may sit down, Billy.
Thank you, sir.
Captain, will you be good enough
to give us your account.
I speak to you not as your captain,
but as a witness before this court.
The master-at-arms, early this morning,
detailed to me...
...an account of mutinous sentiments
expressed by Budd...
...and spoke of overhearing a specific
conversation last night during mid-watch.
- Budd a mutineer? That's absurd.
- Lt. Wyatt.
- He's one of the best liked...
- Lt. Wyatt, do not interrupt the witness.
And now, sir, with your permission.
Budd...
...did you speak with anyone
in the master-at-arms' hearing last night?
I spoke a little with the Dansker, sir.
- The sailmaker?
- Sentry.
Sir.
Do you know a seaman
referred to as the Dansker?
Sir.
Go on deck and find him.
Let him know apart he is wanted here.
And arrange it so that none of
the other people notice his withdrawing.
See you do it tactfully.
I want no curiosity aroused
among the men.
Sir.
Will you go on, sir, please?
I sent at once for Budd.
I ordered the master-at-arms
to be present at this interview...
...and to repeat his accusations
to Budd's face.
May I ask what was the prisoner's reaction
on being confronted by the master-at-arms?
I perceived no uneasiness in his demeanor.
I believe he smiled.
And for the master-at-arms?
When I told him to make his accusations
to Budd's face, he faced Budd and did so.
Did Budd reply?
He tried to,
but could not frame his words.
And then, sir?
He answered with a blow.
The accuser fell.
It was evident at once
the blow was fatal...
...but I summoned the surgeon
to verify the fact.
That's all.
You've heard Captain Vere's account.
Is it or is it not as he has said?
Captain Vere speaks the truth.
It's just as Captain Vere says.
But it is not as the master-at-arms said.
I've eaten the king's bread
and I'm true to him.
- I believe you, boy.
- God knows, l...
Thank you, sir.
Was there malice...
...between you and the master-at-arms?
I bore no malice
against the master-at-arms.
I'm sorry that he's dead.
I did not mean to kill him.
If I'd have found my tongue,
I would not have struck him.
But he lied foully to my face, and I had...
Well, I had to say something.
I could only say it with a blow.
God help me.
Anybody seen Mr. Claggart about?
Well, he was not at the inspection.
You'd better not let him catch you
lying around like this.
You have been summoned
in secrecy...
...to appear before this court
as a witness...
...of which I am senior member.
I may not, at this time, disclose to you
the nature of the offense being tried.
However, the offender
is William Budd, foretopman.
Do you consent to give this court
your testimony...
...though ignorant of the case at trial,
and further...
...to keep in strictest confidence
all that passes here?
Aye.
Do you so swear?
I do.
Then this is my question:
In your opinion...
...is there malice
between the master-at-arms and Budd?
Aye.
Explain your statement.
Master-at-arms bore malice...
...towards a grace...
...he could not have.
There was no reason for it...
...that ordinary men could understand.
Pride was his demon.
And he kept it strong
by others' fear of him.
He was a Pharisee among the lepers.
Billy could not understand
such a nature.
He saw only a lonely man, strange...
...but a man still.
Nothing to be feared.
So Claggart...
...lest his world be proven false...
...planned Billy's death.
I notice in your testimony
you've been using the past tense.
Why?
I look around...
...and sense finality here.
- Have you any more questions?
- One thing more.
Ever since this master-at-arms
came aboard...
...from God knows where...
...I have seen his shadow
lengthen along the deck.
And being under it...
...I was afraid.
Whatever happened here...
...I am in part to blame.
Have you any further questions
to put to the accused?
- None.
- No.
William Budd...
...if you have anything further
to say for yourself...
...say it now.
I've said all, sir.
Sentry.
- Sir.
- Remove the prisoner to my compartment.
Have you anything to say, Ratcliffe?
Yes, sir.
Claggart was killed
because Budd couldn't speak.
In that sense, that he stammers,
he's a cripple.
You don't hang a man for that,
for speaking the only way he could.
If you condemn him, it's the same...
...as condoning the lie
the master-at-arms clearly told.
I'd have struck him myself.
The boy is clearly innocent,
struck in self-defense.
- Aye. I'm ready to acquit him now.
- Good, then we can reach a verdict at once.
One moment, gentlemen.
With your pardon, sir,
as senior member of this court...
...I must ask if you speak now
as our commanding officer...
...or as a private individual.
As convening authority, Seymour,
I summoned this court.
I must review its findings and approve them
before passing them to the Admiralty.
- Aye, sir, that is your right.
- No right.
Which one of us here has rights?
It's my duty, and I must perform it.
Budd killed a man, his superior officer.
We've found a verdict, sir.
I know you have, and your verdict
sets him free, and so would I wish to do.
But are we free to choose
as we would if we were private citizens?
The Admiralty has its code.
Do you think it cares who Budd is?
Who you and I are?
We don't forget that, sir, but surely even
within that code, each crime is different.
We can't ignore the facts.
The facts. Come, you know the facts,
which are the Mutiny Act's provisions.
At sea, in time of war,
an impressed man...
...strikes his superior officer
and the blow is fatal.
Now, according to the Act...
...the mere fact of the blow
would be enough to hang him...
...be it fatal or no.
Now, the men know this
as well as you and I.
They know the penalty
for Budd's action.
But they know Budd, sir.
Claggart too, I dare say.
As well as any dry letter of the law.
They would applaud
the decision that frees Budd.
They'd thank us for it.
Fight the better when the time comes.
String him to a yard,
they'll turn round and rescue him.
- And string us up instead.
- Aye, that's the point.
It's twice as dangerous to hang the boy
as to let him go.
Yes, that's possible, Ratcliffe.
Whatever step we take,
the risk is great, but it is ours.
That is what makes us officers.
If by our lawful rigor mutiny comes,
there is no blame for us.
But if in fear,
miscalled a kind of mercy...
...we pardon Budd against specific order
and then the men revolt...
...how culpable and weak
our verdict will appear.
I can see that, sir.
But this case is exceptional.
And pity, if we are men,
must move us, captain.
So am I moved, Ratcliffe.
But we cannot have warm hearts
betraying heads which should be cool.
Officers are only men in uniform.
We have our standards,
ethics, scruples.
Challenge your scruples.
Come, do they mean something like this?
Can we adjudge to summary
and shameful death...
...a fellow creature
we believe to be innocent before God?
- Does that state your case rightly?
- That is my feeling, sir.
- Acquit him, then you say, as innocent.
- Yes.
Oh, I know the Articles prescribe death
for what Budd has done...
Stow the Articles. They don't account
for such a case as this.
You've said yourself, sir,
Budd is innocent.
In a court more merciful than a martial one,
our views might count.
- They might even set him free.
- Sir, when Claggart told you his lies...
...the case immediately went beyond
military justice.
There, Seymour, you reveal
the whole weakness of your argument.
Here, nothing is beyond the scope
of military justice.
When we first put this on,
we resigned our freedom.
The gold we wear
shows that we serve the king...
...the law.
For the term of my active life,
I am bound by an oath I took...
...when I was half the age
of any of you here.
And now, for the first time in my life,
I feel the weight of those words...
...I spoke so solemnly as a midshipman,
ignorant of their meaning...
...with nothing but dreams of glory
in my mind.
Yes, but...
...gentlemen, you took that oath as well.
There's no escape.
All I know is that I can't sit by
and see an innocent man hanged.
- Who'd gain by Budd's death? Admiralty?
- You want to make us murderers.
What is this ship you serve in?
An ark of peace? Go count her guns...
...then tell your conscience to lie quiet,
if you can.
But that is war.
This will be downright killing.
It's all war, Ratcliffe.
War to the death for all of us.
Oh, you see that, Seymour?
That this war...
...began before our time?
- And will end long after it.
- Aye...
...if ever men deserve to be at peace.
Couldn't we...
...mitigate the penalty
if we find him guilty?
No, Ratcliffe,
the penalty is prescribed.
I'd like to think about it, captain.
I'm not sure.
The French are not far off.
Soon the men will know what happened.
Our consciences are private matters,
Ratcliffe, but we are public men.
Dare we give our consciences precedence
over the code that made us officers?
And which called this case to trial?
Dare we?
No, sir.
Can you stand Budd's murder
on your conscience?
Wyatt, hold your tongue.
- I say let him go.
- Sit down, sir.
I won't bear a hand
to hang an innocent man.
My blood's not cold enough for that.
I cannot give the kind of judgment
that you wish to force upon us.
I beg to be excused
from sitting upon this court-martial.
Wyatt...
...we do not deal with justice here,
but with the law.
Was not the one conceived
to serve the other?
Wyatt, can't you see that you must
first strip off the uniform you wear...
...and then your flesh before you can
escape the case at issue here?
Decide you must, Wyatt...
...or else reason with us.
Show us how to save the boy
without setting aside our function.
You think Seymour, Ratcliffe and I
wouldn't save the boy...
...if we could find a way
consistent with our duty?
Well, perhaps you can do this.
Can you do this?
Speak, man.
Speak.
Show us how.
Save him, Wyatt, and you save us all.
Do not think me pitiless
in thus demanding sentence...
...on a luckless boy.
I feel as you do for him.
And for myself...
...revulsion...
...shame...
...and rage.
Is there hope for me, captain?
Billy...
...what hope is there for any of us?
Tell me why.
I only want to understand.
A child, with his endless ''whys.''
''Why are there wars?
Why must men kill each other? ''
A child will ask...
...and the parent will grow impatient
believing these questions to be foolish.
They're not foolish,
they're questions...
...to which grown men
have lost the answer.
The answer went with innocence.
Why?
I cannot tell you why.
I feel sorry, captain, but not guilty.
Nor should you. Claggart killed you
the moment you killed him.
But I'm still alive.
You, in your goodness,
are as inhuman...
...as was Claggart in his evil.
Well, at least be human now, Billy.
Give in to anger for once.
Hate me for what I do to you. No...
Please, Billy.
Promise me your fury and resentment.
Hatred will make you
conquer your fear.
I'm not afraid, sir.
I did my duty. You're doing yours.
Sentry.
Take Budd into your charge.
Merryweather.
Time to get up, Budd.
Marine detachment. Attention!
- Marine detachment present and correct, sir.
- Thank you.
Over there. Mr. Seymour.
Ship's company, form ranks!
Come on, move up there.
Attention! Division commander's report.
Afterguard present or accounted for, sir.
Starboard battery
present or accounted for, sir.
Larboard battery
present and accounted for, sir.
Fore-, main-, and mizzentopmen,
five working party...
...one absentee, sir.
One absentee.
All hands will stand by
to witness punishment.
Stand easy.
Who could they be punishing?
And what for?
It's got to be a flogging.
I ought to know.
But why have they kept us
off the catwalks?
They flog men at noon.
The early morning...
...is for a hanging.
- Hanging?
- Hanging.
Hanging?
Where's Ferguson? Where's Billy?
And Turner.
Aye, Morrison too.
There were four hammocks
empty last night.
- That will be the working party.
- But there's five in the working party.
One absentee.
Hey...
...where's Claggart?
- Well, you don't suppose it's him, do you?
- Oh, Judas, let it be that fish-blooded...
- Not him.
He's too smart, he is.
Where's Squeak, come to that?
Well, he'll be with Claggart.
Why isn't Claggart here?
He is here.
Where? I don't see him.
You're barmy, old man.
Ship's company, attention!
Marine detachment, attention!
Ship's company
present to witness execution, sir.
Very well.
Ship's company
ready to witness execution, sir.
Captain Hallam.
Escort, bring forward the prisoner.
- Billy!
- Billy.
- They can't, Bill.
- They've got old Billy.
No talking in the ranks.
- They'll pay for this.
- Steady, mate. Steady.
Form up.
Do you hear me? Silence in ranks.
Escort.
I'm sorry, Billy.
Come on, keep moving.
Keep silent there.
Proceedings of the court-martial
held aboard HMS Avenger...
...on the 28th August, 1797...
...convened under the authority...
...of Edwin Fairfax Vere,
post captain, royal navy...
...and composed of the first, second
and third lieutenants of said vessel.
The case of William Budd,
foretopman, royal navy.
While attached and so serving
the aforesaid vessel...
...he did, on the 28th day
of August, 1797...
...strike and kill his superior officer...
...one John Claggart, master-at-arms...
- Did you, Billy?
Quiet!
Silence, you men! Form up!
Stand to attention there, hang you!
Silence in the ranks!
You will be silent and remain
at strict attention until dismissed!
- Master-at-arms, royal navy.
Therefore, the court sentences
the aforementioned...
...William Budd, foretopman,
royal navy...
...to die by hanging on the first watch
following these proceedings.
Don't worry, Billy.
Do you hear, sir?
By authority of His gracious
Majesty George Rex...
...and Alan Napier, Viscount Kelsey,
First Sea Lord.
Signed...
...Philip Seymour, senior member.
Let them dance on a rope's end!
You're not hanging Billy Budd!
Silence!
You will resume discipline instantly!
Be warned!
For the last time, you scum,
will you obey orders?
Stand back into ranks.
Resume your ranks there
and be quick about it!
Prisoner...
...have you anything to say?
If you have nothing to say,
the sentence of the court will be carried out.
God bless Captain Vere.
Sound off!
Marines, cover the hanging party!
No, Billy!
Permission to dismiss the men, sir.
Sir?
You may do as you wish, Mr. Seymour.
It's of no further concern to me.
Sir, a decision must be made.
A decision has been made,
Mr. Ratcliffe.
I'm only a man,
not fit to do the work of God...
...or the devil.
Ship's company.
Ship's company, by divisions, dismiss!
Afterguard dismissed.
Starboard battery dismissed.
Larboard battery dismissed.
Fore-, main-, and mizzentopmen dismissed.
Repeat the order!
Captain Hallam, fire into their ranks.
Marines, take aim.
Beat to quarters!
Clear decks for action!
Come on, lads, let's punish the French
for turning up late!
The rest belongs to naval history.
But if the sacrifice of Billy Budd...
...has served to make men
more conscious of justice...
...then he will not have died in vain.
Men are perishable things...
...but justice will live
as long as the human soul...
...and the law,
as long as the human mind.