François!
Francesco!
François?
François. François.
He's ill!
What's happened to
you? Speak to me.
He's come back from the war
because he's ill.
He's not a coward! He...
- My dear son.
- Come on!
Come, come.
Francesco, please!
Come on!
We've been riding
all night, too.
- All night?
- Yeah, on a girl,
not on a horse.
And tomorrow,
we'll be riding to battle.
We must be mad.
Is it true
if we win the battle,
we get all the girls we want?
Of course!
That's what wars are made for.
Kill the enemy
and get the ladies!
It's getting late.
Let's go home and prepare.
Wars are serious business.
Such profundity, Bernardo.
Why?
Bernardo.
What a pity.
It's over.
Yes. It's a pity...
but I hope we'll live to see
another dawn like this.
The last night of our youth.
Do you realize that?
We tried so desperately
to make it never end.
We should've stopped the sun
from rising.
Come on, Francesco!
Wait!
Leave me alone.
Please.
Brothers!
Lepers.
Yes. Lepers.
No!
I don't want to feed them!
Get them off!
No, no,
no, no, no...
No, no, no, no, no!
Oh... you're not dressed yet?
What have you been doing
up until now, eh?
Pica. Pica!
Will you please stop
all this sissified nonsense?
The boy's going off to war.
Besides, I don't understand
a damned word.
Why do you two always want
to leave me out of everything?
Don't speak French
when I'm around.
How many times...
If you wanted a wife
who speaks like you,
why didn't you marry
some thick-headed
butcher's daughter?
Bravo, François, bravo.
Forgive me, Father.
Hey, wait, we must talk.
What shall we do with
all the money we'll make
out of this war?
Have you thought of that?
Ah... I see.
A true son of his father,
eh, Pica?
We are going to be late
for mass, Monsignor.
Ah, they'll wait.
Listen, Francesco...
out of the way, out of the way.
Francesco, w-when you're
in Perugia,
don't forget Ugoni's storerooms
behind the marketplace,
near the main tower.
He's as rich as the pope.
There's everything there.
Yes, yes, leave it to me.
Ooh, and Francesco.
What else?
Remember the triptych I told you
about for the cathedral?
It'll save us a fortune
in indulgences.
Yes.
Yes, war is beautiful.
This is my death mask.
Go forth, sons of Assisi.
God is with you!
Francesco!
Flowers in the
meadow softly sway
And all the little birds
sing merry May Day
Rabbits in the orchard
sport and play
And all the little creatures
smile and are gay
My little boy,
sing out your joy
I am near, my dear
My darling, do not fear
Love is all around you
Comforting with gentle lullaby
to make your heart sing.
What's he doing up there?
Oh, that's Bernardone's son.
Francesco!
Get down.
Francesco.
Francesco, what is it?
Francesco, my sweet, Francesco,
what's happening to you, eh?
You can tell me.
We've always understood
each other.
We...
We've always
been close, you and...
Let me help you, my darling.
Well, sit down, sit down.
Take a drink.
Yes, business is booming.
Life's back to normal at last.
Yeah, talking about business,
I have some fine stuff
to show you
that you won't find
anywhere but here.
Well, not anymore, that is.
Look at this tapestry.
It comes from Provence.
That's beautiful, isn't it?
Feel the texture
of this material.
Now, I'd like you to compare
this with one from Venice.
Ah! This one here.
Look at your hands.
Look at your hands!
Forgive me.
If I find one finger mark
on any of my silks,
I'll beat you
till you're black and blue,
you dirty little pig!
Ah!
These servants are
just like animals.
How's your son? Better now?
Oh, yes, thank God.
He's cost me a fortune
in masses to our blessed Mary,
but the worst is over now.
Now, there we are.
Oh, he's begun to get up,
and one of these Sundays,
you'll see him with us at mass.
Yes, please, please.
Take it into the light.
Do you remember me?
I'm Clare.
People say you're mad.
Do you know that?
When you went off to war,
they said you were fine
and intelligent.
But now you're mad, because...
because you sing like the birds,
and you chase after butterflies,
and...
and you-you look at flowers.
I think you were mad before,
not now.
Am I disturbing you?
I'll go...
You see?
He talks with her.
Thanks be to God.
That's obviously what
was wrong with him.
The boy needed a woman, eh?
Oh.
You look at things
so clumsily, Monsignor.
His heart is waking.
Well, you can call
it what you like,
but if you ask me,
that lad's after a woman.
That's why he's been
acting strangely.
What a lovely creature Clare is.
Hmm. Not much
of a catch, though.
Her father won't even
give enough dowry
to pay for a wedding.
Still, if that's what
Francesco wants,
we'll find enough money for
both of them, hey, Pica?
And you know what?
Yes.
I'm going to put him
to work again.
But...
No buts. You've mollycoddled him
long enough.
- But, Monsignor...
- Shh, shh, shh.
Besides, Francesco's always
been very good at business.
He likes it.
He does.
He takes after me.
Always has done.
Come, come.
You shall see.
I followed your advice,
Francesco,
to the very letter.
I bought and bought and...
and bought.
And now, we prosper.
Oh, I may curse the war
for having given you this,
uh, this fever,
but-but for business,
it was a blessing.
Come, come.
You shall see.
What you're going to see now
will send the blood
coursing through your veins.
Better than all those
potions and medicines
the women give you.
Eh?
Go, go.
Look at that, eh, Francesco?
Look.
You see this? See?
And to think people
speak badly of war.
Come, come.
I'll show you.
You know how it started,
eh, Francesco?
With the war supplies.
And then, after the war,
the soldiers came
to sell their loot.
And then the wights who'd been
looted by the soldiers
came selling whatever
they had left
in order to rebuild,
practically giving
away things for nothing.
I'll show you,
I'll show you.
Look at these.
Look.
Francesco, see these, huh?
Family heirlooms, hmm?
Titled people.
On their knees, they were.
Cost me less than nothing.
And this is not all.
It's just the beginning.
And there's so much more
than that.
Now we have enough money
to manufacture and sell
with nearly 200 workers...
dyers, weavers.
Well, see for yourself.
It belongs to you, too,
Francesco.
Don't forget that.
God bless the master
of this house
And a lu-la-lu-la-lo
And a lu-la-lu-la-lay
Now milady, lady of
He be handsome, she be fair
And a lu-la-lu-la-lay
Bring them buttons
and bells and bows...
A penny a rhyme
will do me fine
And a lu-la-lu-la-lo
And a lu-la-lu-la-lay
Tuppence a rhyme,
I told you so...
God bless the master
of this house
And a lu-la-lu-la-lo
And a lu-la-lu-la-lay...
Yes. Yes.
He invited them, if you please,
out for a stroll,
just like that.
He simply led them
into the sunshine,
and they sat there
all afternoon.
Nobody did a stroke of work.
Oh.
And that-that... that simpleton,
that-that idiot boy...
he just... he just looked on.
He doesn't get it from me.
There's never been
a history of insanity
in my side of the family.
I've had enough of
your high and mighty ways.
You're not in noble
Provence now, madam,
and you'll not play the
great lady in my house!
You've ruined that boy!
You've pampered him
and spoiled him
with your Frenchified
airs and graces.
He's nothing more
than a cringing idiot.
Something's got to be done,
for God's sake,
but not by you!
You are a stupid, thick-headed,
vulgar animal,
that's what you are.
Don't you understand
what Francesco needs?
He's desperate.
Oh, Jesus, when I think
of my own youth,
I feel like flaying him alive.
That's typical of you.
Treat him like...
like one... like one of
your clerks who comes to you
whenever you stamp.
But, but, but Francesco's
not like that, Monsignor.
- No?
- No, no.
And what's more,
all the fathers and
mothers of Assisi
envy us such a son.
So... so sensitive,
so intelligent.
Ah.
This is the, uh,
envy of Assisi, huh?
Now you've gone far enough!
No, Monsignor.
No son of mine,
do you understand,
however mad,
is gonna behave like this.
Have you no respect for me,
huh?!
You will obey me in everything!
And if you do not,
I will crush you
- within an inch of your life!
- No!
Is that clear?
Is that understood?
And... And starting
tomorrow morning,
you'll come with us to mass,
even if I have to drag
you there like a dog!
Come on, sit up.
No!
No...
No.
It's... It's mine!
This one.
All of it!
And this.
Out of the way!
Where is he?
Where is he?!
It will never make you happy!
Throw it all away!
Burn it, my brothers,
all of it.
You...
But he doesn't realize
what he's doing, Monsignor.
Be patient.
Father...
Father, I want
to share my joy with you.
Our treasures are
in Heaven, Father,
not here on Earth.
Don't be a slave to these.
Throw it all away.
Do as I do.
It's so simple.
Be free.
Father... no...
No!
Oh! Stop it!
Stop it!
You lunatic!
No. No, my brothers.
Don't touch that.
Throw it into the gutter.
Throw it all away!
It will only make you miserable.
Look at my poor father.
Quiet, you idiot.
Call the guards.
See how he struggles.
I want to see him hang
in the public square!
It's Pietro di Bernardone.
His son's gone mad.
What is all this commotion?
Di Bernardone's son,
he's gone berserk.
Has he only
found that out now?
Oh, anyway, you'd
better alert the guards.
He's out of his mind.
What's the matter
with you, Bernardone?
Have you gone
mad as well?
I want justice,
and I want it here, now,
in front of all Assisi.
Well, it would be helpful
to know the charge.
What has the justice
of men to do with me?
God is my only judge.
Well, unfortunately, He isn't
around to help us out.
Why not go to Bishop Guido, hmm?
Do you think I'm going
to interrupt my meal
because of some sordid
family squabble?
What heresy.
Your Grace...
Oh, tell them I'm out.
Say I'm praying or something.
But the whole town
is down there.
They insist that
the church intervene.
It's becoming
an outrageous scandal.
I really believe...
Guards!
I've only just got over Lent,
and here you all are
imposing another on me.
But, Your Grace...
Have it kept hot.
God's teeth!
Can a man not be left alone
to dine in peace
in his own home?
The bishop's coming.
Pietro di Bernardone,
this will not do.
How dare you disturb us
when we are in the middle
of saying our office.
What's the matter with you, man?
Have you lost your senses?
It's not my fault, Your Grace.
It's him...
that lunatic there.
Yes...
it's me.
My soul is in your hands.
What?
Are you trying to cause trouble?
Is that what
you're trying to do?
Is this some damned plot
to rob the church
of its authority?
That's nothing to what
he's done to me, Your Grace.
I mean, God only knows,
I've always given him the best.
I, I, I brought him up.
I, I... I clothed him.
I...
I mean, you ask anyone.
They'll tell you.
He's never wanted for anything
since the day he was born.
But today,
he threw all my belongings
out of the window!
And he even opened
my strongbox!
Oh!
Thrown to a mob of cutthroats
like himself
down in the street.
Years of hard work
and self-sacrifice
just... just tossed away.
Then what is the answer
to these accusations?
Surely you are sufficiently
intelligent
to understand
that Holy Mother Church
must punish those who subvert
the established order.
A man such as you is a...
is a menace to society.
He's either criminal or...
Or someone seeking the light.
Someone in darkness.
I was in darkness.
But Brother Sun
illuminated my soul.
And now,
I can see so clearly.
Just as you did the day
you chose the sacred vestments
you are wearing now.
Are you seeking holy orders?
Me?
No. No.
I'm not worthy.
Then what do you want?
I want to be... to be happy.
I want to live like
the birds in the sky.
I want to experience
the freedom and the purity
that they experience.
The rest is of no use to me.
No use.
Believe me.
If the purpose of life
is this loveless toil
we fill our days with,
then it's not for me.
There must be something better.
There has to be.
Man is...
is a spirit.
He has a soul.
And that, that is what
I want to recapture...
my soul.
I want to live.
I want to live in the fields.
Stride over hills.
Climb trees, swim rivers.
I want to feel the firm grasp
of the earth beneath my feet
without shoes,
without possessions.
Without those shadows
we call our servants.
I want to be a beggar.
Yes.
Yes, a beggar.
Christ was a beggar,
and his holy apostles
were beggars.
I want to be as,
as free as they are.
But, Your Grace,
even beggars show respect
for their fathers.
I'm not your son anymore.
What?
What is born
of the flesh is flesh.
of the Spirit is spirit.
I now...
am born again.
Father, I give you back
everything that belongs to you:
Your clothes...
your possessions.
Your name, too.
There are no more fathers.
There are no more sons.
And everyone who has left
houses, or brothers,
or sisters,
or fathers, or mothers,
or children,
or fields,
for the sake
of our heavenly Father
will receive a hundred times
more in the life to come.
Cover him.
Cover him up.
Hey, come and see!
Look at the crusader.
Bernardo di Quintavalle?
Welcome.
Welcome home.
As I am presenting
the keys of the city
to the emperor,
it would hardly be
very bright of me
to present them
from the rear, would it?
Besides, this is not
a religious ceremony.
My dear governor,
Otto of Brunswick
is going to Rome
to be crowned emperor
by His Holiness.
How can you possibly say
this is not
a religious ceremony?
God moves in mysterious
ways, my dear secretary,
and He has arranged,
on this occasion,
that I move forward.
Ah! This is...
pure blasphemy!
What? Do you suggest you are
in direct communication
with the Word of God?!
Sylvestro.
Come here, Sylvestro.
Paolo.
Something really
marvelous has happened.
Guess what.
What?
Bernardo's back.
Yes! He rode in
through the gates
half an hour ago.
He looks... fantastic.
Yes.
...and I will make
the speech of welcome.
Let's not discuss it further.
Everyone will have
his assigned place.
But, but you are here.
Mm-hmm.
Streets ahead of me.
He couldn't have arrived
at a more appropriate time.
Let's meet tonight
and celebrate.
Giocondo, you arrange it.
- Oh, yes.
- Yes.
Hey! Bernardo!
How do you like your chicken?
Leg? Or breast?
The only one of us
that's stayed the same.
It's all show.
He's trying to go
back to his youth.
Why else would he
choose this place
to celebrate your return
from the crusade?
Crusades are nothing
to sing about, I assure you.
Oh, come on, Bernardo,
you're, you're famous.
You're a war hero.
I say, you must have slaughtered
thousands of Muslims.
What?
How many, at a rough guess,
would you say that you killed?
Too many.
Oh.
Where's Francesco?
Oh, uh...
He doesn't live in Assisi
anymore, Bernardo.
I gathered that, but...
What's happening?
Where is Francesco?
Oh, you're not still talking
about him, are you?
We told you, he's mad.
What do you mean, he's mad?
Don't take any notice
of him, Bernardo.
He's pissed, as usual.
But Francesco isn't mad,
is he, Paolo?
No.
He's not mad.
He's... He's changed.
He is mad.
A raving bloody lunatic.
Only a lunatic will believe
that God Himself
had come down from heaven
to talk to him.
Right?
Listen, God has spoken
to lots of people sometimes.
How interesting.
And I suppose you think
that God personally decided
that San Damiano should be
the first church
in His rebuilding program.
San Damiano...? Rebuil...?
Is that where he's living?
Well, y-yes, I, I suppose so.
Is he all right?
Surely... Surely to God
one of you went along
to-to see him,
speak to him.
You must have done something.
Look, he...
He is our oldest...
...and dearest friend.
He might need our help,
for God's sake.
Bernardo, listen to me,
not Giocondo, he's drunk.
Francesco's not mad.
Maybe he's very sane indeed.
But you are a hero
of the crusades.
You can't afford
to have your name
associated with his.
- What?!
- None of us can.
Francesco's been a great
friend to us all, but...
quite simply, we have
nothing in common anymore.