JULES CÉSAR
Citizens of Rome Gather round.
Welcome to Gordias. Now Gordias
was famous for his knot.
The oracles predicted that who
could untie the knot...
would conquer the whole world.´
Many came from far and wide but
none succeeded,
until one day the mighty Alexander
arrived
Alexander, Decended from the mighty
God Apollo.
Advance !
Apollo enlightened Alexander
and showed
him how to untie the knot.
Sylla has returned to Rome to
establish order.
He declares that the innocents
have no reason to fear.
But that those guilty of crimes against
him shall be most severly punished.
The men whose names are written on
these lists are declared outlaws.
They have no rights as citizens
enseforth they may be killed on sight
Anyone who takes it upon himself to
kill any of these men...
will be considered a friend of the state..
and shall be rewarded with the properties
and posessions these outlaws leave behind.
The biggest crime under Roman law.
Mother?
- Cornelia?
Where is my wife?
- at her fathers.
Grandmother The soldiers are comming
- Julia stay with her.
Sulla has taken the city with his army
He has made lists hundreds of people are on them
Are you?
- No my wife's father is.
Julia stay in the house.
Don't go.
- Father where are you going?
To get your mother.
Is he not on the list?
He's the one you want overthere.
- Right.
Have you heard?
- Yes we have to hurry.
What's the point running away
might as well die right here.
Please go.
- - She's right Cinna We must leave now.
Cinna hurry.
Go.
- Please, father.
Go Hurry!
Go.!
Please Cornelia, run !
He has helped Cinna to escape
Give me your name.
It's Caesar, from the house of Julia.
Arrest him.
No please no !
Are you Julius Caesar?
-Yes.
This way....
This way.
That is not negotiable.
Who is he ?
Julius Caesar.
Nephew to Marius...
You have unfortunate ancestery.
If you think it's unfortunate
to be descendent from the Gods.
Which God is that?
- The Julia descendent from Aeneas,
Who was...
- The son of Vénus, yes yes.
I recall Marius making such claims.
There are many people these days who
claim to be descendents from the Gods.
We have a crest which proves it..
I believe you can have them
fashioned in the market place...
...for a couple of dinars.
Why did you ask to see me ?
Your mother...
She came to see me.
Did she ask you to spare my life ?
And what you agreed ?
Well I promised that I would consider it.
And I'm supposed to be grateful to you ?
- No.
To you we are old friends.
- You killed a lot of old friends...
True, true true.
Old friends of the day become
fresh enemies at night.
What do you want in
exchange for my life ?
Why do you think I want anything in Exchange ?
And like you don't give things
away for free.
I'm not a man without compassion.
I will help you if I can.
First you must understand the
gravity of the crime.
Cinna was my greatest enemy.
And you helped him to escape.
Did he?
Of course not.
He escaped my soldiers only to be
killed by one of his servants.
My wife ?
- She's well.
I leave women to their health.
And since you are only the son of
Cinna by marriage,
I intend to leave you to yours.
If... ?
If you divorce your wife.
Well ?
No I refuse.
- You refuse to devorce your wife
Even though it may cost you your life ?
My wife is my teacher.
She's more clever than I am She's
more honest than I am,
She's a more compelling argument
than I am or you are.
Or your office is.
I won't devorce her.
That Is my answer.
- Ah, Pompée...
What can we do with men such as this ?
I don't know wether to embrace
him or strangle him.
I think we should let hin go.
- What ?
His uncle Marius
was my greatest enemy.
He got ten Marius inside him.
Look at his eyes.
You want to let him go ?
It's the ones who smile and flatter
you should worry about.
He speaks plainly.
You speak plainly don't you ?
Always.
Tell me...
Would you kill me if you could ?
In an instant.
You can go.
I said you are free to go.
What a big heart that boy has.
Bring it to me in the morning.
Was this Sylla's plan to slaughter me outside
so I wouldnt foul the carpet with my blood ?
I came to warn you.
- Why?
Because if you don't leave Rome
I'll have to do as he asks.
And ?
And I don't want to see men like
you die young..
What do you know about me ?
- You refuse  Sylla.
I'll tell you more some day
when there is time.
But now you must leave Rome.
Your family will be safe,
here take this.
Go east to Bythinie. Show this ring to
Nicomède, it will keep you safe in his service.
How do I know I can trust you ?
- You don't.
I'll not hand my fate over to that man.
So you'd let him kill you ?
He can try if he wants,
I'm not leaving Rome.
Why must you be so stubborn !
Pompée himself offers you help.
Why don't you accept it?
He's Sylla's man,
it could be a trick.
Don't you trust anybody at all ?
- yes.
I trust you.
- Then listen to me.
You're not the heaven and earth.
You're just a man.
And some things are bigger
than you are.
When you were in jail...
...I thought you were dead.
I started to grieve your death.
I'm asking you to spare me that, Caésar.
How can I live with myself if I knew
I had one chance to save your life.
And I failed
Is this pig for sale ?
- How much will you give me for it ?
Ten dinars.
- That's good money for a swine.
He requires carving.
Jules César.
We will feed it to my dogs.
That's the coast of Crête.
The ruler there used to make up laws
and hang them so high
that people couldn't read them.
And if they broke the law he'd
show then no mercy.
Today the shores are infected
by pirates pirates.
We need to anchore for the night.
Where has father gone ?
The other side of the water.
How long does it take to cross the water ?
It depends on the wind.
Sometimes you can cross it in days.
Sometimes if the air is still
you may not move at all.
Easy on the ropes,
we could use nails.
Its the Roman way isn't it ?
What kind of ransom do you get
for a Roman these days?
Two talents.
But I'll pay three to watch a roman drowned.
You'd get fifty from me alive.
And who would collect it ?
They would.
If your men...
...don't return before dawn,
you die.
Your time is up, Roman.
I'll fight one of you for another day.
That's another day.
Nobody is comming back for this Roman.
Throw him in the sea.
Ship !
Fifty talents.
And the money just happened to
find it's way into your purse ?
Sir I never stole a coin from you.
And I suppose it was the goldsmiths
who just happened to rob me again.
Sir they've been convicted for it.
_I know how these things work.
You share the profits with
these men.
You pay me well I would never risk
my life for a gold coin.
This is the magistrate's testiment
the goldsmiths have confessed.
Flavius had nothing to do with it.
Are you trying to tell me that a
man who handles so much gold.
never put a piece into his pocket ?
He's been proven innocent.
This needs your signature.
Strangle him.
- Wait !
He's been proven innocent.
Well I,
just disaprove of the verdict.
Sylla...
He's a good man,
and he's here on my introduction.
Allow me to vouch for him
and protect him.
You can vouch for him all you like.
But protect him you can't.
the penalty protests strangulation.
Strangle him.
- There seems to be an error of jugement.
My jugement ?
Pompée...
You're becomming very critical.
You want to rise above me.
Just waiting for your chance.
Those men worship the rising sun
and not the setting sun.
That's how the saying goes isn't it ?
But I am not the setting sun not
yet but in the meantime...
...I expect you to subordinate yourself
to my wishes wether you understand them...
...or not.
Strangle him !
No...
You...
You strangle him.
No.
Taije did you hear him say no ?
Ah, my dear general.
I asked you to strangle Flavius
and strangle Flavius you will.
And you will do it with your own bare hands.
You will strangle Flavius
or you yourself will be strangled.
Strangle him !
Strangle him now !
I will not have my orders disobeyed !
I swear to...
Father...
Who are your friends ?
Portia and Marcus.
Don't you remember them ?
Of course Cato's children.
Just don't grow them so much.
Thats our cousin.
Brutus...
What you reading ?
- ´Ethics.
Aristotle ?
- My uncle Cato gave it to me.
How is he ?
- He's as grumpy as ever.
Hasn't chamged a bit.
- Mother.
Caesar !
Don't get up.
- I'm not ill.
Let me get dressed.
I'm well,
I just got up too fast.
You don't have to get dressed.
Lets lie down together.
No wait.
Just...
Cornelia...
I never stopped waiting for you.
I never stopped missing you.
and now...
Here...
This is not supposed to happen.
I'm back now,  my love.
Two years is just too long.
There are those of you who work with Sylla.
and those of you who worked...
...against him.
But not all that worked with
him agreed with his laws.
I therefor propose that the rights
of the tribunes be restored
So that once again the people
can be fairly represented.
I propose a thorough reform of the courts.
And an unqualified reenstatement
of the senate
As the principal body of gevernment.
Caesar !
Its good to se you fresh
from another victory.
Oh he let me win.
It makes me feel old.
I'm Glad to see you made it back safely.
I hear you met with a number
of obstacles.
Yes. Fortunqtely your friend
Nicomede proved to be a valuable ally.
I never had a chance to thank you...
...for saving my life.
You defied Sylla.
He told you to devorce your wife and you
said no even though it meant sudden death.
That impressed me.
And it ...
reminded me of something.
You see my friend,
Sylla once told me
to devorce my wife.
And unlike you I obeyed him.
I left the one woman I loved.
Life is full of lessons .
So we tought each other
a thing of two.
Tell me how to get where
you are now.
Don't tell me I was wrong
to hope you were spared.
I have something to give to Rome.
But I have no voice.
If you want a voice in Rome,
Win the people,
Speak from your heart...
And when you make apromise,
Keep it.
Pompée...
Ipromise you
if you ever need my help...
...just give me a sign,
I'll come to your aid.
My name is Julius Caesar.
I'm here to honor
my wife, Cornelia...
...publicly
and for the last time.
She was a good woman.
She gave no thought to her own wellbeing.
Only to the wellbeing of others.
Rome was her first and greatest love.
We shared that love.
We dreamt of a Rome
without dictators.
Where sons never raise their
hands against their fathers.
Where brothers never raise
their swords against brothers.
Where Romans lived at peace
with fellow Romans by their side.
I ask you now to join with me,
In honoring not only the
memory of my good wife,
But in memory of all the good men and
women who have died fighting for a better Rome.
People of Rome, I, Julius Caesar,
make you this promise on the
body of my beloved wife...
...I will not rest until the Rome
she dreamed of is the Rome we live in.
Join me.
By not only the nephew
to our beloved Marius,
Who fought against the evils of Sylla
who took his life from him.
But I'm also a son of the Julia,
Who are descendents of the goddess Venus herself.
I offer you my hand.
A power supreme amongst mortal men,
Granted by the gods
superior to kings.
Let us work together comrades,
in our quest for an empire,
that is boundless,
united ...and free.
We shall have to watch him.
Or use him.
Good morning to you, Caesar...
Hail Caesar.
Greetings, Caesar.
Julia, I have something for you.
Now then... Ah here it is.
And I hope it will make you smile.
That's the first I seen
you smile in weeks.
Stop it all of you !
There is nothing he can do about it.
What happened ?
- The price of bread has tripled.
There is no grain in Rome.
--Why ?
Because the grain supply from Egypt
was cut off by pirates.
Half of Rome is without bread.
The city is close to panic.
Only the very rich can afford bread.
We must fight the pirates now or
Rome will be crippled forever.
So I propose that Pompee be given leigons
to attack this problem once and for all.
It's not a question of wether or
not we fight pirates,
It's a matter of how.
I propose we equip ten small armies to fight
the pirates at different parts of the coast.
So the pirates can destroy Rome
one two by the time ?
The pirates are a bunch of
uneducated hoodlems.
I hardly think they could stand
against a Roman assualt of any size.
Lets talk about things are gentlemen.
Not the way we would like then to be.
I can attest to the threat posed by these scavengers.
I was a victem of one of their assults myself.
Then perhaps you will regale us
with your sea stories Gaius Julius
In the tavern after the work
of the senate is done.
The work of the senate
is rarely done.
You see there are not thousands of pirates
in our waters. But hundreds of thousands.
Enough for all the rogue bands
preying on single vessles.
There are pirate admirals seeking,
With thousands of ships and troops
more skilled in naval combat even than our own.
Pretty speaches like this won't
even cook our lunch.
No speeches do as little
work as the senate.
How dare this arogent newcomer
insult this Auguste body ?
Auguste and plump, Bibulus,
like your own body.
Apparent from ardent chatter and inactivity.
Enough,...enough,...enough!
We have a man in our company who can
resolve this conflict with the pirates.
But do we honor him with that duty ?
No.
I'm with Caesar,
we have no bread.
Now are we a great empire or
are we going to be ruled by outlaws ?
To perform this commission,
Pompée will have to be given
an army twice the size
of the one Sylla used to take Rome
Have we learned nothing from the past ?
I see Rome should go hungary because Cato
can't find a single man he can trust.
Not any man with an army would take the state.
Not every man is a Sylla.
some men are ruled by circunstances but men
of character bend circumstances to their will.
They make nature behave in such a way that
their will is carried out on this earth.
They defy the elements.
And sometimes defy their own base of nature.
In order to see their ideals come
alive before their eyes.
Pompée is such a man.
Those of you who have lived know one
thing to keep the nation small.
Civil strife.
Tribes fighting tribes rather than
banding together in one arm of power.
As long as we fight in this room
seeking personal victories,
enacting petty revenges,
Rome will stay small !
I propose we put our opinions aside
and let one feeling rule us for a time
The love of Rome.
I propose we put our strengths
together and become a force
The world has never seen.
I propose you let a man...
...a single man,
lead us out of the dark.
I propose Pompée.
All those in favor.
Marcus...
- Julia.
Julia... look at you.
Brutus, wake up and tell Julia
how beautiful she looks.
.
Beautiful.
- You like it ?
All dressed for Pompée's triumph...
Who's going with me ?
None of you wants to join
the counsel of Rome ?
No offense, father, but do you really think we're
going to trail around with your lecters around.
Rome's greatest general has returned.
And we want to be free to run and follow him...
Run yes,...run...run
Go and enjoy yourselfs.
Come on.
- Thank you pompus.
Brutus ? Arent you going with them?
I want to return this to Apollonius.
- What is this ?
´Ah yes the Plato's law... Did you read it ?
- Yes.
And ?
Plato thinks that democracy is doomed to faliure.
He thinks that a state should
be run by a dictator.
A dictator who's become
enlightened through experience and learning.
I don't think plato would get
along with your uncle Cato.
Brutus ! Hurry up !
- Come on !
Hurry and catch up with your friends
or you'll have to come along with me.
See you at the ceremony.
Goodbye, father.
See, See...
Do you know what i want ?
Thank you for your kindness.
Let me take care of my son now..
Mother...
- Shh... rest.
Something happened to me there.
It's a affliction no more no less.
Your grandfather suffered the same
spells and lived into old age.
Name something else.
What happen I was watching Pompée.
He's been a friend to me.
We speak together easily like brothers.
Yet we couldn't be more different.
He's a great army leader.
His province has made him the richest
and most powerful man in Rome.
Your father wanted you to be a statesman
and now you are a counsel of Rome.
Happened to be beyond his dreams.
I need an army.
To turn yourself into a Pompée ?
How would you pay and feed such an army ?
Your counselship already costs a fortune.
Yes, I am counsel and I am broke.
Your attack today was stronger than usual.
There was something else mother, this
attack was different in other ways.
How ?
I saw something.
I saw something at that moment.
Not just about myself.
But about the whole humankind.
How we keep ourselves small.
Then  I realized I had not been inspired.
And as I watched pompee I saw
that he was not inspired.
And he would never be inspired.
And I realized the difference
between Pompee and me.
Pompée has merely done something.
But I, am for something.
I need légions.
Pompée has them.
He will lend them to me.
Why would pompee do that
diminishing his own power.
What could you offer him in return
to equal the value of an army ?
We trust in the wisdom of our fathers
And in their laws. and I, Cato,
trust in him.
Hail Pompée !
Cato, you flatter me.
But let us give credit to another man.
For I could not have fought
a war across the sea
Without knoledge that Rome was
in safe hands here at home.
For that we owe a debt of gratitude
to my friend and fellow council,
Gaius Julius Caesar !
Hail Caesar !
This is my daughter, Julia.
- Yes I know we've met.
It would honor my house if you
would give us a recitation.
Not in front of so many people ?
- You've done it in larger groups than this.
Father I assure you that I'm
not prepared for it.
Come...
The daughter of Caesar will recite for us.
Tonight,
Stands beside me and prays with me
A man dear to me and dear to the gods.
Mightier in victory than
the kings of Mycènes
With their golden haired horses.
And stronger more than the battle ghosts
That ride the shores of  Troy.
Hear me,
Sons of gold headed men.
Hear me sing the victory
Of a man dear to me and to the Goda.
Its really nothing.
- No, Its not your fault.
I'm not sure who's fault it is but I assure you I
will find out and he will be punished severly.
Thank you, counciler.
What is your name ?
- Calpurnia.
From who's house ?
- Lucius Piso.
I'm sorry for staring,
I thought perhaps...
...we met somewhere before.
Would you like to eat together ?
- I'd be delighted.
What hour do you call this ?
I think it's known as the fifth hour.
- Yes, The sun is comming up.
You're right, I was out with him.
We drank and ate and had entertainment.
He cares for me.
- Ah yes, he's twice your age.
And your friend remember.
Yes, he is my friend.
I just want to know if he
treats you with respect.
I like him... I do.
I don't love him not yet but ,
..that may come
Why are you behaving in such a manner ?
He is council.
He's the first man in Rome.
He has légions.
The price is high.
What price ?  It's customary for
the father to offer a dowery.
You know I have nothing to give you.
I accept.
I want a commission.
Gaul.
- Gaul ? It's taken.
By Cassius.
- I need a victory in battle.
Your not experinced enough in
warfare and you need legions.
Your légions...
She's all I got,
...I want 50 thousand for her.
50 000 talents ?
Soldiers.
How could you do it ?
How could you take my commission away ?
Because I think Caesar's
the right man for Gaul.
But I've put my staff to considerable
expense preparing my men.
And you'll be re-embursed.
- What ?
And I'll propose that you will
look after the garrison.
The garrison ?
- This won't do, Pompée.
We should put this before the senate...
- Lets not talk business...
...At my wedding.
It may tempt bad luck.
I have a confession to make.
What's that ?
We did meet before.
or rather...
...I met you
but you didn't meet me.
It was at the Pompée triumph.
You fell.
Nobody saw it but me.
I held you  to make sure you wouldn't hurt yourself.
- Thank you.
It shames me.
I never know when its
going to happen.
Many believe those who
have the condition
are holy...
...Blessed by God.
Perhaps.
What do you suppose a child of both our
faces blended together would look like ?
I think that it would look  rather beautiful.
Do you ?
Is it something you'd like to find out ?
- Yes.
Are you sure ?
I am less sure about my own name
than I am about this.
I am terible to have to ask.
- We have servants.
And if I want to go to bed early?
I'll follow you.
Ceasar...
You must make me a promise.
- Anything you like.
Come back from this war alive.
I promise you.
And hurry.
- That's two promises.
And win it.
- That's three promises.
Now it is your turn to promise me one thing.
Will you marry me before I leave.
How many dead ?
- In the region of 23 000 Celtes.
And Romans ?
- 1 12.
I'll have to prepare the burial back in Rome.
We're not returning to Rome.
We're going farther north.
There's a lot more of Rome out there.
Just has'nt called Rome yet.
The Romans !
We must tell Ceasar to retreat.
What I gave to Ceasar,
I will not revoke.
Wait !
Put down your blades.
Why have you come here ?
This land is ours,
you have no right to be here .
What is your name ?
Vercingétorix.
You stayed to fight alone ?
- This is my house.
I built it with my own hands.
And you'll burn it down.
You're free to go.
Give me a horse.
You heard him.
Give him a horse.
My dear Ceasar,
The people speak of you with admiration.
Some call you the great as
they called Pompée.
In the market people sometimes
bow to me as they pass.
You will also be delighted to know
The mariage that began as an advantage,
has blossomed into romance.
Watching Julia and Pompée together
delights me and saddens me.
That you're not here.
No one could be prouder to be
your wife, Ceasar.
But after so long without you,
I fear
I'm getting used to my solitude.
Come home soon my darling.
Until then I will be waiting.
Ceasar has killed 300 000 Celtes.
He attacked peaceful villages,
villages who pay taxes to the  Roman state.
Its beyond tolleration !
This is how you thank a great Roman general ?
Ceasar sent
100 000 slaves back to Rome.
Are you saying you havent taken any of them?
Then if any come from him I would have
got them from somewhere else.
Pompée, you have to be warry.
He's been away three years
fighting with your légions.
He's doubled their salary.
They are totally devoted  to him.
My lords,
As Cicero has put it so well:
Strain every nerve for the
preservation of the state.
Look in every corner for the storms.
They will burst upon you if
you do not see them in time.
I just remembered who he is !
What are you talking about ?
- That man.
Marc Antoine ?
Running from his debtors in Rome
to find wealth in the provinces.
Like all of us.
- not me !
I still fight for the glory of Rome.
My calvery has been attacked.
- By who ?
Gaél tribesmen. 14 000 dead.
- 14 000 ?
And many more wounded.
They acted under one leader.
His name is Vercingétorix.
Where could we find him ?
- In Alésia.
How long is the march ?
- Eight days.
Vercingétorix is in there
With 18 000 of his men.
Its the most invincible
stronghold in Gaul.
We'll never break it.
- We won't have to break it.
We'll build a wall around their city.
We'll trap them inside and starve them.
Noboby has ever built a
fortification of that length.
Then we will be the first.
Let's not waste time.
What do you want ?
I'm here to see Pompée.
- Come here.
Cato...
- Pompée.
Julia...
What brings you to Pisa ?
I've come to speak with you.
Your absence in Rome has been..
criticized.
As you can see,
my wife needs me here.
Can we speak privately ?
What's the matter, Cato ? Did your conversation
depend on speaking ill of my father ?
Sit, sit , Cato.
Thank you.
Ceasar is about to take the
last stronghold in gaul.
Vercingétorix has called for every tribe
from the mountains to the sea.
They are on the move toward Alésia.
How many men ?
Two hundred and fifty thousand.
And my husband ?
- Forty thousand.
He'll survive.
He has survived these many years.
He's never been up against so much.
Is this true ?
Will my husband lose this time ?
I don't know noone knows
the outcome of war.
You are consul, Pompée.
Do something.
If ceasar wins this battle...
- He will become the next Sylla.
Thats what you were going to say
was'nt it ?
That if he wins he will
become the next Sylla...
Why are you worried, Cato ?
You said he didn't stand a
chance against the Gauls.
Why call him back ?
Why not leave him there to fight
this battle to his own death ?
If you leave him there your next
Sylla will extinguish himself.
Your waiting for my husband to fail,
Aren't you ?
And so are you.
To arms !
This is it.
Soldiers at the gate !
He's trying to fool us into
gathering our troups here.
How do you know what he'll do ?
Because that's what I would do
I will wait here for
Vercingétorix to make his move.
His men are to weak to
attack our main camp.
He will move his calvery here and
try to break through the main wall
While his allies attack from the outside.
We cannot let these two
forces join together.
If they do,
We will not survive.