[#]
MAN: The snipers, who killed
three of your brothers,
are in that complex, moving
from building to building.
And while an air strike
would solve our problems,
we'd rather not blow
every civvy in those residences
to their beloved Allah.
So you are
the United States' scalpel.
You will remove the cancer
and save the lives
of those citizens.
We're only two clicks
to the kill zone.
And even though it is a dry 100
in the dark shade
of this lovely evening,
you will keep frosty.
Ooh-rah!
ALL:
MAN: You know
what you're here for, Spooky.
[#]
[GRUNTS]
[KNIFE SQUISHES]
[THUD NEARBY]
[WOOD CLATTERING]
[GUNSHOT]
General Dullarah?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Liar.
[GUNSHOT]
SOLDIER 1: You have to move.
You can't stay here.
Come on, you're gonna have
to come with me.
SOLDIER 2: No, we don't need
a medical unit.
All clear.
What's going on, man?
Hey, sweetie,
what do you have there?
Hey, uh,
you're really fast.
Could barely keep up
with you back there.
SOLDIER 2: Sir, they wanna know
where they're going.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Is that your teddy bear?
Oh, look at that.
SOLDIER 3:
Move that back, two clicks.
[BEEPING]
Bomb!
SOLDIERS:
Get down! Get down!
[GRUNTS]
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[IN RUSSIAN]
Gum?
My wife sends these
from Puerto Peñasco.
It's American gum, though.
Because Mexican gum
tastes like car tire.
She can't wait for me
to get back, my wife.
Hey, hold on.
Check it out.
That's my Lucinda,
my boy, Juan Miguel.
He's so full of energy
I get tired
just looking at the picture.
When I get back,
and get my papers,
once I'm a legal citizen,
gonna bring them to America.
# Don't try to find me #
# 'Cause I'm already gone #
# Your star
Will keep me dry #
# Don't try to follow me #
# You'll never guess #
# Feel like coming
For days... #
[WOMAN MOANING]
[PANTING]
# Used to think about #
# Yeah #
# Don't try to find me... #
Hello?
[IN RUSSIAN]
[PHONE RINGING]
# Don't try to follow me #
[RINGING CONTINUES]
WOMAN [IN RUSSIAN]:
[MACHINE BEEPS]
MAN [ON SPEAKER]:
Spooky, come on, man, pick up.
How's anyone gonna know
they reached you
if you don't put a message
on that thing?
Spooky. I know you're there,
you're always there.
Okay, I'm just gonna keep on
talking until you pick up.
It's Watership Down,
you ever read it?
No?
Oh, man,
it's a good book.
I've read it, like, 10 times.
SPOOKY:
What's the writing?
Oh, that?
That's English class.
This book right here has
taught me how to read English.
Found a copy in Spanish,
a copy in English.
Any word I didn't understand
I wrote in the margins,
looked it up.
This book was my first step
to becoming American.
I love these rabbits.
[OVER SPEAKER]
Spooky, come on, man, pick up.
What?
What do you need?
What's with the chitchat?
You're going to use up
all my cell minutes.
You think about my offer?
I'm not moving to Arizona.
Come on, what do you got
keeping you up there?
Things.
I laid in a hospital bed
next to you for nine months.
I know
when you're full of shit.
Come on, Spooky.
Por favor.
Get your ass down here.
It's sunny, open blue skies.
It's Lucinda and Juan Miguel
finally get their papers.
Come on, man,
I could really use some help
to get the ranch in shape.
Miguel, I'm not moving
to Arizona.
Hey, man, I'm just trying--
Listen, lose my number, okay?
Don't call me again.
[PHONE BEEPS]
[BANG OUTSIDE]
[FIRECRACKER BANGS]
Hey, knock it off.
Hey, man,
go fuck yourself.
Watch your language.
Come on, let's just go.
Screw that. Crazy vet rat
don't scare me none.
He's sorry. We're sorry, mister,
we didn't mean to--
[PHONE RINGING]
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[MACHINE BEEPS]
MIGUEL [ON SPEAKER]:
Hey, Spooky, it's Miguel.
Come on, man,
I know you're there.
Hey, look, I'm just
gonna keep on calling
every day until you say yes.
Come on, man.
I could really use your help.
Don't make me say it.
Okay, shit, man,
I need you out here.
Sir, sir.
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Let's get this guy out first.
It's okay, you're gonna be okay,
we're gonna get you out of here.
SPOOKY:
Him first.
I got a lot of injured men,
he doesn't need help as much.
He saved me.
Him first, him first.
Him first.
Him too.
Let's get him on board.
MAN:
Stretchers now!
Thank you, Spooky.
I owe you.
Damn right you do.
MIGUEL:
I need you out here.
When do you need me?
Bro, thank you, man.
I'll pick you up in front
of the clock tower, 11:30.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
# With all this tension #
# And this hatred
In the world #
# I stand here
Broken in two #
# I'll be back
When this is through #
# With all this tension #
# And this hatred #
# It seems our world
Is in reverse #
# When we come down... #
Thank you.
# I don't know what to do #
Semper fi.
# I just don't
Want to stay here #
# I want to stay alive #
[JOE WEST'S "HEAVEN" PLAYING]
# There's no going back now #
# There's no going home #
# Now that you're stranded #
# On the sand and stone #
# How you miss that old town #
# And how you miss
Your friends #
# But I tell you, my comrade #
# This isn't where it ends #
# We'll meet again in heaven #
# Halos in our hair #
# Everything will be forgiven #
# And everyone'll be there #
# You may
Find yourself feelin' #
MIGUEL: Watership Down.
Man, this is a good book.
About these conejos.
Any word I didn't understand
I wrote in the margins.
I love these rabbits.
# That you wanted to be #
# And all your friends
Are so successful #
# You're bitter
And you're blue #
# But Jesus and his angels #
# Are rootin' for you #
# We'll meet again in heaven #
# Halos in our hair #
# Everything will be forgiven #
# And everyone'll be there #
[HOOVERVILLE'S
"OLD OLD RIVER" PLAYING]
# You know I always feel #
# Like an old, old river #
# Not goin' anywhere #
# But I can go both
Night and day #
# Though I seem so still #
# I'm just trying to forget #
# And I might #
# I just might some day #
# There's a well-worn path #
# By an old, old river #
# Somewhere through the past #
# I can see the interstate #
# I ain't goin' back #
# But I'll try and forget #
# Never thought
Leave it up to fate #
Hey.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
I don't think you know.
MAN 2: I know exactly.
I lived there for 12 years.
MAN 1:
I think you're a damn fool.
Afternoon. You ain't
with the Halicorp folks?
No.
You're a real genius there,
Terry.
TERRY:
Thought I'd check.
What?
What can I do for you?
Need a room?
No, I'm, uh...
looking for a friend
at this address.
Oh, uh, that's out
in the desert, I-I think.
Uh, Don,
this fellow's looking
for that place out on New Hope.
What place?
TERRY: You know, the one that's
all the way out there.
There ain't nothing
out on New Hope
but a bunch of construction.
You here
for a construction job?
No, I'm here
to visit a friend.
That's his address.
That's funny 'cause
there's nothing out there.
All the land's been
bought up by development.
No one's living there yet.
What's your friend's name?
Miguel Silva.
I've never heard of him.
Is there a rental-car service
or a taxi?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Tell you what. Check back
with us in a few months.
The way things are going,
we'll be real modernized
by then.
You said there was
a construction site.
Is there a crew shuttle?
What's with all the questions?
Hey, take it easy.
Don't mind him, he's not
the welcome-wagon type.
Yes, there's a shuttle,
leaves in the morning
about 5 in the a.m.
But I'm telling you,
there ain't nothing out there.
Thanks for your help.
Have yourself a good day.
[DOOR CLOSES]
What the hell?
I'll tell him.
MAN 1 [IN SPANISH]:
MAN 2 [IN SPANISH]:
[LAUGHS]
SPOOKY:
Excuse me.
You speak English?
Sí. Yes.
Did I hear you say something
about, uh, New Hope?
Why?
I wanna go there.
I-I know it.
I'll pay you.
How much?
Twenty bucks?
Okay, 40.
Okay, but up-front.
Okay, get in.
MAN 3 [IN SPANISH]:
Wait on me, Francisco, okay?
[ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[IN SPANISH]
Si, Papa.
Andale.
[#]
My son,
he should know better.
Then he wouldn't be a boy.
Si, verdad.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Whose place is that?
Uh, I-I--
I don't know.
[#]
SPOOKY:
Halicorp.
Why is a defense
and reconstruction outfit
building houses in this area?
Hombre, it's cheap.
The land, the labor.
First the plant,
then the housing.
Now the corporate offices.
It's good for today,
keeps me working.
But next year it's
too expensive to live here,
and I have to move
my family again.
Who knows? Maybe north to Aho.
What kind of plant?
I-I-- I don't know.
I wasn't on that build,
you know?
I, uh-- Listen, hombre,
I-- I need to make a stop, okay?
And-- 'Cause I gotta load
the truck.
Maybe you can walk down past
the construction and I'll--
I'll pick you up
as soon as I'm done.
Look--
Now, look, it's just I can't
bring you to the job site,
you know?
And I'll only be
about 10 minutes.
You know, you should
probably take your bag.
Ah, don't strain yourself.
Look, it's just that I--
I can't be seen.
[HAMMERING]
[#]
Hello.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
...Miguel Silva?
[#]
Well, come on.
VICTOR: This is the address
you were looking for.
SPOOKY: What?
This is it.
SPOOKY:
What the hell?
This is it?
What happened out there?
I-- I don't know.
[IN SPANISH]
Hey, hombre...
Okay?
You know who runs Halicorp?
No, no, I--
Really, I don't.
MAN:
Victor!
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Victor.
[VICTOR SPEAKING
IN SPANISH]
VICTOR:
Stay away.
We have enough problems
without some gringo.
Just leave us alone.
Now, that's a damn shame.
Boy should watch
where he's going.
But you know what they say,
people start playing
where they shouldn't,
look what happens.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[HORN HONKING]
You find your friend?
Quite a town you got here.
I beg your pardon?
A kid gets run over by a car
and nobody says anything,
nobody does anything?
Folks in New Lago like
to keep to themselves.
Besides, the boy seems like
he's gonna be okay, anyway.
You picked a heck of a time
to visit our little slice
of heaven.
We've seen more action today
than we've seen in an age.
Must be the heat.
You be sure to drink
lots of water.
Most city folks can't handle
our generous helping
of sunshine.
Have a nice day.
Oh, hey. Oh. Oh, it's you,
you're back.
Uh...
Wha-- What can I do for you?
You need another map, or...?
Uh, you know, you could a take
a trip on down to old Mexico.
I got some maps for those--
No, I need a room.
Oh. Uh--
Well... Ooh.
You know, I don't know if we--
If we have any rooms
available just now.
I'll take one of those.
Oh, one of those?
Yeah, no, those--
Yeah, right-- Uh, those are,
uh, for a tour group
we got coming in
later today.
Okay. Uh...
That'd be terrific.
Uh, I just need
to see some ID.
You--? You don't have
a driver's license?
Okey-doke.
Well, I-- I just gotta--
The state law--
Make a-- Make a copy of that.
And, uh-- Just gonna
take a second on that.
Copy and...
It's kind of an old machine.
Take a--
It's gonna take a second.
Okay, ha!
Well, here we go. And, uh...
It's a real nice room, right
up the stairs to the right,
all the way down
to the end of the hall.
Got a great view
of Main Street.
You--? You need
some help with that?
Okay.
Uh, you know, that-- That's the
lobby Yellow Pages.
If-- If you--
But you know what? That's fine.
You return it whenever you want.
[#]
Oh, thank you. Bye-bye.
[CHIMES JINGLING]
Um, good afternoon, I'll-- I'll
just be with you in one second.
Uh...
WOMAN [IN SPANISH]:
Hi, um, so sorry.
Can I help you?
I'd just like to check out
the lending library.
Did the cable go out
in your hotel room?
Uh, it's just that
I know everyone in town,
and, um, the only reason
they come by to use the library
is because the cable's gone out.
You know, they-- They did
the whole Wild West look great,
but just the modern amenities,
you know, not so much.
So, um, yeah, you can look
in the library,
but I have to warn you,
it's not the Smithsonian.
GIRL:
I'm done, I'm done, I'm done!
Who are you?
WOMAN:
Don't be rude, it's a customer.
Did you do all the math?
Yes, and it was so hard.
And I read three chapters
of Nancy Drew,
and two of them were
for extra credit.
Well, good work.
So can I help with the customer?
Excuse me, sir,
what can I help you with?
"May I."
What may I help you with?
I just wanted to check out
the lending library.
Well, that's right over here,
silly.
I'm so sorry.
Your hand is all rough.
I'm Carly,
what's your name?
Carly?
I thought your mom was Carly.
Her name's Joanna.
She named the store after me.
See that over there?
That's Carly's corner.
It's where my mom
used to read to me.
Now I read there by myself.
Hm.
So how does this work?
Do, uh, people come in
with books
and trade them
for different things?
Yeah, lots of times.
But usually me and my mom
drive up to Aho
and get the really old books
from the library.
They have
this ice-cream shop there,
and you know what they have?
No.
Malt ball French vanilla.
It's my favorite. Do you have
a favorite ice cream?
Uh...
Chunky Monkey.
[#]
Excuse me, miss?
Oh, please, it's Joanna.
Joanna, uh, do you happen
to have a book
called, uh, Watership Down?
CARLY:
That's an awesome book.
I read it twice. It's so sad--
We-- We did have a copy,
but, um, we gave it away
a couple months ago.
We did?
We did.
Why?
Because that's what happens
when people bring us books,
we sometimes
give them books to take.
But, Mom,
I love that one.
I need you to go and finish
reading your Nancy Drew, okay?
Can I use my corner?
Not now.
Mom.
Not now, okay?
[#]
I'm really sorry,
she's a bit of a handful
sometimes.
Um, did you find
anything else?
Because I really need
to close up.
Um, the people
who you buy books from,
do you have a list of some sort?
No, no, nothing like that.
Do you know of a Miguel Silva?
No, that name
doesn't ring a bell.
I thought you said
you knew everyone in town.
You ask a lot of questions
for someone who's just looking
for a book to read.
[DOOR OPENS, MAN CLEARS THROAT]
But, you know, I really have
to-- Have to close.
Okay, I'll just check this out.
Oh, okay.
Um...
You know what? I-- I--
I seem to have run out
of, um, the loan-out forms.
Um, so if you can come back
tomorrow and I'll give it to--
That's all right,
I'll just buy it.
We're purely a lending library.
So if you come at 9 a.m.,
I'm sure I'll have the forms.
Okay, I understand.
Okay, I can do it.
No, that's all right.
It's all right.
Okay.
I'm really sorry
I can't be of more help.
No, you were very helpful.
You've got a great kid.
Thank you.
Sergeant MacPherson,
what are you doing out of bed?
You removed your IV again.
I, uh--
I don't care.
Get back in your bed.
And whatever you do,
do not wake up Corporal Silva.
MIGUEL:
Don't listen to her, Spooky.
Nurse D gives
a badass sponge bath
if you don't behave.
Fine.
You two deserve each other.
Two minutes.
[GRUNTS]
What you doing, Spooky?
What is this?
Where did you get this?
eBay.
You--? You bid
on an auction for me?
This is the nicest thing
anybody ever did for me.
I mean, this-- This is really
something, man, I mean it.
Okay.
You think we can
go steady now?
Lousy beaner.
Thanks, man.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Well, hey, darling.
What can I get ya?
What have you got?
Honey, we got everything.
But you want something special,
I'd try the chili,
it's world-famous.
Well, county-famous.
I'll have that
and, uh, a glass of water.
You got it.
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, Susie.
Can I grab, um,
two burgers and, uh,
some fairy chicken bites
for the fairy princess?
Sure, sugar.
You want Coca-Colas?
Oh, no, just to go,
tonight.
You got it.
Here you go, soldier.
[#]
[DOOR OPENS]
[WHISPERS]
How are you, sweetie?
Howdy, stranger.
Enjoying a bowl of our chili?
It's world-famous.
Well, county-famous.
Hey, Susie, uh,
put this man's chili on my tab,
all he can eat.
SUSIE:
You got it.
John Rhodes.
A fellow buys you dinner,
you don't even shake his hand?
I'll shake your hand,
and I'll buy my own meal.
Well, I like that.
A man who stands
on his own two feet.
World is sorely lacking
in that kind of attitude.
But I wouldn't expect
any less from a Marine.
I own the hotel.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, heck,
I own most of the town.
You must be the one
with the John Ford obsession.
Oh, yeah.
Truly the...good old days.
I want our little town
to be like none other.
Excuse me.
[CHUCKLES]
RHODES:
That's good.
[CHUCKLES]
You're a funny fellow.
But even with that said
what kind of landlord
would I be
if I let just anyone
saunter on in
and cause trouble?
I'm no trouble.
Oh, I'm sure you're not.
A man like you, rich heritage.
Your mama was
a Cherokee, right?
Proud people,
Native Americans.
The first real Americans,
if you ask me.
And your father was
a Navy man, Irish.
But you were brought up
in the Marines, special forces.
And you were
an embedded contractor for SIA.
Commendations
long as your arm.
Are you--?
You looking for work, son?
I'm looking for a friend.
Well, I can be your friend.
I can also give you a job.
I mean, you haven't
filed tax returns
for the last two years,
so I'm sure money's
been pretty tight.
John Rhodes.
CEO of Halicorp.
Founder of United Borders.
Friend of presidents.
The very man who's rebuilding
most of the places
I was sent to blow up
with weapons...
[SNIFFS]
...made by your company.
Are you writing
my biography, sir?
Or are you just one
well-read Marine, huh?
United Borders, uh,
just a group
of concerned citizens
who think that--
Vigilantes.
What the hell is
your problem, boy?
[CLEARS THROAT]
You'll have to forgive
my overly-sensitive friend.
We prefer
the term "patriots."
People who don't know any better
often make that mistake.
Unlike vigilantes,
United Borders
does not condone violence,
we are simply there
to assist enforcing
the laws of this country.
Protecting our borders from
those who would seek to...leech
off an already
over-leeched system.
I mean,
you're a Marine.
You want someone
to come in here
and destroy everything
that you fought for?
I was a Marine
a long time ago.
Well, once a Marine,
always a Marine.
No disrespect intended.
I'm...not a Marine.
As I said, son,
you never stop
being a Marine.
Well, if you're not
here for a job,
maybe I can offer you the kind
services of Sheriff Bock here.
He'll make sure you get to
the bus station in the morning.
BOCK: It'd be my pleasure to help you
find your way, sir.
Community service.
That's why it's so peaceful
around here.
Peaceful.
[SCOFFS]
Susie, you got Miss Hollis'
order ready yet?
Yes, sir,
coming right up.
Here, let me carry this
for you, darling.
You have yourself
a fine evening.
[CHUCKLING]
You know what I find funny?
No matter how much
people say
Marines are all
hard-core and such...
every one of them I meet
seems to be a big old pussy.
E.B., you cannot
just come back here.
I'm just getting some pie
and some milk.
[SIGHS]
[SLAMS GLASS]
Oh...
Now, that's a shame,
wasting a glass of milk
like that.
SUSIE: Goddamn it.
Martina, trouble, por favor.
Hey there, señorita,
I sure would like to stick
my burrito in your taco. Hm?
[LAUGHS]
Didn't your parents
ever teach you manners?
What'd you say, boy?
I'm just saying
if your mother ever saw
the way you're
treating that girl...
she'd probably die of shame.
You half-breed
son of a bitch!
[MAN SCREAMS]
[E.B. LAUGHS]
Now, isn't that
perfect, huh?
Soldier boy's got
a headache.
There are ladies present.
What would your mama say to
such a disgusting display, huh?
[CHUCKLES]
I think it's time
for you to go.
[PUKES]
Oh, God. God.
Ugh.
You sick piece of shit.
[YELLS]
[GRUNTING]
[#]
You gonna fight?
[GRUNTS]
You're a goddamn cripple.
Crippled son of a bitch.
BOCK: Hold it right there,
mister.
We don't take too kindly
to people littering
here in God's country.
BOCK:
Check his gear.
It says here
you were in Desert Storm.
So how was that?
Winning the war and all?
We didn't win anything.
Hey, chief, take a look.
You don't think he's hiding
any drugs on him, do you?
I have heard stories
about people hiding things
in them hollow legs.
Well, guess we better
check it, then, huh?
You don't wanna do that.
[GRUNTS]
You know,
I think this fella's
a flight risk.
I'm gonna go get him processed.
You boys clean him up.
Take the leg.
MAN: What's it like to kill
a sand nigger?
I bet you took out
a lot of towelheads.
Must have been
where he lost it.
Hell, with that third leg
he's sporting,
I don't think he's too upset.
That's enough.
That's enough!
It's clean.
No drugs here.
What about weapons?
Well, not unless you consider
a plastic leg a weapon.
You like that, boy?
All good
and squeaky clean?
Long time since
you had a shower, huh?
You eyeballing me, boy?
DON: All right,
leave him be.
He's in it deep enough
as it is.
I just don't like anybody
eyeballing me.
MAN 2:
Did you hear the man?
He said he don't
like nobody eyeballing him.
Now it's a fair fight.
[GROANS]
[#]
Look at that.
I guess it can be used
as a weapon.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Howdy.
Ooh, you don't look
so good.
You're not much
of a conversationalist, are you?
Answer the man.
Ah, that's all right, son.
Uh, you can leave us.
So you don't want me to--?
No, no. Here.
[SIGHS]
I been reading a bit more
about you. Fascinating.
Seems I wasn't as respectful
as I should have been.
PTSD's no laughing matter.
But, uh,
even with your condition,
the way you handled
E.B. back there?
You're a man
of extraordinary talents,
talents that, uh,
despite the loss of the limb,
I could pay you
a sizable sum for.
Where is Miguel Silva?
Well, who knows?
He probably ran off
back to Mexico.
You're lying.
[SCOFFS]
[#]
Son, I'm offering you a life.
This town is about to explode
with new jobs and industry.
Hell, the goddamn
Secretary of Defense
just bought 4000 acres
down the road.
I mean, can't you see
what I've built here?
An amusement park?
You seen Times Square lately?
Don't be a fool.
At least I'm trying
to restore God's country,
preserving it as the last
bastion that hasn't been overrun
by foreigners.
We're the foreigners.
Well, heck, somebody's got
to scrub the toilets, right?
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, son, you are in desperate
need of a sense of humor.
Look, I can't legally do
anything
about the ones
that are already here,
except maybe, uh, detain 'em
when they break our laws.
Like littering?
Yeah, among others.
But once I bring the property
values up, they'll move on,
and then I assure you,
you can be damn sure
that my fellow patriots and I
will see to it that
no more get in.
And a man like you,
with your knowledge
and expertise,
can make that job
a lot easier.
Miguel Silva.
[SIGHS]
Now, you're in a heap
of trouble, boy.
You really could use a friend
to make it all go away.
I'm sure I'll get time served
for the littering charge.
Oh, well, we threw out
the littering, so to speak.
We're not even gonna
charge you with, uh, assaulting
an officer of the law--
Jefferson can be
a little overzealous.
--but theft,
that's a different matter.
That book you pocketed
from the lending library,
that's larceny and that's
a mandatory 90-day sentence
in this town.
We have a zero tolerance policy
on theft at Halicorp.
That woman's store
is not Halicorp.
Oh, yeah, of course it is.
This whole town is Halicorp.
Hell, this whole country
is Halicorp.
Now, you sure you don't want
to reconsider my offer?
A lot can happen to a man
in 90 days.
Shoot, a lot can happen
in just one night.
I have an offer for you.
You tell me what's happened
to Miguel Silva
and I won't have to start
burning down God's country.
I respect a man
who knows his mind,
but remember, a working man
held out his hand in friendship.
You can play dress up
all you want,
but the only work
your hands have ever done
is counting money.
Have yourself a safe night.
[OWL HOOTING]
[CELL OPENS]
[#]
[SPOOKY GRUNTING]
Let me see his face.
How tough do you think he'll be
if he loses the other leg?
[CRIES OUT]
[ALL YELLING]
MAN [ON RADIO]:
He ran out of the station.
I'm coming, goddamn it.
I don't see him,
just Jenson's unit.
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[GUNSHOTS]
MAN:
That son of a bitch.
He's got the car.
MAN: Get him!
MAN:
He's getting away, let's go.
[SIRENS BLARING]
MAN [ON RADIO]:
Foster, where the hell are you?
MAN 2:
Anybody?
I think the bastard's
heading to New Hope.
Did you get that, Lee?
Roger that.
MAN 3: Is it okay
if I bang up Unit 4, chief?
BOCK: You do what you got to do
to stop this son of a bitch.
MAN 4: Mr. Rhodes, sir,
you sure you don't want us
to handle this situation?
It looks like the only one
handling this situation
is that smart bastard
in one of your squad cars.
He gets out past this road,
he might just get away.
So would you boys please try
and overtake him? Over that.
[GROANS]
For God's sake,
I bet this son of a bitch
has been listening to us
the whole goddamn time.
Radio silence.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[#]
RHODES [ON RADIO]:
I guess us southern folks
can fool you big city fellas
after all, huh?
[GRUNTS]
Stop!
You want to go get that car
when it goes over the edge?
Foster,
cover him.
This sure look familiar,
don't it?
Shut your mouth. Back off!
Nobody get too close.
Just wouldn't listen, would you?
I guess
I'm just a slow learner.
Yeah, so smart,
yet so damn stupid.
[LAUGHS]
Shoot him.
Hold your fire!
I was okay with E.B. and Lee
beating some sense into him,
but killing another
in cold blood?
This ain't what I signed up for.
You signed up
to keep the peace. Heh.
Now do your job.
We can't keep doing this.
What is it? Your conscience
or your cowardice?
E.B.
You finally grew a pair,
huh, kid?
I wish you hadn't knocked him
down the ravine, but--
Sorry about that.
Hey, no harm, no foul.
Now, you get down there
and find him,
take him across the border
and bury him deep.
[HELICOPTER APPROACHING]
DAN:
One of ours?
No, border patrol.
Goddamn it.
All right, everybody move out.
We got enough heat without
any of us being found carrying
a decorated war vet's body
with a bullet in it.
Let me tell you,
tonight you get back here
and deal with this situation,
and then I don't want to hear
anything about this ever again.
All right.
[DOORS SHUTTING]
[#]
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
MAN:
Bomb!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Thanks, Spooky.
I owe you.
Damn right you do.
[#]
[WOMAN SPEAKING
IN SPANISH]
[MAN SPEAKING
Gracias.
[IN SPANISH]
JOANNA:
Mexico.
You've been unconscious
for days.
You lost a lot of blood.
I-I think you may have
broken some ribs.
It's a really good thing
you were wearing that vest.
Could you--?
Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
It's surprising you didn't
break anything else.
You fell, like, 20, 30 feet.
You stitched me up.
Oh, you did good work.
It looks like
it's healing nicely.
Who brought me here?
Marina, the woman that works
for me, and her brother,
Eduardo, and some friends.
How did they know
where to find me?
I should go.
Why do you stay in New Lago,
Joanna?
John Rhodes.
He's Carly's--?
No, no, he's not.
No. No.
You grow up in a town like Lago
and you marry the first guy--
And he was no winner, either.
He died when Carly was 2.
He drove head-on into a, uh, bar
that he just spent
a week's salary in.
And Rhodes?
After Jerry died,
the only thing I had left
was unpaid bills.
The only family
I had in the world
was Carly and my brother,
Donnie, and he couldn't
hold on to a job
if it had a handle on it.
And then Rhodes came to town,
and he was rich,
and kind,
and smart,
and he courted me for months.
After we started...
seeing each other,
he set me up in my own store,
and he was--
He was good to Carly and me.
He was so gentle.
And then he decided
to make Lago his home,
and no one could believe
that a man like that
would want to stay here.
And he started to throw money
into everything,
and he started
to rebuild the town.
And everyone felt safe.
Hell, I felt safe
for the first time in my life.
For a while.
And then suddenly
the rules started
and I couldn't go anywhere
without him knowing about it.
And before we knew
who John Rhodes really was,
he had owned us,
and in a blink, there were
no more business owners,
there were just employees.
I stay here because
I know he'll hurt my child.
And I know there's nowhere
that I can run
that his money will not find us.
How many times have you
been out here to check on me?
A few.
[SIGHS]
Doesn't Rhodes know you're here?
No.
No, I, uh, cross the border
all the time
to get low-priced items
for the town pharmacy.
He doesn't have any problem
making money
off the Mexican economy.
Yeah, I had a feeling
those construction workers
weren't, uh, from Scottsdale.
Yeah, they're just cheap slaves
and he'll send them
right back to Mexico
when he's done with them.
Why are you helping me?
Because someone needs
to stop him.
I'm not your man.
Why?
Well, you need a soldier.
I'm not...that anymore.
Is it because--?
No, because of what caused it.
You know that sound after you've
heard a really loud noise?
Ringing?
Yeah.
That's the sound
of a frequency dying.
Once the sound is gone,
that...part
of your hearing's gone.
I haven't been able
to...make a fist, or--
Or pick up a gun.
Nothing.
But you fought off
all those men.
Just instinct.
Just, uh, defending myself.
That part of me that did damage,
that's gone.
I think there's something
you need to see.
[STATIC HISSING ON TV]
MIGUEL:
I am a citizen!
The law says if I serve
in your Army
I am a citizen. Please!
MAN: He's a decorated
United States Marine.
MAN 2: I don't give a fuck
what you say he is, Morgan.
All I see is a beaner.
MAN 3:
These look real.
MAN 2:
Just 'cause you got papers
doesn't mean you can
bring your family.
MIGUEL: I fought for this country,
and I was told
when I become a citizen
I can bring my family here.
I am a citizen!
I don't care how many
sand niggers you killed,
you'll never be an American.
RHODES:
Let me see that!
Is this great country
so hard up
for good men to fight for it
that we're gonna sell out
our most basic rights
to someone like you?
I might have
to let you stay,
but I'll lay down dead
before I let them cross over.
No, sir.
If I have to cuff 'em
and load 'em
into my truck myself,
I will send these two
back to where they belong.
MORGAN:
These are good people.
Miguel has worked
my farmland for years.
RHODES: You admitting
to a crime, Morgan?
It sounds like you are.
These papers were issued
eight months ago,
but this fella's been working
for your farmland for years.
That means either you're lying,
or these are misdated.
MORGAN: I was just saying Miguel
is a good--
Which is it?!
You're a liar,
or these papers are incorrect.
I'm just trying to--
Which is it?!
He did nothing wrong!
I believe you.
So if he did nothing wrong,
then the date on these papers
is incorrect,
and according
to the immigration laws
of this great land,
renders them invalid
and void.
No!
WOMAN: No! No!
[SCREAMING, THUDDING]
WOMAN: Por favor! Por favor!
[GUNSHOT]
[#]
I-I swear I didn't mean it.
It just went off.
RHODES: Who cares if you didn't
mean it, goddamn it?
MAN:
What the hell do we do now?
Finish it.
MIGUEL: Oh, please.
MAN: You can't just shoot them,
that's insane.
RHODES:
Do what I say.
Kill him, now.
MIGUEL: No, please!
Goddamn it,
what's wrong with you?
Even cockroaches have babies.
MIGUEL:
No, please, not my son!
[GUNSHOT]
No!
Kill him.
[GUNSHOT]
[TV TURNS OFF]
Why hasn't anyone
done anything?
What could we do?
What?!
What--?
Why haven't you done anything?
I showed you!
You saw the tape.
All you see is Sheriff Bock.
No one else's face appears.
Do you live in the same world
that I do?
People who have money
get away with everything.
John Rhodes would hire
enough lawyers
to make people think
that you killed Miguel's family
and he should get a medal
for bringing the killer
to justice.
You don't understand
how powerful he is.
Him and his government cronies,
they make an excuse
to go to war,
and suddenly he has contracts
for tanks and planes
to destroy an entire nation.
Then when it's time
to rebuild,
he gets paid to-- To fix exactly
what he's knocked down.
Then with that money, he buys
more and more of America,
and does he put any money
in the pockets of Americans?
No.
He hires slaves
and doesn't pay them
an honest day's wage.
Then with that money he puts up
a private border guard
and convinces people
he's stopping terrorists
from crossing the border.
And it's just an excuse
to start another war,
and it all goes around again.
So was it worth it?
Losing your leg for a lie
to line John Rhodes' pockets?
Who gave you the tape?
Were they there?
Yes.
They were there,
then they're witnesses.
Yes, so what?
Who gave you the tape?
He would be killed
before he even got to testify.
I mean, wake up,
John Rhodes
is never going to see
the inside of a prison cell.
He was my friend.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[GUNSHOTS]
[#]
Come on, come on.
Go, hurry up. Come on.
[CRIES OUT]
SPOOKY:
Is this really on foundation?
EDUARDO: Si.
JOANNA: What are you doing?
Get under the house, okay?
JOANNA: Okay.
All right,
get under the house.
He knows I'm here.
He's gonna go after Carly.
Please, he's--
Your daughter's going
to be fine, I promise.
Hold your fire,
hold your fire.
Any sign of them?
E.B.:
Roger?
Anybody close to Roger?
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
E.B. [OVER RADIO]:
Monty? Monty?
What the hell's going on here,
E.B.? I don't see nobody.
The hell do you mean
you don't see nobody?
Let's get the fuck outta here.
[KNIFE SQUISHES]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
E.B.:
Guy's like a fucking ghost.
How did you--?
[E.B. YELPS, GROANS]
No, God,
please don't kill me. No.
[SCREAMS]
[GUNSHOT]
No, please, no.
[GASPING]
The only reason you're alive
is to deliver a message.
Anything you want.
Just please don't kill me.
You tell John Rhodes
I'm bringing hell
to God's country.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
MAN:
Gentlemen.
Thank you, but, uh,
this little beauty's
all a man should ever need.
You're the boss.
So who you got watching Carly
at my place?
Jefferson and two of the fellas
from out of town.
We're keeping
our newly-appointed sheriff
away from all this, right?
Yeah. And about that--
Just get this all done and I'll
make things right by you,
don't you worry.
But you ever disobey me again,
you'll be the one
out in the desert
with E.B.'s gun up your ass.
The hell is taking him so long?
Look, the most important thing
right now
is you draw enough attention
to yourself,
we got an airtight alibi.
[VEHICLE APPROACHES]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
MAN 1:
Look out!
MAN 2:
Wha--? What's going on?
MAN 3:
Get outta there.
Hey, is that him?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
He's coming.
[GURGLES, GASPS]
Call everyone.
[#]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
MAN:
Make sure you're armed.
He's calling in everybody.
You're kidding.
Okay, Main Street, we're coming.
Get this guy in the truck.
We gotta get back.
Something big's going down.
Move it, Pancho.
What you're doing is illegal.
You're not border patrol.
Mira.
I have my work visa.
What the hell?
I don't see no damn papers.
Looks like runners.
Move it.
[SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
I'll get the binoculars.
I don't need it.
Burris is twice as powerful.
So how many points--?
Well, lookie here,
two chiquitas.
Shit, one of 'em's white.
The hell?
Nothing. They're the ones
who haven't called
to say they were on their way.
Well, try again.
Unit 42, Unit 42,
what's your 20?
Unit 42, respond, unit.
SPOOKY [OVER RADIO]: Bock, is that
you and Foster up on that roof?
Looks like everyone's there,
sheriff.
[GRUNTS]
All units, all units.
Vehicle Number 42 has been
hijacked by suspect.
Do not approach.
Suspect is armed and extremely
dangerous. Wait on my command.
MAN [ON RADIO]:
Number 42 has been hijacked.
Do not approach.
William MacPherson,
[OVER MEGAPHONE]
this is Sheriff Foster.
Stop your vehicle and step out
with your hands
behind your head.
[GUN COCKS]
What's this idiot's plan,
suicide?
MacPherson,
this is your second warning.
Stop your vehicle.
All units, ready your aim.
The second he steps
out of the vehicle,
you are to take this man down.
MacPherson,
stop the goddamn vehicle.
[GUN COCKS]
This moron wants to get dead,
let's send him to hell.
Open fire, open fire!
[GUNSHOTS]
Hold your-- Hold your fire.
DON:
Hold your fire!
[GUNSHOTS]
Hold your goddamn fire!
You two, back. You in the front,
let's go. Expect anything.
MAN:
I think he's dead.
Yeah? That's what we thought
the last time I shot him.
Nice going, Bock.
I'll be sure to let Rhodes know
you're the one who ordered
the men to shoot.
[EXPLOSION RUMBLES]
[GUNSHOTS, GRUNTS]
Jesus Christ.
Terry's down. Terry's down.
Come on, come on.
[GUNSHOTS]
All units, all units,
suspect is alive
and inside construction site.
Somebody get inside there
and kill that fucker.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Oh.
Come on, let's get outta here.
Come on.
I thought he'd come here,
not you.
I stayed to face him.
Guess he chose
the coward's way out.
You're not half the man he is.
You gonna shoot me, Joanna?
You're a murderer.
And you'll never come near me
or my child again.
After all I've done
for you and Carly?
You kept us prisoners.
[GUN COCKS]
You-- You can't shoot me.
I'll do whatever it takes
to-- To protect my child.
It's about time
I start cleaning up my own mess,
while he's out there
taking down everything
that you've built.
[GASPS]
[GASPS, YELLS]
Mommy!
[JOANNA COUGHING]
You disappointed me so.
Put her in the car,
we got a fight to go to.
[GUNSHOT]
Goddamn it, goddamn it.
[BULLETS WHIZZING]
He's out of ammo.
Or reloading.
He hasn't shot
at me.
He's out,
let's move in.
Good,
I'm sick of this hiding shit.
Get up, Bock.
Why? So he can pick us off
when we get closer?
He's only got what he took
from Turner and Cribbs.
He's out, let's go.
The building's collapsing.
He's gonna come out.
We can wait it out here!
You fucking pussy.
You wanna let him
escape again?
Huh? This guy is like a ghost,
all right?
We wait longer,
he's in the damn wind,
and who knows
where he shows up next.
Maybe in the media.
Maybe at your house, Bock.
[#]
[GUN COCKS]
[GRUNTS]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMS]
[NAIL GUN FIRING]
[GROANS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Looks like you're not the only
soldier that comes prepared.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
[GUNSHOTS]
[ALL GRUNTING]
[GUNSHOT]
You'll need this.
[GROANS]
Nice work getting those guys
to come in here.
I was running out of ammo.
My sister told me
what you're trying.
I just never thought
you'd get it done.
I know you gave Joanna the tape.
I do have one question--
How'd I know you wore the vest?
That's the question.
[GUNSHOTS]
Because the deputy
you stole it from
wasn't wearing his.
That was your only clue?
[GRUNTS]
Well, I saw it under your--
Under your jacket.
I mean, you're big,
but you're not that big.
I bet that hurt, huh?
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
Anyway,
I figure with all this,
we're evened out, right?
[GRUNTS]
Now we are.
[GROANS]
I know I deserved that, but:
Ow.
Anyway, this place
is about to come down on us.
[#]
Best way out
is through the front.
Where the rest of
the United Border Patrol is?
How fast can you draw down?
Hold your fire.
Hold your fire, I got him.
MAN:
Stand down.
[GUNS CLICKING]
DAN:
Bock,
go get a squad car.
BOCK: Got it!
JEFFERSON:
Foster's in it with him.
MAN:
Get him!
[GUNSHOTS]
[GRUNTS]
MAN:
Watch it!
[YELLS]
MAN: Got him!
MAN 1:
Watch yourself!
MAN 2:
Where's your line of fire?
Come on, shoot!
MAN 3: Look out!
MAN 4:
What are you doing?
[GRUNTS]
[GUNSHOTS]
[GUN CLICKS]
[GUN COCKS]
[GROANS]
Not a good strategy, soldier.
Not if your opponent can
follow your lead.
[GRUNTS]
Look over there.
I want her to see me
humiliate you
before I kill you.
I don't think she'll ever
stray again. Do you?
That right.
And you, I trusted you,
and what did you do?
Ooh.
Oh, such a brave soldier.
Too bad you're
a traitor.
9/11 was a wake-up call.
A call to stop letting
every godless mongrel race
onto our soil.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Free men built this country.
That's the country I fought for.
I don't give a damn
about your politics.
You--
You killed my friend
and his family,
and that makes you a murderer.
They were illegals!
Real Americans
are taking
this country back.
Men who belong,
men who are pure.
Not half-breeds.
[GRUNTS, GROANS]
You filthy--!
[GROANS]
Bock,
shoot this fucking cockroach.
[RHODES GRUNTS]
Well, what are you waiting for?
Shoot him!
In front of all these people?
Fuck 'em. They got a life
because I give it to 'em.
That's enough!
I'll say when it's enough.
[LOUD SQUISH]
[BLOOD SPLASHES]
[SQUISHES]
[MOANING SOFTLY]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTS]
Help me.
Help me, someone.
Get me a doctor.
[GASPS, RETCHES]
God, you damn bastards.
This town was nothing
without--
[SPLUTTERS]
[GROANS]
BOCK:
All right!
Everybody head home.
And you, you're under arrest
for the murder of John Rhodes.
DON: Are you out
of your fucking mind?
Drop your weapon and put
your hands over your head.
And if you give me
any trouble, Bock,
I'll deputize
every last one of 'em.
[#]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[COUGHS]
[BREATHING RAGGEDLY]
DON: "The recent controversy
has forced
"the already under-fire Halicorp
"to rethink its move
to the city of New Lago.
"Acting Halicorp CEO Ronald Core
"says that it will end
its funding
"of United Borders
and all its affiliates,
"in the light
of the class-action suit
filed earlier this week."
You believe that?
I can believe it.
Hey, you sure you don't wanna
move into Rhodes' place?
Yeah, you can have it.
You can have it for nothing.
Miguel Silva saved my life.
He invited me here.
I think I'll stay.
You think you're
gonna be safe here?
Rhodes had
a lot of true believers
working for him.
Carly, lunch!
Let 'em come.
I'm not going anywhere.
[#]
Subtitles by LeapinLar