Peloton!
Apunten!
Wait, wait
We want to hear
the whole story
Why did you come
to our country anyways?
Yeah, why did you come?
- You want the whole story?
- Everything
How much time
have you guys got?
Sit down
- We're not going anywheres
- Nowheres
Okay
Do you know my fiance
Will Gallagher?
- We heard about him
- We heard him
He went to Switzerland on a business trip
He gets to go to
postcard country
l get to stay home
You get the picture?
But, he forgot some documents
Will!
l was gonna drop them in the mail
but then l thought.
why not make this
our first Christmas together?
Snow- capped mountains
Swiss chocolate
yodelers in the street a.
a cozy fireplace in a chalet
l didnt take long
to convince myself
Everything was exactly
as l imagined it.
except for Will's office
Excuse me
Hi, l'm looking for
Raffke and Partners
suite five seven seven
Raffke? Yah
You dont speak English?
Over there
number five seven seven
No- no- no
Um, thats a, thats a P.O box
- Yah, thats a P.O. box
- Yah
So much for the cozy fire place
Now l dont know
if you've ever been
to Switzerland but.
They've got these computers
for phone books, you know
hi- tech yellow pages
Very impressive
Still didnt help me
l found nothing
What did you do?
The obvious
l ate half a chocolate cake
and called my best friend Rita
Where did you get
the P.O. box address?
From, from the envelope
that Will left at home
the one that he wanted me
to send to him
So whats in the envelope?
lm opening it
Claire?
Are you there?
l'm here
- Only Will isn't
- What?
l just found his flight itinerary
and he never even
came to Switzerland
- He went to El Coronado?
- Oh my God, he's having an affair
You haul your ass all the way
to the Matterhorn
and he's off screwing someone in
Where did you say he was?
l can't even think right now
Claire, l am so sorry
l'm gonna call you later Rita
l was so angry
But l was also worried
And then l got more angry
because l was worried
Why did he have
to lie to me?
And then he had to go to the most
obscure place on the planet
no offense
Coronado?
Where the hell is Coronado?
l hadnt really packed for Central America
But nothing was
gonna stop me now
- Do you need cupons?
- No, no thank you
- Take a look
- No thank you
- Look, l'll give them to you
- l need a taxi
- Look, its valid forthirty days
- No, no
- l'll give it to you at a good price
- No, no, no little boys, no
- Move. Please
- No
- Come on move
- Oh, please
- Not now. Look, lll give it
- Senor
- No one will give it
- l am not, no, no, no
l'm now buying
anything from you
l am not buying
- No one will
- Comprende, no, no!
Taxi!
Hey
Just arrived?
So
how do you like it so far?
Paradise
Arnet, l got a perfect place
to shoot the stand- up
We've gotta go now
before somebody blows it up
Excuse me
The military splinter group
led by General Rafael
is becoming more and more powerful
as witnessed by todays attack
on the governments military
installations at El Coronados airport
Rebel sources say that
these small tactical attacks
are only attempts
to bleed out
President Hugo Luis Ramo's
military power
a tactic which for now
appears to be working
For C.B.B.
l'm Arnet McClure
All right, cut it Renny
Excuse me
Can you please recommend
a decent hotel?
Look, in case you havent noticed
- this isnt exactly a tourist place
- Oh, really?
You mean there isn't
good skiing here?
- Come on
- Take the, take the Grand
lt's the only one
without cockroaches
Good luck
Hey do you wanna
do you wanna share a cab?
Thanks, we're fine
Hi
- Oh, hi miss
- Hi
l would like a
l'd like a single room, please
- Yes, just register here
- Preferably non- smoking
And uh, if you have
one with a view
Take the east wing
West wing
- Here ya go
- And also um
do you have a guest registered here
by the name of Will Gallagher?
- Actually l have a picture
- No, l have never seen this man
lf l had
l would remember him
Okay, okay
- Welcome to our hotel
- Thank you
What did you say to him?
l said
l said that you were
really a man
- You, you did what?
- l'm kidding
- l said you were my wife
- That's funny
Gosh, that's almost as funny as you
leaving me on the street today
Oh, ow, we're still
angry about that
Well lm sorry
l had to get some footage
of the airport for the
uh, New York feed
Look l'll make it up to you
l'll buy you another drink
- Not you, her
- l already have a drink
Well its not gonna
get you drunk
Well who says
l wanna get drunk?
Well why else would
a tourist wanna be here?
Oh, maybe you haven't heard
This isn't exactly a tourist place
Touche
- Are you from the states?
- No, l'm a native
- Whats your name?
- Claire
- Arnet McClure
- Hello, Arnet
Hello, Claire
How long have you been
down here?
About two years
when all hell broke loose
But then you probably
recognize me
l'm the one
who did all the
reports on the attempted
rebel coup about a year ago
- Oh my God
- Yeah
- That was you
- That was me
l didn't see it
Well, you know
you should really pay better attention cause
it's your tax dollars that keep
the government in power down here
A full- blown revolution
could break out at any minute
You trying to scare me?
No, l'm just saying
you shouldn't be here
unless you have
a damn good reason to be
Okay, well first of all
l can take care of myself
And second of all
l do have a damn good reason
Would that reasons name be
Will Gallagher?
- Do you know him?
- No
l heard you say his name
at the front desk
Do you always eavesdrop
on peoples conversations?
Yeah l do
l'm a reporter
So, why are you
looking for Will?
Fiance
How'd you lose
your fiance?
l don't think the story's
good enough for your network
Fine, just trying to help
Well, why don't ya help me
find my fiance?
You know l'm sorry
l'm gonna be gone tomorrow
l got a little expedition
into rebel territory
But you oughtta check with
the uh, American Embassy
They keep pretty
good tabs on the Americans
- that come in and out of here
- Thank you very much, Mr. Reporter
- Good luck on your quest
After checking all the hotels
and all the hospitals in town
the Embassy seemed
to be a good idea
Your fiance
could be anywhere
He arrived on December eleventh
l have him down right here
Look
the U.S. government supports
the Coronado government
under President Ramos
So the rebels don't
exactly love U.S. citizens
l don't wanna alarm you
but there have been twenty- two reported cases
of U.S. citizens being
kidnapped by the rebels
l only hope that your fiance
isn't number twenty- three
Well
why would he even be in Coronado?
l mean he never
mentioned it before
You said he had some
documents written in Spanish?
Well obviously he was here
on some sort of business
No, no, no, no
No No
He uh, he was doing
business in Switzerland
He has a post office box
thats in Zurich
And l have
a time share in Maui
Look theres nothing we can do
Right now we're
working frantically
just to establish contact
with the rebel leaders
But so far without any luck
Okay, well that doesn't seem
like an awfully big country
- Why don't we just get
- Miss
Roughly a quarter
of this country
is now rebel territory
and they're expanding
That's thirty thousand square miles
of desert, mountain and jungle
Can you imagine trying
to find somebody in that?
We don't even know
where the main rebel base is
And it dawned on me that
that's exactly what l'd have to find
My God
The Grand Hotel
West wing, huh?
Well, least you got your view
Why would they do this?
Because the west wing
is full of brass
- Brass?
- Military, high- ranking officials
Listen
Honey, you wanna stay
as far away from
the military as possible, nope
Could l uh, could l
take you up on your offer?
- What offer?
- You, you said
that you were trying to help
Could you take me to the rebels?
You wanna fight?
Well they have my fiance
What, hostage?
- What did he do?
- l don't know
Okay wait
You want me
to give you a ride?
That would be so very great
Thank you
- Thank you
- To the rebels?
Then what?
Then l'll, l'll
have to rescue him
Right, by yourself
- Yeah
- ln the jungle?
ln your evening dress?
- You don't even speak Spanish
- Well l speak a little Spanish
My maid speaks
Spanish at home
Whoa, Whoopee
Big deal
What are you gonna do
go politely knock on the rebels door and say
- please release my uh, fiance?
- Now, now, now
No one said anything
about politely
Oh man
How's the clutch, Jose?
Tip- top boss man
Almost tip- top
Here, take this will ya?
- What's your name again?
- Claire Winslow
All right, look Claire
l need you to know that
this isn't some Barneys Warehouse sale
Roughly one- quarter
of this country
is rebel territory
and expanding rapidly
That's almost thirty
thousand square miles of
jungles and deserts
This isn't a scare tactic
all right?
- lt's a fact
- l appreciate the warning
l just, l need a ride
What's the problem?
Come here
ln almost two years
l've gotten maybe a couple
of snippets of rebel action
This story is gonna change
everything for me
l am betting
my career on it
So there is no way
no matter what
that you will be coming
with me, Princess
He's stubborn
How did you
change his mind?
What can l say?
l just.
appealed to the most
noble side of his nature
Five hundred bucks
Where's the air- conditioning
in this thing?
Don't touch anything, please
Look for Temeagualpa
- lt's a little village
- Found it
Go three miles
on this road
and then make a left
at the crossing
How do you know these
people are in Temagulpa?
The rebels are hiding out
in the jungle
Temeagualpa
is a rebel- friendly village
When we get there
we'll find out
where their base camp is
The people are
just gonna tell you?
Just let me worry about that
all right?
Okay
l'll be back
Not to fear ladies and gentlemen
Arnets gonna get us through this
He knows how to communicate
with these people
He's a gringos gringo
You know
We gotta find
another way
- There is no other way
- l know
Hey guys, come here!
The enemy! Lets go!
They've got tanks!
Told ya l had a plan!
Lets go!
Yeah, nice plan McClure!
This is where
the fun begins
Jeez!
Showtime amigos!
- We're carrying guns?
- l'll explain later!
Son of a bitch!
Shoot! Come on!
Put your foot on the gas
Come on!
All right now
grab the wheel!
- What are you doing?
- l'm saving your butt, Princess!
- Slide it over, will ya?
- Don't yell at me!
Come on Renny
what're you doing?
Shoot
No not shoot, shoot!
Careful!
Well, that takes care of that
Did you call me
Princess back there?
- Yeah, l might've
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Oh just relax, will ya?
- And why are we carrying
- Forget about it
- an arsenal of guns back there?
Well how else am l supposed
to get into rebel territory?
You're supplying
the rebels with guns?
No, l'm supplying them
with toilet paper!
This is so insane
You never said anything
about going into battle!
Relax
We just won the battle!
Oh really?
You think so?
- l...l gotta go back
- Yeah go, go, go, go!
Jose, hang in there
You're gonna be fine
Tip- top, boss man
Floor it Claire!
Hey, there's
a crossing up ahead!
Dont try to make it past!
Get past?
l'll never make it!
Train is moving too fast!
The trains going too fast!
- lt'll crush us
- Rush?
Oh l'm going
as fast as l can!
Dont try!
All right, lll try!
What, is she crazy?
He's crazy!
Stop, stop, stop!
- Cuidado!
- Okay
- You really study medicine?
- Yes, please, please hold still
l've studied medicine
for three years now, Jose
- You studied on real people?
- Yes
Well, kind of, sort of
l mean they're dead bodies
They're real people
Were they dead before
or after you practiced on them?
Stop it
Don't be a baby
lt's a scratch, Jose
l got hit by
a thirty- eight caliber bullet
lt didn't even
hit the bone
Dad would not approve of this one
l'll tell ya that right now
Why?
Well because with the tools l have
l- lm afraid its gonna leave a scar
lt'll just add to
my collection
Look, My back
Ouch
What happened?
Government wanted to know
where the rebels were
Guess what?
They still wanna know
Sons of bitches
l'm finished
- Gracias
- You're welcome
Tip- top boss man
- What are you writing?
- Oh nothing
Oh, Sorry
l just...
notes...reporter notes
l used to dream of this
when l was a little girl
Campfire
coffee out of tin cups
underneath a starry night
lt is so Rio Bravo
- You've seen Rio Bravo?
- Oh, like a hundred times
l used to spend my summers
with my grandfather
up- he had a ranch up near
Cody, in Wyoming
l know where Cody is
Oh, well we used to uh
- we used to horseback ride
- Big rodeo in Cody
- And we used to milk
- Fourth of July rodeo
- the cattle
- l've been to that rodeo
- and husk corn
- And a bar fight in Cody
Never mind
Well l guess
we'd better get some sleep
- Big day tomorrow
- l know
Okay
All right
You got a choice
You can share my tent or uh
shack up with the boys
We need to push!
l said we need to push
That means everybody!
l paid for this, remember?
You we're the one who told me
that l was a passenger!
Yeah l did
Now lm tellin' ya to push!
Just pretend you're
what's- her- name in Rio Grande!
She didn't have to push a truck
out of the mud in that movie!
Sure she did
Now push!
Push, push!
Come on, come on!
That evening
we arrived in Temagulpa
Temeagualpa
That's what l said
lt was completely
destroyed and deserted
Christ, these people
stop at nothing
Bastards
lt's Rafaels birthplace
He's the rebel leader?
They burned it down
By the looks of it
we weren't gonna find anything
that would lead us to the rebels
All right Renny
l need some coverage of this
What d'ya say?
Two wide shots of the street
and uh, some close- ups inside
the burned out houses
l just saw something
move right there
All right Claire
this might be a trap
So l want you to go around
and stay close to Jose
Close
Claire
stay close to the truck
What the hell?
Thought l heard something
Hi
lt's okay
Don't be afraid
Here you go
lt's okay sweetheart
There ya go
lt looked like we had found
the only survivor of the raid
Hello
Where are your friends?
Your parents?
They were taken away
Everyone was taken away?
My brother
Your brother is Rafael?
Do you know where he is?
Will you show us?
- Press!
- lt's okay
- Journalist!
l thought you guys
ditched me
Who's the kid?
No no no no
Can we cross the bridge?
Jose
He says that the bridge
is solid and strong
and that he's seen
many trucks pass
Come forward
Slowly
Keep coming
Shit
Slowly
That's fine
You're doing good
Stop, stop!
Come slowly
Careful to the left
to the left
Slowly
Wait!
We gotta go out there!
We gotta go, we gotta get em
Lets go
Wait, wait here
Jose, Renny!
- Get out of here!
- No way
All right
l'm gonna try
to drive outta here
Be careful
Okay boss, l'm ready
The Lord is with me
How's that thing go again?
All right, do it
One, two, three!
All right!
Come on!
One more time Jose!
One, two, three!
Do it!
Jose?
Yeah boss?
What the hell did
that old shepherd tell you?
Honestly...
l have no idea
Well then what about
the many trucks pass by?
turn off the engine
Claire, go get Anna
Jose, l want you
- up front walking the bridge
- Tip- top boss man
Time to go to work baby
Come on, it's clear
Come on
Hello Pulitzer Prize
Come here Anna
Come on
Renny!
Forget the camera!
l wanna catch this
Anna, come to me, please!
Give me your hand, Anna
Come, come here
Come on, come on
Reach up
Reach up...my hand!
No! Claire!
Two hundred feet?
You fell two hundred feet?
Yes
Maybe it was a hundred
l must of washed up
on the bank blacked out
And when l opened my eyes
l was met by some
friendly locals
Excuse me
Gringa?
They fished me
out of the water
l was so scared
l thought
they were gonna
have me for breakfast
And this one guy
took my wallet
And he wasn't
interested in my money
You know this man?
Will Gallagher is delivering
weapons for you guys?
Yeah
From the government
of the United States of America
So, but without a doubt
without a doubt this is the guy?
He came with the mercenaries
about a week ago
Son of a bitch
Raffke and Partners
what was that?
Son of a bitch
Why are you trying
to find the guy?
Well because he said
he was going to Switzerland
on business as a lawyer
and now he's in Central America
as an arms dealer
Son of a bitch
You know you can't
trust a man like that
Wait, wait a minute
wait a minute
You said he delivers weapons
for the US government?
But that doesn't make sense
No, no, because the government
is for Ramos, not the rebels
- Well, that's politics
- So, so?
So, you are a woman
This country definitely
needs a revolution
Yes, you're right
We headed deeper and deeper
into the jungle
With every step l left
more of my world behind me
But l was determined to find Will
l needed answers
And a shower
There
Welcome to our home!
Lets go!
What you see is only
part of our equipment
Half our men in our army
are simply waiting for our signal
You see those
ospreys over there?
We got them really cheap
from the United States
We found this in the jungle
a couple of nights ago
What about, what about
the driver of this truck?
The driver, he's, he's um
he's medium build, medium size
He's American
He has blue eyes
very blue eyes, he's uh
he's, he's kind of a mess
He's kind of- -
What do you mean
lm a, a mess?
l'm so glad you're alive
Claire
Hi, hi
- l thought l'd lost you guys
- Well not yet anyway
- Did you uh, find him?
- Who?
Will, no, not yet
For Renny
- You light
- Okay
lt's a tradition
to always light a candle
for the dead
That was very sweet of you
Claire
Thank god
Long time no see
With your permission, sir
So you want to see this
other guy too or, or what?
Yes
Are you gonna take me?
Yeah
Yeah, okay
l'll see you guys soon
Fixed everything boss man
Tip- top, boss man
See?
l'll fix that right away
This wasn't your typical
day in the jungle
For a moment
l even forgot
about finding Will
l felt like an explorer
discovering this place
the grace of thousand year old temples
lt was like the coolest
theme park ever
Okay
You stay here
- l'll go get him
- Okay
go kids, go
So?
So...
So the bread
is uh, not too old, huh?
No uh, not the bread
Uh, Will, where is he?
Will, he's uh
he's not here
What do you mean
he's not here?
Well he's here
but he's, he's not here
He's uh, in the jungle
with Rafael
Be back soon
What's- what's soon?
Okay
l go find out
for you now, okay?
No- no- no
Never mind, never mind
lt's okay, it's okay
So uh, what
is this place anyway?
lts called Tauxacapa
He was a great chief
He built this um
how do you...? temple
to worship the sun god
This is the only place
the conquistadors never found
And it is from this place
that we lead our revolution
Almost a quarter
of this country is ours
And its expanding
Thirty thousand
l know, l know
Okay
Hi, oh sorry
Did l wake you?
Next, this piece, watch this
you see?
And the this part, over here
l learned a lot
during the days in the camp
l brushed up on my Spanish
l got used to
real spicy food
And l was taught by
highly trained professionals
Finished
What, what about
these pieces here?
Those?
We don't really need those
l've been looking for you
Your boyfriend is here now
Claire? What...
l mean all of a sudden
l find out that
my boyfriend
is an arms dealer
l know, sweetheart
listen to me
No don't, don't
sweetheart me, no!
- Listen
- l thought that l knew you
You do, you know me
lt's, it's still me, just...
consider it a job change
Claire...
Consider it a fiance change
- lt's not funny
- No, listen to me
- This isn't funny
- lm sorry
l know l should've
told you
- from the beginning, but l...l...
- Yeah
l didnt know what it was
the beginning of l...
- Listen to me l...
- l'm listening
l worked behind a desk at first
And, and then things just got
a little bit more involved
- More...
- l flew to Switzerland
l'm sorry, l'm sorry
l uh...
l, l've never been
to Switzerland
Oh well l know, l know
So, just in case
you, you care um
they do yodel in the streets
and it's freakin gorgeous
l had a Christmas
surprise planned for you
Well, l sure got your
surprise across
lt was supposed to be
a chocolate cake
Not a...
not a punch in the face
Claire l'm so...
l'm sorry
that l lied to you
Agent Gallagher sir, excuse me
- l need the exact coordinates
- Oh, yeah
of the freighter
with the weapons
- Thank you
- No problem
Sir
Without you
the revolution
would not happen
Gracias
Oh and Rafael is making a speech
You shouldn't miss it, Follow me
Rafael! Rafael!
A quarter of this country
is now in rebel territory
And it is expanding
About thirty thousand
square miles of desert
mountains and jungle
l hold a letter in my hand
a document
that will become
part of our history
the history
of the overcoming of tyranny
in El Coronado!
ln this document
the final confirmation
of support
by the government
of the United States of America
Welcome our American friends!
This earth is the land
that belonged to our fathers
and their fathers
before them
This land has been
plundered and raped
by the ones
who took it from us!
Off the Western Coast
a US freighter
with shipment of arms
is waiting for us
Tonight
our helicopters will head out
to pick them up
ln two days
we will regain our freedom
the sun will rise again
over our homeland
ln two days
this land
will be ours again!
All of it!
Viva El Coronado!
Rafael! Rafael!
Viva la revolution!
lt's a tough one, huh?
What?
You now have
three great guys
to choose from
Well
Ah...the ring
Ah so you've already
made your choice
l don't know
Well l mean l guess l, l have
to give him a second chance, right?
l didn't come ten thousand miles
just to punch him in the face
Ten thousand miles, thats a
that's a long way
to come to find your man
Television will start
our revolution
Tomorrow night
a group of ours will have
the national TV station
in San Coronado
in their hands
From there
we will broadcast
a taped speech
which we will record
in here tonight
With the speech
l will mobilize the people
The city has to be boiling
We need chaos, momentum
We fly a massive air raid
on the Presidential Palace at 2300hours
By dawn the city...
No
The country will be ours
l need a volunteer
to deliver the tape
to the television station
l'll do it
No uh...
We'll just...
we'll do it together
A new day has dawned
for El Coronado
The city is in our hands
This is the beginning
of a new era
- Anna
- What?
l will see you in a little while
Okay
There is nobody on the ship!
The whole ship!
We searched every corner!
They betrayed us!
lts a trap!
The american betrayed us!
lt's a trap!
lt's full of explosives!
We lost three helicoptors
No, we lost three men
You have to catch up to them
We shouldnt have
trusted the American
Sancho...leave now
All is not lost yet
Stay inside
l'll handle this
Okay
Fix your door
Hey! Amigo!
That's okay, hombre
Move over
What are you doing?
Your boyfriend is one of em
Soldiers, fire!
fire! fire!
- Fuego!
- No, amigos, no!
Jump!
l hit the ground
Pieces of debris
falling left and right
l didn't know if l was
dead or alive
Thank God Arnet did
He gave me the tape
with Rafaels speech
Take them away!
Watch her Come!
Sit down here!
Viva la revolution
Attencion!
At ease
Pomopoconsita
With your permission
The old temple...
they're hiding
behind the waterfall
Pomopoconsita!
l knew it!
Pomopoconsita
Actually it's right here, sir
Oh that's Pomopoconsita
We are going to crush them
like an eggshell
We are going to
slap their faces...
Mr. President
Don't forget
they, they know about me
They know l spied on them
lm sure they're aware that
l report to you
You mean they know
we're going to attack them?
Correct
They know that we know...
- What!
- Where they are
They know that we know
that they know where we are
So, they know that we know
that they will attack
We have to be
one step ahead of them
We simply have to be
a step ahead
We anticipate their next move
and then we counteract it!
What do they think
we think they think?
What do we think
they think?
What is the opposite of that?
They expect us
to change our plans
They think
that we are going to attack
- But
- But, we dont!
At least it will seem that way
Because we know they know
we think they expect us
to change our plans
We do the opposite
and stick to the plans
We catch them when they are
at their most vulnerable
ln the air!
Let his jets leave the city
We fly our attack
one hour earlier
We attack in two hours!
With your permission!
Uh, President Ramos
l've been meaning to speak
with you about something
Anything, anything
The uh...
CBB reporter has become a...
real threat to you, sir
Maybe you should...
make a statement
Make a statement?
Statement
Oh...a statement
l love you my boy
l know you understand
what l am saying
Do you understand me?
She's a tourist
She doesn't know
anything about this
Just let her go
Just release her, Jesus
What do l...
How much?
What do you have?
What?
What did you say?
What'd you say?
How much money do you want?
What do you want?
Visas?
Do you have any children?
l can get your family out of here
l can get them to
the United States
l, l don't have a family
And l'm gonna stay here
in Coronado
No corruption!
This is a civilized country
you ignorant gringo!
Goddamnit!
You and your girlfriend
will end at the pole
The tape is in Ramo's hands
And so are the Americans
There will be no speech
on television
Rafael, without the tape
we won't have the people
out on the streets
You always said the revolution
can't be won without the people
Yes l have
But forging forward is
the only thing we can do now
lf you have a better idea
please speak
Stay away from window
l heard you were
single again
How did you, how did you
get through to me?
Well it wasn't exactly
a walk in the jungle
Yeah, yeah, yeah, don't worry
we'll lose these guys
Turn right!
Where's Arnet?
- He's at the Presidential Palace
- Okay
l hear he's going to be
shot at daybreak
What?
We have to go get him!
The only thing that's
going to be able to save him
is our revolution
Wait!
- l have it!
- What?
The tape
- The tape?
- Yes!
- Rafaels speech?
- Yes
- l love you!
- lt was Arnet's idea
Lets go to the television station!
- Go!
- Alright!
They are airing the speech
A new day has dawned
for El Coronado
The city is in our hands
This is the beginning
of a new era
l call on the people
of San Coronado
Go out into the streets
We are expelling Ramos
out of his palace
out of our homeland
We shall put an end
to our misery, our poverty
You have to join us
in our revolt
This is a new beginning
Viva Coronado
Viva la tierra
de nuestros padres
Viva la revolucion!
That God damn journalist!
l want him dead!
gangster
parasite
weed, noxious animal, bastard
l could run faster than this
Yeah but you wouldn't
get very far
Rafael! Rafael!
No need to be scared now
We're gonna be
too late for Arnet
too late for ourselves
ls there any other way in?
l'd have to make a way
How? How?
That's how
Execution square's this way
Marktime, march!
Right face!
Here they are!
Hold your fire, cease fire!
Mr President
this way, this way
- lt's Will and the president
- Yeah, l know
- We can't let them get away
- Okay
- Let's split up
You go after the man
that you like
and l go after the man
that l don't like
- Okay?
- Go, no, go
Get ready!
Aim!
Viva la revolucion!
Watch out! To the right!
Jose
Tip- top
Fly the helicopter!
What did l put you
through the school for?
Think we can
make a run for it?
Hello!
Anybody?
Look, l could use a hand here
Hello?
Who is that?
Coronado, viva!
Very entertaining
Happy ending, huh?
But l don't think so
- l don't buy your story
- l thought it was good
lt's not possible
A girl from Beverly Hills saves
a revolution in Central America?
- No
Well gentlemen
l have to go
l think they're
ready out there
lt was really nice
talking to you
Bye guys
Bye
Tip- top boss man
Fixed everything
What were you talking to
those guys about for so long?
They wanted to hear my story
What, your story?
Hah, You're a tourist
l am not a tourist
Oh, you paid for the trip
didn't ya?
Well, that was
out of pure courtesy
Five hundred bucks
- You would've done it for free
- You didn't even bargain
- Girl before was two- fifty
- You were desperate
- She wasn't even cute
- l knew that at the very beginning
Besides, would a tourist
save a reporter's life?
You didn't save my life
- Oh, l didn't?
- No
They just didn't get around
to shooting me in time
Oh, Jose!
Sorry boss
l'll fix that right away