(CHILD SINGING HÄNSCHEN KLEIN)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(HÄNSCHEN KLEIN RESUMES)
(BRASS FANFARE PLAYING)
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(SHELL FIRING)
This is Regimental Headquarters
calling Corporal Steiner.
(SHELLS FIRING)
Can you pick me up, Steiner?
Steiner, can you hear me?
Steiner.
(SHELLS FIRING INTERMITTENTLY)
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
(SHELLING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
(MAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN ON PHONE)
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE IN DISTANCE)
(MIMICS GUNSHOT)
(SOLDIER EXCLAIMING IN RUSSIAN)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
- Good kill!
- KERN: Beautiful.
Look, my new weapon.
Get one for yourself. Some ammunition.
- Give him a hand.
- Of course.
Look at that!
STEINER: Nothing we haven't seen before.
ANSELM: Steiner.
Look what I found running around
in the back. A little Russian fledgling.
Put it down.
(PLAYING HARMONICA)
STEINER: Quickly!
We go.
See if you can get Meyer. Tell him we'll
need transportation from checkpoint seven.
ANSELM: Right, sir.
Bring him with us.
- (ENGINE STRUGGLING)
- Push, push, push, push, push!
Come on, come on! Quickly!
All right, stop.
(STRANSKY URINATING)
This damned country!
Once it was a new adventure,
but I have a feeling that one of these days,
this land will swallow us up.
Captain Stransky, sir.
- Colonel Brandt. You're welcome.
- Thank you, sir.
BRANDT: This is my adjutant, Captain Kiesel.
Captain, how are you?
Thank you for asking, Captain.
I feel terrible. I've got diarrhoea.
How are you?
You should meet your own adjutant.
Lieutenant Triebig.
He's also a new arrival.
Won't you join us in a glass of wine?
STRANSKY: Oh, that's very kind of you, sir.
Take my coat, please.
ORDERLY: Yes, sir.
STRANSKY: Hmm.
(MAN HUMMING)
My respects, Colonel. A 1 937 Mosel
in the southernmost corner of Russia.
Remarkable!
A bottle of Mosel is no more out of place
in this region than we are ourselves.
Your health, gentlemen.
I'm not going to drink to my health.
It's not worth drinking to.
To the end of the war?
Colonel, why does our presence here
strike you as so absurd?
Captain, why did you ask to be
relieved from duty in France?
I want to get the Iron Cross.
We could give you one of mine.
- (LAUGHS) No, no, I'm just joking.
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
Actually it's exactly what my
commanding officer in France asked me.
"I can't stop you, " he said.
"Since I'm convinced that
without you the Eastern Front
"would collapse in a matter of days.
"Go ahead, you heroic horse's ass. "
(LARGE EXPLOSION)
"Heroic horse's ass. " His exact words.
I withdraw my toast to the end of the war.
To heroic horse's asses everywhere.
To the patient foolish.
Colonel, I would like to make something
quite clear to Captain Kiesel.
I volunteered for this campaign because
I feel that men of quality are needed here.
It is time to destroy the myth
of Russian invincibility.
Just how do we do that?
Bolstering morale, punishing those
who are insubordinate and rebellious.
Instilling a new respect for ranking officers.
Low morale goes hand in hand
with defeat after defeat
followed by impending defeat.
Now you are new to our Russian front,
so I don't blame you
for talking like a horse's ass.
(CHUCKLING)
Of course, sir, I'm not familiar
with the Russian front yet,
but I firmly don't believe that the ideals
of the German soldier even...
The German soldier no longer has any ideals.
He's not fighting for the culture of the West,
not for one form of government that he wants,
and not for the stinking party.
He's fighting for his life. God bless him.
Well, sir, I am a soldier, and as a soldier,
I feel it is my duty to subordinate
my own ideas to the principles of my country,
right or wrong.
Colonel Brandt, Lieutenant Meyer, sir.
Ah. (CLEARS THROAT)
- Yes?
- Steiner's on his way back.
- What sort of shape are they in?
- The usual!
BRANDT: Very well, I see.
I want a briefing as soon as they're rested.
- Yes, sir.
- And, Meyer, Captain Stransky is here.
See that he is informed of our situation.
Yes, sir.
(SHELL WHISTLING)
(SHELL EXPLODING)
(SIGHS)
- Steiner's back.
- Of course.
Who's Steiner?
To you, in some ways, he could be a problem.
But he's a first-rate soldier.
So, we look the other way.
Anything to add to that, Kiesel?
Steiner is a myth.
But men like him are our last hope.
And in that sense,
he's truly a very dangerous man.
Well, I will see.
Colonel, with your permission.
Well, what do you think of our new captain?
I feel he thinks he is on
some kind of special mission,
that is, to achieve spiritual domination
of his battalion,
thereby symbolising the purity
of the great German Wehrmacht itself.
(MEN SCREAMING)
Even when going down in defeat.
(SCREAMING)
If they're the last of us, Stransky and Steiner,
then God help us.
SOLDIER: Medic!
Medic! Medic!
Captain Stransky,
welcome to the second platoon.
- Lieutenant.
- Meyer, Captain.
I am to show you to your quarters,
brief you on our current situation.
(EXPLODING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
- Where's my bunker?
- Down there, in front of the factory, sir.
- The second platoon is guarding your post.
- Where are they?
They're just returning
from reconnaissance, sir.
STRANSKY: Who's in charge of it?
MEYER: Corporal Steiner, sir.
Oh.
What is so special
about this Corporal Steiner?
MEYER: Early in the Novorossiysk attack,
Corporal Steiner saved Colonel Brandt's life.
- Ah!
- And mine, too.
STRANSKY: Interesting.
Corporal Steiner!
I'm Captain Stransky.
I'm your new commander here.
Yes, sir.
Who's this?
STEINER: Corporal Schnurrbart, sir.
And the other one?
That is a Russian prisoner, sir.
You know as well as I do that there are orders
that no Russian prisoners are to be taken.
Get rid of him.
How, sir?
Well, shoot him!
You shoot him, sir.
I will. On the spot.
And then I'll deal with you.
No need. I'll see that it's taken care of, sir.
I want to see you in my bunker. One hour.
With your full report.
- Clear?
- Of course, sir.
(SHELL EXPLODING)
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING)
(STEINER GROANS)
- You already drank both the vodka.
- I'm using it for the cooking.
(SHELL EXPLODES)
(SIGHS)
Oh, shit.
- Corporal Steiner?
- I'm Lily Marlene.
Come here, son.
Steiner!
I want to show you
what our new army looks like.
- What's your name, son?
- Private Dietz, sir.
They're sending us babies now.
Hello, child.
Private Dietz.
How long have you been soldiering?
Six weeks, sir. I volunteered, sir.
Don't volunteer for anything around here.
Just keep your eye on Krüger here,
and myself.
Do exactly as we say or you'll be wearing
boots up your ass for a long time.
- Clear?
- Yes, sir!
- And don't call me sir.
- Excuse me.
Go with this foul-smelling one over here.
Put him in Schiller's bunk.
Kern, see if you can find a jacket or a blanket,
something for the boy.
Get Schiller's jacket.
He must have something over there.
Yes, sir! Oh, excuse me.
STRANSKY: Stand at ease.
Thank you, sir.
(CHATTER ON RADIO)
- My report.
- Thank you.
I regret the incident this afternoon, Corporal.
But orders are orders.
We have enough trouble with the feeding
of our own troops without taking prisoners.
Anyway, it's very bad for security.
I've read your preliminary report,
and it gives me great pleasure
to inform you that
Colonel Brandt and I have
agreed to recommend you
for promotion to Senior Sergeant,
effective at once.
Your promotion doesn't seem to have
made much of an impression.
No, it doesn't.
All right.
I've read your report. Anything to add to this?
Russians, sir. We should be
hearing from them very soon, sir.
- An offensive?
- Yes, I should think so, sir.
- Starting when?
- Soon.
- What about your platoon?
- Two killed, one missing.
Two killed, how?
Bullets. Mortar fire. Artillery.
Heavy salvos. Bad luck.
Terminal syphilis. The usual things, Captain.
The missing man,
did you look for him, Steiner?
- No, sir.
- Why not?
I felt that it would be irresponsible of me
to risk the safety of the entire platoon
for the sake of one man.
You felt what?
A non-commissioned officer does not permit
a missing man in such a case, in any case!
I'll try to do better next time, sir.
- I'd like to have that in writing.
- If you wish.
You know, Corporal... Sergeant,
I have a feeling you somewhat
overestimate your importance.
At the moment,
I am free of any such illusions, sir.
Well, may I suggest to you that you do not
underestimate your present company.
Everything you are and may become
is dependent upon this present company.
No, I will not forget that, sir.
But I may add that a man is generally
what he feels himself to be.
Of course.
You're dismissed.
I shall be back soon, sir.
Is that a salute?
Yes, sir.
- Triebig.
- Yes, sir.
MEYER: You must be careful, Steiner.
He's taken a strong dislike to you.
STEINER: I'll survive.
MEYER: You're not dealing with
just another Nazi Party type.
This one is pure Prussian
military aristocracy and rich.
Hey, why are you bringing in the apples?
To eat, you overgrown idiot.
You know the ruling classes?
Come now, Lieutenant,
what's left for them to rule?
Don't be naive.
Stransky will survive this war
one way or another.
And he'll still have his land, his wealth,
and his status.
But he'll be very dangerous in defeat.
Be careful with him.
He doesn't live in the same world we live in.
Ah, no, he's living in my world now.
Yeah, sure.
- Lieutenant?
- Yeah?
Please, would you come inside for a minute?
There's something I'd like to show you.
KRÜGER: Kern, don't just
stand there drinking, help us!
(ALL SINGING IN GERMAN)
(MEN CHUCKLING)
Thank you. I didn't realise that you knew.
Oh, you forget we are
a reconnaissance platoon.
Happy birthday, Lieutenant Meyer.
- Yes!
- ALL: Happy birthday!
Explain everything to the Captain's orderly,
so he doesn't make any mistakes, will you?
And take care of your uniform.
He's rather strict about it.
Russian vodka, German wine, chickens.
Oh, Maag, I don't know
how we have stayed alive so long!
He's the best scavenger
in the entire regiment.
- Cheers to all of you.
- ALL: Cheers!
Here's to the last Russian bullet.
ALL: Yeah!
Here's to survival.
Yeah, yeah.
ALL: Yeah, yeah!
Here's to your wife, girlfriend, women!
ALL: Yeah! Women!
ANSELM: Here's to the women
of the Folies-Bergère.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
To the girls of the Reeperbahn!
ALL: Ooh-la-la!
(MEN LAUGHING)
STRANSKY: Gently, gently.
ANSELM: Here's to Dietz's virginity.
(MEN LAUGHING)
MAAG: Play your cards right
and we'll introduce you to Triebig.
All you have to do is just bend over.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Here comes the cake.
MEYER: Oh, cake!
Captain Stransky should see this.
- Captain who?
- Here's to the cake.
ALL: Cake! Here's to the cake!
Stop it! Stop it!
What are we doing here?
What do you think we are doing here?
Playing birthday games?
Right in the middle of all that shit!
- Come on...
- You shut up when I'm talking!
If you want a party, okay, drink.
Get drunk. Okay?
- KRÜGER: Take it easy.
- There's a bullet for you, too.
- For all of you arseholes!
- Come on!
You, arsehole. You don't touch me.
You stink like a shithole.
(BOTH SHOUTING)
Come on.
Let's not spoil everything.
This is Lieutenant Meyer's birthday.
Happy birthday, Lieutenant.
Have a good party.
MAN 1 : I'll have some more vodka.
MAN 2: Here, fill it up.
MAN 3: Yeah, here's some
vodka for everybody.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
All right, now.
Lieutenant Meyer is to have a meeting
with our illustrious new commandant,
Captain Stransky,
whom you'll all meet shortly.
This is not a funeral, gentlemen.
This is a birthday party.
Now let's drink.
We'll have a song, what the hell.
(ALL SINGING IN GERMAN)
Thank you, sir.
Where were you stationed
before you joined the battalion?
In the South of France. Biarritz.
(CHUCKLES) I know it well. Sit down.
Sit down. Tell me about it.
It's such a beautiful country.
And being transferred
must have come hard, hmm?
I applied for it as you did, sir.
As I did?
That's interesting.
And your orderly?
- TRIEBIG: We served together.
- In the South of France! (CHUCKLES)
Ah, those French girls!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(LAUGHS) Those French girls, Triebig!
I did not have much time
to think about those French girls.
Really? And you, Keppler?
Did you enjoy the French girls?
On occasion.
(SINGING SUR LE PONT D'AVIGNON)
Let me ask you a question, Triebig.
Do you like soldiering?
Certainly, I like it, sir.
But it's strange at times.
It is indeed a very different world.
A world of danger, and a world of men.
A world without women, hmm, Keppler?
(CHUCKLES)
- Yes.
- A world without women.
Thank you.
It's an old theory of mine.
Men can get along without women easily,
easily, I tell you.
A man's true destiny
is not just breeding children,
all this childbirth, and chocolate,
but to be free, to rule and to fight.
In other words, to lead a man's existence,
women are no more than a nuisance.
Sometimes... Sometimes necessary.
I'm a soldier, sir.
If I have to, I can do without women.
Really?
And you, Keppler?
Can you do without women?
I do as I am ordered, sir.
(LAUGHS) I like that! I like that answer.
"I do as I am ordered. " I like that.
What is your first name?
Josef.
Josef, Josef.
If it will help you,
I'll put your thoughts into the right words.
You prefer the society of men
to that of women at any and all situations.
Right?
I don't understand, Captain.
Come on, Triebig.
You don't have to put up a front with me.
With me of all people.
What I said was right, wasn't it?
You prefer the society of men
to that of women.
Come on, we're all soldiers.
There's no harm in it.
Say yes, for heaven's sake, man, say yes!
Possibly.
You said yes.
You said yes!
He said yes, didn't he, Keppler? He said yes!
You said yes. Didn't he, Keppler?
He said yes, didn't he, Keppler?
- Yes.
- Louder!
Didn't he, Keppler? Louder! Say yes, loud!
Yes!
- Louder!
- Yes!
I can assure you of this,
if you get caught, you'll be hanged slowly,
both of you.
Together.
Now get out of here.
ANSELM: Ammunition supply's running low.
Sector three needs more nine millimetre.
(SHELL EXPLODING)
Steiner's platoon all secure.
Perimeter taking light mortar shelling.
Section Z47, no casualties.
By the way, we didn't get the mail.
That's a big one... Thank you.
Oh, I see.
- Ah! (LAUGHING)
- Take your hands off my lice.
(FARTING)
- Merde!
- MAN 1 : Oh, not again!
MAN 2: Belch before farting, that's the rule.
(SHELL EXPLODING)
Sector seven, no activity.
(FARTING)
(SNIFFS)
Get him outside.
Kern, get yourself outside. Come on, quick.
No, no, no, the Russians
might think it's mustard gas.
The Geneva Convention
forbids the use of mustard gas.
(MEN LAUGHING)
KRÜGER: God damn it, Kern!
What type of exhaust pipe do you have
and when was it broken?
I'm well-organised and without problems.
STEINER: Are you equally guilty?
Krüger, is that your natural smell?
(MEN CHUCKLE)
Listen, idiots,
I stay dirty for a reason.
If you'd been in the field for
as long as I have been, you'd know why.
Explain.
I learned after Stalingrad.
Natural body oils combined with dirt
can keep you waterproof.
Waterproof?
Sure.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
How goes it?
Quiet.
Too quiet.
SCHNURRBART: Yes.
They'll wait till first light.
Rolf, what are we doing here?
We are spreading the German culture
throughout a desperate world.
Didn't someone say that war
is the highest expression in life
for the truly cultured people?
Yes, a foolish wise man named
Friedrich von Bernhardi.
- Right!
- Yeah!
- And Von Clausewitz said...
- Von Clausewitz?
Ah, Von Clausewitz said,
"War is a continuation of state policy. "
"By other means!"
Yes, by other means.
Do you ever think about your children, Rolf?
- Always.
- Where are they?
I don't know.
Take off one uniform,
there's always another one underneath.
Go!
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
It's all an accident.
An accident of hands.
Mine, others.
All without mind.
One extreme to another,
and neither works.
Nor will ever!
Here we stand in the middle,
in no-man's land, you and l.
Go home.
Go home!
Steiner!
(EXCLAIMS)
(GUNS FIRING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
- Yes, sir?
- Is it a probe, Stransky?
A probe, sir? It's an avalanche!
No, sir! It's an attacking force!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Sir, counter-fire is needed at once.
Otherwise, we'll be destroyed.
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
We're overrun! Move out!
I need help!
Be calm, Stransky. You are not alone.
What do you mean I'm not alone, sir?
I am alone! I am alone!
(ALL YELLING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
Steiner is gone, Triebig is gone,
I don't know where Lieutenant Meyer is.
I don't know! Is he dead?
- BRANDT: Then go to your second platoon...
- Is he dead?
... salient sector and find them!
And stand by and prepare the counterattack
as quickly as possible.
Yes, sir! I will be counterattacking, sir!
Stay in your positions!
Hello? I will be counterattacking.
MEYER: Get some more ammunition!
- Where's my weapon?
- On the wall, sir.
Get that ammunition!
(MEN SCREAMING)
Keep down, you fool!
You, get over there!
Get back to your post!
- Get that phone fixed.
- Yes, sir.
STEINER: Get back there, damn you!
MEYER: Keep your positions!
Everybody, keep firing!
Fall out, men! Fall out!
STRANSKY: I need air cover!
MAN: Fire!
MEYER: We're winning. We're winning!
(MEN SCREAMING)
Where's my air cover? Where are my tanks?
(SCREAMING)
Shit!
- (TELEPHONE RINGING)
- The phone is ringing! Where's the phone?
(YELLING)
(MEN GRUNTING)
MAN: Fire!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
- Captain Stransky.
- Where's your counterattack?
We are attacking! We are defending!
We're counterattacking!
I'm wounded, sir. But I continue.
I know my duty, sir. Don't worry.
But I need ammunition!
MAN: Lieutenant Meyer!
Hollerbach! We must cover Steiner!
Look at me.
Follow the light with your eyes.
Very good.
That's it. Now look at me again.
Sergeant!
All right.
Did you sleep well?
Reasonably.
Smell?
(SNIFFS)
Nothing.
Any sense of taste?
lmproving.
Quite usual in concussion.
You've been like this for a week.
They should return soon.
Your records indicate multiple wounds
over the last few years.
Any residual effects?
Headaches.
Blurred vision.
I can't urinate out of my left ear any longer,
but otherwise I feel rather well.
The doctors recommend that you stay with us
for another three weeks
until they've completed your tests.
Then they recommend home leave.
Home.
(LIVELY INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC BECOMES DISTANT)
(MAN'S LAUGHTER ECHOING)
Schnurrbart? Schnurrbart?
MAN: Attention! General Von Hessel!
(ALL SINGING IN GERMAN)
Hello, soldier? How are you?
Tell me, how do you feel?
This man has severe concussion, sir.
He's been highly decorated.
I want 65% of these men
returned to active duty in three days.
Ah, food!
VON HESSEL: Delicious!
MAN: Take the pig, the meat and the wine
into the private dining room.
Come! Eat! Eat, eat, everybody! Everybody!
Vegetables are good for you.
They're with the compliments
of the High Command.
(SOLDIERS SINGING DISTANTLY)
(SINGING ECHOING CHAOTICALLY)
(ECHOING GUNFIRE)
(DISTANT CHANTING)
(MAN DELIVERING SPEECH)
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC RESUMES)
STEINER: Everybody looks
like someone else around here.
Did I have a bad spell?
Yeah, you were very violent.
Violent?
Violence should stop. It must stop.
You say the violence must stop?
(CHUCKLES)
(SHOUTING)
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
(VIOLIN PLAYING WALTZ MUSIC)
Oh, no, I'm on duty.
- Have a drink.
- No, I couldn't.
They'll throw me out.
Do you dance?
(CHUCKLING)
Hold my bottle. I'll hold your waist.
And we dance.
Listen, this is ridiculous.
It's nice.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Schnurrbart!
Rolf?
What the hell are you doing here? Lost?
No such luck, Rolf.
I got it in the leg same time
you got it in the head.
Schnurrbart!
My vacation's over.
It's back to the bad side
of old mother Russia.
They took us all from our hospital.
It looks like we're picking up
some of your boys as well.
You want to come along
or are you doing all right?
Attention, men! Prepare to leave.
Corporal! Hold this truck.
What the hell are you talking about?
That's an order, God damn it!
- Rolf?
- What?
- What is it?
What's the matter?
I'm going back.
I thought you were going back home.
I have no home.
My home.
Our home.
Do you love the war so much?
Is that...
Is that what's wrong with you, Steiner?
Or are you afraid of what
you will be without it?
Long live Germany.
I said to hold it, right?
Steiner, I didn't mean it. You're crazy!
Schnurrbart.
Rolf!
Son of a bitch!
- Schnurrbart!
- Hello, Kern!
- Hello, Hartwig.
- Hello, Sergeant.
- Hartwig!
- Schnurrbart, how are you?
Caught with your
pants down again, huh?
(SIGHING)
STEINER: Anselm.
Welcome back, Sergeant.
- Hollerbach!
- Rolf, hello.
DIETZ: Good to have you back, Schnurrbart.
Krüger!
You're back too soon.
I don't want to talk to you.
Leave me alone.
Get your ass out of there, you old pirate.
(LAUGHS)
I missed you. I missed you! Yeah.
My, my, my! What is this?
ANSELM: That's Zoll.
HOLLERBACH: That's a Party member Zoll.
KERN: With compliments of Captain Stransky.
S. S. Special Action Squad.
STEINER: You still a Party member,
Hollerbach?
Well, Rolf, I'd dance with the party
if I could find one.
(LAUGHS)
Hey, silence. The Party's convinced
we are winning the war.
Yeah, sure, we're winning the war.
(MEN LAUGHING)
I hope you've memorised our serial numbers,
our mothers' maiden names correctly.
I wouldn't want the Gestapo to come and
arrest the wrong man, woman or child.
I don't care what you believe,
or what you've done.
Your duty is to us, the platoon and me.
Fulfil those responsibilities or you will have
a bayonet up your ass.
- Clear?
- Yes, sir.
KRÜGER: I am playing nursemaid
to the third squad, any volunteers?
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
- Not me.
- SOLDIER 1 : No chance.
SOLDIER 2: Go alone this time.
SOLDIER 3: Enjoy yourself.
KRÜGER: Thanks a lot.
What have we here, a hawk and a hare, eh?
I'll take you.
Come on, have a drink.
- That's your bottle.
- Cheers, Rolf.
Ah, give me that thing. Come on.
Gentlemen.
SOLDIER 4: Cheers.
TRIEBIG: Some papers
for you to sign, Captain.
- STRANSKY: I'll sign them later.
- (RAT SQUEALING)
Stop that! Be careful with my J. J.
Yes, sir.
Have her treated correctly.
- Sergeant Steiner reporting as ordered, sir.
- Come in.
Thank you. That will be all, gentlemen.
- Welcome back, Sergeant Steiner.
- Thank you, sir.
Please sit down. Make yourself comfortable.
(FAINT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ON RADIO)
Well, now that you're back,
and I'm glad you're back.
I think we should make a fresh start together.
But the main point is
the regiment feels or believes
that I deserve the Iron Cross now.
And they've asked me to produce
two witnesses to the fact
that I led the counterattack and threw
the Russians out of their positions.
I have named Lieutenant Triebig and you.
Especially you.
Lieutenant Triebig
has already submitted his signature.
Am I to believe this is a private conversation?
That would occur to you, wouldn't it?
All right, have some wine, a '36 Mosel.
I'll have some.
Thank you, Sergeant.
But still remember that in civilian
as well as in military life
the distinction is made between people.
Is that what you meant when you said,
"All you are and may become
"is dependent upon this present company?"
Well, the difference
is a matter of ethical
and intellectual superiority which is caused,
whether you like it or not,
by blood and by class difference.
If I remember correctly Kant was
the son of a saddle maker
and Schubert's father
was a poor schoolmaster.
Perhaps talent, sensitivity and character
are no longer privileges
of the so-called upper class.
But Kant and Schubert were exceptions.
We're talking about general concepts,
- not individuals.
- But I am one and so are you.
Didn't your führersay that
all class distinctions were to be abolished?
I'm an officer of the Wehrmacht.
I've never been a Party member.
I'm a Prussian aristocrat
and I don't want to be put
into the same category!
So we agree for once.
Good.
But he is still our führer.
Unfortunately.
Oh...
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
That is a different question, Sergeant.
That's not up to us to judge.
Why do you want it so badly?
It's just a piece of worthless metal.
Look!
It's not worthless to me.
Why is it so important to you?
Tell me, Captain, why?
Sergeant, if I go back
without the Iron Cross
I couldn't face my family.
(BOMB EXPLODING)
Personally, sir, I don't feel
you deserve the Iron Cross.
Incoming!
Where are you going?
I'm going to point 1 24.
Corporal Krüger's over there.
Are you crazy?
No one could survive this kind of assault.
Get out of my way, God damn it.
I'm going after him.
Steiner!
You get me some stretcher-bearers, damn it.
Steiner! Steiner!
(SCREAMING)
The others?
Dead, all dead.
Oh, God. Listen to me.
We are going to leave now.
Will you get up and follow me out of here?
All right?
Three hours.
Three hours I've been here by myself.
(EXHALES)
I don't ever want to be alone again.
You won't, you won't.
(BOMB EXPLODES)
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Come on.
Why the hell wasn't I told
of Steiner's return to the battalion?
My apologies for that, sir.
There were more important things to do.
I want him here at once.
... about a predicament of which I am sure
you don't need to be reminded.
- Clear, Stransky?
- Quite clear, sir.
Now we shall see.
I don't like the tone of his voice.
I'm fed up with the whole situation.
Well, it doesn't matter any more.
I know from reliable sources
that headquarters
have already written off
the Kuban bridgehead.
And soon the whole Crimea
will be a cul-de-sac.
Report to Brandt.
If you have the choice, Triebig,
between Biarritz and Siberia,
what would you choose?
- Steiner.
- Colonel.
Sit down please, Steiner.
How was hospital?
Oh, interesting.
I recommend it.
Did Captain Stransky lead the counterattack
the day Lieutenant Meyer was killed?
Lieutenant Meyer led the attack.
Captain Stransky was nowhere in sight.
You're sure of that.
I saw Lieutenant Meyer die.
(BOMB EXPLODING)
Fetch Triebig.
Stay, I want you to listen.
Sir?
You signed your Captain's report.
Were you present when Captain Stransky
led the counterattack?
I accompanied Captain Stransky to the field
and saw him calling several men around him.
Then he sent me back to the command post.
Then how do you know that Captain Stransky
led the counterattack?
You've signed a statement
to that effect, Triebig.
I wasn't there. I learned of it from
wounded men who were returning.
Can you give me the name of
one of these wounded men?
They were not staff men, just company men.
I knew them only by sight.
Besides, the smoke, the battle.
We had been under fire, sir.
I want you to know, Triebig,
that I have had your statement checked.
Captain Kiesel will inform you
of the results of our investigation.
Our investigation so far has disclosed
that the men in the second company who
took part in the action declared unanimously
that the action was led by Lieutenant Meyer.
None of them saw Captain Stransky
or Lieutenant Triebig.
To my mind there is nothing
more contemptible
than stealing the laurels which
properly belong to a man
who was killed in action.
If Sergeant Steiner stands
by his last testimony,
I should be compelled to
institute disciplinary proceedings
against the Captain and you.
Yes, sir.
Do you stand by your statement
that Captain Stransky
was not with the company?
(BOMB EXPLODING)
(EXHALES)
Would it be possible for me to give
my answer in three or four days, sir?
Did you see Stransky or not?
(EXHALES)
You may go, Triebig.
You're no longer needed.
What in God's name has got into you?
This is your chance!
You are the only person
that stands between Stransky
and his Iron Cross.
And you could be called as
a primary witness against him
in a court of honour.
My differences with Captain Stransky
are a personal matter.
BRANDT: Now listen to me.
You know that I've always shown
a great deal of understanding for you,
but I'm becoming tired of
battling with your superiors.
I never ask you to.
Didn't ask me to!
You never asked me to?
Are you out of your mind?
Steiner, why are you so ungrateful?
What do I have to be grateful for, Captain?
Your tolerance?
Do you think that just because
you and Colonel Brandt
are more enlightened than most officers
that I hate you any less?
I hate all officers,
all the Stranskys, all the Triebigs,
all the Iron Cross scavengers
in the whole German army.
Have you any idea what you're saying?
Do you know how much I hate this uniform
and everything it stands for?
God!
Get out.
Please, just get out.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
ORDERLY: Regimental headquarters.
Division headquarters, sir.
General Von Kellinshofe.
Colonel Brandt.
Yes, General.
Yes, sir. I didn't know it was as bad as that.
I am very sorry to hear it.
Well?
We're pulling back
to the bridgehead at Kuban.
No rear guard. Not even Steiner's platoon.
We're not retreating. We're running.
(BOMB EXPLODING)
Captain Stransky. Yes, Captain Kiesel.
I was just about to leave.
Don't leave just yet. Now listen to me.
Regiment feels that it is unwise
and also suicidal
to leave behind any rear guard
platoons including Steiner's.
I want them to join the
evacuation immediately.
You understand that?
Yes, Captain.
Triebig?
All real guard platoons
to join the evacuation immediately.
Shall I notify Steiner's platoon?
Yes.
Give me Steiner.
Calling Regiment.
Regimental headquarters. Come in, please!
Regimental headquarters! Come in, please!
B Company, can you hear me?
Anybody come in, please!
Tanks!
ANSELM: Captain Stransky,
can you hear me?
Krüger!
All the lines are out.
STEINER: Better get 'em out!
Down the tunnel!
Out!
Go into the factory.
Get everything?
Fire!
- (SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
- (MACHINE GUN FIRE)
Zoll, grab some mines. Bring them up. Quick!
STEINER: On the tracks, Zoll.
Put them on the tracks.
(ENGINE STRUGGLING)
Hurry! Move!
STEINER: Heads down.
Into the factory. Over to the factory!
Move, damn it!
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Maag, they're coming in from both sides.
Kern, up above!
Krüger, get up on the gangwalk! Hurry.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Quick! Down the tunnel!
Anselm! The grenade! Come here!
Throw it!
Shit! Jesus Christ!
Steiner, let's go!
STEINER: It's clear.
Dietz. Cover for us.
SOLDIER: Hurry! Move!
- Captain Pucher reporting, sir.
- Ah, yes, Captain.
You have your orders?
PUCHER: And a letter for you
to be delivered personally.
Thank you.
You can guess what this is, can't you?
- A transfer.
- Exactly.
Our Stransky is to report
to Paris within a week.
Captain Pucher,
my orderly will see to your billeting.
But don't unpack everything.
We might be going away.
Captain.
(EXHALES) Stransky.
Without Steiner to contradict him,
he'll get his Iron Cross
and strut all around Paris.
The arrogant, unbloodied bastard.
Stransky in Paris and Steiner...
God knows where he'll be.
It seems there's...
What, 22, 23 kilometres between...
... here and Anapa.
Marshland. Wilderness.
It's the same trap behind the Russian lines.
Again shit, again shit, again shit...
Here take your gun.
We'll try the road.
(RUSSIAN SOLDIERS SINGING)
(STAMMERING) Hey, we'll never
get over this road.
Shh!
What's your hurry, kid?
We'll get out of this mess
in time for the next one.
Steiner! Steiner, it's clear now.
(WHISPERING) Let's go. Move it, move it!
Anselm, move your ass!
BRANDT: The cattle cars
or whatever they're sending
are due to arrive at 1 200 hours,
provided, of course, that the Russian sappers
have not blown up the track.
- Any questions?
- No, sir.
Dismissed.
Carry on probing and aggressive actions
all along the front.
(DOOR SLAMS)
They're not listening.
You, too.
I beg your pardon?
(SIGHS)
BRANDT: Who needs a railroad track?
When we break out of here, we'll push on
with a blitzkrieg through Stalingrad
and up to the outskirts of Moscow.
What will we do when we lose the war?
Prepare for the next one.
Do you think he'll get through?
Steiner?
I don't see how he can.
Anselm, go bring Zoll in.
- What is it?
- Bridge.
Just bring what you need to kill with.
- It's a game.
- A game?
It's a kid's game.
It's bad luck to step on sunlight.
I thought perhaps if I miss the beams
we would all come through this all right.
Come on.
(SOLDIERS CONVERSING IN RUSSIAN)
(GRUNTS)
(WOMEN CONVERSING IN RUSSIAN)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(CRYING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(HENS CLUCKING)
DIETZ: Come on, come on.
Over there, get in the corner.
Jesus Christ!
Get these weapons out of here!
Krüger, upstairs! Schnurrbart, perimeter.
Check the other buildings.
Come here. Get in that corner.
Get in that room.
Come on, pretty rabbit.
(LAUGHS) Don't hide from me.
STEINER: Check the radio,
and get that body out of here.
Anselm.
- Stay there!
- SOLDIER: Get your hands off.
STEINER: Anselm, stop it, damn it!
- (LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
- (WOMAN PROTESTING)
- Anselm! Anselm!
- Leave me, Steiner.
Wait. Stop it!
Stop your fucking silly game!
This isn't a brothel!
This is a war!
Rolf, look what I found. (LAUGHS)
STEINER: I said get that body out of here.
SCHNURRBART: Everything clear out here.
What is this?
It shows their basic positions
in front of Anapa.
- (CHUCKLES)
- STEINER: Good.
Means we're halfway home.
Thank the ladies
and tell them to take their clothes off.
And what shall we do with the bodies?
Who's gonna keep them warm?
- Tell them we want their tunics and trousers.
- We are going to die anyway.
- Do it! Do it!
- We are going to die anyway. Let me...
Let me keep one.
(KRÜGER INSTRUCTING WOMEN IN RUSSIAN)
(WOMEN GASP)
(KRÜGER CONTINUES IN RUSSIAN)
(WHISPERING IN RUSSIAN)
Major.
Major!
She's dead.
- Dietz, Zoll, watch them.
- Yeah.
The rest of you, put these uniforms on.
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
Come on, get over there with the rest of them.
Pick up your weapons.
Up, up, out!
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
Get that uniform and take it inside.
(CONVERSING IN RUSSIAN)
Oh, shit.
(GERMAN SOLDIERS CONVERSING OUTSIDE)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Ah, go over there.
- (GRUNTS IN PAIN)
- Come on, pick it up.
- (LAUGHS)
- You want to play? All right.
That's a nice little girl.
That's it.
Come on. (LAUGHING)
I'll give you something to play with.
- I'm gonna be busy for a while.
- (CHUCKLES)
- (GRUNTS)
- Come on.
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
How would you like it, huh?
That's nice.
Ah.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(BOTH SOBBING SOFTLY)
(MOANING)
DIETZ: Steiner!
Oh, Dietz.
Jesus Christ.
Dietz.
Oh, God. God.
Don't...
... hurt the girl.
(MOANS)
ANSELM: Do you believe in God, Sergeant?
I believe God is a sadist
but probably doesn't even know it.
(SCREAMING)
Zoll!
(ZOLL CRYING OUT)
Stupid man!
Steiner! God!
Take the women outside. With me.
Come on. Go!
Move out! Come on!
All of you get inside. Inside!
(CRYING) Steiner!
(ZOLL SCREAMS)
Now we're even.
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
(WOMEN GRUNTING)
(ZOLL CRYING)
BRANDT: And there's one other thing
you could do for me.
There's a man here
that I would like to get out quickly.
I spoke to you about him before.
If there is a chance that he could leave
with your headquarter staff,
I will be most grateful. Thank you, sir.
KIESEL: They're rolling up both flanks.
It's chaos.
That need no longer concern you.
(SHELLS EXPLODING)
You're to report at once
to General Headquarters.
You're being evacuated.
I can't leave the Command, sir.
While I'm still in a condition to issue orders,
those orders will be obeyed.
I'm prepared to disobey that order, sir.
You've been around Steiner too long.
Come, listen to me for a moment.
For many of us Germans,
the exterminator is long overdue.
But I have decided that you are worth saving.
(SOLDIER SCREAMS)
But I'm part of all this.
There are better people than me.
Most of them are being killed out there.
There's nothing wrong with you
except that you smoke too much.
You're a brave man.
Braver than you think you are.
One of these days there will be
a need for brave civilians.
Had you thought of that?
In the new Germany,
if such a thing is allowed to exist,
there will be a need
for builders, for thinkers...
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
- BRANDT: For poets.
- (SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
I begin to see now what your job is to be.
I will make this my final order to you.
You will search out
and contact all of these, um...
... better people, you call them?
And together you'll take on the responsibility
that goes with survival.
Now you must leave.
Please leave.
Braun, take Captain Kiesel to the railhead!
Go.
KRÜGER: Steiner, how do we get
through the Russian trenches?
It's only a matter of time.
They'll be building them
for a thousand years.
- If not here, somewhere else.
- (LAUGHS) Not Germany.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS) Germany.
Do you think they'll ever forgive us
for what we've done?
Or forget us?
We'll make it. We will make it with your help.
To tell you the truth I'm...
I'm beginning to enjoy it.
Well, you want, uh...
to be sitting in some mud hole some place,
waiting for the top of your head
to be blown off?
At least here we're free.
(BLOWS INTO HARMONICA)
MAAG: Steiner.
Steiner?
(MAAG PLAYING HARMONICA)
(ALL SINGING
IM FELDQUARTIER AUF HARTEM STEIN)
STEINER: Sing it!
(ALL CONTINUE SINGING)
(SOLDIERS CONVERSING IN RUSSIAN)
Go! Go!
(SHELLS WHISTLING)
(SHELLS EXPLODING)
Here, Sergeant. Here's your weapon.
SCHNURRBART: Then all we have to do
is hope our own artillery doesn't get us.
KRÜGER: Or the landmines.
(LAUGHS)
Two hundred metres to go.
Anselm.
- Yes?
- Try to raise somebody on that radio.
Tell them we're coming in at dawn.
We need a password. What's, uh...
What's the password? Uh...
Reconnaissance Patrol
with several Russian prisoners
and no shooting.
Password, Krüger, God damn it!
"Demarcation. "
Why not? "Demarcation. "
"Demarcation. " Sign it Steiner.
Captain, special password "Demarcation. "
Signed Steiner.
Coming in with prisoners.
Looks like a trap.
My thoughts exactly, sir.
He may have been captured.
- Wolf.
- Sir?
Did you recognise the voice?
No, sir, it was in code.
Good code, "Demarcation. "
Triebig...
If in the dark,
you saw half a dozen men,
some in Russian uniforms,
advancing on you.
Could anyone blame you if you opened fire?
No.
Will you check the situation for me
and, uh, take care of it?
You do like Biarritz, don't you?
You do like the South of France, don't you?
(SHELLS FIRING)
Come on.
(SOLDIER SCREAMS)
KERN: Oh, shit!
- STEINER: Kern.
- Yeah.
You and I will carry the weapons.
The rest of you make sure your hands
are clearly placed behind your heads.
SCHNURRBART: I'll go first, Sergeant.
No, Goddamit, Schnurrbart.
There might be some asshole
who didn't know what the message is.
SCHNURRBART: No, I go.
Rolf!
SCHNURRBART: You've been responsible
for all of us.
This time I'm responsible for you.
(LAUGHS) Take us in.
Sir, look here.
Welcome, Sergeant Steiner.
My passage home.
KERN: Steiner!
Demarcation! Steiner!
SCHNURRBART: Steiner, we're coming out!
STEINER: Demarcation!
SCHNURRBART: Demarcation!
Steiner's coming in!
STEINER: Demarcation!
(SHELL EXPLODING)
SCHNURRBART: Demarcation!
STEINER: Barrage!
Russians right in front.
STEINER: Schnurrbart, move out!
Stand by to fire.
STEINER: Go, go!
Fire!
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
Demarcation!
SOLDIER: It's Steiner!
It's a trap. Fire!
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
No!
God damn it!
(SCREAMING)
Sir, they look like prisoners.
Steiner!
(SCREAMING)
There are German soldiers with them.
- Stop it!
The fucking idiots.
(KERN SCREAMING IN PAIN)
We're German soldiers...
Fire!
KRÜGER: Stop it!
Stop it!
No!
- Keep firing!
- Stop, God damn it!
(KERN CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Fire!
Oh, my God!
It's Steiner!
You, stop!
Go get my men, go!
SOLDIER: Stop it!
STEINER: Stretcher-bearers.
KRÜGER: Bloody Nazi swine!
Swine!
TRIEBIG: It's all Stransky's orders!
I had no part in it.
We're sorry.
He's dead.
I had no part in it!
I'm Private Dietz, sir.
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(KRÜGER STABBING TRIEBIG)
(SHELLS EXPLODING)
You're on your own.
If I don't find you,
join up with another outfit, another platoon.
A deserter. I don't care.
It doesn't matter any more.
Where are you going?
To pay my debts.
You are our platoon leader!
This thing isn't over yet.
You're the new platoon leader.
And Anselm is your platoon.
That should make you happy, you old pirate.
Steiner! Steiner!
Steiner!
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
Yes, Colonel Brandt?
Situation is worsening here. You're needed.
If my orders are here...
And they are here, sir,
then my replacement is already
with the Company.
You may leave, Stransky.
Your Triebig is dead.
It didn't work, Captain.
I live.
You are dead.
Lieutenant Triebig has not been
under my command for several hours.
- He has been transferred.
- You aristocratic...
... pile of Prussian pig shit!
Leaving without your Iron Cross, Captain?
Just a matter of time.
Where's the rest of your platoon?
I said, "Where's the rest of your platoon, "
Sergeant Steiner!
You are...
Captain Stransky.
You are the rest of my platoon.
- Know how to use it?
- Yes, of course.
Fine, I accept.
I'll show you how a Prussian officer can fight.
And I'll show you
where the Iron Crosses grow.
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
Now!
SOLDIER: Hey, get out! Get out of the way!
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Stop there!
Advance with me.
(CHILDREN SINGING HÄNSCHEN KLEIN)
Get up.
Stransky, God damn it! Get off your ass!
I have to reload.
How do I reload, Sergeant Steiner?
(LAUGHING)
(STEINER CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(LAUGHTER RESUMES)
(CHILD SINGING HÄNSCHEN KLEIN)