Open the gates,
and we'll let you keep
your life and your freedom !
Who are you?
The masters of the world !
You will be, if we perish !
THE DACIANS
I got him !
- No, I got him !
- Well, whose arrow is this?
Yours. He's around here.
He can't have gone f ar.
Uncle Luper calls us.
We'd better go back.
You'd rather go back, than see
that I'm the one who got the deer.
Come on !
He's so sad !
His eyes are full of tears.
You were right.
It's your arrow.
Your aim is pretty good.
Have you forgotten I'm the one
who taught you how to aim?
Where have you been ?
I should break your bones !
You're making me roam
the mountains !
Shut up ! No...
Guess what news I bring you !
- What is it?
- Take a guess !
- The youth contest?
- Right. Next week in Argidava.
Come on, leave it here
and follow me ! Decebal waits for us.
- You'll catch me !
- Who's reaching him first?
- So, you're here !
- Your horse was better.
That's what you say.
I'm a better rider.
Aren't you going to help me ?
Will you go and fetch
some spring water?
Will you?
You should know that a warrior
doesn't do any woman's choir.
Well, you warrior !
- You'll go get some water ! Right?
- No !
Tell me, who's going to bring water?
Who's the one ?
You're hurting me !
You'll be sorry.
I had a surprise in store for you.
You're just saying so.
Meda !
- Meda ! Is he mine ?
- Yes, he's yours !
- Can I take it?
- Yes !
Come on !
Fuscus, will you show these ninnies
how to throw a spear?
It's the Rhine legions.
I bet ten jars of Falern wine
that his spear will thrust the eye
of the target !
Do you trust me?
I gave you your first lesson.
Prove that you deserve my trust !
You're on time, as always.
Tell me, how is it that our beloved
emperor Domitian
didn't come with you?
I'd have thought him much more eager
to take the credit for our victory
and acquire the title
of "Dacicus".
- He'll be here in four days.
- Four days, you say...
Yes, he's right behind me.
The imperial house moves slower
than the horsemen.
He has a lot of slaves,
both men and women.
And what women they are,
dear Fuscus !
He took everyone with him:
sorcerers, cooks...
He even took some historians with
him, artists from Asia Minor
and many accountants
to count the Dacian treasury.
To have his back watched,
the emperor took with him
the Fifth ltalica Legion.
He'd better stayed in Rome,
for the sake of all of us.
For our sake and for his.
Let's take advantage of these four
days ! You, more than anyone else.
- Why is it so ?
- Come !
Father !
It's been so long since I've seen
you ! You're strong like a bear now !
Forgive me ! I'm happy to see you.
I missed you and your advice.
You did well by yourself.
Atius, you can be proud of your son.
He's covered himself in glory
on all battle fields.
Glory and dust, also... Allow me to
wipe the traces of this long journey.
- You have my bath at your disposal.
- I'll hurry.
Atius... Domitian will be here
in four days.
How many soldiers
did he keep with him?
The Fifth ltalica. They were
under my command in Syria.
Their actual leader is a good
soldier, but he likes wine and money.
He shall have both.
It seems, though, that it will be
toughest to convince Severus.
I'm the one who taught him
to stay away from the plots
that eat away at the empire.
I foresee that,
during our first battle,
a terrible misfortune will happen
to our "divine" Domitian.
- There mustn't be any first battle.
- Atius, you know you can trust me.
Why don't you want
war against Dacia ?
Ever since we met, when you were
a poor officer with no master,
and up to this day, when you became
f amous and rich,
I've been the one
who put the questions.
All right. Forgive me !
We'll do it your way.
It is the right way, Fuscus.
It's always been like this.
My decisions were always
the best.
There's our hero !
My supper will be poorer
than Domitian's,
but I invite to join me
with all my heart.
To victory against the Dacians !
So...
You're indulging yourselves
in disgusting orgies...
You thought I was a tired old sag,
that I needed four days
to get here.
Why aren't you on the other side
of the river, brave Fuscus?
Look ! There's Atius, the heart
and nerve of the Roman Senate !
What are you doing here ?
You have news, haven't you?
Bad news, of course.
What else ?
I'm listening and prepared
to hear anything.
Funny ! Why is it that the Marcomanni
rebelled just now?
Maybe because
of the Dacians' gold.
You're either crazy, or traitors.
You want me to give up this war
and go back to Rome
without paying my legions?
No. You will cross the Danubius
at once !
I'd like to give the Senate
Fuscus' opinion, as well.
I'm a soldier and I obey Rome's law
and the decisions of the Senate.
I tell you that I would need another
five legions to defeat the Dacians.
Fuscus, you told me in Rome
that a single legion would crush
the barbarians
Not even the last of my soldiers
would say such a thing.
You've been plotting against me.
You'd like to see me back to Rome,
defeated by the Dacians and with
all legions unpaid and dissatisfied.
What do you have to say,
Severus?
I'm for going to war.
Let's not forget that Julius Caesar
said the clash with the Dacians
would be more difficult
than the one with the Gauls.
Now I want to meditate more
about Caesar's end, than his words.
Domitian, let's be frank !
You're interested more in Decebal's
gold, than in a battlefield victory.
I always said that rich people
are also the most intelligent.
Don't you think that several
messengers led by a shrewd man
would get from Decebal what you
want so badly, but without a war?
Who might this man be?
When I came from Asia Minor,
ten years ago,
I had some fruitful negotiations
with Duras, the former Dacian king.
All right. You go, then ! But take
one of my personal guards with you.
Meanwhile, you build the bridge !
You'll plea a better argument
in front of the barbarians,
if our twelve legions will be
on the left shore of the Danubius.
I'll be merciful with the barbarians.
After all, I don't like wars.
I might be a poet,
had I not in mind Nero's fate.
It was a short reunion.
Allow me to come with you
on the other shore !
I wanted to ask you
the same thing.
I've been waiting for this moment
for so many years !
I waited for it and feared it.
I'd like to understand you.
There are so many things
we don't understand, my son !
We're like a shell wanting to gather
the immensity and howl of the sea.
Sometimes, life makes us hide
before our most beloved.
Son, do you trust me ?
You know too well that you matter
the most to me, of all things.
I'd like to stay with you
for a few more moments.
Yes, f ather. I'll announce the guard
that must come with you.
Search everywhere !
Domitian, let me be the one
who starts the battle !
The Senate and the Roman people
lost our very best man.
I'm in pain.
I'll send the urn with his ashes
in Rome,
the city he loved and served
like no other.
And those barbarians will know
Rome's wrath !
Only five of you are left
in the great contest.
Fight bravely !
May the best win !
- There are only three left !
- Now you can see my teaching skills.
But, to be honest,
I'd have been better !
See ?
Decebal, the Romans are crossing
the Donaris.
I've killed their first nobleman
who trod on our land.
He was the only Roman
who shouldn't have died.
I thought that... it was a good
thing.
Cotizo !
Don't win this contest !
- You're crazy.
- I'm not.
There's going to be a war, Cotizo.
Please, don't win the contest !
- Do you hear me ?
- All right.
Promise me !
I promise... I'll win the contest.
Decebal !
Our best warrior won the contest.
It's your son !
No !
We'll wait for them here
and we'll crush them like ants.
What does this mean ?
You want that l, Luper, run from
the Roman's faces like a woman?
There are twelve legions,
that is 72 354 men.
They are led by general Fuscus.
- How do you know that?
- Zoltes told me.
From now on until we die
or beat them,
I'm the one who gives
the orders !
The children, women and old people
will go in the mountains.
You'll keep the Romans here
until midnight.
Don't you dare die like a hero,
or I'll break your bones !
Father, you didn't teach us to flee.
Why aren't we f acing the Romans?
We must avoid this war,
Cotizo.
Forgive me,
but you talk like Meda.
If I were you, I wouldn't turn
my back on the Romans.
My son, is it that you and the
others don't trust me anymore ?
I didn't want to say this. Everybody
loves you and will follow you.
I'm proud to be your son.
Go !
Take Meda and help the other
people ! I'll reach you later.
It looks deserted.
Yes... It's for the first time
they greet us with flowers.
They're withdrawing their troops.
We put them on the run.
No, young man.
The charge is ahead. Look !
Faster ! Come on !
We must survive until midnight !
Do you hear me ?
We must ! Hurry up !
We will take the fortress !
Cavalry... Charge !
Fuscus !
Your bravery on the battlefield
commends you.
Your f ather, the illustrious Atius,
will be avenged.
What a stench !
And now, Fuscus, the prisoners...
Marcus !
What is this?
You have only one prisoner?
You fought well.
Speak, and you'll know
Rome's generosity !
Where is Decebal ?
Had I also a weapon,
you wouldn't be so brave.
I can see you didn't wash
your f ace.
Do you want a weapon ?
Take it !
Quite shiny...
And tasteless.
Are all these necessary,
for a bunch of barbarians
who are giving themselves in ?
Domitian, this is Burebista's throne,
one of Caesar's mightiest opponents.
If you receive them here,
they will be impressed.
Let's impress them then, Fuscus !
Let the barbarians in !
Which one of you is Decebal ?
Decebal is the great king
of the free Dacians.
We are bearing his message
to the Roman emperor Domitian.
Are you that one ?
I'm listening.
A mouse... A frog...
A bird... A quiver of spears...
A plough knife...
Your message pleased me.
I'm for peace.
My conditions will be sent to Decebal
by my messenger.
Give these messengers
a tour of our camp !
They should see most of it !
Describe their awe and astonishment,
at the sight of my wisdom !
Fuscus, do you know
what all these mean ?
It's a common habit
with the barbarians.
They are hiding their pride
through silly fables.
The mouse is the land,
the frog, the waters.
The bird is the sky and its freedom.
The spears are their weapons
and the plough knife
is the plenty of the land.
Rest assured that Decebal
submits to you !
Write it down !
My dear Fuscus, you have once again
astonished me with your wit.
You can do as you please
with these animals.
I'll keep the cages
as a memory of your insight.
Severus will deliver our answer.
Hail, Decebal !
Welcome, general Severus !
What is the message
of your master?
Domitian, emperor of Rome,
has willingly deciphered your
message and here's his answer.
He accepts your surrender.
He'll come to Sarmizegetusa
and will crown you himself
as king of Dacia and subject
of undefeated Rome.
The Senate will nominate you,
Decebal, for your merits,
a friend of the Roman people.
This is all.
General Severus, according
to our ancestors' custom,
you are our guests.
Drink the wine of this earth,
where Dionysus was born !
Tomorrow we'll talk
about masters and slaves,
for tomorrow we'll know each other
better.
It's your turn, Roman boy.
I want to ask you something,
Decebal.
Wherever my f ate and my gods
lead me,
I try to understand the life
of those we fight against.
Tell me, why do the Dacians laugh
before dying?
You're bragging that you saw
Dacians die, you Roman !
Meda, pour a cup of wine
for our guest !
Forgive me, father.
I'm not any Roman's slave.
This Roman is my guest.
Pour him some wine, Meda !
Come on, warrior,
take some raspberies !
Forgive me if I insist, Decebal,
but this is very important for me.
Why do the Dacians laugh
before dying?
Zalmoxis gave us several lives,
Severus.
How could we leave this life
and live another,
where other secrets of the skies
and earth are to be revealed to us?
Crying and moaning? Or laughing,
so that Zalmoxis may see our joy?
But how do the Romans die,
general Severus?
We'll see them soon.
Forgive my children, general !
They are like young wolves.
They must bite,
to have their teeth grown.
Where do you have
this medallion ?
My father gave it to me.
Atius was the only Roman
whose death I did not want.
There are many things
we don't understand, Severus.
We are like a shell which wants
to gather the great howl of the sea
and its secrets.
I would very much like
to understand this, Decebal.
Come with me, and you will.
We have plenty of gold,
Severus.
Maybe gold and wealth
are our curse.
They spark the hatred or the
excessive love of foreigners.
Some of them are strong.
They haven't been defeated.
I know that.
I always hosted them as friends,
and never as masters.
This is the law of this land
and of every man.
If we who live today are to die,
the law will stay the same.
Here lie the ashes of those
who fought for us,
so that we may never feel
the harsh rule of other strangers.
Here lie kings, priests,
clan leaders...
Oroles, Burebista...
Deceneus, Scorilo...
And this urn was supposed to shelter
the ashes of great Zoltes,
whom you knew under the name
of Atius, your f ather.
He went to Rome 40 years ago
and took the name of a Roman
patrician who lived in Moesia.
Each year, I would send him
a vessel full of gold.
Rome opened its gates to him.
Gold is a wonderful key.
Atius told me every plot
weaved in Rome.
Now I see why he didn't want
to fight against you.
His death, the earth in his fist...
Why didn't he ever talked to me
about this?
He taught you to be a fine warrior
in the world's greatest army,
so that you may serve your people
one day.
You were much too young
for him to unveil his secret.
Today is too late.
What do you want from me
now?
What have you stirred
in the heart of Zoltes' son?
Even the tamed wolf returns to the
woods when his kind calls him.
Was my call strong enough ?
Now you're as lonely as I am,
in the belly of the earth,
waiting for Zalmoxis' signs.
Will you be able to defeat them?
They lost battles, but they were
never defeated.
They're stubborn, strong,
numerous and greedy.
Then, let's give them the gold
they are asking for.
Never !
I kept my soul in darkness
and solitude.
It judges the world by other measures
than those of ordinary people.
Sometimes, it's harder for us
to subdue our pride
than to win a battle.
Think, Decebal ! Wouldn't it be
better for you to subdue your pride ?
Great priest,
if people on this earth of ours
learn that they can live like slaves,
then, we are defeated forever.
But if we fight so bravely that,
several centuries later,
those who want to surrender
will be ashamed,
it means we won the battle
and we'll stay here,
no matter how many storms
we wil f ace.
Decebal...
If you decide to go to war, you must
send a messenger to Zalmoxis.
You know our ancient law.
The messenger will be...
I know.