DEATH OF A SHADOW
Colombier Street
Jan Ternauw
I'm sorry.
July 6th, 1983, Colombier Street
Beaten to death
by Boran Kassovic.
Nathan Rijckx
November 10th, 1917, Parc de l'Abbaye
Shot dead by
Franz Baumer & Joachim Dünker
Mr. Rijckx?
Did you bring me Jan Ternauw?
Excellent, Mr. Rijckx!
The work of a beginner,
this Kassovic.
However, a strong composition,
concrete.
An excellent combination
of fear and suffering,
of passion and form.
So energetic!
I'll be very sorry to see you
leave my service, Mr. Rijckx.
- But,... you could also stay.
- No.
Why so attached to life,
Mr. Rijckx?
So little happiness,
so much pain...
I could... show you
the true beauty of death.
Two more, Mr. Rijckx.
Two more...
Accident
Explosion
Exhaustion
Murder
Old age
Thomas Belcourt, November 30th, 1918
Parc de l'Abbaye - Old age
Parc de l'Abbaye...
Thomas Belcourt
Sarah Winters
Sarah...
Sarah?
Daniel Hainaut
Daniel?
Death by old age?
Don't you know that these shadows
are almost never interesting.
It's a worthless composition.
I know that not all deaths
are masterpieces, but nevertheless...
I hope that your final project
will be more interesting.
The spontaneous aesthetics
of an accident, for example...
For example...
A train, a plane or a car...
An explosion...
Or a drowning...
We haven't had a drowning
in a long time.
Or a murder.
Murder is always expressive.
There we have it,... murder.
Murder
Daniel Hainaut, March 7th, 2015
Rue de la Brabande
Stabbed to death
by Erik De Rooch
Daniel Hainaut, November 3rd, 1940
Buchenwald
Gassed by Erik Mengel
Murder
Daniel Hainaut, September 1st, 1917,
Fort van Chartreuse, Shot dead by...
Adolf Weber
Daniel Hainaut
I'll see you soon, Sarah.
Attention!
Line up!
Load!
Aim!
Fire!
My offer still stands,
Mr. Rijckx.
You can stay.
No.
You have lived 10,000 days.
You have given me 10,000 lives.
Your death is erased.
Mr. Rijckx...
The door to life will remain open
for exactly 1 hour.
You can go wherever
and whenever you want.
Choose wisely... because,
when the time has passed,
this door will be
closed to you forever.
I knew you'd come back.
No one wanted to believe me,
but I knew it.
Daniel?
- Sarah!
- Daniel?
My apologies, sir.
Ms. Winters is a bit confused.
Her Daniel... She was never able
to accept the awful truth.
And now, she thinks that
every soldier in uniform...
But dead soldiers do not return.
Right?
One life for another,
Mr. Rijckx.
When a shadow disappears,
another one has to stay.
The choice is yours.
She is waiting...
Nathan Rijckx, September 1st, 1917
Fort van Chartreuse, Shot dead by...
Sarah?
Daniel?
Sarah Winters, May 20th, 1997
Rue des Tournelles - Old age
Nathan Rijckx, September 1st, 1917
Fort van Chartreuse
Shot dead by Sebastian Koch, Adolf Weber,
Albert von Schlieffen, Hans Cluck & Herman Becker
>>> RED SKY FILMES <<<
http://www.redskyfilmes.blogspot.com