Subtitle Translated by Arif chandio
19.4.1943 / 688 Jews deported from Berlin  to Auschwitz .
LAST TRAIN
- Well?
- About sedmiset ...
Minister Gobbels and Minister Speer wants to give
Fuhrer our unique gift.
Berlin is almost cleaned of Jews!
Almost 70,000 Jews who have stayed there have been exported from Berlin.
It is the latter, who are still here.
Few of them  eventually disappear!
- Let's start today!
- The sooner, the better!
Mom,
Move Come on, you know what to do!
Jakob Noschik?
Open, Gestapo!
At last!
You have five minutes to pack up !
Come on, outside. Everything will be fine!
Faster. Put your shoes!
How it could happen, Henry?
- Henry Neumann?
- Yes.
Do not be afraidl. We'll take you there
to safety, where Mom and Dad will  work
to help the country in difficult times of war.
Why Mom and Dad can not work and stay here in Berlin?
Because where you go is much
safer, my little.
There will be lot of bombs.
going to fall upon berlin
Gestapo! Open!
- Luckily, I found it.
- A joke?
Yes! Even my smoking. You never know when it will come in handy.
Just never know!
- That you certainly will not be needed.
- I know a million of such jokes.
Please give me a topic now,
and I immediately tell you a joke
"I hear the sirens screaming, every body is running to
cover, except one man who ...
Who is seeking something in the house. His wife shouts
"Hurry up, what are you still looking?
"My prosthetics course," he is responsible.
"Give me a break from protézama!" screaming woman
"Do you think that they bombard at our house?"
Get going! already! you Lose your time!
No, it is a wall of hard board! All of these apartments
They have the same size. But the rooms are smaller.
This wall is fake!
I am a doctor! Obstetrician! Thousands of German
Children came to me , Thousands!of them
Mom? Can't you tell them that you don't want to go?
- Unfortunately, not now.
You're a lucky! You are carrying
your little sister with you.
.
Are you alone?
My father, Dr. Friedl.
Neumann.
What's his name?
Aaron.
Are you sure you are inside? Middle. I bet!
I knew it.
Bastard!
Come on, leave it!
You will no longer need to wear fur
- Please, take the fur,and let us go.
- Even though we are not married!
Can I get more of them, gems and other precious things
just let us go!
- You want to insult me, Jew?
- Well, well!
Please at least let her go! I beg you!
she does not deserve to die!
Bloody Jewish pig!
you Enrich yorself at the expense of German citizens, eh?
That's not true ,he is a good man!
Saint. Jewish saint!
All the wealth is left by my parents!
- How were your clients are, the Holy Jew?
Germans! Christians, Jews, I do not distinguish.
Be patient. On the train We give? No food and drink on the train.
No food no water! They sending us on vacation?
Do you know, where we are going?.
No, I do not know until we get there,
Jacob ... is already well ...
I performed in so many places, I counted them.
Over 350!
from small villages to large city theater!
Kings, queens, princess -...almost everyone laughed by this  Jew
Jacob Noschikovi.
Excluding to the fascists!
- Jakob, stop!
People in this world who does not
have a sense of humor.
Please wait. We give? No food and water on the train.
Henry Neumann?
- Yes?
- Albert Rosen. Mrs. Neumannova.
Could you kindly give me a time to speak a bit.
I was on the boxing match,
when you knocked Mr.Lehmann.
How many years have been passed? Ten?
- It seems it was in another life.
I got the axe and saw  in my trunk .
I just want to know who I can count on
I'm with you.
Do you gentlemen are brothers?
Yes.
Dory, Manny Gerber.
Can I ask you something?
Go ... Everything will be fine.
- Gabrielle Hellmann.
- Hello, Ruth Silbermannov?.
- Jakob Noschik.
- Good morning.
Please step away! Please step away from the track!
Attention! Away!
Do not drink, because our Fuhrer does not drink?
Once my mother knows that I drank
she gets angry.
But your mother is not going with you on this trip?
How many are there?
There are about
Now it's your problem.
Trains travel several days, what is the problem?
It's a big responsibility.
By this your transportation,
Capital Empire will soon be cleansed from Jews.
You can count on me.
This will be my gift
to our Führer's birthday tomorrow.
- Heil Hitler.
Please quietly get into the wagon.
We all get water and food there.
I do not understand, Mom.
all coaches looks like for animals!
Is war, Nino.
It will be all good, just hold on to me tightly.
Why do these gentlemen holding weapon?
In order to protect us.
- These are the coaches for the animals?
- No!
Freeze, Jewish pig!
Let me stop them!
Let me go! Do not force me!
I know where this train is going,
don't believe them ,they are not taking us to work?
it our last journey
Leo!
- Please consider the children. they are getting afraid.
- "i'm saying its our last journey ..."
Come ...
"it will lead us to blue sky ..."
Is she? ! The
wife of our carpenter!
"Because the desired hour is already near.
Dress up!
Stop! Back!
Faster!
we will soon be free people in our green land, where  palm
trees grow,the white snowbe fall our Jerusalem .
its all Come from our misfortune, and pain
Sara, no, Sarah ...
Let me go! I want to be with my wife!
Take your suitcase, Nino.
Gabriello ...
These two tried to escape!
shoot Both of them .
don't waste bullets let them rot in to train.
As you wish.
- Nino?
- Dad
Dad!
Gotcha I got you! Fear not We will not leave you.
Here! This is water for us all!
And it should be toilet for a hundred people!
its insult,insult
Erika!
Dr. Friedli! This is his daughter!
please  me see her,
she is Fainted Release her, please!
Hallo! Mrs. slytem you hear me,
We need a doctor!
Doctor!
Aaron? Where is Aaron?
Calm down, it is here, everything will be all right.
Dad, there must be water after all.
They said after that it will be no water.
Yes, they said.
There is a bucket of water in front of us for all.
Henry, we need to organize,
otherwise we'll kill each other.
Look, I am so sorry
that happened to your son
Why did not you take leave for few days?
- I tried it
but apparently
they found no other fireman.
I lost three sons in the war and did not get even
one fucking day off!
And one and two, and three, and four ...
Mom, it seemed to me
I'm the best dancer in the world!
You will,
I swear.
- You swear?
- I swear.
Put the legs aside need to pass! I need to pass!
Henry!
- Yes?
- I need some water.
Me too!
Wait a moment! Please ..We will have to keep a record
on Paper and register those who got the water, and who is not.
A bucket of water stand next to you,
that does not entitle you to take when you want
I will no take more.
I am sixty years, and my husband
seventy and has severe diabetes.
Each of us needs water!
we will find a way to regulate it
Yes! Sure, right after your wife
gets the first drink!
Please! I want to say something
I know some of you to carry water
and a meal. ...., I think that those who have something
Should not use a common water until
consume their own supplies.
What are we talking about ? Water is not
much enough by tomorrow morning!
One bucket for all!
So I'll wait until the afternoon.
Then everyone will be able to drink.
And what about your wife?
She is Breast feeding! If she got no milk
the child could die.
Or anyone has any objection to the two mothers
who get little more water?
Or is there perhaps some other woman can breast feed,
instead of my wife Erika?
Thank you.
The wood is hard as steel, will never move.
Should We try those iron bars.
And then what?
We find the boy, who will stretch out of the window ...
Sticks his fingers into the gaps to keep.
Opens the door from outside and then we can jump!
Take care of her, I find the boy.
Of course the train must go slowly
otherwise it will be too dangerous.
come to me.
What Nina What's happening? Hungry?
We have some food, but we still
wait a bit longer ...
- I'm hungry.
- Just?
- she needs to eat ...
- Later ...
Oh, angelica.
We have her clean clothes. You take it?
Nothing happens baby,don't worry.
It's hot, as in Ethiopia, .
Or it has something to do with my age?
Once  its hot, later cold.
I am glad only that I've lost the sense of smell.
If you get water, we die.
Why do you tell a joke?
- I agree.
- And who know? I say "No". Go away, please!
I have with me several gold coins. When we get out
we can make a good use of them.
Do not stop me from it!
I warn you if  you come close to us,
I will kill you! Understand?!
I am from the Bar Mitzvah. I had a man!
Stop it! Approaching the station!
Bullshit!
On the other track coming passenger train
from Berlin! Beware!
Please! We need more water! Water, please!
We need water!
- Exceptionally well, congratulations!
- Shut up! His youngest died!
- My condolences.
I also lost a son in the first weeks of the war.
Water!
Go ... did not really need a water.
Move on
Water, water! Please give us some water!
do'nt stop
keep yeiling, we need water
Anyone else want some water?
Now they don't need water any more any longer.
Albert! Can not just lie her there!
We'll put her in corner
let me do .
Look this a Jew Sold it to me
for the crumbs of bread.
Saddle up! Ahead! We gotta go!
Come to America! You hear? You have to go to America!
- They have a lot of pianists, they do not need me!
- imigrate to America, right?
- And what will you do without a pianist, my dear?
- I must die of hunger. So?
With your taste?
Our relationship is over!
Leave now , i never want to see you.
I divorce  you! Simply you divorce me.
Stop, Jacob You already know,
that i will never leave you.
A Pianist....Look at these hands.
- Do you play?
- A little ...
What's happening? Why it stops?
What do we do when very afraid?
The first sentence of the prayer Shema Israel. This helps!
Well ... Shema Israel, Adonai Elheinu, Adonai
Echad ... Baruch ...............
I'm sorry, this a military transport. we preferred
occupie all the tracks!
How long this will  take?
Hours, days, God knows. trains Pass
in both directions. In any case, we must wait.
Shit, shit!
Mr. Perles we think about your
suggestion.
We all think that escape is not the best idea.
What do you think, where are they taking us,
is it Auschwitz?
It is not certain. but its sured,
that if we get caught, then all of us will be shot.
- In any case, try it.
- We should vote.
No vote! No discussion.
Once the opportunity arises, we must escape.
Henry, boy, maybe you're right.
Would you like To throw their
children from a moving train?
While at the end of our destination there will be an
expensive hot meal and a roof over  head are waiting for us.
.
As the train starts,
we'll get to work.
It is about MY son!
Sooner or later, when it stop again,
do we need water and food.
It can not be so difficult
we give small sign to him when we see soldier
Silence! not a single word
shut your mouth.
they will kill him
kill him
while passing If something happens to my child,
God will Take care of him.
They think I am feeding prohibited animals.
We will die of heat.
- I was completely dries.
- We have to get away.
not giving us no food or drink.
They do not care even if we gonna die!
But, they need us! You said
we're going to work!
They're so stupid to
keep us here to let us Die.
May God hear our words. If still exists.
And what will happen to those who can not work?
God ... God ... Where are you?
Stop!
Please think about your child, You must stop
Maybe we're lucky,
hope should not dies untill last.
You have to believe that we
will be all be happy, again
Look at him ,he is smiling.
This is a princess. And waiting for your prince,
it comes to awaken with a kiss. Here, look.
What's happening?
- Ukrainian SS!
- What is it?
Real devils! We can only pray,
that they will not here In connection with us
It was quite dusty. Disaster!
- Please enter, please. It's a jeweler, like any other.
- Thank you ...
- Mr. Silberman is such an honor, an honor?
- today is the 18th  birthday of my daughter Ruth.
Congratulations! I do not know that you have a beautiful daughter.
I told you this often ,
but you  did not listened.
What would you like to see miss?
See this chain,which will
always bring you happiness.
We stay some time here .
Headquarters gave us a nice order.
"Give a little water to the Jews."
Let's Ukrainians take care of this
Lets see how lucky they are!
Go!
Water! Water! They carry water!
For us?
They bring us water!
Careful! We must protect the water!carefull
don't pour,beware don't pour
Please! Please, we need more water! Please!
Henry, no!
Henry, no! Stop! Stop hell, stop!
Henry!
- It must never happen!
- No more ...
Just look ...
- Hangman
- Builds the gallows.
Well, what do you smell?
- Vanilla?
- Yes.
- Lemon and vanilla?
Gallows? Really?
Do not you think the worst
They have lot to do before hang us.
My beloved optimist!
- What's going on Mom? Whats all that happening?
- Nothing! Nothing, my child, nothing special ...
Whats that rich smell,a New perfume?
- From a secret admirer.
- Just do not say anything about it.
I would have to kill him.
Please ...
Thank you.
try a little sleep
- Papa, when we go?
- For a moment, quiet. A moment.
I'll give you whatever you ask, if you get back
even pull the ball from the well.
She said the beautiful girl.
"Let me eat with you at the table," said Frog.
"Let me sleep in bed with you.
the ... Princess ... told the frog
if you recovered the ball well .
Get going!
Frog princess said ...
- Gallows is not for us!
they will not Hang us! not Us !
Their time has arrived a little
before us.
Silence!
What's going on? Are you crazy?
Move!
What are you doing? Immediately come down!
Immediately!
What will they do to us and our kids?
Good question.
Everyone in the train! Departure!
You want to stay? Get in!
Let's go!
I can not stand any more.
Go faster, cursed train. Go!
Still going east.
Also we have some such.
Little Ruth.
And now what are you thinking?
When this is over we'll get married.
Do thiink we will succed?, Albert!
- Easy, no!
- Let go!
Let me go!
I do not want here to die like a dog!
Easy
I need a coat ...
I want to try.
- You know what to do?
- Yes.
Easy ...
Easy.
Easy!
Mom! Mom! What's happening?
What he did, it was my son!
You killed my son! don't blame on me!
He's not dead!
My son is dead!
Mommy, Mommy, wake up!
Wake up, wake up. Mrs. Perlesov?.
We have to try again.
The boy is failed.
- Someone else has to die?
- No one else want to do.its madness
Mother, please.
I will do it!
I might go. Well you know!
Ruth, I have only you!
Pick me.
Please, God ...
I've never prayed so much.
- We must wait until the train slows down a bit!
I will not wait! Jump out now!
Just that she endangered her life!
- For others, train goes too fast!
- No! No!
Good luck!
Now they will kill us all!
For all the idiots we will die!
Excellent!
Congratulations!
We must some how  have to set the rods..
give me your hairpin!
- And something with edge
I have a knife in the trunk.
I'm so scared!
Try to sleep now.
Think of something nice. Also I will think of something nice.
When David was still in your belly?
You remember when we were lying
on the bed under those soft blankets .
What are you doing?
You feel his kicking.
Out! Get out now!
Hurry up! Set in a row!
Immediately surrender all knives and other tools.
If we found any tools not surrendered
will be immediately shot.
Jews out!
You were about to escape
once? to shorten the trip?
No tools, Lieutenant!
Very interesting.
Can anyone tell me how to open the door?
Probably not well closed.
We slept, I know nothing, sir Say ...
We all slept!
What is your name, dear girl?
Nina Neumannova.
Are you also asleept, Nino Neumannov??
- Yes, please sir.
I do not believe you.
Doesn't your parents taught you not lie?
Small little girls who lie,
can happen bad things to them
Even such a beloved little girl like you.
And her parents can become too terrible things.
No?
Yes, please sir?
I'm sure you like your mother.
Well let me ask again.
Did you see the tools, you know whom it belongs.
Tell the truth and I'll bring
hot breakfast for you and your family.
I was asleep, was asleep.
Thank you sir,
You have very good manners.
I guess you're right, perhaps it's our fault.
Stupid lack of attention! But you can believe me.
This will no longer have to repeat.
Schmidt!
Close the
double door and tie with wire.
Jews! pig
Thanked me, I would shoot you first,
and then your daughter.
put them into train!
Please! can we finally get something to eat?
You do not leave us here to die.
No!
Still anyone hungry?
Get in train!
All Aboard! Hurry!
No! Let me! Oh, God! Samuel ...
You can not go now! What i'm gonna do without you?
Leave him, get in!- No! i want to stay
with him! What i gonna do without him!
Departure!
I've never met such a brave little girl
like you.
Henry? What do we do?
Through the floor. At the rear, axles
It will take at least a day, not longer.
Every hour counts!
- Yes.
Is he so hungry.
Here is something written.
- Dad
- Your dad is not now, baby.
"The Dream, so terrible, it was no longer my people.
disappeared, no longer exist
To fulfill the dream''.
What do you play?
Sleeping Beauty Waltz . Close your eyes ...
Look, we're going back to Berlin!
Albert! You see anything?
Yes! Go to another window!
It should have some water? Or bread?
Water, please!
Let no one not near the train!
Come.
Supply are well!
Please guard these people! This is my train!
Your train? My God, please
Look at these poor people they are starving!
- I give them water ...
- Come on!
- Are you crazy?
Surely you must at these poor people
to prove your manhood? At the front you failed?, huh?
That these are the people? Fuhrer finally get rid of the plague!
- Calm down!
- Stop!
Are you crazy? He wants to shoot at German
Lieutenant?
- I have wanted to do the same thing!
- I'll put you before a military tribunal?
Yes, but when the war ended,
you will be hang on the gallows.
And they call a German officer? Traitor
Coward Deserter!
At least I'm not such a hero like you, asshole!
Departure!
Go on, give them everything you have!
- Come on!we can not move
-. soldiers standing infront
What? Fuck it, immediately go!
At least two to three hundred meters!
Please, bread! I have a candy for kids!
- Not all at once, otherwise you will be sick!
- Thank you!
Spread out, let everyone gets a piece!
More, we need more bread!
Jed!
Come to Mama.
Take it ...
We go to mamma, come on ...
My big boy!
Where do you go?
They said Hitler had a nightmare.one wzard
that looks into the crystal ball and says:
"Oh, "Dear leader, I see that you will die on the great
Jewish? holiday,
Adolf barked."What?"
"My leader, no matter which day you die.
It will be a great Jewish?holiday.
We should do something for jews.
no need to sympathize
I can not help them,
we Better concentrate to our work.
you're getting sensitive
I packed them because I thought that when David grows up,
he will be happy when he show you.
These people are not
lead us to a new home.. Right?
wil There be a new school.
But I want to go to school and dance!
I want to become a dancer!
Do not fear, Nino! you will must Become a dancer!
Sure! I swear!
- Really?
- Upon my soul!
Tell me a story about
the first time you met to papa?
Ask papa, he can tell you much better story.
Come on, Nino.
So ...
It was the wedding of my cousin Herschel.
Since you're such a shy, Henry?
Just look at her!
Lea Hertzbergov? ...
Her father has a big business of import and export.
It is said that the girl receive?
a huge gift of dowry.
- You're drunk.
- she knows about you.
I know it from your aunt Rosalie.
you are always been a very gossipy
Coward
- My name is Henry.
- I know!
If i do not get anything to drink,i will die
Avram, what's going on?
What's wrong with you?
- Doctor Friedlichu!
- He needs help!
Dad! Doctor, faster! My dad!
Dad, what's wrong with you?
Take these coins ,Avram, what's going on?
Take care of them...
- Avram? Please help him!
- Mom, what happened to him?
- Avram, wake up!
- Mr Perles ...
Avram! My God ...
What will I do?
You think he will be back
I'm with you, Mom.
It's not your fault.
I could not think that it will become
such a misfortune?
Back to work!
Henry, can you give me a diaper?
- None I do not.
- We have a few of them.
In this case we get back, David.
David?
What about him?
Sometimes babies stop breathing, but it's just
a moment. It's normal. but This looks not normal.
We will continue all night.
Let us pray that we have enough time.
Wake up!
Erika rehearsing yesterday.
I think it's a little help.
Even Aaron got a little bit.
Does it really do?
It can save David's life.
Will it harm?
I think not, my angel.
I can not.
We have nothing there.
I'm sorry. So sorry!
- We have to hide, underground ...
- I know, Henry.
- He have to come. Please, you must trust me, ...
- I know, Henry! I know!
Henry? Can you continue?
I need to rest.
How do you feel?
Strong. In any case,
you're stronger than me.
Your hands are like my grandmother's hands.
I am helpless
I feel so helpless
Go to your mother.
Please. We need water!
My son is dying!
- Give us water, we die of thirst!
- Just one word Jew and shoot you!
Please, even a sip. He is only 12 months!
You will receive your food as soon as we get
to the next station.
But until then all gonna die!
coach is already full of corpses! Full of corpses!
At least be some water for those who are still alive.
What song should I sing for?
Jacob, you're a crazy?
I can choose the audience.
These kids need food.
You too ...
we are hungry little children and Women.
- We get at least a piece of food?
- Shut up, Jew!
I can sing. I am a great comedian.
Sing your beautiful song.
Or recite few verses from Goethe. What do you think?
I'm hungry. Do you think that they give something?
- Please!
- you did not convinced us.
In any case,i will not
share my meal with a Jew!
Rozmla give him a blow  open Jewish head!
... eight, nine, ten. End!
Fraud!
I said I like animals!
Simply we lost too much time!
I got a sign that we can enter into the station.
Let's move on!
Please give us some water.
I have no gold! But ...a watch!
Please, my gold watch!
Gabriello!
Water! More! We need more water!
Do you have jewelry. Watches, necklaces.
I want water, too!
Let me!
- Drink, my angel!
- I want to drink too! That's mine!
You crazy lady? I will give you water. Please.
Watch Jewelry!
stay away
you Fucking Poles
Aboard!
Immediately departure!
- Red Light, do not you see?
Shit.
Jacob, i''m very happy.
Why do I feel the taste of blood in my mouth?
I'm so scared.
Don't to worry., we will jump
from the train when it moves.
- Wait until the train stops.
- papa You have to shave,
But I love you so much.
Sometimes I'm not very good to you,
because I take your hair many times.
Nina! no matter what ever you do
i love you
- But only a little.
- Just a little.
David?
David!
Doctor Friedlichu!
He is dead, leave him. Leave him alone!
What's happening? Why is she crying?
Nothing. Is she good she had a nightmare
Just go to sleep. Close your eyes.
No!
What are you doing?
Where is the ax? Where is the ax?
Fell.
How much longer we arrive?
We arrive at dawn
You try it?
Once the train is a little slow, you have to try.
Leo, please.
- We need to prepare Nina.
- No, I'm not going anywhere without you!
Listen, my angel. You have to wear black suit,
so that they can not see you in dark.
You have to go with her!
-You also need them!.
- Take them its my advise to you.
Nina you have to take care of your mom,
Promise? Yes?
- And if you're afraid, you know what to do?
- Renounce the prayer Shema Israel.
Yes. And if you will be sad for me?
You can not leave us alone.
Nina, see you soon again, you see!
The war will end soon.
- What do you do when you will be sad for me?
- I renounce the prayer Shema Israel.
Speak upward to sky. To heaven, and I hear you.
But you're not God.
I so hear you!
Leo, you go first, and then marry Nina.
Then Ruth!
Come with us, Erik. Come on, put it out!
You have to go with us! Eriko!
Children are entered. You have to try it.
Once the train stops.
Who try to slip through the hole?
Children and small women with stretch.
Slowly go down Leo, now!
- Henry,take care of yourself.
Pull me!
- Nina, let up!
- Take care of her as your own child.
- You do not know how much I love you!
- I love you too.
- No!
- Nina, go!
I hold you tight! Everything will be fine.
Nina, go!
- Nina please let up!
- Albert, help me!
I'm scared!
You jump and then immediately bend.
Now, understand?
Without Nina, no!
It's too late!
I  am scared! Sorry!
- Everything will be fine.
Approaching the station.
When it stopped,
Ruth and Nina can should run along the tracks.
There are soldiers everywhere!
Check doors and grilles! pigs should
not escape, Our journey willl ends in a couple of hours.
I love you!
Water! We need water!
Silence! Shut up or we'll shoot!
- Wake up!
- I can not!
Water! Water!
Can not you close the ugly snouts?
You take off the shoe!
Water! Water!
I said quiet!
Something is moving on the track!
Georg saw it!
My God! Let's go out!
Who are they?
Silence. Be quiet.
Train hit shooting sholdier
and they managed to run succefully.
They did it!
It's a miracle! They succeeded. I saw everything! A miracle!
For people in the coach next to it
will go into hell.
- Let us pray.
- Why? God does not hear us anyway.
God is not listening,? Why we pray?
Please ... you help me?
Excuse me.Careful! Careful!
Come on, wake up! Hurry!
wear Something.
Leave her and get out!
Take off your glasses, they will think that you can work.
I told you, I will not be performed without my tuxedo.
Give a child the old woman!
Are You ready, Garbielko.
They areCalling  us,
it's time to go on stage! Come!
Hurry!
What are you taking? Go on, hurry up!
"Oh joy, sparks of the gods,
flowers Elysian Fields,
Glory shining in your doorstep
It becomes our soulful chorus
Your light overshadow everything
It connects you shared destiny.
All men are brothers,
where is your speaking voice.
Listen! That's Schiller? This is Beethoven? Bravo!
These are the fields Elysee!
Indeed, Mr. Schiller, yes it is.
Nice Brother  love
Located under the vault of heaven.
Give the whole of humanity
Once again, kiss him.
How did you know that they will try to escape?
We go there every night.
It is the last stop before Auschwitz (Auschwitz)
Death Trains arriving  from all sides
- Are you here every night?
- Yes.
Today we will go there again. and wait
If someone ...
... escape ...
... so we can help them.
I always be with you,i Promise.
Nina? Do not go away.
Just a bit.
hears, oh God of Israel. God is ours, God is mercifull
Blessed by the name of
His glorious eternal kingdom.
And we love you God,
With all our soul and with all our possessions,
Subtitle by Arif chandio
Director
Screenplay
Played
Music
Editor