Sir?
Sir, Everything is
loaded into the truck. Sir
All we're leaving in the morning.
According to our intelligence reports,
the Japanese are here,
here, here and here.
And they are completely
surrounded by our forces.
So Japanese shouldn't be there then.
No. You're wrong.
According to our
British Intelligence reports,
the Japanese are here,
here, here and here.
And both sides are equal strength
This is ridiculous. According to
our French intelligence reports
All those area there are
no Japanese left them all.
It's not true. All you're...
Gentlemen. It is bad news for you.
The Japanese arrived here.
I occupy here, you, you, you,
tell me, tell me, you.
French Major General Pierre Retreat.
British Major General Robert Foste
American Major General Amberhang Wakins
Africa Major General Gabyi Zakro.
So I am. President. Hands up
Our four General have been captured.
If this news disseminates,
Our sentiment will be
adversely affected.
Be quiet.
The best way is
before the news is known.
We have to save our General.
The agenda of today's meeting is
who will lead our task force?
The number 7 agent
is on duty in South Africa.
The bald detective
has deflective.
King of Snake is dead.
Rocky is not suitable for
this military action.
Captain Hei-hu retired
to forming a family.
Who is he?
Captain of Devil, Duan-hun.
His bravery is well known.
This is not ajob for
ordinary task force.
I don't think so.
I am General Qiang-chun, this
is General Tang Mu-shen.
I told you the backdrop on the phone.
According to the information, General
Si-wei is being held in Luxembourg.
In four days time, Japanese will
take back to Japan for propaganda.
I order you to organize
a special task force.
Capturing the hostage
in four days time.
Remember, our mouth is shut
whatever happens.
I love everything that flies in
the air or crawls on the ground.
Send me the best food,
I will take all.
My friend, send me the best food.
I enjoy the food and drinks,
the bill are yours.
My stomach is full of crabs.
I have a good appetite.
Ha, ha
Give me a dozen of beer on ice.
I can take more than
ten pieces of steak.
My friend, send me the best wine.
I enjoy the food and drinks,
the bill are yours.
My stomach can take all kind of food.
I have a good appetite.
Delicious food, ha, ha.
I enjoy the food and drinks,
the bill are yours.
Oh, I am your dad.
Dad.
Don't move, this is a robbery.
Cut it off, I give up.
It's all yours.
Don't be cheeky.
Yes.
Oh, I thought I was a dead meat.
I got ajob for you.
You got the right man.
I can manage all jobs.
We are not ordinary Joe.
Damn, you did it on purpose.
So what?
Forget about it.
What? You can't leave
after having my food.
Who are you?
I know who you are, it
doesn't matter who I am.
Cao Shang-fei, the escape specialist.
What do you want?
According to the escaping record,
you did New York six times, London
three times, China eight times.
You escaped within a day
in Japan, is it right?
So you know
why do you bother to take me in?
You can't escape for your whole life.
I can delete your escape file,
as long as you promise a thing.
Really? Forget about a thing.
I can promise a hundred things.
Fool, I know you would run.
Say it, what do you want me to do?
We want to make use of you
to help someone escape.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to
this fight being held
at the National Square.
The one coming out is the Japan Killer.
The next one is King of
Orange from New York.
Our music is unbearable.
Bear with it for doing Thai boxing.
We got the band from the cinema.
What? Cinema?
Laugh.
If we win,
we will be rich.
Yes.
You look smart.
Take it, we have a full house.
You take it.
Take it easy.
Take it.
Hurry.
Two pieces of laxative will do him.
Have you got it?
You are next.
What are you doing? Trying to kill me.
You can kill yourself.
I didn't tell you to.
I am the Japan Killer.
He changed my pills.
I will kill you.
What a shame what you have done?
It's not right, I hate you.
The fight begins.
Wait...
Is there any rules?
No.
Cow, pick yourself up.
I am leaving, I am out.
Look at that money;
it is ours if we win.
Come on.
Cow, come on.
No.
Cow, we are rich.
I am rich.
Cow, run for your life.
This is my life saver.
If you carry on like this,
you can't run away.
Stay where you are?
This is illegal gambling.
This is a fifteen years sentence.
What? Fifteen years.
Ten years.
Five years.
It will soon be fifteen years.
You are not guilty,
you are free to go.
Yes.
There isn't enough evidence,
you are freed.
Thank you.
The more the better
It's enough for us to
be rich for a while.
Last month, you used the same trick
to make a lot of money.
Leave the money and run.
I am leaving.
You know coming back.
It has been a year.
I won't leave this time.
I have heard it too many times.
I mean it this time.
I can swear, do I look like a liar?
Do I look like a liar?
If you lie again, I will kill you.
Take it easy, I won't leave you again.
Listen,
I have met so many women.
I like none of them but you.
What? What did you call me?
Xiao-hui.
Nicy.
No.
Yes, I got it, you are Lucy.
Say mum.
Lei-li, you are up early.
Would you like breakfast?
Lei-li.
Damn.
Hay, you still enjoy fooling people.
I just want to test if
you have gone rusty.
Oh yes, there is ajob for you.
But, I can't do it.
Get someone else.
What a pity, I got Sun
and Cao Shang-fei.
We can make money out of it.
Oh, Sir.
Sir, to be with Sun and Cao Shang-fei
and making money, I
will do it whatever.
But you got woman, what about her?
She, I... don't know her.
Please.
This is nice, full of lives.
This is war, go on.
Oh, mind the flying bullet.
Mind your hand.
You are surrounded.
Give up your arms,
and surrender, this
is your last chance.
Otherwise, we will fire.
Who dares to move, I will kill him.
Wait, what do you want?
This is a matter between us.
It's not your business,
I will leave with him.
Retreat.
I don't want to harm any of you.
Please.
She will fire.
Again.
We can talk this over.
Shit, there is nothing we can talk.
Who do you think I am?
I warned you already.
I am not kidding.
Lei-li, it's full of people,
it's not worth it.
I am full of explosives.
If you want to play tricks,
we will all die.
Get in the car.
Move.
Sir, I don't know how to drive.
What?
Rubbish, start the car.
Yes, I will.
I got him.
Entering the barrack and taking the
hostage, this is a death sentence.
Death sentence?
It's only a life, it's up to you.
Sir, you must let her go.
She is all right.
I can guarantee it with my life.
You can leave.
I can leave so is he?
This is a matter of life and death.
You can't leave me out.
I can swear, I am not
making fun out of it.
It's my duty.
I know you.
I can swear, I won't... swear.
If you don't believe,
you can ask them.
I did it for the money.
Oh.
Billy.
Oh... I.
You should have told me.
I will follow you even
if it costs my life.
I am in.
Being brave to attack.
You have to keep it up day and night.
I will do it at all costs.
You will be chosen on merit only.
Do you like her? Do the chasing.
I wouldn't dare.
It's only hero who can match beauty.
You are not heroic for her.
See me.
It's yours.
Thank you.
What a lemon?
What ajoke?
When I got money, I will
have all the women I want.
Sun, when you have money?
What do you want?
I have been wandering without home.
When I have money, I will get a house.
Get married with a healthy woman.
She will give me a army of children.
I will teach them all I know.
I am different.
When I have money, I have a wish
to leave you all.
Why?
Because I will be involved one day,
I wouldn't run away from you all.
Sir, what about it?
I haven't thought about it.
Be careful, I might
take all the money.
You won't get any share.
You can all dream about it.
Don't move, can you hear me?
This is robbery.
I...
Give me all the money.
We will leave after getting the money.
Don't play tricks, be wise.
Get the money out.
You can get a 20)% % % off
for being a woman.
If I can do one with
you, you are free.
What about you?
You are familiar.
I swear you have never met.
Really?
Yes.
I remember.
The National Park, the Scottish leader
Yes, I recognize you.
We are thieves because of you.
It is a misunderstanding.
Where is our money?
Where is it?
Say it.
It's a misunderstanding.
Don't see it this way.
Robbing a thief.
Damn it, taking tiger's tooth.
Sir, they want to kill me.
Let's go.
Let's run.
Wait for me, I will be back
Porridge.
Do you fancy one?
Excuse me; it's only enough for two.
Excuse me.
You don't want it.
Oh, I can't take it anymore.
Listen, it's dangerous, let's leave.
We will think of a way of leaving.
When a tree is down, the
dependents are gone.
Let's go home and get married.
Whoever mentions leaving
again, I will kill him.
Don't be cruel.
Mind your manner.
Yes, smarty.
Watch out, or I will kill you.
You dare.
Lei-li, you...
So what? I like him.
What are you doing?
Let's go.
Does it hurt?
No.
Oh, I didn't see anything.
It doesn't matter.
We are all men.
Damn it, don't play tricks.
That's enough.
We can't afford any internal conflicts.
We must work together
to finish ourjob.
Lei-li is right, I am sorry.
It's my fault, please forgive me.
Never mind, it's all over.
You are good.
I got a cigar which I treasure.
You must take it for my thankfulness.
No.
You must take it.
Wait, have you noticed.
We have been here for half a day.
We haven't seen anyone yet.
Are they all dead here?
Now you mention it, I can
sense something is wrong.
Don't worry, I am here.
Damn it.
They haven't been visited by any male.
Especially those young and handsome.
Thank you.
The only male among all females
We must enjoy it while we can.
You can't take them all.
Do you need our help?
Most of the men are dirty.
Your mentality and language
is dirty and evil.
You don't sound like a man.
Oh, yes.
I am an artist, full
of sense of beauty.
Any imperfect disappears
slightly and slowly.
Wait, I am a woman,
take a look of me.
Don't I look beautiful?
Thank you.
This is what I call perfect.
You are one of them.
Full of remorse.
No, you misunderstand.
I am a hostage.
I have been degraded, he is the one.
I... Lei-li, you are making it up.
Do you really hate him?
I do.
Kill him.
No, but I love you.
Take him down.
Lei-li.
The day belongs to life and the night.
Any male who comes to this tribe?
He can't see tomorrow's sun.
No, I am begging you.
Please forgive me.
I have an old mum and a kid.
I am begging you
to forgive me.
I told you begging is useless.
I am telling you.
What is a real man?
You let me go already,
why did you get me back?
He has been too hearty.
Any woman he likes, I will kill.
How dare you?
I will kill you today.
I get you now; we will have
ginseng chicken today.
Sister, I didn't see anything.
I am here for the chicken, see you.
You are a girl?
Fly, don't you like flying.
Let's see if you can fly.
I can see you have a few tricks.
I am fighting for my life; don't
just watch it over there.
I am praising you.
Er-niu said it before,
I can't really fire.
Boxing is my favorite.
Who is Er-niu?
My partner whom you met before.
Do you listen to his advice?
I wouldn't.
We have agreed that
it's my say on all majors;
it's yours on petty things.
We haven't met any major yet.
So it was her idea to come to help me.
You are half right, she
told me to follow you.
If you can survive this,
the money is yours.
What do you think?
We are on it together.
Thank you, see you later.
Where are you going?
Your creditor is still
with the woman tribe.
If I don't go, I will
never get my money back.
Don't forget, I helped you before.
I didn't ask for you help.
You can't tell the good from the evils.
What are you up to?
What do you want me to do?
Take it off.
Taking what off?
I know.
Can't you see they are hungry for sex?
Knowing what we are good at.
If we can perform to please them
they might let us go.
Take it off.
This is what you call hunger.
I... they are hungry.
Damn it.
Chase them, they are still around.
God, hurry, run.
Wait, Lei-li is still in their hands.
Damn it, we are surrounded.
We must think of a way to escape.
I will cover you, watch me.
It is over; they must have
gone through the water net.
Lei-li.
Where is she?
Let's spend a night here.
Wait, we don't know our enemies yet.
It may be a trap here.
Let me go in first.
Is it all right?
I didn't see any.
You have been boxing for
half a day in there.
This is called first move.
Oh, your head is broken.
I couldn't have shot at the wall
and the rebound bullet hit my head.
Are you crazy?
Ghost.
It's inside the coffin.
There is ghost inside the coffin.
What do you want? What do you up to?
There is.
There is nothing.
Don't go.
Oh, one is missing, let me join.
Are you passing through?
Which one did you play?
I will kill you.
If you don't let me sleep,
Do you know?
Where are you going?
I will sleep in the coffin.
Would you like to join me?
No.
Please forgive me.
I don't know how I came in.
I don't know there is a beauty
God, please help.
Help, thank you for your mercy.
God bless me, thank you.
Mum.
My kindness God.
Thank you, God.
Oh, what is it?
You are scared because I took a card.
I am warning you,
I will pick the winning card.
Mind your game manner.
Damn it.
I got it, stop stealing card.
The one sitting opposite
to me is a devil.
The black hand coming under the table
feeling my card.
Really, let me see.
Help.
I have to shit.
Shitting.
Thank you.
Little fool, don't say anything.
Put me to bed.
Yes, I will take your order.
God of darkness, offering their blood.
Hurry, crossing the fire wall.
You are still alive, I
was sorry of your death.
I worried about you.
Don't worry, the evil lasts forever.
Do I look like a good guy?
It's nothing.
They learned some black magic
to scare people off.
The true is...
Damn it, it's all because of you.
We have been working hard.
They must be inside.
Let's rush in and kill them off.
Oh.
What is it? They are all dead.
Yes, it was far too easy
to have come through.
Yes, it was easy.
The Japanese died
without any chance of counter attack.
Someone came before us for the hostage.
Don't shoot.
It's us.
I was right, we are here to help.
Good, we are being followed.
Where is the hostage?
What hostage?
Stop pretending; settle
the debt of $50)0), 0)0)0).
$50)0), 0)0)0).
Oh, you got it right.
I told you already.
Those ghosts being together
for some personal gains only.
Cut off the crabs, I will
kill you if you don't pay.
You are a fool.
If I got the money,
I wouldn't be here.
Did you kill these people?
We?
We are not as good as you think.
I know you are here for the hostage.
I can tell you where the hostage is.
We stop fighting each other,
we want money only.
You can have the hostage
as soon as you pay.
There must be demons around.
Damn it, that money disappeared.
Where are you going?
I have to piss when I am nervous.
It's a lot of money.
Why the money is here?
We got a way out.
We can survive if we pay.
It's not easy to give
up this sum of money.
Do we get a share?
Those who worked get a share.
Yes, we live for money.
Even if we give them the money,
they wouldn't let us live.
We will take the money with us and
the alive will share the money.
Yes, the majority wins.
I won't die for sure.
I will retreat to give you
time to think it over.
We will wait until dawn.
When the first light appears
if you don't give up the money by them
we will come in.
We got enough time to make
a time bomb, the last survivor
will activate it so we all die.
Yes, if we die,
they will die with us.
Cow, when this deal is over.
This will be our last deal.
I will take your order.
Yes, I want you to live on,
you can't die.
After tomorrow, I will
have a new plan.
You will like it.
All right, I trust you one more time.
Being brave to attack
You have to keep it up day and night.
I will do it at all costs.
You will be chosen on merit only.
I don't think we can
help at this battle.
Not necessarily, I am prepared for it.
What is this damn thing?
This is an ancient firearm.
One has show one's worth
before making money.
I spent fifty dollars
to get it from the vendor.
Let's see how powerful it can be.
It worth's every cent of it.
Damn, it's powerful.
Even if it doesn't kill someone,
it will kill me.
How beautiful you are when you kill.
Disgusting.
Concentrate, stop sweet talking.
Be careful.
What?
I am alright.
I told you to be careful,
you are careless.
Don't worry; you don't
have to guard me.
Damn it, you are really.
Thank you.
Shi-tou, I have known you for a long
time you showed your real self today.
The leader is proud of you.
How are you Shi-tou?
Shi-tou, you can't die.
I won't allow you to die.
Leader, I can't finish your order.
Damn it, Shi-tou is so honest,
but you killed him.
I will kill you.
Damn it, counter attack.
We can only survive if
we can get some arms.
You cover me, I will get some arms.
Wait, Lei-li, I hope
you can think like this.
After we have our share of money,
we will settle down in a place.
You will bear our children.
But I... will be a pig.
Let's go.
Lei-li.
Listen to me.
Cow, you are something.
We are rich now.
Oh, why did you appearjust like this?
The money will be cut
by one more share.
Leader, you are still alive.
But they have all sacrificed.
What is it?
I am Sun.
Aren't we in the same gang/
Why did you kill him?
It is always the outsider who
reaps the benefit of a fight.
They died for me.
How cruel.
Don't blame me, who
doesn't want money.
Blame them for being a fool.
I understand.
It looked like they worked for you.
The reality is you hired
a gang of people
to fight with them,
what a faultless plan.
You made money without being known.
You are only guessing.
This is his business; it's
none of our business.
Believe me; we don't know any of this.
See you.
I only believe dead people,
because the dead mouth can't talk.
If you dare.
You should have been here earlier.
Why are you so late?
What kind of attitude is
it? What unit you are in?
Do you know who are we?
We are the Lieutenant General.
Never heard of it.
Hello.
THE END