Eastern Condors
Executive Producer: RAYMOND CHOW
Associate Producer: LEONARD HO
Producers: WU MA, RICKY LAU, CORY YUEN
Screenplay: BARRY WONG
Production Manager: CHAN PUI WAH
Starring: SAMMO HUNG, YUEN BIAO
Co-Starring: Dr. HAING NGOR
Co-starring: JOYCE MINA GODENZI,
LAM CHING YING,
CHARLIE CHING, K.K. CHEUNG, BILLY LAU,
YUEN WO PING, CORY YUEN, YUEN WAH.
Director: SAMMO HUNG
Well we've lost this goddamn war,
but it isn't over.
During the last two years of the war,
we'd transported a large
shipment of sammo 26 bombs
to a secret military arsenal in Vietnam.
Before we pulled out,
we tried to destroy that arsenal,
but sadly we failed.
In other words, 2 million pounds of
explosives could fall into the wrong hands.
If that arsenal is found,
you can imagine the consequences.
There's no way the US can send troops
or bombers in,
but that arsenal has simply got to be
destroyed whatever the cost is.
And we need your help. Understand?
Yes sir, we understand.
I've already chosen from among our troops
12 Chinese Americans for an assault force.
And this file here contains your orders.
But as far as the
U.S. Defense Department is concerned,
it simply does not exist,
only the name of your mission...
"Eastern Condors".
Go!
All the information you requested
on the Asian prisoners is here.
All of them have had connections
with Vietnam in the past.
It's in the files.
Anyway, take your pick.
But are you sure you only need 10?
Why not take 100 if that's not enough?
It's no problem.
I can always arrest more.
Joey Chu, alias "Turbo",
jailed for fraud for 15 years.
Benny and Danny Wong,
jailed for 20 years for assault and battery.
Jeff Ling, alias "Sunny".
15 years for armed robbery.
Ricky Lo, alias "Mouse".
20 years for manslaughter.
Steven Yau, alias "Fingers",
petty theft jailed for 20 years.
Jack Wang, alias "Filter",
life sentence for murder.
Alex Yuen and Frank Chau,
convicted on 8 counts of grand theft auto,
both serving 15 years.
Shawn Su,
convicted for killing a federal officer,
sentenced to 30 years.
You men have been chosen for a mission.
If you accept
you'll all receive special training.
After training you'll be
joining a up with a covert unit.
Throughout the duration of this mission
you will still be considered convicts.
But upon its successful completion
you'll all receive full pardons.
In addition,
you'll each be paid $200,000 US.
Any questions?
No sir!
I think they're staring at me Mouse.
Bet you can't make them blink.
They didn't even flinch!
Bet they're stoned.
Mouse, how are you going to
spend your 200,000 bucks?
Half's going to my daughter,
the other to my wife.
You never told me you were married.
You never asked, and where I'm from
it's a lot safer to keep your mouth shut.
Hell of a policy. I couldn't do it.
Benny,
what're you gonna do with all your money?
What's it to you?
It's none of your damn business.
Ease up bro.
Well it ain't!
Ok Ok Ok, sorry for asking.
What about you, Sunny?
I... I'm go...
gonna g go...
Don't worry, tell me later.
Shawn, I know in the past we...
Forget about it. It's the past.
Ten 'hut'! Move out!
Colonel, this is one hell of a mission
you're taking on here.
Well war is hell, sir.
Take my advice. Your objective here
is to divert the enemy's attention,
so our commandos can get their job done.
There's no need for heroics, understand?
What those men are facing is real.
That's right. But this isn't battle.
That war is long over, you know.
This is a one off. We're correcting
a mistake made years ago.
Listen, just do the job
and don't get killed. Right?
Right.
Colonel, do me a favour.
This is my brother. When we withdrew
from that ammunition dump,
he was wounded and had to stay
behind in a nearby Nai village.
When you're there if you get a chance,
try and get him out.
Ok I'll do my best sir.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
How many?
Just six. And they're drunk.
We'd better hurry, more will be coming.
You know what to do.
Hey boys! Any of you looking for
some good company for the night?
Not all at once.
Come on!
I can't stand this! Where are we going?
Why won't they tell us?
Hey bro, calm down!
Why's it matter anyway?
Why's it matter? I wanna be ready!
If it's cold then I'll need an overcoat
but if it's hot, I'll just go naked.
Who cares, we're gonna die anyway.
You wanna die?
I'll throw you out right now!
Benny, take it easy!
Shit!
Calm down!
Shawn, I've been thinking.
You know, I think he's got a point.
It doesn't matter.
I'd rather die fighting than locked up.
Maybe for you. They sent you away
for 30 years for what you did,
my sentence was only 8. How's that fair!?
Hey man you got what was coming to you,
Shawn got a bad rap.
That's what they all say.
Just telling you what I heard.
After this mission's over,
we all get a second chance
a fresh start.
Hey guys we've been heading south
southeast.
If the air speed is 400 knots,
it means that in a couple of hours,
we'll be somewhere over Vietnam.
Bullshit!
They wouldn't be taking us to Vietnam.
What's that? You calling him a liar?
You watch your mouth!
Benny, take it easy!
Come on, sit. Relax!
You guys need to calm down.
Yeah right, these guy are all animals,
aren't you?
Hey Forget it.
Why'd you get everyone nervous by
saying we're going to Vietnam?
'Cause according to calculations
it's where we're going.
At ease.
Alright sit down, just relax.
We'll be over the drop zone in 2 hours.
- Tell them to get ready.
- Yes, sir.
Now listen up! To avoid detection,
we're at high altitude.
Open your chute too soon and
you'll miss the target zone.
Once you're out of the plane,
count to 20 and then pull the rip cord.
Pull the cords by ourselves sir?
But sir, we didn't cover that in training sir.
Nothing to it. Count to 20,
then pull the thing.
What if the chute doesn't open?
Kiss your ass goodbye.
You'll never have to worry about
another thing,
who knows I might not be far behind you,
we all might be there soon enough.
Any more questions?
Yeah how...
how can... we...
Spit it out!
I guess it's out of the fry pan
and into the fire.
Count to 20 before you pull it
Go!
Count to 20 before you pull it!
O... k... kay!
Go!
Damn it!
Sir!
Sir, orders just arrived,
the mission's cancelled!
What?
There's been an explosion on
Colonel Yang's plane.
No one survived,
the orders say we must return.
How about the ones who already jumped?
But sir, this is an order.
Report Lieutenant Colonel Lam
has already jumped!
Sir!
They're landing behind the trees
Go!
Sir! Sir!
Sir! We're Cambodian underground,
sent to meet you.
Where are the others?
Behind the trees.
Alright good, help me with this.
Hey I'm here!
Shh, keep quiet!
Everyone okay? We all here?
123456, yes sir!
Idiot, we're missing one.
Sunny's not here!
Search the area!
Right!
Sunny!
He's over here!
S...
sixteen.
Sunny!
Sunny! Sunny!
He's dead
The order to abort came right
before I jumped,
we're on our own now.
Alright, then we're on our own.
Shawn, should I tell the others?
No. They're scared enough as it is.
If we tell them, it'll just make things worse.
This is your first check point,
from there go east you'll hit a river. From...
No. The plan's been changed.
We're going to the Nai village.
Nai village?
I wasn't informed. Are you sure?
It was last minute.
Oh man, that really stinks.
Something wrong?
No sir, don't let me stop you.
Smell bad? I told you it was her.
That ain't no kinda woman
I mean it sure looks like a woman,
but it smells like some sort of rotten thing.
You'd have to be pretty damn desperate.
I wouldn't go near that!
I would.
I'm not kidding, it's awful!
I'm going to take a shit!
Now!
There's a unit in that village and
a camp a few miles away.
They get wind of you and
you ain't never coming back.
If you'd told us we could
have prepared the way,
evened the odds.
VC!
Where's Fingers?
Can you see them yet?
Ssh!
What?
Be quiet!
I ain't scared of those dudes!
Forget it you idiots!
We'll get you next time!
Don't just sit there, fix it!
Stupid piece of shit broke down again!
What the hell happened?
Get down there and figure it out!
Well see you! Goddamn!
So what is it?
Start the engine, come on!
It's just an old piece of crap!
This happens every time you're driving!
Son of a bitch!
Damn!
It's a pack of American cigarettes!
That's weird.
Forget about it.
Over there!
Take them!
In the water!
No no don't shoot!
Fingers!
We'll rest here.
Don't you worry, Fingers. You'll be okay.
You'll be fine.
We'll get you out of here alright.
Listen to me, you'll be okay.
You just hang in there, alright?
I'm sorry!
He's dead.
Fingers had no business being here.
He wasn't a soldier.
Benny, don't!
Be quiet!
Two of us are dead,
I don't want to be the next one!
Colonel, I've had it!
It was a damn sight safer
back in my prison cell!
Screw your mission!
Benny!
Piss off!
Benny, come back!
Be careful man
he might shoot you in the back!
Leave if you want to. I won't stop you.
Bro!
Well then I'm getting out of here too!
Benny, we're in the middle of Vietnam
for god's sake!
We don't even know where we are!
What if we're captured by the Vietnamese?
Or fall into a trap or something?
We're better off if we stick together,
you know look out for each other. Right?
Come on!
You gonna just up leave you friends
in the shit? What about me?
Fine. I'll go back.
But this is for you, not for them.
You're going back there? Wait for me!
There it is.
The rest of you stay here.
We'll rendezvous at the west hill in 2 hours.
If we're not there then you're on your own.
See you soon.
If they get in trouble,
do we go down to help them?
Alright, gather round!
Give me some room here kids.
Come on out of the way! Stand back!
Okay who wants quality goods
direct from the west
and all at reasonable prices just for you!
Look Weasel! Here.
This is gold. Where'd you get it?
I got it from my uncle.
He said that if you'd take our whole family
to Hong Kong,
then he'll give you a great big case full of it.
But he'll only deal with you.
Right. Tell him to come meet me
at the committee house.
Okay.
Here, for you.
Thank you.
Here
Don't worry mister, we'll take care of him.
You okay pal?
Looks like I saved your neck again!
How about a reward?
Ring a ring of the roses,
pocket full of posies,
a... tishoo a... tishoo, we all fall down!
Save me the idiot act.
Now come on
where'd you hide the treasure?
Once we're rich
we can fly right out of here!
Fly! Fly! Fly! Fly just like a bird!
Yeah that's right, wherever you like.
But it takes money.
Now tell me where is it?
- It... It's...
- Go on!
Right here!
Wait!
What can I do for you today?
Let's drink.
It's not my birthday.
Smartass.
You see this shit? The stuff's contaminated.
I took one sip and shit for a week!
Impossible!
We'll see how impossible it is!
Now drink! Finish the bottle or I finish you!
No problem. To your health, and mine.
Brother!
Now asshole,
I don't really want to have to shoot you,
but if I see you again I will! Beat it!
Where'd he go?
It's alright! Please, your brother sent us.
Right, I know who you are!
You're the chief and vice
chief, and piglet.
I know, why don't we all
play cops and robbers?
You're the cops, I'm the robber,
you catch me!
Sir, you're coming with us! Let's go!
Soldiers!
Sir? You peeing?
Of course I am!
What's it look like I'm doing?
It's just... you don't need to pee here.
Use the crazy guy's can.
I need to use your can.
Sir! Guess what sir?
The are three Americans here.
Yeah where?
They're in there.
There's one in there, and 2 in there.
You idiot!
But they're here! I can prove it!
Move!
Hey sir, just look!
Where're you going? They're right here!
Wait! They're here, the Americans!
It's Americans...
Colonel, this guy is crazy.
Let's get him up.
Uncle! Uncle! Hi!
Hey take it easy! And don't forget
there are soldiers out there.
They're gonna hear if you shoot me.
We wont' shoot you.
We don't want any trouble.
We're here for Mr. Yang.
What? You wanna take my uncle?
But he's lost his marbles!
He won't tell you anything,
you're wasting your time mister.
What won't he tell us?
Oh about where he hid the tre... nothing!
You got three seconds
to put your gun down.
I don't give a damn if those soldiers hear us.
You can all go to hell!
You win.
Let's go!
Put that thing away it's dangerous!
You have my uncle, don't you?
And I'm not much of a threat.
Well now!
Move!
Hold it!
Just what are you doing on an oxcart,
Weasel?
Oh I'm going to get married
in my fiancé's village.
Here, you wanna meet her?
That's her father and her brother.
Hi there!
Here, for you.
Thanks. Okay.
See you!
Help me!
Get them...
Stop! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Move!
They're gonna tear us apart!
Now look, this is between you and them.
Let me go and surrender. Well?
Come on!
Stop shooting! It's Weasel!
Those guys are animals!
Give me a gun! I'm a real good shot.
Come on!
Thanks a lot.
Colonel, let me try to lure them away.
You'll have a better chance.
You'd never make it.
Don't! Listen, that's not a bad plan.
You all run, I'll help my uncle.
Keep quiet!
Not next to my ear! Get the cannon!
Yes sir!
Hurry! Come on! Hurry!
We're dead, we're dead!
We're outnumbered
and they've got a cannon!
Come on, I'm sorry!
I know I've been bad but not this bad!
Fire!
You brought backup? My wheels!
Spread out!
Are you ok?
What are you doing? I told you to stay put!
See what did I say?
We should have left them!
Alright! Cool it!
You'd better get going.
More soldiers are coming.
Good thinking. Lets move out!
Move out!
Right!
Let's go!
Come on you're slowing us down!
Come on!
He's doing his best.
What!
Shouting at him is not going to help.
Here's fine.
Colonel, he's hit bad.
We'll have to remove the bullet.
You've done enough damage!
Uncle, I'm here.
Who the hell are you?
Who the hell am I?
You wanna know who I am?
I'm the one who just got you out of there!
I just saved you ass,
that's who the hell I am!
Because of you I'm homeless!
And I almost got killed this morning!
Do you think I like running around
getting shot at all day?
I used to be a quiet businessman,
but you've just turned me into a bandit!
You've screwed my life!
My uncle and I used to make a good living,
but thanks to you we're now both fugitives!
And you have the nerve to ask who I am?
Here, sir.
Deng, I don't know you that well.
But I have to say you got a terrific figure
from what I can see.
You're very kind... and such a pretty face.
I wouldn't want to have to ruin it.
You get my drift?
That's one mean ass chick.
She'll come around.
You mean it? 200,000 if I help you?
That's right. Not a bad deal if you trust me.
I don't, but then I don't know you.
Are you with us?
I don't have a choice. Can't go home,
but my uncle...
You just get us out of here.
Don't worry about your uncle
we're gonna take care of him.
Well I'm your man.
I know the place like the back of my...
More of them are coming!
Give me your knives!
- Look after him!
- Right!
No thanks. You keep it.
Over there! Move out!
Sir!
Alright men! Spread out!
You okay?
It's me!
Come on quit spying!
Observing, not spying!
You know you've really
got to lighten up on people.
You know your problem?
You're always complaining!
Whenever I try or do something,
you always have to find
something wrong with it!
Can't you just get off my case?!
Quiet! You're too loud!
What's it to you?
I'll holler as loud as I like!
Go ahead ignore me!
You never even listened to
what I say anyway.
I'm surprised you haven't killed each other,
all you do is argue.
Keep out of this!
Unless you wanna sit out there!
Sorry, whatever you say sir.
Are you making fun of me?
Benny, calm down will you?
Keep observing. Go on!
Observing? I'm spying!
Mouse, quit moving!
You're letting water in.
Why don't you go have a rest?
I'm alright, Deng.
Why don't you girls just find a husband
and settle down?
Why are you risking your lives like this?
We're fighting for our freedom.
Don't waste your breath.
He doesn't know what a guerilla is.
Sure I do. From what I've heard,
guerillas are wanderers, badly prepared,
and badly organized.
Don't!
I'm serious!
That's what they say. I believe them.
I was just kidding with you!
Great!
Lets hope that next year
we can have another party.
Don't tempt fate, okay?
Goddamn it! 2 days!
When's it gonna stop raining?
We don't deserve this shit.
Deserve has got nothing to do with it.
Here.
Look I gotta come clean,
there's something you should know.
The mission that we're on...
Listen it don't matter.
Whatever happens we know you're doing it
for our own good.
We trust your judgment.
It's just all this damn rain.
It's starting to get us down.
Can't sleep?
I couldn't help thinking,
somehow this is no place
for a young woman.
You need the protection of a man
who'll look after you.
But look no further, I'm right here.
Listen if I did need a man,
it wouldn't be you that's for sure.
Now take a hike, you get me?
Wait!
But you can do something for me.
Take over the watch, I'm tired.
One of these days you'll
come back and beg me!
Who's there?
Stop or I'll shoot!
Don't shoot, it's just me. I need a pee.
Take a leak somewhere else!
That's disgusting!
Yeah or what?
I bet I can hit you from here.
There's so much rain,
you wouldn't be able to tell the difference
between water and piss.
Hey either you stop or I'll shoot you!
Think you got the guts? Here!
We're under attack!
Get down!
Shoot at something!
Look out! What the hell is that?
They're right here!
Don't shoot!
Drop your weapons!
Go!
Keep moving!
Move!