It's 4:00.
We are over Trollness again.
Look. Look. That flag.
- That's not ours.
- It's Norwegian.
Let's go down.
Our garrison headquarters
flying a Norwegian flag.
That's right. A Norwegian flag.
Suggest you investigate immediately.
Not a sign of life.
No smoke coming from the chimneys.
There can be fire without smoke.
Go away! Go away!
This is mine!
All mine! I own all this!
Go away! Go away, I tell you!
This is all mine. Go away!
Stop.
- What happened here?
- What happened here? What happened here?
The cannery, I built it.
Yes, I built it. With beautiful machines
that stamped out on millions of cans...
...Kaspar Torgersen, Torgersen,
Torgersen.
I owned half the boats.
Now I own them all. I own everything.
Hopelessly insane. Get rid of him.
Mine. Mine. Mine.
The landing party will be divided
into four groups.
Each group will scour a section of the town.
When they accomplished that...
...they will assemble at the hotel.
- Yes.
It's all mine.
If you're not too squeamish, lieutenant,
I would like to dictate a report.
At your service, Herr Hauptmann.
We entered the town of Trollness,
October 28th, 1942.
Former German garrison...
...commanded
by Hauptmann K-O-E-N-l-G.
Hauptmann Koenig.
Herr Major Ruck.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler, Herr Major.
My credentials.
Please sit down, Herr Major.
May I offer my apologies
for this surprise visit?
I'm a member of the führer's bodyguard
attached to the Academy of War Sciences.
- Of course. Of course, Herr Major.
- Sit down. Don't be alarmed.
We discovered
we obtain our best results...
...by not announcing our arrival
beforehand.
In Berlin I have seen the files from all the
commands of the central Norwegian coast.
You are mentioned as a student of tactics,
a good disciplinarian, worthy of promotion.
- Herr Major means...
- Sit down. That's not what I have come for.
- Can we be overheard?
- No, Herr Major.
I will be brief.
I stopped at every station
between here and Trondheim.
On one point, there is dissatisfaction
both in the general staff and in Berlin.
It is the attitude of the Norwegians
toward our troops.
I've come here to correct it.
I want all the available information
concerning your town.
Facts, figures, et cetera.
This is Trollness.
Main industry, fishing.
The cannery, it employs
about a hundred men and women.
A few shopkeepers, a few professionals.
In the hills, a few scattered farms.
Total population, a little under 800 persons.
Against them, our German garrison
of 150 men...
...well-equipped, well-seasoned troops.
This hotel is our headquarters.
Breastworks have been put up,
trenches dug.
Machine guns are scattered
all over the town.
I can defend this town against anything,
except an attack by sea.
A revolt would be crushed
within an hour.
I compliment you on your thoroughness,
Hauptmann Koenig.
Thank you, Herr Major.
I have been working on a plan every night
since I've been here.
It's not just a plan for this town alone,
but a master plan for all occupied territories.
- lf Berlin accepts...
- Sent it to Berlin?
Yes, I have.
And I expect an answer by the next boat.
If they accept it,
I hope I shall be transferred.
To the Russian front, preferably.
- You don't like it here, Hauptmann Koenig?
- I'm a soldier.
It's one thing to fight soldiers.
Those are ghosts.
- Then there is trouble here too?
- Nothing you can put your finger on.
Once in a while, a fire breaks out,
a boat is sunk, a wire is cut...
...a shipment of fish is spoiled.
The kettle boils.
It's clear this town is no different
from many others.
Yes. Especially of late.
The underground newspaper
keeps the people excited and stirred up...
...with their silly tales
of commando raids, guerrilla warfares...
...our losses in Russia.
After all,
I can hardly be expected to take...
I have carried out
all military regulations to the letter.
Blackout every night after curfew.
- Precautionary searches...
- I am sure you have.
One thing more.
My stay here will be brief.
A few days at most.
I shall want a list of all the troublemakers
in this town.
Ha, ha, ha. I would have to give you the
name of every man, woman and child.
- The leaders, do you know who they are?
- Every one.
We begin right here in the hotel,
right where my soldiers are quartered.
The woman downstairs, the innkeeper...
...her father was shot as a hostage
when we first took over the town.
She steals army food
from the commissariat...
...and distributes it in the village.
I close my eyes to that
because she's very efficient otherwise.
I took the liberty of fixing your chair.
You have a habit of tilting it back
and I noticed that the legs were too weak.
Try it.
Don't be afraid. I'm a good carpenter.
You always have flowers on the table.
My dead wife loved flowers.
You bear such a strong resemblance
to her.
I'm busy. I have work to do.
Yes, I know. Too much for a woman.
This could be a fine hotel.
It needs a man around to fix things.
I'm a good carpenter.
You're a German.
Now, for the rest of them,
here in the town.
There is Jensen, the shoemaker.
He is sly. He bears watching.
Solveig Brategaard, the baker's widow.
Her husband was shot,
but she carries on his work against us.
Petersen, the butcher.
He will run amuck some day.
Old man Mortensen, the tailor.
His son was arrested in Oslo. He is bitter.
Lars Malken, he runs the general store.
An old fool.
But he's useful to them for errands.
Karen Stensgard,
very active, very dangerous.
Daughter of the only doctor in town,
Martin Stensgard.
- Where are you going?
- To Gunnar Brogge.
- Karen, I forbid it.
- What have you against him, Father?
- He's not for you.
- I think he is.
Germans will stand him up against a wall,
you along with him.
Someone has to fight.
I'm a good Norwegian.
I wanna hold this family together.
You're not the only one in Norway
that wants that. Good night, Father.
A few farmers.
They're not very important.
In the cannery, they are all against us.
- One with us.
- The owner?
Of course.
- Who is the leader among these rebels?
- A man called Brogge, Gunnar Brogge.
A fisherman, about 30.
Served in the Norwegian army
when we first came in.
Head of the fishermen's union
when they had one.
Why don't you make arrests?
If it comes to an open rebellion...
...I can assure you, Herr Major,
within ten minutes.
We're 150 against 800.
We could be 150 against 8000.
Eighty thousand.
We have guns and they are afraid to die.
This man Brogge, where does he live?
Here on the wharf in this shack.
I can sail the course to England
blindfolded.
The moon is bright tonight.
They won't see me.
Gunnar, maybe you could wait?
- For what?
- For another night, a darker one.
- I've had my fill of waiting.
- All right then, go, now.
Karen...
...you think this is easy for me?
I can't stand it here any longer.
More than two years now with the Nazi
without striking a blow.
Other Norwegians have gone to England.
They're doing something.
But you've been doing things.
- Everyone here depends on you.
- Yes.
"Gunnar, how long? Gunnar, when?
Will we get the arms, Gunnar?"
And we wait. And they never come.
- So you leave us.
- I must.
You leave me.
Go now or I shall hold you.
Into the other room.
Gunnar.
- Gunnar.
Karen.
Hammer, what happened?
What are you doing here in Trollness?
- In Stoksund, revolt.
- What?
- There's a revolt in Stoksund.
- How? When?
Gunnar, I walked here.
- Talk.
- I can't.
A bullet here.
Karen, take him to Osterholm's farm.
It's not far.
Gunnar, I can't walk anymore.
Then crawl. Did you hear that bugle?
Koenig must have gotten the news
from Stoksund.
They'll send patrols.
They'll search every house for arms.
This is the first house they'll come to.
The patrol.
The trap, quick.
Hang on under the wharf until they leave.
Stay in the water then use the rowboat.
Hammer, please,
try to hold on a little longer.
Open up in there.
Open up in there!
We have orders to search the place.
All right.
Come here.
What is this for?
That?
Oh, I fish down there
when it's stormy and I'm afraid to go out.
All right. Hurry up there. You too.
What's this?
I was fixing my net.
You banged so hard on the door...
...it startled me and I cut myself.
Now, with your permission, I'd like to go
to a doctor before I bleed to death.
There's no use crying anymore, Anna.
They have gone.
They had no right to search this house.
- They're searching every house, Anna.
- No. They had no right to search this house.
They're not searching
your brother's house.
Oh, I'm sorry, Anna.
I didn't mean to say that.
Anna, you'd better go upstairs
and go to bed.
It's after 9:00.
Martin.
It's just... I want them to treat you
with respect.
You're a doctor.
Doctors should be treated with respect.
Yes, Anna. Yes. Thank you.
Hulda, take Mrs. Stensgard upstairs.
It's after 9:00.
After 9:00.
In the old days, we used to sit up
until 11, sometimes 12.
Well, Hulda...
...we'll have to give this house
a thorough cleaning.
I hope that lamp the Germans broke
can be mended.
It was such a beautiful lamp.
- I cut my arm.
- What do you want?
A man is on his way
to Knut Osterholm's farm.
He's badly hurt.
- Who is he?
- A Norwegian.
Brogge, why don't you let me alone?
You're the only doctor in town.
Let us understand each other, Brogge.
It is my duty to heal the sick.
I go with you only because I am a doctor.
Please, Hammer.
It's just a little ways now.
I can't go any farther.
Send my daughter on a mission like this.
Maybe to her death.
Dr. Stensgard, please.
We're all as worried as you are.
- Karen, are you all right?
- I'm all right.
- You're wet, shivering. You're cold.
- Father, that man is in agony.
You must change your clothes.
You'll be sick.
Gerd has some dry clothes for you.
- Hammer.
- Here. Cut his sleeve.
Gunnar.
You're all right now, Hammer.
You're all right.
Gunnar.
Listen.
Important.
I got out.
No one else.
From the beginning.
- From the beginning, Hammer.
- This man is in no condition to talk.
He must be quiet. Quiet. Hold the light.
Will he live?
I don't know.
- What are you doing?
- Putting him to sleep.
- Supposing he doesn't come out of it?
- Then let him die in peace.
Hammer, listen to me.
- Are you listening?
- This is a human being, Brogge.
I'll ask questions. You answer.
The skin has burned off his face.
It's agony for him to move his lips.
How did the revolt start?
We got arms.
They got arms.
I've known you all my life as kind,
decent people.
Hammer, how did you get the arms?
He's going to sleep.
I could kill you for this.
Hammer, you've got to hold on.
How did you get the arms?
The English.
They're...
What, Hammer? What?
Delivering arms,
all up and down the coast.
Not to us, they haven't.
- They will.
- Are you sure, Hammer?
Hammer, are you sure?
Yes.
Sure.
I'm sure.
Hear that? Did you hear what he said?
We're gonna get arms from the British.
He was sure.
- Arms.
- At last.
God help us.
God help us all.
Goodbye.
How many mornings we've said goodbye
on these steps?
Will there be one more morning, Gunnar?
I must make arrangements to get Hammer
across the border into Sweden.
Before he goes,
we must hold a meeting in the church.
It's important that in receiving the arms
the whole town be with us.
They'll be with us. They'll follow you.
Thanks.
All right, Gunnar.
I'm through crying now.
Karen, I gave you many reasons
for wanting to go to England.
I don't care now why you wanted to go.
All I care is that you're staying.
- But there was one reason I didn't give you.
- Yes?
You.
I worried about you.
I was afraid
that if anything happened to you, l...
I might lose my head.
Then I wouldn't be
of much use anymore.
But now I stay. Now, I've got to stay.
Karen, if were going to fight...
...we have to be like steel.
Yes, Gunnar.
I'll have some more butter, please.
There isn't any more, ma'am.
There won't be any more
until the day after tomorrow.
Good morning, Mother, Father.
Good morning, Karen.
Good morning, darling.
- How pretty she looks. You slept well.
- Wonderfully, Mother.
Oh, I'm so glad you weren't here last night
when the Germans came.
I was visiting the pastor's wife.
She's not feeling very well.
You must've stayed late.
I didn't hear you come in.
Did you hear her, Martin?
- No. No, I didn't.
- I'll help you straighten out the house.
Yes.
Yes, this house must be straightened out.
- This house must look as pretty as you do.
- Isn't she sweet?
Darling, I had a dream.
I had a wonderful dream.
I dreamt things were like they used to be.
I had made a great big supper...
...and we sat around the table
talking, laughing.
Your father drank a little bit too much,
fell asleep just the way he used to do.
And Uncle Kaspar told stories...
...about how he worked his way up
in the world.
And you were playing the piano
and Johann was singing.
- Wasn't that a beautiful dream?
- Yes, Mother.
Darling, that wasn't a dream.
That's the truth.
That's just the way it's going to be.
Johann is coming home.
Johann's coming home?
Well, aren't you glad?
Yes, Mother.
I got the letter this morning.
I must have read it 20 times.
No. No, it isn't in my pocket.
It's upstairs.
I'll go and get it. I'll read it to you.
I didn't even know he was coming
until your mother got the letter.
I didn't send for him.
- Who did?
- Your uncle.
- Birds of a feather.
- Karen, Johann is your brother.
In Oslo, in 1940 when the Germans came,
he was one of the first...
- He didn't know what he was doing.
- He knew.
His whole world was crumbling.
He was bewildered.
I have seen men stood up against a wall
with the Germans.
They had more to lose than he did.
Wives, children.
Their world was crumbling too.
They weren't bewildered.
Karen, we are not all strong.
There are some of us that are weak.
- When he comes, what will you do?
- Villagers of Trollness are his countrymen.
- They will be his judges.
- They don't have to know.
Why must everything in the world
be either black or white?
That's the way the world is these days.
Johann may have changed. Men repent.
Why don't you wait and see for yourself?
Let your mother see him once more.
If he doesn't come home now,
she probably never will again.
Would it be better
if she were to find out?
We can keep that from her.
We've kept everything else.
Karen, let her dream come true.
There are so few dreams left that do.
Poor father.
- Poor father.
- There were good things in the old life.
Don't tear up everything by the roots.
Maybe, when this is over,
we'll all wanna pick where we left off.
Karen, please. Two years is a long time.
A man can change.
Let him stay here in peace. Let him feel
there is still a home to come to...
...that there is still a place
where people love each other.
Father, I say this for your sake
and for his sake.
If you can still stop him from coming,
do it.
- Father, promise me you'll try.
- All right, I'll try.
Why do you come to see me
in the middle of the day?
I'm a busy man.
I have troubles of my own.
Well, whatever it is, come on,
say it and get it over with.
Kaspar, why did you send for Johann?
Because I need him.
He should stay in Oslo
and finish his education.
Ha, why do you lie to yourself?
He hasn't been near a classroom
in almost two years.
That's a fact.
I'm a man who deals in facts.
If he comes here, there'll be trouble.
No trouble. Johann's a smart boy.
He understands the new order.
Write him. Tell him not to come home.
You will tell him to stay where he is,
to go back to school.
Tell you daughter it's too late.
He's on the boat. He'll be here Sunday.
I don't want you to get him mixed up.
Your daughter doesn't want me
to get him mixed up.
- Let him alone.
- Your daughter wants me to let him alone.
Anything happens,
I'll hold you responsible.
Why is Karen so worried
about his coming here?
This is a peaceful village.
Or maybe it isn't.
Maybe there's something going on.
Something you ought to tell
your brother-in-law about.
Well?
Well, well?
Facts. Give me facts.
I'm a man who deals in facts.
I can't understand.
You're an educated man. A clever man.
A man who's been willing to take advantage
of every opportunity that came along.
Now when the greatest opportunity
of a lifetime comes along...
...you flounder like a fish out of water.
What is it? You want to be a patriot?
Well, it's men like us
who are the real patriots of Norway.
Shut your fat, evil mouth!
The polite doctor shouts.
The cultured gentleman raises his voice.
What's the matter, Martin,
holding out for a bigger price?
Hauptmann Koenig.
Good morning, Dr. Stensgard.
Herr Torgersen.
Good morning, sir. Good morning.
- It is exactly 11.
- Everything is arranged.
- The men are waiting for you.
- Excellent, Herr Torgersen, excellent.
Did you hear what he said?
"Excellent, Herr Torgersen."
And you slapped me.
There've been incidents
in this cannery in direct defiance...
...of the order
of the German high command.
Let me remind you how the order reads.
"The economic life of a country
occupied by German troops is to continue.
Everyone is to remain at his position
and continue with his work as before.
Any acts to the contrary are sabotage."
I have been lenient, heretofore.
If there are any more accidents...
...if there are any more attempts
to spoil the fish...
...such as making them unfit for
consumption by kerosene or other means...
...men will be chosen at random
and tried for sabotage by a military court.
I will impose stricter measures
on the town.
Forbid public gatherings.
Close the church.
- Tonight at the church.
Fishing will be forbidden.
The cannery will be shut down.
We got arms from the British.
We were told to wait for the day
the entire coast was armed.
We couldn't. We were betrayed.
Some quisling must have told the Germans
the guns were buried in our gardens.
They came with searching parties.
Then it started. House to house.
The men defending themselves.
What else could they do?
Possession of arms meant death anyway.
It was like a blood bath.
They offered us a truce on their terms.
We told them to go to the devil.
How were you situated?
How many of you?
A hundred and four.
One machine gun
and 2000 rounds for the rifles.
We were facing them
with our backs to the water.
On the other flank, we had a little hill
which we could keep pretty well covered.
That's how we stood
when the attack started.
About that time was when young
Olav Brande tried to launch the boat.
Olav Brande was a friend of my son.
The one who was arrested in Oslo
for cutting wires.
Shh.
He called to women and children
to get in the boats...
...and he'd set them adrift until
it was over, but they couldn't make it.
The Germans raked the wharf
with machine gun fire.
The women and children?
Most of them were lying on pilings under
the wharf. You could hear them crying.
What happened to the women
and children?
Those that tried to run for the boats
were shot.
There's no time for tears. Be quiet.
Go on.
We fought until dark and held them off.
About 9:00, their firing stopped.
We sat back and began to talk over...
...whether or not we could make the boats
in the dark.
There had to be a way out.
Then the planes came.
They sent down flares and then dived.
Houses started bursting into flames.
First one, then another.
The whole fjord was yellow.
Even the trees were on fire.
I guess that's all.
Stoksund was a nice town.
Once I was gonna open a butcher shop
in Stoksund...
...but my wife was against it.
Oh, excuse me.
I didn't mean to be funny.
Hammer has told us that the English
are delivering arms up and down the coast.
We'll get them here.
You've heard what happened
in Stoksund.
That may also happen here.
Oh, no.
Not if you plan your strategy.
Lars Malken may be right.
That's another question.
The question now is,
do we agree to accept the arms?
Are we together when they come?
Each man should speak his mind here.
Now.
- You say the whole coast will be armed?
- Yes.
Then what is there to speak about?
Is there anyone here
who can't see what that means?
No, this is not the way.
Every man must speak his mind.
Pastor, what do you say?
I say it's wrong.
I say it's against God's will.
I say it's murder.
They slaughtered us in the streets
and you talk about murder.
Yeah, that's it.
- Wait.
Wait. You'll all have a chance to speak.
Let him have his say.
Believe me, I understand.
But do not infect us.
It would only make it worse.
By him who died on the cross,
I swear I'm no coward...
...but in my very soul,
I know this is wrong.
You are a man of God, pastor.
But in these times, you...
In these times,
I must cry out all the louder.
How can you trust a man
who talks like that?
God have mercy on you.
We pay you a good wage,
300 kroner a month...
...and now you turn on us.
I am not turning on you.
He has a right to say what he thinks.
That he has. Go on, pastor.
No, I've said my share.
And you, Dr. Stensgard?
- No, not now.
- Then it's settled.
No, not yet.
I don't agree with the pastor,
but there are doubts in my mind.
You doubt. But my son in Oslo
was arrested for cutting wires.
To the devil with your son in Oslo.
- You're a traitor.
- I'm a farmer.
If I lose my farm,
there must be a reason for it.
The sacrifice of one poor village,
what will it accomplish?
What sacrifice?
What are you giving up? Your life?
Maybe they'll take that from you
whether you fight or not.
Your farm? It isn't yours anyway
until you fight for it.
Your peace?
What peace is there when a body of troops
can come in the middle of the night...
...and arrest you as a hostage
to be shot...
...for something you never did
or never even thought of?
Like my father.
To live in constant fear,
to have blackings at your windows...
...to talk in whispers,
to have guards at your church doors.
Do you have anymore objections?
All I did was ask a question.
A man has a right to ask a question.
I'm satisfied with the answer.
Sixtus Andresen, you're a man
for whom we all have respect.
You have taught our children,
even some of us.
We have found you to be wise.
- Surely in this matter, your wisdom...
- He's fallen asleep.
No, no, I was not asleep.
I was thinking what to say
when you asked me.
And I knew that you would ask me.
What can I say to you?
How can I advise you?
I find now that I've lived
more than 70 years...
...and all I know, I know from books.
And in all the books I've read, not one
do I remember that gives me an answer.
Perhaps I read the wrong books.
Forgive me if I've failed you.
All this may prove a point.
Vote. Let's have the vote.
We are all Norwegians. I love my country
as much as you do. You must believe that.
What would you have us do,
Dr. Stensgard?
Wait.
A tidal wave has swept over us.
It'll recede. When it does...
We'll all be drowned.
Ask yourself these questions. Do you
want your country ravaged, homes burned?
Your children bombed
as they were in Stoksund?
Ask your children those questions.
All right. Take the vote.
All those in favor.
Hold on, Gunnar.
How do we know the pastor
and some others won't betray us?
No.
Dr. Stensgard won't betray you.
He's a good man. I work for him.
I know he won't betray you.
Excuse me.
Thank you, Hulda.
Those with us.
Don't try to go further than Olsen's farm.
It's too rough on a wounded man.
Good luck.
Don't worry about me.
- Just a minute.
- Run.
- What do you want?
- Do you want them to hear you?
Where's the guard? Don't they have one?
He's at the back.
He'll be around in a minute.
Who are you?
- Who's down there? I heard voices.
- I did not see anybody.
- Hauptmann Koenig.
- Not now. Later.
So you're Gunnar Brogge?
Lovely night, Miss Stensgard,
for running though the woods.
Feeling better, Sister Gerd? Good.
Now let's get down to business.
A dictionary. Oslo edition, 1937.
I give it to you
in case we have no opportunity later.
- Who are you?
- A British agent.
- How do we know you speak the truth?
- You don't.
- When arms are landed in this village...
- We fight.
Gerd.
No. You wait. No matter what happens.
Keep your people in check
till the whole coast is armed.
Beginning tomorrow,
you'll have a man stationed...
...between midnight and 4 on the plateau
about half a mile up from the hotel.
He must keep a watch out to sea to a point
due west to the center of the village.
- Due west to the center.
- He will be signaled by a ship...
...lying 12 miles off coast.
- And then?
He will answer the signals
with 20 candlepower brilliance.
One flash for yes, two for no.
Ten seconds between answers.
For each word,
we will flash two numbers.
The first designates page number, second
the number of the word on that page.
So 212-9 would mean page 212,
the ninth word.
Will you remember all that?
If I don't, she will.
She's a very educated girl.
Due west, 20 candlepower, one, yes,
two, no. Ten seconds between answers.
Page and word number in dictionary.
- Correct.
- You see? She went to college in Oslo.
When does this happen?
Don't ask me. I only carry the news.
An Englishman in that uniform.
How do you do it?
Do I ask you how you catch fish?
I'll not be left out of things,
do you hear me?
Why wasn't I asked to the meeting
with Hammer at Osterholm's farm?
I'll make an issue of it.
Look here, Gunnar,
why don't you let me in on things?
Reason? I demand a reason.
Should I talk to him that way?
Or should I be clever,
wheedle it out of him?
You're wearing out your shoes.
Leather is rationed too.
I'll show you.
I'll show all of you. I'm not useless.
You'll come to me yet,
Mr. Gunnar Brogge.
I'll show you how to beat the Germans.
Go on up to the hotel. Start shooting.
Good morning.
- I want a bag for traveling.
- Is this the best you have got?
- This is all I've got.
- How much?
- Norwegian or German money?
I get paid by the Germans.
Twenty-two marks.
"Go up to the hotel," she says.
"Start shooting," she says. The old...
Hotel.
Say, maybe that's not such a bad idea.
- Hey, Paul, want a boat ride?
- We're going out to get the mail.
No, thanks.
Put the breakfast on the table.
Would you hand me a towel?
There's one on the bed.
Thank you.
Is there any news from the town?
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
I'm sorry to disturb you. l...
You thought I was somebody else.
You remember me, don't you?
The shop and the bag?
What about it?
Did I pay you too much or too little?
Oh, no, no, no. It's not that l...
I wanted to talk to someone.
Someone who'd been down
on the Continent since I was there.
I heard you were Polish.
I have a cousin in Warsaw.
And I thought, perhaps,
you might be dressed...
What was your cousin's name?
His... Malken same as mine.
Sit down.
Give me your hat.
What a beautiful new one it is.
Do you mind if I dress?
Is there any trouble in the town?
Trouble? Why should there be trouble?
Tell me about your cousin.
I know a great many people in Warsaw.
Well, I think... I think...
Was he a Pole or a Norwegian?
What was his business there?
- Well, l...
- Was he in Warsaw during the siege?
- You mustn't ask me questions.
- Then tell me why you've come to see me.
I wanted you to help us.
To do what?
Well, I thought...
...see, you living in this hotel with
the Germans, you might have information.
- What kind of information?
- Well, we could use all kinds of information.
For instance, number of guns, where
they're placed, have they got a wireless?
What do you want that information for?
Well, you see,
everybody in town thinks I'm useless.
- I'm not. I thought if we could bring them...
- We?
Will you help us?
What makes you think I'd do this?
What good will your filthy money
do me here?
Think I'm crazy enough to get mixed up
in anything like this?
I'm leaving here. Today.
They promised me.
- Well, I don't know. I just thought...
- Oh, you fool. You fool.
Go before somebody finds you.
Go, go.
Do you want me to give you away?
Wait a minute. How did you get in here?
Through the corridor window.
If you don't want to get a good beating,
you better go out the same way you came.
You wait here.
I will go and see
if there's anybody in the hall.
What are you looking at?
It isn't forbidden to look.
For you it is, you swine.
- You Polish sow.
- Go ahead. I dare you. I dare you to hit me.
You won't always be with the officers.
I can wait.
You will rot first!
Hello, Grandpa.
Oh, muscles. Heh, heh.
Not bad.
Teeth too.
Hey!
What's your hurry, Grandpa?
Look, men.
Look what came out of Katja's room.
Let me at him. I'm jealous.
No, no. Wait a minute.
Here. Before he dies, he's gonna tell us
the secret of his success with the ladies.
Let me go.
Before I tell you what I think of you.
What every honest man thinks of you.
Quiet! Quiet, everybody!
All right, Grandpa, tell us.
Brave Nazis. Very brave indeed. But not
so brave when you're patrolling at night.
I've watched your faces. Somebody
slams the door, you think it's a shot.
And how do you sleep at night?
Not very well. And why?
Because my Norway
has a fighting tradition.
There was Eric the Red.
There was lbsen.
You're dealing here with giants.
I could have told them all those things.
I didn't say a word.
Well, Johann.
You remember me, don't you?
- Of course. How are you, Brogge?
- Fine.
- I didn't know you were coming home.
- He surprised us.
Oh, surprise.
Well, that's the best kind of a visit.
I'm sorry. We have to hurry.
His mother is waiting.
Letter for Hauptmann Koenig
from Berlin.
Maybe we'll be lucky
and they'll transfer him.
Berlin has said no to my plan.
They have ordered me to stay here.
Now I remain nothing.
A commander of a garrison.
A garrison
in which even my own troops hate me.
- You weren't listening.
- I was. But the boat is leaving...
You will not go to the boat.
You weren't listening.
You kept thinking about yourself.
- You promised.
- You are not.
You're staying.
Here in this hole like I am.
- You're staying.
- You promised!
- You are staying!
- Liar! Liar!
You are staying!
Draw the curtains,
before someone sees me in here.
Weren't you taught to knock
before you enter someone's room?
Please don't be angry with me. Help me.
I don't know what to do.
Hauptmann was quite upset.
- You heard?
- Yes.
- You're Polish, aren't you?
What are you doing here in Norway?
Well, you see, at the time
the Germans took my country...
...I was in Berlin on the stage.
Then they wanted me
to work in a factory.
After all, they said, I was only a Pole.
I told them I was an actress.
Then they said
that before I could act anywhere again...
...I would have to prove my loyalty.
And to prove it,
you agreed to come to Norway?
They promised I would only have to be here
a little while.
Now I have been here almost two years.
What do you want me to do about it?
I thought that since you are here,
a high officer...
...that maybe you would talk to
the hauptmann, get him to send me back.
I am afraid to stay here any longer.
- What are you afraid of?
- Everything.
The soldiers. This town.
There's something going to happen here.
I feel it.
Only today, a man came up from town
and wanted to know if I would help him.
- Did you report him?
- No.
- Why not if you're loyal?
- I'm not loyal.
I'm not anything. I hate them.
I'll have you shot for such talk.
No, you won't.
I know you're not
what you pretend to be.
I saw you talking to those people
last night.
It was I who warned you.
I can't risk the fate of a whole village
just to help you.
- What must I do?
- You could do a lot.
You could help us all.
Remember the old man
who came and asked for help?
- No, no, I won't.
- You wanted me to tell you what to do.
I'm not going to get mixed up in anything
that will get me killed.
I want to get out of here alive.
Are you going to speak
to Hauptmann Koenig for me?
No.
Do you want me to speak
to Hauptmann Koenig?
Now, before your boat leaves?
I could do it so easy.
Only a word.
One little word.
You'll find my shirts in the top drawer.
Will you bring them here?
Ten o'clock and we're still up,
just like in the old days.
I'd like...
I'd like to make a toast.
Father, Mother wants us to drink a toast.
Oh, I'm sleepy.
No, Martin, you are drunk.
- Hello, Hulda.
- Good evening, sir.
Well, it's a fine thing.
My sister's son comes home, I'm not invited
to my sister's house to welcome him.
Oh, forgive me, Kaspar, I forgot.
- You see, there's so much excitement.
- Oh, forget it.
- Welcome home, Johann.
- Uncle Kaspar.
Well, this is nice. Family life.
Mother, father, children, all together.
I can see now I missed a lot
by never getting married.
But I have Johann.
Like a son he is to me, just like a son.
Now I can settle back
and take things easy.
You'll help your old uncle,
won't you, Johann?
Well, that's why I'm here, Uncle Kaspar,
to help you in the cannery.
Kaspar, we were just drinking a toast.
Will you join us?
Now, let me see,
what were we drinking to?
Oh, yes. To peace.
May peace come again and soon.
To a free Norway.
I'll drink to that.
From Trollness, 500 blankets.
From Trollness, 300 overcoats.
From Trollness, 800 pair of shoes.
From Trollness, 100 tons of fish.
From Trollness, milk.
From Trollness, eggs.
From Trollness, butter.
It will be ready in a minute.
Fräulein.
The orders are that any person out
after curfew may be shot on sight.
Well then why don't you shoot me?
Why should there be hate between us?
There's such a thing as being in the war
and yet outside of it.
We all have our own lives.
All of us, even those who have the
strongest faith would like to stop fighting.
We'll fight until we push the last one of you
into the sea.
Perhaps what you say is true.
Perhaps that will be the end.
The resemblance is remarkable.
Good night, Fräulein.
The 59th watch.
I feel like shouting out across the seas
to the world.
"Hey, world, we're waiting here
in Trollness. Don't forget us."
Go ahead. Shout.
Maybe it'll help.
But tell them to be quick. I'm getting old.
When my father was my age,
he already had two children.
What must it be like to live in world
where there are no Nazis.
Good.
I might have been a German guard.
At a time like this, you've no right
to think of yourselves.
Poor Gerd.
She's unhappy.
I would be too if I were in love
with a German soldier.
- You got everything?
- Yes.
Why don't you go home?
We'll stand your watch with you.
It's lonely out here.
I'm sorry I was angry.
Lend me a handkerchief,
will you, Gunnar?
The glasses are dirty.
That's better.
Thank you.
They've come. They're here.
Stack them over here, men.
The British captain says, "Look,
there's Norway, only four miles away.
Must be quite a place in peacetime."
"Captain," I says,
"it's quite a place now."
Karen, you should've seen that wonderful,
big fisherman of yours.
Collar up, cap pulled over the eyes,
face streaked with salt water.
There he was, squinting dead ahead
through the spray.
The picture of a Viking.
I never heard Gunnar so talkative.
Every time the boat rolled, he'd say:
"We're not in your store now,
eh, Malken?"
And me so seasick,
I was afraid I wouldn't die.
Same with me. It got to the point
where I thought I could stand no more.
And at that moment,
I heard our motor stop.
"Are you sure this is the right spot,
Gunnar?"
"Yes," says Gunnar. "I marked it yesterday
on the side of the boat."
Did you have trouble finding the sub?
No. I had the good fortune to be looking
in the right direction.
I saw it all.
First, a white line of breakers
and then something like a fish in the middle.
When, all at once, she was up
not 50 yards away...
...with sailors pouring fast
out of the hatch...
...training a light and a deck gun on us.
We heard a voice calling.
"Brogge, Gunnar. Are you there?"
That was Ruck.
He was the first to greet us.
"You wanted to know
when we'd deliver the arms?
Here's your answer.
The last night in September."
I knew he wouldn't forget us.
He didn't. "Clever woman you have
in sister Gerd," he said.
"Kiss her for me, will you?
And the beautiful Miss Stensgard too."
Now, to work. I want to see
what our friends sent us.
I wrote down every box...
...as the quartermaster
was calling out their contents.
Read it.
"Fifteen thousand rounds
of 50-caliber ammunition.
One hundred hand grenades,
300 bayonets.
Three hundred rifles
and four light machine guns."
"And don't stop to count them," he said.
I don't wanna say anything.
We should be glad to get that much,
but still, it's the old story.
Four machine guns
against the German army.
That Osterholm,
always on the gloomy side.
Here, Karen, feel how light that is.
Does no one here remember Stoksund?
Sure. We remember Stoksund.
But in Stoksund, they were betrayed
by a quisling.
In Trollness, we, too, can be betrayed
Speak up, Karen.
Tell them who might betray us
here in Trollness.
My brother.
- This is the tree. Mark it.
- All right, Gunnar. I won't be long.
Down.
The flashlight, they shot it
out of my hands.
- Where is it?
- Don't know, shouldn't have lit it.
That's bad.
Hello?
You can see for yourself
what ungrateful people they are.
They speak of loyalty to their country.
And how do they prove it?
By provoking the Germans
into destroying it...
...with their plots and conspiracies.
What do you want, Uncle Kaspar?
You and I, Johann.
We're the only sane ones.
The only calm ones, the only smart ones.
We'll come out all right,
no matter who wins.
When I came here, it was with the clear
understanding that I was to be left alone.
Well, I've left you alone.
Well, let it continue that way.
I made a mistake in Oslo. I'm not a Nazi.
It isn't a question
of being a Nazi, Johann.
It's a question
of protecting what's yours.
This cannery is mine now,
but it'll be yours someday.
Tomorrow morning,
because of this nonsense on the hill...
...Koenig is confiscating
all the fishing boats.
He's afraid the villagers
might use them to get arms.
Do you know what that means, Johann?
It means that our cannery
will have to close.
Now, wouldn't it be better
if quietly and without any fuss...
...you could find out
what they were doing on that hill?
It wouldn't be hard.
The villagers trust you.
You could listen, ask a few questions.
- Well, Johann?
- No.
I won't go through it again.
What I went through in Oslo...
...when all my friends found out.
What will you do, Johann?
I'll go away to some other town.
All right, let's deal in facts.
One, travel in Norway is forbidden
without a German visa.
Two, it will be very simple
for the people of Trollness...
...to find out you were a traitor.
Three, the Nazis consider you
one of them.
They don't like traitors either.
They shoot them.
See, Johann,
the facts speak for themselves.
Where did you get this?
Can you fix it, Mr. Malken?
I think it can still be used.
- Well, where did you get it?
- I found it.
- Up on the plateau in the woods?
- Yeah.
Why? Is it yours?
It's lucky you found it
instead of the Germans.
How do you mean?
- Well, you see that hole?
- Yeah.
German bullet went right through there.
Shot it right out of a fellow's hand.
Oh, what a night.
My back's almost broken.
Hauling all those supplies
from the plateau to the big ravine.
From the plateau to the ravine.
- Well?
- A fool's errand. There's nothing.
I told you word for word
what Malken said.
It's not my fault.
Lucky for us, Karen warned us in time.
Her own brother.
Maybe it wasn't such a fool's errand.
Lieutenant, the following measures
are to be carried out immediately.
Confiscate their fishing boats.
Evict the schoolmaster
and convert his home into a blockhouse.
All restrictions on our troops
are to be lifted.
- They're free to do as they choose.
- There'll be trouble, Herr Hauptmann.
That's exactly what I want.
Your son, Anna. He's a traitor.
- Father.
- It's time for her to know.
Know what, Martin?
He's a traitor. Ask him why.
Maybe he'll tell you.
Johann, you tell them the truth now.
It'll be better.
You tell them the truth.
All right.
When the Nazis came into Oslo...
...I had to make a decision
and I thought...
- You thought of yourself before Norway.
- Yes.
That was in Oslo, but here,
on the boat, you gave your word.
I didn't realize, father, that once you're in
you can't get out.
You can.
If you're not afraid to die.
Karen...
...if I could get out of Norway
to Sweden, England, any place.
You can help me get out.
You people have ways.
I know you've smuggled thousands
across the border.
Not long ago, in Trondheim...
...they helped a quisling
to get across the border.
No sooner was he across, the people
who'd helped him were arrested.
Ten men were shot.
The rest sent to a concentration camp.
No. No, I wouldn't do that.
You know I wouldn't.
Karen, tell him I wouldn't.
You wouldn't want to do it, Johann.
You didn't want to go back
to the Nazis either...
...but you can't help yourself now.
- You're weak, Johann.
- Karen.
Mother, I wish I could speak for him.
I wish I could say to Gunnar,
"Help my brother."
I wish I hadn't been the one
that had to warn them against him.
Father, they'll kill me.
No.
No, we won't kill you.
It isn't necessary to kill you.
There isn't a single person in this town
who doesn't know that you're a quisling.
Soon all Norway will know it.
JOHANN
What can I do?
Mother...
...what can I do?
Oh, my boy.
I don't know.
"In the name of the German army
high command, I decree...
...the immediate confiscation
of all vessels.
It is forbidden to leave the harbor.
It is forbidden to remove
any equipment from these boats.
Any resistance will be crushed
by military force."
Come in.
- Yes?
- Good morning.
Good morning.
My name is Sixtus Andresen.
I'm the schoolmaster of Trollness,
retired seven years.
Your men came to see me this morning.
They were kind enough
to offer me 48 hours to move my things.
What little odds and ends I have,
my books...
Yes?
Hm.
Do you mind?
What with the scarcity these days,
it's been some time since I've smoked.
What do you want?
Thank you.
I thought it only right...
...considering that you are
de facto commandant of the village...
...to acquaint you with a decision
that I've made.
I'm very busy.
I know. I hope you will forgive me.
I know I'm being selfish, but, uh...
Why did you want my house?
For a blockhouse.
But what was it you wanted
to see me about?
I cannot let you have my house.
- You what?
- I must forbid you to enter my house.
Are you insane? I could have you shot.
I know.
But if you're interested, I'll tell you
what brought me to my conclusion...
...which is, I can assure you,
completely unshakable.
You see, I'm well past 70.
And at my age, it would be foolish for me
to be like Socrates' enemies...
...and fear death more than I love truth.
- Go on.
- I have no guns, no airplanes, no force.
- I disdain...
- Silence!
What you don't understand
is that the individual man...
Quiet, you fool!
The individual man must stand against you
like a rock.
Will you stop?
No.
If I were afraid, there might be hope
for you, but I'm not.
There are certain things
you cannot take away from me.
What is mine is mine.
Do you think you can stop
the working of my brain and my heart?
We are not animals, we are men.
That is the foundation of law.
You cannot win.
Where are your courts,
your judges and your juries?
Until you bring them forward,
I must forbid you my house.
He forbids!
Attention!
I give you 45 minutes
to clear everything out of his house.
Clear him out too.
We have no room for philosophers.
Take all his belongings
to the public square...
...and burn them as a lesson
to the others.
They must be taught to obey.
That's an order.
Stack arms.
Throw the old goat to us.
We'll catch him.
Well, my little goat almost got away.
You better throw me a rope.
So you like to run, Grandfather. Go on.
Come on.
After you've been here for a while,
you'll get used to it.
Hail! Halt!
One!
Two!
The professor has so much in his head
that he doesn't need his books anymore.
He asked us to distribute
a little knowledge among all of you.
Here's some knowledge for you,
my friends.
There's some knowledge.
Knowledge for you.
Here's some knowledge.
Here.
Do nothing. This is not the day.
Wait for the day.
- Do nothing. Wait.
Wait.
Wait. Wait. Remember Stoksund.
Wait. Our day is coming. Wait.
This is not the day. Wait. Wait.
Remember Stoksund.
Wait. Wait.
Wait now.
Remember Stoksund. Wait.
Our day will come.
This is not the day. Wait. Wait.
All right, Brogge.
You must forgive us, Sixtus Andresen,
for not helping you.
But, you see, if we had
then all our hopes...
I understand.
Is this why you came to see me?
- To explain?
- Yes.
And the others?
They've asked me to speak for them.
I'm a fool, Brogge.
We all think
that you're a very brave man.
Still a fool.
Koenig is a fool too, but I, a worse one.
Thank you for coming.
Each day we learn a lesson.
What is the lesson for today, Stensgard?
The individual cannot stand like a rock.
Even a rock can be crushed.
It's obvious.
Tell me, Stensgard.
Do you think that again I prove a point?
Another patrol. Every day. Every day.
The days to come will be even worse.
Koenig wants to make us lose our heads.
He's trying to forced our hand.
He will, Gunnar.
Our people won't stand it much longer.
Soon, we'll have to fight.
There are some of us
who won't come out of it alive.
Every battle must have its dead.
We've been lucky, Karen.
We've had two whole years together.
Time is measured differently these days.
A day is a year.
In a way, this war's been good to me.
Because of it, I met you.
We must be ready for whatever happens.
The plans have got to be well laid.
Tonight we'll meet in Osterholm's cellar.
I'll go back and tell those inside.
Notify the others, I'll meet you at my house.
No. I'd better go home.
It's a lonely house now.
All right, I'll pick you up there.
Will you shut that off?
When the English gave us this,
they told us to use it.
Well, why do you have to use it here?
If the Germans caught me,
I'd be dead even if I had nine lives.
A meeting in my cellar,
guns in my cellar...
...and now an illegal radio in my ce...
Will you shut that off?
Mr. Churchill's going to speak.
For a week, you've been saying,
"Mr. Churchill's going to speak."
So far, all I've heard is static.
All the same,
Mr. Churchill is going to speak.
Good evening, Hulda.
Is...? Oh, good evening, Mrs. Stensgard.
- Doctor.
- Good evening.
- I came for Karen.
- Karen's not here.
Oh, please come in. You're welcome.
We were about to have some tea.
We could sit and talk a while. Hulda?
No, thank you, Mrs. Stensgard.
I haven't got much time.
I left Karen an hour ago.
She was gonna meet me here.
- We were going on together to Osterholm's.
- An hour ago?
- Perhaps, we'd better go and find out.
- No.
She's probably stopped some place to visit,
perhaps with Gerd, and went on with her.
We're holding a meeting, doctor,
in Osterholm's cellar.
We'd like you there to help us plan.
- Me?
- Yes.
I'll wait for you if you like.
Oh, no, no. No, you go ahead.
You go on.
All right, you know where we are
if you change your mind.
Good evening.
Good evening, Mrs. Stensgard.
Martin, you go.
Go on with him.
Your heart's with them. I know it is.
I knew it this afternoon
when you stood in the square and you sang.
And I knew it here all evening
when you were silent.
I knew what was on your mind,
what was in your tongue.
Martin, I want you to go with him.
Now, there's your hat, the cane.
Doctor should always look his best.
I'll go and look for Gunnar.
That's all we need, somebody to go out
to look for someone else.
You shouldn't have let Gunnar go out.
- He was here. He should have stayed here.
- Then why didn't you try to stop him?
I think they're here.
- Now will you turn that off?
Dr. Stensgard.
I brought my wife.
I hope you don't mind.
You're both welcome.
- Dr. Stensgard, this is your chair.
- Thank you.
Mrs. Stensgard, will you sit here?
- You were expecting him to come?
Why, yes.
Oh, thank you.
But my daughter and Gunnar Brogge,
they were supposed to be here.
Yes, we're expecting them.
They're a little late.
- It's raining.
- Yes.
Oh, that's a pretty shawl you've got on.
Did you make that?
Yes.
Don't you think it'd be a good idea
for you to turn the radio on?
But you said...
Mr. Churchill's going to speak.
- She's not here.
Gunnar.
I've looked everywhere,
every house, every street.
When you came to my house, you told me
she'd gone with Gerd. I remember clearly.
Karen, what is it?
- Perhaps you all better go, leave us alone...
- No.
Let them hear. Let them all hear.
I know the man.
I know him.
Gunnar, if you think that now
is the time to fight, we fight.
- Listen to me.
- I'll listen to no one.
You're going to throw away everything we
hoped for, struggled for, to be revenged.
Gunnar, all over Europe
this happens to many. They go on.
Happened to you's all I know.
All I wanna know.
I didn't have to tell you,
could've kept it from you.
They killed Gerd's father,
Solveig's husband.
- Why am I any different to them?
- Why am I?
I'm human. Is there a man in Norway
who wouldn't kill for this?
Yes, there is such a man. Gunnar Brogge.
Gunner Brogge is our leader.
The people of Trollness trust him.
There's a chance for them to win
if he doesn't throw it away.
He said himself, "In these times,
we must be like steel." Like steel.
Were they just words, Gunnar?
It's...
It's hard to find words
for such a thing as this.
When you put flame to the tip of a harpoon
to temper it...
...even the hardest steel melts
if the flame is too hot.
I was full of such a flame.
Karen is right.
We'll not fight now.
These things are not forgotten.
They're written down in books.
In days to come, people will say,
"There were giants here in Trollness."
We came here tonight
to learn our plan of battle.
What is it, Gunnar? You're our leader.
From now on,
every one of us must be a leader.
I'll draw you the plan here.
Remember it.
Remember it well.
That is symbolism and that is the message...
...of the Atlantic meeting.
Do not despair, brave Norwegians.
Your land shall be cleansed...
...not only from the invader...
...but from the filthy quislings
who are his tools.
Yield not an inch...
A German soldier
has been brutally assassinated...
...when in foreign land,
surrounded by enemies...
...by a civilian population of thieves
and assassins.
But the fatherland stands with us.
I want you to remember the honor
of the Third Reich lies in your hands.
No man shall die unavenged.
There stands the self-confessed assassin.
The depraved product
of a degenerate democracy.
That a man like that
could have such a son.
But the life of one Norwegian
is not payment enough...
...for the life of a German soldier.
As an example to the rest
of the population...
...every one of their leaders
will be shot...
...tomorrow morning at 7:00
in the public square.
Their bodies will be buried there,
graves will serve as a reminder...
...to slave populations
that there must be complete submission...
...to the master race.
They will dig their own graves.
Three minutes.
- Forgive me.
- There's nothing to forgive, Father.
When I saw their faces, I had to kill.
I had to.
If it hadn't been you,
somebody else would have.
The noose was drawn too tight
around our necks.
You will see, Torgersen, from now on
this will be a peaceful village.
I hope so.
Oh, God.
If this suffering must be...
...bless those that serve thee
and want only freedom.
But whatsoever thou decidest...
...may thy will be done.
Well, Mr. Torgersen, I think it is time.
Lieutenant, proceed.
Lay down your shovels.
Lieutenant, cover each entrance.
If they don't stop when ordered, fire.
The execution will proceed.
This time
Koenig's guns won't stop them.
This time none of them are afraid to die.
Get the prisoners ready. Out!
Attention!
Go back,
your leaders have betrayed you.
They deserve to be shot.
Go back. I will intercede in your behalf.
The canneries will be reopened.
Fishing will be resumed.
Your boats will be given back to you.
There'll be peace again.
Work again, bread again. Go back!
Ready!
It's an armed revolt.
- Headquarters, headquarters.
Yes, sir?
Lieutenant, revolt. It's come. They have
arms. Dispatch reinforcements to all posts.
Hold force to protect hotel
in case they break through.
Women and children should stay
under cover until they get to the boats.
The order was women with children
get under cover. I fight.
Excuse me.
Harbor detachment, harbor detachment.
This is Hauptmann Koenig.
Revolt. They've got arms.
They will break through to the boats.
Dead!
Go back to your room.
Blockhouse.
Blockhouse? Blockhouse?
This is Hauptmann Koenig.
Blockhouse, blockhouse,
will you answer. Corporal!
Your corporal is dead.
We're coming up to get you next.
Free Norway!
Harbor detachment? Harbor detachment?
Yes, this is the harbor detachment.
The Norwegian harbor detachment.
If you want a ride to England
with women and children, come.
We're saving a place for you.
Machine guns in woods east
and west of the hotel.
Rabble advances across the clearing,
wipe them out with crossfire.
Yes, sir.
- Is this is what you wanted?
Thank you.
Here's the rest of your instruments.
Martin? Martin?
Martin!
Martin, goodbye.
Goodbye.
The machine guns are placed, sir.
The enemy is heading this way.
Many of them.
Radio to Trondheim.
Tell them I want planes.
It means our radio is dead.
They'll never get beyond the clearing.
Machine guns on the flanks
will cut them down.
You don't know, didn't see them.
They kept coming and coming.
Check the east wing.
Attention!
Our outposts have been wiped out.
The radio is dead.
We are cut off from the outside.
If we succeed in holding this hotel
until 4:00...
...until the patrol plane
flies over Trollness...
...we'll be able to communicate
with the outside.
We'll get reinforcements.
We are German soldiers.
Soldiers of our führer.
These are rabble.
They must not win.
They cannot win.
- Heil, Hitler.
Heil, Hitler.
Leave me alone.
I want to make a speech
to the German army.
I have ordered you to your room.
To the invincible German army.
To the master race.
To the conquerors of the world.
To Hauptmann Koenig,
the father of the Koenig plan.
You are frightened.
You, remove the body,
then report down here.
You'll take care of wounded.
Now, remember,
as soon as you get out of the woods...
...spread out so you won't make
good targets.
Walk slowly.
Don't fire until they do, then charge.
We'll keep our surprises for them
until later.
We've gotta get this over with before
their 4:00 patrol plane checks the town.
Goodbye, Gunnar.
We've said goodbye before,
we're still alive.
Just in case when this is over one of us
is not around, the other gets to England.
Only women, children, and wounded
will get to England.
Your plan
was for the rest of us to follow them.
No, we stay here.
These fascists will never drive Norwegians
out of Norway.
Those of us who come out of this alive
will take to the hills.
Fight on from there
until we drive them out.
Corporal.
Hold your fire until I ordered it.
The crossfire from the machine guns
I've placed on our flanks must not fail.
Pick up their guns.
We need all they've got and more.
Why aren't they firing? Where are they?
Norwegians!
Go back!
It's a trap!
They've got machine guns
on both sides of you.
Gunnar, it's Johann.
JOHANN
Go back! Go back!
How can we trust him? Keep going.
Keep going.
It's a trap!
Go back! Believe me, I'm with you!
With you, believe me!
Osterholm.
Take some men, cover the woods
on the right. Lars, you cover the left.
Got to get behind the machine guns.
Do you understand?
The rest of us will charge
just as soon as we hear your fire.
Now I can talk.
You're dealing here with giants!
I tell you, giants!
Stop me from saying it now. Stop me.
"Go to hotel," she said.
"Start shooting," she said.
"We entered the town
of Trollness on October 28th, 1942.
Thorough investigation disclosed the fact
that no one was left alive on either side.
The former German garrison,
commanded by Hauptmann Koenig...
...evidently fought a battle of annihilation
with the people of Trollness."
Add this:
Hauptmann Koenig died a hero's death.
For the führer and the Reich.
The town of Trollness is once again
flying the German flag.
See anything?
One of their soldiers
is sending up the German flag.
It's all right, I can walk alone.
No, you don't have to.
If there is anyone who still
wonders why this war is being fought...
...let him look to Norway.
If there is anyone who has any delusions
that this war could have been averted...
...let him look to Norway.
And if there is anyone who doubts
of the democratic will to win...
...again I say, let him look to Norway.