THE FUHRER'S TABLE
MUNICH, NOVEMBER 8, 1939
We welcome our Fuhrer
with three cheers
- Sieg
- Heil!
I give the floor to the Fuhrer
Fellow party comrades!
Fellow Germans!
I have come to you
for only a few hours,
to evoke in your midst
the memory of a day
FOG! AIRPLANE UNABLE TO START!
which was of great importance for us,
for our movement,
and for the German people
If, during the four years
from 1919 to 1923,
the National Socialist Movement
was able to grow to such an extent
that it succeeded, for the first time,
in mobilising the entire nation
in a stirring event,
then this was due to the general state
Germany found itself in.
KONSTANZ, LAKE CONSTANCE
A terrible catastrophe
had befallen our country and our people.
What forced Germany to succumb
at the time
were the lies of our adversaries.
GERMAN-SWISS BORDER
The lies told by the same men
who are lying again today.
However, everyone must understand
that they are not sacrificing any more
than all the others
sacrificed before them
We are also aware
of how much
destiny has assisted us
and enabled us to do so much.
It let us forge our plans in the right way
and blessed their successful outcome.
Hello!
Where are you going?
I'm looking for an old friend
Feuchtelhuber
of the Konstanz Folklore Society
I used to be a member there
None of us know
whether they will suffer
What our women sacrifice
to bear the nation's children,
our men sacrifice
by defending the country
We National Socialists
have always been fighters
Now the great moment has come
to prove ourselves as fighters
No one but us can be victorious.
That Mr. Churchill doesn't think so,
I shall put down to his old age.
Others didn't believe it either.
They will be told by Churchill,
by Chamberlain...
Why are you wearing that badge?
Out of support
The Red Front
is an illegal organisation
...if we hadn't been
drawn into it by England.
England boosted its power
through agitation and incitement.
REICH SECURITY MAIN OFFICE
Heinrich, I'd like to join
my wife at the opera
The Reichsfuhrer wants our new figures
submitted to him
for the big meeting tomorrow
What's complicated
about listing all detained lunatics?
The clerical task isn't complicated
But we need to decide
whether to include church institutions
No exceptions
This reflects the Reichsfuhrer's wishes
The priests will make a fuss
They'll calm down again
I'd propose to Himmler
that we proceed step by step
First
Not now, Bauer!
An attempt on the Fuhrer's life in Munich
A bomb
Half the roof is said to have caved in
First MG squad, take position!
Second MG squad, take position!
Alight!
Move!
- Move!
- Line formation!
Line up!
- Here's the list
- Thank you
Heil Hitler!
My name is Eberle,
I'm the Local Party Leader here
At your service
Heil Hitler
All relatives of one Georg Elser,
last known address Turkenstrase 59
in Munich, to report to the square
What has Georgie done?
You instruct my men
But the Elsers are harmless
That's an order!
Yes, sir!
Is this the lot of them?
Yes, Major,
including his former fiancee,
Elsa Stephan
The whole lot to Berlin for questioning!
Come!
How dare you?
- Let go!
- Don't, Elsa, or they'll take them, too
I'll bring them to your mother
These are the corrected lunatic asylum
statistics that we're re-submitting
- Including the church ones?
- Yes The gentlemen are waiting
Gentlemen, we cannot afford
to make a mistake now,
not even the slightest
Halt!
Heil Hitler, Mr Elser
Heil Hitler
Good day
Or good day, if you prefer that
My name is Nebe
Head of Criminal Police
I'm in charge of your case
This is the head of the Gestapo,
Oberfuhrer Muller
Elser
How do you think
your wicked assassination attempt ended?
We mourn the death of seven innocent
people for which you are responsible
Seven men and women,
including a waitress,
married with two children
A marching band flautist, leaving behind
a wife and teenage daughter
What did these people do to you?
Who gave you the right to kill them?
Don't you have anything to say
to the relatives?
Not a single word?
Do you think the Fuhrer is dead?
You think you succeeded?
The Fuhrer is alive
He left the Burgerbraukeller
13 minutes before the explosion
Your assassination attempt failed
You were carrying bomb schematics
when you were arrested
You spent a lot of time
at the Burgerbraukeller
Take off your trousers
I want to see your knees
Off with your trousers!
Elser
I'm now giving you your only chance
to own up to everything
You think you know everything already
Shoot me and get it over with
We're not there yet by a long way
Let's start right at the beginning
Name? Date of birth?
KONSTANZ, LAKE CONSTANCE 1932
Where we gather
Under the linden trees
A t eventide
Where we gather
Under the linden trees
A t eventide
Many hours we've spent here together
Sitting in a...
You know you'll have to make up
for your attack
Do you love me?
You never commit, do you?
You know I like spending time with you
And what about Bruni?
Nothing She's having fun too
I'll leave if you want
Are you crazy?
I hope no one died
That stupid old drunkard
Your father? Is he dead?
He sold another two fields,
our best land
Now I'm supposed
to sort things out at home
The Messerschmitt is worth two
Georgie Elser is back
- Hi, Lore How's the leg?
- Same as always
Will you stay with your folks now?
Looks like it
They need you urgently
You have to register within 48 hours,
that's now the law
I won't stay longer than four weeks
- Still
- All you can think of is supervising
Hi, Elmar
My dad says
Lore shouldn't act like a big shot,
she's with a Jew from Heidenheim
Who turned you
into a moron all of a sudden?
There, you better
give me a hand with this
Good day
Are there soldiers
at the Konstanz border crossing?
Customs officers, that's enough
What's in the box? Show me
There's no show today
Mother?
Georg
At last
Come here, my boy
- Thank you for coming
- Where is he?
Come on, no stopping
Leave the cider alone
Damn it!
Keep the blade straight!
If I'm supposed to help you,
stop the boozing
You little shit!
That cider was expensive!
I never booze and I'm still alive
I don't like repeating myself
Name? Date of birth?
Name?
Date of birth?
Name? Date of birth?
Again:
Kiss my ass
I can't hear you
Kiss my ass!
Send this to Baumann I want him
to order this weed killer from IG Farben
Very well, Oberfuhrer
I know this breed from the Swabian Hills
They'd rather
be beaten to death than give in
Shall I tell this to the Reichsfuhrer SS?
There's this breed
from the Swabian Hills
That guy is merely a puppet
Just look at his physiognomy,
his eyes
He's not some naive idiot
The man knows what he wants
He may be a country boy, but he's
not lacking ideological conviction
And the evidence is overwhelming
The Fuhrer doesn't want evidence,
he wants a written confession
Goebbels needs it for the press
I'll pull out every one of his teeth
to make him sign if I have to
You saw that he won't budge
Are you telling me
how to do my job now?
Your lot should have
known about this sooner
Now where is that list
of the arrested relatives?
I'm asking myself how an ethnic German
can hate our Fuhrer so much
to carry out such a despicable attack
And on November 8th, of all days
Now look who's joining us, Elser
Come in!
Evening all
- Ernst, a beer and a kirsch!
- Beer and a kirsch, coming up
No Erich has had enough
Two orange sodas, please
What's it going to be, Erich?
Soda or the usual?
The usual, you dumbass!
Thank you
Shall we get some fresh air?
That's Elsa
She's married
Those are the best ones
This seat is taken, Eberle
We found another dead hare
in a sling today
In the woods, near the ltzeIsberg
- That's above my field
- Piss off, Eberle
I'll give you a good kicking
if the poaching doesn't stop
The dance is called a tango
It's from South America
It's very close, almost sinful
Watch
One
One, two, tango step
One, two
Something like that
I'm Georgie Elser
You're Elsa, aren't you?
I'm going back to my Erich
Hans, a round, time to celebrate!
So, what was the percentage?
The NSDAP is the biggest party
in the Reichstag with 44%
Come, Lore Let's go
The Reds lost
What do you say now?
There you go
- Come on, let's go
- No, I'll finish my drink
There you go
To our Fuhrer Sieg Heil!
Sieg Heil! Sieg Heil!
- Quiet, we're playing cards!
- Hang on
We'll have no shouting here
- Who's shouting here?
- Calm down
Stay calm
Calm down Let's stay calm
Schurr, you'll be the first
to be strung up once we seize power
And you'll be shot after the revolution
Idiots
You've been to Konstanz
and Switzerland?
- Yes
- Did you go to the cinema there?
I saw a picture of Jacqueline Wells
in a magazine
She's so beautiful
in "Tarzan the Fearless"
They say she's wearing
hardly anything in that film
That would interest you, of course
Just die, you bastards!
Sons of bitches!
Why did you leave?
You've been fighting
with the Nazis for years For what?
Musician! Go home and pray
Dirty pacifist!
- So what?
- Shut up!
You're a coward?
Yes, maybe I am a coward,
because violence
has never achieved anything
Elser, now tell your girl here
why you did this
Did you do this, Georg?
Elsa
Take her away
Where are they taking her?
That's entirely up to you
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come Thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses, as we
forgive those who trespass against us,
and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil
For thine is the kingdom,
and the power, and the glory,
for ever and ever
Amen
- Elsa
- Yes?
She has nothing to do with this
Will you guarantee
she won't be harmed?
She's not important to us
if we have a confession from you
If not, it's a different matter
My word as an officer
That means nothing to me
I can't offer more
All right then It was me
My name is Elser, Johann Georg
Born 4th January, 1903
Let's begin
Party membership?
None
And this?
My Red Front badge
But I was never
a Communist Party member
- Red Front
Good that you're with us
WORKERS VOTE KPD
- Josef!
- What?
The H
- The H
- Shit!
- Add it!
- Or the Browns will say we're idiots
- Come on!
Watch out!
Shit!
Stop! Halt!
Site security!
"I joined the Konstanz
Folklore Society"
Just for the companionship?
I didn't join to pick up girls
You can meet girls anywhere
And before you ask, I wasn't close
to any girl from the society
Of course there was the occasional
Why don't you just admit
you're a communist?
No, I thought it was enough to vote KPD
I'm sure you were involved
in demonstrations, handing out flyers
No I didn't even attend meetings
It's highly unlikely an apolitical person
would plan and carry out
an attack on such a huge scale
I was a free human being
Meaning?
You have to do what's right
If humanity isn't free,
everything dies with it
Am I allowed to write one last letter?
Please, just a few lines
to my fiancee and my mother
Take him away
MUNICH ASSASSIN CAPTURED
ASSASSIN CAPTURED
That small-time carpenter is trying to
hoodwink us, claiming he acted alone
Just one man can't construct
such a powerful bomb
Elser insists he carried out
the attack on his own
- There's no evidence
- We won't let criminals call us liars!
The Fuhrer wants us to get him to talk
by any means necessary
He must say who's behind it
Obergruppenfuhrer, it's becoming clear
no one else is pulling the strings here
You might trigger the Fuhrer's reaction
for being soft and failing when it counts
We don't believe a word of it
What?
"For 30 nights, I waited until I got
locked in to the Burgerbraukeller
"I wrapped a rag around
the rear part of the drill
"I benefited from the lavatories
automatically flushing every 10 minutes
"I used the sound to conceal my work,
then waited another 10 minutes
for the flushing to start again "
Correct
A lowly craftsman like you
couldn't build a bomb like that
Who supplied your material?
For the last time,
who were you working for?
All right, I'll tell you
We only have two telephones
in the village
Churchill called me at the dairy
The mayor's office
would have been a bad idea
Churchill called and said,
"Elser, build a bomb to blow up Hitler
for me, we can't do it on our own "
I can't tell you what didn't happen
Just give me pen and paper
and I'll prove it to you!
18, 20
I'm out
- Three
- I'm out
I'll go for diamonds if you don't mind
- Heil Hitler, everyone
- Heil Hitler
Hi
Ah, I see, voluntary disbanding
Very sensible
But if you think that the strike fund
will disappear with you,
you've got another thing coming
Listen up, national comrades
How about attending
the Gauleiter's rally in Heidenheim later
instead of playing cards at the pub?
Heil Hitler and good day
- Heil Hitler
- Good day
Ernst, the usual combo
Coming up
Tell your Gauleiter
there was another hare caught in a sling
You can do whatever you like
But don't complain if it hurts
That was Elsa
But let me tell you, Eberle,
she won't talk back any time soon
Elsa?
- Elsa?
- Leave me alone
- Why?
- I don't want you to see me like this
What about Erich?
He'll get drunk at the pub
The children are asleep
You
It's different with you
Do you know that?
When will you be going back
to Konstanz?
If the instrument maker pays
for the maple wood, we could make it
Yes, Georg, God willing
If not, the marshals
will come take our house away
Where do we go then?
I don't know
I might move in with Elsa
You shouldn't fool around
with married women
There's no fooling around
Erich is asking for a lodger
because he's hard up
You're not fooling me
No one around here has any money
You want to be near that woman
She has a bastard child and you too
Don't get carried away, mother
I'm a bastard myself
But your father married me
Elsa made her daughter
legitimate too So what?
You left Mathilde with your child
Is that the done thing?
I don't care what the done thing is
If two people aren't right together,
it's misery
Just look at you and father
You'll see what this leads to,
always doing exactly the opposite
of God's plan
Where else could they be?
We'll find them, don't you worry
- Halt! Gruppenfuhrer, you'll go there!
- Yes, sir!
Georg, I need your help
Eberle is after me
Why?
After their last rally,
the Nazis arrested all party members
Come in
- I knew I'd find you here
- Put your hands up
What have we here?
We only have orders
to go after party members,
but soon it'll be the rest
of your Bolshevik scum
Take him away
What do you think you're doing?
Is he one of them too?
He's just a big-mouthed musician
Go inside
This is none of your business
All right, then Let's go
WITH THE STURMER AGAINST JUDAH
HARVEST FESTIVAL 1934
Flim-fum, church scum
The Fuhrer blows up the churches
And all the priests will be strung up
Like your saviour on the cross
Flim-fum, church scum
Beat it, you dirty scoundrels!
Leave it, Leonhard!
Now they're even blasting things
on the Lord's day
OK? Well, go on
Hello, hello
Stand closer together
NSDAP CINEMA
SHOWING THE SHEPHERDS' RUN
- Alfred!
- Eberle!
Good that you could make it
Have you eaten?
When does it start?
It's about to start
Listen up, everyone! The screening
will start in five minutes' time
First come, first served
Let's go then
One after another
Like a farmer eating dumplings
No, no, Elmar
You have to get in line too
Leonhard
We saved you a space
I took part in the Shepherds' Run
Maybe I'm in the film
There's free beer and a sausage stew
We only have turnip at home,
but we're decent people
So?
You'll have to decide, son
National comrades, I'll keep it short
I know you're more excited about the film
than Eberle's speech
However, today
we witness once again
how the Fuhrer brings us
technological progress
Even the most remote parts
of the German Reich
will see wealth and comfort
That's right Bravo!
Within three years,
we will all have our own radio set,
connecting us to modern times
I promise you,
all of the village's streets
will be paved and lit
This is progress
This is our Fuhrer, Adolf Hitler
- Sieg
- Heil!
And now, our wonderful Shepherds' Run
as a motion picture
Please
Georgie
You're lucky you can still
move freely in the village
You claim to have organised
your own gunpowder plates
Where exactly did you get them from?
Before deciding
on the actual details of my plan,
I used my position at the steel works
to steal a total of 250 pieces
of pressed gunpowder
How do you know
it was exactly 250 pieces?
I counted them
Who else knew about this?
Nobody The theft was not
discovered by the company
I wrapped the powder in paper
and hid it in my wardrobe at home
And the dynamite?
I stole it from the quarry at night
What was the name of your boss?
I can't remember
I only met the man three or four times
If you don't talk,
they can have you shot,
any time, up there in the yard
It's true
I'm not covering up for anyone
Do you really think
we won't uncover everything?
No, Mr Nebe, I don't
That's why I'm
completely honest with you
And?
We inquire about a monumental attack
and the Swiss send this
"The proprietor describes Elser
as hard-working"
"It was noted he often left work
to go swimming in the afternoons"
"He more than made up
for the missing time in the evenings"
"We have no knowledge
of Elser's acquaintances"
Take your hands off your face!
Dot, dot, comma, swish,
makes a face round like a dish
What about the hair?
What about the ears?
Iris!
I found something!
The marshals will come on Monday
We'll have to leave our home
I sometimes wonder
how it would be with you
You and me together
You could play in an orchestra
Maybe in Switzerland
Or in America, they pay more there
Are you serious about me, Georgie?
This might be the first time
I'm serious about anyone
I'm pregnant again
Don't The children mustn't find out
They talk a lot at home
I think it's your child
But I haven't always been able
to fend off Erich
I prayed for the Lord to take the child,
regardless of whether it's yours or his
You mustn't say that, Elsa
Who will feed the child?
Why can't they let us be how we want?
You have to get a divorce
Am I supposed to move in with you,
now that they're taking your home?
Where will you live now?
Uncle! Mummy says
you'll sleep in our basement
I'm not your uncle I'm Georgie
Are you going to paint faces
and protect me from the bogeyman?
If he comes, I'll get my accordion
and play so terribly that he runs away
Mummy, Georgie is here
And, very important:
no female visitors Understood?
Your reputation isn't the best,
but I must protect mine
That's why I won't tolerate anything
So it's free board and lodging
until the furniture is finished,
and then 20 a month
Sign it
So this is it
There's a mattress in the other room
that you can have
I'll clean the window for you, Georgie
To make it brighter
My wife doesn't clean for lodgers
First we need to oil the hinges
If you can't pay
or you breach the contract,
you'll have to move out
- Understood?
- I'll always find work
Come on! Beat it!
I'M THE BIGGEST PIG AROUND
AS I MlX WITH JEWS IN TOWN
But, Lore
What's all this about?
You can join her if you like
Get lost!
It's not my birthday
I bet they wear this in Ulm,
or even in Stuttgart
You're crazy
Thank you
Shall I take it up like this?
Or maybe even shorter?
Shorter is nice
But don't wear it
when Erich's around
Don't worry, it's just for you
What's wrong?
They sat Lore in the square
with a sign round her neck
Because of her boyfriend?
Poor thing
But there's nothing we can do
It's getting worse and worse
Elsa
It's Schurr!
I can't be seen with people
Come on in Hurry
After the Heuberg concentration camp
they sent us to work at satellite camps
There was at least one death every week
- Where are you working now?
- At the steel works
I get out every two weeks for
good behaviour, but mustn't see anyone
Gosh!
And you? Out of work,
being at home at this time?
Self-employed
But it's hard, not being a Nazi
The steel works are hiring
But be careful
They toe the party line
There
You do realise we fed a camp inmate?
If the Gestapo come
I'll tell the pricks it's my bread
- I do what I want with it
- But you're living in our home
If the Gestapo come, we're all in for it
You didn't need
so many fuses to detonate the bomb
Correct I knew two or three
gunpowder plates would suffice
But I thought the extra ones
would increase the explosion
Why two clockworks in the bomb?
I didn't want to rely on just one
clockwork for my plan to succeed
Matching the 12 combs (B)
of cogwheel (A),
I was able to set each clock
with its run-time of 14 days
144 hours or 6 days in advance,
accurate within 15 minutes,
to the time of the explosion, 21:20,
and activate it
All of 13 minutes were missing
How did you build the detonator?
The block with the three inserted
and sharpened nails (N)
hits the bolt (U), on which it has been
loosely set, before the spring (
The tips (W) then hit
the cartridges opposite,
thus igniting through the impact
on the cartridge primers
the blasting caps Y,
inserted at a short distance from them
The charge detonates
And?
This ignition head requires
a pressure of 35 kilopond
The spring is set to 40 kilopond
Everything matches exactly
This Elser works intuitively
and very accurately
Everybody knows
you need pressure to detonate
Elser must have had instructions
Technically, he conceived and built
the bomb all on his own
If you know all the parameters,
you don't need any help or instructions
This man knows what he's talking about
10, 15, 20
Come here Get lost! Beat it!
You're hurting me
You're hurting me!
OUR GREETING:
"HEIL HITLER!"
Josef!
What's the big secret they're hiding?
I'm not sure yet, it might be
moulds for ignition heads
Do you think you can
earn your money talking?
Any contact with
the forced labourers is prohibited
Workers of the world, unite!
This is Radio Moscow in German
on 25m short-wave
On April26, 1937,
Adolf Hitler ordered his Condor Legion
to bomb the Spanish town of Guernica
Never before
has such a devastating attack
on a civilian target area
been witnessed
At least 260 people were shot,
torn to pieces or burned to death
Guernica's destruction is a violation of
international law and an important step
I've had it with this wretched scum
Why do they all follow this gangster?
They're the master race now
They think the Nazis make it better
Nothing's better
GERMAN TANKS
German domination in the air
is not just due to the outstanding
aviators of the Luftwaffe,
but also to the tremendous contributions
of the aviation industry
As Fuhrer and Chancellor
of the German nation and the Reich,
I hereby announce to German history
the accession of my homeland
to the German Reich
Sieg Heil!
JEWS NOT WELCOME
VILLAGE OF KONIGSBRONN
They want war
It'll be brutal
They're building tanks as piecework
Maybe it'll be like Bohemia and Moravia
With Hitler attacking
England and France?
We'll all die and the country with us
I'm a forced labourer, Georgie
We really ought to do something
But what?
Blow up the Special Unit?
That would only mean dead workers
and the Nazis would carry on
We have to do something else,
and soon
Soon and radical
Attack the leadership
You'll need guns or dynamite
There's dynamite up in the quarry
and detonators here in the factory
- Someone has to stop this madness
- Yes, but not you or me or us
Hitler must be stopped
by other countries, by generals
We're not strong enough, Georg
We can't wait till it's too late
It has to happen
What's wrong?
I can't stand you
doing it with this drunkard
There's nothing I can do
You filthy whore!
You slut!
Just one more, you swine,
just one more
I'll kill you
I'll kill you, both of you
Both of you
Elsa?
How's the child?
- It's kicking
- Thank God
What happens now?
This here is over
Just come with me
Where to? To your mother?
So we all go to heaven?
There's no room for me there
I now work piece rate
It's better money
It'll be enough
if I repair furniture on the side
There are cheap flats
in Heidenheim now
Only for Labour Front workers
Not for you
BURGERBRAU ADDRESS
THE FUHRER SPEAKS!
THE FUHRER SPEAKS
TIMETABLE
MUNICH 1938
We've checked everything
A talented worker such as yourself
should be a staunch National Socialist
It's obvious that the Nazis
don't support the people
Today, a carpenter's hourly wage
is 68 Pfennigs
In 1929 it was 1 Mark and 5
You're not trying to tell us that our
Fuhrer isn't looking after workers
Hitler is bad for Germany
- Have you gone completely insane?
- It's true though
He's sending dissenters
to concentration camps
And the Jews are being robbed and
tortured just because of their faith
To cleanse the population
Your blitzkrieg was a brutal attack
Poland will be annihilated,
Hitler will incorporate it
That's the law of the strongest
It's always been like this
Do you really think
there'll be no consequences?
France and England
declared war on us on September 3rd
Soon, a terrible fire will steamroll
Germany and destroy everything
Endless amounts of blood will be shed
Then the bombs will drop on us, too
Can't you see what's happening?
You're suffering from paranoia
And what about the victims?
Hitler always talks about destiny
So you National Socialists, too,
must have a higher law
And it states, "thou shalt not kill"
That's rich, coming from someone
who murdered eight innocent people
Yes, you heard right
Last night,
the injured Schmeidel died as well
I only wanted to prevent
even more bloodshed
I knew it would not just hit
the highest ranks
But it had to be done
All right, take this down
The considerations I undertook
led to the conclusion
that conditions in Germany
could only be changed by extinguishing
the current leadership
I said the highest ranks
Very well, the highest ranks, then
By this, I mean
By this, I mean Hitler
and all the government
I am the sole perpetrator
I procured the necessary means
for the attack on my own
I was working entirely alone
Correct
And, funnily enough,
nobody would have joined me
You will regret this, Elser
Miss Secretary,
may I ask you something?
You're not allowed
I know you're not wholly unmoved
Please
I would be grateful if you could
pass on my condolences to the relatives,
my heartfelt condolences
I think about them all day
And, if possible, tell Elsa and my family
that I'm well at the moment
And that I'm praying
for the Lord to protect them
And that I accept
sole responsibility for everything
Could you pass that on, please?
You can't get any more out of him
than the truth
We make the truth
You're not normally so soft
It's from the file Put it away
You didn't get it from me
That'll do for today
Take him away
Thank you
And, what did you have, a boy?
A boy He's ours
I can see it
I already told Erich
he'll be called Georg
He was shouting
But I signed the midwife's certificate
- You get some rest now
- Stay
Erich has gone drinking
I have to get to work, Elsa
The prisoner to the left, please,
with the gentlemen at the table
The Oberfuhrer on the left, please
If the prisoner could point
to the schematic, please
And if the Oberfuhrer
could bend down a little, please
You stated the Fuhrer was bad
for Germany
That's right
Heil Hitler! Heil the Fuhrer!
Our Fuhrer made Germany great
and will lead us on to glory
He is the greatest leader
and won't die until our destiny is fulfilled
What is a worm like you
to do with such a man?
What lunatic has controlled you,
you imbecile?
It's like I said
The Fuhrer demands to know
who instigated this fool to act
Have him hypnotised,
drug him, I don't care
Use any means that our scientists
have been working on
The Fuhrer wants to know who set it up
He wants to know who's behind this
His patience has run out
I could stay with my mother
for a while after the divorce
What do you think?
She'll have the children
There's work in Esslingen
You can come down
from Munich on weekends
I must know
if you really want this, Georgie
I love you
Elsa
The boy
Georgie!
Georgie
So you're off to Munich
Without a goodbye, just like that
Don't move
So you do have something in Munich
And it's decided?
It's just for a short while
I love you, Georgie,
but I have no choice
I can take a lot,
but the children are hungry
I'd give you money,
but I need it for Munich
Elsa, wait for me. Be faithful to me
I've got something planned
I can't tell you what,
but it's vital, and it'll be fine
I want to marry you when it's all over
We'll move to Switzerland
with the children
Think of the dancing
It's not about dreams
It's about life, Georgie
I know you left women before me
Then I'll just have to be
a single mother forever
I can't hear what you're saying
Tell us the names
The names
No
The name!
Who provided the cartridges?
Who supplied the explosives?
I can't hear you
You bastard!
The names, Elser! Tell us the names!
Heil! Heil! Heil!
I did it on my own
Nobody helped me
I shall try and atone
for the bad things that I have done
By doing what?
And how?
By trying to
By trying to integrate myself into
the national community
and work within it
Would you be able to?
I changed my conviction
Because you were arrested
No
I'm certain
my plan would have succeeded,
if my conviction had been right
Since it hasn't succeeded,
I'm convinced
it wasn't meant to succeed
and that my conviction was wrong
Take him away
Can I see a priest?
No
5 YEARS LATER
SPRING 1945
BERLIN,
PLOTZENSEE EXECUTION SITE
"The First Senate of the People's Court
ruled on March 2nd, 1945:
"The former SS Gruppenfuhrer and
Lieutenant General of Police Arthur Nebe
is of thoroughly flawed character"
"He took part
in the conspiracy of July 20th
"He supported
the attempt on the Fuhrer's life,
and was willing to assist the coup
by providing police personnel"
"He is sentenced to death for high treason
and will forever be without honour
"His estate will go to the Reich "
SPECIAL OCCURRENCES:
NONE
DACHAU CONCENTRATION CAMP
SPECIAL PRISONER WARD
Nebe was executed a few days ago
Did you hear me? Nebe's dead
At Plotzensee
- How do you know?
- From the new inmates, as usual
They strung up Nebe? Why?
He designated policemen for Stauffenberg
to arrest all ministers after the coup
So much for the great show trial
that Goebbels wanted to put on for you
It'll soon be over for me, too
At least you got
a few more years out of them
If only I knew what happened to Elsa
You keep asking about that woman
How should I know?
With so many people dying
She's not necessarily dead
She might be alive,
imprisoned somewhere
There's also good news
The College of Music for the Disabled
has accepted me
I'll learn how to sing now
Viennese songs for zither
As a little thank-you for recommending
I try the College of Music
You were young
I was young
Now it's all gone
Only the memories
Are all that carries on
You were pretty
I was smart
And so in love
Think back to the places
To the sweetest faces
Just because there 's nothing
you can place above
Franz, you know about these things
What's quicker:
gas, hanging,
or being shot in the neck?
I've been waiting for so long
It might as well be over quickly
hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come
Thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses
The English reduced Dresden to rubble
Not one building is left standing
One hundred thousand civilians
killed in one night
For thine is the kingdom
Praying is pointless
God is in America or in Moscow
He won't hear you
How can one man fail as horribly as I?
Prisoner Elser,
for interrogation!
During one of the next terror attacks
on Munich or the Dachau area,
Elser will allegedly
suffer a fatal accident
I therefore ask you to secretly liquidate
Elser when this situation arises
Make sure that only very few specially
selected personnel know about this
The incident report filed to me
should read along the lines of:
"On ( ), following
the terror attack on ( ),
"special prisoner Elser,
among others, was fatally injured "
You must destroy this letter once
you have taken note and carried this out
A FEW DAYS LATER,
ON APRIL 29, 1945,
THE DACHAU CONCENTRATION CAMP
WAS LIBERATED
STARTED BY HITLER,
THE SECOND WORLD WAR
CLAIMED AT LEAST 55 MILLION LIVES
IT TOOK DECADES FOR GERMANY
TO RECOGNISE GEORG ELSER
AS A RESISTANCE FIGHTER
FOLLOWING HER DIVORCE,
ELSA WAS MARRIED
TWO MORE TIMES
SHE DIED IN WIESENSTEIG
ON OCTOBER 11, 1994
SHE NEVER GOT OVER GEORG ELSER,
THE LOVE OF HER LIFE
13 MINUTES
THIS FILM WAS BASED
ON HISTORICAL EVENTS
SOME SCENES FROM
GEORG ELSER'S PERSONAL LIFE
WERE FICTIONALISED