Akelei. Akelei.
Claire?
- Move up.
- Thank you.
Roast mules go topsy-turvy.
Ten letters ending in "T."
- I'm hopeless at this.
- Me too.
"Somersault. "
Bletchley.
It's a walk.
I know.
I've been here before.
This bus for Yardley--
This bus for--
Hello? Yes.
I'll try that extension for you.
Please hold the line.
I'm just putting you through.
Yes, you're through.
- Mr Skynner?
- Come in.
It's been a pleasure, sir.
I never wanted you back.
Logie says he needs you.
Well...
he's got you.
Conference in half an hour.
And keep your mouth shut.
You're only there for show.
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
You do look bloody terrible.
- We missed you, Tom.
- I know why you want me back, Guy.
You've lost the crown jewels,
haven't you? You've lost Shark.
We got a call from one of the
intercept stations in Scarborough.
And they started picking up a single
word broadcast on the hour, every hour...
coming out of U-boat headquarters
in Sainte-Assise.
- In Morse?
- No, it was a human voice.
- "Akelei. "
- Meaning what?
- It's a flower.
- I know it's a bloody flower, Guy.
Aquilegia. Columbine.
But what did it mean?
It meant,
"Change the weather code. "
The Germans have switched their U-boats to
a new code book, and we're blacked out again.
Is that why the Yanks are here?
Skynner's in a panic.
They want to take over his empire.
Here comes our team.
- You! You!
- Hello.
- You in the Royal Navy?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Only for a day or two. I mean, actually on a ship.
- What was your ship?
Look, I can't be expected
to remember every little thing.
Sorry.
Welcome to Bletchley Park, sir.
Three convoys left New York
in the past week...
and are presently at sea.
Convoy SC 122.
Fifty merchant ships
carrying fuel oil, tanks...
iron ore, bauxite,
also meat, sugar and wheat.
Convoy HX 229 departed
New York on Monday.
Forty merchant vessels
carrying explosives, manganese...
timber, powdered milk.
Convoy 229-A left New York
on Tuesday...
carrying steel, timber,
powdered milk.
I don't want a shopping list.
What's the total?
One hundred and forty-one merchant ships,
gross tonnage just under a million tons.
- Plus cargo of another million.
- And where are the U-boats?
A submarine tracking rumour
had three U-boat packs operational...
in the North Atlantic
as of 00 hundred Thursday...
here, here and here.
Midnight Wednesday?
- So where are the U-boats now?
- I'm afraid I have no idea.
I thought that was why we were here.
Our intelligence has been shut off.
You're telling us that the largest
assembly of merchant shipping...
we've ever sent
across the North Atlantic...
is now steaming towards
the largest concentration of U-boats...
the Germans have ever put
in the North Atlantic...
and you don't know where the hell
the goddam U-boats are?
- Gentlemen, if I may--
- Shut up.
What are our convoys making, hmm?
Something over 220 miles a day.
Well, I'd say we have
four days, maximum...
before the convoys come in operational
range of where you last had the enemy.
So, Leonard, this blackout--
will it be over in four days?
Uh, it's possible.
Yes, well, all things are possible,
Leonard, but is it likely?
Is it likely that you can break this
code, this, um-- What'd you call this?
This Shark? Before our convoys come
in range of the U-boats.
- We'll give it every priority.
- Yes, I know damn well you'll give it every priority, Leonard.
- That's not the question.
- Well, sir, as you press me, yes, I think we may be able to do it.
Is that what you all believe?
Um, well, I suppose you could say we know more
about Shark now than we did the last time.
If Guy thinks we can do it,
I would certainly respect his opinion.
And you?
You don't seem
to have much to say.
Tom Jericho. He's the one who got us into
reading Shark. If there’s anyone alive--
Can you break Shark again
in four days?
Have you any idea
what you’re talking about?
Tom's been on sick leave for the last month,
so I don't think he's fully in the picture--
Enigma is a very sophisticated
enciphering machine...
and Shark
is its ultimate refinement...
so we're not talking
about The Times' crossword.
It weighs 26 pounds,
battery included...
and goes anywhere.
The Enigma machine.
The Germans have thousands of them.
What's it do?
It turns plain-text messages
into gobbledygook.
Then the gobbledygook
gets transmitted in Morse.
At the receiving end, there's another Enigma
machine to turn it back into the original message.
Press the same key any number of times,
it will always come out different.
- And you have one of your own.
- Courtesy of the Polish Cipher Bureau.
So what's the problem?
Problem?
The problem is the machine has 115 million
million million ways of doing it...
according to how you set these three
rotors and how you connect these plugs.
And that's Shark.
No. No, no, no.
This is the one we can break.
Shark is enciphered on a machine with a fourth
rotor specially developed for U-boats...
which gives it about 4, 000 million
billion different starting positions.
And, uh, we've never seen one.
Holy shit!
I haven't understood a word.
Can somebody give me a straight answer
to a straight question?
- Will this blackout definitely be over in--
- Nobody can say definitely, sir.
Yes or no?
- No.
- Thank you.
So it isn't over in four days.
When will it be over, hmm?
Hmm? Hmm? You.
Well, all I have to measure it by is how long
it took last time when Shark first came in.
- And how long did it take?
- Ten months.
Well, this is a great day
for Adolf Hitler.
Ten months?
But you did break it?
Yes.
- How?
- I'm afraid I can't tell you that.
I think it's time we--
I think it's time
I got back to London.
It's not just a million tons of shipping.
It's a million tons of shipping every week!
It's our capability to supply Russia,
to support the army in North Africa...
to invade Europe
and drive the Germans out.
- It's the whole fucking war.
- Sir.
Satisfied? Now, send the stupid bugger
back to where he came from.
Don't waste a match.
Back to Mayfair?
No.
How many people knew
about the German weather code...
how important it was to us?
A dozen, maybe. Why?
Make me a little list?
What are you doing here,
Mr Wigram?
You think there's a spy
in Bletchley Park?
I'm Cave.
Naval Intelligence.
I'll be liaising with the admiralty.
They've given me an office in your hut.
I'm ultra-cleared.
- What does that mean?
- That means I know how you broke Shark, in principle.
You used a captured copy
of the German Navy's weather code book.
Gave you a pretty good idea of what their
weather signals were supposed to be saying.
Can I see it?
Midnight, two days ago,
the Germans changed to a new book.
- So we lost that crib.
- Well, why do you think they did that just then?
Don't know.
And the other one?
Short signal code book.
The U-boats employ it for reporting
their position, course and speed.
Unfortunately, if you don't know where
the U-boat is or what it's doing...
the short signal code book
isn't much help as a crib.
Two men died
saving those little books...
from a sinking submarine.
Fasson and Grazier.
We caught the U-boat
on the surface in the eastern Med.
The sub went down when they were inside
trying to bring out its four-rotor Enigma.
November '42.
I was in destroyers.
It was my last ship.
Bletchley is the lucky number
in this war.
- One and six, please.
- One and six.
Here you are.
Girls, guess I'm off.
- See you later.
- Yes, I'll see you later.
Miss Wallace?
Mr Jericho.
When did you get back?
Just today.
How, uh-- How are you?
How am I?
Yeah, all right.
How is she?
She's-- She's Claire.
- Well, will you tell her?
- If I see her.
She hasn't been sleeping
at home the last two nights.
Sorry.
Good morning, sir.
- Worrying about your babies?
- Puck.
Thomas.
So, they say you’re
not crazy any more.
- It thinks it's found a possible.
- "It thinks"?
- Why not?
- Been in the hut?
- Come on. Get it over with.
- No, I'm fine, Puck.
Sure, you are.
Hey, Betty, wait for me!
Gentlemen, we have a ghost.
Tom, how the hell are you?
- Well. Very well.
- Have you escaped, or what?
- I thought this was the asylum.
- How are you?
- Good.
- Bloody hell!
- How's the revolution, Alec?
- Coming along, comrade. Coming along.
- T-- T-- T--
- Yes, it's me.
I, uh-- I want to see all the Shark
traffic we haven't been able to break.
- In at the deep end.
- Why not?
- Yes, why not?
- Have you got yesterday's Porpoises?
Open the file.
Besides, it wasn't really Shark
that made you crazy.
Was it, Tom?
I suppose you all know.
You think I made a fool of myself?
Forget about it.
You're among friends.
So, what about the code breakers?
King come, De Brooke,
Upjohn, Pukowski.
- Spot the odd one out.
- Puck lost his parents when Poland was invaded.
His kid brother is missing in action.
He hates the Germans.
Pinker?
Bit of an arty, isn't he?
He writes detective stories.
Baxter. They say he sleeps with
a picture of Stalin under his pillow.
Perhaps you haven't heard.
Stalin's on our side now.
- And Jericho. The famous Mr Jericho.
- Mathematician.
Went off his trolley, didn't he?
About some girl.
We took him out of Cambridge
on the first day of the war.
He worked himself into a breakdown, so we
shipped him back to Cambridge to get well.
And that's all there is to it.
It's never all there is
to anything.
Shift's not over yet, ladies!
The 3:00's from Beaumanor
all need blisting.
You know, without your glasses,
you don't look half bad.
Do you know, without my glasses,
nor do you?
Claire?
I'm here.
Sorry it took an age.
Well, now you know where I am.
It's, um, off the beaten track.
Yes, well, it's better
than being snooped on by landladies.
Welfare found out I had a spare room,
so I had to share.
But Hester's a sweetie, really. Oh, there's
no sugar, I'm afraid, but it's lapsang.
And I always think sugar would
rather spoil lapsang, don’t you?
Don't know.
You're my first lapsang.
I knew you’d ask me out.
- I thought you asked me out.
- Well, I had to get you started. Aren't there any pretty girls in Hut 8?
- How do you know where I work?
- We've got an interesting men tracking room in Hut 3.
- You're not supposed to tell me where you--
- Besides, you're rumoured to have done something very clever...
and I want to know what it is.
Oh, my God.
Where did they find you?
Oh, where did they find any of us?
I'm the lucky one.
You know, they've got perfectly clever
girls working like post office clerks.
Not like me
on the German book.
I want that for my scrapbook.
- Can I see it?
- If you want. It's upstairs.
That's Hester.
And this is me.
You've been busy.
- Where is this?
- Loch Feochan, in Scotland, where I'd like to be old.
If I'm ever old.
Do you think it's beautiful?
Why are you a mathematician?
Do you like sums?
I like numbers.
Because with numbers,
truth and beauty are the same thing.
You know you’re getting somewhere
when the equations start looking...
beautiful.
And you know the numbers are taking you
closer to the secret of how things are.
A rose is just plain text.
My God.
What have you done?
What has she done?
- Mr Jericho?
- Miss Wallace.
I came looking for Claire.
I was worried about her.
I could fill a bus with men
who are worried about Claire Romilly...
but that's no reason why
I shouldn't go to the police.
She'd be the first person
they'd arrest.
Miss Wallace,
please put that poker down.
And if you know where she is,
for God's sake, tell me.
She's gone missing.
What are those, exactly?
Intercepts. German signals.
Yes, I know that much.
Five- letter groups. German Navy signals
are sent in four-letter groups.
So this must be army
or Luftwaffe.
Picked up by the radio scanners
at Beaumanor.
All sent between 9:30 and midnight
on April 17, nine days ago.
- But never deciphered.
- How do you know that?
Well, if it'd gone through the machine,
then plain text would be stuck on the back.
All from the same source.
"ADU. ADU. "
Does the call sign ADU
mean anything to you, Miss Wallace?
Miss Wallace?
"Angels Dance Upwards. "
- What?
- Well, that's how we'd reference it.
- Who is it? Who is ADU?
- I don't know.
But you could find out.
Do you have any idea
what you’re saying?
We can't just go digging through Bletchley looking
for information about missing cryptograms.
If we want to find Claire, then we need
to find out what she was hiding.
- You think Claire is a traitor.
- Would it matter if she were?
Of course it matters.
Look...
she was probably flirting with an officer
and forgot to file those intercepts...
so she hid them
rather than get told off.
Or she stole them
and then she ran away.
You really are mad,
aren't you?
And I would have to be even madder to have any
part in this little amateur sleuthing adventure.
Miss Wallace.
Miss Wallace!
You said yourself
that she was missing.
Now, is that normal?
Is that her habit?
Well, she does always come home
to change her clothes.
Well, there you are.
Is she seeing anyone,
do you know?
What exactly is your interest here?
You can reach me at Armstrong's
Guest House in Albion Street.
ADU, Miss Wallace.
Angels Dance Upwards.
# They call it Black Bottom
the new twister #
# It's sure got 'em
and, oh, sister #
# They clap their hands
and do a raggedy flop
and hop #
# Old fellows
with lumbago #
# And high yellow
The waves they go #
# They jump right in
and give us all that they've got #
# They say that when that river bottom's
covered with ooze #
You silly, silly girl.
These people keep
such funny hours.
I haven't heard--
Oh, Mr Jericho!
You have a visitor.
You can have the parlour.
We don't have guests
in the bedrooms after 10:00.
Oh, Mrs Armstrong, it's perfectly
sweet of you to worry...
but I don't mind taking
the risk just this once.
Well, I suppose it's all right
if you’re from the park.
Mr Wigram, would you care
for a cup of Ovaltine?
Ovaltine?
I haven't had Ovaltine since--
no, no--
Ovaltine. Thank you.
I don't think my system could take it.
What a charming house.
And hunting prints.
Do you hunt?
Where are you based?
Here?
Bliss.
What can I do for you,
Mr, um, Wigram?
There's something
I've been wondering about.
You're the man
who broke the U-boat code.
Hmm?
Champagne all around.
Happy days are here again,
all right?
Then you fell out of your pram.
So what happened?
It was personal.
I can keep a secret.
Wonderful thing about war--
Peacetime is about keeping
the people in their place.
But then war breaks out,
and life was never so glorious.
The toiling masses
turn into heroes...
and their little women start dropping
their drawers like debutantes.
- Well, if that’s all you--
- And best of all, the swots.
Dragged out in a cloud of dandruff
from some dim backwater...
and invited to the ball.
At Bletchley, you're as glamorous
as fighter pilots.
Girls you couldn't even hope to meet
go weak at the knees...
at the thought of the size
of your brain, isn't that right?
If talking through your arse
is what they teach you in spy school--
I'm talking about you
and a girl called Claire Romilly.
We're rather worried about her.
Officially been missing for 14 hours, give or take.
When in fact, it's more like 48 hours.
She hasn't been seen
since she went off-duty on Thursday.
Rather a good friend
of yours, I gather.
I- I haven't seen her since befo--
since before I--
Quite.
Heard from her?
- No.
- Apart from the postcard.
Let's try to remember everything.
It saves misunderstandings.
Did you go to the cottage tonight?
Don't think about it.
- Yes.
Yes.
Mind if I sit down?
I've been away for a month.
I wanted to look her up.
You ever discuss
your work with her?
- Of course not.
- Um, how about a gun?
- Any guns?
- A gun?
A gun from that museum of yours...
liberated from a captured U-boat along with the code
books, the captain's teddy bear and what have you.
All very improper and unsigned for,
but I turned a blind eye.
But no reason why you should know,
a chap like you.
Mind if I check the coat?
While we're at it--
- You sure you don't mind?
- I'm beginning to.
You see my point, though,
don’t you?
One day the Germans black us out
in the North Atlantic.
Next day, girlfriend
of crack code breaker disappears--
vanishes.
- Code breaker returns, shiny new shooter goes missing.
- She's not my girlfriend.
Hmm? What is she, then?
We were-- I suppose the phrase is
"seeing each other"...
for about a month.
Is that what happened to you?
What?
Is Claire Romilly
what happened to you?
There was a concert.
I went on my own.
Oh, it’s you.
You found my slipper.
Afterwards, Claire, Hester--
Miss Wallace, who shares the cottage--
and I, we came out together.
Next week was going to be Bach.
Oh, we must go.
Oh, I can't.
I'm on the night shift.
Oh, Hester. Poor you.
"Poor you, " she said.
That's one of her phrases.
So, I asked her.
I say, I hope you don't think it
fresh of me, but should we go together?
Of course you did.
And, uh, after that?
After that?
I had the happiest month
of my whole life.
Not happiest. Something.
- You can! You can.
- I can't.
You can. Yes.
Ready? One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight.
- Sorry.
- No, you can't.
- Claire!
- Aaron!
- May I?
- Do you mind?
No.
It's my favorite club.
- Mine too.
- Oh, yes, I'm sure.
How do you get the petrol coupons to go
zipping up and down to London?
Secret, darling.
I know a chap.
- No, but how?
- It's not what you think.
Do you have to know everything?
I don't know why you want me.
Let's get married before it stops.
- Tom, don't.
- I love you!
They say you shouldn't fall in love
in a war. You never know what's coming.
I love you.
I really love you.
No cottage.
- Is that code, darling?
- Yes.
- I want to see where you sleep.
- Landlady has rules.
So have I.
Hester's at home.
Oh.
I'll be quiet as a mouse.
Promise.
Shh. Shh.
Sleep with her?
I'll take that as a yes.
And then you quarreled?
Quarreled? No.
Claire? Darling?
Sorry, darling.
Go back to sleep.
- What are you doing?
- I'm just looking through your things.
No photographs?
You've never given me
a photograph.
You're all secrets,
aren’t you?
I've no secrets from you.
Please come back to bed.
What's this? What's the
entscheidungs problem when it's at home?
That's just something
I was working on at Cambridge.
It's a-- It's a theoretical
machine that--
- Theoretical. So it doesn't exist?
- Please, come back to bed.
Well, this will do.
I want something of yours to keep.
Give it back.
- Why?
- Because it means nothing
to you and a lot to me.
- Aren't I clever enough, darling?
- Please, Claire!
No!
Give it back.
It's not funny, Claire!
Claire, I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
I'm really, really sorry.
Claire--
She moved on.
Why won’t you answer my letters?
Are you seeing someone else?
I'm always seeing someone else.
Yes.
She moved on.
Not right, Mr Jericho.
Can't quite put my finger on it...
but definitely not right.
Were you surprised when they told you
that Admiral Doenitz...
had changed the German Navy
weather code?
Any bells go off?
Germans were always nervous
about Enigma.
Well, the Germans are supposed to think
that Enigma's an unbreakable system...
because it would take thousands of years
to go through every setting...
to find the one that turns
the code back into the plain text.
Next day, it's different again. Using
human beings, Enigma is safe forever...
but we don't use
human beings for that.
Do we...
Mr Jericho?
- No.
And that is the secret
inside the secret.
All they know thus far is that the weather
code opened a crack in the system...
because somebody told them.
But what if somebody tells them
just how we do do it?
Your thinking machine.
Clackety- clack, day and night.
Programmed with a menu,
thanks to your big brain...
that reduces the odds
to just a few million to one...
till it locks on to
the winning combination.
There goes the war.
Oh.
I've got a little list.
You're on it.
Communists, foreign nationals...
geniuses just this side
of barking mad.
Altogether, a security nightmare.
But of all these names, Mr Jericho,
you are the only one...
who got himself fucked into
a nervous breakdown by a missing blonde.
You live quietly from now on.
Where does one pee around here?
To the right.
Good night, Mrs Armstrong.
Talk to me!
What do you want to know?
Do you want to know about Shark?
Any secret. Ask me.
Ask me! I'll tell you!
Poor you. I really got
under your skin, didn't I?
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- You look tired, sir.
Morning!
- Have you heard the latest?
- No.
Utility knickers--
one Yank, and they're off.
Naughty, naughty.
- Came through the door for you.
- If there is some other way
To prove that I love you
I swear I don't know how
Thank you for your note.
I take it it's about Claire.
Have you heard anything?
She hasn't turned up,
if that's what you mean.
But you’ve got something.
I don't know why I'm doing this.
ADU is the call sign
of Nachtrichten, Regiment 537...
a motorized German
Army signals unit based...
in the Ukraine.
Its messages are encoded in the standard
cipher for the Russian campaign.
- We call it Kestrel.
- Kestrel.
Seven messages
with the call sign ADU...
were intercepted
in March and April...
not counting the last four
on April the 17th, which you found.
I've written down the dates
and times of interception.
A spy doesn't steal the enemy's signals.
And anyway, they were never de--
They were never decoded. Why would
she steal four messages she can't read?
She must have stolen them
to read them.
She stole them to read them.
But there's no way she could have.
- Why not?
- She couldn't. It just--
Just take my word for it.
God preserve me.
Another one.
I seem to move, Mr Jericho,
in an endless round...
from one patronizing male
to another...
forever being told what I am
and what I am not allowed to know.
Well, that ends here.
So, what would she need
to read them?
I'm sorry.
You can't ask me that.
But you can ask me to sneak into the Index
Room and risk getting hung up by my thumbs.
Cheerio, then.
Oh, Chr-- Miss Wallace.
Miss Wallace!
She'd need--
She'd need a Typex machine.
Every day, our Typex machines
have to be set...
the same way the Germans
set their Enigmas.
Otherwise, you just get
nonsense from nonsense.
And working out each day's settings
is the hard part.
That's where
the code breakers come in.
- How?
- Well, you-- you need a crib.
Suppose that gravestone was in code.
If I knew who was buried here, more
or less, I'd know what the code meant.
That's a crib.
And when you've set the machine,
you type in the coded message.
If it comes out nonsense,
the settings are wrong.
If it comes out
"Mary Jane Hawkins"...
you've broken Enigma for that day.
Why would Claire get hold of the
Kestrel settings for April the 17th?
She couldn't have,
unless she had help.
Kestrel would be filed in Hut 6.
It’s your hut.
So now I'm a traitor too.
Well, maybe she got access
to one of the Typex machines from you.
Typex girls work around the clock.
Sorry.
Stuck.
Look.
The first seven ADUs were decoded.
Now, what happens
to decoded messages?
They get written into the German book.
That's Claire's job.
Then what?
Well, then they get filed with
everything else in the main registry.
- Ever been in there?
- Once or twice to check some--
No. No, no, no, no.
Oh, dear, would you like some tea?
- Reference or loan?
- Reference.
- Section?
- Hut 6. Control.
- What are they?
- Kestrel intercepts, March and April.
- He's been a dark horse, hasn't he?
- Hmm. Surprise a minute.
But there are complications.
Sorry to have been so long.
I've never come across this before.
- The file was empty?
- There was a typewritten note...
dated April the 17th...
referring all inquiries
to the Office of the Director General.
And that night, four final ADU
messages got in under the wire...
never deciphered, never filed...
taken home by Claire and hidden.
Who is the Director General?
Chief of the Special
Intelligence Service.
And he gets his orders straight
from the prime minister.
We're stuck again.
Maybe. Maybe not.
I've got the hang
of this detective work.
You're out of bounds!
- Mr Mermagen.
- What are you doing?
Can you help me?
Machine Room needs the Kestrel settings
for the last couple of weeks.
They've found a batch of intercepts
fallen behind a desk.
- They've done what?
- I know.
But please don't tell.
It was actually a friend of mine.
Ah, you girls.
You know, I should really
report you for this...
but--
One good turn
deserves another, hmm?
Why, Mr Mermagen.
What will your wife say?
The Kestrel settings
for the whole of March and April.
Christ.
So, at least there's still a chance we can
read the ones you found in Claire's bedroom.
- I've burnt them.
- You what?
Hello, Tom.
Mind if we join you?
- You can't m-m-m-mean it.
- Well, of course I mean it.
Drowning herself was Virginia Woolf's greatest
contribution to English literature.
- Actually, we were just leaving.
- Waste not, want not.
Whale meat.
Brain food, Tom.
- You burned them!
- I had a close call with that lounge lizard Wigram from Special Intelligence.
I panicked. But the worst of it is,
I could have read them.
- How?
- I didn't need a Typex machine.
We've got a real Enigma
in the museum.
- Well, when did you find that out?
- Well, I knew. I just-- I just forgot.
You forgot?
And you're the genius.
You know, I won a newspaper
crossword competition.
I beat two men. All three of us
were recruited for Bletchley.
They're cryptanalysts now.
And I'm a glorified file clerk.
'Course, if I'd been a daddy's girl
from some posh finishing school--
God, look, it's time
to go back on shift.
- You?
- Not for a bit.
Right.
Did she ever say anything about me?
Well, she must like you.
The way she talks about the others--
A bus load, you said?
The Romilly effect.
One look, and they're "Romillied. "
Who was she seeing?
I only mean it might be a way forward.
- I know what you think about me.
- No, you don't.
Well, I feel like an idiot.
And you aren't the one standing here with
the Kestrel settings stuffed into your knickers.
Look, I don't know
who she was seeing...
and I really think
we'd better call this a day.
Don’t you?
Bye, then.
Miss Wallace.
I haven't been lookin'
to the right or left...
so there's something
I didn't see clearly.
What's that?
That you’re a remarkable--
I think you’re simply wonderful.
Tom, nice of you to turn up.
- Look, I don't known what Skynner's been saying.
- Shut the door.
He wants you out.
"Send him back to Cambridge,
and this time make the bugger walk. "
I got you the rail pass.
- Not now!
- No, you can't do that, Guy. Tell them
you want to give me a couple of days.
- Why?
- To see if I can find a way back into Shark.
Tom, it was you that announced
that it couldn't be done in four days.
It was you that made Skynner look
a fool in front of his clients.
Now you want me to go back and
tell him-- Piss off, for God's sake!
Sorry, Guy. Hello, Thomas.
You'd better come and hear this.
Two long signals from U-boat
headquarters in the last 12 hours.
One just before midnight,
one just after. Rebroadcast twice.
- Then nothing. U-boat fleet is on radio silence.
- Christ.
They're on battle stations.
Say 12 U-boats 20 miles apart...
possibly two lines,
possibly three.
An ambush covering
hundreds of miles of ocean.
And this time,
we don't know where.
And one golden rule--
absolute radio silence.
- And wh-- wh--
- What then?
Either the convoy is lucky and misses
the ambush, or it isn't lucky.
And the first U-boat to make contact
with the convoy breaks radio silence.
- How?
- Minimally, using the short signal book.
It compresses the necessary information
to a few letters--
sighting of convoy,
position, course and speed.
That's repeated every two hours. As it's
picked up by the other U-boats in the line...
they start to converge on the convoy
and send a contact signal in their turn.
Contact signal.
They'll shadow the convoy till nightfall.
They prefer to attack in the dark.
We haven't got as much time as we'd thought.
I'd say, a day, a day and a half at the outside.
- Mary Jane Hawkins.
- The oracle has spoken.
They changed the weather code, but they
didn't change the short signal code book.
It's our way back into Shark,
so long as the U-boats find our convoy.
Don’t you see?
It's our convoy.
We know what the U-boats are sending.
It's the crib that we've been looking for.
- Would you get enough material?
- How many signals do you need?
One group of letters
for the convoy sighted...
two groups for grid reference, one group
for course, one group for speed.
Five groups of letters
per contact signal every two hours.
Shadowing the convoy for maybe 10 hours,
12-- that's 25 groups of letters.
And how many U-boats joining in?
Eight, ten?
Each one a contact signal
every two hours.
My God, he's right.
He's found us a crib.
- Brilliant.
- A-A-Appalling.
We've never had an operation on this scale. The contact
signals could easily build up to give us a crib...
of 100 group of letters and we've got
the short signal code book in the museum.
He's right, Guy.
Where are the keys to the museum?
Good Christ, Tom. We have to protect
the convoys, not sacrifice them.
You know what it's like out there.
The success of this plan
depends on arranging a massacre.
No. No, we are not arranging anything.
What happens is going to happen.
But if we can use it to our advantage,
we'll be able to decipher every signal...
sent by every U-boat
on the high seas for 24 hours!
- Including the weather reports.
- Yeah. We'll have the plain text.
We can make a start on reconstructing
the new weather code.
- This puts us back in the fight.
- And there will be many more convoys to protect.
You're back in business,
old thing.
Garbled text from Beaumanor.
Somebody get on the blower.
Miss Chamberlain, would you?
Get them to check their file copy.
Pam, does Beaumanor keep copies
of everything they send us?
- Yes. It's all there on file.
- Thank you.
Hello. Could I have Beaumanor 392?
Miss Wallace!
No female visitors upstairs.
That's the rule!
Mr Jericho, wake up.
It's not over.
- We need to borrow your Enigma machine.
- Didn’t you hear?
Top copy goes straight to
your people by teleprinter...
or by dispatch rider,
depending on priority.
The second copy we keep,
in case of garbles.
Can we see?
Well, if you want.
There's not much to it.
It's a treat for us, you know, a visit
from head office to the country cousins.
It's good of you to say so,
but, um...
a fat lot of use we'd be
without your intercepts, Major.
We keep them a couple of months,
filed chronologically.
These sets are tuned to the
Eastern Front-- Kestrel, Buzzard, Kite.
- And you're intercepting everything?
- Absolutely.
Except that time
the other week, of course.
Kestrel, wasn't it?
Yes, your Miles Mermagen came
on the blower in a frightful panic.
"No more ADU, thank you very much.
Not now, not ever. "
- What's that about?
- Orders from above.
We'd just sent him
four good, clean signals.
It was Kay here who handled
our mystery station.
Carry on.
Yeah, he has a good fist, ADU.
Touch like a concert pianist.
He's still transmitting?
Of course, I don't take him down any
more, but he was awful busy last week.
Oh, excuse me, sir.
What was it you said
you did again, Mr--
- Jericho.
Can't say, I'm afraid.
Catch you up.
- Major, how many machines did you say you have here?
- We have 48 here.
Excuse me.
He's on now,
if you’re interested, sir.
Thank you.
I don't mean
to bother you, sir...
but it is important,
isn't it?
I know I shouldn't ask.
I mean, no one ever tells us.
You are making sense of it?
It is important?
Yes.
This is our only war, you see,
in here-- beep, beep, bloody beep.
And it's always nonsense,
nonsense, nonsense.
Yes, we are
making sense of it...
and it is important.
Eleven ADU signals
and launchings.
That's the car.
Man, woman, two-seater roadster.
Invite him to stop, shall we?
Take him, man! Take him!
Mr Jericho, stop! Stop! Stop!
Look out!
Shit.
Bravo, Mr Jericho.
Reckon, given the circumstances,
Miss Wallace...
we might now risk
first names.
Hester.
Tom.
This might be good.
It looks deserted enough.
Well spotted.
Bliss.
- What would they do to us if they knew?
- Feed us to the dogs.
Charming.
Right.
March and April
Beaumanor log sheets...
and the intercepts
from March 28th...
April 3rd, April 9th,
15th, 16th, 17th...
and Kestrel settings--
last one first.
Might tell us
why Claire disappeared.
Right. April 17, rotor order.
3- 5-4.
R- X-O.
- Plug board settings.
- A-O-E-M.
The current passes
from the keyboard...
to the lamps by way
of the rotors and the plugs.
And every time you press a key,
it changes the path of the current.
Press the same key ten times, it comes out
ten different ways on the lamp board.
You never know which letters
will light up. Simply brilliant.
Message key X-A-T.
- Ready?
- Ready.
- "Y. "
- "K. "
- "E. "
- "A. "
"W. "
"C. "
- "U. "
- Zed.
"M. "
"V. "
- "Q. "
- "X. "
It's not right, is it?
This isn't German.
Keep going. Sometimes the operator
pads out with nonsense.
Keep going.
- Um, "K. "
- Zed.
- "E. "
- "R. "
- "O. "
- "A. "
- "F. "
- "D. "
Isn't German.
Come on, genius!
I'm sorry. It's double coded,
or the settings must be wrong.
It's all been for nothing.
I'm afraid I have to ask you
to hurry up.
Search the barn.
This is Mr Leveret.
Detective Inspector Leveret.
He wants to know what you've been up to.
But first things first.
You've been here before?
And you?
Line up in the street
and search the area.
Have a look at this, sir.
It's down there.
- Right, sir.
- There?
Drag the river.
Please talk to me! What do you want to
know? I'll tell you anything you want.
Give me your hand.
Do you wanna know about Shark?
Any secret. Ask me!
Come this way.
I've got something to show you.
Get your notebook out.
Miss Wallace first.
I am showing the witness
one ladies' coat, colour grey...
trimmed with black velvet.
Label: Hunters, Burlington Arcade.
- And the witness responded--
- Yes. It's hers.
Yes.
Next, one ladies' shoe...
black high heel.
Uh, heel snapped off.
And the witness responded--
Yes.
It's an old quarry.
They built the town
with what they dug out.
That makes sense,
making one hole out of another.
- How deep is it?
- Sixty, seventy foot in the middle.
Christ, we'll need a submarine.
I would very much like
to arrest you...
but we don't have a body.
It's a quarter to 8:00.
Mr Leveret will take you back.
I believe your day
is just beginning.
Chaps.
Easy, everyone.
Just stopped by to wish you luck.
I'm sure you’re all aware,
as I am, what's at stake here.
I don't think I'm exaggerating
when I say...
this could be one of
the decisive nights of the war.
- So shut up, then.
- A mighty battle.
Probably...
the greatest convoy battle
of all time is about to start.
Three hours ago,
convoys HX 229A...
229 and SC 122...
had entered the presumed
operational area...
of the U-boat packs.
Now, in our long island history...
we have picked up the gauntlet
more than a few times.
Shakespeare coming up.
"Out of this nettle, danger,
may we pluck this flower, safety. "
So, gentlemen, go to it.
Come and dance.
Boop- boop
Come on. Come and dance.
- No, I can't.
- Yes, you can. It's easy.
- No, really, you do it.
- Right, left.
Left, left.
Ah! You're getting the hang of it.
C- Can someone remind me?
A- Are w-we hoping for the U-boats
to find the convoys, o-o-or not?
- Not.
- I am.
- Yes, well, you would, Baxter.
- Y-You'd sacrifice o-o-our--
Sacrifice a convoy
to get back into Shark? Of course.
How many men has Stalin had
to sacrifice so far? Five million?
It's called the greater good.
Spoken, of course,
by someone who doesn't happen to be
in the North Atlantic at the moment.
You can only fight your own war.
What do you think, Tom?
About what?
So, Claire,
what were you doing?
What were you hiding?
Right.
Start at the beginning.
Kestrel settings, March.
Atlantic time
is two hours behind.
It's still dark.
Here, mate,
I got a lighter.
Thanks.
"Urgent. "
Mary Jane Hawkins.
It is German.
Signal 7-3-6-9-K-C-S.
We're in business.
Direction finders have a fix.
Scarborough, 2-5-9 degrees.
Witt, 2-4-6, 30 degrees.
Flower down, 2-6-8 degrees.
There she is--
37.5, 49.5.
She's shadowing convoy HX 229.
No air cover. Sitting ducks.
Grid square?
B- D-1491.
- Convoy course?
- Seventy degrees.
- Convoy speed.
- Ten knots.
- From the code book, we have C-K-S-A for convoy sighted.
- First message?
K- A-F-B-N-W-Zed-Jacob
for position.
Q- K-D-X for course, Q-R-Zed-A for speed.
That's five four-letter groups.
Message setting, B-H-B.
"A- V, V-K, A-K. "
Check.
Yeah, me too.
- "M-S, S-M. "
- Check.
Two loops. Confirmed?
And no clashes.
10:04.
One down.
Now the wolves
will be gathering.
Still nonsense. Why?
Can you fix B-D-1611?
Convoy speed and direction same.
New position:
K- A-F-V, N-C-L-A.
Skynner's offered a bottle of Scotch
to the first man to come up with a menu.
- Does he know I'm still here?
- He didn't ask.
Oh, Puck, there's a message
left for you at the switchboard.
It's Adelphi 4-2-4-3.
There's no name,
and I'm not your social secretary.
- Message key: R-M-U.
- Sorry, Guy.
How much more material
do you need?
We've got 9 signals.
Another 20, 25 would be better.
Suppose it starts
before you have them.
Naval grid square B-D-1386.
Course: 70 degrees.
Speed of convoy: 10 knots.
I'm pretty sure there's enough
for a stab at a menu. Let's try it.
- You have 17 contacts, Mr Jericho.
- It's not enough.
Well, why the hell not?
When I'm done, we'll be looking
for a needle in a haystack...
but if we stop now it'll be
a hundred thousand haystacks.
You know that.
Full moon.
Ten U-boats, somewhere.
Thirty- seven merchants, five escorts,
one of which has lost contact with the convoy.
No rescue ship
and no air cover.
Eighteen.
- Flower down, 2-6-8 degrees.
- It's what you might call a bitch.
- Twenty-three.
- Not enough.
- What have you got?
- I need one more link.
I can't see it.
Names. They're names.
- You?
- No.
Getting a very bad feeling now.
Polish names.
- There.
- Yes.
- Menu.
- Let's hope to God it works.
It's started. Bastards.
Don’t you have homes to go to?
- How's it going?
- Four hits so far.
Probably 300 men lost.
A Dutch cargo and a Norwegian freighter
went straight to the bottom.
And an American liberty ship's
on fire.
Half the crew are drowning.
The other half are trying to save them.
Tom. Unfinished business.
Congratulations.
It's a half bottle,
as it turns out.
Typical Skynner.
That should go back.
Where's the museum key?
Oh, sorry, Guy.
I've still got it.
Tsk, tsk.
Security around here.
Then get off home, old thing.
- Haven't you got a girl waiting for you?
- She's dead.
Tom.
Oh, my God. Come on.
- What?
- Come on.
It's Polish.
Polish names, all of them.
The Germans
found a mass grave.
Look, doesn't it say
4, 000 corpses?
"Polish officers buried
in the forest at Katyn in 1940...
"during the Soviet occupation.
Shot in the back of the head. "
Murdered by the Russians.
By our Russian allies.
They were comrades-in-arms
against the Nazis.
My God.
That's why the file was empty--
on the orders of Secret Intelligence.
And that's why Beaumanor was ordered
to stop intercepting the signals.
It was too big a secret.
Just knowing that
can get you killed.
And Claire discovered it.
Copied it into the German book,
and she had to tell...
someone.
- Adam Pukowski.
- What?
Missing in action.
Kid brother of Jozef Pukowski.
Claire stole those intercepts
for Puck...
because he was looking
for his brother's name.
- Puck!
- Wait! Please!
This Puck killed her. Why?
Because he had a secret, too,
and she could've given him away.
- What secret?
- I can't tell you that!
Tom!
Hello. Could you get me
London Adelphi 4-2-4-3, please?
I'm sorry. That number
is not in service.
What the hell is this about, you and
some skirt waltzing around Beaumanor?
Leonard, unless you're asking me
to dance, let go of my arm!
I should've cooked your goose when you made
a fool of yourself over that blonde...
who fucked half the park.
What?
Stand away! Stand away!
What the bloody hell
do you think you’re doing?
He's two carriages up.
Snug as a bug in a rug.
Morning, sir.
You knew?
About Pukowski?
We had no proof,
but when Miss Romilly went missing--
- Puck and Claire were having an--
- Were seeing each other, as you like to put it.
Seeing each other's
brains out.
Jozef Pukowski, who'd been wondering
what could have happened...
to all those Polish officers who hadn't been
heard from since the first year of the war...
and Claire Romilly...
who was reading the Wermacht traffic
from the Eastern Front.
They were made for each other.
And lo, mass graves.
Polish uniforms, names.
- We've been bracing ourselves for the Nazi propaganda.
- Propaganda?
Four thousand Poles
murdered by Stalin?
It's what Hitler would
give his last ball for.
Think of all those Polish names
in the U. S. of A.
Think of our convoys
full of American goods...
some of them
in American ships...
running the U-boat gauntlet so our
supplies can keep Stalin in business.
- But it's true, isn't it?
- The Katyn massacre?
Oh, really, do shut up. There's a war
to win, and Stalin's helping us win it.
And they hate
the Russians, you know.
They've hated them
for centuries.
So what's Pukowski
going to do to get back at them?
Help the enemy. That's what.
His enemy's enemy.
And he's got a big piece of knowledge
that can help the Germans-- Shark.
- The weather code.
- Claire couldn't have known what he'd do. She wasn't a traitor.
I'm sure you’re right.
But then Pukowski heard
that you were coming back.
Jericho, the lover who wouldn't let go,
who'd cracked once before.
The swot who was invited to the ball,
found Cinderella's slipper...
and went so crazy
he would've told her anything.
And you would have, wouldn’t you?
About how we lost Shark.
And the rumour that there was a mole
in the park, probably in your hut.
How long would it have taken Claire to work out
that the traitor was Puck? About a minute.
So he killed her.
One- way to Manchester,
according to the ticket collector.
Change the watch.
Well, let's see where
and to whom he will lead us, hmm?
Train approaching, platform three.
It's the 3:15 to Manchester.
How do you get the petrol coupons
to go zipping up and down to London?
Secret, darling. I know a chap.
Train standing, platform three.
3:15 for Manchester only.
Manchester, next stop.
That's it for you.
Go home, keep your head down...
and I might try and forget about you and
your moll breaking the Highway Code...
and the Official Secrets Act
on the same day.
Train standing, platform three.
3:15 to Manchester only.
You've been trying to frighten me into keeping
my head down right from the start. Why?
Because somehow
I frighten you. Why?
Because of Claire.
My connection with Claire.
Be careful now.
The night you came to my room, you
already had Pukowski in your sights...
yet you went out of your way
to play the heavy with me.
And then you were more concerned about
Claire Romilly than you were about Shark.
- A girl who'd missed her shift? Why?
- Why? She was his girlfriend.
Oh, no. She was more than that.
She was working for you.
Claire was your agent.
She told you everything,
even how I found her shoe.
As you said, Bletchley was a security nightmare,
so you put a girl in the park to do your dirty work.
Surely you mean
her patriotic duty.
Everything that she did, she did because
you told her. You had her fucking for England.
And then when she got to Pukowski,
it went wrong. She took pity on him...
and she told him what she was
writing in the German book.
No wonder you were frightened.
You'd made a terrible mistake, and your
agent paid for it with her life. Claire.
He's jumped!
He's gone!
Come on! Back it up!
Back the train up!
What are they doing?
Sir, please. The station's clear.
Roadblocks are in place.
- Search the train again.
- He's not on the train!
- We'll have to let it go.
- Please be patient.
Oh, Puck, there's a message left for you
at the switchboard. It's Adelphi 4-2-4-3.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you very much.
- To the station, rather fast, please.
- Ma'am.
You bloody idiot.
This time I can't save you.
You broke Skynner's cheekbone.
Tom. Well, weather code is,
uh, c-c-cracking open.
Where's Puck?
- Check our weather report--
- How bad is it?
It's bad.
But we are reading Shark,
thanks to you lot.
- What's this?
- Grid square A-M-2-9. We think it's a garbled signal.
- Signal to a U-boat?
- Mmm. U-617.
Ordered out of battle
to proceed immedi--
Yes?
Where is this?
Loch Feochan, in Scotland, where
I'd like to be old. If I'm ever old.
So, it's the real thing.
U- 671, rendezvous in 24 hours.
Our turn to find a sitting duck.
My God.
- Be careful.
- I will.
Damn it.
- I'm on the chosen frequency.
- Sir.
- There's probably interference.
- Swing around. I'll fine-tune it.
Perfect.
Just in time to bugger up
the whole operation.
- Do you want to abort?
- Are you serious?
- I didn't kill her.
- I know.
Do you think
I'm here for that?
- That's right, my darling.
- They're ready.
Up you come.
What about the rest of it?
The real secret you want to tell the Germans,
about how we really broke the code?
- About my machines!
- Thomas, Thomas.
- You can have your enemy. Let me have mine.
- No.
Well, shoot me, then.
- It's your show, but your man--
- He is not my man.
Serve it up.
- Go ahead.
- Tell Auntie Mae the package is ready.
Dinner's ready.
Bulls eye!
- Run out a couple of yards there.
- You're looking in the wrong place.
Oh, it's Mr Jericho.
Come home again
with his batteries dried out.
You turned out to be
some swot.
- I tip my hat to you.
- She's not there. Didn’t you hear me?
She's moved on.
The murder scene was like
a pile of clothes left on a beach.
Sometimes it means
somebody's dead.
somebody wanted to disappear.
Like an agent who'd been
turned by her target.
It was you
who saw it before I did.
What makes you think that?
Pukowski was on the train,
and you were letting him run.
He knew the secret that could lose us
the war. Remember? The thinking machine.
You were holding back to see
who he would lead you to.
Who the hell could it be
to make you take that risk?
Only Claire.
Well, I was wrong, wasn't I?
She wasn't with Pukowski.
She was waiting for him up the line to take
him to her little Scottish hideaway...
where a couple of runaway lovers
could sit out the rest of the war.
Do you think I didn't check?
She loved him, and Pukowski brought her
all the way to the brink...
but then he had to tell her
what she didn't know...
about the U-boat
coming to pick him up, and why.
If they got caught,
they'd both hang.
But there was no going back.
Only forward, to Germany.
But then,
he didn't know Claire.
She was no traitor.
She's out there, somewhere...
like a sword
hanging over your head.
In different ways,
she fooled us all.
She was unreadable.
- Stick to sums.
- I think I've got something! Easy does it!
What have you got there?
Steady.
- We're losing her, lads.
- Do you want it to be her?
Steady, now.
False alarm!
Shut up.
Keep looking.
Oh, I will.
I will.
- Sorry I'm late.
- It's all right.
I was getting worried
about you two.