You're up early.
- More bad dreams?
- No, no. It's the goddamn church bells.
I hope you haven't been to the loo.
I need a morning specimen.
Actually, it's a good thing you're up.
You've got a busy morning of tests ahead.
But if everything checks out,
it looks like we'll be letting you go today.
- No kidding.
- Don't talk.
And don't smile.
You're well on the mend,
and we need the bed.
Your squadron leader
will see to your billeting and transport.
Peter. Good.
You are really that anxious
to get back to the war, are you?
No. Not the war.
But I wanna try out this retread of a leg...
you guys fixed me up with.
Make sure it can still do all the old things
that it used to.
You know...
I'd hold off on the tap-dancing
for a while, David.
I think you may be right there, Ginger.
The mattress is all new.
And a room with a bath
is an unheard of luxury...
in Jerusalem nowadays.
- There.
- Very nice.
- There's no water.
- It's rationed, old chap.
Half the city is supplied on even days
and the other half on odd ones.
Well, included in the price
you'll have two eggs every morning.
They alone cost me a shilling.
I have to buy them at the black market.
Well, David, what do you say?
Well, I've been living
in a boarding house for 10 days.
This is paradise. Where do I sign?
Oh, good. Would you know
how long you'll be staying?
I'm afraid not. We could be relocated
anywhere more or less anytime.
How awful this war is.
May Hitler burn in hell.
Okay. If this place is so terrific...
why are you letting go of it?
What's the catch?
There's no bloody catch, you ingrate.
- Want one?
- No.
Was that true?
Or just for public consumption
about us not knowing...
how long we're gonna be here?
It's absolutely true.
The whole bloody war
is bogged down in the desert.
Rommel's been stopped,
but he's pretty well dug in by now.
So, pushing him back's
not gonna be all that much fun.
So that's why they're holding us in reserves.
God knows.
There's no end of rumors.
I even heard Burma mentioned.
By the way, there's been
an American military attaché...
inquiring if you might like
to change uniforms...
now that you Yanks are in it officially.
Tell him I'm not interested.
Of course you're a bloody awful wingman,
but I'm used to you.
Still haven't told me
why you're moving out of here.
- Well, I've met this girl who...
- Oh, no.
Don't tell me that girls are off-limits up here.
No, no.
As long as you're discreet.
I just thought I'd be more comfortable
in a flat.
Because of this girl?
- What girl?
- The girl you almost told me about.
Why are you being so cagey about this?
I'll tell you all about it, but later.
In the meantime,
if you have any interest in washing today...
Well, I thought there was no water.
Yeah, but that's only on this side of the city.
You mean black market showers?
Victoria, you know I'm your friend.
But you always overdramatize.
Not this time.
Sarah, they take turns
spying on me.
You have to help me.
Oh, God, there's my father.
Laugh, Sarah.
He mustn't suspect anything.
Come on. At least smile.
This is silly.
My cousin Nessim
is already suspicious.
Who cares about your cousin?
Unless you're afraid
to be seen with me.
Of course not.
I told Nessim
I'd go to the movies with him.
I must see Peter.
He's waiting for me.
Sarah, please!
Only you can help me!
All right.
Go and be nice to your father.
I'll figure out something.
I got tickets for the Carmen Miranda film
with The Ritz Brothers.
I prefer The Marx Brothers.
Nessim, dear, don't be difficult.
- Victoria needs to talk to me.
- What about me? Don't I need you?
- To go to the movies?
- What am I to tell your parents?
I'm supposed to keep an eye on you.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- You know I love you.
I know.
- But you don't care.
- I do.
But Victoria's waiting.
David, I'm getting married next Monday.
I want you to be my best man.
- Will you do it?
- Yeah, sure. Sure.
- Good. Thank you.
- Are you nuts?
Isn't that what people in love
are supposed to do?
Crazy things like get married?
Peter, you can make love to a woman...
without marrying her
and without being a bastard about it.
- Look, David, I'm crazy about this girl.
- But marriage? Peter, Jesus Christ!
There's not one single aspect of our lives
that we control right now.
- The war can't go on forever.
- So wait.
It could be a bloody long wait.
Remember the Hundred Years' War?
Not personally. No.
This one doesn't have to go on
that long for all of us to wind up dead.
Have you thought about that?
Look, all I want to do
is a bit of normal living before I die.
- What is so wrong with that?
- Is that fair to her?
Luckily, she wants to do
a bit of normal living before I die, too.
- So it could work out quite nicely.
- So live together.
I can't ask her to do that.
She's from a very respectable Jewish family.
They're already less than thrilled
that she's seeing a Gentile.
Well, that's great. That's just great.
You really know how to pick them, Peter.
Hold it, here she comes.
- What's her name?
- Victoria.
Oh, well, won't the folks at home
be pleased.
Peter.
I nearly didn't make it.
Oh, this is Sarah. She's my alibi.
- And an absolute angel.
- Sarah, Victoria, this is David.
Oh, you are the American.
Peter's told me how madly brave
you were when you were shot down.
But of course it was madly brave of you
to go all the way to England...
to enlist when you didn't have to.
Well, it was Canada, actually.
Peter, darling, please tell me. Right now.
Even if the news is bad.
How does a week from Monday
strike you as a wedding day?
Peter and I are going to be married.
We've just been waiting
for him to get permission.
Sarah, be happy for me, please.
Be happy?
When you've lost your mind?
I'm 21! I can do what I want!
I'm entitled to be happy.
You had no right to use me this way!
No right at all.
Sarah, I've ordered some champagne
to celebrate.
- I hope you'll join us.
- Please.
David's agreed to be our best man, darling.
I hope you'll come, too, Sarah.
I know it'd mean a lot to Victoria.
Yes, it would.
Peter, darling, we have so little time.
- Can't we dance?
- Yeah.
Sarah and David will understand.
Well, they certainly do look good together.
I'll give them that.
- Is that a good reason to get married?
- No.
But I think they might say something
about being in love.
Yes.
People do seem to talk about that a lot.
But you're a skeptic
when it comes to love, is that it?
No.
But it is not something
I know very much about.
What was that language
you and Victoria were speaking?
- Spanish.
- Spanish, yeah.
How is it that you happen
to speak Spanish?
It's what we speak at home.
- Your family came from Spain?
- Yes.
- Recently?
- About 400 years ago.
I see.
- They must have some terrific memories.
- Yes.
Why are you staring at me?
Am I staring?
Yeah, I am. I'm sorry. Yes, I was staring.
It's just that you have
the most extraordinary eyes.
Like to dance, little lady?
If you've no objections, mate.
It's up to the young lady.
I'm sorry, I didn't realize he was that drunk.
If you knew he'd been drinking,
why didn't you say anything?
Well, he's probably just on a short leave,
and he's in a tank division now.
And anybody facing going back
inside one of those little metal ovens...
probably has a right
to have a couple of drinks...
and a dance with a pretty girl.
You think I should let a drunken soldier
maul me to show I'm grateful?
No, I'm not implying that.
Look, I would've asked you myself,
except I can't...
because of my leg.
I'm sorry if it was unpleasant for you.
It doesn't matter.
I must be getting home.
Would you explain to them?
Sarah, don't go away mad.
In fact, don't go away at all.
Please, sit. Come on.
I must. Really.
Where are you off to, love? Just one kiss.
- Leave me alone!
- One little kiss.
- Hey, hey, leave her alone!
- Leave me alone.
- Leave me alone, leave me alone.
- One little kiss.
My God. You killed him.
No, I'm afraid not.
Nessim.
- You know this man?
- No, I just happened along.
- How did you happen to be here?
- You know, I just...
- You followed me, didn't you?
- No, no.
- You were spying on me.
- How dare you? How could you?
- Sarah, please, listen to me.
No, I don't want to hear it.
And I don't want to see you again.
- Not as long as I live.
- Why? Sarah, please, why?
I apologize for Sarah.
- I'm sure she meant to thank you.
- It's all right.
You must let me buy you a drink
to show our appreciation.
- No, no, it's okay.
- Yes, yes, yes. I must.
- It's fine.
- And I must buy you another walking stick.
It's not important, really.
Sarah came in here with another girl.
Are you serious about this drink?
- Yes, yes, I know just the place. Come.
- Good.
- Thank you very much.
- It's all right, it's all right.
You know how many times I tried to enlist?
Every time they tell me I'm underweight.
- It's not for lack of appetite.
- Oh, no, I eat all the time.
I am a bottomless pit.
Where does it all go, you wonder, huh?
Doctor says I burn it all up.
Maybe I worry too much.
Tell me, David.
May I call you David, Lieutenant?
- Yes, yes. Sure.
- Good. Then you must call me Nessim.
- Nessim.
- Nessim. Nessim.
David, what shall I do?
If I don't see my cousin,
it's like not seeing the sun.
- Your cousin?
- Sarah.
The girl you saved from the Australian.
She's my cousin.
I've known her practically all my life.
At least all her life.
She is only 18, and I'm 28.
David, I loved her the first time I saw her.
She was only one day old.
I'm the right man for her, David.
No one can love her more than I do.
You don't think I'm too old for her?
- Sarah, what does she think?
- I wish I knew.
Everybody thinks she'll be my wife.
I thought so, too.
Now I don't know.
She was so angry.
You think she meant that?
About never seeing me again?
If she does, I'll die.
Well, before you die,
I'm sure that she will forgive you.
Oh, no, no, no. She can be very stubborn.
And very fierce.
Well, you are right.
Where there is life, there is hope.
- Tell you what, David, are you Jewish?
- No.
It's not so unlikely. The name, David.
And I know there are many Jews in America.
Yeah, but not in Missoula, Montana,
there aren't.
The reason I was laughing is because
my father is a Christian minister.
Well, it doesn't matter.
You can still come for the Sabbath dinner.
- That's very nice of you, but I don't think so.
- No, no, no, no. You must come.
You must give Sarah a chance
to thank you properly.
I'm not taking no for an answer.
Then let's just say
that one of these Sabbaths...
Friday. Sabbath dinner is every Friday.
Friday.
You sure you've had enough, David?
Oh, good heavens, yes. It was all wonderful.
Mama, the officer complimented you.
Thank you very much. I pleased you like it.
When is the Sabbath dinner
not delicious?
No, no, "liked" isn't the word.
I usually don't make such a pig of myself.
What is he saying?
He's ashamed because he ate so much.
To his good health.
One never eats too much
on a Sabbath.
Tell him it pleases the Lord.
Hear that? No need to be ashamed.
The Lord is pleased.
Tell me, do you think Rommel will get here?
Only if we let him.
Well, he can come for all I care.
We are ready for him.
- Right, we will show Hitler a trick or two.
- Yeah.
But the British won't,
I mean, they will not let Rommel through.
- There is no reason to worry?
- Elie's a tough guy.
As soon as he smells danger...
he takes his courage in both feet
and runs for dear life.
I can feel a draft.
You are the only one.
Every single door and window is shut.
- The heat is killing all of us.
- Albert is a boxer.
We are very proud of him.
He is fighting the "Ogre of Aleppo"
next week at the Y.M.C.A.
- You must come.
- Tell me, how is Mr. Winston Churchill?
The lieutenant is an American, Papa.
What does that matter? I mean,
he wears a British uniform, doesn't he?
- You have something against the British?
- No, no, no. On the contrary.
- We love everything British, yeah?
- Absolutely. English breakfasts.
Crosse and Blackwell marmalade.
Huntley and Palmer biscuits.
- The King, the Queen.
- Fish and chips.
It's a long way to Tipperary
Soccer.
- Craven "A" cigarettes.
- Habeas corpus.
But we don't like British rule.
And one day we will throw
all British troops out of Palestine.
Are you from anywhere
near Chicago, perhaps?
Not really. I grew up in Montana.
Is that near Seattle, perhaps?
It's nearer than Chicago, yes.
Oh, then we have relatives you must know.
The Peres Shoe Store.
- It's run by two brothers, my cousins.
- Well, it's a fairly big country.
Peres Shoes are well known, I believe.
A very large store.
- And we have other cousins, too.
- Peres, yes, I think I've heard of them.
His father is a priest, right?
How can a priest have a son?
Papa, I love you.
He's a Protestant.
Their priests are allowed
to have wives.
How many?
Papa was asking about your father.
Will he be a priest too?
Papa, all these questions.
David doesn't mind.
Do you?
Uncle Raphael wants to know
if you'll be a priest like your father.
- No.
Grandma Rosa
knows everything about you now.
Oh, really? Can she tell my future?
He wants his fortune told.
He needn't worry.
Nothing bad will happen to him.
He is a good man.
She says you'll live to be a 120,
you'll be rich and famous...
and the most beautiful girls
will be at your feet.
- Nessim.
- What?
What did she really say?
That you are a good man.
And nothing bad will happen to you.
I want to thank you.
What for?
Oh, for breaking my stick
over the head of a drunken Australian.
That also.
For not telling Nessim how we met,
or about Victoria.
Is it like this every Friday? All these people?
And on high holidays, even more.
The grandparents from the other side and...
The aunts and the uncles,
and the nieces and the nephews...
and the brothers and the sisters.
We are really a tribe.
What's it like being part of a tribe?
It has good points and bad points,
like everything else.
- Did you like them?
- Yeah. Well, they're a little...
overwhelming at first, but...
At the café, when you left...
I was following you because I wanted
to ask you if you'd be interested...
in going out with me sometime.
If the Aussie hadn't gotten in the way,
what would you have said?
No.
- What if I asked you right now?
- Still, no.
Well, why not?
The rumor has it, I'm a very good man
with a very promising future.
Is it Nessim?
I know that he assumes that one of these
days you and he are going to...
What Nessim assumes
has nothing to do with me.
Okay.
Am I supposed to ask your parents
their permission first, is that it?
No, don't.
Oh, there you are.
You're keeping our guest of honor
for yourself, Sarah?
No, I'm not.
She forgave me, just as I said she would.
Lovely night, isn't it?
- Lieutenant.
- Hello.
I hope I'm not intruding.
I brought these
as a token of my appreciation...
for the dinner last Friday night.
Thank you very much.
He thinks we need charity?
Bring us some coffee.
And these are for your grandmother.
Could you also explain to your mother...
that I am here to ask her permission
to take Sarah out sometime.
Sarah can do as she wishes.
Then would you like to go out
one day this week?
No, Sarah is busy this week.
- Perhaps next week, then?
- I am busy next week, also.
- I seem to have made a mistake.
- I think so.
Kindly thank your mother once again
for her hospitality. Goodbye.
That boy is in love with you.
That's ridiculous.
For once, listen to your mother.
I forbid you to see him again.
I never intended to see him again.
But don't give me orders!
Who wants coffee?
...take thee, Peter Ross...
- To be my lawful wedded husband.
...to be my lawful wedded husband.
By virtue of the powers vested in me
under The Foreign Marriage Act...
I now pronounce you man and wife.
Thank you.
- You may kiss the bride.
- Thank you.
Yes. You are married. Congratulations.
- Well, how's it feel?
- It feels great.
Okay, now, make a wish.
Okay, now, who would like a bit of cake?
Here, here, here. Wonderful. Wonderful!
None for me.
Thank you for coming.
A wedding with no parents. It seems odd.
Maybe it's better like this.
Nobody's losing a daughter
or gaining a son.
You think Victoria's not losing anything?
You're supposed to get drunk at a wedding.
It's not like you to drink like that.
- How do you know?
- I know.
Look, I wouldn't mind getting out of here
and you're uncomfortable as all get-out.
Would you like to take a walk?
Yes.
That over there is King David's tomb...
so they say.
- Would you like to see it?
- Do I have to?
- No.
- Good.
What did your family think
about you joining the RAF?
Well, my mother died long before that.
My brother and sister
didn't have an opinion.
My father was disappointed. He's a pacifist.
I was bound to disappoint my father.
Joining up just got it over with
nice and quick.
- This is very beautiful.
- Yes, it is.
When you told me
that you were too busy to see me...
was that because of your mother,
or were you speaking for yourself?
For myself.
Then why the hell didn't you just say so
that night after dinner...
that you weren't interested?
I did.
No, you implied that it was
because of your family.
And that's why I made
such a jackass out of myself...
- coming to ask their permission.
- I told you not to.
All you had to say was that you, Sarah,
didn't want to see me again.
So, why did you come
to the wedding today?
For Victoria.
You think I came because of you?
- You are very conceited, aren't you?
- No. No, I'm not.
Look, you think I don't feel it?
I was hoping like crazy
you were going to come today.
But I was half hoping that you wouldn't...
'cause I knew that if I saw you again
I would want to go on seeing you.
Again and again. And again and again.
It's not possible. And you know it's not.
Okay, I can think of some reasons
for myself. But I'd like to hear yours.
You are in Jerusalem for how long?
Not very long, I think.
Why should I want to get involved with you?
And there's your family.
Why would I want to get involved
in anything so complicated?
Well, there you are.
I guess we should
just stay out of each other's way.
I think so.
Well, come on.
I'll take you home in a cab.
No. It's not a good idea.
Then I guess this is goodbye.
Goodbye, Sarah.
Goodbye.
- What is it, Sarah? What's bothering you?
- Nothing.
You can't fool me.
Everyone else, yes, but not me.
Something is making you depressed.
You know I love you.
What's funny?
You are. I know you love me.
You tell me every day.
And you have no feelings for me?
I love you. Like a brother.
That will change once we are married.
What if I met someone else?
Someone that I don't love like a brother?
- What if I have already?
- You can't have.
You would have told me.
Who else can you talk to about such things?
Oh, Nessim, you are such a foolish man.
The first night was fine. Lovely, in fact.
It all started the next morning.
A few tears at first,
and then a never-ending flood.
It took me hours to get it out of her.
- Get what?
- Her family.
She can't bear the thought
of never seeing them again.
Well, that's funny. I didn't think Victoria
gave two hoots about her family.
Yeah, she was pretty casual about it,
wasn't she?
Damn her all to hell!
Now, come on, Peter,
Victoria is crazy about you!
Well, be that as it may. Right now,
she seems to regard our marriage...
as a mild form of eternal damnation.
Christ, I'd be willing to let her off the hook.
Maybe look into an annulment.
But the real hell of it is,
it wouldn't do any damn good...
because her family
would still regard her as a pariah.
- That's some family.
- Well, mine's just the same, David.
They're as suspicious of Jews
as hers are of Gentiles.
That's why making it legal was so important.
If I bought it, well,
they'd be honor bound to accept my widow.
Raised eyebrows or not.
It's ironic, isn't it?
- Bloody hell.
- Yeah, isn't it, just?
Well, come on.
No more sulking.
It's time for some constructive activities.
I don't need a bloody glove
to catch a ball, David.
You will for this one.
Oh, God! What's in that thing?
- Catch.
- No, come on, overhand, like this!
All right. Get ready.
- What the hell is that, David?
- That is the wind-up.
Pure poetry is what it is.
Don't worry, Sarah.
He'll kill him yet. Just wait and see.
- Where are you going?
- Home.
Wait, wait, wait!
Get up! Get up and fight! Come on!
Don't look at me like that.
It makes me feel drunk.
I feel I could look at you forever.
- Don't tell me you have to get home.
- But I do.
Sarah, every time we meet,
it's just to say goodbye.
If I am too late, they will ask questions.
All right, but this time, I'm taking you.
This is as far as we can go together.
When can I see you again?
I have to see you again.
How about the weekend?
I can't leave my house on the Sabbath.
- Which Sabbath?
- My Sabbath. Saturday.
Sunday, then. That's perfect.
They never schedule operations
for a Sunday.
- What operations?
- Oh, nothing.
We just take the planes up
to make sure they can still fly.
I think I can get a car.
- David...
- No, Sunday.
In front of the café. I'll be there at 9:00.
You get there when you can.
I'll wait for you.
What's the matter, little dove?
Nothing.
I love you, that's all.
Get up now.
You're too old
to be sitting on my lap.
You're back.
Where have you been?
Nowhere.
Where's this nowhere?
Nessim was looking for you.
He said you left the match
before the end.
It was horrible!
I couldn't stand it.
Who won?
Your brother. Who else?
These fights will be the death of me.
Did you see his eye?
It's all black and swollen.
Where's everybody?
Gone to celebrate.
- What about you?
- I'm celebrating here with Grandma.
Have something to eat.
I'll bet you're hungry.
No. I'm not.
I'm going to bed.
Good night.
Your daughter needs a husband.
What are you saying, my soul?
She's barely 18.
I was carrying your child
at her age.
If we don't watch out...
she'll come home one day
with her belly full.
It's you, little bird?
I couldn't sleep, Grandma.
It's too hot.
You sit out here for hours on end.
What do you think about?
Nothing.
Things just go 'round in my head.
That's all.
- What is it, little one?
- Nothing.
No. It's not nothing.
You know it's not.
Does it show?
Who is he? The American?
I was afraid of that.
What should I do?
What is there to do?
He's going away soon.
Would it be wrong to see him again?
Don't ask me what's right
and what's wrong.
I never could tell.
And don't expect anyone
to understand.
But you understand.
Don't you, Grandma?
I understand all too well.
My heart aches for you, little one.
Why is life so difficult?
Why do I feel happy,
just the same?
This is beautiful. And cold.
- Yes, it's very cold.
- Yes, it is. This is very, very cold.
Where are you taking me?
- You'll see.
- Where?
See, it is cold. Sorry. Told you. It's cold.
Oh, you're wet.
Is it very strange
being so far away from home?
No. Felt like a stranger there, too.
Like I was living in a country
with only one citizen.
As of now, two citizens today.
Well, I'm honored.
- Does this place have a name?
- Ein Gedi. It's biblical.
Everything here is biblical.
Ein Gedi, that's Saul and David.
- We Presbyterians, we know our Bible.
- Especially the son of a priest.
- I forgot about that.
- Yeah. Well, we call them ministers.
Or parsons, or reverends.
The reverend.
The Reverend Thomas Bradley.
- Tell me about your father.
- My father?
He's a very admirable man.
He's very principled.
I don't suppose you know
what The Grange Movement is.
Do you? No, of course not.
He's a socialist.
- You know what that is, right?
- Really?
Every Russian and Polish Jew
in Palestine is a socialist.
- Yeah, well, not your family.
- Good heavens, no.
To share everything and be poor together,
this is madness.
Why were you bound to disappoint him?
Well, he...
Because my father believes
that God is just and merciful.
And that the world
can be remade in his image.
And you don't?
I think God has a lot to answer for.
And I don't think you can change the world.
Not much, anyway.
Well, this is the place.
Are you sure it's all right?
Well, you're the one who said
you couldn't go home looking like this.
The bath is completely private.
No one will disturb you. Not even me.
If you need anything, just holler.
Don't be angry. Please.
- But I have to.
- I know. I know.
You have to get back home.
- You're angry.
- No, I'm not angry.
- Tomorrow?
- Yes.
When?
After work.
Here?
Yes.
- No!
- Wait. Hey.
No!
What is this? What are you doing?
Stop it! Stop it!
Vandals! Hooligans!
Oh, my God! Lieutenant.
Is it true, child?
Tell your papa.
Speak up!
What were you doing in his room?
How long has this been going on?
Oh, God! Why do this to me?
What did he do to you?
Answer me, bitch!
Stop me, or by God, I'll kill her!
Where's the swine?
I'll tear his eyes out!
- Where's the assassin?
- Sarah, I beg you!
Tell them it's not true!
The son of a priest too.
A curse on him.
I'll fix him good! Just wait!
It's not true!
I don't believe it! It's impossible!
It's a mistake!
Tell them it's a mistake!
An American in a British uniform.
What can you expect?
How far did you go?
Look at me!
Are you still pure?
Have you slept with him?
Please, Mama, I love him!
Did you hear that?
She's lost! She's dishonoured!
My own daughter, a whore!
She's without shame!
Stop, woman!
I'll kill you!
I'll tear your heart out with my hands!
Enough, woman!
You call this love?
You've lost all sense of decency!
I'll root this "love"...
out of your body...
with a red-hot iron!
I'll teach you to behave...
like a prostitute!
You're no longer my daughter!
You're dead!
I'll never forgive you!
You've ruined my life!
Have you all gone mad?
Why are you torturing her?
So what if she loves an American?
Why not stone her while you're at it?
Shut up, idiot!
You just don't understand.
I understand you're a stool pigeon.
That's enough!
Go to your rooms, all of you!
You, woman, get your mother to bed!
I did nothing wrong, Father.
- Don't you believe me?
- Yes, I do.
- I love him.
- You've already said that.
It's the truth. I can't help it.
True love is marriage.
Could you be his wife?
Would he marry you?
I don't know.
A man is made for one woman only...
and to be the father of her children.
You hardly know him.
I know him with my heart.
I'm sure he's a good man.
He's good-looking too.
A lover is always better-looking
than a husband.
Poor Nessim.
How can I marry Nessim?
He's like a brother to me.
"Oh, if only you were
my own true brother...
then I would kiss you...
and no man would despise me."
The Song of Solomon.
You see, my little dove...
true love means coming home...
to find him waiting for you.
He takes your hand, talks to you...
gives you strength.
Young women are lead to believe...
that love is pure spring water...
and marriage a sewer.
Papa, I'm so tired.
I can't think any more.
All I want to do is sleep.
What are they gonna do to her?
Those guys
did a really professional job on you.
There's hardly a mark.
- Don't you think you should see a doctor?
- No!
Victoria, I've asked you three times now.
What are they gonna do to her?
And I've told you. They'll scream a lot.
- And maybe beat her up a bit.
- Beat her up?
David, you don't understand these things.
They will be very, very angry.
So, maybe give her a few slaps.
But they'd never injure her.
They really do love her.
Yeah, I could tell that by the way
they dragged her out of the room.
I know what her brothers think,
but they're wrong.
- If I could just go and explain to them...
- Oh, David, don't be an ass.
It's bound to make it worse.
David, forget about doing anything
for a week.
- Maybe two.
- He doesn't have a week.
Why doesn't he have a week?
Because we're pulling out of Jerusalem
the day after tomorrow.
- Where to?
- Egypt.
- Oh, please, Peter, let me come with you.
- Darling, that's impossible.
Let me go to England to be with your family.
- There's a war on in England as well.
- I don't care.
I can't stay here alone with no more family.
Damn it,
I've told your bloody family I'll come back.
Christ, I'm willing
to become a Jew tomorrow.
Peter...
let me come to Egypt.
Or send me to England.
Or give me a divorce!
I think England is the answer
if you can arrange the transport.
Davey, can you imagine the sort of reception
she'll get there from my family?
What the hell were you planning on doing
after the war?
I was planning on being there with her.
Listen, why don't you stay here tonight...
in case the brothers decide
to pay you another visit.
Sure.
Thanks.
- Where are my clothes?
- You don't need clothes.
You're not going anywhere.
Who says so?
I say so. Your brothers say so.
I can't believe it!
Perhaps you'd like to go out naked.
Not that it would surprise me
if you did.
Who can that be?
Go and see, Clara.
Hello, Clara.
- Who is it?
- It's him, Mother.
The American! He's at the door!
Just open the door!
I just wanna talk to Mr. Perrera.
No, he is not home! Go away! Go away!
Have you no shame?
You ruin my daughter
and you dare knock on our door! Go away!
Mrs. Perrera, it's not what you think.
Please let me just speak with Sarah.
- Go away before I call the police.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Would you give this to her, then? Please?
No, no, you can't see Sarah.
My sons are close by.
Go away or they will come here and kill you!
Go! Go! Go! Get your brothers! Go!
- She's upstairs?
- Please, just go on.
Get them and my husband.
He's crazy, this one!
Sarah, just listen to me.
I have to leave in the morning.
But I'll be back. I promise you, I'll be back...
and then we'll straighten
this whole mess out.
David!
Give me the key!
Go back to your room at once!
David!
He's gone.
Who is it?
Mama, open the door.
What's going on?
Nothing.
What are you doing here?
Go to the kitchen.
Dinner is ready.
- Quick, my clothes!
- I couldn't get to them.
I got some clothes
from my girlfriend.
She's about your size.
I love you, brother!
Oh, Lieutenant!
I hope I did the right thing.
Lieutenant...
I took the liberty of letting the young lady
into your room.
You see, I couldn't have her in the lobby.
She had no shoes on!
I almost didn't come back here.
- I almost went out and got drunk instead.
- But you didn't.
They took my clothes.
- You walked here like that?
- I had to see you one last time.
- I must look...
- Adorable.
Damn it, why can't you look terrible?
I've been out walking the streets...
trying to convince myself
I wasn't in love with you.
And I come back here
and you're barefoot and you're adorable.
Today was the worst day I've ever spent.
I think of not seeing you again.
Sarah, I love you...
I wanted to tell you last night,
when you were still here.
Are they really sending you back to the war?
Egypt.
But it's not that far away.
I'll come back as often as I can.
I'll write you every day.
- I'll dream of you every...
- No, don't.
What do you mean? What's wrong?
- Promise me.
- What? Anything!
Promise me you won't come back.
- What are you talking about?
- You said "anything."
Sarah, I just told you that I love you.
- I can't stay...
- Are you trying to drive me crazy?
Please, promise me!
All right, if that's what you want, I promise.
Don't look so miserable.
I'm here and I can stay all night.
If you really knew how much I love you.
Sarah...
No, don't say it.
- But, how do you know?
- I know.
Just a postcard.
When the war's over.
So you'll know I made it.
I already know you will.
I don't need a postcard.
But, after the war is over.
By then, you won't even remember.
You're nuts, you know that?
You're just plain nuts!
- But you still love me anyway.
- Yes.
Say it, then.
I love you.
And, I love you.
- Now, go to sleep.
- No.
- Yes.
- I can see you're sleepy.
- I'm afraid to.
- I'm afraid you'll slip away.
- Not without saying goodbye.
I promise.
Now, go to sleep.
Sarah?
Good morning, Uncle.
What are you doing out so early?
Has anything happened, God forbid?
What is it, Saltiel?
Nothing! It's Sarah.
What Sarah?
Great heavens!
Please, Auntie, Uncle,
I'm sorry to wake you up.
- I'd like to see Nessim.
- At this ungodly hour?
What has happened to your shoes?
Is Raphael so poor...
that he can't buy you
a pair of shoes?
And what is this disguise?
You think it's Purim?
Can't you see
the poor girl is upset?
Sarah?
- What's going on?
- I must talk with you.
Haven't you caused him
enough trouble?
Quiet, woman!
Make us some coffee.
Let's leave them alone.
Go, go.
I had to see it to believe it.
What is the world coming to?
What is it, Sarah?
Is it your mother? Did she...
No.
Sit down.
I want you to answer me without thinking.
Would you marry me?
Marry you?
- You want me to marry you?
- Yes.
- I'll gladly die for you, Sarah, you know that.
- I'm not asking you to die.
Yes.
Yes, I'll marry you.
- Even after what happened?
- Nothing happened, Sarah.
Something did, and you know it.
All I know is that I love you.
What if I don't love you?
You don't?
Not even a little bit?
So what if you don't love me?
It's not the end of the world.
What is love, after all?
I'll be a good husband, Sarah.
And I'm sure you'll be a good wife.
I have enough love for the two of us.
You might, perhaps, one day.
Who knows?
Sarah?
- You all right, sir?
- Yeah. Baxter bought it.
- Bailed out?
- Burned.
Peter, what do you say?
I think you're mad.
You'll be spending two days
out of three days traveling...
just to spend one day in Jerusalem.
Why don't we spend three days
on the beach at Alexandria?
Because, you've got a wife in Jerusalem,
to start with.
Actually, as it happens, I haven't.
Or, not for long, anyway.
Vicky and I are gonna pack it in, David.
Her father's arranged
some kind of bogus annulment...
she's gonna go back to her family
and I'm gonna be a happy bachelor again.
You just gonna sit there
and let that happen?
I'm rather surprised
to hear this coming from you, David.
You were the one that told me
marriage was crazy and selfish.
I think you're taking this awfully easy, Peter.
Believe me,
nothing between Victoria and me...
has been easy, David.
I think you're feeling more down about this
than you're letting on.
And I really want to see Sarah.
And if we're going off to Burma
like everyone is saying...
this may be the last chance I'll have
in a long, long while.
You're absolutely sure, are you,
that Sarah wants to see you?
And just what makes you say that?
This might be the last chance we get
in a long while to have some fun, David.
If you're not sure, then why waste the time?
Peter, I'm going back to Jerusalem.
What if I were to order you not to go
on the basis...
of three days not being long enough
to make it there and back?
Then I'd probably tell you to go to hell.
What is with you, Peter?
Sarah's getting married, David.
Victoria wrote to me about it.
She didn't give many details.
Not even what the man's name is.
But you're welcome to read the letter.
Isn't it beautiful?
Gorgeous.
I'm so happy for you.
- Where's the veil?
- It's ready.
Let's have a look.
You look lovely, child.
What day is it?
It's only Tuesday.
Why isn't it Thursday?
Are you in a hurry?
No second thoughts?
Why should I have second thoughts?
It's not for me to say.
This was my own decision.
If you feel you're making a mistake...
better to admit it now
than to ruin the rest of your life.
I'm not making a mistake.
I'm only drowning.
Wait, please.
Wait a minute. Please.
- Leave it be. Can't you, David?
- No, I can't.
You think it would make any difference
whether you see her or not?
I don't know what I think anymore!
But I do know
that she's not marrying Nessim...
of her own free will!
You are wrong, David.
Her family would do anything to stop her
from marrying a Gentile.
But they'd never force her to marry someone
she doesn't want!
No! No! You're wrong! It's not possible.
She cannot marry Nessim!
- She doesn't love Nessim!
- So what?
Love's so wonderful?
It makes you so happy or me or Peter?
She is going to marry Nessim.
You can't stop it.
I'm not here to stop it.
But I do want to talk to her.
I want her to explain.
God damn it, she owes me that!
Look, this isn't your problem, Victoria.
It's mine.
David, wait.
He only wants to talk to you.
- No, I can't!
- Why?
He promised he'd go away
and never come back!
I don't understand.
- It doesn't matter.
- He loves you.
No, I don't want to hear.
He's at a café down the street.
We can pretend to take a walk.
No.
- Sarah, he only wants to understand!
- I don't care what he wants! I hate him!
You can tell him that!
No, don't.
Tell him there is nothing to understand.
Tell him to forget me
like he forgot his promise.
If she changes her mind,
she knows where to find you.
Jesus Christ. What am I doing here anyway?
I should've just stayed in Alexandria.
I should've gone to the beach.
Should've drowned myself.
You know, I've been thinking.
Maybe Sarah isn't really so special.
Maybe she's just peculiar.
What do you think?
I think if it helps you to think that,
then you should think it.
You haven't said a word about how Peter is.
- You didn't ask.
- How is he?
- He's like you, I guess.
- Good. I don't like suffering alone.
Well, D. H. Lawrence said
that all love has to offer us is pain.
Let's not talk sad, David.
No, let's not. Let's have another.
- She knows that I'm leaving at 6:00?
- She knows.
She won't come.
Even as a child...
you always knew
the right thing to do.
It made me proud of you.
Now I'm not so sure.
I saw the American with Victoria.
Did you meet with him?
No, I swear I didn't.
Is he the reason
you're rushing to marry Nessim?
I'm not rushing.
Yes, you are.
No one is forcing you into it.
Why didn't you come to me?
I would have said nothing about
whatever might have already happened.
Only that I mustn't see David any more.
Yes, I would have insisted on it.
But I wouldn't have forced you
to marry Nessim.
Nessim loves me.
And he's such a good man.
Papa, help me.
I feel like I'm drowning.
Suffering has no use.
No use at all.
You must understand one thing.
If you choose the American...
I cannot help you.
You will be alone then...
outside of the law...
outside of the family.
You will no longer be my daughter.
No, this must be said...
and it must be understood!
Tell me that you understand.
Yes, I understand.
- Where is he?
- He's gone.
- Where?
- To Atarot airport.
He said he had to take a plane back
to Alexandria.
- But you said he'd be here in the morning.
- He must've left earlier.
His plane takes off only at 6:00.
David!
Look, I've realized
that I don't want an explanation.
I don't have any.
Well, that's good.
That's good.
Fine.
Well, I'd like to stay and chat,
but I have to go catch a plane.
You cannot marry anybody else.
Do you hear me? You can't!
No, I can't.
Don't say that unless you mean it!
I'll be here waiting for you.
I'll come back as soon as I can
from wherever it is they send me.
Burma, Australia, Antarctica!
I wish I could tell you when.
It doesn't matter when.
If it takes a hundred years, I'll be here.
I know. You have to go.
- I'll write you every day.
- I'll write you, too. But where?
I don't know.
I'll have to send that to you in my first letter.
What about you? Where will you live?
Do you need any money?
Stop worrying about me. I'll be fine.
You take care of yourself.
Oh, don't worry. Nothing bad can happen.
Your grandmother promised.
- I have to...
- Go.
- Come with me to the field?
- Yes.
Come on! Come on!