When I was 12 years old,
my father was the Governor of Virginia.
And none of us knew it at that time,
but our world was about to explode
over the issue of slavery in America.
My father's heart had long
since changed on the topic,
and one night, he took me to a place
that would forever change my own.
- Reading the Englishman again?
- Will I be shot for treason, Father?
Most likely.
Another one of those long titles, is it?
"The Personal History,
Adventures, Experience,
"Observation of David Copperfield,
the Younger of Blunderstone Rookery..."
Which he never meant
to publish on any account.
You read it. Guess that's why it's here.
Suppose so.
Get your coat, John.
We're going to take a little ride.
I don't think I like these
surprise trips anymore, father.
'Cause they're usually lessons in life?
Exactly.
Well, tell me about the play
your mother took you to in Philadelphia.
You mean "Uncle Tom's Cabin"?
And why have we not talked about it?
Because we'll disagree,
and disagreeing with you
is so... disagreeable.
Your mother said
you were not impressed by it.
Think it's all made up
by the people who don't like us.
Yes. Well...
there's lots of those in Philadelphia.
All right, ladies and gentlemen!
We are about to get started!
Step on up! Step on up! You're gonna
love what we have on store tonight...
A slave auction.
Doubtless those people in Philadelphia
would not approve.
- You're not coming?
- John...
I have never known you to need
help making up your own mind.
These slaves are trained by some
of our most respected citizens
in the central Virginia area.
Oyez! Oyez!
Step on up, ladies and gentlemen!
Sale's about to begin!
A fine lot of slaves
belonging to the estate
of the late Colonel William
Jasper of Amelia,
sold in no fault,
but to sell the estate!
We got all kinds. Old ones, young ones,
men and women, gals and boys!
And as some of you may or may not know,
Colonel Jasper's plantation slaves made him
a pretty penny for the last 20 years!
Gentlemen, what we have
to offer here is so damn good,
old Mr. Lumpkin even up
and married one of 'em!
You won't find the mark
of a whip on a one of 'em!
We're not talking some low-class
Louisiana branding-iron stock!
We got the best slave stock
from all of central Virginia here tonight!
Colonel Jasper's staff represents
the finest stock in the state!
This is the best group
of dining room servants, farmhands,
cooks, milkers,
seamstresses, washerwomen,
and the most promising group of sassy
young females just ready to breed.
Martha Ann is the favorite
of the household.
Perfectly healthy, no blemish at all.
Look at that complexion.
I offer Martha Ann at a reduced price,
because it is the wish of all concerned
to keep them together.
Now, Israel here is not what you
would call an able-bodied man,
having broke his leg in the field,
which didn't exactly mend right,
but he can do all sorts of light work,
and you can have him
and the young'uns mighty cheap!
Masters...
if you'll buy me,
the children and Martha Ann,
God knows I'll work myself to death.
Come on. No bids at all?
400. Do I hear 450?
Come on, people, 450!
Look at her! He can work!
This is one of the best slave lots we're
gonna see all night, ladies and gentlemen!
400 going once.
400 going twice. Sold! Will you take
Israel and the young'uns with her?
No. I'm lucky to be able
to afford one as it is.
I don't need no more mouths
to feed than hers.
No, please! No! Don't leave me!
- Don't make me!
- You'll have more children, Missy.
- Come on!
- No! Israel!
No! Israel!
Ladies and gentlemen...
Five years later, the Civil War began
closing in on the Shenandoah Valley,
the place that was home to the military
school my father had sent me
when he became a general
in the Confederate Army.
I was 17 years old...
and in my second year
at the Virginia Military Institute.
Johnny Wise! Always in a hurry!
You think he'll do?
He's a rabbit, a mouse.
And he's perfect,
like he shipped straight from heaven.
- Round up the boys.
- All right.
Good morning, young sir.
- Let me give you a hand to the barracks.
- But, sir, you're an upperclassman.
This is true. One day,
you will be magnificent yourself,
somehow find a way to repay my kindness.
Well, imagine this.
A welcoming committee.
Robert, come on and meet some
of the boys. This here's Duck.
Let's get you unpacked.
And this is Jack Stanard,
a real soldier and a hard man indeed.
You want to grow up and be a man,
you pay attention to him and not me.
You looking for an easy ride,
you come to the wrong place.
This handsome creature
is our resident Jew.
His name is actually Moses,
and he's an artist.
He's got the best heart of the bunch if you
ever need to cry on somebody's shoulder.
We'll start by me telling you all about
Sammy here so you can protect yourself.
Couldn't you do one of them,
but without the clothes?
What have we here?
- What's that?
- Well, that looks like food to me, son.
Anybody tell you there's a war going on?
Concealed foodstuffs, that's contraband.
Clear violation
of Institute regulations.
- Immediate dismissal.
- Might even be criminal.
Oh, Bobby, how could you?
Cadet Stanard, could you please fetch
the Officer of the Day?
I don't know how it got there.
This is Cadet Garland Jefferson,
Officer of the Day,
whose jurisdiction covers this matter.
And since his family are direct
descendants of Thomas Jefferson
- and own the eighth-largest plantation...
- That'll do, Atwill.
Now, if I take charge,
this goes to the faculty,
which ends horribly for the boy.
- Please, sir.
- Could we have Duck fetch John Wise?
Handle this within the barracks?
Bobby, this is John Wise,
our unofficial Chief Magistrate.
Now, his father was once governor
of this Commonwealth,
so he is as close to an aristocrat
as you can find in a democracy.
Look me in the eye, son.
Tell me the truth as if
your very life depended on it.
- Did you do this?
- No, sir.
I swear on my father's soul.
I believe this child. I ask that we
be allowed to settle this here.
All right.
You understand, son, if this gets out,
it could be bad for Cadet Jefferson.
Therefore, there must be
some evidence of punishment.
Will you submit to a caning?
Yes, sir, and thank you
for being so... merciful.
Take your shirt off.
First-year cadets are known as rats.
You are a rat.
But you're a special rat,
you understand?
You're my rat.
You're under my protection
and under the protection of all here.
Are you with us, Robert?
Oh, yes. Oh, yes, sir.
I want you always to remember
the horrible injustice
you thought was gonna
befall you here today...
of one human using his authority over
another without decency or conscience
and of the need to assert a code of honor
that transcends the temptations of power.
I hereby raise you
above the level of common rat.
You shall be known in this company...
as Sir Rat.
Now put your shirt on, son, before we
find ourselves a healthier specimen.
- You hungry, boy?
- Oh, yes, sir.
What do you gentlemen say
to a little midnight requisition?
- What?
- Never mind! It's tradition.
Right there.
All right.
Come around.
Help me with this doorknob.
- Easy. Easy.
- Go ahead.
- Oh, that smells good.
- Oh, that does smell good!
- There's us some bread, boys.
- Here we go.
That's pretty good right there.
That one's mine. That one's mine.
Well, now, evening, Judge.
No need to be afraid of Old Judge, boy.
He's just a grumpy old slave.
I may be the property of this Institute,
but I have the ear of the Superintendent
and the full trust and confidence
of the Commandant.
- I'm the master of this bakery.
- You also have a cleaver.
There's nothing worse in a time
of conflict than a thief of food.
Tell the Judge why we're here, son.
We're... we real hungry, Mr. Judge,
and those loaves smell awful good.
I'm new just today,
but Mr. Wise here tells me that the bread
is the best part of this school.
Go on and get yourself
one of these loaves, son.
- I suppose I could spare three or four.
- Thank you, Judge.
Oh, that's good.
- That's fresh.
- I'm not here for a handout, Judge.
I'm here to negotiate
a business arrangement.
Now, you seen the best of us
on the shooting range.
Jewish boy's the best, then you.
We'll bring in some squirrel,
rabbit and some possum,
harvest a fugitive chicken or two.
Your people share in the meat.
In return, we liberate some bread.
See, the terms of this arrangement
is a little more serious
for some parties than others.
If this comes crashing down,
it will not fall on you.
- Tell me this one is different.
- We think so.
He's not afraid to take action.
It's a welcome change
from your other generals.
Some call Grant a butcher.
Well, sir...
that may be precisely what we need.
General...
congratulations on your victory
and promotion.
Gentlemen, thank you.
They say you are the general
the nation has been praying for.
They also say you fight like a savage.
Oh, I agree with both.
War is not opera nor theater.
It is for winning.
Winning ends the death,
ends the destruction, begins the healing.
And to win, brutality is required?
Each game has its rules, Mr. President.
Are we to play chess or war?
And if I were to name you
General in Chief?
I will attack our enemies
at all times and all places.
I will take away his crops,
his animals, the food he has sheltered,
his railroads, his industry,
his clothing,
his ammunition, his gunpowder,
his steel, his armament, his salt,
and I will take from him
the flower of his youth.
I will destroy everything my enemy loves
and anything that might give him
the means or the hope to prevail.
Do you see me as a monster,
Mr. President?
I see you as a true general.
The only way back across the Blue Ridge
and into our flank...
...through the New Market Gap,
and that's where Grant will send 'em.
Sir, General Lee does not believe
an attack will come this spring.
Well, then, General Lee is dead wrong.
The Federals will come and soon.
Inform my brigade commanders
to concentrate the army and move
at best speed towards New Market.
And I am going to need
everything they got.
Sir, you're asking me to tell
the commander General Lee is wrong?
Well, thank God you been listening.
I won't have to repeat myself.
If General Grant is the wolf
and we are the lamb...
then New Market Gap
is surely our throat,
and trust me, the wolf will come.
Shoulder arms!
Order arms!
- I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Order arms!
Shoulder arms!
I got it. I'm good.
Sam, help me. Come on. Come on.
Sir, the battalion is formed and ready!
All cadets are present
or accounted for, sir!
Ladies, can you help us out?
Thank you very much.
Oh, watch him.
- We...
- May we help you?
We...
Is he dead?
What kind of thing is that to say?
We got company!
- Sam, what happened?
- I don't know.
Ma'am.
Ma'am?
- Oh, my goodness. He isn't dead, is he?
- No, ma'am.
Notwithstanding what that girl
decided to the contrary.
Well, young man,
that girl is my daughter,
and we're not from these parts,
and she has never seen a cadet before,
so she would not know what is normal
or not normal around here.
And the only thing she decided
is that there is an intellectually
impaired cadet at my doorstep with...
perhaps a drunken colleague?
Well, bring him in.
Let's see what we can do.
- Let's go.
- All right.
You're...
- not from around here?
- I should say not.
My aunt lives here.
We live up at New Market,
you know, up north where Jackson fought.
So is this the best you can do?
At conversation?
Well...
Yeah.
Pleasure chatting with you.
While I'm taking the main army
south towards Richmond,
I'm sending General Sigel west
to the Shenandoah Valley,
Lee's breadbasket.
If we take the Valley before the summer
harvest, we'll cut off Lee's food supply
and end the war.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
This campaign is going to be
something of a family affair.
Our First Lady, Mary Todd Lincoln,
is a cousin to the Rebel general
we're going to be facing in the Valley,
John C. Breckinridge.
You're wondering what the hell
you're doing here.
As a matter of fact, sir, I am.
Well, Franz Sigel
is a politician, not a soldier.
All he has to do is take the railroad,
but I'm not gonna take any chances.
I'm gonna attach you and your guns
and a regiment of Ohio boys.
Is that your daily briefing from Mary?
Ever since she turned 10, the girl just
won't let me run the war without her.
Well, then, what does your daughter
say about the New Market Gap?
She says that Grant has a big problem.
Yeah, the only sizable force
he has to throw at us...
is Franz Sigel.
She says Grant knows
that Sigel's an idiot, so...
he will surely send a real soldier
along to help him out.
But she thinks...
Sigel is almost certain to take offense...
and resist the help.
Smart girl?
So then at New Market...
We will break Grant's back
and save Lee's Army. Jolly.
Unless, of course...
the soldiers I asked for
don't arrive in time.
Which case, we'll lose the war.
It's my fault, it's your fault,
and from the Union gallows
next to you, I'll surely remark...
that I told you so.
- We already got our delivery, son.
- This is from me.
- This is extra.
- One slave to another?
Not exactly. I just thought, you know,
some families could use these.
Of course I do.
This ain't about your people
and the Pharaoh...
and you feeling something
them other boys can't feel?
- What's that you got there?
- Oh. Oh, nothing.
You let me be the judge of that.
Well...
my, my, look at this.
I thank you for these.
There are some children
who won't be hungry tonight.
And... who's this?
Someone who will go hungry.
- All right, sir. 18 credits.
- Thank you, sir.
- How much are the sausages, sir?
- Get behind, rat!
- Hey!
- I said get behind!
No! I was here first, sir.
What's going on here?
This is my rat! Hands off!
Butt out, John, if you know
what's good for you.
You have no right to push
a cadet out of your way.
He's just a rat.
Don't pretend to boss me around, Johnny.
Wasn't it your father, the governor,
who opposed secession?
The old fool.
- Come on!
- Hey, stop it!
Down there, stand fast!
You're all under arrest!
- This ain't over, Johnny!
- You bet it ain't!
- Come on. We gotta go!
- Hey! Hey!
General Sigel, my respects.
I have the honor of providing
artillery support for your advance.
Welcome, dear Captain DuPont.
You have been sent
by General Grant to spy on us?
I wish only to provide the best possible
support for your command, sir.
Are there any maps of the route?
Any intelligence of the enemy's
dispositions or intentions?
General Grant is your patron.
Let him provide whatever you need.
Libby... Miss Clinedinst,
I need to tell you something.
When I first saw you...
your eyes... No, not "your eyes."
Something else.
Your... your mouth...
All right, then I say, "Good evening."
She's gonna say, "Good evening..."
She doesn't know my name.
- She doesn't know my name.
- You need to come inside?
Well, I better not, given my recent
problems with conversation.
A wise boy.
Shall I get you something?
Conversation would be nice.
Are you counting on an uncontrollable
attraction to the uniform?
Wouldn't help.
You'd soon find out
I'm not much of a soldier.
See, I didn't think that I believed
in anything enough to fight for it...
until tonight.
And what is that, Mr...
Sam. Mr. Sam.
What is it you believe in tonight?
I believe in something...
more than just...
sudden, superficial attraction.
Tonight I believe in love
at first sight.
Get him.
That's what you get
for giving away food!
I think you should stick to drawing.
That's a woman's work.
I see how you could pick up
on a local with that. Nice.
- Well, what do we have here?
- I hope he's got warm bread.
It's Old Judge, sir!
I went to the bakery
to make our delivery,
and the soldiers
were all in there with him!
Dear God. Do you know
where they took him?
To the faculty, Captain,
the one called Chinook.
Get Jefferson.
Was it very bad?
Ain't gonna be nothing compared
to what the hanging's gonna be.
This don't make no sense.
They need the Judge.
They can't need a slave, son.
- But they can forgive one.
- Oh, yeah.
Captain Chinook's just...
dripping with the honey of forgiveness.
Y'all, it's time to go.
Johnny...
weren't your fault, son. Hungry got fed.
I promised.
Don't you know
it's the other way around?
Old men make the promises
the young'uns got to pay on.
That's war, ain't it?
I'm coming back for you, Judge.
- I'll stay.
- All right.
Let's go, boys.
He fed people who were starving.
And hanging is the consequence
a slave faces for stealing food.
He didn't steal it.
I did, sir.
No, Captain, it was I.
- I did it, sir.
- I as well.
And I bring the confession of Moses
Ezekiel, so it's five gallows, then.
Shall I organize a detail
to assist the hangman?
You know very well you won't be hanged.
Are you so willing to end your careers?
With all due respect, sir, who would offer
a career to five dishonorable men?
What kind of satisfaction
could such a life bring?
You too, Colonna?
- Jefferson?
- Honor is honor, sir.
It is the most precious quality
in our profession.
- All for one, sir.
- That's the honor thing, sir.
Get out of my sight.
And don't be late for morning class.
And, Jack, looks like I'm gonna get
some baked bread this morning.
Get 'em out of here.
So Echols and Wharton are, what,
joining us on foot?
60 miles for Echols, 75 for Wharton.
- Gentlemen.
- They can make it.
If they march through the night, don't eat,
kill most of their horses, maybe.
Well, there is one more
possible solution.
We have 250 trained troops and artillery
less than 50 miles from Staunton...
- Jesus, Charlie, the schoolboys again?
- Cadets. Just in reserve...
and only if Wharton
and Echols are delayed.
In reserve to fight.
And if we have to put
those children in to fight,
then what kind of dire circumstances
will they find themselves in?
Yes, they are young,
and, yes, you have told me on
six occasions in the last four days
- that you will not permit them near the Gap.
- And I won't.
But we do need them...
in reserve...
just in case, sir.
The Yankees burned his home.
The mill's gone.
Everything's gone.
His sister Margaret?
His baby brother?
No one knows.
That there is your Grant, Johnny.
That's how he is.
You take me...
where I could get revenge.
Son...
I must speak to the superintendent.
We do not expect General Sigel's
forces to proceed south
through the valley at best speed,
but if they do...
I understand. Of course.
Thank you, Major.
200-odd boys really gonna
make the difference?
- Is the situation really that dire?
- I am quite sure.
I have promised General Breckinridge
that you will be in Staunton by Thursday.
That's 50 miles in 2 days.
Yes, sir.
Battalion, fall in!
Quickly now! I said fall in!
Attention to orders!
The enemy in heavy force is advancing
up the Shenandoah Valley.
General Lee cannot spare forces
from the Army of Northern Virginia
to meet this advance!
All available forces from southwestern
Virginia and elsewhere
are hereby ordered to assemble
in Staunton to defend the valley.
The battalion of cadets
of the Virginia Military Institute
is ordered to march
with four companies of infantry
and one section of artillery
by the Valley Pike.
All cadets will appear with canteen,
blanket and weapon
at 8:00 tomorrow morning
prepared to march!
That is all!
Yeah!
Dismissed!
Revenge, Johnny.
Revenge.
- Scared?
- Are we really going to fight?
They tell us no.
We're gonna be held back in reserve,
but we can't be sure.
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
What makes you think
I want you to feel better?
I want you to stay safe.
Whatever happens, you stay with me.
I guess we should declare a truce.
- Of course.
- This ain't over, though.
I'm still gonna whup you good.
That boy is outside.
Come to say goodbye, have you?
Absolutely.
I'm gonna miss this old house.
Women's work, darning socks,
mending uniforms,
packing food and blankets, and...
of course...
pulling together medical supplies
and bandages
for those who'll follow to help...
if needed.
Well, I hope you're not gonna do that.
It's a war,
not a party.
Of course not. Why would I go?
There's nothing I believe in
enough to fight for...
- while you, on the other hand...
- Oh, yes.
Love at first sight.
Let's go!
Hurry!
Fall in!
Battalion, fall in!
Order! Arms!
Eyes front!
Battalion of cadets,
Virginia Military Institute!
Forward, march!
Why is the answer no
insufficient for you?
General, with all respect...
There is no respect, not in your face,
your voice, your words!
There is no respect in you.
When I'm comfortable,
then I will advance.
Sir, if we do not reach New Market Gap
before Breckinridge gathers his troops,
it will be too late.
If I advance before I'm comfortable...
that will be too early.
And early comes before late.
Why would he do that, Sigel?
Just sit there?
Oh, I'm sure it's a whole
bunch of reasons,
cowardice near the top.
And with General Wharton on the train...
Yes, things would appear
to be going better, Charlie.
Observe my elation.
- You won't have to use the boys.
- No.
- They still on the way?
- Yes, sir.
Attention, cadets!
The young ladies of Staunton have
invited you to a welcoming social tonight!
- Look sharp, boys!
- If you insist, sir. Orders are orders.
Sorry, boy.
Down to just bread and dried beef.
Thank you very much.
You think there's gonna be
a lot of ladies at this dance?
I hope there's more than one.
Otherwise, you boys are out of luck.
I know I'll be looking
for one in particular.
Do you think Captain Chinook
will let us rats go tonight?
My goodness, I forgot to ask him
in our last intimate chat.
Sorry, I won't be able to make it.
Got guard duty.
Looks like I'll be dancing
with old Chinook instead.
Oh, I hear old Chinook's known
for his waltzing abilities.
You could do far worse
than Captain Chinook.
Be careful, Johnny. He might
just sweep you right off your feet.
Well, now, that's making me
mighty uncomfortable.
- Hey, rat.
- You want to splash a little?
Rat! Come on now! I'm in the middle
of shaving. I just did my hair!
I gotta move and get some food
I never meant to stay...
Is it all right that I don't have
a uniform like you do?
Not to worry, Robert. One day,
you will be magnificent, remember?
When you're an upperclassman,
you will have a coat just like this one.
But for tonight, you're perfect.
Now let's find you a lady.
Excuse me, miss.
I'd like you to meet
a real Southern gentleman.
Hi. I'm Robert.
- Kara.
- Go enjoy yourselves.
Go on.
Well, welcome, soldier.
Can I persuade you to a dance?
No. No, thank you.
- I knew I should have worn the red dress.
- Miss, you are lovely in that dress,
and whoever dances with you
is gonna be the envy of all.
- The hair, then? I can take it down.
- Please, don't trouble yourself.
This is about a girl
I left behind in Lexington.
Married, are you?
Not yet. Childhood sweethearts.
Been together as long as...
long as I can remember.
I just came here tonight
for the refreshments and music.
Do you know if all the other ladies
have arrived already?
I'm sure I wouldn't know.
All right, of course. Evening.
Would you just excuse me a moment?
I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
I told you not to come.
Yes, you did.
- Tomorrow...
- I know where you're going...
to New Market. I'm going, too.
You haven't seen the last of me.
Still not much at conversation.
Or anything else.
I'll be the judge of that.
You are absolutely right.
Oh, Miss...
No way to talk to a soldier
on the eve of battle.
You'll be fine.
That's the plan.
For good luck.
So you won't forget me.
No, Sam, this is the plan.
A farm, a shop, a trade.
Your choice.
Four babies, my choice.
That'd be all?
We'll fight a good deal.
We will, will we?
I'm sure of that, even when
we're old on a porch together
with nine grandchildren
and our teeth falling out.
Well, we'll laugh some, too, I believe.
And there will be conversation.
I do like conversation.
- You missed a good party.
- Cadet Wise, I'm here to relieve you.
If you ask me, something big is coming.
Only one day's march from New Market.
By Saturday night...
the battle will begin the next day.
You and Breckinridge figure it all out?
Well, I have it
from Grant himself, actually.
We shared a whiskey, foul cigar.
He said let's end
this whole bloodstained mess...
Sunday at New Market Gap.
I'm sure of it, actually.
It's an omen.
How?
Stonewall Jackson
always fought on a Sunday.
I'm worried about you, John.
If you don't believe
in what you're fighting for...
you won't make it out of this valley.
A man must believe his cause is just
in order to gladly die for it.
Defending our homeland
against strangers?
You know I come
from a family of bankers.
We don't own slaves.
But the South's way of life's depended
on slaves for over 200 years.
You rip it to pieces all at once,
and you destroy the rest of us.
We should not be fighting
to keep people in chains.
Will you or will you not
defend Virginia?
I will defend my family.
My friends are my family.
This school is my family.
I will fight for that.
But if God grants us victory,
we must change.
Keep your thoughts to yourself, John.
The others, they...
they may doubt your resolve.
They would be fools if they did.
Sir, Union Cavalry in force
approaching from the east
just on the other side of that hill.
So it is to be tomorrow.
Finally.
- We'll have Wharton?
- Almost certainly.
Goddamn it, Major!
Can you not speak plain English?
Is that half certain?
Is that more than certain?
At least half.
We will win tomorrow, sir,
because we have to.
- I didn't hear that, Charlie.
- I said...
I do not want to hear the language
of losers from you, Charlie.
Victory will not come
because we think it must.
Well, then, what is the language
of the winners, sir?
I will lose, and I will die,
and I will fail everything
and everyone that I love
unless I find the way to win.
The Confederates
cannot sustain the losses.
Is that what Grant says?
The general doesn't speak
in predictions.
Nor in boasts.
What news does he give
of the Valley campaign?
We're better fed, better supplied,
more experienced.
The report is...
that Breckinridge has actually
conscripted schoolboys,
cadets from the Virginia
Military Institute,
he's so desperately shorthanded.
So we've stooped
to massacring schoolboys?
Only if he chooses to use them, sir.
Help me, please! Somebody!
Please, sir, can you spare a moment?
Can you help us, sir?
- My sister's hurt.
- Get away from me.
- Her leg is... Please.
- Somebody help me!
- Somebody help us.
- Help me!
- Please! Help me!
- Mister.
Anyone asks, I'll be right back.
Keep marching!
Please, sir, help us.
- We're gonna get you out of here!
- Please, help me!
- Go to the other side.
- Help me!
Moses, let's go.
I got it.
Ready, come on.
- Help me!
- Come on, Moses!
- Think it's stuck on something.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Are you okay, Miss?
- What are you doing here?
- Don't break rank!
- But you are, sir!
- Let him help.
- What are you doing, Jack?
Somebody needs help, don't they?
Don't you worry. We're gonna get you out.
Jack, take this side.
Yeah, pull her out!
Ready? Lift!
You okay?
- Thank you.
- Of course.
- You all right, darlin'?
- Okay.
- Don't you worry. We gonna send help.
- All right.
You're gonna be okay now. I promise.
All right, boys!
We got a battle to fight, remember?
- Let's kill some Blues!
- Let's go.
Thank God! Thought you had
a sudden attack of humanity.
It's gonna be all right.
- Stand easy, men.
- Do you have time for this?
If I might be asking them to lay down
their lives in the morning,
then I can surely make time.
- Oh, right.
- Cut your toe off.
Bet you you cut your toe off.
I'll grow it back.
Gentlemen.
John C. Breckinridge.
- John Wise, sir.
- Governor Wise's son?
- Yes, sir.
- I did not know you were out here.
I have the privilege of knowing your
daddy. He is an extraordinary man...
and a very able general.
I'll send him a wire.
You have a message for him?
That I love him.
'Course you do.
All right, stand easy.
Sit down. Sit down.
Well...
purpose of this little visit
is because it's my fault you're here.
In many ways, it's my fault that
everyone is here in this valley,
'cause when I was Vice President,
I tried to solve this problem, and I...
I could not.
And now good men
of the North and the South...
will die here,
and I will have some difficult decisions
tomorrow, some of which...
may involve you.
So I'd like to know
what you think of the war,
what your plans are for afterwards.
Young man?
We find ourselves invaded
by a conquering army
whom I must consider foreign invaders.
Defending our homeland is an imperative,
and I can't understand anyone
who thinks otherwise.
- Who might you be, sir?
- I'm Thomas Garland Jefferson, sir.
- Are you, indeed?
- Yes, sir.
Well, my family's owned a plantation
for close to 150 years,
so I'm defending my heritage
and my future,
but that ain't the whole of it.
I believe folks of a certain class
have a heavy responsibility.
We must use our position to see that
the common folk among us are cared for.
Well, we common folks
surely do appreciate that.
- I meant no offense, sir.
- None taken.
Your good heart
does you credit, soldier.
Who's next? Young man?
I think war is stupid and cruel...
and nowhere near as necessary as...
those leading the fighting
like to tell themselves.
I see.
And do you think I could negotiate
our way out of this thing tomorrow?
No, sir, not any more.
We will stand with you and fight.
And what of your future?
All I know I really want
is to find the right woman,
settle down...
provide somehow for her
and our children.
That sounds like a good plan.
I will fight Grant's bullies, sir.
I thank you.
I tell everybody...
I'm going to be a farmer,
but if Mr. Wise would let me,
I'd like to help him be governor.
Is that so?
You seem very quiet, young man.
My family and my home were burned.
I'll kill as many Blues tomorrow
as God permits, sir.
Young man,
I'm truly sorry for your loss.
This cadet here, his name is Moses, sir.
He's a genius artist.
You should see his portraits.
I would like to try
my hand at sculpture.
- It's a hard way to make a living.
- Yes, sir.
Look, I know that you must be afraid,
and I know because I'm afraid.
We all are, but we must all
take strength from your teacher,
Stonewall Jackson.
Do not take counsel of your fears,
to which I would add,
do not let anger ruin your lives.
This war...
will end, I swear to you,
and you boys...
you're the future of this country.
And having met you,
the future is bright.
So you all sleep well,
and God bless you tomorrow.
God bless all of us.
- Duck, gather the boys.
- Yes, sir.
Company, at attention!
Fall in on me!
Don't make me say it again. I'm tired!
Bow your heads, gentlemen.
Heavenly Father...
this morning, we march into the valley
of death as brothers in arms.
Help us to be strong.
Help us to do our duty...
for our mothers, for our fathers,
for our sisters and for our brothers,
wherever they may be.
- Amen.
Form 'em up, and move 'em out.
Company...
fall in on me!
Left! Left!
Left, right, left!
Looky here!
You boys are babes in arms we got!
You little boys want
a sugar rag to suck on?
Hey, does your mommy know
you snuck out so early in the morning?
Poor little boys, little old boys!
Poor boys.
- Confederate infantry already?
- Sir, General Breckinridge just arrived
with the units of the Virginia Cavalry forming
just south of the village of New Market.
Bring the 34th Massachusetts forward,
back from their defensive positions.
Get the cavalry to go east
toward that mountain!
Where is Echols?
- He's getting into position.
- Calvary probes?
- Already commenced.
- Reserve units?
All in position, including the cadets.
I want those boys at the very rear.
You understand me?
And I want 'em protected.
Of course they are.
Everybody ready? Fire!
Wake up the Yankees. Time for breakfast.
Fire!
Forward!
Lay down your colors, Virginia!
Slow down! Six paces behind the colors!
Battalion...
- halt!
- Halt!
Drop excess gear...
and prepare to march!
Drop gear!
And prepare to move out!
Put that on the ground.
Captain! Captain, shall we advance?
No. He wants us to commit.
We will not take the bait!
Send this to Sigel!
Facing large combined rebel force!
Immediate reinforcements required!
Commence fire!
Wharton's brigade is in position on the west
side, commanding from the hills to the Pike.
I can see that,
but I do not see Echols.
He has arrived, sir. He's filling in
on the east side of the Pike as we speak.
Commence fire!
Libby! Help me, please!
No matter how many bandages,
there will never be enough.
Colonel Wharton, you move your brigade
from your current position
down the hill at best speed
into that depression
below the Union artillery.
- You'll be protected there. You see it?
- Yeah.
And take the reserve with you.
The cadets will be in last position.
Under no circumstances can they engage.
Send orders to the reserves
to conform their movements with mine.
Men, move out!
Drop in!
Gentlemen, as soon as we go
over the crest of this hill,
I want you to drive your men
straight down into the valley.
You run like hell. Go! Go!
- Company...
- Forward!
- March.
Hit the front side of that hill!
They can't reach us here!
Where the hell are the reserves?
My order was for them
to conform from my moves!
One piece of luck.
Load shells! 2,000 yards!
Give 'em everything you've got!
Fire! Fire!
Run!
This is not a parade!
My God, they're holding formations.
March!
Close up, battalion!
Forward, march!
Mark time, battalion!
- I'll be damned.
- If I didn't see it with my own eyes...
- We're losing 'em behind the house!
- Aren't they trapped there now, sir?
- Only till they decide to charge.
- But we're vulnerable here, Captain!
We defend this hill
for as long as we can!
And halt!
Did y'all see that?
Even the rats held up under fire.
We showed those old boys, didn't we?
Sugar rag, is it?
I can't believe it.
You two actually smiled at each other.
Get ready! He'll be coming
to us Bushong's farm!
We'll give him an Ohio hello!
Follow me, but keep at least
300 yards back, well to the rear!
- Do you understand, Captain?
- Yes, sir!
Virginians... forward!
Come on, boys!
Come on. Come on, boys!
Battalion...
prepare to advance!
First and second rank, ready!
Steady! Steady!
Wait for my command!
Fire! Fire!
God bless those Pennsylvania boys.
Holding fast!
Reload! Hurry up!
Now! Now! Now! Now!
Ready! Fire!
Fire! Fire!
They've torn a hole
in the center of our line!
If we can see it, so can the Blues.
Sir, you must put in the reserves
to restore the line.
When the Union forces regroup and
counterattack, that line will divide in two.
They'll pull right through
the hole in the center.
Sir, you must put in the cadets.
Send the boys in.
May God forgive me.
Sir.
Battalion, forward to the line!
Forward to the line!
Come on!
Let's go! Get to the fence!
- To what?
- Let's go!
Get to the fence!
Fire at will!
The cadets are filling the gap.
Fire!
Keep shooting, boys!
- Johnny!
- I'm right here, Moses!
Fire! Fire!
We can't stay here!
Must be somewheres a little more useful.
Gentlemen, what do you say
we charge those guns?
I don't know, gentlemen,
I bet that sounds a bit dangerous.
John Wise, that was what I was
suggesting. I was just being subtle.
No sense in dying if we can't
figure out who takes the credit, right?
- Sir, battalion is ready to attack!
- We don't have further orders!
No, I don't suspect
we'll get further orders!
The cadets are ready to charge, sir!
I suggest we attack and take those guns
before we get blown apart!
- Fix bayonets!
Fire!
Go get 'em, boys.
What're you waiting for? Face front!
Charge! Charge!
But they're just a bunch
of damn schoolboys. Kill 'em!
Kill 'em all!
Jack!
We showed them, didn't we, George?
Jack, stay with me!
You can't die.
I still gotta whup you good.
I can't carry you forever, Johnny.
It's up to you now.
Come on, Jack! Jack, come on!
Jack!
Retreat now! Now! Run!
Let's go, gentlemen! Someone's gotta
cover this godforsaken retreat!
Let's go!
My God, sir, the cadets
have taken Bushong Hill.
Must be an illusion, Charlie.
Their general told them not to fight.
Where's Jack?
He's dead. Torn to pieces
during the final charge.
And Johnny?
A shell exploded.
Johnny?
Johnny.
Come on.
Here you are. Here you are.
Hey, hey, hey! You come over here!
Give me a stretcher! Come on.
Come on. You'll be all right.
Oh, God.
Johnny, you hear me?
Here you go. Here you go.
You hear me? Hear me, Johnny?
There you go.
There you go. Johnny.
Johnny. Can you hear me?
Johnny.
Hey, we won the battle...
all of us.
People are gonna call us heroes now.
They're the heroes...
Jack...
all of them.
Here.
Bring them inside!
Look at that wound.
Take that young man to the back bedroom.
Could I speak with Libby
just for a minute?
Oh, son, Libby's not here. She's up
at the field with the older girls.
He's at the house. That boy,
he's wounded, but he's asking for you.
Thank you so much.
Will he survive?
Bullet went through his chest
and lodged in his back.
Is this your son?
These are all my sons.
Let's stitch him.
Ma'am? Ma'am?
Do you have a New Testament?
This is a Christian Bible.
I understand you're Jewish?
I'm a Jew.
It's for my friend.
He requested it.
I do not believe my faith will object.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
From the 14th chapter...
of Saint John.
"Let not your heart be troubled:
"You believe in God,
"believe also in me.
"In my Father's house are many mansions:
If it were not so..."
"I would have told you."
"I go to prepare a place for you."
Would you... would you light me a candle?
I don't want to listen in the dark.
My, my, my.
Find me a man who knows
how to set a fire.
Next time we go into
that godforsaken valley,
we'll burn it to cinders.
If I can.
Thank you.
Let's leave him, gentlemen.
We were gonna spend the rest
of our lives... together.
Stand easy.
Mr. Wise. Mr. Colonna.
I am told that you cadets decided to lead
the charge of your own volition.
Is that so?
Are they not teaching you
the value of the chain of command
at the Institute?
- I am sorry, sir.
- Are you?
Then what in good God's name
were you thinking?
My father says the best thing about doing
what's right is it requires no thought...
- no thought at all.
- Well...
I guess I have to thank you...
for not thinking.
Well done, Virginians.
- Well done, men.
- Thank you, sir.
Private Stanard died
on the field of honor, sir!
Private Jefferson died
Corporal Atwill died
on the field of honor, sir!
Sergeant Cabell! Private Crockett!
Private Hartsfield!
Private Haynes! Private Jefferson!
Private Jones!
Private McDowell! Private Stanard!
Private Wheelwright died
on the field of honor, sir!