SOLDIER (O.S.)
Base camp, base camp.
This is Red Four. Over.
Base camp to Red 4,
about 14 clicks out. Over.
ROTH (O.S.)
While I'm out here trying not
to get my ass shot off...
she's back in the States
shacked up with my best friend.
No way.
So the bitch filed for custody.
So I go to First Sergeant...
trying to get home on emergency
leave so I can handle my shit.
You know what he told me?
"Deal with it."
Oh, man, you can't roll over on
that one, you gotta fight back.
Meanwhile she was the one with
the drinking problem, but I'm
unstable because I'm overseas.
Well, you are a little unstable,
we just won't tell them that.
Roger.
Are those tracer rounds?
SOLDIER (O.S.)
Red 4, this is Red 2!
Come inside, contact.
Contact front!
Contact, front!
Command 6, Command 6 this
is Red Four, we've got contact.
IED, IED!
What the fuck are we doing?
You didn't see that truck
in front of us?
Command 6, this is Red 4.
Four VICs intact.
Who's in the VIC in front of us?
SOLDIER (O.S.)
Medic! Medic!
Ramp down, I'm going in!
Doc! You need to wait
for dismounts to kick out.
Don't have a minute!
Medic on the ground!
RADIO TECH
Red 4, we got a medic
on the ground. Over.
Medic!
What the hell?
You're gonna get shot!
Get out of there!
White, come in!
Where are you hit?
I can't feel my legs!
I can't feel my legs.
You're gonna be all right.
Cook, you're gonna
be all right.
10:00, Jersey!
All right this is ready. Angel
to dust off. I need a medevac
500 meters past TRP 1
Doc, we need to get out of here!
You! Over here! Right now!
Help me out!
Get him under the arm!
Get him under the arm.
Go!
Clear!
Nice and easy.
All right, take off his ACH.
Give me some light.
You're gonna make it,
you're gonna be all right.
What is it? Am I gonna die?
Cook, breathe,
you need to calm down, okay?
( SCREAMING )
Please?
Open my bag.
Let me know what you want me
to get from here.
Just open it. All right, I need
you to calm down, okay?
You'll be all right.
( SCREAMS )
What the hell is that?
What is it?
It's got fins.
Holy shit, is that live fucking
ordinates?
You can't touch that, Doc.
We need EOD.
Please, please, I promised my
son I was coming home.
You're gonna cut him open here?
Hold him down.
Please! Please, God,
I don't want to die.
Don't move, okay?
( HIGH-PITCHED RINGING )
( NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE )
( SHELLS CLINKING )
WILSON (O.S.)
You okay, Swann?
Yes, sir.
I heard about what you did out
there. If he pulls through,
it's because of you.
Shit luck on your last day.
( SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING )
SOLDIER (O.S.)
What's up, Swanny?
Boy, you suck.
Welcome to the party.
Ah, it's good
to be at the party.
Ducky, my man.
You know your kid is gonna go
ape-shit when he sees you?
He better.
All right, one last one.
No! No, no!
You gotta be in it.
Say Hadji.
Come on.
This is the happiest
day of my life.
Hands down, bar none, the
happiest fucking day of my life.
Mine, too.
( SOFT MUSIC FADES UP )
( CROWD CHEERING )
( MILITARY BAND PLAYING )
( MUSIC ENDS )
Left face!
On behalf of Fort Bliss,
and a grateful nation...
thank you for a job well done.
Welcome home and be safe.
Captain.
Company, attention.
Dismissed.
( ALL CHEERING )
( BAND PLAYING )
RICHARD (O.S.)
Maggie.
Hey.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
How was your flight?
Long. Where's Paul?
Oh, Paul, he--
he just wasn't on my way.
I got caught up with a client.
I was showing him one of those
developments over in Mesa...
and the guy said,
"Great, I'll take it."
And the next thing you know,
I gotta check credit
and get a deposit.
Richard, I know what it
takes to sign a lease.
I can still tell
when you're lying.
Goddamn it,
wait a minute.
Maggie!
What?
You know... he didn't want
to come, all right?
I tried to talk him into it,
and he didn't want to come.
I think he's a little bit
confused right now.
You know, it's been 15 months
since you've been gone...
so... that's a lifetime
for a little kid.
RICHARD (O.S.)
Turn over?
Seems to, battery is shot
to hell, though.
Yeah, that's what sitting
on its ass for a year and
change will do.
Well, you don't look so bad.
So Alma hasn't walked out
on you yet, how come?
Well... actually,
we're doing pretty well.
Got engaged.
About a month ago. I was gonna
tell you, but I figured you'd
be home soon enough.
She's pregnant.
Sounds familiar.
We're not telling anybody yet.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You can follow me,
I'll try not to lose you.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
More chicken.
Mm-hm.
What's the magic word?
Please, please, please.
Here you go, sweetie.
Careful, it's hot.
Wow, a garage and everything.
You're really moving up.
He knows I'm coming, right?
Yeah, of course, he knows.
Hey, there, kiddo.
Guess who I brought home?
( DOOR CLOSES )
It is nice to meet you...
finally.
Nice to meet you, too.
Hey, buddy. It's me,
it's Mommy. I'm back.
Hey?
We talked on the computer,
remember?
Alma.
RICHARD (O.S.)
Hey, go give your--
give your mom a hug.
Yeah, she travelled a really
long way just to see you.
No.
Come on, come on.
Hey, what are you doing?
Give her a hug, come on.
It's okay.
We got time.
Sure you don't want to stay for
dinner? Alma cooked up a storm.
Is that all his stuff?
Yeah, well, I figured you'd want
us to keep on a couple things,
because--
...at least until you get to
your, you know, your place.
I have my own place.
You know what I mean,
something permanent.
He's not coming back to live
with you, Richard.
Listen, I know what we agreed,
I know what we said.
I'm saying that he's
doing real well here.
And I'm saying
he's coming home with me.
And then we'll see each other
on the weekends, okay?
You ready?
PAUL (O.S.) No!
Honey, you don't want to make
your mom sad, do you?
She's not my mommy.
Paul, don't say that.
Hey, buddy, listen,
we talked about this.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
Big boys don't cry.
Hey! Hey! Paul!
She's not my mother.
Hey!
( NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE )
( PAUL SCREAMING )
Alma! No!
It won't open!
Alma!
I want Alma!
( PAUL SOBBING )
Hey, Paul...
Paul, I'm sorry.
All right, he's clear.
All right, sir, you're clear,
take your hands off.
Join your friend over there.
( INDISTINCT DIALOGUE )
Get in the shade
and hydrate, Sergeant.
I'm all right.
I said get in the
fucking shade, Swann.
I got this.
We're being relieved in an hour.
That's an order.
( SOLDIERS CHANTING )
Is that enough?
Hey... you want
to see your present?
Come on.
Hold on.
Hm?
You know what it says
on the cover?
Ducky's Adventures
in Afghanistan.
Remember how you gave him
to me before I left?
You made me promise to take
a picture with him every week.
You really don't remember?
Well, you did.
In every page, in every picture,
is me and Ducky.
There he is, on patrol.
There he is in the medic tent.
And there he is with my friends.
I don't play with that
stuff anymore.
It's for little kids.
Forget it. Hm?
Eat it before it gets soggy.
Alma!
Hey!
How are you?
PAUL (O.S.)
Good.
How'd you sleep last night?
PAUL (O.S.) Good.
ALMA (O.S.) Yeah? Okay, good.
How are you doing?
Do you want to water
some flowers?
RICHARD (O.S.)
Tell you what, I think you're
gonna love the marble bath.
I need to talk to you.
Okay. Hey, Donna? I'm gonna
call you back, all right?
I'll call you back and we'll
set it up. All right.
Hey. I'm kind of busy
right now.
He wants nothing
to do with me.
It's been a day.
Did you do anything
to prepare him?
Yeah, I told him his mother's
coming home. What do you
want me to do?
Well, he acts like that woman
is his fucking mother.
Maggie, you've been gone
for a third of his life.
What do you expect?
Yeah, uh-huh, hard,
isn't it?
Hard when you left, too.
Because he wanted Mommy to brush
his teeth.
He wanted Mommy
to put him to bed.
And Mommy to give him
all his food, so he didn't eat,
and he didn't sleep.
And then he started
sleepwalking, which scared
the shit out of me.
What do you mean,
he started sleepwalking?
I mean, he started sleepwalking.
He started walking around
here with his eyes open.
And the doctor said he was--
he was asleep.
Well, where did he go?
Go everywhere, he'd go in here,
he walked into the closet...
and pissed on my shoes once.
Tried to go outside
a couple times...
probably looking for his mother.
Wasn't looking for me.
I didn't know how
to handle him, either.
You know who did
a good job, was Alma.
You should be grateful to her.
Turned him back
into a happy kid again.
I know it's hard, and I know
it's a lot to come back to.
And, uh, I don't know...
maybe Paul should come back
and stay with us for a while.
Why?
'Cause I want
what's best for Paul.
And you don't think
I can take care of him?
I think if you wanted
to take care of him...
you wouldn't have
stayed in the Army.
Need anything?
MIKE SWANN
(ON PHONE)
Hello?
Hey, Dad.
Maggie!
God, they've been jerking me
around for about six weeks.
She'll be back
on this day, on that day.
I'm very proud of you, sweetie.
Thanks, Dad.
And how's my little man?
Paulie, I bet he
was excited to see you.
Yeah, he was excited.
And Richard?
No, he's still Richard.
Do you remember when you were
little, I read you stories?
The one about Rip Van Winkle?
Yeah, I think it was a guy who
fell asleep for like 100 years.
One day the guy wakes up, thinks
everything's gonna be the same.
Can't get his head around the
fact that everything's changed.
That's what I went through
when I came back.
You just have to be
patient, sweetheart.
Were you patient?
No.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
Hey. Hey.
We're gonna start over, okay?
And that means we're gonna
pretend like we've never met
each other before.
My name's Maggie.
What's your name?
Paul.
Paul? Nice to meet you, Paul.
How would you like some
space to run around in, Paul?
Okay.
Hey. Want to give me a hand?
Right.
Don't judge, just eat.
Wow.
Mm-hm.
Wow. That's a kick-ass
burger. You're right.
I swear it's worth deployment
just to come home to eat
and fuck.
Here I'm still trying
to work on that second part.
See? I'm married,
otherwise I'd happily oblige.
Shut your face.
God, you're so gross.
So what's up with the
reassignment?
Mm, Charlie Company, 2nd
Platoon, the platoon sergeant
was killed in a car crash, so...
I heard about that.
I also heard that CO
is a bag of dicks.
Mm-hm.
Good luck with that.
Thank you.
What's up?
I don't know, fuck.
You know, I just couldn't wait
to get out of that hell hole,
and--
I don't know, now since
I've been back...
I don't even know what to do
with myself half the time. So...
I know. Me, too.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
Hey.
This must be Paul.
You see that bed over there?
That's yours if you
want to keep sleeping.
You're gonna have fun.
You're gonna make some new
friends, okay?
I don't want to go, Maggie.
Hey, we're gonna do something
special for dinner tonight,
okay?
Okay.
Iron soldier, sir.
Team Bliss.
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
Sergeant Swann! Come on in!
Reporting for duty, sir.
At ease.
I've heard a lot of great
things about you, Sergeant.
I commend you
on your Bronze Star.
Thank you, sir.
Glad to see you re-enlisted.
You are a glutton
for punishment.
You want some tea?
My wife's got me drinking tea.
No, thank you, sir.
So how does it feel?
Be back second time around?
It's always an adjustment, sir.
I always say, coming home is a
lot harder than going to war.
So many damn expectations.
Yes, sir.
So, what's the deal?
You married, you got kids?
I have a son, he's 5.
Oh, man, that's a great age.
I have a couple of little
ones myself.
How old are they, sir?
Oh, the photos
are a little out of date.
It's amazing how fast
they grow, huh?
It is.
So, I take it you know why
you've been assigned here.
Yes, sir. I'm sorry about
Sergeant Stevens, I heard
about the accident.
Man survives Anbar to kiss
a guard rail on his way
to the Wal-Mart.
Find the justice in that.
Now here's the deal.
We are in the pipeline
to ship out in nine months...
and I've got an ambulance
platoon walking around like
a chicken without a head.
I'm making you Platoon Sergeant,
until I find a suitable
replacement. You up for it?
Yes, sir.
You got your work
cut out for you.
Moral is in the shitter.
I put in a request with brigade
for a permanent fill, but until
then, you are in charge.
Best guess, you'll be here
three months, maybe six.
Don't suppose you're in a hurry
to deploy anytime soon?
No, sir.
I can't say that I am.
First Sergeant Killens will
be back to show you around.
Welcome aboard.
Thank you, sir.
We got a lot of newbies. Some
of these kids don't have a clue.
Closest they've seen
to combat is Kill Zone 2.
Roger, First Sarn't.
A word of advice. Act like
you're here to stay.
Go ahead and secure your gear.
I'll be in there in a minute.
BUTCHER (O.S.) Hurley.
HURLEY (O.S.) Sarn't.
Where are your 02 tanks?
I got them right there, Sarn't.
5 gallon water jugs?
I got my camelback, Sarn't.
You got a heat casualty
with a core temp of 112...
and you wanna cool him down
with your canteen?
How you think that's gonna
work out for you?
Not good, Sarn't! You want me
to grab the water jugs on it?
Fucking fix it.
Roger, sir.
Everybody circle up!
Meet your new Platoon Sergeant,
Sergeant Swann.
Just got back from theater.
Second time over.
Sergeant, these are your squad
leaders, Sergeant Morrison.
How are you doing, Sergeant?
Nice to meet you.
Sergeant Williams.
Nice to meet you, Sarn't.
Sergeant Butcher.
Nice to meet you.
I trust you'll make her
feel welcome.
Hoowah.
All right,
dinner is almost ready.
It's looking good.
Alma usually makes
the yellow rice.
Okay.
Eat.
It's too crunchy.
Alma doesn't make it crunchy.
You know, I really don't
care how Alma makes it.
This is how I make it. Okay?
I don't like it.
Just take the skin off, huh?
See? There.
Can you just eat properly,
please?
Don't even think about it.
Pick it up, now!
Pick it up! Pick it up!
You think this is funny?
Ow! You're hurting me!
Do you? Pick it up now!
Don't you ever disrespect me,
do you understand me?
If I tell you to eat something,
you eat it.
Pick it all up!
I want Alma.
You can cry for Alma all you
want, you little shit.
ANNOUNCER (V.O.):
For Monday, mostly sunny
and not as warm.
ANNOUNCER (V.O.):
High temperature 60 to 65
degrees.
DONOVAN (O.S.) Close 'em.
MAGGIE (O.S.) Can I trust you?
I think so.
Okay.
Sit down... you better
keep them closed.
Hey! What the--
You're gonna ruin my surprise.
All right, open them again.
Make a wish.
Where'd you get that?
Oh, no, where there's a will...
I got a little leprechaun
back on base.
Mm. Oh, my god.
Hey, happy birthday, kid.
Oh, my god, I think
I love you. I'm just kidding.
Oh, my god, thank you!
( DOOR OPENS )
Oh, Christ. You scared me.
What are you doing?
Paul?
Hey. Hey.
I'm sorry
I yelled at you, okay?
Hey. Hey, look at me.
Where are you trying to go,
buddy?
Okay, so you can pick out one
thing for your room...
but then we gotta get everything
else on that list, all right?
( LOUD CLANK )
Oh, no. Oh, god.
Shit! God.
It's all right, hold on.
Hold on.
Piece of shit.
You said a bathroom word.
( ENGINE STALLING )
( SPEAKING SPANISH )
Can I get some help?
Sure. What do you need?
I had to get it jump
started to get it here.
Let's see.
It'll be the alternator.
I doubt it.
Yeah, why is that?
The battery probably drained
out. So what, I need a new
cylinoid?
And your battery cables
are corroded, too.
So, how much?
$400.
If you want to rob me,
just put a gun to my head.
I'm not trying to rob you,
I mean, we're talking
about parts and labor.
No, we're talking about
a $30 part, and you should be
able to do it in 40 minutes.
I'll do a special price
for you. What about that?
Maggie, I have to go
to number two.
Do you want me to come with you?
No?
I can do it by myself.
Okay, good.
It's white door, over there.
He looks like you.
I thought he was your son.
He is.
Okay, I just need some initials
and signature and that's it.
I think I can have it for
Thursday. If I get it done
sooner, I'll call you, okay?
Is there a car rental agency
around here?
No, nothing like that.
You need a ride?
Is there something
I can rent from you?
Not really, no.
What about the bike?
My bike?
You got a license?
Ah, since I was 16.
What about the kid?
How old is he?
Old enough
for the state of Texas.
Ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
Hi.
Um, Paul forgot his sandals,
I thought you might need them.
Uh, he's actually sleeping.
We get up early.
Okay.
Come on in.
Thanks.
Um, I'm just in the middle
of doing some laundry, so--
Um, I just wanted to see
how he was doing.
Do you guys need anything?
No, we're fine.
Okay.
Thanks.
I don't know if Richard
mentioned the sleepwalking?
Uh, yeah, I know.
It was really stressful
in the beginning.
But, it's not dangerous,
so long as he doesn't get
out of the house.
You should hang some bells
along the doors, it seems
to help with him.
I don't really sleep anyway,
so--
I guess I just, um...
It's just I really miss the
little guy, you know?
He misses you, too.
( BEEPS )
Alma usually makes them
in the pan.
Does she?
Well, she can make them
her way tomorrow.
Do you like trucks?
Me, too.
You said you like trucks.
Wow.
Go on, yeah, yeah, yeah,
of course.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
What do you think?
I like.
Huh?
That steering wheel
is bigger than you.
All right, are you ready to
drive this green machine?
Uh-huh.
Do you know what you're driving?
Do you know how to drive it?
Uh...
Do you know what these are?
These...
These are your terrain switches.
Highway?
Highway, that's it.
Right here, here you go.
This is Little Truck,
Big Truck, are you there?
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
Pull it, pull it. Good?
Here we got lots
of all these colors.
Thank you, specialist.
It's called a rifle, it's what
we actually use over there
to fight the bad guys.
Alma doesn't have a gun.
I bet she doesn't.
Let's try opening
your eyes next time, dude.
Yeah, like you did any better.
So what, man? I'm a fucking
ambulance driver.
You think the insurgents give
a shit that we're medics?
Negative, Sarn't.
Get over here.
Roger, Sergeant.
If you do not hit your target,
you'll bring back your buddy
in a body bag, you want that?
Negative, Sarn't.
Hit the ground.
Roger, sir.
You will go until you puke
and then you will give me
another 200.
Roger, sir.
A word, Sergeant.
Take it easy on Hurley,
he just found out his Mom's
got stage-four cancer.
We all have problems, Sergeant.
The Army isn't about holding
hands, passing out tissues.
What are you saying?
They don't gotta like you, but
if you do not lay down the law,
they will walk all over you.
Are you telling me
how to do my job?
No, Sergeant.
If you see that our guys need
more training, you make sure
they get it.
And maybe I didn't make
myself clear earlier.
When I say lay off Private
Hurley, I wasn't asking
for your opinion.
Roger.
I wasn't sure you were coming.
Car's been ready a week.
Everything okay with the bike?
Mm-hm.
No call back?
You kind of hurt my feelings.
I can tell.
I didn't know you were, uh,
what's that? It's-- S--
Staff Sergeant.
Staff Sergeant, yeah.
You like telling people
what to do, huh?
I like getting things done.
How much do I owe you
for the bike?
I tell you what,
I'll let you buy me dinner.
What do you think?
No, not tonight.
I have plans.
When?
When I say so.
All right.
Clear!
Move!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Medic!
Come on, Diaz!
We got a man dying,
soldier, move!
BUTCHER (O.S.)
Come on, Diaz!
Take your time, Diaz.
It's only his hand,
he's got another.
You're moving so slow,
he's gonna heal naturally.
Hey! Hey!
Where's the blood sweep?
Hurry! Hurry!
Keep him talking. If he's
talking, he's breathing.
How are you feeling?
It fucking hurts, moron.
Come on, find out where all
that blood is coming from.
You're gonna be okay, buddy.
Just take it easy.
Are you trying to save
him or jerk him?
There's shrapnel in his leg,
femoral artery.
No, stop! He would
have bled out already.
STODDNER (O.S.)
You killed him, man.
That's not funny.
I'm going as fast as I can,
Sarg.
Try telling that to his family.
You should be able to do
it in half the time.
With all due respect, Sergeant,
I don't think so.
Time me.
STODDNER (O.S.)
Oh, shit. Damn.
Again!
( MUSIC PLAYING )
Clear!
Medic!
What happened?
It blew off my hand.
We were patrolling and out of
nowhere we heard this explosion.
Am I gonna be okay?
Yeah, you're gonna be fine.
Please.
Where are you from, soldier?
Time.
Whoo!
I don't know.
How about the blue one?
This?
You don't think
it's trying too hard?
No.
( MARIACHI BAND PLAYING )
You're late, Staff Sergeant.
You're lucky we showed up.
How are you doing, little man?
Good.
Remember me? I'm Luis.
We need a chair for you.
Ah, here you are.
What do you guys want to drink?
Orange soda.
Orange soda, perfect.
( SPEAKING SPANISH )
LUIS (O.S.)
Watching TV?
You like baseball?
Mm-hm. The Rangers
are my favorite team.
Mine, too.
And Josh Hamilton
is my favorite player.
Maybe we can watch a game
together sometime?
Okay.
Go Rangers.
Yeah, go Rangers. We're gonna
watch some baseball. Give me
five. Yeah.
Ah, gracias.
Thank you.
Uh, this is my friend Maggie.
Maggie, this is my cousin Elena.
Hola.
Hi.
Wow, I have a feeling we're
gonna be great friends.
Cheers.
( BAND PLAYING )
I love this song.
You want to dance?
No.
Naw, come on.
Ah, let's dance.
No, no, no, no.
Just one song.
No, no, no, I'm actually really
good with this, thank you.
Help me here... uh...
I buy you a ticket
for the Rangers if you
tell your mom to dance with me.
Help me?
Dance with him.
Come on, come on,
let's dance.
How do you even dance to this?
You follow me.
Can you do that?
Come on. Yeah, yeah. Come on.
That's great.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Eh, eh, eh, eh.
What are you talking about?
Come on, come on.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
Ssh.
You're beautiful.
Just fuck me, okay?
Oh, fuck.
Get off! Get off me!
Get off me! Get off!
What?
Get out.
Look, I don't know what just
happened back there, but--
It's not your fault.
I'm sorry if I did
something that--
No, I'm-- I'm sorry.
I should probably go.
You can stay if you want.
Stay.
What does that say?
El Porvenir.
It's the name of my hometown.
It means the future.
That's nice.
It's not, believe me.
It's a good thing you left,
then.
I still got my father and my
little brother back home.
I'm just starting to bring
them over here, you know?
Until then, it's like my
heart is in two places.
What about you?
What were you doing
in Afghanistan?
I was a medic.
Like a doctor or something?
More like an EMT.
I rode around in convoys and
assisted them when they got hit.
Sounds hard.
What?
I don't know too many
Mexicans with blue eyes.
girls in the Army.
Come on in.
Hi, I was on my way out, sir.
You wanted to see me?
Have a seat, Sergeant,
close the door, please.
I just got word from battalion.
They moved up deployment.
We ship out in 60 days.
Sir?
I need you to keep a lid on it
till COB tomorrow when we make
the formal announcement.
This was supposed to be
a temporary assignment.
I have a son,
and you assured me--
I'm sympathetic
to your situation.
But orders are orders.
There's nothing I can do.
What about my replacement?
Last I heard they were trying
to pull someone from distro...
but they're running on empty
same as everyone else.
If you don't mind my asking,
sir, how old are those photos?
A couple of years, why?
Do you ever worry you won't
be able to catch up anymore?
I know what I am...
and I know what I'm good at.
The world's best dad ain't it.
I've come to peace with that.
That'll be all, Sergeant.
Sir.
LUIS (O.S.)
Sir, I told you I couldn't
guarentee the repair cost...
of the roof for your car.
MAN (O.S.)
And now you're telling me
it'll cost 500 bucks?
You guys are all the same,
aren't you?
Why don't you take your
business somewhere else?
Yeah, why don't you go back to
your own country, huh? How do
you feel about that?
You want to see my
green card, pendeho?
You want to see
my green card, asshole?
Get the fuck away from me!
Get the fuck out of here!
I'm gonna report your ass
to the Better Business Bureau.
Yeah, fuck you, coolero!
I don't give a fuck what you do!
I'm sorry you had to see that.
Terrell was picking you up?
You sure?
Okay.
( MUSIC FADES UP )
It's pretty good.
Mommy?
Yeah.
Why aren't you talking?
I've got nothing
to say, buddy.
Okay.
We got a monkey over here.
Yeah. Tell me about it.
You're still cream
and sugar, right?
Ah, no sugar. I'll take it.
Really? Shit.
It's been a long time since
we've been at a playground
together, huh?
Thanks for the call.
PAUL (O.S.)
Hey, Dad.
Hey, buddy, looking good.
I got my orders.
What are you talking about?
My unit was in the pipeline
for deployment later this year
and they moved it up.
You just got back.
I know, but my replacement
hasn't come in yet, so--
No, so you tell them
no fucking way!
Besides, you get out
in like six months, right?
I re-enlisted.
What?
When I was in theater,
I re-enlisted.
Why would you do that?
Because I'm good at my job.
PAUL (O.S.)
Look at me!
I can see you, buddy!
Jesus Christ, Maggie,
I don't believe you.
That's the thing, if a guy
has to go away to work,
nobody questions it.
But if a woman leaves her
family to go to work,
she's a bad mother.
No, we're not talking about
a three-day business trip here.
You know what? Who's gonna
get us health insurance?
Health insurance?
We would buy health insurance.
With what? Your commissions
from those bullshit condos
that nobody wants?
We should have talked
about this.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Oh, so you're the only one
who gets to do whatever
the fuck you want.
No, this isn't about me,
this has consequences for Paul.
Oh, really, consequences?
So you fucking some big-titted
bimbo you met in a bar didn't
have consequences?
Hey! Don't talk
about Alma like that!
RICHARD (O.S.)
You didn't even try
to get out of it, did you?
Oh, you know that's
not how it works.
So what? So Afghanistan?
For how long?
Nine months... maybe a year.
Could be 15 months.
It could be.
So why aren't you
more upset about this?
I am upset about this!
No, no, you just don't
feel anything anymore?
The Army takes that
away from you?
Oh, you don't even know what
the fuck you're talking about.
You know what? I look at you
and I look at the woman
that I met six years ago.
I don't even see the
goddamn resemblance.
You don't give a shit about
anybody but yourself, do you?
That is not true!
Huh? Well, why don't you
give me something then, huh?
Why don't you give me a little
taste of how you feel coming
back after 15 months...
and then you get
to leave Paul again.
It sucks!
Because I'll tell you
how I feel about it.
I want to put my head
through a fucking wall!
You think I don't know
what it's like?
Let me tell you something.
You don't know what it's like.
You don't know what it's like
when there's a voice on the
phone and I don't recognize her.
Somebody rings a doorbell,
and I think, hm...
I wonder
if it's dress uniforms.
Wonder how I'm gonna tell Paul.
I'm sorry.
No, you're not, you're
just trying to break
that little boy's heart.
Because you'll fight for your
country, but you won't fight
for your son, will you?
I don't have a choice.
Bullshit. You had a choice,
and you made it.
And I'll tell you something,
if he comes to live with us,
he's gonna stay with us.
You wouldn't do that.
Well, you made your choice,
so I'll make mine.
Can you play with me?
Do you see I'm in the
middle of something?
It's bleeding.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Can I put a Band-Aid on it?
How come you don't cry?
Alice cut her finger
at Day Care and she cried
for like three hours.
I used to cry when I was little.
I guess the older you get,
you just do it less and less.
I guess it's just a part
of being a grown-up.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
All right, man, looks good.
Congratulations.
See you at the movie all right?
Hey, save me a seat this time.
All right, I'm gonna head out.
This good?
Yeah, it's great, it's all done.
Hang on. Stick around.
Talk to me.
How you doing?
Can't complain.
Can't or won't.
You miss your kid?
Oh, god, every day.
Are you trying to make me cry?
No.
It won't work.
Can't deal with tears.
You can talk to me, though.
You know that, right?
Yeah, I know that.
Because we're all
we got out here.
That's right.
You make me feel good, Maggie.
You always have.
The truth is... you excite me.
Relax. Nobody's coming in.
Mark, we're friends, okay?
You're married.
We're more than friends,
and you know it.
Listen, I've been on the
other side, it's not--
Ssh...
No, that's enough. No.
No, we cannot.
I want you so bad.
No. Look, hey!
I think about you all the time.
That's enough. Stop, stop.
Please stop.
Mark, I mean it, up!
Come on, get off!
You know you want this, Maggie.
Stop it! Get off me!
Get off! Don't do this!
I'm gonna make you come so hard
you'll be begging me for more...
Don't do this.
Let go!
How the fuck?
Ow! Fuck!
Jesus Christ, Maggie!
What are you doing?
I will fucking shoot you.
Come on, Swann, we were just
messing around, right?
No, not me.
All right, I fucked up, okay?
I lost my head for a second.
I'm sorry.
Come on, Maggie, let's not
leave it like this, huh?
What are you doing?
What does it look like?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
You'll feel better if you
talk about it, you know?
No, no, I don't know that.
Is it about going back there?
Did something happen?
A lot of things happened.
Why is it so hard for you to let
your guard down for a second?
Why? You think--
Look, I really appreciate
you trying, but do me a favor.
I don't ask you about your shit.
Perfect. Perfect.
Sergeant.
Yes.
A few of us are heading out
to celebrate my promotion,
care to join us?
I wish I could, but I've got
some load planning to do.
To tell you the truth,
I wish we could just fast
forward the next four weeks.
I feel like a kid
waiting for Christmas.
Don't tell your wife that.
Well, you know what they say,
first wife is for
practice anyway.
Hey, um, congratulations.
Thanks.
MALCOLM (O.S.)
Maybe I could get you
a reassignment.
We just got a two-year
tour to Korea. Super kush.
I could put in a word
with the CO?
Oh, god, are you crazy?
Like I'm gonna leave
my kid for two years.
You tell him yet?
I feel like an asshole.
Orders are orders.
I know... fuck.
I feel like I should be pissed,
and I am, I'm really fucking
pissed.
But you know,
part of me actually...
It's really fucked up.
All I know is you're
one hell of a medic.
Now the trick is to get it right
in the vein, just like that...
because that's where the
medicine needs to go.
and then we put a piece of tape
over it, so it doesn't move.
Nice and easy,
hold on... okay.
Good job. Okay?
Now we're gonna let the patient
rest, because we're gonna talk
about something.
Does that mean no bedtime story?
No, no, we can have a bedtime
story, but just pop up here
for a sec, okay? Come on.
Okay.
Remember how I had to go away?
For a while because of work?
To Afghanistan?
Mm-hm.
It looks like I have to go back.
Why?
Because I have a very important
job and those people
depend on me.
So will you be gone one day?
It's gonna be the
same as last time.
Okay? And hopefully
a little bit shorter.
Well, that's too long.
It is too long.
But the most important thing is,
is that I love you a ton.
Okay, and Daddy's gonna
take really good care of you
while I'm gone.
With Alma?
With Alma.
Now can I have a story?
Yeah, you can have
a story, come here.
( TV BLARING )
Paul?
Paul.
Paul!
Wait! Wait!
Have you seen a little boy?
Five years old, have you
seen a little boy?
Paul! Paul, where are you?
Paul!
( CAR HORN HONKING )
Paul! Paul. Oh, my god.
I want to go home.
Oh, my god,
I thought I lost you.
Go to sleep.
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
Hey.
Maggie... you all right?
Yeah, I'm good,
I need to talk to you.
Now?
WOMAN (O.S.)
Who is it, Brian?
Look, I need you to get me
on that assignment in Korea.
I looked into it, and it's an
accompanied tour, which means
I can take Paul with me.
Who is this?
Uh, Maggie Swann,
we served together.
Just-- give me two--
MALCOLM (O.S.)
She's just my friend, Ami.
AMI (O.S.)
Got any other friends stopping
by I should know about?
Uh-oh.
It's a two-year assignment.
I realize that, but they won't
let me out of deploying, because
it'll set a bad precedent.
This way I'm volunteering
for a longer mission,
everybody's happy.
And you?
We're talking some base clinic
in bumfuck Pyeongtaek.
Where you'll be looking at
sprained ankles and refilling
malaria prescriptions.
Just do this for me?
What's it look like I'm doing?
Downloading porn?
You never know with you.
Sir?
Korea?
You think that's the answer
to your problems?
Sir, I can explain.
How dare you go
behind my back?
I apologize, sir,
I was going to tell you.
I'm trying to fight
a war here.
You think you're the
only one with a family?
No, sir.
You know what you are?
A baby.
Besides it's too late,
they're never gonna grant it.
Country first,
you ever heard of that?
Yes, sir.
Try living it.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
Lift!
Looking good. Move it!
Keep it going.
Thanks.
Thanks for dinner.
Just eat.
What about you?
Not hungry.
You're not hungry?
Mm-mm.
You said you wanted to talk?
I was riding with an infantry
unit and we were working a TCB.
Basically a checkpoint
for cars.
It was an especially hot day.
We were a few guys short,
so I volunteered to run
some of the searches.
And the guy running the squad,
Staff Sergeant Donovan...
we were like equal in rank,
but it was his mission.
I must have looked like I was
gonna pass out...
because he comes over and he
asks me to take a break.
I'm all right.
I said get in the fucking shade,
Swann. I got this.
And he takes my place.
And then a car drives up.
Stop.
( SPEAKING PASHTO )
Turn off the car.
Get out of the car.
Get going, open it up.
Hurry up! Open the hood up.
Let's go.
Keep walking. Keep walking.
Far side looking good.
Keep walking. Over here, start
walking. Here. Hurry it up.
What the fuck you got up there?
Let's go, then. Hurry up!
Let's go. Fuck!
Go!
DONOVAN (O.S.)
Shut up.
You see anything in there,
Kolozel?
( SPEAKING PASHTO )
Let's go! He's gonna go over
there and fucking search you.
Let's go! Keep walking.
Sir! Hurry up!
Sir! Excuse me! Excuse me.
I need you to step over here,
we're gonna search your body.
Sir! Sir! Please be quiet.
All right, listen to me!
Shut the fuck up!
Sir! I need you to step
over here, we're gonna
search your body.
Popcorn! Popcorn!
Allah akbar!
( HIGH-PITCHED RINGING )
There were no bodies.
Three guys standing there one
second... and then nothing.
That's not your fault.
You didn't ask him to take over,
just-- I mean, he was doing
his job.
No, he took my spot because
of something stupid he'd done.
But that's not the point,
I don't expect you
to understand.
Why not?
Because I wasn't there? Because
I don't know what it's like?
You don't.
You don't have to be in a war
to see people get killed
for no reason.
Try coming back to a life
that doesn't want you in it.
You know,
sometimes I think that--
Sometimes I think Paul
would have been better off
if I hadn't come back.
No, he wouldn't be better off.
How do you know?
I know what it's like
to grow up without a mom.
And believe me, you don't
want that for him.
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING )
( PHONE RINGING )
Hey.
MALCOLM (ON PHONE)
You can have the re-assignment.
Now you gotta talk to your CO.
Ball's in his court.
Wow. I really owe you.
I won't forget.
Thanks, man.
Three weeks from deployment.
You gotta be shitting me?
Sir, I would not be doing this
if I didn't think there was
a suitable replacement.
And who might that be?
Sergeant Butcher.
No kidding.
He's tough, he's demanding.
He served two tours in Iraq
and he's got his E6.
He's more than capable
of leading this platoon.
You willing to stake your
reputation on that?
Yes, sir.
You don't back down easy,
do you?
No, sir.
And why is that?
I love my son
and I love my country...
and I don't think I should
have to choose between them.
Your son will be here when
you get back, just like
all the other kids.
With all due respect,
no, he won't.
If I deploy with our company,
my ex-husband wants
sole custody.
That's exactly what
my ex-wife did to me.
Except she didn't have the
decency to warn me first.
Final decision isn't up to me.
But you make the recommendation.
So now you want me to help you.
Yes, sir.
You are a royal pain in my ass,
you know that, Swann?
Yes, sir.
Hey, Sergeant?
Yeah.
You mind if I ask you
a question?
Shoot.
Word is you're
skipping out on us.
Who told you that?
Is it true?
It's not final, but I do
have my son to think about.
You'll be in good hands.
With who, Butcher?
I'm not at liberty to say.
The guy is a nut job.
Okay, he doesn't know
the half you do.
And what about you
always having our backs?
Talk is cheap, Sergeant.
Is this about you getting
even with me? Huh?
Hey, he's sleeping.
Huh? You're gonna take Paul
halfway across the world...
where he doesn't speak the
goddamn language, he doesn't
have anybody but you?
And you're gonna be off at work
all day like you always are.
And that's in his
best interest? Huh?
No, I know it's not
a perfect solution.
And when do he and I get
to see each other?
Once a year? If that, if we
get lucky? If I go to Korea?
Why are you doing this?
You didn't give me a choice.
And you always said a child
should be with his mother.
Always!
Yeah, well, you're not
what I had in mind.
Well, you got your new family
to think about now, don't you?
I do, and Paul's in it.
I'm gonna get him back,
and it's gonna be for good.
Is that what's best for Paul?
You'll be hearing
from my lawyer.
Is it?
( CAR ENGINE STARTS )
Show me your tourniquets.
Tourniquets.
Headlamps.
Lamps.
Turn them on.
Uh... mine was working
yesterday, sir.
Fuck yesterday.
You got extra batteries, Diaz?
Shit... uh.
Want me to go get some extra
batteries at the supply room,
Sergeant?
DIAZ (O.S.)
I'll get some right now.
Sergeant?
( PHONE RINGS, VIBRATES )
Swann.
Hello?
( RINGING )
(ON ANSWERING MACHINE)
This is Derek Butcher,
I can't come to the phone.
You know what to do,
so do it.
I gotta go.
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
Butcher, it's me.
Open the door.
Come on, I see the light.
Open the door, that's an order.
What do you want?
You gonna let me in?
Cut the shit and open the door.
I wasn't expecting company.
Where's the furniture?
Bonnie took it.
Left the coffee maker,
though, so, that's a plus.
Sorry.
Did you get in a fight?
Yeah, some college shitheads...
acting all friendly.
Like they knew me,
why I joined.
They don't know shit.
I told them not to touch me.
I fucking warned them.
You ever feel
like killing somebody?
All the time, just waiting
until I get paid for it,
that's all.
Mm-hm.
Is that why you decided
to become a medic?
Every time I light up those
Hadji motherfuckers, I'm gonna
be thinking about my wife.
It's her face I'm gonna see,
underneath those fucking
turbans.
Get that shit out of my face.
Give it to me.
Relax, Sergeant.
Give me the fucking gun!
What's in it for me?
Me not calling the cops.
I knew you were no fun.
Why'd you call me tonight?
Wrong number.
God! Goddamn it!
Fuck!
( DIALING )
GARVER (ON PHONE)
Hello? Who's this?
Sergeant Swann, sir.
I'm sorry to call you so late.
GARVER (ON PHONE)
What is it, Swann?
It's about Sergeant Butcher,
sir.
Okay, good. Good.
All right, here we go.
I guess this is it, right?
Right here, right now.
If you're looking for tears and
a bed of roses, you better go
looking for another gal.
Maybe I will.
I bet.
Do me a favor.
Take down your hair for me.
This is how I remember you,
like this.
Just so you know,
I plan on coming back.
I plan to stay here.
No promises.
Okay, pick any two.
Any two I want?
Mm-hm.
This one and this one.
Good choice. Okay, so we're
gonna set one to Texas time.
How do you set them?
You gotta pull it out.
And then this one, we're gonna
set to what time it is in
Afghanistan, okay?
And that way, we know what time
it is where the other one is.
Hm.
Sound good?
Now, would you like one
on each wrist?
Next to each other.
Next to each other? Wow.
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
You're late. We're supposed
to go over the custody papers.
I didn't bring 'em.
Jesus.
There's nothing to sign.
I didn't bring them.
I just want
what's best for Paul...
and I don't think that right now
is a good time to be getting
into all of this...
so, just go, and we will talk
about it when you get back.
Thank you.
Okay, where is he?
I'll get him.
Can I do that?
Promise you won't die.
I promise.
Me, neither.
You got it?
Are you gonna hit a lot
of home runs while I'm gone?
Are you excited
about your new bedtime?
8:00, right?
No, 8:30.
Oh, it's 8:30.
Hey, Daddy, we got a new bedtime
of 8:30, are you cool with that?
Sure.
Hey, kiddo.
Hey, buddy,
look what we got here.
Check that out.
You like the color?
Yeah. Can I ride it?
RICHARD (O.S.)
Yeah, I hope so, it's yours.
What are those for?
It's a coaster break,
you stomp on it real hard,
and you pedal backwards.
Mommy?
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy!
( SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING )
Mommy.
I love you, Mommy.
I am so proud of you.
Give me a kiss. Okay?
I love you so much.
Take one of these every four
hours and you'll feel better
in a few days, okay?
STAFF SERGEANT
Swann, change of plans,
you ride with me.
Roger that.
Bedtime, buddy.
( MUSIC FADES UP )
( MUSIC CHANGES )
Oh so familiar
Yes I've been here before
And like a photograph
You're etched in my mind
Always
I know we all falter
We all stumble we all fall
I am tired but I am hopeful
We carry on
Through the fire
Through it all
With each new day
The sun will rise
The sun will fall
The world keeps turning
Turning
I feel it coming
Change within my soul
I'm always learning
Learning through it all
No matter what comes next
I hold my breath
Cannot regret
I am tired
But I am hopeful
We carry on
Through the fire
Through it all
With each new day
The sun will rise
The sun will fall
The world keeps turning
Turning
We carry on
Through the fire
Through it all
With each new day
The sun will rise
The sun will fall
The world keeps turning
Turning
( MUSIC ENDS )