GENERAL DELLA ROVERE
- Has the curfew finished?
- Yes, it's ten past six
Luckily, the sky is also covered.
When it's cloudy is...
Lady, we are first
Eh, you, come here!
I've told you to come here
Shouting is useless, sergeant.
Probably he can't speak German.
Excuse me, sir, could you
tell us where could we find a phone?
I don't know. All the bars are
closed now.
Is it a puncture?
Yes, it's the fourth time and the
spare wheels are damaged.
Ah! If you're looking for a workshop,
there's one near here, round the corner...
...they repair tires.
- Do they?
- Yes
Thank you.
- A cigarette?
- Thank you.
Thank you. Ah, come here! It's
the first one on the left. 'Rechte'
Thanks
- Genoese?
- Neapolitan.
Ah, Naples! Last year we were
in Naples at this time of the year...
...in the Vesubio hotel
- Vesubio
Yes. In the morning I opened
the window and I had the sea just there.
At one side Marcellina, Posillipo
and at the other Capri and Sorrento
- And under the window Aunt Teresa
- Ah! Aunt Teresa
We felt very sorry when we had to leave
Naples, we liked very much that city.
Nevertheless, your fellow 'citizin', I mean
your fellow citizen...
...were very happy when they
saw that we were leaving.
They were so happy that due
to their joy they even shoot us.
I'm not Neapolitan, really.
I was born in Sora...
...a little village between
Naples and Rome
As a matter of fact, I feel
more Roman than... Neapolitan.
Romans don't love as too much either.
Do you live in Rome?
No, I don't. I have been living
in Milan for six months.
Ah! Do you like Milan?
Nothing at all. The weather is unpleasant
...and the inhabitants are
distrustful, hostile and rebellious.
You Italians don't
like too much this war.
We don't like any war.
This is a necessary war
because it's fair.
Don't you agree with me?
Yes, I do, but everybody don't
think the same.
Yes, not everybody. That creates
very embarrassing situations.
- Can I do something for you?
- No, thank. Thanks.
- I'm going to work, by your leave
- Thank you very much, sir...
Grimaldi, engineer Grimaldi
Colonel Müller. I hope I will
see you again.
Me too. I hope it too.
- What time is it?
- Very early, it's six o'clock. Sleep.
Have you gambled tonight too?
Shut up now. We'll talk later.
Did anybody phone?
- You have lost today too, haven't you?
- I've asked you if somebody phoned.
I don't know! Ask Maria.
Maria?
- Who is it?
- It's me. Tell me, did somebody phone?
- Yes, the lawyer Borghesio
phoned twice.
- Someone else?
- No. Ah, yes! Lady Camelli
Cantelli. What did she want?
She told: "Tell the Colonel that
my brother is free
Regards and thanks anyway"
Have they set him free? Are you sure?
Yes, she said that he was at home.
Free. Who can understand
Germans?
- Do you want me to make some coffee?
- No, thanks. Keep on sleeping.
Ah, colonel!
You received a parcel.
I brought it to the dinning room.
I send you a parcel for my father,
I hope you could give it to him
Salami. Always salami
They have disconnected the light again.
Valeria, I'm in trouble
You have to help me
What do you want?
Lend me some things for some days,
I swear I will redeem them really fast
But yesterday Y saw you changing a very big
group of one thousand liras notes
I'm very unfortunate. 100.000 liras
The poor lawyer Borghesio gave them to me
for his son and I have gambled with them
With that money I wanted to earn 50.000
liras... that's what I wanted but...
Besides, it was my lucky night
The night before I lost just a little...
...so the next night I should have
won and look at me...
...the damned German
jinx took it all
It has been a terrible night
Only god knows what I've
suffered.
But if I run these risks,
I do it also for you
Do you that I don't know
what is to live with...
...a woman like you?
That I don't suffer for not
being able to give what you deserve?
You have been repeating the same
things for three months
I can't stand it more
Hello? Ah! It's, lawyer
No, you don't disturb me
at all, I get up very early.
News?
Listen, mister lawyer,
I'm doing my best
What do you say, sir?
The bill?
No, it hasn't arrived yet, but...
...I'm sure that this morning
...everything will be solved
Yes, I understand
I understand your anxiety, sir...
...but don't give up hope
Tell this to your wife too
Yes, I understand. Poor woman,
tell her I'll do my best
But you must trust in me
I've take this case very seriously,
I can't sleep at nights.
Yes, believe me, don't worry. Today, no
matter how much it takes, everything will be solved
Stay calm, sir
Sure, everything is going to be okay
Valeria, listen, is
a life and death situation
If before noon, I don't give
Walter, that avaricious German...
...greedy as a vulture,
the 50.000 liras I promised him...
...he will send lawyer
Borghesio's son to Germany
And what can I do?
If you let me pledge, at least
for a couple of days, something...
No, you've already stolen
me the earrings with the emeralds
- Stolen?
- Yes
But I will redeem them,
I swear it, don't you believe me?
No
Valeria, don't be cruel
I swear I won't gamble anymore
You can do whatever
you want... I'm going away...
- Where?
- To Turin
- I've been offered a job in the radio
- To do, what?
To sing, you stupid
To dance, to act...
to come back to life at last
Valeria, you don't realise these
are bad days...
...very dangerous days...
...but I'm prepared for everything,
I'm preparing something important
I want to organise a tour of
spectacles for the army
Then, when the war is over,
I've promised you that I will form that...
...revue company that your friends will envy...
...I have promised it, haven't I?
- You have promised me so many things...
But, tell me, what can I do if I've
got everything in the south?
Emanuele, you and your south. Do you know?
I'm starting to doubt that that south exists
Then?
Then, what?
I'm asking if you let me
pledge the necklace and the bracelet
Ah, yes! And the ring and the brooch
No, I said no. Don't insist
Listen, why don't you pledge
this ring you gave to me?
The ring with the Oriental
sapphire, ah? Take it
Come on, pledge this
Did you think that I didn't know
that it was a fake? Poor stupid
Nobody has been able to fool
Valeria yet
I never said anything
because I'm a lady
Who is Dorio?
- It's me
- Come in
Excuse me, can I talk to lieutenant Hageman?
- He's busy, but you can come in
- Thank you
May I come in? Do I interrupt you?
Come in. You can come in,
but wait a moment
He was arrested three weeks ago
in San Gregorio
I have been in Marazzi prison
to ask...
...and they have told me to come here
- What's his name?
Canevalli Alberto, de Matía
Check if that name is there
If he is this communist, he was
shot last week
No, he isn't communist. My husband
never has been interested in politics...
...I swear it on this
child's head
He was arrested together with the
communists, but if it's true...
...that he is a good man that
is not interested in politics...
...he'll be set free
- But, when?
- That doesn't depend on us
Could I see him? Bring any parcel
to him, a few clothes?
You have to ask this to the
prison management
Thank you
- Excuse me, please
- Wait, I'm busy
No, ladies first
- What do you want?
- Thank you
We come to ask about lieutenant
Michele Fassio...
...he was arrested last Thursday in Savona
- Are you relatives?
- I'm his wife
I'm his mother
My son is not interested in politics
He fought in Africa and Albania...
...they gave him a medal
- Have you said Fassio Michele?
Please, look it up
Lieutenant Michele Fassio, of
Angelo and Matilde Mazzuero...
...born in Barigotti
on June the eighth, 1916?
Yes
This says that lieutenant Michele
Fassio has been arrested under the...
...charge of being member of armed gangs
that fight against...
...our troops and the legitimate
government of the Social...
...Italian Republic
That's not true
Since September the eighth my husband
didn't go out of my father-in-law's house
When his duty was to
present himself before his superior.
An Italian officer doesn't
need to be told...
...what is his duty
Relax. The Colonel only says that maybe
Michele should have presented himself
You have to understand it, they
are young boys, so many things have happened...
The war has affected Michele a lot
Yes, these are difficult
moments for everybody...
...it's necessary a lot
of comprehension
Hate policy exasperates
the spirit...
...but don't give up hope...
...our German comrades have always
been very comprehensive
Let's go, mum
I told you we couldn't expect
anything from this people
- What a temperament!
- A cup of coffee, colonel?
If it's coffee- coffee, yes. But
if it's like the last time...
- It's like the last time
- It's okay. Thank you, miss
- I have seen the lawyer Borghesio
- And?
He wasn't able to get the money,
but he gave something that is more valuable
Look at this wonder, an Oriental
sapphire, mounted in platinum
I'm sorry, but I wouldn't
know what to do with it
- I said 50.000 and it must be 50.000
- But this is much more valuable
- I want the money
- Jewels are a good investment
They can be identified and money can't
- A sapphire is always a sapphire
- I want the money
Don't be stubborn, Walter
What can I do? Where can I find it?
I think it's very easy. If the ring
is worth more than 50.000 liras...
...you can sell it and keep
the difference. It's easy, isn't it?
Yes, but it's a pity,
I wanted you to have it
You're engaged, someday you
will get married, won't you?
Someday. But can happen many things before
that day arrives
Here is the coffee
Then we agree, colonel
Always at your service
Thank you,
Walter. See you
Can we do anything for that mistress Fassio?
No. That is a hopeless case
- And I think that girl is very disagreeable
- I don't think so
Remember colonel...
...I wait for you tomorrow morning
- I'll be here
Ladies, I wait for you in
that bar. Good news
- Do you want to sit there?
- Thank you
Please
May I? Colonel Grimaldi
The Gospel say: Don't judge and
you won't be judged
So, you mustn't rely only
on appearances, lady
I have told you my name...
...don't ask me why I
am connected with Germans
These blue badges say that
I have served to my country...
...with fidelity and honour
The country, our country...
...denigrated and abused
Three coffees, but it has to be real coffee
- Neapolitan?
- Yes
Excuse me for the way in which
I've asked you to follow me...
...but these days we are living
in justify it
Ladies, I'll be brief
Let me be discreet about
some questions...
...as you probably will be in
other matters
- I suppose you have understand me
- No
I wanted to say that in these special
circumstances...
...some reserve is,
I would say, is... necessary
Listen, colonel, we should be outspoken
If you can do something
for my husband, tell me what and how
But Carla!
Let's come to the point. You ask me
if I can do something for your husband
I answer you: In the limit
of my possibilities, yes
Unfortunately, the charges, I don't know
if fair or unfair, are serious
Ah, somebody is waiting for me,
his case is very similar to yours
I think I've done the right thing, that's
what matters, help us each other
In spite of any party hate
Excuse me a moment, I'll be back right now
Carla, I think he is a good man
Listen, you can be calm,
your son won't go away...
...I'll give you my word
Thanks for all that you have
made for my poor son...
...and also for what you are going to do,
but, do you think that it's possible...
...that they set them free?
Don't ask for too much, for the present
we should be happy with this
Later, we'll see
Lawyer, I want to talk you about some matter
Two ladies whose names
I can't say...
...need to dispose of an
object of their family
An Oriental sapphire
- It's beautiful, very beautiful
- A unique jewel just for 50.000
50.000 liras!
Who will give them to me?
Listen, to be able to get the 100.000
liras that I've given to you...
...I've had to mortgage the house
And you can't imagine the conditions
- Yes, I can
- But, colonel, if you want...
...I can show it to some friends of mine
No, no. It doesn't matter, don't
worry. Goodbye, lawyer
- Thank you very much, colonel
- Don't worry
Excuse me. Haven't you
taken the coffee? It's authentic coffee
We have always drunk authentic
coffee at home
We have quintals in the cellar
Don't mind her, colonel
- She's nervous. Don't leave us
- No, don't worry, madam
Listen, colonel. If anything is necessary,
if you need something...
Mum, do you think that Michele can be
released because his father is rich?
And the others? All that men that
have been arrested like him...
...the others, will you pay for all them?
- I'll take charge of this
- Where could I find you?
- You can phone us. Fassio...
- 86386
- Fassio.
Fassio 86386. Very well
Madam, I hope that I will give
you information about your son as soon as possible
Thank you. Bye
There's nothing new in
the front of Anzio
An enemy bombardier has been
drifted by our fighters
Two planes haven't come back to
the base, they are disappeared
- This has been the first bulletin in the night
- Good morning, Mrs Pina
A bargain, a beautiful Oriental
sapphire. It belonged to my mother
An unique objet just for
100.000 liras. Look
Yes, it's very beautiful, but I can't
I can give you easy payments. You pay
a part now and the rest with hire system
It's very beautiful, I'd like
but we are in a bad moment
Pay me 50.000 and we take away the
rest from the money I owe you
Don't tempt me, I can't buy it
Look. I have been able to find
some chops. Good morning
- But, what's the matter?
- Nothing. Business with Mrs Pina
- Bye, Michelle. Good morning
- Good morning
A bargain, a beautiful Oriental
sapphire. Look what a wonder
- I've thought about you
- It's beautiful, very beautiful
- 80.000 liras
- I like it, but I'm not interested
I'm very sorry, but I don't want it
- Are you sure?
- I'm sorry. It's beautiful, but...
A bargain, an Oriental
sapphire. Very beautiful
It belongs to a Jew lady. You understand
me, she has to sell it
- She content herself with 70.000 liras
- No, thank you. I'm not interested
It's closed. We open at two o'clock
I'm a friend of Miss
Olga. Open, please
- She is eating
- Tell her I'm an old friend
Who is asking about me?
- It's me, Olga
- Emanuele
Olga!
- How did you know that I was here?
- I found a friend of yours two days ago
Evelina
Two days ago? She went away three weeks ago
I wanted to come right away, but
I had many things to do
I imagine it. And
now, why have you come?
I feel like seeing you again
- I expected that it would be reciprocal
- Seriously?
- I see I was wrong
- You are right, you were wrong
- Then, goodbye
- Olga, your food is getting cold
- Mrs Vera
- Emanuele
What a surprise! How are you?
And, what are you doing in Genoa?
The house of Livorno was bombed,
so I've moved here
Why haven't you told me that
Emanuel was here? Have you eaten yet?
Well, really, not yet
- Eat with us, we will love it
- No, I don't want to disturb
Don't be silly. Come on, get in
We have to talk a lot, it has been
ages since we saw each other.
- Do you mind?
- Me? She is the owner
- I'll stay
- Yes, of course
- Ready
- Come, come with me
- Give him your seat. Olga!
- Pleased to meet you, girls
You, take this plate off and
start to serve
Tell me, all this time,
what have you been doing?
- Where have you been?
- A little here, a little there...
- Sometimes up and sometimes down
- Yes, a little up and a little down
But you, always up. Do you know that
I see you really fine, Mrs Vera?
- I defend myself
- How is the job going?
What do you expect with the
curfew at night?
- Besides, people are worried
- Yes, that's true
And you, what are you doing now?
Apart from gambling, of course
I've quit it. Well, almost
I'm not interested in it anymore
- Now I'm a serious person
- Oh, come on!
- I buy and sell jewels
- As you did before
No. This is not the same
- Now I do business with this
- It's very beautiful!
Let me see
It's wonderful
Give it to me
Marvellous
It's a beautiful Oriental sapphire
This is a good moment to buy
There is necessity and it's sold cheap
The lira goes on falling and the
jewels don't stop increasing
It's a magnificent jewel, but
who knows how much it costs
Not too much, 50.000 liras. It belongs to
a woman who is in a bad moment
Her husband is in
Sicily
- Yes, but... 50.000 liras...
- I'll buy it
- You?
- Yes. Can't I buy it?
Well, Mrs Vera was interested and also
that other girl
- Oh, I don't care, if Olga likes it
- I'll give you a check
- Really I...
- Don't you trust me?
- No, it's not that
- Then, what's the matter?
- Has it been a long time since you saw her?
- Yes
- Since Livorno?
- Yes, since Livorno
- Then we went to Spezia and...
- She has changed a lot
She's nervous, she
quarrel with everybody...
...if I didn't love her as if she was
my sister...
Do you want Mrs Vera
to sign too?
Excuse me
Emanuele
Come
If Mrs Vera or one of the girls
had buy it...
...you'd have taken the money
Why not from me?
And you, why have you given me
the check knowing that this was a fake?
There are 30.000 liras. It's all
I have. Is it enough?
Why are you doing this for me?
I don't know. I don't know. Maybe I know why
You hurt me, but with you
I spent happy days too...
...for the first time in my hole life
I live in the remembrance of those days
No, go!
Go. Go away and don't come back again
- Never
- Miss, go to the living-room
Ten thousand. Bank of ten thousand,
gentlemen
Ten thousand. Nobody wins
- Play, you can bet now
- Bank
Only bank
- Card
- Card. Good for the bank, sir
- And baccarat. 19.500
- Table
Bet, everybody can bet,
you can still play
- Bank
- Play. The bank goes on. Rien va
- No
- Huit a la banque.
- Turn off!
- There's one bank
Thirty-nine, madam. Take your
money, take your money
Calm down, don't worry, there's no danger
Sorry
Broadcast this immediately
"The tuner has arrived"
I gave you definite orders,
I thought I could trust you
For us, it was fundamental...
...that General della
Rovere was captured alive
I've transmitted your orders
You'll have to account
personally for his execution
We didn't know his point of arrival,
I couldn't be everywhere
You justify your conduct very well, but
it's your fault that a brave soldier...
...had been murdered like
a common bandit
But, even if we had caught it
alive, he would have ended up like this
And what do you know?
We could have interchanged him
kept him as a hostage
Listen, the responsible men will depart
immediately for the oriental front
And bury the General in secret
away from Genoa
We'll do it, Colonel
Meanwhile, you can tell that the
General is in our hands
Yes, sir
Something will happen. Somebody will move
You can leave
Can I?
- Hello? Hello?
- I'd like to talk to Mrs Fassio
- Yes, it's me
- Ah, it's you! Colonel Grimaldi
Don't cry, madam. I've got good news
I've taken your husband's case
with a lot of interest
- Really?
- Cheer up, Mrs Fassio
This isn't a very orthodox procedure
What? What are you talking about?
I know a men
who, unfortunately...
...well, fortunately for us,
hasn't got principles. So...
Are you talking seriously?
Alright, we'll meet in the same
café in which we were yesterday
See you, Mrs Fassio.
I'm sorry for the delay
Did my call surprise you?
No, not at all
I mean that maybe you didn't
expect that I did it so soon
But I'll tell you that, since I leave
you yesterday...
...I haven't had other concern
that your husband's situation
I have gone everywhere, I've
used all my connections...
...and I don't want to boast but,
I know many people
Results?
Results... ah... this is not
an easy case, I need time
And a lot of money
You don't know how avaricious
that Germans are
I imagine it
Here you are 100.000 liras, do you think
that this will be enough for the present?
Yes, of course, I'm going to
hand them over, wait for me here...
...I think I'll bring you good news...
...don't give up hope, and trust,
trust in my friendship
- Where is the phone?
- On the right
One moment, Colonel,
I'll be whit you in a minute
- Good morning, engineer
- Oh, Colonel, what a surprise!
What are you doing in suchan unpleasant place?
Any problem?
Yes. Do you remember, Colonel, that you
told me that this was a fair war...
...and I told you that I thought the same
but that not everybody thought that?
Perfectly
Well, I have a young relative and
this unfortunate boy, I'm not ashamed of...
...telling it,
doesn't think as I do
Son of an eminent jurist and
a noble woman...
...great-granddaughter of one of the thousand.
That young man didn't answer to the call of duty
He didn't answered to the call
of his country and besides we let them caught it
I mean he was arrested and
he is going to be deported to Germany
Why didn't he ask for fighting in our
side? He would have been released immediately
- Why?
- Yes, why?
- Do you want to know it?
- Yes, I do
Because of his pride. That boy is very
proud. He is like his... grand-grandfather
She said: If I ask for fighting in
our German comrades's side...
...they'll think that I do it for cowardice,
to avoid the concentration camp
I don't want the brave Germans to think
I'm a coward
- I'll see what can I do for him
- You'll talk to captain Schrantz?
I don't need to talk to anybody,
dear engineer. Come with me
Come in
- What's that boy's name?
- Borghesio, Vittorio Borghesio
Ah! But here it says that
besides deserting...
...that boy made clandestine
activities too
Mister colonel, if we paid attention
to everything the police says...
Engineer, I work in the police
Then, let me tell you that if all
the policemen were like you...
I don't like to be flattered
This Borghesio will stay in Genoa
- He is in the list of transferred
- Then cancel it
- Perfect. He'll stay here
- You are lucky to be able to do good deeds
But this doesn't happen often
I'm going to tell the good
new to his poor parents
And I take the liberty of anticipating
their gratitude and their blessings
I don't like neither gratitude
nor blessings
- Come and see me whenever you want
- I'll do it. Thank you, Colonel
Good news, excuse me, I'm doing an
urgent call and I'll be back right now
Lawyer Borghesio? I am the Colonel
Yes, mister lawyer. Victory!
No, no. Victory for Vittorio
He will stay here. And I hope
that he will be released
I'll tell you when we meet
and give this good new to your wife
No, I don't like neither gratitude nor
blessing. See you
Mrs Fassio, your husband is alright
It has been difficult but at the end
is the word freedom
My husband is free, Colonel...
...he was shot yesterday in the morning
behind the cemetery of Staglieno
Shot?
- But... then...
- Then, what?
- Come whit us. Calm down. Come on
- This is a big mistake
When did you meet that man?
Four or five months ago
In the Olimpia of Mondovi. I was
artist in a revue company
I am a dramatic actress, but these are
bad times and I have to adapt myself...
...besides if you are good at this...
- Try to be brief
- How do you meet this man?
- I've told you, it was in Mondovi
After the show I went with some friends
to a restaurant but it was late...
...and it has begun the
damned curfew
A patrol stopped us and they wanted
to lock us up, then the Colonel...
- What Colonel?
- Ah... him
- Well! You are a Colonel too
- Later... I'll explain it later
- Go on
- Then he escorted us to our hotel
- And then?
- Well, one thing leads to another...
- He obliged me to leave the company
- Go on, please
We went to Genoa, he promised me the moon,
he said that when the South was released...
What are Colonel's activities? And
say the truth, it will be better for you
I don't know what to say, only that he received
many calls, many people came...
...they bring parcels to him
- Parcels? And, what did they have inside?
Personal objects: Clothes,
food, a lot of salamis
I have eaten so much salami
that I have hives
That girl can leave. Over there
You, do you know that man?
Why? Why don't you answer?
Why don't you tell him that
you know me? It isn't anything bad
Colonel, maybe I've made a mistake,
but for a good reason
It started with Mrs Dominicis.
Mrs Dominicis, come here
She lives upstairs from me, one day I found
her crying, her son had been arrested
In the presence of a mother's
pain, what could I do?
- I told her: 'I'll help you', didn't I?
- Yes, Colonel
Do you see? I started this way. Later, more
people come and I feel obliged
What could I do? I wanted to help them
but they never were satisfied...
First they wanted to know if they are alive,
then give her news and parcels
Later they wanted me to avoid them
to be sent to Germany...
Later that I made them to be released
What could I do? Tell me
Put yourself in my place
I was trying to do good deeds
Later I knew terrible things
That they slept standing like horses
That they were beaten and tortured, that
they were sent in a wagon to Matthausen
And I shut up, I didn't have
the courage to tell it to them
Would have they preferred that I tell them?
No, it was better that they had a hope
Only me knew the truth
Set these people free
"Jawhol". You can leave, you're free
Come on
And now tell me: Do you prefer to summon at a
German war court...
...as a Colonel accused of
sabotaging the German law of war...
...or do you prefer to be Emanuel Bardone,
son of Luigi and Teresa Camarano...
...born in Sorrento on May the third
in 1894 and to be denounced for swindle...
...aggravated with the
illegal use of a title
Why are you asking me? In the first
case I could be shot...
...in the second case I will only spend
three years in prison
And the matter of the tittle is ridiculous,
They could fine me with 1.000 to 10.000 liras
The article 310 can be a problem
for offence during the war...
But this war will finish and then there
well be an amnesty like the other time
You were an cavalry officer, you were
expelled for debts and peculation
Later you were condemned for times
for swindle disabled people...
...for possession and sale of
narcotics and even for bigamy
If you had went on in the army,
you could wear a colonel uniform
Yes, of course. And also a general uniform
The sergeant Walter
Hageman has confessed
The sergeant Walter Hageman
was Bardone's accomplice
Well, he must be
punished severely