Afternoon, Mr Smith.
Afternoon, Mr Munroe.
- Hello, Bert.
- Hello, Gus.
- Lovely afternoon. Hmph!
- Not 'alf, it ain't.
- Hello, Mr Miggs.
- Hello, young fellow, me lad.
What you got there?
- Package for Major General Denistoun.
- Retired.
Oh. Been chasin' 'im 'alf over
the bloomin' country, that 'as.
- Oh, it has? I'll see that he gets it.
- [Bell Dings]
- Thanks, chum.
- Righto.
Here you are, Horace.
Give that to Major General Denistoun.
And this here, kindly hand it to
Mr Quentin Reynolds. Do you know him?
Yes. [Sniffles]
He's the American.
All right, hop along now.
And blow your
blinkin'nose, will you?
[Sniffles]
- Food is pretty scarce, though.
- Mr Quentin Reynolds?
- Yes.
- Telegram, sir.
- Thank you, son. Excuse me, boys.
- Thank you.
Yes, certainly.
- Beg pardon, sir.
- Yes?
- Package, sir.
- Oh, thank you, Horace.
Well, I'll be damned.
His ears are pierced.
That's what we've been
telling you, old boy.
Yes, but a man like Denistoun.
Old school tie. Sandhurst.
A general with his ears
pierced like a gypsy.
Why, it's fantastic.
What's the idea?
No one has ever had
the cheek to ask him.
He was in Europe
when the war broke out.
Came home
and there they were.
Must have been black magic.
He came home a changed man.
Used to be a most
frightful stuffed shirt.
Quite a nice old chap now.
I say, what's the rush?
Oh, this. I have to grab
a 5.30 plane for Paris.
But look, if either of you boys
get the lowdown on Denistoun's ears...
- drop me a line, will ya?
- Be glad to, if and when.
- Fine.
- Well, so long, Reynolds.
- And thanks for everything.
- So long, man.
I'll be seeing you.
- Nice fellow... for an American.
- Hmm.
Right. Right you are.
Righto.
Bit of a mob on that Paris plane, sir,
but I finally wangled it.
5.30, Northolt. The fog's lifted.
Oh, you're wonderful, Miggs.
You're beautiful!
I love you, Miggs!
Come, let me give you a kiss.
You'd better hurry, sir.
That is, if you're going to pack.
Thank you, Miggs.
- Why don't you ask me and have it over?
- What?
- At least you'll admit you're curious.
- Curious?
- Why, curious about what?
- My ears.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean-
Oh, come, come.
Own up.
Well, all right.
But it is odd, you know.
What I mean is, they look
like they've been pierced for earrings.
Do they really?
By Jove, they probably do.
Well, well.
- I was wondering if you'd
mind talking about it.
- Not at all. Not at all.
Then why has it been
top secret for so long?
For the very simple reason
that nobody's ever asked me.
Wait a minute.
Let's go back a bit.
How did you know
that I was thinking about your ears?
- How did you know?
- Well, that's part of my story.
There's a woman in it, of course.
A woman of such extraordinary
accomplishments that I-
well, it all started
shortly before war broke out.
I was in Germany. A prisoner.
Before the war? A prisoner?
Yes, I was a lieutenant colonel then.
And together with a youngster
named Byrd was on a special mission.
Very hush-hush, you know.
Not at all in my line, exactly...
except that I spoke
German like a native.
We were trying to nail
a poison gas formula.
Something new. An appalling
by-product of Nazi frightfulness.
Anyway, I don't think
I was very good...
because the blighters knocked us off
like a couple of sitting pheasants.
And we were being held
for questioning, Byrd and I...
in a farmhouse
not very far from Weimar.
[Denistoun] One way and another,
we were in a pretty tight spot.
Our guards, an S.S. First lieutenant
and a couple of troopers...
were as pretty a crew
of cutthroats as ever you saw.
There was also an official
of the Geheime Staatspolizei.
A dreadful fellow named Hoff.
Oh, he was a horror!
He'd questioned us
more than once and we knew.
Young Byrd called him
"Jack the Ripper."
J felt particularly sorry for young Byrd.
Nicest chap imaginable.
His affection for me was positively
touching. A sort of hero worship.
Used to embarrass
the devil out of me.
Though why he liked me
J'll never know.
Looking back, J must have been
a pretty offensive sort of fellow.
You know, pre-war army.
Spit-and-polish.
"Stand to attention when you address
an officer. "All that sort of thing.
Anyhow, we'd planned to escape,
and this was the night.
This was it.
Wasn't much of a plan.
Odds against it coming off...
were about
a thousand to one.
We'd chosen this particular
night to escape...
because Hitler was going
to broadcast from Munich...
and a pretty safe bet his laddie boys
downstairs would listen in.
J didn't know about Byrd,
but personally J was scared stiff.
I don't know about you,
but personally I'm in an absolute sweat.
- Positively trickling, sir.
- [Dog Barking]
## [Triumphal Music On The Radio]
Well, here we go.
- Let's hope only one comes up.
- More than one, we're sunk.
[Hitler, Crowd On Radio]
Sieg heil! Sieg heil!
- Sieg heil!
- Why doesn't somebody throw him a fish?
Sieg heil!
- [Hitler On Radio] Wir mussten-
- [All] Heil Hitler!
... in der minoritaet belieben
wir die wertvollsten...
- elemente des kampfes
und des opfersinns...
- [Dog Barking]
- In der nation mobilisierten die,
die zu allen zeiten nicht...
- [Dog Barking]
- Ah! That dog! Why doesn't somebody-
- shh!
[Hitler]
Die minderheit ausgemacht haben.
Ja. Ja.
- [Crowd Applauding On Radio]
- [Banging]
- Zweig!
- [Banging Stops]
[Hitler]
Weil dieser beste rassenwert-
[Dog Barking]
They're coming, sir.
[Hitler]... mutig und kuehn die
fuehrung des reiches-
Pfeiffer, see what's the matter
with that dog! Pfeiffer!
[Hitler]
...groesserer zahl dieser fuehrung...
angeschlossen und unterstellt.
I say, look!
There's something frightfully wrong!
- J saw him put something
in his mouth. Then he-
- [Zweig] What was it?
- He said it was an aspirin.
- Aspirin! Where would he get aspirin?
And then he had a sort of fit.
His heart's hardly beating!
You're a stupid English swine!
If he's taken poison,
if he's dead, I'll-
[Crowd Cheering,
Applauding On Radio]
[Hitler] Wer sich als traeger seines
besten blutes fuehlt...
und dieses wissen zur fuehrung
der nation erhoben hat...
und entschlossen ist diese
fuehrung zu behalten.
Wahrzunehmen und nicht-
[Crowd Cheering]
Where is Obersturmfuehrer Zweig?
He's upstairs.
He told me to go see about that dog.
You imbecile!
Get back up there!
All right, you blighters!
Take off the uniform.
Tie him up.
I say, old boy.
You can't do that, you know.
[Hitler On Radio]
Von ihnen wird mehr gefordert als von-
- Get on with it, man!
- Sorry.
- Hurry up!
...den millionen der
uebrigen volksgenossen.
[Denistoun] We stole Hoff's car,
a big, black brute of a Mercedes...
and heading for Stuttgart,
drove all night.
One thought cheered us.
They couldn't broadcast a general
alarm for two Englishmen...
without tipping off
the British embassy.
Jt would have to be
a private manhunt.
However, sooner or later,
we knew we'd have to scupper the car.
So shortly after dawn-
- Well, here's where we separate.
- Right, sir.
Now listen carefully. First thing
you must do is get rid of that uniform.
Get some other clothes. You'll probably
have to steal them, understand?
- Perfectly.
- Then make your way to Esbach,
near Freiburg.
Esbach, remember.
And J'll join you there.
Now here's the thing.
Whoever gets to Esbach first...
marks the road signpost
to Freiburg with three dots...
and then waits for the other.
Is that clear?
Quite. Three dots
on the signpost to Freiburg.
Yes. Then we'll carry on
from where we left off.
- Contact Professor Krosigk.
- Yes. How about money?
Loads. Hoff was
absolutely stinking with it.
That's good.
Well, good luck to you.
I say, sir.
Thanks awfully, sir.
- I mean for everything.
You've been absolutely marvellous.
- Goodbye.
Yes, and thanks to Hoff's blunderings,
we've lost a good five hours.
Of course the man
is an idiot. Goodbye.
You are, you know,
with all your brains in your belly.
Hmm. The car was
last seen near Marbach.
If no further reports come in,
I'm going to assume that the car
has been disposed of.
Possibly in a river.
The Neckar, for instance. Come here.
Heavily wooded country.
I think we shall begin from here.
Yes.
## [Woman Humming]
## [Humming Continues]
## [Humming]
[Woman]
Jn there it is very damp.
J have good fire here.
And stew.
## [Humming]
- You are hungry.
- Yes.
Yes. As a matter of fact,
I am, very.
I wonder, would you sell me
some of that, whatever it is?
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I make good fish stew.
- Look.
- Yes, it looks excellent.
Onions and potatoes.
And garlic and barley
and mushrooms.
Plenty of fine, fat fish.
The fish I catch in the river.
The vegetables,
tonight was farmer with a sick cow.
I made it well. Oh, it was easy.
This morning I put black curse on it.
[Branches Rustling]
That is Apple.
- Apple?
- My horse.
Stop watching.
There's nobody.
You're safe here.
Quite safe.
You look like a military man.
Eat! It is good.
Thank you.
- There's something on your chin.
- Huh?
There's something
on your chin.
Ah. This is to keep
evil eye away. Good.
Gypsy superstition.
By the way, I thought gypsies
always travelled around in caravans.
You want to know why
I travel alone, huh?
It was that evil,
misbegotten son of a goat, that Zoltan.
May he rot and swell
and split himself inside out.
With coals of fire in his belly
may he die slowly.
Better you put that
coat on, liebling.
Coat?
Thank you, I'm not cold.
I know it is a military coat.
And there's also a good pair
of trousers too. Huh?
And you were going to throw
into the river that bundle.
Tsk, tsk, tsk. You must never throw away
things that are worth good money.
German uniform.
You're not German.
You're... English... huh?
Madame, you're drawing
some very dangerous conclusions.
That man you kill,
you look in his mouth?
You should. Sometimes these Germans
have gold in their teeth.
You are the colonel, huh?
They catch the other one,
your friend?
Oh, liebling, liebling,
you must not kill me. Not with that.
The patrols would hear.
They would come.
Oh, don't be afraid, geliebter.
Before I ever saw you, when the water
spirits told me you were coming...
I say to myself,
"This will be my man."
Liebling, you are my man. Mine.
- Nothing can change that.
- Never mind that nonsense.
How did you find out about me
and the escape and the rest of it?
They know it in the town.
They're searching the forest and the lake.
Good wool.
And gloves.
Oh! Mm!
I never before had gloves.
Hmm.
Beautiful gloves.
- That is right.
- What's right?
What you were thinking.
That it would be safer
to travel with me.
As a matter of fact, I-
how did you know what I was thinking?
- It is there. Yes.
- The wagon?
We could travel by day. Back lanes.
Gypsy lanes.
They are not watched.
How far you think you go
in these German officer's boots, huh?
- I do wish you'd stop reading my mind.
- They always look at your feet.
So frightfully disconcerting.
Like being found without one's trousers.
Oh, mein süßer!
Why do you not trust me?
Afraid I'll have to.
I've no alternative.
Come then, into the wagon.
It is warm.
Good wagon. Not like
others with holes. Come.
- Give me that.
- No. Tomorrow...
in the morning, early,
we get rid of it.
Now you are to sleep. Come.
- You didn't tell me your name.
- Liddie.
"Liddie"? If you don't mind,
I think I'll call you Lydia.
"Lydia"?
Huh. That is nice.
Jojezakad kedvedsen.
Tomorrow, I have
wonderful coat for you.
Fine blue and yellow gypsy coat.
And boots and razor.
Razor belong to
my second husband.
Thank you, I-your husband?
Where is he?
- He kill a gadze and they hang him.
- Good. I mean, poor fellow.
Good, huh? Huh?
Here you sleep.
Come, take off boots.
Lydia, what is a gadze?
Someone who is not gypsy.
[Groaning]
Gadze sounds like a swear word.
It is, but not when he has blue eyes
and brings you luck.
You know, I'm perfectly
capable of undressing, you know?
Oh, this is comfortable.
It's very pleasant, indeed.
By Jove, I'm tired.
I must be getting old.
No! You are young
and you are strong...
and you are my beautiful man.
Please. Please, your hands.
Couldn't you arrange to sit
on them or something?
As a matter of fact,
I'll sleep by the fire.
No. Outside, I must watch.
By the river.
- What for?
- The Nivashi.
- I beg your pardon?
- The Nivashi and the Pavushti.
- The spirits that live in the water.
- Oh, yes, yes, the pixies.
They sent you to me
because I have no man.
- Oh, tommyrot!
- No, truly.
Five days now I travel alone.
Woman should not be alone.
So tonight, when spirits
come out of river...
I will thank them for you.
[Snoring]
What is that ghastly odour?
- My hair.
- Your hair?
Uh-huh. Look.
- Jasmine, violet.
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
[Sniffing]
And cod liver oil! Oh, my word!
Good, huh? Tomorrow,
on your hair, I put some.
Now you rest, mein süßer.
What the devil!
- Lydia, your husband,
did he have any papers?
- Papers?
Yes, you know, identification card
or whatever I'd need if I took his place...
- in name only.
- No. No papers.
- Huh.
- They take them. But I have his clothes.
Clothes?
Lydia, do you think you
could make me into a gypsy?
What idea!
What cleverness!
Huh! And in a gadze!
Oh, mein süßer!
I can make gypsy
out of log of wood.
Oh...
and you are not
log of wood.
## [Humming]
What is that
filthy mumbo-jumbo?
Stain, to make
your white skin gypsy.
And in your ears,
J put holes.
Little holes.
- Holes?
- Yes.
For my husband's
beautiful gold earrings.
When I finish, you will
even smell like gypsy.
Now look here, old girl.
Let's not overdo this.
## [Humming]
- Ow!
- Lay still.
There's no need
to tear off my ears.
## [Humming]
[Groaning]
Come.
- [Shouts]
- It hurt?
No. No, but I can
still die of tetanus.
Tetanus?
I do not know. Come.
[Denistoun] Lydia, this awful coat!
Why, it's frightening!
Put it on.
- But where on earth did you get it?
- I stole it.
But do not worry.
I steal it from friend. [Spits]
Then you did him a favour.
Well?
Oh, mein süßer!
Jaj istenem!
Oh. Oh!
Look at yourself.
Oh. Oh.
- Not bad.
- Bad?
You are wonderful.
You are beautiful!
Mm! You look like wild bull.
Girls will be crazy for you.
But these eyes, they won't fool anybody.
They're blue, you know.
Keep them low.
Look humble. Gypsies do.
Gadzes teach us how.
- What now?
- Hmph.
- Now you push.
- I beg your pardon?
Go, push. Go!
Geliebter.
I just find name for you.
Janos Kalompa.
Janos Ka- oh, great Scott, Lydia.
Can't you do better than that?
- What's the matter
with your husband's name?
- Uh-uh.
Dead man's name.
Bad luck. No.
Janos Kalompa.
Good.
He was young fiddler
in Transylvania.
Oh... how he could
fiddle! [Sighs]
That Janos.
How I loved him. Ha.
Come. Sit here.
- Come.
- I'm perfectly all right here, thank you.
- Oh...
- Now behave, Lydia!
- But I love you.
- Now look here.
We just simply cannot go on having
these attacks of- well, these attacks.
- It's positively indecent.
- Oh, mein süßer.
Now look, get this
clear once and for all.
You simply must learn
to behave like a good woman.
But I am good woman.
I just want to kiss you little.
Come, I show you. You will like.
You jolly well
stay where you are!
If you dare to move as much as an inch,
I'll- I'll thrash you.
Oh...
first you beat me, huh?
And then you'll be sorry.
Then we kiss and make up.
[Chuckles Seductively]
Here, take whip.
Giddap.
[Lydia]
Stop, liebling.
Lydia, stop it.
Don't you know that's stealing?
Yes, stealing.
But I like apples.
Sit down. Come on.
[Denistoun Makes Kissing Sound]
## [Humming]
# Ha te engem #
# Szint oly szivvel #
# Szeretnel #
# Nagyobb lenne #
# Melebb lenne #
# Szerelmunk a tengernel #
# Ha te engem #
# Szint oly szivvel #
# Szeretnel #
# Nagyobb lenne #
# Melebb lenne #
# Szerelmunk a tengernel ##
Hmm, nice.
Oh, liebling,
if you only knew words.
Mm, such words.
Oh, such love!
Oh, mein süßer!
Uh!
## [Lydia Singing Gypsy Folk Song]
Oh!
## [Singing Continues]
Tell my fortune.
Gypsy, tell my fortune.
I tell fortune. Come.
Now, you have good hand.
See? Line of life is strong.
But you have been in danger of death
three times, huh?
Now I see happy, long life for you.
I see two husbands, huh?
Two? Oh, thank you.
- Giddap! Come on!
- Thank you.
Mama, mama! The gypsy told
me I would have two husbands.
Ah, that's silly.
Don't pay attention.
Hmm. You know, she thought
I was really a gypsy.
It was earrings.
## [Humming]
"You have been in danger
of death three times."
- You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
- Why?
Sometimes it's true.
You know, in England, for this
sort of hocus-pocus, you'd go to jail.
I go here also. Many times.
In winter, not bad.
Tell fortune?
Fortune?
Lydia, please, I must get to Freiburg.
Let's get a move on!
These fools have money.
I get a little.
Is forbidden, but I try.
We don't need any.
I have enough money.
Of money there is never enough.
And also is woman's job
to get money for her man.
- Tell fortune?
- [Denistoun] Come on!
Fortune?
Tell fortune?
Watch this.
Giddap!
You, get down. Get down!
Gypsy, tell my fortune.
Well?
Ah. Ah! Three times
you've been in danger of death.
See? The line of your life
in three places is broken.
Ja.
And I see two husbands.
Hey, wait a minute!
She takes our money, then doesn't tell us-
- Ah, I see girl here.
- Ja?
Fine girl, big.
Jaj istenem! Such a girl.
- Ja?
- Yes, love is waiting
for you just inside door.
That is because her father
keeps the windows locked!
[Soldiers Laugh]
[Indistinct Chatter]
Krausse! See what is
going on with the gypsies.
Tell me, gypsy.
Will there be a war?
Yes.
You lout! You swine!
You get out of here!
Hold your head down, geliebter!
Do not let him see your face.
- Hold your head down!
- Get out of here!
We are going, sir.
We are going.
Wasting your time like that.
Now get back to your duties.
- Get out!
- We are going, sir.
Come on! Hup!
Come on, old boy.
Come on!
Come on.
Whoa. Whoa.
He kicked me, the swine.
He kicked me.
I will put curse on him. His blood
will turn to milk and his bones crumble.
I'm sorry. I almost gave the show away,
losing my temper.
That is because
you are gadze, liebling.
You suckle pride and become ruler of world
at your mother's breast.
But he kicked you also.
Gadze pats his dog
and beats gypsy.
In old days,
they hunt us like wolves.
Do not forget that, liebling.
I shall remember it
in the future.
One day in this accursed land
they will kill all of us.
Come, liebling, come.
Come on, boy.
- [Lydia] Stop. Stop here.
- [Denistoun] Whoa.
- Now what?
- Before we cross...
you spit in river three times.
Go. Spit in river.
I shall do nothing
of the kind.
Then we do not
cross river.
- Lydia, don't you believe in God?
- Hmm.
Then don't you think the lord's
prayer might do just as well?
Huh. You are
my very clever boy.
You do both. Go.
Go. Spit in river.
Go, spit.
Three times. Go.
[Spits Twice]
Good. Now we go.
Giddap.
Stop watching, I tell you.
Lydia, must you
clean fish on the bed?
Why?
Is fine fish. Huh!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Here.
Your friend not come, huh?
No. He was supposed to mark
this signpost with three dots.
He probably had to walk.
I made much better time.
We'll have to find
a place to camp around here.
- But if your friend not come?
- Then I'll have to do it alone.
- Do what alone, liebling?
- Oh, meet a man. Talk to him.
That man, he live far?
A few miles from here. We'll have to find
a place to camp. I'm starving.
- There's old fish only.
- Oh, no, Lydia. Not fish. Not again.
You would not stop
in village, buy meat.
Oh. Look, you get the wagon
off the road and pitch camp.
I'll be back.
You will not go
in village alone.
I'm not going to the village.
You just get a fire started.
[Chickens Clucking]
[Creaking]
[Growling]
[Clucking]
[Clucking, Squawking]
[Chickens Squawking]
[Dog Barking]
- [Banging]
- Papa, the chickens!
[Barking Continues]
[Chickens Squawking]
Oh, you thief! You thief!
[Man Shouting, Indistinct]
Ah! Mm!
You feel good, huh?
I have never been so utterly
content in all my life.
You know, this was stealing.
Stealing, yes.
But I like chicken.
- Oh, mein süßer!
- Oh, Lydia, please!
There's a fire somewhere.
I smell smoke.
[Policeman]
So do J.
Careful, geliebter.
Let me speak.
Where are you two
coming from?
From there, masters.
[Neighing]
Come on.
Where are they?
Who, master?
- Are they in there?
- No.
Where are you two going?
We broke wheel.
We lost caravan.
- [Car Horn Honking]
- We try-
- Anything to report?
- Not a trace of them, sir.
We're searching-
All right, all right.
Keep searching. Hmm.
What have we got here?
Schultz, the spotlight.
[Policeman] Gypsies, sir.
Chickens have been reported
stolen from a farmer, sir.
Chickens, huh? Look,
you bring in my chickens.
They're two English ones,
and J'll make you a sergeant.
Drive on, Schultz.
All right, hitch up.
On your way.
The rest of your filthy gang
is camped by the river.
[Lydia] Thank you, masters.
Thank you.
[Denistoun]
Come on!
- [Lydia] Stop, liebling.
- Whoa.
[Denistoun]
What's the matter?
There's fires, campfires.
- Gypsies?
- Yes, liebling, like police tell us.
- Will we be safe there?
- No, no, it's better go away from here.
But I told you,
I have to wait for young Byrd.
Then it's safer stay with my people
than on road alone.
Do not worry, liebling.
I tell them you are escaped convict.
Come on.
- Liebling?
- Yes?
When you meet him,
you make your big, beautiful smile.
You say loud like this,
jo napot, brother!
- Say loudly to whom?
- Zoltan.
Who the devil is Zoltan?
- Zoltan?
- Yes?
He's brother of
my second husband.
- Ah, the one who, uh?
- Yes, liebling.
You see this coat...
this beautiful coat?
Well, I was wise woman of the tribe.
Very important. I am seventh daughter
of seventh daughter.
Let us stick
with Zoltan, shall we?
Yes, liebling.
Zoltan is chief of tribe...
and with me wise woman,
naturally-
- Naturally what?
- Nothing, liebling.
That what make him mad.
- So I hit him with shovel in the head and-
- Well, go on.
And while his senses are knocked out
still a little I went away.
But first, I steal his coat for you.
Don't be silly.
You never even knew I existed!
Oh, yes, Nivashi tell me.
That is why I take coat.
- On you it is wonderful.
- I don't want the coat.
He can have the beastly thing back!
- Liebling, you do not understand.
- What don't I understand?
If Zoltan see on you his beautiful coat,
he want to fight you for it.
And if he win, well-
- I go with coat.
- Don't worry.
I have much more important
things to fight over than you and a coat.
Come on.
## [Jndistinct Singing]
[Man]
Liddie!
[Woman]
Jo napot, brother!
Ha, ha.
[Gasping]
[Hissing]
[Grunting]
Ow!
Liebling. Liebling!
We beat him!
## [Violin]
# Szol a kakas mar #
# Majd megvirrad mar #
# Ha az isten nekem rendelt #
# Enyem leszel mar #
# Varj madar varj #
[Chuckling]
Look at our gadze.
Like real gypsy he becoming.
With fingers he eats.
- Fingers were made before forks.
- Likewise gypsies.
Ah, gadzes
I cannot understand.
Such a strange people.
I hear that every day
they wash. Is true?
- [Music Stops]
- Yes!
Ohhh, not good.
Washing very dangerous.
When they put my father
in Hungarian army...
every day they made
poor fellow wash.
He died young,
before he was even 60.
- Did he really?
- Uh-huh.
Uh.
# Micsoda madar #
# Kek a laba
zold a scarrya #
# Engem oda var #
# Varj madar varj #
# Tied oda var #
## [Humming]
My tooth, brother,
the one you knock out.
You keep it.
It makes us blood brothers.
Thank you very much, Zoltan.
I shall treasure it all my life.
# Reji nese #
[Chuckling]
- # Cigamyok az arany #
- What is that thing?
Liddie keeps singing it to me as if she
expected me to swoon or something.
I will translate for you.
# There is story #
# Gypsies know is true #
# That when your love #
# Wears golden earrings #
# He belongs to you #
# Old love story #
# That's known to very few #
# But if you wear these #
# Golden earrings #
# Love will come to you #
# By burning fire
they will glow #
# With every coal #
# You will hear desire #
# Whisper low #
# Inside your soul #
# So... be... #
# My gypsy #
# Make love
your guiding light #
# And let this pair #
# Of golden earrings #
# Cast their spell #
# Tonight #
# La, la, la-la #
# La, la, la,
la, la, la... #
# La-la-la-la
la-la-la-la-la, hey ##
[Zoltan Chuckling]
Give her my little present, brother.
- Oh! Jaj istenem!
- [Laughing]
Oh! Liebling! Liebling!
Oh, mama! Look!
- What was that all about?
- It means she'll have lots of children.
My tooth brings
special luck, brother.
I've had 30... and three.
## [Gypsy: Humming]
Zoltan! Zoltan!
[Boy]
Zoltan! The signpost!
I come from the signpost!
- This is the boy.
- The signpost!
- I come from the signpost!
- Yes?
The dots! The dots! On the
signpost are three more dots.
- Who put them there?
- It was gadze with bicycle.
- You saw him?
- With my own eyes I see him.
[Boy] Be careful!
There's soldiers working in the woods!
Liebling, be careful!
Liebling!
[Sawing]
- Tell your fortune, master?
- No.
- Cross palm with silver.
- Look, will you please run along?
Master, at this moment
you are in great danger.
[Sawing Continues]
Pump up your bloomin'
bike, guv'nah?
- Aye!
- Good heavens!
- By Jove, that's you.
I mean, it is, isn't it?
- Yes, I suppose it is.
Oddly enough,
I sometimes doubt it.
My word, sir, that get-up.
Those earrings.
An absolute knockout, sir.
Really. Who is this?
Oh, yes, I forgot.
Miss Lydia, Mr Byrd.
How do you do?
- Lydia, better go take a look at them.
- I go tell their fortune.
Maybe they tell me
something, huh?
- My word, sir.
- What that woman's done for me.
- Fortune, tell fortune.
- You just wouldn't believe it.
- Let's get on with this blasted bike.
- Fortune!
Standing there, we'll be knocked off
like sitting ducks.
- Awfully glad you made it, son.
- When I saw those three dots of yours...
I went off in the bushes
and did hand-springs, but really.
- And now for your friend, Krosigk, eh?
- Right, sir.
You write a note, give it to me.
I'll take it to him.
You? Oh, no, that won't do at all.
The whole point is Krosigk knows me.
He's one of my father's oldest friends.
He's known me since I was that high.
You'll stay here. Wait at the gypsy camp.
It's down by the river.
- Is that an order, sir?
- Don't be an ass. Of course it isn't.
- I'm just telling you.
- ## [Drums Beating]
Don't talk, don't look,
just give me your hand.
Ah, you have very
lucky hand, master.
Rarely have I seen hand
with so much good fortune.
## [Drum Continues]
You see this line?
That is your life. It-
My word, sir, you're a knockout.
An absolute knockout.
Liebling?
Liebling, last night
they came to inn, the gestapo.
One was big, like hog.
They say here, he has scar.
Hoff. Come back.
Come back, I say.
Why your friend
ride away so sudden?
Because he knew I'd-
I'd never let him go.
Lydia, something's happened to me.
It's terrifying, incredible.
- I read his fortune and-
- Yes?
Lydia, that boy's going to die.
I saw it in his hand.
How, I don't know, but there it was.
Lydia, I tell you, he's going to die,
and I let him go.
Do not be sad, liebling.
If you see it, it is true.
There's nothing you can do.
Come, liebling. Come.
## [Humming]
# Senkisem #
# Borul #
# A kopor #
# Sojara #
# Most latszik meg #
# Ki az igazi #
# Arva #
## [Humming]
[Lydia] There are no wings
on bicycles, liebling.
And that man,
this Krosigk, where he live...
is good five miles.
Give to your friend time.
Give to him time.
## [Woman Humming]
You know, Lydia,
I used to be a rationalist.
- What is that?
- Well, it's sort of believing...
only in what you see or hear...
or feel.
But lately, I've begun to suspect
there are more things...
in heaven and earth
than I ever dreamed in my philosophy.
You learn much
when you learn that.
You know, you never did
tell my fortune.
You get back
to your country... safe.
You still know
what I'm thinking.
You are easy, liebling...
very easy.
What else?
You will be famous
and you'll never go hungry...
except in your heart.
What else?
You have been in danger
of death three times.
I can go on
from there myself.
You're thinking
I'll be leaving you soon.
How you know?
You're easy, liebling, very easy.
Lydia, afterwards...
I mean, when I'm gone...
would you go back to Zoltan?
- Would that make you unhappy?
- Yes! Yes, it would, very.
Oh! What would Zoltan want
of woman whose heart is stone?
See? Already it is growing cold.
Oh, Lydia.
I want you to know that
in these last few days...
I've been very happy.
Happier than I thought
it possible to be.
And that's very odd because
they've been days...
of danger and uncertainty.
I don't suppose I've begun
to realize it until...
until now that my time
with you is almost run out.
You are the most wonderful
person I ever met.
Your generosity...
and your warmth
and affection...
and your loyalty and devotion.
The way you spill over with it.
It's made me feel very good...
and very secure...
and very inadequate.
Oh, you not know
your sweetness.
You say something.
Maybe it is your head you turn...
and smile at me.
And then there's beauty
in you like water in sun.
And it make my heart
pour down into me...
'til I love you so.
More than I can bear.
Oh, liebling, liebling.
[Crying]
[Machine-gun Fire]
[Machine-gun Fire Continues]
[Jndistinct German]
Byrd? Byrd!
Go in woods quick.
Leave him with me.
Krosigk, never got to him.
- Come on, help me
get him away from here.
- No, no, go away.
Leave me. Find Krosigk. Tell him I-
[Hoff]
Halt!
- There he is!
- Go away, liebling. Go away.
Before he dies
he has got to talk.
Where is Denistoun?
- I told you I wanted him alive.
- I shot for the legs.
Rindvieh!
I think he's coming to.
Where is Denistoun?
Where is the colonel?
Get his shirt off.
I will make him talk.
[Ripping]
[Hoff]
Where is Denistoun? Where is he?
- Talk!
- No! No!
- [Hoff] Where is the colonel?
- Right here!
Denistoun.
[Gunshots]
Dicky? Dicky,
it's me, Denistoun.
It's no use to grieve.
This is way it has to be.
- Zoltan, get these away from camp.
- Uh-huh.
- Car too?
- Yes.
Bury this boy here in the woods
and all of you get out of here.
You go to Krosigk, huh?
No! No! They catch you!
They kill you!
Go back to your people.
This isn't your war.
- Go on!
- Liebling.
So I asked myself...
why was Byrd seen in
the vicinity of Freiburg?
Not once, mind you,
but three times.
Why is he hanging about?
- For whom is he waiting?
- For the other Englishman.
- Denistoun.
- Of course, but why?
Why meet here?
Why meet at all?
In their shoes, I'd be getting out
of the country as fast as I could.
No, they have business here.
Business important enough
for them to risk their necks.
But what kind of business?
And with whom?
With whom, gentlemen?
Hmm?
What would you say
to our great humanitarian...
that earnest disciple
of brotherly love...
the inventor of
our new poison gas?
What would you say, my friends...
to professor Otto Krosigk?
Yes, Herr Reimann.
Oh, of course you can
come over. Not at all.
We shall be delighted.
Well then. Goodbye, Herr Reimann.
- What does Reimann want?
- He's coming over.
I'm worried, Otto.
He suspects you.
- We're being watched.
- Now, come, my darling.
There's nothing
extraordinary in that.
Today in Germany, everybody is watched,
even the watchers. Come.
Tonight would you be entertaining
the chief of police...
these Nazi party officials
and elite guard officers...
if you weren't forced to?
- They suspect, Otto.
- Let them.
And if they searched me,
would they ever suspect this, uh...
piece of money?
- Let me keep it.
- No, darling, I have got to have it handy.
I never know when and where
I may meet... Byrd.
And if Byrd doesn't show up?
If they have caught him
and sent someone in his place to trap you?
They won't trap me.
If anyone else but Byrd comes...
I won't have anything
to do with him.
Please, stop worrying, will you? Come.
Let's go back to our guests.
[Rumbling]
What are you two doing here?
I told you to get away.
- This man, you see him?
- No, too many people. Now go back.
Go back? Liddie say go in.
Go in, go back?
What is this talk, huh?
We go in and tell fortune.
Then you talk to Krosigk. Easy, huh?
No, go back.
Zoltan, it's not safe for you here.
Already not safe for me there.
Liddie break my head.
Whoa. Whoa.
Go on in, brother.
We waste good time.
Come.
Masters, ladies? Read your fortunes?
Read your palms?
Tell past, present, future.
- Beautiful lady, with your permission-
- You! Be off!
- All of you, get out of here.
- Wait, Herr Lieutenant.
- This may be very amusing.
- Nonsense!
These filthy gypsies.
These non-aryan swine.
We of the master race
should not contaminate ourselves.
Our little policeman,
chewing up the landscape.
Handsome soldier,
like me tell your fortune, huh?
[Major]
Jf you can make it interesting.
- With man like you, easy.
- Is it all right, Krosigk?
- [Krosigk] Of course, by all means.
- This I must hear.
[Man] Ask her if there's
going to be another war.
- Tell your fortune, master,
past, present or future.
- No, gypsy.
I'm not interested. Maybe you?
Not interested in an old Oxford friend,
Herr Krosigk?
- Or his son, Richard Byrd?
- Careful, it's a trick.
Go away.
- Get out of here, gypsy.
- I'm not a gypsy.
- My name is Denistoun. I'm an Englishman.
- Isn't that interesting?
- An English gypsy.
- I told you I'm not a gypsy.
You've got to believe that.
J'm Colonel Denistoun
of the British army.
A colonel with holes in
his ears and rings in them.
That's a little hard for me to swallow.
But frankly, my good man...
I'm not at all interested in
who you are or what you are.
[Mrs Krosigk] Certainly not,
and we don't want our fortunes told.
- We must go back to our guests, Otto.
- Wait! Richard Byrd is dead.
They shot him, tortured him.
He was on his way here
to see you.
Why do you...
tell me all this?
- There... there must be some mistake.
- There's no mistake.
I killed the two brutes
that murdered him.
He counted on you,
you because you're a patriot of humanity...
rather than a tool
of these war-mad Nazis.
That is dangerous talk, gypsy.
Look, there's going to be a war.
A war, do you hear?
Give me your horrible formula
and Germany dare not use it.
You know that we won't!
Jt's your duty as a scientist,
as a humanitarian.
Do I get it?
I don't know what
you are talking about.
[Radio]
Bekanntmachung des oberkommandos.
If ever I get out of this mess,
if I get back to England...
I shall have to tell your friends,
young Byrd's mother and father...
just how their son died. I don't want
to tell them he died for nothing.
[Man]
War! Jt's war!
- War!
- [Jndistinct Chatter]
- Did you hear that, Otto?
- Yes, my dear, I did, I did.
This gypsy's a traitor.
He'll get you into trouble.
No, my dear. No, he won't.
I'll report him to Reimann
when he comes.
I know you think
I'm trying to trick you-
It's war, Herr Krosigk! On the radio,
it just came over! Poland attacked us!
We are already across the Polish border!
Heil Hitler!
- Heil Hitler!
- Deutschland ueber alles!
Hurrah!
Hurrah! Hurrah!
Sieg heil!
# Deutschland ueber alles #
# Ueber alles in der welt #
- You have it?
- No. Get out I'm in trouble.
- Our luck goes bad.
- Already around neck I feel rope.
You two get away and I'll-
too late.
# Bruederlich zusammenhaelt- #
Good evening.
- I see everyone has heard
the glorious news.
- Yes! Yes! Glorious!
On the radio, heil.
- Good evening, Herr Reimann.
- A little slow getting over, Krosigk.
Had to wait for a report
on two of my men.
They were murdered while
tracking down two enemies of the Reich.
Our enemies are all around us,
Herr Reimann.
Sometimes under our very noses.
How true. As a matter of fact,
I am very glad you came over.
- I just-
- The murderers of my men
were two Englishmen...
named Byrd and Denistoun.
The names mean anything to you?
To me?
I don't understand.
I once knew a Mr Byrd
at Oxford, yes.
- But he is very old now.
- [Reimann] Oh, you admit that?
Do you realize the borders are very
closely guarded now that war is declared?
These men most certainly
will be caught...
- and made to talk!
- Talk about what?
Who are they? Herr Reimann,
that sounds very melodramatic.
Krosigk, we have reason to suspect...
that they may have
some business with you.
Really?
Then I insist that you
post a guard around this house.
I must be protected at all times.
You're very clever, Krosigk, but-
They have been telling
our fortunes...
and very well too.
Get them out of here.
[Krosigk]
Gypsy! Wait.
With your kind permission.
Here. This is what you wanted...
for telling my fortune.
And I believe it too.
Every word of it.
[Whispering]
Let's get away.
Well, this is it.
From here on I travel alone.
What about you and your people?
This war's gonna make it difficult.
We separate, scatter.
Like water in sand.
- Country will swallow us.
- Brother, you've been a good friend.
I shall never forget it.
Farewell, brother.
And one day you take
earrings from ears...
but you find roots of them
in your heart.
Goodbye, Lydia.
Goodbye, my dear.
I go with you to Rhine.
Without me, you do not get out of country.
- No, absolutely no.
- I am your luck.
- I won't have it.
- Ah, brother, with her,
what good is words?
'Til your tongue hang out, you say "no."
In the end is "yes."
That I have found out. Now go!
Come, liebling. We must be in mountains
before sun come up. Come.
[Car Approaching]
Not much of a war going on.
Sentries pretty well under cover.
- Not safe to swim across.
- Lydia, you're not going to try it.
No, liebling, before I meet you...
I seldom wash.
No time learn to swim.
Let's find a place
to wait until nightfall.
- I imagine this runs into the Rhine.
- Yes.
I'll follow the stream
down to the river.
It's luckier when you stick
close to running water.
Besides, the sound
will cover my footsteps.
Oh, liebling.
There is spell on me.
My head go round and round...
and I feel weak...
and frightened.
To me nothing matter any more...
only you.
All my life I believe
if I do not love one man...
I love another.
But now is different.
Is like... like...
having sickness.
No. You never knew
what real love was.
And I never knew what life was.
Now we've become like each other.
We've merged into each other.
Gypsy, gadze. Gadze, gypsy.
It's all one, Lydia.
- Mein süßer.
- Uh-huh.
Now it is dark.
No moon, no stars.
Clouds.
I told you my luck
would keep you safe, huh?
- You worry when you swim,
keep money dry, huh?
- Yes.
Here. Here. Put in here.
Now you make your way to Switzerland.
You'll be safe there.
- You too?
- No, the Swiss would intern me.
But you would be safe.
No, I can't.
You... you are only half gadze.
And I, half gypsy.
Because I say go.
Goodbye, Lydia.
O spirits
of the earth and water...
guide my beloved.
Make him strong
like the oak tree.
Let him live in the beauty
and vigour of his seed.
Sweet spirits
of the earth and water...
I give you back my beloved.
[Spit, Spit, Spit]
- Paris.
- She was quite a woman.
Quite, Mr Reynolds, quite.
- But I thought you said
you returned them to her.
- Did I say that?
[Woman] We will land in four minutes.
Fasten your safety belts please.
We will land in four minutes.
[Spit, Spit, Spit]
Lydia.
Oh! Oh.
Oh, mein süßer!
Oh! Mein süßer!
I think you never come.
Oh, I just leaving.
Oh, mein süßer!
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Oh, süßer.
Come on, Apple. Giddap.