During the second World War II disappeared almost
300 Swedish soldiers trace.
This is the story of six of them.
On Christmas Eve, 1942.
Five miles inland in Norway
Nearest abutments, a charge.
If you discovered that you must do it themselves.
It's cold, it would be good
with something warm to drink.
I fetch water for coffee.
BORDER
Next station Torsby.
Terminus, all please get off.
What are you doing? It's cold.
- What happened?
- It's barbed wire.
- What do you mean by barbed wire?
- I can not talk about.
- What have you done?
- You know I can not say it.
- You must go to the doctor.
- I do it this afternoon.
- I know you!
- You're right, the doctor should look at it.
Come to bed.
- Hello, my boy.
- Boy? Know you not.
Good morning, pusling. Hello. Do you sleep?
- You can already see it.
- No.
I will not marry the big belly on.
So I have to bury grandma simultaneously.
- Maybe we'll see you again.
- Yes, it was nice.
Book Today mom and I church
to on Saturday.
And so to book dinner at Björn sided.
To think that soon we can live together.
We're getting married.
- And you must be in uniform.
- No ...
- No, no uniforms, I beg you.
- Then look at your grandmother and not the abdomen.
She loves men in uniform,
she is completely crazy with them.
Where are you cute when you talk like that.
She is named after Signe Signe Hasso.
- His name Gunder.
- After Gunder Hägg?
He's just the world's fastest man.
- Have not you forgotten something?
- What?
Sven.
- Damn, where are my pants?
- Where you threw them.
- Do not forget the doctor!
- No.
- Good morning, Lieutenant.
- Pipes.
Thank you.
Should I be honest, it's not mine
rings, but when I saw you, it felt ...
- It's something with your smile, your mouth.
- Let me try.
- What are you doing, may I ask?
- Arrest of lottens hand, Lieutenant.
I'd better take my call,
before you make love you with all Värmland.
- Anna, you can go back to the fair.
- Yes, Lieutenant.
She is lovely. What is that?
A mustache.
It's good to see you.
Take the gun and went with them.
We might as make it clear.
I give orders and you obey.
What a luck, I came
so I can keep an eye on you.
- Have you got pea soup?
- It's cold.
- Who have you borrowed it?
- A driver Birger Johnsson.
- How many are we at the roadblock?
- Five man.
- How close to the border is it?
- Five km. This is the last post before Norway.
Have you seen any Germans?
No, no, you have to dig snow
and bar the way, that's all.
- Tell it now ...
- No, I will not tell you anything.
Do you think you are protecting me by not
to say something?
- And you're getting married.
- Yes.
- With whom a woman or?
- Karin has been after me for long ...
You, I Need
curfew on Saturday.
I have two tickets for Jussi,
he keeps field concert in Karlstad.
Nope, you can forget about
You must be in the bunker.
Will I feel so boring
when you have a mustache?
The border with Norway
That's fine Johansson, fine.
- Add to the lead, sur ersatz coffee.
- It is you who makes bad coffee.
- How the hell would you do it?
- Wicksell, how did you become group chief?
- I'm from Gothenburg.
- It is no recommendation.
- Keep up with the complaining.
- We are doing not know otherwise.
Shut up, there's lieutenant.
- Hello.
- Hello, pipes.
- Where's the roadblock?
- We had no warrant.
Think, or I do another
the group manager.
- I create it now.
- It must wait.
First make sure the new soldier.
Instruct him.
So turn off the fire and gets men
underway, it looks like a scout camp.
Must be done, Lieutenant.
- Sven Sten Ström, Eskilstuna.
- Bergström, Karlskrona.
- Bengt Johansson, Forshaga.
- Axel Halvar, Falun, Dalarna.
- Sten Ström.
- Are you related to the lieutenant?
- Yes, that's my brother.
- Welcome to the roadblock 83rd
Henrik Wicksell, group chief.
I heard the lieutenant, erect roadblock.
And every six months, turn off the fucking fire.
You come with me to the Hotel Nyskoga.
We live here then.
There are straw bags over there.
- Hotel Nyskoga.
- It's a good group, it will be good.
- Where are you from?
- In 10, Sörmland.
- What is it?
- Peace on earth.
Fine cases.
6.5 mm.
- Should there be two?
- Yes, but the other is to repair.
- Your brother is indeed grim.
- Yes?
- But it is said he is righteous.
- Make it so?
I must look to the boobs out there.
Install yourself and came out.
- Can I fire a salvo?
- Yes, the term Halvar.
I'm flat and free as a bird.
Hello, majors have visited,
but take a seat for a moment, Sten Ström.
&lt;i&gt; Now you're fucking, I say! &lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I know there's a damn renderi &lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; across the border into Norway during the night. &lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; - I have complete control of my ...&lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; - Shut up! &lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You must guard the border, period. &lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Is that understood? &lt;/ i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Yes, Colonel. &lt;/ i&gt;
- Sten Ström, entered.
- Good morning, Major.
- Do you want?
- Is not it a bit early?
It's cold.
- Do we have a problem?
- Nothing that can not be done.
That was not the Colonel.
He has received information about
ski over the border -
- But he does not know that it is ours.
- It was a little renderi tonight.
- It could have gone to hell.
It did not. Now we can offer
Germans in a surprise.
Burial Berg bridge was the last. Now
I need it leave, we talked about.
I've got new information
from my Norwegian contact.
Between Elverum and Flisa find there
troop movements in place unprecedented extent.
You may find out
about von Schell planning an invasion.
- We agreed that it was about the bridges.
- I will shit on your privacy.
It is here that we have worked for.
Now it happens, and it must be completed.
- When do we leave?
- They are watching me now.
I can not go alone into Norway.
That is you have to, there is no other.
- So I want to Järvinen.
- Honestly, how naive can you be.
He's crazy, he stays where he is.
Also, you have a contact who is waiting.
- In Velta.
- It's deep.
Have I been wrong about you?
If you have not grasped the extent of it here?
This is bigger than you and me.
- How do I find my contact?
- He finds you. Run in the morning.
- If the movements suggest invasion?
- Then we blow up bridges.
So may God take care of the rest.
It's not true, it is
many examples of Krylbo ...
- Krylbo was an accident, it at all.
- It's a matter of time.
Who says they will take Sweden? Would
they do, they had done it long ago.
If you see a German soldier on the road
you shoot him?
No, I would go and talk to him.
- Is it a good idea to talk with the enemy?
- What a fucking enemy?
I do not think the Germans see us
as enemies. We is not doing what they say.
We have our orders, we are here
to protect its borders against them.
That is the problem, we aim in the
wrong direction. The danger comes from the east.
Shit, Hitler has taken Europe country
for land, he lacks only Sweden.
- What prevents him from taking us?
- You mean well, we should stop Hitler.
No, let's clear the snow
so he does not get the shoes.
The Russians bombed Pajala for two years
ago, Hitler made us something?
Now we enjoy ourselves.
Bergström, how many cards do you want?
- Sven?
- I do not know.
Is the choice between Stalin and Hitler,
I choose Hitler.
- So you're a Nazi?
- You do not hear after.
- It's wise to stick with winners.
- Winning team.
What do you think of jew issue?
I have nothing against Jews.
- But they always do something damn ...
- Stop There!
Stop it!
- No more talk about politics!
- You fucking idiot!
Now take a small one and sit down.
- Where are you going?
- I would go jogging.
- Want to go skiing now?
- I want to see the boundary.
We are full. Come, we go into
and sleep. We need shovels in the morning.
I can not sleep.
I will look at Bergstroem friends.
- There is nothing to see.
- Then I'll probably look at it.
We must go back. Sten Ström, come on.
Schss, it's right up there.
Sten Ström!
- It all looks the same.
- Quiet, come on.
Come, we go back
You must see it a second time.
- It's Germans. Did you see any limit?
- No.
They are looking for us.
There!
Help me!
Come on, every six months, come on.
So come, however!
Awake, awake!
Halvar.
Come on.
- What?
- Nothing, just slept on.
Come on, you do not get up yet.
I would leave a little earlier.
How romantic. You come and go,
when I sleep.
Sorry, but Adolfsson is constantly
after me.
I have a whole company,
which freeze your ass of in the bunker there.
You know what? We got the church on Saturday.
Was not it good?
Did it so easily?
Come, stand here, close your eyes.
No. close your eyes, do not look.
See.
Where are they beautiful.
- I love you.
- And I love you.
- Karin, I ...
- No.
Sit.
Fall on your knees.
Karin ...
I ...
I can not marry you
on Saturday.
- Aaron, it's not funny.
- I can do nothing, that's an order.
- You're an officer, give a different order.
- I can not.
- You are injured, they may send another.
- I really try.
- I have done.
- You do what you want, it's fine.
You're not listening, I can not
do anything, period.
And on Saturday I go to church
with or without you, period.
- Do not promise something you do not.
- What are you talking about? What have I promised?
- What did the doctor?
- Which doctor?
- What did he say?
- He made it.
- Let me see. Show me.
- Stop Now.
Stop now.
Stop it!
Good morning. Lieutenant.
- Is Järvinen here?
- Yes, Lieutenant.
- Is this roadblock 83's KSP?
- Yes, now it can easily be printed by.
- You have done well here.
- Have you had a shit morning?
- How about a little ski trip?
- How could it happen?
I spy 25th Armored Division.
I need someone I can trust.
- When the shit for Adolfsson, you're here?
- No, and he must not know.
Fine, I need some fresh air.
I'll get the gear, and you stick
at rest, till I'm back.
What the hell are they doing?
Wicksell, up with you, then come.
- The absence of two men.
- They must have escaped while I slept.
Here lies schnapps bottles everywhere.
I have been drinking.
- How can you afford it?
- It was ...
- You are standing in shit.
- I thought it was good for ...
Ten so quiet!
When Ekström comes, you say, I took
Sten Ström and every six months with at skitræning.
- It's an order.
- In that case, I will.
- You are responsible for the roadblock.
- And for Sven and every six months.
He's right, Lieutenant.
Several pairs of eyes see more.
Go to Järvinen.
I put on skis for two minutes.
We continue to stand,
I keep you three yards behind us.
Satan, what have they done?
Sten Ström. Aaron, you hear for?
Aaron, it is he your brother?
Now you must take command, you hear?
The two have gone from here now!
They have taken him.
They have taken Sven with him.
We must put behind them now.
Sven is gone.
Aaron and I follow the trail.
I take back every six months equal to
the roadblock.
Hear ye?
To hell then!
You are soldier.
You must see your dead buddy.
Wicksell.
Wicksell, help me now.
Aaron, Aaron!
- Truck Trail. We follow them.
- It is impossible.
- No, it is not.
- They have seven, eight hours ahead.
- We have no alternatives.
- Yes, we have.
We have one dead and two are scared
to death, them we must first make sure.
- We lose him.
- We have already.
I have command,
and you do as I say.
Which direction should we go?
Come on, there are always ways to locate
people.
We find him, I promise you.
We need to get them away from there.
Bergström, Wicksell, climb above!
Climb over here!
Wicksell! Help.
Help now. Climb over here.
Climb over here, Bergström climb here.
Climb now!
Climb over here!
Bergström! Climb over here, Bergström!
Järvinen, get them away from here.
Here, come with. Come on!
- Come on!
- Follow Järvinen.
Come, come, come!
Coffee and eggs and anchovy sandwiches.
Here you go, Major.
Thank you, madam.
- Excuse me, may I ask something?
- There you go.
I know who you are, but you know
not me. Karin Lindström.
- Yeah, so ...
- Aaron Sten Ström is my fiancé.
Well, however, take place.
It is such that major and I have
a common problem.
My fiance has always busy,
so we can not manage to get married.
- Wedding, I must congratulate.
- Thank you.
- It's high time you could say.
- I understand.
- Can not replace Aaron a few days?
- Sorry.
Sweden is not at war,
everything can not stand or fall with Aaron.
- In these times, we must all sacrifice something.
- I understand.
But he can not have just one day's leave?
It's not so much to ask.
I apologize.
- Sorry disturbance.
- It was so little.
We offer coffee
and sandwiches today.
Major, it is
roadblock on 83rd
Four miles to the northwest is a big lake
On the other hand, there is a mountain pasture.
- It is even deeper in Norway.
- Did you hear me? Go!
Come along, now!
Move! Go!
The Lord is my shepherd ...
Let me rest in green meadows. He directs
me to the water, where I find peace.
He refreshes my soul
and looking me in the right direction.
Do you think we get the death penalty for this?
What?
We come to a court-martial,
when we get home.
Court-martial?
- What do you mean? We were just following orders.
- We shot against the Germans.
I know what you are experiencing.
One must simply suppress it.
- Try to get some sleep, Wicksell.
- I can not.
I think about every six months,
located there.
- We get him tomorrow.
- Then it becomes damn without me.
Then the mind never fail you.
When we met the Russians at Soususalami,
They had between 35 to 40,000 men.
They had tanks and artillery.
We were 1800 men in the whole battalion.
I had 132 men in my company.
Damn bad odds.
When the Russians came, it was hell.
Mon ... they were everywhere.
They were all over.
It was pure butchery.
I lost 73 of my people.
More than half of one and the same day.
But we stopped them.
When the war was over,
I had only one thought.
To get them home.
We found all but eleven.
We carried the frozen corpse
on horse-drawn carriage to Kaunusmäki.
There we put them in the sauna
and thawed them out.
We washed them in warm
water and gave them clothes.
So we gave the boys back
to families.
But there is not a day where I do not
think of the eleven, we did not.
Helps you me find my brother?
First we have the two homes.
The Germans will guard the border yet
stricter, now they know we're here.
Maybe it's a Swedish.
What the hell are you doing?
Are you getting us into war?
- What happened?
- Your soldiers have fired on the Germans.
- Well, you ordered it?
- I have not ordered it.
However, we have had an episode
at roadblock 83rd
Sten Ström panicked.
Do not lie, you end up in a court-martial
for this, get those fucking hands up!
- It makes you too.
- Enough is enough!
I am taking over here and get cleaned up.
Take your gear and join
Karlstad tomorrow.
This one incident has never occurred.
Understood?
I do not lie.
- And the Colonel is good to correct everything up.
- It's too late for that.
We take his stuff.
We take a different route back.
I have the State Department on his back.
The Germans took one of them prisoner.
- Who?
- I do not know. We have 48 hours.
So we have six soldiers
on the wrong side of the border.
If they are killed it is tragic.
But if they survive and interrogated,
it ends up on your table.
What the hell have you been doing?
You said you had a plan.
- How many more than we do about this?
- Only three of us. Why?
It's going to cost.
Two lieutenant degrees.
The dry might not take you the job?
- Do you know who it is?
- Yes, it was damn questions.
This man probably killed
over a hundred Russians in the Winter War.
He ran against their tanks and stack
birches into the tracks.
Järvinen will never
follow voluntarily.
If we pick him, it is clear
I respectfully ask -
- The idiot who sent him
to Norway.
- Can you solve the problem?
- Yes we can.
They went from 83 at roadblock
Norway and Black Bergen. Make it fast.
And if they refuse to follow back?
Solve the problem.
This time I get Finnish satan.
The fucking idiot.
Come out!
Come out with your hands on your head!
- Come on!
- I am a friend.
- I am a friend. I'm Swedish.
- Go to the captain.
- I'm Swedish.
- Yes, you're Swedish.
- Are you alone?
- Yes, I got lost.
- Do not lie, tell the truth. Reply!
- Let him be.
He is our friend.
And friends help each other.
- I tell the truth.
- Well, I'm Captain Keller.
- Bergström.
- Is it your cottage, Bergström?
I know you're lying.
Where are the others?
Can you see ski there?
It is your friend.
You help the Resistance.
- Answer.
- I am a friend.
I am a Swede, I got lost.
Have you met your friend?
Him, I left by the tree?
He would not talk to me.
Where are your friends?
Where are they?
Who is there?
There are tracks there to. Who?
- Should I shoot?
- They are taken away.
They are looking for a plane.
Thank you.
Let me go.
Release me!
Do you realize, we follow the ski tracks.
Wicksell.
We must get away from here.
Come on.
Here, come on Wicksell.
I must rest a bit.
Operation Arctic Fox
This must to Sweden.
They will attack.
Here is where the collection areas are.
And where the depots are
here says it all.
Is there a date?
- Be patient, Larsson.
- It feels wrong.
He will see me in the eye when he dies.
Wicksell.
Sven is with them, Sven.
Up in the cars!
Damn! Damn!
400772nd
- Do you think we are so close to Velta?
- Everything looks the same in the fucking snow.
Wicksell, how are you?
Wicksell?
- How are you?
- Things are going fine.
- Are you down and keeps looking at the road?
- Yes.
- We might as well be here.
- I do not trust that shit compass.
We have nothing else, we can rely on
but there are stone bridge.
It is not the right truck.
This fits not know if ...
Wicksell.
- The idiot.
- What the hell is he doing?
Sven, you have a Sven?
- Who is Sven? Lower the weapon.
- I do not understand German.
Do you understand him? Are you Swedish?
I do not understand you, drop the gun.
Do you know where Sven is?
I do not understand German.
Lower the weapon. Lower the weapon!
Retreat, Wicksell, running hither, run!
Run for hell!
Wicksell!
Hold!
Aaron!
Aaron! Help!
He is already dead.
Get the dogs.
Come on, there is not much time.
Hurry.
Aldofsson waiting by the road.
Come on.
We can not reach ...
We must get away before the dogs come.
Bear to the wolf came.
Järvinen!
Damn!
You must have some water in you.
We're safe here.
But we have not only Germans after us
it is also the Swedes.
It was the Swedes
who tried to kill us.
I know the pigs
who attacked me on the ice.
Hagman was in my Company
in the Winter War.
I found him about to rape
a woman.
It cost me an eye,
but it was worth it.
And now we're even.
- Aaron?
- Yes.
Egil. Eat.
You took your time.
- The Germans?
- Yes.
And with the Swedes.
There are many
that wants to get hold of you.
The Germans killed three of my soldiers.
And they have my brother.
- Are you sure?
- We saw him on a truck.
There were at least two prisoners.
- On the way north?
- Yes.
It is not completely safe
but I think I know where they are.
Where?
They use the old school in Lundemyra
as a barracks and interrogation room.
- Are you expecting someone?
- No.
Hello.
Well ... where are the others?
- Where are your soldiers?
- They are dead.
Your task was to solve,
what troop movements meant.
It was the Germans who were chasing us.
Why do you have the damn uniform on?
How else could I move myself?
Pak, are going home.
- I'm not going anywhere without Sven.
- And how will you get him?
Egil know where he is.
- Pak ...
- You sent Hagman after us.
Yes.
- Were you ordered it?
- No.
You shot some Germans.
Do you know what happens if they get you?
You know too much about what I do.
It is for Sweden. Others may decide
whether it is right or wrong.
I ask you to take home.
I know you must be a dad.
I must bring my brother home.
It is important that this comes
to Sweden than we do.
- Where are you from?
- From a German kurerfly.
It is their whole plan.
Your task is complete. Thank you.
Now we have a dram.
- Cheers.
Kippis.
How do we get to school?
- Are you sure you want there?
- I have to.
My son died in the schoolhouse.
He was 18 years.
I became a resistance fighter
the 9th April, 1940.
In recent years I have worked alone.
You are more effective in a way.
Then blew the Captain Keller on me.
He was close to me several times.
He is not stupid. But it did not.
So he threw himself into my family.
They inquired Jon in the schoolhouse.
But he did not know where I was.
If only he had known.
He did not know.
Captain Keller threw his body
the yard at home.
So he knocked on the door.
When my wife opened
he shot her in the head.
I found them.
They're here.
They're here. They are below us.
How many Germans are there in the school house?
- 15-20 pieces.
- We need more weapons.
We should be able to get by with it here.
First we get your brother out so that evens us
the damn house to the ground.
Yes, it sucks
but it is effective against the cold.
We get 35-40 minus degrees the next day,
do not forget the purse.
- It will not do.
- Why not?
So much fat you do not.
Bear to the wolf came.
The wolf here, come.
Aaron ...
I know you can hear me.
Say something I need to hear
your voice.
I yearn for you.
You need to come home.
We need you.
- I come as soon as I can.
- Aaron.
You ...
I know you do not get home
until you have done what you need.
But I'll just ...
I love you.
Now we do it here.
Here is the school house.
Down the road is a guard post.
In front of the entrance and on brick wall
the landscape is open, the rest is forest.
I'm sure
prisoners in the basement.
There is a basement drop on the back.
We have cold weather on our side.
If we get your brother out alive
puts you into the woods with him.
Get in the car, quickly.
It is your car.
Come, come.
Sven, it's me, it's me.
Go, hurry.
We must get away from here.
Do you hear, Aaron?
We must away!
Aaron!
We must get away from here now.
Egil Egil!
Get out! Get away!
- Egil!
- Do you hear, we must get away from here.
Aaron, Aaron!
Aaron, Aaron.
Open your eyes, open them, I say.
We must get away from here.
Then wake, however. We must away!
Come on up, get up.
- Run across the bridge.
- It will not do.
It sits under the bridge.
It sits under the bridge abutment.
- You should aim for the detonator.
- It will not do.
Yes, you can do it, you'll hear.
Aaron.
Awake now, Aaron!
Aaron! Wake up now!
Talk to me.
Aaron, we are on the way home.
Now we come home.