September 21, 1945...
That was the night I died.
Damn tramps...
Watch it!
Disgusting!
Is he dead?
The Americans'll be
arriving any day now...
It's disgraceful,
having these bums here!
Mama... - !
What day is it?
Setsuko...
Another one.
What is
this stuff?
Never mind.
Just dump it!
This one's a goner, too.
You can see
it in their eyes...
HOTARU NO HAKA
~Grave of the Fireflies~
Production Designer/
Original Story SATO RYOICHI
Executive Producer NOSAKA AKIYUKI
Character Design KONDO YOSHIFUMI
Art Director YAMAMOTO NIZO
Music MAMIYA MICHIO
Layout MAMOSE YOSHIYUKI
Character Color YASUDA MICHIO
Director of Photography KOYAMA NOBUO
Sound Design URAKAMI YASUO
Producer HARA TORU Written
& Directed by TAKAHATA ISAO
Air raid!
Get to the shelters!
We're in for a big one!
The shelter behind the
firehouse should be safest!
It's hot!
Be a good girl...
Try to be patient.
I'd better get
over to the shelter.
Be careful, and get over
there as soon as you can.
Setsuko, be a good girl
and mind your brother.
Never mind us!
Get to the shelter!
Yes, yes...
Mom, do you have
your medicine?
Right here.
Don't worry.
I hate the shelter!
Well, you'll be sorry if you get
blown up by a bomb! Now get on.
My doll!
Air raid!
Seita!
Get down!
Long live the Emperor!
We're safe here.
Don't worry.
Where's Mama?
In the shelter.
The firehouse shelter can take
a hit from a 250 kilo bomb easy.
Don't worry about her.
She'll probably go to
Niponmatsu station to find us...
We'll meet her there.
Let's just
catch our breath first.
Are you okay,
Setsuko?
I lost one
of my shoes.
I'll buy you better ones.
I have money.
Open this.
Wow, you're rich.
Black rain,
from the bombing...
It's all gone!
Look, that was the civic hall.
We ate lunch there, once.
Is our house
gone too?
Probably.
What'll we do?
Dad'll make them pay for this!
Mother!
Well, it's not like I was the
only one who lost his house.
We're all in the same boat.
At least
we're still alive.
There were two direct hits.
The fires're impossible to put out!
When you try to smother them,
it just spreads the oil around.
It's not her...
She's not down here!
Seita, I have to pee.
All residents of
Ichirizuka and Kaminishi!
Please report to the elementary
school for first aid services!
What's wrong?
My eye hurts.
Don't rub it.
We'll get it washed
out at the school.
Where's Mama?
She'll be
at the school.
School?
Uh-huh. Let's go.
Seita!
Have you seen your mom?
She's hurt. You'd better go.
I'll watch your sister.
Wasn't that scary, Setsuko?
Did you cry?
Seita has to go somewhere.
Why don't we wait for him?
Seita. I've been looking for you.
Are you okay?
My mom...?
This way.
This IS your mother's, isn't it?
In here.
She's finally asleep.
She really should be in
a proper hospital.
I think Kaisei hospital in
Nishinomiya wasn't hit.
My mother has heart trouble.
Can she get her medicine?
I'll ask.
I'll be around if
you need me.
Mom...
You saw her?
It's terrible...
I'm thirsty.
If there's anything
I can do, just ask.
Oh, did you get your
biscuit ration yet?
I'll get it for you!
Keep this ring in your purse.
Don't lose it.
Mom's... hurt.
She'll get better, though.
Where is she?
In the hospital.
In Nishinomiya.
We'll stay here
at the school tonight.
Then tomorrow we'll go to our
aunt's place in Nishinomiya.
Okay?
We'll all be on the second floor.
Why don't you stop by later?
Thanks a lot. We will.
See you later, Setsuko.
Want some?
I want to see Mama.
Maybe tomorrow.
It's too late now.
Watch me, I'm good at this!
We haven't unbandaged her.
You don't want to see the body.
With this heat we're having...
She'll have to go on the truck today.
Where's your sister?
In Nishinomiya.
We have a distant aunt there.
I think she'll
take care of us.
I see. Lucky for you.
I'd better get back to work.
Good luck to you.
Mama!
Where is she?
Is she still sick?
Yeah. Still sick...
Welcome back.
How's your mother?
Is she at Kaisei?
Lucky your dad's in the Navy.
You get to have a truck
help move you over here!
I've laid out futons and
mosquito netting in your room.
Thanks.
Doesn't Mama need her ring?
Did she give it to me?
Just be careful
you don't lose it.
Mom's...
When Mom's a little better,
I'll take you to see her.
Time for bed. Okay?
Dried bonito... Herring...
Dried potato... Eggs...
Pickled plums...
And I do believe this is butter!
You can't get these for
ANYTHING nowadays.
Soldiers always get the
best at times like these.
Anyway, did you stop by
the hospital?
I'd like to tell your mother
what's been happening.
And I could take Setsuko
along to visit her.
That bad?!
Mom... died while she
was still at the school.
What?! She's dead!
Then why didn't you tell me?
Why were you hiding it?!
I didn't want Setsuko to know.
Dead... How awful!
You'd best write your
father and tell him!
Seita!
Look!
She bought me new shoes!
Good for you,
Setsuko.
Hello there!
You poor dears...
Thanks ma'am.
What's that?
Bullfrogs.
Nothing to be scared of.
Firefly!
Try to catch it.
Whoops! Squashed it.
Ew! It smells!
You squeezed too hard.
There're millions of them!
Setsuko, close your eyes
and say "ah".
Why?
Just do it.
"Ah..."
Fruit drop!
Fruit drop! Fruit drop!
I almost swallowed it.
We're home.
Where were you?
Did you thank
the lady?
Yes ma'am.
That food looked good...
Seita. Shouldn't you be
going to school. Or something?
Yeah, but the steelworks they
had me working in was bombed.
And my school burned down.
There's no place to go.
Well, I hope you've
written to your father.
I already sent a letter
through the Naval Office.
When?
Just after we came here...
About 10 days ago?
That's strange...
There should have been
a reply by now.
Return the scissors when you've
finished with them, Setsuko.
How's the
war effort?
It's starting
to look hopeless.
The more factories we lose,
the harder the others have to work.
We're getting ready for
when they finally invade.
You're right. That's why food's
getting so hard to find.
Our soldiers aren't the
only ones who are suffering.
You work for our country's
defense too, young lady.
You eat up and work as
hard as you can!
Not again...
So you've taken in a couple
of homeless children?
Poor things... To lose their
mother when they're so young.
What's wrong?
Ltch?
It's hot.
I hate shelters!
Just hang on. Don't worry,
I'm here for you.
Wanna go to
the beach?
Yeah! Yeah!
Let's go!
It's all
vegetable fields now.
What're they doing?
Making sea salt.
It's because all the salt
and soy sauce is rationed.
Hurry up, Setsuko!
It might be a
little cold...
Cold!
Feels good, right?
You won't itch now.
It's a big bathtub!
HEY!
Come back here!
Grrr, I'm a bear!
I'm gonna eat you!
Snip... Snip... Snip...
What's wrong?
Is he sleeping?
Don't look at that.
When it gets a little warmer,
I'll teach you how to swim.
We'll swim,
and that'll make us hungry.
Seita!
Setsuko! Come on!
You're hungry, aren't you?
There's food here for you.
Mother! Were you waiting long?
It's good to see you again.
Are you all right here?
I'm fine. Don't worry!
They're very nice here.
I'm hungry.
Let's get home before we're
caught in the raid.
I'm tired... Carry me.
Air raid!
Your mother won't be
needing her kimono anymore.
Why don't you trade
them for some rice.
I've been trading off my
things bit by bit for food.
You can probably get a
full toh of rice for them.
That much?
You need your
nourishment.
You can't be a soldier if
you don't grow up healthy.
A whole toh of rice?
Your mother would be glad you
didn't let them just go to waste.
Why don't I take them?
NO!
Setsuko.
You're awake?
No! No!
They're Mama's!
Don't take them!
Setsuko...
Let them go!
Setsuko... Setsuko...
Fine rice, isn't it?
We'll have a proper rice
dinner tonight, Setsuko.
Here, this is yours.
White rice, Setsuko!
Here you go.
With my daughter and our lodger
working overtime so much...
...l've felt bad not having
rice to give them.
It's great, huh?
Real white rice!
More!
Yes, yes...
You're just gobbling it down
tonight, aren't you Setsuko?
It's good!
What's wrong?
I don't want
rice porridge!
Don't we have any more
pickled plums?
We finished
those off ages ago.
Here's
your lunch.
Thanks. I'd better
get going.
See you.
Bye.
Take care.
We'll have rice balls for lunch.
Just hold on till then.
Stop that!
You'll have it for lunch too!
You think a lazy
slug like you deserves...
...the same as people who
work for our nation?!
Seita, you're old enough to
know everyone has to cooperate.
You keep saying you want rice,
but do you earn it?
No, you absolutely do not!
I even give you some rice,
and you still complain!
But it's our rice.
Oh, so now I'm
cheating you, am I?
How dare you say that!
After I take you two in!
Fine! We'll just make our
OWN dinners from now on!
Seita, you have other
relatives in Tokyo, don't you?
On your mother's
side of the family?
Why not write to them?
WE could be bombed any day!
Problem is,
I don't know their address...
Let's
go home.
Uh-huh. Papa's
waiting for us.
Frogs are singing,
it's time to go home.
Sorry you had to
wait so long.
What's wrong?
I'm hungry.
And I'm thirsty too.
Okay...
Here, have a fruit drop.
Mom has 7000 yen in the bank.
7000... That's enough to
live on, so don't worry.
I'm telling Dad to write back
soon, because you're waiting.
You're in luck.
You can't buy a stove like
this easily nowadays.
It's almost impossible to
find any hardware to sell.
I'll take that comb, and...
Do you have an umbrella?
An umbrella... Oh yes!
It's raining, it's raining.
Big brother's coming home
with an umbrella just for me.
Drip-drop, plip-plop.
Down the rain comes!
That's got it!
Be careful
with that fire.
Right...
What are they up to?
They're doing their own cooking.
Good for them! More please.
Mother, did you scold them again?
Yes, but they refuse to apologize.
And that boy even bought a
stove. Just to spite me!