Devils On The Doorstep
Forward!
er bozi
Sir
neck
Who want to be my good children.
It is time to give away sugar.
Here you are．．．
look at this
which hand?
So smart
Try again，which hand?
no
This one
clean water,no diry water
Or I'll knock your block off ,understand
yes!you'll have clean water tonight
Please let me look!
At what?No!
Come on
Quick
let me take a look
quick
Don't stop
who's there?
me!
who?
Harry
What'll you do?
The used
who?
me!
close your eyes
Ma Dason
What's this village called?
Rock-Armour Terroce
Whats you doing up so late?
Thinking
well,think away.
Listen to me
I'm leaving two things with you
I want 'em both back. both
Don't let the Jap devils find out
Any slip up...
and you will be dead man
But... they got a blockhouse here
It could be hard
It will be alright
This is called
"shadow under the lamplight"
understand?
yes
if there is trouble
who responsible?
you!
who is it?
Danm
It is alive
This is bad!
I'll tell that guy
Ma dason
listen
in your sparetiem,
interogate them
We will collect them
on New Year's Eve...
together with their statements
understand?
yes
who'll collect them?
me!
It was like this
Just like this
Then he junmped the wall and ran off!
so what was his name?
Didn't say.me
so what'd he look like?
Dunno
My eyes were closed
How about his clothes? was he tall?
with your eyes closed,
can u see me?
How many were there?
I didn't dare open my eyes
So what exactly did he say?
He said he leave 'em here
till New Year's Eve
when he'd come for 'em
He sounded really fierce!
He called this "shadow under the lamplight"
I'll kill you,turtle_fucker!
You can take family bussiness later
Dasan's been with your son's widow
for some time
we have to talk
with these good-for-nothing!
go to bed
Dad，have some water
Don't call me dad!
Shameless Slut
A father-in-law can't take this way
Go for me,then!
I'll fed up with you
I'll kill you turtle-fucker
Get down
It's fortune ,not misfortune
when misfortune can't be avoided
Well, it is fortune or misfortune?
What should we do?
Take'em to the blockhouse
I'm in with their chief
What?
Hand 'em over
That's no good
What'll I say
when that guy comes back for 'em?
Tell him to see the Japs
What would he dare do?
you kidding?
This guy tie up Japs in gunnysocks
What wouldn't he dare do?
Are you a collaborator?
Seem like it
I'll throttle on with each hand
and then we'll bury 'em!
That's it
Well just dig a hole!
I'll do that
You would,But the guy said
if anything happens to 'em
or if the Japs find out...
we'd be killed
killde?who'd be killed?
He said he'd kill
everyone in the willage!
nothing
what
forget it
speak!
I thought we could run away
and leave the socks here
what could he do to us
sit down
you made me say it
if we have to die anyway
what if we just kill you!
stop it
if you don't , I am going
come back!sit down
It's unheard of
he's threatening us all?
I'll throttle 'em
and bury 'em
Such work are not the work of idle men
Provoke neither those
who dwell in the hill
or cones from sea
New years Eve is five days away
on that day the'll come,
steal away with them,
and diaster will be overted
Young San
For the sake of the village
act with care these next few days
Er Bozi
Yes, Old Uncle
Don't tell your mother about this
She got a big mouth
I'll keep it to myself,alright?
Alright...we can go home
wait
There's something else
That guy said
we should interrogate them
interrogate them?
Sense
Have some candy
Boy Good Have another
Er Bozi，come here
Coming Sense
Late no good
If you late once again
I'll knock your dock off!
understand?
Name?
Speak
Go on
name?
speak
Don't kill us
First tell me your name
Dong Hanchen
Age?
Occuppation?
Translate Office
What sort of official is that?
I turn Japanese into Chinese
and Chinese into Japanese.
So...What is his name?
Hanaya Kosaburo
Have him tell us himself
Shoot me! Kill me!
If you got the guts!Cowards!
How come his name's so long?
Come on,we don't want to be killed
We don't understand.
Turn it into Chinese!
His name's Hanaya Kosaburo.
He's 25
Has he killed Chinese men?
Violated Chinese woman?
Of Course!
That's what I come to china for!
He's new to China.
Hasn't seen any woman yet.
He's killed no one.
He's a cook.
What's all this talk?
They kill me now
or I'll kill them!
Why are you doing this?
I want to anger these cowards!
I can't cooperate with swine!
Will you two stop chattering?
Speak slow.
Wait for the questions
He begs you not to kill him!
what else?
Could you ask him
Who was that 'me' person?
Who was 'me'?
Listen，
I want you tell me who is 'me'?
You．．．Now I am stumped.
How would I know who you are?
Not me!That 'me' who nobbed you.
Just tell us who broght you here.
If we know,
we wouldn't have let him get us
You mean you don't know either?
Where are we anyway?
who's interrogating whom!
Stick the questions.
Just do it!
He beg you not to kill him.
Don't be afraid.Listen.
I'll read back to you
Don't kill us.Dong Hanchen Chinese
28，translation official，Don't know
Hanaya Kosaburo，25，Japanese
Just arrive in China
Hasn't killed anyone.Don't kill me.
Is That Correct?
Is it?
More or less
well then do what must be done.
I've got more to say.
kill me，I'm not afraid to die!
There are few of 'em，
You can kill us，
but never insult us
They've telephones,radio sets...
I'll never surrender!
Or betray the motherland!
.. on ammunition depot.
We'll be victorious!
Long live the Emperor!
And fourteen horses!
shoot me
That's it.
I am as old as your grandfather
To me ,you're still kids
This business,
we are asked to do it
Put your fingerprint here...
we'll transfer you.
Old Uncle! He's wounded
He's bleeding!
Escape!
We've got to escape!
There is no escape
Better to die now.
These peasants won't allow it
It's the guys who captured us
who'll decide our fate.
Bastard! I'll wait to die then.
You don't get it!pig-brain
Bastard，what'd you say?
I said，you're a clever man.
Bastard
Sensei
Have some candy
We're in here!Hurry!Help us!
Son,What'll we do?
Help!
stop Shouting!
Bastard!
Yell!Dong Dammit!
Help!Help!
Don't smother him!
Use Japanese!
Sit on him
Er Bozi!
Son，are you crazy?GetDown
Er Bozi
Are you mad?Get down
Move
Help!We are here
Go on
What's wrong?Shout!I'll help
Save us!Save us!Help!
A gunship is passing by!
You think they can hear you?
I try out the front
and they couldn't hear
How noisy is that?
How noise is that?
Shout your head off if you like
What are you thinking?
we'll try again next tiem.
Forget it，
Between the noise of the ship
and the band,they'll never hear us
All right，Enough talk，eat
Nothing beats a good meal
But we'd better change your bandage first
I'll change your bandage
I'll change your...
Move over
It's for your own good,you idiot.
Dong,tell this woman...
she may touch me now,
But I'll touch her later.
More than once or twice，
And more than just touch!
Hanaya，she's helping you
Don't you have any conscience?
It's Chinese.
who've got no conscience.
First they shoot,
then they help
Mongrels can't even shoot straight!
If they shoot straight,
you'll be dead.
I'll kill me now
What the hell is going on?
You want to kill yourself?
Use a sharp stone,not wood.
Sister-in-law ignore him!
I'm not your sister-in-law.
Shut up
Thank you,brother.
do me a favor.
Let me go!
We are all Chinese, after all
Why not shut up?
Hurry!
I was captured once before
Captain eight let me go
Don't give me that.
I've nothing to do with this
We'll be pals,you do me a favour
Of course.Name it
You two came as you had to
Go as you must
Don't make it trouble
Alright?I'm treat you well enough
Why are you so thoughtless?
He's coming to
I'll tell you one thing
If you keeep this up
I could get nasty!
It's me!Wake up.It's dawn
Was it cold last night?
It wasn't warm
What's happening in there?
Quiet so far
If they don't settle down,
they'll be the death of me.
Have a look
Brother，I am so hot，
Could you take this off me?
Better hotter than dead
Show some thanks,will you?
I damn pleased if someone fed me...
Clean my ass everyday
But why suffer like this,brother
I hear you coughing all night
You were freezing
Let's make this simple，Release us
I'm not putting your life in danger
So don't put mine in danger
Alright?If I let you go
I'm a dead man
Why aren't you eating?
Why isn't he eating? Move over
You．．．Light up.
People are iron,food is steel.
You can't eat
C'mon,have some
That's good
what is the hell?
Bastard!
Humiliationg an Imperial army soldier!
I'll kill you!Chinese pig
what he wants?
White flour
White flour?
Where am I gonna get That?
I wouldn't mind some myselft.
Just eat
那你看他不吃，饿死咋整?
He won't.Can't let him starve
I sent them to get flour
son of bitch!If I havenot eaten,
God danm you cann't eat.
Bastard!I'm not eating
and neither are you
They'll never find flour
They're scared we'll die.
They'll let us go
We'll be saved
Son of bitch.
What?Flour?
Do you thik That aunt Ba look like Flour
Eat me, why don't you?
Now that's silly.
Isn't it a capital crime
to hoord that stuff?
Trying to send me to the gallows?
Auntie This is a mater of decency
Decency?
You've a mistress in your bed
and Japs in your cellar
Son of a bitch!
You swearing at me?
NO,not you Er Bozi
I'm his mother
Curses at him travel straight to me
You don't understand
He swears at me, too
He hasn't kept his word.
He said he wouldn't tell you
If he lied to me,
He wouldn't be my son,
Whatever you say.
But I really need your help
Auntie.
You're fond of me,aren't you?
这两天我就为这俩人
I've done so much for these two men.
For the village
I've slept with my clothes on
I've spent night in the cellar
That's your fault.
I have no choice!
The Jap's threatening suicide!
He won't eat..
Unless his food's made of flour
Otherwise, he'll starve himself
It's mess
If you care about me...
You won't let me leave empty hand,
will you?
That's exactly how you'll leave today
A man going to starve
Let him starve
Japs are monsters anyway
That's no good.
If they starve,
our village is done for
I'd rather die than be a collaborator
What're you talking about?
This guy risks his neck to bring 'em
ask us to look after 'em
And we let'em starve?
What's a collaborator?
That's a collaborator
keep talking,there's no flour!
What's in here?
nothing
There's flour inside the chest
in the blue bag.
Who told you that?
who?The one who keep secrets.
He tells me stuff too.
That damn son of mine!
I don't care anyway,
There's none
Auntie，How's this?
I'll repay you double what I take
Triple it.There is none
Four times
Five times
and there's still none
How about six?
Seven and I'll give none!
All right. 8 then!
Dong teach me some chinese
what?
I want to swear at them.
To use the most terrible words.
Hummiate them
and they'll have to kill me.
Basterd!Teach me now.
Yes,sir
Cut it out
At a time like this,Thinking of that
You've heard them call us
brother and sister in law
Besides．．．when I saw Auntie,
I tell her all about us
What'd you sy?
I sadi... it is what it is
Have you no shame?
She said,no story,no flour
She wasn't nasty about it.
Things are what they are
Why not just admit it?
Don't push it，They're all ben too
Busy to think about us
After tonight,
when those two leave
How can I walk in the streets
with everyone talking behind my back?
What can I do?
If a big man like you doesn't know,
Why ask me?
Well．．．
I'll marry you
You have to anyway!
What're you saying?
You have no choice
Who's there?
Me!
It's him!
It's me!
Don't use that word!
It scares me!
I've got their statement
When the guy comes
Give him this,
I'm glad I didn't forget
Anyway, we've made it.
True!
Once they've left
we can celebrate New Year's...
all over again.
They're here，Dong
The time's come
I hear their footsteps.
I can see them taking up their weapons.
I want to turn the curses
you've tought me
in to bullets to fire them!
I want to enrage them!
Dong, Goodbye forever!
Brother and sister-in-low,
happy new year!
You're my granddad, I'm your son.
Brother and sister-in-low,
happy new year!
You're my granddad, I'm your son.
The words are nice.
Why dose he sound so angry?
Japs sound the same,
whether they're happy and angry.
Why d'ya think we call them devils?
Brother and sister-in-low,
happy new year!
You're my granddad, I'm your son.
Enough,
I get the message.
But your generations are mixed up,
If i'm your granddad,
you're my grandson,
Not my son. See?
How come they're not angry?
Japanese are always cursing them.
They're used to it.
Brother and sister-on-law, happy...
Okay, okay. Shush.
Twice is enough.
We've made you dumplings.
Just what you asked for.
Did you teach him that?
Yes. It's the spring festival.
I tought him propitious phrases
to thank you both.
Nice of you.
Now, eatup. It's your last chance.
By tonight, you'll be on the road.
Let's bring over the table.
Hold on. We'll set this up.
Eat hearty.
Hoarders!
I'll kill you for sure.
No chance of that.
Why not?
"On the road" means "to die" in Chinese.
This is our last meal!!
We're goners!
Why don't the act
like they gonna kill us?
Even when a chinese kills someone,
his expression never changes.
How are they gonna kill us?
You afraid of dying?
I just feel stupid dying this way.
But I'm not afraid.
I won't beg for mercy.
Shall we do it?
Move aside.
Let'em finish their meal.
Untie them.
Please, one favour!
Send my parents a message for me,
in the northeast.
Of course.
Don't panic.
You'll be on the road soon.
And whatever happens, happens.
Enjoy your dumplings.
All right. I will!
And then, i'll go on the road.
I lived by my mouth,
Now i'll die for it.
If only I hadn't learned Japanese!
In my next life,
I'll come back a mute.
Eat up...
Or we'll be lat.
Tell him...
we've still got to trouble you
to get back into those sacks.
What?
They're putting us back
into those sacks
What now?
The Japs are like this.
They cry, they sing.
before he goes,
we should give him a drink?
I want a drink!
He'd like a drink.
Just what we were thinking.
Let's get some wine from Old Man Qi.
San... think they'll give us a reward?
Go!
It's time for lunch.
I'm not going.
Not going to the Base?
No. We're having Chinese chicken today.
You serious?
Know how to get a chicken
from a Chinese?
'Excuse me, can you give me a chicken? '
Idiot! You wouldn't get anything in that way!
Watch me.
Bastard! Hand over that chicken!
You're pathetic. You'll get thrashed
Watch me.
You are going beat them.
Get it?
So they will scary you.
Bastard! Hand over that chicken!
What the hell?
Halt!
Bastard!
You scared the shit out of me!
What you do?
I'm from the village!
No leave village.
You go back.
Head down. Come here.
Here, have another.
Go back.
No go out, understand?
See?
That's how you deal with them.
Get it!
Halt!
Don't let it move!
You come back?
What's wrong?
What's all this?
Speak!
i must eat that chicken today!
Look, it's him!
You... dammit, what're you doing here?
I ordered you stay in the circle!
Bastard!
Please don't kill him.
Get out!
Japanese!
You must be dreaming.
No get out! Understand?
Yes!
Maruyama!
The chicken!
Captain-san!
This what you're after?
Bastard! Hand over the chicken!
Forget it, moron.
Captain-san?
Want me to kill it?
Now he's talking..
Let's sit over there.
No!
bastard! I heard!
Bakayaro! Fool!
It's ture.
Japanese speaking Japanese.
Soldiers of the imperial Army!
You stay here.
I'll get some kids to make noise.
Okay!
The Japs want more water.
It's ture!
There are Japanese up there!
Heaven's looking after us.
Becarful.
How'd they get here?
I ran into them.
Not you bring it here?
Captain-san.
Go fan the fire.
Our chicken is nearly ready.
I'm going to scream!
They still won't hear you.
Hanaya.
I've got an idea!
Don't worry about us.
We've got our own luch.
We'll save you the bones.
It was bloody delicious.
Why did he hit you?
I said 'knock you block off'.
Can't you say the opposite?
Well... you try.
Not me.
I can only say bakayaro!
It's worse.
Say baka-NO-yaro!
Cut the crap.
I'll watch them.
I have a idea.
Please save us!
Please save us.
Please!
Attack!
Son of a bitch!
Sense.
San, he's gone inside!
Move! Move!
What're you doing with that?
Captain.
It's for kill the donkey.
Donkey?
Eat donkey!
This maron is terrified
at the very sight of us.
They thinks us can eata donkey!
Idiot!
That pretty maid.
is a bird on high.
I am going to do my best.
Maruyamo!
Get your gun!
San!
What're you doing?
I'm getting you another chicken.
I see.
This gun...very good.
Save it...We eat next time.
Understand?
Understand.
We should be at our posts.
Right.
Playtime's over.
Two telephone lines to set up.
Why's he always waving
a knife around?
Get back!
No move!
You scared?
Course not.Not with you around.
Sensei...
Look at this!
What now?
That idiot is still inside the circle!
You're something else!
You're got these mongrels worked out.
I can teach you a few things.
I'm still learning.
You?Still learning?
You're never too old to learn.
Fucking cunts!
What're you doing?
Japanese soldiers!
They're coming!
Fuck you,Jap!Fuck!
Fucking cunts!
Move!
Turtle-fuckers!
What the fuck is this about?
So you pull this on me!
Trying to get me killed?
Get this straight.
You try and get me killed...
and I'll kill you first!
What's going on when you left the village?
I left the village.
Crossed the river.
Climbed the mountain.
Entered the town.
Went to ask fot Pockmarked Li.
Get the point!
This is the point.
You always leave the village,
cross the river...
If i didn't leave the village.
How could i cross the river?
Give me some water.
Go on!
Where was I?
Crossing the river...
Get the point.
You saw Pockmarked Li.
I didn't say that.
You did.
I said i saw Captain Five.
What did Captain Five say?
He said,
'Haven't i told you what i do?'
I said,'No,i've never met you before.'
Captain Five said,
'Are you from Xia-Village?'
'I'm from Rock-Armour Terrace.'
He said,'Rock-Armour Terrace?'
'We've never left anyone there.
Do what you have to.'
I said,'What's that?'
He said,'You've a blockhouse there?'
'What are you waiting for?
Do the deed.'
So this captain said'do the deed'.
Yeah.
He gestured like this.
'Do it!'
Tell us again.
What was that gesture?
Was it like this?
Or that?
Like this.
So he meant kill 'em!
No.
What do you mean?
Like this...like this...
Of course he meant kill 'em.
Looks like it!
There's an old saying:
Better to obey than respects to pay.
Well...
better obey then.
Old Uncle,if he wanted us to kill 'em,
why didn't he say so?
Why say 'do the deed'?
Men in hidh postions
can't always sat what they mean.
It was so clear!First those guns
yelled out to the brass band.
Then,today,
they tagged the chicken.
What's next?
Better to obey orders.
Did he sat how to do it?
No
Or who should do it?
No.He doesn't know us.
How could he?
He knows you!
Be thought i was from Lower Village.
Never saw him before.
This is a hard one.
What's so hard?
Japs are all bastards.
More water!
I'll throttle 'em
Twist their necks and bury 'em!
Shut up!
Bury 'em?That's an idea.
So...
It's not that i'm afraid.
How can i put this?
It's not right.
Why not?
We were told to look after them.
We can't just decide to kill them.
It's not good.
Besides,that Captain Five
who Liu Wang found.
Didn't drop 'em on us.
His orders don't count.
What if Captain Four or Captain Seven
comes for 'em?What then?
So why don't you go your self?
Go find Captain Four or seven?
Don't be stupid.
Uncle.
Stop looking at me!
If I weren't such a wuss, I'd do it.
We've got to reason this out.
Why? My putty mouth came from my mom,
never true at all.
If I let go of my mouth,
everyone in the village would be dead.
Our village is that famous?
I've kept my mouth shut for over half a year.
I "sensei" this and that all day along to keep quiet
Thats my contribution
That's some hard work.
Hard Work?
'Sensei'You,collaborator!
You do it then!
Well...Liu Wang
What the heck are you looking at me for?
What should I be scared of?
lets get this straight.
You know the saying
"Stick your neck out"?
Thats me!
I almost died at the entrance
of village, today.
Why do I keep on saying,
out of the village, over the river
Because it makes me sick
I even dream of leave out of the village,
cross the river, leave,cross,leave...
And you scold me for slurping?
Give me that
I'd choke them to death,
one after one, and bury them.
Don't talk about it any more!
If you guys aint gona do it, then I will.
You wont do it, then leave to me.
We'll draw lots then
heaven will decide
Whoever catches this red bean do it.
Uncle
Two big guys... can't even handle it
then find one more.
Forget it, I've got both.
Give me some water.
Bro, give it.
here you are ,san
say something.
Whats there to say?
Leave them to me,I'll throrrle 'em
don't talk no more.
Give me a hand, help out.
Just digging, ain't it?
fine I will do it.
You two dig, Da Sun do it!
lets just get it done,
we will do it tonight.
OK?
agree
Bro, the hole is done, right here.
We'll wait at the bottom.
We fixed you some food,
to help you over the shock
Er Bozi's mum says
dont worry about repaying the flour
She said, dont mind it too much.
eat on, I should get going.
Go ahead.
Yu'er?
Don't touch me, You dare touching me!
For the sake of my unborn child.
Are you all right?
Don't touch me
Who?
ME!
Stop saying "ME, ME"
Here, eat.
Your Mom?
She ain't coming.
Not Coming?
NO?this is terrible!
Uncle san!
Screw You this dumb ass.
I didn't kill anybody.
Geez
Whats wrong with you?
Anybody saw?
Noone
Hurry and get the door shut.
Mom, I am back.
back eh
Only one lolly，whats wrong uncle san?
nothing，forget about it
I am going to grandpa's
Go go go.
Yu'er, why not... just run away!
Bring little Thresher
and the old man, yuh?
Then, don't send meals tomorrow.
ah? If I don't go? Who's gona go?
Thetwo Japanese captives
are locked in the Great Wall.
Too long, Kids ain't gona remember.
Yuh
" Nihonjin " means uncles
"Chorijio" is candy
" Inguyo " is give
Here, Learn with uncle.
Jap...In... Great Wall
Say it
Japs... IN... GreAt Wall.
He remebered it
Jap．．．geez
the great Japs
big Japs．．．dont have candy
kill me.
What are you doing?
Kill me, what are you waiting for?
Listen to me, you two.
Those guys are at Fenghuotai
Did you send the meals?
I sent.
You listen?
Enough's been said!
Say What?
First they shout to the brass band
then they tag the chicken
Now they're using Little Thresher
three times unlucky!
If something happens, We'd lose out heads?
Of Course!
Get Up, let me ask you,
that two idiots should be killed?
Should
Should, then why didn't you
You didn't kill them，
then you are gona kill us?
Where are they from?
You know the guy with the gun?
What the heck are you saying?
I only say stuff I needed to say,
I don't know those guys!
You don't know? Two big guys in the bags.
Need at least two guys to lift one bad.
We need four peeps.
Then we need at least 4 guys,
may be even more.
Can't see anybody at all?
What the heck are your eyes for!
They are closed
Really? You open the door?
You did it with your eyes closed?
No, i closed 'em after
Yuh, You saw it.
No, I didn't see,
it was dark, I couldn't see.
Stop saying shit! Half a year passed,
You think we are idiots?
I have no goodie out of this.
No? I don't think so.
If Not why do You keep on helping them?
You said you'd pay me back eight-told
Where's that coming form?
Yes, we all see through that
see that
All You want is the lives
of our village people.
Whoever wants the lives
of the village people,
I will be waiting for him
He wants my life? How dare he.
He only wants your life, eh?
Stop arguing, will you?
Why can't I? What am I afraid of?
It's been 8 years
since the Japs took over our village.
8 Years, man.
He dare touching me?
My behavior is right and proper
Wherever they should look up to me
screw that,
don't wana argue with him over this.
you speak Japanese, Don't You?
You practice first,
practice with your uncle, go
Japs in Great Wall.
Why hit the kids, Why Not Hit ME!
Don't Cry.
The Truth about this kid in me,
is when the day
when the two men came to village,
me and Da Sun got.
I can't let him kill anybody.
Force us to kill.
Once we kill, you don't
give a rat's ass about us.
Freaking scared of Da Sun.
so,they'are still alive
We cant do anything right.
you know all anwers
We didn't kill anybody,
We can't Kill People!
We can't kill nobody
Can't Kill anyone,
I afraid, I just can't do it.
Yu'er how can you talk like that?
Whats going on with you and Da San.
We all see it.
Nobody said anything eh?
nope.
You havn't marry him yet,
and now you are all on his side.
You are afraid to kill people, so do we.
You're scared to bear
a cursed child,and us?
We all be cursed souls soon enough!
Da san
I want my flour back Eightfold
Pay me back now!
look at you!
Do you look like a man?
Whether Dasan's a man thats for me to say
Dont tell me you'd know better than me
Wanna goto the blockhouse?
Go then!
I'll leed you there
No big deal
If they come down,
no one can escape
We'll all pay our lives
Who are you threatening?
if we go we 'll die
and if we stay we die
its all the same
just behead me now
please get it over with
otherwise i'm not movig
Say something old uncle
such is fortume.
whe misfortune cant be avoided
i;m young,kill me first
i'm in this too
dont push me!i can do anything
fine
its not too late to action
we will help you dig
me too
do it
you do it
i'll do it!
I'll run away
next
its all bean
right
move
hold on
show me
this way
deard,different form the pic
cut shorter
understander?
understand
move it
next
bread guy,over here
welcome japanese
we are all one family 800 years ago
we all erite same words
and our soup use pickles
when beat us,it really ticks
if they say “bakayaro”
I think its good
The imperial army give us"misi" food
we love imperal army like family
they released us from fall
now we are free
and happy
where are you from?
Rack-Armour Terrace
name?
Dasan
Who send you here?
Old uncle five
No wonder you call me
brother-in-law four
Whats up?
where to start?
You want to "borrow an assassin"
Didn't old uncle five tell
you about my marksmasnship?
He said you can hot a fly at 100 paces
Thats right but with a gun
A nin-chamber automatic
The further the target
the more accurate the shot
Natuarelly
There's a blockhouse at
Rack-Armour Terrace,yeah?
Yeah
The village is as big
as an ass-cheek
How can you use a gun then?
This is a job for a sward
But old uncle five is asking you
You cant say no,can you?
Can't do it
Alright
What are you doing?
Going home
you can go,
but you gotta leave the beans
What?You wont help
but want the beans?
I cant help you out
but you gotta leave them
You want to kill a jap,
but dont want to anyone to know,right?
right
its a secret,right?
yeah
so,i'll keep your secret!
it's like this，
If i dont take something
How can you trust me to keep mum?
I dont need your beans
I just want you to feel okay about this
Silly man
You've simply came to wrong place
I make tofu if you throw in sorghum,
would that still be tofu?
The more sorghum you put in,
the less it will be like tofu
in the future,remember:
if you want a swordsman
dont goto the one with the gun
do you get my logic?
no
no?
Let me show you What i mean
Attention!
What we do?
Take a detour
halt!
what are we afraid of?
running means we've sone wrong
get down
They have lost this bat
When they see me,they bo and escape
They're back!
Sister Yayoi,look!
They have been away for a long time
At last they are back
Yayoi,what's wrong?
Matsuno?
Idiots!Go back inside
Whats all this fuss?shameless hussy
Look at him
You need wits and bravery!
I've remarried. Silly man.
Besides,I've got a Chinese heart, too!
SO you do.
Let's go.
Brother-in-law.
Where are you taking me?
-To the military police.
-WHat?
To the bath-house!
-you know the empress Cixi?
-Yeah.
-How about the Eight Ministers?
-Yeah...Uh,no.
-Didn't think you would.
-Darlings of the court.
All beheaded!
Know who wielded the sword?
-Old man Liu!
-Really?