Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Fire!
Sir Edward Pellew himself to
see you, sir.
-Very well, you can leave us.
-Your Honour...
-I shall have to lock you in.
-Then do it!
That it should come to this...
...you of all people.
It's good of you to come
and see me, sir.
This is not a social call, man!
Good God, sir! In a few hours-
you'll be on trial for your life,
and unless there are extenuating
circumstances, you'll hang.
-Hang in front of the entire squadron
-I believe it was-
our duty to restore order and
discipline aboard ship, sir.
Order and discipline.
Black, bloody mutiny, sir.
That's what the charge is.
and against a captain who was a hero
of the Nile and-
the Battle of Cape St. Vincent.
One of Nelson's own...
Dear God!
It was for the good of
the Service, sir.
Hero or not, we were headed
for disaster.
The English Channel
Six months earlier.
We're carrying too much sail, Archie.
Mr. Buckland, we should take
another reef.
You're the officer of
the watch, Mr. Hornblower.
It's your decision.
If this keeps up we'll be aloft
before long, I'll warrant ya.
-That'll sort out the men from
the boys.
-Oh, God!
Don't worry, Kid. Stick with me,
you'll grow up as bitter-
-as the rest of us.
-Mr. Wellard,
my respects to Captain Sawyer.
Please inform him-
-we are about to shorten sail.
-Aye, aye, sir.
Matthews, hands aloft to double
reef that mail tops'l.
Told ya.  Come on, lads.
Come on, Randall.
Come on, you little runt,
get up there.
Come.
What brings you to interrupt
my fruit, Mr. Wellard?
-Captain Sawyer, sir…
-Come on, boy.  We won't eat you.
I don't believe Dr. Clive and
I have enough room left-
-for a young midshipman.
-'Couldn't manage another thing.
Mr. Hornblower sends his respects,
sir, and-
to inform you he's shortening sail.
-Watch what you're doing, Styles.
-Just watch yourself,Randall.
Keep your little friend out
of my way.
Where do you think you're going?
Captain Sawyer, sir, I've
ordered another reef in-
-the main tops'l, sir.
-So I hear, Mr. Hornblower.
-Your decision alone?
-Indeed, sir.
Mr. Buckland, you're
the first lieutenant.
Do my standing orders require
the officer of the watch-
to inform me before
shortening sail, or not?
"Sir"?  What kind of answer is that?
Do they or do they not?
Yes, sir; they do, sir.
-Mr. Hornblower?
-With respect, sir;
your orders require us to inform
you when shortening sail, sir.
Don't come the sea lawyer
with me, sir.
Ahoy, there!  Gunner, Mr. Hobbs!
Have you ever had difficulty
interpreting my orders?
-Indeed I have not, sir.
-There you are, then.
A gunner has no trouble
understanding my orders,
what do you say to that,
Mr. Hornblower?
My apologies, sir; I must
have misunderstood.
The excellent men of your
own division, are they not?
Perhaps by teaching them a lesson,
you'll learn something of your own.
But sir, it was I who made
the mistake.
Get to it, you lubbers!
The last man off the yardarm
gets a flogging.
A dozen at the gratings for
the last man on deck.
Out 'my way, Laddie.
Come here, boy!
Pass the word for the doctor!
He's dead, sir.
-Well?!  Well?!
-He's dead!
Dr. Clive will be the judge of that.
Doctor?
Dead, sir.
What are you waiting for,
Mr. Hornblower?
Have the lubber thrown over the side.
Do you hear, Mr. Hornblower?
For God sake, Horatio.
The lad's dead, sir.
Nothin'll bring him back.
Is that right, Mr. Kennedy?
-Yes, Styles, that's right.
-We can read over him later, sir.
Mr. Hornblower, get that man
off my quarterdeck.
Aye, aye, sir.
Plymouth Sound.
Stow those barrels forward
on the gun deck.
'Morning.
Bush, second lieutenant.
-Look out, there!
-Look out.
Hornblower, third lieutenant.
An interesting welcoming ceremony,
Mr. Hornblower.
My apologies, Mr. Bush.
Are you quite all right?
Nothing damaged but my pride,
I think.
Hey there, you at the stay tackles!
Mind what you're doing!
-Mr. Hobbs, keep an eye on
your men, there.
-Aye, aye, sir.
Mr. Hobbs, lay aft here.
Mr. Hobbs, your recklessness nearly
injured one of the ships-
senior officers; not to mention
damaging vital supplies.
Don't use that tone of voice
when replying to an order.
Aye, aye, sir.
Perhaps if the men were better
supervised, these accidents-
wouldn't happen, Mr. Hornblower.
Captain's coming off, sir!
Quite right.
Run for'ard and tell Mr. Buckland.
Boswain's mates, sideboys,
lively now!
Marine guard, present arms!
Shoulder...arms!
-Lieutenant Bush come aboard,sir
-You came in my absense,did you?
-I did, sir.
-Did you report to the
first lieutenant?
-No,sir
-In my absense,you should have
reported to Mr. Buckland.
Mr. Buckland, why did Mr. Bush
not report to you?
I'm very sorry,sir. I was unaware
that Mr.Bush had come aboard.
He should have made himself
known, sir.
I was forward, inspecting
the anchor cables.
-Mr. Bush?
-I arrived only a few minutes
before you, sir.
I wished to present myself
personally.
And may I say, sir, what an honour
it is to serve-
under a captain with so
distinguished a record?
-Well, Mr. Bush, you are welcome.
-Thank-you, sir.
In time, you may indeed thank me.
Very well.
You don't know Captain Sawyer, then?
I know his reputation.
As a fighting captain, or as a man?
-What are you implying, Mr…?
-Kennedy, sir; fourth lieutenant.
Well, Mr.Kennedy, I don't think
I much care for your tone, sir.
Mr. Kennedy was merely
making conversation,
weren't you, Mr. Kennedy?
-Now, let me show you the wardroom.
-Very good of you.
I don't think I much care
for your tone, sir.
What an honour to serve under
a captain with such a record,sir.
That's enough, Mr. Wellard.
Now, get below and find out what
that hullabaloo is all about,
before it brings the captain
down on us again.
Yeah, I pushed the little devil
off the yardarm. Who cares?
Silence!!  Do you hear me?
Silence!
Mr. Matthews, you're the boatswain.
Will you-
get them to stop
this blinkin' racket?
Silence!
Right.  What's going on here?
You, Randall, what's all this?
Just settling a little difference
of opinion, you might say.
Captain Sawyer loves a little bit of
bare knuckle between-
the men. It keeps them ready
for the real thing, he says
Come on, Mr. Matthews, get them
to break this up.
Aye, aye, Mr. Wellard.
Come on now.
Hold hard there, Mr. Matthews.
This hasn't been settled, yet.
The captain wouldn't like it if he
knew we were interfering-
-with the men's sport,would he?
-The captain doesn't need-
-to know does he,Mr.Hobbs?
-Yeah, not unless some little toady…
-Randall, break it up, now.
-Make me, little boy.
Sir!  Randall, you call him sir!
Any man, any man, Mr. Hobbs, who
thinks differently had better
remember the punishment for
disobeying a superior officer.
-Tell them, Matthews.
-Death, sir.
Indeed, death.
And best you all remember it.
Get the ship underway,
if you please, Mr. Buckland.
Aye, aye, sir.
Loose the heads'ls!
Hands aloft to loose the tops'ls!
-Carry on, Mr. Bush.
-Heave!
Heave!
Put your backs into it!
-Mr. Hornblower.
-Sir.
Set a course to weather The Lizard
and then southwest, sir.
Weather The Lizard and
southwest, it is, sir.
South by west a quarter west.
Well, gentlemen,...
it's the West Indies
for us.  Santo Domingo.
The blacks are in rebellion there.
Very good Mr.Hornblower,very good.
Gentlemen, we can certainly-
rely on Mr. Hornblower to keep us
abreast of current events.
Yes, a slave rebellion.
They're uprising-
against their Spanish masters,
started by that darned
dangerous French revolutionary
nonsense.
Liberty, fraternity, stupidity.
You're not a revolutionary,
are you, Mr. Hornblower?
-Indeed I am not, sir.
-No.
We know how to deal with them
in His Majesty's ships, don't we?
Santo Domingo, gentlemen.There is
a nest of Spanish privateers-
right here in Samana Bay menacing
our trade-
through the Mona Strait. It's
our task to clear the vermin out.
It's a far cry from Napoleon,
sir, but we've ten times-
more chance of action than
with the Channel Fleet.
That so, Mr. Bush?
That's so.
Now there's a man after my own heart.
And plenty of action you shall have,
Mr. Bush; along with-
an abundance of yellow fever
and ague, eh, Dr. Clive?
Putrid fever and poisonous
serpents, sir.
-Tropical heat, bad water.
-Hurricanes and shipworm.
When were you last in the West
Indies, Mr. Buckland?
-Sir?
-Answer the question. When were you-
-in the West Indies, Mr. Buckland?
-I regret to say…
Never, you were never in the
West Indies. That's when you were-
in the West Indies, Mr. Buckland.
"Hurricanes and shipworm."
Not a day's sail from Plymouth
and you're out-
of your depth already.
Am I not right, Mr. Bush?
I said, "Isn't that right?"
Sir, I protest.
We all have much to learn, sir,
from your example.
Quite right, Dr. Clive.
"Hurricanes and ship worm."
Gentlemen.
Then how would you describe
such unsound behaviour?
-Captain Sawyer's just weary, Archie.
-Weary?
The man's bedeviled, Horatio.
Do you think Bush would agree
with you?
-Well, no.
-Or Buckland?
-Each captain has his own way,Archie.
-Tell that to the poor-
young seaman of yours that
we scraped off the deck-
-and threw over the side.
-May I remind you-
that when we first heard we were
to transfer to Captain-
Sawyer's command, we
drank Portsmouth dry in celebration.
The man's a national hero.
He's earned his place in history.
It's not history that concerns me,
Horatio, it's the future.
It's far more uncertain.
-She sails well.
-Yes, she loves a stiff breeze.
This is a bit more than a
stiff breeze.
We'll have to get some sail off her.
The captain has to be informed first,
sir. Standing orders.
Very well.  Mr. Kennedy,
if you would, please.
-You want to take a reef, Mr. Bush?
-Yes, sir.
With your permission, sir.
Very good, Mr. Bush.
Call all hands.
All hands! All hands to reef topsail.
Man the halyards and reef tackle.
Reef tackles - haul!
Put your backs into it!
'Vast hauling there!
'Vast hauling!
Who is that countermanding my orders?
-It's me, sir, Wellard.
-You'll be sorry for this, Mr.Wellard
Get down here immediately, sir.
There's a reef point caught in
the block sir, weather side.
-The sail was starting to tear.
-What do you mean,-
coming between me and
a man who disobeys me?
Mr. Wellard is on my station, sir.
He was only doing his duty.
Get down immediately, both of you!
Mr.Bush, be so good as to send
a hand to clear that reef tackle
Aye, aye, sir.  You there, lay aloft
to clear that tackle.
Get below, Mr. Wellard.
You too, Mr. Hornblower.
I'll teach you to conspire.
Trying to make me a laughing-stock-
in front of the men.
Do you hear me?  Get below.
Mr. Buckland, call the hands
aft here, if you please.
All hands lay aft here.
I know where loyalty is to
be found, men.
I've seen it.  I see it now.
I see your loyal hearts.  I watch-
your unremitting labours, as
I watch everything-
that goes on in this ship.
Traitors meet their just desserts
and loyal hearts get their rewards.
We'll splice the main brace!
A tun of rum to every man!
And to every boy!
Rum, on the forenoon watch.
They'll be drunk as lords.
Come on, close up, close up.
Mr. Matthews, lay aft here and
bring your mate with you.
Give me your rattan, Mr. Matthews.
Mr. Wellard's presence is required
by the captain, sir.
You too, Mr. Hornblower.
-Very well.
-I don't like it, sir.
-The lad were only doing his duty.
-No way out of it, Matthews.
-I could go a bit easier...
-Don't even think it.
He'll notice, sure as sin.
It'll only make things worse.
No hard feelings, Mr. Wellard.
I've seen a beating, sir.I believe
I will stand it well enough.
-Good man.
-Come on then,let's get it over with.
And sir, thank-you
for speaking up for me.
It's an injustice, Horatio.
It's discipline, Archie.
One...
Two...
Three!
Four...
Five...
Six.
Well, doctor?
The full dozen, if you please,
Mr. Matthews.
-Aye, aye, sir.
-Come on.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten!
Eleven.
-Twelve.
-That's it, twelve.
Serves the little bugger right.
Very well.
The dishonourable part of
Mr. Wellard has paid-
the price for his dishonour.
May that be a lesson to you,
young man.
Now, Mr.Hornblower,your punishment.
You think to be a colluder-
and corrupter of your juniours
and to walk away scott-free.
-Were that the case, sir…
-No quibbling with me, sir!
Were you still a midshipmen,
I would flog you like-
we have Mr. Wellard.
Your position, however,-
dictates a more imaginative approach.
You are on continuous watch for
the next 36 hours, and I would-
remind you that an officer
caught sleeping on duty
is subject to the most rigorous
penalty of the Articles of War.
-And you know what that is.
-Yes, sir.
Then God help you if
you're found asleep.
Continuous watch, then,
Mr. Hornblower.
Yes, sir.  Thirty-six hours, sir.
It's a long time.
-Are you up to it?
-It is Captain Sawyer's wish, sir.
It doesn't do to cross the captain.
-It's a lesson we all learn.
-That was never my intention, sir.
´Glad to hear it.  'Glad to hear it.
Stand firm.  Accept your
punishment and-
-we'll near no more about it.
-Yes, Mr. Buckland.
Carry on.
-Reporting for duty, sir.
-Very good, Mr. Wellard.
Mr. Wellard,
those sandglasses need to
be run against each other.
Aye, aye, sir.
Mark off each minute on a slate
or you might lose your reckoning
Concentrate on the task in hand.
It will help you to keep your
mind off the pain.
Thank-you, sir.
Mr. Wellard at work.
-Aye, aye, sir.
-"Aye, aye, sir."
Mr. Wellard has learned better now,
perhaps, than to conspire-
against his captain…
against his lawful superior-
set in authority over him by act
of His Most Gracious Majesty-
King George II… has learned
that it is the painful duty…
Picking on Wellard again.
Yes.
Is that reasonable, do you think?
I don't see where reason
comes into it.
Mr. Wellard is sulking.
So,you decided to hold me up in
derision in front of the hands?
You and that cub, Mr. Hornblower.
You plotted and planned so
that my lawful authority-
-should be set at naught.
-No, not at all, sir.
Why attempt to deny it?
Which one of you was it planned
to snag that reef point?
-No one, sir.
-"No one, sir." How can that be?
No one.  It was a plot.
So you pretend to be busy
to hide your face-
because of the guilt that is
written upon it.
You think to deceive me.
I gave orders that Mr. Wellard should
test the glasses-
-against each other, sir.
-You are sadly mistaken, Mr. Kennedy,
if you believe there is any good
in this young fellow…
unless, of course, you are part and
parcel-
-of this infamous affair.
-I was merely observing, sir,
that he was busy only because
I told him to be so.
What do you say, Mr. Bush?
We can rely on your
judgment, I'm sure.
The boy knows nothing, sir.
He doesn't know the bobstay-
-from the spanker boom.
-Oh no, Mr. Bush. You're too honest.
I knew it the moment I first saw you.
You don't understand-
these...poisonous young reptiles.
We must dredge the truth out of him.
Oh yes.  Get below, Mr. Wellard.
I'll have it out of you, by George,
I will.
Quartermaster, run for'ard and
get Mr. Matthews-
-to lay aft here, and his mate.
-Aye, aye, sir.
Another dozen and
he'll coo like a dove.
We must intervene.
-The captain is master of the ship.
-And he sought-
your opinion sir,which I note
contained nothing to dissuade him
from this beating upon which
he is now embarked.
Mr. Hornblower, may I suggest you
take the time to remind-
Mr.Kennedy that he is merely
fourth lieutenant aboard this ship?
He has the captain's ear,
why did he not speak-
-when he had the chance?
-To say what?
The captain's blood was up.
For Mr. Bush to have spoken up-
for Mr. Wellard would only
have provoked him further.
You think I should have
held my tongue?
-You think I made it worse.
-You acted for the best.
Oh, well, there's precious
sop for my conscience.
All on deck, there!
Sail-ho!
-Where away?
-Four points abaft the beam, sir!
Run aloft with your glass,Mr.Kennedy.
See what you make of it.
-Matthews!
-Hello.
-We're wanted aft.
-What now?
Bring your cane.
Oh no, not another one.
Who is it this time?
Young Wellard again.
There, sir, just for'ard
of the backstay.
French frigate!  Thirty-six guns,
she's cleared for action!
-Thirty-six, eh?
-Should we inform the captain, sir?
-She's catching us fast.
-Disturb the lion on his prey?
-Rather you than me, Mr. Bush.
-I'll go, sir.
No… no need, Mr. Hornblower.
36 guns to our 74.
They'd never dare.
There's two of them.
Two Frigates!
-Darn.
-That's changed the odds a bit.
-Sir!
-Mr. Hornblower, you'd better have-
-a good reason for this interruption.
-Yes, sir,-
Mr. Buckland's respects, sir and
there are two French frigates
-on the starboard quarter.
-Tell Mr. Buckland I shall be-
-on deck directly. Boswain…
-Sir, they're cleared for action-
-and coming up fast.
-Thank-you, Mr. Hornblower.
-That will be all.
-They'll be up with us in minutes,sir
Darn it, man, we can blow them
to pieces long before-
we come into range of their
piddling little popguns.
Not if we're not cleared
for action, sir.
You will answer for this later.
We thought perhaps, sir, that...
Clear for action. Clear for action,
darn you! Beat to quarters!
Come on, men, look lively!
Open the stern port.
-By God, they're fast.
-Mr. Hobbs, you will oblige me-
by taking a rope's end to those men
if they don't bestir
their miserable selves.
What's wrong with them?
-Aye, aye, sir. Come on!
-Smarten yourselves up, men!
They're drunk. That's what's
wrong with them.
Beware a loose tongue, Mr. Matthews.
You never know-
-where it might lead.
-Me tongue may be loose, Mr. Hobbs,
but at least it's not raw from
licking the captain's ass.
Come on, put your backs into her!
My God, she'll be across our stern
any moment. God help us.
I'll have no muttering on my deck.
-Where are those damned powder
monkeys?
-Right here!
First powder monkey to stern chaser,
please, Mr. Wellard.
-Put it on the side.
-Mind that tackle!
Do you think we'll be cleared
in time?
God knows.  If this crew weren't
such an ill-disciplined,
-drunken rabble, we would.
-That's not what I asked.
Nevertheless, it's the point
at issue.  Mind that, damned it!
´Way for powder!  'Way for powder!
Mr. Wellard, here!
-Sir.
-If she shows any signs of bringing-
her guns to bear, you're to
shout it out immediately.
Come away, look lively!
Load!
Pass it along, pass it along.
They're running out the guns on
the starboard side, sir!
-Shot!
-Sir,I think she's about to open fire
Belay that shot. Run her
out as she is, darn it!
-We're firing wadding, Mr. Bush.
-Wadding? What the devil?
She has to see our smoke.
None of our guns is ready.
-Very well.  Shot.
-Fire!
Sir?
Stand clear!
Reload!
-Frenchman bearing further away, sir.
-Very good, Mr. Wellard.
-Look lively, lads.
-Run her out!
Fire!
She's running off now, sir.
-We've frightened her off, sir.
-Very good. Very good.
An original concept, Horatio,
to fire the contents of your
cot at him.
It would certainly have put
me off my aim.
The Frenchman fell off the wind
at the first whiff of it.
Well, Mr. Hornblower.
Sir.
I'm informed that you fired your
stern chaser with no shot in it.
-Is that true?
-The Frenchman was bearing away-
preparatory to firing, sir.
I thought it of capital importance-
to make him think again, however
briefly,so as to give Mr.Bush-
time to fire properly before we
received the full broadside,sir
Subtle, Mr. Hornblower, subtle.
How long did it take you to cook up
that story?
Is this to be your career,
Mr. Hornblower, covering up-
your incompetence with
ingenious fairy stories?
I submit, sir, that the ploy caused
the Frenchman to…
You submit?  Good.  Submit
to just criticism and in time-
-you might make a seaman.
-Sir, with respect,
Mr. Hornblower and I agreed upon
a course of action, that-
-his stern chaser should fire
its wadding.
-You too, Mr. Bush.
-Are you joining Mr. Hornblower?
-No, no, sir; it might-
have been the wrong course
of action,but I agreed to it.
Mr.Hornblower posted Mr.Wellard
to observe the French frigate.
Mr. Wellard… ah, yes.  I'm obliged,
Mr. Bush, much obliged.
Mr. Hornblower and I have some
unfinished business-
with regard to Mr. Wellard.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Well?
-Sir, do I proceed?
-Well…
It's quite straight forward,Dr.Clive.
Mr. Matthews had beaten-
Mr. Wellard insensible.
Does he continue?
Punishment, ended.
-Bring him to the sick-bay
-Then get back on watch,Mr.Hornblower
Mr. Hornblower.
Nasty business, that,
nasty business.
But then again, boys have been
beaten since history began.
It would be a bad thing for
the world if ever boys-
should cease to be beaten.
That may well be your medical
opinion, Dr. Clive,
but I can see no useful purpose
served by thrashing a young boy
-within an inch of his life.
-Come, come, Mr. Hornblower.
A little tincture of laudanum
for the pain...
and all will soon be forgotten.
Forgotten, maybe, Dr. Clive.
But, forgiven?
Careful, Mr. Hornblower.
I've had the good fortune-
to serve the captain for over
15 years, and he has inspired-
nothing but loyalty in the men
under his command.
And that, too, is your medical
opinion, is it, Dr. Clive?
Article 19: "If any person in or
belonging to the fleet-
shall make, or endeavor to make,
any mutinous assembly-
upon any pretense whatsoever,
every person-
offending herein and being convicted
thereof by the sentence-
of the court martial shall
suffer death.
And if any person shall utter
any words of sedition or mutiny,-
they shall suffer death.
And if any officer, mariner or
soldier shall behave himself-
with contempt to his
superior officer...
or shall disobey any lawful command,
every such person
shall suffer death."
And I'll have you all know that
these articles apply-
to my officers as much as
to anyone else.
-Carry on, Mr. Buckland.
-Aye, aye, sir.
Division officers,
dismiss your divisions.
Dismiss!
-Mr. Buckland.
-Sir.
Half-duty Sunday, today.
Double rum for all these good men.
Sir.
"Extra rum for the crew."
"This rule applies to my officers."
Yes.
It's an interesting method of
fostering cooperation in the crew
Have you ever come across it before?
No, I most certainly have not.
Perhaps Captain Sawyer's methods
will prove consistent-
in the end.
Perhaps it's only an impression.
What?
The erratic nature of his command…
How do you find it?
Erratic.
Most erratic, to say the least.
Thank-you, sir. I needed reassurance
that I was not misjudging-
-the captain's mental powers.
-Not at all.
That is to say, probably not.
I suppose it's a matter for
Dr. Clive to pronounce him.
That would be the appropriate
course, yes.
Good evening, gentlemen.
You are the officer of the watch,
are you not, Mr. Hornblower?
If you'll excuse me, sir,
I'm needed up on deck.
Well, waste not, want not.
Put that back.
Or do you want me to smarten
up that big ugly face of yours?
Randall, put it back.
Mr. Hornblower.
-Well-rested, I trust.
-Sir, I'm…
Asleep on watch, you're as
good as dead already.
I'll take you out and hang you
by the neck,
unless…
I do believe your life is in my hands
You fear me, sir?
I've always held you in
the highest regard, sir.
Indeed.
I was once like you,...young,
intemperate,...
a danger to fellow officers.
-You would shoot me where I stand.
-Sir…
Here.
-Captain Sawyer, please.
-Don't trifle with me, sir.
-Shoot me.
-Stop that!
You, too, Dr. Clive?
-Is there no one I can trust?
-You should be in bed, sir.
Give it to me.
You could do yourself an injury, sir.
Come, I shall give you something
to help you sleep, sir.
Your life is in my hands.
Don't forget.
-Your life is in my hands.
-He won't forget sir.
Will you, Mr. Hornblower?
I will not, sir.
You'd do well not to let
Randall get to you.
-But, he's so…
-Hey…You're boatswain's mate now.
It's your job to keep order.
Message from Mr. Hornblower.
Could you attend to him on deck?
-Is that all he said?
-No, he said, "Look lively."
Archie...
Ah, long night.
Oh, time is only the half of it.
I feared you were
the captain returning.
Oh, why?  What new madness
has he embarked upon?
What can we do for you, Mr. Hobbs?
Captain Sawyer...I've never seen
a man so unstable in his mind.
He wants to die, Archie.
Then, let him.
My fear is that in doing so,
he'll delight-
in all of us dying with him.
What now, Hobbs?
It's Matthews, sir.
You wanted to see, me, sir?
I think I'll call her, "Bessy."
Sir…
We have unfinished business, Styles.
You're not so tough without your mate
Matthews around, are you?
I don't need any help to teach
you some manners.
You don't need no knife, neither.
Get off me, bastard!
Get off!
'Should have realized I'd been
sent on a wild goose chase, sir.
Get off him, darn you!
By God, you'll pay for this.
Now, put him in irons.
I was winning.
-What?
-He says he was winning, sir.
-Now, take him to the sick bay.
-All right.
-What the devil do you want?
-I heard there was some sort of-
an argument going on.
Natural high spirits below decks,
I dare say, sir.
I therefore ordered Randall to
be placed in irons;
Styles, who they'd kicked
almost to death…
You exaggerate, Mr. Hornblower.
There he stands, large as life.
You're too squeamish.
I've noticed that about you.
I daresay, sir.  Styles,
if you would, please.
Nevertheless, there he stands.
As I say, your squeamishness-
clouds your judgment.
I advise you to conquer it.
It does not bode well for your
conduct under fire,Mr.Hornblower
-With respect, sir, I find…
-Respect?
What do you know of respect?
You come before me with these
men whose-
boisterous high spirits led them
to knock each other-
about a bit, and you expect
me to punish them.
I like high spirits in my men,
do you hear? What I do not like-
are weak-kneed officers who do
not know how to keep order.
-Do you understand?
-I understand, sir.
Charges dismissed.
-Well?
-Charges dismissed.
Believe me now, do you?
-What the devil is he up to?
-I suspect the evidence was before
the captain before I opened
my mouth, the evidence-
-he wanted to hear, that is.
-By God, I believe you're right.
"Weak-kneed officers who do not
know how to keep order."
I've never heard the like.
Order?
He doesn't know the meaning
of the word.
Stay where you are, gentlemen.
There, every sign of guilt.
Bear witness to it, Mr. Hobbs.
Stand still.
-A mutinous assembly, I believe.
-No, sir.
Do you give me the lie on
my own quarterdeck? Plotting,...
whispering, scheming… now treating
me with gross disrespect?
I'll see that you regret this,
Mr. Buckland.
-I intended no disrespect, sir.
-Again you give me the lie.
Mr. Bush, I'm disappointed in you.
Why did you not see fit to report
this mutinous assembly to me?
I wasn't aware of them, sir.
I was helping Mr. Wellard-
take a noon site.
Mr. Wellard. Of course.
He will be in this, too.
You will be in trouble-
with these gentlemen, Mr. Wellard.
You didn't keep a sharp enough
lookout, did you, boy?
I doubt if you have a friend left
on the ship.
But, later for you.
The lieutenants first,-
as their lofty rank decrees.
You…
Mr. Hornblower,
you will resume your continuous
watch for a further 36 hours
and these three gentlemen
can report to you-
-when every watch is called.
-Aye, aye, sir.
And, at every hour of every watch,
two, four, and six bells.
Every watch, day and night,
every hour.
And, they're to be properly dressed,
that there be-
no slackness in the execution
of this order. None!
I will have means of knowing if
I am obeyed or not.
-Dr. Clive.
-Mr. Buckland.
-Mr. Buckland?
-May I rely on your confidentiality?
Good, good.  Good.
-The captain...
-The captain?
Do you think…
How would you describe his mental…
-powers, his mental state?
-I would not presume to describe-
-my commanding officer's mental state
-You can't have failed-
to notice his management of the ship.
I would not presume,Mr.Buckland.
I advise you not to,either,sir
-Ambition is one thing…
-Ambition?  What do you mean?
I'm talking about the indiscipline
of the crew.
-The ship is barely manageable.
-Hasn't it occurred to you-
-that you would be captain?
-What? What are you talking about?
For God's sake, man, if the captain
were declared unfit,
you would be acting captain,
Master under God and all
the rest of it;
sole arbiter of all lives aboard.
Sir.
Matthews.
How many hours is it now, sir?
-Thirty-five.
-Well done, sir.
'Managed 19 hours meself, once,
before I collapsed,-
-dead on me face, sir.
-What happened then?
The captain was a kind man, sir.
He gave me a dozen lashes and
let the whole matter drop.
-Pray God I'm as fortunate.
-Indeed, sir.
-Not that it'll…
-Let us hope not, Matthews.
A lively crew.
Not all, sir.
Some of the men don't like it
any more than I do.
-Watch your tongue, Matthews.
-Sorry, sir.
I speak for a third of the men, sir.
-Carry on, Mr. Matthews.
-Aye, aye, sir. Mr. Wellard.
-You understand you duty, Mr.Wellard?
-I do sir.  Good luck.
I didn't know you were
a dancing man, sir.
Just keep it down, would you?
Who threw that?
The captain will hear of this.
He'll have a right laugh
when he does!
Suppose we declare him unfit
for command?
Suppose we put him in irons?
We'd have to be quick and sharp
about it… if we do it at all.
He'll call on the hands and
they might follow him.
But, suppose we were quick
and sharp about it?
-Surely there must be some chance…
-Sir.
-Horatio?
-Listen.
I thought I'd find you here.
Did you, indeed?
The wardroom is deserted.I thought
you might be up to something
I thought you might feel that
something had to be done...
I'm not sure I follow you, Mr. Bush.
...About the captain.
-What?
-I thought you might feel...
that the captain
wasn't fit for command…
-Mr. Bush…
-…as I do.
I think we're all of one mind,
Mr. Bush.
Well, in that case,I'd be very glad
if you allow me to join you
Mr. Wellard!
I was expecting to see
Mr. Hornblower on watch.
Call of nature, Mr. Hobbs.
Well, I'll just wait a moment
for his return.
He's made a mockery of us.
Officers on continuous watch,
that's as good as a death sentence.
And Mr. Hornblower, here,
how many hours has it been?
It's certainly a novel
approach to captaincy.
-Novel? What about Wellard?
-I like it no more than you,
-Mr. Kennedy.
-So, do we act now?
Do we take a chance…
and declare him unfit?
And in Kingston, sir…
what will await us there?
-A court-martial.
-Why?  Why?  What on earth for?
Well, this is mutiny, Mr. Buckland.
Mutiny.
Well, perhaps I should check
the wardroom-
to see that Mr. Hornblower
is all right.
I hardly think that necessary,
Mr. Hobbs.
Well, we wouldn't want anything
untoward to have happened,-
would we, sir?
Where are they, Mr. Wellard?
And this is the point.
It'll sound different in court.
We've been punished;
that could happen to anyone.
-It's no grounds for mutiny.
-And the crew?
Double rum, make and mend.
It's not for us to criticize-
the captain,
so the court will think.
But when they see him, Horatio…
He's cunning.
And we all know he can talk...
and find a reason for anything.
And he's plausible.
Wellard? A midshipman, no friends,
no family.
What will the court say when
they hear the captain had-
a boy beaten a couple of times?
-They will laugh.
-And so would we...
-if we didn't know.
-We will hang for it.
Twenty-two years,
I've held my commission.
And now he'll break me.
He'll break the whole bloody ship.
Sir…  Sir…
-Hobbs.
-You said to tell you, sir.
-Yes, who?
-Lieutenants Hornblower, Bush,
Kennedy and Buckland…
-Yes?
-Not on watch, sir;
nor in the wardroom; and I thought…
Yes, by God, so do I.
-Call out the guard!
-Sir?
You heard me, Sergeant,
there's mutiny brewing,-
black, bloody mutiny.
Call out the guards!
If you find two or more of
these gentlemen together,
you will tell them to stay
exactly where they are.
Forward you go, Mr. Hobbs,
to the hold and midship.
Flush them out, the verminous scum!
-Mr.Wellard,why aren't you on watch?
-The captain,sir,he's coming
-Oh God, holly God!
-Anyone else?
He sent Hobbs to cover
the midship  section.
He's turned out the marine guard.
Mr. Wellard, come with me!
You three get for'ard-
and scatter when you're on deck.
Quickly now!
You two, go forward.
Come on!
It's the captain.
Help me, help me here.
Thank-you.
Let's get the grating.
Mr. Wellard, this way.
-Who's there?
-It's me, Hobbs, sir.
-Where are they?
-They're around here somewhere.
Let's split up, here.
Over there.
Down there!  After them!
Hurry!
I hear you.
Out!  Out!
-Or do I shoot you where you stand?
-Run, go on, get out.
Stay where you are!
They've abandoned me.
Universal treachery.
Universal desertion.
My men, where are my true men?
Keep away!
-Sir…
-Keep your distance.
Sir...
Hold on , what was that?
Come on.
-Is he dead?
-Dr. Clive is with him now, sir.
What happened?
-It would appear he fell, Mr. Bush.
-Fell?
-So it would seem, sir.
-Are you all right, Mr. Wellard?
-You're shaking.
-Quite well, sir, considering.
Mr. Wellard, would you kindly
retrieve the captain's pistols?
They could be vital evidence, sir.
Ah, yes, indeed.
Sir, Captain was talking
about mutiny, sir.
"We've got to catch the mutineers,"
he says.
Did he give you any indication
as to the identity-
-of these mutineers?
-No, sir. But, sir,
Mr. Hobbs was with him.
'Might have confided in him, sir.
Yes, thank-you.
Dismissed.
-We need to sway him up.
-Yes, very well.  Ah, Mr. Bush,
-get a tackle rigged.
-Aye, aye, sir.
Mr. Hornblower!
Mr. Kennedy!
Mr. Hornblower,
about this… accident…
Sir?
Never mind.  No, never mind.
It'll keep.
-Sir?
-Thank-you, Mr. Wellard.
Lift him together now, steady.
-The pistols, sir.
-Very well.  Over there.
-Will he survive?
-I think so.
-Will he recover?
-Depends on what you mean by"recover"
He's very severely concussed.
I think what Mr. Buckland means
is will he recover sufficiently
-to resume command?
-Impossible to say.
His skull's intact.
That's all I can tell you.
I will be on continuous watch, sir.
We'll go with the captain's orders
until we know more.
Well, what else can I do?
He might wake up this afternoon,
for God's sake.
Then what?
Out of my way, please, Mr. Hobbs.
I don't seem able to move.
Awkward, isn't it?
It can't be helped.
Though, uh…
-you can help me, sir.
-In what way?
Well, I was wondering what
happened to the captain.
And I fancy you know exactly
what happened.
Get out of my way or
I shall report you.
How can I help you with that?
I wasn't there.
Oh, I think you can, sir.
For when the captain's recovered,
there'll be shootings and
hangings aboard this ship.
And you won't want to fall foul
of those. So, I think-
you'll tell me. Afterall,
we wouldn't want to see-
your young neck stretched
like a chicken… sir.
I don't like it.
I don't like it at all.
-Mr. Buckland, we didn't do anything.
-Perhaps not.
-We all know what was said.
-Yes, but to no effect.
-The events overtook us.
-That does not mean that-
-I am comfortable with it.
-We did nothing other than consider
-our options in those circumstances
-Fate intervened,Mr.Buckland
And the air smells all
the better for it.
The captain's incapacity is not
a matter for celebration,Mr.Kennedy
Unless and until Dr. Clive pronounces
otherwise,
I would remind you that he is still
in charge of this ship.
You want me to wake him, sir?
He hasn't slept for days.
Let him have a little longer.
I don't envy his position.
He's the one that would have
to assume command.
I bet the responsibility
weighs heavy.
Why don't you get some sleep,
Mr. Kennedy?
I'll stand watch for you.
Thank-you, Mr. Bush,
-but I will share the watch with you.
-Very well.
Two days' sail from Santo Domingo.
Not long to whip this crew
into fighting shape.
No, Mr. Bush, but I am sure the task
will not prove beyond us.
-How did it happen?
-How did what?
How did the captain fall down
the hatchway?
-He must have overbalanced.
-Is that all?
-All? What do you mean"all"?
-You know what I mean.You were there
Mr. Buckland's compliments and
can you both attend him-
in the captain's cabin immediately?
-He's lost his memory, you say?
-Yes, he does not remember-
his accident at all,
or the hours preceding it.
Is he capable at present
of commanding this ship?
It needs to be established,
Dr. Clive.
-At present, no.
-Then we all know where we stand.
-For the present, we do.
-How do you propose to treat him?
Well,  bleeding him.
I may purge him later.
I've yet to refine a regime.
He's certainly calmer.
Calmer?
In what way has he not been calm?
-He looks comatose.
-That may be a natural reaction-
to his memory loss and so on…
to his injuries.
What was this quite
"natural reaction"?
He became a little agitated,
that is all.
-How?  In what way, "agitated"?
-He showed symptoms,
not extreme, of a certain
paraphronesis with occasional-
-phrenetical impulses.
-And in plain English?
I could perceive certain symptoms
as I say…
tendencies which led me
to suppose some irritation-
of the meninges, the brain lining,
in plain English,
-which caused me to think…
-In plain English, Dr. Clive,
is the captain capable
of resuming command?
-No.
-Thank-you.
-For the time being.
-Oh, we're back there again, are we?
And we won't know, will we,
if you keep him in this condition?
-What do you mean?
-You're giving him laudanum,
aren't you?
What business is it of yours?
I'm his doctor.
One does not need to be a doctor
to know the effects of opiate.
What, you're dosing him with
laudanum, Dr. Clive?
-Well, are you?
-A certain dosage seems to be
appropriate.
How will we ever know if the captain
is capable of running this
ship if you're keeping him in
a constant state of sedation?
You will oblige me, Dr. Clive,
by leaving off-
your drugging of the captain.
I do believe a bit of bruising
about the face-
improves your looks.
I've had worse beatings at
the hands of me father…
if he was me father.
Next time, I'm going to do you
for good, Styles.
It's you we'll be tossing to
the crabs, Randall.
'Cept they'd spit him out.
Because they're very particular-
about what they eat, are crabs.
It's more likely when the captain
comes back, you two-
will be dancing from the end
of a rope.
You and whoever it was who pushed
the captain into the hold.
Save it Styles.  He's all mouth.
Oh no, that's a promise.
I've got a nice bit of yardarm
for you two,
and an extra bit for Mr. Wellard.
The captain fell; we all know that.
-'Course he did.
-Anyway, you two won't be so leery-
if the captain doesn't come back,
I can tell you.
-Why not?
-Because Lieutenant Buckland is
a born fool.
He couldn't command a trip
around the bay,
never mind a seventy-four.
Dr. Clive, it is necessary
for me formally-
to assume command of this ship.
-What's preventing you?
-You are, Dr. Clive.
You will not declare the captain
unfit for command.
You keep prevaricating.
Until you declare him unfit,
it would be a usurpation of power.
"Mutiny" in other words! Why are
you so frightened of the word?
You don't seem frightened of
the fact that someone-
may have shoved him down that ladder,
nearly killed him.
That's what you should be concerning
yourselves with,
not the niceties of taking over!
-Dr. Clive, this is hardly helpful.
-Helpful be darned.
I served with him on 3 ships.
I know him!
-The man's a hero.
-You're drunk, darn it, drunk.
Dr. Clive, we are less than
2 days' sail away from Samana Bay,
where we are to see action.
It is vital that you declare-
the captain unfit to command
this ship and for it to be noted.
You will please satisfy us as
to this point.
Darned if I will.
There he is, you decide.
Satisfy yourselves!
It may be a useful, cautionary
measure, sir, if Mr. Kennedy-
were to note Dr. Clive's inebriated
condition.
It may be that he is
incapable himself-
of carrying out his duties.
Too slow, gentlemen.
And we need to be faster-
-when we engage the enemy!
-Call yourselves a gun crew?
We'll be blown out of the water!
Right, let's show these bastards
how it should be done, eh?
Reload!
-Gun ready, Mr. Hornblower.
-Run her out!
-Gun ready, Mr. Bush!
Fire!
One minute, 35, Mr Bush,
to my one minute 28.
-Better.
-But not good enough.
Reload!
You're a real taskmaster,
Mr. Hornblower.
We'll make a crew out of them,
yet, Mr. Bush.
-Much better, gentlemen.
-We're getting there, sir.
You unwell, Mr. Hornblower?
No, sir...
but I have a request, sir.
-He wants to do what?
-That's what he said.
Well, whoever heard of that?
Come and look at this.
Could you do that?
Hey, stop that Styles!
Pump, you sons of sea cooks, pump!
They're pumping as hard
as they can, sir.
Styles!
This is my ship, not a public
bath house!
Mr. Buckland, you will arrest
lieutenants-
-Bush, Hornblower and Kennedy.
-Sir!
Arrest them!  Unless you care
to join them!
Very well.  Sergeant Whiting.
Sir!  Come along, gentlemen.
And clap them in arms like
the mutinous dogs they are.
Santo Domingo
Samaná Bay
By the mark...Five!
And a quarter less five!
Deep four!
And a half four!
Heave!
Belay.
It's no good, sir.
We'll never bring the guns to bear.
The fort's too high up.
-Sir…
-Get away!  Get away!
Sir, I beg you.  We are standing
in to terrible danger.
By the mark three!
There is only a few feet
of water under us, sir.
We must turn now,
before it's too late.
No, no, I don't want to.
I want to fight them.
Then at least let me release
the other lieutenants.
Without them there will be no one
to command the guns.
Oh, no, you don't, Mr. Buckland.
I know what you want.
They'll stay just where they are.
We're going to come under
fire at any minute.
Why doesn't Buckland do something?
Most of the hands-
would back him up.
They're not stupid.
Hobbs, come here now!
For God sake, man, this is madness.
Get us out of here.
'Can't do that sir. You know I can't.
You can't work the guns
on your own, Hobbs.
-You need us, Hobbs.
-I can't.
Hobbs, get us out of here now.
That's an order.
No.
-Darn, I thought we had him there.
-We did.
That's it!  That's more like it!
Return fire, Mr. Buckland.
We cannot elevate the guns
enough, sir.
I said, "Return fire" or by God
I will!
-Engage the enemy, Mister.
-Sir…
A quarter less three!
This is my ship!
Fire!
What the devil?
We're aground. God help us.
We're aground.
Styles.  Come on!
Heated shot!
They're using heated shot!
I wouldn't worry, Mr. Kennedy.
We'll drown long before we burn.
Ahoy there!  Ahoy there!
Here!
Go, grab ahold.   Hold tight.
Why is it I can never find you
when I need you?
Get Clive.  Get the doctor.
And tell him to bring
a straight jacket.
-Where do you think you're going?
-No, you don't!
-Oh Randall, get out of my way.
-Make me.
Two, six, heave!
-Hold him down.
-Mr. Buckland's compliments
and will you-
-please come to the quarterdeck?
-My respects to-
the first lieutenant,but no,
it's impossible.You see why,surely
-The captain, sir, he's not himself.
-Is he wounded?
-No, sir, but…
-Well, these men are!
Now pass me that sword.
Stand back, gents.
We'll soon have you out of there.
Do your stuff, Styles.
Thank-you, Matthews.  Now, find
the carpenter and get that hole
-plugged up, then meet us up on deck.
-Aye, aye, sir.
-Mr. Buckland, you all right,sir?
-We're aground.
-Fast aground.
-We'll have to get her off with
the anchors.
-Where is the captain, sir?
-He's gone to earth somewhere.
I've sent young Wellard to
look for the doctor.
Where the hell is he?
We'll need to get a cable out
through a stern port.
Well, Matthews can do that, sir.
I'll take a boat, and stand by
under the stern to take the cable
if you'll bring the anchor
round in the launch.  Mr. Kennedy
can man the capstan.
-Very good.
-Styles, you come with me.
-Give us plenty of slack, Matthews.
-Aye, aye, sir.
-More slack!
-Come on, men!
Now give way together.
Sir, if you please, the captain
was in a very bad way.
-I do beg you to go to him.
-In a minute.  In a minute.
More ligatures.
Stretch out, Mr. Hornblower.
Stretch out.
Row, darn you, row!
Come on, quickly. We're going to lose
the anchor, come on!
She's ready to go, come on.
Quickly, men!
Feed it through the anchor ring!
Quickly, she's going to go down!
-Quick, she' gonna go! She's going.
-Pull it over the stock.
She's going down!  Quickly!
I'm drowning!  Mr. Hornblower,
my arm's trapped!
-Anchor's let go, sir!
-Heave away, there!  Heave away, men!
Powder monkeys!
Where are the powder monkeys?
Mr. Bush.
They pushed me, that's what they did.
Pushed me.  Mutiny.
By God.  It is mutiny.
-Come on men, the ship's at stake!
-Heave, men!
Heave and wake the dead!
Move those bodies there.
Stay to your post.  Get up!
Move the capstan back!
Where is he?  Where is he?
He's over there somewhere.
Mr. Wellard, find Sergeant Whiting.
Bring him here with four of his men.
Quickly, now.
Captain Sawyer, sir, it's me…
Dr. Clive.
I was right.
Heave, darn it! Heave!
Do you want to sit here-
till the next tide while they shoot
us to pieces?  Heave!
-Did you feel it?
-When the guns fired.
It must have broken the suction.
Double shot the guns.
-I'll tell Buckland.
-Double shot the guns!
Mr.Hornblower,what's happening below?
-If we miss this tide we're finished
-Mr.Bush's compliments,sir
We're about to fire every
gun double-shotted.
But, we can't elevate the guns
enough even to hit the fort.
Recoil may shake us free, sir.
There, there he is.
He's one of them.
Mutineers, all of them.
You're under arrest-
for mutiny and treason!
Now, Sergeant Whiting, do your duty.
The priority is to refloat
the ship, sir.
What?  So we should, yes.
Mr. Wellard, my respects to Mr. Bush.
Tell him to carry on.
Stay there, you puppy!
I give the orders here!
-Mr. Wellard, if you please.
-Aye, aye, sir.
Do your duty, Sergeant.
Darn your eyes, do your duty
or by God, I will.
Dr. Clive, is the captain fit
to command this vessel?
-You know it's not as simple as that.
-Arrest him!
Dr.Clive,if you continue to
prevaricate, we shall all die here.
-I'll count to three…
-Sir, I beg you.
One, Two!
-You're endangering the ship, sir.
Dr. Clive!
-All right, yes!
Three!
Keep it going now, heave!
-What happened?
-Sergeant Whiting,
the captain has been declared
unfit for command.
Please disarm him and
escort him below.
We're coming off!
Stand by the sheets!
Horatio, what's going on?
The doctor has finally decided
that the captain-
-is unfit to command.
-It was under duress.
Did you or did you not declare
the captain unfit for command?
You were being threatened with
a pistol, for God's sake!
-By whom?
-By the captain.
-Take him to his cabin.
-You'll swing for this. You all will.
Tell me, Mr. Hornblower,
did you know that the captain-
-had fired his pistol?
-No, sir.
Oh, I see.
We were hard aground, sir.
We were as good as dead already.
-You just took a gamble
-They seemed reasonable
enough odds,sir.
-Ready when you are, sir.
-Mr. Bush?
You're in command of
the Renown now, sir.
Yes.  Very well.
Let's get this ship underway
before the Dons sink us.
-Raise sheets and tack!
-Home, mails'l home!
Helm hard a larboard!
And so the ship was saved.
Yes, sir.
It was Dr. Clive's opinion
that Captain Sawyer-
was unfit to command?
Reluctantly, yes;
that was his opinion.
Well, that's something, at least.
But, you do realize, sir,
it's your word against his.
It was for the good of
the Service, sir;
-and for the safety of the ship.
-By God, Mr. Hornblower,-
I hope you can back that up with
solid evidence because from-
where I'm standing, I wouldn't lay
great odds on an acquittal.
No, sir.
-I'm afraid you're right
-So, you say Captain Sawyer's
condition
-was due to falling down the hatchway
-That's what seemed-
to push him over the edge, sir.
That's a very interesting choice
of words, Mr. Hornblower.
How did the captain come to fall?
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org