Master Bediuzzaman's
opinions about cinema and art:
'The lord must be as elaborate as
the nature of its meaning allows.
The form must be drawn
according to its content...
...and the meaning's permission
must be taken during its drawing.
The style must be featured, but the purpose
and meaning must never be failed.
The imagination must be supported
with an ample scope...
...but the truth must never be hurt.'
Bediiuzzaman Said Nursi.
Dedicated to the heroes
of the Divine Light.
A FILM BY MEHMET TANRISEVER
Nurs Village - Bitlis 1882
Bismillah! (in the name of God)
Look! The moon has eclipsed!
What does it mean, mom?
Why is it like that?
Because a snake has swallowed the moon.
But it is still visible.
The snakes above are like glass,
they show Ihat's inside.
Bismillah!
Bismillah is the beginning
of every charity, son.
Don't be afraid mom, don't be afraid!
I am next to you.
Declare the concision of Koran.
Don't be afraid, brothers.
The freedom is in the faith.
We will fight with the knowledge
against the ignorance.
We will tight with art and craft
against poverty.
We will tight with unity and solidarity
against controversy
EASTERN FRONT 1916
Magnificence and grandeur pertains to Allah
and we only obey to Him!
These cannon balls of the infidels can't kill us!
Felt-caps! We will not deign to retreat!
We will not deign to retreat!
Bismillah! Allahu Ekber!
Write my brother Mullah Habib!
Bismillah is the beginning of each and
every charity. We too start with it.
Kosturma Prisoner Camp - Russia 1916
Attention!
Stand up. Stand up.
I don't think he recognized me.
I don't think you recognized the commander.
I did. He is the chief commander of
Caucasian Front Nikola Nikolovich.
He is the uncle of Russian Czar.
I did. He is the chief commander of
Caucasian Front Nikola Nikolovich.
He is the uncle of Russian Czar
So you are insulting me.
So you are insulting.
No, I am not insulting.
I duly oblige my faith.
I am a Moslem scholar.
So I lon't rise.
Stand up immediately!
By not standing up, you are insulting me,
my army and the Czar!
This is a big crime!
Set up an immediate court martial and try him!
-What is this? An escape plan?
No. This is the plan of my school!
You should say your last prayer
instead of thinking such plans.
Youll probably be executed soon.
You may never know commander!
Fate is unique, can't be changed.
Take aim!
Fire!
Please don't kill me! Don't kill!
Take aim!
Fire!
Stop!
A man who is about to be executed takes it slow.
Why do you hurry?
I want to reach my Lord as soon as possible!
I am sorry! I thought your intention
las to insult me.
Now I see that your behaviors
truly come from your faith.
After 2 years of captivity, Said Nursi
found a chance to goto Istanbul via Europe...
...in the chaos of 1917 Bolshevik Revolution.
He started a civil resistance
against British occupation.
He las officially invited to Ankara
by Mustafa Kemal Pasha...
...for his activities supporting
Kuvay-l Milliye (National Forces).
He wasn't satisfied with the negotiations he did
after his address to the congress.
He lent to Van City.
SHEIKH SAID REBELLION - 1925
Stop! What are you doing?
We are revolting Seyda!
Against what? Against who are you revolting?
The caliphate has been abolished.
An irreligious government has been established
in Ankara, we are revolting against this, Seyda!
Fighting against the descendants of a nation who
served Islam for thousand years is against Islam!
Bismillah.
My Allah!
I want to explain the whole world that
Koran is an undying, inextinguishable sun.
Help me!
Surrender Hodja! We came to take you.
What am I accused of?
We have orders.
What do you want from us?
These people have nothing to do
with the Sheikh Said rebellion!
It is a mistake to take away
the scholars of this city!
If they go, the people won't be educated!
Take us, send us to exile but let our scholars free!
Hodja! Let's go!
We will flee you away.
Our horses and men are ready!
Let's go in this mess.
We will take you to Iran.
Come on Hodja. That's our chance!
Don't lorry!
Said is not going to exile, but to his cause!
Hey you, move away.
What are you talking about? Go away!
Handcuff them two by two!
Come on, stand up! Stand up!
Enough. Enough!
We have nothing to do with the revolt!
We aren't involved in the evolt!
We didn't even see Sheikh Said!
Stand up! Move!
Bediuzzaman has stopped us!
It is a huge mistake to hold him!
At least let him free!
Assalamualaikum Seyda!
Waalaikummussalam Sheikh Masum Arvasi brother!
They didn't care you are the Mufti of Van City
and arrested you too?
Yes Seyda!
I don't think they know what they're doing.
That's true, brother.
These men don't know what they are doing,
but someone knows it!
Stop. Listen to me!
There is nothing to lorry!
These soldiers are not our enemies,
but your brothers! Don't counter!
I have surrendered to Allah. I am going
to the heart of Anatolia with my own lill...
...into the caring arms of my nation!
One of the Van exiles,
the hodja named Said-i Kurdi...
...has been sent to your district,
accompanying with a gendarme...
...to stay compulsorily.
Do not be fooled by
his innocent manners.
His ideas are extremely dangerous.
Warn the people and
break his contact with the people.
Keep him under surveillance and
report the developments to provincial authorities.
Signed: Governor of Isparta.
We shouldn't travel in this leather
but let's hope the best.
I have my orders. I will bring this hodja
to Barla today even the Flood breaks!
Look at the act of Allah, look at the leather.
Soldier friend, how do you bring this hodja
on your own, don't you scare?
I told the same to my commander.
But told me that he is a saintly person,
and does not hurt anyone.
It's the time.
Excuse me.
What is it, hodja?
Boatman, turn the boat to the direction of Mecca,
the hodja will perform the namaz.
I shot it! I shot it, hodja,
I shot it! I shot the partridge!
Let it go, soldier friend!
It's the breeding time!
Ouch my foot!
Hodja!
Is he too dangerous?
And how!
The District Administrator said so.
His ideas are very dangerous.
They will jail everyone who speaks to him.
That's enough.
You don't know what you are talking about.
What kind of a people you are!
You believe everything like children!
You have to shame on your age!
OK, fine. We are cowards
and you are brave huh?
Go greet him and End yourself in the jailhouse.
Sure I will go!
They can do whatever they lill.
Here he comes!
-Assalamualaikum!
-Waalaikummussalam.
Welcome.
What is this all about?
Commander, I hope this hodja is not a
dangerous person as the Governor says.
If he were, they would have sent him
with a squad of soldiers.
Oh yeah, look to the Gendarme, look.
What is this?
What is going on?
Guardian, go help the soldier.
-Welcome hodja!
-Thank you
I am the District Administrator Yasar!
Top Sergeant is the commander of our patrol.
Sir!
I am from 18th Regiment.
Don't lorry about the report.
Go and get a treatment!
Thank you, sir!
This is the file of the hodja.
Take him inside, soldier friend.
Please hodja, please come in.
Come in.
Oh, is that you Emigrant Hodja?
Wait outside, I am coming!
I will give the hodja into your custody.
But you have to be very careful!
He is very dangerous.
Don't take your eyes away from him!
But mister administrator.
You know him wrong!
Enough, shut up and know your limits Emigrant.
Ifl say that he is dangerous, then he is dangerous!
Do you know better than me?
Look, they will not only hang you,
but me and the top sergeant as well.
Do not take your eyes away from him.
Do you know what happened in the east, huh?
They hanged thousands of hodjas.
Do you know that?
Life is sleet Emigrant, life is sleet.
You are responsible from him. Be careful.
And don't talk about this to anyone.
Please come, hodja.
I was waiting for you.
-Allow me to take it.
-It is not necessarily.
-Let me take it, my hodja,
-All right.
Please come in my hodja.
My humble house is on that lay.
I am the imam of this village, hodja.
As our grandfathers immigrated from Rumelia,
they call me Emigrant.
And I know a little about being an imam,
so they call me Emigrant Hatiz.
Hodja, I had read on the newspaper.
You made a wonderful speech
in the Congress in Ankara.
Everybody esteemed you,
listened your lords.
But hodja...
Even though they know very well that
you did not participate into Sheikh Said rebellion...
...why did they send you to exile?
What do they want from you, hodja?
Allah may give you happiness
in both worlds my brother.
Hodja, you take rest.
I will have your meal ready.
Come in.
You too, come.
Open your hands.
The breakfast is ready, husband.
All right.
I will let hodja know.
Hodja!
My honorable Hodja!
Hodja.
He is not here!
He is gone!
Oh no! What will I say to
District Administrator now?
-Look, did you see the hodja?
-No, I didn't see him.
You didn't see?
Oh my God, where did the man go?
What will I do now?
The administrator will hang you!
Allah forbid.
I know! I know!
Do you knol? Listen lunatic, please tell me
for Allah's sake. Where did he go?
There he is. There he is!
-Hodja, Assalamualaikum.
-Waalaikummussalam.
I'm sorry hodja, just curious,
what are you doing here?
I am laying the foundation of my school.
-What's it hodja, what school?
-Medresetiiz-Zehra. My new school.
One day mister Hatiz,
this Barla that you see, will be a great school!
And with Allah's willing, its branches will be
opened in the entire world!
If Allah willing, hodja.
What's going on, husband?
We had a stroke of a great luck, life!
This place used to be the village hall.
Now you can stay here alone and rest.
Hodja, I just wondered.
Why didn't you stay in Emigrant's house?
I didn't want to disturb him.
I see. Oh hodja, let me tell you this.
Ankara is uncomfortable about you.
Please don't put me in a hard situation OK?
We support the law and order, administrator.
You don't have to worry.
Just don't fall into the same delusions with Ankara.
You are right about that.
Mister hodja, the view here is really nice.
Do you see this maple tree?
It must be 800 to 1000 years old.
Hello my maple brother. Hello.
Welcome, come in.
Come on look what I will give you.
You came also?
And you will also come?
Come in.
You are my first visitors.
The believers, the immigrants, and the ones
who tight with all their properties and lives...
...in a holy lar for Allah
have great values on Allah's side.
Those are who reach
to salvation and bliss.
-Assalamualaikum, hodja!
-Waalaikummussalam.
-Let me carry for you.
-Don't bother yourself.
Not at all.
Let me take.
Welcome to Barla, hodja.
My name is Suleyman.
Thank you brother. My name is Said.
-Where are you from, hodja?
-I am from Nurs village of Bitlis.
They brought you from so far away huh?
Here.
Assalamualaikum.
Waalaikummussalam Suleyman brother,
please come in.
Come in.
-I brought you larm soup, hodja.
-Thank you.
-And these are your new shoes.
-Please come and sit.
I better not sit.
I will go to district directorate.
I have a field problem you know.
All right my brother, all right.
How much are the shoes?
-They cost 2 Liras my hodja.
-Two Liras. Here is the price of the shoes.
And this ten kurus for the soup.
I can't take it, hodja.
It is a treat.
Yes you can, my brother. Take it.
Hodja, I am an illiterate man.
How about if I come here time to time
and you tell me about Allah and prophet.
You can come anytime, brother.
But only with the condition that, this doesn't hinder
the livelihoods of your family and your children.
They are making great preparations in Ankara.
The script will be changed.
The books will be completely renewed.
The dress code be changed.
And superstitions such as religion and afterlife
will be removed from the books.
-It's not possible mister inspector.
-What do you mean, administrator?
I mean, whose idea is this?
Europe praised education, science,
technology, and abandoned the religion...
...so they progressed.
What did we do?
We praised Allah and Allah and we regressed.
That's the lay it is going to be.
You just don't bother
whose idea this is.
Or you will get into a big trouble.
Just don't say I didn't lam you.
They will remove all the religion and so.
We will be like the Europeans.
-What is it, hodja?
-So it is, huh!
Hodja.
Meal.
What happened to hodja, Suleyman?
I will never ever allow this.
I will prove. I will prove.
Allah is my witness, I will prove this.
I will never allow this.
TAHIR PASHA RESIDENCY - VAN 1907
Mullah Said, you have some perseverance, huh!
You have been my guest in my mansion for a year.
You have read and finished all the books
in my library about religion and science.
God knows you already memorized them.
Last week you said 80 volumes, right?
We fell really very behind of Europe
on sciences, Pasha.
So we have to work hard.
The Ottoman is collapsing because of this reason.
We must do something.
I lent to the Ottoman Sultan
to suggest opening schools...
...in which the religion
and science will be taught together...
...and I found myself in a nut house.
We can illuminate the darkness of the
ignorance only with Koran's divine light.
That's how we can rise.
Someone is obviously alare of this.
Look at the newspaper.
The British Secretary for the Colonies adressed
the House of Commons with a Koran in his hand.
'As long as this Koran stays in the hands of the
Muslims, we can't truly dominate them.
We should either take Koran from them,
or alienate them from the Koran!
We will bring them in such a position that they will
read Koran, but will not understand its meaningl'
Koran is an undying, inextinguishable Sun!
I will prove this to the entire world.
Allah is my witness, I will prove it.
Please Allah, grant it to me!
Nol look at Allah's merciful arts.
How come a Creator of
endless mercy and power...
...who ressurects a dead and lizened
world and gives life to it...
...who turns winters into springs
and show His might in recreating...
...more then three hundred thousand plant species...
...does not bring the Judgment day?
How come He does not
or cannot bring the Judgment Day?
or cannot resurrect humans?
A needle cannot be without a craftsman;
a letter cannot be without a clerk...
...a book cannot be without a writer!
On the earth page of this book of universe,
every tree is a lord...
...every fruit is a letter
and every kernel is a dot.
-Selamiinaleykiim uncle.
-Waalaikummussalam.
-How are you, are you fine?
-I'm fine.
-How is your health? Let me kiss your hand.
-Thank you.
Look what I brought for you.
Mehmet!
-Mehmet of Damascus!
-Assalamualaikum. Welcome!
Waalaikummussalam, thank you uncle Emigrant.
Do you know who came to Barla after you left?
I wish the best.
It's good.
My hodja! It is you!
It is you, hodja.
Welcome, hodja!
You're welcome, you're welcome.
Thanks my Lord, I saw you again!
God bless you by brother, God bless you.
-Don't bother hodja, let me do it.
-You are my guest. Please.
-Please.
-Thank you, hodja.
Hodja. I can't forget that day.
I las just 13 years old
I saw you in Damascus.
We listened to you in Umayyad mosque
together with my father.
What a wonderful speech that las, hodja.
My father's told me to serve you as his lill.
Please allow me to serve you, hodja!
Not at all.
Not to me, let's serve to Koran together.
Write it down, brother!
First lord.
Bismillah is the beginning of
each and every charity.
The faith is both the divine light and the power.
The faith makes a man a human
and maybe a sultan.
Assalamualaikum.
-Waalaikummussalam.
-I brought some food for you.
-Thank you brother.
How are you, hodja,
is your health good?
-Thanks Allah. I hope you are also in good health.
-Thanks Allah, hodja.
Praise be.
Please.
Look at AIIah's mercy arts,
look how he resurrects the world after death.
Doubtlessly, He who makes it
is the one who resurrects the death people.
His power is enough for everything.
Husband, you've been lriting the
treatise of the divine light since the evening.
Drink your coffee and take some rest,
let me write a little bit.
Thank you my life, thank you.
After hodja came, the peace and
the prosperity in the house grew.
Thanks to him. Our master
taught us to live frugally, my life.
Let's lurk hard and lrite much, brothers.
These divine lights illuminate Barla
and all the villages lith Allah's willing.
Look at AIIah's mercy arts,
look how he resurrects the world after death.
Doubtlessly, He who makes it
is the one who resurrects the death people.
His power is enough for everything.
-Assalamualaikum.
-Waalaikummussalam.
I brought you cherries, hodja.
-How much is a basket of cherries?
-Five kurus, master.
Not ten kurus my master. I said Eve kurus.
No! I brought them as a present,
I will not take the money.
-Then I will not take the cherries!
-We don't take, neither.
We, neither.
-Yes Mehmet.
-All right, master.
Here.
We are writing non-stop my master...
...but who will know about what we write
in this middle of nowhere?
Felt-capped! Felt-capped!
One day, the whole world will read these writings!
Both my writings and Barla are very important!
Barla will serve like a school!
The divine light written here,
will spread to the whole world!
You are still not alare
what kind of a cause you are helping and why.
Guard...
-...what are they doing over there?
-They are writing and reading.
-What?
God is Almighty. God is Almighty.
(prayer call in Turkish)
Oh Lord.
Everything is going to change, guard.
Everything is going to change.
-Everything?
-Everything.
Who are you?
I am asking you who you are,
and you are asking me who I am.
Now I am asking you, who are you?
I am the District Administrator.
District Administrator.
-Do you know what these are?
-What?
These are called Treatise of Divine Light.
These are going out from this small district
till Ankara, making them anxious!
Even though they are lritten in the banned script
they are passing from hand to hand.
Are you sleeping?
Are you blind, District Administrator?
Well, and you are...?
I am sorry sir, my apologies.
We sent him to the most remote corner
for oblivion, but you couldn't silence him.
You made him more famous!
You just couldn't control him.
Shame on you!
He is only writing sir.
He writes, but he writes another script,
District Administrator.
May it be easy, sister Zehra!
Seeing you carrying the woods,
Friend Hafiz must be very busy, I assume.
Who is she, guard?
She is the wife of
Mehmet Hafiz of Damascus.
Hafiz of Damascus. Who is he?
He is one of the Hodja's major,
most royal men.
Oh! So he is!
Welcome sir.
Where the hell are your hats?
Didn't you hear the new law?
Listen to me! From not on, everybody
will wear a fedora like this gentleman.
If can't find it, then wear this.
But we don't have money.
'We don't have money.'
Take them oh'. Come on.
Don't you even have chickens!
Sell them and buy one.
Listen to me.
From not on it is forbidden
to go out without a hat. Do not break the order.
I'II put you in jail.
You will fade in prison.
Move it!
Ignorant folks, sir!
They don't know about the civilization.
Where is hodja, guard?
Where is the hodja?
We are almost there, sir.
Why didn't you take off your turban brother?
There is a law.
Yes my friend. The government gave an order.
We have to obey this order.
If the guard sees you, he will seize you.
-Take it off. Do you want to get into trouble?
-Is it worth for a turban?
Will you fade away in prison?
You have a family. Pity.
Aleykiimselam.
-He came from Ankara, from Ankara!
-Oh, is that so!
Who are they, guard?
That one is Hafiz Ali of islémkiiy.
The other one is from Sav village.
That one is Hiisrev of Isparta.
And the other one is Captain Hulusi.
Captain?
And who are they?
They call them Divine Light's Messengers.
They are lriting and distributing.
And you are just staring, is that so?
Yes please?
You too?
Me too, brother.
The man has established not an organization,
but a state!
What has he done in this small district?
Where is this hodja? Where is he, guard?
Where are they, guard? Where are they?
Dear sir:
One day, together with the toln's guard...
we climbed to a hill
which the local people call Pine Mountain.
771ese men are crazy. I saw it, sir:
They are climbing to the mountains
and lriting books, reading books.
Their number is increasing every day.
Guard told me tllaL they climb
every summer to Pine Mountain like the nomads.
Said-i Nursi asks them to do this.
771is man is really crazy.
He doesn't wear the hat, either, sir!
E verybudy keeps in step with the mndemity...
...ony he and his students
are not changing their clothes. They are crazy, sir.
They camp on the top of the mountain,
they are organizing and training.
They are breaking the bans
and challenging the modernity.
VW1at do you avant me to do about these camps?
I am waiting for your orders. ismet.
Master.
-May I shave my beard?
-Why Mehmet?
But master, you don't have, either.
My brother Mehmet, I spent a life
with wars and difficulties.
Noll am living in exile.
I fought even for this turban
at the cost of my head.
Ifl had a beard and it las shaved,
I Iouldn't stand it and I would die.
We have guests, master.
Welcome sister.
I brought milk for you hodja.
Goat milk.
God bless you.
-Here.
-I brought this as a present.
Please take this.
It is not how I do things.
I brought partridge for you, hodja.
Thanks. What is your name?
-Sadlk.
-Praise be.
What a nice name you have. I hope
you will be faithful as your name means.
Do you know how to read and write Sadlk?
All right, then I will accept
this partridge with one condition.
-You will learn how to read and write with us, deal?
-Deal hodja.
We shepherd the goats downhill
with my son.
We allays hear your voices.
My son is curious about you.
He imitates your speech every day.
Show him, son.
Bismillah is an endless power,
is an unending blessing.
Praise be! He is a very clever boy.
All right, not go with your mother.
Tomorrow you can come and
study with your brother Mehmet.
-Thank you, hodja.
-God bless you, hodja.
God bless you, too.
Mehmet, is there anyone
who will go to the town?
Praise be.
Uncle hodja.
I learned to write.
Come here, come and sit.
Let me see.
Bravo Sadlk! Your handwriting is beautiful!
-I also like these high hills.
-Hold this.
Look.
Lt also loves heights,
flying freely over the heights.
What do you say,
shall we let it free?
What is happening hodja?
Look! The moon is eclipsed
What does it mean, mom?
Why is it like that?
Because a snake has swallowed the moon.
Don't be afraid my son, don't be afraid.
Say Bismillah!
Bismillah is the beginning of every charity, son.
In astronomy science
this is called the solar eclipse.
Who darkens the sun, hodja?
No one darkens the sun, my son.
Make your hands like fists.
This is the sun, this is the earth
and this is the moon.
When the moon passes between
the sun and earth, it covers the light...
...so the sun is eclipsed.
Don't lorry, nothing can turn oh' the sun light.
Look, it is brightened.
Oh no! My mother told me to come back
early enough. We will milk the goats! I am late!
Where are my shoes.
These are your new shoes, our present.
No, I Ion't wear them!
I don't accept unrequited presents, either.
Then write a complete copy of this
and we will be even, ok?
I will write. I will write
the exact copy and bring it.
Silence.
Everybody listen to me.
I will read the reforms
which must be complied from not on!
One: No one will write and read in the old script.
It is banned!
Two: From not on, no one will give the call
for prayers or listen to it in Arabic.
Banned!
-Selamiinaleykiim!
-Waalaikummussalam!
Listen to me.
From not on, no one will talk
to the exiled hodja. It is banned!
Come on, guard. What does the reforms
have got to do anything with talking to hodja?
Listen, from not on it is also forbidden
to play the Saz and singing the folk-songs.
From not on, this one will be played.
-This is called the mandarin. Got it?
-Are you sure it is not orange, guard?
Thank you.
Baker brother! Don't give me
more than I deserved.
-This is redundant. Here.
-Don't mention it, hodja.
I can manage for 15 days with a loaf of bread
and 3 months with a kilo of honey.
My ration is two loaves of bread. I deserved
this much. Wish you a good business.
Hodja you are making our lives easier.
Give me bread. Give me bread.
Here, friend Sevket.
Sevket loves the hodja.
Would you like some, too, kids?
Seyda. Will you accept a guest?
Welcome.
Please come in.
Thank you. Thanks Seyda.
They exiled us to the villages of E§irdir.
We are coming from there.
We are the relatives of Sheikh Said.
Sheikh Said's letter.
Honorable Seyda Nibs.
Unfortunately it is no more possible for us
to come to an agreement with the Government.
The religion will be lost.
We're laiting for your urgent support for our cause.
Sincerely yours.
We will uprise.
An right!
Sl I ask, which holy purpose
makes you consider joining to this revolt?
We want Sharia.
Do you want Sharia?
But what you are doing is against the Sharia!
It will help the foreigners!
They abolished the caliphate.
If we don't help the Sheikh, they will totally
erase the name of Islam from our country.
They keep talking about Turkishness Seyda!
They are allays bashing the Kurdish people!
Listen, honorable men.
A mistake cannot be corrected
with another mistake!
Just because someone is making a mistake,
doesn't mean that you have to do the same.
Turks and Kurds are brothers and sisters!
They have been sewing together
to the religion for centuries.
If there are faulty people among them,
go and lam them mildly.
The Sharia cannot be saved with actions
against it, with the idea of tribalism!
You cannot achieve anything
with revolt or revolution.
You will just kill the innocent people.
You will cause brothers kill brothers.
And you will be slapped
by the opposite of your purpose!
I will not join you!
I will not tight with you against
the descendants of this gallant nation...
...who has served the religion!
In a country, the lar is made with
science and following the right path.
Renounce this purpose.
Tell Sheikh Said that...
...he should also renounce!
How have you been doing?
We struggle.
I struggle a lot, too, brothers.
I lost 9 teeth in the last three months.
I am under a continuous pressure.
Iwish I had a craft to lurk and support you.
I am just a hodja.
All I can do is teaching.
I can't provide you a financial relief.
Be patient.
These hard days will be over, with AIIah's willing.
It's a great honor to see you.
It gave us patience.
It strengthen us.
May Allah be with you.
Thanks Seyda. God bless you.
May Allah help you my brothers.
Who are they?
Relatives of rebel Sheikh Said.
Aha, the commander is coming.
-Assalamualaikum.
-Waalaikummussalam, sir.
-Who is he?
-Major.
-Where is he going?
-To hodja's house.
God is Almighty. God is Almighty.
(call for prayer in Turkish)
Allalruekben Allalruekbed
(call for prayer in Arabic)
-Lailahaillallah!
-Hands up!
Hands up!
Come on.
How dare you, mister soldier?
Banned! It is banned
to call for prayer in Arabic.
Is it also banned inside the mosque?
Your lay of clothing is also banned.
The turban on your head is also banned.
Is the Kurdish Hodja orders you
to do like that?
Son, this is banned, that is banned.
Are we unbelievers huh?
May Allah forbid.
-Yes?
-Move away. We lill make a search.
-What is it, what search?
-Where are the treatises?
Stop, how dare you trespass on my privacy?
You are coming with us
to the police station. Move!
-What station?
-The commander has ordered.
Father! Father!
Move. Move.
Come on, move.
Where do you take us?
Where is our master?
Hodja, we have the orders.
They want you from Isparta.
I las expecting this, Administrator.
I las expecting.
We will keep you in the station
and then set forth in the morning.
So, the time has come.
Then please allow me till the morning.
No, you have to come with us.
Let him stay, Administrator.
l'll put a guard to the door.
Will you?
All right, as it is then.
But, Hodja...
...I cannot send you to Isparta like that.
You have to take your turban off and wear a hat.
Listen to me, District Administrator!
I represent your grandfathers!
This turban will only be taken off
together with this head!
They are also forcing me.
I am also an aide.
Then go and say to your superiors
who gave the orders! This is what it is.
All right, hodja.
Go on, lalk.
I feel the strikes on the Islam-World
in my own heart first!
Oh our Allah!
I am poor, lonely.
I am weak. I have no power.
I say: help.
Oh our Lord!
You gave an enormous glory, grandeur
and wealth to the pharaoh...
...and his men in their worldly lives.
Was that to deviate your subjects
from your path, our Lord?
Oh our great Lord..
...sweep away their wealth...
...and strongly crush their hearts.
Obviously, they will not have faith
unless they don't suffer such a torment.
-I beg for your mercy and help oh Lord!
-Mom, I hear a voice from the roof.
Hodja says Allah.
Hodja recites His name, son.
Lailahaillallah!
Allah makes everything good.
Allah makes everything beautiful.
Lailahaillallah!
Mom it's finished, it's finished!
I will take it to hodja. I will take it to hodja.
Where is hodja?
They took hodja away.
They took hodja away. Run, hurry.
Hodja, wait for me.
Hodja, I wrote the book!
Hodja, it is here.
Are you Sadlk?
Master hodja left this for you.
After centuries of struggle, we destroyed
an empire which dominated three continents. Why?
Gentlemen! You know that the states
are established by revolutions...
_.but the civilization needs reforms.
Said is after the reforms, in other lords
after the civilization.
The government is administrated
by a certain people with politics.
But the individuals carry the civilization.
That's why Said educates the individuals
who will carry that civilization.
That's why he is not falling
into our trap to commonize him.
He is interested in the individuals one by one.
He stays away from the politics intentionally,
expands his studies to a century...
...emphasize allays the future and damages
our plan. This hodja is very clever, really!
The man has challenged the world
in a small district like Barla.
I believe it las lise of us
to bring him to Isparta.
Do you call this wise?
We told you to organize an incident in Isparta
such as the one in Menemen...
...but your men messed it up.
Your plot didn't work as you planned.
But this man is a very smart one, sir.
He overcame whatever we did.
As if an invisible hand protects him.
Due to your orders, we tried to finish him off
on his lay to Eskisehir prison.
You would finish him off,
but hodja finished him off.
The captain you sent to kill him became
his student. What kind of a finishing is this?
He is bewitching our men.
It didn't work in Kastamonu for 8 years either,
no matter who we sent.
We poisoned him
and it didn't lurk, either. As if...
Don't give me cock-and-bull stories.
Tell me what you are going to do!
Yes, you have arrested him in Kastamonu
because of an article that he wrote.
You put him into the jail in Denizli.
So you proved yourself for a change.
Tell me what we are going to do noi.
What if he is acquitted?
Don't lorry, he will not appear in the court.
How come?
We have a very good agent who followed him
since Barla and he knows him very well. ismet.
How many times did you get
arrested, sir?
This time you have been
arrested in military uniform.
Sir, what can I say to a brave
commander like yourself who fought in Gallipoli...
...and in the War of Independence,
who has lar medals.
How should I report?
You are a military man, you know such things.
You and I are both officers.
We serve to the government.
I am under pressure, sir.
I have to write my report.
As a matter of fact, I'm not a stranger
to your ideas. We, too, have Koran in our house.
Be patient my brother.
Allah willing, a solution will be found.
Give me a clue.
How should I report?
Give me some time.
Guardian! Where are our friends?
What are you doing to them? Guardian!
Where is our master? Guardian!
Guardian! Where is Major Aslm?
Where is the commander?
Hiisrev brother, Mehmet Feyzi brother,
what shall we do now?
My Anam
I don't want to tell lies, my Allah.
If I tell the truth, my master and
the service will be suffered.
If l tell lies...
my loyalty, integrity and my martial honor
I kept for 40 years of life will be stained.
Rather than committing such a sin...
...Iwish you take my life my Lord! Amen!
Enough, stop it!
-Shut up and go inside.
-Where is Major Aslm? What did you do to him?
-There is also no sound from our Master!
-Go to your places, that's enough.
What is going on?
Show him to us.
Goto your places.
Enough is enough.
-Don't do it. Stop.
-Just come here.
Do you lant, too?
Stop, don't do it. Stop, don't do it.
Take him up and put back to his bed.
You sacrificed yourself for us, brother.
Iwish you didn't.
I can never stand injustice.
Sir. I brought a prayer rug and soup for you.
Sir!
We came from him, and we will turn back to him.
Our brother Aslm became a martyr.
German Land Forces are marching in Russia.
771e German leader Adolf Hit/er
continues to fight in five fronts.
Gaibels, the right hand man nfAdnlfHitler made
a press release about German internal affairs.
Why didn't you tell the guardians who I am?
Mr. ismet wanted so.
So it will be more convincing.
Look at me, huh. I will make a complaint
about you to Mr. lsmet.
Thankfully, I succeeded. Soon they will
go into hodja's lard. I will be one of them.
-Will they accept it?
-Consider it done, warden.
You take care of the parole issue,
and then sit in a corner and latch.
The parole is granted. I will tell the guardians.
Ah, I also ordered a meal for you.
See here, you will make them blow
their things up lithout the toilet.
-You are starving them to death.
-OK, fine.
Come in.
Put it over here son.
Here, warden.
What is he doing here?
Now we are even.
Come in my friends, come in.
So, how are you today?
-Selamiinaleykiim, Master.
-Waalaikummussalam brother Mehmet, Waalaikummussalam.
Master.
Master, this is our famous Ziibeyr brother.
I know. You are Ziibeyr from Konya.
So, you love us that much to snitch yourself
and get into jail eh?
Master I am at your service.
Hodja I am also your admirer.
I know. I know.
Master, our brothers
are very worried about you.
They don't have to lorry Mehmet.
They don't have to lorry.
Saint Yusuf (Joseph)
is the spiritual guide of prisoners.
And this is the Madrasah of Yusuf.
You must be patient.
Don't break your unity and solidarity.
Where is this toilet?
It will blow up.
Be a little patient brothers.
Sit down.
Guardian! Take us out for the toilet!
Here I am.
Why are you shouting?
You will fix it, there.
Hurry up.
These friends are in need. Hurry up.
Why haven't you taken us out
for the toilet for days?
We will burst! Look at us!
From not on, you will do your toilets here.
Are you joking Mister Hasan?
Will you suffocate us in crap huh?
Are we animals?
How can we perform the ablution?
How are we supposed to perform namaz?
Hey, look.
This place will stink!
Why are you shouting at me brother?
This the order of the warden.
Come on.
Uh, well, sir. Do you think
we don't get into any trouble for that?
Don't you lorry warden,
this is the definitive solution!
This poison is strong enough to kill an elephant.
The hodja will never appear in the court!
Now take it.
-Here, brother.
-Hol am I supposed to?
Out of necessity, brother.
But brother, next to you.
We don't have a choice.
Feyzi go nol.
-We will die because of the urine poisoning huh?
-They are poisoning us.
Easy brother, easy.
-Mister Hasan.
-Yes, hodja.
This tea is too much for me.
Can you give this to my brothers?
So that they can drink.
You didn't eat your breakfast hodja.
Go in peace my brother, go in peace.
Hodja sent this
for you to drink.
By the lay, your toilet is very nice.
Our master sent tea for us, lets drink!
ZUbeyL
You have a spy with you.
Be careful with Erdal!
No, no.
No it's not me!
Guardian! Help!
You are poisoning our people
and youth with your writings.
You are preventing us to progress
on our lay to lesternize.
If Divine Light Treatises are poison;
we need tons of that poison.
If mister prosecutor knows
where that poison is...
...he may transfer us by planes to that place!
Your honors. Said Nursi, with his books,
turns the people against the government...
...and aims to prevent the reforms
by strengthening the religious linds
And it is very clear that he established
a secret society to realize this aim.
Yes, that's right.
We established a society.
A society with 350 million members.
And our leader is Prophet Mohammed.
Lt says that you are against all the innovations
such as radio, train, airplane and cinema!
We are not against the wonders of the civilization.
These are all blessings.
Both radio and cinema are blessings
if they broadcast useful things...
...but they are disasters
if they broadcast deleterious issues.
We are establishing a modern world
on our country like the western people.
And you are damaging our world
and peace with your writings.
I have nothing to do to with damaging
neither your world, nor your peace!
My goal and purpose is something different.
Right in front of me, there is an enormous tire,
its flames rising up to the sky.
In this tire, my descent is burning,
my faith is set on tire, its burning.
I am running to put the Ere out, I am running
for saving my faith. I am telling about Allah.
How dare you!
Your honor, here you see!
He disregards the court!
Who do you trust
to speak so reckless!
You are insulting the Supreme Court
when you say 'you are not my addressee'!
Who do you trust?
To this and to Allah!
We are trusting to our shrouds!
To our shrouds.
Bismillah is the beginning of every charity.
We too start with it at the beginning.
Know oh my soul, this holy lord is the mark of
Islam. And it is what all the existing creatures...
_.recite it in their own language.
If you want to understand what an endless power,
how is an unending blessing the Bismillah is...
...listen to this figurative story!
Here it is:
A man making a journey through the
deserts of Arabia...
has to travel in the name of a tribal chief
and enter under his protection.
So he maybe saved from the bandits
and secure his needs.
We said at the beginning:
All the existing creatures recite
Bismillah in their own languages.
Right?
Mister Said. The prosecutor claims that
you are the enemy of the republic.
What do you think about the republic?
Your honor.
They asked the same question in Eski§ehir court.
My history in that rile proves
that I am a religious republican.
The deceased pasha knew that, too.
Your honors!
We are accused of exploiting
the religion and breaking the order.
You too know that this is a lie.
I am trying to direct people
to Allah and Koran.
Can such people break the order?
For tlenty years, thousands of people
have read my writings and found peace.
They never broke the order.
The secret blasphemous committee
wants to destroy us...
...by abusing the members of the government,
and by misleading the justice.
If the truth is so, then we will tell them
with all our power that:
You miserables who sell their religion
for the world! Do what you can!
May the world be your demise.
And it will be!
If we have millions of heads,
they are all worth sacrificing on this lay.
We are ready for every punishment
and your death penalties!
Do you have any additional things to say?
Is this your last lord?
My last lord:
'Hasbunallah wa ni'mal wakil.'
Allah is enough for us.
He is the most beautiful attorney.
Your honor! Excuse me, this is the time
for namaz. I will perform the namaz.
No lay! This is against the regulations.
You can perform your lapsed pray later on!
No! No Iapsing,
I will perform my namaz!
You can't!
Mister prosecutor!
We are here to defend namaz!
That's all we are accused of.
I have to confess that this is the
hardest case in my professional life.
We should be fair in our decision.
You know the expert's opinion
from Ankara.
What do you think about it?
I consider him guilty.
My fellow judge had the same opinion
but he is sick.
Only if if he didn't change his mind later on.
His treatment is extended,
so he lon't be coming for a long time.
I commissioned Mrs. Asll for the duty.
She is examining the file.
In that case, her opinion
will be decisive.
Yes?
-Welcome Mrs. Ash.
-Thank you sir.
I read the expert's report and the files.
I examined the case and gave my decision.
Here it is.
Per curiam!
The evidences presented to our court and the
expertise report sent from Ankara...
...have been carefully examined
and we arrived at a verdict.
The expert group has determined that there is no
element of crime in the books...
...called Treaties of Divine Light
as a result of their detailed investigation.
And our court committee has decided that the
evidences presented by the prosecution...
...don't qualify to prove
the claimed crimes...
...and it has been unanimously decided
to dismiss the charges.
Shame on you!
With all the means we provided you,
you just couldn't succeed it.
But sir, I included my statement
in the expert report, sir.
You are dismissed. Out!
How come we can't handle
one single person! After all he is just a man!
But a man who doesn't bow to anybody.
They call him Free Man!
He doesn't listen to anyone, he doesn't accept
any offer and he is not afraid of anything.
Remember all the things we offered him.
Properties, goods, money!
But he didn't accept any of them.
He thinks that he is free, but we will teach him
to live in captivity as a free person.
His freedom will be very distasteful.
Where is he now?
-He is on parole. In Emirda§.
-So he is in Emirda§ (Order-Mountain)!
He will see if it is Emirdagj (Order-mountain)
or Demirdagj (Iron-mountain)!
Hodja, this mosque is locked.
Everywhere in the world is a mosque
for a Muslim, brother.
At this rate, Hitler will finish the Russians.
Russia is a slamp, mister mayor.
I think Germans are committing suicide.
Stop, stop!
What is the man doing? How dare he?
Let him, mister mayor. He is harmless.
Is this a place for prayers?
Prayers should be performed in the mosque.
Mister mayor.
This is the hodja that we are waiting.
Oh! So this is the man Ankara
has been hassling for years.
We run into big trouble.
Welcome, hodja.
Thank you.
I am the doctor of the town
and also Housing Director Tahir.
I am responsible from
your health and housing.
We want to help you settle.
Would you like to stay in a hotel or in a house?
-House.
-All right.
We have a house,
but you will have a drunkard neighbor.
It's better than staying alone in a hotel.
May Allah give you good customers.
Bless you. May Allah be pleased with you.
You have a guest Hasan!
-A guest?
-He will reside upstairs.
-Please, hodja!
-Selamiinaleykiim! May it be easy.
-Waalaikummussalam. Welcome!
-Thank you.
That's fine you brought him here,
but I hope he Ion't be uncomfortable from me?
Please, hodja.
We have to leave, hodja.
Thank you brothers.
May Allah be pleased with you.
After you, hodja.
This room witnessed some bloodshed.
It has been locked for years.
They call it the Death Room.
Mehmet!
Master.
Mehmet! My dear Mehmet.
My brother.
Didn't I tell you to goto your life and children?
It's worth the sacrifice my wife
and my children for you, master.
You are my everything.
I didn't forget my father's lill.
My dear Mehmet.
Come. Come. Sit.
Come brother, let's take the other lay.
Master, Afyon Governor and Chief of Police
visited Emirda§ 5 times...
...and Chief Public Prosecutor visited
2 times in the last 10 days.
What do they want from us, master?
Master! Duck, my master!
Don't be afraid my brother, stand up!
The fate is unique and will not be changed!
What do they want from us, master?
My Brother. They are preparing a trap
10 times bigger than Sheikh Said...
...and Menemen incidents.
But we will not fall into this trap!
My Allah.
For the one who knows you,
a dungeon is a palace...
...for the one who doesn't know you,
even a palace is a dungeon.
...and for the one who doesn't know you,
a palace is a dungeon.
My brothers.
The one who knows Allah is in a palace
and happy even if in a dungeon.
And the who doesn't know him is in a dungeon
and unhappy even if in a palace.
The one who finds Allah, finds everything.
Bismillah is the beginning of each and every charity
Since everything spiritually says Bismillah,
we too should begin with it.
We have to give, in the name of Allah.
We have to take, in the name of Allah.
We have to love in the name of Allah.
We have to hate in the name of Allah.
Hey you, stop.
What are you doing with the Kurdish hodja?
It's forbidden fellows, forbidden!
We have to find another house for our master and
take him away from this poisonous workshop.
It's obvious that they put
him here to be poisoned and die.
-Assalamualaikum.
-Waalaikummussalam, brother.
I brought you tea, hodja.
Thank you.
Don't revere me, brother!
Revere Allah!
Hodja, what do they want from you?
How can you endure such pressure?
My nature does not tolerate the vileness
and indignity mister Hasan.
There were times I wished to die
rather than living.
If my religion did not forbid to commit suicide...
...maybe this Said would have been
under the ground and had already faded away.
For the faith of the society
and millions of Turkish children...
...not even one Said but thousands of
Saids may be sacrificed.
This is the secret of my patience mister Hasan.
I better go now, hodja.
Hodja.
I rented a new store. I will move.
Will you allow me to visit you time to time?
What is it, brother?
Why you are moving?
Our profession is noisy, dirty and smoky.
I don't want to disturb you any longer.
Stop!
Don't enter in! Where are you going?
Don't you know what a restriction is?
Put them into jail!
Lock the door.
We have orders, hodja.
You are under house arrest.
From not on it is forbidden for you to go out!
Is this a communist country?
Why are you arresting the hodja in the house?
Did he cause any harm to anyone?
Is this veteran fought
against the Russians for that?
Do you think you really did a good thing?
We are also sorry for your situation!
But we are aides, too.
Our mosques are all clean.
We have Turkish hodjas in them.
Go and perform your prayers in there.
How can you perform your prayers
in a lhitesmith-store!
What have you got to do with that Kurdish hodja?
We are Muslim, too.
This country belongs to all of us.
I will let you free.
But I don't want to see you anymore
with that stranger! Understand?
Is that clear?
My brothers, I am under an unnecessary
pressure and cruelty. I suffer an enormous ordeal.
They luck my house
both from inside and outside.
I am lonely in all senses. I am living my life
as a sick man in a boring room, without neighbors.
We have to reach to our master somehow.
-Assalamualaikum.
-Waalaikummussalam.
My name is Mehmet. I am shopkeeper.
They call me the Hard-Worker around here.
This is my son Ceylan.
My name is Mehmet, too.
This is our brother Ziibeyr.
-Nice to meet you.
-Hello, hello.
We also want to see the hodja.
Sometimes, one day here suffocates me
more than one month in prison at Denizli.
It? enough that they have prevented my freedom
and liberty lith such a horrible cruelty...
...fur 20 years.
Is it too much to ask for the freedom
everybody has? Your brother Said.
Allah makes everything good.
Allah...
Master! Master!
What happened to you?
Master.
-My brothers.
-Is he poisoned again?
They haven't given me bread
or later for 15 days.
Master, we brought some food for you!
My name is Ceylan.
Fifteen days.
Bismillah.
Master, I fix radios.
People always ask me.
They ask if a Muslim should fix radios.
They say that I help people listen to songs.
My brother. You are acquiring
merits for all the Koran letters come out...
...from every radio you fixed.
A man can say good lords and the bad lords.
Should we cut out the mouth
in case of a bad word?
From not on lets print the treatises not
in Arabic script, but in Latin script.
No master. We shouldn't change the Arabic script
le've been using for a thousand years.
Now they teach
the Latin script in schools.
All the correspondences, magazines, newspapers
are in Latin script.
We are minority nol.
People who can read the Arabic script
have decreased.
But master...
Don't move! Everybody stand up!
Up!
How could you enter in even though
we sealed the door? Did you dig a tunnel huh?
Chief! We found the secret entrance!
They dug a hole on the la!! and entered Chief!
Mister Doctor, you too?
What do you think?
Take them all into the jail except Hodja!
Take the doctor to the mayor! Hurry up!
But this is ridiculous Doctor!
How can you join them?
He is a reactionary! A reactionary!
Mayor, how can a man who has acquitted from
various courts be a reactionary?
This hodja is not an enemy of our homeland
or enemy of the sate. He is a republican.
If Ankara Iasn't scared so much, would they
continuously request information from us?
I have been to many conversations with him.
All he tells us is to believe in Allah...
...to read a lot, be a honest person,
and to achieve wealth by working hard.
He feels very sorry
for the ignorance of our people.
Have you ever read what he had written?
Yes, I have. He wants unification, and
he wants brotherhood. But they don't let him.
Who do they think we are?
We govern not only Turkey, but the whole world.
We created a hero out of him.
The more we strike, the more he grows.
I am afraid he will take the army
and the state on his side.
He has students from military officers
and parliament members.
It is time to change our policy.
We will not touch him anymore.
In other words, we will forget him.
But sir, how come?
If we forget him, then everyone does.
Your house arrest is over, hodja.
Hodja left the house!
Mayor asked a bribe from me!
Brothers, this is the fate
of the tyrants who take bribes.
Our master asks for you.
Look mister officer.
Being a policeman is a very important duty.
He prevents unjustice,
he protects the aggrieved ones.
He saves the properties and honor of the people.
You are the physical guards of this nation,
and we are the spiritual guards.
Together, we serve to the order of our nation.
Hodja, all the things they say
about you confuse me.
They say that you are an enemy of the republic.
And...
...they say that you are a reactionary.
They even say that you insulted the Pasha.
Did you really see him?
I mean the Pasha, did you speak with him?
Listen brother.
After the victory,
Pasha invited me to Ankara.
He offered me a mansion, a farm and ten thousand
Iiras as salary for working together with him.
I didn't accept the offer.
I said, 'My duty ends there.
The nation should have everything.'
Congratulations for your
your speech in congress, hodja.
Especially your lords on science
and knowledge grabbed my attention.
Pasha, the mind is satisfied with sciences.
And the soul is satisfied
with religious knowledge.
When these two come together the truth emerges.
CHAMBER OF SPEAKER OF THE CONGRESS
ANKARA 1922
Mental and physical progress
is the greatest power today
Because the Europeans are crushing us
with their mental pressure...
...powered by their
weapons of science and industry.
That's why we must tight through science and arts
against ignorance, poverty, and conflict...
...which are the most powerful enemies of
spreading the unity of Allah.
Hodja, I admire your struggle,
your attitude and honesty.
We will make some reforms.
And we need your support while doing so.
For example we want to ease off the issues
such as alcohol and dressing code.
Neither the authority
nor the promises of Allah will ever change.
These gospels are the biggest happiness.
He is the one who gave the earth
to your command...
...for you to lalk on it with justice
and eat the food Allah provides.
Pasha! Pasha! Make reforms on science and art,
but to don't try to ease of! Koran's orders!
We allays need a brave hodja like yourself.
We invited you here
to benefit from your high ideas.
Hodja! Hodja!
I respect you since the day
you spoke in Thessalonica.
Don't interfere to our reforms. Live free!
I saw confusion in Ankara.
A new generation must be educated
for the faith of this nation.
Oh, hodja. I am under command and pressure.
Please try to understand my position.
I don't want to follow you, either.
Do you think I enjoy it?
Oh hodja. Besides, do you know that
my grandfather is an Alaii Sheikh.
We are brothers.
I honestly love the true Alalis and
our esteemed master Ali.
Our master Ali could perform his morning prayer
with his evening ablution.
He las very sensitive about the praying.
Ah by hodja, please.
Do not strive with this order, leave it!
Brother!
My 30 years of struggle is about...
...giving answers to European philosophers
who are working in the name of irreligion.
This Pasha. What has he said
15 days before he died?
Read it.
He sent this message
to all the Muslims in the world.
Moreover he announced this via Prime Ministry
and Foreign Affairs channels.
All Muslims should follow the path
that the last Prophet Mohammed showed...
...and should practice his instructions.
All the Muslims should take Prophet Mohammed
as a model and act as he did.
They should obey the orders of Islam
as they are.
Because people can only survive
and develop in this lay.
He shouldn't have said that.
The reactionaries can take courage from this
and they can queer our pitch.
Cover this up immediately.
Also inform the queen.
Write, my brother Mehmet!
To the Members of the Parliament, to the
Prime Minister, to the President of the Republic.
Gentlemen. Our mission is
to strengthen the people's faith.
To live fraternally, without discriminating
the friend and the enemy, and without partisanship.
Write, my brother Ceylan.
To Chief Rabbinate, To Vatican Pontificate.
In this recent times; we the Christians,
Jews and Muslims should put aside...
...our controversies
and we have to join forces...
...against our common enemies such as
immorality, irreligion and depravation.
We have to be unified and act together
on the path of Allah.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My valuable, loyal, gallant brothers...
...being friends with great nation such as
America which works for the religion...
...can only be achieved
by faith and Islam.
We, as the servers of Koran,
declare this to them and we also pray...
...for their success at sewing Islam.
Allah's willing.
An mighty Aman.
Bismillah is the beginning of each and every charity
We, too start with it. Know oh my soul.
Ismet.
You lost yourself.
Please collect yourself a little.
Look, we are here.
-My dear father, welcome.
-Leave me alone.
I don't feel good. I don't.
I spent my life for the government.
I helped them catch hundreds of
enemies of the state.
But they chucked me out when I am finished.
I don't feel good.
Hello.
It is for you.
This old man lent too far.
He wrote a letter to the parliament members,
commissioners, to ambassadors.
He even wrote to the Pope.
How dare he!
This men is not establishing a state,
but an emperorship.
We shouldn't have left him alone.
Please.
Come in.
Ismet.
Good afternoon sir.
Good afternoon.
Do you think
you will succeed this time?
Yes sir.
So, what are you planning to do?
The prosecutor started an investigation
about Saidi Nursi.
7 cult members were caught yesterday
during rituals.
Saidi Nursi incident is spreading.
An reactionary organization is found out
3 cult members in Ankara
and 1 cult members in inebolu is arrested.
Your honor.
You brought a lot of people here because of me,
and you are trying them.
Who brought them? Who brought them?
Did they steal anything?
Did they kill someone,
abduct a girl...
...overthrow the government? What did they do?
Where are the witnesses? You brought
all these innocent people with lies and untruths.
Don't they have children?
Now who will provide their living?
Who will pay for the harm
those fatherless children got?
Will you be testifying for them
beyond the veil?
I'm warning you!
Do not fight with Divine Light's Treatises
which is based on Koran.
It cannot be defeated.
Ifl had many heads as much
as the hairs on my head...
...even if you decapitate one of them each day,
they may be sacrificed for the truths of Koran.
I will not bow to blasphemy and irreligionl
I will never give up my duty for the faith!
With Allah's willing, this court lill break
the plans and attacks of our secret enemies.
Mister Hodja, tell us,
how many students do you have?
You turn the entire Afyon City into a prison
and I will tell you.
Hodja hodja! Why don't you mind
your own business at this age!
Are you responsible from people's faith or Koran?
Why do you care?
Go and live your life!
Faith is a divine light, a power.
I'm willing to burn in the flames of hell...
...If I'm going to see that
the people's faith is secured.
Because my soul will be in a bed of roses
when my body burns in flames.
I have no desire for the paradise
nor the fear of hell.
So, are you challenging
the court and justice?
No!
I have trust to the loyalty of court members
for the justice, and also to justice itself!
My lords...
Defendant Mullah Said. Stand up!
Why doesn't he talk?
Because he can't End anything to say.
You are tried for your life with the charges
to cause the events on 31st March...
...by your provocative articles
on Volkan newspaper...
...and by various social movements
that you organized.
Oh you pashas, officers!
My purpose is to save
the constitution from the defect...
...to save the religious people from the despair...
...and in the eyes of history, to save the people
of this century from ignorance and madness...
...from anxieties and doubts!
So you have demanded Sharia
like others. Is that so?
Yes! I want Sharia, too.
But, not like the revolutionists want!
Ifl had thousands of souls, I am ready
to sacrifice them all for a single truth of Sharia!
Because Sharia means justice, honesty, virtue!
And you have provoked the people, the students,
the officers and the porters to revolt.
On the contrary! I directed them from revolt
to obedience with all my speeches and articles!
Really?
Look. Look outside.
You may end next to them.
I lived freely on the east mountains of Kurdistan.
Your menaces will not affect me!
No! My son is not a bandit.
He will never hurt any living creature.
He is a great gallant, famous scholar respected
by the eastern clans and scholars!
You are tyrannizing to such a hero.
Your honor!
Justice! Justice!
Rule with the justice, don't tyrannize!
Sit down old man.
I don't understand even a lord that you say.
Father, don't lorry.
Allah have justice.
You cannot horrify me with death!
I prefer to die tyrannized
rather than be a tyrant!
I will gladly depart to afterlife
from the station of gallows...
...with the execution passport
that you will give me.
Long live hell for the tyrants!
-Long live hell for the tyrants!
We are listening to you Mister Hodja.
My lords, your honor,
isn't directed to yourself or the judges...
...but to the secret godless committee
who try to manipulate the court and abuse it!
And to the obsequious people
who betray this nation.
With Allah's willing, this court lill break
the plans and attacks of our secret enemies.
Verdict.
Allah makes everything good.
Allah makes everything beautiful.
Hit. Hit. Hit.
Look, you tell us the truth and le'll set you free.
What do you say?
My brothers! Let's try to endure
and not shout so loudly.
Our voices shouldn't reach to
our master and torment him!
Hit. Hit. Hit stronger.
Enough! He will die.
Stop it.
Where did you hide the weapons?
You have weapons don't you? Speak up.
We have... We have...
He is confessing.
Write it down, write.
What kind of weapons do you have?
Which are destroying the ignorance,
illuminating the darkness.
We have weapons which are challenging against
all the tyrants of the world.
We have nuclear bombs.
He is making fun of us! Nuclear bomb, huh!
Nuclear bomb. Nuclear bomb.
Hit. Hit.
Long live hell for the tyrants.
Oh you miserable ones who burden me!
I don't care whatever you do to me!
The cruelties that you unlawfully committ...
...the pressures which touch my veins
terrorize everyone but enrages me.
But it has been warned into my heart...
...'Don't rage against these tyrants
but pity them, because they lill be...
...subjected to hellish tortures physically
and mentally for the cruelties they have committed.
Your revenge will be taken
from them thousand times!
They will have deadly qualms of conscience
as long as they live!
Even though the windows of hodja's lard
were broken, he didn't freeze.
Sir, please come.
Have a look.
Even that we applied too much pressure,
we couldn't make them talk.
They didn't talk but they have cringed,
look at them.
I don't think so sir.
Continue to torture, warden!
Keep the pressure.
They will be scared! They will be really scared
and they will say everything!
Come on hodja, you are lucky again.
Salt dealer Avni from Afyon has sent these to you.
Since I don't accept any presents,
I lon't also take them. Give them back.
Brothers. Stand straight. Be gladsome.
It's time to end this.
Hodja, you have to be inoculated.
Open your arm hodja.
-H ere.
-It is for your own health, hodja.
-Get well hodja.
-For your own health hodja.
Oh Healer oh Allah!
Oh Healer oh Allah.
Oh Healer...
...oh Allah.
Oh Healer oh Allah!
Please heal me, Allah!
Mother. Mother.
Mother.
BEKiR AGHA WARD- iSTANBUL 1909
Said.
Will they execute you my son?
What will I do if you die, My Said?
The hawk of the Eastern Mountains, my gallant son!
I am proud of you.
The truth will always lin.
My son. Your mother may die for you.
I missed you too much my son!
Look what I brought for you.
This is the oregano of our mountains.
I know you like it.
And this is the soil of our village.
It is very cold.
Please take care of yourself huh?
My Said.
My Said do not forget! You are a man of struggle!
My struggle.
My struggle, my struggle.
Uncle Hodja! Uncle Hodja,
what happened to you?
Mehmed! Ziibeyr?
It's me, Bayram.
Brother, I am dying.
My master, my master, what happened?
-Don't leave us my master, please!
-My brothers, they poisoned me again.
Damn with them, master!
I am dying! Dying!
Guardian! Come on!
Cravens! They have poisoned our master!
Where is the doctor?
Master is dying!
Guardian!
Brothers! I am very ill,
perhaps I lon't survive.
All my existence may be sacrificed for motherland,
nation, youth, the Islam lorld...
...for the happiness
and welfare of the human!
If I die, may my friends
not take my revenge!
You will endure some troubles
but it will end all good.
-Long live my master!
-Get well my master.
Allah makes everything good.
Allah makes everything beautiful.
Get well, my master.
Here, master.
I had promised you.
I am Sadlk, master. Sadlk.
Sadlk. Shepherd Sadlk!
I missed you very much, master. Very much.
Hodja has survived again.
Hodja is free again.
There is something in this system.
Hello.
It's for you, sir.
Yes?
Mr. ismet, welcome.
Please wait for a while.
The president is here but he has a foreign visitor.
Please take a seat.
l'll bring you a cup of coffee.
Friends. Now I will tell you
the new world order.
You were the rulers in Asia, Europe and Africa.
But you couldn't succeed.
The queen of the empire
on which the sun never sets, is finished.
That's why we are taking over
the new world order.
We will not establish this new order
on bans and threats like you did...
...but on cooperation basis.
We care a lot about Turkey.
This place has a history of emperorship.
We have to lurk lith the public
especially to prevent any more heroes.
The Ottoman spirit should never lake up.
The people of this country must allays
consider themselves helpless.
They must allays be dependent to us.
But sir. This hodja is not an ordinary person.
He is like Gandhi of India.
Gandhi collaborated with us.
Now he establishes his government.
Mister ismet?
Mister ismet Ihat's wrong?
Welcome hodja, welcome.
Assalamualaikum.
Waalaikummussalam.
Hodja, welcome hodja. Welcome
Thank you Sevket.
Hodja, not I'm your student, too.
Hello. Hello my friends in Barla.
Hello my faithful brothers
who open their hearts for me! Hello.
Allah makes everything good,
makes everything beautiful.
-Welcome hodja.
-Thank you.
Welcome master.
Brother Mehmet, if Allah willing, the services of
Koran will develop more and more.
All the world will be enlightened
with the divine light.
With Allah willing master.
With the blessing of your pray, hopefully.
Welcome my hodja.
Welcome hodja.
Forgive our mistakes.
We don't support animosity,
but friendship.
Hodja.
Will you accept me as a student?
Please forgive me hodja.
My brothers!
We hurried up and came in linter.
You will come in a heavenly spring!
Our duty is to act positively,
not to act negatively.
I carefully analyzed the ones
who tyrannized me.
There aren't any Turks among them.
Because, there is not a tyrannizing vein
in the real Turkish people.
I Ion't have a temper or complain about
the people who tormented me.
I forgive them.
May Allah also forgive them.
Allah is the most merciful of the mercy showers.
Allah speaks the truth!
We are all like the leaves of this maple tree.
We have to clamp together.
Oh my friends who gave their hearts to Koran,
the seeds of Divine Light that has been sow...
...will blossom on earth.
As a payment of our services
we are not expecting from you...
...to visit us at our graves
when you come to pass away.
Put some of those spring flowers
on the gravestone. And pray for us.
We will advise to the doorkeeper.
You will be welcomed.
I can live without bread.
I can not live without freedom.
What gives me pain is only
the menaces which Islam is exposed to.
In the past, the menaces were coming from
outside, so it las easy to tight against them.
Now, the menace comes lithin.
The lorm entered into the body.
Now, the fight became harder.
I am afraid that the body of our society
can not succumb.
Because, they lon't sense the enemy.
They'II think that the biggest enemy who tears
their vital vein off, who drinks their blood is a friend
If the society's eye is blinded, then
the fortress of the faith will be in danger.
This is my agony, this is my one and only agony.
I don't have time to think about the pains
and troubles that I experienced personally.
Iwish that I encounter pains
thousand times more than this...
...but the future of the
fortress of faith be secured.
I see all the big heads in negligence.
The corrupted columns of the blasphemy
can not hold the fortress of faith.
Therefore, I concentrated
all my efforts on faith.
They ask me:
Why you attacked this and that?
I am unaware.
Right in front of me, there is an
enormous tire, its flames rising up to the sky.
In this tire, my descent is burning,
my faith is set on tire, its burning.
I am running to put the Ere out,
I am running to save my faith.
On my lay, somebody wants to stop me
and my foot hits him, what does it matter?
Against such a horrible tire,
will this small event mean anything?
Narrow minds! Small minds!
Do they think that I am a man
who wants to save his own soul?
Throughout my eighty years of life,
l've known nothing about the worldly pleasures.
I spent a whole life in battle fields,
in slavery dungeons, or in homeland's prisons...
...homeland's courtrooms. There is no torment
or cruelty left that I didn't experience.
I have been treated like a criminal
in the court martial.
I have been sent to exile from
a place to another like a Vagabond.
I got disciplinary segregations
in homeland prisons for months.
I have been poisoned many times.
I have suffered various affronts.
There were times I wished to die
rather than living.
If my religion didn't
forbid me to commit suicide...
...maybe this Said would be under
the ground and already molded away.
Then, I have sacrificed my afterlife
for the salvation of society's faith.
I have no desire for the paradise
nor the fear of hell.
Not only one Said, but thousands of Saids
may be sacrificed for the society...
...not only for the tlenty live millions of
people in Turkish society...
...but for the whole Islam society
with hundreds of millions.
If our Koran stays on earth without community,
I don't want to be in heaven because...
...it will be a dungeon for me.
I'm willing to burn in the flames of hell...
...If I'm going to see that the people's
faith is secured.
Because my soul will be in a bed of roses,
when my body burns in flames.