The film you are about to see is based
on documented facts.
The atrocities shown were performed
as "medical experiments" -
-In special camps in the Third Reich.
The crimes are historically accurate-
-But the film's characters are compos
of several notorious Nazis.
They showed the events were collected
to a place of dramatic account.
Because of the shocking subject
father movie is only for adults.
The film is dedicated to the hope of
that these atrocities never happen again.
- Yes!
- No, not yet!
No, please! No!
You would have expected.
The weather today will be mostly fine.
In the north, it gets a little chilly
and it becomes essentially clear.
It's time to go now.
Go where?
Heading south, we have temperatures ...
- With them.
-Get dressed!
- Ilsa, you promised ...
-What did you call me?
Ilsa. I mean commandant.
Fräulein doctor.
It was better.
Much better.
You said I'd never
return to camp before.
It would not be the same, you say!
- Yes ...
-Why there for me?
You had the honor
to lie with a German woman.
An SS officer. You, a laborer,
belonging to an inferior race!
- Do you dare to challenge me?
I say nothing, commandant.
That is true.
Let me stay here with you.
I give you great pleasure.
- Like an animal in heat!
No, as a lover.
You bastard! How dare you
say that word to me?
But last night promised you ...
That you would not return
to camp before.
It was everything I promised.
Bring him.
When a prisoner has slept with me-
- Is he never with a woman.
If he survives
he remembers only the pain from the knife.
- Knife?
-As castrate you.
No!
- Begin!
No, commandant.
No! No, Commander!
No! No, Commander! No!
I will finish it.
There is a doctor Baum in Berlin.
He believes that the inferior races
proves their inferiority-
-With a certain body part.
Can you guess which body part?
It makes a man a man.
The doctor has a collection-
-That proves his theory and ...
Your ... will be send-
-To him.
No!
You see, little man.
I have kept my promise.
You see again never camp again.
- How many this time?
-15.
Get out, quick!
Down!
Get out, bitch! Quick!
Out with you! Fort now!
Forward!
Stand up!
- They expect miracles in five days.
-Someone has to say that is too many.
Our research is important
than their sterilization.
Deon is most important in all camps.
Every job is different.
It is significant.
You need not be afraid.
This is not Dachau,
no Ravensbruck.
We are doctors and will help you.
Your stay with us will be brief, but
you father a chance to serve the Third Reich.
It is your destiny.
Welcome to Camp 9!
This way, girls. Harat!
Then we start.
746.
Come, my child.
- Remove clothing. We do not see.
I am ashamed.
Shame?
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
We need you to know
what work we'll give you.
We are doctors.
- How old are you, friend?
-18, Fräulein doctor.
18?
- Excellent
Thanks, fräulein doctor.
332.
Commandant?
- Have you decided?
I do not know ...
- Hardly labor, huh?
-I am strong.
I can work with whatever you want
and is not afraid to take in.
It's good. Great.
Stop! You were not allowed to go.
- I thought ...
-You think you can not, you obey.
Do you understand?
- Yes, what then?
-Yes ...
... Fräulein doctor.
For you it will be that door.
Next!
977.
894.
444.
- Go, go!
-Fräulein doctor ...
- What do those women with?
-What?
- Those who enter there.
-They will be retrained.
To earn the Third Reich soldiers.
- And I?
-You will earn kingdom otherwise.
You will help our medical research
and thereby saving thousands of lives.
Right.
What is your name?
Rosette, fräulein doctor.
Rosette?
I will not forget it.
You there! Do you hear what I'm saying?
- Come on!
No. ...
You will when I tell you.
No! Stop it!
Let me be!
You must obey orders! Do you understand?
Or would you like more tea?
Give the bitch to me.
I'll shave her so close to skin-
-That the blood flowing.
- Leave her alone!
I'll teach her!
No, she gets their lesson last night.
Tonight she will work in the guardhouse.
Our research is too important.
I implore you to inspect it.
General, if I replace the procedure now-
-Delayed all our experiments.
General, our discoveries will
change the outcome of the war.
Yes, General.
Yes, mein General.
That was good news.
Then the general judge it yourself.
And, General, I ...
I conducts its own research
-That probably interests you most.
Thank you, General.
Heil Hitler.
- Hello.
-Welcome. My name is Kala.
This is Irene.
Get out!
Quick!
Achtung!
Achtung, commandant.
- You are blond.
I was born in Germany.
- Addressing the commandant with respect!
He learns, sergeant, he learns.
- Are you German?
I am American, commandant.
American? Why are not you
in a POW camp?
I read in Germany
when my country declared war.
- I have been in camp since.
-Your Country? You are German!
There was I not over, commandant.
Take them.
- I'm ready.
-Cruising!
Quick!
Dr. Baum will be very pleased.
And you call yourselves men?
I see no manhood
between your legs.
You, the oäkte German!
It is clearly visible
that your blood is tainted.
This is not a real Aryans built.
Size is not everything, commandant.
Does not it?
We'll see.
I have only one thing to add.
Inmates found to
to speak with patients becoming whipped.
Even the woman.
- Why all sleep?
They've been infected with the bacteria.
Typhoid, tetanus, rabies.
All known fatal diseases.
- Leaving the them there to die?
No, that would be too merciful.
- They develop experimental drugs.
-Medicaments ...
- Do they work? Fines of them?
-If they were to die of the disease ...
... They had died with less pain.
And you, Kala ... What did they give you?
Syphilis.
The only question is when I will die.
God can not help one here.
He has forgotten this place.
- The third?
-Yes.
- No changes?
-Only the pulse, commandant.
Berlin laughed at my theory.
Soon I'll give them
documented evidence.
- Then they laugh no more.
-They do not want to believe it.
No, they're men.
It is unthinkable for them
that a carefully trained woman-
-Withstand more pain than any man.
- What is this camp?
What it is?
- Gateway to Hell.
-What do they do with all women?
The sterilized
and then sent to the field brothels.
- Oh my God!
-They might be lucky.
- Lucky?
-Yes. There are others.
The selected few.
They are taken by the commandant.
- Why?
I do not know.
She has a room in his home.
No one knows what she is doing there.
But the women never return.
Though soon it will not matter.
- How can you say so?
-Because, my friend ...
You get enough of their own problems.
Problems? We are well here
just to work, huh?
No.
That time will-
-When Black Widow sends after you.
Castrated? Why?
Maybe it's her way
to punish the man-
-That makes her
to feel as a woman-
-But that nevertheless still
her thirst for more. Who knows?
Only one thing is certain:
when he has served her-
-He is out of that one.
You too?
- Yes, I had her one night.
-Mario ...
It is better
to live as half-man of the moment.
Why?
In order to get revenge.
I live only for revenge.
It may come sooner than you think.
- What do you mean?
-The Allies approaching fast.
- How fast? When will they?
I do not know. But soon, Mario.
I've been waiting for weeks.
I can wait even longer.
Until my time comes.
Mario ...
- Cut her out of your ...
-No.
It had ...
Destroyed ... Dr. Baum's theory.
Up!
Why?
Have you already forgotten, sweetheart?
Where are you taking me?
You will be working in the night.
- The guard barracks.
-No.
- Please, no!
It's too late to repent.
Get up!
- Heil Hitler!
-Heil.
Commandant, a worker has just
caught talking to a girl.
- What area is she in?
Sterilizers, commandant.
- Excellent. You can go.
-Commandant's special room?
- You!
-Good.
You are not like pigs
they usually send to us.
You are different.
So warm, so smooth.
Are you a tigress?
Do you resisting?
You have to kill me first!
Hardly.
Save your strength, dear.
Doctor ...
We are both from Poland. We talked
if every country - no more.
You are strong. Stronger than he.
- Help me, doctor.
-You have to help yourself.
Begin!
For them and hang them up.
It discourages the other pigs.
When you finished ...
Download American to me.
You are so strong.
So though.
You are beautiful.
I need you.
I need to feel you in me.
I will satisfy you.
Empty promises ...
Attention, Alert-
There is a red alert.
Hostile flight ...
I will satisfy you
until you beg me to stop.
Do it then.
Interference harder!
Not now! No!
Now!
Harder!
Makes me ill!
Now!
Not yet.
Attention!
Red preparedness is now called off.
There is now a blue alert.
We resume broadcasts.
We continue with a selection of music
the Kingdom's finest ...
Not more!
Oh no ...
Please.
You are made of iron.
Oh my God. Did you kill her?
No.
You see ...
When I hit puberty, I noticed
something that separated me from the other guys.
Something that made me unique, I guess.
Outstanding.
What? What was it?
It is very simple.
I discovered that I can
hold back as long as I want.
I can still.
All night if necessary.
You could call me a freak of nature.
A kind of human-machine
-Who can set the controls
pa "fast," "slower" ...
... Or "never."
Oh my God.
Want to know something?
Never switch made her
almost insane.
Never.
Never! I do not use
like an animal.
Help us Kala.
There must be a way to accommodate.
You guys are crazy.
But the guards are so few.
Why would they need more?
This is a world of crippled,
broken women.
They have lost their strength-
And their dignity.
- There's nothing to do.
-Then we must take over the camp.
Before it becomes our turn.
It was the only chance.
- An uprising?
-Yes.
They crush us like flies.
No. Rosette is right.
It would be the last thing they expect.
- Anna, most can barely walk.
But we can.
Until they start on you.
We still have some where on us.
You need help.
By whom?
The workers.
They move everywhere in the camp.
Only they can help us.
In the evening, Mario. It is very important.
Achtung!
The next few days
you should go through a series of tests.
They show everything we need to know
if your bodies-
-Before you have to participate
the research project.
I advise you to cooperate fully.
If you refuse to make diet
you will be punished severely.
It was one of you experienced at night.
You are here to serve the Third Reich.
It is your sole function.
Begin.
- Please, go. They see you.
-Can you make it?
- Yes. Join now.
What's your name?
- Rosette.
My name Wolfe.
I know that.
Up!
- No, the commandant. I have pain.
-Evil?
You do not know what evil is.
But we'll show you.
Go!
Please commandant. Please.
Spread your legs.
Do I need to say to everyone.
Go!
- We have much to learn from them, Bintz.
Yes, mein commandant.
So there is the strong?
Pain then? Are you afraid of pain?
Who does not, commandant?
We'll see.
De: is clear. Go!
I think
that we have found the right one, Bintz.
The one we've been waiting for.
6000m, commandant.
Luftwaffe may owe a lot to us.
It's been 50 minutes;
commandant.
Reduce pressure by five pounds.
- How hot is it now?
-82 Degrees, mein Ketel.
- And for how long?
-Ten minutes.
- And her values?
-Absolutely no change.
Then we have to move on.
- Increase by five degrees.
-Five? But ...
Our soldiers are dying in the inferno
to be burning tanks.
It is for their sake we do it.
For the Motherland.
Five degrees.
No one can perform for you.
No.
- Do you think it was a dream?
I do not know.
You have to prove it to them.
- How about you?
'I SGI' on.
I must know the truth.
Mario ...
This is Anna.
Anna.
And Rosette.
- Rosette.
-Hey.
Kala ...
I will!
The map is just a rough,
but you have to learn it by heart.
Now you, my beautiful commandant.
- This time it will be different.
-Say.
Take off your clothes. I want you to undress
When I sit and look at you.
No!
Slowly.
Show yourself to me - slowly.
You are beautiful, Ilsa.
Hello! Hitler!
I must go now,
but whenever you need me ...
When victory is ours, we do children.
They are beautiful.
And strong.
- They are determined.
Who is their leader?
- The new - Anna.
-Yes.
I said they can die as cattle.
I warned them.
Maybe not.
Thank you, General.
Heil Hitler!
He will most certainly.
The General himself.
He has promised - finally.
Now he'll see for himself
all the work we do here.
And how important it here.
And my own forskninog ...
He'll see it too.
Every day that we're wasting on
not daring to do so-
-Us closer to that room.
I can not wait for the butcher's knife.
Mario will find a solution.
If you do not help me-
-I hold myself at night,
over the fence there!
- Really?
She did not mean it, commandant.
I'm going to say
that General Waldeck come here-
And hear you
encourage people to accommodate.
Nothing to say?
You think I'm stupid?!
- Ingrid ...
Yes, commandant?
- The punishment for escape attempts?
-But she ...
Quiet!
A prisoner convicted of that offense
to be flogged to death before the whole camp.
- I'm not afraid.
-Good.
Great.
It is better to die than ...
I'm not going
punish you that way.
No ...
I have something special in store for you.
You are so brave,
you fear nothing ...
But we'll see?
We'll see ...
And General ... shall see.
It is said that fear of pain
is greater than the pain itself.
Do you know what this is?
Sure looks harmless?
What happens if I put it on fire?
Then maybe ...
... It becomes something completely different, right?
Not as harmless anymore, huh?
Reply when I'm talking to you!
Do you still feel nothing?
But soon it will burn deep within you.
It consumes you.
It distorts your meat.
- Does she not sent for you?
-No.
- Why not? O
She's well else to think about.
She must be cracked.
No one can so much pain.
That's more than four hours now.
Only she can prove my theory.
Why?
No screams. Not even a sound.
Take her back to her hut.
Her barracks, commander?
She'll be back later.
But first ...
First, I want everyone to see her.
It serves as a warning.
- We have so little tig for preparation.
-The girls have so little time.
Some have less than that.
How much more can she?
Up! Quick!
No ...
You think you can hold out.
You are wrong.
You will be screaming for mercy.
You beg me to stop.
I'd rather die.
More!
More! The bitch should feel it.
- Irene, Kala - this is Wolfe.
-Hey.
Hello.
This is what I learned today ...
Here is the big gate and sentry box.
This switch must be killed first.
- He's here?
I'll take care of him.
- What's this?
-Guards' barracks.
- We still need weapons, Wolfe.
-We leave them.
- When? O
-The morning after the General Act.
- You know what you should do?
-Yes.
You!
You, American!
Come on!
- You talked.
No, commandant.
You helped the bitch.
- Do not look at me like that.
I can not be lazy to remember.
In the evening - when the general sleeping.
If you come to me?
- Yes.
-Will it be like before?
Better, commandant.
Achtung! Heil Hitler!
Welcome to Camp 9, General.
A pleasure to meet fräulein major.
The reports on your charm
and your beauty was not excessive.
- The General is too friendly.
-Not at all.
May I introduce
my adjutant Captain Richter.
- Commandant.
-Well, sir ... What have you to show us?
Wait here.
I have very much liked to see
General my experiments.
- Do you use no nakors?
Ger-man experimental caviar?
But five there, General, is too short a time.
It's war, fräulein major.
We all have to sacrifice something.
Yes, General.
And these ...
... Masks-
-Has been infected with a new strain typhoid?
Yes, General.
So she gets ...
Vector ...?
In two weeks she rubs it all
and everyone she comes in contact with.
Gott im Himmel!
You can destroy an army!
The wound is infected with gangrene reply.
Gas gangrene?
It kills many brave men.
Soon, not for long.
Have you discovered an antidote?
We see many encouraging signs.
It's only a matter of time.
Verdammt! Time ...
It is always a matter of time.
And now, General,
my own private experiments.
You will
find it very interesting.
For three nights, general,
and all that without a single scream.
No man had endured such a pain.
She proves everything in my theory.
Not just everything, fräulein major.
This is a camp
for medical research.
You must not waste time Germany
on your private projects.
- But ...
-Momentl
- Could not you break her?
We tried everything.
It seems so.
Well. I will present your evidence
for Reichsführer itself.
Now we just get women
on hazardous items.
But if you are right ...
Thank you, General.
Macht nichts.
Tonight we
a special surprise for you.
Then there will be two surprises.
Because I have one for you too.
Achtung!
Remarkably.
Remarkable!
But her legs ... They are so cool.
- As marble.
-Yes.
Looking forward, General.
When we eat ...
Exactly.
I thought it would amuse you.
Lovely! Lovely!
Cold pain or destruction!
In reich Führer Heinrich Himmler
name I give you this order.
Reichsführerns is cross-
-The highest award
that can be given to someone in the SS.
Reichsführer shows hereby
its recognition and praise-
-The great dedication you have shown in-
-In the service of the Third Reich.
Heil Hitler!
- Sends her after you?
She said that.
Oh, Wolfe ...
- I'm so scared.
-I know.
And you with her ...
I do not think about stuff like that.
Rosette, listen to me.
Just think about tomorrow
and what must be done.
Nothing more. Okay?
Yes, Wolfe.
And after that ... freedom.
Free hot?
- With you?
-Yes.
That's not a workbench!
Me first!
Then all of you!
It was an unforgettable evening.
Cheers!
It was a pleasure to have the general here.
We leave here tomorrow morning.
Shortly after dawn.
So early?
Duty first.
Of course, General.
-But no ceremonies.
I only go when I'm done.
Can I help further the general?
Yes ...
No. No!
Not coat.
Just pants.
The briefs also.
Yes ...
The boots ...
Put them on again.
Fraulein Ilsa ...
Do you understand?
You are like a blonde ...
... Goddess.
Mother Earth for all of us.
For me ...
... Is only one way.
One way to pleasure.
Do you understand?
Come on, please.
Come on.
I love you!
You have to ...
Now.
"On the
meadow!
Wolfe?
But, commandant ...
Get him.
I need a real man.
This is Radio Deutschland
nation voting ends for Tonight.
-Damn!
-Yes!
Reports from our enemy
distort the truth-
-In an attempt plumt
to force our people to surrender.
- Do not believe these lies.
-Different?
Yes, Ilsa.
Everything we've done before ...
All enjoyment.
All ecstasy.
It will be forgotten.
Show me how. Show me!
Your socks, Ilsa.
Go get your silk stockings.
... Developed a new fighter.
Heinke 162 reaches
to speeds of 1000 km / h.
These planes may soon be in-
And then add the enemy
yet another devastating blow.
- We continue; with ...
-Lie on the bed, Ilsa.
No, Ilsa!
- I thought ...
-I asked you not to think!
I ordered you
to lie on the bed.
Do as I say, Ilsa.
Out with arms and legs now.
Fort. Quick!
No, not fast, Ilsa.
Slowly, step by step.
First wrists. Then the feet.
Hard, Ilsa. It has to be tight.
Only then can you be my slave.
My love slave.
- I am your slave.
-It would not you?
Yes ...
You are trying to escape from me-
-But you will find no protection.
- Soon, soon.
-Pray for mercy.
Ask me quit.
Do you feel the ecstasy, Ilsa?
- Should I hurt you?
-Oh, yes.
Makes me sick. Was Cruel.
Be Cruel!
- What are you doing?
-Ensures that you will not loose.
I'm ready now.
Good.
Attention!
There is now a red alert.
I'll be back.
- You did not stay so long now.
That's right.
Go ahead of me quiet and nice,
otherwise you get a big hole in your stomach!
- No, it was not me!
-Come on!
Get off me!
Get them here!
Help me-
Attention! There is a red alert.
Hostile aircraft approaching.
- We have to go out and all that fast.
-One thing must be done first!
What?
Revenge. Let those who tormented us ...
Themselves ... to feel pain!
No, Kala.
- If you release them free?
We give them to the Allies.
They are brought to justice, I swear.
Before the right one? What they gave us
for justice?
In five months I've been here.
They've done things with my body
and the bodies of others ...
- Let's go to the mountains.
-Goodbye, friends. God be with you.
Mario, come with us!
What life awaits a half man
outside the fence?
Attention! Red readiness now called off.
There is now a blue alert.
We resume broadcasts.
... And betraying their national duties
loss of both life and honor.
... Communications and transport centers
must be defended to the last-
-Without regard to the enemy lines.
Local commanders
held personally liable for this.
They are sentenced to death
for negligence in that respect.
General?
Your orders have been executed.
Camp 9 has ceased to exist.
You can communicate Reichsführer-
-That the Allies did not find anything.
They must never know anything.