BUENOS AIRES,
DECEMBER 2001
We're rebelling!
We demand freedom
for all those imprisoned...
for fighting for their rights.
We want health care and education.
We want jobs, comrades!
We say No to hunger.
No to repression.
Stop stealing!
You bastards!
Stop stealing from us!
Let the people decide
and govern this country!
Get rid of them all!
Let's go to the Plaza de Mayo!
Hello?
Yes.
Where?
I'm on my way.
What have you got?
-An attempted suicide.
Alcohol, drugs, pills...
What else?
-There's no pulse.
Give me the tube.
What's on the monitor?
Have we got the airway?
It's clear. Massage.
Insert it.
Hold it a minute.
-Wait, let me detach this.
Ready?
Keep going.
What's on the monitor?
-Still no pulse.
Stand back.
Good evening.
Casualty?
Thank you.
ENLIGHTENED BY FIRE
Marta?
Esteban.
I'm sorry, I called you,
I didn't know what to do.
That's OK.
What happened?
I knew he was going to do it.
I knew it.
It's my fault.
Calm down, it's not your fault.
What happened?
He mixed everything.
Brandy, coke, pills,
everything.
If I hadn't found him,
he'd be dead now.
Have the doctors
told you anything?
They asked some questions.
They told me to wait.
All right.
Vargas?
How is he?
What's going to happen, doctor?
Who are you?
-I'm his wife.
I'm a friend.
He's in a coma,...
on a ventilator, because
he can't breathe on his own.
At this moment,
there is no ocular reflex,...
he's not moving
his arms or his legs...
or responding
to painful stimulus.
It's still too early
to say anything.
We have to wait.
Over 290 veterans
had committed suicide.
The number of suicides
was equal...
to the deaths on the Islands
during the war.
The photos in the scandal press
were shocking.
Faces and bodies
showing signs of suicide.
But seeing Vargas,...
finding him there,...
between life and death
in a hospital bed,...
was something else.
The Malvinas came back again...
and covered everything.
What's wrong?
Can't you sleep?
No, it's all right.
Go back to sleep.
I'll watch TV for a while.
AIR BRIGADE IX,
APRIL 1982
Everybody out!
Group 3 with me, on the double!
Move it, soldiers!
Come on!
Attention!
-Attention!
Get your kitbags!
Group 1, on the double!
Group 3 with me!
Come on, soldiers!
On the double!
Attention!
-Attention!
Reports!
Support group, all quiet.
Group 3, all quiet.
Group 2, all quiet.
Group 1, all quiet.
Attention!
-Attention!
At ease!
Fall out!
Permission to speak.
Come here, soldier!
What is it?
-The bathroom, sir.
Two minutes.
On the double!
I said, on the double!
Hello, mom!
It's Esteban.
In Comodoro.
Mom, I'm fine, I'm fine.
I'm fine, but listen.
Can you hear me?
I'm going to the Malvinas.
I love you too.
Please, don't cry, I'm all right.
I don't have much time,
we'll be cut off in a minute.
No, I sneaked off to call you.
I'll send you a letter about
everything that's going on.
Can you hear me? Mom?
Hello? Hello?
Mom?
The world should know...
that a country which is
as fiercely determined...
as Argentina is,...
will stand up to anyone.
Let them come if they want!
Few Argentineans doubt
that it was a military tragedy...
and a severe setback
for the country's chances
of recovering the Malvinas,...
seized by England 150 years ago.
The British Prime Minister
took the opportunity...
to consolidate
her political position...
which was in deep crisis
at that time...
That's all I could get.
You want it on tape?
-Yeah.
Let me finish this first.
Alberto...
Can you hear me?
Look who's come to see you.
Love, do you know who's here?
It's Esteban.
He's come to see you.
We're here with you.
Come back, my love.
Come back, darling.
I'm here with you,...
come back.
MALVINAS, MAY 1982
What's the problem?
-Private Alarcon is sick.
What's wrong?
-I can't feel my foot, sir.
Let me see.
OK, take him to the infirmary,
quickly.
Yes, sir.
Attention!
For Lt. Gilbert,...
eyes right!
Good morning, sir.
-Good morning.
Group all present,
with the following report.
Private Alarcon is sick.
Thank you, sergeant.
Soldiers,...
good morning!
Good morning, sir!
At ease!
I don't see fiber, soldiers.
I don't see morale.
I see a bunch of sissies
and half-hearted recruits,...
shit scared and freezing cold,...
who don't understand...
and don't want to believe
we're going to win this war.
If you thought a bit,...
you'd realize...
that we have been here
for months,...
preparing our defenses
for months.
Carefully preparing our defenses!
But not our supplies.
They, on the other hand...
Think about it.
They've spent all that time
inside their ships.
Imagine the shape they're in.
Coming so far by ship...
and then landing
on these unknown islands.
For God's sake, soldiers,...
they're not even used to the cold!
As if I were used to it
in Corrientes.
You have been chosen...
to defend our homeland
from the invading enemy!
Cold doesn't exist!
Hunger doesn't exist!
Only God and our homeland!
Hurrah for our homeland!
-Hurrah!
Fuck the gurkhas!
Fuck the gurkha, soldiers!
Those guys are dead already.
They'll have to get the hell
out of here!
Red Alert!
Any wounded?
All normal, sir.
Get them into position, quickly!
Right away, sir.
Soldiers!
This bread gets harder every day.
It's like a rock.
But this is hotter
than a black stripper.
Look at poor Pinasco.
He's all fucked up.
He wanted to eat porridge
with piss.
When?
The other day, he said...
he couldn't take any more,...
and if he ate that,
he'd get...
What's it called?
-Hepatitis.
And he'd be sent back home.
If that didn't work,
he'd shoot himself in the leg.
He doesn't want to be here.
He cries all night.
The "porridge and piss"
doesn't work.
You know how many have tried it?
You know what piss is?
This is piss.
Here, take this,
it's Pizarro's piss.
I'm off.
Come on, let's go.
Got a cough?
If my mom saw me now,
she'd have a heart attack.
She's always saying,
"Betito, wrap up warm,
you'll freeze".
I can warm you up real easy.
-Our camp faggot!
Go see Corporal Dumas,
he likes brunettes like you.
Come on, move!
Get moving!
He was unlucky.
It all went wrong for him.
For us.
Do you have kids?
Yes, a daughter, Sofia.
Sofia?
A pretty name.
We had a great time together.
We had some lovely years.
He made no money
with the garage...
but he really enjoyed it.
Crazy guy!
When he had to close it,
he got a job in a factory.
You know he was very handy
with tools.
Yes, we had a great time.
We had a great time for years.
Then they closed the factory.
He had no job...
and like all the veterans
ha had to beg in the street.
We started to go downhill
way down,...
and we never stopped
until now.
There's a group of them,
about twenty or so.
Take a look.
What do we do?
-Attack separately.
What?
You come with me.
I'll give the order.
Let's go.
I've got it, help me!
Esteban, Dad's got the meat.
A barbecue for three.
Come on, let's go.
We should shag it first.
Private Chamorro Juan,...
you fed us today.
And, look.
Right on time,
with English punctuality.
If Pizarro sees that
he'll stick it up your ass.
How will he know I swiped it
from the officers' quarters?
Look, one day I'll grab him, tear
off his lieutenant's stripe,...
have him serving us hot drinks
and he won't even notice.
Hey, tell me,...
where did you learn
to kill animals?
In the country, whatever walks
ends on the grill.
Every week we kill
at least two chickens.
And in the winter, a pig.
Can you imagine?
Do pigs really squeal a lot
when they're killed?
Like pigs.
I've never seen a sheep
like that,...
with its fleece and dead.
In Barracas, all we kill
are mosquitoes.
Don't you miss your girl?
I miss her loads,...
especially now
we're living together.
I left home to live with her.
Some day we'll have kids,
get married...
Or not, I don't know.
But now we're really keen.
Remember that letter I got?
-Yeah.
It was from her.
When I finished reading it
I put it here.
It gave me a kind of warmth,
I didn't feel so scared.
If you saw how she writes.
It's good?
When I'm reading it,...
it's like she's beside me
while I'm reading it.
Then she goes away.
But she only sent me one letter.
She might have sent you
a thousand.
These shits give us nothing.
No packages, no food, nothing.
No, she just sent one.
A week before I was told
about being sent here,...
I had a terrible row with her.
On my day off, I didn't go home,
I stayed in the barracks...
and we all went out dancing.
I didn't even tell her.
And I think I'm being pissed on
by all the penguins here.
It was the first time...
we'd had a row,...
and then the transfer.
I don't know about you,
but I wasn't allowed to go home.
I couldn't say goodbye...
or give her a kiss.
Or kiss my folks.
Or pick up a toothbrush.
"One phone call", they said.
So I called her.
"Hello."
She recognized my voice
and hung up.
"One phone call, soldier."
That was my farewell.
But at least she wrote to you.
Yeah, she did.
This is Marta.
She's pretty.
Watch it.
-He'll wipe your eye.
As the bitch doesn't write
I keep thinking.
She's got some other jerk.
-Don't be stupid.
Otherwise, she'd have written.
Maybe when I get home,...
I'll open the door and see her
in my bed with another guy.
I'll have to beat her up,
kill her.
You'd do that too.
You'd kill her, wouldn't you?
Hey...
I'm getting rid of the sheep.
If they find it, we're in shit.
Let me go.
I found a place near the barrels.
What barrels?
-The ones by the road.
Nobody'll find it there.
-Be careful.
I'm not so sure
that's the best place.
Halt!
Why have you left your post?
Answer me!
Why are you endangering
your companions' lives?
You thieving shit!
You should be shot!
Do you know what we do
with thieves here?
Do you?
We've told you 1000 times.
But you can't get it
into your head.
Grunt!
Turd!
Get up!
Attention!
Stand to attention!
Move, on the double.
Get up!
Move, on the double!
Get over here!
On your hunkers, and jump!
Get down on all fours!
A snake, I want to see a snake.
Crawl like a snake.
Permission, sergeant.
What the hell is up with you two?
It was the three of us.
We killed it
because we were hungry.
Down on the ground.
I want you on all fours.
You... Kneel down.
Look at me.
You don't know me.
You know how many pretty boys
like you I've wiped out?
You know how many?
-No, sergeant.
Look at me.
So pray that I don't accidentally
fire a shot some night.
Understand?
-Yes, sir.
Pray!
Got that?
-Yes, sir!
But this turd is the loser now.
I want you to crawl slowly
back to your holes. Move!
And you, turd...
Get that animal you stole,
we're going to see Lt. Gilbert.
Move, move!
Come on.
Come on, grunt, move.
What he said was that
there was an improvement.
You saw what the doctor
was like.
Can this be happening?
I'm sure he'll pull through.
Really?
-Yes, of course.
The hospital wants some papers
that are in his apartment.
I don't want to go on my own.
Would you come with me?
I'd come to pick up some things.
Luckily I had a key,...
so I came in
and I found him here.
Just like he is now.
I had to dump a few things
to avoid problems with the cops.
He took a whole mixture.
He always did,...
but this time
he put in everything.
You weren't living here?
I put up with everything.
With everything.
His bad spells,
not having any money...
When he became an activist
with the veterans,...
when he fought with them.
I put up with it all.
When he drank,...
when he drove me crazy
with his jealousy,...
when he'd kick me around
when he came home drunk...
Everything.
Not having children.
You know,...
the two...
or three times
we talked after the war,...
he always said the same thing.
We had to go back
to the Islands.
"We have to go back."
Fuck, you should've said
it was you.
I'll blow you away
the next time, motherfucker.
Asshole!
Any word of Vargas?
They brought him to the hole
a while ago.
They fucked him over.
How is he now?
He's a wreck.
Soaking wet.
I'm scared today.
Scared the English will come.
I keep seeing ships in the mist.
When I was a kid,...
my dad would take me hunting.
I was afraid of the dark,...
so he taught me to listen
to what I couldn't see.
"When you can't see, listen",
he told me.
It's the same with the English.
You're either afraid or not.
I stopped being afraid
of the dark long ago.
When my son is older
I'll teach it to him.
You've got a son?
Yes.
Why did you never tell us?
He's 18 months,
and he's beautiful.
He looks at you with these
big eyes, he's like an owl.
When the sergeant caught us
the other day,...
and they took Vargas,...
I don't know
if it was from fear,...
but I dreamed about him.
What did you dream?
He was watching me and laughing.
I want to teach him things.
I don't know,
to play the guitar,...
not to be afraid of the dark,...
walk him to school.
I'm afraid I won't see him again.
You'll see him again.
Attention!
You are under
the lieutenant's orders.
Get ready, men.
You have a mission
at the battlefront.
You have to take this equipment
to Sgt. Garrido.
You heard the lieutenant.
Prepare your weapons,...
your blanket, rain cape,
mess kit.
I want you ready in five minutes.
Do it in orderly fashion.
On the double! On the double!
Permission, Sgt. Gilbert.
-What is it, corporal?
I think the equipment
is too heavy for two men.
Do you?
-Yes, sir.
OK, send the three of them.
Yes, sir.
Vargas too?
-Affirmative.
Vargas too.
Vargas!
Get your gear,
you're going to the front too.
I can't move, I'm sick.
Leave your post
and come out here immediately.
I said, now!
What is it?
You want to be staked out again?
Come on, get out of there.
Get out.
Move.
Attention. Attention!
Attention!
What's wrong?
You wimp!
Are you crying?
Are you crying, soldier?
Answer me!
What's wrong?
You want to break my heart
with your tears?
Your mommy's not here,
there's no one to look after you.
You're on your own!
Now, get your stuff.
You're going out again
with those two grunts.
Get ready to leave.
And you two mules,
what are you doing in there?
Get out here!
Come on, ladies,
I don't have all day.
Move those tits, come on!
You two,
get that stuff over there.
Come on, move, move!
Now, listen carefully to this.
You're taking this stuff
to the front,...
to the first lines,...
where the real fighting is.
You're going to find
real soldiers there...
who are giving their lives
for their homeland,...
not faggots like you.
Chicken shits! Apes!
Now, move your asses!
I can't go on!
-Come on.
Come on.
You can't come this way!
Go around the other side!
It's all mined.
Crazy fool!
Since I've seen you,
I keep going back there.
Awake or asleep.
As if the ghosts I've tried
to bury all these years...
were all knocking at my door.
I can see them, smell them.
Come on, wake up.
We have to go back
to the Islands.
Remember when you talked
about closure?
Well, now's the time.
Or the ghosts will always be there.
Can you hear me?
Move forward!
Attack!
For the homeland!
Pull back!
Pull back, men!
Retreat!
Mom! Help me, mommy!
Mom!
Don't leave me!
Pull back!
Retreat!
Pull back, for crissake!
Move it!
Come on, pull back!
Let's get out of here!
Come on!
Pull back!
Help me!
Look at me, Juan!
Look at me!
Stop it, stop it, look at me!
Chamorro, look at me, come on!
Stop, stop, for God's sake!
Chamorro, look at me!
Stop, no!
Stop, stop, no!
Don't leave me here.
Esteban!
Where are you?
Esteban, look what they did to me!
Where's Juan? Where's Juan?
-We have to move!
Stop! Stop!
Stop it, you bastards!
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Esteban, are you there?
What is it?
-Sgt. Pizarro wants to see you!
What does that fucker want?
What's up?
We're pulling back to Puerto
Argentino, so go see Pizarro.
Coming!
Stay here. I'll see Pizarro
and come back for you.
Report immediately to Lt. Gilbert!
Yes, sir?
Pack my personal belongings,
quickly.
Any further news?
-Nothing.
Keep trying.
Ready, sir.
The cassette player!
Ready, sir!
Take the bag to where I tell you.
Quickly.
No, you take it.
What?
I have to help a wounded comrade.
Get over here!
Who do you think you are?
Are you refusing
to obey an order?
We're losing because
of faggots like you!
No, it's because
you're all incompetent!
What did you say?
-You heard!
Get over here or...
-Will you stake me out?
Come here!
Come on, pal.
Wait, I have to help Vargas.
He's still in the hole.
Come on, hurry up!
Vargas!
He's up ahead!
Come on, get up.
-I can't.
Help me,
I can't do it on my own.
I'm staying here,
save yourself.
I can't move my leg.
It hurts a lot.
I can't walk any farther.
We have to go to Puerto Argentino.
It hurts so much.
I'll never get out of here.
Come on!
Come on, men!
Gather in front of
the governor's house.
We're entering Puerto Argentino.
The enemy
could be hiding anywhere!
There may be urban combat.
The enemy could be hiding
in Puerto Argentino.
There may be urban combat.
Gather up, on the double!
Come on, men.
Hurry!
Come here, soldier!
Come on, soldier, help this man!
Come on, soldiers!
Gather at the governor's house!
Keep your eyes open.
The enemy could be waiting for us.
There may be urban combat.
We're entering Puerto Argentino,
the enemy may be waiting for us!
To the governor's house.
Keep together, we're going
to the governor's house.
Keep together!
Head for the governor's house.
Private Leguizamon!
Come here.
Listen, you're to go
to the governor's house.
We have to take him
to the infirmary.
Soldier!
Come here.
Help Leguizamon.
Leguizamon, come back afterwards!
Bring him over here.
Careful!
When was it?
-Yesterday.
Take it easy!
It really hurts.
-Take it easy.
You brought him in too late.
They're going to cut off my leg!
They're going to cut it off!
-No, they're not!
Don't believe that doctor!
I'm fine, I'm going home!
Who are you?
-A friend, I brought him in.
Well, you can go now.
-No, I'm staying.
Get out of here.
-No, don't go, Esteban!
Quit pretending you're Maradona.
Pass it.
Give me the helmets
for the goalposts.
Come on, Maradona, pass it.
Goal!
Soldiers,...
I regret that I have to make
this announcement,...
but it is my duty...
to inform you...
that a ceasefire has been ordered
on the entire island.
From this moment,...
we are under the orders
of the British commanders.
We are going to remain
at our positions...
until our troops...
are regrouped.
At 13:00,...
you will see a helicopter
with a white flag.
Do not open fire.
You men...
have fought like true soldiers...
and you will be remembered...
by all the Argentineans...
as heroes.
You can be sure of this.
You gave all you had...
to defend our homeland.
Soon...
you will be back
on the mainland.
You will be reunited
with your families.
But what
you have experienced here...
will be with you...
forever.
Despite our efforts,...
the bravery of some,...
and the courage of our pilots...
who flew low
over the English ships,...
the improvisation, sadism...
and treachery of those who had
tortured their own people...
had led us to defeat.
The English didn't need to use
the nuclear weapons...
that were on their ships.
The support of NATO
and aid from the U.S.A...
helped them seize a territory
that wasn't theirs.
They took our Islands again...
and rejoiced over our blood.
We buried our dead and, defeated,
returned to the mainland.
Our officers hid us
in the barracks.
We were forced to stay silent.
Why not talk about the Malvinas?
Who thought we were heroes?
Who hailed our homecoming?
Our return to life?
When I got home
I was expecting banners,...
people welcoming us
with hugs and tears.
A dog was barking
in the empty night,...
and at the end of the street...
only my mother was waiting
with open arms.
Doctor!
-Calm down, ma'am.
Nurse, take her outside.
Come on.
He's in ventricular tachycardia.
-Start C.P.R.
Go!
Right, let's go!
Right, once again.
What'll we do?
-Nothing, that's it.
Nothing else?
Will I turn off the ventilator?
-Go ahead.
I'm so glad I called you.
You really helped me.
You helped me too, Marta.
Honestly.
He wore it to the very end.
Take it with you when
you go back to the Islands.
Leave it in the Malvinas.
We shall shortly be landing
at the Falklands/Malvinas airport.
We have now entered
a military area.
The use of cameras
is strictly forbidden.
Thank you
for your cooperation.
The sea is measured by waves
The sky, by wings
And we are measured
by our tears
The air rests on leaves
Water, on eyes
And we rest
on nothing
It seems that salts and suns
we and nothing
"Argentineans, you will be welcome
when you stop claiming sovereignty
and accept our right
to self-determination".
The old loves that are gone
the dreams of those who lost
all the promises that fade
and those who fell in any war
everything is stored
in our memory
the dream of life and history
The deceit and complicity
of the genocides
who are walking free
the "Reprieve" and
the "Full Stop" law
to the beasts from that hell
everything is stored
in our memory
the dream of life and history
Memory awakens to wound
the sleeping people
who will not let it live
free as the wind
The missing who are sought
along the paths of their origins
the hunger and abundance
that come together
cruelty and its painful memory
everything is nailed
in our memory
a thorn of life and history
Two thousand could eat for a year
on the cost of a military moment
So many would cease to be slaves
for the cost of a bomb
dropped in the sea
Everything is nailed
in our memory
a thorn of life and history
Memory stabs until it draws blood
from the people who tie it down
and won't let it walk
free as the wind
To the conscripts who fought
in the Malvinas.
To the dead of the Belgrano.
To those who fought with dignity.
I'm sitting here
under the tiny sun
the one that gave us
the eagle and also the sparrow
What can you do with the silence
when your head explodes?
How can you stop the impotence
of not being able to do anything?
Why do you want
to kill your children?
Your suffering will last for years
Yesterday, for not loving
the homeland
today, for loving it too much
Old laws and genocides
a bad omen for life
With the light filled with shadows
and with the sun
deep in suffering
I went back home on my knees
and left my dead friends here
In a country that's sick
all the cards are on the table
We play perverted games
between soccer and war
Blood of glory,
hatred against love
gods and beasts,
madness and pain
I'll open the doors
of this emptiness
because fate threw me upwards
Old laws and genocides
a bad omen for life
I'll insist with a sea of roses
and I'll build on ashes
I'll have a new dream in my hands
and I'll fight for justice
to be done
My children's cheeks
against my lips
And I'll find rest again
in their eyes
Old laws and genocides
a bad omen for life