Liz Eddington, pie-eyed.
- Where?
- Over there.
Happy, baby?
I'm gonna put a stop to this.
- Paul Eddington can take care of her.
- No, he can't.
He's at sea on gunnery practice.
Please play something else.
- Thank heaven they stopped the music.
- Why did they stop?
- Come on, they've had their show.
- I don't wanna go.
- Come on.
- I don't want to!
It's a stuffy Navy joint.
Let's get outta here.
- We should take her home.
- Mac...
- One last dance.
- We can't let her...
She's with that officer.
What about her husband
out there doing his duty?
Eddington knows about Liz.
If he wants to put up with it,
that's his business.
- I love you.
- What?
- I just said, "I love you."
- Why?
Never mind.
If you've cooled down now,
I think we can go.
I'm not sure I want to go now.
You've got the duty in the morning, early.
- Lieutenant J G McConnel.
- Yes, ma'am?
You've got to play
captain of your ship at 6 a.m.
Liz!
Come on in. It's great!
Come on!
I'm awake, Leary.
Tell the exec to join me
in my sea cabin for breakfast.
Leary?
Oh.
- Well, then, bacon and eggs for me.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Eddington!
Paul, wake up.
In case it slipped your mind,
it's gunnery stations at 0830.
So why don't you write me up?
Because your record already looks like
a bunch of pig tracks.
One more scratch on it
and your career in the Navy is ended.
That's how it should be,
I should be scrapped.
I'm obsolescing like this old
straw-bottomed cruiser of ours.
We both know what's eating you, Paul.
You can't wash it out with booze.
- What would you know about it?
- I tried it one time.
You? The Rock of Ages?
I don't believe it.
You're forcing me to throw
my weight at you. Fish or cut bait.
Get on your feet or take your troubles
elsewhere. I got a ship to run.
I'll put in for a transfer.
You've had one transfer already,
out of naval aviation.
- Might not get another chance.
- I don't give a damn.
Well, that isn't what I wanted
to hear you say.
I'm sorry, Rock.
OK.
If you can hold a razor, you might shave
before you come topside.
Aye, aye, Father Torrey.
You bum!
- Cut that out.
- Take me home!
Come on, I need a bath.
Good morning, sir.
If the captain were aboard,
would you dress that way?
I suspect not, sir.
Put on your uniform.
You make us look like pirates.
Aye, aye, Mr McConnel.
All right, 15-2, 15-4...
Double run of 8 for 12, your crib.
- Anything interesting?
- I got a run of three.
- The carriers pulled out Friday.
- For where?
South. Lahaina Roads, maybe.
I got that Hawaiian Sea Frontier
dispatch decoded.
Give it to our captain,
Lieutenant J G McConnel.
- More fun and games?
- No.
Destroyer Ward dropped depth charges
on a submarine contact
inside the defensive sea area.
Some poor Joe's got it in the wringer.
Attacking one of our own subs...
Commence evasive zigzag pattern,
Commander.
- Set extra lookouts.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Morning, Captain.
- Morning. How are you this fine day?
Splendid, thank you, sir.
What's the alert?
Ward dropped depth charges
on what they think is a sub,
15 miles away, near the sea buoy.
Another poor whale lost its blubber.
Sir, are we just looking for subs
or planes, too?
Anything, son.
There's a formation of planes
north of the island, sir.
The pilots are up early
for squadron exercises.
Strange place to rendezvous.
Why aren't they over Diamond Head?
There's a formation
off Diamond Head, too.
I don't like it, Paul.
Sound General Quarters.
- Make it no drill.
- Yes, sir.
This is not a drill.
General Quarters.
All hands man your battle stations.
On deck.
Attention to colours.
Bridge. Aye, aye.
Mr McConnel?
- McConnel.
- We're getting some funny signals.
It sounds like plane-to-plane chatter,
in Japanese.
- Japs!
- What?
Japs!
My God, they're Japs! Come on!
Emergency sortie signal
from the yard tower.
Engine room? Light off all four boilers.
Make preparations for getting underway.
- Report readiness status in five minutes.
- Cut in all burners.
Disengage checking gear.
Open guarding valves.
Flip the electric rolls.
General Quarters!
Man your battle stations!
- Quoddy.
- Aye, sir.
- Can you take us out?
- You call it, Mr McConnel.
- Wait for the captain.
- Screw the captain.
- Ring up turns for 20 knots.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- 20 knots through the harbour?
- You heard.
Take her away. She's got enough
to move now, building fast.
Quoddy, right 10 degrees rudder.
Steady up on 1-2-0.
- It's Captain Harding, sir, and the exec.
- Slow down!
How can we stop?
It'll take 20 minutes at this speed.
Does anybody here
see anything back there?
Let us board! Stop!
If they does, I'll guarantee
they'll never see nothin' again!
Let her rip, Mac!
Advise me of any further messages.
How many ships answered
the emergency sortie signal?
Destroyer Cassiday's moving, sir.
The Harkness, Ballard,
cruisers Greely and Jackson...
The battleships, man!
None, sir.
- Out of nine battleships?
- None, sir.
Lookout reports tin-can breaking out, sir.
Paul, signal all ships coming out
to form up with us.
Aye, aye, sir.
- That can't be all.
- That's all Captain Torrey reports, sir.
Three light cruisers, eight destroyers
and Captain Torrey's heavy cruiser.
- None is equipped with radar.
- 12 bat-blind ships.
Well, gentlemen. Your opinions.
We must position them
to repel an invasion.
- You mean wait, Admiral Broderick.
- We have no choice. Wait.
Seek out and destroy, if at all possible.
What can 12 ships do
against the Jap task force?
It would be a futile gesture.
It could give us time
to bring our carriers within range.
What if Torrey can't contact the Japs?
Suppose they slip by him?
He has no radar, one scout plane.
The risk is too great,
leaving our shores unprotected.
- I repeat, sir. We must wait.
- Thank you, Admiral Broderick.
Order Captain Torrey to assume
command of his task group
and seek out and engage
the enemy if possible.
- All your personal problems resolved?
- Let's say they're cut down a size.
Dispatch has come in
from Fleet Operations, sir.
- Burke?
- From CinCPac.
"Japanese believed retiring for refuelling.
"Proceed to latitude 18 north,
longitude 162 west.
"Seek out and engage the enemy.
Godspeed."
- Well!
Have all ships report
useable fuel aboard.
Break radio silence. Ask CinCPac
for a tanker rendezvous at first light.
- After you figure our projected position.
- Aye, aye, sir.
We'll play hell
getting a tanker out of Pearl.
If we don't, we'll be sucking air
instead of oil by midnight tomorrow.
Sir, the starboard lookout
has a ship on the bow.
A tanker, he thinks, sir.
She's riding high. She's empty.
She's going home,
if a sub doesn't get her.
At this rate, we'll have to head home
inside 10 hours.
We could reduce speed to save fuel.
Crawl at 10 knots?
We'd never find any Japs.
- If we stopped zigzagging...
- That'd be an invitation to enemy subs.
There may be subs out there, maybe not.
Whether there are
or aren't subs out there,
if we steer a straight course, we'd add
another six hours to our steaming time.
Resume our base course.
- Straighten us out, Commander Burke.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Rock, you just threw the book away.
How long will Torrey keep pushing?
We haven't enough fuel
to hold the keel down.
He'll run the rope out
and then add some string to it.
- Where'd you know him?
- He instructed at the Academy.
We call him the Rock.
Scared the hell outta you.
He's all Navy and nothin' but Navy.
He never left the campus,
like he had nowhere else to go.
Sonar contact, sir, bearing 0-2-0.
Range 2,000 and closing.
Make turns for 20 knots.
Set condition able.
Close all watertight doors.
- Tell Sonar to keep the ranges coming.
- 1800 and closing.
- Cline? You on the recorder?
- You know it!
Signal flagship we're about to attack
sonar contact.
Cassiday reports submarine contact.
- Have all ships resume zigzag.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- 0-1-5 it is, sir.
- Stand by to roll depth charges.
Stern racks. Roll one.
Roll two.
They're on it, sir.
They hit the cruiser!
- Reports from damage control.
- She's dead in the water.
- Midship damage control won't answer.
- Shall I go below, sir?
- Tell me when you locate the damage.
- That arm's busted.
- What's wrong?
- The door's jammed.
Get a message to Pearl: "Have taken
two torpedoes" - fill in our position -
- "Will advise on damage."
- And break radio silence, sir?
Burke, don't you think the Japanese
know by now where we are?
Aye, aye, sir.
The door may blow. Stand clear!
Griggs, get those mattresses down.
Stand by to fire another full pattern.
Order the destroyers back to Pearl
at best possible speed, zigzagging.
- Cassiday got the sub, sir. Definite kill.
- Hold it!
Have all ships return to Pearl
at 20 knots, except the Cassiday.
Have her stand by
in case we have to abandon ship.
OK...
- Compliments of Cdr. Eddington.
- Just give me the word.
Cdr. Eddington says
this old tub'll float, sir.
- At ease.
- Thank you, sir.
Full report.
We halted the fires up forward
where we took the first torpedo.
And we stopped the flow
of water at Hatch 26.
Cdr. Eddington said to tell the old man -
I'm sorry, sir, the captain -
that he'd better start
thinking about a tow.
May I also say, sir,
that Cdr. Eddington is hell on wheels.
- What are the casualties?
- At least 40 men were trapped.
- 40 men, maybe more.
- Cassiday coming alongside, sir.
Take care of this boy.
Nice work, Harding.
You did a four-o job on that sub.
Thank you, sir.
I'm not Commander Harding.
- Where is he?
- Ashore, sir.
- Who's in command?
- I am, sir. Lieutenant J G McConnel.
Did I hear "Lieutenant Junior Grade"?
William McConnel, class of '38.
- Can you rig for towing?
- Can do, sir.
Can you pass some
portable pumps to us?
Can do, sir.
Carry on, mister.
Can do.
Oh, Rock of Ages.
We got ourselves another war.
A gut-bustin', mother-Iovin' Navy war.
It does seem to shape up that way,
Commander Eddington.
Captain Torrey,
the admiral will see you now.
Thank you.
- Please sit down, Captain.
- Thank you, sir.
I wasn't aware you'd been hurt.
A simple fracture, sir.
It won't interfere with my duties.
You have a remarkable record,
Captain Torrey.
- Thank you, sir.
- Save your thanks.
I'm relieving you of your command
pending a court of inquiry.
I don't understand.
You weren't zigzagging
when you took the torpedo.
I was stretching my fuel, sir.
If you didn't have enough fuel,
why didn't you turn back?
My mission was to engage an enemy
of greatly superior strength.
I could only take that one way:
My group was expendable.
I doubt a court of inquiry
will accept that.
You're caught in the vacuum between
a peacetime Navy and a wartime Navy.
Soon they'll make admirals
out of captains with guts.
Now, they're reacting to Pearl Harbor
and punishment is order of the day.
You don't have to abide by
what a court of inquiry decides.
You can ask for a general court martial,
get a couple of lawyers and fight it.
I wouldn't care to do that, sir.
- Why not?
- Second-generation Navy, Admiral.
I see.
I don't plan to ask for a court martial
either, and I've lost a fleet.
I expect we'll both take what they give us
and trust it'll be a useful job.
Yes, sir.
- Good luck.
- Good luck to you, sir.
If I haven't got him, maybe he's still alive.
It must be a mistake,
he was clever...
Comb, compact...
- The child can't be lost...
- Two rings... purse.
- Maybe the police know where he is.
- Sign here.
He was my only boy,
and I love him so much.
- Won't you do something for me?
- This way for identification.
- Go back to the police.
- I want you to help me.
- Lady...
- He was my only boy.
You don't have a boy!
Disposition?
What do you want to do?
- I'll send someone.
- Thank you.
And the man she was brought in with?
Army Air Force claimed the body
a couple of days ago.
...a very pretty name.
- Been here long?
- I'm from Hawaii.
- I like Hawaii.
- Me, too.
- Where's my drink?
- I made you a fresh one.
- Thanks.
- Bourbon.
- Sorry, nothin' but beer. Martial law.
- OK, beer.
- How come the Air Corps rates a drink?
- They brought that bottle in.
Running dry, Commander?
Let me sweeten your beer.
Share and share alike,
we're all in this war.
Little more? OK... How's that?
Would you like to join us?
Only two chicks but we can share...
Send the police to the Blue Lagoon.
Come.
Sir, I just got word
on Commander Eddington.
- What about him?
- He's in the Honolulu brig.
- In the brig?
- That's the word, sir.
Will you see my clothes are packed
and sent over to
the bachelors officers' quarters?
Yes, sir. Can I help you with that?
- Is that all, sir?
- I travel light.
Well, Commander Burke...
Oh, sir...
- Goodbye, sir.
- Goodbye.
You're released into
your captain's custody, sir.
Sergeant.
This is yours, sir.
I'll walk you to the Duty Boat.
I've been relieved of command.
Bastards!
Sorry about your wife.
You got yourself into a pretty good fix.
A public brawl...
What the hell.
A new AA cruiser
going out to join Halsey.
She's a tiger.
A fast ship going in harm's way.
A lousy situation,
Commander Eddington.
Lousy.
Stay still.
Good. Come with me, please, Captain.
Shoot those over to Dr Lyons
as soon as they're ready.
- Doctor?
- Yes.
A 3-month-old fracture, some infection.
The X-rays will be along shortly.
Thank you. Sit down, Captain.
That's a real nice sound to wake up to.
- What is Vicki Marlowe's secret?
- Not what it says in here.
Her secret is that she's making
half a million bucks a year
and she still collects alimony from me,
in my present reduced circumstances.
Well, anyway...
I have the satisfaction that
all her pictures have been stinkers
since I stopped writing them.
Rockwell, my boy, I tell you never,
I repeat, never marry a movie actress.
- You married three of 'em.
- It's like eating peanuts.
Once I started, I couldn't stop!
Hey, look at you!
Two hands, congratulations.
- Shall we celebrate?
- How?
There's some action
at a place in Moanalua.
No, no parties for me.
Anyway, when do you special intelligence
officers do what you're supposed to do?
Seems you sleep all day
and go to parties every night.
Us civilians need more rest
and recreation than you old salts.
Not that you couldn't use a little.
It's time you crawled down from
Mount Rushmore and looked around.
You'd be surprised at the changes
we've made in the last 100 years.
I tell you, the women are
smoking cigarettes, drinking whiský,
doing the shimmy-sham-shimmy
hot damn, man...
- Very funny.
- Come on, Rock...
No, no thanks.
- OK.
- What?
Maybe you're right.
I gotta do something besides sit at a desk
and count the ink stains on the blotter.
Who's our host?
Whoever knows the host?
Some pineapple moneybags.
Were you invited?
One sailor looks like another.
Gimme your hat.
Egan Powell!
I want you to meet Captain Torrey.
This is Mrs...
...Let me see...
- Henderson.
How do you do?
Follow me.
Hello, Paula.
Well... Thank you very much.
Let's go over here.
It's very important to relax, old boy.
- Paul, how are you?
- Hello, Egan.
- Introduce me.
- Gaby, this is Egan.
- How do you do?
- You don't mind?
Hold that, will you?
- Enjoying the party, Captain Torrey?
- Yes, thank you. Fine party.
- You think so?
- It's great.
Thank you.
- Funny.
- What's funny?
Not exactly funny, it's just that
you're so different from your son.
- My son?
- Ensign Jere Torrey.
At least he claims his father's a captain.
I supposed you were it.
That's my son's name. Jeremiah. Jere.
He's been dating my room-mate.
Frankly, it worries me a little.
She's a green kid from Vermont,
he's a smooth Harvard type.
I think she's about to fall in love with him.
That's what worries me.
- Will it be all right?
- I hope so.
Not much comfort.
- How's the arm?
- I beg your pardon?
- Your arm!
- Oh, it's... fine.
I'm Nurse Lt. Haynes.
I took the X-rays today.
- I'm sorry!
- Thank you for not recognising me.
I made a special effort
to not look like a nurse.
Don't worry about your son.
I'm sure he's all he should be.
I'm flying under false colours,
Miss Haynes. I don't know my son.
I've been divorced many years.
He was raised
by his mother and her family.
I didn't even know he was in the Navy.
Well...!
Much as I'd like to,
I won't ask any more questions.
I hate to leave but
I have to get to the hospital.
I don't have to get any place but out.
Share a cab?
Let me drop you. I borrowed a car
from my landlord's gardener.
Thank you, Miss Haynes.
I'm Maggie...
if you'd like to be less formal.
Thank you for that, too.
But don't wait too long.
My unit's due to be shipped out soon.
- Captain.
- Maggie.
- Ensign Torrey?
- No, sir.
Your duty office said Ensign Torrey
had the watch aboard this craft.
- Yes, sir.
- Well?
- I'll get him for you, sir.
- Thank you.
Get topside, quick. Brass!
- Did you hear me?
- I'm going.
- I shouldn't have stood your watch!
- Take it easy.
I'm Ensign Torrey, sir.
You wanted to see me?
- I'm your father, Jere.
- Yes, sir.
- You look like your mother.
- Is she well?
- Very well, sir.
Sit down.
Thank you, sir.
Do you often stand your watch
in your cabin?
Ensign Farris relieved me
for a few minutes, sir.
Motor Torpedo Boat duty.
How do you like it?
I don't like it, sir.
Why did you choose it?
It's a voluntary duty.
I volunteered on advice. This unit's
assigned to Admiral Broderick.
I was advised that a transfer
could be arranged to the admiral's staff.
Who gave you the advice?
Cdr. Neal Owynn,
the admiral's public relations officer.
I'll be his assistant.
I expect you've heard of Neal Owynn.
No.
He's quite a well-known
Congressman, sir.
He resigned from office
to join the service.
Your mother's family
can usually get what they want.
- You disapprove, sir?
- You trained on these boats.
You'd be a damn sight more useful here
than in public relations.
I majored in journalism at the university.
If I must do my bit
in this trumped-up war,
I prefer to do what I'm suited for.
Did I hear you say "trumped-up war"?
It is Mr Roosevelt's war, isn't it?
You not only look like a Cunliffe,
you talk like one.
I remember they said the first one
was Mr Wilson's war.
- What's your duty, sir?
- Routing convoys.
I expect to be in the forward areas,
if not actually in combat.
Admiral Broderick is to handle
a very important offensive, Skýhook.
I wouldn't know about that.
I wouldn't expect you would.
Cdr. Owynn gave me the information.
Are you leaving, sir?
Yes. Before I pick you up
and throw you to the fish.
I was four when you left my mother.
I don't even remember you.
And for 18 years
you haven't bothered to remember me.
Why come here tonight?
Let's just say that I did come
and let it go at that.
Goodnight, Ensign.
- How!
- Egan!
Where've you been for the last 10 days?
Or should I ask?
You shouldn't,
but there was snow in Washington.
Washington! Got the war all worked out?
If you buy me lunch,
I'll give you the date of victory.
- I am your man.
- Good.
- Run these courses off on the big chart.
- Aye, aye, sir.
We ensure information
given to the press corps
is good for the war effort
and for the Navy.
And for Broderick.
What's good for him
is good for the Navy.
With a little left over for Neal Owynn?
- How's the nurse?
- I'm seeing her tonight.
Why don't you come along?
She's got a room-mate that's not bad.
What do you know about
an operation called Skýhook?
- Where did you get that?
- Is it important?
Only 20 people between here
and the White House know that name.
There's 21 now, or maybe 22 or 23.
I got it indirectly through
an ex-Congressman named Owynn.
That's Broderick's drumbeater.
He needs a zipper in his face.
That's top secret.
I can't tell you about it.
OK!
You say you got it indirectly,
from Owynn?
See that young ensign,
lighting his cigarette?
- That's Owynn he's sitting with.
- That's where I got it.
From that ensign?
He's my son.
Well...! I'd like to meet him, Rock.
No, you wouldn't.
He had his chances to ask me.
Ten days' worth of chances is enough.
- He didn't call me. So I called him.
- How did you have the nerve?
Annalee, past a certain age,
men avoid making sudden moves
where women are concerned.
The women have to move
before it's too late.
It gets late fast in these times.
I like this man,
I want him to know it. Now.
Suppose they meet?
Jere's very funny about his father.
Oh, let them. It might be interesting.
- This must be Jere.
- I'll go.
- Hello, Ensign.
- Yes, ma'am, Lieutenant.
- Be a minute or two... She'll be down.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Lieutenant, ma'am...
I'd like to invite you to come with us.
Dinner with Commander Neal Owynn.
Thanks, but I'm waiting for a friend.
You're more than welcome
to bring her, or him, along.
Well, if my friend
arrives in time, we'll see.
I'm here to see a nurse.
What are you here for?
To see a nurse.
Seems like we have
something in common after all.
I'm just a chip off the old block, sir.
- Hello.
- Miss Haynes.
Captain Torrey.
Ensign Annalee Dorne.
- Miss Dorne.
- You've met my friend.
Sir, I've invited Miss Haynes and friend
to dine with Cdr. Owynn.
- I hope you'll accept.
- That's very gracious of you.
But we have other plans.
Right, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
- In that case...
- Good afternoon.
Miss Dorne.
- You run a taut ship.
- He's not a bad-Iooking kid, is he?
No, he isn't.
Oh... I brought you something.
- What is it?
- Candy.
Candy...! Thank you.
- Shall we eat at the Chinaman's?
- No.
We're going to eat here,
if you don't mind.
- I wouldn't want to...
- Please!
I haven't cooked for a man
in a long time.
Pour us a drink.
If I can get this oven hot enough,
we're gonna have biscuits.
- Want water in yours?
- Yes, but don't drown the whiský.
I'm not a lady.
I started life as an army brat
and never tried to change.
Here's how.
- Did you say Army?
- My father was a one-star general.
Daddy... He was an angel
and a devil and I was nuts about him.
So nuts, in fact, that I married his aide.
Would you open this can for me?
You married his aide?
- He wasn't much of a man.
- This cutter's broken.
Not very smart or very brave.
Maybe I expected him to be Daddy
and he wasn't.
That's quite a knife you carry.
Can opener, screwdriver, punch,
straight blade, even a skinning blade.
That is useful. What do you skin?
Lieutenant nurses who pull my leg.
- Where was I?
- Just married.
Yes. I left him, right here in Honolulu,
shacked up with a wahine from Kauai.
That was eight years ago.
He quit the service and married her.
I drifted till I had to latch onto something
or go down the drain.
I went to nursing school
and joined the Navy.
- Now I'd like to know more about you.
- Navy.
My father was a chief petty officer
and I went to the Academy.
- That the best you can do?
- Unless you want my service record.
There's your son...
Aloha.
- Hi!
- Hello, Jere. Just the two of you?
- Miss Haynes couldn't come.
- I'm sure it's my loss.
- Cdr. Owynn, meet Ensign Dorne.
- What a beautiful place.
I'm afraid my friend
didn't leave much liquor
when he decided to
sit the war out on the mainland.
I can give you a choice of... Pernod...
...and gin... Oh, yes,
there is a little brandy.
- Brandy for me.
- Miss Dorne?
I don't know...
Gin, I guess, but not much.
Gin, but not much.
My unit got orders today.
We're being assigned to ComSoPacSub
Area 3, whatever that is.
Commander Third Sub Area,
South West Pacific.
Sounds very impressive.
- Have you been alerted?
- No, just assigned.
Third Area is
Admiral Broderick's command.
- Jere's Admiral?
- The same.
Can't get away from the Torreys, can I?
We can sit down.
- Hey!
- We're alone.
- Where's Commander Owynn?
- It's OK.
Dinner is ready.
- Aren't we waiting for Cdr. Owynn?
- He was called to Headquarters.
I guess it's just the two of us.
- Ever hear the name Cunliffe?
- An expensive New England name.
She was a Cunliffe, Jere's mother.
I met her at a Navy ball, 1917.
She was beautiful.
I don't know why she married me.
- I was just an ensign.
- I bet you were something as an ensign!
I fell over my feet most of the time.
When I came back from the war,
I had a son.
And the Cunliffes
had great plans for me.
I was to resign
my commission in the Navy
and do something useful,
the stock market.
They sat with teacups on their laps
and ticker tape coming out of their ears
and I said "No".
It was quite a scene.
Then Athalie -
that was her name, Athalie -
said, "Rockwell,
I will not become a camp follower.
"Whenever you're not busy boating
with the Navy, feel free to visit us."
And that's the way it was. I visited.
I was assigned to duty in the Philippines
and that ended it.
You left out one small detail.
You were terribly in love with her.
You're a good cook, Maggie.
And you look lovely in the candlelight.
- You haven't had much to say.
- I guess I haven't.
- Would you like to dance?
- I don't think so.
Come sit over here.
- Please don't.
- What's the matter?
We'd better go home.
I don't like this, any of it.
- Since when?
- Since your commander disappeared.
I didn't know you missed him so much.
I'm jealous!
You know what I mean.
It makes me feel cheap.
Take it easy!
He won't be back for a long time.
I'm sorry, Jere, but I want to go.
- Think I'm an idiot?
- What?
- Nothing's cheaper than a teaser.
- Isn't that what you've been doing?
- I have not!
I thought we... I thought you...
- Wait a minute!
- Let me go!
I've spent my life learning about men
and ships and how to use them in action.
I just don't fit behind a desk, I...
...I'm not cut out for it,
I feel dry-docked.
- Oh, well.
- Thanks.
Thanks?
Who else have you said
these things to recently? Or ever?
- That'll be Annalee and your son.
- Oh, I'd better...
- Thanks, fellas.
- You're welcome.
I think that had to happen.
Goodnight, Rock.
Goodnight, Maggie.
- Any time, Rock. Any time at all.
- Thank you, Maggie.
Yeah, go ahead and I'll be there.
- Sir, Cdr. Powell is waiting for you.
- Thanks.
- Greetings!
- What are you so happy about?
This... Want to close that door?
I have a very private little job for you,
no one but you.
Three convoys to be routed
to this island, Toulebonne.
- Paul Eddington is stationed there.
- It's Broderick's new base.
Skýhook again, huh?
Here's the shipping list.
- A lot of tonnage.
- Hard to come by.
CinCPac wants it all to arrive
on time and intact.
The first convoy is loaded,
personnel go on board Thursday,
when they shove off is up to you.
I think I see it.
See what?
Skýhook.
All right.
Jap supply lines must be spread out
pretty thin south of Cape Titan.
So Broderick could hit
Lalatea, Muk or Gavabutu.
From any of those islands,
he could launch a strike against...
...Levu-Vana.
- Why Levu-Vana?
It has a central plain
large enough for B-17 airstrips.
Get B-17 s in there and we can control
1,000 miles in any direction.
Goodnight.
- Maggie!
- Hello, sailor!
Pleasant surprise.
You're not easy to talk to on the phone,
so I decided to ambush you.
Come in.
- This is nice.
- Sit down.
- Can I offer you a drink?
- No, nothing. Thanks.
My unit is to report to Ford Island
in the morning at six.
We weren't told any more
but it can only mean one thing.
You'll be at sea by noon.
- Did you know I was going?
- I knew there was a convoy pulling out.
Any hint about our destination?
You know I can't say.
You'll be told after you sail.
- Is it a long way?
- Long way.
Then we won't meet again
in the foreseeable future, right?
Right.
Do you think we'd better let it go at that?
- Hello?
- Commander Powell.
Just a moment.
For you.
- Commander Powell speaking.
- Egan?
- Can you bunk out tonight?
- I can manage.
Thanks, Egan.
Maggie?
Yes, Rock.
Permission to board, sir?
- State your business.
- Cdr. Eddington. Toulebonne Base.
- I'd like to see Nurse Lt. Maggie Haynes.
- Permission granted.
Ahoy, there! Is this the admiral's harem?
Lieutenant Maggie Haynes!
- I'm here.
- Compliments of Capt. Rockwell Torrey.
Paul Eddington. I'll call you Maggie
because that's what the Rock said.
"Make sure Maggie's welcome
when she gets to Toulebonne," so...
Welcome, Maggie Haynes.
It's beautiful.
There's a bottle of cognac
under the bananas.
I know how dry
these naval transports can get.
Will you excuse me?
Soyez la bienvenue.
This is Annalee Dorne.
- Hi.
- You've been here a long time.
- Since January.
Getting this old French base
ready to service our ships.
You have a barracks for 50 nurses?
We've been on this tub three weeks.
- Didn't you get the word?
- No.
This convoy sails again tonight,
300 miles to an island named Gavabutu.
- That's where they'll need nurses.
- An offensive?
I guess so.
- Are you also going to Gavabutu?
- No!
The Navy can't do without me here,
the island might sink!
You don't like what you're doing?
It's like working in a filling station,
watching the cars go by.
Goodbye, Maggie Haynes.
When you write to the Rock,
tell him I was sober.
He won't believe it, but tell him anyway.
Bye, Commander.
Control...? Station 26.
I have him.
PBY approaching from south-west.
- Roger 26. Patrol plane off course.
- Hi.
- Spotter 26.
- 26.
Formation north-east of your station.
Should be F4Fs.
Check, Control.
Three F4Fs proceeding north-east...
...to south-west.
- Roger, 26.
- You read those planes pretty quickly.
- At first I couldn't tell them apart.
How are you?
There's no way to make this easy,
Mrs McConnel.
I came to tell you
that your husband is missing in action.
You won't get the official telegram
for a day or two.
I read it in a report this morning and...
Ask Control to relieve you.
I'll take you home.
I'm all right.
Where did it happen?
His destroyer was working alone
in the Gavabutu area.
Reported two aerial torpedo hits,
then communications were cut off.
An aerial search the following day
failed to produce anything.
- No survivors at all?
- None reported.
Station 26.
- Are you there, 26?
- 26.
We have a bogey on the screen
to the south. Can you see it?
AT-6, about 9,000 feet.
- Are you there, 26?
- AT-6, Control.
Those damn training planes
wander around like bats.
OK, 26. Over and out.
Thanks.
Captain, was Mac wasted?
Wasted? What do you mean?
I want to read you
part of a letter from Mac.
"We are getting hell from Jap planes
that are based right on Gavabutu.
"I don't know much
about amphibious operations,
"but if Admiral Broderick knows anything,
I'll eat my hat.
"This has been a mess
since it began..."
I'm surprised that Mac
would put that in a letter.
He wouldn't have,
unless he were discouraged and angry.
Beverly, don't show that letter to anyone.
I don't intend to... Is it true?
If it is, if things are that bad,
I'm sure there'll be some changes.
Aren't they that bad, Captain?
Yes, I believe they are.
Station 26.
- 26, Control.
- Check plane to north-east.
Check, Control.
Small training plane
moving north-east to south-west...
- Message from CinCPac.
- What is it?
You're requested to appear
at 10 Makalapa for dinner.
Early, sir. 1800.
- You'll just have time to change.
- OK, Simpson.
Take me home.
Gentlemen, we'll get to
the business of the evening.
I could have saved time and liquor
by doing this in my office,
but it needs a little ceremony.
Powell, you got that dispatch?
From Chief of Naval Personnel
to Capt. Rockwell Torrey.
You are advised that the President
has approved your advancement
to temporary grade of Rear Admiral,
lower half, date 1 August 1942.
In regards to promotion,
physical examination...
...acceptance of appointment,
and so forth.
This came about, Admiral Torrey,
because that civilian next to you
wormed his way into my staff
and had the audacity to suggest
the Navy was wrong in judging you.
Well, we all know
the Navy's never wrong, but...
...in this case,
it was a little weak on being right.
- So, congratulations, Admiral Torrey.
- Thank you, sir.
- Powell, you can do the honours.
Gentlemen, to Admiral Rockwell Torrey.
- May success follow your flag.
- Hear, hear!
I do thank you and I'm grateful.
With your permission, sir.
To our country, our Navy,
and all the best things they stand for.
Hear, hear!
Admiral Torrey,
when the congratulations peter out,
please join Cdr. Powell
and me in my study.
- Gentlemen, I'll see y'all later.
- Goodnight.
Congratulations, Rock...
We gave him the molasses,
now let's feed him the sulphur.
Admiral...
...know what that is?
Yes, from the shape of those islands.
This is Gavabutu, Levu-Vana,
Toko-Rota and Pala Passage.
It's Skýhook.
Powell says you guessed
the strategy months ago.
- A wild guess, sir.
- Wild, but accurate.
- What's your opinion of it?
- In theory, good.
In fact?
Delay has cost you the surprise element.
How far has Broderick
advanced on Gavabutu?
He's bottled up behind these mountains.
Hasn't advanced an inch in four weeks.
He'd better take that whole island
or you can forget Skýhook.
He's got to attack Levu-Vana
before the Japs are ready.
You just named your own poison.
You're going to mop up Gavabutu
and mount the invasion of Levu-Vana.
How about Admiral Broderick, sir?
Some smart man once said
that on the most exalted throne
we are seated on nothing
but our own arse.
With Broderick, I'm on mine.
I can't fire him,
scramble his whole command overnight.
He's bad for our allies,
a comfort to the enemy.
All I can do is put you
in tactical command of the operation.
Abe Lincoln was once in the same spot
with George B McClellan.
McClellan was a great organiser
but he couldn't decide when to fight.
Indecision is a virus
that can run through an army
and destroy its will to win,
or even to survive.
Lincoln called in a Yankee named Grant
who didn't care about organisation
but wasn't afflicted with the virus.
He pointed his battalions
in the right direction and shoved off.
Torrey, you're going to be my Grant.
How you deal with Broderick
is your business. Just get the job done.
How far can I go with Admiral Broderick?
You can't kill him.
- May I name my own chief of staff?
- Who?
- Eddington, my old exec.
- I'll attend to it.
Take Powell with you, he's familiar
with Broderick and I want rid of him.
- Reserve officers give me hay fever.
- Thank you.
Torrey, these were my stars
before I picked up this heavy hardware.
I like to think they brought me luck.
Wear 'em on your collar.
If there's any luck in 'em,
you're gonna need it.
Thank you, sir.
Saree?