Halt! Where are you going?
Go on! Move along!
No!
Belorussians!
Each of you has a mission
to assist in the reconstruction
of your region.
You must be aware
that this cannot be accomplished
without support from the Germans.
Any resistance to German orders
will be considered sabotage,
in the same way as
incitement to riot.
There are still individuals
who do not understand
the path to follow.
These partisans
who attacked the German Wehrmacht
shall be justly punished.
Look at what happens
to enemies of the German Reich.
Do not support the partisans.
Their situation is hopeless.
All those who rally with the partisans
will meet the same fate.
Now is the time for grand solutions.
Take an active part
in the reconstruction
of the Belorussian state
for the Belorussian people.
Hang them!
IN THE FOG
from the novel by Vassil BYKOV
Come on!
Damn!
Don't just stay there!
Move on. It's not very deep.
The last thing I need!
What a pain!
See it?
Over there.
I see it.
We'll wait.
We'll go at nightfall.
You think he expects us?
Probably not.
Maybe he ran off already.
To join the German police.
Wait here.
Anything wrong,
I'll shoot.
Don't be long.
I won't be. Not long.
Nice little paws...
We need to give her eyes,
then some ears.
Pointed ears, like a fox.
What do we call her?
Belka.
We'll make her little ears
very pointy.
Hello.
Look at the horse that my daddy made.
It's a nice horse.
He also made me this doggy with a tail.
With a tail?
That's nice.
What's your name?
Grisha. My father is Sushenya.
So you're Grigorij Sushenya.
How's life?
Sit down, don't stand.
I didn't recognize you.
You've changed.
You seem different, too.
My friend plays with a bullet.
Really?
That's not for children to play with.
It's not a real cartridge,
only the casing.
The casing...
I've really come for you, Sushenya.
Where's your wife?
Milking the cow.
I heated up bathwater.
We were going to wash up.
To wash...
That's nice.
I knew you would come.
You did?
That's good.
You recognize your guilt.
There's nothing to recognize.
I am guilty of nothing.
That's the thing.
Nothing?
Nothing.
And those men?
The ones that were hanged?
They were hanged.
Hello.
Hello...
Anelya.
Well...
I'll prepare some food.
You must be hungry.
There's no time, Anelya.
Do you have cloth wraps
for my feet?
Mine need replacing.
Your mother, is she still alive?
She died.
Six months ago.
And your sister Nyura?
She's dead, too.
Killed last spring
in Lisichansky forest.
Let's have a drink.
No.
I don't want to.
What a pity.
I will.
May I?
Go on.
But make it quick.
This is not what people do.
And it's just not true.
It's not true!
What's not true?
We didn't wish this. We didn't want it!
I was so afraid when they arrested him.
I couldn't sleep.
I cried my eyes out.
Then they released him.
And what were we to do then?
He didn't ask for any of this!
He didn't do anything wrong to them.
He tried to protect them!
But they were hanged.
And he was freed.
Why?
Who knows why!
No.
There's a reason.
Go on, Anelya.
There's nothing to discuss.
It's fate.
Come on, let's go.
Where are you taking him?
I must go. Not for long.
Don't cry. Calm down.
We have...
something to take care of.
- He'll be back soon.
- That's right.
Fine but it's still...
Why not take something with you?
At least take some lard.
You need something to eat.
Don't leave without food.
- Let me give you an onion.
- No, it's okay.
You like onion with lard.
Go ahead and take it, if you like it.
Fine, give me one.
Everything tastes better with onion.
Especially lard.
It will be good with a drink.
In case I'm late, wash up without me.
Which way?
Over there.
Should I take a shovel?
Yes.
Go on.
You know what happens.
If you betray...
I betrayed no one!
- Then who did it?
- I don't know.
You were freed, right?
Yes, those bastards.
I wish they would have hanged me.
Move along!
How could you, brothers?
This river floods in springtime.
It's like a swamp.
What were you expecting? Sand?
Well, not this.
Sand would be better.
You might face this someday, too.
Sand?
Fine.
Let's move on.
There's sand amongst the pines.
There's higher ground up ahead.
Go on, move!
Stop.
So?
As good a place as any, right?
For any occasion.
Occasion?
If you had told me...
Anything can happen in this kind of war.
- This is savagery!
- Shut up!
Voitik, stand guard over there
while we take care of this.
Go.
It would be better
not to tell Anelya about this.
About what?
That you shot me.
Tell her the Germans killed me.
Of course, later,
she'll find out.
Keep digging...
We'll see.
Maybe that's enough.
It will take too long to fill it back up.
Do it, as a favor to me.
This coat...
You must give it to Anelya.
Your coat?
Fine.
I'll take care of it.
It's a good coat.
She's not likely
to find one like it.
A widow...
Voitik, is that you?
Don't move!
Halt!
Missed!
Stop, bastard!
Take him from the right!
Are you alive?
Where are you wounded?
What? What do you want?
Where...
Where are you taking me?
I don't know.
Voitik...
I'm not Voitik. I'm Sushenya.
L...
am...
hurt badly?
Who knows.
But you were shot.
And I didn't
kill you in time.
No time.
The police appeared suddenly
out of nowhere.
Take me to Zubrovka.
I must go to Zubrovka.
Over there,
look for Kienya.
Kienya? Fine.
Bu rov?
Comrade Voitik?
What happened to Burov?
Well...
they shot him.
This is what you get!
Into the barn!
What were you doing?
Nothing.
What are you plotting?
Nothing!
I didn't build this truck
with my own hands
so that those bastards could drive it!
Don't be foolish!
Haven't I had enough grief?
- Haven't I had enough?
- Go to sleep, Mother.
I know you're plotting.
You want justice!
I've suffered enough.
I'm sleeping.
You sleep?
I know how you sleep.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
deliver us from evil.
O Lord, Jesus Christ, deliver us
from evil and forgive us, our sins.
Lord have mercy. Lord have mercy.
Save and protect us. "
Aunt Anisya, is Kolya home?
- Is Kolya home?
- Don't shout. I'm not deaf.
You're dressed fancy!
Hello, Kolya.
What do you want?
Mikitionok sent me.
We need your help.
We can't manage
with that troublesome truck.
It won't start.
But you can get it running.
Come and give us a hand.
Mirokha, I once knocked
one of your teeth out.
And?
Looking at you now,
I should have knocked them all out.
You fool!
So?
Are you coming?
Get the hell out!
That's how you want it?
I could order you to do it.
You're asking for it.
Come closer and I'll spit in your face.
I've had it with you! Get out!
I'll get you one day! Count on it!
He's upset
because they took his truck.
I'll have your backs
to the wall someday!
You'll regret this, Kolya!
You were a fool before
and you're still a fool today.
Say I went to my aunt's.
Where are you going?
I'll hide out until this mess settles.
You shouldn't have done it.
Idiot...
I sent you to stand guard.
And you...
I did stand guard.
But they sneaked in from the other side.
The other side...
You're so sly.
Oh, yeah.
Sly. yourself!
Why did we go into the pines?
You really don't understand anything.
Where is Sushenya?
Sitting over there.
Don't harm him.
As you want.
What do I care?
What will the Commander say?
What do we do now?
Just sit here?
Wait to be shot like rabbits?
From where?
Babichi?
Probably.
There's no way I'll make it.
You can't carry me.
We need a cart.
If not, then he's...
Where are they shooting?
Who knows.
Over there.
Babichi?
Probably.
Stay here.
We'll go and find a cart.
Hurry and do your best.
Sushenya...
You know your way around here.
You know where a village is?
Babichi is over there.
Near the virgin woods.
- Near the gunfire?
- Yes.
Go and find a cart.
Wait.
I'll go.
You stay here.
Stand guard.
Give me my gun.
Your gun?
Here.
I'll try to be quick,
if it's not far.
Why didn't I...
kill you at the house?
If I had done it
there,
I wouldn't be dying now.
In my own home?
My boy was there.
The boy...
Yes...
And why...
haven't you escaped, Sushenya?
Escape to where?
To the Germans?
I've been with the Germans.
Here.
Look.
It was you...
You betrayed them,
those three men.
I betrayed no one.
Then why...
didn't they hang you
with the others?
If they had hanged me,
I would be grateful.
But no...
they freed me.
I thought they'd come back for me.
But no.
I sat at home for two weeks.
Where should I have gone?
Then little by little,
I began to understand
why they freed me.
They used me as bait.
You fell into their trap.
I was a rail road worker
for 13 years.
Surely you know that already.
I almost quit when the Germans arrived.
But the station master came by.
You must know Tereshkov.
He told us to go to work
or the Germans would kill him.
What could I do?
I went.
What a bastard!
He was a bastard under the Soviets, too.
His kind adapts to any regime.
If ever I cross him in a dark alley...
Bastard!
Give him a punch during inspection.
Surprise him!
That's it! And I'll say it was your idea.
I won't be alone before the firing squad.
That's it. Don't say a word.
Keep your mouth shut and take it.
Until the right moment comes.
The right moment?
Well...
We can loosen ajoint
and send everything flying.
We can do it on a curve.
Who is responsible for maintenance?
That bastard.
The Germans would execute him.
A joint, you said?
Good idea!
The Germans are not stupid.
They would figure it out.
They would discover
that the joint had been sabotaged.
Not at all!
When a train goes off the tracks,
not one joint will resist.
Everything is destroyed.
Remember last month?
Not far from the Lemeshev post,
there was an accident or some sabotage.
A total mess. Impossible to detect.
If anyone, the partisans
would be suspected.
Nothing to do with us.
We just do our job.
We go back, put away our tools,
and then go home.
Why suspect us?
And the nearby village?
If partisans are suspected,
they'll raze the village.
They'll shoot everyone.
All those innocents.
It has happened many times.
Which village?
Only a few old women there.
And are they not human beings?
You must not do this.
So you're afraid?
The train runs at night.
We won't even be there.
Or maybe he likes
being punched around.
Will you help us?
You must not do this.
You want to call the Germans?
Let's speak like friends,
with open hearts.
You seem like a reasonable person.
Yes.
And we want to help you.
Tomorrow, we will hang the others.
But we are offering you life.
Except...
Yes?
You will live.
Except...
You must sign a collaboration agreement.
What collaboration?
A secret collaboration, of course.
With the German authorities.
Then we'll organize your release.
You will return to your people,
the ones who dispatched you
on this mission.
We will stay in close contact.
Secretly, of course.
No.
You know...
I can't.
I can't do that.
What?
What did you say?
I can't do that.
Are you an idiot?
You're refusing to live?
You want to die?
Of course not, but...
Then sign the agreement.
We will take every precaution.
No one will suspect a thing.
I can't do it.
So...
you want to die.
The hanging is tomorrow.
Give it some thought.
You have until tomorrow.
Move it!
Let's go...
Not Sushenya.
Why not?
Get up.
Did you think about my proposal?
You still want to dangle from a rope
with your friends?
I mistook you for a clever fellow.
But you're an idiot.
You want a noble death?
Want everyone to honor your memory?
Want them to write pamphlets about you?
No...
That's not going to happen.
I will arrange another sort
of death for you.
For the last time:
Yes
or no?
I can't do it.
Fine.
You can't.
Get out of here.
Go away.
Go.
What could I do?
I envied them immediately.
Everyone honored them.
Their children were proud.
Neighbors helped their families.
But I was hated.
I sensed
that even the person who loved me most,
my wife Anelya,
no longer looked at me
like before.
One day, she burst into tears and said:
Hanging you would have been better!
I started to wonder
if I might even hang myself.
But even that...
People would say: "His guilty conscience.
He was a traitor.
How could I live like that, Kolya?
Kolya...
Do you hear me?
Kolyag
Don't forget to ask about the tobacco!
He promised.
I won't forget.
How is he?
He's resting. He has very high fever.
The guys asked about tobacco.
Halt!
Come here!
Where are you going?
Where are you from?
Where did you get this?
I don't know.
I stopped by some guy's house.
He gave it to me.
Where?
I don't know.
Take us there.
Damn!
You still here?
But him...
I knew it.
When?
Yesterday afternoon.
Well...
No need for a cart.
They're all there, waiting.
Since yesterday.
So?
There's no cart?
No cart.
The Germans are in Babichi.
The Germans?
So what now?
What now?
We hide the body and leave.
We might get through.
To go where?
Each goes his own way.
I'll go to my platoon.
You'll probably go back to the Germans.
I'm not going to the Germans.
Take me with you.
To my platoon?
Yeah, they're waiting for you.
We must take Burov.
We can't just leave him here.
Did you see all those crows?
But you carry him.
Yes, I will.
Understood.
Then get up.
You know where to go?
If we want to avoid Babichi,
then we must head left.
Lead the way.
Be careful!
Steer clear of Germans.
Where's that coming from?
The main road, I think.
The main road?
Yes.
Where are you taking us?
Where else can I go?
You said the Germans are in Babichi.
They are.
Then this is the only option.
We have to cross the main road.
What do we do now?
Do we cross?
We should wait
until the darkness of night.
That's along wait.
But it's better.
You knew each other well?
Since childhood.
We lived on the same street.
He was younger than me.
He always loved cars.
Yes...
That was his downfall.
And you, with him.
Him, maybe.
Mine was something else.
What?
That I didn't die back there,
in the police station. That's what.
Why the hurry to die?
Burov was in a hurry.
He couldn't wait.
His foolishness is to blame.
Yes...
He died too soon.
He was still young. A pity.
What do you care?
It was kind of my fault.
Except not at all.
I didn't Wish it.
I just didn't want to die in that swamp.
If you had,
Burov would still be alive.
Isn't that right?
Yes, probably.
You'll tell everything to your commander?
Tell what?
Everything about me.
If I don't make it.
After all, I have a wife,
a son..
Oh, that!
Yes, I'll tell them.
I better write it down.
Writing it would be good.
It would be documented.
You rely on documents?
Well, yes.
Maybe they'll sort it all out someday.
But they did enlist you, didn't they?
Go on, confess.
If Only!
But no.
They tried.
But I couldn't.
I just couldn't do it.
You really couldn't?
You must be lying!
You know that's impossible.
Not this situation.
We cause our own ruin,
but also our family's.
What kind of life would they have?
If they remained alive...
Anything can happen.
This is wartime, of course...
You refer to war,
how anything can happen...
But did everything change
in a year-and-a-half?
Do people really change so quickly?
Does war really transform us
to that extent?
I've lived here for 37 years.
Everyone knows me.
I was always respected.
I never had troubles with anyone.
So why not trust me anymore?
Why do we trust the Germans,
but no longer our neighbors?
No one believes me. Not you...
Not even my wife...
She has doubts.
Did I change?
How, if I was born with this character?
People can change a lot.
They are unstable by nature.
Especially if they want to survive.
Exactly.
If you want to live,
why choose to betray?
In the face of death,
everything looks the same.
But when you want to live,
you live with hope.
If not for yourself,
then maybe for your children.
Maybe they
will be lucky to survive.
So, you go first.
Wait for me on the other side.
Halt!
I suddenly saw him.
Damn it to hell!
No way I missed him!
- Where is he?
- Hold on.
There he is.
He has rifles.
- I knew he was a bandit.
- Is he dead?
Seems that way.
The holster...
It's empty.
So where's his pistol?
Search him.
Look at those boots.
Hurry UP...
Damn!
He's still alive.
Finish him and let's go.
Adaptation
Richard LORMAND, Maria BAKER
Subtitles TITRA FILM Paris