In 1980, a civil war erupted
in the small country
of El Salvador.
It began as a conflict
between the Salvadorean Army
and the peasants over land.
The peasants soon organized
and became the guerrilla army
known as the FMLN.
This conflict escalated
into a brutal civil war
that would last 12 years.
Cuscatanzingo was one of
the last villages trapped
between the guerilla
and the army
Here is where this story
takes place.
INNOCENT VOICES
BASED ON A TRUE STORY
I'm so thirsty...
...and my feet hurt.
I have rocks in my shoes.
They're going to kill
us for sure.
Why do they want to kill us
if we haven't done anything?
My dad left us and
went to the United States...
...when the war started.
Mom didn't come
out to say goodbye.
She said that now I was
the man of the house.
But first I had to pee.
Two wings.
Who could have two wings?
Two wings to fly.
This afternoon in the mountains,
I almost had them...
...and the desire to spread
them open over that sleepy ocean.
No, not me!
Fito help me!
Help me!
Let's go.
I'm home, Mom!
I'm sorry.
I had to walk Antonio
and Fito home.
Don't they have feet
to find their own way?
You know how
chicken they are.
Don't be late again.
These soldiers
aren't playing.
One day, God forbid, they'll grab
a rifle and shoot you.
You understand?
Yes, Mom.
Temo! Temo!
We were all scared
of turning 12...
...because that's
when the army takes you.
I had one year left.
You know, Ancha?
Me and you are alike.
We are!
We're both little.
-Yes, I'm little.
-Big.
In size, but not up here.
Ancha was my friend.
Everyone said he was
a fish brain.
Thank you, Anchita.
But he was the only one who
wasn't scared to have a birthday.
Good. God bless.
Hi, farty sister.
Where were you?
It's late.
-Take care of your brother and sister?
-Don't worry.
Rosita,
don't feed Ricardito
after eight, ok.
Even if he screams.
Why mommy?
I love you.
Take out the garbage.
And close the door, bolt it
and don't let anybody in.
-You're my man of the house.
-Yeah, right, the man of the house.
You don't even know
how to wipe your own butt.
Leave my brother alone!
Come and eat.
He fell asleep.
The mattresses, Chava!
I want my mommy!
Watch out, Chava!
Don't get up there!
Get under the bed!
Quick! Get under here!
Good night.
Grandma Mamatoya!
Mamatoya!
-Have you heard from Beto, mother?
-Nothing.
I haven't heard
from your brother...
...since they closed
the university.
Let's hope
he's alright.
We'd know if he wasn't.
Bad news travels fast.
He'll show up.
It was really bad
last night.
And the kids were
alone.
I have to quit my job.
And who's going
to support you?
Why don't you come
live here?
How can we, Mother.
There's not enough room.
I don't mean with me.
Refugio's house is empty.
That way I can keep
an eye on the kid's...
...and help with
their homework.
If we move,
he'll never find us.
Don't fool yourself.
Those who go North
get swept away.
Lift your head up, Kella.
Those who leave suffer more
than those who stay.
and those who stay fight.
Take these savings...
...and buy yourself a weapon.
Since Mom started
working at home,
the war didn't seem
so big.
Beto loves you a little
a lot or nothing at all.
Cecilia!
It's curfew, go home.
Just a little longer.
Angelita, don't worry
your grandma. Go inside.
Please, grandma, five minutes.
Tell her.
Bye.
You too, Chava.
One day, there they were.
The Gringos.
The same as they are
in the movies.
They said they were
here to help us.
Don Yeyo!
Spit that out, Chava.
-Don't you hear me? Spit it out.
-Why? It's yummy.
Because the men who
gave you that gum.
Are training our soldiers
to kills us.
Not so yummy anymore,
is it?
Angelita finished first
in her class...
...so her grandma is
taking her to the beach.
-But she's a dummy.
-What do you know?
Lots.
You wish.
-You too.
-Kids!
-You more.
Go to sleep.
Get on the floor!
Ricardito!
Get down!
Uncle Mario!
Dear God... why?
Why?
Why? What happened?
You drunk!
Wake up!
Go home shame on you.
-I'm going to tell your mom.
-Don't get mad, lady...
-...he'll get his cut.
-Drunks!
It's for the hangover.
What hangover?
Go home!
This time nothing sold.
I'm sorry, Chavita.
Are you trying
to steal it?
-What are you doing? Answer me!
Just playing.
-With whose permission?
-I need to work.
-You want my job?
-No.
Take it.
It's yours.
I got you, kid!
I got you!
Why do you like driving?
Because... you go lots
of places...
cruise the streets
and make lots of money.
Yeah, right.
-How old are you?
-11.
Let's see. Stand up.
11 months?
Hold on, hold on.
You want to work?
Here's the deal.
You call the stops,
I collect the fares and drive.
But if you rob me,
I'll cut your balls off. Shorty.
Downtown!
What happened with
the dresses?
Where did you get that?
I didn't sell anything,
but I got a job on the bus.
So you don't have
to work so much.
You should have
asked me first.
Can I?
Will you be careful?
And you'll be back
before curfew everyday.
I promise, ma.
-Where did you get the money?
-I got a job.
-I'm driver.
-Yeah, right.
Did you hear Miss Sol
had a nervous breakdown?
-Why?
-Because of all the shooting.
They say she's
in the nut house.
Chava!
The following
boys will form a line.
Pablo Argueta...
...Manuel Ayala...
...Antonio Gutiérrez...
...José Rendón...
...Alfredo Argueta...
...Mario Sánchez...
-What's your name?
-Temo.
-Temo what?
-Morales Morales.
-Get in line!
-He's only ten!
It's not fair!
How can you do this?!
-Temo! Temo!
-Sergeant!
Sergeant!
Mario Sánchez...
...Arturo Reyes...
...Gerber Reyes...
...Roberto Olsen...
Continue.
Roberto Olsen...
...Bardo Pérez...
...Agustin Reina.
Quickly!
You should feel proud,
boys.
You're going to be
soldiers like us.
You will defend
your country.
Sergeant...
...let's go.
Who gave the order
to do this?
Step aside, Father.
Worry about their souls.
Hi baby.
How was school?
Are you deaf?
What's wrong baby?
Tell me.
Did somebody hit you?
-Did the teacher punish you?
-They took Antonio.
-Antonio? Who took him?
-The soldiers.
They took him in a truck
with some other boys.
And they took Temo.
Temo?
To find the common
denominator...
...multiply these two numbers...
-3x4
-12
Very good.
YOU'RE UGLIER THAN A FROG.
CHAVA
If you like her so much,
go tell her.
Don't be a chicken.
Hi.
I wanted to know
if... maybe...
...if you can... and
if you want to...
...come play with Chele,
Marcos, Fito, Ancha and me.
We're going to fly
paper fireflies.
-Uglier than a frog?
-I didn't write that.
No?
Then who?
If you want, we can meet at
Dona Celia's at 4.
Okay.
-Let's go!
-Let's go, Chava!
-The paper fireflies were fun.
-Yeah.
Well... I have to go.
Bye.
Ancha! Lets go!
We were flying paper
fireflies...
...and they started shooting
and we had to run for it.
I'm going to show you some fireflies.
So you learn to be back early!
Sit down and eat.
Stinky girl!
Farty sister.
Sorry, ma.
Yuck...
...that really stinks.
Uncle Beto!
...so mom bought
a sewing machine.
She makes dresses
and I sell them.
And I give her my money
from the bus.
I collect fares
and call the stops.
Yeah? Show me.
Downtown! Downtown!
Downtown!
That's great, Munchkin.
And since mom keeps telling
me I'm the man of the house...
...I take care of my
brother and this one.
Yeah, right.
Especially me.
I'm glad you're
so responsible, munchkin.
Daddy!
Oh, this boy!
He calls every man "Daddy".
-What's your name, little boy?
-Ricardito.
Ricardito.
Mom is worried about you.
Don't disappear like
that again.
You're not in trouble,
are you?
My brother takes care
of me and one day...
...he bought me a cookie but
I dropped it and the ants ate it.
Chava, the mattress!
Chava, Rosita!
Under the bed.
Shhh, baby.
Angelita!
Angelita.
My God... Help!
Doña Amalia, it's Beto!
I'm coming!
-Beto! What are you doing?
-Angelita!
Angelita!
Get down, Chava!
Get down!
Baby?
Chava!
-What's happened?
-My girl.
I'm here with you,
don't be afraid.
Chava, press here.
Hard, okay?
Uncle Beto!
Kella!
Stay there! Don't move!
Angelita!
My girl, don't leave me!
-Angelita!
-Help me, please!
My girl is dying!
Don't leave me.
Angelita! Angelita!
-Angelita!
-Baby!
Baby!
Oh God!
Please help me!
Angelita!
My girl.
Dear God!
My girl!
dear God,
my girl has died.
What's happened?
Oh God, help me!
Don't cry, baby!
Don't play that Beto.
They'll kill us all.
How sad the rains sounds...
on the cardboard
rooftops.
How sad my people live...
in the cardboard houses.
Children the color
of my land...
with the same scars...
...bellies bloated with worms.
Look at the suffering.
The burden of
the suffering.
Above in the village...
he leaves his pregnant wife.
Below in the city...
he gets caught in it's web
The bullet that killed Angelita could
have come from the guerrilla.
How long have you been
involved?
For a while.
We're preparing an offensive
to disrupt the army, Kella.
This is the only place left between
the capital and the guerrilla.
And it's going to explode.
It's going to get
dangerous.
much worse.
Chava's about to turn 12.
We've got to get
him out of here.
Yes...
...your side also
take boys.
Morazán and San Vicente
are liberated areas.
He'd have a roof.
He'd have food.
We're building schools.
What he needs Beto...
...is to be here,
with me.
He's too little.
-lf you stayed here with us.
-Kella...
...you've got
to understand.
The army will take
him away.
At least with me,
he'd be safer.
Let me take him.
-Got a girlfriend?
Just one.
Just one?
-What's her name?
-Cristina María.
The new teacher's
daughter.
She's the prettiest
of all.
Listen, Chavita.
What I'm about to tell you
is very important.
So pay attention.
What happened to Angelita
are things that happen.
Chavita, I won't lie and say
things are going to get better...
...because they'll get worse
before they get better...
Understand?
This might help you understand
what's going on.
Look for "Radio Venceremos"
here.
It's the voice
of our people.
It's not always on,
so you have to keep looking.
But Chava, it's banned
so you have to be careful.
You can find the song
I played last night.
Did you like it?
-Ratón!
-Chavita!
Will I see you again,
uncle?
Next time I'll take you
with me.
At this moment we are
broadcasting...
Radio Venceremos, voice
of the guerrilla resistance...
What's your answer?
Hey, no!
And you?
I asked you first.
One.
Two
-Three!
Can we go out?
-Did you finish your homework?
-Yes.
Okay...
...but don't forget the curfew.
Take care of her, Chavita.
Let's go.
Don Yeyo!
Hey...
That's, Don Yeyo.
He won't talk to anyone
except to his animals.
Why?
Doesn't he like people?
This song is banned.
My mom says we have to fight
so that nothing is banned.
-You're really pretty.
-And you're uglier than a toad.
But I like you too.
Bastards!
-Good afternoon.
See you.
Let them go!
-Let them go!
Out of the way!
Move!
-Father!
-To what do I owe this miracle?
Are you okay?
Yes, Chava. Thank you.
The soldiers hit you
really hard.
There are worse pains
than this.
And the girls?
Did they recruit them too?
No.
Are they going
to kill them?
Here,
help me light
the candles.
Get out of the way!
Come on!
Are you crazy?!
I hate loudmouth women.
Didn't you see it was
running out of gas?
What?
Was I the one driving?
Can I?
You look like a bald girl.
What's wrong with
you baby?
What happened?!
We were working and
we ran out of gas...
...he started sucking gas
from the can with the hose...
...he swallowed half.
You irresponsible
old man!
Daddy!
Daddy, my ass!
Get out! Don't come
near my son again!
Get Out!
...in the cardboard houses...
Down comes the workman...
Turn it off. Turn it off!
Below in the city...
...he gets caught
in it's web.
That song is forbidden,
Father.
Nothing is forbidden
to God.
I must ask you
to turn it off.
Turn it off yourselves. But
leave your weapons here.
No one may enter the house
of the Lord with weapons.
Children the color
of my land...
What kind of crap
is in your head?
What did I do now?
Give me the radio.
Why?
I didn't do anything.
Don't lie to me.
I'm sorry, mom.
I didn't mean to.
I won't do it again.
I know you won't.
Because you're going to give
me that radio right now...
...I won't do it again.
I'm sorry.
Give me that radio.
For the last time,
give me that radio!
Don't just sit there sulking.
Help me, fussy.
And don't grunt. Your mother
knows what's best.
Why do you always
take her side?
There's only one
side here.
But you're very touchy,
Chava.
You hear something you
don't like and you run away.
So I can be with you.
But when you're
on your bus...
...you don't see
how bad it is.
And it's getting worse.
And you still don't know
how to take care of yourself.
So you have to obey.
-Can I ask you something?
-Of course.
-Do you pray?
-What do you mean, do I pray?
Do you pray for
the war to end?
Not for that.
This damn war will
never end with a prayer.
Never?
Who would like
to read their poem?
-Okay, Yanira?
-May I go to the bathroom?
Go out quietly
and don't take long.
Let's hear yours, Chele.
None of the kids in my
school want to fight.
They don't like war because
they want to play...
"Don't be sad about your radio,
Toad." Cristina María.
But when the soldiers come,
me and my friends will hide.
What's wrong, Yanira?
Chava!
Chava, get down!
Don't shoot!
There are kids
in the school!
No, son!
Chava! You're crazy!
Go back!
Chava!
Mommy!
You asshole.
You let them in the bell tower.
You son of a bitch.
That sniper killed
three of my soldiers.
Brothers,
there will be
no mass today.
But I want to speak
to you here,
on the street.
I want to speak
to everyone.
The word of Our Father
must also be heard...
...by those who have not yet
found grace within themselves.
What is grace?
Grace is the presence
of the Divine in every one...
...of our actions.
Look around you.
The faces of our children
have lost their innocent spirit.
In its place,
there is fear.
Because our children have
lost the hope to survive.
The skeptics say, if God
existed, there would be no war.
And I respond,
...if men would obey the word of
God, then there would be no war!
Because God, Our Father,
has given man the privilege
to live in grace...
or, on the contrary,
to provoke disgrace.
I assure you, when one
lives in the grace of God,
war does not exist.
Nevertheless,
there are those who...
...ignore their own
divine nature,
and they satisfy
themselves by robbing,
...humiliating and killing
their own kind!
Brothers, it is
the time to raise...
...our voices against
them.
To defend our right
to live!
To use our strength to
oppose the force of death.
Today, brothers,
it is not enough to pray.
They closed
the school for good.
Ancha hurry,
walk faster!
Because our village was
between the guerrilla...
...and the army...
...mom decided to move
us to the other side...
...of the river.
She said it was safer.
Grandma Mamatoya!
Boys!
No, Ancha. The table!
I like my new house.
Why did you change
the station?
Put on Radio Venceremos.
Fito! Shhh.
What's up shorty?
-When are you coming back to work?
-When I grow up!
Then you're never
coming back!
Where are you going?!
You're on! Let's go!
You're going to run
out of gas, shorty!
What's wrong little boy,
what's wrong...
-Shut up, boys!
-...they ask me at school...
...and at home
Now I know all of the sudden...
...when I heard roll call
and she was not there.
The girl with
the blue backpack...
...and sleepy eyes...
Got me very excited
and low grades.
Super bomb!
-Antonio!
-What's up?
-Where have you been?
-What are you doing here?
Just hanging around.
Look at me, like a monk.
Every day, more a hunk.
-Yeah, right.
-Who do you think you are?
Come on, let's play.
Do you know how
to skip stones?
When we arrived at the army base
we we're more than 40...
the majority 13
and 14 years old.
I was one of the youngest,
but I learned fast,
because our teacher was a Gringo
who had been in Vietnam.
He showed us how to shoot
and ambush.
Last week we ambushed some
guerrilla motherfuckers,
and I was the one who
caught them with this.
You guys are next.
They're recruiting
everybody.
Big ones...
...and little ones.
So... are you still a
bunch of chicken shits?
-I'm not a chicken shit!
-Me neither.
Fucking chicken shits.
Don't call us that.
You'll be pissing your pants
when they come to recruit you...
...like the chicken
shits that you are.
Chicken shits!
Chavitita!
Don't be scared.
It's me, Raton.
I heard shots last night.
Was it you guys?
-We cleaned out the area.
-And uncle Beto?
He sent a message.
The army is recruiting tomorrow.
Warn your friends.
Hide.
Okay drivers, you know what to do.
One under each door.
Let's go!
"Recruitment tomorrow"
Where are the boys,
lady?
I haven't seen them
since this morning!
Where are they?
-Sergeant, there are no boys!
-Keep searching!
8...
...9...
...10...
...11...
...12.
11.
Did we count right?
Chava is 11.
Happy birthday to you!
Chava!
Wait, Chava!
You run fast.
Here. Open it.
It's batteries
for your radio.
Toad.
Thanks.
"Recruitment tomorrow"
We've got a snitch.
Chava!
What happened?
Chava! Chava!
Father! Father!
They're going to kill Raton!
Help him!
They took
him to the river!
-Where's the priest?
-The soldiers took him yesterday.
Don Yeyo.
Chava! Did you know fat
Marcos left?
-Where?
-To join the guerrilla.
-When?
-I don't know.
-Chava!
-What?
Maybe we should go too?
-To join the guerrilla?
-Well, what else?
Let's count them.
Look at that one!
There's another one!
We would stay
there all night.
One time we counted
up to 230.000 stars.
I wanted to tell
Cristina Maria.
First I thought
I was on the wrong street.
That it wasn't her house.
Hey, kid!
Where are you going?
Let me go!
Chava! Chava!
I have reasons...
...to look for you,
I have the need to see you...
...to hear you, to talk to you.
I have reasons
to wait for you.
Because I don't believe...
...there is anyone
in the world I can love.
I have reasons,
more than enough reasons...
...to ask the wind to return
you even as a shadow.
I have reasons...
...to not want
to forget you.
Because that little
piece of happiness...
...it was you who
gave it to me.
-Chava, let's go.
-We know where to go.
Marco's mom said we have to get
to the Little Face Woods.
Turn off the light!
Shut up!
-Who else is with you?
-No one.
Shut up!
Follow me.
Sleep here. Tomorrow we'll
see what to do with you.
Chele, Chava!
Silence! No names here.
Lie down!
-Do you have anything to eat?
-Cookies.
Shut up!
Lie down and
go to sleep!
-Want one?
-Yes.
Hands on your heads!
Wake up!
What's wrong?
We've to go. The soldiers are coming.
They're burning everything down.
Grab their clothes!
Get dressed. Hurry!
-Where are we going?
-I don't know.
For now, into town
with everyone else. Let's go!
Baby, wake up.
-Where's your brother?
-I don't know.
-Where are we going, grandma?
-We have to leave.
-Chava!
-We have to hurry.
-Because of the bullets?
-Yes, because of the bullets.
Chava! Chava!
The Birth Certificates,
where are they?
Put yours and your
brothers clothes here.
His clothes are gone.
And his good shoes.
Where's my brother?
Let's go.
I'm so thirsty...
...and my feet hurt.
I have rocks in my shoe.
Take the sewing machine.
I'm going to look for him!
Soldier go home!
Your house is being burned
by a soldier like you.
Murderers! Murderers!
Chava!
Mommy?
Let's go away from here.
His documents are here.
I didn't want you to sell
your sewing machine.
Don't worry about us.
Promise me
you'll be strong.
-Promise
-I Promise.
-Bye, farty sister.
-See you.
Be careful.
Bye, brother! I'll miss you!
Take care of yourself!
Now I'll be the man
of the house.
I don't want to go
to the United States.
But if I stay,
they're going to kill me.
But I'm coming back...
because I promised mom,
I would get Ricardito out...
...before he turns 12.
This story could
have been told by Fito or Chele...
...or Cristina Maria.
But it was left up to me.
It's for them.
Chava escaped
to the United States...
...where,
with the help of many...
...he reunited with
his family 6 years later.
The civil war lasted
with more than 75,000 deaths,
and around one million exiles.
The United States government
sent troops to train...
the Salvadorean army
and over one billion dollars...
...in military support.
Today more than 300,000
children are recruited in armies...
around the world,
in more than 40 countries.