Western Poland, 1932
INVINCIBLE
(based on real-life events)
It was in a country far away.
I don't know which one.
But it was a distant land.
A prince lost his mind
and imagined himself...
- ...to be a rooster.
- A rooster? Like this one?
Yes. He took refuge
under the dining-room table...
...striped naked, and refused
to eat anything but grain.
- And then?
- The King called in magicians and doctors...
...to cure his son,
but to no avail.
One day, an unknown sage
arrived, took off his clothes...
...and joined the prince under the table,
saying he too was a rooster.
Eventually, the sage convinced
the prince to get dressed.
And finally to sit down and eat
with the others. "Don't ever think"...
...said the sage, "...that by
eating like...
...a man, with other|men at the table...
...a rooster ceases to
be what he is."
"You can do anything with...
...men in their world.
Or even for them."
"And yet remain the
rooster that your are."
I'm so proud of you, Benjamin.
Such young little fellow, and
brighter than all the adults.
Guess what?
I have some money.
How would you like to
eat in a restaurant?
A restaurant?
Really?
What do you think
about her and me, huh?
- You'd be fine.
- Yeah, it's true!
Miss? Miss!
She has nice tits,
and a fine ass.
- I wouldn't say no to sleeping with her.
- Miss!
Miss, miss!
Hey, miss! Where the hell are
the...
...girls in this stinking
place, huh?
Could I have another one, please?
Hey, fatty!
You should watch your weight.
Or soon you'll be wider than
you're tall. Like a potato.
Like a stuffed pig!
Hey, fatty!
What's your name?
He's not fat!
He's my brother and he's strong.
I'm a blacksmith. My name
is Zishe. Zishe Breitbart.
Hey, fatty!
I'm talking to you.
Our fatty is a jew.
A big fat jew.
A fat one, and a thin one.
The fat jew eats too much,
and the thin jew not enough.
Hey, fatty! Why doesn't...
...the little one
eat anything, huh?
You should eat more,
like your fat brother.
Good idea.
You're too thin.
- The thick and the thin...
- ...together through thick and thin.
- Open your mouth!
- And eat!
Hey!
You will pay me for this!
Have you an idea...
... how much beer that was?
One hectolitre.
And do you know how much a barrel costs?
And how much that table costs?
It wasn't his fault,
the others started it!
As for the money,
I'd like to pay.
Yes, we'd really like to pay for
this, but we don't have any money.
What I should do
is call the police.
But I think there's a way
for you to pay for the damage.
The circus is in town.
Outside, by the gate.
There's a famous "strongman".
And there's prize money to be won...
...for the man who can beat him!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
dear children!
I would like to announce that our
Hercules has a challenger!
A strong young man, without doubt.
But in more than 20 years...
...our Hercules,
our Colossus of Rhodes...
...has never been defeated.
For years we have been
raising the prize...
...to the amount of 5.000 Zloty
for any man...
...who proves himself stronger.
Not without reason...
...the ancients have proclaimed
the Colossus of Rhodes...
...one of the 7
Wonders of the World!
And now, highly esteemed audience...
...his challenger this evening:
Zishe Breitbart!
Blacksmith from this town.
I can do more!
Yitzak, come! There's a visitor.
A real gentleman.
- What does he want?
- I don't know. He arrived in a motorcar.
And, oh my God, I have
nothing to offer him.
Landwehr. Alfred Landwehr.
Pleased to meet you,
Mr. Breitbart.
And this is your strong son.
- Please! Sit down!
- Thank you.
I'm an agent for variety artists.
Dancers, chucklers, magicians.
Everything that is in demand.
And the demand in Berlin is enormous.
I possess an instinct for
great talents.
For people who will go
straight to the top.
I was at the circus yesterday to
see the local strongman, when your son--
You need not go on.
We are respectable people.
For a jew this is not
the right thing.
But the most gifted people
in cinema, in theatre and art are.
I never even thought about leaving.
I belong in this smithy...
- ...in our little Shtetl.
- You see, our jewish Shtetls...
...are like holy
books, open...
...to the eyes of God. And the
Day of the Torment...
...even the fish tremble
in the brook.
In spring, during Passover,
the trees rejoice.
Sir... you're like a shopkeeper,
with empty shelves.
With nothing to sell.
Son... you'll have
to attend university!
You've said that beautifully...
...really.
Do you know how old the
boy is? 9!
This little fellow
is just 9 years old.
And to think that this
is my brother, Benjamin.
Look at what an incredible
boy my brother is.
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.
Are you all right?
- Yes, thank you.
- Fine! Me too.
Good morning, Mr. Landwehr!
We've just been talking about you.
Did you sleep in the motorcar?
There isn't even a hotel
around here to spend the night.
- Good morning. Mornin'. Mornin'.
- You are an exceptional man.
I am, when i'm after
an exceptional talent.
Zishe, listen!
I want you to come with
me just for the day!
I have something to show you.
- But i can't leave. I must work.
- Your father...
...would excuse you
for an afternoon, huh?
My son is able to make up his
own mind...
...about such things.
You'll be most interested to see
what i'm going to show you.
Look Zishe, look
at all the motorcars!
There must be every motorcar
in the whole world...
...right in Berlin!
More than motorcars, young man.
Watch what's coming.
That's a flying machine!
I've read about it.
Look at how many
people it can carry.
Aeroplanes will never compete
against that.
Benjamin!
- Benjamin, wake up!
- I am awake!
- I've been thinking.
- So have I.
Do you believe God gives to
each of us a gift?
Of course.
God made me strong,
Benjamin. Don't you think...
...that he made me strong
for a reason?
A blacksmith needs to be strong.
But I am stronger than a
blacksmith needs to be.
Sometimes we don't understand
why God does what He does.
This is what I must find out.
- Zishe?
- What? Tell me.
The Book of Prophets says:
"Spare me...
...that i may recover strength,
before i go hence...
...and be no more.
And be no more."
- And?
- And, what?
- What do you think about it?
- About what?
Berlin.
Let me talk to the
Rabbi first.
But before anything, we have to
celebrate Passover.
But...
Children, when we fled Egypt,
we didn't...
...have time for the
bread to rise.
Hannah? What happened
when we came to the sea?
- Hashem opened the seas.
- Yes, he did!
And, Raffael? How many
years did we stay in the desert?
Forty.
Yes. All right.
- Search for it!
- Yes!
Where is it?
It must be somewhere.
Maybe under the pillow.
Hannele found it!
- Wonderful!
- Hannele found it!
- She has found it.
- Very well!
Wonderful!
- How much do you want for it?
- 6 Zloty.
No, that's too much!
Yes...
- 6!
- Yes.
I want to thank the Allmighty
for my good wife, and my children.
You are the salt of earth.
And you fill my heart with joy.
Today, I want to thank
God in particular...
...for my strong firstborn.
Zishe, my son! You will
go out into the World...
...but don't ever forget
who you are!
Hold on! Hold on!
I've travelled very far. I've been as
far as Vilna. But a thing like this...
...a thing like this i've
never seen before.
Can you give me a ride?
- Where can we take you?
- You're not going to Berlin, by any chance?
- Are you hungry?
- All the time.
My mother has never been
able to feed me enough.
And you want to walk
all the way to Berlin?
Yes. I have a ticket for
the train, first class.
But i'm going to return the ticket, and
my mother will get a new dress instead.
I've heard there are
many pretty girls in Berlin.
Girls like you won't find in
the country. Maybe you'll meet one.
I have already, sort of.
In a dream.
But I couldn't see her face, because...
I know it sounds strange...
...but there was so much light.
I think she was a princess.
You didn't come specially for me?
How did you know?
Your reputation is
faster than your feet.
My name is Delilah.
Better take care, Samson!
Berlin, May 1932
It's me, Zishe!
Zishe Breitbart!
You want to talk to Mr. Landwehr?
Are you still there?
Hello? Hello?
- Speak please.
- What?
- Please speak.
- Yes!
- Where are you?
- In Berlin.
Come and see us at once.
Mr. Landwehr...
...is expecting you. We
thought you were lost.
A girl you say.
And she wanted to marry
you at once?
Well, actually no.
She just wanted to keep me.
Don't just stand there,
have a seat.
Thank you.
You realize, that the possibilities
to employ you are...
- ...somewhat limited.
- Yes? What do you mean by that?
No, no, don't be afraid!
I'm good at the work i do.
The best, if i may say so.
I'm going to employ you in an
establishment called...
..."Hanussen's Palace
of the Occult".
I don't quite understand.
What am i supposed to do there?
I've talked to Hanussen, and he
was immediately pleased with my idea.
Hanussen has understood something
about the insecurity of our times.
Inflation, unemployment,
mass strikes...
...attempted coups, bank rushes.
People long for a
strong man, a leader.
And Hanussen is the clairvoyant,
the prophet of this longing.
And what does that have
to do with me?
I can tell you! You will be
a kind of contrasting program:
The strenght of the body,
against the...
...dark powers of the
spirit of the occult.
And i have to point out to you
right now that you...
...must play a certain game.
I can't do that.
I'm strong, that's all.
I don't demand anything else from you.
And furthermore, you'll keep your mouth shut!
I'll meet with tomorrow
at Hanussen's.
Dismissed!
PALACE OF THE OCCULT
No, impossible!
What if he carries a weapon,
pearhaps a spear?
No, he shouldn't look like
some primitive man.
Someone from primordial times.
That's my demand.
Take it off!
Take it off! I hope you're all
in for the dark instincts.
How about a Greek or a Roman?
You know, a gladiator?
Turn! Turn around!
Pearhaps for the first act.
After the break
he can be dressed as...
...some kind of
heroic figure.
How's "Zishe, The Strong"?
By no means! The jewish name
must go at once!
You see, my boy... my public
consists of film stars.
Above all, followers
of the National Socialists.
Big shots of the party.
We will aryanize you.
A jew should never
be as strong as you.
The new act!
- Yes, i'm the strong man.
- I'm the magician here.
You don't look like a magician.
Oh, indeed?
Well, then watch!
Don't be deceived.
The ace may seem like the ace.
And the queen may seem like the queen.
But the truth here is always...
...what one does not see.
If you want to see the place,
i can show you around.
Follow me, but quiet.
This is Hanussen's
"Circle of the Occult".
No, performers really
shouldn't be here.
Hanussen doesn't like it.
Place your hands in the light.
Make contact with one another.
Feel the energy surge
through you.
I am... your clairvoyant.
I see your future.
Excuse me!
My name is...
Actually, I wanted to tell you...
...you are the most...
Ladies and Gentlemen!
I'd like to welcome you...
...with all my heart to a new
spring and summer...
...program at Hanussen's...
...Palace of the Occult.
Now we shall begin with someone
all of you are certainly familiar with.
Herr Rothschild, the banker!
Trying to run off with
the profits of the Great War.
The laughter backstage
is not permitted! If...
...anyone laughs, it'd better be
the audience, do you understand me?
Yes. I understand.
Wig!
Put your wig on!
- Put it on! Quickly!
- And now, Ladies and Gentlemen!
Helmet!
A novelty in our program. A man
of monstrous physical strenght.
The victor of all
roman gladiators.
I give you: Siegfried!
Out!
After the great battle against...
...the Cimbers and
Teutons, Siegfried...
...was taken to the
roman arena as a prisoner.
They put him in chains.
But chains could not hold him.
Ladies and Gentlemen:
Siegfried, the Aryan King!
Siegfried won every fight.
He took the cuirass...
...from the strongest
of all defeated gladiators.
And from Varus, he took
not only his...
...head, but his heirlooms.
And now Ladies and Gentlemen,
the man who...
...is in league with
the powers of the occult.
The Master of the abysses of
the soul, whose power over the...
...soul itself is able to
achieve unbelievable things.
The man who is endowed
with more power..
...than the strongest body could
ever possess: Erik Jan Hanussen!
Venerable audience:
You are familiar with the
phenomenon which i myself...
...cannot fully explain.
I have been endowed with
a misterious gift.
Retracting the aura
of the cosmos...
...and transmitting its rays back to
people who are gifted... mediums.
And, are we not all in reality
endowed with a medial gift?
These rays of cosmic energy
are known as "Hypnosis".
And they manifest all
the power of the occult.
The unknown side of
the human psyche.
And it will prove to you that
all our german people...
...are full of unknown power.
A die will be cast.
- Four!
- Four. Table four. Is there?
Count Helldorf!
Good evening, Sir.
Good evening.
The Police Chief of Berlin!
May i ask your
enchanting companion...
...to come up on stage,
please?
Please.
- What is your name?
- Hedda Christianson.
- And i think i've seen you on the screen.
- Yes, I've done two talkies.
But I'm still a beginner.
The beginning of a
great carrier, no doubt!
Don't worry.
Just relax.
I'm now going to send
you into trance.
Count Helldorf, the most
charming of all...
...police chiefs, will be there
to keep an eye on you.
And some of our sturdiest
Stormtroopers...
...in Berlin will be
there to support him.
- Certainly!
- Always ready! To victory!
Focus on this object.
And listen to my voice.
Follow my voice.
My voice is leading you.
Keep your eyes fixed,
watch this object.
Focus your eyes.
The power of the whole people...
...will concentrate in you.
Your legs are getting heavy.
Very heavy.
Your arms are getting heavy.
Heavier and heavier...
Your eyelids are
getting heavy.
Very heavy...
You feel sleepy.
You feel tired.
Very tired...
You want to sleep.
Your eyes are closing.
Your eyelids are becoming heavier.
And heavier.
Your eyes are closing.
And you feel sleepy.
Tired. Very tired.
You want to sleep.
Let yourself sink. You're sinking
deeper and deeper.
To the bottom of a
bottomless lake.
You are asleep.
I now place a coin
on the back of her hand.
I invoke all black powers
from the blackest abyss.
The coin on your hand
is growing hot.
Very hot.
You feel your hand getting
hotter... and hotter.
Yet you feel no pain.
No pain.
The coin is burning now.
Your hand is being burned.
Yet you feel no pain.
No pain.
Listen to my voice.
I'm now going to wake you up.
I will count to three.
When i count to three,
you will awake.
You will feel well, very well.
And you will awake.
One. You feel your body
becoming lighter. And lighter.
Two. Let your body
drift up slowly...
...towards the surface
of the lake.
Three! You break the
surface of the water.
You open your eyes,
and you're awake.
You're awake.
You're strong.
You are feeling strong,
and you are feeling good.
Are you awake now?
Are you awake?
Yes.
- Where am I? What happened?
- Count Helldorf, Sir.
Can you please come up on stage
as a witness?
Will you please take
the coin from the back...
...of the hand of your
charming companion?
- What do you see now?
- Hedwig, my darling!
For God's Sake,
what has happened?
Please describe what you see.
A blister. A blister
from a burn.
- A big blister on her hand.
- Are you in pain?
No, not at all!
Come in.
Well?
Well, the cost--
The costume and all this.
What about it?
Marta... my darling!
Have you met our new strong man?
His name is Zishe.
Yes.
I have big plans for him.
- I've seen you before.
- Yes, backstage.
- No.
- Where then?
A dream.
- A dream?
- Yes, actually...
What i want to say is...
The costume... I don't feel
quite right as a Teuton.
Champagne!
Sit.
Sit!
Take a sip.
No, thank you.
Now listen! My boy!
You don't seem to
be quite clear yet.
We are entertainers.
We work for a sole employer.
And that is the public.
We give them what they want.
We articulate their colective dreams.
Now: if you still don't understand this
at the end of intermission...
...pearhaps we should send you
back to your little Shtetl.
In Poland.
I'm homesick.
I miss my brothers and sisters.
And working with my father.
I work here for a clairvoyant.
His name is Hanussen.
And he is a mystery to me.
I have the power to radiate
energy onto you.
You feel pulled.
Something is drawing you.
You're sinking. Sinking.
Sinking...
What the power of the body can
achieve, Ladies and Gentlemen...
...the power of the spirit
can also achieve.
And more, much more.
The frail body of
our pianist is...
...able to perform far
greater things...
...Ladies and Gentlemen.
Just as our people...
...are capable of developing
unimaginable powers.
They merely need to be led.
And, like a cosmic event,
like a comet in the sky...
...a figure of light has
come among us.
And this force, which will
crush all foreign vermin...
...has a name: Adolf Hitler.
He will. I see it, i see it
clearly before my eyes.
One day he will lead
our thirsting people.
I am the seer.
I am the prophet of his coming.
To victory!
The flag up high...
...the troops tight together!
SA marches with firm...
...and calm steps!
To victory! To victory!
So lively, so early
in the morning?
I am, you see... possibly
in the wrong place.
Marta, leave us for a moment.
I'll call you when i need you.
- Something on your mind?
- You see, the audience...
I don't feel right
with the audience.
Pearhaps i'm just too jewish.
I understand you
better than you think.
Really?
We are alike, you and i.
Yes.
We are showmen.
We provide the...
...bewildered a beacon of light.
The audience doesn't seem
very bewildered to me.
There are a lot of those
nazis out there...
...who seem to know exactly
where they are going.
And i am their prophet.
You know, my boy, what
my dream is?
Something... much
grander than this.
And i've already found it.
I want to be to the present
what the...
...Oracle of Delphi
was to antiquety.
High ranking party
members have..
...already intimated to me
that I will be the Minister...
...of the Occult in
Hitler's future cabinet.
I have just awakened the barbaric
prehistoric demons...
...to a new godless life.
Look, I am not particularly
religious...
...but in my family
there is God.
If there is such a
thing as God...
...then he dwells here.
And this God protects me.
Gives me power.
Do you want to see what
real power is? Marta!
Marta!
Sing!
- Which song?
- The one about chandelier.
"As long as my panties
are hanging...
...in the chandelier
come morning...
...you can be sure that
i still love you."
Now the proof.
Turn around.
Look, my boy.
The roundest butt on
God's wide earth.
And it's mine.
All mine.
EXIT
I didn't want to disturb you.
I'm sorry.
You're not disturbing me at all.
Please, stay.
That was really won--
Wonderful.
Why don't you sit
down next to me?
I don't know anything about music.
Tell me, where did you learn all this?
I thought you were a princess when
I first heard you play. Tell me.
I studied at the Conservatory,
in Prague.
You see, i had high hopes then.
And i've never really
given them up.
And why are you here?
The reason is that
i'm a stateless person.
Do you know what that means?
As a child they kept pushing
me around between three countries.
I never knew my parents.
And when Hanussen was in Prague...
- ...he took me away with him.
- He was in Prague?
Yes, in Prague. And he gave me
work with his Palace Orchestra.
I'm sure you have noticed that
he doesn't treat me well.
Ye. Yes, i've noticed that.
But i stay with him all the same.
Well, yes.
Why am i still with him?
Miss Marta, I want you to...
I am...
Zishe, I know what you mean.
Your music...
It's so beautiful when you play.
- You see, I have a dream.
- Can you tell me what it is?
Someday I'd like to play
Beethoven's Third Piano Concerto.
With a full orchestra
to accompany me.
I would give anything for that.
I have a vision deep inside.
Come with me.
I'll show you.