MERRIMETTE: A story.
A man has a lot of choices.
And these choices made in
life are rarely perfect.
So he decides to sign a contract
'cause he wants to
make a difference.
He wants to save this world,
make it a better place.
But when that contract is signed,
he will no longer choose
when he wants to eat,
sleep, fuck or fight.
Those decisions
will be made for him.
He will be part of something
bigger than himself.
He will train for
70 consecutive days
and get to know every inch
of his M16A4 rifle
better than his own dick.
Then, he will go to
the desert and fight.
And die.
Why is he fighting?
Why is he dying?
What's the fucking point?
(EXPLOSION)
(GUN FIRING)
MARINE 1: Go, go, go!
On your .50 Cal, now!
Go! Go!
Watch it, watch your back.
Take cover!
Take cover! Take cover!
(FEEDBACK)
Tiger one-seven!
This is P.B. Cobra
requesting
immediate fire mission
in the same vicinity
of my last grid.
MARINE DISPATCH: Confirming grid 8-8-3-7-6-5.
More ammo!
We gotta get this stuff outta
here so we can get the hell out.
Let's go, hustle,
get this unloaded.
This is crazy, man.
For fuck's sake,
go get that truck unloaded!
Right away, Staff Sergeant!
DICKSON: Let's go! Let's go!
Move it! Move it!
(FIRING)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Watch out! Watch out!
(GROANS)
Kett, give me.
Merrimette, you can carry
more than one!
Let's go!
Dickson,
we need some more 5-5-6!
Merrimette,
bring down that 5-5-6!
Go! Go, go, go!
Danni, grab me the ammo!
Hey, yo! What do you need?
MERRIMETTE: I need, uh, 5-5-6.
Here you go. You got it?
MARINE: Get the ridge!
Get the ridge again! Again!
You guys doin'
all right down there?
I don't know, man.
It's crazy. Thanks!
(GRUNTS)
Come on. Here you go.
How much more is left?
A shitload, Staff Sergeant!
DICKSON: Hurry up!
I'm on it.
Is every bad guy
in the world in our face?
Let's go! Let's go!
Staff Sergeant! Request
permission to get some!
That's a negative, Corporal.
You wanna provide support,
then fly and get in
that truck and unload
the rest of that
goddamned toilet paper.
These boys may need
to drop a deuce
when that thing is done,
you got me?
Yes, sir!
(SCREAMING)
MARINE 1: RPGs!
DICKSON: (WAILING) Oh, God!
KETTNER: Man down!
Crap! My fucking leg!
MERRIMETTE: Sergeant!
DICKSON: Oh, God! My fucking leg!
My fucking leg!
MERRIMETTE: Sarge, Sarge.
Stop the bleeding.
My fucking leg. Everything's okay.
Corpsman!
Corpsman up!
My leg's all the way
over there, man.
Corpsman!
DICKSON: My fucking leg, man!
I'm gonna die.
Corpsman!
DICKSON: I'm gonna die.
Help me! God! No!
I'm gonna die.
MERRIMETTE: No, we're not
gonna let you die.
That's what's happening.
I'm here.
I'm with you, sir.
I'm sorry.
Come on, boys.
(MAN CALLING OUT
INDISTINCTLY)
(HOOTING)
Motherfucker.
Relax, bitches.
(WHOOPING)
(HOOTING CONTINUES)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
What up?
Hey, Li, what's up?
Aloha, boys.
Hey, guys.
Oh, what do we got?
A crown for the queen.
Ah, cute.
What, we both get both of them?
Doesn't matter, dude.
Oh, my God, what is that?
Pineapple juice?
Oh, that is disgusting.
No, I don't want that.
Give me something stronger douchebag.
I'll get you a bib.
Get the fuck outta
here with that shit.
Hey! Stop dickin' around.
Go escort Sergeant Dickson
to Mortuary Affairs.
Yeah, stop dickin' around.
He's talkin' to you, fool.
MARINE 1: He keeps takin' my cup.
You're just the man
I'm lookin' for. Sir.
MARINE 2: Like that hat.
Lovely lid, Li.
It's Luau Sunday, sir.
It's my party hat.
Well, carry on.
Yes, sir.
Walk with me.
Staff Sergeant
Dickson was a good man.
Yes, sir.
(GRUNTS)
Is this allowed, sir?
No. Jack Dickson.
Sit down.
Your wife,
she's expecting, yeah?
Yes, sir.
How far along is she?
Eight months, sir.
I'm afraid that's one delivery
you're gonna have to miss.
Yes, sir. I've been
there, I share your pain.
The things we do for the Corps.
Corporal, this job of ours, driving
trucks in heavily contested areas,
it's just about the most
dangerous job on the planet.
We lose good men and women
every day, don't we?
Yes, sir.
I expect you and your
people are wondering
who's gonna take over
as squad leader.
I haven't really had time
to think about it yet, sir.
Well, you better
give it some thought.
You're the new squad leader.
Major?
Congratulations. You just got
yourself another stripe.
Sir, maybe there's
someone else. I...
Come again?
Corporal Kettner. He's the same rank.
He's got more experience...
Corporal Kettner's
an exemplary marine.
He made the short list
but you drew the long straw.
Sir, it's just that this is my
third deployment in four years.
After it's over,
my contract's up.
I'm not sure if I'm
going to re-up, sir.
(SCOFFS)
Is my beloved Corps not living
up to your expectations?
It's a big decision
and my wife and I,
we haven't made up
our minds yet.
Well, I've been there, too.
Just the way I felt
after my third deployment
and hey, look at me now.
How about this, Corporal?
You're taking over
the squad. That's a fact.
But, if and when you wanna
walk away from this,
there's no reason you shouldn't
walk away as a sergeant.
Can you live with that?
Yes, sir.
All right. You're dismissed.
You have a shower, some
grub, grab some sack time.
You leave on mission in the morning.
Yes, sir.
Corporal?
Sir?
Keep the faith. Semper Fi.
Semper Fi, sir.
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
ALLEN: No, no, no.
I'm out. I'm out.
(MEN SCREAMING INDISTINCTLY)
You don't feel like
staying out there?
No.
Grass skirts and desert camos
aren't really my look.
I don't know.
The right set of shoes, I
think you could pull it off.
(CHUCKLES) Ha.
Times like this, there's
only one place I wanna be.
Go call her.
Have fun.
Wish me luck.
Ain't happening, Soto. Keep your
dick away from me. Shut it, Li.
(TYPING)
HEATHER: Hi.
Hi, baby. How you doing?
I'm okay. I'm just
doing some laundry.
I didn't expect you to call.
No, I know.
I just wanted to say hi.
Hi. Everything okay?
Yeah. I just really
wanted to hear your voice.
How's our little lady doing?
(CHUCKLES)
She's been jumping on my
bladder, but we're doing good.
Wow, I've really missed you.
You sure everything's okay?
Yeah, I'm good now.
Okay.
Did you send that letter yet?
Have you told them
you're not re-enlisting?
Mmm-mmm.
Not yet. Don't worry, baby.
I'll do it. I love you.
I love you, too.
JONES: Okay, Marines,
fire when ready!
(WHOOPS)
Hey, bud, what's the good word?
Yeah, we're getting
a new sergeant?
Yup.
Word is Davidson from over
at Fox Trot's coming over.
No, that's not happening.
Can you tell us who it is?
Yeah, who's the FNG?
Fucking new guy, buddy.
Seriously, the last thing we
need is some uptight asshole.
Okay, come on.
Tell us who it is.
It's me.
Say what?
What?
No way.
You? Get outta here.
I'm sorry, man.
Hey, if it wasn't me,
it was you.
So you down for being
my alpha team leader?
Hell yeah. A-slash gets the
girls, shoots the bad guys.
Squad leader does the paperwork.
Shit.
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's actually true.
LI: Right?
Right.
Wow.
Nothing changes, guys.
Everything changes, man.
I can't give you shit anymore.
I love givin' you shit.
Soto, you can
still give me shit.
I can just bust
your ass for it now.
(ALL LAUGHING)
SOTO: That's cute.
Well, we said we didn't want
an uptight asshole.
Yeah, at least he's not uptight.
Very funny. No, you guys
should really laugh it up.
Because once I get my stripes,
you guys are just
pushing all day long.
(ALL LAUGHING)
MERRIMETTE: Hard.
Crew, back to
marksmanship training.
I need the best damn
squad in the Corps.
SOTO: Oh, yeah.
LI: I'll remember that.
SOTO: One, two...
ALLEN: Hey, Soto, do you
actually have a penis?
MERRIMETTE: All the way down.
All the way down.
Easy on the ammo, Danni.
Just in case.
Just in case what?
Just in case
you animals piss me off.
I'm a gear queer.
What can I say?
You're a toolbox.
That's what I can say.
Yeah, but I look good.
You're all right.
ALLEN: Don't deny it.
Good afternoon, sirs!
All right, listen up!
Stand easy.
You'll be transporting
supplies to Forward
Ops Base Ouellette in
the Garmsir District.
Those poor people have been
taking beaucoup casualties.
They need to get
resupplied ASAP.
Now this is definitely
outside the Green Zone.
So watch your corners,
keep your head on a swivel.
LEDs, HMEs, ambushes, whatever.
Questions?
Are we taking route 605, sir?
Affirmative. It's a
straight shot 75 clicks,
then a hard
right under Route Red.
(SOFTLY) We're totally fucked.
Son. This is Private
Khalid Hassan Abu Faisal.
He's with the Afghan National Army.
He's joining the squad.
KETTNER: Muji motherfucker.
You got a problem with that,
Corporal Kettner?
No, sir!
That's good.
This is part of
the drawdown handoff.
Private Faisal has received the same
training as every one of you has,
so he deserves your
cooperation and your respect.
Would you agree
with that, Corporal?
Yes, sir!
That's fine.
All right, Marines, you stay
safe, get the job done.
They're all yours,
squadron leader.
Thank you, sir.
Oorah, sir.
All right, Marines, top up your ammo.
Let's get ready to roll.
Faisal. Corporal Merrimette.
Thank you. You'll be riding
with Corporal Kettner.
You ride in the back.
Go ahead, man.
Go ahead. Go.
You speak English?
Easy, Kett.
Let's go. Show time.
All right, Li. You look stupid.
Thanks.
(GRUNTING)
Corporal!
What's up, A-slash?
You really gonna
let him have a gun?
They let you have one, don't they?
You really want him to be armed?
I don't know.
Let's find out.
Private Faisal?
What are you doin', man?
Can I have a minute
of your time, please?
Yes, sir.
Uh, Private, uh,
Corporal Kettner here
is concerned that you may
be a terrorist in disguise
and you're planning
on killing all of us.
Now, do you have
any plans like that?
I have no plans to harm
anyone in this unit, sir.
Thank you, Private.
Carry on. Sir.
You happy now?
Do I look happy?
You never look happy.
Come on, let's roll.
(EXHALES) This is some bullshit.
Hey, Corporal.
MERRIMETTE: Hey, Lance Corporal.
Now that you're a top dog,
can you put in for
a new transport vehicle?
Yeah, man, we're tired of
getting army hand-me-downs.
Look... (TAPS VEHICLE)
This has got up-armor,
a 10-foot whip.
Hmm. I love it
when you talk dirty.
I know you do.
If only I weren't married. And you
weren't so obviously a lesbian.
Is it that obvious?
Is it really that obvious?
All right, let's get
ready to roll, Marines!
I still think I can turn you.
ALLEN: Not a fucking
chance, Soto.
Remember those days,
rollin' out in force
with your M16
and a full set of balls?
Smokin' and jokin'.
Good old days.
Yes, sir. Well, it's
a young man's game.
Keep your hands off my porn!
MARINE: I'd rather
keep my hands on you!
I'll say hi to your wife.
(GRUNTING)
Systems check, Corporal.
Blue force tracker?
Check.
Green comm?
On it.
Thunder Ops, yeah.
This is Gunmetal 2-5.
System check. Over.
COC TECH: (OVER RADIO) This is Thunder Ops.
Systems are online and operational.
Be safe out there. Over.
Roger that. Out.
ALLEN: (OVER RADIO) Hey, guys.
What do you like better,
chocolate chip cookies
or brownies?
Chocolate chip.
Chocolate chip,
only if it's baked hard.
I heard you like it hard.
(LAUGHING)
Okay, pizza or sushi?
Sushi!
Pizza.
Sushi all the way,
I'm Asian, dudes.
(LAUGHING)
Blonde or brunettes?
Brunettes.
Brunette.
That's right!
Um...
Okay, hot face or banging body?
It's definitely hot face.
It's all the same in the dark.
Ass!
(LAUGHING)
I gotta go with the hot face.
I don't care
what she looks like,
as long as she's got a not
face and a banging body.
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
I knew it!
There's no surprise there.
What's going on up there?
I got trash on
the side of the road.
A hundred yards
to my 11 o'clock.
You see any wires?
Detonating device?
Disturbance in the dirt?
CONVOY DRIVER: Affirmative, Corporal.
Which one?
CONVOY DRIVER: I got a pile of
trash and disturbance in the dirt.
Thank you.
(SIGHS)
Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5.
We have a visual on
a possible IED. Over.
COC TECH: Gunmetal 2-5, do you have
a visual on the actual device?
Negative. We have
a trash pile
and some disturbance
in the dirt.
Copy that, Gunmetal 2-5. Hold your
position and wait for EOD. Over.
Standing by for EOD.
Gunmetal 2-5 out.
(SIGHING)
First fucking mission
as team leader.
Had to be.
What's going on?
We got orders to
hold and wait for EOD.
Any idea how long?
As soon as possible.
Just do your 5's and 25's.
Get everyone back in
the vehicle. All right?
Soto!
Corporal?
Stay sharp, man. Keep an eye on that ridge.
Look for snipers.
Roger that.
Dude, I got a serious case of swamp
ass sitting in this friggin' heat.
How long has it been?
Two hours.
(MUMBLING)
At this rate, we will
be traveling all night.
Hey, Soto?
Hey, what up, big boy?
I got a Dear John letter from my
girl a couple of days ago, man.
Damn, man.
You been holding out on me?
Yeah. I didn't
believe it was real.
Said she needed a break.
Maybe she's bangin'
some other dude, huh?
Yeah, man. Your girl's probably
sleeping around on you.
I really thought
she was the one, man.
One of many, brother. You know,
it ain't easy being a jarhead.
Seven-month deployment.
The uncertain future.
Hot as hell.
All this sand, goats everywhere.
Ugly chicks. Ugly dudes.
That's for you, brother.
(SOTO CHUCKLES)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Poco dinero, Bro.
Jarheads for life!
Por Vida!
I love being a marine.
Oorah!
(LI CHUCKLING)
Hey.
Yo.
Chin up.
Oh, yeah. Thanks, buddy.
Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5.
We've been waiting here
for over two hours.
We're sitting ducks.
Do you have an ETA
on the EOD? Over.
(FEEDBACK OVER RADIO)
COC TECH: Negative, Gunmetal.
They'll get there as soon as they can.
Hold tight.
Understood.
Gunmetal 2-5 out.
FAISAL: Fuck this.
I'll do it myself.
KETTNER: What the fuck
you doing, Muji?
Get back in the fucking truck!
(TAPPING VEHICLE) Corporal.
MERRIMETTE: Where the hell
is he going?
Private Faisal, where the hell
do you think you're going?
Don't worry. I got this.
God...
That's why I don't like working
with these motherfuckers.
Look at this guy. Take
charge, go get him.
Muji! What the fuck
are you doing?
Get your ass back in the truck!
Soto, watch him.
Roger that.
MERRIMETTE: Make sure he
doesn't get his ass killed.
Hey, Muji!
What the fuck you doing?
Tell him not to touch a goddamned
thing and get his ass back here.
You should wait there.
Who do you think you are, John Wayne?
Get back in the truck.
I have a visual on a pressure
plate to my 12 o'clock.
Stop walking
before you blow me up.
Blow you up? What about me?
What about you?
Do not let him touch that mound.
KETTNER: What the fuck
you doing, Muji?
Get your ass back in the truck.
We got movement at 12 o'clock.
Shit.
Donkey! Who's that?
That your boy?
That's your boy? He's just
carrying water to his village.
I don't care about his village.
Lower your weapon.
How do I know he's not
gonna set this thing off?
Because it's
a victim-activated IED.
There could be a secondary.
Cell phone! Cell phone!
Drop the cell phone! Relax!
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
What's on that donkey?
Drop the cell phone! (FAISAL
SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
A-slash, take charge.
I'm gonna put one in him,
I ain't killed...
Do not let him touch... Get
him away from there. Shh!
Drop the phone! (SHOUTING
IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Fucking asshole!
What the hell does a Muji on a
donkey need a cell phone for anyway?
Probably texting
his girlfriend, huh?
KETTNER: You got jokes, huh?
(FAISAL PANTING)
You can relax now.
You see it? You see it?
Yes. I see it.
KETTNER: Wait, what...
What the fuck is
goin' on, A-slash?
This is just a car radio.
Maybe it'll play the Beach Boys.
We're cool. He says
it's just a car stereo.
What are you doing, man?
Are you playing in the sand?
Come on, man.
You tell him to get
away from that thing.
What? What, man? What?
(EXHALING)
The radio was just
a decoy device.
Leave it alone. Let's go.
It's a HME, maybe 40 pounds
of bang, maybe more.
So if I trip it,
I'll be going to paradise
sooner than I planned.
That's fine for you, right? You got
72 virgins waiting for you, right?
Tell him not to touch a goddamned
thing and get his ass back here.
KETTNER: I'm gonna shoot you
right in the face, motherfucker.
I swear to God, man,
you touch that thing,
I'll shoot you and say you did
it to yourself. Let's go.
Let's go! Let's go! No!
(FAISAL GRUNTS)
KETTNER: What the fuck
did I say?
(FAISAL GRUNTING)
I told you not to fucking do it!
I'll kill you, motherfucker!
Are you listening to me?
MERRIMETTE: Get off him!
KETTNER: Listen to me.
Kettner, get off.
I'm telling you, man.
Get off him.
You cool? I'm cool. I'm cool.
I'm cool.
Daniel?
I'm cool. I'm cool.
You cool?
Yes, sir.
If you ever pull any shit like
that again, I'll kill you myself.
You got that, Private?
Yes, Corporal.
Now get in the trucks!
FAISAL: Yes, sir.
(PANTING)
FAISAL: I told you
I got this.
KETTNER: Shut the fuck up,
Muji!
COC TECH: (OVER RADIO) Gunmetal
2-5, this is Thunder Ops, over.
CONVOY DRIVER: Roger, Thunder
Ops, this is Gunmetal 2-5.
Send your traffic. Over.
COC TECH: What's your ETA
to FOB Ouellette? Over.
CONVOY DRIVER: 67 clicks over rough
terrain. Two hours Max, over.
COC TECH: Roger that, Gunmetal 2-5.
Thunder Ops out.
Got another one for you, Li.
Yeah, go for it.
Bush or no bush?
LI: I think bush is
highly underrated.
George Bush?
No, come on, man.
What do you know
about bush, man?
You still live
with your parents?
So?
You pigs never cease
to disgust me.
Come on, Danni,
you know you dig it.
ALLEN: What?
Being objectified
by a bunch of
drooling troglodytes?
Not so much, boot.
What's a troglodyte?
Google it.
It means caveman.
Oh, come on, Danni.
You could tell us.
We're all friends here.
What are you rocking
downstairs, baby girl?
You couldn't handle what I'm
rocking downstairs, mama's boy.
(LAUGHING)
Come on, Danni, you gotta give
us a little something something.
What are you rocking downstairs?
Full '70s style?
Bermuda triangle?
Landing strip? Bald eagle?
Come on, leave my bush
outta this conversation.
Yeah.
Okay, fine.
I got a hardwood floor
with a Queen Christina.
Uh, what's a Queen Christina?
Hey, what about you, Soto?
You look like a pretty hairy guy.
You trim the hedge?
Uh...
Come on, Soto, you can tell me.
You squeaky clean down there?
Or you got a little chin
tickler for your girlfriend?
Maybe.
Oh, come on,
what is a Queen Christina?
Am I making you
uncomfortable, Soto?
Yeah, kinda.
Okay, that's what I thought.
Let's leave my bush out of
the conversation, okay?
Come on, guys, what the
fuck is a Queen Christina?
Google it, boot!
Whoa!
What the hell?
Sit tight.
They're friendly, Corporal.
U.S. Marines!
CPO Fox, SEAL Team 10.
It's a SEAL.
Chris Merrimette. Echo Company
Second Battalion, CLR 10.
We need a ride outta here.
You mind if we catch one?
Yeah, sure. Where's
the rest of your team?
Coop, let's move.
That's it?
Taliban hit us really hard.
That's all we got.
Our comms are down.
Get ready to roll, Marines.
Who's she?
She's with us. I want to Evac ASAP.
Let's go, come on, move.
Danni? Call in QRF. Let's get these
guys a chopper to the Green Zone.
Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5. Over.
Listen to me, keep trying. This
valley's shit, you understand?
Hey, Coop? Let's go, move!
ALLEN: Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5. Over.
Let's roll.
FOX: Go!
See you, boys!
Get the hell outta here!
FOX: Go, go, go!
Thanks for saving our ass, Corporal.
No problem.
We need to get her
outta this valley ASAP.
ALLEN: Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5. Over.
I repeat, Thunder Ops,
We got no talk.
Just keep trying.
ALLEN: Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5. Over.
What's that right there?
What's that there?
Hey, I got movement
at my 3 o'clock.
(POUNDING VEHICLE)
3 o'clock-50!
What the hell!
Oh, shit!
ALLEN: What the hell!
Get up on
the fucking .50 Cal!
Thunder Ops,
this is Gunmetal 2-5.
We're taking heavy
fire in the vicinity
of our last coordinates. Gunmetal
2-5, we're taking heavy gunfire!
Soto, get your ass
back up there!
Get on the goddamned .50!
Gunmetal 2-5.
They're shooting, Soto,
you get on that .50 Cal.
Son of a bitch!
SOTO: I can't do it.
Tell him you're marines!
Il: They don't give a shit!
MERRIMETTE: This is Gunmetal 2-5.
This is Gunmetal 2-5.
RPG, move!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
FOX: Move, move, move!
(GRUNTS) LI: Soto,
get the fuck down!
(SOTO GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
Grenade!
MERRIMETTE: Suppressive fire!
Come on, move, move!
Go! Get him!
Get your asses down. Go!
Down, damn it!
(GRUNTS)
FOX: Reloading!
Save your ammo, Marines!
Only shoot what you can hit.
Soto, snap out of it!
Shit!
COOPER: Get behind the rocks.
Behind the rocks!
FOX: All right, listen up!
Forty Mike Mike!
Go three, gunner acknowledge.
Up top!
KETTNER: Three on the ridge.
(GRUNTS)
9 o'clock, Cooper.
Nine, nine, nine!
I need a Mag here.
Soto!
Get down! Soto!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
MARINE: Man down!
Soto! Soto!
(GRUNTS) Ah!
(SCREAMING)
Fuck you!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
Ridge clear!
(MOANING)
Li.
Li, come on, man.
No.
No, buddy, come on.
(PANTING)
(COUGHING)
FOX: Relax. Let it go.
(GASPING)
(SHUSHING)
It's okay.
(COOPER COUGHING)
Shh!
Let it go.
Li. Li.
(MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Fuck!
Hey! Marine!
Stand down!
Walk away!
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(GUN FIRING)
(PANTING)
Easy. Easy, easy.
Slow down. Slow down.
Slow it down.
Breathe, Marine.
There you go.
Let it go.
(RUMBLING)
(SIGHING)
Hey.
Cowboy up, do you hear me?
Get back in the game.
Let's go.
Corporal, we need to move.
That was a coordinated attack.
We're gonna have every Muji in
the province gunnin' for us.
And I need to
get her out in 48 hours.
We can't leave our men behind.
I know what it's like
to lose good men, Corporal.
But if we don't get our asses in
gear, we're gonna lose a lot more.
Let's go.
Senior Chief.
I don't think we can help you.
We're box kickers,
not a fire team.
You are now, kid.
Hey, Private, keep it together.
Go pull Li's dog tags.
Consolidate his ammo.
Roger that.
Everything's
shot up or blown up.
Vehicles are toast.
We got no SatComm.
Let's go. Come on.
(PANTING)
Thank you.
Move or die, Marines!
Standard diamond formation.
Package in the middle.
Let's move.
Set up a perimeter.
Aye-aye.
Anoosh.
(SOFTLY) Here, drink.
Thank you.
Thank you. You okay?
Okay, come on.
Here.
Stay here.
You watch her.
FAISAL: Yes, sir.
(FOX WHISTLING)
You go low. I'm gonna
take the high ground.
All right.
(SIGHS)
(CONVERSING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SCOFFS)
I don't trust this Muji.
He fought with us, took
the same gunfire we did.
KETTNER: Still.
I'm not invitin' him over
for Sunday night dinner.
I don't think
he'd show if you did.
(CONVERSING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
What do you make of her?
Hard to tell.
She must make some kinda juice
to have SEALS come extract her.
(SIGHS)
She's kinda hot.
Think I can hit that?
(CHUCKLES)
You're a sick fuck.
Stay sharp.
Soto.
(SIGHS)
Tough day, huh, Bro?
(SNIFFLING)
He took a bullet for me.
If I had just done my job.
Don't do this to yourself, man.
He knew what he signed up for.
He didn't deserve that.
No.
But it's not your fault.
Yes, it is.
We all get scared sometimes.
It's what you do when you're
under pressure that matters.
Now quit your whining
and man up.
(SNIFFLES)
Are you ready to lay some pain for these
Mujis and make it outta here, man?
That's how we honor Li.
(SNIFFLES)
Oorah?
Oorah.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
JONES: Major Gavins.
We have a situation, sir.
CLR 10 didn't make it
to FOB Ouellette.
GAVINS: Where are they?
Well, COC reported them offline in
the vicinity of the 67th gridline.
And?
Not good, sir.
Supply train was
totally destroyed.
KIA?
We brought six back last night.
And here's where
it gets interesting.
One of the KIA was a SEAL.
He was part of Team 10.
They went into the Tangi Valley yesterday
to extract a high value package.
What kind of package?
What the hell's a Navy SEAL
doing with our unit?
Don't know.
And sir, five of our
marines are missing.
Missing? Who?
Merrimette, Soto, Kettner,
Allen, and the new guy, Faisal.
Li?
Didn't make it, sir.
And the unit? You got a
fixed position on 'em?
No.
We have a best guess.
I want a no-bullshit
assessment, Captain.
We believe they've gotta be on the move
somewhere in the Helmand River Valley.
We gotta get them outta there soon,
sir, or they'll be eaten alive.
Well, let's not write 'em off.
They're marines.
They're supply marines.
Strap in and bring everything to bear
we have to get our people outta there.
I'm trying, sir,
but we can't push air.
There's a sandstorm kickin' up
between them and us right there.
We got red air?
Yes, sir. High winds, low visibility.
Air support's grounded.
I don't want excuses. Find me a
workaround and let's get this solved.
You hear me?
Yes, sir.
Let's bring our boys home.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Shit!
Bring up grid 67,
give me weather.
(EXHALES)
It sure is pretty, isn't it?
Yeah. It looks like
a five-star resort.
Take a look at your 12.
So what exactly am I lookin' at?
You're lookin' at the most
dangerous place on Earth,
with the toughest enemy
you'll ever face.
There's a reason why
they've never lost a war.
Now, look at your 10.
There's a village called Minar.
It's about 20 clicks away.
And there's a captain there,
he's a pretty good guy.
If we can make it there
by this afternoon,
I think you got a chance to make it
back to Leatherneck for a little chow.
What do you say?
What about FOB Ouellette?
That's too far.
With the heat we got on us, we'll
never make it back in time.
And you can trust
this police captain?
If you're lookin' for guarantees in this
country, you're in the wrong place.
And the wrong war,
for that goddamned matter.
Who are we protecting?
That doesn't matter. What
matters is she gets back alive.
She's bigger than you and me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
So you like this play?
A midday trek through
the Helmand River Valley,
humping a tier one package,
short on water, short on ammo,
and everybody in this
province gunning for us.
What's not to like? (CHUCKLES)
ANOOSH: Is that your daughter?
Yep.
She just turned five.
She's beautiful.
You have children?
No.
I had a younger sister.
She was killed by the
Taliban when she was 13.
What for?
To punish me.
To punish my family for
violating Sharia law.
Sharia law as interpreted by the Taliban
forbids women to have an education.
My parents broke with this
tradition and sent me to college.
When I returned to Afghanistan,
the Taliban wanted
to make an example of me.
It was decided by the tribal elders to send
a message to the people of my infidelity.
But they couldn't kill me.
Then I would be a martyr.
I begged them to take
my life but...
(GUNSHOT)
She was just a child, had
so much life ahead of her.
I'm sorry.
(EXHALES)
So am I.
(GUNSHOT)
Sniper!
Get down! Get down!
Where'd that shot come from?
I don't know. I can't see 'em.
We're going to need another round
if we're gonna zero in on him.
Another round?
(GUNFIRE)
He's got us pretty
well dialed in here.
All right, heads down, Marines.
Dude, my head is
not goin' anywhere.
Give me your binos.
All right.
Let's find this son of a bitch.
Where you at?
Come on.
There you are.
MERRIMETTE: Where?
At 700 meters.
Look at your one.
Do you see the glint?
The sun's reflecting
off his optics.
MERRIMETTE: Yeah, yeah, I got it.
He's far. Danni?
Yeah, I see him.
Can you take him?
In perfect conditions, if we
were 300 meters closer, maybe.
All right, so what do we do?
Get 300 meters closer.
That would be choice number one,
but when we get there, if we
miss, we're in the same boat.
Only worse.
Because we're closer.
FOX: Exactly.
So what's choice number two?
Well, Merrimette, we can sit here and
wait until one of them shoots one of us.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, then we all get shot.
(BULLET RICOCHETS)
I'm not feelin' that.
FOX: You know what? Enough of this shit.
Khalid?
Let's go get up close
and personal.
MERRIMETTE: Not all of us can make that.
Not all of us.
You and me.
Gear down. Let's go.
Lose your rifle. Come on.
Man, always sitting
and babysitting the Muji.
Hey, Corporal? You take care
of her. You understand me?
Yes, sir.
All right, Corporal,
listen to me now.
I want you to stay behind me and
just be patient. All right?
All right. Come on,
let's go have some fun.
(GRUNTS)
You all right?
Yeah.
All right.
I want you to start
movin' forward
and I'm gonna flank around and go on
the right hand side. You hear me?
I'll come with you.
No. I move better alone.
Now, listen, I want you
to keep this field of view.
When you see me hit him,
I want you to come in hard and fast.
All right.
Now, no gunfire. We do this hand-to-hand.
There's too much enemy.
See you in a minute.
You got this.
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Ah!
Oh!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
FOX: Good job.
Keep your eyes down range.
Anoosh, get a drink.
Get a drink.
(SIGHS)
Don't do it, Corporal.
What's that, Senior Chief?
Overthink it.
Killing.
Let me tell you somethin'. Every
day we go out, it's life or death.
It's him or you.
This is my first time
out as squad leader.
Before yesterday, I...
I never even fired
my weapon at anybody.
And I never thought
I'd have to do it that close.
It's all the same.
They died today.
And we lived.
Look at me.
Today was a good day.
Now, I want you
to do something for me.
I want you to get out
of your head and focus.
Focus on the mission.
The mission is God.
All right.
I'm gonna give you another
second and then we gotta go.
Soto, start gearin' up.
Let's go.
You speak very good English.
Thank you.
Which is very unusual
for a woman in our country.
May I ask where did you learn?
I went to university
at Cambridge.
May I ask the same of you?
I was trained by the U.S.
military as a translator.
In Lexington, Virginia.
KETTNER: Whoa.
You learned how to speak
English in Virginia?
With the help of my iPad
and Rosetta Stone.
I'm not buyin' it.
I'm not selling it.
Brunswick stew, thick or thin?
Well, if it is thin, it isn't
Brunswick stew. It is soup.
Right, Corporal?
What's up?
Opium poppies.
They're in harvest.
Yeah, and where there's opium
farmers, there's Taliban.
You got it.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Move, Marines! Move! Move!
Marines, 100 meters, follow me!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Get down! Get down in it!
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Cover me! Cover me!
Cover fire!
(GRUNTS)
Ah!
Watch your six!
Shit.
Ah!
Chief!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(COUGHS)
Hey. Hey, hey. I got you. I got you.
I got you. I got you.
Get me a poppy. A poppy.
Kettner, go grab a poppy.
Listen.
You gotta get to the village and
talk to the police captain.
You hear me?
I will. Yes.
Okay.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Now listen to me,
you gotta get her out.
You have 24 hours.
Chief, we're truck drivers.
You're a marine!
And this country needs her.
You wanna risk the lives of
my men for some symbol?
What do you think this is?
FOX: Bring me Anoosh.
These men are gonna get you out.
What is your name?
It's John.
Thank you, John.
Okay.
Give me your hands.
Merrimette,
no easy day, huh?
What are we gonna do now, man?
We gotta get outta here.
You're in charge, Corporal.
Your orders.
Call it.
Just...
Just gimme a minute.
Come here.
MERRIMETTE: Come with me.
Who the hell are you?
I'm not unlike you.
I am fighting for the
rights for my people,
and your government
is supportive of my cause.
A lot of good men have died for
you, so I hope you're worth it.
So do I.
We need to get to that village.
I think we should
talk about this.
Nothin' to talk about. It's
my squad, makes it my call.
I don't mean to question you.
Then don't.
All due respect,
Corporal, this...
ALLEN: She's not our mission.
She is now.
Get ready to move out.
Standard diamond formation.
Package in the middle.
Let's go.
MERRIMETTE: Door on the left.
FAISAL: Clear.
Windows and door on the right.
Clear.
Stay sharp, Marines.
U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
Jeez, kid.
Beat it, kid. I'm not in the mood.
All right.
Get the fuck outta here.
Hey, I got somebody with a
video camera at the window.
Is he armed?
I can't tell.
Keep an eye on him.
Hey, put the camera down.
Put the video camera down.
Put the camera down.
KETTNER: Movement.
Hey, hey!
KETTNER: Gun!
Drop the weapon!
Khalid, tell him to drop
his fucking weapon.
(SPEAKS LOCAL LANGUAGE)
That's right, be smart, stupid.
Be smart, motherfucker.
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
What's he saying?
He's invited us to
come inside and talk.
All right, let's get
her inside now.
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Hey, Soto, stay on this door, okay?
Roger that, sir.
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
What's goin' on?
He is offering us chai.
Thank you.
Tell him Senior Chief Fox
sent us.
We need to make arrangements with
our base so they can come get us.
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
What have we got, buddy?
It looks like everyone's
clearing out, Corporal.
It looks good.
Still got that video camera
in that window though.
Hey, A-Slash.
Yeah?
Stay sharp, buddy.
Roger that.
About to be on the
evening news, sir.
Well, just stay
on him, all right?
Let me know if anything changes.
Hey, Corporal?
What's up?
Can I get one of those chais?
I'll see what I can do.
SOTO: Corporal Kettner?
Yeah?
Ever have a camel milk
chai latte?
He says he is sorry to hear about Fox and
that he was a true friend to the village.
And that he will help us
contact our base. How soon?
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Shortly.
He is curious about the package and
wondering if she is our prisoner.
No.
FAISAL: She is
Afghani national, yes?
Yeah.
FAISAL: Then why does
she travel with us?
That question's
above my pay grade.
I just need to get her out
of here and back to base.
He is saying she is safe here.
Tell him I have my orders.
FAISAL: He has his also. What the
hell's that supposed to mean?
FAISAL: Because she is Afghani
national and not our prisoner,
he must seek permission
from the provincial commander
before he can allow us
to leave with her.
All right. Let him know that
we're running out of time.
Time. We need to
get this done now.
I don't understand. We got
goddamned satellites up there
that can see everything,
they can see up your asshole.
You know that, don't you?
JONES: Yes, sir.
See into your bedroom.
All this goddamned technology,
all this manpower,
we cannot locate five marines?
Perfect storm of bad
stuff happening, sir.
They got ambushed, marine comms go
down, sandstorm between them and us.
Well, what about
the air on station?
Do we have any direct support?
Still grounded, sir.
Son of a bitch!
I got a Humvee column rollin'
outta FOB Keenan now, sir.
Keenan?
That's Royal Irish Regiment?
Imjin Company Second Battal...
We goddamned better hope for a
little luck of the Irish here.
They're on the other side of the
sandstorm and they got access.
Now you're telling me that this
is our best worst option, right?
I'm afraid so.
I do have some actual intel on who's the
package that they're traveling with.
Talk to me.
Her name is Anoosh Hassan.
Anoosh Hassan?
I know the name. Who is she?
It's a women's rights' activist.
She's a real hero to the
people in the provinces.
She's a beacon of hope.
The Taliban wants her dead, sir.
And Washington wants her alive.
Yup. She's good PR.
She's good PR. You know
what's bad PR in my book?
Dead marines are bad PR.
She's a keynote speaker
at the United Nations
International Summit
on Human Rights.
She's scheduled to be
in New York in 36 hours.
That's direct from Washington. She's
the president's guest of honor.
And she's with our marines?
Yes, sir.
Fuck!
Can we call our base?
How are we doin' out there?
Fine as fuck, Corporal.
All right.
What's goin' on with
the video camera guy?
He's still there.
MERRIMETTE: You think
he's Taliban?
KETTNER: Or a sympathizer.
I don't care if he shoots
for National Geographic.
Let me turn his lights off?
Easy, A-Slash.
It's too quiet.
I don't like it.
The calm before the storm.
Yeah.
Here's that storm you're
talkin' about, Corporal.
MERRIMETTE: Close the door.
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Get her to cover.
Now.
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
All right, Devil Dogs, remember
your training. Semper Fi!
Semper Fi.
Comin' in heavy.
Okay, here's what
we're gonna do.
We're gonna draw
their fire out front
and then we're gonna fight
our way through the back.
What's everyone's
ammo situation?
I got four mags left.
I'm doin' about the same.
I got nine full mags.
You got nine full mags?
Hey, I'm the gear queer,
remember?
Jeez.
Funy loaded.
I love ya.
Give me three.
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Plus up.
Video camera guy fucked us.
Hey, you ready for what's
comin' through that door?
Hell, yeah.
You sure?
Hell, yeah. (CHUCKLING) Ain't no one
comin' through that door, Corporal.
Semper Fi.
Oorah.
All right,
here's the deal, Marines.
We got 19 hours to get her out
and get her to
wherever it is she's goin'.
So, I want you to keep
your fields of view open
and only shoot what you can hit.
Fire on my command.
Kettner, I need you
to take Khalid
to the back door.
You guys are our way out.
KETTNER: On me, Muji.
FAISAL: Yes, sir.
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SHOUTING)
(GUNFIRE)
(WHIMPERING)
Ready?
Yeah.
(YELLS)
Spider Muji, huh?
You have Mujis
where you get that?
No!
Huh?
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Anoosh, stay down!
Danni, get on that front window!
Kettner, how's the back
coming along?
I'm working on it!
Danni, we gotta take
out that machine gun.
I got it.
Fuck.
I got you, bitch.
I'm crossing. I'm crossing.
All right.
Hello.
KETTNER: Front clear!
KETTNER: Reloading!
RPG!
(ALLEN SCREAMS)
MERRIMETTE: Soto, get down!
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
(YELLING)
(ANOOSH YELLING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
Move or die, Marines.
A-Slash, let's roll out.
(PRAYING)
You ever pray?
Sometimes.
With my little girl.
So what's next?
We're going after her.
Four of us against every Taliban
fighter in the province?
KETTNER: You ready to die
for this chick?
We don't know
anything about her.
That chick inspired the nation.
Because of her,
the people have hope,
for the first time
in a very long time.
Soldiers and bullets and fighting
will never save my country.
The people will.
People like her.
People who are brave enough to
stand up for what they believe in.
It is a beautiful country. I wish
you could see it the way I do.
Where'd they take her?
Only one place.
To Mullah Nafiz.
She will be stoned at dawn.
You know how to get
to this Nafiz guy?
Yes, sir.
Listen to me, man.
I know you wanna make a
difference in this war.
So do I.
See, the thing about
what you're doin',
I'm your A-Slash, I'll
follow you anywhere, man.
But you need to ask yourself
if you are ready to live
with the consequences
of your decision.
We're marines.
We're the tip of the spear.
I'm not gonna
let that woman die.
We go in at dawn
during morning prayer.
Are you sure she's in there?
We can't go in
through the front door.
There is another way.
Follow me.
Once we're inside,
where's she gonna be?
FAISAL: In the Nafiz's
chambers or imprisoned.
So we find her and then what?
Then we fight.
We're going in silent.
That means no gunfire until
it's absolutely necessary.
(MAN SPEAKING IN
LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(CALL TO PRAYER OVER SPEAKERS)
That's it.
The call to prayer.
Kill your lights.
(SPEAKING IN
LOCAL LANGUAGE)
We got exactly seven hours to
get her back to Leatherneck.
Take the door,
A-Slash.
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING IN
LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SPITS)
(GRUNTS)
My guess, she's in
one of those towers.
All right, let's go.
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(SCREAMING)
Help! Help! Help!
ANOOSH: Help!
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
Here!
(ANOOSH WHIMPERING)
Let's get you
outta here. Let's go.
Marines! Standard
diamond formation.
Package in the middle.
Khalid, shield her.
Yes, sir!
MERRIMETTE: All right, move out.
(SHOUTING IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
We're pinned down! Chris!
We're pinned!
Kettner, go!
I'll hold them off!
Kettner, let's go!
I'll make my stand here.
Go!
Looks like I'm stayin'!
Come on, let's move!
Chris, move or die.
Chris!
Don't you have
some paperwork to do?
(GRUNTS)
KETTNER: I'm hit!
Kettner! Get up!
Cold!
You gotta cook it over a
low flame for a long time.
Brunswick stew.
You can't rush it.
Most people like chicken, but if you
want real Virginia Brunswick stew,
you gotta use rabbit.
I prefer lamb.
Never tried it with lamb.
Danni, I don't have a shot!
I'm movin' in.
When we get home,
I'll have my grandma make a big
ol' pot of Brunswick stew.
I'll tell her to use lamb.
There's plenty to go around,
and I know the old gal
would love to have you.
I would like that very much.
(MAN SHOUTING
IN LOCAL LANGUAGE)
On your command, Corporal.
Clear!
Seventy-two virgins, huh?
Let's get some, my brother.
Let's do it.
Come on.
Let's go.
MERRIMETTE: A story.
A man has a lot of choices,
and these choices made in life
are rarely perfect.
So he decides to sign a contract
because he wants to
make a difference.
He wants to save this world,
make it a better place.
The consequences are punishing,
unforgiving,
and he questions why
he ever signed that contract.
So what's the fucking point?
I guess the point is
responsibility of duty.
Love of country.
A way of life.
Are we on
the right side of this?
These aren't our
questions to ask.
A marine fights for the person
standing next to him.
He fights for the man
who can't stand anymore.
He fights so that others can have the
opportunity to make a difference.
That's how we make
the unforgiving forgivable.
And if we're lucky, somewhere in all the
fighting and dying, we discover hope.
And the marines who killed
and bled and died
will always be jarheads.
Their families will have to live
with the unbearable demands
of their ultimate sacrifice.
MARINE 1: Unidentified
vehicle, 12 o'clock!
MARINE 2: Get out
of the truck!
Show me your hands!
U.S. Marines.
Marine.
Hey, it's me, Merrimette.
Unload.
Come on.
Welcome home, Marines.
It's good to have you back.
Thank you, sir.
MERRIMETTE: And the ones who make it home,
we never really leave
our brothers behind.
We always remember.
We're professional fighting men.
We are jarheads.