Our brothers of the Nationalists'
168th Division
This is Captain Gu Zidi of the 139th Regiment
3rd Battalion, 9th Company
the Special 2nd Division of the Liberation Army
On behalf of my company, I'd like to greet you
You are completely surrounded
If you keep fighting
You won't like how things end up
We offer you two choices
You can get bullets
Or maybe you'd prefer dumplings
We can keep the bullets coming
If you have had enough
Trade in your weapons for chopsticks
Sit down with your brothers here in the 9th company
We can all eat dumplings
Gu
Quit the bullshit
Let's move in
Wait
They're already cooking in a pot
What's the hurry?
Captain
Something doesn't look right
Have they already retreated?
The battalion ordered a hasty attack
What are we waiting for?
Jiao
Coming
Take six men and get a closer look
Find them six helmets
Smoke grenade
Jiang
Go
Take cover
Up there.
Give me your hand
Pull me up
Help me!
Jiang
Take out those two up there
How many are there?
I don't know
Cease fire!
Help the wounded
Hurry!
Covering fire
Medic
Hurry
I'm going to die, save me
Hurry up
Slowly. Slowly
Get the bandages, hurry
Hang in there man
OK
Hurry up
Move him
First platoon
Follow me
Second Platoon
Protect the flanks
Don't bunch up
Spread out
Keep spreading out
Keep up
There's lightning
Get down, take cover
Fall back
Captain Gu
Get down, get down
Everyone get down, don't run around
Get down,
Get up
We've been ambushed
Take cover
Get down
Second platoon, attack
Reinforce first platoon
Third platoon, save the wounded
Leave the dead
Tend the wounded first
Luo, get on the roof
Lu and Jiang
Stop cowering
Let's go
Bring up the heavy weapons
Yes sir
Follow me
Get down
On the ground
Move in, now!
Get the machine gun
No one move
Gu
Set up a base of fire
Send in the assault forces
We're pinned down
The enemy has artillery
Let the troops regroup
How can we stop now?
I disagree
I am the captain
I'm in charge
That is cowardly behavior
I won't let that happen
Are you moving in or not?
I'm going in anyway
What for?
If you want to get yourself killed
No one can stop you
Political Officer!
Hurry
Brothers
Attack!
Political Officer!
Don't shoot
We surrender
We surrender, don't shoot
Don't shoot
The enemy has surrendered
Let them pick up their weapons
No surrender accepted
Pick up your weapons
No one move
No one move!
Luo
What are you waiting for?
Fire!
They have already surrendered
Jiang
Fire
You cannot kill POWs
Stop pretending to be a saint
The Political Officer was blown apart
Harder
Those in the back, keep up
Including the wounded
Anyone who were not carried away by stretcher
We still have forty six men left
A hundred seventeen minus forty six
Our company lost seventy one men
Get me a casualty list
Report the final count
On the double
Fight a battle, report a funeral
Don't keep making me do this
You are the only one who can read
The Political Officer is gone
Who else is there?
The Nationalists have good uniforms
But their fighting is not up to snuff
We found a wheel
See if it fits
The 7th Company found three howitzers
Two ten wheelers
All we find is a small, crippled mountain gun
Bite your tongues
Feel the pain?
That means you are still alive
What is the use of all these metal scraps?
In our last battle
The 3rd battalion's 9th company
Fought bravely without giving up
They suffered heavy casualties
We were going to commend them
But Captain Gu Zidi
Ordered the POWs shot
And stole their uniforms
He disobeyed army discipline
And disgraced our entire regiment
The Division Commander has ordered us
To punish him
for his misconduct
Therefore
The regiment's Party leadership has decided
To punish all those involved accordingly
Firstly
The 9th Company's troops are to be transferred
Captain Gu Zidi's forty six men
Will all move to the regiment's Advanced Guard
Until further instruction
Secondly
Captain Gu Zidi, of the 9th Company
Is to be punished for his mistake accordingly
He's to be locked up for three days.
Captain Gu
Have something to eat
The food is getting cold
You know when I last had a bed under me?
I am having the ball of my life
Food can wait
I guess I caught up on my rest
This is the best I've felt since
joining the battalion
This barn is huge
How much grain can it hold?
What a waste locking us up in here
What's your name?
Wang Jincun
What's your job?
I was a teacher
You were busy writing when I first got here
You were still writing when I woke up
What are you writing?
A letter home
To your wife?
And this?
Did your wife knit it?
Huh?
Yes
I heard them say
A teacher in the 1st Battalion
Pissed in his pants in battle
And he was disciplined
Are you the one?
No? Not you?
Who cares if it is?
All you did was pee
That's better than getting killed
Bullets flying everywhere
Grenades exploding down your pants
Even a god would pee
Don't get the wrong idea
Moving you to the front
It's not part of the punishment
It shows our trust in you
I've seen the old mine battlefield
The location is good
It's much higher
than the north bank
They won't be able to see our movement
We'll get the upper hand by securing it
We planned to
transfer two companies from the 2nd Battalion
But now
The defensive area has expanded
I can't spare the troops
Are you following?
Say something
Damn delicious
Look
Only girls wear down their shoes here
When will you learn to walk like a man?
Stop messing around
Tell me what you need
I'll do whatever I can
What you want?
In that case
I don't have enough artillery
I need Maxim machineguns
I'll.
Give you two machine guns
And three thousand rounds
I want to keep that mountain gun
Shells are hard to find
The quartermaster will check
You can take whatever he finds
My troops are good in the trenches
Especially with explosives
You've got to let me take all I want
Go ahead
Take as much as you can carry
I don't have enough men
Give me thirty more
No way
After all, I'm the provisional
captain of the advanced guards
How about twenty more men?
No way
Five?
That's not a lot to ask
The regiment's troops are all deployed
I can't spare a single man
Gu
There really are no men left
The Colonel's bodyguard is dead
And there is no replacement
I now serve as the Bugler and his bodyguard
It's the truth
Fine
Then just give me one person
I need a Political Officer
You've only got half a company
What you need a Political Officer for?
In the last battle
If the Political Officer hadn't died
I wouldn't have made that mistake
Now you know
You can be your own Political Officer
Can we.
Keep the helmets and boots
we took from the POWs?
What?
Okay, keep them
Liangzi
Get the stuff for him
What are the goodies?
Yellow Dragon cigarettes.
The Colonel won't even smoke them himself
Why is there only half a carton left?
Give the rest to him
You're always so stingy
Giving half a pack at best
What's so special this time?
Gu
How many of us are left?
I mean from the old guerilla unit?
You. Me
Anyone else?
Okay
Have the troops get ready on the double
The defensive position
Has already been built by the 2nd Battalion
You.
Take good care of yourself
I have one last request
I'll find myself a Political Officer
You can't say no
I want my cellmate
He'd be shot anyway
He might as well die in battle
Liangzi
That bent up bugle dangling on your butt
Is it busted?
No
It is fine
You better blow as hard as you can
Don't worry
You've heard my bugle call before
My ears are already wide open
Repeat the orders
By tomorrow twelve noon
No matter what it takes
We must secure the old mine on the southern bank
What else?
Always listen.
For the assembly bugle call
Fall back whenever we hear it
If you don't hear the bugle call
Even if you're the last man standing
You will keep fighting
Yes, sir
In this open area
It's impossible to last even four hours
Move the small canon to the rear for now
Yes, sir
Push harder
Get two more people here
Put them inside
Put them all inside
If a shell lands on them
We'd all be gone
Put them inside
Bring more bags here
Pack it in real tight
It's for your own protection
Yes, sir
Pack it in real tight
Hey, Lu
How many times have I told you?
Don't tie it straight
You have to tie it at an angle
Wrap it around twice
As tightly as you can
Got it?
Lieutenant
Last time we tied it at an angle
They ended up not flying straight
They landed on the 5th Company
No shit?
Why wasn't I told?
Jerk, I'll kill you
Look
These make obvious targets
Gather everyone together
Place them like you're supposed to
Make sure they're twenty paces apart
No, not this time
Put three in front and three in back
Captain
I found him for you
Good
Over here
Come over
Jiao
Your message bag
Here
Your rifle
Hey guys
I have someone to introduce
This is our company's new Political Officer
Wang Jincun.
Let's welcome him
What's wrong?
Are your fingers frozen?
Do I need to chisel them apart?
Political Officer Wang can read and write
He's your man if you want to write home
Lieutenant Jiao
When we had our victory party at Luoyang
He was nearly choked to death on flapjacks
Lu, Demolition Specialist
Jiang, Sniper
Sergeant Meng
Old Hedgehog
Luo, Machine Gunner
Gong, Ammo Bearer
Call me Blacky
Captain
I wrote a letter home
I don't know how to write some words
Can the Political Officer fill them in for me?
Get down!
Get in the mine
Hurry, get in the mine, and stay there
Captain
Something doesn't seem right
It is raining shells
Leave two men behind to keep a look out
Tell the rest to get into the mine
Take the Political Officer with you, hurry
Yes, sir
Get up
Follow me
Don't be scared
Hurry into the mine
Yong and Shun, you two stay behind
Hurry up
Get down
Everyone get into the mine
Stay focused
Hurry
What are you praying for?
Are you praying for the firing to stop
So you won't be hit?
Stop screwing around
Pray with me
It works
Show me how to pray
You've killed too many people
Prayers won't do you any good
But they were the enemy
Political Officer
If we make it through this one
Help me write a letter home
But forget it if I'm gone
It'd be less work for me
And less work for you, too
Make way, make way
Just leave him
We'll drag him away later
He's dead
It stopped again
Forget about the time
Just listen for the bugle call
Keep your ears open for the bugle call
Has everyone rested up?
When the bastards come to the door
We'll give them what they deserve
Captain
This new guy's a wimp
Don't worry
He will get over it after seeing some blood
Stay calm
Let them come closer
Fire when the grenades explode
Do you know why dogs bite people?
People smell funny when they're scared
Dogs only bite those who are scared
Bullets are like dogs
They only hit those who are scared
If you aren't scared
The bullets will go around you every time
Check your backpack
Leave the useless stuff behind
Stay calm, wait for my orders
Wait for my order before fire
Do you see their officer?
Let's take him out
I've got him in my sight
Let them get right in front of you
Fire
Reload
Done
Political Officer
Looking good
Brothers
Follow me
Remember where he is, he's all yours
Fire
Medic, come with me
He's dead
Bring the dead into the mine
Yes
Political Officer
Blacky
Blacky, hang in there
Bandages
Bandage it
Let's go
Captain
Retreat!
Retreat, hurry!
Cease fire
Save your ammo
Hedgehog
Have a smoke
Come give me a hand
Help him up, slowly
Eleven dead
Nine wounded
Two seriously wounded won't make it
Forty seven minus eleven
Minus two more
Only thirty four men left
If things keep going like this
We'll all be gone before we hear the bugle call
Get some men
Carry the dead and wounded into the mine
We'll go in
Forget about the dead
They will be blown apart
If we leave them out in the snow
We won't be able to collect the pieces
Hedgehog
Carry the dead and seriously wounded
Into the mine
No one could have saved him
If I get wounded like that
Don't bother with the bandages
Save them for someone who needs them
He's in the way
Take him into the mine
This is his letter home
Finish it for him
Blacky
Your worries are over
Rest in peace
When I was a kid
I tended livestock for a rich family
Take this
I accidentally
Lost their pony
The old bastard
Beat me with a club
After I got home
My father was even angrier
He beat me with a long pole
My family had half an acre of land
We had to hand over half of it
That's not him
I remember he was an officer
Take care of the fields
Look after our elders
It's getting cold
Don't let our son play near the well
The ice is slippery
Don't let our son near the livestock
Don't let him walk behind them
I don't want him injured in the wrong place
Political Officer
That'll do
That's all for now
I'll add a good ending
Wishing the entire family
Peace and happiness
Not bad
After the war
I'm going back home
What about you?
I'm not going back
I've got to make something of myself first
At least I have to get the land back for my dad
Over there
This guy?
Is he wearing a watch?
Yes
Now Captain will know what time it is
Lu
Don't move
Medic!
Captain
He got a watch for you
Who told you to go?
Who?
We saw your watch was broken
Trade a life for a watch?
For a watch!
Is it worth it?
Lu
Hang in there
Enemy tanks!
Jiang
Move Lu into the mine
Fire after the tanks get closer
Yes
Get the Molotov cocktails ready
Bring them over here
Bring out the mountain gun
Demolition Team
Explosives!
Get the explosives ready!
Hurry, wait for my orders
Aim at the infantry behind the tank
Yes
Point it this way, hurry
Load the shell
When I say fire, pull the cord
Will I be okay?
Lu
You'll be okay
You'll be fine
It's cold
So cold
Lu
Warmer now?
Fire
Get down
Captain
Fire
Bulls eye!
Give me the torch
Take it
Luozi
Don't throw the grenades
Let us get over there first
Go that way, now!
Jiao
It's too dangerous, come back!
Sergeant
Jiao
Jiang
Jiang!
Wait
Captain
Listen to me
I just heard the assembly bugle call
Hedgehog
My hearing is not good
What did he say?
He heard the bugle call
You heard the bugle call?
Assembly
They played the Assembly
Who else heard it?
Hedgehog
Did you hear it?
Tell me if you heard it!
I did
Assembly was played
It's been playing all along
You're deaf, you didn't hear it
Captain
Let's go
Get us out of here
Did you hear the bugle call?
The bugle call?
When was it sounded?
Who else heard it?
Did you two hear it?
Did you hear it?
Political Officer
Political Officer!
Tell Captain how many of us are left
Thirty two dead
Louder!
Our Company has fifteen men left
Six are seriously wounded
We're all who's left
The two in the mine took care of themselves
I have always listened to you
Listen to me this time
We have to leave
If we don't go
We'll all die
He said
We always listen to you
Listen to him for once
Let's get out of here
If we don't
We'll all be killed
Wang Jincun
You're the 9th Company's Political Officer
I want to hear your advice
Did you hear the bugle call?