JOAN OF ARC
(subtitle by alanchiawc at www.subscene.com)
And so by disposition of the divine mercy,
it was done most opportunely,
that Joan, child of god,
daughter of France, today be placed among the
number of the saints.
Saint Joan of Arc
whose history is recorded here,
lived only 19 years on this earth.
She was born in 1412
in a village of Domremy,
on the marche of Lorraine.
At the time when France,
losing the hundred years war,
was overrun by her enemies,
her cities ruined, her farms stripped bare,
her people hopeless.
But the enemies of France did not reckon
on the girl Joan
praying in the little ruined
church of her village.
As she knelt there, the voices
of the saint spoke to her again and again,
urging her to become a soldier,
to lead the armies of France
to victory.
But how?
How can I?
Save France?
Lead the Dauphin to his coronation?
I'm only a poor girl of the farms.
I've never seen a king or an army.
How?
I'm not fitted to speak to
great people or among them.
All this time I have... I have
tried to make a beginning
but I can find no ways
so nothing is done.
I know that everyday now
we lose France. But I
still don't how to go about
what is asked of me.
So I do nothing.
Forgive me, forgive me.
I am helpless and anguish.
Will a voice come and say that
I am forgiven.
I've tried with all my soul, I've tried.
Then I must go
and do what I can without knowing how.
Uncle Durand!
- Jeannette, did I forget something?
- No, only uncle Durand
I must go to Vaucouleurs, take me with you.
- To Vacouleurs?
- Yes.
Your father said nothing about this to me.
Your mother said nothing about it.
No.
Well this is very strange, Jeannette.
You want to buy something in the city?
I have to speak to
Sir Robert de Baudricourt.
What about? Why would you
speak to the King's captain?
- I can't tell you Uncle Durand.
- Then I can't take you.
I shall walk then.
Even if I wear my legs
to the knees, I must go.
It maybe that I do wrong...
but come.
- Next.
- Gerard Morseau, Sir Robert.
- Morseau, you are late for the taxes.
- Uh they burn my house, Sir Robert.
- Stole my grain.
- Give him till next harvest.
Durand Laxart,
- Taxes in your village is not due yet.
- I know, Sir Robert.
- This is uh... this is my niece.
- Hm.
She is the daughter of
Jacques D'Arcde of Domrémy.
Yes, yes.
She wish to speak with you.
- I... I...
- Yes, yes, go on, go speak up. Tell me.
I... I bring
you a message Sir Robert.
You must send me to the Dauphin.
My lord commands it.
Your lord? I am your lord!
- My Lord is the King of Heaven.
- Hm, that's a point. That's a point.
But I am to lead the Dauphin's armies.
To lead his armies?
When did the Dauphin have an army?
And women don't lead
armies girl, they follow!
And if you want to become them,
the camp follower can be arranged.
- But I'm to save France.
- To save France?
Go home girl and don't be an idiot!
If it would have been possible to save France,
it would have been done long ago.
But you must send me to the Dauphin,
I must save France!
I am sorry, Sir Robert.
I didn't know what she is going to say.
I'll take her home.
What a fool you made out of me, if
I've known what you are going to say...
I didn't want to bring this on you uncle
Durand, but there was no other way.
And I had to speak to him.
You had to? Your father
will never forgive me.
- Never in the world!
- Hush, hush cousin.
Make way!
Attention! Make way!
Jeannette! No, Jeannette, come back!
- Sir Robert has spoken!
- Sir Robert!
Sir Robert, you must send me
out to take part in the war!
Orleans is in great danger,
and even today a battle is raging.
What? Orleans is 200 leagues from here,
nobody knows what's going on there.
Sir Robert!
Jeannette!
That's a very strange thing you said girl.
Yes, they are strange.
I'm sent here to speak to
Sir Robert, but you saw
that he cares neither for
me nor for my words.
Nevertheless before the middle of Lent
I must be with the Dauphin.
Believe me I rather go home
and spin with my mother.
For this is not my proper place.
But there is not one person in the world,
not among Kings, or nobles, or princes
who can bring help to the France we love.
Not once save this maid you see before you.
It's not because of anything in me, but
because the King of heaven wishes it so.
Have you heard of a prophecy?
There is a prophecy that
a maid from Lorraine will save France.
- Have you heard it?
- No, I know nothing of a prophecy.
Why are you here again?
You know Sir Robert won't see you.
Go home girl and don't come back tomorrow.
That's she, coming now.
- Forgive me, but are you the maid?
- I'm Joan, daughter of Jacques D'Arc.
We heard about you in
Lille, we wanted to see you.
And to tell you that we believe
in you, we prayed for you.
We held a mass for you last Sunday.
Thank you.
I know that your prayers will help.
The gates were locked in my face again.
Mother.
I came to take you home, Jeannette.
You must come home, Jeannette.
A dark dream has crept over you for a little
while, but its done no harm, and soon
it will be gone and when it's gone
no one will think of it.
But come home.
I never wanted to hurt you, mother.
For I love you more than
anyone else in the world.
But if I had a
100 fathers and a 100 mothers,
I could not go back.
I must go forward now.
Then tell me where, Jeannette?
Toward what would you go?
- Where's the girl?
- Sir Robert.
That's the one.
Exactly 2 weeks ago you came
to see me and spoke of a battle.
Today a courier came with messages.
There was indeed a great battle on that day.
And a heavy defeat for the Dauphin.
How did you learnt this?
Have you studied witchcraft?
- Oh surely you know I have not.
- That is just what we do not know.
Father Fournier, put her to question.
If you are a thing of evil
and sent from Satan, depart from us.
If you are good and from god, come near
I ask your blessing, father.
And I ask of whatever is evil
fly far from you.
Whatever is good remain to help
our cause in the course of France.
She is no socerer, Sir Robert.
Whatever you have heard or see,
whether prophecy or not,
the devil has no part in it.
Thank you, father.
- You still wish to go to the Dauphin.
- My Lord has commanded me to go.
These 2 gentlemen wish me to
send you forth on this wild
mission of yours, they are willing
to ride with you as escort.
To me it seems like a fool's attempt,
but they believe you may help our country.
Now if there is a chance of that,
I don't want to put anything in the way.
Then it shall all come true.
Goodbye, my child.
Ever since I heard you speak,
I've got a kind of dream.
But I never yet seen it
clearly where I must go,
or what I must do with my life.
But suddenly, when I heard your voice,
it seem to me that I knew.
I come to be your follower.
Thank you.
You are the first.
And I'm quite willing to be the second.
When do we set out?
Today rather than tomorrow.
Tomorrow rather than the day after.
Joan, have you ridden before?
By the time we reach Chinon
I should ride well.
Take care that you ride only by night,
the news of your coming will run ahead like
fire and the enemy will
want to watch for you.
I fear them not.
A mother bears children and gives them to the
world and she thinks she knows them well.
But she doesn't know them at all.
And now you must go. Guard her well.
With many leagues to ride
and icy rivers to cross.
Go to the shrine of redeemer,
mother, and pray for us.
- Goodbye!
- God be with you!
- Godspeed, Joan, come back soon!
- Goodbye, Joan!
- God help you Joan.
- Thank you!
Go then maid of Lorraine,
I expect but little of you,
but go...
and come what may.
Farewell, Joan!
- Goodbye!
- Farewell, Joan!
Well, tell us who you are!
Travelers, my friend, just travelers.
- And who may you be?
- I'm the head constable of Clairevaux.
We're honest men.
You may be, but I must look at you.
Are you a lad?
- Let me tell you why we meet you here.
- Well, tell us and let us go on.
There is a party of
Burgundy soldiers in our town.
They say that they're here
to lay hands on the maid from Lorraine,
the one that is coming to help the Dauphin.
If one of you should be that maid,
- Then go round our village.
- Thank you, constable.
This does not concern us.
My wife send two loaves of bread.
- That was the best we could do.
- Thank you again.
I would like to if you would permit me to
lay them in the hands of the lad myself.
If it should be that you're
the maid from Lorraine,
I don't say that you are,
but if it should be,
I have a message for you from
the people of Clairevaux.
It's this:
"God go with you."
"God go with you and save
France and save us too."
Now we can go to our homes, neighbours,
we've seen her and we've
given her the warning.
Those are the towers of Chinon.
Oh we've come through safely.
We're here.
- Did you bring the gold Tremouille?
- Gold?
Gold? No, I did not.
You should bow when you come
into the presence, Duke.
Your attitude is... slovenly.
- You owe me money.
- Money?
I have definite information that
you plan to abandon your kingdom.
You're leaving us.
You're deserting us.
If I lent you 3,000 crowns,
you dissapear to the North or the
South and I can whistle for my money.
Not only this loan in question but the
enormous sums you already owe me.
Then lend me a thousand.
It's safer, I can't go very far on that.
I'll need your signature.
I refuse to sign until I have the money.
I'll need your signature first.
- Lacky, a quill for my Lord.
- You robber! You thief! You brigand!
Gentlemen, not before the court.
Before he lends me money he demands my
signature at the bottom of a blank page,
and I know why.
Everytime I borrow from
him he uses my signature
to sell some of my territory to Burgundy
to raise the money he lends me.
A prophet has come from Lorraine.
Promising to save France
and crown our Dauphin.
The game is we put the
Count of Clermont on the throne,
he will pretend that he is
the illustrious Charles.
When the evening is over, I shall
be Dauphin by popular demand, huh?
Fortunately, that is not enough.
- Now, sit on the throne.
- Please,
a little obeisance, my good people.
That's better.
Now, let her enter.
Let her enter, I say.
Ah... there are three of you.
And which may I ask
is the maid of Lorraine?
- I am the maid from Lorraine.
- Who are these other maidens with you?
This is Jean de Metz and Bertrand de
Poulengy came with me to guard me.
A family of three?
Sir if you mean anything against the
maid or doubt our respect for her
I advice to watch what you say.
My apologies.
I'd rather nobody knelt to me.
Then nobody will. I assure you, it's not
a position one chooses for comfort.
But come, here's our great Dauphin.
Well, here I sit waiting for the crown
you promised me, maid of Lorraine.
See that I am crowned.
See that I am crowned at once.
Here,
your Dauphin offers you his hand, maiden.
My gentle Dauphin it is you I seek.
I've come a long way to find you
and no other can take your place.
God has spoken to me thru his messengers.
And it is his will that I come to aid
you and that you'll be King of France.
How did you know me?
I can tell you that when we are alone.
What is your opinion?
This girl is dangerous,
there must be a third party.
- I could swear she was sent by your enemies.
- My Dauphin, I say to you
from this hour the war will change.
And your life will change.
But the truth is, Joan, I'm
not the sort of person
God would be very likely
to be interested in.
Truely, I'm not.
Though I'm no worse than the
others here probably but...
God bothers very little with any
of us if you should ask me.
Now, I've been honest with you.
Be honest with me.
What is it you want?
Money?
Lands?
Presents?
I'm a poor man in spite of being...
It is not true that God
takes no interest in you.
You say that to hide yourself from me
as you just now hid among the women.
But God will find you out.
And make you King.
This is an honest voice.
Listen to her, Charles.
I think you've come just in time.
For a moment... I thought
you were the Dauphin.
I'm his cousin, the Duke of Ronson.
I'm glad you're here, good Duke.
The more we gather of the
royal blood of France,
- the stronger is our cause.
- Don't trust her my Lord.
I'm trying not to trust her.
But everytime I looked into her eyes,
- I believe what she says is true.
- More reason to distrust her.
Gentle Dauphin,
if I tell you things so secret that
they are known to you and God alone,
will you believe that I am sent by him?
Come with me, Joan.
Nicholas, unhinge from the plow!
Bring your horse!
Come and join the maid's army!
Maid?
She has no army!
- Then she will soon have one!
- Come along, Nicholas!
- Come along!
- Join us!
Men come flocking by the thousands.
The maid's name is magic.
- My people believe in that.
- Nobody holds back?
Why? Why? Why?
The army gathered.
Men are coming from everywhere.
Gold and jewels are dug from the
ground and poured into the treasury.
Grain and cattle we couldn't
buy are sent as gifts.
You ordered us to raise
the army, we've done it.
- But you still haven't given us the word to march.
- But I couldn't very well
before the girl had been examined by the
archbishop and the officers of the church.
But the examination has finished.
20 learned and loyal priests questioned
her over 3 weeks at Poitiers.
They sent to Domremy and Vaoucouieurs
for all the available evidence of allure.
The church finds Joan untouched,
religious and pure at heart,
- and says so formally.
- Yes.
Although we find nothing except good in her,
still we are not certain if it's
wise to send her into battle.
At present you are at least alive, Dauphin,
but if you throw yourself
into this war you may lose not
only your kingdom, but your life.
I'm not going to lead the army.
She's going to lead it.
A green country girl
leading an army of France?
You will be the laughing
stock of Christiandom.
I've been there for a long time.
Thanks to you... and you.
For years you've tried to convince me that
I'm a pretender to my father's throne.
A scoundrel, an imbecile.
At times I've been inclined to believe you.
But then she came...
and sort me out.
What did she tell you in the chapel?
I can't tell you that.
And I won't.
You'll tell us.
You've never kept a secret in your life.
I shall keep this one.
The truth is I don't yet
know what I want to do.
It's my own head, mind you.
My own head and my crown.
I don't know whether I want to risk them.
But how long are we to wait?
Are we never to relieve Orleans.
I don't know.
The longer you wait the wiser, your Majesty.
I'm not sure of that either.
- Your majesty, l...
- My Dauphin, forgive my bad manners.
For days I've tried to see you but the
guard said no, you were in council...
My dear Joan, that cloak
becomes you, you look radiant!
I thank you for it, my Dauphin,
all preparations are made.
Let us have action.
Men of action and not men of words!
Send me to Orleans, the sign
you asked for will be given.
- Now is the time.
- There is always time, Joan.
No, there is not always time, my Dauphin.
Use me well, for I've told you
I shall last a year but a little longer.
Come ride with us to Orleans.
If you wish me to say yes, you must
not ask for unreasonable things.
You must not ask me to lead an army.
I warn you again, your Majesty.
It's not common sense to trust this girl.
If it be God's will to deliver Orleans,
Why do you need soldiers?
The soldiers will fight
and God will give them victory.
I cound be sure...
You see it's myself that I'm not sure of.
- I'm not sure I would make a good King.
- What you need is faith in God.
When you have that
you have faith in yourself.
I'm not sure God wants me to be King.
Why should God send me help, when I am...
what I am?
Put aside your doubts and fears, my Dauphin.
Be noble as I have dream you to be,
be as God requires you to be,
be as France needs you.
Your France, your nation and your people,
so helpless without you, but unconquerable
as soon as you turn your trust to God.
- Can you look at her face and doubt, my Lord?
- No.
I do not doubt now.
Alenson, take her to the captains.
God is with this girl,
and will be with her in battle.
Gentlemen, I present you Joan the maid.
This is Antel,
Couvert,
Poulon,
Derrogaux,
Serseraille,
and this is Laire.
Hah! By the wild bull of Bujon!
It's a girl... and in harness! Hahaha!
Laire takes pride in being a plain blood
fellow without polish for anybody,
so think nothing of his greeting.
He fights well.
If he fights well, I shall like him.
If I'm a fool, God at least
does not held it against me.
Joan I promise you, that
so long as you don't try
to give any commands, we
shall all get along well.
Oh, I shall not try to give any commands?
I wouldn't know what commands to give.
By the rock of Moses, that's the first
sensible word I heard you say, wench!
You stick to that and by the thunders
of God there will be no trouble.
Don't swear, Laire.
Don't swear?
Now, by the black rock of...
There must be no swearing in
this army among high or low.
Do you want to strike the army dumb?
- This must begin with you.
- You said you would give no order, Joan.
Oh, but this is not a military order, sir.
Surely you must see that.
But the army that is to march on Orleans
was raised in a holy cause.
I saw the men today,
there were women among them,
they drank and swore.
These things must cease and every man
must go to confession before we march.
- Before God...
- Don't swear, Laire.
But if you must, swear by my staff.
By my staff?
What kind of an oath is that?
No army was ever sent to confession.
If we gave such orders, we'll be laughed at.
- I shall give no such command!
- Or any of us, you may be sure of that.
By the swords of Lazarus!
What war have it's leaders had to sit
in council with a green country girl?
A pat on that silly Dauphin of ours.
Bad enough when he was a plain coward.
Now he sends children to lead us.
She's not to lead us, you great ark.
She's to ride before us as a
sort of symbol, a figurehead
for the soldiers to rally around.
No by the love of Janice and all his 2 face
Janissaries, she will not rally me around.
I don't expect she be
of much help in battle,
- Nevertheless I'm grateful to her.
- For what?
For giving us another chance.
Do you play this game often?
Every day all day.
That takes it all.
From now on there won't be
much time for games.
- It's the maid.
- The maid.
- The maid... the one we follow.
- Is it something we can do perhaps?
Yes.
Pick up your dice for a moment.
Pick up your dice, my friend.
They tell me that armies are
like this, that all armies
are like this and that
there is no changing them.
Yet we cannot have victory
we are not worthy of it.
But we came here because
you promised victory.
It is true that God has called us
to the work we are to do,
but it is not enough that God is on our side,
we must be on his side.
What are we to do, maid?
There must be no gambling.
- No gambling?
- No, not even in secret.
And you must not swear
and take God's name in vain.
- What was that?
- No swearing the maid said.
And you must send away all your women.
- What? What's that?
- No women.
- There must be no camp followers.
- She means us.
And before we march each
man must go to confession
and clear his soul of all evil he has done.
What does she thinks we are? Monks?
- Be quiet!
- Let her speak!
Please hear me.
As many as can.
You see, there is no strength in me.
And no strength in my hands.
There is no strength in any of our hands
great enough to win against the English.
Our strength is in our faith.
And if our faith is eaten away by
little things that God hates then,
so there be a million of us,
we shall be beaten back and die.
Yes, come near!
And you men too!
And those who cannot hear!
Give them this message!
We can win only if we become God's army.
It is not easy to stand here before you,
and ask this of you.
Perhaps it will not be easy to do.
But I know that if these things are done
then though the English
hang from the clouds
and ride on the whirlwind,
we shall beat them.
Though their arrows
fall like hail from the sky
and their spears be a ring of steel
and their cannons speak and strike
like the thunderstorm from heaven,
yet they shall be ours!
For this, God has promised.
Our father who is in heaven is our leader.
He will be with us,
while we hallow his name.
He will give us all we need.
Our daily bread,
our victory and the land
that is forever free.
Why are we on this side of the
river if that is Orleans?
You've come this way for order of Dunois.
- Bastard of Orleans.
- He commands here?
Yes, girl. That must be he
riding out to welcome you.
- Greetings Dunois.
- Greetings, my Lord.
You're most heartedly welcomed, my friends.
More so since you bring the maid with you.
This is the hour.
Now is the time.
In God's name, strike!
Strike boldly!
- Forward!
Forward!
- Fire!
Fire!
Forward! Man the slits!
Get those cannoneers!
Fire the catapults!
Fire!
Hurry with the meurtriere!
Follow the white banner!
Forward! For God
and our country, forward!
Follow the banner!
God is with you all, Lords! All!
Fire!
Break thru the walls! Close with them!
In God's name, forward!
The witch, the witch!
Stay there, coward!
Forward, my friends, forward!
Up and over!
France! France!
God is your protector!
Forward! Forward!
Brave men, good soldiers, hurry!
On the walls!
Archer!
Hurry men!
Altogether, to the walls!
I hit the witch!
She's down, she's down!
She's down, the witch is down!
Victory, England has won!
That must come out, Joan.
Hold my amulet, maid.
It will conjure away your pain.
Thank you, my friend.
No, no thanks.
I rather die than use sorcery.
I'll cleanse your wound with
ointment, dress it with lard.
Yes. Bind me.
And I lie here... for a while.
Father Pasquerel, do you hear.
- The Tourre has fallen.
- No, Joan. That's the note for recall.
We've been ordered to retreat.
- Help me to my harness.
- Child, you are wounded.
I don't feel it.
No! No, men of France!
Do not give up!
Courage men, do not fallback!
Laire, Dunois, Alenson, turn back!
Friends, come with me.
We must not give up.
We've done all we can this day, Joan,
our men are exhausted.
- The English are just as exhausted.
- We held a council and decided to retreat.
You've been with your council
and I've been with mine.
And I say to you, the council of our Lord
is better and stronger than yours.
We need only to go forward
and the fort is ours!
If she wants to attack, we attack.
When my banner touches the wall
- we shall have victory!
- Sound the trumpets, forward men!
Forward!
Follow the banner!
On your feet!
Do not give up!
For the glory of France!
To the walls! To the walls!
French men, French men!
There is no turning back!
We shall have victory, God wills it!
- To the walls!
Scale the ladder!
France, rise above!
Death to the enemy!
Forward men, this is the victory!
Resist!
Enter boldly, victory shall be ours!
God say yield!
Yield to redeem your life!
God say yield to redeem your life!
I'll never yield to you, sorceress witch!
You call me harlot, but I have great pity
on your soul and the souls of your men!
Yield to the King of heaven!
I say never!
Not to you, fiend from hell!
No, no, no!
Burn in hell!
Death by fire is a horrible thing.
Joan! Joan,
we've been looking for you.
Why are you crying?
I thought victory would be beautiful.
Look at this so ugly and bloody.
Why it was never a more
beautiful victory than this.
And it's your victory.
The whole city is waiting to receive you.
- You must lead the army through the streets.
- No!
Our soldiers see her banner and run away.
Her victories will be remembered as
the most shameful episode of history.
I quite agree with you.
Mighty England and great Burgundy,
the richest prince in Christendom,
beaten by a green country girl.
My Lord, did you come to
me for aid and advice,
I have this to say:
Think, Duke.
Think carefully before you reject
the maid and her invitation
to the coronation of your dear cousin.
This no moment for jesting,
Count of Luxembourg.
And no subject toyed.
The fact remains that tomorrow
in the Catherdral of Reims
the maid will crown her dancing master,
the Dauphin, King of France.
She's victorious and she has
made no mistakes so far.
If she decides to march on París,
and no doubt she will,
Paris will be lost... and we'll fall.
This is a grave moment in
the history of Burgundy.
- And of England.
- And of the church.
We had to deal with many heretics,
but none as dangerous as this one.
The maid a heretic?
I thought the church had examined her
and found her good, pious and untouched.
If I had sat as judge of Poitiers,
I can assure you the verdict
would have been different.
Count Bishop your hatred
for the maid is justified.
Had she chased me from my
castle or I was noticed
I would have called her much worst names...
than a heretic.
It may be luck for us that
she's exactly where she is.
- Luck?
- She's about to make her first error.
Tomorrow she will crown Charles.
She should set the crown on her own head.
Charles is a fool, a gull, a knave.
He sold out to us before.
- He may do it again.
- You offer him money?
Not I, you. For a truce.
For first time in a 100 years
France is victorious,
Why in heaven's name should
Charles grant us a truce?
Dangle gold in front of him and
he might take it, he always has.
Tremouille is with him as usual.
And Tremouille would sell anything.
Very well my Lord,
I'll send the messenger away.
- Messenger? What messenger?
- By Burgundy.
- He's here begging for a truce.
- Truce? What nonsense.
How much will they pay?
50,000 crowns if you give
the order to stop fighting.
- And how much do you get?
- I? I... I've nothing to do with it.
Your usual share is half, my loving
crocodile and you haven't changed.
I want your share.
I want 100,000 in my hands.
And I'm not even sure that I'll take it.
What shall I tell him?
You tell him to wait, we are in no hurry.
Very well, my Lord.
Sire,
this is the day we fought for
and waited for and it has come.
I'm as happy as any mortal has ever been,
for I've watched the anointing
and the coronation of my King.
- Hurray!
- Long live the King!
Long live the King!
Joan the Maid!
Joan the maid!
On to Paris!
I'll see the messenger in the robing room.
- Oh, they didn't touch, they didn't touch.
- They kissed, they kissed.
Just as I kiss you now.
Your Majesty...
Only our kissing is a very
different matter isn't it, my dear?
- Oh, your Majesty, you must take care.
- No, that's your part to take care.
Mine is to be bold, careless and reckless.
To win the world I win
and depart when I choose.
For look, the world is mine.
Look about you,
this is a real court now
and I'm a King to be reckoned with.
It is lovely, the scent of jasmine.
I could stay here in Sully forever.
Yes, well next week we must go to
Lausa to be feasted,
And the week after that to Pion.
There seems to be no end
to these invitations.
And to the tributes!
See?
And for the reference, do
you remember that little
tailor at Chinon who wouldn't
trust me for a new coat?
Now...
Nay, here comes that vulture again.
Well Tremouille, do you
come to bring me money?
Or to take it away with you?
Your Majesty, this is a much more
important matter than money.
The man's mad.
Here, take my place. And don't cheat!
- She's here.
- Is she alone?
No, she brought Alenson with her.
Remember Sire, it's absolutely imperative
that this time you keep your word.
- When have I not kept my word?
- Yesterday.
Well, that was yesterday.
Greetings, my friends.
Joan, we've asked you
into the presence because
we've missed you, our
most favourite subject.
My noble King, for weeks we have waited
outside the walls of Paris for your arrival.
We should have struck in the hour of victory.
But it is not too late now.
Keep your promise.
Ride with us and.
Paris shall yet be ours.
I'm sorry Joan but you've
to cancel all such plans.
I have just negotiated
a truce with Burgundy.
A truce?
- That's madness.
- It's been too much bloodshed.
The Tourre has been terribly torn,
we need peace.
Our enemies need peace, my King, but not you.
Let them go home to their island and
they can have a good and lasting peace.
We only have to go forward now.
- And their last great stronghold will fall.
- I tell you I have decided upon a truce.
I have decided.
But you cannot do this, my King.
It would mean that you
threw away all the advantages.
We have fought so hard and
have given so much blood to win.
- His Majesty has signed the truce.
- Signed it?
Yes.
And our King never repudiates his word.
You know how this looks, your Highness?
Like betrayal or stupidity.
Or both!
I never said that I was wise, I never said
I was honest, I never said I was handsome.
I'm not a particularly
good person to be a King,
but as long as I am a
King, I will be a King.
What do you know statecraft?
What do you know of the experience which
the heads of nations must stoop?
A ruler must compromise and bargain with
the lowest sort of people, even the enemy.
Men are governed by corruption, they like it.
Men hate corruption and God hates it.
I don't know, but men take
to it very naturally.
Cannot be true.
My King,
have you taken...
money from our enemies?
That is not a question the King
should answer. Or be asked.
Then you have done it.
You have betrayed us.
All of us.
Your country and even yourself.
I shall tell the people of
France what you've done.
I hate war, I don't like battles,
everytime I see French blood flowing I can...
I can feel the hair rise on my head.
- With all my soul I prayed for peace.
- We are at peace.
We cannot have peace so till our land is free.
It happens that I am the one that decides
what war we fight and what peace we keep.
I warn you, make any dirty truce you like.
We'll march on Paris
with or without sanction.
No my dear cousin, you will not.
I ordered the dismissal of the army.
I'm sick of all these warriors
clanking about in armour.
You Alenson, Laire, Dunois, all of you.
Put down your battleaxes, you're ordered home.
And from now on, all commands come from me.
If my captains leave, I shall leave also.
Not your captains, my captains.
And you also will do as you are told.
Not as you pleased.
- About the present...
- Ah, yes.
Joan, we've decided to ennoble you
as a token of our gratitude.
And your town of Domremy
will be exempt from taxation.
But you must remain with the court
until you are given permission to leave.
Now come and join us.
We'll meet again, Joan.
I was never much for... words, Joan.
Except for profanity.
This is beyond swearing.
Goodbye, dear friend.
And good soldier.
Did you say your prayers this morning?
That's what I forgot.
Remember me when you say them.
Joan,
let me kneel to you this once.
You are more to me than any
King or Queen could ever be.
To me you are France and France is yours.
You lifted her up when she was dying
and set a cup of victory to her lips.
We all drank from that cup.
To make a new nation of us.
Made new men of all of us.
Many have fallen and now dead,
as I could wish I were
now that this has happened.
King of heaven,
I've come to fulfill a vow.
The truce with Burgundy signed.
We're at peace and I shall
wear this white armour no more.
I leave it here, at your altar.
We're at peace, my King.
But not such a peace as we dreamed.
No, horribly and evil in armies,
this was much of the war to be fought.
And our enemy is preparing.
And we dwindle here from town to town,
holding court.
Receiving embassies and dismissing soldiers.
From town to town we have feasted.
From city to city I have attended,
doing the King's bidding.
We must feast in many more if the plan holds.
Oh, my sweet God,
the food is bitter.
I would rather sleep on the ground again
and chew my handful of bean and rice and to
face the rank of English spears,
for this way we shall lose all we have won.
Even I can see that.
And my voices have said nothing.
If only my voices would speak to me again.
If they would tell me what I should
do then I could sleep at night
and accept what comes to me
but they are silent.
I asked again and again.
Must I remain with the King and his household?
Busy with the nothings that fill these days?
If my voices do not answer,
I cannot stay here.
I must arm again and find the enemy
and fight as before.
Let my voices speak to me if this is wrong.
Let them speak to me now.
There is still no answer.
Then I must go.
And fight the enemy, King of heaven.
I shall find another armour, not this shining
one in which I rode as your messenger.
But another dark and humble,
fitting to a common soldier.
Long ago my voices told me
that I would be taken prisoner.
When it comes,
at least I shall have arms in my hands.
I think I have courage to die.
But not to die thus in small sick ways.
Inform the master that
we've bring in the witch.
The maid is captured.
Come here, look!
There's the witch! The witch!
The witch is a young girl!
So you are the maid...
The peasant girl who leads armies,
crowns Kings,
and sets soldiers quaking in their boots.
As a French men, your great admirer.
As a Burgundian, your fortunate captor.
- At the gates of Compiegne?
- Yes, my Lord.
The city shut the gates in our faces,
we descended upon her and her few followers.
- We were careful not to wound her.
- Well done, captain.
My dear, look after her good health.
- You shall be in good hands, Joan.
- They've taken my ring.
I want it back.
His Grace, the Bishop of Beauvals.
- Welcome, your Grace.
- Greetings, Count.
A cup of wine?
Wine is always good over a bargain.
Yes, thank you.
Seems to me, I remember this room
under less happy circumstances.
Yes, I remember you were a bit breathless.
You were running from the maid.
- Whom you now have.
- Whom I now have.
Shall I have the money sent up?
5,000 pounds is not enough, your Grace.
I can do much better elsewhere.
5,000 pounds is a great deal of money.
Kings have been ransomed for less.
But this is something
different, this is a witch.
Witches are expensive.
5,000. Yes or no?
I've use 10 bags.
The question is does each bag
contains 500 or 1,000 pounds.
Bishop, could it be
possible that you're lying?
It looks to me as if you're authorised
to go as high as 10,000 pounds.
If I said that I were, you would want 15.
If you're a true christain,
you'd give her up for nothing.
She's a sorceress, a heretic!
An idolatress!
- She must be burned.
- Oh now, now... wait Bishop.
If this is entirely a religious matter,
why do you offer me English coin?
England is a true daughter of our church.
She's with us heart and soul,
in the matter of scorching this heresy.
Oh, yes. When the maid beat the English.
Yes of course, that was heresy.
Not to mention her
putting you out of your Bishoping.
- Whose side are you on, my friend?
- This same side we're all on.
The me side, what's in it for me.
That's my side, and that's your side.
And the English side, and the French side,
and the Burgundian side. Of course...
this girl, she's the only one
I know who is not on the me side.
And that's why I'm ashamed
when I think I would sell her.
- Yes, even for 10,000 gold pounds.
- Very well, 10,000. Will you take it?
If I am not, may God put me there.
If I am me, may he keep me there.
That is a good answer, Joan.
We can do without your comments.
Who council you to throw off
womens clothes and dress like a man?
A thing indecent... and contrary to the
teachings of the holy scriptures.
For that I blame no one.
Having lived among soldiers it was more
fitting for me to wear mens clothes.
But give me a woman's dress and I will
wear it if you permit me to hear mass.
Otherwise I will not put it on since it
pleases God that I wear this one.
All I have done, I've done by the
command of my Lord.
That is all that I've done well.
How do you know that your
voices come from God?
I knew that they came from God because
what they commanded me to do was only good.
My Lords, I have answered
the same questions at Poitiers.
My King charged the Archbishop of Reims
and other loyal and learned priest
to examine me before
I was allowed to lead his army.
Send for the records at Poitiers,
you shall have all my answers.
The examination at Poiters by the Archbishop
of Reims has no relevance.
We are your judges now and
you must answer us!
But you are not fitted to be my judges.
You are my mortal enemies.
English... and Burgurdians.
All of you.
And you are not the church.
You are the valets of the enemy King
whose orders you obeyed.
If I am being tried by the church,
why am I not in a church prison among women.
I am in a English prison guarded
by English soldiers and chained...
chained to my bed. If I must rise for
any purpose I must ask the guards
to unlock the bonds.
We, your judges, keep you chained
because you've attempted to escape.
Is it not the right of all prisoners
of war to try to escape?
You say that you are my judges.
I do not know if you are, but I say this,
take care not to judge me wrongly,
for in truth I am sent by God and
you place yourself in great danger.
Take her back to her cell!
Good day, my Lords.
You and your flawless trial.
The girl's too clever for you!
She ridicules you!
Yes and threatens you in public.
I can assure you, my dear Warwick.
It won't happen again.
No it will not, for there
will be no more public sessions.
You will continue behind closed doors
according to my orders.
Is that the chapel, Father?
- Yes, Joan.
- May I enter?
No daughter, it is forbidden.
Do you know why?
It is forbidden.
Your Grace,
perhaps we should not say
no so quickly to this
child's request concerning
the records of Poitiers.
Since we were not on the maid's side
in the war, we can hardly judge her...
- in unbiased fashion.
- This is an ecclesiastical court,
governed solely by the
unbiased laws of the church.
The laws of the church?
Do they demand English guards at the doors?
Do they insist that English
gold bears the expense?
- Silence Calleis.
- No, your Grace.
Such a procedure contravenes our laws.
- I can take no part in this trial.
- Then you may leave.
And any of you who herd his
opinion may leave also.
But remember this,
if you go now,
you carry my enmity with you.
And the enmity of the King of England.
The King of France and England.
I'm sorry to leave what to your mercy.
Or your lack of mercy.
But for my conscience sake
I cannot witness what
seems to me but a preconceived
and shameful farce.
You will come with us.
- I?
- Yes. You're under arrest.
I should be in a church prison,
guarded by women.
Must you leave me here, Father?
I'm commanded to leave you here.
God keep you, child.
Joan, this is Master Jean Laverne,
who has been assigned by the
most revered Inquisitor of France.
To assist us at you trial.
Master Jean has read all the reports
of the preceding sessions.
And is therefore well
acquainted with your case.
I am Jean and I promise you that
we will judge you justly.
But you're an illiterate
girl and need council.
You may choose one of the
judges to advise you.
I thank you.
But I have no intention of departing
from the council of my Lord.
What do your voices tell you?
To answer you boldly.
Did they promise to deliver you?
Saint Catherine told me
that I would be rescued.
I do not know whether this
means that I would be
delivered by a French attack
upon this city Rouen.
Or something else,
but I was told that I would be
freed by a great victory.
- Can you remember the exact words?
- Yes.
Accept everything with courage.
Do not fear your martyrdom.
For in the end, you shall be
in the kingdom of paradise.
What does the voice mean by...
your martyrdom?
I...
I am not sure.
It may mean what I suffer here in prison.
Night after night, I have no sleep and still
I must come before you and answer questions.
Same questions.
Come before you've met with
what I must endure in my cell.
Without...
without rest, without rest, day or night.
I do not know how much more
I would have to suffer.
I reave for myself to God.
This harlot mocks our court!
You ask me questions I
have sworn not to answer,
and yet you keep asking them.
What do you wish of me that I perjure myself?
Scriveners, stay your hand.
Don't write that answer.
Joan, if we proof to you that
you have acted against the faith,
are you ready to submit to the church?
I beg you to believe that,
I would never do or say
anything against the church.
And if I have done such a thing
I would willingly reject it.
- That is a good answer Joan. Now I...
- If you accept the decision of this court,
you would reject your voices.
If you still maintain that your voices
are right, you reject the church.
If you do not obey, you are a heretic!
I would not reject the voices
of my Lord nor the church!
It seems to me that it is all one.
Our Lord and our church.
Why do you make such a difficulty about it?
Why did you display your
banner at the coronation?
It had shared in the toil.
It was only right that it
should share in the honour.
I appeal to the Pope who is at Rome.
Take me there and I shall submit to him.
- Silence!
This is very serious, my Lord.
- She is within her rights.
- This appeal is expensive.
- We cannot proceed with the trial.
- We shall proceed.
But if we were to continue, the trial
would be illegal and the verdict null.
- You're saved, Joan.
- The devil's tail, Priest!
If I see you whisper to her again
I'll have you thrown into the Seine.
As for this appeal to the Pope,
I refuse to allow it.
The King commands here, not the Pope.
He's paid a high price for this witch.
And he's also paying for
your services, my Masters,
Doctors and Bishops.
That is why I appeal to the Pope,
who takes orders from no King.
The appeal is overruled.
Erase it from the record!
Yes, you surely write what is against
me but nothing that is for me.
Take her away!
May I have your attention, my Lords?
His Grace, the Bishop of Beauvals,
send me the articles of
accusation of this case,
and ask me to give him my opinion
of the conduct of this trial.
I assure your Grace, but
I would hardly hope that
you would trouble yourself
to appear in person.
I fear that my letter might become lost,
as so many others have.
However, having witness today's session,
I am ready to render my opinion.
Write this down, Scriveners.
I, Jean, Bishop of Avranche,
declared that this trial is unlawful.
That the appeal made by the accused
and witnessed by me among others,
is definitely and completely suspensive.
And that all future procedure of this case
must be referred to Rome.
- Why don't we go to my apartment...
- If the maid's appeal is overruled,
it is further proof of
the widespread rumours
that circulate throughout
the Christain world
that this is not a religious
but a political trial.
I warn you, you the so call judges,
you may suceed in sending her to the stake.
But one day, your English King will
be ashamed of these proceedings.
Rome will declare the truth about this girl.
And France will praise the maid
for it's birth as one nation.
And as for you, Pierre Cauchon,
Count Bishop of Beauvals,
I declare you a traitor, for you have
betrayed your country and you betrayed...
your church.
Your Grace, at this time I cannot permit...
I will not permit...
Tomorrow morning, in the cemetery of St Ouen,
we've decided to hold our last session.
With your physician's consent,
we are taking Joan there.
And if she again refuses to abjure,
we're abandoning her
and handing her over to the civil authorities.
I shall order the execution
under being readiness.
This Joan, whom you see before you,
has fallen from error into error,
from crime into crime.
Never before in France has there
appear such a monster.
She's a witch, a heretic, a schismatic
even her King himself is a heretic,
because he sort to
regain his throne
with the help of such an apostate,
we brought you here to this
sacred and divinest cemetary to give
you your last chance in public.
Will you or will you not revoke all the
acts to which your voices drove you
and which where your judges have condemned?
Burn the witch!
I submit to God and our holy Father the Pope.
The Pope is in Rome, we cannot go so far.
You must submit to us.
If you do not, we shall hand you over
to the executioner now.
I submit to God and our
holy Father the Pope.
You must submit to us or die.
If you submit, we'll send
you to a church prison.
Do you hear, Joan. If you
submit, you'll be taken
to a church prison where
there will be women guard.
Joan,
he's reading the sentence
of your excommunication.
Submit.
- This means her death.
- Abjure, Joan!
Abjure!
Abjure?
What does it mean to abjure?
It means to submit to your judges.
If you do, you'll escape the fire and you'll
be delivered from the English prison.
Almost, sweet God.
Submit! Submit!
- Abjure Joan!
- Abjure!
- Please abjure!
Save yourself! Save yourself, Joan!
I submit
my words and actions to you.
- I'll abjure than be burned.
- She submits herself! She submits!
Damn!
No, Joan. You'll sign your name.
Silence!
The maid has submitted.
We must receive her with penitence.
In the name of our Lord, Amen.
At last, you've come back to the
bosom of our mother church.
And thus we absolve you
from the excommunication.
But in order that you
should expiate your crimes.
And to make sure that you
would not fall back into heresy,
we condemn you to perpetual prison,
to the bread and sorrow,
and the water of affliction.
Father, take me to your church prison.
Give me women to guard me.
No! No!
They told me they would
take me to church prison!
Oh! They lied to me!
They lied to me!
No!
Oh, sweet God.
Forgive me. Forgive me.
I was afraid.
What I said...
was for fear of the fire.
I have damned my soul
to save my life.
You speak to me,
and I denied you.
Exactly as I expected.
She has not kept her word.
- She meant nothing of what she said.
- She meant all that she said.
But we have not dealt honestly with her.
The guards are still here, just as before.
She has retained the clothes of a man.
- She has broken her signed abjuration!
- We made it impossible for her to keep it.
- You exceed your function here!
- I appeal to the Inquisitor.
She shall have her
sentence and nothing else.
One moment, my Lords.
If this girl has been tricked
into breaking her vow,
I will not share in a sentence against her.
If we leave your cell, all of us,
will you put on this dress?
No, my Lord, I will not.
I've heard my voices again.
They told me I did a very wicked thing by
denying them but they have forgiven me.
I have faith in them.
I have none in you.
This is a fatal answer.
Joan,
Do you know what this means?
To live without faith is more terrible than
the fire, more terrible than dying young.
I have nothing more to do here.
Send me back to God for whom I came.
Only a child!
- Someone save her! Save her!
- Back away!
Back away! Back away!
You, the devil Bishop!
In the name of our Lord, Amen.
Could I have a cross!
To hold in my hands!
Ah, what shame that after the abjuration
of your errors, the devil of heresy
has once more risen in your heart.
You've returned to your crimes,
therefore we the judges same decree
that you, Joan, commonly called the maid,
have been on the subject of your
pretended divine revelations.
- A relapsed heretic,
- God bless you.
A sorceress, lying, seducing,
pernicious, presumptuous, seditious,
cruel, apostate and schismatic.
And so we abandon you to
the civil authorities,
requesting the same authority that it
may be pleased to moderate its judgement
and if true signs of penitence should appear
that the sacrament of penance
may be administered to you.
I am a good Christain.
Executioner!
Do your duty!
Thus the short life of Joan nearing its end.
But the truth will emerge
in the pages of history.
Her physical death was not a defeat
but her last and greatest triumph.
Father, pray for me.
I will be damned forever,
I've burned a Saint!
Go,
child of God,
daughter of France!
Go.
- Go!
- Oh, sweet God.
You've been with me always.
Be with me now,
through the darkness.
For I meant to hurt no one.
Let none be hurt for me.
Come to her assistance, she sings of God.
Come forth to meet her,
the angels of the Lord.
Receiving her soul,
offering it in the side of the almighty.
May Christ receive you with chorally
and may the angels lead thee to paradise.
And... and that the hour
of our death... amen.
Jesus.
Jesus!