A Japan Association of Music Enterprises
50th Anniversary Project
"But what is it that will make
people happy?" continued Giovanni.
"I don't know,"
Campanella muttered.
"Anyway, we're going to hold on!" said
Giovanni with an explosion of breath
as if his chest were brimming
with new-found energy.
from Kenji Miyazawa's
"Night on the Galactic Railroad"
How many years
have passed since then?
That was the year
we traveled to Shikotan,
the island where
we once lived.
To our old home,
full of so many memories.
To our lost island.
Miss Sawako, we're almost
at the island.
So we are.
We've finally come back.
What's it been, 50 years?
It brings back a lot
of memories, doesn't it?
Not for me.
I get rid of things I don't want
to remember with an eraser.
Can you, though?
I suppose not.
You can't get rid of them.
I can't forget,
even if I want to.
I'm sure it's the same
for you, Junpei.
I suppose it is.
Our old home. The island
where stars fall to Earth.
The island of the Galactic Railroad.
Giovanni and Campanella’s island.
- July, 1945...
- July, 1945.
Eggs, eggs, eggs, eggs—
Over here! Look at me!
Look at me!
No one's home!
- You can have the floaters, Kanta!
- No fair, Brother!
Got 'em.
The floaters are the ones
that are about to hatch!
Here's your eggs back!
Sorry to bother you...
July 4,1945
- Hey, wait!
- Hurry!
- Good afternoon, ladies!
- Hi, Junpei!
- Delivery, ma'am!
- It's so big! Look!
- Thank you, Kanta.
Have a good day, everyone!
- Hello!
- Hey, boys!
- I wish I had their energy!
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
- We're home!
- Oh, there you are.
- That smells so good!
- I'll cook you up some.
- I'll help!
Good boy.
Galactic Railroad, now departing!
All board who's coming aboard!
Hurry, we're now departing!
Depart station!
Campanella, hop on!
Hurry!
Wait for me, Giovanni!
Next stop is Cygnus Station!
Cygnus Station!
GIOVANNI'S ISLAND
Air raid alert!
This is an air raid alert!
More than 120 dive bombers
are advancing towards Nemuro!
Make for the air raid
shelter immediately!
Air raid alert!
This is an air raid alert!
I wonder if the Dawn Corps boys up in
the mountains will shoot them down?
Darn it all.
I think they're up too high
for their guns to reach.
- Let's go to the shelter.
- Hurry.
- Dad!
- Hurry and get to the shelter.
- Yes, sir.
Father, look after the boys.
Don't worry, son.
My father was the commander
of the island's defense force.
Well, in fact the real soldiers,
called the Dawn Corps,
are holed up
in the mountains.
He was basically the head of
the village's fire brigade.
The war's finally come
all the way up here...
Nemuro is burning...
August 15, 1945
- What did His Majesty say?
- I couldn't hear very well...
- It's over...
- The war is over.
August 15th.
Japan... was defeated.
Dad...
Don't worry.
Even if the war is lost, as long
as we have our island...
As long as our people are still alive,
the country will never fall.
What's going to happen
to the country now?
The Americans will come
and make everybody into slaves.
What?
Those Yanks are
red devils, after all.
You're joking...
There's no telling what they'll do
to you womenfolk if you don't hide.
You better paint your faces black
to look like men.
Stop trying to scare me!
Well, I'm off.
Even if we've lost the war,
a fisherman has to fish.
I'll have Kanta
do it today.
Kanta, will you
read this for us?
Yes, sir.
"'What on earth can I do
for their happiness?'
Giovanni, completely despondent,
hung his head.
'Who's to say it wasn't for the best?
However painful a thing might be...'"
Our father loved Kenji Miyazawa's
"Night on the Galactic Railroad"
After I started primary school,
he had me read it out loud
almost every day, too.
He said that our mother loved
this book when she was alive.
We were named after
the characters, too.
Junpei comes from "Giovanni",
and Kanta from "Campanella".
September 1, 1945
- Miss Sawako, good morning!
- Good morning!
Good morning, Junpei, Kanta.
Ma'am, do you think the
Americans will come?
Our grandpa said that the women
should run and hide!
Miss Sawako doesn't have to worry!
They're only after young girls!
What's that supposed
to mean, Junpei?
- Stay down, everyone!
- Junpei!
It's blanks!
They're firing blanks!
Stay calm, everyone!
We're fine!
Look at that flag!
That's not the Americans!
It's the Soviets!
Soviet soldiers are called "Russkies"!
They kill bears with their bare hands!
- Take your seats, everyone.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Ma'am!
- Yes, what is it?
I hear the Iwasakis and Komanos fled.
Shouldn't we run away, too?
It's all right. In times like this,
we must remain calm and collected.
We mustn't panic.
Yes, ma'am.
Miss Sawako! Look!
- It's the Russkies!
- Look at that gun!
Miss Sawako...
Everything will be fine. Stay calm.
Children, take your seats!
Focus only on me.
Can you do that?
0.5...
Go outside! All of you!
Please leave the room.
We're in the middle of a lesson.
All right, can anyone
solve this problem?
Junpei, then...
Please come up to the board
and solve this problem.
Junpei?
Do you know the answer, Junpei?
Yes, ma'am.
Stop right now!
What's the matter?
These people aren't obeying,
Comrade Major.
What do you want?!
Here you are, lad.
Thank you...
- We're leaving.
- Comrade Major?
It's so fast!
Kanta, don't!
Junpei...
The Dawn Corps
had been disarmed
and had come down
to the village.
Poor devils. If they're sent to Siberia,
they're never coming home.
The defense of the island
rests with you now.
Company, STOP!
They're in your hands now.
Company, march!
Surrender your valuables!
What's this garbage?!
Your valuables! Hurry up!
There's nothing left for you to take!
You people keep coming and coming!
Go away!
Go away, I said!
First I can't fish, and now look at
what they did to the house.
- Grandpa!
- Here, take good care of this.
You can come out!
Mitchan!
- What's so funny?
- Your face is all black!
But I had to pretend
to be a man!
Oops! Sorry!
Hey!
- Uncle Hideo!
- Uncle! You're back!
Uncle!
Look at you! I go away for a
while, and you grow up on me!
Where were you?
Off fighting, of course!
I come back, and Japan's nothing
but ashes. Burned to the ground.
And when I'm finally home,
what do I find? Russians, no less!
What's this country coming to?
It's good to have you home, Hideo.
Let's celebrate with a drink.
Oh, by the way.
I have a souvenir for you two.
Really?
And what have we here?
Ta-dah!
- It's the latest train engine!
- You've never seen the real thing.
- Where's mine?
- Play with it together.
You have that locomotive that
Dad bought you, remember?
I'm amazed you got your hands
on something like that.
There are empty houses all over.
I found it in one of those.
- You mean... you stole it?
- Welcome home, sir.
W-Welcome home!
Good, you're all fine.
- Long time no see, Big Brother!
- Hideo, you're alive...
- You bet! Alive and kicking!
- I'm glad to hear it.
The devil's children
have the devil's luck!
- This man isn't dying for his country!
- Hideo!
Oh, this sake is good!
No, I'm staying.
I have a duty as the island's
defense force commander.
Face up to reality, Brother!
Japan lost! The island's been
occupied by the Red Army!
We should just pack up
and leave!
If you want to run,
I'm not stopping you.
Man, what am I gonna
do with you?
Come on, Pops!
Say something!
A fisherman who can't fish might
as well be dead! Am I right?
The Soviet patrol boats won't
be out in a storm like this.
This is the perfect chance
to get off the island.
The storm is just as
dangerous for us, son.
Do you have any other way to avoid
those patrol boats?! Damn it!
They say the boat
washed up this morning.
And the Noguchis had
a little kid, too... That's terrible.
Noguchi's family fled the island
in the storm last night.
They were lost at sea.
Pray silently.
Be seated.
I had planned to spend first period
today on Japanese history,
but the study of Japanese history has
been prohibited for the time being.
What do we study, then?
Today, we will be moving a few desks
into the classroom next door.
That's the lower graders' room!
The families of the Soviet soldiers
will be coming to the island.
We must vacate
this classroom.
Are the Russkie kids
gonna study Japanese?
Or are we gonna have
to learn Russian?
What's that?
- It's electricity!
- Wow! The island's getting electricity?
Fly!
Junpei, look at it go!
Awesome!
Fly all the way to the sky!
Who's she?
Excuse me, who are you?
What brings you to our house?
That book!
That's Dad's book!
Give it back!
Give back our book!
Hey! Open the door!
Open the door! Open the door!
- Kanta, stop!
- Open up!
Hey! Over here!
The Russkies claimed the main house.
Starting today, we're living here.
Thanks for having us, Hana!
No way!
Why us?! Why is this
happening to us?!
Try some of your uncle's
special burnt rice. It's good stuff!
- We'll run out of rice soon, though.
- Where's Mitchan?
She fled the island with the rest
of the workers.
- I hope she's okay.
- Oh.
- Mitchan's not coming back?
- I guess not.
I brought you something amazing.
This is round two!
Pretty cool, huh?
Amazing, huh?
And you have Uncle Hideo to thank.
For round three, we'll make
it move with batteries!
- Really?
- Oh, wow!
Thanks, Uncle!
Actually, Junpei, I have
a favour to ask you.
At 10pm tomorrow, can you make sure
there's no Russkie boats around?
If there aren't, can you light a
bonfire at the top of the cape?
Don't let the Russkies
find out what you're doing.
I can't do that!
Sure you can.
You're a man, aren't you?
But I...
We'll run out of rice if we don't do
something. We'll starve, you know?
Look! This was left behind by
the Takashimas when they fled.
It's like they're asking us to
put it to good use, don't you think?
Better to use the proceeds to buy rice
than let the Russkies have it, right?
No one will miss it, right?
This will let our own
family survive.
Here! Special treat!
I'm home.
Look at you, the war is over,
but you're busier than ever!
I bid you good day, young men! Toil hard
with grand ambitions in your hearts!
I'm counting on you!
Later!
"Tickets, please."
"Thank you, sir."
- "Here!"
- "Thank you, sir."
"Is... this all right?"
"Did you bring this from
the third dimension, sir?"
"I'm not really sure."
"Your ticket is in order. We will
arrive at the Southern Cross
at around the third
hour tomorrow."
"Wow, would you look at this!
You could even go to the
real Heaven with this ticket!
And not just Heaven! This is
a free pass to go anywhere!
With this ticket, I bet you
could go wherever you wanted
aboard this imperfect, imaginary,
fourth dimensional galactic rail road.
You're one lucky fella!"
I was dreaming?
Dad?
Oh, no!
- Junpei!
- Ow!
What are you doing
out here?
Don't sneak up on me like that!
I burned myself!
Beat it, kid!
- You're a kid, too!
- You wet the bed!
All right, fine...
Here.
Don't tell Dad
about this, okay?
Okay.
Red dragonfly in sunset sky
I saw it one day from nanny's back
so long ago now.
Picking mulberries
in mountain fields,
put 'em in our little basket,
was that all but a dream?
Just fifteen,
nanny went away to marry...
Hey, that's our organ!
Red dragonfly in sunset sky
. . .about her true love,
whose letters she was keeping.
Picking mulberries
in mountain fields,
. . .about her true love,
whose letters she was keeping.
- Red dragonfly in sunset sky...
- Apple and pear trees were blooming...
- ...resting at the top of a thin pole...
- Katyusha set out on the banks...
We're home!
Uncle!
I went ahead and laid out the tracks.
It's just about finished.
Will it work, Uncle?
It would be a lot simpler if those
Russkies would wire up the house.
Okay, all done!
Okay, you two.
The train drivers sit here.
Let's see, when is
the next one?
Junpei, my next run
is next week!
Make sure the coast
is clear, boy!
- How do we work this?
- What do we do?
It's simple! It'll move when
Junpei twists that dial!
- This makes it move?
- Wow!
And now, I must away!
Don't try to stop me!
It's moving!
Look!
It's the same kind of track!
- Should we?
- Yeah!
We are about to depart!
All aboard!
Look, it's got a ribbon on it!
"The fine little train went on
through the fields
of heavenly marsh grass
waving in the breeze,
on through the faint blue light
of the triangular beacons,
on by the water
of the great river..."
"The fields outside looked like
a magic lantern.
Triangular beacons - a hundred,
no, a thousand..."
"Campanella still whistled
lonesomely to himself,
and the little girl looked off in
the same direction as Giovanni..."
"And they saw that on the
shimmering edge of the Milky Way,
heavenly fields of marsh grass
were glistening silver
and murmuring wavelike
in the wind."
May 28,1946
So, what shall we
sing today?
- "The Village Blacksmith"!
- "We Are Children of the Sea"!
I want to sing
"The Monkey's Palanquin"!
Let's do math today.
Katyusha set out on the banks,
on the steep and lofty bank.
She was walking, singing a song
about a grey steppe eagle,
about her true love,
whose letters she was keeping.
About her true love,
Red dragonfly in sunset sky
I saw it one day from nanny's back
so long ago now.
Picking mulberries
in mountain fields,
put 'em in our little basket,
was that all but a dream?
Got you!
Oh, crap!
Try and catch me!
Sorry!
Playing with you guys was fun.
"Ice"
Tanya.
Tanya?
Yes, Tanya.
Tanya!
- What are your names?
- Us?
Giovanni.
Giovanni?
She wouldn't understand
our names in Japanese, anyway.
Campanella!
Campanella?
Da, da!
- Giovanni!
- Campanella!
- Hey! Get off my cart!
- Sorry!
Please come in.
Wow...
Kanta, quiet!
What's this?
This is huge!
This is Grandpa and Dad's room!
And this is our room!
Look at what they've
done to it...
This one is my room.
All of our things are gone...
I came from here.
From here...
to here.
This is our island?
It's so small...
Sure you came from
a long way away.
I've moved from one place
to another all my life.
And now, to this island
at the ends of the earth.
My papa is an officer, so we
have to go wherever he's sent.
Supper's ready.
Wow...
This looks so good!
Hey!
I'm home.
That commander,
he's Tanya's dad?
I see we have guests for dinner.
Good evening, lads.
Enjoy the meal.
Let's eat!
Let's eat—
- Oh, I get it!
- Here goes!
Oops!
That's hot!
Oh, poor thing!
Come, dance with me!
- That's my girl!
- One more time!
Let's dance!
Come on!
I'll dance with you!
All right, Campa!
Like this! Then this!
Then this and this and this!
As I watched Kanta
dancing so happily,
it reminded me of when
Mum was still alive.
I was overcome by a warm feeling
that I hadn't had in a long time.
- Maybe I'll join Tanya's family!
- You'll what?
Then I'll get to eat great food
and dance all the time!
A Japanese can't become
a Russkie, dummy!
Why don't you
marry Tanya, then?
You like her, don't you?
I... I don't. Okay?
I'll marry her, then!
You can't do that!
You just... can't!
I'm glad you're here, Junpei!
- Where's Kanta?
- He has field chores today.
Too bad, I've got
some tasty treats.
- Look!
- Wow!
They've got everything
on the mainland.
I'm heading out again tonight.
I'll be counting on you!
- Please, no more...
- It's for the good of the country!
Endure the unendurable and
suffer the insufferable! Okay?
Better hide the rice. Can't be
too careful these days.
What do we have here?
Way to go, Big Bro.
Oh, well.
See ya. Don't forget
about tonight, little man!
- Oh why me?
- Hi, fair lady!
Hello.
Zdravstvujte, Madam!
Goodness, Campa,
your Russian is excellent!
Where's Tanya?
Oh, she left with Giovanni
to pick raspberries.
With Giovanni?
Not that way, Tanya!
There's lots of raspberries
over this way!
We'll do that later. Look at
all these flowers! Come on!
- We're not picking raspberries?
- So beautiful...
No, not like that!
So pretty...
"Pretty"?
The ice man is out here?
- Let's go!
- Da!
That's it.
That should be enough.
Dad?
Be careful.
Giova—
Thank you for everything.
But you've done enough.
If the Soviet soldiers find this,
it'll spell big trouble for you.
Please, let me help.
You can't distribute rice to
the whole village by yourself.
But it's only a matter of time
before we're discovered.
I mustn't ruin your life.
No!
Being useful to you
makes me happy, Tatsuo.
You know my feelings for you
ever since we were little.
I won't go.
Let's go!
Listen, Tanya. You can't tell
anyone what we saw here today.
I understand.
- Promise me!
- I promise!
- Go home, then!
- I won't go!
Go home! Go! Go!
No. I'll sit here until I rot, and the
animals will feed on my carcass.
What am I gonna do?
What's the matter, Giovanni?
I'm seeing if there are any
Russkie boats around.
Soviet. Boats.
Boats?
No, everyone is celebrating tonight.
There won't be a patrol.
Boats. No come.
Really?
Really.
There's a blanket in my bag.
Use it if you want.
Give it back! Give it back!
You want to draw me,
don't you, Giovanni?
Draw you?
Make me look pretty.
I wished that time would stand still
and we could stay that way forever.
That's Uncle Hideo's boat!
Junpei... Where did you go
with Tanya today?
Come on, what were you
doing with Tanya?
- What's the big idea?!
- Uncle!
Are you trying
to get me killed?!
Thank goodness, you're alive!
Of course I am! It'll take
more than that to knock me out!
I'm sorry, Tanya said
there was no patrol, so I —
- "Tanya"?
- Yeah.
Oh, that girl in the main house?
Now I see.
She's the Soviet commander's daughter.
Be careful, you hear?
Beware a pretty face, kiddo!
What? She's not like that, I —
- By the way, is your dad around?
- He's not home.
He left real early
this morning!
He's an early riser, my brother...
- What is it, Junpei?
- Something's been bothering me.
Like what?
Dad and Miss Sawako
were at the cave, and—
What? What about the cave?
Why were they together at the cave?
That's the Dawn Corps' emergency stores!
You can't just help yourself to them!
They belong to all of us. We need
them to keep from starving.
They mustn't fall into
the Soviets' hands!
Don't be stupid! I'll turn that
rice into money on the mainland.
- That's the smart move!
- I won't let you!
Try to stop me!
Enough. The folks next door
will hear.
I get it, you've been getting the rice
to the villagers through Sawako.
- Distributing it from the school...
- Not another word, I mean it.
So, are you two an item?
The war is over, Bro.
It's time to face up
to reality.
Hideo...
July 16, 1946
It's Sawako!
It's me, Sawako!
- It's Miss Sawako!
- What's going on?
Please open up!
Open the door!
- It's Hideo, he—
- What about Hideo?
Hideo was trying to smuggle out
the rice, and he was caught by a patrol!
If he talks—
Tatsuo, wait!
Look after the boys, Sawako!
Dad!
She's the Soviet commander's daughter.
Be careful, you hear?
Don't go, Dad!
Dad...
Dad... Dad...
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Dad!!
Tanya!
- Giovanni? What's the matter?
- Tanya! My dad's been taken!
What? Speak slowly.
Tanya, did you tell them?
Tell them what?
Your father arrested my dad!
Because you talked!
I didn't say anything...
Liar! How come your father
knew about the cave, then?!
- It wasn't me!
- You told him!
I said nothing!
I said it wasn't me!
What's the matter, pumpkin?
Wasn't that Giovanni I heard outside?
But they took my dad...
Dad's been arrested
by the Russkies...
"'What kind of light is that?
What can they be burning
to get such red flames?'
asked Giovanni.
'It's the Fire of Scorpius,' said
Campanella, again referring to his map.
'O God, look into my heart,'
prayed the scorpion.
'Instead of throwing my life away
in vain like this,
grant that my body be used for
the true welfare of all.'
And then the scorpion's body
suddenly broke up
into beautiful crimson flames,
and he was placed in the heavens
to light the darkness of the night.
My father said that the fire
burns to this very day.'"
September 25, 1947
Genzo! Genzo!
Genzo!
What's all the ruckus?
Everyone on the island is being
sent back to the mainland!
They say to gather at the harbor
with only what we can carry!
Get a move on!
- Grandpa?
- Right.
- Will we be allowed back?
- Move it!
Put on every piece of clothing
you can and wait outside.
Miss Sawako will
be here for you soon.
Here you go.
You are a big boy now, Kanta.
Grin and bear it.
It's fine.
I'll catch up with you soon.
Until then, look after Kanta.
You can count on me, Grandpa.
Is everyone ready?
Miss Sawako!
Everyone's heading to the wharf.
We have to hurry.
Right.
- And your grandfather?
- He said to go, he'll catch up.
Uncle Genzo?
I'm an old man who doesn't
have many years left.
I'm sorry, but look after
Junpei and Kanta for me.
With us fishermen, we live,
we eat, we fish, and we die.
We're content with that.
That's a life we're proud of.
Hey! Miss Sawako!
- Kanta!
- Miss Sawako!
Junpei! Kanta!
It's Uncle!
- Hideo!
- You're okay!
You are speaking to an
indestructible wandering crow!
They interrogated you, right?
Sure, but your uncle
doesn't break easily.
Your dad is so stubborn.
If he'd played along,
they would've let him go.
It was you?!
Hey, It's not like I
sold him out or anything.
I tried to help him.
Oh, well.
Say, where's Pops?
I asked Miss Sawako
about him afterwards.
She said my grandpa
had made up his mind
that his last moments
would be on the sea.
I wonder if we'll ever be able
to come back to the island?
Junpei! Look!
Isn't that Tanya?
Tanya...
I'm sorry.
Tanya, I'm so sorry.
Tanya!
Tanya! Tanya!
And that was how
we left the island.
- Haven't we reached Japan yet?
- We must be almost there.
It's freezing...
Need the loo...
Give her back!
Give back my baby!
Please!
Get off me!
Please! Give her back!
- We're not allowed!
- lt's the orders!
The baby's dead.
There's nothing else to do.
No!
Yasuko!
Yasuko! Yasuko!
Poor woman...
Day after day,
the storm raged on.
October 3, 1947
What is this place?
This doesn't seem like
Nemuro or Hakodate.
This isn't Japan!
Keep walking!
Sugar! Sugar!
Who wants sugar?
It's sweet!
I'm beat...
This is so heavy...
Kanta...
Are you okay, Kanta?
Sweet sugar, sir!
Wait here!
Three sugars, please!
Thanks.
Sugar!
Turn those frowns upside-down!
Wow, it's sugar!
Thanks, Uncle!
A token of my love, milady!
Be my guest!
The bottom is sand!
Sand? That little crook!
Where'd he go?!
Come back here!
- It's so fast!
- It's so big!
For the first time in our lives,
we saw a real train.
- Wow!
- That was the real thing!
The internment camp was a
primary school at the top of a hilt.
Hey, no cutting!
This is all?
It's gross...
Boo!
Ta-dah!
- Wow, biscuits!
- Eat up!
- Look, everybody!
- Let's share them.
Apparently, we're in Maoka,
in western Karafuto.
Oh.
Everybody from the islands
is being rounded up here.
Then a ship from Japan
will come pick us up, they say.
So we'll be able to
go back to Japan?
I'm not so sure. Something tells
me it won't be that simple.
Why?
- Junpei, I'm so cold...
- Kanta?
I'm so cold...
Everything will be okay.
I wonder what Tanya
is up to?
With everyone gone,
she must be lonely.
- Get moving!
- Get on the trucks!
Every day, they took the adults
deep into the mountains to out wood.
It was back-breaking work,
and some of them got hurt
or got sick from the cold.
Kanta...
Where is Dad?
Don't worry.
I'm sure he's fine.
Miss Sawako...
Were you and Dad—
Forget it.
I care a great deal
for your father.
He knew that he would be arrested
if he went to the cave.
He felt it was his duty.
I wonder if Dad has turned
into the Fire of Scorpius...
Well, I —
I'm sure that he has.
Your father lived
his life for others.
And for you boys.
I have to be strong now, too.
You gave me the courage
to go on, Junpei.
It's so cold...
Once they've taken everyone in
the girls' school, it'll be our turn.
- Hang in there.
- I can't...
I have great news!
I found out where Tatsuo is!
- Dad is alive?!
- Really?!
At the logging camp, I met a guy
who's housed in the same place!
He says he's in the
prison camp to the north!
Beyond those mountains!
It's just a stone's throw from here!
- Thank goodness...
- Kanta!
He didn't get sent to Siberia!
He said he's just past
those mountains, right?
- Did he mean those mountains?
- I guess.
Junpei, I'm gonna
go see Dad.
- Let's go!
- How?
We'd have to go way beyond
that train's final stop.
I don't care!
See? You have to
get better first.
I'd get better real quick
if I saw Dad!
Still...
Don't you want to ever
see Dad again?!
But how?
Let's take the
Galactic Railroad there!
Kanta...
I'm freezing...
What's the matter?
Those kids!
Kanta!
- Kanta! Hurry!
- Junpei!
Go on!
Real trains sure are bumpy, huh?
This will take us to Dad
in no time flat!
Kanta, are you okay?
This thing cost me
everything I had, damn it!
Will we catch them?
The end of the train line
is just ahead.
- I'm so sorry...
- Don't worry about it.
- Thanks.
- Are you okay?
I'm fine...
If they got off the train and walked,
they should be around here.
You two idiots!
Uncle Hideo!
If I were a Soviet soldier,
you'd be dead right now!
What were you thinking?!
We're sorry.
Come on, we're going back!
No! I'm gonna see Dad!
Kanta!
No! Put me down!
You dumb kid! Even if you
do see him, then what?!
I wanna see him!
We're going to see Dad!
Our minds are made up!
Ow!
You stubborn little kids!
That's the last thing he wants!
No! We're seeing him,
no matter what!
Of all the stupid...
Hey!
Come back here!
Uncle, please!
We want to see Dad!
No!
I can't let you two die
in a place like this!
No, I want to see him!
You're the one who said he was
just a stone's throw away!
Fine, I said that.
But I didn't mean it literally!
What am I gonna do
with you two'?
Come on, Sawako!
Talk sense into them!
- I'm going, too.
- Wha—?
Please, let us go.
I want to see Tatsuo, too.
Besides, we're closer to his camp
than we are to ours.
Guards might be
on our trail, too.
Oh, for crying out loud...
At a time like this,
what's a man supposed to do?
Could one of you tell me?
- Thank you, Uncle!
- Thank you!
- Cut it out, damn it!
I wish I were as popular
as my brother...
Man, you two are heavy...
What's that?
A fortification?
It's so warm...
Thank goodness
for this pillbox.
- I'd love a hot bath right about now.
- Here.
Boy, this warms you right up!
Hideo!
Wow, it's freezing!
What's up, Sawako?
- Soldiers.
- What'?
Looks like they found
where I hid the car.
- Sawako, wake up the boys!
- Right!
What's wrong?
While I keep them distracted, you
and the boys make a break for it.
Here's the address of our
relatives on the mainland.
Junpei, look after Kanta
and Sawako, you hear?
Uncle...
Hideo...
If I were a Soviet soldier, I could give
you a big bear hug to say goodbye.
Maybe I will anyway.
Sawako. I always
loved you.
I hope you get to see
your dad, Kanta.
Uncle...
Hey, I'm an indestructible,
wandering crow!
And now, everyone,
I bid you farewell.
- Look, look!
- Halt!
Halt!
Stop, or we'll shoot!
Let's go, boys.
Just a little further, Kanta. Hold on
until the settlement up ahead.
Kanta...
"Wow, would you look at this!
You could even go to the
real Heaven with this ticket!
And not just Heaven! This is
a free pass to go anywhere!"
Kanta, this is a sign that
we can make it to see Dad!
We're almost there!
Junpei...
This is the Galactic Railroad,
isn't it'?
I have this free pass
to go anywhere!
Please take me to where
my father is!
Please!
Please! Let us on board!
Please let us on!
Let us on, please!
Eat this and go.
Thank you so much.
About that matter we discussed.
I do hope we can count on you.
I swear...
If we weren't talking about kids,
I wouldn't feel the least bit obligated to help a bunch of Japs.
Go on, move it!
There's nothing to see here.
It's so warm...
Junpei...
Take a look
out that window.
- What's this?
- My end of the bargain.
I only pulled it off because I'm on the camp's kitchen staff.
Thank you so much!
So kind of Japan to send ships for you,
but not bother to send us home to Korea.
Junpei!
"Wait here tomorrow at midnight.
-T"
Dad...!
"Wait here tomorrow at midnight.
-T"
That day was the
Russian New Year.
The night of their
Yolka Festival.
Junpei...
Happy New Year!
A mail troika dashes
along the frozen Mother Volga...
Hey, cool it!
We'll get in trouble!
Relax! The Commandant
will overlook it today!
The coachman hums a sad tune
and shakes his head...
Hey, come down here
and drink with us!
As you command!
There!
No, wait!
It's Dad!
Kanta! Kanta!
Dad!
What were you thinking?!
What if you're caught?!
It's not safe here!
Go back this instant!
Go back.
Go back right now!
Junpei!
- Kanta!
- Dad!
Thank you.
I'm so glad you came.
I'm so glad!
We came on the
Galactic Railroad!
You did?
You did, did you?
Dad!
Junpei!
Kanta!
Dad!
Wait for me! I'll come
home alive, no matter what!
Thank you, Sawako.
Please look after the boys.
I will.
Dad...
Let's go.
Kanta!
- Kanta!
- Kanta! Kanta!
- Are you all right, Kanta?
Kanta!
Tomorrow? Then...
Yes. Of course.
Kanta...
Here.
Thank you.
Put them on a truck
and take them to Kholmsk.
Comrade Commandant?
A Japanese repatriation ship is
leaving from Kholmsk tomorrow.
- Make sure they're on it.
- At once!
Happy New Year!
Kanta! We're going home!
We're going back to Japan!
I told you to keep quiet!
Can't you see that he's sick?
Be kind and let them talk.
The stars are so pretty...
Are we riding
the Galactic Railroad?
That's right! We're Giovanni
and Campanella!
You and me,
together forever!
Look, Kanta! The Indian and
the Bird Catcher are here, too!
I can see the Southern Cross
and the big Coalsack!
Junpei...
Am I gonna die?
No way! You're not
gonna die, not here!
We have this magic ticket to go
wherever we want, remember?
See, Kanta? It's a ticket
for the Galactic Railroad!
It is...
It's a magic ticket that will let you go
anywhere you want in the whole universe!
Kanta, let's go home to Japan.
We'll head straight home and
eat a whole bunch of tasty food!
We can do anything.
What do you want to be, Kanta?
I know! A conductor on the
Galactic Railroad, right?
An airplane pilot?
You could even be a sailor or
own a toy store or a bookshop!
You can be anything!
When you grow up, you can even
get married and have kids!
You can ride in cars,
sing songs,
go swimming, see movies,
go fishing!
You're right, Junpei...
I can see a light...
I wonder if it's
the final stop?
No! Don't go there!
I can see a lovely field...
It's such a lovely field...
This has to be
the final stop on the line.
Dummy!
We're supposed to stick
together forever!
Right, Kanta?!
Kanta?
Kanta!
Kanta...
Hey!
- Uncle?!
- Hideo!
I'm an indestructible,
wandering crow, you know!
Hideo, what happened
to your leg?
The Russkies are rusty,
but their bullets have bite.
Did you see Tatsuo?
Hey, Kanta.
What's the matter?
He didn't make it, huh?
Damn.
Come on, let's all
go home together.
Honey!
If you die, you get thrown
by the wayside.
Junpei! Prop up Kanta!
Make it look like he's alive!
Talk to him! About anything!
There has to be something!
Think!
I know! Kenji Miyazawa!
Wasn't the Galactic Railroad born here?
It was! Kenji Miyazawa
came to Karafuto
because he wanted to talk
to his late sister.
The Galactic Railroad was his way of
communicating with his sister in space!
That story was born right here!
On this very spot!
Junpei!
Kanta. Let's go home together.
Back to Japan!
"It was at that precise moment
that it happened.
In the far distance of the
Milky Way's downstream course,
a cross, bejeweled with bright
orange and blue lights,
appeared, standing shimmering
in the midst of the river."
Kanta, can you see it?
Can you see the cross?
"'Hallelujah! Hallelujah!'
Brightly and happily the passengers'
voices resounded together.
From far off in the distant,
cold depths of the sky
came the clear, bracing,
indescribable blast of a trumpet."
Kanta, can you hear it?
Can you hear it?
Just a little further.
Just ten more meters!
There's the border!
It's Japan!
"I'll no longer be afraid
of that vast darkness.
I'd go looking in there for what
would make people happy.
You and me, always together!
Always together!
Always together,
forward we go!"
"Together!
Hey! Don't those fields
look so lovely?
And everybody's gathered there!
That must be the real Heaven!
Look! She's there!
There's my mother!"
Kanta, we're home!
We've come home to Japan!
Kanta...
More than fifty years have
passed since all that happened.
The island where my family lived...
The island where I met Tanya...
Our island stood before us,
looking exactly the same.
"Seno Family Grave"
We've finally managed
to come back.
Kanta.
Tatsuo.
That day, a primary school
graduation ceremony was held.
For those of us who weren't
able to graduate back then.
"Welcome, Visitation Group!"
I hereby certify you have completed
your primary school education
at Shikotan National People's School
after a 56 year course of study.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- I'll never forget that.
- Me, neither.
Wait, did that happen?
Tanya!
Giovanni?
My grandma told me
to give that to you.
Is Tanya here?
This is Nina.
She is Tanya's granddaughter.
Tanya was my mother.
She passed away last year.
She always said that she
hoped to see you again.
So, she's gone...
Then this is for you.
"Night on the Galactic Railroad"
What's it about?
When people die, they rise up
into the heavens
and become stars
in the night sky.
Those countless stars fill the sky,
shining brightly and eternally,
and we live our lives down here,
basking in their light.
That's what the story is about.
That's very beautiful.
Giovanni? Shall we dance, too?
Thank you.
Hold this, Mum!