Good morning.
Morning. Back to work.
November 27, 1937.
They say the Japanese
razed Shanghai to the ground.
I just don't want to believe that.
Typical Chinese propaganda.
AlI is quiet here in Nanking.
Except for a few
who are running scared.
l hope our leaving doesn't
make it seem like l'm backing out too.
But shouId l go around
telIing everyone
I've been promoted to director?
And was called to Berlin?
Of course not.
Put me through to John Rabe.
But still.
my heart bleeds at the thought
of leaving this alI behind
after so many years.
Hello, Rabe household.
No, no, no. That won't work.
You've got to tilt the piano.
What are you doing? Tilt it.
-l'm telling you, it won't fit.
-Well, it went in.
-Yes, 20 years ago.
-l suppose the piano grew since then?
Put it down, put it down.
My God,
these idiots are good for nothing.
December1. 1937.
A Iarge Japanese force lies in wait.
just 70 km off Nanking.
So says Chang, my Chinese driver.
He won't say who told him.
All the same,
we're off in two days.
Japanese or no Japanese.
Though it wouIdn't be bad if Japan
gained more infIuence in China.
After all,
they are aIlies of the Reich.
-What about the hat?
-l loved that hat.
-We agreed, everything we haven't...
-Yes, fine. Get rid of it.
-Do you still need insulin?
-No, l've got enough.
When l'm dead.
l know, then l can read your diary.
But not before.
l think l'll outlive you
out of sheer curiosity.
That's my tactic.
Boss!
Chang! How many times? Knock first.
-But boss...
-For God's sake!
We knock in this house.
Now get out.
How can someone be so dumb.
-There was a knock.
-l heard it, but he has to learn.
We leave in two days.
-lt's the principle of the thing.
-Come in.
Just has arrived Herr Fliess.
What? Here already?
Couldn't he call first.
He call.
But you not have time when l tell.
Chang,
what's the point in you having a head?
Well, so that...
So that it not rain into my neck.
Quite right.
Herr Fliess.
l'm John Rabe. Welcome to Nanking.
-Heil Hitler.
Hope you had a good journey.
This is Herr Han.
He is my deputy, soon to be yours.
Heil Hitler.
Welcome to Nanking.
You wouldn't believe
how long they took to learn that.
Not long enough it seems.
He's saluting with his left hand.
Not the left.
Right hand. Right hand!
That's it.
The Chinese are like children.
You have to teach them,
but they do what they're told.
You have to be able to spot
a good Chinaman right away.
You have to see it at first glance.
That, for example,
is a good Chinaman.
Those are our W-923 systems.
We provide
for the whole province of Jiangsu.
Over 15 million people.
The population is growing so rapidly
that we'll hit our capacity soon
without the dam.
How does it feel
to be returning home after so long?
Siemens sends me to China,
so l go to China.
Siemens wants me in Berlin,
so l'm off to Berlin.
lt sounds as if you'd rather stay.
That's the control unit
for the system.
You could call it
the heart of the plant.
lmpressive,
what you've built up here, Rabe.
But so much work,
just for the Chinese?
For Siemens.
ln a few years we'll make millions.
You haven't been told?
Rabe, Germany is taking a new course.
And so is Siemens.
What's that supposed to mean?
There isn't going to be a dam.
Siemens Nanking is to be phased out.
What the hell!
We've wiped out the Chinese here.
Our armored divisions
are proceeding to the west.
We are now preparing
to advance on Nanking.
Who is leading the advance?
Major Ose, Your lmperial Highness.
A great undertaking
for such a young man?
Yes, sir.
But young men
are capable of great deeds too.
Your report, Major.
This is our position.
My troops
are joining the 33rd lnfantry.
And
Lieutenant Yanagawa's Sixth Division.
We will surround Nanking
from three sides and close ranks.
This way
we will avoid significant losses
and force the city to surrender.
Major.
Have you ever
taken part in an elephant hunt?
No, Your Highness.
You don't encircle an elephant,
wear it out or force it to surrender.
Either you kill it,
or it will kill you.
ls that clear.
Dora?
My God! What are you doing in here?
-What are you doing in here?
-Back to bed, it's a surprise.
Have l forgotten
my own birthday or what?
l know how hard it is for you
to leave everything here.
You don't know that.
Okay, perhaps l don't.
But l do know
nobody could have done a better job.
Nobody.
And that's why l made you this cake.
-Gugelhupf.
Shujuan, a little to the left.
Welcome to the Nanking NS group.
l'm Krüger, group president.
l'll introduce you to the others.
This way, please.
-And that's mine, gentlemen.
-l'll get you next time, l swear.
This is the NS group?
We're not all here yet, but...
Gentlemen!
And what is that?
Bernd.
No, leave it. l'll do it.
We share the room with the...
With the English Veterans Club.
How dare you...
-Hello everybody!
-That's Hans.
Ah, you must be the new one?
Hans Scheel, baker by trade.
Please excuse my tardiness.
But l brought you something.
Cinnamon rolls. They're still warm!
That's unbelievable.
Did you really join the Pa¤
to eat pastries
under a photo of the King of England?
No! We have talks too.
The conditions you tolerate here
are scandalous.
And that is the flag we sent you
for the Party's anniversary?
You haven't even opened it.
We'd need to build a tower,
it's so big.
lf you were real National Socialists,
you would have done just that.
Here too.
Why's that, Dr. Xu?
To pull out now
would be a terrible mistake.
China is the market of the future.
We'll regret it forever.
There is no war yet,
and if the Japanese do come,
then they'll need electricity too,
probably more than the Chinese.
You can't close Nanking
without asking me.
l set the whole thing up myself.
Herr Lehmann, l...
Herr Lehmann?
-They're closing Nanking down.
-They can't do that.
They can.
They haven't promoted me.
They kicked me upstairs.
They tricked me.
And the dam...
lt would have been my legacy.
And then that Fliess comes along.
-That awful little cretin.
-John, John.
Look at me, please.
This is our last night.
Let nobody spoil it.
Not Fliess, not Siemens
not the Japanese.
And certainly not you.
Your Excellency. What an honor.
-What a toady.
-Fukuda?
l have always liked him.
You've had no dealings with him.
l wonder what awaits us in Berlin.
Christmas.
Café Kranzler.
Marzipanstollen.
Mulled wine on the Ku'damm.
A daily newspaper
you can actually read.
Proper bread and butter.
And beds that aren't too short.
Did you know
that you're still the man l love?
Even after 27 years.
Yes, l do know that.
You conceited thing!
Dora! Dora!
Everybody out! Get out of the room!
Out!
Open the gate!
Open it! Open the gate!
Go, go, go!
Come on! Quick!
Han!
Which idiot had the gate closed?
That idiot would be me.
Open the gate!
-Keep it closed.
-They're our workers.
They'll be killed!
-My concern is the plant.
-No... Not yet.
Open the gate!
Dora, you take the women and children.
Come on! Quick, quick!
Quick! Come on! That way!
You're going to regret this, Rabe.
l'll be happy to regret this.
Women and children! Quick!
Come on! This way!
Rabe!
l swear...
Where's the flag?
-What for?
-The flag, damn you!
lt's in the trunk of the car.
Han!
Turn the floodlight on! Full power!
-Are you mad?
-Do it!
-Chang, come here!
-Yes, boss!
Over there! Quick!
Everyone, under the flag!
Come on, run! This way. Quick!
Come on!
Come on! Quick!
They're going away.
We did it.
They're leaving.
They're leaving!
There are just too many to cope with!
Nine shot in the stomach.
One in the head.
Three are dying. Four amputations...
Enough. Crying won't help.
-Where is Dr. Xu?
-He's not here.
Lucky they only hit the guard house.
l want this hole filled in.
And get the grounds cleaned up.
Han, check the plant for damage
and check the turbine functions.
l want a report
sent to Shanghai and Berlin today.
Yes, sir.
-Chang.
-Yes?
You're to reinforce the sheds
to make provisional shelter.
ls that clear?
Boss, l'm driver.
And without shelter
you'll be a dead driver soon.
Herr Fliess.
Stop. Stop the car.
Close the gate! Close it!
The early bird catches the worm, eh?
Get out of the car.
-Open the trunk.
-Herr Rabe.
May l remind you,
you had your send-off yesterday.
You're talking to the new director
of Siemens Nanking.
-l don't remember handing over.
-Don't worry.
You've been busy enough
with your move.
What are your plans
as the new director?
Considering
what we witnessed yesterday,
the plant
will have to be closed immediately.
And what about the workers?
They will be contacted.
-Should we resume business.
-Do you have everything?
-Files? Accounting books? Contracts?
-No need to worry.
German efficiency.
A good plan, Herr Fliess.
lt's just a pity your contract
doesn't start until the sixth.
The day after tomorrow.
lf you doubt me, look in the trunk.
The contract must be with the papers.
German efficiency.
That may be so.
-But you have no say here anymore.
-You're right, indeed.
And you have no say here, yet.
But somebody has to have a say here,
don't you think?
Han?
Han.
Tell him to open the car trunk.
Herr Fliess,
would you please open the car trunk?
And now tell him
that for insurance purposes alone,
his access to the company grounds
must be restricted.
He'll stay in the guest apartment.
Staff will look after him.
-Herr Fliess...
-Don't bother.
Herr Fliess.
The apartment is over there.
l'm sorry.
lf the Führer knew
the people they send here...
lt's just ridiculous.
l know you mean well.
But let it rest, please.
Someone has to look after it.
-Someone, but not you.
-As long as l'm here, l will.
-And where are my fried eggs?
-You can look after them yourself.
December 4. 1937.
As the Japanese shelIs
tear through the sky overhead,
I open the gates
and let in all who come to us.
Women and children crouch
under the huge German fIag,
with terror in their eyes.
The flag is said to be bombproof.
The Japanese
are faithful allies indeed.
They hoId their fire
as soon as they see our flag.
Very honorable.
Hurry up there!
Come on! Quickly!
What is all this?
The refugees can't stay
in the front yard.
That's company grounds.
l'd need permission.
So they're staying in our yard?
Yes, exactly.
They're staying in our yard.
This way. Bring it over this way.
"The Japanese soldiers
are your friends!"
The Chinese took the bait.
lnform headquarters.
Congratulations, Major.
You'll make
an excellent commander one day.
But l ask myself,
why is it that l give orders
not to take prisoners,
and you arrive with thousands?
Please forgive me.
-Your Highness.
-l didn't ask you to speak!
So, Major.
What do you propose?
Your Highness.
lt would be extremely difficult
to execute that many prisoners.
ls that so?
Furthermore,
l believe such executions
could be considered to be illegal.
lllegal?
l am entrusting you personally
with resolving
this matter once and for all.
l want no prisoner
alive by tomorrow morning.
We will also shell the city center.
Nanking must experience
the superiority of our troops.
Attention!
On your feet!
Now you are going
to get warm soup to eat.
December 5. 1937.
I never thought that a single day
could have changed my life compIeteIy.
To stay or to go.
To pIay the hero or steal away.
And what shall l tell Dora?
You're not asleep.
Neither are you.
The difference is, l can't sleep.
You don't want to.
Tell me what thoughts are inside
that head of yours, John Rabe.
What life holds
for those poor devils outside.
You think everyone is like you.
Those poor devils
out there in your yard
are just happy to be in your yard.
They're happy
about what you pity them for.
l am the way l am.
l know.
Do you remember,
27 years ago,
what we promised one another?
Remind me how old was l back then?
19.
Yes, l remember.
And?
Now and forever, come what may.
And do you still mean it?
The statute of limitations may be up.
But yes, l mean it,
now and forever,
come what may.
This way.
Quick, come on.
Keep moving!
Stay with me, Dora.
Did you really
have to bring that damn bird?
Just stay with me.
Out of the way! Get out of the way!
Let me through. Just let me through!
Stop!
You're not coming.
Take care of yourself.
l love you.
l'll come later.
Dora!
Boss.
Go on. l'm staying here.
lt's too dangerous.
Han, l know you mean well.
lf l'm hit, all the better.
lf not, then so be it.
Now go, before l get angry.
December11, 1937.
Suddenly. peopIe are flooding
the gates of our zone
by the thousands.
News of the zone
must have spread Iike wiIdfire.
We can hardly handle the influx.
Even the Japanese ambassador.
Mr. Fukuda.
has given our zone his approval.
December13, 1937.
We're stilI transporting rice in
from outside of the city.
The zone needs flour. salt. firewood,
medicine. utensils and blankets
before the Japanese get here.
We have to be weIl prepared,
for we'll be cut off from the world.
The Japanese
have 600 pIanes in Shanghai.
As well as armored divisions
and an enormous army.
If an army
of that size attacks Nanking.
they mean to raze it.
But perhaps this is mere chiId's play
compared to what a new world war
would mean in Europe.
The Chinese soldiers who haven't left
are posted at the main city gate.
They want to defend Nanking,
at all costs.
A compIeteIy pointIess
and futile venture.
Why have you ended the siege
and begun to attack the city?
Forgive me, General.
Answer my question, Major!
His lmperial Highness gave the order.
Lieutenant General... your report!
My nephew, the Emperor,
wants a swift victory.
A modern war.
One that shows Japan's superiority.
The advance can't be stopped.
Tonight we will attack Nanking.
Hello? Hello?
What's going on here?
-What's going on?
-The lines are down.
Then do something. Fix them.
And set up lines to the exchange.
Lives are at stake.
Send news: Nanking has fallen.
Out of the way!
Get out of here!
Quick! Quick!
Shut up!
What are you doing here?
-Search in there.
-Yes, sir!
Two of you search that room.
Check it.
We found him.
Onwards.
December15, 1937.
Feeding the zone's 200.000 peopIe
is getting ever more difficult.
Our various appeals to the Japanese
to allow more rice into the zone
have remained unanswered.
We alI hope the dipIomats
wiIl return to Nanking soon.
Rosen believes onIy
an international presence
wilI curb Japanese aggression.
-Forward!
Attention!
To the prisoners camp, march!
December19, 1937.
Bodies Iie in piIes before the gates.
The Japanese won't touch them.
And we aren't allowed to do so.
We Europeans
are paralyzed from the shock.
The executions are rampant.
Sometimes
with machine guns at the barracks.
At the Army Ministry.
And down by the river.
To the Führer of the German people.
Chancellor Adolf Hitler.
My Führer.
As a Ioyal party member
and upstanding German.
I turn to you in a time of great need.
The Japanese Imperial troops
conquered the city of Nanking
on December12, 1937.
Since then l have witnessed
atrocious crimes against civilians.
PIease heIp to end this catastrophe,
and make an appeaI
to our Japanese alIies
in the name of humanity.
With a German salute.
Your Highness, his wife survived.
She is in Shanghai.
You have to stay in the car.
l don't understand Japanese.
Get back in the car.
Should l get in the car?
l said back in the car!
l could get back in the car.
Take your hat off.
Take your hat off!
Damn it.
Move on! Move on!
Boss! Boss!
l'm in here!
-Have them line up.
-Yes, sir.
Everybody stand up
and get into a line!
Stand up! Go over there!
Quickly! Quickly!
Quickly!
-Ask if anybody speaks German.
-Yes, sir.
Raise your hand if you speak German.
-Front and center.
-Yes, sir.
Come to the front!
Do you understand me?
Say something.
Just say something. Anything.
You.
Children? You.
December 21, 1937.
We're cut off from the outside wo¤d.
No post, teIegrams
or calls can reach us.
Nothing works anymore.
I never thought
I'd have to put a vaIue on human life.
weighing one against another.
ls it better
to hand over a few hundred soldiers
to protect the zone.
not knowing if it wilI heIp at aIl?
Or to stand one's ground?
There is no answer.
Hi.
How did your hair get so short?
Got cut off.
Where is she then?
-Who is it?
-Where's the girl?
-ls she in here?
-Who?
-There's no girl here!
-What are you blathering about?
-What did l tell you?
-You were right!
Nice haircut.
Come on then.
Just you wait.
Who do you think you are?
Not so fast.
-Spread her legs.
-Just calm down.
Just calm down.
Keep her still, will you!
Keep quiet.
Be quiet there!
Quiet! Stop there!
We're Germans.
Germans. We're Germans.
Help me out here, damn it!
Heil...Shitler.
Heil Shitler.
-That's not funny.
-We got through.
All the same,
he is the Führer of the German people.
And shall l tell you
what l don't find funny?
Yes, what is it?
lt also concerns
the so-called Führer.
-Listen here...
-Friedrich Rosen, my father.
An ambassador and foreign minister,
forced to flee and die in China.
Simply because my grandfather,
Beethoven's best friend, no less,
happened to be Jewish.
My father couldn't die
in the country he always lived for.
That's not funny.
Nor is my position as secretary.
After years as embassy councillor.
l should be glad to even be alive.
Do you think that's funny?
Heil Shitler.
Why do we have to bury him?
lt's our duty.
l hated him.
And you hated him too.
He is still our father.
Not being buried
is like dying a second time.
Well, he deserves it.
Hold the candle.
l hated him.
Forgive him.
He has orders to fill the hole
to make the road passable.
-With corpses?
-lt looks like it.
Are you all right?
Yes, l'm fine. Don't worry.
An officer.
Lieutenant.
These people are hindering our work.
Come on!
Listen, we have to split up.
Run in there. Quick!
lt's me, Langshu.
Ssh! lt's me, Langshu.
-Quick! Help me!
-lnto the stove!
-Search from top to bottom.
-Yes, sir!
Quick, get into bed!
-Wait outside.
-Yes, sir.
Onwards!
December 23, 1937.
Tomorrow is Christmas.
We're at the end of our rope.
We can't maintain
the zone much Ionger.
I used to say. "Never stop.
it wiIl stop on its own."
And that
will have to hold true even now.
l've decided
to Ieave our savings to the zone.
What eIse are they good for?
Now that Dora is no Ionger with us.
December 24, 1937.
l've celebrated every Christmas
with Dora for nearly 30 years.
With a Christmas tree.
And Christmas goose.
And Dora's famous Gugelhupf cake.
I don't regret staying behind.
We have saved a lot of lives.
But I haven't words for my grief.
We have been questioning
some girls from the college.
Hundreds of soldiers
are being hidden there.
We could close the security zone.
So what are you waiting for?
The zone must be cleared
before the diplomats
and the press return to Nanking.
Or the whole world will hear about it.
That's an order!
December 25, 1937.
News that Prince Asaka
wants to clear the zone
did not take Iong to get around.
Hundreds of people
have gathered outside the zone
to block the entrance.
They're prepared to risk their Iives
to defend the zone.
Their time is up.
Clear the zone, damn it!
Reinforcements?
For what, exactly?
This is ridiculous.
Reinforcements for what?
Battle order!
-Load.
-Load!
-Aim.
-Aim!
Your Highness, let us shoot.
Aim!
Stand down.
-Stand down!
-Yes, sir!
Unload your weapons!
Order arms!
To the left!
Quick march!
December 29, 1937.
ln front of the diplomats
Prince Asaka acknowIedged the zone.
But this victory was the end of us.
The committee was forced to step down.
We handed over most of our photos
and films to the Japanese.
who destroyed them before our eyes.
And l...
l have to leave the city today.
But I wiIl see Dora again.
lt almost seems like a miracle.
The struggle is over.
Thank you.
Good luck.
Clear out!
Rabe is coming!
Goodbye! Goodbye!
Far more than 200,000 people
survived the Rape of Nanjing
in the protection of the Safety Zone.
Nevertheless the number of victims
was staggering.
Censuses revealed that at least
300,000 people were killed.
Until the present day
the Japanese government
has refused to officially acknowledge
the extent of the Rape of Nanjing.
On his return to Germany,
John Rabe was arrested as
a suspected collaborator of the Chinese.
He was forbidden to report
on his experiences in Nanjing.
His diaries were confiscated and
only rediscovered 60 years later.
After the war
John Rabe was at first refused
denazification by the Allies.
Forgotten and impoverished,
he died in Berlin in 1950.
Based on true events
lnspired by JOHN RABE
DER GUTE DEUTSCHE VON NANKlNG