All compartments report readiness.
- Compartment one, manned and ready.
- Compartment two, manned and ready.
Compartment four, manned and ready.
Compartment five, manned and ready..
- Compartment six, manned and ready.
- Compartment seven, manned and ready..
- Compartment eight, manned and ready.
- Compartment nine, manned and ready..
- Compartment ten, manned and ready.
- Comrade Captain...
the boat is manned and ready for live
firing of the main missile batteries.
Activate emergency action procedure
for nuclear weapon release.
Comrade Captain, the Political
Department stands ready to do its duty.
Excuse me.
Hydraulics
to number-one missile tube open.
Comrade Captain, Moscow has confirmed
nuclear weapons release authority.
Number-one hatch open.
Silo free ofwater.
Powering up consoles for missile launch.
Powering number-one missile console.
Poliansky,
maintain current course and speed.
Course steady 2-9-0.
Maintaining speed six knots.
Hatch number one open.
Silo free ofwater.
Fueling in progress.
Proceed with activation
of the warhead on number-one missile.
- Up scope.
- Periscope going up.
Demichev, back to the conn.
Prepare number-three tube
to the active state.
Switch fire control console to primary.
Console to position one primary.
Sixty seconds within range.
Prepare for emergency dive after launch.
Number-one missile fueled.
Table elevated.
- Table elevated.
- Down scope.
Ready for firing sequence.
- Launch number-one missile.
- Time to launch: 1 5 seconds.
1 4, 1 3, 1 2...
1 1, 1 0--
Captain, we've been fired on.
Enemy torpedo at bearing 1 -9-0.
- 7--
- Dive the submarine. Keep 50 meters.
- Keep 50 meters.
- Both turbines full ahead together.
Full ahead together.
3, 2, 1. Captain!
Force manual override.
Missile launching sequencer
not responding.
- Estimate torpedo at 6,000 meters.
- The drill is over.
Well, Comrade Polenin...
do you have an explanation
for this disappointment?
Comrade Admiral, it's just another
burnout in the ignition sequence.
Comrade Captain, I will require
the names of those responsible.
I don't know their names. How the hell
would I know the name of the jackass...
that supplied a 30 kopeck insulator
to do a 50 kopeck job?
That's what I have to fight
before I can fight a war.
Comrade Admiral, the boat
will be at sea on schedule...
before the month is out.
I'll give you a name. My name. Polenin.
Mikhail. Captain, K-1 9.
Write it down.
Afteryou've successfully
completed trials...
on the mechanical, propulsion
and navigation systems...
in the Bering Sea...
you'll proceed beneath the ice
to the launch area here...
and test-fire the missile.
My orders were to prepare K-1 9 for sea
trials, and they'll begin on schedule.
But until the trials are complete...
to undertake an exercise of this scope...
may be, with respect, premature.
There is no doubt in my mind...
that K-1 9 is ready to fulfill her mission.
Operation Arctic Circle
is no mere exercise.
What is to stop the Americans
from destroying Moscow and Leningrad?
Only one thing.
A certain knowledge...
of destruction in return.
K-1 9 is that knowledge.
But not until Kennedy has been told
by his own spy planes that we have it...
and it works.
I promised Comrade Khrushchev...
that the American president will receive
his message before the end of the month.
Comrade Marshall...
perhaps Captain Polenin might--
Captain Polenin put his boat
and his men before the party.
He will be underyour command.
That's all there is to it.
- A captain on the CCP.
- Captain.
- What's your name, please?
- Demichev.
Torpedo officer, Comrade Captain.
May I ask the captain's name
and his purpose aboard our boat?
My name is Vostrikov.
Where's Captain Polenin?
Come in.
Yes?
- Good morning, Captain.
- Comrade Captain Vostrikov.
That'll be all, Yuri. Come in. Please.
Captain.
With the short lead-in time to sea trials...
headquarters wanted
your expertise on board...
and I'm pleased to have it.
I know this could be difficult--
It's never difficult
to do one's duty, Captain.
I was preparing my briefing
on the crew and on the boat.
- I see.
- The problem's fitting her out.
But my orders said you would
not be arriving until tomorrow.
The briefing can wait.
Please, show me the boat.
Of course.
We're finally getting
the turbines up to speed.
With luck, I'd say in another week
we might be able to run a test.
The equipment has not yet arrived,
Comrade Captain.
- Noted, Comrade Captain.
- The reactor compartment.
How hot are you running it?
We're at 50 percent
for the turbine test, Captain.
What is the absorption rate of the rods?
Three percent above normal.
Where is the reactor officer?
Lieutenant Yashin?
This man is drunk. Do you tolerate this?
- Of course not.
- Prepare charges against this man.
Inform command
we need an immediate replacement.
Yes, Captain.
Lieutenant Yashin is
the best reactor officer in the navy.
He's never been drunk on duty before.
We need him, Captain.
I urge you to reconsider.
I want this boat out of dry dock.
Sea trials begin in two weeks.
The boat isn't ready, Captain.
The problem is Moscow.
They organize party VIP tours...
while we're stuck with incompetent
yard crews and defective parts.
Sea trials will begin as scheduled.
We deliver or we drown.
In the history of the Soviet navy...
no sailors...
have been given such a boat as K-1 9.
It is the finest submarine in the world.
You have been given the honor
to be her crew.
I have been given
the honor to be your captain.
Without me...
you are nothing.
Without you...
I am nothing.
Much is expected of us.
We will not fail.
We're cursed.
Easy, easy. Keep it level.
Steady!
Now, down. Down.
Coming through.
Permission to pass.
- What do you have there?
- A new scope for the sonar station.
- Carry on. Install it.
- I work on the reactor.
- Where is the sonar officer?
- He's on a 24-hour pass.
Captain, I initiated the relief rotation.
- It's good for efficiency.
- No more passes. Cancel all leaves.
-We need everyone here to do their jobs.
-Yes, Captain.
Comrade Captain.
Lieutenant Vadim Radtchenko
reporting for duty.
I'm your new reactor officer.
- What was your last posting?
- Nuclear training academy.
He's never operated a reactor at sea.
I was first in my class.
Thanks.
- Report to the reactor control room.
- Yes, sir.
- That way.
- Thank you.
- Captain--
- He's qualified...
or command wouldn't have
sent him to us.
Officer on deck.
Pavel Loktev, senior technician.
Stepan Komarov, Anatoly Subachev...
Grigori Dyomin, Oleg Argunov.
Show me to the control room.
Watch out! I have to stop the truck.
They gave me the wrong drugs!
Stop the truck!
Stop! Stop!
Wrong drugs!
You gave me the wrong drugs!
You idiot! Stop!
Doctor!
It's the doctor!
He's dead.
Stay with the body
until the ambulance comes.
The rest ofyou, back to work.
Back to work!
Gavril.
Captain. Ever since
the solid ballast was loaded...
we've had a half-degree list to port.
I've tried everything,
but she won't even up.
Half-degree we can handle.
We'll compensate with seawater ballast
till we get back to port.
Ifwe get back to port.
You know what the men
are calling this boat?
The Widowmaker.
Five died from fumes sealing the tanks.
Another four in construction.
And now the doctor.
The champagne bottle.
Ten dead...
and we haven't left dock.
I'm surprised they confide their fears
to their commanding officer.
A crew is a family.
The captain is the father.
My own father inspired
more fear than he indulged.
I was told there are two versions
about your father.
One, he was a hero of the Revolution.
Two, he died in the gulag.
Both are true.
How are those safety checks
going on down below, Captain?
Proceeding.
Misha, Misha.
There you go.
Forty centimeters of headroom,
and he gives half to a rodent.
Yevgeny...
wrap this around your private parts.
The gamma rays can--
You should also take your dosimeter
once a day to the doctor.
Why?
He reads it and tells you how long
you have before your torpedo falls off.
Captain?
I'm Gennardi Savran,
your new medical officer.
- What was your last posting?
- No. I am the base physician here.
They said there was an emergency.
So here I am.
Welcome to K-1 9, Doctor.
Captain, we will be back soon, won't we?
- I get--
- What?
Seasick.
Gentlemen. Gentlemen.
Misha, please.
- Vostrikov marries a girl--
- Yuri, you promised. You promised.
Vostrikov marries a girl
with top party connections.
He knows which fork they use for salads,
so they make him a captain.
- That's why you've never been promoted.
- Be quiet.
We are all good communists here.
- To good communists.
- To good communists!
You're drunk. Sit down. Sit down.
Gentlemen, a little bit of respect.
Captain Vostrikov does not
know you the way I do.
You're still the captain,
as far as we're concerned.
He's the captain.
I'm executive officer.
I'm pleased. I'm gonna be with my boys.
My turn.
They say there was a cosmonaut
who orbited Earth before Yuri Gagarin.
But he was not loyal enough...
to hold his breath...
when his life-support system gave out.
So now...
he never existed.
Gagarin was lucky.
Let's hope we are too.
- To luck!
Kataya!
- Don't worry.
- Don't go.
Please.
Defense Minister Zolentsov,
Admiral Bratyeev...
request permission to carry out orders
in defense of the motherland.
Carry out your patriotic duty.
- All hands down.
- All hands down!
- Single up all lines.
- Single up lines!
- Confirm single up!
Land the gangway.
Land the gangway!
Gangway landed!
- K-1 9 ready for sea, Captain.
- Port turbine, slow ahead.
Port turbine, slow ahead.
Slow ahead together!
I just hope you picked the right man.
- All compartments prepare to dive.
- Top hatches closed and latched.
- Open the midship vent.
- Midship vent open.
- Ready to dive, Captain.
- Dive the boat.
Speed six knots.
Make your depth 50 meters.
Planesman, make your depth 50 meters.
- Making depth 50 meters.
- Slow ahead together.
Slow ahead together.
- Course?
- Course is steady 3-2-3, Captain.
- Depth under the keel.
- Echo sound reads 350 meters, Captain.
Twenty meters.
Thirty meters.
Don't worry. It'll stop
once the pressure increases.
Simulate an electrical fire
in the galley, please.
Fire in switchbox number 65.
This is a drill. Repeat. This is a drill.
It's stuck.
Fifty meters.
Fire has spread
to the next compartment.
Simulate electrical failure,
compartment four.
Electrical failure, compartment four.
This is a drill.
Compartment four,
loss of electrical power.
- This is a drill.
- Emergency lights. Let's go.
Fire's out in the galley, Captain.
Too much damage.
Too many casualties.
Simulate flooding, compartment four.
Make them work in the dark.
If this were not a drill...
the boat would be crippled
and half the crew would be dead.
- Let me speak to the officer in charge.
- Try it again tomorrow.
I only wanted to say...
how sympathetic I am
about the change in command.
These decisions aren't always
for us to understand.
Thankyou, Comrade Suslov.
Still, you must feel it's an honor...
to serve on this boat in any capacity.
- Indeed.
- It's historic.
Excuse me.
Checking the aft pressurizer?
Yes, Lieutenant.
You know religious icons are forbidden.
This is the future, Pavel.
Cars that never need refueling.
Free power for every family.
Maybe even travel to the planets.
It's a privilege to be a part of this future.
Yes, Lieutenant.
Good morning, gentlemen.
- What's this?
- At sea we only shower on Saturdays.
Action stations. Chemical fire
in motor control compartment.
This is a drill.
Watch out!
Fire in the main switchboard. C2 L.
Valve rupture in compartment eight.
Torpedo fuel spill in aft torpedo room.
Start the drill again.
Comrades, officers and sailors,
remember...
the American propaganda
will always try to play...
on your baser, primitive instincts.
Greed, lust, individualism.
In American propaganda,
you will see how everybody...
has a car, nice clothes,
a nice apartment...
but you will never see
the truth behind this lie.
You will not see police dogs attacking
strikers and civil rights demonstrators.
You will not see the beggars
in the streets, the homeless...
the Negro shantytowns of the South.
You will not see the warmongers...
who threaten the world
with nuclear holocaust.
Stand by to simulate
firing torpedo number eight.
Number eight isn't loaded, Captain.
I know that.
I want you to unload
seven and load eight.
Now, please.
Captain.
Ice formations near our depth.
I suggest we go deeper
and run the drill later.
Negative. Ice formations will not
be suspended in the event ofwar.
Unload seven torpedo.
Load eight torpedo.
Load eight torpedo. This is a drill.
Do we ever stop?
- We need the rest.
- Yevesky, quiet.
Proceed to your action stations
immediately.
Come on!
Engage running gear.
Torpedo withdrawn.
Open breech door number eight.
Traverse torpedo.
Traversing torpedo.
Dmitri! Come on. Help me. Help me!
Don't stop!
- Two men are injured.
- Have them seen by the doctor...
and start the drill again.
- Two men short, Captain.
- Have them put the torpedo...
back in tube seven
and start the drill again.
Traverse torpedo!
Traversing torpedo!
Going under. Clear.
Attention!
At ease.
I was told there was some complaining.
But I said, "Not my men.
They're the best crew in the fleet.
They will pull to the last."
So...
any complaints?
There's no complaints here, Captain.
Good.
It's not the men's fault.
It's your fault.
The officers.
You have failed to set high standards...
to correct their deficiencies.
Ifyou do your job, the men will do theirs.
That is all.
- What's her name?
- Kataya.
She's pretty.
- Sorry.
- I'm writing to her.
- Where are you going to mail it?
- It's in case I die.
In case you die?
In case I die.
Report to captain.
Five miles from missile launch area.
We are ahead ofschedule.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Course to steer, 1 -8-5.
1 -8-5.
Captain.
Conduct emergency dive drill.
Bow planes are jammed 20 degrees down.
- Bow planes jammed 20 degrees down.
- Set. Twenty degrees down.
- I have the conn.
Move!
1 20 meters.
1 30 meters.
1 40 meters.
1 50 meters.
Take the boat down
to maximum operational depth.
Make your depth 250 meters.
Turbines slow ahead together.
240 meters.
250 meters.
Captain, I respectfully suggest
going below 250 meters...
is an unnecessary risk.
Continue the dive to 300 meters.
300 meters is close to crush depth.
I know.
260 meters.
Make your depth 300 meters.
280 meters.
290 meters.
300 meters, Captain.
- Level the planes.
- Level the bow planes.
Simulate flooding
in the aft torpedo room...
and emergency surface.
A rapid ascent beneath the ice cap
is not advisable, Captain.
I did not ask foryour advice.
Flooding in compartment ten.
Emergency surface.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Man stations!
Poliansky, bring the planes
to full rise. Keep ten up.
Make turns for 20 knots.
Full ahead together.
Planes to full rise. Full ahead
together. Keep ten up. Speed 20 knots.
Pavel, wedge!
Hold it steady! Go!
Go! Go! Go!
- The rupture is sealed, Captain.
- Excellent.
Recommend we stay
at safe depth, Captain.
- How thick is the ice here?
- Kornilov.
Ice recon.
- Come on. Come on.
- Less than one meter in this area.
- These reports are almost a week old.
- This time ofyear...
the ice is only getting thinner.
Continue surfacing.
I'm not sure ifwe can control
an ascent this fast, Captain.
- Neither am I.
- 1 30 meters.
1 20 meters.
- 1 1 0 meters.
- Blow main ballast.
- She's starting to roll.
- Permission to hold at safe depth.
- Denied.
- 80 meters.
Pump room,
are we pumping the trim tanks?
She's rolling to port.
- Blow port. Shut starboard.
- Changing over to alternate air supply.
- 60 meters.
- Stop turbines.
Stop both turbines.
- Level off, damn it.
- 40 meters.
- Brace for impact.
- Brace for impact!
Brace for impact.
Take the conn.
Raise the radio and radar masts.
Give them three sweeps.
Medium range.
Prepare to fire the test missile.
Prepare to launch test missile.
This is not a drill.
Central command,
missile control manned and ready.
Preparing silo three for firing test missile.
Power up console for missile launch.
Number-three launch door opening.
Comrade Captain, Moscow confirms
test missile launch authority.
Attention! Initiating
power-up procedure, Captain.
Very well.
Fueling in progress.
Simulate activation of the warhead,
number-three missile.
Let's go. Come on.
- Contacts?
- No contacts.
Radar, sonar. Contacts?
No contacts.
- Fueling complete. Table elevated.
- Ready for firing sequence.
Fire missile three.
Time to launch:
Fifteen seconds.
1 4, 1 3, 1 2...
1 1, 1 0, 9...
8, 7...
6, 5...
4, 3...
2, 1.
Confirm missile away, Captain.
Congratulations, Comrade Captain.
We just wrote our names
into the history books.
Captain.
Confirm successful missile launch
to fleet command.
Yes, Captain.
This is the captain.
We have successfully
launched ourtest missile.
All hands stand down
from combat stations.
Yes!
You will be in my report
for leaving your post.
And you will be in mine.
You needlessly endangered
this boat and its crew.
Two hundred million Soviet citizens are
depending on us, Captain Vostrikov...
to save them from nuclear attack.
You risked them as well.
I took this boat and these men
to the edge...
because we need to know where it is.
These 1 20 men are a crew now because
they achieved something together...
that they did not think they could do.
Next time, when it is not a drill...
they will go to the edge and past it
and die, if necessary...
because that is what
their duty demands of them.
You were lucky, Captain, this time.
I hope I'm on another boat
when your luck runs out.
Misha, Yeltsin, come on, quick. Everybody.
Get that laundry out of there.
Form a group around the flag.
Branan, you're asleep?
On the double. Get closer.
Everybody move, yes.
Closer. Closer.
Move closer.
Winning team closer.
Smile.
Good.
Everything all right? Problems?
Yes. There was residual condensation
in the reactor compartment.
But I shut down
the number-three generator...
and that should reduce the condensation.
I'm counting on you, you know?
Yes, Comrade Captain.
Comrade Captain.
Message from command.
Comrade Commander, the crew
is lined up to your order.
We have received a message
from Moscow.
They congratulate us on the successful
launch of our test missile.
- We have proved our readiness.
- Serving the Soviet Union!
And now they honor us
with a new assignment.
K-1 9 is to assume missile patrol
along the eastern seaboard...
of the United States.
This is a mission
of critical strategic importance.
The boat will come
to full operational status.
Do your best. I expect nothing less.
Crew dismissed!
He nearly got us killed today.
And for what?
To show the men he didn't win his bars
by marrying a Politburo member's niece.
You are still our captain, Misha...
and the only one we trust.
- Captain Polenin?
- Yes.
Captain Vostrikovwants
to see you in the chart room.
Yes.
Command wants us on station
as quickly as possible.
Our course will take us past
the NATO base at Jan Mayan...
and from there to our patrol zone...
400 kilometers off the coastline...
between Washington...
and New York.
- Make turns for 1 5 knots.
- Speed 1 5 knots.
Speed 1 5 knots.
- No contacts. Down scope.
- Periscope going down.
Dive the boat.
Andrei, more wine.
You only get one glass.
But because we are
the creme de la creme...
a glass of red wine with dinner...
is the headquarters' way of telling us
that the crew of the K-1 9 has no equal.
No. It's because we're sitting
on a pile of uranium.
Red wine gives you strontium...
or takes it away.
Or something. Something good.
So, we should be 70 miles...
from Jan Mayan NATO base.
One mountain. No trees. 1 5 men.
One radio station.
I've seen that island
so many times from the periscope.
What's the matter?
I miss seeing the trees...
seeing the sun, the stars.
You get used to being underwater.
When I muster out...
I'll just go work
in the coal mines with my brothers.
So it's all the same to me.
A loss of pressure in the primary
circuit on the aft reactor.
Check the other sensors.
Confirm loss of pressure.
Let me through!
Watch out!
- We've got a leak!
- Give me the emergency manual.
- Come on!
- Lieutenant...
I noticed the pumps
were drawing too much power...
during the turbine tests, but
I didn't think it was serious.
Out of my way!
Move!
The control rods are dropping,
Lieutenant.
- Auxiliary pumps.
- Pavel, auxiliary pumps.
- The pumps aren't working either.
- Recycle them!
I have, but the pressure
keeps dropping.
Confirmed.
- But the rods will cool it, right?
- No.
They can't control the reaction
by themselves. They need coolant.
Lieutenant, the core temperature
is at 400 degrees and rising.
Cut equalization!
What's the problem?
The primary coolant loop
on the aft reactor's ruptured.
- What? How did this happen?
- What difference does it make?
- Answer my question. How?
- I don't know, Captain.
The core's heating up.
The mission's over.
I'll tell you
when the mission is over.
Who's responsible for this?
I want a name.
You want a name? I'll give you
a name-- Vostrikov, Alexei.
- Watch yourself, comrade.
- And here's another name--
Radtchenko, Vadim.
The untested reactor officer
you put on this boat.
We will fix this problem.
We will continue the mission.
- Surface. Surface the boat!
- Surface the boat.
- How bad is it?
- The leak is in the sealed area.
There's no way to get to it.
The temperature will keep rising
till it reaches 1,000 degrees.
- And--
- And?
- And what?
- No one knows.
It could start a chain reaction.
There would be radiation leakage.
The core would melt through
the reactor...
and start a thermonuclear
explosion.
- How long do we have?
- Three or four hours.
It could be less.
Get whoeveryou need,
regardless of rank.
- And solve this.
- Yes, Comrade Captain.
Solve this. That's why you're
here, you understand?
Get up!
Doesn't he ever
get tired of drills?
Let's go! Let's go!
This is the captain.
We've had a malfunction
in the aft reactor.
Measures are being taken
to correct the situation.
Remain atyourstations.
- Read it again.
- "In case of sudden drop...
in the pressure
of the primary circuit...
measures must be taken to reduce
precipitation heat release."
But this doesn't work.
The reflux valve isn't here.
- What measures?
- There are none. It's useless.
The rest is about the backup system,
which was never installed.
When we reach periscope depth,
I need to speak to fleet command.
Yes, Comrade Captain.
Why can't we just
shut the reactor down?
We have shut it down, but
we can't control the reaction.
Suppose we use the forward
reactor?
We could cross-connect its pumps.
Use them to cool both.
The rupture in the reactor
is not accessible.
Therefore, we can't seal
the leak...
and we'd have two reactors
out of control.
So we still have
to cool down the reactor.
- Permission to speak, Lieutenant.
- Of course.
The coolant is
just distilled water.
We have 30 tons
of fresh water on board.
Yes.
- But how do we get it to the core?
- Pass the schematic.
I need contact
with fleet command. Now.
Still trying, Captain.
The air release pipe can deliver
coolant deep enough to the core.
We can hack off the valve
and pump in the fresh water.
We've got 30 tons, Captain.
There's some high-grade pipes
in the torpedoes.
It's not much to weld.
Thirty minutes, at the most.
- And ifwe can't fix it?
- Hiroshima.
1.4 megatons, ifyou factor in
the two reactors and the warheads.
Only Hiroshima was less.
It was a lot less.
Scuttle the boat.
Get the men off in rafts.
We will not abandon this boat.
Scavenge the pipes.
We'll be ready to go when command
authorization comes through. Go!
- Have you reached fleet command?
- No, Comrade Captain.
Captain, the long-range antenna
feeder has shorted out.
The seal must have ruptured
when we submerged.
What's the range of the emergency
transmitter, 90 kilometers?
- Up to 1 00 kilometers, Captain.
- Core temperature at 490 degrees.
That's it.
Take it, Dmitri.
- I'll take it, Captain.
- Take it.
Make sure no debris
gets into the pipes.
- Where's the hacksaw?
- Let me have your attention.
Men, listen.
I have decided that the reactor unit
will affect the repairs.
You will go in teams of two.
Ten minutes inside, maximum.
- I will go in the first team.
- No.
I need my executive officer
to command.
- But under the circumstances--
- I am aware of the circumstances.
- It's out of the question.
- I'll go in the first team.
- It's my duty.
- I am ready to serve.
You will go in with the third
team to inspect the repair.
Yes, Comrade Captain.
That is all. Carry on.
Quick! Get something!
- Quick.
- Fuel spill in aft torpedo!
Good.
- Chief.
- Toolbox.
Feed water system isolated!
- Vent off the feed water tank.
- I've got three more meters here.
Meat.
Just meat falling off the bone.
Nice and tender.
Melts in your mouth.
- Dumplings.
- Dmitri likes dumplings.
Reactor temperature?
Five hundred and thirty degrees.
- How long?
- About 1 5 minutes, Captain.
Good work.
- Comrade Captain?
- Yes?
Our equipment is prepared
and we're standing by to enter.
We have a few minutes.
Take the men up top.
- Get some air.
- Thankyou. You heard him.
Get some air.
- Go, go.
- Lieutenant.
- Go on.
- I was getting married.
You will.
Your hair falls out,
or something like that.
- It won't be that bad.
- Ten minutes is nothing.
An hour later and ourwatch
would have been over.
It's fate.
- We don't have radiation suits.
- The warehouse was out.
They sent us
chemical suits instead.
- They might as well wear raincoats!
- Misha, I know.
Tell the men these will help.
What else can we do?
Yeah.
It's only ten minutes.
Ten minutes.
- Do what you can and get out.
- All right, Anatoly?
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- It'll be fine.
- Captain.
Men.
This difficult task
has fallen to you.
Our fate is in your hands.
Request permission to carry out
reactor repair, Comrade Captain.
Permission granted.
May God be with you.