Helsinki-Filmi presents
in co-production with
Two Thirty Five-2 35 & Mogador Film
an Aku Louhimies film
Finnish Civil War, end of April 1 9 1 8
The victorious Whites hunt down
the remaining Red Guards.
2,000 female soldiers fought
amongst the Red ranks.
Ready? -Yes.
Let's go.
Cross the river!
To the shore!
Let go of me!
There!
From the flank!
TEARS OF APRIL
Will mother come soon?
Dig, and you'll soon
see your father.
Dig, damn you!
Miina...
If I don't make it,
you'll look after him.
Promise me.
I promise.
On your feet, whores!
Kajander, Svan, Virta!
Why did the music stop?
Detachment - halt!
They have to be sentenced first,
Sergeant Major.
Sergeant Major, sir.
-Get in line.
They have to be taken
to be court-martialed.
Red whores, be gone with you.
-This is unlawful!
Go.
You're free to go.
Go home. Go on.
Go! Get out of here!
-This is unlawful I tell you.
Go, red whores!
Go on now.
The prisoners are escaping! Fire!
Don't shoot, damn it!
That's that.
Now lads, let us drink!
Harjula, secure the area.
Take it easy now!
Damn it, Harjula!
You were to secure the area!
The men are celebrating!
This is war.
Escaping prisoners are shot.
There's no war here.
Who do you think you are?
I won't awaken
the Jaeger Lieutenant. He's tired.
Very tired.
He's very tired!
I need to take the prisoner
to be court-martialed.
Damn it, Harjula!
I won't do anything illegal. I'll
have this woman court-martialed.
I need a horse.
You need a horse!
Take a boat.
Fucking Russian whore!
Go! Get out!
Put these on.
My name is Aaro.
What's yours?
It was curious,
intercepting your troop.
You all spoke Finnish.
We thought
we were chasing Russians.
We'll get there before dark.
We once taught the boy next door
to swim.
We tied him with a rope
to a boat like this -
and dragged him across the lake.
He screamed like hell,
but learned to swim nevertheless.
You row like shit.
Well, well. You can speak.
Here's a coat if you're cold.
Bloody weather.
Judge Hallenberg
is a sophisticated man.
A writer and a humanist.
He's fair,
the best judge you can have.
Give me a cigarette.
-What?
A cigarette!
Sit down, no standing
in the boat. That's the rule.
Damn it!
Poor Finnish people
Starting to break free
They've had enough of suffering
The White oppressors...
Tell me your name.
Then I'd know who
I'm taking to be court-martialed.
If you got a good fuck, would you
forget about the court-martial?
What?
This isn't too bad.
A hungry person
will eat anything.
Another person, if necessary.
What they did to you
when you were caught...
It was wrong.
There's a boat.
Get dressed.
We had to swim to shore.
-These waters are treacherous.
I guess you can take these off now.
Let's just go.
Here you are.
Sir, Jaeger Harjula
reporting for court-martial...
Thank you.
Paasonen, knife.
I've heard about you, Harjula.
Your unit wondered about you.
It took you a week to get here.
Our boat capsized in high winds.
We were shipwrecked on an island.
At ease, Jaeger. We're taking
the last prisoners to Tammisaari.
What's the name of your prisoner?
-I don't know.
I've asked several times,
but she refuses to answer.
You've had a rough time
with that she-wolf. -No...
Paasonen,
take care of Jaeger Harjula.
You're quite a hero.
You've had the best
military training in the world.
The saviours of the fatherland.
You're top quality, Harjula, just
like this wine. Excellent bouquet.
This used to be a mental hospital,
a sanatorium.
For upper-class loonies.
Doctor Carpelan was a reformist.
He wanted to treat patients -
according to
a Tolstoian ideology.
Carpelan had a vision.
Patients used to fish
and do gardening.
They could meditate in tree huts,
naked if they liked.
Carpelan was interested in the
effect of light on the human mind.
I, too, have studied ways
to repair the mind.
Fascinating business.
Paasonen.
Set out the coffee and cognac.
Then you may leave. -Thank you.
Shall I serve the port as well?
-Yes.
Don't get me wrong.
My interest in the human mind
is purely professional.
In civilian life, I'm an author.
-We have your book.
I see. Which one?
A poetry book.
I haven't had the time to read it.
I did read your articles
before my training.
They inspired many people to leave.
-You're flattering me.
Everybody wanted to get rid
of the Russians. -Jaeger.
Judge Advocate, sir.
-To the fatherland.
Child of Finland, thou shalt never
Abandon the greatest country of all
They say you're an excellent judge,
honest and just. -Jaeger.
They're scum, with blood on their
hands. Do they deserve mercy?
I clear up things
if they need to be cleared up.
The prisoner is not well.
-You don't even know her name.
Even these savages
have human dignity.
And humans always have a name.
Fear not.
Justice will be done.
Can you imagine -
that at first,
my firing squad were all sheep.
For God's sake.
I am a literary man -
and I had to show them
how to kill a man.
How ironic is that?
An author and a humanist
teaching people to act like animals.
Killing without remorse.
It seems we can learn
to love anything.
You look tired. Get some sleep.
Tomorrow we'll start
solving the mystery.
Good night.
-Good night.
Soldier boy, soldier boy...
Load.
Aim.
Fire!
There.
Stand still.
Move.
Name.
Profession.
Place of residence.
When did you join the Red Guard?
What was your mission?
Were you forced
or did you volunteer?
Take her away.
What's this? -Sit still.
Ghosts.
-What ghosts?
Doctor Carpelan.
He hanged himself.
His life's work was taken away.
Konsta was the only patient
who survived. -I've finished.
The others died of thirst.
-Water, water.
At ease.
Tragic, if not horrific.
You've slept like a baby
while I've been working.
People have been condemned to Hell.
I've questioned your prisoner.
Hallenberg.
The West Uusimaa HQ, please.
You don't seem too timid.
What did you do on the island?
Have you studied the human mind?
You can read, can't you?
And not only propaganda.
Spit out your name
and you'll get food.
Have you ever had a dream -
in which you were young?
You didn't know it was dream.
Your name.
Now then.
Do you hunt, Aaro?
-Not really, no.
Neither do I, but I love
the taste of wild game.
Now we know
the name of that woman.
Miina Malin.
Now we know her name.
-Something happened on the island.
Paasonen.
-Judge Advocate, sir.
I know she survived an execution.
I wasn't involved in...
Do I have to arrest you
for assisting the Reds?
No. -She stays confined,
but I assume she's guilty.
Paasonen.
Let's get drunk.
The ends of our swords
Hold the key to our happiness
We shall not give in
We go to war for our country
That wants to break free
Paasonen!
Where's Paasonen?
He's in the kitchen again,
drinking our booze.
Aaro.
To meet one's own wife,
after all these executions...
After having waded in blood up to
one's knees, it feels repulsive.
Aaro, do you have a wife?
Waiting for you
to return from the war.
I guessed you're a bachelor.
Thank you.
Miina. Was it Miina?
Miina.
Give me a cigarette.
I came to say goodbye.
I've been away for so long
that it's better for me to go back.
Help yourself and tell them
what you've done.
Tell them you didn't fight
and didn't use a gun.
And don't say anything about us.
If there's anything I can do...
Wait.
The boy is called Eino.
He's in Tammistonkylä.
At the house of Rapola.
Go and see if he's alright.
Promise me.
I promise.
You got out of there alive.
-I did.
You deserve a drink.
-No, thank you.
Did Miss Malin talk?
-Not much.
Never mind.
We're having roast for dinner.
I have to return to my unit.
Your unit...
Pity.
I could have used
sophisticated company.
Good day.
Is this the house of Rapola?
Are you Eino?
-Yes, I am.
He's Eikka the Bastard.
-I see.
What's your business?
I came to see the boy.
-To collect him?
He's all yours.
We can't feed them all. -No...
The court-martial in Ruukkio
sent me to see how he's doing.
He's starving
like all the other children here.
Are his parents dead?
His father is, at least.
Do you know about his mother,
Miina Malin?
Her name is Martta Kivelä.
She followed our son to war.
We haven't heard
from that whore since.
She left her bastard son here.
-Do you know my mother?
His mother is a whore.
-Shut up, Vieno.
Eikka the Bastard.
Get inside! Eino, too.
Is my mother alive?
What the hell are you looking at?
Get back to work!
She fucked them all,
that fucking socialist.
The biggest whore there ever was.
Put the axe down.
-Fucking butcher. Be gone with you.
She was a whore alright!
Did you run away?
Mr. Soldier, can I come with you?
-Go home.
Is my mother dead?
-Yes.
Go home.
-Did she love me?
Go home!
As death is upon us,
Lord Jesus, look after me.
Strengthen my hope and my faith,
be with me.
I give myself to Thee.
Have mercy!
Can I shoot?
I'm sure mother will come back.
Give me that.
Where are we going?
The oppressors whipping our backs
We must fight the White Army
We must die or win
The result remains to be seen
Thank you.
The oppressors...
...whipping our backs
We must fight the White Army
You'll be better off in town.
It won't be long.
Come now, don't fret.
You'll be better off there.
Will someone come for me?
Of course. I'll come.
Promise me.
You can get washed, Miss.
From the Judge Advocate.
And some clothes.
Dismissed.
How's the food?
How about the wine?
I agree.
It's from Doctor Carpelan's cellar.
What happened on the island?
Not much.
We froze.
Did Jaeger Harjula treat you well?
A Finnish freedom fighter
is a gentleman.
Did I sleep with Harjula,
is that what you want to know?
Sit down.
What do you think?
Have a good look.
You must be very lonely.
Fine, shoot me yourself.
Aim for the womb.
Shoot the butcher's child as well.
Why am I still alive?
Is it because of Jaeger Harjula?
Mr. Hallenberg sir,
you have visitors!
Take her away.
Good day. I'm to visit the prisoner.
-The judge forbade visitors.
He doesn't mean me.
-The judge forbade...
What's the trouble here?
Stand still.
Good day.
Harjula, by the devil.
I didn't think you'd come back.
I was posted back here.
-It's good to see you.
Aaro, isn't she beautiful?
-Very beautiful.
It's our anniversary today.
-I decided to surprise my husband.
Congratulations.
-I thought I married a writer -
instead he's a vicious man
judging savages.
This will be something
to write about, right?
These are extraordinary times.
-Really!
I've been bored to death
in the city.
Misery is everywhere,
and so little beauty.
Luckily it's beautiful here.
-Let's drink to that.
To beauty.
Paasonen!
Why can't I hear music?
Vyborg was conquered.
This will soon be over.
All prisoners have been condemned,
there's no-one alive.
Except that woman of yours,
she's a special case.
Did you finish questioning her?
-She's guilty.
I have to give her
the maximum sentence.
She has a son.
Her name is Martta Kivelä,
not Miina Malin.
She became a Red Guard escort girl
almost by chance.
She whored for the cause.
-She didn't fight...
She whored. I'm sure she was in
the female platoon of the Red Guard.
As a commander,
out of her own free will.
I guess you know that.
She even offered herself to me.
That she-wolf.
To Finland!
To the fatherland!
Fly, Aaro, fly!
You're evil, Emil. Helpless
creatures should be protected.
What's your opinion, Jaeger Harjula?
-All God's creatures have rights.
Jaeger Harjula is more human
than you, Emil!
Stand up straight, guard! Don't let
the cancer of socialism infect you!
Harjula, let's go!
That's the way it is, Aaro.
I get to do the dirty work.
To kill these good-for-nothings.
The big wigs in Helsinki don't even
want to hear about the executions.
They'd rather fuck their maids
like there's no tomorrow. -Emil!
That's the truth!
Men will do anything to get laid.
-You're coarse.
Aaro is a soldier.
He understands.
He's sophisticated, different,
like me.
Emil, recite something.
In honour of our anniversary,
or our guest.
O who rides by night
thro' the woodland so wild?
You're good, Emil.
-Stop it, Bea.
You know full well
that was Goethe's verse.
O who rides by night
thro' the woodland so wild?
It's about you, Jaeger Harjula.
It is the fond father
embracing his child; -
And close the boy nestles
within his loved arm, -
To hold himself fast,
and to keep himself warm.
Is it about a father?
It's dialogue between a father
and his ill son.
They ride through a forest at night.
''My boy, upon what
dost thou fearfully gaze?''
''O father, see yonder! see yonder!''
he says.
In the forest, the son sees
some sort of elf king -
that the father cannot see.
The king wants the boy for himself.
To the kingdom of ghosts.
The king offers the boy his daughter
and wife to play with.
The father rides through the night,
but his son dies.
He joins the Elf King.
Isn't that so, Jaeger Harjula?
Bullshit.
Beautiful words,
feverish hallucinations.
What kind of an author
are you, Emil?
There's not an ounce of poetry
in your soul.
You've become a savage
among savages.
I think that Beethoven
had that poem in mind -
when he composed the Allegretto
of his Symphony No. 7.
Do you know that one?
Bea, be so kind as to play
the Allegretto of Symphony No. 7.
I think you know this one.
I hear you play the piano very well.
I can imagine the son
pining after the elf king.
A masked death.
''O, 'tis the Erl-King
with his crown and his shroud. "
''No, my son, it is
but a dark wreath of the cloud.''
Did you know that they play this
at childrens' funerals?
I did.
Take me, Aaro.
Thank you.
-You're welcome.
And the prisoner. What about her?
Move.
Come with me.
You'll be freed.
Tell him that you're Martta Kivelä.
You were an escort girl
in the Red Guard -
but you weren't
involved in fighting.
And you have a son
who misses his mother.
Jaeger Harjula tells me that you're
not Miina Malin, but Martta Kivelä.
He also thinks
that you should be set free.
To take care of your fatherless son.
Are you Martta Kivelä?
Are you?
Miina Malin.
-No. She's Martta Kivelä.
Martta Kivelä!
Miina Malin of the Red Guard.
You're guilty of military action -
as leader of a female platoon.
You have murdered civilians
and civil guards.
According to Finnish martial law,
I sentence you to death.
The sentence will be carried out
tomorrow.
This case is closed.
Take the prisoner away.
Paasonen, you may leave.
Take the men with you.
Aaro, future generations
will remember us as heroes.
Tell me you didn't really think
I'd pardon her.
Your superior, Lieutenant Manner
told me on the phone -
that you haven't
reported back to your unit.
That you're a wanted man.
And that those women weren't raped.
They wanted it.
That woman of yours copulates
like a beast, she doesn't know love.
Right, Aaro?
-If you say so.
I'm not a monster.
I'll let you say goodbye to her.
Why didn't you defend yourself?
Martta is dead and her son needs
a mother. You could have survived.
He sees us.
He wants you. Fullfill your promise.
Get me out of here.
Emil.
You can go home.
I feel like dancing.
Did you enjoy my wife's company?
Did you?
I don't much enjoy her company.
I think she's more your type.
What about that prisoner of yours?
Is she your type?
-How do you mean?
Tell me something.
-What?
Do you promise to tell me the truth?
No tales.
Just the truth.
I promise.
Did you and that Malin...
Or whatever her name is...
Did you two fornicate
on that island?
No.
I didn't touch that woman.
I knew it, Aaro.
You're different, just like I am.
We're special. -Yes.
Aaro.
Will you dance with me?
Like two soldiers dance together.
Do you ask clemency
for your prisoner?
I do.
You want to free the she-wolf.
Aaro.
In that case,
will you grant one wish for me?
I will.
You're a good soldier.
What's your wish?
Will you lie next to me tonight?
But not as two soldiers would lie.
You will do your duty, won't you?
-I will.
You will be back, won't you?
Get up.
Water, water. Water, water!
Water, water!
Go and get Jaeger Harjula.
-Water, water!
Harjula!
Jaeger Harjula
took the prisoner and...
Wait.
Hold this.
Just in case.
Put it on if you need to.
Come with me.
Would we be good together?
Go. Go.
Harjula! God damn you!
You're letting the prisoner escape!
She's been set free.
-Liar!
Hallenberg pardoned her.
Judge Hallenberg pardoned her.
Jaeger Harjula seems to have taken
the law into his own hands.
That woman won't be shot.
She's been set free. -Liar!
Alright, so we won't shoot.
Judge, this gun belongs to you.
The Red got away, but I'm sure
she's been caught by now.
Konsta.
Finland, my home country so lovely
The dearest of them all
Where the white-crowned trees
Surround the meadows so green
That is where I heard the birds sing
For the first time in my life
That is where my mother
Rocked my cradle
With a loving smile
Hands.
Come here.
Come now.
You didn't tell me you have an aunt.
It's wonderful to see you, Eino.
Now you get to go home with me.
A terrible tragedy,
what happened to Hallenberg.
We lost a great author.
How well did you know him?
Very well.
That's what I thought.
I feel sorry for his widow.
I hear she's pregnant too.
You've grown so much.
Do you remember your aunt, Eino?
Do you?
My name is Miina.
You're not my aunt.
-No, I'm not.
I guess we fooled them proper.
Can I call you Eikka?
-Can I call you mother?
Subtitles: Anitra Paukkula
Broadcast Text