Director originally the. Mulberry
add especially
star the aroma ofJoe. Rather
star the aroma to reach the
the name of movie wears the crusaders
of the cowboy
still leave 30 seconds
strange troops of promise 0-1 tempo
rarily wait to fall behind
whether this is the promise destin
y of the strange brigade?
The strange brigade forward of the
man promise runs about warea
he get the ball to prepare the to
shoot to was unfortunatelketkeeper
the appearance buttons up the
public to hang
see the water buffalo brigade
wicketkeeper did not foul from t
judge a game of a sound be over
along with the lord
...Promise the strange brigade
took the offensive to announce
...Thus they can't win the success
you do actually what? - You again
is at say what?
Is you ruined the troops
I am very helpless... - Also should
make at least an orders th
you make us disappoint too we take
you for ball team soul
still put blame on do I say you?
Need not worry the elder brothers
hello, man of.
Your treasure the son came
did not take care of first...
see the circumstance is thus- how
to can not see to sit the m
sit the mark to need yourself to settle
hello, man of. Today compete I
heard me very sad
in fact nothing important I now
is much better
input an after sit the mark the
machine will carry out the ins
will make to experiment with the
animal tomorrow
today stop here
you can affirm would send to the
target district? - Isn't very
...We are in from the monkey body
take out 24 hours valid DNA
if time did not compute false
it should come back within two days
help me to position to sit the
mark to is all right?
Send out
activate
what's the matter? - Can play?
Sat the mark to make sure
position the xy to sit to mark 200
times to set 48 hours
the xy sits to mark the fixed
position success
position time limited efficacy
48 hourses
the z sit the mark? - 15071212.
Hope that the laboratory usually
uses of sit the punctuation-
see the result of the time machine now
do you are really not sad? - Not sad
again is not my wrong- with a
clear conscience go
believe me....From where fall
flop from stand up there
greatly not change a club to
kick ball
is not one game of the feet
door- mother
game between strange brigade
and the water buffalo brigade of
...The strange brigade of a dragon
promise can't keep the body
this is the strange brigade history
of promise to ascend the m
certainly this is also the water
buffalo brigade history ascen
win the strange brigade of promise
after all is a very hard ma
this words are the water buffalos
brigade the bishop practices
still need to go where? - Right back
the athletics center of Talin
sits the mark
mother let I to take she wrap
12 hours
the computer of the laboratory how
at operate- I see
target area
not complete date
what do you do?
Close everything quickly come back
I will go to Spain
...You are also a peregrinator to
do not worry that I have no malice
lift his shell promise of walk
the food came
quickly walked to have no time
quickly walk you still delay what I...
don't walk again you will be eat
up by the wild beast of
Jean.
Don't hear and then calculate we walk
what person are you?
You again is what person
want to walk with us together? -
Need not I will leave tonight
Jean. The next move go where-
Walk while say
etc.
Go where? - Saint palace Christ church
you are Christians
today what day of the week?
Am I to ask several numbers of today?
Day of the Christ banister
you from which come? - Luo's virtuous
City, Holland
is your name? - Not yes I call
the man of.
Know this is today of Middle
Ages is July 15
15-07-1212(July 15 in 1212)
Damn to make the person hard to
place the letter
damn?
You are seek what things?
Also is not I all the way at
consider the problem
are you a Christian? - Isn't I
or student
at where go to school? - Virgin
Mary's morals schools
promise schools of? - Virtuous
college of card of? V
still in the monastery? - All is not...
at where where are you? - The
terrible affair took place
where are you at where?
He went to the ancient times
your son really went to the ancient
times I discovered to sit
he need help- I will save he
what? - Save him
you can't do so supervisor the boss
knew that you would be dis
we must wait for an inning
this is the big brigade of the
dynasty saint
young sport start by thousand
child of quite a few
young sport? Day and night and is
all right?
Is now that be constitute by the
adults before different
because God likes the child who
have the heart of
we act according to God of idea
aim let children go to dynasty
certainly act is all a religious
saint palace to start of
now...
give way
see inside the of
inside the
do not block inside the
defenseless thing of your this runt
walk to continue to walk
do not stop over
the young regiment that children
constitute arrives at here
regrettable I can't put you pass
we are god's son peoples this is
the god's battalion
the words that don't walk again I
Don't mention it
bow and arrow once shoot and then
didn't opportunity that take
don't want to be so and extremely
feeling we can measure with
hand over 200,000
continue to go forward
shoot!
I say to us 200,000
God's son the peoples please
say with me
...We are proletariats
stop the boy
stop to me
grasp you have you good-looking
what do we do now?
Wait my father to save us, I am
to say that negotiate with the
then? - Go to Jerusalem
we want to carry on dynasty's
do obeisance there
that is God to lead of place-
have no necessity to walk so an
you where know that only take
sincerely give activity
God would regard with affection
we give us a life time does th
Hey, shell promise.
Do not say that the big fish of
the lo lo came first
very big fish
do you how to go fishing?
I am to say...
use the pike
use the pike?
Do you not believe? - He has a
liking for to go to very handsf
thus very unpalatable arrive the
fish- we can
thus definite very unpalatable
arrive the fish we have plenty
you do not know that we from
generation to generation are all
I did not not understand to just
feel- smelly boy
I see your boy with a revolting
feeling I will polish off you
let you know my severe and smelly boy
(slander the words of the rebel)
Smelly guy(slander the words
of the rebel)
The Hey does not want to be thus-
(Slander the words of the
go to your mama of- bearer
Help- bearer
he is very strong
he is not strong he will
certainly be drown
he has no your thus small belly
chicken bowel
do not touch- he died
does the Hey hear?
He at dry what?
Useless
useless
he is at close family
don't want to be thus enough
certain very painful- the small
wound does not consider as wh
is this what things? - Watch
tell time of. - See what?
You don't say with other people
do you want to be dry- I have to walk
so and late you can go where?
You follow let him see he do what
very heavy rain
at where? - What?
The signpost that I let go of
at where?
Exactly at where? - Were washed
away by the rain-storm
at where? Where is the signpost
I want you
we take the devout heart to arrive
at here
but meet to block the road tiger
to have no way past
if now you can show supernatural
power to suggest for 1:00
you exactly from where come?
From my house- What?
I must leave here- do you have
the way?
Want to don't ask the pastor
probably he has the way
God openned with me a fun
God will not fool anyone
these are all the very impressive
- Iooking troops of child's ba
once the saint of dynasty these
childs all want to return to a
do not drop the brigade
the Hey returns to me
return to me
this is what things- Chicken
chicken?
Very delicacy
have no chicken in difficult way
in Holland?
We only have the plastics there
plastics
said with you that don't understand
this is the chocolate
chocolate
still consider the problem?
I want to go home now to want
to go home
if you would like to of words
can continue to walk with us
why?
I do not want to see your person
fall the brigade
certainly you have your viewpoint
Mary is thus useless
don't try to how to go- the strong
dint medicine powder is q
I can make sure that the xy sits
the mark to is a z to sit the
however I will get the answer by
tomorrow morning
I have this self-confidence to
believe me- useless
I have to tell you a fact
the monkey died
carry on on trial animal's dying
to know that but the most strong
animal in vitality
is mankind of 8000%- even they
all died
I know but my son is all right
and will not die within 2 days
go away
everyone wants to pick up the fuel
everyone...
do not go to bed quick pick up
the fuel
if the words of the thirst can
come to river water
trust the water and didn't be
poisonous
let do not push
step aside
a ground
I feel that you be subjected to
the beguilement
quickly the opportunity to seek
escape- talk the careful poin
all right you not are to say that
have the pastor
you can't still see the pastor now
you want to seek the dead again
I call the man of. The add.
Come from Luo's virtuous City
I want to see your leader of a group
leader of a group
this is the leader of a group
the thou pulls the.
The night is best I call the man
of. The add. - Talk taint
continue to say. - I call the man
of. The add...
...Come from Luo's virtuous City
quickly take the man of that
virtuous of Luo come
what person are they?
They are too hungry the thou of
pulls the leader of a grou
...I am from yesterday start
consider you plan it is very good
a crazy speech
is the words of the man of are
not our meaning
the thou of pulled the leader
of a group of to bring 200
is 8000.
you want to say exactly what
I want to ask you to beat the
way return to mansion
God tells me your everything in
the dream
you are unfamiliar
I want to obstruct the all these
shut up
he just wants to save me
I call the card I am a daughter
who wears the...
you need not doubt him
all right I know how to do
although very difficult can we
are a teams
this debt camp is how we should
protect them
the children caught cold in the
evening the second day have a
I think this reasonable
we can save their why not
host but you should know we have
more than 100 childs here
have a lot of childs this is
their misery
my in a dream did not appear the
stranger from the beginning
God is how to tell your be careful
careful save these childs
compare especially. The thou of
pulls the, can you promis
we have this responsibility not is
this is really too terrible
there are more than 8000 childs here
I how to do? You need not worry so of
this is our II everythings
this is our dream
arrive in spite of where do we
can't forget
we can't leave this
here you what also can not get
find the to pull the for thou
he is a very generou
he will believe I of
you saved them
they will hear your because you
are a leader
this is a miracle to me
did you see him I never saw...
gram of...
this is the most meaningful affair
of life
the sorry bothered
the tile is virtuous. Anne the
promise wishes to see you ver
he let I to invite you
have today how much have 100
be missing
this nation?
You take this is all
very good today is not bad
this is the wealth that we continue
to develop
Joe's gram man.
Don't know whether you would like
to sleep in our tent or not
do you think the accommodation
probably you two can
tell me that you like now of
very perfect
you really let are them thus?
They are not childses to have
no right thus
if good care child... of their
ability
he would to host's loyalty
but the children combine the
insecurity you know what?
This seemed to ask for not a few
troubles to me
however I will look after good
these childs of
do you think so Joe's gram man
I have the kind thing to you
the is strange
this is just the... I am not in
the mood for
ask you to do not mind... - The
is strange.
I am not an in the mood for...
in Luo's virtuous
sorry
have no matter of can't
if you come over again I would
be Don't mention it
you think we whether... - Mary.
Please say, the cloth of. - I
saw the.
I want to let him leave at once
this to the utmost
this is the decision of my end
you can't do so of
you can't contact with him again
the man of is innocent
I must bring back he come sorry, Mary
can the boss has already
hand over to you
welcome you, the is virtuous.
WEN NUO4 will not let°pass the
thou of to pull the of
I think and would come to this
sees him
Mary.
Is the? - Not just very certain
this is the thunder gram- Today
we really shouldn't come out
why come to this you receive what news
we can't accept these childs
an also can't
they also can't be in my LIN2
QU's activity
I will release my dog
you dided not hear the recent
occurrence what?
I think that God can't protect their
you are just not to comprehend
they are future everythings and
you what also is not
is true?
You very the courage dares to
talk to me thus
I extremely disallow you enter
the here
can I am unique to can make this
we are best to go to together
you can't
not, we need to make to order to
eat for the children of you c
work well your own business
I will feel grateful very much
of please
your really very generous my host
can I want to help these ch
do you have to order food for me
I want to bring them
have already had no time now
card.
I have this
bring from Holland
hope that you can accept
do not fear
boy, you think where is that I
come from? - Holland
I went to Holland is not to come
from there
probably this is similar to you
I did not see such thing from
the beginning
if you have what help you can
tell me
where do you come from?
The is virtuous...
do you see God? He is very the
kindly
not, can I know and should do what
can you never saw him
we must face some affairs
what we to face is much more
than only now
Jean, come to
is my American
you are see what
the child got sick the disease
very seriously
I miss that he just wears cool
does she will die
we want to let these childs separate
you know that this kind
infect yes
will infect yes
we want to separate with others they
want to be quickly
take some water
take the child to come over