Apple, lemon, mandarin,
strawberry, banana, orange!
THE MAN WHO WILL COME
Martina! Look at your dress,
it's all creased!
You can't go to church like that!
DECEMBER 1943
Martina,
you shouldn't have been born.
You should have been born
into a family of masters.
Come here, get on this.
Take it off.
Try this one on.
That was my dress!
It's nicer than the one you've got.
My girl, I don't understand you
and your superior attitude.
You stayed away for so long
and you never wrote home.
No one can read here,
what's the point?
I'm glad you're back,
but with that coat and that dress...
what'll people say?
I won't be a maid for long.
What'll you do then?
You'll end up being a prostitute!
So all the women who go to the city
are maids or prostitutes?
Just don't come home pregnant!
Who'll put baby Jesus there?
- Me! - Me! - Me!
- Martina, give him to me!
- You can't do it, he'll die.
- It's her mother's fault, not hers.
- Give him to me! - Give him to me!
Enough!
I'll do it. Tomorrow, when it's time.
See you in church tomorrow!
Hey, dumb girl!
Has your belly grown?
- Witch!
- What's in your tummy, a baby?
You dog's daughter!
Witch!
What do you think you'll find there?
Everyone's hungry.
On Christmas Eve
you shouldn't do certain things.
You want it more than me.
You want it, you always love tojoke.
Go easy with that bread!
If you do lots of hours,
do they pay more?
A day's work is a day's work.
Whether you're a farmer
or a bricklayer and get paid daily,
it's always work,
the money's the same.
Uncle, you're wrong. I'm right.
- We have to go.
- Go where?
If we go to Bologna, you'll get
more money for a day's work.
And even more in Milan.
And if you go to America,
you'll get whatever you want.
And if you work seventy hours?
You always use silly examples!
What did you do?
I'll speak to you later.
We're here to celebrate
and there's no food.
Ask God Almighty why
you were born poor and ignorant.
If we're ignorant,
ignorant we'll remain.
You should've been a priest
if you wanted to eat!
"Blue blossom of benevolence,
bless my mom and dad."
"Beautiful blonde baby
you lie in a straw bed
yet you are king of the world."
"I want to cover you with kisses."
"I give you my heart, my Lord,
but with the angels
who surround you in heaven
bring me their love
and make me good like them."
"Make mom and dad happy, Lord."
Move up.
Feel how cold you are.
You know what the biggest sin is?
What do you mean?
Is it worse to kill...
or to make love?
- What makes you ask that?
- I thought you knew.
When you make love it's nice...
If it's a sin, that's a shame!
And if another man touches you?
Are you the sinner...
or is he?
I don't know, you should
ask the priest these things.
Are you expecting?
No...
but I think I'm in love.
I've come about the farm.
No, nothing's changed.
The law stipulates
that you cannot leave the farm
without the approval
of the local Fascist group.
The work force?
How many children do you have?
You've been around the world
for work,
you should be grateful that
they're still giving you the land.
- Must I fill in another form?
- You farmers are stubborn!
Only God commands me...
and that's enough!
Why are you here?
You're nothing but a beast!
They were dropping bombs,
it was mayhem. I ran away.
The fascists already came here
looking for deserters.
We need to keep moving,
it's going to rain.
Why must we stay here all day
when we have so much to do?
Don't worry. Lf you think about
the debts, the grapes will go sour.
It's the way you do things
that changes things.
Calmly, patiently...
- Master. - Good morning, Armando.
I'm accompanying these Germans.
They want wine, I've run out.
Lena, take them home.
Get some eggs and wine.
I'm glad, master,
that you have new friends.
You know I gave to your friends,
but if I have these,
I must keep them happy.
Why aren't they at home, looking
after their families and their land?
- We've got enough worries.
- History is full of wars.
- History? Who cares about history
and who makes it?
All those that kill people and steal
from the poor become important.
Is that history?
Then they recite the words
of Jesus Christ!
- I didn't mean you.
You shouldn't talk like that, because
I can understand you, but them...
Let them catch me then
and kill me, but enough!
They can't kill me twice!
I can smell snow.
When night falls at sea,
it's dark...
and you can hear sounds...
The sea is full of giant fish,
as big as houses,
with huge mouths...
as they chase ships
and try to eat them.
And they want to eat us too.
Everyone prays on the ship,
but every so often
a giant wave arrives
and takes the bad men away.
And the fish?
They eat them!
At the end of the voyage,
we arrived at a port in Sardinia.
We took the train from there
then we walked across mountains
like ours
where there were only shepherds
and brigands.
How many trees did you cut down?
The elders did that,
I was too young.
I was just a helper, like him.
But I worked all the same.
Day and night, like the others.
I'd make polenta, fetch the water...
I even kept watch.
Sometimes, it seemed like
the trees were watching me
and telling me about their life.
And then...
Good evening. I'm a merchant, I can't
go back to Bologna with this snow.
- Come in.
- Thanks.
If I could stay the night...
Wherever you want...
I don't mind, even with the lad.
- The stable's big.
- Thank you.
Sit down.
I can pay for the bother.
I was taught that you don't
ask money from those who need it.
You have to be careful round here,
I've heard there are rebels here too.
On a night like this,
even the rebels feel the cold.
Poppet!
I've got some candies.
What's your name?
Aren't you cold?
Here...
There you are.
One and two.
You're a pretty girl.
Poppet!
They sent a spy.
A guy from Vergato.
While everyone was asleep
in the refuge
and the Wolf was keeping watch.
This guy, I don't even know
how he did it.
He pulled out a knife
and stabbed him in the stomach.
Then he jumped on me,
but I woke up
and moved away.
It was dark...
The Wolf was on the floor,
yelping like a beast.
The guy looked mad,
he was stabbing whatever he could.
I didn't know what was going on.
I don't know how Fonso did it.
He pulled out a gun
and shot that piece of shit
right in the face.
This is our land, we were born here
and we've always lived here.
- Why should we let the Germans command
us now? - They think we're beasts.
You know what? I've never seen
what they do anywhere in the world.
They do the opposite
of what we were taught to do
What shall we do then? Put
on a uniform and take up arms too?
We'd become like them.
We are the same as you.
Come with us.
- We have to do something - You're
right, but this is real war.
And a real war has to be fought with
guns, weapons... You need the works!
- It's not a game. - We have to think
about what we want to leave our children.
The spies come up here too.
You've got some courage.
- You could be team leader.
- No.
Go ahead and shoot,
you may as well...
I don't want to command.
Let me do what I want, but I don't
want to command, I'm not capable.
If you want mines planted,
I'm not scared, I've been a soldier.
But I don't want to shoot.
No one uses their real name here,
you have to choose another name.
Because if you're caught,
the less you know the better.
You have to respect
all of your companions
and don't get any political ideas
in your head.
You know why you're here?
I'll tell you why.
You're here because back there...
There are fascists and Germans.
But this is your home,
and that of your grandparents.
And it's where your family lives.
Remember that
and when you see a German,
don't run away, fight him.
We don't have much time,
we have to be quick.
It's still warm.
Try it, it's nice and sweet.
Are you scared that pig's ghost
will come for you at night?
You can't even kill a pig in peace
anymore!
They've put a tax on pork,
damn them!
They'll put a tax
on farting too soon!
Be quiet, Saint Anthony
is watching you.
My family are farmers.
There's only a few of them
buta baby brother's arriving.
They work the land for a man
who has a beautiful horse.
But my father says that
he takes too much of the harvest
and that he's still a master
Sometimes the Germans come up
to buy things.
They can'tspeak Italian
and I don't know why they come here
... when they could be at home
with their children...
Because they have them too.
The Germans have arms and they shoot
the enemy, I don't know who that is.
I heard that they're at war against
the Allies but I've never seen them.
Then there are the rebels,
who fight because they say
the Germans must leave.
The rebels have arms too.
Many of them speak our language
and dress like us.
Their chief is called Wolf.
Everyone fears him,
but they all care about him.
My Uncle Dino cares about him too
and says we must help him.
My father says we must help him too,
but that he has the land
and can'tgo with them.
There are fascists too...
"There are fascists too that come up
And they speak our language too."
"But they shout and say that the rebels
are bandits who should be killed."
"This is what I've understood:
Lots of people want to kill others,
but I don't understand why."
Are you mad to write such things?
Forgive us.
Don't worry,
but you'd better burn it.
Yes, thank you.
Why do you want to go dancing?
We're always working, slaving away,
I'm begging you.
I said no so it's no!
They always do the same round,
the tree, the roof then the chimney.
Wine... good wine.
Pity, we could've had some bread.
It needs baking.
Eggs and wine.
I'll see if there are some more eggs.
No! Martina, you'd better go.
We're lacking lots of things
in these times.
- Nice hands.
- Sorry. I'm married.
And I'm pregnant too.
You certainly don't lack courage.
Beniamina! Maria!
Why are you here?
Shame on you! Go home.
We'll deal with you later.
Go home, Martina
Go on, go home.
In the name of God,
have mercy.
This is what happens
when people don't respect rules.
Father...
you are not leading
your flock along the right path.
- I'll go there and take them down all
the same. - I told you it's forbidden.
If it's forbidden then follow me
and shoot me.
One moment...
One moment, I'll give you some candies.
Here, one for you...
Wait...
Don't go near the donkey.
Come in, I've got some wine
and need some company.
I'm coming, Armando.
Who's this?
You're more beautiful than ever.
Forgive her, she's become wild.
She hasn't spoken since her newborn
brother died in her arms.
You could send her to the institute
for the deaf in Bologna.
May I?
I didn't forget about you,
I told you.
- I've come for the baskets.
- Thanks, to our good fortune.
My cousin came here because
Bologna's too dangerous now.
They keep dropping bombs
and they've issued a proclamation
calling up soldiers.
If they catch me, they'll kill me.
He could pay to stay here
and do some work in return.
Many men hide in the tunnels
made for the Direttissima.
I've not come here to hide.
If there's a war to be fought,
I want to be on the winning side.
It's impossible to know who'll win.
The winners are those
who remain alive.
They've made a group here...
that lot.
How can I meet them?
Go into the woods. If they're there,
sooner or later you'll find them.
- They're coming too. - How much
money will they give? - I don't know.
You should tell your employers
that they must pay us.
You're full of lice.
Isn't your head itchy?
- We'll need to shave your hair off.
- No, use some oil.
You've come to teach us things?
Oil? Oil costs money!
Good morning.
Here...
- My mother.
- How do you do? - Nice to meet you.
- It's not as nice as your house...
Don't worry. It'll be fine,
we've come here to be safe.
They keep bombing Bologna,
we can't trust anyone anymore.
I hope you'll be happy here.
We tidied up the room a bit.
Don't worry,
we've come to be safe.
If we don't help each other,
in these times...
My niece and my sister-in-law.
- Hello, I'm Giovanni Bugamelli.
- Nice to meet you.
This is my wife.
- Hello, I'm Clara. - How do you do?
- These are our children.
- Laura and Guglielmo.
I brought something for you.
You can't even get anything
on the black market anymore
What do they expect us to do?
- Here.
- Thank you.
It's beautiful, thank you!
It's for the baby
you're expecting.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
- One times eight?
- Eight.
- Two times eight?
- Sixteen.
- Three times eight?
- Twenty-four.
- You stink!
- 4 x 8? - You stink, how gross!
Enough!
Martina!
Go to the back
so they won't bother you.
Come on, don't be upset.
They're all idiots.
Why don't you say something to me?
Come on!
Why won't you talk to me?
"I'm going... to have...
a little brother."
Are you happy?
But they'll ignore you.
"I'm going to have... lots."
How do you know?
What is it?
A parachute?
Mr. Bugamelli! Madam!
They'll be in church with the women!
Hurry, you go too!
What are you doing in there?
They're coming!
We're all going to Casaglia,
the men will go into the woods.
- You'd better go into the woods.
- Where?
Into the woods, I'll take you.
Into the woods, let's go!
Let's go to the church,
they won't bomb that.
Go.
I can't stay in here.
I'll go out, onto a tree.
- Wait!
- Don't do it!
They're coming from all sides.
The partisans will defend us, right?
- Well? - The partisans
are hiding and they're getting shot.
They're sending them back.
Gnac, Penna...
Tell the other groups
that we're leaving.
- What?
- What are you going to do?
Why are you staying here?
To prepare a fire for the Germans?
Lots of them will arrive.
We have to do what the allied
secret service said,
strike then leave.
Come on!
The soldiers!
The Germans are coming!
Come on, let's go!
What are you doing?
We'll starve now!
Tell me, where are they?
Where are they?
Talk to me!
Where were you?
Let Mary be my mother,
Saint Joseph my father
let the saints be my relatives
and may you be safe.
- Come on, Lena, rest a while.
- There's still a lot to do.
- The weather's about to change.
- We can do this later.
Sit down here.
We'll get some water.
Come on, we'll make it.
Come here.
It's nothing.
Look after it,
it's all I've got.
Thank you, for the job too.
Don Fornasini, my wife
would like you to baptise our child.
It's best the doctor sees him,
it's a deep wound.
Why split you up? You're mad.
What'll you resolve then?
Wolf is incapable of commanding.
Sugano left because Wolf
doesn't want to know about politics.
You can't stay here.
Keep this paper, after the war...
What'll we do with it?
We can't eat paper.
First they take our cattle,
now you're taking the rest.
In the war, you need to know
which side to be on.
Anyway,
we're on your side.
Lena, got any salt?
The Germans!
I'll bring you some.
Good morning. Did you want
some salt? This is all we have.
Why are you here?
Don Fornasini sent me,
I got here during the night.
- Did you come about the roof job?
- Yes.
Good.
I brought a hen.
Turn around.
What is it, Martina?
What's happened?
Martina, what is it?
Do you need to confess?
What's it like?
What's in there?
A whole world.
Put this on. There.
Pull it down.
Stop.
Don't move, I'll adjust it there.
You're so beautiful, Martina.
You look like a bride.
Give your brother a caress.
Is your little brother sleeping?
Why are you wearing
your communion dress?
Take it off after.
It's going to rain.
Go get some firewood.
And see if you can find some apples.
Did something happen to the baby?
Come with me!
Come on, move it! The Germans!
They're coming.
We have to go, the Germans are coming.
Again?
Hurry, we have to get out!
We have to go, the Germans are coming.
Lena can't go anywhere,
I'll stay with her.
- Are you sure? - Go to
the woods, they'll spare us.
Martina has to go to the function
at the school in Cerpiano.
Let's go, Martina.
Let's go. Martina!
- Come on, Martina!
- Let's go, Martina. - Go with auntie.
Martina, let's go!
It's slippery here.
Take this.
Stay calm, don't worry.
- What's going on?
- Don't worry.
Stay calm...
Don't worry.
The young men must go to the woods,
women and children in the church.
Stay calm.
You go down to Cerpiano,
I'll arrive for the Angel service.
- Yes. - All right.
- All right. - Go, Martina.
- Guglielmo, come here!
- Leave him, he's with the children.
Dai che andiamo dentro noi.
- We're praying.
- You have to come with us.
Now! Come on, now!
All hell broke loose in Cadotto.
They made a surprise attack on us.
- Let me see.
They're taking them away.
- Filthy partisans!
- Are you blind?
Can't you see we're all women,
children and elderly people?
- What partisans?
- The baby!
We've got nothing to do with it,
we're from Bologna.
You see? We even have
something for you.
I'll be back.
She looks just like my wife.
Is the baby yours?
Mom! Mom! Mom!
Mom! Mom! Mom! Mom!
Holy Mother!
Mom! Hurry, give me a hand.
Holy Mother! What have
they done to you? Give me the baby.
Come inside.
Give it to me.
Give me your foot.
Good girl.
Women, children...
This morning, in San Martino,
they found another forty of them.
We buried them all together,
we couldn't take risks.
I asked around,
but no one saw him.
He'll be hiding in the woods.
You'll see, many men will have escaped.
We all are...
what they taught us to be.
It's a matter of education.
I don't think the young lady
knows how to dance.
Don't you agree?
Those aren't the steps.
Come away from there.