[ Skipped item nr. 1 ]
[ Skipped item nr. 2 ]
Left, two, three, four!
Company,,,
halt!
Weapons straight ahead!
Take cover!
On your feet and march!
Left face!
Left, two, three, four.
Company, halt!
We're so exhausted.
A German must never fear fatigue.
Karl, I'm not complaining.
Damned chicken!
Fifty plus 1 0 equals 60, my friend.
Did you count my king?
This is a republic.
Kings don't count here.
This is how you dress
when visiting a foreign land?
Candles, socks...
Mr. Haussmann, your bill is ready.
It comes to 57 francs
and 7 5 centimes...
barring any error, of course.
I trust you, Mr. Rechampot.
You'll be paid
within three months, as usual.
I'm not worried.
You always pay on time.
Maryvonne?
Come down here.
Our friend is about to leave.
- What?
- He's leaving.
He's leaving.
Let's have one last drink.
Alas, I cannot.
You mustn't insult us.
A quick one will do you good.
The road is long.
I must be back by tomorrow evening.
Exactly.
It'll give you strength.
Another time, madam.
So, my friend.
At ease.
If we weren't here to keep them supplied,
the Germans would be in trouble.
Please convey my respects
to your priests.
I'm sure they're out in the bush
making new Christians.
They'll be back in two weeks,
if they're not eaten alive fiirst.
Attention!
Take up your packs!
Hurry up over there!
Faster!
On the double!
Company, right face!
Forward march!
Good Lord.
He works them hard!
Give my best to your offiicers!
Jawohl, madam. I'll do that.
That's all well and good...
but let's have a drink
before Mr. Rechampot sells it all.
Look at this,
all broken and beat up.
What can I give you for that?
Here, I'll give you a cross.
Now go on.
Let me see.
Here.
This Sacred Heart card is very nice.
Tell him a Sacred Heart
is more than fair.
That's not even worth a cross.
He says he wants the big colored statue
of the woman and child.
He says his necklace
is extremely valuable.
Then he can keep his necklace
and I'll keep my Sacred Heart.
I'll give you a cross
for the rest and off with you!
This is really getting on my nerves!
- You shouldn't expect much here.
- They know us too well.
Next.
Fidele.
HAPPY NEW YEAR 1 91 5
Yes, Sergeant?
Nothing.
I thought you might want
to talk about...
the younger sister
of my brother-in-law's cousin.
The one I spoke to you about.
No, it was nothing.
Just talking.
But the young girl says...
she can do everything
just the way you like it.
Who taught her?
The old woman
who comes often to visit you.
Tell her to come knock
at my door one evening.
I'll do that.
You'll be pleased.
Leon?
Come on.Just for me.
I'm not in the mood.
The appetite grows with the eating.
Come on.
What's wrong?
Don't you ever get excited anymore?
To Mr. Lucien Herr,
College of Advanced Education...
45 rue d'Ulm,
Fifth Arrondissement, Paris...
in care of Administrator Tarato...
St. Pierre de Samba,
French Equatorial Africa.
Fort Coulais,January 6, 1 9 1 5.
Dear teacher and,
if I may, dear friend.'
Here is my punishment for not excelling
in nobler gfields of study.
I should be teaching Greek
in one of those pleasant schools...
of which our province is so proud...
but instead here I am
under a summer sky...
wandering through virgin savannahs...
picking native grasses
and collecting mineral specimens.
What good fortune
to be a simple geographer.!
Africa is far from being the hell
depicted in writings from the colonies.
Where I expected
to encounter gfierce beasts...
I fiind only dogs, cows, chickens...
and the occasional duck.
Where I expected ferocious savages...
armed with spears, lances
and poisoned arrows...
ready to turn all travelers
into a quick meal...
I meet only peaceful villagers...
whose pastoral lives remind me...
of the country folk
in many parts of our own land.
The only dangers I battle here
are boredom...
and the company
of a handful of our compatriots...
with whom I must rub elbows.
Listen,just because it's my turn
to be on watch tonight...
you don't have to take
such a long siesta.
Don't worry.
There's lots more for you.
The bastard!
Where are those empire builders...
those modern-day knights
and intrepid pioneers...
that all those adventure novels
had us dreaming of?.
Payback!
So I feel quite alone here.
Moreover, it's been six months...
since we've had any visitors
or correspondence.
It seems such delays are not unusual
in this part of Africa.
But I'm longing to know
what is happening in Paris these days.
What are they playing
at the theater and the opera?
What is Debussy composing?
What is Peguy up to?
And what's new
with our socialist friends?
As for the colonies,
tell our friends not to be so sure...
about the inferiority
of the black race.
Seen up close, this inferiority has less
to do with the shape of the skull...
or the composition of the blood...
than with the conviction we hold
of our own superiority.
At the risk of shocking you...
I daresay that in many respects...
the natives are not far from meriting
the honored name of''men. ''
Thank you, Barthelemy.
Dear teacher, I wish you
a happy and peaceful 1 9 1 5.
Respectfully yours...
Hubert Fresnoy.
There's no end to this junk.
Garbage!
This one's not too bad.
This we'll keep too.
Like the monsignor says, you can't even
give this stuff away to charity.
In the provinces, maybe.
Bad taste has limits
even in the provinces.
How I love this song!
Oh, my back!
- Thomas, how are you?
- Fine, Father.
- Are you here all alone?
- All alone.
- The other fathers aren't here?
- No.
But surely they'll be
returning tonight?
I don't know.
Have they been gone a long time?
- Long time.
- Long time very much?
Long time a little.
And they left no word for us?
They said monsignor said
they should join him.
What's all this about?
I don't know.
Didn't anything arrive for us
at Fort Coulais?
Nothing.
So there is something after all.
This isn't for us?
Not for you.
It's for the young man
who loves plants.
And where does that young man live?
Fort Coulais.
And where do we live?
You live at Fort Coulais.
But this isn't for us?
It's for you.
Great! Something to read!
Jaures has been assassinated!
Who?
- Who?
-Jaures.
Go on.
Mr. Hubert, you mustn't get upset.
God in Heaven!
My friends, we're at war.
Who is ''we''?
Us. France.
What's the date on that, Father?
- August 3rd.
- My God.
Does it say how it turned out?
They only go up to August 1 3th.
Who are we at war with, Father?
Germany, of course!
Really?
I would have said the English.
- Damn it!
- What?
That means I'm out
57 francs and 7 5 centimes!
Germany's never going to pay now!
What?
Germany.
- It's right out there!
- So?
The Krauts are out there!
That's right!
Luckily they can't know yet.
Everything comes through us.
- You hear that, Bosselet?
- It's time to wake up.
What are you so excited about?
- We're not excited!
- Yes, you are.
Remember: The military authorities
take charge in a case like this.
Exactly!
And around here, that's you!
In any case, it's clear:
The motherland is in danger.
Vive la France.!
Aren't you going to say
Vive la France?
You can't do that.
Imagine how you'd look.
- Like French patriots, that's how!
- French patriots!
How do you even know
this war isn't already over?
How can it be over?
It's hardly gotten started!
Mr. Rechampot, your little expedition
could turn out very badly.
Something like that
takes preparation, believe me.
And be careful about declaring war
on the Germans. They're no amateurs!
- There's only three of them!
- And they're all fools.
And I'd say their leader, Mr. Krafft,
in not much different than you.
All brains and no brawn!
Mr. Krafft doesn't seem to me
a man of action.
Please, Father, stay out of this.
Ever heard of Alsace and Lorraine?
Maybe I never told you...
but I'm from Alsace.
Couldn't you show a little spirit
at a moment like this?
To fiight three Germans
who've never done you any harm...
you so-called Christians--
- What do you mean, so-called?
- That's right.
You're willing to risk
massacring dozens of men!
What men?
There are only us and the blacks here,
and at most a few soldiers.
That's enough, Mr. Rechampot!
Watch your tone, young man!
I'm on my home turf here!
- Anyway, this is a discussion for men!
- I am a businessman, sir!
In light of the law ofJuly 7, 1 900,
on organizing a colonial army...
and the decree of February 7, 1 91 2,
and subsequent dates...
on recruiting an army...
and in light of certain indications
of the existence of a state of war...
between France and Germany...
and in light of the responsibility
vested in me...
I, Sergeant Auguste Bosselet...
hereby call upon every man
of French nationality...
with permanent
or temporary residence...
at Fort Coulais
in French Equatorial Africa...
to place himself at my command.
Article Number 1 :
A general draft is now in force.
This is better
than a New Year's Eve party!
Hey, Marius,
they're celebrating something.
Maybe that way
they'll leave us alone tomorrow.
Residents of Fort Coulais...
the Republic needs you.
In the name of France,
I call upon all able-bodied natives...
of the masculine sex...
wishing to volunteer to support France
for the duration of hostilities.
The engagement of such volunteers
will go forward legally.
They will be provided
with clothes, shoes and equipment...
as supplies permit.
As a special bonus...
each man will receive,
while supplies last...
a useful household item
provided by the House of Rechampot.
Registration is now open.
Go on and join.
I'm glad that's over with.
These men don't understand French.
Someone should interpret.
What does it matter? If they don't
understand now, they soon will.
Anyway, I'm sure they agree.
Perhaps.
But it should be explained to them.
Marius, did you understand all that?
How would I not understand?
- Then you could explain to them.
- Of course I could.
What are you doing here?
Get the hell back to the store!
Step forward!
Did you see that?
Nobody helps out anymore.
Press your fiinger here.
Open your mouth.
We need to fiind you a name.
Let's see.
Saturnin.
Your name will be Armand.
What is it, son?
Don't like that one?
Then give him a different one.
I wrote down two
and only give him one.
Jerome.
Open your mouth.
Alexis.
You are Volunteer Hippolyte.
Hippolyte.
I know your sister.
That's two, four, six, eight--
Two, three, four, fiive, six--
Out of my way.
Two, four, six, eight, 1 0, 1 2.
I counted 1 2 this morning.
That makes 1 2 rifles on the table...
plus fiive hunting rifles,
one of which is an automatic.
- I want that one back.
- Okay. Return to owner.
So six and six is 1 2, and six is--
And six is 1 8.
Hey, knock it off!.
You're making me lose count.
Six and fiive makes 1 1 .
Six and fiive make 1 1 ,
plus six make 1 7, plus 1 2--
Seventeen and--
Twenty-nine.
- Seventeen and 1 2 make 29.
- Whatever you say.
Twenty-nine?
Hell, this should be over quickly.
We've got fiive dry cases and two
slightly damp cases of cartridges.
You see, Bosselet?
God is on our side.
Of course. God is French!
All right.
I'll need a week to teach
the volunteers the bare rudiments.
What? A week?
Are you crazy?
We're not running a pension! They don't
eat much, but it costs all the same.
All they need to know
is how to load a gun!
They may well be idiots,
but they can learn that in a day!
The regulations dictate
a certain minimum instruction.
Don't think you're going to make
these men into a real army!
You may not realize it, but we've been
at war for six months now!
If you're looking for the element
of surprise, Bosselet, don't draw this out.
You're right, Father.
I propose Sunday.
- Sunday?
- Why not?
You mean this Sunday?
Are you crazy?
We'd have to leave tomorrow night.
Exactly!
Sunday is when Protestants
put on their big show in church.
They're distracted.
We show up and -- pow!
We'll give them a blessing, all right!
Without getting into that...
you can't go wrong
choosing the Lord's day.
Still, tomorrow night...
That's not much time.
Clear the way!
Thank you, Lamartine.
So, my son, you chose the infantry?
I'd like to speak to you
about something.
I intend to visit the Germans
without delay.
If Mr. Krafft is indeed
as much like me as you say...
I should have no trouble
persuading him...
that with ten against one,
resistance is pointless.
But my plan would be
more effective and persuasive...
if one of you would accompany me.
No, Mr. Fresnoy.
Why?
You don't know the Germans.
You can't comprehend
the German mentality.
At the moment
it's yours I can't comprehend.
Look at this chic fellow!
You haven't seen my brother yet.
Fathers, take a look
at the ambassadors of French style.
Ladies, are you going
to keep us waiting much longer?
We're almost ready.
Look at her tiny waist!
A delicate orchid.
She's so pretty!
It's now 9:1 2.
9:1 2 on January 22, 1 91 5.
We're preparing to go forth
from our native land.
The land where life is sweet
ends right here.
Over there is enemy territory...
which we will conquer by force.
That over there
could easily be the Rhine.
In fact, it is.
Let us cross the Rhine...
even if, due to unfortunate
circumstances...
it is but a modest stream.
I must set an example.
Bosselet, send the flag over.
The flag has made it.
This is so exciting!
There it is.
We're there.
I recognize this spot.
Through that shrubbery.
Those two white spots.
Next to the cliff.
That's their base.
No use going on much further.
It's too hot.
Bosselet, we'll leave you here.
We're stopping here, but you keep on.
See you later.
But we're with you in spirit!
Here.
There's shade...
and a nice view,
and we're not too close.
We'll stop here.
Stop.
Halt!
The House of Rechampot
is proud to bring you...
an aperitif of noble
and patriotic character...
that you won't fiind
at even the best seaside resorts.
Perhaps even Mr. Hubert...
our Marquis of Geography,
will do us the honor of--
Where is Hubert?
- Where is he?
- He was back there.
There he is.
Don't go! Come back, Fresnoy!
Are you crazy?
Get over there!
Listen to me, son.
You'd had some schooling.
I'm sure you're a real brain,
but this is our home and our business!
These are serious and tragic events,
bigger than all of us.
This is war, son,
and we're all in it together.
You've been drafted like everyone else.
He thought he was beyond the law.
Hard to understand
such a mentality.
Your fiield may be geography...
but what we're creating here
is history!
Marius, give me that bottle.
You'll drink like everyone else.
Weak stomach or no weak stomach,
you'll drink to France.
Assomption!
Mr. Rechampot asked me to fiind out
when your chickens will be ready.
- It's starting!
- To our brave soldiers!
That's the way, Bosselet.
He's really letting them have it.
Listen.
Pass me a little--
That's called a machine gun.
What? What did he say?
A machine gun, madam.
I think they're right.
The bastards!
Whatever it is...
if it keeps up like that...
I'd say it's time to close up shop.
QUick, get everything together.
Hurry!
What does that fellow want?
- What's he saying?
- The volunteer says, ''I fell in a hole.
I didn't see it.
It was hidden by branches.
At the bottom of the hole
was a sharp stick.''
The volunteer says, ''You must go
fiind my friend in the other hole.
The stick stuck him in the butt
and he can't pull it out.''
Virgin Mary, have mercy.
Others are coming!
It's nothing. It's nothing!
The volunteer says, ''I fell in a hole,
and in the hole was a--''
Yes, we know!
Damn it! This can't be!
Look at that!
Go away!
You know any doctors in the area?
There are no doctors here!
Come on, come on!
Father.
We really only lost the bugler, after all.
So let the Krauts come anytime.
We've still got fiive soldiers.
I say they won't come.
And so what if they do?
The Germans aren't total savages.
We know them, after all.
White men can always
reason with one another.
Unless we killed one of them.
What are you saying?
We didn't have time.
Don't worry.
We put up a pathetic fiight.
Go on! Have you no shame?
We recovered everything, sir.
Nothing is missing.
You witnessed my fiirst defeat.
You couldn't well have witnessed
my second, now, could you...
since this was my fiirst battle.
Make no mistake about it:
With their weapons,
they can slaughter us anytime they want.
We're in a bad mess.
Very bad.
I acted like an idiot.
No surprise there.
I am one.
Not tonight, darling.
This isn't the time.
Come back some other night.
It's me, Sergeant.
Forgive me, Mr. Fresnoy.
What's going on?
What's the matter?
I'd like to speak with you...
because I know you and I
understand each other.
That's very kind of you to say.
Because I'm--
Five years away from retirement.
I was just putting it all down
in my report.
Too bad we lost the bugler.
They gave us six soldiers
and we have to return six to them.
They're counted
the same as white men.
You may have to account
for him one day...
but I know you were pressured...
by certain people around here
taking the law into their own hands.
I wasn't keen on it.
You think those people can get us
out of the fiix they've put us in?
If you only knew them.
They're...
What do you plan to do now?
Finish my report.
What I meant is,
do you know where you're heading?
For the time being,
I've taken certain precautions.
And what about later?
Do you have a plan?
Yes, I do.
No, I have no plan.
Sit down.
I have a few ideas to propose
to remedy the situation.
I know one doesn't learn
how to fiight a war from books...
and you know me primarily
as a geographer.
But I've also studied a bit of history.
I'm sure you have, Mr. Fresnoy.
Idea number one:
War is too serious
to leave to shopkeepers.
I agree entirely.
Then follow me.
What is it?
Another of his nightmares.
I was dreaming--
You sure were.
There's someone here.
No, Assomption, there's no one here.
Everything's fiine.
I said, ''There's someone here,''
but they don't answer.
It's us, Father.
Ah, it's you.
Forgive us for disturbing your sleep.
We weren't asleep.
Sergeant Bosselet feels
the moment has come...
to calculate the consequences
of yesterday's unfortunate expedition.
He's asked me to study
how best to correct the situation...
and I accepted.
But I'm well aware
any effort will be of little use...
unless our entire community
is behind it.
That's why we've come
to consult with you.
Well done.
We appreciate your initiative.
I consider a German attack
unlikely for the next few nights.
They'll need to check up
on their equipment fiirst.
So the danger--
the immediate danger--
will begin Thursday or Friday night.
A very brief delay.
You're right.
That doesn't leave us much time.
Also, given the improvised...
not to say idiotic, nature...
of our demonstration...
it's clear we should
expect no mercy.
Especially, Father,
given the ''German mentality.''
I'm afraid you're right.
Then we agree. Sergeant?
Please assemble our friends
in the clubhouse in ten minutes.
The clubhouse in ten minutes.
Do we need to be there too?
Yes, of course.
What is all this about?
I won't be led around by the nose!
This is a republic!
Damn it, we're free men!
Paul.
Stop being an idiot.
Mr. Rechampot...
what do you propose?
We're here to listen
to everyone's ideas.
Do you know what you want?
Of course I do.
We want...
We don't want the Germans
to come here.
And if they do?
If they do... we surrender.
Maybe you, but not me.
I won't surrender.
A Frenchman never surrenders
if he can do otherwise.
That's what I meant.
If Mr. Fresnoy fiinds a way...
of course I would not surrender.
Just think of my inventory.
So, Mr. Fresnoy, here is my answer:
If they come, we don't surrender.
But...
they mustn't come.
- They mustn't come.
- We won't surrender.
We won't surrender if they come,
but they mustn't come.
If that's what you expect of me,
I have a few ideas to propose.
One thing is certain:
Mr. Rechampot has just said
he has substantial inventory.
Substantial... but not enormous!
Paul, don't start.
When destiny places you
in challenging circumstances...
you must forget
you're a businessman.
Precisely, Mr. Templier.
I propose you set out
for St. Pierre de Samba tomorrow.
Yes, Mr. Hubert.
Sergeant Bosselet will give you
a sealed envelope...
which you will hand over
to the military authorities.
Your mission is to bring back
precise instructions...
and all the men and equipment
you can fiind.
Why me?
I have a store to run.
Everyone has a store to run.
Do as he says.
But there are two of you.
Why doesn't your brother go?
Because my brother is...
an idiot!
You've been chosen...
because you're best suited
to such a sensitive mission.
Let's not get bogged down
in shop talk.
Especially since the store
is not very busy right now.
I could take care of it myself.
It seems everyone agrees.
- Yes, we do.
- Certainly.
And how will you defend us
until reinforcements arrive?
The sergeant admitted
his volunteers keep disappearing.
We shouldn't expect miracles, you know.
We're dreadfully low on natives.
You said it, not me.
We shouldn't expect miracles...
and that's not what I expect of you.
Mr. Hubert.
What's going to happen?
Why, you're nervous too!
What's to become of us?
I'm frightened.
Jacques.
- Come with me.
- Where?
Come give me a hand.
Put your hands like this.
For you, me and Maryvonne,
in case things go sour.
QUiet, you fool!
We should add some sugar...
green beans, corned beeF
and sardines.
And maybe a few bottles of wine?
Right. And we'll tell 'em
it all went missing.
Please, the floor pads.
Of course.
Good day, Mr. Fresnoy.
Be seated.
Well?
The men have fled.
The villages are empty.
- All of them?
- Every one.
Yet as of this morning
we know for certain...
that Lieutenant Krafft is recruiting.
And successfully, too.
Do you have something to propose?
Unfortunately, no.
The drums warn them
the minute we leave here.
There's nothing we can do
about their drums.
True.
There's nothing we can do.
Convey my greetings to the chief.
The chief says...
''It's a great honor to welcome the chieF
of the white men in my home.''
Tell the chief I've come
because his village is in great danger.
The chief says, ''I know.''
Tell him the men of his village
have attacked white men.
Now the German white men
want their revenge...
and they're very ferocious.
The chief says, ''I know.''
To defend his village,
the French will need 1 00 men.
He says, ''I don't have 1 00 men.
I lost many of my best men
in the great battle.''
The French know the tribes
on the savannah have many men.
If the chief can bring us
many of those men...
the men of his village
will no longer need to fiight.
The chief says,
''I can capture many of those savages.
There are many of them.
They are strong but stupid.''
He says...
''The people of my village have never liked
the people of the savannah.''
He says,
''Why didn't you think of this sooner?''
Come along.
Mr. Fresnoy is waiting.
So how many
have they captured for us now?
I say, how many
Counting the ones
from this morning, 1 9.
Say what you like...
that man's really something.
He's something, all right.
And you only see him from a distance.
To really know him,
you have to live with him.
Well, I don't live with him...
and I daresay I was opposed...
but I do recognize...
that's he's a real brain.
What is he really like in private?
Is he nice?
No, nice isn't the word.
I mean, he may be that,
but it's more like he's... he's...
He's what?
He's terribly refiined.
Terribly refiined.
And he hasn't changed.
We used to say
he was like a young schoolboy...
a bit taken with his own learning.
But I'm here to tell you:
Despite his education,
he's a real man.
I'll bet the poor baby's still a virgin.
I wouldn't put my hand
in the fiire on it.
That's not where you're supposed
to put your hand, you fool!
Madame Rechampot!
Madame times two!
The things she says!
Don't be embarrassed, Madame Caprice.
To Mr. Hubert!
On your inventory declaration...
you listed only 1 7 5 pounds of sugar.
Precisely.
And even that is gone.
Demand has been very high.
With everything going on,
I haven't had a delivery since...
June of last year.
- Madame Caprice is in the same boat.
- Yes, the poor dear.
Yet she has listed
300 pounds of sugar.
Marius!
There are white men talking here!
It's the broom making the noise.
Of course,
they have a different clientele.
They're small retailers,
while we're wholesalers.
Wholesale, right.
Very well. We'll see.
As strange as it sounds...
a wholesaler will sometimes
have less stock than a retailer.
But please go ahead
and look around.
Mr. Fresnoy.
My brother made me do it!
What a liar!
Who hid those things there?
Did you hide those things there?
''The yellow-speckled leaF
in the fecund autumn...
surrenders gently all its golden grapes
to the fruit-gatherers.
Thus will fall
the passing flowers of life...
youth, love, pleasure and beauty.''
Drink that.
Drink it. It's the white man's drink.
Makes you strong.
It's good for you.
That makes 20.
An even 20.
It's getting harder every day.
They haven't captured one
in three days.
I asked for 1 00 men,
not 20 invalids.
If the chief thinks he can
put one over on us, he's wrong.
Why not take it up with him?
Tell the chief I didn't come
to listen to this idle chatter.
He promised me many natives.
He hasn't kept his promise.
Therefore I won't keep mine either,
and his men will have to fiight.
The chief says some of the captives
know where the natives are hiding.
Well? Haven't his men
been able to make them talk?
The chief says they tried...
but those captives won't talk.
You'd have to torture them brutally.
Damn it!
He's coming this way.
Is it serious?
Not serious. Important.
Let's see it.
It's not for you.
It's for your brother.
My brother?
I no longer have a brother!
It's for you, Cain!
Look at the yellow belly!
''Decision No. 23:
A military squad is hereby established
to obtain the necessary information...
for the recruitment
of a native militia...
to aid in the defense of Fort Coulais.
The squad will be led by
Mr. Rechampot,Jacques Victor Louis.''
Signed, Fresnoy.
And that fiixes you.
Say something, idiot!
I'm so happy!
Look at that moron!
Bravo,Jacques!
See what you can do
when you set your mind to it?
Hurrah for the squad!
These men are tall.
The ones they caught before
were all so short.
Long live Mr. Fresnoy!
- The priests wish to see you.
- Show them in.
The floor pads.
Be seated.
It's like this:
FatherJohn of the Cross
and myself were thinking...
perhaps it might be helpful--
To help you get a fuller picture
of the delicate issues in this situation.
Issues which,
under the circumstances...
one might be tempted
to deem secondary...
but which, nonetheless, must
never be entirely neglected...
by a Christian conscience.
I'm listening.
Certain murmurings and rumors...
From native sources,
I hasten to add.
lead us to fear that
certain means have been used...
to attain certain ends.
Highly commendable ends.
Means which are-- how can I say?
Not in keeping
with the respect due...
even to God's most humble creatures.
Mr. Rechampot is following my orders
in an attempt to ensure your safety.
The thing is, we've heard rumors...
of brutality and injuries--
Did you hear rumors when
the wounded were left to rot in the sun?
Was there any talk
of the Christian consciences...
who fled those people
in their moment of agony...
without offering
even a drink of water?
Or of the Christian consciences
who refused to lift a fiinger...
to prevent that massacre?
Remember: I didn't ask for this war.
The knife.
The cartridge.
The rifle.
Good day, Sergeant.
Good day, Mr. Fresnoy.
- The bayonet.
- The bay-net.
The coast is clear!
Assomption, get the bicycle!
Our Lord Jesus Christ.
White men are stronger
than black men. Why?
Because they have a better god!
The white man's god gives strength!
This is a bicycle.
Any black man
who tries to ride it falls.
Who wants to try? You?
See what the white man's god
can do.
The recruit says...
''That's a white man's machine.
But the white man's God
doesn't give strength to the black man.''
Then watch this.
Assomption, it's your turn.
This man is black...
but he believes
in the white man's god.
Halt! Who goes there?
Creuse.
Don't be an idiot.
It's me-- Caprice.
- Creuse.
- What do you mean, Creuse?
It's the password.
You have to answer Chef-lieu Gueret.
Oh. Well, then, Chef-lieu Gueret.
Very well. You may pass.
Good evening, Mr. Caprice.
Good night, Mr. Caprice.
Gueret la Creuse is the password?
Well!
No one can go in.
Isn't Fresnoy in?
Mr. Fresnoy is in.
What's it for?
That's my business.
Did I ask you anything?
Give me that doorknob.
You can't have it.
Things not going well today, pal?
My name is not ''pal.''
I am Barthelemy.
Do you know who I am?
You're Mr. Caprice.
- You know where I've come back from?
- Yes. St. Pierre de Samba.
Fill in this form.
Watch it.
Don't play games with me.
I'm warning you.
Mr. Fresnoy's been expecting me
for three months.
I've worked my ass ofF
for three months...
rounding up grenades
and everything else for him!
Very good.
How many cases?
Bastard!
Must not disturb.
You will see boss Sunday.
You can't be serious.
With a black woman?
Just like I said.
Him!
Bosselet I can understand.
But him?
Is she pretty?
Pretty?
She's black, like the others.
Just shows you everyone
has their share of misery.
How awful.
Mr. Caprice, you were assigned
a diffiicult mission in every respect.
I'd like to state publicly...
that you carried it out
in exemplary fashion.
Madam, you can be proud
of your husband.
Thank you, Mr. Hubert.
I'm sorry. Mr. Fresnoy.
Mr. Fresnoy, please take your place.
Attention!
Right shoulder... arms!
Present arms!
Company at ease!
I wish you all a pleasant Sunday.
I hope you'll stay with us.
Please.
Alas, we must get back.
Ladies, gentlemen.
He's leaving?
Well, that's that.
Before we go back...
I want to show you
how they manage with the grenades.
Good idea.
It'll give 'em some practice.
That didn't go down well with me.
I didn't fiind it heavy at all.
I'm not talking about the mutton!
I'm talking about him
and his black woman.
Let us not judge, ladies.
True, there are some bizarre quirks
in that young man's nature...
and his attitude seems
designed to provoke us.
But we must at least give him credit...
for guaranteeing
our peace and security.
And for giving us back so quickly
our accustomed lifestyle.
Long live the Republic!
Charge!
He's brilliant.
He took them by surprise.
- I didn't see it coming.
- Me neither.
Of course not.
First section.
Come on, men!
Line up for your wine!
You didn't drink it!
Open your mouth
or you can't drink.
Good, eh?
It's the real stuff.
Go now, quickly.
Congratulations. It's as good a trench
as we saw in the newspapers.
And without the mud, too.
That's for sure.
With Mr. Fresnoy in charge...
we won't wait for the rainy season
to give the Krauts a trouncing.
Soldiers of the French, surrender.!
We have machine guns.!
We have warm clothes.!
you don't stand a chance.
It's not true.
We're going to win.
God's on our side.
Take heart!
The Lord is with you.
- How are things?
- All right.
- There's one man in bad shape.
- Inside?
Let's go.
What a mess!
He's in sad shape.
- Are we losing a lot of them?
- Two or three a week.
This one here is the sixth this week.
Can't you do anything for him?
Wait for the rain to stop.
The French are using you.!
you die to save their skin.!
Germany is kind to us.!
ComeJoin us.!
France says go to hell!
Tell him everything you just told me.
I have run a very long way.
The priests and ladies sent me
to say they're coming with soldiers...
who wish to speak to you.
What's he talking about?
- Have they sent reinforcements?
- You're not lying, are you?
- Are you pulling our leg?
- I saw the soldiers with my own eyes.
French soldiers?
Not French.
Krauts?
No, not Krauts.
Then who are they?
I don't know.
How am I supposed to know?
But their chief is a black man.
There they are.
Let go of my foot, for God's sake!
Give me your hand.
They're coming out into the open now.
Now I see them!
Move over a bit.
What if the branch breaks?
We have to let Bosselet know.
Absolutely not.
I shall translate...
what the captain says.
The Germans surrendered at Yaounde...
quite a while ago.
The Allies decided to send
Captain Kapoor here...
with a letter that reads as follow:
''To the Germans still fiighting:
There's no point.
The war is over. Stop it.''
We beat 'em!
The Germans are to surrender...
only to Captain Kapoor.
Perhaps you're wondering why.
Because the Allies
decided in London...
that this territory should be ceded
to His Gracious Majesty.
We have come
to take possession of it.
Where do we come in?
I'm sure the captain
would like to freshen up.
Nice uniforms!
Hey, you, the smart one.
Come over here.
Come here for a minute.
Tell me, did this agreement
in London...
say that our land will remain
part of France?
It will still be France
up to the point...
where it used to be Germany?
Exactly.
So that means
only one thing will change:
The blacks who were German before...
will now become English.
Exactly.
Let me tell you something:
It serves 'em right!
Arms!
Mr. Krafft.
Come closer. Don't be shy.
How are you?
What a nasty business, eh?
My brother.
Let me introduce Mr. Fresnoy.
He's the young man
who gave you so much trouble.
If it weren't for him,
you might have--
- You put on some weight.
- He looks good!
Yes, Sergeant?
Nothing.
White people.
Really!
Listen, don't worry about that bill.
We'll work it out.
Philology?
Yes, I was tempted at one point.
But I must say, our philologists
can't hold a candle to yours.
- Which university did you study at?
- Heidelberg.
Of course.
This will give you a laugh:
I was a socialist.
Oh, sorry.
Me too.
[ Skipped item nr. 987 ]
[ Skipped item nr. 988 ]