THE LITTLE SOLDIER
Narrator: I'm too old to play
an active role.
It's time to think things over.
Geneva.
Lake Leman divides the city
in 2 parts.
3 days ago, secret agents
declared a deadly war open...
here on neutral territory.
$800.
I thought of myself
suddenly...
Bruno Forestier...
a reporter for the French
Information Bureau.
More Terrorist Attacks
Geneva Professor Dies
Following Attack
They're at it again. Shit.
They're completely crazy.
Geneva, May 13, 1958.
Argon once wrote,
"Painless May...
"June, cut to the heart."
"Love one another"
Things OK?
Someone called for you.
- You said I was here?
- Yes.
I told you not to!
The sky reminded me
of a Klee painting.
"Where do you come from?
"Where are you?
Where are you going?"
What's going on, kid?
Hi.
Bruno, what are you up to?
A nice Paul Klee.
My date's nicer.
Who is she?
You're to take
photos of her.
What if I don't
want to see her?
She's chic. Come on.
I'm due
at the Brazilian Consulate.
Go tomorrow.
I can't do it now!
Girls like lots of chit-chat.
Is it that Danish gal?
Yes. You know her?
Michel told me about her.
I bet you want to lay her.
She has a mouth
like Leslie Caron.
No. I only screw girls
I'm in love with.
I bet 5 minutes with her,
you'd be in love.
How much will you bet?
- I don't know.
- $50.
If you want.
$50 that I don't fall for her.
The first time I met her...
she seemed to be right
out of a Giraudoux play.
Veronica?
Kill a guy from behind
with a gun or a knife...
but not with a bomb.
Killing from a distance
isn't honorable.
You don't know a thing.
What are you talking about?
Lachenal, the art prof killed
yesterday.
His car was booby-trapped.
By whom?
The French.
What do you know about it?
You don't know what
you're talking about.
It's irritating.
Students are all alike.
I know his daughter.
She's often at the ice skating
rink.
You're right. It's terrible.
Aw, shit.
What's up?
This is a bore.
They thought I said "war."
I said it was the same thing.
She stared at me.
Good-bye.
For your photos, tomorrow
at 5:00.
Where are you going?
A mystery.
You really are mysterious.
Yes. I'm a secret agent.
Veronica.
Shake your hair loose.
Here's your $50.
Where are you going?
Is it important?
One never knows
what's important.
I was still very young
and foolish.
Blue skies? Rain? Who knew?
Up to now,
my life had been simple.
A guy with no ideals.
And tomorrow?
I asked him for a light.
Again I asked him
for a light.
At times I felt
I was wasting my time.
Veronica...
did she have Velazquez-gray
eyes, or were they Renoir-gray?
Alfred Latouche or his brother
usually met me.
Maybe they'd been caught.
And what about me?
- Hello, Jacques.
- Hello, Bruno.
Get in.
Our antiterrorist group
was financed
by an ex-parliamentarian
who had been pro-Vichy.
How's it going?
OK. You?
Do you know Jacques?
That's him?
I don't know the other guy.
Your man?
No, the one in back.
Who's he?
If anyone asks, play dumb.
Good luck!
Bankers, parachutists,
car salesmen, prodigal sons.
The secret war mixed men
and ideas at a deadly pace.
Do we go or not?
We're good.
It's 10 to 5:00.
If his car's there,
stop by the fountain for Paul.
It's a '57 Nash convertible.
Well, Bruno?
What?
What are you thinking?
I don't know.
You're supposed to know.
What were you
going to say?
Nothing.
Go on, say it.
I changed my mind.
What's that book?
"Thomas the Imposter."
Ah. Jean Cocteau.
Yes. Listen to the end.
It's wonderful.
"William flew, leaped,
and ran like a hare.
"Not hearing the shots,
he stopped..."
"turned breathlessly.
"Then he felt a sharp jab
in the chest.
"He fell.
"He'd become deaf
and blind."
"'A bullet, ' he thought.
"'I am lost unless
I pretend to be dead. '
"But for him, fact
and fiction were one."
"William Thomas was dead."
It's beautiful.
I'd like to die like that.
Don't worry.
Maybe you will. Soon.
What's gotten into you?
Why?
Because you're a pain
in the ass, big boy.
We're thinking about Saturday.
What were you doing in Annecy?
I was hoping to take
Veronica to Brazil.
I'm opening a painting gallery.
I was planning to buy
3 Modiglianis.
Lucky for me
I don't have any.
With whose money?
I'll pay it back.
We're here.
"O, days of changing flowers...
"I recall the rose bowers."
Why was I obsessed
by that poem?
Turn the radio down.
You know that guy
who does that show?
Palivoda on Radio Geneva?
Yeah, that's him.
There he is.
I soon realized they suspected
me of being a double agent.
Let's go.
His show's called
"A Neutral Speaks."
That kills me.
You ever seen Palivoda,
Bruno?
Before today?
Yes.
No.
- Take a good look at him.
- Why?
Because you're going
to kill him.
Why me again?
I got the order from Paris.
I'm just passing it on.
Jacques said it would be
very easy.
Drive along next to him
like now...
and fire...
when you're opposite him.
Roll up the window!
They're sure in Paris
he works for the rebels?
I'm amazed. He's Swiss.
I'm not. It's less dangerous...
to talk on the radio
than to fight.
The Swiss have never been
very courageous.
Just look how they drive.
They even signal
to pass a biker.
It infuriates me.
Want to go to the hotel?
No. To the office.
Is it true
Latouche is dead?
Yes. They found him
in a bathtub Tuesday...
at the Bristol Hotel.
They'd cut out his tongue.
There was blood everywhere.
Scared?
Shooting people
isn't a joke.
We can loan you the car
if you want.
It doesn't have
Geneva plates.
It's too dangerous.
Why me and not Paul?
Because you're the best.
I don't want
to kill Palivoda.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
A moment ago, yes,
but now, no.
I don't know why.
If I killed him,
I'd feel like a loser.
That's unimportant.
Victory's better than defeat.
The Spanish Republicans'
welfare is fine.
It's not mean. It's
a thing to be proud of.
Benjamin Constant and
Mme de StaeI lived there.
We chose you expressly
to see if you're afraid.
Afraid? I'm not
afraid at all.
I just don't feel
like doing it.
I won't do it.
We'll make you do it.
You can't force me.
No one can force
a soldier to kill.
What are you thinking?
it's easy.
The Swiss know
you're a deserter.
One little slip, you get
sent back to France.
I mustn't lower my eyes.
No one'll get you out
of an army jail again.
Kill him, or
it'll be your turn.
Ask Jacques.
You'll kill me.
26 is awfully young
to die, little prince.
If they force me, I'll kill,
but not till then.
So that's what I told them.
Let me out. So long.
So I can count on you?
No. I'm a pain
in the ass.
That's not funny.
Jacques!
What's he doing?
I felt it was important
not to be a loser.
Next I phoned
the Brazilian Consulate...
to ask about visas for
a Frenchman and a Russian girl.
They were already closed.
I'd call the next day.
At night, the starlit skyline
is very moving...
both hard and mysterious...
in the likeness of mankind
and what goes beyond it.
She pretended not to see me.
I didn't stop.
I'd see her the next day.
Later I noticed
a car tailing me.
I had trouble losing it.
"Now all is still.
"The enemy rests
in the shadows."
Summer was coming,
yet I felt it was winter.
Paul, what are you up to?
Her place wasn't bad.
I've just moved in.
It's not bad.
Yesterday I didn't see you,
but I thought of you.
Now I see you, but
think of something else.
Is this all you have?
Yes.
I thought
you'd need lights...
Oh, no, no, no.
This is very fast film.
It's Agfa Record.
When photographing a face...
Iook at me...
you photograph the soul
behind it.
She had deep shadows
under her eyes.
They were Velazquez-gray.
Where do you want me?
Anywhere. Doesn't matter.
Do as you please,
and I'll shoot.
I'll ask questions.
It'll make it easier.
You seem afraid. Why?
Yes. I'm afraid.
You don't need to be.
It's like being questioned
by the police.
She was less pretty
than the day before.
Yes, yes, a little.
Photography is truth...
and cinema is truth
24 times a second.
Your name's Veronica what?
She didn't answer right away.
Veronica Dreyer.
You're a Finn.
No, Danish.
No. I'm Russian...
but born in Copenhagen.
Are you with your parents
in Geneva?
No. I'm alone.
A foreigner speaking French
is lovely.
Where are your parents?
They were shot
during the war.
Huh. Shot by whom?
That's no concern of yours.
By the Germans?
By the Russians, then?
That doesn't concern you.
Why won't you tell me?
That's just the way it is.
Hold your hair up.
Veronica's charm was herself...
the fall of her shoulders...
her anxious look...
her secret smile.
It's strange. My father
was also shot...
on Liberation Day.
Drieu La Rochelle
was his pal.
Don't be afraid.
Don't remain motionless.
What would you like me
to do?
I don't know.
Whatever you want.
Light a cigarette...
take a shower.
I don't think so.
No? Why?
She turned suddenly.
You never take showers?
I said whatever came
into my head.
I'd like to take shots
of you showering.
You really don't want to?
No.
Why?
Because it's idiotic.
Afraid I'll see your body?
What do you mean,
idiotic?
What are you thinking
right now?
Move a bit.
Do you ever think
of death?
She looked so anguished.
And suddenly I had
the extraordinary sensation...
that I was photographing Death.
Then all became normal again.
Have you dated lots of boys
since coming to Geneva?
Yes.
Why?
Just asking.
I bet you've posed
in a bathing suit.
No. Never.
Now what are you thinking?
Are you thinking about me?
Yes.
What are you thinking
about me?
How come you won't answer?
You're afraid.
Pull your hair back.
Hold that record jacket
up over your face.
Do you believe in freedom?
No.
Would you be afraid
to kill someone?
Oh, you annoy me.
Do you have any brothers
or sisters?
Yes. I have a brother.
What's he do?
He's in Moscow.
He's a student
at the Stanislavsky Theater.
The Russians
are always studying.
What?
Russians are always studying.
Odd that you wanted
to be an actress.
She lighted a cigarette
and asked why.
Why?
Actors just shuffle along.
I have contempt for them.
You tell them to laugh...
they laugh.
Tell them to cry, they cry.
Tell them to crawl,
they do it.
I find that grotesque.
I don't see why.
I don't know.
They're not free people.
- Look.
- What?
"An actor."
Yes. It's by Klee.
Do you like Paul Klee?
Yes.
It's not important
how others see you...
but how you see
your own face.
Did Paul Klee say that?
No, I did.
Do you have a record?
Yes. What would you like?
Some Bach?
No. It's too late.
Bach's for 8:00 in the morning.
A Brandenburg at 8:00
is wonderful.
Mozart?
Beethoven?
Too early.
Mozart's for 8:00
in the evening.
Beethoven's music
is very profound.
Beethoven's for midnight.
No, what we need
is some Haydn...
some good old Joseph Haydn.
What are you thinking?
Same thing as you.
Do you know
what a test is?
No.
It's a drawing to discover
a person's character.
I'll do one for you.
I often used this on women.
They love to play games
like little girls.
So you suggest playing
children's games.
Do anything you want,
anything at all.
Just finish the drawing.
Did Hugh tell you about
our bet the other afternoon?
When you gave him $50?
Yes.
No.
You don't know why
I gave him $50?
No.
You do it, too. I'd like
to know your thoughts...
OK.
also.
You'll see.
"I love you."
Jacques and Paul were parked
in front of the Century.
I pretended not to see them.
Veronica and I
talked about art.
She insisted Gauguin was
a greater painter than Van Gogh.
She was obviously wrong.
Who's the girl?
A cover girl.
Are you staying with me
or not?
I don't know.
I don't know, Bruno.
When we left Club 58...
you remember?
You took my arm.
I shouldn't have?
No.
Why not?
Because it made me
want to sleep with you.
Now you seem to be saying
that's impossible.
You shouldn't give your arm
to men you don't like.
Good night.
You think it'll work?
Sure. Bruno's a coward.
Then Paul took my car.
He and Jacques put
the Swiss police on my neck.
Go on! Go on!
Go on!
My Pontiac!
You schmuck! My Pontiac!
Stop! Stop! Police!
It's a German song.
Shall I translate?
"O, radiant dawn,
"radiant dawn!"
"Too soon you announce
my death."
"Soon the trumpets
will resound..."
"and then..."
"I shall have to leave
this beautiful life."
7:00 in the morning.
A handful of snapshots taken
from around the world...
pass by me
like bad dreams...
Panama...
Rome...
Alexandria...
Budapest...
Paris.
The bad dream continues.
"We entered the war
as if entering school."
So began Bernanos' novel
"Humiliated Children."
Fear Destroyed This Couple
I lit a cigarette.
This morning I feel
like a little boy. Why?
Asking questions is more
important than finding answers.
Veronica.
Give me a drag.
I'm hungry.
I had a nightmare.
I was in a theater.
I met the devil
during intermission.
And he was very well-dressed.
It was truly him...
with hairy legs
and horns.
And he had a thigh wound...
a big red scrape.
It was awful.
Yes? Who is it?
Where are you going?
Go back to sleep.
God, she was beautiful.
I wondered if she was only
pretending to sleep.
Police.
Are you Bruno Forestier?
Yes. What's wrong?
Put on a coat
and come with me.
No. I've done nothing.
Don't play games with us.
You're wanted in France.
Yes, I deserted.
But my papers are in order.
Get your coat.
We'll see.
All right, I'm coming.
He seemed quite serious,
the inspector.
"Hit-and-run,"
the papers said.
In time, the perpetrator...
would be turned over
to French authorities.
As I didn't know anything
yet, I denied everything.
There. You see?
Sir...
please?
- You shouldn't have fled.
- I wasn't there.
Oh, so it's a Frenchman?
They try to get away
with anything!
Were you there or not?
Never look down
before a cop.
You don't know?
What an ass I was.
But... the gentleman
has witnesses.
In that car!
I understood too late...
the crap had begun
for my not killing Palivoda.
So... are we going
to the station?
I had lost
my first major battle.
So, are you going
to file charges?
A tremendous feeling of
Ioneliness settled through me.
Maybe freedom began
with remorse.
- Where'd you go?
- To get cigarettes.
You didn't take a bath?
I didn't feel like it.
A woman's shoulders are
very pretty and noble.
You're odd this morning.
Yes. I'm becoming a coward.
What?
I'm becoming a coward.
It's strange. When I look
myself in the face...
I get the feeling I don't match
what I think is inside.
In your opinion...
what's more important,
the inside or the outside?
It was a beautiful object...
black, mysterious,
incorruptible.
It's what cameraman
Raoul Coutard called...
the law of the big hassle.
Each time I was ready
to fire...
an unexpected event
prevented me.
And each time
the coast was clear,
I hesitated several seconds...
and again it was too late.
It's especially difficult,
if it's not your profession,
to try to kill a man
several times.
It's like fouling up
a suicide.
After a while,
I became fed up.
I don't think it was
the act of killing someone...
that upset me.
That's happened before.
No, it wasn't that.
And I've always thought...
conscientious objectors
were fakes.
Simply, each act has
a right time and a wrong time.
Paul's always as frisky
as a cub scout.
He and Jacques
are full of ideas...
of secret plans.
Nothing stops them,
not even a wild idea...
like making me kill Palivoda
in front of 36 people.
Accused of being a traitor...
for me to strike down an enemy
was my only way out.
When I drew my revolver,
I felt Paul aim his at me.
Bruno!
Hey, Bruno!
How's your Danish
lady friend?
Shit. They're leaving.
What are you doing?
You do work for them.
Me? Not at all.
OK, are you dreaming?
I'm fed up.
Go to hell.
Now with both the French
and the Arabs after me...
I was done for sure.
Yes.
No. I'm going
to take a bath.
I'll see you later
at Club 58, if you want.
Why?
I can't stay here.
Tomorrow I'm going
to Zurich.
I'm catching a plane
to Brazil.
Veronica...
why don't you say something?
I don't know
what to say.
Tell me lies...
and that you're not sad
that I'm leaving.
I'm not sad
that you're leaving.
I'm not in love with you.
I won't join you in Brazil.
I won't kiss you
tenderly.
I packed and went to Zurich.
They were no longer Geneva's
lights, but more like Rio's.
And I wondered if I was
happy to feel free...
or free to feel happy.
Hello, Jacques?
It's Paul.
Be careful, big boy.
Yeah.
Today the tragedy
is politics.
No, not for me. Napoleon.
Listen, Bruno...
Let... let me talk!
I'm calling to say
your car's at the Century.
My head hit the ground so hard,
I lost consciousness.
I forgot to count the stairs
to know where we were.
Who did you call
in the garage?
Are you going
to torture me?
Are you scared?
Of course I'm scared.
His passport.
Who issued this passport?
The French Consulate here?
There's an Arab joke
about a guy...
who calls and says, "Allo?"
The other guy says, "It's Ali."
- Do we strip him?
- Yes.
If I'd yelled, they'd
have hit me again.
Better to just take it.
Who is he?
I don't know.
And him?
Never seen him.
Jacques Aurelian Mercier.
Ex-volunteer in Indochina.
Disappeared after a trial
for dealing in piasters.
Reappeared in '57
in Rotterdam...
when the freighter Aramis
was blown up...
in '59 in Frankfort...
when Professor Dietrich
was assassinated.
And now he's in Geneva.
He's the one
you were phoning.
What number did you dial?
What was the number?!
I didn't care whether
I told them or not.
I simply didn't feel like it
and said so.
They asked me
to work for them...
but refused me an advance,
so I said to go to hell.
Him, too... Alfred Latouche...
he refused to talk.
And so did his brother Etienne.
You want the same?
Poor Etienne. He'd lowered his
head to protect his throat...
resulting in his catching
the razor full on the chin.
I hope you're brave.
This'll be tough.
I don't know if I am...
but we'll see.
Take him to the bathroom.
Get up!
One is soon stricken
from the world of the living.
And being a realist...
it's the sole privilege
of the dead.
What privilege?
To no longer die.
Torture is so monotonous
and sad...
it's difficult to talk about it,
so I'll barely mention it.
What number did you call?
Are you afraid?
Why are you doing that?
Sometimes you have to...
make your way with a dagger.
A spark can set
the entire plain ablaze
In Budapest, I'd already
seen torture.
I wondered if I'd
be able to bear it.
Now my moment had come.
The faucets.
I know that others
endured worse...
but I never encountered
any martyrs or screams...
so I can't discuss it.
I only know I forced myself
not to yell...
and soon stopped struggling.
Think of anything, quick,
anything to avoid the pain.
The sea, the beach, the sun.
Think so fast you can't
think of anything.
Write to Veronica! Quick!
Don't think about the pain.
Quick! Write a letter.
Faster yet.
Beat the speed of pain.
A letter to Veronica...
better than the one
Desnos sent his wife.
Veronica...
What happened?
You passed out.
Did I cry?
Why do you ask?
What's going on?
He asked if he cried.
I wonder why
that interests him.
Because it's important.
Between torture sessions, we had
great political discussion.
They said I was an idiot
with no ideals.
And like all organizations
with specific goals,
they tried to indoctrinate me.
"The French also tortured.
"Prisoners awaited in obscurity
either prison...
"or the result of
their attempts to escape...
"that is to say, a hail
of bullets in the back."
Djamila's fiance...
died that way.
There's no doubt that strength
is superior to intelligence.
You have to be strong,
it's true, to resist strength.
I again thought of other
things... vacation, Brittany...
bicycle rides,
girls with flowers.
Why didn't I give up the phone
number? I can't recall.
Out of dignity? I don't
even know what that means.
The phone number.
When I was worn down,
I screamed for help...
but I didn't realize
I was so weak...
I couldn't be heard
two meters away.
When I thought I was screaming,
I was barely murmuring.
I wondered what
the shirts were for.
Palivoda?
It's Cavalier FK.
Air doesn't penetrate cloth
soaked with water.
It's impossible to breathe.
"A revolution's leap forward
is like a ship...
"already visible
on the distant horizon.
"It's like the sun's disk...
"whose rays..."
"already pierce
the darkness.
"It's like a child...
"who's soon to be born."
Did he tell you
the phone number?
No. No. Nothing yet.
But with this,
we'll learn something.
No, no.
We don't want to leave
any marks.
Why did I want
to commit suicide?
I should've given them
the information.
That's how the French
got themselves so disliked.
I put the blade
between my teeth...
because I couldn't manage
with my hands.
For better or for worse for me,
they came in too soon.
Then...
then came the electricity.
A guy I knew
brought the material.
Now I remember.
He's the one...
who gave Veronica a puppy
the first time we met.
OK, it'll work this time.
Electricity's very simple.
They attach electrodes
anywhere on your body...
and turn on the current.
You don't die,
but you're maimed.
Remember what Lenin said...
that in a revolution,
there are no easy tasks...
nor easy methods.
Everything's valid in all
aspects of the struggle.
The revolution's victory
is certain.
It will triumph.
Then they told me to get
dressed. I was exhausted.
I thought about jumping
out the window.
If we were on the ground floor,
good. If not...
What are you
thinking about?
I'm thinking
about Pierre Brossolette...
how he died.
It was in '47
at Gestapo headquarters.
He'd been tortured
for 2 months.
They'd put out his eyes.
One day they took him to a room
to question him again.
He'd suffered so much
he knew he'd crack.
He sensed there was
a window in the room.
So as they questioned him,
he moved near it...
little by little...
groping.
And when he touched the glass...
he threw himself
through it.
Luckily, it was
the first floor.
Veronica had told me
she worked for the Arabs...
but that she would flee
to Brazil with me.
Excuse me. Have you seen
my pal Forestier?
Miss?
No.
OK. Thanks.
He's surely there.
Then why wouldn't
she tell us?
I don't trust her.
Why would you rather
die than talk?
They'll kill me anyway.
I don't know.
Luckily, it was
only the first floor.
You look nicer
without makeup.
I watched her sit down.
I liked the way
she lit a cigarette.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
Why is it empty?
Because I was leaving.
I was going away.
We didn't dare
look at each other.
There aren't any marks.
No. Just a burn here.
They were very careful.
Due to the UN, Cairo
surely gave them orders.
No one came
to ask about me?
Yes, just as I came in.
I saw your friends again.
Which ones?
They came yesterday...
on behalf
of the French Consulate...
the thin one who looks
like an elevator boy...
and the other one...
a gigolo.
Who are they?
It's Paul and Jacques.
I'm sure of it.
We're the ones
who killed Lachenal.
Why did she turn her back?
No. I find that
idiotic.
Palivoda, yes...
but Lachenal
had done nothing.
He thought the Algerian war
was unfair.
But that's all.
Yes. I don't know.
You always say that.
I'm listening.
Mohamed Messousa...
16 Chapelit Street.
Where can I call you?
Why not?
OK, big boy.
You call us.
In exchange for
2 diplomatic passports,
I gave him
the Arabs' address.
Tell the photographer
to see Paul.
In your files...
do you have a girl
named...
V... Veronica Dreyer.
Veronica Dreyer?
Call me back.
Veronica Dreyer.
And what about me?
Why do you work for the rebels?
Some political conviction?
It's difficult to say.
Little by little...
I just became exhausted.
but at any rate...
I decided that the French
are wrong.
The others have an ideal.
But not the French.
It's very important
to have an ideal.
Against the Germans,
the French had an ideal.
Against the Algerians,
they don't.
They'll lose the war.
You think so? I don't.
Yes, I do.
Today everyone hates the French.
I'm very proud to be French.
But I'm also
against nationalism.
One defends ideas,
not territories.
I love France because
I love the films of du Bellay...
and Louis Aragon.
I love Germany
because I love Beethoven.
I don't love Barcelona
because of Spain...
but I like Spain
because Barcelona exists...
and America because
I like their cars.
I don't like Arabs because
I don't like deserts...
nor Colonel Lawrence...
nor the Mediterranean
or Albert Camus.
No, I like Brittany.
And I hate the south.
Breton light is very soft...
not like in the south.
And the Arabs are lazy.
But I have
nothing against them.
Or against the Chinese.
No, I'd like to ignore them.
But today it's terrible.
If you calmly do nothing...
you get hell
for doing nothing.
We do things
without conviction.
It's a pity to make war
Why is the Vatican
anticommunist?
He's an odd pope, this one.
All men are brothers.
I'm not a brother to train
conductors in Peking...
nor in San Francisco.
A priori, I don't care
about them.
Maybe someday...
I'd like to know
what's become of Sasovotsky.
He's not automatically
my brother...
because he has eyes
and ears like me.
And vise versa.
There are objects,
I don't know...
One likes them,
but not others.
Or colors.
For example,
I hate dark red.
It's the same with men.
We can't be made
to love them all.
As Guitry said, "We no longer
know where to love."
She looked at me.
I think women should never
be more than 25.
Men become more handsome
as they age.
Not women.
It's greatly unfair
for a woman to age.
And I've noticed
something strange.
Women, when they
commit suicide...
they always leap...
under a train
or out a window.
They're so afraid that they'll
mess up the attempt...
that they throw themselves
forward.
That way, it's
impossible to turn back.
Men never do this.
Men rarely jump
in the subway.
Women rarely cut their wrists.
It's both brave
and cowardly of them.
Yes. I don't know.
Life says women are right...
but gives death to men.
Death is what's important.
Van Gogh said we'll use death
to go to a new star.
There's something more
important than ideals...
but what?
There's something more important
than not being conquered.
I wish I knew what, exactly.
Pathetic.
At school, I admired
that word.
Now I despise it.
"Taciturn."
There's a beautiful word.
Like "guild."
I'm lost if I don't
pretend to be lost.
I think everyone
has an ideal.
But everyone is missing
something more important.
I'm sure that God
doesn't have an ideal.
There's a very,
very beautiful saying.
Whose is it?
I think it's Lenin's.
"The future esthetics
is ethics."
It's a beautiful saying,
very moving, too.
It reconciles
the Left with the Right.
What do Leftists
and Rightists think?
Today what's the revolution for?
The Right wins, then
applies Leftist policies.
And the other way around.
I win or lose,
but fight on alone.
In the thirties, young men
had a revolution.
For example, Malraux,
Drieu La Rochelle, Aragon.
We have nothing.
They had the Spanish
Civil War.
We have no war.
Aside from ourselves...
our own faces,
our own voices...
we have nothing.
But maybe it's important
to recognize the sound...
of your own voice...
and the shape of your face.
On the inside,
it's like this...
but when I look at it,
it's like this.
You look at me but don't
know what I'm thinking...
and never will know
what I'm thinking.
Right now,
a forest in Germany.
A bicycle ride.
It's over.
Now... a cafe terrace
in Barcelona.
Now... it's already over.
I'm trying to delimit
my own thoughts.
And speech. Where
does speech come from?
Maybe men talk endlessly
like goldminers...
Iooking for the truth.
But instead of digging
in rivers...
they dig in their thoughts.
They eliminate words
of no value...
and end up finding one...
just one...
just one golden one...
and already all is silence.
Why do you love me?
I don't know.
Because I'm crazy.
Who are you calling?
French Information Bureau.
Hang on.
OK. Give him to me.
Hello? Who's this?
Who is it?
It's Bruno.
Who is it?!
Bruno!
What's wrong?
I don't know. Bruno!
Bruno Forestier!
Wrong address?
Maybe they moved.
We've just spoken with Paul.
Paul found no Mohamed Messousa
at that address.
So no passports for me
and Veronica...
unless I kill Arthur Palivoda.
OK. Come over now.
Brilliant.
Yes.
Thanks. You're great.
OK. See you next week.
You're right, Paul.
A girl.
Alone, in town.
Is either a whore
or an informer.
She must know the Arabs'
address. She must know it.
Lock the door.
You never know.
Do they know
you were tortured?
Yes.
I'm glad.
The police found my Chevy
on a Swiss highway.
When will you be back?
I have to find Palivoda.
Maybe tonight... or tomorrow.
That's a cute dress.
Yes. It's a present.
From the guy
who gave you the puppy?
Did you sleep with him?
He dated me
a long time.
It's not important.
But it is.
See you soon.
Who is it?
It's Bruno.
Who's there?
Bruno!
It's you, Bruno?
Bruno Forestier!
The rest happened fast,
and the situation...
which seemed very complex
became very simple.
While I went to meet them...
the French hid Veronica
in a villa on the lake...
and tortured her badly...
to get the Arabs' address.
I didn't know it yet.
Jacques said he'd give me
Veronica and our passports...
once I'd killed Arthur Palivoda.
At times you must make your way
with a dagger.
It was after killing Palivoda
I learned Veronica was dead.
One thing I've learned is
not to be bitter.
I was just glad to still
have so much time left.