THE SILENCE OF THE SEA
To the memory
of Saint-Paul Roux murdered poet
This film doesn't have the pretense
of contributing a solution to the problem
of the relationships between France and Germany
problems that lasted
I release time for the crimes of the Nazi barbarism
perpetrated with the complicity of the German town
and that they will be in the memory of the men...
It left,
she/he underwent
as the other ones
as all the other ones
as all their unhappy town
it tried to fix in my memory
all that happened during those 6 months
the veiled ones, their words,
and that rebellion that that man didn't have
the anger of not accepting
the orders of their bosses
it preceded it a great unfolding
of military apparatuses
later a soldier came
accompanied by another
they spoke what they supposed it was French
I didn't understand neither a single word
without embargo,les I showed the free rooms
they seemed happy.
The following morning
a military car entered in the garden
Two soldiers lowered two boxes.
Hours later, I listened noises of horses
three horsemen appeared
they armed with my carpenter bank
and a hole that they made in the wall
a system with a rope to tie
to the horses before my shop
during two days I didn't see anybody
the horsemen left early,
they returned at night.
They slept on the straw of the loft.
In the morning of the third day it returned the car
A couple of sheets, please
My niece had just given me
a coffee as every night
The coffee makes me sleep. It was seated
in the bottom of the piece, in the dimness
Please!
My name is Werner von Ebrennach.
I sit down it a lot, but...
Naturally, it was necessary.
If it had been possible, it had avoided it
My ordinance will look after your tranquility.
Me...
I have great esteem
for people that loves to their homeland.
It would ascend to my piece,
but I don't know the road
My niece opened the door
that she/he gives on the stairway and it ascended
without looking at the official,
as if is alone
The official followed it,
I saw that she/he had a rigid leg
My niece returned.
For luck it seems to be correct.
The following day
the official lowered when we had breakfast
Not you if German had listened to us
or if for chance she/he had come somewhere around
She/he said,
I spent a very good night,
I wait that you also
The Mayor wanted to lodge in the castle
my men made a mistake
and I will congratulate them
this it is a lot a castle but beautiful
It returned at night
at the same hour that the eve
We took coffee, it hit,
but she/he didn't hope we opened up.
He opened up same.
I fear to bother them...
if they prefer it, I will go by the kitchen
they will close this door with key.
I wish them good night
We never close the door with key
I believe that the reason was not very clear neither very pure
my niece and I decide
to not change any detail of our life
as if the official didn't exist
as if it was a ghost
Maybe another feeling
she/he mixed with that will
I can not offend somebody without suffering
neither to my own enemy
During more than one month the same scene
she/he repeated day after day
It hit, she/he entered, she/he spoke
of the time, the temperature
or of topics without importance,
of those that she/he didn't wait answer
She/he stayed a while,
she/he looked around to its
and a smile translated
the pleasure that caused him that exam
the same one every day,
and the same pleasure
Their eyes were nailed
in my niece's profile
severe and insensitive siempe
and when it returned their view,
she/he guessed in him a smiling approval
I wish them good night.
The things changed abruptly one night
A very fine snow snowed,
terribly glacial
I put in the chimney a very big log
that it conserved this way for days
I imagined the official out
and she/he hoped to see it enter full with snow
but she/he didn't come.
The hour of its arrival passed,
and I recognized that he occupied my thought
My niece knitted slowly
it seemed very applied
we hear steps inside the house
I recognized for the unequal sound
walking of the official
I realized that she/he had entered
for the other door that she/he came from their room.
Without a doubt, she/he had not wanted to be shown
with their wet uniform and without prestige
First it was changed clothes.
We hear it lower for the stairway
The door opened up and the official
dress appeared of civil
Forgive me, I don't have heating it was
very mojado,y my room is very cold
I will warm some minutes
with your fire
Well. Well.
Here it is not anything,
the winter in France it is tempered
in my country it is very hard,
there are pines, there are thick forests
they fill with snow.
Here the trees are fine,
the snow forms a fitting in them
there it is thought of a very strong bull,
that she/he needs their force to live.
Here it is the spirit,
the subtle and poetic thought.
I always loved France, always.
In the other war, era a boy. It doesn't count.
I always wanted it.
Alone that from a distance, like to a distant princess
for my father...
for my father.
She/he was a great patriot,
the defeat caused him a great pain.
and however, she/he loved France and Briand
She/he believed in the Republic of Weimar and in Briand
It was very enthusiastic
She/he said: "It will unite us as husband and woman"
she/he thought that the sun will come out in Europe
but Briand was conquered
and my father vi?that France continued directed
for cruel bourgeois
men like Of Vendel, Henri Bordeaux,
and for your old marshal.
She/he told me: "Don't return to France,
until being able to go with boots and helmet."
I should be promised it since it was moribund.
When exploding the war all Europe she/he knew
except France
I am a musician, that is to say, composer.
There all my life is
I find strange to see I eat up warrior
and however, this war doesn't weigh me.
I believe that of all this big things will come out.
Forgive me if I offended them,
but what I say, thinks it
with the best intentions
I have a lot of love for France
big things will come out for Germany and France stops
I think as she/he made it my father,
that the sun will shine in Europe
I wish them good night.
Maybe be inhuman to not direct him the word.
From that day their visits were this way.
Very rarely she/he went uniformed.
It was to avoid us to do it with the uniform
or so that we forgot it and us
did we go accustoming their person?
Maybe for both reasons.
She/he called and she/he entered without waiting answer
she/he knew that she/he would not have it,
she/he made it candidly
She/he came to warm,
that was their constant pretext
that she/he didn't deceive him to him, neither to my
and whose conventional character didn't hide
She/he didn't come every night but not
I remember none that doesn't speak to us
she/he leaned toward the fire
and while a part was granted
of the heat of the flame for if same
their voice cantarin rose sweetly,
during those veiled ones
speaking of the topics
that their heart harbored
the music, France.
It was an endless monologue.
She/he never tried to wait an answer,
an approval, a look.
She/he didn't speak a lot of time,
not more than the first night
Some cut sentences
for the silence, they were chained
with supreme monotony,
sometimes immobile, against the chimney,
as a caryatid,
and other, coming closer to an object,
to a drawing, then she/he was quiet
and she/he leaned.
I wish them good night.
She/he said in one of their first visits
Which the difference is among
this fire and that of my country?
The wood, the flame, clear,
the chimneys look like each other
but the light not, this depends
of the objects that it illuminates
of the inhabitants.
Does reason love so much this piece?
It is not so beautiful, forgive...
I mean that it is not...
a museum, nobody would say
that it is a marvel
but here there is a soul,
the whole house has a soul
Balzac, Baudelaire,
Corneille, Discard, Hugo
how many geniuses,
and only arrive to the H!
Neither Moliére, neither Racine,
neither Rabelais, neither Pascal, neither Stendhal,
Voltaire or Montaigne,
or all the other ones
The Englishmen think alone in Shakespeare
the Italians in Dante,
the Spaniards in Cervantes
and us in Goethe,
then it is necessary to look for.
But if one speaks of France,
at once Moliere arises
Racine, Hugo, Voltaire,
Rabelais, or which another?
They are a crowd,
it is not tasted like the one who to mention first
But in music we are us.
Bach, Haendel
Beethoven, Wagner, Mozart,
which is the first one?
No, we were not born for the war.
It will be the last one, not
we will fight more. We will marry.
If, if.
It will be the most beautiful marriage in the world.
I wish them good night.
I will warm, it follows your.
She/he never made allusion to that encounter
When we enter to Sainte I was happy.
They received us well.
It was very happy,
I thought: "This will be easy."
But then I saw that it was not this way,
it was pure cowardice
and I feared for France,
I thought: " Has she/he become this way?"
No, not. I saw it at once.
And now I love to see their severe face.
I love to have found here
a worthy man
and a silent young lady
It will be necessary to conquer that silence
That silence of France.
I like that
And one night
If, it is better this way.
Better.
That makes solid unions,
in those that each one wins in greatness
I read a beautiful story for children
You will also have made it
I don't know if the title
it is the same one in both countries
In my country it is
"You give Tier und you give Schöne"
"The beast and the beautiful one"
Poor beautiful!
The beast has it to her grace,
impotent and prisoner
it imposes him at all times
their implacable presence
the beautiful one is proud,
worthy, she/he has become hard
the beast is worth more than what seems
If, it is something ordinary,
clumsy, brutal, silly
beside the beautiful one,
so fine, but she/he has heart
a soul that aspires to rise,
if the beautiful one wanted.
The beautiful one took a lot in wanting
and she/he discovered in the eyes
of the hated jailer a light
a reflection in the one that
it was read the prayer and the love
then it felt less
the chains of their prison
She/he stops to hate. Their perseverance
it moves it and it spreads the hand
the beast transforms,
she/he becomes a gentleman
very beautiful and very pure,
delicate and well educated
to the one that each kiss of the beautiful one
she/he adorns of qualities
their union determines a sublime happiness
their children that add
and the gifts of their parents mix
they are the most beautiful in the world
Don't they like that story?
I always liked it to my
She/he reread it unceasingly,
she/he made me cry
She/he loved the beast mainly,
she/he understood their pain
today it still moves me to speak of her
I wish them good night.
One night I ascended to my room
to look for tobacco
and I listened the song of the harmonium
They were the preludes and flights that my
niece studied before the defeat
The notebook had been open,
my niece had not played more
To hear it caused in my pleasure and surprise
What interior necessity
had it impelled it?
But not, she/he had not abandoned
neither their armchair, neither their task.
There is not nothing else big that this,
and big it is not the word.
Outside of the man,
outside of their meat,
that makes us understand,
to guess?, no...
Better,
to foresee what is the nature
the divine nature,
of the human soul,
If, it is an inhuman music
Bach, it could only be German.
Our earth
she/he has that character of inhuman
pale,
to the man's measure
I love this music,
I admit it
it is in my as,
the presence of God...
But it is not mine,
I want to make music to the man's measure
That is also a road
to reach the truth
It is my road,
it could not follow another
Now I know it,
sure, I know it.
From when?
Since I live here.
Now I need France,
but I request a lot,
I ask him to receive me.
I won't live in her as a stranger
a traveler or a conqueror.
In that case, she/he doesn't give anything,
anything can not be removed
their wealth, their great wealth
you can not conquer
it is necessary to drink it in their breast
she/he should offer it
with a maternal movement
I know that it depends on us,
but also of her
she/he should accept to understand
our thirst, satiating her
it should accept
to unite with us
I will have to live a lot of time
here, in a house like this
as the son of a town,
resemblance to this
it will be necessary...
I will conquer the obstacles,
for that it serves the sincerity
I wish them good night
I can not remember all that she/he said
during a hundred o'clock veiled of winter
but the topics didn't vary a lot
their rhapsody of the discovery of France,
the distant love
that it felt for her before knowing it
and the love that grew
to newspaper since she/he lived in her
The truth, admired him,
she/he didn't loose heart and never
she/he tried to shake that implacable silence.
with violence in the language.
On the contrary,
when the silence
it invaded the room
and it saturated him
as a heavy and unbreathable gas
it was the one that more comfortable
she/he felt of the three
my niece looked with approval,
smiling and serious
that it had been his,
from the first day.
I felt my niece's soul
to become agitated in the prison
that herself was built
she/he noticed it in certain signs,
in a slight tremor of their fingers
and when Werner
it dissipated that silence
smoothly,
for the filter of their voice zumbona,
we seemed to be able to breathe
plus freely
The house where nací|estaba in the forest
I went to the school of the town,
I didn't leave it until going to Munich
for the exams
and to Salzburgo for the music
from then on I lived there,
it hated the big cities
I met London, Vienna, Rome
and Warsaw and the big ones
German cities naturally.
I don't like them to live,
only Praga that has more soul.
And mainly Nuremberg,
it is the city that dilates the heart.
a German finds in her
their ghosts,
the memory of the nobility
of the old Germany
I believe that the French
they should feel the same thing in Chartres
the presence of their ancestors,
the grace of the soul.
the splendor of their faith and their kindness.
The destination led me to Chartres
Attention!
950 meters! 10 more!
Fire!
And it is true, so many things
moved in the soul of a German
even the best of those which
she/he wanted that cures him.
In the neighboring castle to house
there is a very beautiful and sweet youth
my father had liked it
that I married her
when she/he almost died we were boyfriends,
she/he allowed to stroll alone
One day, being in the forest...
I am so happy Werner!
How sacred it is this creation of God!
I am also happy.
Damned animal!
It chopped me!
Look! I caught it!
Now I will punish him.
I will pull up him a paw after another.
For luck, she/he had other festejantes...
I didn't have remorses.
But I was always afraid
to the German girls
They are this way our politicians,
for that reason never I united to them
to weigh that my friends told me:
Come with us!
But not,
I preferred to stay in my house
It was not very good for the Music,
but I didn't care it
the success is not anything,
a calm conscience is a lot
I believe that my friends
and our Führer has ideal noblemen
but they would pull up the paws
of the mosquitos some after others
that passes the Germans
when they are alone
that always revives and she/he has
more alone than those of the same one
party when they are the masters
but they are no longer alone,
they are in France,
this will cure them. They know it,
they know that France will teach them
to truly be
big and pure
for that she/he makes love,
shared love.
I wish them good night
They arrived the spring days
the official returned to the decline
Decisions will be made
historical of an unique reach
One night it lowered with a book
Their face was illuminated
with that smile that foresees
the neighbor's pleasure. She/he said:
Forgive that it bothers them,
but I lowered this for you
It is a page of Macbeth
What greatness!
It is the end, the might of Macbeth
she/he is escaped from the fingers.
with the fidelity of those that measure
finally their black ambition.
The gentlemen that defend
the honor of Scotland
they wait their fall, one of them
it points out the symptoms of the hecatomb.
it feels that their secret crimes
they are hit to their hands
The heart men, indignant,
they reproach him their bad faith.
Those that sends,
they obey for fear, and not for love
And you see their title
hanging around to its
as the suit of a giant
on the hands that she/he stole
It is not what perturbs
the nights of your present
I pity that man
although I reject him
as you they make it
and those that obey
"they make it for fear and not for love"
A boss that is not loved,
she/he is a miserable puppet
but could another thing be wanted?
Alone a dark one ambitious
it would have accepted that
it was I specify somebody,
that she/he accepted to sell to their homeland
because today, neither in a lot
time France, it can not fall
in our open arms,
without losing the dignity
sometimes, the most sordid celestina
it is the base of a happy wedding
the celestina
it is not for anything worthless
neither the less happy union.
The train of Paris.
I should warn to my hosts
that I will leave two weeks
I am glad to go to Paris,
I have permission and I will pass it there,
for the first time.
It is a great day for my.
The biggest,
awaiting other,
that I want with all my soul,
and that it will be even bigger.
I will know how to wait for it.
Years... if it is necessary.
My heart has a lot of patience
I suppose that in Paris,
I will see my friends.
Many business
with the political men of here
preparing the wonderful union
of both towns
This way, I will be witness of that wedding.
I am happy for France,
their wounds will heal this way quick.
But I am happy
even more for Germany and for my.
Nobody will take advantage of this good action
as much as she/he will make Germany
returning to France
their greatness and freedom.
I wish them good night.
THE FRENCH ARMY
EMBARKED IN BOULOGNE
ENGLAND THREATENS.
A THIRD Coalition
It is ALREADY IN THE CONTINENT.
THE FRENCH
They FLY FROM THE OCEAN TO THE DANUBE.
BAVIERA is LIBERATED
GOD AND THE KING Send ME
To EXPEL THEM OF ALL FRANCE
When it returned we didn't see it.
We didn't know reason.
The presence of a guest
it is revealed by diverse signs
Although it is invisible.
During many days, more than one week
We didn't see it. I admit that that
absence didn't leave alone me
She/he thought of him, and non sé|si it felt to weigh or restlessness for it.
My niece and me,
we didn't make any comment
When we sometimes heard up
the unequal steps
to weigh that she/he guessed in her
for their attitude and their face
with the obstinate expression
and it attempts that their thought
she/he didn't walk far from mine.
One day I had to go to the Command
for a declaration of rubbers.
Happen.
BY A FREE EUROPE.
What does she/he want?
If, Boss.
Make 5 copies and send a...
and one send to each unit
Of agreement, my Lieutenant
I didn't count anything to my niece,
but the woman has intuition
Along the veiled one,
she/he didn't stop to lift the eyes
to look at myself to every minute
trying to read something
in my face that I made an effort
to maintain it impassive.
smoking my pipe.
Finally,
she/he allowed to fall their hands like tired
and folding the fabric
she/he requested me permission to go to bed
She/he kissed me, I believed to read in their
beautiful gray eyes a reproach
and a deep sadness.
After their departure,
I felt an absurd rage.
The rage of being absurd
and to have an absurd niece
What was all this idiocy?
She/he was not able to mantenemerlo.
If it was an idiocy,
she/he seemed to have deep roots
They were later 3 days,
hardly emptied our cups
we hear without place to doubts
that they approached the family steps
I remembered that first night
of winter where those steps
6 months they were heard behind.
I thought Today it rains."
My niece had a silk shawl
on the shoulders
and I warmed the fingers
in the hornillo of my pipe
although we were in summer.
I looked like each other to see
to the man behind the door
preparation to hit,
retarding the moment
in that for their expression of hitting,
it would commit the future
Finally, it hit.
I don't say with hesitation neither with
the abruptness of the conquered shyness
they were 3 sure and slow blows.
Dice with that calm
of somebody resolved to everything
I hoped the door opened up,
but she/he didn't open up
An indescribable agitation invaded me.
She/he will leave.
Which they were that night,
the commandments of the dignity?
Among, Mr.
That day I knew that a hand
she/he can for a correct observer
to reflect the emotions
the same as the face
until better than him,
since it escapes better to the control.
I should tell them something serious
What I said these 6 months,
all that the walls heard,
it is necessary to forget it.
How much light!
I saw those victorious men.
I spoke to them. They laughed at my.
It was so happy
of having gone to Paris!
Treblinka? Perfect. And what?
What does Treblinka mean?
Anything. Already anything.
How anything?
No. She/he leaves that.
That is not for the weak characters.
They execute mass
in cameras of gas
built for such an end,
with suffocating gases
and crematory ovens.
The yield today in day
it belongs to 500 people.
But the methods are perfected.
And in 2 months they will be been able to liquidate
2000 people per day.
It begins the spring.
Begin the spring!
These cameras of gas
do they work at the present time?
No. Treblinka no longer uses it.
She/he ended. To retirement.
There is no longer the one who to execute.
I am surprised their point of view.
She/he doesn't realize
that we deceive them?
She/he believes that we are as silly as
to let that France rises?
We are not musicians. The politics
it is not any idolatry.
For what reason did we make this war?
To please the marshal?
We are not crazy,
neither we are imbecile.
We can destroy France
and we will make it.
We will destroy their force and their soul
there the great danger is.
That is our task,
don't make you illusions.
We will keep the smile
we will be soft,
but we will make that France
be an obedient dog.
You are influenced
for your love to France
It is dangerous. We don't go
to cure Europe of that pest.
We will expel the poison.
We will praise their writers
We already take cautions.
Any French book
she/he will enter in Belgium and Holland
neither in any busy country,
except for publications
on ballistics
or cement production.
You work cultural, none.
We will pull up to the beast,
their poisonous teeth
they begin to be afraid,
they tremble for their money
for their stomach,
for their industry and their trade
that is their only restlessness.
Clear, there are exceptions, but to those
we will tranquilize them flattering them.
Anything is simpler.
for a plate of lentils
do they know what they are making?
Do they measure the reach?
Do you believe that we will doubt?
We are of another species.
but the shipwreck of France,
it will be eternal.
It is a matter of life or death.
To conquer coarse the force,
but it is not enough.
We know that the army
it doesn't reach to reign.
But not to expense of the spirit,
not to that price!
The spirit already other vi?
the spirit is immortal.
We will create a Reich for a thousand years
and the first thing is to destroy,
it is our right and our duty.
Wait here.
A box of matches,
please, Sra,
There are not hopes.
Anything. Anything.
Nobody.
Not alone the modern ones,
the Peguy, the Proust, the Bergson.
The other ones. All the other ones.
All.
They will turn off the flame of everything.
Europe won't be illuminated by that light.
One of them was my friend.
She/he was my brother.
We study together.
We lived in the same room in Stuttgart
3 months we pass together in Nuremberg.
She/he played him my music,
she/he read me their poems.
It was sensitive and romantic.
But she/he abandoned me.
And she/he left to read their poems to Munich.
Before other partners. She/he wrote
requesting me that it was with him.
I did it in Paris with their friends.
I saw that they made with him.
It was rabid.
It mixed the rage with the laugh.
I looked at myself inflamed and she/he screamed:
It is necessary to empty
the poison of the beast!
I said:
Do they realize that they make?
She/he looked at it in the deep thing
of their clear eyes.
It was I am honest.
That is the terrible thing.
They will make what they say.
With method and perseverance
I know those beasts!
Their lips you entreabieron,
I believed that it would throw us
an exhortation for
to induce us to the rebellion.
But it didn't pronounce neither
a single word on that.
They told me:
"It is our right and our duty"
Our duty...
Blissful the one that finds with so
simple certainty the one on the way to their duty
In the crossroad, they tell us:
take that road!
But that road doesn't go
toward the luminous heights
it lowers toward a sinister valley,
she/he collapses in the fetid ones
darkness of a forest.
God!
Show me where my duty is!
Is the duty maybe to accept a crime?
I made be worth my rights.
I asked to go to the front.
That favor was granted me.
They authorized me to leave tomorrow.
And I will return to the combat, as hell.
I wish them good night. Good-bye.
Good-bye.
I hardly heard that word, but I heard it.
von Ebrennach also heard it.
Lower my things.
ALIVE THE SOLDIER THAT
DISOBEY A CRIMINAL ORDER!
All clever one is.
Well. I already go.
My niece me preparó|el eats lunch as always
it served me in silence,
we drank in silence.
A pale sun shone
through the fog
I found that it was very cold.
October 1941
This book, published thanks to a patriot
she/he finished printing under the Nazi occupation
February 20 1942.
Subtitulos Oski!