Some people hear their own
inner voices...
with great clearness...
and they live
by what they hear.
Such people become crazy...
or they become legends.
Tristan Ludlow was born
in the Moon of the Falling Leaves.
It was a terrible winter.
His mother almost died
bringing him into this world.
His father, the Colonel,
brought him to me.
I wrapped him in a bearskin
and held him all that night.
As he grew into a man...
I taught him the great joy
of the kill...
when the hunter
cuts out its warm heart
and holds it in his hands...
setting its spirit free.
Colonel Ludlow had three sons...
but Tristan was his favorite.
I had had sons too.
But they were gone now...
forever.
It was a very bad time.
The Colonel had tried
to help the People...
but it was no use.
So he decided
to go his own way.
He wanted to lose the madness
over the mountains, he said...
and begin again.
"Lose the madness, "he said.
And so we lived for many years...
and the boys grew strong.
Alfred was the older brother...
old even for his years.
Samuel was the youngest.
There was nothing these brothers
would not do for him.
They watched over him
like a treasure.
One year--
I am an old man
and cannot remember the year.
But it was the Moon
of the Red Grass...
when Isabel Ludlow,
their mother...
went away for the winter.
She said the winters
were too cruel for her.
She said she was afraid
of the bears.
She was a strange woman anyway.
That spring, though,
she did not return.
And, after that,
she did not come much to see us.
Alfred wrote her many letters...
but Tristan refused
to speak of her.
His world was here with me.
Every warrior hopes a good death
will find him...
but Tristan couldn't wait.
He went looking for his.
Tristan!
Here.
- Was it a bear?
- Yes, sir.
- Can you breathe?
- Yes.
Move your hand.
Take it away.
You're a stupid,
half-brained jackass.
- Yes, sir.
- One Stab put you up to this?
You deserve to be dead.
God knows how you've
lived so long.
It'll be all right, son.
I have these letters...
many letters.
Read them.
They are from all of them.
Ludlow...
Isabel...
Samuel...
the whole family...
the whole story.
It is all written here.
April 13, 1913.
Dear Isabel:
I am not fool enough to try
to reorder a life already lived...
but I fear I have not done well raising
our sons alone in this wild place.
What did I know of children?
I was trained to lead men.
This is infinitely harder.
Dear William:
You take too much responsibility
on yourself, as always.
Our sons are finding their own paths.
They are willful, certainly,
but then...
who are you and I
to complain of willfulness?
As for Samuel,
I have big news.
At a Harvard tea
for Amy Lowell...
he met and instantly loved
Miss Susannah Finncannon.
I know it will
surprise you greatly...
but they are engaged.
He will bring her to Montana
this summer to meet his brothers...
and you.
So, William,
please behave yourself...
and be as charming
as only you can be.
There he is.
- How the hell are you?
- Good. And you?
- Samuel. Good to see you, boy.
- Father, how are you?
- Good to see you.
- Hello.
This is my fiancee, Susannah.
- Miss Finncannon.
- Nice to meet you.
- It's an honor.
- This is Alfred.
- How do you do?
- Here's youog, miss.
- Thank you.
- It's a horse.
- That's a strange-looking animal.
This is Finn.
He's a champion.
You like ex otic-looking dogs then,
Miss Finncannon?
Very much, Mr. Ludlow.
- Please call me Susannah.
- All right.
- He's just plain old Alfred.
- Shut up.
- Where's Tristan?
- He's off somewhere. You know him.
He'll welcome you home tonight
or I'll know the reason why.
Miss Finncannon, please.
Did you have a good journey?
She is such a lovely creature.
But I fear the loss
of her parents...
has given her
a certain fragility.
I think she feels very alone
in the world.
But she has found a new family now,
hasn't she?
The German military is ready
to use chaos in Croatia...
to justify actions that could plunge
the entire civilized world into--
The word " civilized" has no place
in discussing the affairs of this world.
Mother told us of your sympathy
for the social reformers.
You make it sound like a disease.
No, I'm in agreement.
You mother told me all about One Stab.
She says he was a great warrior.
Yes.
He has a bag of scalps
to prove it.
But don't worry.
He's devoted to Father now.
Rather, they're devoted
to each other.
Can he speak English?
Stab, speak English?
He wouldn't lower himself
to speak English.
But watch out because
he understands it perfectly well.
There's Tristan.
- Don't they feed you?
- Not much.
- You smell.
- Miss me, did you?
- Still hung over?
- Still drunk.
Isn't she amazing?
So this is Tristan.
And does he speak English?
For God's sake.
Miss Finncannon,
it's a pleasure to meet you.
I hope you and Ugly here...
find every happiness together.
Don't mind my brother. Your dog
has more breeding than he has.
This is Mother's room.
It's lovely.
- It's a pleasure to meet you, Pet.
- And you, miss.
Thank you.
- Which one?
- It's this one.
Angelica Susannah.
Hello.
You must be Isabel Two.
I've already met your mother
and father.
- How old are you?
- Thirteen.
When I was 1 3,
I was sent away...
to boarding school.
I hated it.
May I help you?
You're marrying Samuel.
That's right, I am.
I'm marrying Tristan.
We'll be sisters.
I see you two have met.
Isabel Two is letting me help.
Would you like a rest?
You must be exhausted.
No, not at all.
This is so refreshing...
all this grandeur,
this unexpected...
gift from God.
It doesn't seem like much of a gift
in a hard winter, I assure you.
Where's Samuel?
Inside. I could tell your father
wanted him all to himself.
- You're very generous.
- No, just happy.
Stop mooning over her
and come in here.
Samuel wants to know
about the calves from Cheyenne.
Get in here.
Please excuse my father.
It makes him feel young and powerful
to treat us like we're idiot children.
For all His countless blessings,
may God's holy name be praised. Amen.
Tell Father what you were saying
about Vienna.
- What's that?
- It's the Kaiser.
He won't stop them
from annihilating Serbia.
Let's not talk about war, please.
Susannah hears
that England's mobilizing.
We're stuck out here
while all this is going on.
- Thank God.
- You wouldn't want us to evade a duty.
- Wouldn't I ?
- Father, with respect--
Please excuse me
for being late.
I packed so carefully,
I couldn't find anything.
Thank you.
Would you like some--
As evening fell
a maiden stood
At the edge of a wood
In her hands lay the reins
Of a stallion
And n'er I'd seen
A girl as fair
Heard a gentler voice anywhere
Whispered, alas
She belonged
Belonged to another
Another, forever
Yes, she belonged to
The twilight and mist
Dear Isabel:
How strange to have a cultivated woman
in the house again...
and how intoxicating.
To have all three of my sons
under my roof again...
fills me with such a deep,
quiet satisfaction...
that I thank God.
There's a friend of yours.
A dollar says
he brings her back.
Whoa.
Easy.
You got it.
Nice work.
You all look
like ice cream cones.
I know you would have.
Ready. Here we go.
Go easy on him, Susannah.
Alfred, you take over.
I must talk to Tristan.
You've disgraced the Colonel's name.
- Nice shiner.
- I hit her back.
She's got me spinning.
I'll bet.
She's got these ideas
and theories, and she's so--
What?
Nothing.
How'd you break the mare?
She's what?
She's sort of passionate.
- She a virgin?
- Good Lord, Tristan.
- You brought it up.
- Of course she is.
Are you?
- Yes, I am.
- Going to wait till you're married?
See, she says--
Susannah thinks that--
We won't wait.
And you're afraid
you won't meet her expectations?
I guess I am.
Sort of. I don't know.
Should I be?
Samuel, God bless you.
You are good
at everything you try.
I'm sure it will be the same
with fucking.
Tristan, really.
- She's my future wife.
- You're not going to fuck her?
I'm planning to be with her.
I recommend fucking.
- You're impossible.
- You brought it up.
My point!
Good morning,
Colonel Ludlow.
Tristan's hunting.
He didn't do it.
You don't have to worry
about Tristan.
Meet John T. and James O' Banion.
They own the mer cantile store.
- Morning, James, John T., Sheriff.
- Morning, Alfred.
We're looking for a man we heard
might be in this part of the country.
Name is Tom Cullen.
Here's a likeness.
What did he do?
Do you recognize him?
- Yeah, I recognize him.
- We got him.
This fellow passed by here...
maybe four or five years ago.
Did some work here
on his way to San Francisco.
He hoped to book passage
to Australia.
Or Hong Kong.
I can't remember.
- Can you remember?
- Hong Kong.
- What is he wanted for?
- He--
That would be
of a private nature.
" Private nature" ?
You hold a public office, Sheriff.
Gentlemen.
"There came a low hiss,
a horrid sound...
that made Rikki Tikki Tavi
jump back two clear feet.
And then out of the grass...
rose up the head
and spread hood of Nag...
the big black cobra."
I can read another story.
The Germans broke through
at Armentieres.
The British are trapped
in the Belgian lowlands.
- This paper is a week old!
- Calm down.
With my fluent German,
I could become an officer.
And lead other boys to the slaughter
and be slaughtered yourself.
The men who served under you
worshipped you.
They were all damn fools.
This is a turning point
in history.
- How can we--
- What?
How can we not
be part of this?
- You taught us--
- To think for yourselves.
- And to defend what's ours.
- Yes, what is ours!
We've already lost two cousins.
Don't talk at me as though
I've never seen a war!
Not a war like this.
They said that about the war
of secession and the Indian wars.
They say it to sell newspapers.
These are not the Indian wars.
We're fighting against naked aggression!
There will be no more talk of wars
in this house! Damn it!
I'm sorry, Susannah.
I'm going to Canada to enlist.
I'm going with him.
I'm sorry, my love.
I meant to tell you tonight.
I know you'll understand.
It's the only honorable thing to do.
What's that?
It's a book my father wrote...
to try to convince the government
to alter their policies...
towards the Indians
in the Dakotas.
Samuel won't change his mind.
Change it for him.
What happened between them?
Father says
she never liked it here.
I think they loved mostly the idea
of each other.
Don't let him go.
I'll take care of him.
October 14, 1914.
My dear Isabel:
Today our sons are leaving home...
to defend an England
they have never seen.
I am unable to stop them.
I have tried to shelter our sons
from all the madness...
and now they go to seek it.
Be careful.
You don't have to go.
Good-bye.
Don't worry, Father.
Take care.
I'll bring you
the Kaiser's helmet.
Bring yourself back.
That would please me more.
Yes, sir.
- Take care of Samuel.
- I will.
Colonel Ludlow told me:
"Ride with them to Calgary.
Bring back the horses. "
"Damn fools, "he called them.
The Colonel
would not have his sons...
ride off to war
on old nags...
damn fools or not.
Let's join them.
Bring your plate.
He'll be back.
May we join you?
Sit down.
Feeling lonely in there.
Sit here.
What's her name, Two?
Lady. Tristan's Lady.
In the story,
Tristan's lady was Isolde.
- Do you know who Isolde was?
- No.
Your daughter needs an education.
She can read and write, Colonel.
School might be awkward for her.
- I'll teach her myself.
- May I help?
Yeah. I'll teach her
history and mathematics.
With your permission, Decker,
and yours, Pet.
What do you think?
What will she do
with all this education?
She'll live a richer,
fuller life, of course.
She's a half-breed.
Not in this house.
- Tristan calls me a half-breed.
- He does?
He says I'm half gopher
and half hawk.
- After her chores.
- Yeah.
- To us all.
- To you, sir.
- And you, miss.
- And to the boys.
Get back to your unit.
Those boys are boring.
I'd rather have you
watching my back.
Go, mate.
February 3, 1915.
Dear Susannah:
The horror of this place
is indescribable.
Nothing is
as I thought it would be.
Keep your distance!
Keep your spacing!
Tonight, as I prayed for the souls
of those who died so terribly...
yet so bravely...
I admit that I also prayed
for personal glory.
Is that wrong to want
to distinguish myself gloriously...
in combat as my father did?
Tristan and Alfred
watch over me so carefully...
I may never get the opportunity.
Charge!
Goddamn it!
- Where are you hit?
- It's just a scratch.
Susannah, I see now...
not that my father was right,
but that I was naive.
- Let me up, damn it!
- Stay down!
Fall back!
Still, we place our bodies
in God's keeping.
We go into battle honorably...
full of confidence...
with His name on our lips.
- We're pinned here.
- We'll wait.
- Give him a hand.
- Help him down.
Goddamn.
Susannah:
I try to guard against despair...
but there are moments when it seems
that all human decency is broken down.
Alfred will recover
from his wounds...
but he and Tristan seem
to have drifted apart, or worse.
I cannot understand it.
I miss you more
than you can imagine.
You are all that is clean
and cool and pure.
I close my eyes
and think of you.
I now regret that we listened
to everyone and waited to marry.
Even more, I regret that I left
before we could be together...
as we planned, my beloved.
Please stay on at the ranch
and wait for me.
Don't let Father worry.
I know God's mercy
will protect me...
aided considerably
by Tristan...
who seems to be in France
less to fight the Germans...
than to act
as my nursemaid.
Be well, my love.
Your own, Samuel.
Captain needs me to translate
this before tonight's reconnaissance.
- Alfred will want to see you.
- I'll be there.
- Yeah?
- Go on.
Where's Samuel?
He's translating.
He'll be here.
Boy, that's a good one.
- Vino?
- Put that away.
- They said you'll get a medal.
- Yes.
- They're sending me home.
- I'm glad for you.
I'm an officer.
I belong with my men.
Horseshit.
What's left of them.
MacKenzie was just brought in.
His leg's turned bad.
- He said--
- What?
What is it?
He said your brother volunteered
to take his place...
on the reconnaissance
with the captain.
Goddamn it!
I told you to stay with him!
- I'm here!
- Where? I can't see.
I can't move!
I'm coming!
I got you now.
You're doing good.
We're going home.
God, no!
Goddamn you, God!
Tristan, it's me.
March 20, 1915.
Dear Father and Susannah:
I am being discharged from the Army,
but I cannot come home yet.
I will ask Grandfather Ludlow
in Cornwall...
to let me join him at sea.
As for our beloved Samuel...
all I can send home
is his heart.
Alfred will bring it back.
He should be buried
up in the box canyon...
where he used
to draw the birds.
Your son, Tristan.
He certainly was the best
of all of us, wasn't he?
Good night.
What you saw
before Samuel left--
Please, don't--
No, I want to.
It is Samuel I loved.
All right.
Tristan will be back someday.
Your father will be pleased.
Susannah was to return to Boston
on the morning train...
but a norther blew
for three days...
and drifted over the tracks.
The Colonel insisted
she stay on until spring.
The house was too empty,
he said.
This was still her home,
he told her.
He should have let her go.
But how could he have known
what would happen?
She was not to blame.
She was like the water
that freezes in the rock...
and splits it apart.
It was no more her fault
than it is the fault of the water...
when the rock shatters.
You know how much I --
You know how much
I loved Samuel.
And I think you know--
Out of respect for him,
I wanted to say it here.
I think you know that...
I'm in love with you.
From the first moment
I saw you...
like in a novel.
That's my mother's overblown
romantic imagination coming out in me.
You're not making this
very easy for me.
Sorry.
Is there any hope
that you could learn to love me?
Not the way you love Samuel,
of course...
but enough to--
We could make a life together.
A happy life.
I don't think so.
Sounds like you're not sure, though.
Maybe there's a chance?
- What?
- I can only cause you pain, Alfred.
Why not let me
be the judge of that?
I didn't break it,
but I can fix it.
I can put the damn wheel back on
and take it off myself.
Go take a nap.
- What?
- Look!
I'm going into town if--
Welcome home, son.
I couldn't save him.
Of course you couldn't.
It's all right.
Have a nice ride today?
Excuse me, Father.
Tristan, please.
When are you planning
to be married?
Good morning.
Damn you.
You will marry her.
- Make an honest woman of her?
- Yes!
God damn you to hell.
Yes, I will marry her,
if she'll have me.
If she'll have you?
Do you love her?
Or did you seduce her
just to spite me?
That's not what I did.
- What about Samuel?
- What?
You tell me about Samuel.
We all loved Samuel.
Samuel is dead.
How convenient for you.
Because you love her,
I will forgive you for that.
Once. You say that again,
and we're not brothers.
You know you can't make her happy.
I'm gonna try.
You will fail.
I'll be leaving today.
I wish you both all the best.
- Good-bye, son.
- Wish me luck.
Good luck.
September 7, 1915.
Dearest Mother:
I think I may have found
my place in this world.
Helena is a city
turned modern overnight...
bursting with all the energy
and vitality...
of our times.
I feel alive here.
There is much opportunity
for anyone...
who dedicates himself
to his labors.
Already, I have acquired a reputation
for honesty and fair dealing...
and I am pleased to call some of
Helena's most influential citizens...
my friends.
They are determined to see
this city grow, as am I.
We're proud of you.
Mother, thank you
for your kind letter.
You knew my hopes.
That you understand my disappointment
is a great comfort to me.
Every night I pray for the grace
to forgive Tristan.
I know you understand.
Your loving son, Alfred.
Quit it!
Goddamn it!
If we have a boy,
I'd like to call him Samuel.
And if it's a girl, Isabel.
I'll still love you.
You'll tolerate me
because of how much I love you.
Nothing.
I heard from your mother.
She says Alfred has hooked up
with those damn O' Banion brothers.
- He's doing well.
- Alfred will do well wherever he is.
- Except here with us.
- That's my fault.
- I didn't say that.
- Couldn't save Samuel either, could I ?
Don't you dare say that.
That was in God's hands.
Was it?
Colonel! Lost a couple calves
near Camas Canyon.
- Might be a grizzly.
- My grizzly?
- You take him, Tristan.
- Damn right I will.
I don't know why Tristan
did not kill that damn old bear.
The Old Ones say:
"When a man and an animal...
have spilled each other's blood...
they become one. "
I said four beers,
Mr. Sachtleben.
And I said no Indians.
- He's quite civilized, I assure you.
- Yeah?
- Give him a beer.
- Stay out of it.
- My father said four.
- He heard me.
We're about to reach an understanding.
Just give him a goddamn beer!
Stay out of it!
Damn you.
You're a damn fool.
You're spoiling for a fight
with a man who outweighs you.
As we speak, he's sear ching
for some kind of a weapon.
Isn't that right?
To split your stupid skull
and kill you and good riddance.
Leave it!
- Yes, sir?
- I want four beers, now.
The lousy owner says
he doesn't want to serve Indians.
Get back.
Do you see this man?
Do you?
His name is One Stab.
He's a venerated Cree elder and has
counted coup on hundreds of his enemies.
He's our friend.
He's thirsty.
I think it was the bear's voice
he heard deep inside him...
growling low
of dark, secret places.
Were you going to say good-bye?
How long will you be gone?
Not long.
A few months.
I can make it better for you.
If we'd had a child...
or if I were pregnant,
would you still go?
Yes.
Just give me a chance.
Don't do that.
Look at me.
Please, look at me.
I'll wait for you.
However long it takes.
I'll wait for you forever.
Will he come back?
I don't know.
Stab says yes.
April 20, 1918.
Dear Tristan:
It has been months now,
and still no word.
The only sign
that you are alive...
is a tattered parcel that arrived today
from New Guinea...
covered with strange writing...
and containing what appears to be
a native bracelet.
Meant for me, I presume.
But perhaps not.
Do you still care to know
what is happening here?
Cattle prices continue to fall...
and winter seems never ending.
Why don't you write?
Are you afraid to tell me
you're never coming back?
Alfred continues to do well.
His business has expanded to include
financial concerns in Chicago...
and Washington.
I don't pretend to understand.
He wants us to send Isabel Two
to boarding school in Chicago...
but she adamantly refuses
to leave the ranch.
I think she, too,
is waiting for you.
I have nowhere
to send this letter...
and no reason to believe
you wish to receive it.
I write it only for myself.
I will hide it away with all the things
left unsaid and undone...
between us.
December 1 2, 1 9 1 9.
Dear Susannah:
I have become a hunter.
Tell Stab there are creatures here
that cannot even be found in books.
I have killed them all.
All we had is dead.
As I am dead.
Marry another.
Colonel, it looks like
we've got company.
- I have come to ask for your blessing.
- My blessing?
You see, these gentlemen and--
And a great many others,
I might add.
They're urging me
to run for office.
- What office?
- The United States Congress.
That's how highly
we think of your son.
And what do you gentlemen
hope to get out of this?
I beg your pardon?
I've spoken plain English, sir.
What do you want for yourselves?
Father, I don't think
that these gentlemen--
Did you ask that question
or do you believe these gentlemen...
would back you out of patriotic duty
and your inestimable worth?
You forget yourself, Father.
I am no longer a child.
Colonel, the Congress--
Congress is government, sir.
I worked for the government once.
The issues that we--
Indians! Indians were
the issue in those days.
There is nothing as grotesque...
as the meeting of a child
with a bullet...
or an entire village slaughtered
while sleeping.
That was the government's resolution
of that particular issue.
I've seen nothing since then
to persuade me it's gained...
in wisdom, common sense
or humanity.
Gentlemen, my father, for whom
I have the deepest respect...
says that the government
has neither wisdom nor humanity.
I will then consider it
my absolute duty as my father's son...
to bring both wisdom and humanity
to the United States Congress.
I thank you for your blessing.
Gentlemen.
- Gentlemen, wait for me in the cars.
- Yes. Certainly.
Are you all right?
What's wrong?
I don't know what to say.
Tristan's always been wild.
- You love him for that.
- Do I ?
I suppose I do.
He does love you.
She's to be your brother's wife.
Yes, though you better
remind him of that fact.
He's not here
to defend himself.
No, but I see you are here
to defend him and what is his...
even though
he's abandoned her and you.
I won't even speak
of who else he abandoned.
Damn you, boy.
Don't you blame my son
for Samuel's death!
Samuel chose to be a soldier,
and soldiers die...
sent to their slaughter
by men in government.
Parasites like you!
Damn and blast you!
Damn you.
And damn you too!
Shut your mouth.
Leave her out of this!
Get out of my house
and get off my land.
Why? Because I want
to serve my country as you did?
Or because, like you,
I love a woman who doesn't love me?
He used her and deserted her,
your darling Tristan.
Alfred, don't. Please.
I loved her!
I love her still.
He stole her from me.
If you want to know the truth...
he stole her from Samuel
before the war.
God help me, I'll kill you.
Here.
Read your darling Tristan's letter.
You deserve to be happy.
Late that night we found
the Colonel on the floor...
beside a cold fire.
He could not move.
His hair turned white overnight...
and he became an old man.
And after that,
Tristan sent no more letters.
As the years passed by...
we would hear that someone
had seen him on a ship...
going up some river
no white man had gone up before.
Stories came to us.
Strange stories.
And then, for years,
there was nothing.
He was lost to us.
That was all we knew.
But every year,
in the Moon of the Falling Leaves...
I would dream that the bear's voice
inside him had grown silent...
and that Tristan might again
come to live in the world.
But then the winter would come.
And then another spring.
And still he stayed away.
What the hell is he doing?
She's a mean old bitch,
but she's yours.
Welcome home.
Old man!
Where's Father?
He had a stroke some years ago.
He can't talk now.
Hello, Father.
He wants to celebrate.
I'm happy too.
Father, this is for you.
" Colonel William Ludlow,
from his son Tristan."
I didn't know.
These are boars' tusks,
made by a Javanese warrior.
He, too, was a great man.
I have other things for Mother
and Little lzzy and Susannah.
What is it?
Alfred and Miss Susannah...
were married several years ago.
Your brother's a congressman now.
They have a big, new place
in Helena.
It's as it should be.
Cattle prices dropped
after the war ended.
The Colonel don't seem to care.
He lost nearly everything he had.
We'll make it back...
on horses or something else
if we have to.
He's saying that your brother
voted for the Volstead Act.
Did he? You suggesting
I become a bootlegger?
Good money in bootlegging,
if you know what you're doing.
Screw the government.
Screw them.
Forever turned out
to be too long.
I know.
Here.
I don't want it.
They told me
that this was magic...
that whoever wore it
would be protected.
Keep it.
Don't you want to see Alfred?
It's probably better
that I don't.
Tell him hello...
and congratulations.
He likes you.
Welcome home.
Isabel?
I want you to have him.
I have something for you too.
I brought it back.
It's from lerapetra.
- That's in--
- Crete.
- Yeah.
- I know where it is.
Your father taught me
European history.
A little girl.
That's me, right?
Thank you.
Okay, we'll see you
in a few days.
Don't wait on me.
I'll be fine.
It was then that Tristan came
into the quiet heart...
of his life.
The bear inside him was sleeping.
It is hard to tell
of happiness.
Time goes by...
and we feel safe too soon.
- I heard the oddest news.
- Yes?
Yes.
Tristan...
is back.
Yes, I know.
You know?
How do you know?
I saw him.
He had the audacity
to come here just to see you?
He wanted to see you,
but thought you'd get upset.
He might be right.
What did he--
What did he say?
He said to say hello...
and congratulations.
Silly me.
He told you the news?
What do you think?
Come on.
It's perfectly absurd.
Marrying Isabel Two.
God, she's practically our sister.
She can't be more than,
what, 19?
Twenty.
I can't imagine what the hell
Decker is thinking of...
to allow this.
Perhaps he's thinking
of his daughter's happiness.
Happiness?
With Tristan?
You, of all people,
should know how impossible that is.
I'm not Isabel Two.
June 2, 1921.
Dear Tristan:
I was so pleased to hear
of your coming marriage.
Your father must be very happy.
Isabel Two is like
a daughter to him...
as she was named
after your own mother.
It seems as though it was always
meant to be, doesn't it?
Damnation.
Samuel Decker Ludlow.
Dearest Tristan:
Alfred and I were delighted
to hear of your son's birth.
We hoped for a child of our own,
but of that I despair.
I know Alfred thinks of you often.
I look forward to the day when we
all might see one another again.
Your son bears a proud
and noble name.
I know he will live up to it.
Please give my love
to Isabel Two...
and to your father
and everyone else.
Yours always, Susannah.
Evening, gentlemen.
Been meaning to talk to you
about one or two things.
By all means.
As you know perfectly well...
we handle the liquor around here.
Now, you've been
a small-time operator.
An amateur, frankly.
Lately, your shipments
have been getting a little fat...
and my patience
has been getting a little thin.
So the next time
you get in our way...
will be the last time.
Excuse me.
I appreciate it.
Perhaps you're wondering
why you're not dead already.
Because your brother
is Congressman Ludlow.
And that's it.
That's all.
Kenneth. Thomas.
Can't you just say hello?
- Hello, Alfred.
- Hello, Tristan.
- Who's this young man?
- This is Samuel.
She's beautiful.
Let me see.
- Who is this lady?
- I'm your Aunt Susannah.
I used to know your Uncle Samuel
who died in the war.
- You look like him.
- That's what Grandpa says.
He was very brave and very good.
Grandpa says that too.
Grandpa says I can have
Uncle Samuel's gun when I'm bigger.
Would you come and see it?
I'd love to.
Sometime.
- He's a fine boy.
- He is.
- Is Father well?
- As well as can be expected.
- I wish--
- Pardon the intrusion.
Excuse me.
We're ready for your speech now.
I'll be there in a minute.
Thank you.
- We'll meet again soon?
- I'd like that.
What's this?
Go and get Tynert.
I think you missed a bump, Stab.
Jesus!
Sir, we have information
that you're transporting goods...
in violation
of the Volstead Act.
If you mean a case of I rish whiskey
for my father, I am.
Give it up.
He'll be disappointed.
Hold him down.
Let's get out of here.
- There's an envelope in his pocket.
- Now.
My brother told you
to stay out of our way.
Put him in the car.
- I don't want to see him.
- Father--
I'm so very sorry.
Father won't see me, even now?
He blames the government
for Isabel's--
There's something
we have to talk about.
The officer you beat
almost died.
Now, everyone understands...
but you'll have to plead guilty...
serve 30 days.
And the one who shot his gun?
He was...
reprimanded.
- The O' Banions?
- Nothing.
You have to let it go.
It was a terrible, tragic accident.
Listen to me.
You let this go now.
You got in over your head.
I'll need a minute.
I'm so sorry.
We all loved her.
How are you?
I'm fine.
We never get to see you.
I gave a speech the other day.
- You did?
- Yes.
My first public engagement.
It was on the responsibilities
of women in--
It's good to see you.
I'm sorry.
I still sometimes dream...
that I'm the mother
of your children.
I wanted her to die.
Maybe I even wanted Samuel to die.
You had nothing to do
with Samuel's death.
And you had nothing to do
with Isabel's death.
Didn't I ?
Go home.
Go home to Alfred.
Where were you?
I just went out for a walk.
I needed a walk.
What are you doing home?
Your doctor rang,
said you missed your appointment.
I called home.
You weren't here. I --
I feel very tired.
I'm going to bed.
You have won her.
I am bringing her home.
Alfred.
I followed all the rules:
man's and God's.
And you--
You followed none.
And they all loved you more.
Samuel, Father...
and even my own wife.
I'd like a moment
alone with her.
When Samuel died--
When Samuel died, I cursed God.
Did I damn everybody around me
as well as myself?
You are not damned.
I won't allow that.
You're not damned!
Samuel,
this is a gentleman's gun.
It's smaller,
but it's just as powerful.
That's what you want
when you grow up, isn't it? A gun.
Samuel, come here!
Run along now. Go with Pet.
Get him in the house.
He's a fine boy.
You know we're not here
to arrest you.
You take me to the woods
so my boy won't see.
I don't want my boy to see.
Let's get on with it.
- Father.
- Colonel Ludlow, sir.
What's going on here?
You don't have to be a genius to know
they'll come after you for this.
Yeah.
Yeah?
I want to ask you
to watch over my children.
Watch over Samuel.
Brother, it would be an honor.
How much I wanted
to take scalps...
but it was not my kill.
That night,
we buried the bodies...
and dumped the car in a deep pool
in the upper Missouri.
I remember when he was a boy...
I thought Tristan would never live
to be an old man.
I was wrong about that.
I was wrong about many things.
It was those who loved him most
who died young.
He was a rock
they broke themselves against...
however much
he tried to protect them.
But he had his honor...
and a long life...
and he saw his children grow...
and raise their own families.
Tristan died in 1963...
in the Moon of the Popping Trees.
He was last seen
up in the north country...
where the hunting was still good.
His grave is unmarked...
but it does not matter.
He had always lived
in the borderland anyway:
somewhere between this world
and the other.
It was a good death.