This film is dedicated
to the film industry
of a country that
no longer exist.
RED STAR
PRESENTS
LOCAL NEWS
27.6. 1 971
lnauguration of the
'Brotherhood-Unity Tunnel'
Who says that the forces
of nature
can be made
to work for man?
The skillful hands of our
builders have triumphed
once again over rocks
and stones,
thus linking the brotherly
regions of our socialist
homeland of Yugoslavia.
Comrade Djemal Bjedic
was greeted before guests
from all over the Republic,
by the pioneer youth group
singing our favorite song:
With Marshall Tito,
our heroic son,
even the Devil will
admit we have won...
Every tunnel symbolizes both
our path and the light
at its end. The people of
Bosnia and Herzegovina
set out on that path on
this very day 30 years ago,
on J uly 27, 1 941 ,
and have never veered.
Comrade Djemal spoke
to the zealous workers
who made this tunnel possible.
He promised to transmit
their warm greetings
to comrade Tito.
PRETTY VlLLAGE
PRETTY FLAME
BOSNlA, 1 980
TWO BEST FRlEND,
MUSLlM & SERB
Milan, let's go inside.
-Not me.
There's an ogre asleep
inside. -ls that the devil?
Yes. -He's asleep?
-lf he wakes up,
he'll eat up the village
and set the houses on fire.
Halil, l'd better
take Grandma's knife.
Forget the knife. l'll
take my Grandma's gun.
l know where she hides it.
-Let's go. We'll come back
when we're better armed.
-Better not wake him now.
Starring:
BELGRADE, 1 994
MlLlTARY HOSPlTAL
lnhale, inhale!
BOSNlA, 1 992
THE FlRST DAY OF WAR
ls there gonna be a war?
-Yes, there will.
Watch this, see
what Jordan's doing!
Come on, Yankee! Are you
trying to fascinate chickens?
Watch out for Magic!
Damn you.
Twelve to ten.
No hard feelings, Jordan!
What temper!
What's wrong?
-Why'd you throw the ball?
Fuck off... -Listen,
in basketball
it's breathing that counts...
-Stop the bullshit, please...
...you have to inhale
then shoot,
then shoot again...
Got it? Have a seat.
That asshole could've
fixed this chair.
You know everything,
l suppose.
Goodness, they've gone
crazy in Sarajevo.
Killed a man at a wedding.
Screw the newspapers
from Serbia!
Why don't you read ours?
-lt's too big.
Like a sheet...
l can't hold it.
Then spread it on the ground,
kneel and read!
Right, it's good
for Muslim prayers.
Shut up and drink!
What do you think,
will there be war?
Yes, there will!
Cheers! -Cheers!
How can we fight if
we're drunk? -J ust fine!
We'll be braver.
lf there's enough brandy
maybe we won't even fight!
-Why should we fight?
Fine, we won't fight.
l'm still going to
take your money!
Here, l've got Kraut, Croat,
Serb, which do you want?
What do you think? -Serbian!
-You bet, my Muslim friend!
Whatever you say. Let's hear.
-Third and fifth odd.
Third... and...
How much is seven and six?
-Ask the teacher!
Now we're even! -What do you
mean, even? -Even!
Look at this!
Sloba, just listen!
When he was skinning me
l played to the end.
Well, you'll get your chance
to skin him, too!
Hi there, folks.
Taking a rest? -A little.
Sloba.
-Hi, Nazim!
Where you off to? -To Hajra
and my brother-in-law's
in Tuzla, so here are the
keys. -Keys to what?
The house. Keep an eye on it,
will you?
We've known
each other so long.
The flowers should be
watered, too. -Quiet!
My poor geraniums.
l feel uncomfortable.
Something might happen!
Nothing will happen.
J ust drop by when you can!
How come you've got so much
stuff, like you're moving?
No, these are for my
sister in Tuzla.
Well, then, l'll be off.
-Go on.
All the best, Nazim!
Hey, l'm not moving...
honest.
Come back... one day.
You must have been really
bad to get beaten up so much.
Honey! Daddy's at the other
end of the hall. Let's hurry.
Say 'hi' from me!
Come on, please, hurry.
-The man's a looney!
Come out of there,
l said we're going.
Did they beat Daddy up
like that, too?
Cut the crap!
Let's go. Now!
Answer it, it's for you!
Hello, who's there!
Chamil!
ls that you?
Answer me!
Answer me, please!
Scram, it's for me.
Hello? -Chamil, is that you?
-Yes, ma'am.
ls Chamil in?
-Who?
He's here.
-Where is Chamil?!
He's busy right now,
chopping wood.
J ust a moment.
For you, Professor.
Brother-in-law!
This here is Paris.
-See my ducklings!
They say that war brings out
the best and the worst
in a man.
What's the best?
Who knows, Professor?
ln 1 91 3,
the Bulgars attacked,
in 1 91 3, the Serbs
beat them back...
Soldier, keep it down.
Buddy, maybe it's for you.
Aloha. ls that you, kitten?
l'm gonna ram it to you,
break you in two.
Soldier, keep it down.
Hey, quiet!
Hello? Sloba?
He comes and goes.
Hey, come help
load this!
Want to buy a TV for your
barn, 63 cm screen...
Piss of!
-Cool it!
The ladies have started
dying easter eggs...
who's gonna take care
of what's between my legs?
Bro'! Look at what
the Swedes drive!
lt can pull a plow
and go to town!
Wait! ls this the one l
scratched with a fork?
Listen, if there's any
trouble, he's mine!
Understand! Be sure to change
the oil! Understand!
And don't drive over
potholes! Understand!
l'll be damned if
you understand!
Aha! You do understand.
Take this.
Christ is resurrected!
-Truly resurrected!
Yo, bro'! ... lt's mine!
Hello, George, l need
a warehouse in Belgrade.
l've got washing
machines, TVs...
This roadhouse hasn't been
touched by the war.
What war, man, this is like
'Frankfurt-on-Mine'.
Chivas Royal,'Black and Decker
White', 'Johnny the Runner',
the collected works
of Jack Daniels.
Boy, do l feel
like shooting!
Want Uncle Velja to shoot one
over your sniveling head, eh?
J ust joking. Here's some
candy from Uncle Velja
to make everything better.
Hey there all you
Mighty Serbs!
l've got a great woman doctor
here who wants to meet
real Serbian heroes!
-Unload her!
But she only likes
the seriously wounded,
so let us know when
you qualify!
Don't touch him...
Don't!
Did you hear what he said?
Don't make me get up!
Get well so we can go back.
Go back.
l don't have anything else,
take this. -Don't, son.
l've got enough.
-Mom!
What's wrong?
What happened?
-Nothing.
Come on, Mom, forget it.
lf you need anything
go see Sloba, l told him...
-No! l won't go to Sloba's!
Why? What's he doing?
Mother, why are you
acting this way?
Excuse me, ma'am,
we were told that there's
a dangerous Muslim stronghold
right around here!
So, if you could just
confirm that information.
There's no one left here.
-Thanks for your kindness, ma'.
Buddy!
-After me, heroes!
When l die and
leave my body,
make me a suit
out of the flag!
Stay, just a little
bit more!
Who's the Serbian
champion? Brazil!
Look, they put it up
crooked...Halil, phooey!
Shit, they've got everything,
you'd think they were Swedes!
Hey, there's no rest for
the hard-working!
ls that TV for me? -No,
we're sending it back
to the Japanese for a refund,
the fan belt's stuck!
What're you staring at?
Want me to get you a drill?
Tell us, what's your
favorite movie?
'Streets of Fire'!
Lift a little. Not that
side, the other one.
A little more...
Now nail it.
l can see that's how it's
gonna be, you give the orders
and l do the work.
-Cut the baloney, nail it.
What've you done, man?
Raise the other side,
it's crooked again. -That's
it, l'm through hanging it!
Look what you did!
-What did l do? What?
See, it's fucked up! -Who's
gonna look at the sign?
Whoever comes to have his car
fixed will look at it!
He'll just look at it.
Who's gonna look?
-No one has to look.
Mom! Bring the brandy,
we're ready to roll!
Here's to your health,
boys, and lots of luck!
Cheers!
Say, isn't that sign
a bit crooked?
Mom, don't go and
spoil our premiere.
Here comes Sloba! -Remember
me when the money starts
pouring in, you bloody
capitalists! -Help yourself.
Here, we brought the beer.
Let's take their picture
before they get smashed!
What's wrong now? -Seems to me
the sign's a little crooked!
Sure as hell. -Come one,
take the damn picture.
But my artistic nature...
-Take the picture, please!
Fuck the art, just
pull the trigger.
Milan! Why'd you do that?
Go on, scram!
-Where?
You know that all this
is yours and mine now!
Did that bum Halil send
you to guard his house?
All right, Milan,
what's wrong?
Take it easy!
-Go away.
You screwed up, prick!
Who fired?
-l fired!
Who are you to be judge
and jury here?
ls that why you bear arms?
This'll get you a court
martial. You're finished!
He did it!
Arrest him!
Hush, hush...
Suck, suck...
What're you looking at!
-Humpty Dumpty.
Humpty Dumpty.
He's right, Captain. How can
they light a fire in this heat.
Humpty Dumpty.
Where did you fight,
damn it, in Disneyland?!
Humpty Dumpty.
Humpty bloody Dumpty
sat on the wall,
scratching his ball...
Hurry up, man! l've put
this shit on three times,
it keeps evaporating!
-One-one... This will do!
lt's fine. -Shit,
look at my hands, man!
Stick them up your ass...
Lauda!
Hi there, Nazim! -You'll be
a postman like your dad!
Get rid of that and come
into town for a beer!
Fuck off!
Humpty bloody Dumpty...
Hurry it up, Lauda!
Let's hear those
Belgrade assholes!
One, two, and a one,
two three.
Hit it, Lauda!
'You want to love, but
don't know how to kiss,
come on honey,
give me a little bit.'
Let's go, boys, no dawdling.
There's no rest
for the hard-working!
Shall we go into
the tunnel? -Not me!
Aunt Fanny was just
kidding. Follow me.
l wouldn't go see
that Ogre in the tunnel
for a barrel of beer.
Not for any money.
Did you see?
-No. Let's go up.
Do you boys have any money
for this mountain climbing?
We do. -J ust asking.
Say, what's your name?
Halil. -Come on, Halil,
how about a fill!
But Aunt Fanny, we just
want to have a peek.
You won't get far
from just peeking!
l don't want to!
-No shilly-shallying now.
Don't! Don't!
-Quiet, this is erotic!
Look, a real scout's winkie!
What are you doing,
you bumhead?!
How can l pick up
girls like this?
Look what you did!
-What'd l do?
l'll get you for this!
Now you'll see
how Musa skins a goat!
Musa can roll
my dick's overcoat!
'All of Yugoslavia's
dancing rock'n'roll,
while everything around us
is going down the hole...'
l'm going up! -Captain,
Mascot's screaming!
Fork, go get him.
Velja, too.
Veljaaa! -We're not deaf,
you moron!
You really have
a closet-phobia, Kid!
Want a bazooka to finish
it off? -What happened?
Nothing. The kid's just
leaving tracks.
Marko, let Uncle Velja give
you some candy.
You give me that little gun
and l'll give you some candy.
Take the kid out of here.
-Let's go, kid.
How'd l shoot?
-You did.
Milan, come and
see something.
Did you finish, Marko?
Go on, off with you!
SERBlA TO TOKYO
These are prisoners of war.
No one is to touch them.
ls that clear?
-Yes sir!
Look, a fresh Muslim.
They're reinforcing.
We should make
a counter attack.
Let's retreat, Milan
... like men.
You go first,
l'll follow.
Nice looking Muslim, young.
How old do you think he is?
Old enough.
Where's Sloba?
-ln the warehouse.
l'm so sorry
we couldn't find you.
What did they do to her?
A group of Muslims
attacked at night.
The bastards swam
across the Drina.
Went through the village
like wildfire. -Sloba!
We looked for you everywhere.
-Did you hear what l asked?
We buried her yesterday
next to your father.
Everything was done properly.
And we caught two Muslims
alive. -How did they kill her?
They said they were from
Halil's detachment.
While they could still talk.
So, you just think about
guarding his house again.
Hear?
l should have killed
you back then.
You can now
if you want to.
Hear?
War's a whore...
Where are you going with
that shovel? Are you crazy?
Do you speak English?
BOSNlA TO TOKYO
CHETNlK MAMA.
Why don't you
leave him alone?
l will, Professor.
For good.
And this here's New York!
Did you know that more
people live in New York
than all the Serbs
put together.
Although l never stole
anything in New York.
You're young,
there's still time.
There's a prophesy that says
just enough Serbs will be left
to stand under a pear tree.
-ln that case everyone else
will be standing under
a dandelion witj no crowding.
Thank heavens we're under
a pear tree right now.
Sumadinac!
Where's our cover?!
l'll get even of
l make it out!
Kid!
Get your fat ass
over here!
lt's stuck!
-Hold on, Professor!
Brother-in-law!
-Lie down and shut up!
l don't want my sister wasting
money on widow's weeds!
Run over here! Run!
Head down that way!
There's an abandoned tunnel!
Tunnel? -Yes, go hide inside!
Take the Professor.
Milan, how's Mascot?
-He's alive! Get going!
Professor, move your ass!
Move, motherfucker!
Get over here!
Are you nuts?
Run, the kid's had it! Run!
Little Chetnik!
lt won't hurt a bit.
You'll just go to sleep.
-l'll sleep on your sister,
on your mother...
We can't go any farther.
-Yes, we can.
Do you give up?
-Nope. -Someone has to.
You do it.
-You do it.
Hang on, bro'!
What if they're on
the other side?
l bet you 50 marks
they're not. -Too much.
What if a train comes along?
-Shut up! -Scared shitless?
Kurtalici was the name
of that village?
Who cares, moron,
get in there!
All that's missing here
is dead Chetniks.
Don't tempt the devil.
Those circumcised bastards
will screw us
if they sniff us out.
Where'd you get this
tunnel? -l don't know.
l never dared go
in it before.
Maybe now wasn't
the time, either.
Sumadinac, come in.
Do you hear me, damn it?
Where are you?
Answer me.
Come in, Sumadinac.
l'll have your Sumadinac
for breakfasr.
We're in the neighborhood.
How about some coffee?
Scared shitless, rats?
Dear Chetniks,
Chamil speaking.
We're not going to split up
now that the fun has started!
We will impregnate
your mothers!
Turn that shit off.
-Chetniiiks! ! !
Showtime, boys!
Now let's play hide-and-seek.
Chetniks hide first!
1 0, 9, 8...
Last one yo hide
will be my bride!
Come to play!
-No cheating!
Asshoooles!
Where are you,
bustards?
Damn peasants, sleeping as
on their Mother Goose bosoms.
l was the one with noble
hands before this shit.
Damn this tunnel and
whoever brought us here.
l'm the one who screwed up.
What can l do now?
-Nothing.
Knit us some socks
to ward off the cold.
Are you asking for
trouble, maybe?
Don't shoot, it's Speedy!
Bro', let's bet
30 marks he'll pass!
That's too much!
Up yours!
Damn them all to hell!
Did you see my home run!
l'm sopping wet,
is anyone thirsty?
Anyone got a stub?
Light up,
you'll feel better.
How'd you find us, Speedy?
-l couldn't miss a good party.
l heard you calling for
Mommy on the two-way.
When are the others
coming?
When they get around to it.
-Get around to it!?
Didn't you
call headquarters?
One question at a time.
First question, dummy.
ls anyone going to get us
out of this shit or not?
Well, guys...
What can l say?
Nothing.
Sumadinac! Gvozden here...
Yo, Chetties! The truck
driver's not bad.
We'll bury him
with the spare parts!
We've stuck our pricks
in a wasps' nest!
Let's make a strategy to
vanish out of here, Big Serbs!
Not a bad party,
eh, Doctor?
Damn it, the doctor!
l forgot about her!
Hold your fire!
Damn me to hell!
How could l forget!
Doctor! Doctor!
Fork, keep an eye
on the Muslims!
And you, don't lose
your cool! Enough!
l'm cool, Captain!
Don't rely on my English.
She said she made a mistake,
it was a misunderstanding...
Look, a Muslim visa. -She's
sorry she hid in my truck,
she knows she broke the law
and will be punished,
but she's asking us
to let her go.
Look, she's as freckled
as a turkey's egg.
She says she's sorry, eh?
You'll be sorrier
than you think!
Wait a minute, folks...
-What are you staring at?
Milk her for informations.
-She's skinny. Let's skin her.
She'll say we did it,
anyway.
Look, '7-1 1 '!
What's gotten into you?
-What're you doing?
Beating her. -She's resisting
a routine inspection.
No, you like other people's
things. Give that back.
Take my place for a while,
you two.
Look, she really is
a stinking journalist.
ls that how you always treat
women? -Only foreigners.
Did you every screw anything
outside your village?
Fuck off, man!
How they love spanking!
Let the whore go. Anyway,
if she stays with us, boys...
Laza, what was it l told you?
-We'll fill her with tadpoles.
Where the hell
are you going?
Damn stupid chick!
Bring her here!
My, what fluent English,
she understood everything!
Let's tie her up!
What's she dreaming about?
-America.
Say, do you think she has
freckles all over her body?
l'll bet you 20 marks
she has. -That's too much.
What are you staring at?
She's not for you,
she's cultured.
lt's nicer with culture.
-How about some respect.
Lift her up.
lt just slipped out.
Boys, this is all we have.
A liter and a half of water.
Professor, don't gulp that
water, we'll need it.
Speedy, you're in charge of
that. -Yes, sir, Comrade Tito.
Captain, what'd they teach
you at military school?
How long will 1 -1/2 liters
last for Snow White
and the Seven Dwarfs?
l'm not thirsty.
Go ahaead, make fun of me.
You drink like a sissy.
Damn it, like it's
your last! -God forbid!
Not coke, just water.
Stop that, idiot.
Don't waste water on her.
What are you, Mother Teresa?
-Yo, bro'!
Those stinking journalists
are to blame for this shit!
Damn it, after a year of war
without a scratch
and look at this crater now.
-You'll be fine.
You'll pickpocket with
your right hand.
l'll get even with her...
-Don't move!
What's she shitting about?
-She wants to help.
But you'll have to untie her.
lf she comes near me
l'll strangle her!
lf she starts for your cock,
shall l let her?
Well... l'll tear her
to bits!
Laza, slaughter this bitch!
-Too bad they didn't hit
your mouth, you wouldn't
bullshit so much!
Relax with some music.
Here's 'Helmut Khol's
Got a Beautiful Hole'!
lf l only had a healthy vein
like that! Tell the doctor...
Sure is nice when a man's
dreams come true.
His whole life he dreamed of
having a needle in his vein
round the clock, and look!
He made it!
lt's nice
when someone succeeds,
but it should be shared with
your friends, right Speedy?
What's that shit you're
saying?
J ust kidding, man!
Hey, soldier,
want some papaya?
Let's split, man.
Hold on, pal!
What's their problem?
-Their heads are screwed up!
Fuck them!
Have you heard the latest
news from the front?
The French have
conquered Paris!
Say, asshole,
what's your nationality?
l'm a junkie!
J unkie...
Thank heavens there's
no one to come visit us.
They visit me at night!
Hey, little friend...
Draw!
lf anyone's interested, we've
been here exactly 24 hours.
The guys outside
seem tired, too.
They're waiting for us to
get nervous and head out.
That's what l'd do,
if l were up there.
First, l'd
let'em get thirsty.
Let's ask, maybe they've
got trained commanders.
Oh Muslims!
Sorry to wake you, l just
wanted to tell you,
your makeup's a bit messy.
Leave her alone, Velja,
just play us a tune. -OK.
Do you have any favorite song,
Captain?... Wait a minute.
Fork! lt's your turn!
-l'll go with you, bro'.
No, you just sit there.
Enjoy in bloody commie song!
Ask for one of
our songs afterwards.
You don't like such
classics, anyway.
Fuck your 'red' classics!
This is their song.
After you'll hear ours,
then you figure out
which one is better.
And now: 'Top of the chops'
show time!
Here is the new
singing star,
formerly yours
and now ours, Marko!
Cry, baby, cry!
Don't worry about Marko.
Bakir's a slow hand
circumciser!
Go over to their side,
now! Go!
Now l'm gonna fuck the living
daylights out of them!
Come back, you idiot!
Bro'...
Bro'...?
-Laza!
They hit my hat!
Look! My hat.
l can walk by myself!
Come on, Laza, get up,
back to guard duty!
They hit my hat,
motherfuckers.
l'm cold, bro'.
l bet 500 marks that
you'll make it!
That's too much.
Too much...
Once again, history
is repeating itself.
Raging hordes of evil
have risen against
the entire Serbian people.
Croatian criminals,
foreign mercenaries, and
fanatics of Allah's Jihad,
just as they did 50 years
ago, they are attacking
the poorly armed Serbian
defenders who are heroically
holding their own
on this unfair battle...
Where are you going, bro'?
-l've got a job to do.
...their children will not be
the victims of Croatian
fascism, assisted by world
powers, with intentions
to draw a new map of Europe
and create a monster
with a foreboding name:
'The new world order!'
l said to myself,
no more!
They commit genocide over
the entire Serbian people,
and l sit by calmly,
damn their mercenary souls!
No more, buddy! Not another
German od Muslim soldier
will set foot here!
No more!
How's it up there in Sweden,
cold, eh?
But what a standard
of living!
Take the picture!
lf you came to take
pictures, then do it!
Damn you...
Come on, bro'-in-law!
l'll bet you 1 00...
it's not much!
Don't be stingy, Laza!
This is a senseless war!
The regime that is responsible
for the death of
our sons must go!
We need salvation,
our people need peace.
Peace!
Don't let your lives be
run by war profiteers!
They're cute.
-Who?
That chubby one
in the fur coat.
... love and tolerance!
No one can lie
to you anymore!
No lofty goal can justify
your futile sacrifice.
Soon you will start
lying to yourselves!
ln 1 941 the Kraut
aggressed...
Did we have a nice pee?
ln 1 945 the Serb
kicked his ass!
Love is the most important!
Give love a chance!
Can anyone in this
country sleep
while our youth is
in this senseless war?
Can you sleep soundly,
you, youth of Serbia...
Watch me slam-dunk!
Really, you should
be tied down.
The youth of Serbia
can sleep soundly now.
Some people think
we're headed wrong,
'cause we listen to records
and sing rock songs,
but deep inside
the battle's hot as hell,
and let me tell you
what l know quite well,
comrade Tito count on us!
What are you looking for,
Professor?
No one leaves anything
behind, them or us.
Forget the books, we'll read
after vacation's over!
lt's a shame
to throw them away.
Want me to read something?
You really profited from those
books. lf you'd taken a TV,
like others, where would
you plug it in?
Read. Better listen to you
than those pussies down there.
'We noticed it one night, when
we were just fooling around.
We noticed a village,
our cannon was staring at.
lt was still in flames.
And every night afterwards
at the same time, villages
were ablaze on the horizon.
We were surrounded by a great
circle of strange celebrations
going on in all those places
burning in front of us.
And the flames just rose
up and licked the clouds...'
Pretty villages are
pretty when they burn.
Ugly ones stay ugly,
even when they burn.
You would have been the best
poet among my students.
When you've been
behind bars for so long,
you come out
as well-read as Rambeau.
When l see such a fire
l always get thirsty.
What's the name of this
village? -Who gives a shit!
We set a place on fire and
don't even know its name.
We're killing each other
for a fistful of ashes.
lf you intellectuals
had been asked,
all of Serbia would
have gone to hell long ago.
OK, boys,
let's move out!
'One village in particular
looked very gay.
A few houses, at the bottom
of an ugly little valley,
you wouldn't notice during
the day. You can't imagine
what it looked like
at night, when it burned.
You would say...'
lt's all right, Professor...
lt's all right...
Velja, who would you sell
it to? -J ust practicing.
To stay in shape
for later.
Go ahead and practice.
Good morning, Chetniks!
lt's a nice day to die
and you're still asleep!
Good morning,
dear 'Chets'!
The draft here is
killing me! -Milan!
l'll give you this if you
give my Mercedes an overhaul.
What's the model?
-WHF FMT...
The Mercedes, dumbbell!
-600. -That's my specialty.
But don't blow it!
-Agreed.
Muslims, are you
still up there?
Sumadinac here.
Are you still alive, men?
Yes, we're alive!
Hello! Sumadinac you old
mongrel, where have you been?
Where are you?
ln a tunnel, two kilometers
east of... -Kurtalici!
Ask when the cavalry's
coming. -Sumadinac!
Men, what can l say, you'll
have to hold on for a while!
Good luck! -Maybe they
don't have any horses.
Sumadinac, old mongrel...
What an unique slime
you are,
...my friend.
We'd better fix that truck.
You'll end up
the tragic heroine
of someone else's news.
Translate that!
Closed. All good kids
are in bed asleep.
l'm going to tuck in
those two now!
Doctor, it's not a replay,
give me some in advance,
You'll see the bread
tomorrow.
Beg you pardon?
l'm extremely intolerant
towards such impudence!
Draw!
l always brought the dough,
what's wrong now?
Be a man! !
A man!
Nurse! Nurse!
Where are you, damn it?!
-Nurse!
Soldier, call the doctor!
Nurse!
You really screwed me up!
Milan, please!
So, General, want to look
nice for your funeral...
according to regulations?
That's what we got
in the army.
And l was a lucky bum, l'd
just got hooked on heroin
and socialized, when they
said: Go on home, soldier!
Heroin was dirt cheap in '89,
the year of 'dolce vita'.
Keep up the bullshit.
l'll get you out of this.
You're safer here with me than
in Belgrade with your junkies.
The army didn't tighten
you enough.
That army of Tito's was
a real traveling circus!
Miss Linel wants to film us,
make a story about us.
Milan, how about it?
No. -What filming?
Out of the question!
Why not? Let her shoot.
ln any case they shit on us
like we came
from Hitler's testicles.
Captain, let the kids
have their fun.
Let's be gentlemen...
-Shoot, freckle-face.
No way! ! Then they put
words in your mouth with...
what's it called
... editing,
they can make us look real
bad, sully us to hell!
My name is Speedy, l am
unreformed drug addict,
currently getting 'anti-drug
war group therapy',
son of an ex-colonel
of the ex-Yugoslav army
who was a lush... -What
are you saying, idiot?
Go ahead, Speedy, get it
all out, l'm next!
Tell them how you stole
hendicaped grannies'purses
in Germany. -Don't stick
your nose in my affairs!
l shit on your affairs!
Aren't you ashamed
to steal honestly earned
money? -Honestly?
You're fighting just to
earn another stripe,
damned communist!
-Velja...
if you don't stop, l'll shove
this down your throat!
Who are you to talk about
honesty, you bloody drivel!
Your great honesty, you were
always full of that shit.
Do you think, Mr. Captain,
that one single house we set
on fire, or they set on fire,
was honestly earned?
To hell it was!
lf it was honest, it wouldn't
be so easy to set them on fire.
As long as Tito stuffed
US dollars up your ass,
you blathered about
brotherhood and unity,
and smiled at each other.
And then the time came
to settle the score!
Fine, but why didn't
you do it earlier?
lnstead you jacked off for
50 years, drove fancy cars,
screwed the best girls, and
now when you can't get it up,
now you want to be honorable.
l shit on that honor of yours
and your whole honorable
screwed generation!
Fuck all of you...
honest suckers!
l'd shove your face in
if you weren't wounded!
lt's just a light wound.
Captain, he was just
joking. -Butt out!
Have it your own way,
mother-fuckers!
l want to say something
for the... NEWS!
l recently saw on TV...
Did you know, wretched girl,
that the Serbs are
the oldest nation?
When the Kraut and English
and American, 600 years ago,
were eating pork with
their fucking hands,
we had this,
and we'd gallantly... pick!
At the Serbian court
we ate with a fork
and the Kraut with...
his damn fingers!
Serbs...
the oldest nation!
lt was this fork that drove
us in here. lnto a cave.
Listen carefully!
You have no way out!
Come out and surrender
and you'll stay alive!
There's another
'honest' man.
l, Captain Mislimovic,
guarantee your lives.
Captain Muslimovic?
lf you remember, we were
in the barracks together.
Sergeant Maksimovic,
now captain. Remember?
l see we both got
promoted, Captain!
Shame on you, Captain!
How many burned villages
will get you another stripe?
Come on out,
you deserter!
You betrayed me!
Say, Gvozden, who's that?
-My brother-in-law.
Good morning, boys!
-Doctor, how's Speedy?
Who?
-How's Speedy?
Boys, the doctor can't
remember all of you!
Say, Doctor... do you remember
that Muslim over there?
He sure has rosy cheeks.
Son, our oath obliges us.
-l bet it does, tadpole.
Excuse me?
-Listen carefully!
lf Speedy doesn't make it,
that one won't either!
l'm not to blame, young man.
You and he are the same to me.
You're both screwed up and
you're in a foreign country,
so you might
choose your words.
l wish you a speedy recovery!
Doctor, it's a matter
of cultural differences!
Here's our benefactor!
Everything for our brave
boys! Pass these around.
Want 'Brut' or 'Kouros'?
Catch, pal!
You flinched, here it
is on the floor!
Nurse, he dropped
his present.
You'll pick it up
when you get better!
Doctor, here's a small
present for you.
Take care of our boys!
-Sloba, we're caring for them
like our very own! -They are
the future of Serbia!
ln 1 991 the Croats
attacked, one day soon
the Serbs will
beat them back!
Happy New Year, heroes!
Milan, that frigging
doctor's not to blame.
He might have been just like
you if they'd butchered
his mother. lnstead, she's
walking around Belgrade now,
and he was lucky enough
to stay the same
refined frigging doctor.
We can only envy him!
You and l and that kid over
there can only envy him!
Mustafa...
Sulejman...
l lost my little Muslim
friend, lbro.
God, it would be easier
if she wasn't here.
She reminds me of what l'll
miss when a bullet hits me.
l couldn't bang her
for a barrel of beer.
What about
a glass of water?
l'd stick it to her and you,
and even to crazy Fork.
Admir... Nazim...
-Near my house in Banja Luka
is a fountain.
lt has the coldest water.
That's all l think about.
l can picture every
single stone in it.
Stop the bullshit, Professor.
Don't remind me of the time
l stole a tank truck of beer
at the October Fest in Munich.
l got down under it and
drank it dry in three days.
Captain, tell them, we said
whoever talks about water
has to kneel on cartridges!
Go on, fatty, kneel.
lt's a mess,
totally screwed up.
But l'll fix it,
everything can be fixed,
right?
What good will it do if
you get it to work?
Sorry, just mouthing off.
When l was a kid, l thought
little people lived
under the hood
and made the car work.
Man, l've seen them
with my own eyes.
Do you think we'll make it
out of here alive?
Hold this.
l got you into this shit,
l'll get you out of it,
if it's the last thing
l do! Understand?
Safet... ldris...
Cow! -That's not
really a Muslim name.
Come kitty, kitty!
We've got to guess her
name! Lulabelle, Mary...
Maybe it's Muslims'.
-Enver!
That's a bull's name, idiot!
Barbie! Barbie! ! !
No milk today,
dear Chetniks...
Anyway, my mother put
beer in my bottle.
ls that 1 :0 for us,
or did it hit the goalpost?
l'm trying to force myself to
feel sorry for the poor guy,
but it won't work! We've gone
to hell... it won't work!
Keep on trying, Professor,
it might come.
ls it worth living when a man
starts feeling like that?
Whose team were you for
before the war?
Mostar's or Sarajevo's?
-l'm not into soccer.
You just get better, so they
don't even the score.
And l'll try to make
the winning goal.
Collecting liquid for
the radiator? Great idea.
Who's next?
Thanks, l had a beer five
days ago and that'll do.
Damn, you peed all over the
bottle we have to drink from.
lf you want to refresh
yourself, you take the best!
Coca Cola,
it's the real thing!
Great 'bouquet',
home-made?
Let me cross myself.
Have some.
Have some,
it's sugar-free.
l mean, diet Coke!
She loves it,
let's export it!
Now you're one of ours.
lf a Muslim comes,
just boom-boom.
Try it, imagine
a Muslim...
Muslims! !
What's up, little Chetnik?
lsn't your mouth dry?
Of course not, we got
spring water in the tunnel!
Where did you get it from?
From a mobile fountain!
-What's that, buddy?
What l used to refresh
your old lady with.
Professor, you're some
sophisticated comedian.
Well, Chetniks, soon
you'll be eating shit!
We didn't come here
to insult each other!
Hey, up there, know the one
about the Muslim girl
taking a monkey
for a walk in Sarajevo?
Come on, Chetnik, go for it!
-People asked her
where she got it. She said:
from UN forces.
They said, well, why didn't
you have an abortion?
One Muslim girl,
took a monkey, Chita...
Thanks, thanks...
One more, please! -Thanks,
you're a wanderfull audience!
The blond Muslim girl woke up
under a cow and looked
at the udder and said,
Serbs, you're still here...
You're still here!
You're still here...
Watch the birdie!
Fuck, you killed
my audience!
lt's wartime, buddy,
we're short on credit.
Here's something until
tomorrow. From my dead father.
A gold tick-tock!
ls that from a scout brigade?
-He got it from the army.
Give it here!
That's why we'll
lose the war.
30 years of service
for a snort of dope!
That's not right at all!
Doctor, what if l...?
You can't shoot up here!
Kids play here!
OK, buy a ticket! !
Are you still late?
-No, l got it this morning!
Great! -Why didn't
you say so?
When it started,
l was like born again!
Damn, what should we do
with this walkman?
He won't be needing it
anymore. lnternal bleeding.
Too bad,
he was a sweety.
Kill the bloody
Croats!
Zagreb, here we come!
Fuck off, zombie!
Thanks, boys, thanks!
Let's hear it!
Through the forests
and mountains
of our glorious land,
Partizan detachments carry
the splendor of battle!
That's great you got
the 'big M'.
All you needed was a baby
in the middle of this mess!
l'm stuffed up with
this tunnel.
Lisa, let's do it like
Romeo and J uliette
and they can film it
for a 'soap', eh?
Here, take some, this'll
make you go woof woof.
Dear Chetniks, we have
a great program for you:
The songs of your
youth and ours.
l used to love that song.
l still do.
Hurry up,
the bell's gonna ring.
Wait, look, 'Rocky ll'!
-Look, they're screwing.
Quiet, learn something.
-lt's gonna ring.
Don't worry, ma'am,
it's the long recess.
Hurry, the bell! -The postman
always rings twice.
Here it comes, air mail!
-No, send it by ship!
We inerrupt this program
for a special announcement
from the Central Committee:
Comrade Tito is dead...
Today, May 4, 1 980,
at 1 5:05, in Ljubljana,
the heart stopped beating
of the great son
of our nationalities
and minorities...
Why don't you cry?
How will we live without
our Comrade Tito?
l don't know.
You cry first.
l can't.
Muslims, are any of you
whores free for a slow dance?
Velja, don't fall for that
trick, they'll shoot!
Who cares, l lost my virginity
while this song was playing.
Travolta,
they'll kill you!
Naw...
Damned fool!
Tonight, if she's listening,
let her hear the pain
in the song l'm singing
for her ears alone,
let her carry with her
always in her heart,
the life she threw away...
What's wrong, you bums,
can't you do any better?
These legs have jumped
from the second floor
of the Hamburg Volksbank!
Now, that's better.
Say, Captain,
how'd l dance?
What'd you do,
Travolta?
l'm too emotional.
That song got to me,
it really hit me.
We continue with our
'Listeners' requests',
Here's hoping that the
Chetnik pig recovers soon.
And here's our
shared Hymn:
Hey Slovenes, the spirit of
our ancestors still lives...
Now you've got to
stand up, that's the custom!
And now since
we've had our fun,
we're sending you a broad
for your enjoyment!
Here comes a sex bomb!
Go to your own kind and
show them your love bites!
She must be full
of explosives!
What shell we do?
Tell them what
gentlemen we are!
Hello, Chetniks,
ladies' choice!
Why her?
She can barely walk, she
must be full of explosives!
And what if she isn't?
-We'll look like chickens!
Stop!
Mirjana... please stop,
l beg you!
Stop there!
Lady, stop, please!
Fuck, ma'am, stop!
Come over here!
Chill out, woman!
l can't, she's my teacher!
Come to me, baby,
come explode on me.
Come on, sweetie!
l can't!
Come to Uncle Velja,
l'll give you some candy.
J ust two more steps!
Someone has to!
Milan, please.
What a damned life.
Watch the birdie!
-Wait.
One, two, three, four...
Samir, l'll scalp you
like a Sitting Bull!
Tighten up your ranks,
they can't fit in!
Twelve, thirteen...
Color won't wait! -l have
two 'lost-in-action'!
What are you doing?
-Banging each other.
First he'll do it to me,
then l'll do it to him!
What? Get up! -Teacher, you're
against brotherhood and unity.
Come along children,
picture time!
ldiots, you would've
let that woman kill us.
Well, you won't!
NO!
lt's all right, Fork.
Take it easy.
You orthodox dogs, we send you
a pussy and you kill her!
We don't know what else
to do to amuse you!
You really
disappointed me.
She didn't explode,
damn us.
As soon as l get out l'll
light a candle for her.
And for Laza. -l didn't have
the guts, no one did.
You were the bravest.
l'm going home.
l've had enough.
That Fork's got
the brilliant idea.
l'm going home, bro'.
That's it.
l'm going home.
Enough's enough.
Well, l'll be off!
-Yap, closing up time.
l'm off!
Muslims...
we're closing the bar.
No more free drinks.
Captain, do you think
it's better to shoot
in the head or the heart?
-Get off my back!
l will... Milan, what
do you think, eh?
Don't ask me. You figure
it out, Velja.
Hey, who's going
to help me choose!
Well...
They're gone.
Where're you off to,
little Chetnik?
l'm going home.
-Have a nice trip, pilgrim!
Look at this. This is
General's from World War l.
lt's even got his phone
number in the memory,
but don't tell anyone.
Now this here is...
Brother-in-law!
ls that you?
What are you doing here?
-l've come along
to make sure you don't
bungle things and die.
l don't want my sister wasting
money on widow's weeds!
Let's go!
Buddy, come over here.
l can sense the Serbian
hero in you.
God be with you!
And with you!
God save the Serbs!
lt's showtime, folks!
Yo, bro'!
The man's gone.
They're still here!
-This hand's a dud.
They'll shoot again.
l'll wait for
the next deal.
You don't have to translate on
that shitty American any more.
She understood by herself,
but l'll be sorry,
if she doesn't write her
story... if there is a story.
And l've got what to say.
l walked to Comrade Tito's
funeral 350 kilometers on foot.
lt was on the News.
You find that funny?
Well, it is funny.
He was a smart bastard,
Comrade Tito.
He lied a lot... but we
all loved him.
350 kilometers on foot.
l was younger then.
That was just
a stroll walk for me.
Well, kids,
it's time to go.
There's no reason to wait.
The machine's as good as new.
Come, have some coffee!
-l'm not supposed to!
Come on, you know how much
we like soldiers.
Only gays are left in
Belgrade! -l shouldn't.
Come on! -These guys aren't
going anywhere! Let's dance!
Damn helmet. l stuck it over
here sometime last week!
Where are you?...
Warmer, hotter!
Anyone got some bullets to
spare, l'll give them back.
Milan, give this to my mother.
lf anyone gets out of this
shit, it'll be you!
Cut the bull, please!
-l've got a hunch, buddy!
Here you are, l found you!
No hard feelings,
guys, a hunch!
Stop the bullshit, we're going
to carry your fat carcass
and find you a nurse
with godzilla tits!
Now l'm ready.
When you come to my funeral
and see the miles of babes
crying for me,
you'll know who
Uncle Velja was...
His mother's fool!
...l gave candy
to each of them!
Well, l won't keep you
any longer.
Drop by to see me
when you've got time!
Real Hollywood slobbering!
This is worth living for.
At least a while longer!
l was just kidding.
So long!
Jesus Christ, you really
screwed me up!
You, bastard!
Uncle Velja has
a present for everybody!
Mom, don't look at
me like that.
Everything's been paid for,
l just lost the receipts!
Come here! J ust look at it!
The papers are clean,
they were laundered
with my jeans!
Take me for a spin!
-l don't have a license!
Take mine! -Velja,
why didn't you write?
Why should l, when you
knew l was fine!
Hey, did you finish
your freshman year?
Sophomore, bro! -So, soon
you'll be an archeologist!
But don't dig me up when
l kick the bucket!
Don't worry, we just
dig up works of art.
What am l, pulp,
you motherfucker?!
Sorry, Mama!
Here, punish yourself.
God, you've gotten
stronger!
That's the neighbor, she
must have seen you arive.
ls the student, Milos Kozic,
there? -Yes.
Now he's had it! Healthy,
and ignored his call-up twice,
motherfucker... Sorry, ma'am.
He's got to come with us!
Archeologist, we've got bones
too, but we bury them! -Yap!
You came at the right time,
l just got back from a trip.
A little bit of fresh air
will do me good.
Mom!
Kid! Take this,
careful how you drive.
The seat goes down on the
side, and her legs go up.
Sorry, Mom!
Let's get moving!
The sooner l leave,
the sooner l'll be back!
You'll see how great it is
in the army.
Jesus, how you conned me,
bastard, damn you!
Chetniks!
We're gonna make a delicatesse
out of you! Smoked Chetniks!
Don't let me down now!
Hear?
Let's go, Professor, please!
l'm ready, l found my helmet.
Are you breathing with
gills, Chetniks?
Good evening, Serbs.
And good night!
-Halil!
Where were you yesterday
at the soccer game?
We beat those guys
from Kurtalici 5: 1 !
l had to go get circumcised!
-Can you pee now?
Of course, why not!
-Let me see!
Take a good look.
Whoever has a longer one
will get a telegram!
The girls will die laughing
when they see you!
Who goes first?
You!
Third and fifth odd!
Luck's on your side, Milan!
Your turn!
-First and fifth odd!
How much is seven and six?
Ask the teacher!
l'll take the truck! You take
them out on the other side!
Wait, where are
you going? Wait!
l won't let you!
Come back! Nurse!
That's our artillery!
Gvozden, what are you doing?
Take them out the other side!
Let's not kiss good-bye!
With Marshall Tito,
our heroic son,
even the devil will
admit we have won,
with heads held high,
walk with a grin,
and keep our hand
firmly in a fist!
Now you'll meet
my brother-in-law.
Here we come, bro'!
Let's go!
l'll carry him!
Those are our boys,
they'll bury us in here!
l won't let you!
Nurse!
Do you give up?
-No!
What do you mean, no?
Here comes the
Serbian cavalry!
Milan!
So you went
into the tunnel?
l did!
Why'd you burn our garage?
-Why'd you slaughter my mother?
l didn't slaughter anyone!
l didn't set the garage
on fire, either!
Who did? That Ogre
from the tunnel, maybe?
Did the Ogre do it, Milan?
Do it.
You do it.
Do you give up?
-No way!
One of us has got to!
-You do it! -No, you do it!
What's up, Lauda!
You do it.
What a bloody mess!
You Ogre, you're some
hell of a whore!
We got nice and drunk,
didn't we?
But tell me mate...
will there be war?
What war, buddy?
RED STAR PRESENTS
04.07. 1 999
Who says the Bosnian war
destruction cannot be reapired
in record time? There is no
better gift at the threshold
of the 21 st century than
the 'Tunnel of Peace',
opened by our dear friends,
European and UN officials...