Emmanuelle B¨¦art
Gaspard Ulliel
Strayed
Andr¨¦ T¨¦chin¨¦
Why does it sound so fast?
What is this monster with this good appetite?
It's like the devil there
Yes,the devil who can take away kids
But why does he take away those kids?
Alright?
What's wrong with your eyes?
No,nothing,it's OK
I can wake your sister
When did it rain?
Long before,I've been watching
Mom
How are you doing?
I'll take you to the grassplot to play
I have to comb my hair first
Philip,could you see if there's anyone who can take us there?
Anyone who is as lost as we are?
If we have a map ,that'll be a lot easier
There are some villagers,but we have to pay them
I stole a bottle
Do you need a bottle?
Is there just a little room for me?
Sorry,no
Unless maybe at the back
No,I have to take the kids
That's impossible
But I really hope that you can take me!
Why not taking him?
Just like this,it will do
But everyone is like this
But I can't be like this all the time
Will we meet a lot of people like this on the road?
We must change our plan,
it's a long road
But hometown really upsets me
I'm quite satisfied with their arrangement for the fifteen days
You don't have to be upset
There's a corner ahead
It's a little far from the national highway
Look on your left
See if the baggages are falling down
Can I sleep now?
I need a cigarette
philip
Why getting so far?!
This is just a begining!
We have to get far away their field of vision!
Why do you take off your skirt?
I wanna pee
It doesn't matter
You can go inside yourself
A duck-peak cap
Can I order those animals?
This is fine
You are on the road alone?
Alone,yeah,it's a kind of saying
But your family doesn't know?
Yes,but if I died,they would be living a good life
You came from there?
Yes,I've been walking for the past ten days
This is not the end
What do you want?
Just as everybody does
And you?
We too,we wanna get out here and go to Paris
But Paris,is like a city
It'll break you
And then you will want to come back
You,talking like that
If we get through this village at night
it will be very dangerous
Why dangerous?
We should stay in the bosk
Good luck!
Where are you going?
To find a place to sleep
I want to go with him
Into the woods
Listen to me ,Mum
No,sit down
You remind us that we can't be like this any more
Go have a walk
For those things?
Do as I said
No,Mum,I'm really sorry
I said he could help us
He has a bosk
I'll be right back
Why have they all gone?
To find a place in the village for us to sleep
What are the places with the stars?
It's just that we are sleeping in the nature
Like animals?
Yes,like animals
Are you looking for me?
Yes,I don't know your name yet
How do I call you?
My name is Ewan
Any more questions?
Take me ,if you are leaving
If those planes come again...
I've been running too
You have to learn to be on your own!
You should do more exercises
But how to exercise?
This is  different
Will this fall down?Those Americans?
Did your mum agree ?
Obviously!
You'd better tell me
Because your mother has to know about these
What are you looking at?
You should make a change in your life
They are all over there
And then?
We stopped seeking this time
If I wanna seek,I will seek for a palace
But you'd better be careful,don't go directly
This will scare me?
Don't follow me any more
A bunch of freaks are coming to our country right away
Hold on!
Take it
This will tell you the time
But it's not for children
It's my dad's
It's from the Red Cross committee
You like it?
Thank you,I like it very much
What happened to your dad?
When the war has just started
He was in a loft
He fell down from the stairs
and was badly hurt
They wanted to find a man
But when they wanted it back
This will be stopped by the animals
We have corresponding methods
You don't wanna sleep?
There should be someone watching the fire
I can,I can't sleep now
You are not cold?
You are sitting so far away
How old are you?
Seventeen
When you are talking to me
you have to watch your words
I'm sorry ,but...
But I can't let people talk to me when I'm driving
Those people are driving me crazy
Be friendly,lady
If I sleep,I'll get my stuff
OK?
Are you sleeping?
No,it's nothing
Where are we going?
I haven't seen that man,where did he go?
He left,just like that
Why do you say so?
I don't wanna explain these
OK,let's go!
What time is it now?
Don't you have a watch?
I lost it
How? When?
I'm not sure
Maybe I lost it when I was running
But you should find it back
You should never waste money like this!
It looks like I'll never have the chance to find it back!
What can I do
since you tell me you've lost it
but you can't find it back,son!
OK,what do you wanna ask me?
Listen,if you lie to me like everybody else
We are going back to that road!
We are stronger!
This is more obvious
Where did you go?
I find a house
but it's a little far
The landlord is quite hospitable
He gave me lots of things
Check it out
Did you see a village by the corner?
A village that is slaughtered
Would you like something to eat?
He found a household
Have something
And take some for your sister
With his company,we set out
Emilia's husband left at the same time
He didn't sleep,but was still leading the way for us
It's all because of him that we slept so well last night
Let's take a rest here
Just over there
Do you have a pocket?
For the food? Yes
No
You come,and I'll look for it
Where are you going?
I'll be right back
This body has been here very long
The face has already got rottened
and moldy
I have no idea of what was on their mind when they were in trouble
OK,right there
Get in quickly
You just got in like this?
But it's always like this when you are outside
Mum
I'm scared of the wolves
Maybe it's what you felt last night
Don't worry ,we'll be here the whole summer
If there's wolves
Put me down
Oh,you don't have shoes
Let me take care of that
I've never seen such a beautiful house
I like here very much
What?
Oh,this is exactly the opposite
Maybe no one will ever feel Paris
Listen,do what you wanted to do
or you'll go back home
and when we need your help
we'll give you a call
Do you have a cigarette?
This is my last one
We can share if you don't mind
No,thanks,I'm OK
Don't you wanna look after the kids?
OK,maybe you have your reason,I'll be listening
I don't know how to say this
It's OK
Why would it be OK?
You must have questions if you know
What are you doing?! Get down!
He's really tough
Are you afraid?
No, I don't think so
I don't think this has anything to do with danger
that's it
Why don't you take a bath like he does?
This is generally for girls
Mum,what are you doing?
Nothing,I want a rest
I don't feel like going
Philippe chose a room,you too
What about me?
You sleep with me
This is really a big house
Yes
A big house
Mum
What?
I'm hungry
But I didn't take anything with me
Or you can let me stay and tell you a story?
No,thanks,I wanna be out
To find boys
Oh,this is hard as stone
No,just a little bit
We shouldn't be so unruly when we are hungry
But why cheese?
Because that's all we've found
We'll pass this
I'll be sorry this way
Don't be.
But if the kids don't wanna eat,we'll save it
Then you have it
and that's final
Um,this is all the same to me
I like here
Are we staying long?
We'll sleep here until we find another village
I wanna tell you that we can't quarter at the village
We should find a phone,immediatelly
We have to do this
But I don't have anything else to do
Take care of the kids on the road
We have to be like that
Don't talk about this in front of the kids
Just as always,the war has already started
He have a point
Not at all
It doesn't make any sense that the kids should protect them
Adaults should protect them,too
But adaults are different
They are not always that simple
It would be better if there's a bottle of wine
Good idea
What time is it now?
This is unbelievable,we can't say
I say it's six
Where did dad's watch go?
It's lost
It's lost on the road
When you are on your way back,you may find it
I don't understand
Pick some if you will
May I take a look at what you have picked?
Take it back
this is champine for the morning
This is champine for the morning
That'll be all right,too
Is this easily drunk?
What kind of wine is this?
You take it
Anything wrong?
Nothing
Yvan!
What are you doing there?
I'm waiting
Do you think he will be back?
Maybe not now
We should be good to the foreigners
and be faithful
He probably won't be back any more
Do you know what is the really rank between you?
We should be positive
What are you trying to say?
I feel cold here
I looked for trousers
but they are all the kids' size
Silly
Come on
Lean on me
Your heart is like my bed
Did you wanna cry just now?
On the road
I've been like this the whole night
Why are you afraid of telling me?
You don't have to be afraid
Yes
You know that you can tell me
There is nothing to be afraid of
No,nothing
I'll tell you next time
when we feel this again
Promise me
I'm tired
Where are we going?
I don't know where can we go
We have to find a place where we can rest
Give me
You wanna something to drink?
No,thanks
No,you have to drink
You too
Do you wanna know who came to the house?
Where is the village?
What shall we do?
Keep on going
German!
I'm very scared of these planes
Me too,I'm scared too
I'm also scared but I didn't tell you
Why didn't you say?
Nobody wants to be in a wasteland like this
I don't want to,either
Maybe we are afraid of the wolves
We can't have a day like that yet
It'll be OK if we are finished
Just take this as an exercise
More importantly,I don't wanna one thing leads to another
The safety problem?
I£¬I can't sleep under the stars
Did you go to the German's?
Yes,I borrowed it from the enemy
I've never seen these before
Here is safety pin
It will explode without this
What are you doing?
Nothing
Don't you forget
Where did you find this?
This is something for you
I'm asking you,Yvan
Are these stolen?
I pick them on the road
from someone that is still alive
Go back to your room
But I think I'll know more if I stay in here
At Paris
The army is under too much pressure to stay inside the city
Or it depends on the opinions from the capitol of France
Will leaving be better?
Are you uncomfortable?
What did you do to my stuff?
I put them away from the bed
you fell down last night
Did you take my clothes off?
No,it's billy,he took them off
You OK? Not that tired?
I'm OK
Do you always sleep like this?
Just as you know,I sleep easily
Maybe you'll think I'm falling down like a dead man
Did you lock my gun?
We'll stay later
OK,I'll get another plate
Then we can have dinner
Oh,it's a little weird
It's not fit at all
Go find a stool
This won't be too heavy for you
I don't wanna say yes!
When I'm thirteen,I'm already grown up
Is this a good cancellation?
Who else wanna come?
A great man who you don't know
Everybody is interested in this
Why did you finish the wine?
I'll go look for it.
Tell me that you are not oppose of answering me.
Why you cut your hair like this?
This is because it will make me feel more comfortable.
Where is my gun?
When u leave the house I will give it back to you.
What else you need to say?
Give me.
Mom, I want jam.
We already finish eating, that was the last bottle.
You sit over there.
Okay
eat slowly
Isn't there someone else thats coming?
We have no responsibility on that small car right?
The chicken is good.
I like the one you cook.
This doesn't belong here.
One more time.I'm reporting a news about a missing kid.
We need this news
Outstand its purpose
Listen first
We found four kids, number 39
This is little monick tesi 's only life
-H-E-I-N-H-Y
When he got lost he is only 10 . he borned at Gerkabi
He is missing on Sunday May 17th
During a war time
He was with his father at that time
We didn't pay attention on the kid that time
We hope there's someone with him
And took him back to the capital
The kid was missing for around four years
He has gold hair
Blue eyes
Wear glasses
Straight teeth
No other outstanding information
But he wears a headphone
And a necklace
This is the kid we are looking for, number 39
Now is the kid number 40
This is little shark. born in okando
You see i caught three fishes
This is the forgivenss that gave to us for the famine
You are really a great engineer!
What you mean by engineer?
It's a very smart person
Why you think they are smart?
Why you think this way?
Beacuse i think you will pass the test,Evonnue
This is no joke right?
I will give some commands then you can protect them.
I'm tough enough to handle myself
It's a helping hand
No. i will hlp you
That's great
Why?
Why you ask why? why, no reason.
Because I am afraid of death
I hope everybody lives
Because i am a civilized person
So then there is no other need?
After that where are you planning to go?
I only want a garden
What kind of garden?
You go out, i'm busy
I want a clean house
And open some can
I could also comfort kids
I said that already,Evonnue
After you leave i will come back
Is all girls like this?
But to us it's like this
But I will let the kids recognize these
But I don't understand you
Reseach is a normal way to protect self
But you are not a law
But maybe it's you!
You are a king then i have to hide in the garden
This is not the conditions
These are the disagreement conditions
You can leave
You are too nervous!
But can you give me back my gun?
I need to take it back
Listen,Evonnue
I don't need to look after the door for you
This is your decision
If you want then you could leave
If you want to live with us
You have to follow our living rules, understand?
I don't understand the same thing as yours
Can you clearly finish the left over information?
I wish you could stay too
But the kids like you very much
They just say they want to eat the fish together
I help you is anything
Are you interested in me?
Yeah, your personality
It's hard for me to straight this
You too?
Yeah, me too
Do you have cigarette?
Yeah, in my pant's pocket you can get it yourself
I'll be back soon
He only bring back these this time?
I cannt fall asleep ,i want find out what
I don't know what this symbol means
These groups are all in sake of earning living
Listen to his writing
Over there it let me understand, what women needs
It's not of love
It's of power, to dominate those powers
Stop, mother
I dont interset in that
Feels like the first thing....
I'm not taking about that
It's when we are alive we need to understand
You are going to sleep?
You know that as a same problem, there is no need of having a different idea
Do you think this is a law?
There is no investigation
This is blank,did you find it?
I'm just telling you
This is mighty
When I am alone
I want to sleep with you
Where is your mother?
They all went out
I'll go look for them
I only want to stay with you
There will be no setback to mother right here
If i am not here
She will feel very comfortable
You too
Will you feel cheerful?
It's not like that
Look
What are still doing?
What did you do in the streets?
Then that's it
Then i am like that too
That's it
This need to change, i will give you guys a explanation
Like the others, don't know what to explain
We will continue living like this
We will go crazy
Look i can the root for the futuer
Near to life
I will if you talk
Evonnue my prince
Marry me
Ah~~wait,this is suffering
What are you doing! why are you walking all over?
Don't be like this!
I want marry with evonnue
A kid shouldn't be doing this!
Yes, why don't you  listen to me?
I don't want to tell!
Your not going to know, go
I've find her
Didn't take good care of your sister
What is your mother doing?
She falls asleep
Don't tell her about nonsence
Do you feel confuse?
No, this is nothing
Confusing
We need to face a lot like this in Paris
If it was a short time for you guys to get there
If you guys believe the women in the streets
Shit
Evounne
Can I go with you?
No problem
How far?
Around six
Maybe we will have some luck
I want to ask
How do you choose locations?
Like a pedestrian
Should have to walk in the "tree branch root"
After that we can find the crack on the hole
Ok start hurry up
I found something
Now I can eat what ever i want
What is this
One squrrel
How you do that?
Your parents are from country side?
I dont have parents
You mean they all dead?
Did I said that?
I dont like to remind them
When someone ask a question like this
This way I will be very stupid
The way you talk make u lost your faith
Hehe when I been with u i found faith
I hope so
Ok tell me the truth that night
Your mom hide my pistol away
Did you see it?
Yes but she doesnt want me to say it
Really?
You remmeber that thing found in the garden
My answer is yes
Wait
Ok I will give u back
You give me back the thing
You agree?
I can't answer you right now
Are you my friend ? yes or no?
Sure you are friend but i cant accpet that
What is that mean?
If I have friend i will do anything for him
His voice is like wind
How old are you?
13 years old
Do thing like kid
All adlut are like that
Your mom told me  you like me so much
That is one of reason i going to do that
I never seen a person like you
I wll be back
What you hiding?
I didnt hide anything
You wait there for long time?
Why you didnt with my bro?
Dont ask like that he didnt even clean that up
This is not true
Ok its on this road
Right there
Why I need to agree about this
You look at me
I look at you
They got skill to be that far
I like the way i used to be
You want one?
Ok I want some
This is very good for summer
My mom take care of u
I will teach u alot
There wont be the same
Have you think of my quality
A little
You need to think about what i said
I cant sleep i want to make a good family
Yes, I need to let u take care of it
You need work out
Mom! Did u see me?
No I am looking at u
Nothing to eat
I eat in the corner
I need to explain something
I am not stay here for the same time
To use you as tool
Something can make pain on me
What elsa you like to talk about it
I can help u laying down
Sure , this is very serious?
No, this is not important but.
I used to take care some bussniess from some french
They got alot problem
They are oppsite
This is easy
I never been to school
This all happened in sudden
You must go to school?
What about your parents
I want to rid of it
This make me piss and stress
We also have nothing to eat, i go fish
Mom
What happened?
I got something to tell you
I want to go  wasile
Stop thoes thinking
I am good
I really good
You will be fine if you see your sister at 7am at morning
I feel werid
You said you want get it back
Where is she?
This is very big stress
Have been visited long ago
She meet ikuan?
He went to be with her. we got nothing to eat
I am so happy that you heard alot thong from them
Its not good for u
It sounds logical , but diffcult
I never said that before
You didnt say it but you did it
Or I made a mistake
I think you know what i was saying
I wont control in your hand
Do thing what you want to do
What I want?
If all I done is for friendly
I can feel anyone
Anything that i can eat
Yes I left some chicken meat at here
You didnt eat at all?
Take a disk, sit down make yourself comfortable
No,no  this one
Let me give u a dish
Up to u
I heard a bomb
I am not sure if its on far away
I am scare
I didnt hear anything
Boomb is the benifit of germany
Keep it up
If you want to hide
They are nothing
Want more? no i am drink enough tonight
Once me and my guy were together
Eat some english fruit
Do you know?
No
Its a thing that from outside
He doesnt want to stay paris
You need to cut that into half and put on fire
But you need check it often
Put more thing on it ,i will  be good
You know him so well
Yes its my friend
I can have or not I dont care
You think its bad to know him
No I am interst it
You also intersting on me?
Can u pretend to be my wife?
Are you crazy?
The skillful cooking make u think of marriage?
To be your wife
I think so
We can live like a marryied couple
If there are no other , what will happened
I want go home
Where you going
I want to sleep
No you sit down with me
I know you dont want to
But I wont talk like u
I dont want it this way
I dont know what to say
Its ok but this is u so drink with me
You can just follow I will wait for you
Why I just found out now
Why dont u talk to me?
Becuase I going to paris
This is so confuse
I cant bring you with me
Becuase mom doesnt like it
Inside the school is a doctor
Many many
You go check the school
Same as u you will be there
I dont know why
LeLe didnt get sick
House is right there , it has a black/white TV
Other people will back
After that we coule see
We feel proud of this
We didnt see thoes item
Bill you see the ridio
It hided
Where?
I dont know
This is the same thing
It wont be there
Calm down
Maybe he is too hot
Slow down
Watchout
You makes some nasty sound
But it is not here
You scared him away
Arhh I saw it
Bill you fooling around with me
Get me out of here
Get me out of here bill
-Y-Z
You knwo this y becuase i told u that is your name
Ok good
Enough
What is your name?
Me?
Its my father's last name
If I am not marry
My name is liek this
The last letter o - di - le
You want to write it?
Its the first time
I never touched it
Wait wait
If I dont chase u you will get lost
I am a legal son
In this 6 month , things will happens
Still have 6 month before the war ends
But before this war?
What you knew?
Its not a thing
If I can tell then I know what is it
Once upon time
This is a good chance to learn
Please teach me more
Like this
Ok
Hey kidz
Its so hot in here
There will be a thunderstorm soon
Can I ride on this horse
You want come up
Mom!
Where you guys from
Sesan
295 miles away
They are from country side
Did you finish lunch?
Yes I am listning
I am Shenci he is Mowo
Childrens are so pretty
There are 4 children at my home
15 years old
Who else lives here
No its not my home
Whose house is this
Who is the owner of house
You live here by your self?
I am with my children as you can see
Can we have some
Beer or water
Give water to horse , that is enough
Take look of your sister
You are friendly  dont be scare
Go down
What should we do
If its bad people then we cant let them stay
Becareful tonight
This is fun
Dotn take care of this
Fuck
2 people went into the house
2 soldiers
Your mom lets them in?
This is not her opinion
She told me they won't stand long
How to live ? we are soliders
But they need to stay
Only 2 pepele at their side
How can u let your mom with them there in there
I am looking for you
Why we come here for?
I dont know
Lets check together
Dont just stand there
What is that mean when they said they saw a pain
In order to protect your life you need to take care of them
One woman and 2 soldiers are inside the house.
I gonna take shower
Whose room is this?
This is my son's
You didnt see him becuase he never sleep at day time.
I am sorry ,i will treat here as my home.
Thank for give me this place
I found something in other room
Onine one mini watch
Marks 1952 year
I found death inside of there stuff
Do you know?
The phone line got destory
I dont know what are you talk about
I am taking to you Mrs.
The place with u
There is a disaster usually
I think you are right
Dead people
Did you see
You want some?
Not even a little
When you decide to go to Paris
The government start this war
If I bring my child i wont feel regret
I will teach them how to read , other stuff are useless now.
Where we going
Lets check it up
Only sister inside
They took my stuff.
Didn't u see where the thing?
Yes
This is fear.
Now I cant use my brian to think of any.
I got nothing
I got no clue
You don't know what happened?
I got to go
you and your mom...
shoulder be stronger
remember this!
What are you doing?
Our father hope that we are stronger
That we should realize the outside world clearly
Let me be a powerful man
Be a real frenchman
Reject the seductions
Amen
Stop! This doesn't work
Listen to me
Stop
They will defense themselves
You should face what i said
Not all the people behave like you
Don't do that
Check up the time
I'm gonna have a rest,
then we get together here again
It's 13:35 now
I wanna take a walk
It's too sensitive
You made me like this
We are both lost
Why?
May try it often
Are you allright?
Didn't you kill them all?
I don't mean to hurt you
but you have realized your confidence
You should know how to fight back
if somebody like him moves in
I don't want to know
They try to find the gun
But I hide it, then There's no conflict
but I have no other choice
There is always an odd idea in my head
You don't face the problem by yourself
We should never stay here anymore
Tell your mom that we are going to leave
Don't miss anything
This is very necessary to me
Why you like to keep those bottles?
You should share it with us
They are from your area
It seems not
Came here alone, then go to Duca
Open it, taste it
We climbed on the truck
No enough room for everyone
Then when we got there
Dismiss all of them
No one knows it, no one get the property
Together with Robert
To that place 250km far away
Yvan
We are not clear why we stay here tonight
It's ok even if we changed
There will be this kind of lucky
Never mind, It must be Yvan who did this
He is usually not present
Why does he not be here?
Yvan
Couse he don't want to meet so many people
He don't like that
What's your job?
I run a winebar
near the coast of Nice
Oh, I don't know there
We used to spend holidays in Black Crist
My dad prefers to monntains
This is not a good manner ...
to judge Father like this
This is not correct
Couse I like to say  this
When will dad come back?
Maybe in May
Don't be crap
I want more
Finish the dishes first
Don't be wasting
Why doesn't he have dinner with us?
It's too late
Maybe he is sick
He has a little stage fright
What does it mean?
It means he doesn't like to
stay with a lot of people
But it's not necessay today
Have you been to school?
3 years
You didn't mention it before
Can I tell you this later?
I, a singer
What kind of?
Opera
Sometime I can hold it perfectly
But sometime not before the show
Can you sing for us?
NO, no, it's allright
I don't wanna sing at dinner time
I can sing before all the people
Why you think you are shy?
You said you have known Germany for 100 years?
Yes, and which disturbed me
Yes
Do something else
Why doesn't he come in?
It's desolate outside
You insist to following us?
It's very natural
Really?
Why?
He told me your first thing to do
is reading and writing
And there was another reason before
I can't tell them stories with good imagination
You are a good mother
Absolutely, but you made it at last
good
Or it's time to say "Goodbye"
Sorry, I shouldn't come to bother you
But we are still in jet lag
Is this the first time for you being here?
We stay here to avoid ...
the dangrous animals
Animals have their habits
But it's deceptive
It doesn't mean this is fire
If we insist, it's ok
But if not, it will be different
And me, I can't say it to men
I can't deceive others
I have no friends like others
Yes, very little
And the condition prohibits
I don't know
Get in
Telephone
There is your platform
My time passed by
since I came here
I began to take care someone
Maybe for myself
I am a little selfish
Why not with your husband?
He was shot at the beginning of the war
That day I lost my bright future
And it will never come back again
I saw a black tree
A white document said to me
I am not like before
I am closer, for my husband
He is there, and told me that
If there isn't that consign
I will not see the bright for a long time
I understand
Have a rest
Maybe you know my reason
and think i am reasonable
Sure
This is what I should do
Here
My whole family
You was not on it
I was taking the picture
Sorry, I should stay with you,
But I am so sleepy
And we get up early tomorrow morning
Maybe I will go home
Wait
Good luck
Really?
Give me a hug
What are you doing?
I wanna feel a woman
I have been long for this for a long time
But is it too fast?
Don't say that
You understand me?
Why do you do that?
Is this what I know?
I don't know
Shall I stop?
Don't you want to come back now?
I don't want to see them, but they are leaving
I just stay here today
They told me the war was end
I know this
Do you have any plan?
Since you don't want to leave
Yes, it's normal
You want to go where he stayed, and then Paris
Where else?
I am  hungry
I have no bread yet
and there is none of it
Foolish
And take your cooking art with you
Send away the soldiers, ok?
Hello, Madame
Hello
Do you know him?
Yes or no?
This is our friend
My friend left the house
He want to take back 4 of them
At that time, a men dressing like him...
beat him with a rung
What are you thinking?
He opened a door at the corner
Is he the first man who came in the house?
No, he was hiding somewhere
But he has double guilts
Others has been awake to this
When we met this young man
We wrote a certificate
He can't leave here
We moved in from the outside
He saved us and found a house for us
How did he find it?
It's 23
Haven't you suspect her method?
No, the windows were all closed
How long have you been here?
I don't konw
Ok, we will record this
And the whole thing
We are considering this
To me, it was 14th of June
It's a pity that I have never
seen anything artificial
Thanks
Still the same time to here?
You can spend everyday like this
Look, this is Lulu, right?
It's not the time to play
Sit here
Lulu
Why not eat something?
I don't want to eat
Don't scratch
It's not there
Don't be so nervous
This place made me nervous
Together with you?
Can I talk to you ?
Can I go with you ?
No, you stay here
It will not take you long
It's about that boy we catched
Do you know his name?
I don't know
Don't you like him?
No
I have never liked him
That's it
Sorry, you have to stay here
This way
This is so strange to me
He insisted even after he was injured
He has a lot
Haven't he talk to you something?
Do we have a lot?
No
Immigration
He helped us in this way
Does this mean anything?
NO
I am sorry
This makes you hard to recall
How long will he be kept here?
He has no politic power now
He will be imprisoned for whole life
Do you want to see him?
When?
Tonight, No more details
If someone come, I will inform you
When can I see him?
There's no way to keep the prisoners
It won't take to certificate
Where do you want to come in from?
It's none of my business
you should find a survey
But if you have no ID
Need my accompanying?
NO
Ok, see you later
What are you doing  there?
Nothing
What did they said about Yvan?
Yes, he escaped from the prison sucessfully
We'd better never talk abou him
And he is far away
Where is your sister?
She is there
Three
Six
Four
Five
The End