Morning. In less than 48 hours, a man
his first trip to the moon bet ...
with the hope to land.
While tensions over the war
continue to escalate in Vietnam ...
the eyes of the world at Cape Kennedy
directed where they work round the clock ...
to Apollo 11 to prepare
before launch.
After a four-day journey through space,
astronauts Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin ...
planned to set foot on the moon,
late Sunday evening, July 20.
Quality over Quantity (QoQ) Releases
Love and Honor (2013)
Hey, Joiner.
Is not it time for a snack?
What did he do now?
Seems that our friends again
have a surprise ready.
Handsome seen.
All right, thanks, Joiner.
Thank you, Joiner.
How does he do it anyway?
Tell Jane that she must stop her teachers
to poles and a surprise packet to send.
Shut up you ever?
- Make sure they Cheez Whiz sends.
Thanks, Joiner.
Come on, do you ever wonder story.
- Where was I again?
You were in the ferris wheel with Miss Ohio, in a
exciting satin dress, tiara, the whole rigmarole.
Come on now.
- Yes, of course.
We're in 't rad, she looks at me,
I look at her, and so.
Just as we did above ...
that bastard falls silent.
So what, they always fall silent.
To let people off and boarding.
No, I mean really stop.
A gear broken or something.
Here I am, with Miss Ohio,
at the top.
Looking down at all the lights down.
An open sky above us.
A crowd of people below.
Yes, tell more.
- She looks me straight in the eyes.
And it feels very intensely.
Before I know, her scarf, does her
dress and her hands all over my body.
That's it.
I'm home a thousand times
in a wheel before.
Why me never.
- Of course.
They were your own hands on your body.
Not funny, not laugh.
What is the purpose of nightwatchman?
The claymore's are drawn. These will be
deal with creeps walking around.
HQ, here Jolly-2.
We'd like a large pepperoni pizza
with extra cheese and do it fast, you want.
Come on. That was funny.
Not even a smile?
Wright, would you just shut up once.
HQ, here Jolly-2.
Requests reinforcement.
We are under fire.
I'm out of ammo.
Ammo.
Okay, guys?
- It was about time.
Stay awake.
We now  countries.
LZ is secure.
- Hurry up.
Hold on, gonna be okay.
Doc, you really should go.
On the count of three,
a ... two ...
Okay buddy?
- All good.
Suddenly arrested.
Bulletproof? Really.
What about Burns?
They transported him to Da Nang.
If he stabilized, he may go home.
And you?
Is it?
Oh, fuck.
Makes no sense.
Well, there were fewer letters and packages.
But she had her exams and final exams.
Michigan is a big change
from high school in Indiana, you know.
But this?
That's not Jane.
We had it all planned.
We had our plan.
You think there's someone else ...
- Do not say it.
I'm sorry for you, dude.
- What should I do now?
A new plan.
HONG KONG KAI TAK
INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT
Listen carefully.
You know how to do it,
but I'll say it anyway.
Everything you say and everything you do,
reflected in each of us ...
and our entire country.
So remember gentlemen,
get drunk, fall in love ...
whatever you want, but ...
a week from today, at 8:00
you can find no better return.
Is that clear?
I said, is that clear?
Dismissed.
Check it.
Well, first stop, Madam Whos. For a
price you get it gal, the drink and the room.
This is home.
- Whores and drink, that is him!
From there we distribute, we do
exploration and if the situation permits ...
as the chicks somewhere else much better,
we change places.
Joiner really need a professional.
Where is he?
- You mean Joiner?
Let's go find him.
- You guys go on, I find him so.
He is likely to call themselves
fools making.
I follow you immediately.
What are you planning?
- I'm going back to Jane to see.
Jane is gone.
You can not just take a plane back ...
in the middle of a war
because you miss your girl.
You have surely heard Johnson?
About a week to 8:00, I'm back.
Soldiers fly free.
- This is no joke, dude.
So close I came to my death.
An inch thick.
I have a second chance, and I'm really not
blow by a week in Hong Kong to fuck.
I get it already So ??you go in its place,
the rest of your life ruin.
Deserteer and you go for the ax.
That will forever be in your file.
I'm just a deserter
if I'm not back in time.
You were dumped.
This is not fun and that touches you.
I am sorry But believe me when I tell you,
there are a million other girls ...
with all the same limb
in all the same places.
But there is only one Jane.
It's just a girl.
A girl, I'm sorry but I have to
say it again, because it does not penetrate ...
no longer wants to be with you.
Until next week.
Come here.
T minus 15 seconds.
Control to the cockpit.
Twelve ... eleven ... ten ...
Mark my words.
You'll never forget where you were
like those guys on the moon.
Yes.
Two ... a ... zero.
DEPARTING FLIGHTS
Can I sit at the window?
What are you doing here?
- Soldiers fly free.
I really mean it, you should get off the plane.
- I can not my buddy in the lurch.
Not to mention that if someone accomplish this
gets and it can tell, I 't have.
This is not a stunt.
- They're going to get what when they hear this.
Do you thirsty? I'm thirsty.
Stop it.
Every day there is a,
only if you survive it.
So many nights in ambush,
not knowing who attacks ...
not knowing if it's your last night.
If I had known that it would be so ...
Here, among the clouds, with two
of the most beautiful angels I ever saw.
Then there was Uncle Sam
allowed to keep all my medals.
This is more than sufficient to pay.
Duty calls.
We'll talk more later.
- Good.
I must say, Wright,
You're a slick.
Oh, it was nothing, really.
I made just for my buddy.
He thought it might be like
with two stewardesses.
You're welcome, really.
- She was scared.
The blonde or brunette?
Jane.
It was easier for her to
so to do, than to worry ...
I may or may not come back alive.
If I let her see that I'm okay,
that nothing will happen to me ...
turns them on.
I just want you to be prepared ...
- We promised each other ...
that we were not officially engaged
until I was back. We wanted 't risk it.
But ...
I think they might need.
Something to hold on to it.
That together we can strongholds.
I'm gonna ask her to marry.
That's awesome, dude.
Great idea.
Ladies and gentlemen, Apollo 11 is out
the atmosphere and all systems are good.
I know also the crew good luck
wishes for their historic journey to the moon.
Look at that statue.
I call it the stone dick.
Summarize your guy? Because it's just ...
- Yeah, right. I take him!
How you doing, sweetheart?
A dinner will not work right?
It would be the next right.
- Fuck you, baby killer.
Pardon?
Never mind.
What happened to,
thanks for your service to the fatherland.
Hey, big guy.
Can we?
Are you sure you're good here?
This is 215 Four Street.
I know the address from outside.
Handsome, Meredith.
Students should know that if they
deposit their funds at the Continental Bank ...
that their money into financing the war.
May I give it up?
- Just do it.
Guys?
If you are recruiting,
then you are in the wrong place.
No, I'm looking for Jane.
I'm sorry, this is not Jane.
That's quite suddenly.
Well then.
Is it too spicy or?
Daltons.
Hi there, Janie.
Oh, my God.
Surprise.
What have I missed it.
- I was so worried about you.
I can not believe I got you in my arms.
- Dalton, what's going on?
I thought you had to be in Vietnam?
Damn it!
This always happens now.
I'm ten minutes away and miss anything?
Hello there. Private First Class,
Mickey Wright, and my buddy Dalton Joiner.
And who is this lovely lady?
I'm Candace.
Pleasant introduction, soldier.
Joiner soldier in Vietnam came
Juniper to see.
Or Jane, depending on who you ask t.
Juniper?
Should not you two go somewhere else?
As the bed in?
I can not believe
Juniper 's boyfriend.
In Vietnam than later.
Please advise, you see two guys in army uniforms
and you think that we are the enemy or something, right?
No, not at all.
We know that you have been fooled by ...
Nixon, Kissinger, Westmoreland,
like the rest of America.
It's not your fault that you are unskilled.
- Excuse me?
Error informed.
- Error informed?
I'm sorry, but unless you yourself were,
you have no idea what war is.
Do take it easy.
- No, it's okay. And Joiner and I ...
we have been there.
Damn six long months.
We know that the war is bullshit, right?
Maybe they what our eyes
held or we're just old fashioned ...
but we really believed that to 'Nam go,
a correct decision.
Joiner surrendered even voluntarily.
- Nobody will blame you something.
Maybe not, but you should
respect what this guy did.
He had the courage to it with his own eyes
that what they told us was bullshit and lies.
What did he do?
He got up and went away.
Just so.
Go ahead, call me uneducated,
Error informed if you want.
But I tell you, I'm really proud
I have followed him in battle.
I followed him home.
Protesting.
Why did you not tell me?
This is a great story.
Where do we start?
- With Jane maybe.
Juniper or Jane.
Old fashioned apple wine.
You know, this was a good idea.
Are you crazy?
Paardenpis.
Have you seen those candy-girl?
Deserters.
What are you doing?
Relax, you're a hero.
All you have to do is go up those stairs ...
and good fucking.
- If they know, they hang us high and dry.
I think it's a firing squad.
- I'm serious.
It's bad enough that we have deserted.
- Wait, you said ...
Forget what I said.
You said we were deserters.
This is not about a few days locked up.
This is about big things, martial.
- Who's to know?
Over a few days we returned.
Besides, we are among friends.
We are heroes, dude.
Do you ever after,
for you again telling bullshit?
No, not really.
Listen, soldier.
You have 72 hours to let you crazy fuck.
Dismissed.
Go on up.
A few days ago I did not
that we would get up alive.
If I had known that it would be so.
Here in this place with ...
the most beautiful angel I ever saw.
Then I found out a long time cut.
I am sorry
Did you like the nicest angel?
Yes.
Well then.
It was just a joke.
How are you?
What happened there?
Were you injured?
It's nothing.
Just a scratch.
What is that thing that Juniper?
It's just a name.
Do you know how scared I was?
The next call from my parents ...
- I know.
I know.
It's good.
You must not be afraid.
I am sorry
I did not mean to scare you.
I was one of your articles to read.
Pretty good.
Thank you.
No, I do not drink, actually.
- Really?
Yes.
And I thought
that all reporters were drunks.
I want you to know that I think
what you did was great.
Would you tell me what it is you succeeded?
We walked away.
- We walked?
We were exploring.
I and Joiner at the border of Laos.
We got to talking about the war,
what that meant and what is not.
And Joiner says what
if we were lost in combat?
I am the radioman, so ...
I give a few false positions,
and say that we are the bad guys chasing.
You call the Vietnamese people so?
I refer anyone who is trying to kill me.
Right. Also good.
And when we gave nothing by,
complete silence.
Showed that the leave was easy.
Return home ...
that was a different story.
Janie ...
It's Juniper.
When we were in Thailand would receive
we swapped our M-16s into cash ...
and we bought a Eurasian pilot to,
to bring us to Singapore.
Actually turned out to be a nice guy,
smuggled us to Tran and Au ...
from there it was easy.
- That is so cool.
Why do you still wear your uniforms?
Joiner wanted Jane not scare.
Look ...
- Yes.
Peter and I ...
- Yeah, I get it already
We want to write an article about your
for our next edition.
Shoot me is not enough,
now you want me for a firing squad bring?
I promise you that we do not
real names will be used.
And it is not printed until you're gone.
We want the story about how it really is there.
The truth.
Sleep is a sleep on.
Good?
Well then.
Goodnight.
What do you suggest?
I'm a deserter.
Do you remember?
You look ridiculous.
- I must do it.
I have to ask her today.
- Do it.
Continued from where you were, right?
It was ... otherwise.
Awesome.
Well, do not exaggerate.
I got a ring.
Dalton looks not too weird?
- Never crazier than this.
A new uniform, soldier.
Some of us go to South U.
We will make our own public park.
Will you even look.
Sounds great.
- Come on.
Look there, buddy.
Shoot with focus.
Do you have enough money?
Yes. Thank you.
Do you think I have a chance to make that Candace?
Honestly, no.
- I was hoping you'd say that.
Come on, guys, let's go.
I need to do some quick,
but I follow you, okay?
What you have to do quickly?
Do not worry about it.
I'll find you.
You always do.
Quickly do what?
What then?
You had her as well say
that you went to buy a ring, but ...
quickly do what is good.
- What was I supposed to say?
Is all right.
- Thank you.
Stay out of trouble.
- What is there to like?
Candace, I have an important question for you.
- Yes?
Where can you find a good burger?
The former president promised that
we have a man on the moon would have.
President Kennedy was still alive
so he could see his dream come true.
I actually once a letter
recovered from him, handwritten.
He thanked me, but considering I only
Was 14 I could not 't Peace Corps.
When I was 14, was my only concern
how I could fuck.
I had better not say.
And is you have succeeded, or?
Eventually.
Assume that they are not much you eat there?
- Once a zeerat eaten?
No, I do not usually eat rats.
So you do not drink, no drugs
and you do not eat rats.
Have fun there with you not, right?
- Will or not.
Zeerat's army food. You have not lived unless
you've eaten ham with white beans.
Yeah, that sounds delicious.
When you're at it Peace Corps
gone when you were older?
There were more important issues at home.
- Your parents?
Vietnam.
I have worked on Bobby Kennedy's campaign.
I think if they did not shoot him
the war would be over now.
I know if not.
- Why do you say that?
Is just hard to imagine that
anyone can just stop.
It's hard to imagine them to
the moon, but they do it anyway.
Thank you.
- Are you sure you want anything?
No.
I'm already sick by looking at him.
Thank you.
- That's just nasty.
Will you really eat all that?
- Eventually.
Stop calling up conscripts.
These people do not work?
Let's see, to begin her work
or anti-war protest.
That's not a difficult decision.
- Of course.
As long as it pays the bills daddy.
Peter seems to be a concerned citizen.
He is passionate to say the least.
Passionate about to stop the war?
Among other things.
As ...
So it is up to you,
what you wanna do.
The longer we let it go their lunatics,
the worse it will be.
I do not know.
I think this is naturally passes.
STUDENTS AGAINST WAR
WITHDRAW FROM VIETNAM
No more war.
Put down your weapons, buddy.
Power to the people.
He goes up there.
I think we'd better disappear.
- Come on, man.
In the war fighting and protesting
in the same week. How cool is that thinking?
I mean it.
- Let's go.
Come on.
Power to the people.
We have the power, burlap.
I'll tell you something.
While everyone at the moon ...
look no further for the truth.
Apollo 11.
All single distraction.
It's a circus.
A circus organized by the army ...
our thoughts get away
of the killing in Vietnam.
Say no to Walter Cronkite and
the other media ring leaders there in Houston.
And who cares anything about it
of the dead count in Saigon?
Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin ...
who are they anyway?
They are no more than a few clowns
billions in a circus.
Wake up!
Would you talk about real heroes?
I'm talking about brothers who lost their lives
risked for something they believed.
Look no further.
For we have here and now heroes.
That is correct.
I'm talking about two U.S. soldiers ...
who one day woke up in Vietnam
and decided that it was enough.
Two U.S. soldiers and the heart
had the courage and conviction to say ...
hell no, we will not stay here.
What did they say?
- We continue here.
We remain here.
Deserters?
Not in my service.
What did they say?
- We continue here.
Come on, guys.
Agents, make the street Fri
I repeat, make the street Fri
Spread the crowd.
Come on.
Jane, come on.
Have you not do.
We have rights!
Jutes, go home.
Free speech.
First Amendment.
Beware of my pants, man.
Jane, no.
Come.
Come, we must go.
Please, spread immediately.
Please, go home.
Please, stop.
Come on, dude.
I got you.
Well, come on.
Is it?
- Yes.
That part should not write.
- I just have.
Would someone tell me
what that meant?
Everything all right?
- Yeah, great.
I'm sorry, Ray was too excited,
he just went for it.
Sometimes things get worse
before they get better. - Oh, what.
A lot of kids who throw some stuff
who had nothing better to do.
That is exactly why our best weapon,
the truth is.
Guys like you can a difference.
Listen to me.
Your story will people open their eyes to
what's really going on in that jungle there.
Good, at first,
I have not seen any jungle.
They are rice fields, forests and trails.
Running around in circles, every day all day long.
Second, find it regrettable to say, but
you keep the war against with your newspaper.
Do you want me here just eliminate it?
Yes.
That was fun.
Anytime.
Joiner, listen up.
Your friend has it wrong.
People read about you and soon there will be others
as you do not want so badly to Vietnam.
That's exactly how you can stop this war
and your friends can get home safely.
Say goodbye, Joiner.
Tomorrow we're here.
What?
Do you need anything?
A kiss, perhaps?
No, I'm not going to sleep.
What you did for Isaac,
was really great.
Least I could do.
I'm on your sofa.
Look what I eat.
Properly.
Goodnight.
- Good night, Candace.
You know, Peter thinks you're a hero, Dalton.
That does everyone here.
They want you to stay with us.
Here?
That's just crazy.
- No, no.
That's not.
Peter can write the story,
if you're in Canada and ...
we can give you a false
identity provide ..
a new name ...
- No, Jane.
I do not want another name.
I want my service serve.
Back to home ...
to Hammond, as we had planned.
- You serve out service?
You are a ...
- No.
I am not a deserter.
What?
I've got free time.
What the army is concerned ...
we are in Hong Kong.
But everyone thinks ...
- No matter what the rest think.
Those idiots do not even know
what they're talking about.
Those idiots are my friends.
I am sorry
You can not go back.
You're already here, you can not.
Will you marry me?
Where as I can afford ...
we buy something better,
I promise you.
You will find 'm not pretty.
- No.
I find it beautiful.
Do you like the watchman?
Did you already asked?
We're getting married.
That's awesome, dude.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
We should celebrate.
Before we go back.
What?
Thank you ...
you come with me, and everything else.
I just care for my size.
- It was pretty crazy to me.
And even crazier for you, so ...
I really appreciate that.
Go back to your fiancée.
Is okay.
You will find it terrible.
- No. It's good.
But I tell you, we need the names
to make it real.
We can not make.
No, I'm talking Mickey promised.
Awesome.
Nice sound to the beginning of the day.
Two o'clock in the afternoon.
Have you fat for this thing?
- We have somebody who restores.
Yes?
Then you have to dismiss it.
The bearings are dry.
Let 's now but even walk.
Awesome.
Thank you.
What can I say, I'm good with my hands.
- Yeah, I can see that.
You must not leave or something?
No, not really, Peter.
These two are getting married.
Right? Let them see the ring.
Come on, let's see?
Congratulations.
Where are we doing this last party?
Let's go dancing.
Can not we just ...
Mission accomplished.
Yes, we still have no date, so ...
- Oh, details. Do well once just?
It's a party.
You went down on me.
Try this,
'll Hanoi thoughts disappear.
Joiner is the only guy in Vietnam
which it never did.
What?
Come on, let's go.
Leave that to her.
No, no.
Why do those other poor suckers remains
in the same way as you did?
Because if they catch you,
they shut you up in Leavenworth, therefore.
Good, but not better lock
than a bullet in the head?
Yes, maybe today.
But what if they ever release? Who gives you
work, or do something with you to do?
Nobody.
You might as well be dead.
You find that funny?
- I do not know, dude.
I can only say that I prefer
become trapped, then those useless war.
Yes? Say that once again
if you notice you've got orders.
Right.
Want to dance?
With pleasure.
Why do you always wear the radio?
- I asked.
I would not be able to walk ahead as Joiner.
I'm not so lucky girl home.
Vietnam ...
a big trap.
That you learn from the first time
you have foot drop.
Would you tell me what happened?
Look at that.
Just inhale and hold,
glass empty drink and then blow.
At Captain Joe!
Persevere.
Soldier Dalton Joiner.
Came to her.
On my first day I meet
a large E-4 of Tennessee.
Everyone called him Moonshine.
He comes to me and says, "Hey boy, do yourself
a favor, would you voluntarily as radioman.
You're in the middle of the platoon, the safest place.
And I think I'm a loser or whatever,
with that heavy thing.
And then bang.
The man in front kicks in a trap.
It was Moonshine.
I called the evacuation helicopters, but ...
by the time they were there,
he was dead.
Eleven days and he was allowed to go home.
Joiner went forefront.
We have not walked into a trap.
Now look at my buddy there.
Go away tomorrow.
We have to go.
I want you to take it somewhere,
before you leave.
Where to?
A quiet place ...
a nice place.
You need that.
I must tell you that I
already see something beautiful.
Do not touch her!
Nobody touches my girl.
Do you hear me? Nobody.
It's all right.
Nothing special, he just plays around a little.
Calm down.
She's a man, dude.
It is nobody's property.
Quiet.
- Get up, you idiot hippie Tippie. Come on.
Hold on.
What did you do?
I?
He sat with his hands on you.
What's wrong with you, Jane?
- Stop me if you like.
With what to call it?
- Jane, Janie ...
I'm not anymore.
What are you talking about?
Just go.
Just go, Dalton.
All you fools,
can all fuck off.
Aside.
War and hell have already helped him.
Well, go ahead further.
We are now only twelve hours away
of the first moon landing.
Are you sure you do not need?
Go.
Are you succeed, mate?
I surrender, right?
- It's okay. I'm here for Candace.
How are you with, Dalton?
- Just great.
What do you think?
Are you hungry or ...?
- Mickey Wright has always hungry.
I did not think you'd come back yet.
Then you seem to know me well.
Are we there yet?
Come on.
Just keep walking.
No, not until you tell me
how Peter's.
What are you talking about?
- You know.
And?
If what Peter was,
do you think I would be here with you?
You're very clever, you know?
- Really?
I'm a moose that is ten miles away.
You mean some girls
really fall for that beautiful angel story?
Some.
Okay, close your eyes.
- Why?
Just match them.
- Good.
It's a surprise.
- I do not like surprises.
Trust me.
Well then.
Start walking.
Your hand is on my ass.
Was that your intention?
Keep walking.
Yet a little further.
Properly.
You can open your eyes now.
A quiet, beautiful place.
You should have told me to come in costume.
That was the surprise ruined.
Thank you.
Crashed.
One small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
It looks beautiful from here.
- It looks as beautiful from everywhere ...
it's different, but very nice here.
Someone once told me that I would never forget
where I would be during the moon landing.
And?
He was right.
I can not agree.
I see you do not really play rugby.
People hurt.
Yes, and you see I did not desert.
Is good, dude.
I believed Wright's story anyway.
You have to hand it to him,
he can really crap sales.
He can be sure.
But tell me ...
Be honest,
if you would do it again.
Knowing what you know now,
would you go?
I would certainly not voluntarily give up.
What if they send you to Da Nang.
I thought you were still at school.
Damn, Isaac.
Morning.
The first morning I
Vietnam woke ...
I saw all of those fantastic red butterflies.
And for a moment I forgot where I was.
Sometimes I think we just so.
Flit from place to place,
not really a plan.
At least not one that can be seen.
I have friends in Calgary.
They have a farm, there you go.
- No. I do not belong on a farm.
This is not funny.
The police are looking for you.
They have been going door to door even.
- What?
I'm sorry,
I should have told you sooner.
That was selfish, I ...
- Never mind, we'll be here.
What do you think of Canada?
- No idea.
I must warn Joiner.
You can get off me better here,
if the home is not safe.
You can not just do something without a plan.
I'll meet you at the diner.
Give me a few hours to arrange everything.
You missed the moon landing.
- Have you seen Juniper?
No. I was working.
We have Mickey and Dalton
immediately bring to Canada.
Did not you hear what I just said?
They do not go to Canada.
They go back to Vietnam.
What are you talking about?
Dalton is not deserted.
He just came back to me.
Mickey is only with him gone.
We must go, the cops are looking for us.
- You know what would be awesome?
Neil and Buzz decided would have
not to return.
That would be something.
- Yes.
Neil and Buzz disappearing.
- Or even better ...
Neil and Buzz desert.
Pardon?
They are now where they have a long time to be,
why still go back.
They can not just stay on the moon.
No, they can not.
But we do.
- What are you talking about, we are not going to desert.
Why not?
Because you do not deserting.
You lead us platoon, because you have
signed for. That's your job.
I signed up for a war to win.
Until I came to know, like all others,
that no war can be won.
Come on. You were there. When she boy
from Tennessee dragged inside ...
completely shot to pieces.
You knew it, I knew it, everyone knew it.
That this war is about one thing.
Survive. And from that moment ...
was the only thing I could do,
to focus on Jane.
Stay awake at night watch, the tent
Double check for VC. She is counting on me.
I found every trap, because I had to.
If I'm there again, without Jane,
I'm dead.
What our guys then?
Franklin, Sanchez, Burns and me.
You go also our desertion?
Do not you think I know what you feel?
Do you know how much I want to run away with Candace?
I would be overjoyed to some
farm in Canada, but I do not.
Because it's Tuesday in Hong Kong and we
go back again tonight. End of story.
Burns will not return.
- Because he has saved our lives.
Now he lies somewhere in a hospital, is
wondering if he will ever be able steps.
You are a commitment, not
to win a war, but to our unit.
We trust that our front man
us alive bringing forth.
Why do you think I was buying?
An obligation?
You do not even know what it means.
Burns is dead.
I just with his father
on the phone.
A staph infection,
He did not even leave Da Nang.
There was a guy in our unit, Burns.
Joiner and I had no apparent
a chance to get out alive.
And the others to Burns
showed up to save us.
The truth is, without him
I would not even have been.
Burns was shot.
It was very.
I just learned that in some
kutziekenhuis died in 'Nam.
Are you ready?
I'm not really in the mood
for one of your stories.
What are you talking about?
- You got a nice free time?
Have you found what you came for?
Another great story for your friends?
No, Candace, I did not ...
- Abuses?
You bastard.
Wright has said that I was here?
Isaac.
That's funny.
I have that image in my head ...
of you, me and the house,
kids.
Our parents who come
for the barbecue on Sunday.
But that picture you have not
in your head, do Juniper?
What?
You called me Juniper.
That's who you are now.
Not you?
He's really, really nice.
Keep him.
What time does your plane?
- 8:55.
I will always love you keep.
That will never change.
Thank you for all the surprise packets.
You gave us all something
to look forward to.
Anytime.
This was a stupid idea.
What are you planning?
- Mickey Wright is not half the world ...
then come back without a story
girl with a good finish.
It's over, once again.
- No, not yet.
You go back to Candace and you will
as our friend, stone dick, there.
You're upright, proud
and with a flag in your conviction.
What?
I'm impressed.
That was almost funny even.
Almost.
Time to go pop, dude.
Aim right to the heart.
Can I get a ride to the bus station?
- Step into.
Just have to wait for Wright.
Just want to see Candace.
- I'm pretty sure they do not want to see you.
Why do not you go back to the jungle.
Excuse, the rice fields.
I just told you.
- Stand aside.
Get out of my house.
You know what, Pete?
I'm going to count to three.
If you do not step aside,
I go through you.
A ... Two ...
I'm sorry, Pete.
Just breathe.
What are you doing here?
It was not all a lie.
Not the part that I was in love with you.
Please, Candace, do not do this.
Would you say something?
Just go away.
You've got something beautiful
and you've ridiculed.
That is not true
and you know it.
I'm busy,
was there anything else?
I'm not like you.
I did not save the world when I was 14.
I have in my whole life
never something mandatory.
Not to the school, nor the war, nothing.
Up to now.
Well, I'll leave.
I was at least honest about one thing.
I love you for who you are.
Not for any purpose.
On the ground. I said, on the ground.
- Dwell.
Quiet.
- Against the wall and soon.
Check his pockets.
- Do you have weapons?
No, no.
Let me go.
- Please, I want you not arrest.
You do not understand. He is not a deserter.
He has only his free time now.
He was even in his uniform.
- Oh, really. How does he explain this?
HONOR IN A DESERT STREET WOODY
A true story.
What?
- That I get by staying too long.
You must believe me, I have not written.
This I have not written.
I know.
- You have the right to remain silent.
He has no rights,
this is a military matter.
Would you tell me where you been buddy?
- Yes, in Vietnam.
Well then, boy. Then we go to the office and
wait until you retrieve the Military Police.
No, please.
- I'm sorry.
You denounced him.
- I do not know what you're talking about.
You knew they were not going away.
A dilapidated, yellow Victorian house.
Yes gave them as well as our address.
How do you get it in your head?
- You were not here, okay?
I had a editorial decision ...
- No, that's pure bullshit and you know it.
This is nonsense, Candace.
He has lied to you.
He has lied to us all.
So that makes it right what you did?
You're right, Peter.
I was really disappointed.
It's okay, right?
I thought you were a traitor.
The truth is that only a coward.
That changes nothing, dude.
How long should you take off your service?
Six months.
- Six months?
You were halfway home.
Captain Sinclair.
Yes.
First Sergeant Freeman, from Selfridge ANG
here soldier Michael J. Wright to pick.
This is from you soon.
Was less than 30 minutes
since I spoke to the colonel.
We spent the last two days
the area searched.
This I have been arrested ...
Joiner soldier and I try our all day
to remember where his buddy was.
Not true sometimes?
Is that him?
We got him back into his uniform.
Now only a good shave ...
for his long visit to Leavenworth.
Good luck, kid.
That he certainly needed.
Is not it?
Come on.
Have a nice day.
Not too strict,
they have already served six months.
You will not believe this.
Dalton Joiner has a raid carried out ...
to a prisoner, Michael J. Wright
free.
Without firing a shot, he gets the
Captain flat with rubbish of the first rank.
Franklin and Sanches enter it in their pants.
Where did you get that uniform come from?
Old military equipment.
Nice haircut, Topher.
- Was a special Joiner.
Come, we must hurry.
We have a plane to catch.
I'm going to be here on foot.
How do you walk with those things?
Keep your right, okay?
Hey, Topher.
Keep a watchful 't sail with Juniper, will you?
Will do.
Come on, we've got ten minutes.
Come on.
Share it with the boys.
- What are you talking about?
I'm sorry, dude.
I can not go back.
I would be worthless for the unit.
No apologies necessary.
You certainly do not.
With all those days that you do for sustained,
did you deserved.
Where are you going?
- No idea.
We thought maybe to Toronto,
maybe Montreal.
We?
Isaac received his summons warrant.
A dodger and a deserter.
I want to know all about it when I return.
Now walk it.
Hey, soldier?
Where is Joiner?
He goes ...
He's not coming back.
What are you talking about?
He can not lead the
without Jane in his head.
It's the only thing he could get there by.
She gave us all a strikethrough.
No, no.
Please, do not.
Look ...
- No.
What I know, as I now the guys in the lurch
leave, I will anything or anyone worth something.
I just keep walking.
I'll come with you to Canada.
- No, no.
That I'm not touching you.
You stay here,
make a end to this war.
There you have signed up for.
I love you.
Hey, there.
Nice to see you.
- Yeah, you too.
Would you like something to drink?
- No, not necessary, thank you.
You know, maybe if you look carefully,
you can see that the astronauts back.
Dearest Mickey ...
Topher just called me
to say that you are free.
I drive it in the taxi on the way
to the airport.
Should I miss you.
We...-truth,
I miss you already
I think I now understand why Juniper never
told about her boyfriend in Vietnam.
Because people like me
would have made it difficult for her.
it's funny. I think I was the person
which had to be informed.
In our anger
to war to stop this bad ...
I think we have forgotten,
that our boys there, not the bad ones are.
They are just trying to survive.
Guys like Joiner,
who risk their lives with every step.
And guys like Burns, who lives
sacrifice in order to save their friends.
I wish I had met him, for him
thank, he saved you for me.
Now go back to your radio back to record.
I hope you like this post
received loud and clear ...
in an attractive yellow Victorian house,
there awaits a lucky girl to your home.
With much love, Candace.
And?
What?
Come on, right? Not crazy,
where is he, where did you go?
To the moon.
Dearest Candace ...
here I am again, back at the others.
But I'm not in circles.
Now, with every step I take ...
I'm one step closer to you.