At the Berlin Conference in 1885
Africa was divided.
Congo, became the personal property
of Belgian King Leopold I.
On June 30, 1960, the nationalist
Patrice Lumumba, 36, became
The first Prime Minister
of the new independent state.
He would last only months.
This is a true story.
Nobody knew about that night
in Katanga.
Nobody was allowed to know.
Their mission was clear.
Retrieve three bodies
and then disappear.
No grave, no memory...
Even in death they were afraid of me.
Will you help me?
The children may not
know everything that happened, do you?
They probably wouldn't understand.
Tell them not ...
Say nothing.
You acted in the name of Congo,
but not your party
Is not representative.
- It's now Lumumba's turn.
Let him continue talking.
Right,
The MNC does not represent
every Congolese. Not yet.
But Tshombe of CONAKAT
Katanga does not represent all of Congo.
Our party is big,
yours is nothing.
There are 250 parties
in Congo.
Plus those founded by the Belgians.
Mr. Kasavubu could take power
but he does not have support in Accra.
But what am I to do give out visas?
Why did the government go it alone?
Ask them.
So you could sell your Polar
beer to the Minister.
He could have 51% of the vote.
I did not know.
You know many things,
starting with the protocol.
Is this a joke?
Not at all.
Please read the full text of my speech,
not in newspapers.
I should talk about you
and your rich province.
But I do not see the Congo
as tribes and provinces,
but as a whole.
We need to move beyond provincialism.
Do we have to hear your speech once again?
Do you think you're still in Accra?
You are two people, I
represent many more.
We have 10,000 people. I could get CONAKAT
not to mention Tshombe if you like.
At the next Pan-African
Conference
I will be happy to
talk about your big party.
He derides.
- Your irony is inappropriate
and insulting.
I can only say:
Read my speech.
Or not. But there will be no rewrite.
You travel a far to sell your beer.
Stay away from my region.
Because we do not forget.
Yes, I made some mistakes.
And it would all end badly.
We thought it our destiny
to decide our country's fate
but other, more powerful enemies
were in control.
Why did they fear me so much?
When they eventually killed me,
they made me more important.
I was but one vote for the dream
of freedom and fraternity.
Words they could not accept.
But they were just words.
Everything was nevertheless a good start.
Do you remember?
I came from Stanleyville
A colonial
administrative clerk, third class.
I was 30 and at the height
of my career.
But my job was not
What I had imagined,
But I suppose I shouldn't look
a gift horse in the mouth.
Patrice Lumumba.
You can speak to the people.
Such a person we need.
The people here are hard.
After the triumph of Kasavubu
some businesses flourished,
But not ours ...
We are on our last legs.
If you can do things to help business resume ...
It is even said
that our beer causes impotence.
That is how far they will go.
If you can save the business
You will get a salary of Deputy Director.
Good salary, right?
It's very good, Director.
Within a month we will
need to see improvements.
Can I do what I want?
- If you want ...
Come closer, my friends.
Test, it's free.
Girls?
- Beer, slyboots.
And not just beer. The best!
The King of beers. Polar!
I sold beer. Why not?
Polar or Primus, they all left me cold.
I was in the capital,
that is what was important.
I love Primus.
Long live King Kasa.
Here is the competition.
Long live Congo!
Long Live Free Congo!
Long live independence!
That's strong language. Come here.
Take a Polar. At my expense.
When I met Joseph,
he was an army sergeant
but also an aspiring journalist.
And you?
- Joseph-Desire Mobutu.
To our health.
To our future!
He was not Mobutu Sese Seko
Kuku Ngwendu Wasahanga,
Father of the Nation.
Not yet.
Congo was still
a Belgian colony.
Lumumba?
- Here I am.
Along there.
Name?
Lumumba. Patrice, Emery.
You 're judicial file.
And you hope to travel?
Is that my visa?
Yes, you're lucky. Or have good connections.
Fork on the left!
Indigenous children
learn to work and study,
but are only interested
in relaxation.
I do not speak Flemish!
Can you open this?
If the teacher loses the pedals,
take over the primitive methods ...
Like only a small handful of others
I got my card identifying me
as a "civilized person".
She showed me just how to buy alcohol
in the European quarter.
Throughout the DRC?
- It wsa very Congo.
For political Lessons
we used the gym,
the association of employees,
the association's indigenous staff
and the Congregation
of the Virgin.
No collaboration,
but civil disobedience.
80 years is enough!
First the slave trade, the ivory trade
and then killing for rubber.
Now we sell diamonds, copper, manganese and zinc.
Everyone knows
that independence is imminent.
Uhuru! Viva! Viva!
Independence!
Do you remember it now?
The year 1959?
With its enthusiasm,
the anger and its violence?
What nobody predicted was
that everything would change.
MNC in the middle.
We will see that later.
It's King Baudouin. Come and listen.
They will admit.
... that everything leads to this one decisive step
In the life of
Our African peoples.
I owe it to
my illustrious predecessors,
the pioneers of our work in Africa ...
Do they keep anything on hand.
No, they've lost the north.
Then they have lost.
De Gaulle has admitted
that little Belgium has no choice.
We're going to eat them!
You know, Maurice, they will think
you were are cannibal.
A what?
Someone who eats human flesh.
If that is so,
I will begin immediately.
We decided for Congo
without delay,
and without haste ...
Run!
... that without which
a democratic regime
there is nothing more than deceit and tyranny.
Let him go!
To do this you will pay!
6 months later
Look.
The director was right.
He is smuggling out messages.
Bastard!
"I strongly protest ...
I demand my release
as leader of MNC I am a delegate
and participate in
the Round Table
In Brussels. "
The pretentious monkey!
Do you think we are so stupid
as to release you
while show subversive behavior
the very reason you're here?
You sit for two years and we
take care of you, boy.
Do you see yourself in Brussels?
What would you say to the King?
What would you say to Bwana Kitoko?
He wants to be minister.
They all want to be minister.
Want to be decorated?
We'll decorate you.
Want to be called Excellency?
Is that it monkey?
Should we say Sir?
We found this.
Why is he bleeding?
- As usual. He protested.
We intervened
and he defended himself.
Mr. Lumumba,
I've received orders from Brussels.
The Minister of Congo has requested
that you are present at
the Round Table Conference.
You are free to go.
Tomorrow there is a plane to Brussels.
Take it.
Patrice, welcome!
Good to see you.
How are you?
Will you go and meet Mr. Kasavubu?
- I will meet all Aboko representatives.
How is your relationship with Mr. Kasavubu?
- Very good.
Do you want to meet with European investors?
- Of course.
What are your expectations?
- They are high.
Will you meet with the Belgian Ministers?
I'm just a poor woman.
There are millions of us.
In their name I salute a freedom fighter.
Thank you, ma'am.
Do you think the MNC has a chance?
Were you wounded on board?
- In prison. It's nothing.
Tell me about Brussels.
- It's a beautiful city.
I mean the Round Table.
- Everyone is talking about you.
Which room?
- Room three!
There are no more oranges.
Three Flamingos in 1926.
Who goes to the third floor?
- Send Mathieu.
I do Bomboko.
What you see in this clown?
He has class.
- No, gratuities.
Make way!
There's work to be done.
No, no, no you can not leave now.
It's not over yet.
Back to top.
- Let us go.
Mr. Lumumba will meet you at 7 pm
Not now.
What do you mean
"Vague impulses independence"?
It's a reality.
Yes, it is stretchable.
It is not our fault
that the date is not yet known.
Mr. Kasavubu,
how nice to meet you.
I say that it is a crime.
You attach too much importance to a word.
Independence. A word?
God is a word
but I believe it.
So we will end up giving the Congo to the Communists.
As France did in Algeria.
Anyone without a political mandate
is to leave.
Men ...
Joseph, did you hear me?
- I do not understand.
I am a MNC deputy.
- But aren't you studying in Belgium?
Yes, but ...
This is for delegates from Congo.
I am a MNC deputy.
Joseph, it is the Rules
of the Common Front.
Let them experiment
with freedom.
Either way they will give Africa
one of two lessons,
The European example
of united, hardworking nation ...
or the other primitive, that
has been surpessed will return.
And then ...
And then?
We have an army, militias,
planes, tanks.
We have the two largest parties.
We should take a common
position.
You think to show a compromise?
Independence on June 15?
The minister will refuse.
Would you like us to give way on a date?
A Common Front would give us
more coverage.
They want to save time.
Why?
Do they need to prepare their retreat?
Or to plot against us?
Conspiracy dismantlement?
Union Miniere in Katanga.
The copper, the diamonds ...
They will leave that to our government?
We have no government.
Wait for the elections.
We're not there yet.
I ask you
What should they do with independence?
It's not a nation, it strains already.
The Lulua's hate the Baluba's
Baluba's hate and the Bakongo's.
And canthe Bakongo and
the Bengala's tolerate eachother?
The colonial administration
holds them together.
And when that disappears.
- What then?
We must not make the same mistake as the French.
With their African executives.
Judges, police, the postal service.
All high positions are held by Belgians.
Without them, there will be chaos.
Good, good.
It is June 30 then.
Independence's a fact.
There remains one question:
will she be federalist, as you want,
or unitarian, as I want.
I will make a press release
and we will both sign.
Let me read the text first.
Do you know the latest hit?
Leopoldville, May 1960
We won.
Their coalitions failed.
We did well?
- Even better than Abako.
In Leopoldville too?
- Of course not.
What is "president", Daddy?
- Nothing. Eat.
We must continue.
Until the end.
You do not know what you say, Maurice.
Anyway.
Half a revolution is not possible.
We must throw out the Flemish.
Expropriate the missionaries.
Chase out all the parasites
All the officer castes.
And who will replace them?
They can go to hell!
We did not need them.
You will not have it easy.
I know,
but one thing must be clear.
Should I show a government form
or is it to be an information circular?
an Information Round with an eye
to forming the government second.
I do not understand it yet.
The independence ceremony
is on June 30.
If we have no government,
as my unofficial mission is ...
It's an official mission.
Let me organize things
as I was told
by His Majesty.
Information first, then formation.
All in good time.
I will do my best.
But remember, time is short.
Good luck, Mr. Information.
I accuse Minister Ganshof
and the duplicity of the Belgian Government,
which I consider as dangerous
to me and the government I
want to form.
Brussels prefers a Congo
without a leader on June 30
Instead of a Lumumba government.
In these circumstances
there will be no head of state to
on June 30.
Neither from my party nor our allies
The appointment will need
Mr. Kasavubu approval.
CONAKAT, but not Tshombe.
The coalition will not stand days.
Even as Commissioner of
the Katanga province?
We can find better.
For Finance I accept your candidate.
But I want Thomas Kanza
as Minister at the V.N.
His father was last year
expelled from our party.
It gives me no pleasure.
The son is not the father.
He'll do a good job.
Gentlemen ...
Today is the day.
The Nationalist Block which I chair,
will put forward the candidacy of Mr. Kasavubu
for the post of President
of the Republic.
I never disputed
that it deserves that title.
My first act will be the appointment
Mr. Lumumba
as Prime Minister of
the Government of National Unity.
Unity, which is what the Congo
now needs.
Is it not true that Katanga is not
represented in the government?
Do you not fear separation?
Katanga is represented.
More than Tshombe in Katanga and Munungo.
No more questions.
Congo is united and will remain so.
Is that enough?
United or not, we want to emphasize this.
And money! And comfort!
And no more Flemish people who give orders!
No more bullying!
It's enough!
Moreover, we must cut their grass
and our wives do their dishes.
We get so little bit and we do everything.
Come on. Sit with us.
We can not directly change anything.
I asked for a general amnesty to the king
and promotions for you.
June 30 will be shown to be a memorable day.
Without distinction of rank,
province or tribe.
For the unified nation.
United!
I'm going to sleep. Until tomorrow.
It's Tshombe and the full CONAKAT party.
I'll go back to Elizabeth City.
Yesterday I waited all day
for the list of ministers.
You promised me that you'd send them to me.
We sent them on.
- Liar!
What's he saying?
- Slow down, Maurice.
Apparently you already know the list?
A lot of extremists.
We will use all the means of
the unified structures of
the country to fight.
All resources?
And you will deny the democratic vote?
- I suppose you'd prefer Communism.
Communism ...
We are no more communist than you
Do not argue with them, Thomas. They are fascists.
I do not like that tone!
That's independence.
Well, we're not done.
What a lot of dust!
Can we be that bad that we
cannot leave a few paintings?
But they are owned by the Belgian state.
It's a direct order.
Run for your life. The Bantus are here.
Sire, they give away your Congo
and make a pigsty.
They even showed them the wine cellar.
The governor has not bored of it.
Does no one answer the phone?
No, Governor Cornelis
does not live here anymore.
He does not live here anymore.
This is the residence of Patrice Lumumba,
Prime Minister of Congo.
Already five months
I have not slept.
Are you tired, Daddy?
Give me that.
Read this and tell me what you think.
What time is it?
When will the car be here?
It cannot happen, Sir!
And not because I chair the ceremony,
but because it's provocative.
Who provoked the first?
I have the speech of the King
and the President is not in support.
They've refused an amnesty,
A symbolic gesture
that is essential for the ceremony.
I appointed you as President
of the Senate
because I thought you had character.
Am I to be made wrong?
You need him to give the word.
Kasa Once is finished,
Patrice takes the microphone.
They should stay and listen.
You want the King, General Janssens,
the bishop ...
The King, the General, the Bishop ...
That I forgot.
Exactly. Let them
listen to the truth.
That's something different. For everyone.
Good.
Patrice, do you really have to say?
The independence of the Congo
is the continuation of a process that resulted
from the genius of King Leopold I,
by him with growing
courage a process started
and was continued with conviction
by Belgium.
When Leopold I began this enormous work,
now completed,
He did not do so as the conqueror
but as an advocate
of civilization.
It's up to you, gentlemen,
to prove that we were right
to trust you.
Avoid the name of the King.
Avoid rapid reforms
and not replace Belgian institutions
unless you are certain
you can do better.
Gentlemen, the eyes of the world
are on you.
May God protect the Congo!
Excellencies, dear compatriots,
Now, officially, the Republic of Congo
appears on the world map,
a fully independent and sovereign ...
Patrice, it's too dangerous.
You've improved.
You know what you're doing?
Do you really think you can tackle them?
- You heard him.
We must respond.
What will our children remember?
Kasa answers.
Listen to what he says.
Sire,
your presence
on this memorable day
proves once again your concern
for the people you loved
and protected.
We will not disappoint you.
My dear compatriots,
victors
of the independence struggle,
For this independence of the Congo,
even as it is celebrated today with Belgium
a friendly country with whom
we deal as equal to equal
no Congolese worthy of the name
will ever be able to forget
that it was by fighting
that it has been won
a day-to-day fight,
an ardent and idealistic fight,
a fight in which we were spared
neither privation nor suffering,
and for which we gave our strength
and our blood.
We are proud of this struggle,
of tears, of fire, and of blood,
to the depths of our being,
for it was a noble and just struggle,
and indispensable to put an end
to the humiliating slavery
which was imposed upon us by force
because we were black.
Who could forget the shootings
which claimed so many victims,
the cells in which those
were locked up
who escaped the bullets
of the soldiers
that were used
to dominating us?
All this, brethren,
has made us suffer
and our wounds are too fresh
and painful to erase
them from our memory.
All this, brethren,
we proclaim loudly,
is now forever and ever
behind us.
The Congolese Republic
has been declared.
Our country belongs to our children.
We are now all able to benefit
from social justice
and our children will benefit
from our country.
Your Majesty,
Excellencies, Ladies and Gentlemen,
compatriots, fellow strugglers,
black brothers
that is what I have wanted to say.
Long live independence
and African Unity!
Long live the independent
Congo and its sovereignty!
There! Let's get him
And teach him a lesson!
Treason!
Get out!
Accelerate!
Let's go!
These are but isolated incidents.
Hardy also has a rebel camp.
The officers have been taken hostage.
They want you
They say they want to kill you.
Unbelievable.
What about Jones?
Silence.
Get your reports.
We will carry out all investigations calmly.
Minister Mpolo.
The Force Publique has 25,000 men.
They have stations
aligned along the same wavelength.
They know everything in each camp
before their officers.
They are crazy!
What do they want?
They want promotions!
I know, I heard them.
If I may, Prime Minister, they are tired.
Five months on end:
riots, celebrations ...
- The Flemish General,
Janssens, puts them against us.
And he is against African officers.
Let us shoot him.
- There is no replacement.
I suggest Senator Lundula.
And you, Mpolo as Colonel.
Let us take a vote.
I will not vote for someone
who wants to shoot anyone.
Even that is not military.
Mr. Prime Minister,
I was 7 years in the Force Publique.
I do not deny his qualities,
but I think I am more proficient ...
- An excellent suggestion.
The new commander
must come from its own ranks.
What is that?
Let us in!
We want the minister to speak first!
They are crazy! What do they want?
Where is the military discipline?
There they are!
Excellence ...
We do nothing. We have a petition.
We want an answer. Directly from you.
Give me the petition.
I will study it.
No, Sir! We want an answer now!
"We wish our military to be
disciplined to carry out our mission
and accuse General Janssens
of unfair behavior.
We demand honesty and impartiality,
which is impossible
with officers in the Congolese army."
You mean white officers?
We do not want them!
- Black officers!
No officers!
I understand that you want equality and justice.
But I do not yield weapons.
I ask you to return
to your barracks.
We have a strong,
obedient army.
We've heard it all!
Jones speaks so!
- Answer now!
You are not even in mutual agreement.
I understand your indignation.
And I will got to
Leopold and speak to the camp,
in the morning. You have my word.
Now I ask you to return
to your barracks.
Come on then, shoot.
You will come to Camp Leopold?
I promise you
We have 15 white officers hostage
and their wives.
If you do not come,
We will murder them.
Gentlemen, the meeting is not over.
Hey, you there!
Damn Flemish!
Wait!
Maxence, come in!
They do not scare me.
I will write down their numbers.
You'll see what happens!
Idiot!
You hear me, motherfucker?
Dork!
Losers!
You're a disgrace' to the regiment.
You are not alone.
There are assholes everywhere,
across the province.
In Madimba a
white woman was raped.
They were shot!
You shame the Force Publique.
You are arrested.
Take them away!
Let me be clear.
Independence is for the citizens.
For soldiers there is only discipline.
Before June 30 you had
white officers.
After June 30 you still
have white officers.
It may be that the politicians said something
else, but they lied.
I have always told the truth.
And if you do not understand
I will write it for you.
After independence
equals
for independence.
What are you saying, white?
So you will not go.
They have deceived us.
They lied.
We will not go.
Are you coming to bed?
I must finish.
You will sleep again at your desk.
Do not worry.
How can I not worry?
You sleep no more than 2 hours a night.
I will start to think
that you are actually using marijuana.
They say that?
You have no idea what
the servants tell me.
You have to be strong
for the children.
If something were to happen to me ...
General, you know why you're here?
I wait until you tell me.
And I await your explanation.
I got the telegram.
- That's obvious.
Excellency!
- Excuse me?
You say, Excellency.
I want to know what you mean by:
"I myself do not contradict
nor repeated.
Please consider this
as a final warning. "
A General in Belgium
obeys his superiors
So speak?
Excuse me, sir.
In Belgium there is order.
Here we are heading for disaster,
and there is chaos.
Because your men and
your methods are tired.
The Force Publique has to change
like the rest.
I expect your resignation.
Mr. Lumumba ...
Excellence ...
- I've said what I have to say ...
General.
Get out!
Flemish or Walloon?
- Walloons.
100 francs.
- Why?
What's going on?
Nothing.
- Why, sir?
The Belgian ambassador.
Let him through the garden.
Do you have news, Mr. Ambassador?
Nothing that you do not know.
It's bad.
You were chased out of Camp Leopold.
But order will be restored.
I do not know what order you want,
but I still cannot watch
while my countrymen are murdered.
If you do not have the means, I do,
and they are at your disposal.
An intervention?
- The situation is serious.
You can ask assistance from Belgium.
You have the right.
- I have a different opinion.
If you refuse, I will have to
consult with our Atlantic partners.
Do you understand?
- Not yet.
But this is what I've decided.
First, General Janssens
should leave Congo within 24 hours.
Secondly, you should warn him
and guarantee his departure.
Thirdly, you are responsible
for his actions during his departure.
He served Congo, Your Excellency.
He deserves respect
and courtesy.
- Courtesy!
It's the fault of the Belgians:
the uprising in the Camp, in this City
Camp Leopold, Elizabeth City ...
You spread rumours
of a Soviet invasion...
Since the beginning
You've worked to conspire against me.
And now you threaten me with the U.N. and NATO
In the middle of the night
to the Prime Minister!
Tomorrow I will hold a press conference
and make your conspiracy, threats
and insults public.
I've been advised
to go to Brazzaville,
but count me out.
Belgians will murder me there.
I complain and you become angry.
Allow me but I find that strange.
Then, I would ask you to leave.
I hereby absolve General Janssens.
For his own good and safety.
I ask him the travel by air
at the first available opportunity.
I appoint Major Victor Lundula to
Supreme Commander of the Force Publique
I have also promoted Joseph Mobutu
to colonel.
The Force Publique is now
The Congolese National Army.
The Belgians are worried.
How will you fight the atrocities?
These difficulties are inevitable.
They are caused by a few
agitators and a big misunderstanding.
I have decided to stop them
President Kasavubu and myself
I will make a journey of peace
throughout the country.
Are you going to Katanga?
- Everywhere.
Elisabethville, Coquilhatstad,
Stanleyville, Luluaburg ...
But I warn the
Belgian Government
the situation
must not be misused
for a military intervention or
to encourage riots.
Only had work can make us move forward.
Those who refuse to see
and sabotage us,
are enemies of the people.
What does Mr. Tshombe say about it?
- Will you go to U.N. ?
"Katanga, our beautiful and prosperous
Province, the largest source ...
... The main source
of our wealth. "
What time is it in Elizabeth City?
Just as late in Luluaburg?
No idea. I only hope that this
is the last stop.
We've travelled everywhere, all in 10 days.
I'm tired of this plane.
Congo is too big for us.
Do not say that. Congo is big
and requires great things.
But it is not too large.
"Who says secession, says treason."
We're descending?
Airport Elizabeth City
refuses to let us land.
I repeat, you can not land.
Orders from the government of Katanga.
What government?
This is it. Secession.
We can receive President Kasa Vubu,
but the traitor Patrice Lumumba
will never set foot in Katanga.
- That's Munongo.
Begin our descent.
- Impossible.
Do what I say!
They have placed a truck
on the runway.
We can not but go back.
We have underestimated Tshombe.
He does not do this alone.
The Belgians have encouraged him.
What do we do now?
We can choose
war, shame, resignation
and the loss of 70%
of our resources.
We have no choice.
We must suppress the uprising.
By Union Miniere, the entire financial
world is involved.
Imagine. The whole of Katanga.
It's 16 times bigger than Belgium.
They do not get such a gift.
We will call on the U.N..
Is that the best solution?
For a military operation
the Russians ...
The Russians, and have them say that I a
Communist puppet. The CIA would surely murder me?
What a calm.
It is wonderful, the silence.
Why are we going to Njili?
We said Stanleyville.
I got other directions.
You are under our command.
We decide not you.
I am Belgian, Excellency.
Attention!
Mr. President, Where do you
want the troops to take up position?
Is it a trap.
It is strange that the President
has these troops to behold?
No way!
Go provide a car.
Mr. President,
our troops are here
in order to honor and protect you.
You need them to take up position.
We refuse. You are no longer with you
Mr. President,
We welcome you with the honor
you deserve.
Never mind. Go away.
Mr. President, you do not speak
against "one" Belgian officer.
Look at those women.
They were raped by your troops.
Our men were assaulted.
You shame Africa and the world.
We are here to protect our citizens.
There should be no flow of blood.
If blood is flowing tonight,
you are responsible.
Murderers!
- Bastards!
Murderers, sadists!
You raped nuns
and white women!
The humiliation would not end.
They were ready for anything.
Even sacrificing their own citizens.
They needed someone to blame
for all this.
They had, at any cost,
the rebel silenced.
Hands on your head!
Out!
Get down!
Paratroopers!
The Belgian paratroopers are everywhere!
The white officers have
hidden the ammunition!
They removed the paratroopers there!
Send troops to the airport!
Let the Russians come are not countries!
They've evacuated their families!
They will kill us all!
Is this photograph necessary?
Do not worry.
We'll pay for everything.
It will be in every ministry,
every school
every store and bar.
Excuse me.
We will not make it.
We follow him in two months.
Fix it?
- It's war, Patrice.
The U.N. is talking about genocide.
The U.N. is manipulated
the U.S.A..
Anyway,
There are hundreds of deaths.
You had Kasai recaptured
with no organized massacre.
And what have you achieved?
Most of leaders
have fled to Katanga.
We checked Kasai.
- It was one massacre.
War means killing, kill
or be killed. That's the price.
Who pays?
Always the same!
So far I've got you covered.
But I do not support such atrocities.
Mr. Prime Minister ...
- Enough comedy!
I am a soldier and an officer.
I have proven this.
I took over the Force Publique.
I follow orders ... if any.
And if there are none ...
I make my own decisions.
Women, children,
old people. Trapped in a church
and killed?
Is that what you decided?
Answer!
No, obviously not.
But this is war.
And a war is always dirty.
It makes people crazy with fear.
And at such times
orders are useless.
You let it happen.
You have not executed the guilty.
Do you know what that will cost?
I will be held responsible.
You will isolate me even more.
You're not alone. I'm on your side.
You're not by my side.
You stand behind me.
I do not want a murderer by my side,
and certainly not behind me.
What do you mean?
You should go!
Is that clear?
That's it.
Good.
Very well. Directly.
The president can see you now.
Mr. Timberlake, nice to see you.
I tried to reach you
at the embassy.
I am far away.
- Everyone is lately.
My government has a proposal.
- A proposal?
I want to listen, but I doubt
the reliability of the U.S..
You've probably heard the Bantu proverb:
"The hand that gives, prevails."
And your hand to me seems
far too heavy. Excuse me.
Mr. Prime Minister ...
I am very worried.
The Congolese army ...
- I know.
The slaughter in Kasai.
I am appalled.
I'm talking to the guilty.
The Congo is not.
The problem remains with Katanga.
Our undisciplined troops
have committed atrocities
and U.N. betrays us
by giving passive support to the Belgians.
Ghana supports us, along with Guinea
but they have no money.
Do you have a solution?
The Russians.
They promise us airplanes,
military advisers ...
And troops for Lundula.
He will replace Mobutu, whom I distrust.
Were you not afraid that the Russians
would bring you into disrepute?
That was long ago.
We were already discredited.
What a beautiful place.
And so quiet.
I must insist.
May I ask the Russians?
I'd like to go with a better plan.
If you have one I'll run with it immediately.
I have none.
Joseph, now you have your own men ...
As long as they are paid ...
- Paid and trained.
We're investing in
Congo's future.
The future for us all.
I'll be honest with you
Kasavubu has disappointed us.
And Lumumba is in charge.
We need someone who
will work with us.
I've been thinking.
I think about it constantly.
I guarantee you everything.
Eisenhower?
- Kennedy.
What will I win there?
Everything.
We interrupt our program
to air a statement from the President.
Value compatriots,
Prime Minister Patrice Lumumba,
appointed by the Belgian king
has denied his role.
He has ruled in an arbitrary manner.
He drags the country into
in a terrible civil war.
Hence I think it is necessary
that it must end immediately.
I ask the Congolese army and our
brothers to stop the killings
and that the weapons across the republic
to fall temporarily silent.
Where's Justin?
- Gone to eat.
And Dieudonn?
- Yet again.
There's nobody here.
Take the car keys.
Where are you going?
- Parliament.
What is happening is outrageous!
Mr. Kasavubu
can not dissolve what has been
elected by the people!
We turned to no effort.
For the moment the Congo
has enjoyed the admiration of the world
Kasavubu has given us a heavy blow
and has dragged the Congo through the mud.
Silence!
The Prime Minister has the word.
Mr. President,
respectable gentlemen,
I speak to you because it is my duty
to inform you of events.
Too late!
- Congratulations!
I've never been against Kasavubu.
In any case, because
He is president and because of my actions.
It's true!
- Easy to say!
Some delegates,
also in opposition, do not agree
and say that he is a separatist.
The danger they fear is a reality.
He's right.
If the elected representatives of the people demand
Kasavubu to leave, he is deposed.
Do it!
Millions were spent
on radio campaign against me.
Every day there has been
a psychological battle fought.
In order to mislead the people
I have been named
Dictator Lumumba, Lumumba Communist,
Lumumba Moscow etc.
When we fought in the early days
for our independence,
was I prompted by the Russians?
Did I ask the Russians to
the independence negotiations?
Who has given us 80 years of exploitation?
We are not the imperialists?
Queen Elizabeth is President of
the Belgian-Russian association.
Does it show me to be a Communist?
If they hold Lumumba in contempt,
Lumumba then is the black sheep.
But actually they go on to attack
the future of the Congo.
Dear brothers,
I appeal to your wisdom,
your Bantu wisdom.
The situation is worse than you think.
We must unite, because
divided we cannot save our country.
Let us forget our divisions.
Pauline?
Acute hepatitis.
We need urgent action.
Have you seen her?
- A Treasure. She looks like you.
What will she be called?
I thought of Marie-Christine.
They will bring her to Switzerland.
They say it's her only chance.
They hid that from me.
I want my baby.
You were not in Parliament.
What is it?
- The thick ...
The President wants me to arrest you.
I wanted to warn you.
And you say I'm involved
I am a soldier.
I never butt in
on political conflicts.
Have your men surrounded the house?
A Security measure.
I am not under arrest,
but my house is surrounded?
For your own safety.
Many people want you dead.
My wife or my supporters,
Whom should I fear?
Send your men away.
- Is that a request or will you show me a warrant?
It's an order!
- Kasa you have been deposed.
And for you, he is not president anymore.
What would you do in my place?
I know you. This decision
is not yours alone.
Who stands behind you?
Who?
Out of this impasse
the army has neutralized
President Kasavubu and
Lumumba as Prime Minister.
This is not a military coup,
just a peaceful revolution.
Will there be free elections?
But politicians have been arrested?
Is this a coup?
No military power will take control.
Again, this is not a coup.
What are the Americans doing?
- Involved in a Peaceful Revolution.
We are neutral Congolese
and foreign technicians,
we chose them, to
ask for help to save our country.
Long live General Mobutu!
Not so fast.
Where's Lumumba?
- Do you support the Belgians?
How is payment reform going?
Has Lumumba been convicted?
The phone is still working,
but for how long?
I will not wait until I am isolated.
There's a simple solution.
We go to Stanleyville
and start from scratch.
Why?
We are neutralized.
and I'm trapped
and Mr. Kasavubu's a free man.
Katanga? You're kidding.
If you want to drown your dog ...
then you don't torture
him with shallow water.
Yes, I'm still here.
Excuse me.
I just read that my daughter
has died.
I can not even go to her funeral.
I cannot do anything.
Thomas, it's you.
I am determined.
We cannot tay here any longer.
Yes, I know.
I cannot stay here
under house arrest
while my supporters are being killed.
Are you safe?
Listen ...
One of us must make a sacrifice.
I will definitely be arrested,
tortured and murdered.
It's a sacrifice for the people.
Well, Thomas.
Do not worry.
Forget what I just said.
It was a joke.
Alphonse ...
I've a parcel to get?
I'll be right back.
I smoke the American brand.
Damn rain!
Runs right past your neck.
You must leave the main road.
The checkpoint at Kasimba
saw a convoy.
How far from here?
- 16 km.
Maybe less.
Thank you, comrade.
There is no boat.
We'll use the canoes.
And how is it on the other side?
We look for cars
or continue on foot.
No Patrice, I'm not going first.
Quick!
- I risk nothing.
They're hot on our heels!
I'll wait for the boat.
We leave.
Who are they?
I cannot see.
I must go back.
- No!
That is pure madness!
It is your task to reach Stanleyville.
And let them take revenge
on my family?
What will they say?
- That's suicide.
They are not numerous. They will listen.
You ungrateful creatures!
This is pure madness!
Chief, we wish you no harm.
But if we return without you,
we are slain.
And now they will kill me.
You still have regrets.
I gave you the power
of the Force Publique.
When I die, you are also dead.
He's right.
- I'm for Lumumba.
Stop this nonsense!
Excuse me, Chief,
but we recommend ...
Where were you arrested?
What about your children?
What?
Cannibal.
Very well, gentlemen, it's time to vote.
The proponents raise your hands.
Mr. Carlucci,
Will you cast your vote?
The government of my country does not intervene
in the affairs of a sovereign state.
We'll respect your decision.
This is the message:
"Ask permission from the jew
in order to receive. "
You?
- They arrested everyone.
Where are you taking us?
Katanga, 17 January 1961
I hope they do not ...
Internal bleeding.
Probably showing a perforated stomach.
Broken ribs.
If they are not brought in
for an operation,
it's only a matter of hours.
I warned you.
To never set foot in my country.
Civilians, soldiers,
on this memorable day,
the anniversary of our independence,
we greet you with joy and pride.
On behalf of the Government
we show a minute's silence
in memory of the man
we cry out as our National Hero:
Patrice Emery Lumumba.
You can pray as you wish.
Nobody knew about that night
in Katanga.
The children may not know,
do you?
They wouldn't understand.
Just tell them that I came
50 years too soon.
Tell them what we wanted
for our country,
was not wanted by others.
Dearest Pauline,
if you read this, I am dead.
Tell my children that Congo
has a great future,
that our dignity is
there to recover.
Tell them that during the fight
I had no time to hesitate
that the purpose for which we
gave our lives would be overcome.
Go get him.
Thanks.
Weep not for me, my companion.
History will be the final judge.
That history will not be
written in Brussels,
Paris or Washington.
It will be ours,
the story of a new Africa.
And on that day ...