Three, two, one, take two.
Good morning.
Welcome to Erin Mills town centre.
Home of the world's largest, permanent,
point-of-purchase video wall installation.
My name is Kelvin Flook
and I'm your video host all day here at EMTV.
I want to take this opportunity to extend
a special and warm welcome
to the film crew from Necessary Illusions.
We've got an excellent line-up
of television programming today,
so... let's get on with it.
So, how long have they been working
on this documentary?
Gosh, they've been working on it
I don't know how long.
Every country I show up, they're always there.
They're in England, they're in Japan.
All over the place.
Jesus.
They must have 500 hours of tape.
Bet they put together a really doozy
when they're done, huh?
I can't imagine who's going to want
to hear somebody talk for an hour.
But I guess they know what they're doing.
So, where are you all from?
Florida.
- Florida?
Yeah, Gulf Coast.
You all talk like in chorus.
We're making a film about Noam Chomsky.
Does anybody know who Noam Chomsky is?
No!
Good aternoon and welcome
to Wyoming Talks.
My guest today is well-known intellectual
Noam Chomsky.
Thank you for being on our programme today.
Very glad to be here.
I know probably the main purpose for your trip
to Wyoming
is to discuss thought control
in a democratic society.
Now, all right, say I'm just Jane USA.
And I say, "Well, gee, this is a democratic
society, what do you mean - thought control?"
"I make up my own mind.
I create my own destiny".
What would you say to her?
Well, I would suggest that Jane take
a close look at the way the media operate,
the way the public relations industry operates.
The extensive thinking that's been going on
for a long, long period,
about the necessity for finding ways
to marginalise and control the public
in a democratic society.
But particularly to look at the evidence
that's been accumulated,
about the way the major media,
The agenda-setting media,
I mean, the national press,
and the television and so on,
the way that they shape and control
the kinds of opinions that appear.
The kinds of information that comes through,
the sources to which they go.
I think Jane will find some very surprising things
about the democratic system.
I'd like to welcome all of you
to this lecture today.
Several years ago,
Professor Chomsky was described
in The New York Times Book Review
as follows:
"Judged in terms of the power, range, novelty
and influence of this thought, Noam Chomsky is
arguably the most important intellectual alive."
Professor Noam Chomsky.
I gather there are some people
behind that blackness there.
But if I don't look you in the eye, it's because
I don't see you, all I see is the blackness.
Perhaps I ought to begin
by reporting something that's never read.
The line about "arguably the most important
intellectual in the world," and so on
comes from a publisher's blurb
and you got to watch those.
If you go back to the original,
you'll find that that sentence is actually there.
This is in The New York Times.
But the next sentence is,
"Since that's the case, how can he write such
terrible things about American foreign policy?"
They never quote that part.
If it wasn't for that second sentence, I'd begin
to think that I'm doing something wrong.
And I'm not joking about that.
It's true that the Emperor doesn't have
any clothes but he doesn't like to be told it.
The Emperor's lap dogs, like The New York
Times, will not enjoy the experience if you do.
Good evening. I'm Bill Moyers.
What's more dangerous:
The big stick of the big lie?
Governments have used both
against their own people.
Tonight I'll be talking with a man
who has been thinking about
how we can see the developing lie.
He says that propaganda is to democracy
what violence is to a dictatorship.
But he hasn't lost faith in the power of
common people to speak up for the truth.
You have said that we live
entangled in webs of endless deceit,
that we live in a highly indoctrinated society,
where elementary truths are easily buried.
Elementary truths such as...
Such as the fact
that we invaded South Vietnam.
Or that we're standing in the way of significant,
and have for years,
of significant moves towards arms negotiation.
Or the fact that the military system
is to a substantial extent,
not totally, but to a substantial extent,
a mechanism by which the general population
is compelled to provide a subsidy
to high-technology industry.
Since they're not going to do it if you ask them
to, you have to deceive them into doing it.
There are many truths like that.
We don't face them.
Do you believe in common sense?
Absolutely.
I believe in Cartesian common sense.
I think people have the capacities to see
through the deceit in which they're ensnared.
But you got to make the effort.
It seems a little incongruous
to hear a man from the ivory tower
of Massachusetts Institute of Technology,
a scholar... a distinguished linguistics scholar,
talk about common people
with such appreciation.
I think scholarship, at least the field I work in,
has the opposite consequences.
My own studies in language and human
cognition demonstrate to me, at least,
what remarkable creativity
ordinary people have.
The very fact that people talk to one another
just in a normal way, nothing particularly fancy,
reflects deep-seated features
of human creativity,
which separate human beings
from any other biological system we know.
Tonight, scientists talk to the animals.
But are they talking back?
The Journal with Barbara Frum
and Mary Lou Finlay.
Communicating with animals
is a serious scientific pursuit.
This is Nim Chimpsky.
Nim, jokingly named ater
the great linguist Noam Chomsky,
was the great hope of animal communication
in the 1970s.
For four years Pettito and others coached him
in sign language,
but in the end they decided it was a lost cause.
Nim could ask for things, but not much more.
I would have loved
to have a conversation with Nim
and understand how he looked at the universe.
He failed to communicate that information to
me, and we gave him every opportunity.
Noam Chomsky,
theorist of language and political activist,
has had an extraordinary career.
I can think of none like it in recent American
history and few anywhere any time.
He has literally transformed
the subject of linguistics.
He also has become one of the most consistent
critics of power politics in all its protean guises.
Scholar and propagandist, his two careers
apparently reinforce each other.
In 1957, he published his Syntactic Structures,
which began what has frequently been called
the Chomskyan Revolution in Linguistics.
Like a latter-day Copernicus,
Chomsky proposed a radically new way
of looking at the theory of grammar.
Chomsky worked out the formal rules
of the universal grammar
which had generated the specific rules
of actual or natural languages.
The general approach I'm taking seems to me
rather simple minded and unsophisticated,
but, nevertheless, correct.
Later he came to argue that such systems
are innate features of human beings.
They belong to the characteristics
of the species
and have been, in effect, programmed
into the genetic equipment of the mind
like the machine language in a computer.
One needn't be interested in this question.
Of course, I am interested in it.
The interesting question from this point of view
is what is the nature of the initial state?
That is, what is human nature in this respect?
That in turn explains the...
...astonishing.
Try the next one.
Fa-cki-li-ty
- Facility.
That in turn explains the
astonishing facility children have
in learning the rules of natural language,
no matter how complicated, incredibly quickly,
from what are imperfect
and oten degenerate samples.
- Compli...
- Complicated.
It's a complicated word.
Do you know what "complicated" means?
It means it's complicated.
If in fact our minds were a blank slate
and experience wrote on them, we would be
very impoverished creatures indeed,
so the obvious hypothesis is that our language
is the result of the unfolding
of a genetically determined programme.
Well, plainly there are different languages.
In fact, the apparent variation of languages
is quite superficial.
It's certain - as certain as anything else is -
that humans are not genetically programmed
to learn one or another language.
So, you bring up a Japanese baby in Boston,
and it'll speak Boston English.
You bring up my child in Japan,
it'll speak Japanese.
And that means that... From that it fol...
from that it simply follows by logic
that the basic structure of the languages
must be essentially the same.
Our task as scientists is to try to determine
exactly what those fundamental principles are
that cause the knowledge of language to unfold
in the manner in which it does
under particular circumstances.
Incidentally,
I think there is no doubt the same must be true
of other aspects of human intelligence,
and systems of understanding
and interpretation,
and moral and aesthetic judgement, and so on.
The implications of these views
have washed over the fields of psychology,
education, sociology, philosophy,
literary criticism, and logic.
In the '50s and '60s
the bridge between your theoretical work
and your political work seems to have been
the attack on behaviourism,
but now behaviourism is no longer an issue,
or so it seems,
so how does this leave the link
between your linguistics and your politics?
Well, I've always regarded the link... I've never...
really perceived much of a link,
to tell you the truth.
Again, I would be very pleased to be able to
discover intellectually convincing connections
between my own anarchist convictions
on the one hand,
and what I think I can demonstrate,
or at least begin to see
about the nature of human intelligence
on the other.
But I simply can't find intellectually satisfying
connections between those two domains.
I can discover some tenuous points of contact.
FOUCAULT
If it is correct, as I believe it is,
that a fundamental element of human nature
is the need for creative work,
or creative inquiry for...
...for free creation without the...
...arbitrary, limiting effects of coercive
institutions,
then of course it will follow that a decent society
should maximise the possibilities
for this fundamental human characteristic
to be realised.
Now, a federated, decentralised...
...system of free associations incorporating
economic as well as social institutions
would be what I refer to as
anarcho-syndicalism,
and it seems to me that
it is the appropriate form of social organisation
for an advanced technological society
in which human beings do not have to be forced
into the position of tools, of cogs in a machine.
Since the 1960s
Noam Chomsky has been the voice
of a very characteristic brand
of rationalist libertarian socialism.
He's attacked the abuses of power
wherever he saw them,
he's made himself deeply unpopular
by his criticism of American policy,
the subservience of the intelligentsia,
the degradation of Zionism,
the distortions of media,
and self-delusions of prevailing ideologies.
Under the liberal administration of the 1960s
the club of academic intellectuals
designed and implemented the Vietnam war,
and other similar, though smaller, actions.
This particular community is a very relevant one
to consider at a place like MIT
because of course you're all free
to enter into this community.
In fact,
you're invited and encouraged to enter it.
The community of technical intelligentsia,
and weapons designers,
and counter-insurgency experts,
and pragmatic planners of an American empire,
is one that you have a great deal of inducement
to become associated with.
The inducements, in fact, are very real.
The rewards in power, and affluence,
and prestige, and authority...
Jamie?
This came with the mail.
Be with you in a second.
Oh, God, they've still got their cameras.
OK?
We'll start.
In your essay Language and Freedom,
you write, "Social action must be animated
by a vision of a future society".
I was wondering what vision of a future society
animates you?
I have my own ideas
as to what a future society should look like.
I've written about them.
I mean, I think that we should...
At the most general level, we should be
seeking out forms of authority and domination,
and challenging their legitimacy.
Sometimes they are legitimate -
that is, let's say they're needed for survival.
So, for example, I wouldn't suggest
that during the Second World War...
the forms of authority...
We had a totalitarian society, basically.
I thought there was some justification for that
under wartime conditions.
And there are other forms of...
Relations between parents and children,
for example, involve forms of coercion
which are sometimes justifiable.
But any such... Any form of coercion and...
control requires justification,
and most of them are completely unjustifiable.
Now, at various stages of human civilisation
it's been possible to challenge some of them,
but not others.
Others are too deep-seated,
or you don't see them, or whatever,
so at any particular point you try to
detect those forms of authority and domination
which are subject to change, and which...
do not have any legitimacy,
in fact which oten
strike at fundamental human rights,
and your understanding
of fundamental human nature and rights.
Well, what are the major things, say today?
There are some
that are being addressed in a way.
The feminist movement is addressing some.
The civil rights movement is addressing others.
The one major one
that is not being seriously addressed
is the one that's really
at the core of the system of domination,
and that's private control over resources.
And that means an attack
on the fundamental structure of state capitalism.
I think that's in order.
That's not something far off in the future.
Your life work.
The alphabet has only 26 letters.
With these 26 magic symbols, however,
millions of words are written every day.
Nowhere else are people so addicted
to information and entertainment
via the printed word.
Every day the world comes thumping
on the American doorstep,
and nothing that happens anywhere
remains long a secret
from the American newspaper reader.
It comes to us pretty casually, the daily paper,
but behind its arrival on your doorstep
is one ofjournalism's major stories.
How it got there.
There is a standard view about democratic
societies, and the role of the media within them.
It's expressed for example
by Supreme Court Justice Powell
when he spoke of the crucial role of the media
in effecting the societal purpose
of the First Amendment,
namely enabling the public to assert
meaningful control over the political process.
That kind of formulation
expresses the understanding that
democracy requires free access
to information, and ideas, and opinion,
and the same conceptions hold
not only with regard to the media,
but with regard to educational institutions,
publishing, the intellectual community generally.
It is basic to the health of a democracy
that no phase of government activity
escape the scrutiny of the press.
Here reporters are assigned to stories
fateful not only to our nation, but to all nations.
"Congress", says the First Amendment,
"shall pass no law
abridging the freedom of the press".
And the Chief Executive himself
throws open the doors of the White House
to journalists representing papers
of all shades of political opinion.
But is worth bearing in mind
that there is a contrary view,
and in fact the contrary view is very widely held,
and deeply rooted
in our own civilisation.
It goes back to
the origins of modern democracy,
to the 17th-century English revolution
which was a complicated affair
like most popular revolutions.
There was a struggle between Parliament
representing largely
elements of the gentry and the merchants,
and the Royalists
representing other elite groups,
and they fought it out.
But like many popular revolutions,
there was also a lot of popular ferment going
that was opposed to all of them.
There were popular movements
that were questioning everything -
the relations between master and servant,
the right of authority altogether...
All kinds of things were being questioned.
There was a lot of radical publishing - the
printing presses had just come into existence -
and this disturbed all the elites
on both sides of the Civil War.
So as one historian pointed out at the time
in 1660...
He criticised the radical democrats,
the ones who were calling for
what we would call democracy, because...
Now, underlying these doctrines
which were very widely held
is a certain conception of democracy.
It's a game for elites.
It's not for the ignorant masses
who have to be marginalised,
diverted and controlled
of course, for their own good.
The same principles were upheld
in the American colonies.
The dictum of the founding fathers
of American democracy that:
"People who own the country
ought to govern it",
quoting John Jay.
Fire!
Now, in modern times for elites,
this contrary view about the intellectual life,
and the media, and so on,
this contrary view in fact is the standard one,
I think, apart from rhetorical flourishes.
From Washington DC,
he is intellectual, author and linguist
Professor Noam Chomsky.
Manufacturing Consent -
what is that title meant to describe?
Well, the title is actually borrowed from a book
by Walter Lippmann written back around 1921
in which he described
what he called the manufacture of consent
as a revolution in the practice of democracy.
What it amounts to is a technique of control,
and he said this was useful and necessary
because the common interests, the general
concerns of all people, elude the public.
The public just isn't up to dealing with them,
and they have to be the domain
of what he called a specialized class.
Notice that that's the opposite
of the standard view about democracy.
There's a version of this expressed
by the highly respected moralist and theologian
Reinhold Niebuhr
who was very influential
on contemporary policy makers.
His view was
that rationality belongs to the cool observer,
but because of the stupidity of the average
man, he follows not reason but faith,
and this naïve faith
requires necessary illusion
and emotionally potent over-simplifications
which are provided by the myth maker
to keep the ordinary person on course.
It's not the case, as the naïve might think,
that indoctrination
is inconsistent with democracy.
Rather, as this whole line of thinkers observes,
it's the essence of democracy.
The point is that in a military state,
or a feudal state,
or what we would nowadays
call a totalitarian state,
it doesn't much matter what people think,
because you've got a bludgeon over their head,
and you can control what they do.
But when the state loses the bludgeon,
when you can't control people by force,
and when the voice of the people can be heard,
you have this problem -
it may make people so curious and so arrogant
that they don't have the humility
to submit to a civil rule,
and therefore you have to
control what people think.
And the standard way to do this
is to resort to what in more honest days
used to be called propaganda.
Manufacture of consent.
The creation of necessary illusions.
Various ways of
either marginalising the general public,
or reducing them to apathy in some fashion.
The oldest of two boys,
Avram Noam Chomsky was born in
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania in 1928.
As a Jewish child,
the anti-Semitism of the time affected him.
Both parents taught Hebrew,
and he became fascinated by literature,
reading translations
of French and Russian classics.
He also took an interest
in a grammar book written by his father
on Hebrew of the Middle Ages.
He recalls a childhood
absorbed in reading curled up on the sofa,
oten borrowing up to 12 books at once
from the library.
He is married to Carol,
and they have three children.
I don't like to
impose on my wife and children a form of life
that they certainly
haven't selected for themselves,
namely one of public exposure,
exposure to the public media.
That's their choice, and I don't believe
they themselves have selected this.
I don't impose it on them,
and I would like to protect them from it, frankly.
The second sort of perhaps principled point
is that I'm rather against the whole notion
of developing public personalities...
...who are treated as stars
of one kind or another,
where aspects of their personal life
are supposed to have some significance.
Take one in the reception room.
You said you were just like us -
you went to school, got good grades.
What made you start being critical, you know,
and seeing the different...
What started the change?
Well, you know, there are all kinds
of personal factors in anybody's life.
Don't forget I grew up in the Depression.
My parents actually happened to have jobs,
which was kind of unusual.
They were Hebrew school teachers,
so lower middle class.
For them,
everything revolved around being Jewish.
Hebrew, and Palestine in those days,
and so on.
I grew up in that milieu, so I learned Hebrew,
went to Hebrew school,
became a Hebrew school teacher,
went to Hebrew college, led youth groups,
summer camp, Hebrew camps...
The whole business.
The branch of Zionist movement
that I was part of
was all involved in socialist bi-nationalism,
and Arab-Jewish cooperation,
and all sorts of nice stuff.
What did they think of you
hopping on a train, going up to New York,
and hanging out at anarchist book stores
on Fourth Avenue, and talking to...
They didn't mind, because...
I don't want to totally trust
my childhood memories, obviously,
but the family was split up.
Like a lot of Jewish families,
it went in all sorts of directions.
There were sectors that were super-Orthodox.
There were other sectors
that were very radical, and very assimilated,
and working-class intellectuals,
and that's the sector
that I naturally gravitated towards.
It was a very lively intellectual culture.
For one thing, it was a working-class culture,
had working-class values.
Values of solidarity, socialist values, and so on.
There was a sense
somehow things would get better.
An institutional structure was around, a method
of fighting, of organising, of doing things
which had some hope.
And I also had the advantage of having gone
to an experimental progressive school,
to a Deweyite school which was quite good,
run by a university there, and you know,
there was no such thing as competition.
There was no such thing
as being a good student.
Literally, the concept of being a good student
didn't even arise until I got to high school.
I went to the academic high school,
and suddenly discovered I'm a good student.
I hated high school, because I had to do
all the things you have to do to get into college.
But until then,
it was kind of a free, pretty open system,
and lots of other things as well.
Maybe I was just cantankerous.
As a historian,
I have read with interest and amazement
your long review article
of Gabriel Jackson's Spanish Civil War.
It's a very respectable piece of history.
I appreciate how much work goes into it.
You know when I did that work?
I did that work in the early 1940s
when I was about 12 years old.
The first article I wrote was right
ater the fall of Barcelona in the school paper,
and it was a lament
about the rise of Fascism in 1939.
I guess one of the people who was
the biggest influence in my life was an uncle
who had never gone past fourth grade,
had a background in crime,
and let-wing politics, and all sorts of things.
But he was a hunchback,
and as a result
he could get a newsstand in New York.
They had some programme
for people with physical disabilities.
Some of you are from New York, I guess.
Well, you know the 72nd Street kiosk?
Yes!
That's where I got my political education.
At 72nd Street - where you come out of the
subway, everybody goes towards 72nd Street.
There were two newsstands on that side
which were doing fine,
and there's two on the back.
Nobody comes out the back,
and that's where his newsstand...
But it was a very lively place.
He was a very bright guy.
It was the '30s. There were a lot of émigrés.
A lot of people were hanging around there,
and in the evenings especially
it was sort of a literary-political salon.
There were, kind of, guys
hanging around arguing and talking, and...
as a kid, like 11, 12 years old,
the biggest excitement
was to work the newsstand.
You write in Manufacturing Consent
that it's the primary function of the mass media
in the United States
to mobilise public support
for the special interests
that dominate the government
and the private sector.
What are those interests?
Well, if you want to understand
the way any society works,
ours or any other,
the first place to look is who makes...
who is in a position
to make the decisions
that determine the way the society functions.
Societies differ, but in ours
the major decisions
over what happens in the society -
decisions over investment, and production,
and distribution and so on -
are in the hands of
a relatively concentrated network
of major corporations and conglomerates,
and investment firms, and so on.
They are also the ones who staff the major
executive positions in the government,
and they are the ones who own the media,
and they are the ones who have to be
in a position to make the decisions.
They have an overwhelmingly dominant role
in the way life happens,
you know, what's done in the society.
Within the economic system,
by law and in principle, they dominate.
The control over resources,
and the need to satisfy their interests
imposes very sharp constraints
on the political system
and the ideological system.
When we talk about manufacturing of consent,
whose consent is being manufactured?
To start with, there are two different groups.
We can get into more detail,
but at the first level of approximation,
there's two targets for propaganda.
One is what is sometimes called
the political class.
There's maybe 20 per cent of the population
which is relatively educated,
more or less articulate.
They'll play some kind of role
in decision making.
They're supposed to sort of participate
in social life,
either as managers, or cultural managers,
like, say, teachers, and writers, and so on.
They're supposed to vote.
They're supposed to play some role in the way
economic and political and cultural life goes on.
Now, their consent is crucial.
That's one group that has to be
deeply indoctrinated.
Then there's maybe 80 per cent
of the population
whose main function is to follow orders,
and not to think, you know.
Not to pay attention to anything,
and they're the ones who usually pay the costs.
All right, Professor Chomsky, Noam,
you outlined a model - filters propaganda
is sent through on its way to the public.
Will you briefly outline those?
It's basically an institutional
analysis of the major media,
what we call a propaganda model.
We're talking primarily about the national
media, those media that set a general agenda
that others more or less adhere to,
to the extent that they even pay much attention
to national or international affairs.
Now, the elite media are the sort of
agenda-setting media.
The New York Times, The Washington Post,
the major television channels, and so on.
They set the general framework.
Local media more or less adapt
to their structure.
World news.
It's a sound bite,
that says there's a beach head...
I think 628 is a good one.
This is the operative sound bite for us.
Got a minute for all the times.
I love this sound bite.
And they do this in all sorts of ways, by...
Two and a half minutes to air.
45 seconds.
There is an unusual amount of attention today
on the five nations of Central America.
This is democracy's diary.
Here, for our instruction,
are triumphs and disasters,
the pattern of life's changing fabric.
Here is great journalism,
a revelation of the past, a guide to the present,
and a clue to the future.
The New York Times is certainly the most
important newspaper in the United States,
and one could argue,
the most important newspaper in the world.
The New York Times plays an enormous role
in shaping the perception of the current world
on the part of
the politically active, educated classes.
Also, The New York Times has a special role,
and I believe its editors probably feel
that they bear a heavy burden
in the sense that
The New York Times creates history.
What happened years ago may
have a bearing on what happens tomorrow.
Millions of clippings
are preserved in the Times'library,
all indexed for instant use.
A priceless archive of events,
and the men who make them.
That is, history is what appears in
The New York Times archives.
The place where people will go to find out
what happened is The New York Times.
Therefore it's extremely important,
if history is to be shaped in an appropriate way,
that certain things appear, certain things do not,
certain questions be asked, others be ignored,
and that issues be framed
in a particular fashion.
Now, in whose interests
is history being so shaped?
Well, I think that's not very difficult to answer.
The process by which
people make up their minds on this
is a much more mysterious process
than you would ever guess
from reading Manufacturing Consent.
There is a saying about legislation,
that legislation is like making sausage.
The less you know about how it's done,
the better for your appetite.
The same is true of this business.
If you're in a conference
in which decisions are being made
on what to put on page one, or what not,
you would get, I think, the impression
that important decisions were being made
in a flippant and frivolous way,
but in fact, given the pressures of time
to try to get things out,
you resort to a kind of a shorthand,
and you have to fill that paper up every day.
It's curious in a kind of a mirror image way that
Professor Chomsky is in total accord
with Reed Irvine
who at the right-wing end of the spectrum
says exactly what Chomsky does
about the insinuating influence of the press,
of the big media
as "agenda setters", to use
one of the great buzz words of the time,
and, of course,
Reed Irvine sees this as a let-wing conspiracy,
of foisting liberal ideas in both domestic
and foreign affairs on the American people.
But in both cases,
I think that the premise really is an insult
to the intelligence of the people
who consume news.
Now, to eliminate confusion, all of this has
nothing to do with liberal or conservative bias.
According to the propaganda model, both
liberal and conservative wings of the media,
whatever those terms are supposed to mean,
fall within the same framework of assumptions.
In fact, if the system functions well, it ought
to have a liberal bias, or at least appear to,
because if it appears to have a liberal bias,
that will serve to bound thought
even more effectively.
In other words, if the press is indeed adversarial
and liberal, and all these bad things,
then how can I go beyond it?
They're already so extreme in their opposition
to power that to go beyond it
would be to take off from the planet,
so therefore it must be that the presuppositions
that are accepted in the liberal media
are sacrosanct.
Can't go beyond them.
And a well-functioning system
would in fact have a bias of that kind.
The media would then serve to say, in effect:
Thus far and no further.
We ask what would you expect of those media
on just relatively uncontroversial,
guided-free market assumptions?
And when you look at them,
you find a number of major factors
entering into
determining what their products are.
These are what we call the filters -
so one of them, for example, is ownership.
Who owns them?
The major agenda-setting media,
ater all, what are they?
As institutions in the society, what are they?
Well, in the first place
they are major corporations.
In fact, huge corporations.
Furthermore, they're integrated with, and
sometimes owned by, even larger corporations,
conglomerates, so, for example,
by Westinghouse, GE and so on.
What I wanted to know was
how specifically the elites control the media.
That's like asking,
"How do the elites control General Motors"?
Why isn't that a question?
I mean, General Motors is an institution of the
elites. They don't have to control it. They own it.
Except I guess, at a certain level I think...
Like, I guess... I work with student press,
so I know, like, reporters and stuff...
Elites don't control the student press,
but I'll tell you something -
you try in the student press
to do anything that breaks out of conventions,
and you're going to have the whole business
community around here down on your neck,
and the university's going to get threatened,
and you know...
Maybe nobody'll pay any attention to you.
That's possible.
If you get to the point
where they don't stop paying attention to you,
the pressures'll start coming.
Because there are people with power,
there are people who own the country,
and they're not going to
let the country get out of control.
What do you think about that?
This is the old cabal theory that somewhere
there's a room with a baize-covered desk,
and there are a bunch of capitalists
sitting around pulling strings.
These rooms don't exist.
I hate to tell Noam Chomsky this.
- You don't share that view?
- It's the most absolute rubbish I've ever heard.
It's the fashion in the universities.
It's patent nonsense,
and I think it's nothing but a fashion.
It's a way that...
intellectuals have of... of feeling like a clergy.
There has to be something wrong.
So, what we have in the first place
is major corporations
which are parts of even bigger conglomerates.
Now, like any other corporation, they...
they have a product which they sell to a market.
The market is advertisers,
that is, other businesses.
What keeps the media functioning
is not the audience.
They make money from their advertisers, and
remember, we're talking about the elite media,
so they're trying to sell a good product,
a product which raises advertising rates.
And ask your friends in the advertising industry.
That means
that they want to adjust their audience
to the more elite and affluent audience.
That raises advertising rates.
So what you have is institutions, corporations -
big corporations -
that are selling relatively privileged audiences
to other businesses.
Well, what point of view
would you expect to come out of this?
Without any further assumptions,
what you'd predict is
that what comes out is a picture of the world,
a perception of the world,
that satisfies the needs,
and the interests, and the perceptions
of the sellers, the buyers, and the product.
Now, there are many other factors
that press in the same direction.
If people try to enter the system
who don't have that point of view,
they're likely to be excluded
somewhere along the way.
Ater all, no institution is going to
happily design a mechanism to self-destruct.
That's not the way institutions function,
so they all work to exclude, or marginalise,
or eliminate dissenting voices,
or alternative perspectives and so on
because they're dysfunctional.
They're dysfunctional to the institution itself.
Do you think you've escaped
the ideological indoctrination
of the media and society that you grew up in?
Have I? Oten not.
I mean, when I look back,
and think of the things that I haven't done
that I should have done, it's...
it's very...
it's...
not a pleasant experience.
So, what's the story
of young Noam in the school yard?
Yeah, another...
I mean, that was a personal thing for me.
I don't know why it should interest anyone else,
but I do remember...
- You drew certain conclusions.
- It had a big influence on me.
I remember when I was about six, I guess,
first grade, there was the standard fat kid
who everybody made fun of,
and I remember in the school yard,
he was on a...
you know, standing right outside
the school classroom,
and a bunch of kids outside sort of taunting him,
and... you know, and so on,
and one of the kids actually brought over
his older brother
from third grade instead of first grade.
Big kid.
And he was going to beat him up or something,
and I remember going up to stand next to him,
feeling somebody ought to... help him,
and I did for a while, and then I got scared,
and I went away,
and I was very much ashamed of it aterwards,
and sort of felt, you know...
"I'm not going to do that again."
That's a feeling that's stuck with me -
you should stick with the underdog.
And the shame remained.
I should have stayed there.
You were already established, you were a
professor at MIT, you'd made a reputation,
you had a terrific career ahead of you.
You decided to become a political activist.
Now, here is a classic case of somebody the
institution does not seem to have filtered out.
I mean, you were a good boy up until then,
were you?
Or you'd always been a slight rebel?
Pretty much. I had been pretty much outside.
You felt isolated and out of
sympathy with the currents of American life,
but a lot of people do that.
Suddenly, in 1964,
you decide, "I have to do something about this".
What made you do that?
That was a very conscious,
and a very uncomfortable, decision,
because I knew
what the consequences would be.
I was in a very favourable position.
I had the kind of work I liked,
we had a lively, exciting department,
the field was going well, personal life was fine,
I was living in a nice place, children growing up.
Everything looked perfect,
and I knew I was giving it up,
and at that time, remember,
it was not just giving talks.
I became involved right away in resistance,
and I expected to spend years in jail,
and came very close to it.
In fact,
my wife went back to graduate school in part
as we assumed
she would have to support the children.
These were the expectations.
And I recognised
that if I returned to these interests
which were the dominant interests
of my own youth,
life would become very uncomfortable.
Because I know that in the United States
you don't get sent to psychiatric prison,
and they don't send a death squad ater you
and so on,
but there are definite penalties
for breaking the rules.
So these were real decisions,
and it simply seemed at that point
that it was just hopelessly immoral not to.
I'm Noam Chomsky, I'm on the faculty at MIT,
and I've been getting
more and more heavily involved
in anti-war activities for the last few years.
Beginning with writing articles,
and making speeches,
speaking to congressmen
and that sort of thing,
and gradually getting involved more and more
directly in resistance activities of various sorts.
I've come to the feeling myself
that the most effective form of political action
that is open to a responsible
and concerned citizen at the moment
is action that really involves direct resistance,
refusal to take part in
what I think are war crimes,
to raise the domestic cost
of American aggression overseas
through non-participation, and support
for those who are refusing to take part,
in particular,
drat resistance throughout the country.
I think that we can see quite clearly
some very, very serious defects and flaws
in our society,
our level of culture, our institutions
which are going to have to be corrected
by operating outside of the framework
that is commonly accepted.
I think we're going to have to
find new ways of political action.
I rejoice in your disposition
to argue the Vietnam question,
especially when I recognise
what an act of self-control this must involve.
It really does.
- You're doing very well.
- I lose my temper. Maybe not tonight.
Maybe not tonight...
because if you would
I'd smash you in the goddamn face.
That's a good reason for not losing your temper.
You say, "The war is simply an obscenity,
a depraved act by weak and miserable men."
Including all of us.
Including myself. That's the next sentence.
Oh, sure, sure, sure.
Because you count everybody
in the company of the guilty.
- I think that's true in this case.
- It's a theological observation.
No, I don't think so.
If everybody's guilty of everything,
then nobody's guilty of anything.
No, I don't believe that.
I think the point that I'm trying to make,
and I think ought to be made,
is that the real...
at least to me -
I say this elsewhere in the book -
what seems to me a very, in a sense, terrifying
aspect of our society and other societies
is the equanimity and the detachment
with which sane, reasonable, sensible people
can observe such events.
I think that's more terrifying than
the occasional Hitler or LeMay that crops up.
These people would not be able
to operate were it not for the...
this apathy and equanimity,
and therefore I think that it's in some sense
the sane, and reasonable, and tolerant people
who share a very serious burden of guilt
that they very easily
throw on the shoulders of others
who seem more extreme and more violent.
12 million pounds of confetti dropped into
New York City's so-called Canyon of Heroes.
Americans were officially welcoming
the troops home from the Persian Gulf war.
It worked out really great for us.
It just goes to show that we're a mighty nation,
and we'll be there no matter what comes along.
It's the strongest country in the world,
and you got to be glad to live here.
So, tell me what you feel
about media coverage of the war.
It was good. It got to be a bit much ater a while,
but I guess it was good to know everything.
In Vietnam you didn't know a lot
that was going on,
but here you're pretty much
up to the moment on everything,
so... I guess it was good to be informed.
For the first time,
because of technology, we have the ability
to be live from many locations
around the globe,
and because of the format -
an all-news network -
we can spend whatever time is necessary
to bring the viewer
the complete context
of that day's portion of the story.
And by context, I mean the institutional memory
that is critical to understand why and how,
and that's those who are analysts,
and do commentary,
and those who can explain.
Slug that last piece...
...lTN-lsrael Post War.
David Brinkley once said
that you step in front of the camera,
and you get out of news business,
and into show business,
but nonetheless
that should not in any way subtract or obscure
the need for the basic standards
of good journalism.
Hang tight. Let me
give you a lead for Salinger right now, OK?
President Bush
and Prime Minister Major have...
...closed, or have almost rejected...
the Soviet peace talk...
peace efforts in Saudi Arabia.
The door is being let open.
Rick Salinger is standing by live in Riyad.
- All but closed.
- Yeah. All but closed.
Right.
Accuracy, speed, a fair approach,
honesty and integrity within the reporter
to try and bring the truth,
whatever the truth may be.
Going to war is a serious business.
In a totalitarian society, the dictator just says,
"We're going to war", and everybody marches.
And with this weapon
of human brotherhood in our hands
we are seeing the war for men's minds
not as a battle of truth against lies,
but as a lasting alliance pledged in faith
with all those millions driving forward
to create the true new order-
the world order of the people first,
the people before all.
3In a democratic society, the theory
is, if the political leadership is committed to war
they present reasons, and they've got
a very heavy burden of proof to meet.
Because a war is a very catastrophic affair,
as it's been proved to be.
Now, the role of the media at that point is to...
is to present the relevant background.
For example,
the possibilities of peaceful settlement,
such as what they may be,
have to be presented,
and then to offer a forum... in fact encourage
a forum of debate over this very dread decision
to go to war, and in this case
kill hundreds of thousands of people,
and leave two countries wrecked, and so on.
That never happened.
There was never...
Well, you know, when I say never,
I mean 99.9 per cent of the discussion
excluded the option of a peaceful settlement.
To Washington's Office of War Information
falls one of the most vital and constructive tasks
of this war.
This is a people's war,
and to win it, the people ought to
know as much about it as they can.
This office will do its best to tell the truth,
and nothing but the truth,
both at home and abroad.
The first weapon
in this worldwide strategy of proof
is the great machine of information
represented by the free press
with its powers of moulding public thought,
and leading public action,
with all its lifelines
for the exchange of new ideas
between fighting nations
spread across the earth.
Every time Bush would appear
and say, "There will be no negotiations",
there would be a hundred editorials
the next day
lauding him
for going the last mile for diplomacy.
If he said, "You can't reward an aggressor",
instead of cracking up in ridicule
the way people did in civilised sectors
of the world like the whole Third World,
the media still...
"man of fantastic principle", you know.
The invader of Panama, the only head of state
who stands condemned
for aggression in the world,
the guy who was head of the CIA
during the Timor aggression,
he says, "Aggressors can't be rewarded",
the media just applaud it.
The motion picture industry with
its worldwide organisation of newsreel crews,
invaluable for bringing into vivid focus
the background drama
and perspectives of the war.
Mobilised too in this all-out struggle
for men's minds are the radio networks,
with all their experience in the swift reporting
of great occasions and events.
From every strategic centre
and frontline stronghold
their reporters are sending back
the lessons of new tactics,
new ways of war.
The result was it's a media war.
There's tremendous fakery all along the line.
The UN is finally living up to its mission.
"A wondrous sea change",
The New York Times told us.
The only wondrous sea change
was that for once
the United States didn't veto a Security Council
Resolution against aggression.
People don't want a war
unless you have to have one,
and would've known
you don't have to have one.
The media kept people from knowing that,
and that means we went to war
very much in the manner of a totalitarian state,
thanks to the media subservience.
That's the big story.
Now, remember I'm not talking about
a small radio station in Laramie.
I'm talking about
the national agenda-setting media.
If you run a radio news show in Laramie,
chances are very strong that you pick up
what was in The Times that morning,
and you decide that's the news.
In fact, if you follow the AP wires,
you find it in the aternoon.
They send across tomorrow's front page
of The New York Times.
That's so that everybody knows
what the news is.
The perceptions and perspectives
and so on are sort of transmitted down,
not to the precise detail, but the general picture
is pretty much transmitted elsewhere.
The foreign news comes here
to the Foreign News desk.
The editor is Bob Hanley.
Bob, I suppose you get far more foreign news
than you can possibly use in the paper.
Yes, we do. We get a great deal more
than we can accommodate in a day.
Your job is to weed it out, I suppose.
This is the selection centre, as it were,
and when I have selected it
I pass it across the desk
to one or the other of the sub-editors.
It comes back to me,
and on this chart I design the page.
That is page one and page two.
Fine, Bob. Thank you very much.
- Why do you want to make a film about Media?
- Well...
Such a nice, quiet town.
It's a beautiful town.
We're making a film about the mass media,
so we thought what a good place to come.
Want to know where they got the name?
Maybe you could start
by introducing yourself.
Yes, I'm Bodhon Senkow.
I'm the main street manager and executive
director of the Media Business Authority,
and we are in Media, Delaware County,
in the southeastern part of Pennsylvania.
Media is called "Everybody's hometown".
The motto was developed
as a way to promote the community.
We're a very high
promotion-conscious community.
When you walk through Media,
you'll be treated very well,
and you find that people have taken the idea
of being everybody's hometown to heart.
The local paper, The Talk of the Town...
The Town Talk.
- Do you read that?
- Yes, I read The Town Talk.
What do you think the difference is between
The Wall Street Journal and The Talk?
Well, I mean, The Town Talk
is completely local news,
and it's fun, it's nice to read, it's interesting.
You read about your neighbours, see what's
going on in the district, and things like that.
We're in business to make bucks,
just like the big daily newspapers,
and like the big radio stations,
and we do quite well,
and rightfully so, cos we work very hard at it.
I just wanna show you a copy of the paper here,
the way it is this week.
It's plastic-wrapped on all four sides.
Weatherproof,
and hung on everybody's front door.
And many times you'll find this paper runs
well over 100 pages a week.
You have to remember there are five editions.
This happens to be
the Central Delaware County edition,
which is the edition
that covers Media, Pennsylvania.
What you see here
is the advertising and composition department.
- Say hello, guys, will you?
- Hi.
And what we're doing now is we're putting
red dots, green dots, and yellow dots
up on the map wherever there is a store.
The red dots are the stores
that don't advertise with us at all.
The green dots are the ones
that advertise with us every week,
and the yellow dots
are the ones that run sporadically.
Now, we have computer print-outs
of every one of these stores,
and what we do is we take the print-outs
of all the red dots which are the bad guys,
and our idea is to turn these red dots into yellow
dots, and turn the yellow dots into green dots,
and eventually make them all green dots,
so 100 per cent of the stores
and 100 per cent of the merchants and service
people advertise in our paper every week.
That way, we won't have any more red dots.
I guess there'll always be a few,
but I have high hopes
there'll be a lot more green ones
than red when we're finished.
Hi, I'm Jim Morgan.
I'm with the Corporate Relations Department
of The New York Times,
and I'm here to take you on a tour
of The New York Times, so... let's begin.
So, they're just taking audio in here, yeah.
They're taking audio in here.
Audio. No cameras, no still.
We went over this quite thoroughly.
They don't even take a still camera in here.
We're in the composing room.
This is where the pages are composed.
This is the typographical area.
This might seem big, but it is average.
In fact, below average.
Our 60 per cent might include on some days
maybe...
20 pages of classified advertising all to itself,
where the rest of the newspaper
is weighted much heavier news to advertising,
but the paper in its entirety every day,
large or small,
is 60 ads, 40 news.
Well, that completes our tour
of The New York Times,
and I hope you found it informative, and...
...I hope that you read The New York Times
every day of your life from now on.
There are other media too
whose basic social role is quite different.
It's diversion.
There's the real mass media, the kinds
that are aimed at the guys who... Joe Six-pack.
That kind. The purpose of those media
is just to dull people's brains.
This is an over-simplification,
but for the 80 per cent or whatever they are,
the main thing for them is to divert them,
to get them to watch National Football League,
and to worry about the... you know...
mother with child with six heads,
or whatever you pick up in the... you know...
in the thing that you pick
up on the supermarket stands, and so on.
Or, you know, look at astrology, or get involved
in fundamentalist stuff, or something.
Just get them away, you know.
Get them away from things that matter.
And for that,
it's important to reduce their capacity to think.
The sports section is handled
in another special department.
The sports reporter must be a specialist
in his knowledge of sports.
He gets his story right at the sporting event,
and often sends it in to his paper play by play.
Sports.
That's another crucial example
of the indoctrination system in my view.
For one thing, because it... you know,
it offers people something to pay attention to
that's of no importance.
- That keeps them from worrying about...
...keeps them from worrying
about things that matter to their lives
they might have some idea
about doing something about.
And in fact, it's striking to see the intelligence
that's used by ordinary people in sports.
You listen to radio stations where people call in.
They have the most exotic information
and understanding
about all kinds of arcane issues,
and the press undoubtedly does a lot with this.
I remember in high school - I was pretty old -
I suddenly asked myself at one point,
"Why do I care
if my high school team wins the football game?"
I mean, I don't know anybody on the team,
you know.
It had nothing to do with me.
I mean, why am I cheering for my team?
It doesn't make any sense.
But the point is, it does make sense.
It's a way of building up irrational attitudes
of submission to authority,
and, you know, group cohesion behind...
you know, leadership elements.
In fact, it's training in irrational jingoism.
That's also a feature of competitive sports.
I think...
If you look closely at these things,
I think, typically, they do have functions,
and that's why
energy is devoted to supporting them,
and creating a basis for them,
and advertisers are willing to pay for them.
I'd like to ask you a question
about the methodology
and study in the propaganda model,
and how would one go about doing that?
Well, there are a number of ways to proceed.
One obvious way is to try to find
more or less paired examples.
History doesn't offer true controlled
experiments,
but it oten comes pretty close.
So one can find atrocities or abuses of one sort
that on the one hand are committed
by official enemies, and on the other hand
are committed by friends and allies,
or by the favoured state itself.
By the United States, in the US' case.
The question is whether the media
accept the government framework,
or whether they use the same agenda,
same set of questions,
the same criteria for dealing with the two cases
as any honest outside observer would do.
If you think America's involvement
in the war in Southeast Asia is over, think again.
The Khmer Rouge are the
most genocidal people on the face of the earth.
Peter Jennings
Reporting From The Killing Fields.
Thursday.
I mean, the great act of genocide
in the modern period is Pol Pot.
1975 to... through 1978.
That atrocity...
I think it would be hard to find any example
of a comparable outrage and outpouring of fury,
and so on and so forth,
so that's one atrocity.
It just happens that in that case,
history did set up a controlled experiment.
Ever heard of a place called East Timor?
- I can't say that I have.
- Where?
- East Timor.
- No.
Well, it happens that right at that time
there was another atrocity.
Very similar in character,
but differing in one respect -
we were responsible for it, not Pol Pot.
Hello. I'm Louise Penney,
and this is Radio Noon.
If you've been listening to the programme
fairly regularly over the last few months,
you'll know East Timor has come
into the conversation more than once,
particularly when we were talking about foreign
aid, and also the war, and a new world order.
People wondered why,
if the UN was serious about a new world order,
no-one was doing anything to help East Timor.
The area was invaded by Indonesia in 1975.
There are reports of atrocities
against the Timorese people,
and yet Canada and other nations
have consistently
voted against UN Resolutions
to end the occupation.
Today, we're going to take a closer look
at East Timor,
what's happened to it, and why the international
community is doing nothing to help.
One of the people who have been most active
is Elaine Briére,
a photojournalist from British Columbia.
She's the founder of
the East Timor Alert Network,
and she joins me in the studio now.
- Hello.
- Hi.
One tragedy compounding a tragedy
is that a lot of people
don't know much about East Timor.
- Where is it?
- East Timor is just north of Australia.
About 420 km, and it's right between
the Indian and Pacific oceans.
Just south of East Timor is a deep-water sea
lane perfect for US submarines to pass through.
There's also huge oil reserves there.
One of the unique things
about East Timor is that
it's truly one of the last surviving
ancient civilisations in that part of the world.
The Timorese spoke
30 different languages and dialects
amongst a group of 700,000 people.
Today less than five per cent of the world's
people live like the East Timorese.
Basically self-reliant, they live really outside
of the global economic system.
Small societies like the East Timorese are much
more democratic and much more egalitarian,
and there's much more sharing
of power and wealth.
Before the Indonesians invaded,
most people lived in small rural villages.
The old people in the village
were like the university.
They passed on tribal wisdom
from generation to generation.
Children grew up
in a safe, stimulating, nurturing environment.
A year ater I let East Timor, I was appalled
when I heard Indonesia had invaded.
It didn't want a small, independent country
setting an example for the region.
East Timor was a Portuguese colony.
Indonesia had no claim to it,
and in fact stated that they had no claim to it.
During the period of colonisation,
there was a good deal of politicisation
that different groups developed.
A civil war broke out in August '75.
It ended up in a victory for Fretilin,
which was one of the groupings,
described as populist Catholic in character,
with some typical letist rhetoric.
Indonesia at once started intervening.
What's the situation?
When did those ships come in?
They start arriving since Monday.
Six, seven boats together,
very close to our border.
They're not there just for fun.
They're preparing a massive operation.
Something happened here
last night that moved us very deeply.
It was so far outside our experience
as Australians
that we'll find it very difficult
to convey to you, but we'll try.
Sitting on woven mats under a thatched roof
in a hut with no walls
we were the target of a barrage of questioning
from men who know they may die tomorrow,
and cannot understand
why the rest of the world does not care.
That's all they want -
for the United Nations to care about
what is happening here.
The emotion here last night was so strong
that we, all three of us, felt we should
be able to reach out into the warm night air
and touch it.
Greg Shackleton, at an unnamed village
which we will remember forever
in Portuguese Timor.
Ford and Kissinger visited Jakarta,
I think it was December 5th.
We know that they had requested that
Indonesia delay the invasion until ater they let
because it would be too embarrassing.
And within hours, I think, ater they let,
the invasion took place on December 7th.
What happened on December 7th in 1975,
is just one of the great evil deeds of history.
Early in the morning
bombs begin dropping on Dili.
The number of troops that invaded Dili that day
almost outnumbered
the entire population of the town.
And for two or three weeks,
they just killed people.
This Council must consider Indonesian
aggression against East Timor
as the main issue of the discussion.
When the Indonesians invaded,
the UN reacted as it always does,
calling for sanctions and condemnation
and so on.
Various watered-down resolutions
were passed,
but the US were very clearly
not going to allow anything to work.
So the Timorese were fleeing into the jungles
by the thousands.
By late 1977, '78
Indonesia set up receiving centres
for those Timorese
who came out of the jungle waving white flags.
Those the Indonesians thought more educated,
or suspected of belonging to Fretilin or other
opposition parties were immediately killed.
They took women aside,
and flew them off to Dili in helicopters
for use by the Indonesian soldiers.
They killed children and babies.
But in those days their main strategy
and their main weapon was starvation.
By 1978,
it was approaching really genocidal levels.
The church and other sources
estimated about 200,000 people killed.
The US backed it all the way.
The US provided 90 per cent of the arms.
Right ater the invasion,
arms shipments were stepped up.
When the Indonesians
actually began to run out of arms in 1978,
the Carter administration moved in
and increased arms sales,
and other western countries did the same.
Canada, England... Holland...
Everybody who could make a buck
was in there,
trying to make sure
they could kill more Timorese.
There is no western concern
for issues of aggression,
atrocities, human rights abuses and so on
if there's a profit to be made from them.
Nothing could show it more clearly
than this case.
It wasn't that nobody had heard of East Timor.
Remember there was plenty of coverage
in The New York Times and elsewhere
before the invasion.
The reason was there was concern
over the break-up of the Portuguese empire
and what that would mean.
There was fear it would lead to independence,
or Russian influence, or whatever.
Ater the Indonesians invaded,
the coverage dropped.
There was some,
but it was strictly from the point of view
of the State Department
and Indonesian generals.
Never a Timorese refugee.
As the atrocities reached their maximum peak
in 1978,
when it really was becoming genocidal,
coverage dropped to zero
in the United States and Canada,
the two countries I've looked at closely.
Literally dropped to zero.
All this was going on at exactly the same time
as the great protest of outrage over Cambodia.
The level of atrocities was comparable.
In relative terms
it was probably considerably higher in Timor.
It turns out that right in Cambodia in the
preceding years, 1970 through 1975,
there was also a comparable atrocity
for which we were responsible.
The major US attack against Cambodia
started with the bombings of the early 1970s.
They reached a peak in 1973,
and they continued up till 1975.
They were directed against inner Cambodia.
Very little is known about them,
because the media wanted it to be secret.
They knew it was going on. They just
didn't want to know what was happening.
The CIA estimates about 600,000 killed
during that five-year period,
which is mostly either US bombing,
or a US-sponsored war.
So that's pretty significant killing.
Also, the conditions
in which it let Cambodia were such
that high US officials predicted that about
a million people would die in the atermath
just from hunger and disease
because of the wreckage of the country.
Pretty good evidence
from US government and scholarly sources
that the intense bombardment
was a significant force - maybe a critical force -
in building up peasant support for the Khmer
Rouge who were a pretty marginal element.
Well, that's just the wrong story.
Ater 1975,
atrocities continued,
and that became the right story -
now they're being carried out by the bad guys.
Well, it was bad enough.
In fact, current estimates are... well, they vary.
The CIA claim 50,000 to 100,000 people killed,
and maybe another million or so
who died one way or another.
Michael Vickery is the one person
who's given a really close, detailed analysis.
His figure is maybe
750,000 deaths above the normal.
Others like Ben Kiernan suggest higher figures,
but so far without a detailed analysis.
Anyway, it was terrible.
No doubt about it.
Although the atrocities - the real atrocities -
were bad enough,
they weren't quite good enough
for the purposes needed.
Within a few weeks
ater the Khmer Rouge takeover,
The New York Times
was already accusing them of genocide.
At that point, maybe a couple of hundred
or a few thousand people had been killed.
And from then on,
it was a drum beat, a chorus of genocide.
The big bestseller on Cambodia and Pol Pot
is called Murder of a Gentle Land.
Up until April 17th, 1975,
it was a gentle land of peaceful, smiling people,
and ater that some horrible holocaust
took place.
Very quickly,
a figure of two million killed was hit upon.
In fact,
what was claimed was that the Khmer Rouge
boast of having murdered two million people.
Facts are very dramatic.
In the case of
atrocities committed by the official enemy,
extraordinary show of outrage,
exaggeration, no evidence required.
Faked photographs are fine, anything goes.
Also a vast amount of lying.
I mean, an amount of lying
that would have made Stalin cringe.
It was fraudulent,
and we know that it was fraudulent
by looking at the response
to comparable atrocities
for which the United States was responsible.
Early '70s Cambodia, and Timor too -
very closely paired examples.
Well, the media response was quite dramatic.