This film is dedicated to the
known and unknown heroes...
as victors of the first battle
during World War l.
The battle took place on
the mountain of Cer,
In Serbia, August 1914.
THE MARCH TO THE DRINA
Starring in order of appearance
"The March to the Drina"
Composed in 1914
by Stanislav Binicki.
After the wars with Turkey
in 1912 and Bulgaria in 1913,
an exhausted Serbia was
at the verge of another war.
Belgrade
July 26, 1914.
MOBILISATION
TO THE SERBIAN PEOPLE
Hey kid, bring me a paper.
Veca!
Close the door, Veca.
It's war, son.
Where are you assigned to?
It's the same battery,
but in a combined division.
I've just spoken
to Mr Rajkovic.
Here is your coffee.
Does he need another supplier
and delegate from France.
Send my regards to him.
I'm not going anywhere.
Our hero wants
to go to war again.
There are whispers that many
are leaving by commission.
There are many who want to
leave, and I'm afraid they will.
Good luck to them,
Uncle Laza.
I went last time. Now
it's someone else's turn.
It wasn't bad over there.
Would you feel better lying
in mud, hungry and thirsty?
It was great! That commission
makes me sick to this day!
So many of my friends died,
while I... -Veca, my son.
I'm not leaving! I'm joining
the battery and that's that!
Veca, I know what duty means,
but you were five times more
useful in the commission.
Anyone can stand
behind a gun,
but those guns
have to be purchased.
You were ten times more
useful. -Thank you, Uncle.
I wasn't any use to the Serbs,
to myself or to this bank.
Even in this office,
all I am is a pen pusher.
Milena, have a safe trip and
send my regards to Uncle Uros.
Thank you, Veca.
Hi, Veca. Son, here are some
balloons and some water.
Don't give him any now.
He's just eaten some pears.
Kosta, take care of yourself.
-I will. Send my regards.
Tell father to look
after you and the child.
Don't forget to write.
I will. Good-bye and
have a safe journey.
Come here, son.
Brother Kole, they're leaving!
Trivun is waiting for you.
-I know. I'll be there.
Do you know why?
-I can't think about that now.
Where are you going now?
-To headquarters, of course.
I need to talk to you.
-Oh, no. Let's go! Tonight.
Brother Kole!
Gentlemen and Friends!
-Brother Kole!
I'm much better addressing guns,
but I will tell you this.
We have to go because
they want to trample on us!
Who knows when we'll be
able to get together again.
So, let's drink and make
this a night to remember.
What is it, you snots?
It's "hooray" in the café,
but when you're standing in
your ranks, you'll be cursing!
Get back!
A drink for Kursula!
Get back, now! When you put
on your tunic, get back to me.
Today, I'm not
talking to civilians!
I'm only drinking with
Serbian soldiers. -Kursula!
Brother Kole!
How are you, my beauties?
Brother Kole, I've been looking
everywhere for you!
Hello, Badza! Join us.
When are you leaving?
I should be on my way,
but I need to dampen my throat.
I've been running around the
last three days and nights.
Where have you been
the Last few days?
Business. So much, that my
head hurts. -It can happen.
Gentlemen, this captain used
to turn this town inside out!
He'd chase the gendarme and
whores would jump out of windows!
Now he's washing nappies!
Perfume for the wife
and money in the bank!
I heard that the Major
is getting married?
I was going to, honestly.
It's just that Serbia can't have
two years of peace in a row.
Or I just don't know how to,
not Like our Captain here.
That's correct, Major!
He's my cousin,
more Like a brother. He used
to be my hero! Like a God!
And tell us brother,
who are you?
I told you, that's Veca.
Artillery Lieutenant,
Velimir Hadzi-Vukovic.
Where's your uniform, brother?
Why are you still a civilian?
I'm Leaving tomorrow with the
combined division. Aren't I?
Stop conspiring with Trivun!
Am I staying in the battery?
It's not my decision to make.
We know who decides. Sit down.
Honestly, what do you think...
-Sit down and keep still!
Veca, brother Kole! I've
finally caught up with you.
Good evening, Uncle Laza.
-Kid, tonight you're buying.
Trivun's arranged everything.
-What has he arranged?
All you have to do is report
to Colonel Lukic tomorrow.
Who's this Colonel Lukic?
Tell me the truth!
He's a great man! You'll find
it easy under his command.
Zdravko M. Lukic.
Commissions and the like.
Parlez, parlez, s'il vous plait!
You've got it Lucky, brother!
You can all forget it!
You, the Colonel and Trivun!
Last time he tricked me from
joining the army. Not again!
Well talk tomorrow.
-Stop! Wait!
I'm busy, Veca.
Good night, gentlemen.
I don't give a damn about
your business! Stop!
I haven't been home since this
morning. My wife will hang me.
First I want you to Listen
to what I have to say!
Leave me alone, child!
-Uncle Laza, stop, wait!
Everyone's staring at us! God
help me, you've gone crazy!
Oh, Serbia, Mother dear...
Arandjelovac
August 10, 1914
At ease! Today's exercise is
over. Make sure you rest well.
When a man falls out of
a tree, he must also rest.
Make sure that your conduct
is that becoming of a soldier.
You, boy! Two paces forward!
-Who? Me?
Who do you think?
My father?
You called my "Sergeant"?
-I sure did, Sergeant!
If someone
calls me Sergeant,
it's because we've been
through two wars together!
You are to address me as
"Sergeant, Sir"! Understood?
Understood, Sergeant, Sir!
-Dismissed!
I told you to be careful.
You didn't join yesterday!
In a battery, the Sergeant is
a god. Don't ever forget that!
Otherwise youll be scratching
where it doesn't itch!
They really Look alike,
just like grenades.
The first quads in Serbia.
They were in the newspaper.
Congratulations, Sergeant,
and may they live Long.
I've already congratulated
him. He's a Lucky man.
Some have to slave four times,
but he only had to once.
I'm surprised to see you here.
I thought you quit the army.
I wanted to, but I couldn't
get used to civilian clothing.
I Like it when everyone knows
his duty. -Correct, Sergeant!
The sacred rule
of the army is,
if you take care of your own
business, there's no reproach.
The Lieutenant is singing.
-Let him.
As Long as he's with us,
we'll be safe.
Last time they sent him away,
we fought a terrible battle!
I won't have such talk! They
were his orders. Understood?
Understood, Sir! I just wonder
why we never get such orders.
Keep wondering, but I don't
want to hear such talk!
He's a Lieutenant
and that's that!
Correct, Sir, strictly
according to regulations.
You Listen or I'll
shut your mouth!
Professor!
Are you getting used to the
battery? -Ill be fine.
It's easier in the army,
than dealing with my family.
My family, even brother Kole,
wanted to send me away again.
You won't find it that easy.
I was about to tell you.
They remember,
and so they should.
I'd feel the same towards
anyone who ran from the army.
Ill have plenty of
time to show them.
Come on men, down to business.
Let's fill up these seats!
Sergeant, would you
Like some tobacco?
All you do is waste your time
gambling! -Stop wining!
Tomorrow we'll be
gambling with our Lives!
The Commander isn't even here.
He's gone to headquarters.
I pay in cash. Just like the
Lieutenant's father, Trivun.
I made a joke about him
and got into trouble.
And so you should,
you behave Like a beast!
Wash your feet or I'll choke
before I get near the Krauts!
Let's see...
You're lucky this time.
I'm fit and well. -Leave
that letter and join us!
The first litter is
thrown into water,
and the first letter
is not sent home.
Exactly! They cry for days,
when they get their first Letter.
Come on Alexa,
stop being stingy!
Hey, you rogue, don't you know
that gambling is forbidden?
I know. Join us.
-Did you ask for permission?
I did. -Whose?
-My backside's. -What?!
I asked if it could
withstand 25 lashes.
It said it could. Join us.
Watch out! He doesn't seem
to Like your wise remarks.
Open it, Major.
The 5th and 6th enemy armies
are heading towards the Drina.
The 5th has crossed the river.
Our 3th is under pressure.
One might think this is the
enemie's main attack plan.
Logically, it's not, because
of the difficult terrain.
The enemie's 2nd army,
Located in Srem and Banat,
is bombing Belgrade
and Obrenovac.
It's preparing to attack
Sabac. This is also a fact.
I was in Arandjelovac today.
It's the first time I Liked it.
Gorgeous women! Many
who escaped from Belgrade.
There are whores, as well.
-Anything to say, Kursula?
Nothing, Sir. Private remarks.
-Let us hear them.
I bet that the attacks on the
Sava and Danube are tricks.
The main attack will be at the
Drina. -You find that logical?
If there's only one army
attacking from the north,
and two on the Drina, then
that'll be the main attack.
Well see. Gentlemen,
we have orders to move.
The division is to gather
At Ub, monitor situations,
and react accordingly.
Our regiment will
head the division,
along with the artillery
division. That will be all.
Return to your units
and prepare to move.
Youll have more
details in an hour.
Captain, a moment, please.
-I'll wait for you.
This march could pose special
tasks for your battery. -Yes, Sir!
Are you satisfied with
the state of your battery?
In general. -We could
replace your Lieutenant.
Hadzi-Vukovic is my relative
and was in my battery before.
He's the only son
of a noted family.
They still want to persuade
him. -To Leave the army?
Yes. I'm in a difficult
position. He's close to me.
Let's just Leave it for now.
-Well, you're the Commander.
Where are you going now?
Do you have time for a drink?
I'd love to. What's all that
nonsense about the Drina?
You failed your exams because
of that. -Listen, brother.
Austria's main attack will be
across the Drina, not the Sava.
It's not suitable for an attack.
-That's what they say.
General Stepa repeatedly
told me. "It's not Logical.
The best strategic attack is
across the Sava and Danube."
I said: "The Austrians know
we'll be waiting on the Sava,
and that's why theyll
attack from the Drina."
Well be waiting in the hills
and beat them to a pulp!
Let's make a bet! I say the main
attack will come from the Drina!
Rista!
-Yes, Sir!
Get me Second Lieutenant
Stojanovic! -Yes, Sir.
What time is it?
-After midnight. 12.20.
Try to sleep in the saddle.
Youll need it.
Don't worry about me.
I can handle anything.
Sir, the Commander
is asking for you.
I should have told him
to ask where we're going.
It's against regulations. I hope
we pass through Sabac.
I want to help them, because
the Krauts are bombing them.
I don't care,
even if we go to Vienna.
They say the bridge
is weak here.
Take two men and check it.
If the bridge is incapable,
find a ford. Be back by dawn.
All right, Kosta.
Rista! Milan! Follow me!
Brother Kole, I should have gone.
I'm the Lieutenant.
Miloje will do it better.
It's dark.
It's dark, but there's
a map. I can read it.
Forget about it. Take out
that bottle of cognac.
Do you want some
tobacco, Sergeant? -No.
What are you staring at?
Are you posing for me?
You're worried. Something's
eating at you. -I agree.
You're worrying a lot
about something, Sergeant.
I'm worrying where youll
sleep and what youll eat.
Who's going to worry
about my family?
Your wife will, Sergeant.
Is she pretty?
That's none of your business.
If she's pretty, someone
will always take care of her.
Other men's wives are the
best! -The sweetest!
Stop this indecent talk
in front of this child.
This here child is married.
Since when? -The other day.
What other day? -One day
before I was mobilised.
They interrupted you
in the middle of it!
Why did you get married now?
Did you manage to do anything?
Where Little brother, how?
-In the dark.
You haven't even seen all of
her. Did you undress her?
We peasants are shy.
We don't undress.
She won't be shy when you get
back. Experts will teach her.
That's war. She can be pure as
snow, but when her time comes!
Stop it, you mongrel! The
Likes of you should be shot!
Sergeant! -How dare you talk
Like that about decent women?!
You're a thief and fraud who
doesn't have a pot to piss in!
My wife is the daughter
of a priest. You bastard!
Wait, Sergeant!
-Not another word!
They're housewives and mothers!
I swear I'll kill you!
Stop! Stop the gun! Corporal!
A man has fallen!
-What happened?
Corporal!
Help me men! Help!
It's the gambler!
Turn his head up!
Aleksa, give him some water!
-What? -Get out the flask!
Hold his head up!
-Come on!
What's wrong?
-Hit him on the back.
You're beating the Life
out of me! Stop it!
Look, you dropped your cards!
The tools of your trade.
What happened?
-Nothing, Sir,
the time adjuster fell of the
gun. He's fine. -Very well.
Ill go and see.
-Go on.
Look at all this money!
You could build a church!
Photos as well! A girl!
Maybe it's his relative.
He can't have any relatives.
Who did you steal them from?
Don't touch! Give them back,
you thieves!
I wouldn't let God himself
touch them! Back off!
You're crazy! We weren't
going to eat them!
You crazy gambler!
Come on, Aleksa!
Take your tools!
You've disrupted the entire
battery, you good-for nothing!
Who told you to dismount?
-We need to relieve ourselves!
They wouldn't dare piss
on state saddles! Aleksa!
Mount!
Lieutenant, Sir,
you wouldn't believe it!
Trajko, the cook, was telling
Bogi his future. He said:
"You're going to fall
from a height." And he did.
Corporal, enough
of this superstition!
Yes, Sir, but he did fall!
-That's enough!
Sergeant, can we go on?
-Ready, Sir!
Lazarevac
August 14, 1914
Hey, Trajko! -Here I am,
Corporal Janicije!
Trajko! -I'm here!
Old man, can you do something
for me? Ill pay you.
For you, dear? Who's going to
help me with these beans?
Forget the beans! Please,
Look at your cards!
I was so scared last night!
I heard an owl, twice!
An owl? -I asked, but
no one heard it, except me.
Listen, dear, it's not a good
sign, but you never know.
Come back Later. -Something
bad is going to happen?
You're going to war, dear.
It can only be bad, not good.
Please, can you Look now?
-Ail right. -Take out the cards.
Look. Maybe I can escape my
misfortune. -We'll see.
Cut.
-What? -Cut.
What is it?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7...
Home, happiness, wife.
>Ub
August 14, 1914
Sir, do you mind if the men
get out of the pouring rain?
So they should, Corporal.
Men, who would like a smoke?
-You shouldn't. -Oh, don't.
Go on, who knows how
Long we'll have to wait.
Thank you, Sir. This one
could Last me a Long time.
Take one! Stop being shy as a
bride. -I don't smoke, Sir.
No one in my family does. Only
my youngest brother, Proka.
He's just become a corporal.
How many brothers do you have?
-I had a lot of brothers,
but they were killed
in the Last two wars.
Now, there's only Proka and
myself. He's still so young.
I'm always thinking of him.
He's a teacher, now a corporal.
Boys, you'd be happy about
this rain, if you were home.
Just when the summer sun
is about to burn everything,
it rains, just like this. I
say to Proka: "It's raining."
I go and stand in the rain.
It's as if God is crying.
Even though I'm wet, I still
can't believe it's raining.
When I reach the wet plums,
then I know it's raining.
Damn this war! But we have to,
because they attacked us.
That's right, Sir, we
have to defend ourselves.
When you came, did you
notice us Laughing? -No, why?
We were observing the gambler
making passes at that lady.
He's skilful. Do you
think hell do it?
He could, if we
stayed Long enough.
Dear Lady, I forgot to ask
you the most important thing.
Where's your husband?
-In the army, on the Drina.
That's no good. We're in the
same boat: we're both alone.
What can we do? It's God will.
-You're absolutely right.
We could help each other,
you know. Times are like that.
Stop that. Aren't you a jolly
fellow? I might report you.
Ill knock his teeth out!
-Can't you see he's all talk?
She's Serbian. Maybe her
husband's a soldier, like you.
Petrovic! -Who, me?
-No, my father! Come here!
Can't you see that the
bar is loose? Fix it!
It's on the first gun.
That's not my job.
Don't smart-mouth me!
Move it!
I don't even know
what time of day it is!
Good evening, Sir.
-Hello, Brother Kole. -Hello.
Gentlemen, the situation has
changed since yesterday.
Headquarters now believes
that the enemy won't attack...
from the north across the
Sava and Danube rivers.
It seems that the main attack
will come from the Drina...
with the enemy's
5th and 6th armies.
It seems that Mr Kursula's
assumptions were correct.
Congratulations, Major!
-Thank you, Sir!
Tomorrow your units must be in
the village of Veliki Bosnjak.
Here are your orders
in more detail.
What's the situation
in the battery?
The men are tired, Sir. They
haven't slept since yesterday.
That I know! What about
their morale? -Good, Sir!
It's very important it stays
that way. -Understood, Sir!
Goodbye, gentlemen.
Let's see where they're
sending us, brother.
... She washed her feet,
then fell into the river...
Did you hear the old man's
voice tremble when he said:
"You were right, Kursula."
He would have given anything
not to have to admit it.
If I could see General Stepa,
I'd ask him now:
"Why didn't I pass the exam?'
We're going west,
towards the Drina.
Infantry, let the battery pass!
Move aside! Now!
Keep going, you gunners!
Make sure you don't tire
from all that sitting!
Youll be kissing this gun,
the minute it gets rough!
Really? We're scared we'll
Lose the war without you!
Shut up, you arse!
-Your wife's an arse!
Dusty arses!
-Horse shit!
You had a nap.
Good for you. Who knows
what's waiting for us.
My watch stopped.
What time is it? -Nearly seven.
I keep thinking of Sabac.
Why did we give it up so fast?
What's the exact time?
-Five to seven.
It's best that the men
don't know about Sabac.
Give me that flask!
Captain, Sir! -Yes! -I have a
favour to ask. I don't know...
Come on Sergeant, we've known
each other for a Long time.
Why are you hesitating?
-This isn't official.
Go on. -I don't know where to
begin. It's a personal matter.
Sir, my wife and children
are all alone in Sabac.
Could I pop over to Sabac and
take my family to safety?
Pop over? -You have my word
Ill return. No one would know.
If it were up to me, I'd Let
you go. But we have orders.
I know, Sir. -Maybe your family
has managed without you.
They're not alone in Sabac.
There's plenty of people.
My wife's not resourceful.
She's confused and scared.
And my four children are just
Like her. Their faces naïve.
Their eyes are so blue,
just like the English.
Sorry, Sir. Excuse me.
Sergeant!
Sabac has fallen.
-How, Sir?
It's fallen.
The Austrians are there.
What about the civilians?
It's war, Sergeant.
You know as much as I do.
Battery, halt!
Are you tired?
Ceda!
It's thundering.
Looks like rain again.
Corporal, the rain seems to be
following us. Hear the thunder?
I hear it, Sir!
What are you staring at?
Shall we stretch our legs?
-Why not.
Tell the younger officers not
to wander off. -Yes, Sir!
Sergeant! The battery need not
know about Sabac. -Understood.
Any news? -Plenty.
Belgrade is evacuated.
The fighting in Sabac is worse.
Our troops want to get it back.
Where we're going, Well be
knee-high in blood! -Where?
Listen! It's top secret,
so keep your mouth shut!
You know the mountain Cer?
The Austrians are nearly there.
That's where we're going.
General Stepa is somewhere there.
Sergeant, I want to tell you
something. -What did you say?
I wanted to say, don't be angry.
-lf it's official, say it!
It's not official.
I didn't mean to offend.
I won't talk to you in private.
Not with a ruffian!
It keeps thundering,
but there are no clouds.
What are you talking about?
It's the artillery. -What?!
Fierce fighting somewhere.
At least five or six batteries.
Don't worry, they're already
asleep. -What an ass!
Any artillery man would know.
Corporal Janicije's
thinking now:
"Because you ran Last year, you
can't tell a gun from thunder."
Nonsense. Who says? You
didn't run, you were transferred.
Excuse me, have you seen
the Drina Division?
I've heard that they're in
Krupanj. God only knows!
I have a brother
in the 5th Battalion.
His name is Proka,
Prokopije Pantic.
Who knows, my child. They
say there were big battles.
He doesn't know where he is,
Let alone your brother!
I had to ask. I'm worried!
-You peasants always worry!
You always have to whine!
Why did you have to join?
How could I not join?! Who
would go to war, if not us?
You're an old nag
of a corporal!
Come on, keep it moving!
The army has to get through!
Look where you're going, auntie!
-Poor me, where am I going?
Throw away what you can't carry!
Just keep it moving!
Sergeant, are you with these
people? -As you can see.
Is anyone from Sabac?
-I don't know. Ask further down.
Sergeant!
Listen, I want to
tell you something!
I didn't come to insult you,
so help me God! I'm a man, too!
You, a man? You good-for-nothing!
You don't know what a man is!
I didn't want to insult you!
The village, Veliki Bosnjak
August 15, 1914
Brother Kole! We let you pass,
and still we arrived before you.
You can't beat the infantry!
-Where can I put my battery?
By the city hall. Get there
before the Morova lot do.
Don't you worry!
Your exploiting the situation!
-Not me! -Yes, you!
I would have given 80, but 1 20!
I should hang you from this tree!
I paid a fair price for them!
If you don't take them,
Ill return them to the café,.
Zivko, come and take them back!
Stop yelling! Youll start
a riot, because of this beer!
80! -Zivko!
90! -Zivko, get over here!
Men, didn't you see the beer?
-Yes, Sir! I started to drool!
Well, get some strong lads.
Hurry up!
Aleksa, Rosy, Bogi, follow me!
The boy's doing fine.
-Thank God!
I thought the battery
wouldn't accept him.
They'll accept him,
sooner than you will.
Why? I haven't accepted him?
What do you mean by that?
Brother Kole,
because you're relatives,
I don't want to interfere.
-Go on, say it.
I don't know him well, but
he needs to feel like a man.
What am l, a nanny?
-No, but still...
What's he doing here?
Move over, so I can see!
Now the fun begins.
Aleksa, was it Like this Last
time? -When, what?
Stop pretending! Is this
what happened last year?
I won't discuss it any more,
Veca! That's enough!
Damn the battery!
-Go back from where you came!
Is that how you talk to your
father? Aright, see this letter?
It's from Colonel Lukic.
It's an order for Kosta.
He has to obey it!
-Veca, have you gone mad?!
What are you staring at, stupid?
Start crying for your lieutenant.
-I don't care, you cry!
Youll be crying
your heart out!
It's the same as last time, and
that night was the worst battle!
You Little snot, you've decided
to get killed! Get into the car!
What's wrong with his Leg?
Hey, what's wrong with his Leg?
They say he fell of his horse.
He must have fallen asleep.
More likely the horse fell
asleep. How is he now?
They say he's even worse.
-What did you say, Kursula?
Nothing, Sir,
just a personal inquiry.
Gentlemen, nothing has changed.
Tonight. Signed by General Stepa.
Kursula, your battalion and the
battery of Captain Hadzi-Vukovic,
will be the front ranks
of our division. -Yes, Sir.
Youll have half an hour, while
the sanitary unit passes through.
See if you can get
some supper.
But in half an hour,
you must Leave. -Yes, Sir!
Gentlemen,
I wanted to say this before.
But, as usual,
Major Kursula confused me.
Despite the exhaustion,
I'm ordering a march to Cer.
It's not my order,
nor General Stepa's.
The orders come from Serbia.
Tonight, Serbia will be on Cer.
If you don't get there now,
you never will.
That's all. You may go.
Aleksa, the wounded arriving
are from the Drina Division.
Go and enquire about your
brother. -The Drina Division?
That's what they say.
-Hold this, boy!
Stop staring after him and eat
while you can, you silly child!
I can't, Corporal!
They're all wounded.
I hurried to prepare your food,
but you found a better cook.
He's not better, believe me!
You're the best cook!
Ill get a fire started.
Where's the Commander?
It's too Late, Uncle Trajko.
Well be Leaving soon.
They've taken a right beating!
Are they returning from Cer?
Medic! Medic!
-What is it?
Stop! Why didn't you tell me?
He's taking up two seats!
Get him down, quickly!
Get someone else on here. Hurry!
Couldn't you find somewhere else,
you damn grave-diggers!
Get out of here! I haven't eaten
properly since Arandjelovac!
He's only doing his job. Someone
else will come along to bury him.
Proka, can you hear me?
It's me, Aleksa.
Leave him alone. He's in no
condition to talk. Let him be.
Where are you taking them?
-To the hospital in Valjevo, Sir.
It's a good hospital, isn't it?
Will this fellow pull through?
Of course he will! The peasants
can withstand almost anything.
Come on, men!
Get ready to move!
Battery, forward march!
Take care, Proka!
My battery is Leaving.
I beg of you, take care of him!
-What's this? -He might need it.
Cer
August 15, 1914
Brother Kole, over here!
Hello, Badza!
Do you know where you're going?
-I was told to go to Trajan Peak.
You're lucky the infantry's here,
or you'd be Lost all night!
Over there is Tekeris
and way up there is Trajan.
I sent a patrol
and so should you.
We don't do that.
Our Commander goes himself.
Veca! You, the Sergeant
and two soldiers, follow me!
Miloje, follow on
with the battery!
Stay well, brother!
-Don't worry, Badza!
Stop! The gun's stuck!
Dismount! Get the wheel!
Push! Come on!
Let me try!
Why are you just standing there?
Push it, God damn it!
Come on, push!
Get up there!
Did you know that father Trivun
was here? -Who?
Uncle Laza, as well. There was a
message for you. I tore it up.
What? -I tore it up, because
I knew what the message was.
No one is allowed to touch the
Commander's mail! Understood?
Ill take any punishment,
but don't send me away.
Understand how I feel. I know
I can make it in the battery.
I won't go!
-Stop being a pest!
Ever since you came,
you've been bothering me!
Listen, I've taught you how
to ride, drink and womanise.
I didn't want to teach you
this job, that's so bloody.
I still think you'd be
of better use elsewhere.
We've already gone too far.
I can't send you back.
Thank you, brother Kole.
Halt!
What is it?
Are you Kursula's patrol?
Sorry, Sir, I didn't
see your rank.
There's a light a the top of
the hill. It must be our patrol.
Where did you see the Light?
-Just below the top of the hill.
Show me the way!
This is our machine gun
detachment. -Lead on!
I see the lamps and fires.
-Must be our patrol.
Like hell it is!
Take two men,
and tell those men they're not
in a whore house! -Yes, Sir!
Hey, you Louts, are you the
patrol of the 2nd division?
Hey, you, answer my question!
What did you say?!
They're Austrians!
Get back! Make sure
they don't hear us!
What's happening, brother?
Who did you send up there?
It must be your men.
We don't have a machine gun.
I don't like it, brother!
Let's go and see!
Hell! It sounds as if a whole
division has opened fire!
Major, Sir, this way!
I'm a Czech, Sir.
Feldvebel Novotni.
We wanted to surrender.
-Later! Who's up there?
The 8th corps. You're
heading straight for them.
What?! -The Austrian 8th corps
and the 21st Landwehr division.
Sergeant, back to the battery!
-Yes, Sir! -You stay!
What is the bugle sounding?
-An alert to prepare to attack.
Thanks, brother, if you're
not Lying! -I'm not, Sir!
I surrendered of my own choice.
-Got afraid? -Yes, Sir!
You should be. You can't just
waltz in and take over Serbia!
Take him to headquarters
and guard him with your life!
Where are his boots? -Zivojin
took them when he captured him.
Don't make me hang around
Cer for a pair of boots!
Give them back!
-Yes, Sir!
Oh, great! They've already
started to fire the artillery!
Since Veliki Bosnjak,
I've been hearing a howitzer.
Go up there. It's almost dawn.
Hit them with everything!
Let me know the position of
your men! -I will, brother!
Hit their artillery. For now,
they're missing their us.
Cer
August 16, 1914
Ready to fire!
Sergeant, get me the division
headquarters! -Yes, Sir!
Battery, ready!
Hello, Ceda, they've found me!
They're hitting very hard!
Where's our artillery? Can
you hear me? Who's that?
This is the 2nd battery.
Kursula, is that you?
Get off, Ceda! Brother Kole,
start using your guns, already!
Ill start to fire, Kursula!
Let me know if I'm on target!
Aim at the infantry by
the forest. Drum at 32!
Plate at 0!
Distance at 1800m!
Shrapnel shell!
Time at 54!
Ready! -Left gun, ready!
-Battery, ready!
Salvo fire!
Too far! Cut it by 300! This
time, hit them with everything!
Distance at 1500m! Time at 47!
Three rapid! Fire!
That's it, straight into them!
Get ready to charge!
Hello, Kosta, just keep it up!
Remain at the same elements!
Ready, my heroes?
-Ready, Sir!
In the name of God. Don't yell
"forward", but "follow me"!
Understood?
-Yes, Sir!
What's happening, brother?
Look at them charging this way!
We've been informed of 2 Austrian
detachments surrounding us, Sir!
Here they are!
What else were you told?
If it's anything Like this,
Ill buy you a drink!
Hello, hello!
Headquarters!
They've found us!
-God damn them!
Send out scouts to
find that howitzer!
Hello!
Kosta, have you seen the two
columns heading towards you?
Yes, I have! Where's Kursula?
Hell try for their flanks,
but there's too many!
Get ready to retreat!
-Ail right!
Are you all right, down there?
-Yes, Sir!
Where the hell is it firing from?
Sergeant, find it! -I can't!
Battery, keep firing!
Same elements!
Captain, the Krauts are coming!
Our troops are withdrawing!
Keep firing, or theyll take us
prisoner along with our guns!
Battery, fire!
Sir, the phone's been ringing!
-Have you found the howitzer?
I'm going cross-eyed. It's as
if it's firing from underground!
Yes, all right, Ceda!
Bloody hell!
Cease fire! Veca! Miloje!
Sergeant, get the horses!
Withdraw towards the village
of Tekeris! -All right, Kosta!
Move those guns!
All guns, one column,
through the forest!
What are you waiting for?
Krauts? Move it!
Attach those guns!
Corporal, wake up!
Attach that gun!
Faster! Get moving!
Sergeant, move it!
3rd squad, gallop forward!
4th to the Left!
Faster! Faster!
Get hold of the wheel!
Keep pulling! Pull!
Get out of there, leave the gun!
-But the gun, Sir?
Leave now!
Sergeant, that's an order!
The village, Tekeris
August 16, 1914
Reporting, General, Sir!
It's you, Kursula? Why did
you leave Cer so quickly?
I would have got them,
but they hit our flanks.
I chased them of Trajan, but the
regiment coming from Lesnica...
I know. That's not a regiment,
it's their 9th division.
What do you think of the enemy?
-They're not what we thought.
They can't manage in our hills.
They're scared of knives, bombs.
But... -But, what? -They're Large
in numbers and well armed.
If they hadn't attacked
from the valley,
I would have reached
the top of Cer!
Sir, remember when you
failed my exam on the Drina?
I said the Austrian-Hungarian
army would cross the Drina,
because it was best for them.
Remember? -Yes, so what?
Well, they did come
across the Drina, after all!
They'll pass, just like
you did on your exam.
Has the Morava division
arrived yet? -Yes, Sir!
Cease fire!
Keep a lookout!
Remain by your arms!
Clean the barrels!
Check them thoroughly!
Bring the ammunition!
Yes, Sir!
Take a rest. -I can't.
What's going to happen now?
I don't know. Stop thinking
about the gun. It's no use.
I received your report. Ill see
see you Later regarding that.
I believe you had no choice,
but to withdraw.
Youll get detailed orders Later.
Well take the same positions.
Yes, Sir! -Can I get up there in
this carriage? -Well manage.
The Morova division is gathering
and will advance from your Left.
This will be the decisive moment.
Have your replacements arrived?
Yes, Sir, but I was wondering if
the Lieutenant could...
Not now, Hadzi-Vukovic, it's too
Late. Your gun was Left up there?
Yes. A most unfortunate thing.
Ill send for you later. Branislav!
Sir, at Last, some coffee.
It's made with spring water.
Where are your cards, old man?
-Who cares about that now?
Can you really see
something in them?
There is nothing to see.
The cards are dirty and smudged.
So, you Lie to them?
-I lie, dear. Listen, Sir.
Someone comes to me,
who feels miserable and deserted.
I ask him about his
Life, home and family.
Then I turn it all around and it
comes out well. -And then?
The poor soul wants to hear nice
stories. He's grabbing at straws.
It's just like when you
wish upon a falling star,
or find a four-leaf clover.
You believe it's luck.
The poor Corporal!
It was his fate. -Yes.
Come on, Trajko,
back to work!
Captain, Sir, your coffee!
-Thank you, Trajko.
I'm writing my report. Subject:
How and why a gun was lost.
We know why.
There's no need.
Brother Kole, if you think
it's my fault... -Miloje!
We're returning to
the same positions.
To the left of the forest.
We withdrew through that pass.
When we return, we must
go around. Give me the map.
Well go to the Left of this hill,
then through the forest.
As soon as we're out,
we'll be in our old position.
What the hell are you doing?!
-Don't move!
You mongrel! Do you
want a court-martial?
I won't kill you, just don't
move! -Put that rifle away!
You're a man and I'm not!
I was worried about my family
and all you did was insult me!
Take a Look! Is she pretty?
-What do you want from me?
I asked you if she was pretty!
-She's attractive.
A lot you know! You've
never seen anyone like her!
The whole town stared at her!
Men of rank, better than you!
You didn't say
you were married.
I didn't get a chance! You're
the only one with problems!
I didn't know. -She had it all!
I even had my own shop.
I know my wife.
-But your wife isn't a whore!
Why do you keep her photo?
Forget the treacherous creature!
Why don't you forget Sabac?
Who do you think you are?
You've got a pathetic salary
and wife and only you suffer!
I was a man! I could have bought
you, together with your salary!
Now, I wonder around with a deck
of cards and a photo of a whore!
Only you have the right to suffer
and slap others in the face!
It's worth a try.
Well carry ammunition, in case
the Austrians destroyed ours.
Can I make
a personal suggestion?
The Lieutenant, Veca, should do
this. -Are you afraid, Professor!
I've done more dangerous things.
-Then, what's the problem?
You have to show Veca
that you believe in him.
Anyone could have left
that gun, even you.
Suppose I send him. It means
I could Lose another gun!
You and your bloody gun!
Cer
August 16, 1914
Sir, it's that howitzer again!
Kursula, is that you? Kosta's
battery is on the move!
Lieutenant Veca is going up to
the gun. He's below you now.
I see him, Ceda! Is that the
Morava division I hear?
Yes. We're going to send them
back over the Drina! It's over!
It would be, if the Krauts would
sit back and wait to be beaten!
Move him, quickly!
Enable that gun!
Open quick fire at
the retreating enemy!
Listen!
Aim at the farthest point!
4th company, follow me!
Sir, they didn't touch
the ammunition wagon!
Open fire at the enemy!
Distance, 600 metres!
Gunner, keep your eyes open!
Sir, they're retreating!
They didn't expect us here!
Distance at 500 metres!
Watch that grenade and
stop staring like an idiot!
That's great!
Fire another ten at 500 metres!
They've found us again! It's that
howitzer again! -Get down!
I told you to get down!
What are you waiting for?!
Sir, as long as you remain
standing, so will we!
Leave him! Keep firing!
Fire to the Left!
Kursula is attacking!
We're being hit by the howitzer!
Keep firing!
Faster, boys, faster!
Ready to fire!
Clear that ammunition!
Hit their infantry! Drum 32,
plate 0, distance 700m!
Salvo fire!
Miloje, find that howitzer!
I can't see it from here! -Sir!
Sir, are you wounded?
Get the bandages!
Don't be afraid.
Colonel, Sir.
Hadzi-Vukovic, Kursula
has taken the Trajan area.
Fire in front of him, towards
Kosanin Grad! -Yes, Sir!
That howitzer is hitting us!
-And Kursula as well!
Protect him with continuous fire!
The 6th division is to our Left.
You must not cease fire!
Understood? -Yes, Sir!
Captain, Sir! Kosta!
-Find that howitzer!
Sergeant!
Miloje, if Kosta asks about me,
don't tell him.
Please, he mustn't come here.
Everything has gone to hell.
There it is, Lieutenant,
I can see the howitzer!
It's in the woods,
to the right of the bridge!
You can't see it firing,
because of the forest!
Target the enemy howitzer
at the edge of the forest!
Drum 32, plate 0, distance 4800m!
Destroy! Three rapid! Fire!
Veca!
Where's the Lieutenant?
-Sir, he's right here.
How far is the howitzer? -4800m!
Are you listening? -Yes, Sir!
The direction is right,
but we're falling too short!
Set it to 5200!
Damn, how far can they be?!
A second miss! Set it to 5300m!
Are you wounded?
-I fell, that's all.
Why do we keep missing?
I told you 5300m!
-Sir, that's what we're doing!
Grenade! Get down!
5100!
We found them, Sir!
Stay at 5100!
Destroy! Rapid fire!
Sergeant! Bogi, my gambler!
Yes, Sir, I understand!
Cease fire!
Miloje, the Austrians
are running towards Cer!
Well follow them to the Drina!
Veca!
Sir, we've taken Kosanin Grad!
-What do you say about that?
Stop it! It's taking you all day!
Steva! -Yes, Sir!
Inform artillery that we're going
after them, down to the Drina!
Yes, Sir! -Sir, you're severely
wounded! You shouldn't go...