- What does he want?
- I'll find out.
You don't have to take orders
from this man, you know.
Well, I'm the liaison officer.
So I'm liaising.
You're sure you know what
you're doing, old man?
Yes, and what ever this is,
it's important to him...
that I see it.
- I'll keep an eye on them sir.
- Very good.
MERRY CHRISTMAS
MR. LAWRENCE
A disgracefuI incident has occurred.
I will deal with it myself.
If It's secret why show me?
I want you to witness it.
- Know what he did?
- This dutch soldier?
Not him he was in a cell for stealing bananas.
- The korean guard?
- Of course.
Kanemoto tell this british officer what you did.
Kanemoto come on!
Say it!
Say it! You, Kanemoto!
Why don't you?
Are you too ashamed?
You know now Lawrence?
Last night he stole into the
cell of that dutch boy.
Kanemoto show us how you used
this thing of yours.
Show us how you used it on this
white fellow's ass.
Just do it for us now!
Untie him.
Kanemoto! Do it! Hear me? Now!
Has your dainty thing become
too shrunken to be potent?
If you can bugger him again
you may comit Harakiri.
Have you gone mad?
You haven't seen a japanese
untiI you've seen Harakiri.
I don't want to watch it!
Do you want me to hate the japanese?
I'll do it!
Stop it! For God's sake,
stop it!
Lawrence, out of the way!
Haven't you shamed him enough?
Shame? He didn't even resist being raped!
Can you get up?
You're Dutch, aren't you?
De Jong, sir.Karel De Jong.
Now you'd better
sit down.
Now tell me
what happened.
In the begin in he camein to
dress this wound of mine.
For three days, every night.
He was, he was very kind.
But then last night, he suddenly...
Captain Yonoi! This is
Colonel Lawrence! Come quickly!
Kanemoto, I'll assist you.
Stop it!
Watch this!
Sergeant Hara...
Attention!
What's going on?
Sergeant Hara is going execute this man!
- This is not your concern.
- Then why bring me here?
- Who ordered this execution?
- This is not an execution.
Kanemoto is trying to comit
suicide for his crime.
And you ignore it?
Out of compassion.
His family is poor. If we deem
his death an accident...
they will get a pension.
What crime has he committed?
Let me report in private.
I've no time now. I'm due at a
military trial in Batavia.
Make your report later.
This way, sir.
- Captain Yonoi is here, sir.
- Let him in.
I'm Captain Yonoi.
I'm here for the trial.
We are very honoured to have
Captain Yonoi here today.
This is Colonel Fujimura,
President of the court.
- Pleased to serve with you.
- Good to have you here.
My name is Iwata.
The military situation here is very serious.
Your service is important.
Gentlemen, the defendant is
a very difficuIt man.
All rise to attention!
Before the court is the
case of Jack Celliers.
Your name is given
as Jack Celliers.
Is that correct?
- Why shouldn't it be?
- What do you mean by that?
Answer the question!
Is your name Jack Celliers?
I've answered that question
about a hundred times.
Read the charges.
The prisioner, Jack Celliers,
a Major in the British army...
parachuted with four men into...
the Banten Valley.
They waged guerilla warfare.
On october 16, they attacked a
japanese transport unit.
They took ammunition, killed
PFC Takeshi Tazaki, then...
they wounded Corp. Sawafuji
and four others.
His crime is covered by
martial law regulations.
We recommend a death penalty...
as prescribed in section 1
Accordingly, he should receive
the death penalty...
as prescribed in Section 1,
chapter 5 of the regulations.
How do you plead?
Not guilty. I'm not a criminal.
I am a soldier in His Majesty's army.
One month ago I came out of the
Djaja Sempoer mountains.
I surrendered to Colonel Utsumi
of the Imperial Japanese Army.
I was imprisioned at Sukabumi.
3 days in solitary confinement.
Then I was questioned
by Lieutenant Ito.
He asked me my name and
rankand I told him.
Then Lieutenant Ito asked me:
"Is that true?"
I replied:
"of course, it is. I'm with the British army."
Do you mean you would never
give a false name?
Let me ask you something.
Why would a man who's about to
die give a false name?
A japanese soldier it caught
would give a false name.
A Japanese soldier would never
submit to being caught.
But then, I'm not a japanese.
Why did you refuse to tell
about yourself?
You must tell us your pass history.
My past is my business.
What was the reason for
giving yourself up?
You've just read it,
haven't you?
Your men said they'd kill
the villagers.
- How many men did you have?
- None.
- Liar!
- I'm not a liar.
I had four men but they
were killed in action.
We know you led a group
of native soldiers.
We are bound to find them
sooner or later.
Why don't you confess your crime?
I've never led natives.
Look, why don't I have a defense counsel?
Exactly what kind of trial
are you giving me?
This whole thing's a bloody farce.
Erase all those remarks.
May I question him?
"To be or not to be.
"That is the question,
The prosecutor said that you
landed in Java by parachute.
Under whose orders?
Under the orders of the
Suprem e Commander of...
His Majesty's forces in India.
Were you not under the
commander of Java?
You know I came to Java in August.
You know the commander in
Java was captured in March.
- You know Captain...
- Captain Yonoi.
If this man fought in India
as a legitimate soldier.
Then we must treat him as
a prisioner of war.
- We have no proof.
- I believe this man.
What were you asked when captured?
Were you asked how to
intended to conduct a...
guerilla war with only five men?
Well, I suspect they thought we
were an advance party...
for a new campaign presumably
the invasion of Java!
They wanted to know dates and places.
What did you say?
I said I thought they were crackers.
What?
- I thought they were mad.
- And then?
Then they stopped feeding me,
and started beating me.
Can you prove that you were beaten?
Put on your shirt!
No more questions!
The court retires.
A delay this long usually means
a firing squad.
But nowadays new officers like
to try out their swords...
on white necks.
The verdict in your case
has been postponed.
We shall wait for further instructions.
Stand up.
Good day for it, sir.
Yes.
You have a family waiting for you,
Corporal?
Wife and two kids, sir.
One with, one without.
How's about yourself, sir?
- Tea?
- Yes, I'd like that.
The prisoner, sir!
Can you guess
what I'm thinking.
Yes, I think so. Can you?
He's rebellious to the end.
You have been found
guilty on all charges.
The sentence will be carried
out without delay.
Make him ready!
- I don't need any help.
- Let him alone!
I've practiced walking for years.
Firing position!
I don't need that.
The blind fold is for the firing squad!
So they don't look into
your eyes as you die.
Let him be.
Prepare to fire!
Firing positions!
Fire!
That's a good one!
Sergeant Hara...
Lawrence can't you let me sleep?
I'm sorry.
I was just now riding on top of
Marlene Dietrich's tummy.
In a hideway in Manchuria!
I must talk to you.
Why's he here?
I want you to protect him.
Why?
My men heard about him.
- I told you not to talk!
- I didn't.
There were japanese soldiers
and korean guards there.
You accuse japanese...?
It was probably the guards.
Don't you realize that everyone
is going to know?
I understood.
Will all your men want to
bugger him now?
Is it true that english men
are all homosexuals?
Don't be stupid.
Listen I need your help.
A japanese never asks help
from an enemy.
Hey, are you a homosexual?
He says you are a homosexual.
Are you?
No sir. I am not.
He's not.
You all fear homosexuality!
A samurai doesn't fear it.
Wars create friendships amongst men.
That hardly means that all
soldiers become homosexual.
You are not soldiers,
you are prisioners!
So you lack discipline,
and you beg favours.
- Shame!
- Sergeant Hara...
I've nothing to be ashamed of.
A new prisioner has arrived.
Another queer's here!
I've brought a prisioner from
military prison, Batavia.
I'm sergeant Gengo Hara.
I'll take over.
Your name and rank?
Celliers, Jack. Major,
British Army.
Celliers? Jack Celliers?
Straffer Jack?
Good morning, Colonel.
You bastard!
Stop it!
No! Stop it! Stop it!
You! Officer! Do you
know this man?
We served together in Libya.
We fought the Germans.
Take him to the sick bay.
What kind of a man is he?
Is he a close friend of yours?
No. He's not a close friend, no.
- What kind of a soldier is he?
- He's a fine soldier.
We had a nickname for him
in the 8th Army.
We called him straffer Jack.
Straffer is a kind of um...
it's very difficult to translate.
Straffer is um...
This is astonishingly difficult sometimes.
In any case,
he was a soldier's soldier.
Why are you so
interested in him?
- What did the doctor say?
- I din't talk to the doctor.
You fool!
Lawrecen, I want him in good
health as quickly as possible.
That's an order!
You don't have to order me
to look after a sick man.
I will send the japanese
medic to see him.
Why are you so concerned
about Major Celliers?
Send our medic.
- The commandig officer, sir.
- Let him in.
You spend more time with these
Japs than you do with...
your own men.
I called Colonel Lawrence here.
Now from you...
I want the names of all
prisoners who are informed...
on the subject of armaments
and ammunition.
Who are the experts here?
I am not required under
International Law...
to furnish the enemy with
any information.
This is not North Africa.
We are not Germans!
There is no Geneva Convention here.
If you do not follow my orders,
I will have to replace you.
Replace me?
What are you talking about?
Replace me with whom?
Do you know what
he's talking about?
No sir. I don't know.
You promised to improve our food ration.
You eat the same as we eat.
Give me the names of your experts.
No, Captain Yonoi.
I will not.
Captain Yonoi. Please try to understand.
Group Captain Hicksley
is an honourable man.
"They are all, all honourable men."
As commanding officer, I prefer
another honourable man.
Lawrence, this armaments thing.
I think we can string it out
for quite sometime, don't you?
I mean, young Tojo will never
notice the difference.
They're not fool, you know,
sir, the japanese.
They know how badly the war's
going for them.
A couple months, it could
all be over.
Then why not try and stay alive
for a couple of months?
Sir, I know these people...
I wish you'de be guided by my knowledge.
I know these people, too.
They're the enemy.
And you're a British soldier.
You know they once beat the Russians.
Really? What school did you go to?
Winchester.
Who's looking after Major Celliers?
- I am, sir.
- How's he coming along?
He's a tough man.
Anyone else would have been dead
When will he be up and
about do you think?
Christ, I had to give him a sedative,
so he'll sleep...
most of the time. I'd saya
couple of weeks.
- Good. Where's the big chief?
- I'll get him for you.
All right you malingerers.
Now hear this!
Colonel Lawrence is going to
stay here for a few nights.
- He's one of those, mate!
- Want my boxing gloves?
- Where is he?
- Sleeping.
Take me.
Why was he captured?
He wasn't.
He surrendered.
Why does Capt. Yonoi want to
make him commanding officer?
- I don't know.
- Answer me Lawrence...
Because he's a born leader.
Why are you still alive?
I'd admire you more if
you killed yourself.
A good officer like you!
How can you stand the shame?
We don't call it shame.
Being a prisioner is one of
the fortunes of war.
We surely aren't happy being prisoners.
We want to escape.
We want to fight you.
That's just quibbling.
No! We want to win.
This camp isn't the end.
We won't kill ourselves.
It's the coward's way out.
You're just scared of dying!
Don't wake the patients.
When I was 12,
I visited the shrine in my village.
I offered my life to the Emperor.
I have already died for my country.
Yes. But you're not dead are you?
It's all right, Jack.
It's Lawrence.
It's all right. You're fine.
It's all right.
Sergeant Hara isn't going to hurt you.
Sergeant Hara isn't going to hurt anyone.
What on earth possessed Yonoi
to save me do you think?
I don't know.
What did he say, Lawrence?
What a fynny face!
Beautiful eyes, though.
All right?
What's that bloody noise!
What's the matter with them?
They're trying to become
super human gods.
They live in the past,
these fellows.
God help them, Lawrence.
And that's our Captain Yonoi's voice,
isn't it?
He's been screaming
his head off...
ever since you got here.
If he's got something
on his mind...
why doesn't he come out with it?
I rather think he is.
Perhaps we're both on the same ladder.
Are you okay?
It was a nightmare.
Ueki is worried about these
training sessions...
that they are too violent.
Sir, your shouts make the prisioners uneasy.
Lawrence has come to me.
- Lawrence is here?
- Outside.
Is it true that our shouts
disturb the prisoners?
Yes, yes, sir. It is.
And you? Do you feel uneasy?
Well, I find the noise irritating,
but irt doesn't make me uneasy.
However, some of the sick men...
- That sick officer, too?
- Major Celliers? Yes.
I do not want the prisoners
to become upset.
Thank you, Captain Yonoi.
How wonderful it would have been...
if we could have invited all of you...
to a gathering under our cherry trees.
Yes.
My fondest memory of
Japan is the snow.
The trees covered with snow.
- It was snowing on that day.
- What day?
Don't you know?
February 26, 1936.
Yes... yes.
I was in Tokyo that day.
You too?
No. I had been sent off to
Manchuria 3 months before.
I was not there
for the uprising.
You regret that?
My comrades were executed.
I was left to die after them.
I see. So you were one of the
shining young officers...
And bring that sick officer Lawrence.
Attention.
Salute.
Eyes right.
Lawrence, where is that sick officer?
- The doctor stopped him.
- You stopped him, Lawrence.
He is very weak.
Where is the victim?
Let him step forward.
We're here on your orders.
We're under no obligation to
watch this execution.
If you had any humanity left in you, sir,
you would let us leave.
Any of you who can't watch it...
keep your eyes shut or turn round!
But I will no permit you
to leave this site!
Allied officers do not turn
their back on the enemy.
Ready...
Raised your head.
Roll him over.
Christ. He's swallowed part
of his tongue.
- Pay your respects.
- Come on, lads.
- Not yet.
- We want to pay our respects!
- You Jap lover!
- Stop them.
You have no respect for anything!
Not even your own men!
You're wrong, Captain Yonoi!
By God you're wrong.
You are to say nothing
about today's execution...
or this soldier's death
until it is announced.
If you're so bloody right,
you've got nothing to hide!
We must wait for the
official announcement.
This is the right way.
I am right.
Colonel Lawrence,
am I not right?
No. No, Captain Yonoi.
You're wrong.
We're all wrong.
I order all prisoners,
each and everyone of you...
not to go out to the fields
today or tomorrow.
Instead, you shall stay inside
your barracks for 48 hours...
and undergo "gyo".
You'll observe gyo for 48 hours.
There will be no eating
or drinking. Is this clear?
What the hell's gyo?
It's a Japanese cure for laziness.
Laziness, Jesus Christ!
Why don't you listen?
He means spiritual laziness.
And he believes...
that if he takes away the food
and the water, then he also...
takes away the nourishment
for the laziness!
You don't believe that bullshit,
do you?
I don't fucking know!
Sir, I will tell you something that
may surprise you.
If we do it, he'll do it!
- Pheasant!
- Here.
- Mills!
- Ibbertson
- I'm hungry.
- Adams.
- Eggs and bacon, mate.
- Baxter!
- Steak and kidney-pie.
Put up with it for another 13 or 14 hours.
You can do it!
How about giving us a wee whisky?
What about a double whisky?
De Jong!
Next! Who's next?
He's dead.
He's not dead!
He'll be back in a few days!
De Jong has been killed!
De Jong has been Killed!
Thank you.
Next.
- Craig!
- Here.
- Smith!
- Yes.
Celliers!
- Where is Major Celliers?
- He said he'd be back soon.
One man is missing.
Major Celliers.
Look, he'll be here in a moment.
Just mark us all here.
I can't do that. I'll have to
report him missing.
No, please.
Just a few minutes!
Celliers?
That's right.
What are those flowers for?
Food.
Food?
I wish they were white, but these
were all that I could find.
In memory of De Jong.
It might be nice if you were to
say something Lawrence.
Our father who art in Heaven
Hallowed by thy name
Thy Kingdom come,
Thy will be done
Give us this day
our daily bread
And forgive us our trespasses,
As we forgive them that...
- Give me another.
- And lead us not into temp
What are you doing?
We must observe the gyo.
What the hell are you doing, Major?
I gave Major Celliers permission, sir.
Ah, changed our tune, have we?
What happened to the gyo?
- What are all these flowers for?
- In memory of De Jong, sir.
He didn't give me permission, sir.
And it was my idea.
Really?
Lawrence, over here.
You knew of Yonoi's plan to
replace me as comander?
Yes, sir, I did.
May I ask why
you didn't tell me?
It's still only a rumor, sir.
You don't like me, do you?
Captain Yonoi doesn't like you.
I don't know what to
make of you, Lawrence.
You've either very clever, or
you're bloody stupid.
But I tell you one thing.
I will never give Yonoi any
information about officers...
or armaments.
You understand that?
And I will never resign as
commander of this camp.
You can tell that to Yonoi.
Never!
Bloody hell!
It's an inspection!
Don't waste the food.
Keep eating it.
I'll take the responsibility.
And keep singing.
Rock of Ages,
cleft for me
Let me hide
Myself in Thee
Let the water
And the Blood
Come on now...
From Thy riven side which
Flow'd Be of sin the
For God's sake get those bloody
flowers off De Jong's bed!
No, leave those on.