- AC phase selector.
- AC.
Force trim.
On.
Battery switch.
Fire detector light.
Test.
Caution warning lights.
Test and reset.
By the way, congratulations.
Have you thought of
a name for your kid?
Well, we're still fighting.
I'm holding out for
Joe DiMaggio Mazilli.
The greatest Yankee
that ever lived!
Hydraulic control switch.
On.
Lighting.
In.
Heads up, guys.
Here comes Colonel Braddock.
So, why would the colonel
want to go to Cambodia?
Yeah, he could get hurt
going across the fence.
He's leading a recon unit,
checking enemy strength.
Clear?
Clear left, sir.
Let her rip.
Main generator switch.
On.
- Turn switch.
- Fair.
700 RPMs.
Decrease.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, Sergeant.
Sorry I'm late.
Would you like to take
the controls, sir?
No, thanks, Captain.
I'm just along for the ride.
What are the coordinates
on LZ Sally?
Three-seven-four-zero-
three-zero-one-niner.
We're right on top of them.
Let's give them a holler.
Alligator four,
this is Red Gap six.
Alligator four, we're
taking fire from all quadrants.
Sir, they're in a fire fight
down there.
Charlie's got them pinned down
two miles south of the LZ.
How bad is it?
They're taking fire
from all quadrants, sir.
Do you want to go in?
Hang on, guys.
We're coming down to get you.
Get ready to move.
Take it down, Captain.
Captain, let's move out now!
Keep your shirt on, son.
All right! Go!
Come on!
Come on, son.
We got to get out of here.
Shit! Damn!
You OK?
I'm fine.
Let's go to the chopper!
Come on!
Sir, they're getting
a good bead on us!
Colonel!
Looks like some
more party crashers, sir!
All right, come on!
Get in there!
Come on. Get in there. Quick!
Sir!
Let's get the hell out of here!
What the hell is that?
We're hit! We're going down!
I'm gonna try to make the lake.
Get ready to jump.
Jump!
Jump, Lieutenant!
I said, jump, Lieutenant!
On the day America
remembers its war dead...
a special salute today
to the war dead of Vietnam.
An American serviceman who died
there took his place today...
in a place of honor,
the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier.
Almost 10 years after the last
Americans left Saigon...
the men who fought in Vietnam
got their parade.
Muffled drums and dirges...
a coffin and a flag
wrapped in plastic...
to protect it from the rain.
In the amphitheater
of Arlington Cemetery...
families of the men
still missing from Vietnam...
waited for the coffin
and remembered.
They wonder if their sons
are still alive...
and why the world sits back...
and allows
the Vietnamese government...
to flagrantly violate
the Geneva Convention.
Rumors of physical
and mental torture...
have made
the wait more agonizing.
The families were reassured
by a deeply moved president.
We write no last chapters...
we close no books...
we put away no final memories.
An end to America's
involvement in Vietnam...
cannot come
before we have achieved...
the fullest possible accounting
of those missing in action.
Colonel Yin...
you may not give a damn
about the Geneva Convention...
but someday you're gonna
be held accountable.
The Geneva Convention applies
to prisoners of war.
You men are not
prisoners of war.
You are common criminals.
I have repeatedly told you...
that there is no escape
from my camp...
unless you consider
death an escape.
You are surrounded by cliffs...
mountains,
jungles full of man traps...
and a bridge that is impassable.
None of you have ever escaped,
and none of you will.
The only way for you to leave
my camp...
is if Braddock confesses.
He defends the country
that has forgotten you...
an outlaw nation
the rest of the world reviles!
They are killing
your ambassadors of the evil...
in every part of the world.
I have something for you.
Hey, it's a beaut.
It's a good two inches.
Angelo says thanks.
What he give you?
A B-52.
It's just a worm
for his chicken.
You know, I got to learn
to keep my mouth shut.
What do you do?
You never shoot your mouth off.
I try to decide
if what I'm going to say...
is worth getting hit for.
Wish I could do that.
Franklin?
Hey, it's hot. I'm sweating.
Looks like the malaria again.
Hey...
What the hell is Harry doing?
I'll bite his head off
for a pack of cigarettes.
Colonel Braddock,
I need to talk to you.
Colonel.
Look, I'm real sorry
those two guys died...
but we don't all have to.
Maybe I can get Yin
not to ride you so hard.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you, Braddock?
How about it, Sarge?
I mean, you know you could use
some time off.
Begging the captain's
pardon, sir...
but kiss my black ass.
That's funny.
All you guys are
big, brave soldiers...
and you think I'm a coward.
No, you're not a coward.
You're a traitor.
I'm not a traitor.
Look, our country
has forgotten about us...
and we have to do
anything we can to survive.
Look, I'm not the bad guy here.
It's Braddock
and his stupid pride.
When we first got here...
there were five times
as many of us... 33 Americans.
Now look at us.
I say that all Braddock
has to do is confess...
to some garbage war crime,
and Yin will send us home.
Who's gonna care?
The war has been over for...
for God knows how long.
We don't know that for sure.
There is no war.
And nobody gives
a damn about us.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I hear they're
coming to get us.
And if I were you,
I'd rather die here...
than have to explain
to my kid...
that I was a gutless traitor.
At least I've seen my kid.
Let him go.
Back off, Nester.
Die if you want to, all of you.
Who tell you someone coming?
No one.
I made it up to piss him off.
Why'd those guys have to run?
God, I got to get some sleep!
But whenever I close my eyes,
I see my wife Gina.
Yeah. My Diane's
gonna be mad at me.
I wanted the four kids
more than she did.
We made a deal.
She'd work, and I'd retire
and bring them up.
I fooled the hell out of her.
I haven't even seen my kid!
I'm sorry.
I try to block it out,
but I can't.
No one can.
You do. Nothing bothers you.
I'm just...
I'm just not tough like you.
Lao.
Sergeant Lawrence Opelka...
you have been tried
and found guilty...
of war crimes against
the people of Vietnam...
and have been sentenced
to death.
Please!
Nester.
What does he want from him?
Chou, get over here!
Chou! You scum!
Come down here, Chou!
Mazilli!
Come here, Chou!
You're nothing! Chou! Chou!
You lose.
You're scum, Chou!
Get down here
and shut that door!
Mazilli!
Get down here, Chou!
I said, get down here!
Mazilli!
It's not doing anyone any good.
You know that.
What the hell is going on?
Why are they starting
this torture crap again?
It's OK, kid. It's OK.
Here. Brought you some things.
Did you get the quinine?
No, I can't.
Yin has it locked up.
But he told me to tell you
that if Braddock confesses...
he will give it to you.
Yin can't be trusted.
I've given him what he wanted,
and he's treated me well enough.
He doesn't care about you.
It's Braddock's confession
he's always wanted.
Over the years,
it's driven him mad.
Then why not
just give it to him?
If Yin ever breaks Braddock,
we will all be killed.
Colonel Braddock,
I have spoken to my superiors...
and arranged for you
to be released...
if you will simply let us film
your confession just once.
No public appearances,
no questions.
We could do it right now.
You know I can't do that.
Some of my men feel
I am being too lenient with you.
Colonel Braddock...
I didn't want
to have to tell you this...
but maybe you should know.
Your wife
is planning to remarry.
She has you declared dead.
Your family needs you.
Sign this statement...
I will let you go home
before the wedding.
Colonel Yin, if my wife
is getting remarried...
I'm happy for her...
because if she's gonna wait for
me to sign this confession...
she's gonna be waiting
a long time.
Get him out of here.
Get down! Come on!
Hey! Come on!
That humper Lao is the biggest
asshole this side of Nester.
Leave him alone, Lao.
You hear me?!
Braddock, since you're
in a fighting mood...
I'll give you one.
Nester, you will be
Braddock's opponent...
and you will win.
I can't do that, sir.
Colonel Yin, our deal was that
I would never have to hurt...
any of the other prisoners.
Fine.
Don't fight.
But...
I will put you back
in the Americans' cell.
I'm not sure you would be as
popular there as you once were.
Why don't you just take a few
punches and go down, Colonel?
It’ll save us both
a lot of pain.
Yeah.
Put your hands up, Braddock.
Colonel Yin is watching us.
Put your hands up.
Nester, he's using you.
Come on.
Come on, sir! Get up!
Protect yourself!
Damn you, Colonel. Fight me.
Come on, Colonel.
Protect yourself.
Braddock.
Nester, Nester.
Get up, Colonel! Get up!
Come on.
Braddock!
You bastard,
either stay down or fight!
Come on, Colonel!
Hit him again! Yes!
He's gonna kill you, Nester.
I don't want to fight you,
Nester.
You got no choice now, Colonel.
No more favors.
Now I'm gonna hurt you!
Come on, sir! Get up!
Come on! For all of us!
Get him!
Come on, Colonel!
Come on, Nester,
don't be a fool, man!
Get up, Colonel.
Come on, get up.
Finish him off.
Come on!
Come on.
One more. Come on, in on him!
Give him another one.
Finish him off. Come on.
Yes! Come on, colonel!
Come on, Braddock.
Enough. Come on.
Finish this off.
Give him one good shot.
Come on!
Finish him off, sir. Come on.
- Be careful.
- Watch yourself.
Finish him off!
Come on. Get up!
Get up, Colonel.
Come on, Braddock.
Get up, Braddock.
Get up, Colonel. Get up.
One shot!
Come on, get up. Come on.
Come on, Colonel, get up!
Now! You're beaten!
Come on, soldier, get up.
How's it feel, Nester?!
Keep on him!
Get him, Colonel!
Yes!
Sir, Colonel,
you're killing him!
That's enough!
Lao, that's enough!
No!
You see what happens...
when one does not follow
my direction immediately.
You lose.
Colonel?
What did Yin lay on you
this time?
He said that my wife's
getting remarried...
and I've been declared dead.
He's bullshitting you.
You know that, don't you?
Captain Ho.
Anything on the quinine?
I don't have malaria.
Nothing.
But I have some things for you.
Beer?
Why don't you go give
the guys a drink?
Sure.
Have I got a surprise for you.
You see this baby, huh?
Look at that.
Hey, Lieutenant, have a sip.
This is what you wanted.
Thanks, Captain.
Colonel Yin,
I need to talk to you.
I'm the officer in charge.
If you have to punish somebody,
then punish me.
Confess. Admit your mistake.
No.
Very well.
Dou Chou.
No!
You're right.
You are responsible.
Come on, Franklin.
Here. I'll help you.
Let me get that one.
You get the small ones.
Fine. I ain't doing
so hot anyway.
What's that?
It's a chopper...
A Huey.
It sounds American.
Stop him!
What the hell?
I hope I didn't scare you guys.
How do you like
my new helicopter?
You are a day early.
I had to borrow it.
The other was too small.
I've brought you an arsenal
that will discourage anyone...
from cutting into
our opium business.
Now all that can harm us are
your American friends.
Why are they still alive?
Francois, I have
the situation under control.
Thanks for our treat.
You're a hot little devil.
You know, this time
they're all virgins.
Come on, girls.
Colonel, I don't think
there is a search team.
There's nothing
we can do about it now.
At least we know what they're
putting in that hut.
Those boxes?
They're full of weapons.
That's our way out.
When do you aim to kill
the Americans?
In my own time.
You're risking
our entire operation...
a very profitable operation.
I'm thinking of
getting a new watch.
Do you think you can purchase
one of those digital models?
I told you to kill
the Americans, goddamn it!
If the P.O.W. Search team hears
about it, we're finished!
Don't let your stupid ego
ruin everything!
Francois, will you
come with me for a moment?
Look, I didn't want to...
You will never again speak to me
like that in front of my men.
It sets a dangerous example.
Do you understand me?
Good.
Do you have any new information
about the American search team?
No. It's still rumors...
but there's been a guy
hanging around asking questions.
I wonder if Opelka is dead.
No. If he were...
Colonel Yin would stick his body
right in front of our faces.
So, my friend,
could I convince you...
to spend the night
with us and the virgins?
Sorry. I better not.
Understand...
I'm delivering
the opium personally...
but I will be back
to pick up the girls.
Don't forget my watch.
Colonel Braddock, Francois
brought me something today...
that I'm sure is of
great interest to you.
It seems your ex-wife has
finally written you a letter.
Unfortunately,
you must be punished...
for the incident with
your late friend... Opelka.
He's dead?
Ho!
Playboy, you want to play?
You!
I've been looking for you.
About time you showed up.
Your headquarters.
You take me
to your headquarters.
Name's Emerson... Clyde Emerson.
No. You don't understand.
Now, what is needed here is a
little courtesy and cooperation.
I'm the point man for
a P.O.W. Search mission.
The I.F.H. Got word of this
little operation some time ago.
I must say, we've had
a devil of a time finding you.
Who is "we"?
Ah, yes. The International
Freedom House.
I'm not just running around the
jungle looking for publicity.
He lie.
It's not a lie.
I'm part of a major operation.
There are nine other scouts
like me.
We each have five square miles
to cover.
And all of us call in
to Central Team regularly.
Now, if you think that's a lie,
you are in a pack of trouble.
Why don't you cooperate...
and save yourself a lot
of needless bloodshed?
What the hell is going on?
Damned if I know.
Do you really expect me
to believe you...
and turn over my whole camp?
Well, under
the circumstances, yes.
I believe that's the only thing
that you can do.
I hid a homing device
out there in the jungle.
My team knows
exactly where I am.
Now, they'll be waiting
for my signal.
Now, if I give it,
they'll come in slowly.
If I don't, they'll come in
fast, and you'll all be dead.
What signal?
Stop playing the fool.
The way I figure it...
these are your choices...
you can either cut and run...
or you can wait
until my team comes in...
and then you can try to run...
or you can cooperate
right now...
and save everyone
a whole lot of trouble.
I believe you left out
some of my options.
One, I could kill you
and the prisoners.
Yes. Missed that one.
And two... I can simply
lock you up...
and wait until you're ready
to give the signal.
Yes, you could lock me up...
but I'll never give you
the signal.
I don't care if you kill me.
Now, look, I'm tired of
hanging around under this sun...
playing footsie with
a half-pint would-be dictator.
Give him anything he wants.
I can't believe it!
We're going home!
OK. I want to know who won
the World Series last year.
I don't know anything about
any bloody World Series, mate.
I'm Australian.
Forget it. I love you anyway.
Yin won't give up this easy.
How large is your rescue team?
Large enough to kick
Yin's ass, huh?
I'm alone.
Alone?
Nobody knows I'm here, mate.
Man, there's nobody
gonna come and get me.
But the International
Freedom House...
The Central Team,
The homing device?
It's just a bluff, isn't it?
I had to tell him something.
I've heard rumors
about this place.
I followed Francois in.
I'm just a lousy
photographer, mate.
I needed pictures for proof.
Damn!
One thing for sure,
he's got guts.
Yeah. Nobody ever broke
into a prison camp.
All right, then, let's get out.
We'll head for the cliffs.
Anything happens to me...
I stashed
some ropes under a big rock.
You can't miss it.
Head for the Thai border...
100 miles due west.
Come on, let's go.
Wait. Yin may let you go...
but he certainly
won't let us all go.
What's that?
It's Francois coming
to pick up his whores.
Shit. He knows I'm alone.
Well, move it!
I'm just going to give
the signal, mate.
Mr. Emerson.
I'm just gonna give my signal.
Good.
Damn.
I hope everyone's told you
how well they have been treated.
Well, they don't love you,
but all in all...
they look pretty good.
I'll be right back.
One more moment, please.
I would like you to meet
a friend of mine.
I'll meet him later.
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
I wouldn't want the Central Team
to get impatient, you know.
Francois.
What's the matter, my friend?
You look a little nervous.
He is the goddamn guy who's
been asking questions about us.
He claims he's the point man
for a major rescue operation.
He's lying. He's alone.
I've still got the homing
device out in the jungle.
I am weary of playing footsie
with you.
Take him to the tree.
Move!
For the crimes against
the people of Vietnam...
I sentence you to death.
Don't worry! It's not real!
He's just trying to scare you!
They've got
a lousy sense of humor.
Get up. Get up.
Shut up, you asshole.
You...
We'll get him up.
OK, OK.
I'm OK.
Captain Ho?
He's dying.
Yin!
No, don't do it.
He has to.
What the hell's the difference?
Our struggle was a long one.
As I predicted, you lost.
I'm glad you finally understand
the extent of your guilt.
You do, don't you?
He don't understand shit!
Yes, Colonel Yin...
I understand.
Let's get him up.
Colonel Braddock.
I believe you have
forgotten something.
Now, my American P.O. W...
I will live up to my promise
and will let you go free.
Tomorrow, Francois will be here
and will fly you to Thailand...
and deliver you to your embassy.
You see, Colonel? I told you.
I will try to make
your last day here...
as comfortable as possible.
Here. Come into the next room.
You'll stay there tonight.
I can't believe it.
It's over. We're going home.
I'm going to see my kid!
Something's wrong.
Nothing's wrong.
You've just been here too long.
You're in shock.
I am feeling better.
Yeah, you're feeling better.
Nothing works this fast.
Oh, God! Get him up, Mazilli!
He's been poisoned!
Come on, Franklin!
Come on, on both legs.
Walk!
- Come on.
- Walk, Franklin.
Come on, walk it.
Walk, Franklin!
Is this an American
funeral rite?
I'm afraid I gave poor Franklin
such an overdose of opium...
that he could walk
from here to Los Angeles...
and would not do him any good.
Throw him in the hole.
You son of a bitch.
Wait!
Yin, wait!
Yin!
He's not dead!
God, no!
Oh, God!
Son of a bitch.
Mazilli, I thought
you should know...
that you're completely alone.
Your brave colonel has abandoned
you to die here.
Braddock got away?
He'll die tomorrow.
So will you.
In the meantime...
if you're lonely...
play with your friend.
More wine, Colonel?
No.
Braddock gone!
Why keep him alive?
Now, you know,
I might be wrong...
but I don't think it's
a very good idea to kill me.
Why not?
I could always get
someone to pour my wine.
It's because
I'm the only one left...
who really knows how
Colonel Braddock thinks.
See, he hasn't gone yet.
Is that so?
Yes. He has stayed to try
and take revenge on you.
I will use Francois' helicopter.
We will capture him tomorrow.
We should have killed that guy
a long time ago.
We'd better get back.
You'll never find
this guy alive.
Just keep searching.
Braddock come back,
blow bridge down.
Lock up all the prisoners
and Nester!
You, to the bridge!
In there.
I'll bury him with this.
My God! It's a bomb!
Get out!
Damn American!
Open it.
Mazilli!
What the hell?
Braddock!
Let's go!
Duck!
Come on! Come on!
Damn! We got to find that rope.
They're getting too close.
Let's get out of here.
It's got to be here.
Emerson said
they were under a big rock.
There must be 60 big rocks.
Here it is!
Here.
Good luck, kid.
- Aren't you coming?
- I'm going after Ho.
If you're staying to fight,
there's no way I'm leaving you.
Here they come!
Get your ass down the cliff!
You idiot!
Come in.
So, Yin, we're all loaded up.
I'll see you in about a week.
Francois, I will need
your helicopter...
to look for the Americans.
I believe they've gone down
the river.
I am sorry. I can't help you.
You will not go.
I am going.
Come on, let's go.
Get your hands off...
What the hell are you doing?
They are following my order.
They needed a new leader after
they heard that you had died.
Ho.
Opelka.
Colonel.
I'm glad you made it, kid.
Thanks, Colonel.
Yin must have given up on me.
He thought you were dead.
How come you hung around?
I don't know.
I guess it was just
some kind of instinct.
I want you to guard the base.
If I'm not back in 24 hours...
go down the river
and try to find Mazilli.
Colonel, I know you don't need
me to guard the base.
I want to help you
get those bastards.
Colonel Braddock!
Yin's our enemy, too.
I'll kill him!
The fighting's over!
We all go home!
Colonel Braddock!
Dou Chou.
He's listening.
He knows we're here.
Yin dead. Believe now.
See, Colonel Braddock?
Come look for yourself.
Yin dead!
Sir, the boots. That's not Yin.
I'm going after Ho.
He's in one of those two shacks
down there.
If there's any fireworks,
here, throw these grenades.
Sir, what about Nester?
He can take care of himself.
He always has.
He won't show.
He'll come.
Good. They got Mazilli.
Let's go.
Colonel Braddock!
I'll give you
30 seconds to decide...
whether you want Mazilli
to live or die.
Your 30 seconds is up!
You have just murdered
your last man.
Psst. Mazilli...
anything you want me
to tell your kid?
Hold it!
Mazilli is mine.
Why don't we just tell
the kid that Daddy...
was a very brave soldier
right up till the very end?
Down!
Move it, Mazilli!
Nester... he came back to us.
Yeah, I know.
I'm going after Ho.
Cover us, Ho. We're going in.
Colonel, they're all
in Yin's house.
Opelka!
Lieutenant.
Opelka, left flank.
Mazilli, around back.
Wait.
Ready? Go!
Now!
Nobody could have lived
through this.
Colonel.
Remember how to fly this thing?
You better believe it.
You really didn't think
I'd leave...
without knowing for sure
you were dead?
You'll not just kill me.
You want to know
who the better man is.
That is why you stayed behind.
I also want to know.
That is why I kept you alive
all these years.
Now it is the time...
You and I, one-on-one.
No politics...
no weapons.
Just a little game to find out
who is the better man.
I knew you could not
resist my challenge.
Colonel Yin,
for the atrocities inflicted...
on the Vietnamese and American
prisoners of this camp...
I sentence you to death.
This is for Nester.
Not yet.
The game's over.
And this is for Franklin.
You lose.
This is for me.
Ripped by:
SkyFury