(Tropical birds chirp)
♪ GENTLE PIANO
AND ACOUSTIC GUITAR MELODY
(Footsteps crunch)
♪ PLEASANT WOODWIND MELODY
(Quiet conversation)
♪ TRADITIONAL BOUGAINVILLE VOCAL
GIRL: When I was young,
my mother wove me a sleeping mar.
She said that if I got lost
in a bad dream,
all I needed to do was roll over
and feel the very seam.
That seam was the current
thaf would carry me home.
But what K home was a bad dream?
(Tropical birds twitter)
Our teachers told us that the place
we lived was called Bougalnvllle,
part of a small group
of South Pacific islands
owned by Papua New Guinea,.
But according to my mother, our island
was a woman and we lived in her heart.
She said ntrone could own that.
I1: [*1 I I:'::f IL; Pi'
But Papua New Guinea said our heart
to a mining company.
(Splash echoes)
My dad used to work at the mine,
but when all the trouble staned,
he Ieﬂ to find work in Australia.
Mum and Dad argued a lot about that.
We were going to join him later.
Mum said we 'd go on the next boat.
That's what she said after every boat,.
MAN: Higher.
It's high as I can get it.
TV: ..suppl4'es are running low.
GIRL: News of war came to
our little village in bits and rumours.
We heard that some of ourpeople
declared war on the mine
and shut it down.
We heard that Papua New Guinea
was sending in the army.
We heard they were going to
seal off our island
so no-one would be able
to get in or our.
First, they closed the mine.
(Crowd reacts)
They cut off our supplies
and closed down the schools.
Ah' the whites left.
(Record player plays sombre opera)
AR except Pop-Eye, that is.
Mum said he stayed
because his wife Grace
would never leave the island again.
CHILDREN: Pop-Eye! Pop-Eye!
Pop-Eye! Pop-Eye!
(Children yell, laugh}
Argh!
(Children laugh)
GIRL: We thought Pop-Eye's tribe
had forgotten him.
Or that maybe he was being punished
for an old crime.
Whatever his reason,
was easy :0 see that Grace was mad.
Pop-Eye was more of a mystery,.
CHILDREN: Pop-Eye! Pop-Eye!
(Speaks in native tongue)
(Laughter)
(Laughs)
Mind your own business.
(Laughter continues)
♪ OPERA
WOMAN: The PNG government
mean to starve us out,
but Abraham said,
'God will provide the lamb.'
CHURCHGOER: Amen!
We still have what we always had.
We have our fish...
Amen!
...our pigs, our chicken, our fruits,
and we have our faith.
CONGREGATION: Amen!
(Benches creak)
♪ All good gifts around us
are sent from Heaven above
I' Then thank the Lord
♪ 0 thank the Lord
For all His love. I
(Hymn continues in distance)
Mum.
Mm?
Me laik askim yu samting.
We speak English in this house.
Do you miss Dad?
Why do you ask that, girl?
There's not going to be another boat,
is there?
...
Does it make a difference?
Sometimes I miss him.
Sometimes when you look along the beach,
there is your father, Matilda.
He's walking towards me.
And me?
And you, yes.
Your father is walking towards us both.
Get up.
(Groans)
Come on, lazybones! You've got school.
What are you talking about?
School's been closed for months.
We haven't got a teacher.
You do now.
(Chuckles)
(Children laugh)
(Children speak in native tongue)
He's coming! Sit down, sit down!
(Child whispers indistinctly)
(Clears throat)
(Children giggle)
Thank you for coming.
I wasn't sure you would.
Wasn't sure I would.
Look, I'll be honest. (Clears throat)
I... I have no wisdom.
I'm not a teacher,
but I will try my best.
That is my promise to you children. Yes?
Yes, Mr Watls.
CHILDREN: Yes, MrWatls.
Yes, Pop-Eye!
(Children giggle}
Oh, I know that some of you
call me 'Pop-Eye',
and... that's fine.
I actually quite like Pop-Eye.
CHILDREN: Yes, Mr Pop-Eye.
(D09 yawns)
(Children giggle)
(Bangs panel)
I want this to be a place of light,
no matter what happens.
So, the first ihing we must do
is clear this space for learning.
I have been saving some batteries
for a special occasion.
(Plays Pijin version
of Donovan's 'Sunshine Superman')
So let's open all the windows
and clean all the rubbish off the desks.
'My father's family name being Pirrip,
and my Christian name Philip...
...my infant tongue could make
of both names
nothing longer or more explicit
than Pip.
So, I called myself Pip,
and came to be called Pip.'
Yes. Well, I welcome questions.
And if you do have a question,
perhaps you'd be kind enough
to tell me your name.
Daniel, sir.
It's nice to meet you, Daniel.
Should we call you Pop-Eye,
or Mr Watis, or Mr Pip?
Those words were nof mine, Daniel.
They belong to Mr Dickens-
words that I think can make
a difference in our lives.
And tomorrow,
I will introduce you to Mr Dickens.
That's a white man's name,
No, Matilda. You heard wrong.
Pop-Eye is the Vast white man
around here.
There's no others.
But Mr Watts says there is.
Hey, Leela!
(All laugh)
(Women speak in native tongue, laugh)
CHILDREN: Mr Watts! Mr Watts! Mr Watts!
(Children shout over each other)
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What's your name?
I I  H
Very pleased to meet you, Mabel.
My mother was thinking Mr Dickens
might have some malaria tablets.
My dad wants some kerosene.
(Children shout over each other)
What about some beer?
(Children laugh)
Where is Mr Dickens?
He's right here.
The line you heard yesterday
was the first line of Great Expectations
by the greatest English writer
of the 19th century,
Charles Dickens.
Now, when you read the work
of a great writer,
you are making
their person's acquaintance,
so you could say
that you've already met Charles Dickens
on the page, so to speak.
Although you won't know him for a while.
When will we know him?
Well, I hope some of you will know him
by the time we finish the book.
The book is 59 chapters long,
we'll read a chapter a day...
6th February, 1990.
I'm sorry?
We'll know Mr Dickens
on the 6th of February next year.
(Half-laughs) Alright, well,
I'll take your word for it, uh...
My name is Matilda.
Matilda. That's a lovely name.
Where did you get such a pretty name?
The Australians at the mine gave it
to Dad to give Mum to give me.
(Spats)
(Quiet chuckling)
In a way, you could say that Mr Dickens
got Pip's name from his father too.
Who knows what else
you might have in common?
Right. Who wants to meet Mr Dickens?
CHILDREN: Me!
(Reads) 'I give Pirrip as
my father's family name
on the authority of his tombstone
and my sister,
Mrs Joe Gargery,
who married the blacksmith.
As I never saw my father or my mother,
and never saw any likeness
of either of them,
fortheir days were long before
the days of photographs,
my first fancies regarding
what they were like
were unreasonably derived
from their tombstones.
The shape of the letters
on my father's
gave me an odd idea that he was
a square, stout, dark man,
with curly black hair.
From the character and ium
of the inscription,
"Also Georgiana Wife of the Above,"
I drew a childish conclusion that
my mother was freckled and sickly.'
(Wailing)
'To five little stone lozenges,
each about a foot and a half long,
which were arranged in a neat row
beside their grave,
and were sacred to the memory
of five little brothers of mine,
who gave up trying to get a living
exceedingly early in
thai universal struggle.
I am indebted for a belief
I religiously entertained
thai they had all been born
on their backs
with their hands
in their trousers pockets,
and had never taken them out
in this state of existence.
At such a time I found out for certain
that this bleak place,
overgrown with nettles,
was the churchyard.'
(Crow caws)
♪ INTRIGUING STRINGS
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I came to see my brothers.
I'm sorry.
I never really knew them.
I actually used to think
they'd been born like that,
on their backs with their hands
in their trouser pockets.
Just never taken them out.
I prefer to think of them that way.
MAN: You there!
Get down.
(Gasps)
Stay there.
Wait.
Come here!
No, don't.“ Stop!
Hold your noise.
Keep still, or I'll cut your throat.
Don't cut my throat, sir.
Tell us your name.
Pip, sir! Pip!
You know what file is?
Yes, sir.
And wittles? You bring me lot to me,
at the old Battery. You do it.
And you shall be let to live.
Now, what do you say?
(Girl's voice) A battery, sir?
{Gasps)
TOM: Yes.
Not like the battery in my radio.
'Battery' in this case means
a military encampment.
A place with guns.
Like the no-go zone?
Where we webes awe
Yes. Kind of.
That's very good, Sam.
(Pigs snort, oink)
So he stole his mothefs pork pie?
Pip's an orphan.
He lives with his sister.
Brought him up by hand.
(Chuckles) Sounds like she needed to
use her hand on him a little more.
What would you do, girl,
if a man was hiding in the jungle
and asked you to steal from me?
Would you do that?
No.
Pop-Eye should be teaching you kids
proper behaviour.
From now on, I wanna know everything
that happens in that book,
You hear me, Matilda?
Yes, Mum.
TOM: 'That was a memorable day to me,
for it made great changes in me.
But it is the same with any life.
Imagine one selected day struck out
of your life
and think how different
its course would have been.'
(People speak in native tongue)
Let's go grab the malaria tablets.
(Continues indistinctly)
(Men speak in native tongue)
TOM: 'Pause you who read this
and think for a moment
of the long chain of iron or gold,
of thorns or ﬂowers,
that would never have bound you
but for the formation of the first link
on one memorable day.'
(Helicopter blades chop in distance)
♪ GENTLE PIANO
(Men speak indistinctly)
(Chains rattle)
Where are they taking him?
Exile. Sending him to Australia.
My Dad's in Australia.
Do you miss him?
I guess I'm lucky.
Why?
I never knew my father
long enough to miss him.
Are you ready, Pip?
We'd best get back before your sister
goes on a rampage.
Will I see you again?
Who's that?
She's a friend.
Does she havea name?
WOMAN: Matilda!
What the heck you doing, girl?
Mr Watts?
Yes, Daniel.
What's it like to be white?
(Children chuckle softly)
You mean what's it like to be white,
or what's it like to be white here?
Both'
A bit like what the last mammoth
must have felt, I suppose.
It's lonely at times. I don't know.
What's it like being black?
Normal.
(Chuckles)
We only feel black around white people.
Yes, well, I'd say
the same is true for me.
(Footsteps approach)
(Whispers indistinctly)
Matilda, would you like to
do the honours?
This is my mum, Dolores.
Dolores Naimo,
Mrs Naimo, please come in.
Thank you.
I know you kids have been hearing
some story from Mr Watts,
but I'm here to tell you
that stories have a job to do.
They can't just lie around
like lazybone dogs.
(Giggles)
They have to teach you something.
That's why I brought a book -
the Good Book.
When the missionaries came,
they taught us to believe in God.
But when we asked to see God,
they wouldn't introduce him to us.
So many people prefer to Hve by
the wisdom of the crabs
and the firefish
that is shaped like the Southern Star.
You must believe in something.
'God said, "Let there be light,“
and there was light'
There is no sentence more beautiful
in the world than that one.
MR WATTS: Yes, Violet.
What is the wisdom of the crabs?
(Churchgoers sing hymn)
♪ Hallelujah
♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah... ♪
(Singing continues)
Mr Watts, can I ask you something?
Of course.
Is it strange to feel like I know Pip?
I mean, really know him?
I think that is probably the greatest
compliment you could pay Mr Dickens.
Do you know him too?
My Pip is probably not exactly the same
as your Pip,
but, yes, I believe I do.
Today, we are not going to
start with Great Expectations.
(Children groan)
Today we are very lucky
to have Mabel's mother.
Mrs Tanganani.
Thank you, Mr Watts.
I am here today
hoping to surprise you kids.
What if I tell you that some gardens
begin their life in the ocean?
The heart seed ﬂoats on the water,
then it washes up on the sand.
Seven days later, the sun and the wind
dry it as light as the husk.
Three months later,
a little seedling grows,
its white flowers open and look back
to the sea where it came from.
Why am I telling you this, children?
Because its stamen makes a fierce flame
and keeps away the mosquitos.
Right. Mrs Tanganani, the heart seed.
(Children applaud and giggle)
Thank you.
Alright, then.
(Clears throat) Uh...
(Whispers indistinctly)
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
There's a place in the back.
(Children whisper)
TOM: Now, where did we get to?
The best place to find broken dreams
is down on the wharf.
All those dead fish with their eyes
and mouths open,
they just can't believe
that they are not in the sea
and will never be again.
By the way, fish, they go to Heaven.
(Children giggle)
Don't believe any other shit you hear'
(Children laugh)
WOMAN: Silence is good
for a lot of things.
Boys who shout have mud in iheir souls.
Stay away from boys who abuse silence.
Other than that, I don't want to
tell you girls where to shop.
To kill a pig, you get two fat uncles to
hold it down and whack it on the chest.
How big do these uncles have to be?
Fat ones. Fat is good.
Skinny is no bloody good.
Pop-Eye's no bloody good.
(Children laugh)
MR WATTS: Right. (Clears throat)
(Reads) 'Our conference was held
in the state parlour
which was feebly lighted by one candle.
It began with the strange gentleman's
drawing the candle to him
and looking over some entries
in his pocketbook.'
(All laugh)
(Snobbish voice) '"My name is Jaggers.
I am a lawyer in London.
Now, Joseph Gargery...”
(Children laugh)
(Folksy accent) "'Yes, sir?"
"I am the bearer of an offer
to relieve you of this young fellow,
your apprentice.
You would not object
to cancel his indentures?'
'Well,1he answer is no."
"Very well!
Recollect the admission you have made
and don'1 try to go from ii presently."
'Well, who's a going to try?"
"I didn'1 say anyone is going to try...
(All laugh)
Hmm... (Chuckles)
(AH laugh)
'"Now, I return to this young fellow.
The communication I have got to make is,
that he has Great Expectations."'
(All laugh)
CHILDREN: Shh. Shh.
♪ GENTLE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
(indistinct murmuring)
TOM: 'It is a most miserable thing
to feel ashamed of home.
I had believed in the best parlour
as a most elegant saloon.
I had believed in the front door
as a mysterious portal.
I had believed in the forge
as the glowing road to manhood
and independence.
Within a single year,
all this was changed.
Now it was all coarse and common.
The change was made in me.
The thing was done.
Well- or ill-done,
excusably or inexcusably,
it was done.'
♪ SEDATE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
Is that you, boy?
(Gasps)
Where have you been, girl?
Just playing on the beach.
Idon'1 want you out alone at night
anymore.
(Pigs grunt)
Sam!
(Wails) Sam]
(weeps)
/3&3?“ Sam!
(Wails, shrieks)
(Man speaks in native tongue)
TOM: You can'! send them away.
They're just boys. They're your boys.
WOMAN: Not anymore.
Where's Sam?
TOM: 'What could I become
with these surroundings?
How can my character
fail 10 be inﬂuenced by them?
But I knew very well
thal it was not all good.'
I think the sooner you leave here,
the better.
Thank you, Mr Jaggers'
Thank you so much.
Matilda? (Giggles)
My dream is out, Matilda!
What are you talking about?
I believe that Miss Havisham
intends me for EsteHa after all.
Matilda, I'm leaving.
Leaving?
TOM: Pip has been given the opportunity
to become whoever he wants.
It means he's free to make bad choices.
;. :1  E?
TOM: You're not very fond of Estella,
are you?
She's cruel'
(Helicopter blades chop in distance)
(Birds twitter loudly)
(Man shouts indistinctly)
Matilda!
♪ INTENSE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
(People yell)
Matilda!
Are you alright?
(Soft moans)
It's alright. It's alright.
It's alright, darling.
It's alright,darling. It's alright.
Domes?
(Men shout in distance)
(Gunfire)
(Dog yelps)
(Baby cries}
(Coughing)
No! (Screams)
No, no! No!
(Weep5)
DOLORES' Matilda'
(sobs)
Go and find your own kid!
Do you believe in the Devil, Matilda?
Mr Waits says that the Devil
is just a symbol, not living flesh.
Nor is his Pip.
But you can't hear the Devil's voice.
You can hear Pip's.
That's it. You're not going back
to the school anymore.
Why? So I can be dumb like you?
(Grunts)
If it wasn't for you,
we'd be in Australia with Dad.
TOM: 'Heaven knows we need
never be ashamed of our tears,
forihey are rain upon
the blinding dust of earth,
overlying our hard heads.
I was better after I had cried,
than before -
more sorry, more aware of my
own ingratitude, more gentle.
We changed again, and yet again,
and it was now too late
and too far to go back,
and I went on.
And the mists had all
solemnly risen now,
and the world lay spread before me.
My daughter, my lovely Matilda,
says she doesn't believe in the Devil.
She believes in Pip!
Well, Mrs Naimo,
what if I were to say to you
that on the page
Pip and the Devil
have the same status?
Each one strikes out on their own,
each one has the chance
to make their own mistakes...
And to abandon his family?!
How will Pip even know
if he's made a mistake?
If there is no God and no Devil, how
will he know what's right from wrong?
Mr Watts here thinks
he can know ah things,
but for the rest of us people -
and that includes you,
my beautiful ﬂower, Matilda -
pack the teaching of the Good Book
into your person.
That way, you kids will be able
to save Pop-Eye here
because I'm not going to.
Thank you, Mrs Naimo,
for such an illuminating lesson
on the relationship
between good and evil.
Once again, you've given us
much food forthought.
A shrine. Pip in the Pacific.
Well, why not? Great Expectations
doesn't tell the whole of Pip's life.
In the...
(Yells)
I1: 1.; I ii L-: I I
Yep, you're quite right.
All in good time.
Mr Watts?
Miss Naimo.
Pip's different in London.
I don't understand why he lets
Herbert Pocket call him Handel.
Pip is like an immigrant.
He's moving from one level of society
to another.
A change of name is as good as
a change of clothes.
We all need a change sometimes
to help us on our way.
He abandoned Joe.
Yes, he did.
It's not easy to be
a perfect human being, Matilda.
♪ TRADITIONAL BOUGAINVILLE MUSIC
(Children laugh)
No! Let me.
(Whistling)
(Softly} Matilda. Get dressed.
(Men shout in native tongue)
Hurry up!
(Bangs on door)
Move, move, move, move! Hurry up!
(Pants)
(Shouts commands)
(Soldiers shout over each other)
(Helicopter blades chop)
SOLDIER: Go, go, go, go! Go! Go on!
(Villagers scream)
(Soldier shouts commands)
(Speaks in native tongue)
SOLDIER: Move, move, move, move, move!
(Soldiers shout)
(Shouts in native tongue)
Please, no-one wants to hurt you.
We would just like your names
for security reasons.
You!
Hey. Name'
Dolores.
D-O-L-O-R-E-S'
Now you.
Matilda.
I notice there are no young men
in the village.
Plenty of girls.
(Soldiers chuckle}
Mabel'
But no young men. Why is that?
We saw a signal on the beach.
What 8 P-I-P?
(Shouts in native tongue}
What is P-l-P?
Daniel.
Pip! Mr Pip!
Mr Pip? ls his name on this list?
Pip belongs to Mr Dickens, sir.
Who is Mr Dickens?
(Speaks in native tongue)
SOLDIER: Move, move, move, move!
Hurry' UP!
(Soldier speaks in native tongue)
Past!
(Man speaks in native tongue)
Y-3.1 are Mr Dickens?
(Chuckles)
Yes, I am.
Where is Pip?
Sir, Pip...
Pip is a creation.
He's a character in a book.
I understand the confusion, but if you
will allow me to show you the book,
you will see that Pip is a character
irom the novel Great Expedations.
It's a novel. It's a story.
A wonderful story.
Matilda, would you mind?
I've left the book on my desk.
♪ SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
(Soldiers shout)
The book isn't there!
There is no book?
There is. I just can't find it.
I will not be lied to.
Sir, I assure you...
No. Stay there.
You say there is a book, fine.
Find me the book, orfind Mr Pip'
(Soldiers shout in native tongue)
(Woman shrieks)
(Soldiers shout over each other)
(Shouts in native tongue)
Move, move, move!
(Cries)
Hey! (Shouts in native tongue)
I will give you one more chance.
Bring me this man Pip,
or I will burn it all,
Please, sir! The man
you're looking for is... He's a fiction.
He's a character out of a book.
No. You will speak when I ask you.
I am not interested
in any more of your lies.
Go back, go back, go back, go back,
go back, go back.
(Glass shatters, fire roars)
(Air hisses)
(Woman shrieks)
(Soldier shouts)
Y-cu have been foolish.
You cannot defeat me with your lies.
Next time I come here, I expect
this man Pip to be handed over'
(Soldiers shout in native tongue)
I'm so sorry.
(Gasps)
(Distant g unfire)
(Men shout in distance)
♪ GENTLE PIANO MUSIC
(Women speak in native tongue)
(Women whisper)
(People speak in distance)
(Dog barks}
What's going on?
You stay here.
No!
Matilda!
Don't be foolish, girl!
Let go!
It's OK, Matilda.
It's alright.
Matilda. Matilda!
No, leave it, Matilda!
It's your fathefis!
(Door creaks)
(Crow caws)
(Chains rattle)
(Grunts)
Hold your noise!
(Children giggle)
♪ MELANCHOLY INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
Estella'
Whoo!
Understand that.
(Grunts)
(Metal clangs rhythmically)
(Knocks at door)
I know you lost all your books.
I wrote some things...
...about Great Expectations.
That's very good, Matilda.
Would you like me to leave it?
Put it in the pocket of my jacket.
Thank you.
Wake up. I have something to tell you.
♪ TRADITIONAL SINGING
Our Father which art in Heaven...
(Branches crack)
Mr Watis, your Grace
was the cleverest of all us girls.
We all went to school together.
Thank you, Dolores.
Grace could speak German.
And hold her breath underwater
for longerthan anyone.
And anyway matter,
she was beautiful too.
And remember me day she lost her tooth?
She was lying in the canoe,
watching the fish
and the sea wave came and smacked
that canoe right in the mouth.
(Mild laughter)
When she got her first pair of shoes,
she was so proud,
she carried them everywhere,
'cause she didn't want them
to get dirty.
(Mild laughter)
What about you?
Grace lived in a beautiful big house
in London.
She lived in one part of the house,
I lived in the other.
But... it was very hard
not to notice Grace.
I'd never seen anyone so black
with teeth so white.
She would come by every evening
for a cup of tea
and she would sil
across the table from me.
And then one evening... (Chuckles)
...she brought her chair
around to my side
and she took my hand
and she placed it in her lap.
(Chuckling)
(Wolf-whistles)
(Sighs, sniffs)
My darling Grace
gave me great happiness.
None greater than
when she gave me a child.
A baby girl to whom
we gave the name Sarah.
And we couldn't stop looking at her.
We had a room in the middle
of the house, between us, for Sarah.
We filled this room with our thoughts,
our memories, our histories,
which we'd take it in turns
to write it on the wall.
And Grace traced Sarah's lineage
from her all the way back
to a ﬂying fish.
Was I on this wall?
Uh, yes, I believe you were.
Sarah fell to meningitis
before herfirst birthday.
Grief...
(Breathes heavily)
Grace couldn't...
she couldn't move, didn't speak.
She never left her bed.
And I tried... I...
We moved homes, we moved countries.
Finally, I thought that the best way
would be for Grace to reinvent herself.
I don't know how many of you here know
who the Queen of Sheba was.
It's in the Bible.
The Queen of Sheba
was a very wise black woman
who wanted to see if she could match
Solomon's legendary wisdom.
And she communed with him
of all that was in her heart
and nothing was hid.
(Door opens)
We've all lost a lot in recent times.
And those losses,
I think we should use them...
...lo remind ourselves of the things
that we could never lose -
our minds and our imaginations.
Where are our imaginations?
Out there, and in here.
(Half-laughs)
Alright, let's try something different.
All of you close your eyes.
Now, in a voice that only you can hear,
I want you to say your name.
(Children murmur)
Just say it to yourself, everyone.
...
iii I:::I I fn ..
(Children murmur)
Now, no-one ever-
in the whole history of the world-
no-one has ever used your voice
to say your name.
It belongs to you.
Matilda Naimo. Matilda Naimo.
No-one can take that away from you.
When Mr Dickens sat down in 1860
and started to write Great Expectations,
the first thing he had to do was to
clear a space iorihe voice 01 Pip.
And that is what my friend Matilda
has done.
She's started to write the story of Pip.
She has given us a special task,
a sacred task-
we have to retrieve the story
of Great Expectations.
So, who's with me?
Yes. Christopher.
Pip wanted to be a gentleman.
Yes, he did.
Can anyone be a gentleman?
Yes, they can.
Even a poor person?
Absolutely a poor person
can be a gentleman.
A gentleman... a gentleman is someone
who never forgets their manners,
no matter what the situation is,
no matter how terrible, how awful.
Money and social standing
have got nothing to do with it.
A gentleman always tries to do
the right thing.
Where have you been?
School, of course.
What, with the dumb bugger, Pop-Eye?
Mum, I know you talked Mr Watts
into coming back.
(Both laugh)
TOM: This will remove Pip
from the protective comfort of home
to the unknown metropolis.
Metropolis. Uh... Alright.
Let's say that this here
is our little village.
In Pip's time, greater London
would be this immense metropolis.
We've got a new roof on our place.
(All laugh)
(Children laugh)
(Street vendor calls out)
Tag! Can't catch me!
(Women converse)
Pip'
Iii: I I
Sorry, would you excuse us, Herbert?
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
I'm just... I'm running late for
a meeting with Miss Havisham.
I'll walk with you.
No, it's the young Miss Havisham,
Estella.
Anyways, it was very nice to see you.
Who was that, Handel?
Nobody.
MATILDA: His name is Pip.
Or have you abandoned that too,
along with Joe and everyone else?
And you're so much better?
I'm sorry, Matilda, but you have no idea
what is expected of a gentleman.
I do. I just don't see one here.
Do you not have your own shadow
to play with?
Shit. Matilda. What are you doing
creeping around here?
What Estella says to Pip - do you not
have your own shadow to play with?
Yes. Very good.
Do you want to write this down?
Dxd Mrs Watts read Great Expectatxons?
Grace?
Sadly, no.
She tried.
Till finally she said
that she would reach the end
if I would do the same with the Bible,
and that was that.
The thing is, you can't really pretend
to read a book.
Your eyes will always give you away.
Your eyes and your breathing.
The house could be on fire
and a reader deep in a book
wouldn'l even notice
until the wallpaper was in ﬂames.
And for me,
Great Expectations was such a book.
It gave me permission to...
change my life.
Reinvent myself.
Matilda.
There's a boat leaving
the night after the full moon.
Gilbert's father could take us out
to meet it.
A few hours on the open sea
and you'd be in the Solomon Islands.
And Australia?
Well, in the Solomons,
it'd be up to you.
Your mum too, Matilda.
But it's very important that
you don't tell anyone about this,
not even Dolores,
uniil I give the word.
Understand?
(Whistling)
(Dog barks in distance)
(People shout in distance)
(Whistling)
MAN: Hurry up! Go!
(Gunfire)
(People scream)
(Soldiers shout)
(Soldier shouts commands)
You. Move, move, move, move.
Hey! (Shouts)
(Soldier shouts in native tongue)
SOLDIER: Move!
Move out, move out.
We need medicines.
What medicines we had, you burned.
Lasi time we were here, you were
concealing a man named Pip.
Have you decided to hand him to me yet'?
I thought not.
Move'
I will ask you again for your name.
My father's family name being Pi rrip,
and my Christian name Philip,
my infant tongue
could make of both names
nothing longer or more explicit
than Pip.
So I called myself Pip
and came to be called...
(Gunshot)
(All scream)
SOLDIER: Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
(Gunshot)
(All scream)
SOLDIER: Hey, shut up!
(Weeping)
I'm finished with being lied to.
(Soldiers speak in naive tongue)
(Speaks in native tongue)
Move, move!
(Pigs grunt, oink)
(Blades hack)
(People gasp, scream)
(Pigs squeal, grunt)
(Sobs)
(Soldiers laugh)
(Soldiers converse, laugh)
(Laughs)
Look up!
Who saw this?
No, Daniel.
I saw it, sir.
Sir, he doesn't know what he's saying.
He doesn'1 know what he's saying, sir.
Come.
No, he...
No!
(Men speak in native tongue)
Please, he doesn't know
what he's saying!
(Screams)
W'-"Eli 5)
Would you like to go with him?
Yes, sir.
(weeps)
Get up! Get up! Get up! Get up!
Get up! Get up!
(Speaks in native tongue)
(sobs)
Now, once more I will ask you...
'who saw the white man die?
Who saw?
Mid'
Sir, I saw your men chop up
the white man and feed him to the pigs.
He was a good man.
I'm here as God's witness.
I am God's witness.
(Gunshot)
(Villagers scream)
(Soldiers shout)
Sir, I will be God's witness.
Take her.
MAN: No!
(Soldiers speak in native tongue)
Stay.
(Man speaks in native tongue)
You. Are you related to this woman?
She's my mother.
OK, girl. Move, move. Move.
Move it. Move it.
Does anyone else have anything to say?
(sobs)
Move, move.
DOLORES: No
(Dolores groans)
DOLORES' No! No'
(Soldiers grunt)
No!
Matilda, my darling.
(Whimpers)
(Gasps)
(Chuckles)
Oh, Matilda, my darting. Yeah.
No! Le-1 her go! Please!
OFFICER: Stop it!
Stand up
Stand up.
Please...
Please, sir, I beg you, have mercy.
She's just a little girl.
Now you beg me, and for what?
What will you give me
to save your daughter?
Take me instead.
My men have had you already.
You have nothing left for me.
Take my life.
Did you hear that?
Your mother has offered her rife
for you.
What do you say?
Matilda, don't say anything.
No, I wanna hear.
What do you say to your mother?
Very well.
(Shouts in native tongue)
Move, Move. Move,
No. You stay here.
(Pigs grunt, oink)
(Dolores screams)
(Pigs snort)
(Blades hack)
♪ SOMBRE FEMALE VOCAL
(Matchstick scrapes and ﬂicks)
(Tropical bird chirps)
(Cigarette hisses loudly)
♪ EMOTIONAL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
(Flies buzz)
(Pig squeals)
(Pig shrieks)
(Man coughs)
(Weeping and howling)
(Villagers scream, wail)
(Droplets patter)
♪ SOMBRE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
(Music intensifies)
♪ POWERFUL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
Hold onto me
Held on'
I saw something. I1 is. It's her.
(Woman speaks in native tongue)
Wait!
We have to go, Matilda.
(Motor starts)
(Speaks indistinctly)
MAN: Keep going. Slowly, slowly.
Keep going up.
MAN 2: Right.
Say 'ahhh'.
Ahhh.
Matilda - that's a nice name.
Where did you get that name?
Oh!
Here we are.
You've goi some eating to catch up on.
I bought you birthday cakes
for every one I've missed.
Guess you were still a little girl
in my head.
It's nice.
Alright.
Well, I'll let you settle in.
♪ EMOTIONAL PIANO AND STRING MUSIC
(Joseph sobs)
(Sobbing continues)
(Fan blades whistle)
You alright?
I love you.
(School bell rings)
We've got a new student today.
Welcome, Matilda.
Matilda is from...
I came here from Honiara
in the Solomon Islands.
Oh, right. It says on your form...
My mum couldn'tcome, so I came
hereto help look after my dad.
OK. Right.
So if everyone can open
their maths books to page 348,
we're just gonna pick up
where we left off yesterday.
So yesterday we were having a look at
making up equations with algebra.
Today we're just gonna carry on with
using equations to solve problems.
So that first example there
at the top of page 348.
If I think of a number
and then multiply it by seven...
♪ SOMBRE STRINGS
...I get the same result as if I had
multiplied the number by four...
and then added 15
So if we're writing an equation
for this information...
(Girls giggle)
(Students. converse in distance)
(School bell rings)
(Voices merge and echo)
(Car door opens)
It couldn't wait till after school?
The man travelled from Sydney
to see you. Some kind of lawyer.
JOSEPH: So what's this about exactly'?
Uh, you're aware of the situation
in Bougainville
me the bockade was h'.ed7
You've been there?
How long since you were there?
It's been ten years.
I assume you remember Mr Thomas Watts?
He was my teacher... in Bougainville.
Well, MrWatls passed away
during the conflict.
Did you know that?
I'm sorry.
But it seems he left a will which
bequeaths much of his property to you.
Mind you, we've had a devil of a time
trying to find you.
It's primarily his house - half a house.
It's a flat, really.
The other half reverts to h s wife.
His wife's dead.
No. No, I can assure you June Watts
is still very much alive.
And where's the flat?
In Gravesend, in London.
ANNOUNCER, ON TANNOY: Piaf form four...
(Knocks at door)
Mrs Watts?
I thought you were from Australia.
I am.
Go ahead. It's yours.
I'll put the kettle on.
♪ GENTLE PIANO AND STRING MUSIC
(Crockery clinks)
(Cat bell jingles)
JUNE: Don't get many visitors.
Went out and got the strawberry creams
especially.
Thank you. It was lovely of you
to see me today, Mrs Watts.
Your husband had a big influence on me.
Tom did?
He was my teacher.
A long time ago in Bougainville.
So you knew her then? The other woman.
I married a weak man, Matilda.
I don't want to sound unkind,
but it's true.
Tom was not a brave man.
He should have left me properly
rather than carry on the way he did.
I'm sorry, Mrs Watts.
I didn't know about any of that.
Waier under the bridge now.
We were young.
Everyone was young in those days.
I suppose you knew about
Tom's theatre thing.
♪ MOODY WOODWIND AND STRINGS
There she is The Queen of Sheba
(Half-laughs) He had some funny ideas,
that director.
'Mani-garde,' Tom said.
The Queen of bloody Sheba.
I I::f. %j:I"1“lfilr~:: fin 1...:-::..;I"“:..
I didn't give her nearly enough thought.
She was always laughing.
II: -1:: 1:; ;; Ti"
It was like living next door to someone
who was permanently drunk.
Couldn't imagine him on her island.
What was he like?
When you last saw him.
He was a gentleman.
He was always a gentleman, Mrs Watts.
I'm not going to take the ﬂat.
It's noi mine. It's yours.
Thank you so much, Mrs Watts.
I'll pour the tea.
No. That's OK. Thank you.
You've given me so much already.
♪ GENTLE PIANO
Take it if you want.
But it's yours.
Never read it.
Torn would want you to have it.
♪ GRACEFUL WOODWIND MELODY
So what brings you
to the Dickens Museum?
It's a long story.
Did you meet Mr Dickens?
PIP: I've met Mr Dickens,
and that is not him.
Yes, the Dickens I knew
told stories too.
And he wore a white suit
and a red clown nose
and collected shells
from sparkling blue waters.
Pip--'
(sobs)
TOM: Heaven knows we need
never be ashamed of our fears
for they are rain
upon the blinding dust of earth,
overlying our hard hearts.
I was better aﬂer! had cn'ed,
than before -
more sorry, more aware of
my own ingratitude, more gentle.
We changed again, and yet again,
and it was now too late
and :00 tar to go back,
and I went on.
And the mists had all
solemnly risen now,
and the world lay spread before me.
♪ EMOTIONAL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
BOY: What is the wisdom of the crabs?
Well, my mum always said
that wind and rain are on the way
if a crab digs straight down and blocks
the hole leaving marks like sun rays.
Who is your mum?
L"'::~""li%? I f!
(squeals excitedly)
(Giggles)
DOLORES' Sometimes I miss mm.
Sometimes I will look along the beach.
There is your father, Matiida.
He '5 walking towards me.
MATILDA: And me?
DOLORES: And you, yes.
Your father is waking towards us both.
MATILDA: My mothers name
is Dolores Mary Naimo.
My father's is Joseph Francis Naimo,.
My father woiited with the Australians
who gave him the name 'Matilda'.
He gave it to my mother
for her to give me,
and so they called me Matilda
and I came to be known as Matilda.
♪ TRADITIONAL BOUGAINVILLE
VOCAL MUSIC
Captions by CSI Australia