TV Channel "RUSSIA" presents
Andrei Malukov film
Produced by 'A1 Kino and Video'
(ST.PETERSBURG OVERVIEW)
Subtitles translated by Satvic
- Medal for "Bravery"
- So, how much for everything?
Can you drop the price?
.... for wholesale buyer?
- Look, Spirit
- What?
... you.. With this Borman
how long have you been digging?
- 2nd year
- And how is it making out?
Depends on how lucky you get
and how hard you work
Ashota, our competitor, is digging
with magnetic finders and other gadgets
and they are making $500/month
So why are you wasting time with Borman?
Go to Ashota
Ha Ha! we made $4K in 2 month with Borman!
He's got the nose for it.
Hasn't asked us to dig a single empty hole.
Without any magnetic finders
- Lucky?
- Neah, educated. He was 'history' major,
till they kicked him out
Somebody ratted out his business
- Chuha, how do you know all this?
- We go way back, went to the same kinder garden.
Metaphorically speaking ..
we were raised on the same piss pot.
I see.
- "Bravery" medal
- Yep.
and to "Achievements in combat"
It's nice to deal with you, -
you don't jack up the price
shake on it.
(crown yelling "Gorka" to newly weds)
Listen, turn this crap off!
You're shit!
What did you say? don't understand
Russian any more?
Let me go, come on!
get out of my car.
Tell him not to touch me anymore.
Cherep (skull), your job is to dig,
not to damage my hired labor.
- he started it...
- Tomorrow at 6, I'm not waiting.
Chuha, you hear me? If you're late,
you'll be hiding from the Military Draft
- What? subway?
- We'll walk
- Kick his ass!
- Come on! Come on!
Kick his ass! harder!
(Our Russia. Ours.
Our territory, here is our home. )
(These streets know everybody's face
We'll always be #1 here
Don't cross our way)
(We live without problems,
Without stupid questions
We know what's worth what)
(We have one answer to all questions
It's our town, there is nobody better than us)
(and there is nobody better than us)
(Our territory,
Our base is here
We know what we want from life)
(We go forward, looking for our path
While burning life
So what!)
( They say we're doing it all wrong,
The fact is, we're the best here! )
(We have one answer to all questions
It's our town, there is nobody better than us)
(and there is nobody better than us)
Please, sit down
- What?
- Please, sit down.
- - - - - WE ARE FROM THE FUTURE - - - -
( BACK IN TIME )
Thanks much.
Ashot!
(WHISTLING)
Ashot. Bitch, digging our spot!
- Did you see that?
- So.
- I know. So.
Here, take your hatchet and get the fuck out
What, you think you bought this land?
You think this ground is yours
just because you marked it with sticks?
What?!
Where are you going?! Freeze!
Sergey!!
Listen, Ashot. If I see you here again,
I'll have to kill you. Got it?
- Got it.
- Ok. We're done then.
- You think you came here to sleep?
- Piss off, it's my lunch time.
It's his lunch time.
Borman, war is war,
but lunch has to be on time.
Go, figure out some food,
see what we have.
Here. Thanks.
Cherep, don't you want to put
some symbols on your forehead?
So... here...
Where..?
Guys, who took the canned food?
What do you mean "took"?
We had 3 yesterday,
today only 1 left.
and only 1/2 of bread.
- Why are you looking at me for?
- Who else are we to look at?
What are you doing, Bitch?
How was I to know I was taking the
last of it? It was dark at night.
You're such a cunt!
Left everyone without food.
Telling you right away, I will NOT allow to be beaten.
Hey, Borman, come on!
I'll make up for it,
I'll dig like a tractor!
You're not getting paid for today.
Now go to the store in the village,
buy some food.
- Me? Alone?
- You'll go with him.
Buy Vodka at the store, otherwise we'll
get poised by that home made crap.
What about change?
Till the last penny.
- Dumbass.
- I'll show you "Dumbass"!
Cherep, why the hell did you
come here with us?
I want "steel cross",  or a German knife
- I see.
- But if I find Walther (german pistol), I'll be very happy
Of course, no skinhead is complete without a Walther
Your must be reading "Main Kamph" aloud in your group?
By the way, it's a worthy book.
Right. So, you're praying to Hitler?
If I were Stalin, I'd join Hitler and
take control over the U.S.
You're so dumb, Cherep, whatever was left
of your brain got washed down your stomach.
But your brain is so large it's
squeezing out into this infestation farm.
Gorilla
- Piss off!
- What? Come here!
Piss off!
Cherep, for last time, piss off!
Where?
- Cherep, I'll kill you!
- Where?
Get off me!
- Are you death? Don't touch my dreadlocks! Bitch!!
- Don't move, or it won't come out straight.
Fascist! Bastard! Bitch!
Listen, Chuh, I'm reading some
German's diary, he was fighting here in 1942
That 'oper Bonhof' is describing the war in August
Awesome.
Spirit - is cool, he's got it right.
Let's go eat something? we bought everything.
Let's go work "something".
let's go.
Aaaaa !
What's this here?
Wow.
Quiet, don't move.
We don't want to blow ourselves up.
And don't hide it for yourself
We figure equal shares for everyone.
- It's you who steals food at night,..
- Quiet.
- ...look what I found.
- quiet-quiet-quiet.
Go get a flashlight.
- Ok.
Get over here. Here
Stand up and don't move.
- Nurse?
- Yes, nurse.
You can always tell a woman.
Borman, flashlight!
Give me.
Well, beautiful
Careful.
Officer's bag.
"August 23rd, 1942 ...
Dear Mother..."
Damn!
"...it's been a while since I've written to you.
We start advancing soon.
My soldiers are in a good mood..."
I bet it's a letter by an officer.
Is it possible he was fighting Bonhof here?
Borman! Captain and safe
3 "Cubic" - lieutenant major
This is probably his watch.
- 6:42, precise time
- What?
- They were killed at 6:42.
Take the safe.
Come on.
"TT". (Russian pistol model by Makarov)
Finally.
Take the light.
- This is the shit
- Open it.
Ok, what you got?
We might find some medals...
- Look, ammo.
- Awesome.
- So? See? Didn't we get lucky?
- We really can, when we want to.
Give me.
We can.
For the bag!
to make sure it's not the last one.
To kill you for the dreadlocks?
Huh?
I'm going to stick this spoon in your eye.
Just make it quick, no suffering.
Come'n, don't be scared. Joke.
- Let's go shoot some cans instead
- Let's go!
- How is it?
- Nice! Turn it towards me.
Now I'll make my headshot.
Loaded?
- What happened?! Huh?
- Are you a completed idiot? Get out of here!
- What do you want, I don't get it?
- Get off me! Don't shoot if you don't want to.
- Don't do that!
- Borman!
- Shut up.
- What? You finally got a voice?
- Borman!
Shut up Chug. You hear me?
What?
- Think before you do, dumbass.
- What did I do?
Guys!
- Borman, aborigines are coming.
- Guys!
- What the hell.
There you are, I was looking for you in the woods.
- Hey, grandma, are you sure you're looking for us?
- You, darlings, who else?
Here, I brought you some milk,
just like I promised yesterday.
- I think she's confusing us with Ashot's guys
- I'm curious, what they told her.
You are probably tired.
- Milk restores energy.
- Thank you.
- Huh?
- Come on.
- We should pay for it.
Grandma, how much do we owe you?
What are you saying, "owe"!
You think I don't know what
you're doing here.
It'd be good to bury the soldiers.
- I wanted to ask you.
- Ask, mother, ask anything you want.
- Would you like us to bring you some firewood,
or Chuha can milk your goat.
- No, that's not necessary.
- I have firewood.
- Calm down
My son disappeared here in summer of 1942.
Red Army soldier: Dmitry Sokolov.
- That's not easy
- Yes.
- Only if there are any documents left.
He had a cigarette case with engraving
"For devotion to revolution".
His grandfather gave it to him before the war
- Silver?
- It's shiny with red stone in the center.
- Don't worry grandma, now we'll find it for sure
- Yes we'll find it.
- We'll find it.
We'll find it for sure
- Thank you, may God watch over you.
- We'll certainly do our best.
- Don't forget to leave us your address, grandma...
...so we know for sure
where to bring it.
Take some rest
- It's hot
- Yes
Hot. Hot. Very hot.
- There is a lake close by.
- Yep.
It's good, clean.
- Take a swim, enjoy.
- We will, grandma.
- Thanks, grandma
- Thank you boys.
- Thanks grandma.
Thank you
Let me.
There!
Sorry bro.
Look, -"Filatov Sergey Ivanovich,
born in 1917, private. Not in the Party"
Does he have an exact name like you?
Wait! This is .. that's my photo!
No way? Let me see
Wow!
Yes, that' you.
" Andrei Alex..." That's you - Smirnov
Huh?
That's right. that's me
"Vasilyev Oleg Petrovich"
Cherep, that's you!
Right! Let me look.
I'm not getting it.
What about me?
"Beroev Vitaly Semenovich"
Let me see if I got it right. Cherep
almost put a hole in his own skull?
Where did you buy that vodka, shitface?
In the village, in a kiosk.
Didn't I ask you not to buy anywhere
but at the store?  Who knows what's in it?
Now, because of this imbecile
we're stuffed with Metil spirit
Come on, Borman, no Metil here,
good vodka, right?
- Really good.
- Good.
- Good vodka.
It's hallucinations.
hallucinations? What about this?!
Also hallucinations?!
- Hallucinations?!
- Lets go to the lake. That's it!
- Maybe we should sober up a bit first...
- Bring some books .. maybe we'll figure
out if its really hallucinations
...from the cold water.
And... so... we going to leave
everything here as is?
Hey!
Dammit!
Let's not drown each other,
I swim just like a stone.
What the hell!!
What's this?!
Have you gone crazy?!
Let's get out of here!
Hey!
Fireworks, maybe!
They're celebrating some 'New Year'!
Maybe military training?
No, it's not training!
Not fireworks!
Where are these explosions from?!
MAMA!
No shit!
Borman, what the hell is this?!
Freeze! Or I'll shoot!
Hands up!!!
Let go off me, Bitch!
Let go, hurts!
We're friendlies!
Have you gone mad completely?!
Get up!
I think they are friendlies.
Comrade corporal, they are naked as angels.
Where did you leave your pants, idiots?
We were swimming in the lake.
- Swimming?
- Yes, swimming. Didn't you get that the 1st time?
Get who?
What? you don't understand Russian?
Maybe you'd like it in Chinese?
So, you understand Chinese?
Comrade corporal, may I?
No!
You will speak when being spoken to.
- Elin.
- Here!
Go to the lake, check everything!
Clothes, documents, firearms.
Make it fast, but quiet.
Roger that!
So, you were escaping the Germans
through the lake?
escaping the Germans
through the lake. Yes
Fine.
Get up. Let's go.
Cover your swastika tatoo. If anyone sees it
we'll be shot without a trial.
Take your watch off.
Shoot those defectors.
What do you mean "shoot"!
You're a reasonable, soviet citizen!
If I may, comrade lieutenant major,
It may seem completely delirious
but we're your descendant.
Yes, we're from the future.
2nd World War is long over.
- Very long ago.
- And? Did we win?
- Yes.
- Yes, we won, just like we wanted.
May I, comrade Political Advisor?
There was a lot of bombing,
they could be contused.
So, all together?
As we can see, that maybe possible
comrade lieutenant major, may I?
- Here, I found their documents.
- Where the hell were you!
Yes, 12th division, 131st unit.
comrade Political Advisor, that' right
131st was trying to make it out through
the German ring.
Looks like these are the only survivors.
The whole unit died in front of their eyes,
clouded their minds.
Well, happens
Ok chief, let's decide what to do.
with the contused.
SPEAKER: Russian soldiers!
(It's been 2 years since your country
is in this giant war.)
(This war was started by Stalin and his
Jewish gang from Kremlin!)
(It's a way of Jews nationals fighting for global revolution)
(to implement their dream of enslaving nations
just like they enslaved you.)
SPEAKING GERMAN
So, Borman, are you going to feed us bullshit
that we are all hallucinating?
Maybe we're asleep and it's a dream?
Right, all of us, together!
Look, we got a situation, we're in the past.
What do you mean "Past" ?!
Yes. The real, heroic, PAST!
Wait, let me get this right,
are we all going to die here?
Finally it sunk in.
I want to go home.
Home - is good. Just too early.
Get dressed.
Here brother.
Here, take it
Really, you were really lucky today
Commander was in a good mood.
Otherwise...
Otherwise what?
Otherwise it would have been otherwise.
Comrade Corporal, many defectors?
Happens. They run, get caught and shot.
What did you think?
In War you can run only 1 way, forward
Then you might make it through alive.
Look, not bad guys, real "Armani".
- Awesome outfit.
- What did you say?
I said very good clothes,
Comrade Corporal.
Very good clothes.
Why, did you wear something different?
- Just like Huan's Sombrero.
- Look in the mirror, assface
When are you all finally going to shut up!
Do you think you're still in charge?
There, we have a new commander now
- Greeting, comrade lieutenant major!
- Good soldier.
- Where are you from?
- From St.Petersburg.
- We're all from St.Petersburg.
- No way! where from?
I'm from "Petrogradskaya"
and these are from "Vaska"
And I'm from "Petrogradskaya".
- And where exactly did you live?
- On "Large Posad".
And I'm from "Large Posad"!
- Which building?
- 9.
I'm from the 12th.
Look at that!
- What school did you go to?
- To 23rd.
- Me too!
- Did you go to the boxing class?
- Of course! from my 5th year.
- For real!
- Yep.
- Who was your coach?
- Petrovich.
Petrovich? Listen, is he still
running to pick up fresh paper
in the mornings?
Not sure about papers, but he
watches the news on TV in the teacher's room.
What the heck is "TV"?
Can you imagine, their school paper
is called "TV".
Yep.
Strange name.
- What do you think, Emelyanov?
- "TV"...
- "TV".
- I didn't even know there was such a word.
Do you really want to know today's date?
Well?
August 19th, 1942
Oh-oh..
We got here through the lake,
so the only way out of here is
through that lake.
We won't make it back during the day, we'll get shot
So, stick around and don't move till dark
- Yes.
- Only after dark we'll go to the lake
- Here they are
- some bullshit
Common disorientation. But Nina,
please check well, maybe they are faking it
Let me introduce our nurse, sergeant major Nina Polyakova
I'll be close by
- Great!
- Let me help you
So? What happened with you, boys? contused?
- Contused.
- Got it.
- Down!!!
Get down!
Stay down!
Idiot, go take cover!
- Nurse!
- I'm here!
Run-run-run-run!
Motherf****, it started!
- What started?
- Airstrike.
Next attack.
- Who? Germans?
- Who else?
Grab a rifle from the dead and wounded!!!
Look.
In position!
Get ready to fire!
Get ready to defend!
Guys, tanks!
Grab grenades!
Dammit! Infantry is behind the tanks.
Fire at people, aim at waist, single, shoot!
Bastard!
- Manyakin!
- Here.
Come on, son, try it.
There Bitch!
I'll help
- Is he alive?
- Can you pull faster?
A-aa!
Let me see.
You'll live. Come'n pull!
but maybe.. clean, disinfect, stitches, bandage?
Maybe I should give you a Tit too?!
Go faster!
Hang in there.
- Why are you smiling?
- it's .. from all the commotion.
Sorry
I like you, that's why I'm smiling.
You sure picked the right time to hit on a girl.
- Come on boys!
- Come on.
- Grab.
He's alive.
Dammit...
Give me a round.
Round! - I said!
Give me a round, motherfucker!
Just a little bit, little bit more.
Well?! Did you .. shit your pants!
Mother.
- Did you get enough, bastards!
- YEEEEEES!!!
- Yes!!!
I think the moment was appropriate.
(SHOUTING: Yes!!!)
Where are we going to spend the night?
- Comrade corporal!
- Quiet.
- There, give Petrovich some more.
- There is enough for everyone.
So, you're after nurses now?
looks like I'm not the only one.
Are you asking for it?
Want to be smudged all over these trenches?
We shouldn't be like that here, Borman
Where is your comradeship
Did you just call me Borman?
- Why did you call me Borman?!
- My fault, Sergey Nikolaevich.
- Quiet!
- Get out of here.
- Got it.
Little to the right, just like that.
(SINGING: I'll give you, my dear, a hand crafted handkerchief)
(Show it to everybody
But don't tell them about our Love)
I'm going to go dry it
Well, what do you want?
I'm entitled to the change of bandage.
Even brought some flowers.
Hang in there sweetie.
- Thank you.
- Quiet, quiet.
Jesus! Get out of here, we're short of
bandages, your scratch can be treated
with a little disinfectant.
- And how long have you been fighting?
- Longer than you, that's for sure.
- How long do you think I've been fighting?
- Why would I even think about that?
I have plenty of my own thoughts.
Get out of here, poor bastard.
Get out.
Please forgive me, Nina.
And.. I'm very interested to know
what a girl is thinking of as ...
About the usual: when the war is over,
and the happy life we're going to have
Well, we'll win the war,
I guarantee you that.
I can't promise the happy life though
Unfortunately
Interesting.
What else do you guarantee?
Cities will be rebuilt, skyscrapers in Moscow
- Skyscrapers?
- Will fly to space.
Fly to space?
(OUTSIDE: Trucks are here! Load up the wounded!)
Hold on a little longer, they'll operate soon,
it'll be ok.
Careful. See that he doesn't get shaken up
along the way.
That's about it.
Maria, where do I take it?
Who is this?
Special Unit. I think he's here after us
Listen, Cherep, soldiers talk about
advancing soon, we got to take off
as soon as possible.
What about Motherland?
Who's going to defend Motherland?
We're as good defenders as a grenade made out of turd.
Watch it, bro.
Got to go to the lake, if we get lucky
we'll come out in our happy future
That is if we get really lucky.
On the other hand, it'd be better
you get wacked here.
It'd be better if you get wacked,
and I'll live a little longer. Got that?
And not in this screwed up past, but in my future
Because I find it more interesting.
To yell "Hi Hitler!" and to kill poor immigrants?
- Piss off!
- So you'll go to jail and eat shit.
Only you'll go there before me!
And why is that?
Very simple, you'll be a junkie addict with your black Rap music
Dumbass
- Who's dumbass?
- Yes. You're dumbass.
Your.
Quit that!
Attention!
Look. Attention.
If you hate each other so much,
how did you fight that you survived?
It's called - undermining of military capacity
of a military unit in combat,
another words - treason.
- Treason of what?
- Motherland.
One more time, you'll be court-martialed.
Funny, digged out over there, digging in over here
Startuk, do you have a heart?
Got to be humane
Most important for us is not to end up here instead of them
Got to do something, or I'll go crazy
I beg you, calm down.
When it gets dark we'll go to the lake.
God, please remember the names of our fallen.
And calm their souls in the light of Your face
In the name of the Father, Son and the Holly Spirit
today, before and forever. Amin
What's up, infantry, what news
do you want to hear first: good or bad?
Bad.
Well, there is no booze anywhere.
And the bad?
Your Nina is giving a mind blowing
concert by the kitchen.
- Let me sit
- Get out, let me sit.
"Thanks for everything, kind friend,
For that you were a true friend"
"For field of honey grass
For tiny moon above the field"
Why are you so sad?
Your vocals aren't worth shit today?
Well, I like it.
- "For that village behind the river..."
- It'd be nice to have a guitar here.
- "...Where I walked, forget about tiredness..."
"For feelings that just became another line"
- Come on, show them!
"For lines that spanned from a feeling"
"For feelings that just became another line"
- Quiet! Can't hear.
- Sorry, comrade, sorry.
"For feelings that just became another line"
- Excuse me, may I borrow the guitar? Please?
"For your love that I needed more than bread"
"For me, imagining you in a way you weren't"
"He'll show them now"
I'm going to show you now!  All quiet !
Listen comrade, why are you so touchy?
- Excellent!
- That's how it's done!
Great! Excellent!
Come on!
Excellent!
- Good for you.
- Well, Excellent.
- Come on, one more time!
- May I walk you back?
Well, ok.
Can you do something like that?
Excuse me, may I join you?
- Why aren't you sleeping?
- Can't.
It's SO quiet.
By the way, that's extremely rare.
Nina.. I’m amazed by you and your voice
What?
- Oh come on.
- You sang...
...as if you're a real singer.
oh come on, artist.
You don't have to be shy
You win over any singer, hands down.
You have a soul...
heart.
Thank you.
Your hand smells so...
How?
Here with soap, here with medicine
Enough.
Thinks he found a madam, kissing hands.
Get out before you get it.
- Nina...
- Get out of here.
- ...that time we were running in the field...
- Did you hear what I said?
... everything was exploding around, bullets flying...
Nina, what's going on?
Nina, what's this?
- Sleep.
- Nothing.
- Packing bandages.
Where the hell is he?
We had an agreement.
It's the time to go the lake.
You think it fast and easy to charm a lady?
Chuha, it's difficult and unthankful labor
I guess it is hard for some hardheads.
Is he with that nurse?
Yes, they are having huge sex
in a little forest.
Bastard.
- Can't sleep?
- Waiting for you.
So, did you do it?
Did you?
Did you!
Enough, sort it out later,
we have to go to the lake.
Let's go
- Why are you taking the rifle?
- Without it we're defectors.
Chuha, sort it out later.
Shit, it's so cold!
It was so much warmer then.
Pray to god to make it warm.
Dive!
Damn, cold, freezing my legs.
Maybe we're home already?
In our time.
No, the water would have been warm.
Now it's cold
So, are we going to swim till we drown?
- How am I supposed to know?
- Guys!
Guys! How long are you going to swim,
we're getting cold here waiting for you.
- What the hell?!
- Damn, he's been watching us!
- Turns out that way.
Why are you so attracted to this lake?
As if it's a magnet
- Not really.
- Just decided to go for a swim, comrade corporal.
Right! I can hear from here your teeth drum.
Neah, we're fine here.
Out of the water!
I can hear your teeth grinding from here!
Excellent water!
Absolutely wonderful!
I want potato chips.
How do we get out of here?
Naturally, year after year..
- Hey, dumbass
- What?
Maybe you'll finally shut up?
Enough is enough. Now we have to stick together
Why now?
- We got here through the lake together, right?
- So?
The only way back is by doing it together.
Last night we did dive in all
together, but I'm pretty sure
we're not home.
I can't be here any longer!
Boys!
- Tired? Relax.
- I think I opened the topic.
- That's her.
- Have some cold milk.
- We're all here because of her.
Mother, please forgive us!
Forgive us, mother!
- Boys...
- What are you doing, mother?
- Please, please forgive us!
- I beg you, please!
- Forgive us!
- In the name of God!
- Forgive us, mother!
- Please!
- Forgive us!
- I beg you!
- What's with you, boys?
Did you have a sun stroke or something?
Are you out of your mind?
- What's with you
- Please boys...
- Hi, Avdotia.
- Did you bring some milk?
- Yes...
Ok. Don't pay attention. They are contused. Let's go...
Look, they are not right in the head, what can we do...
Mother..
Mother!
Wait. I'm not getting it..
is that her or not?
No, that's her for sure.
Wait guys, remember that grandma, with milk...
what did she tell us?
Something about her son dying here.
- Something about engraved cigarette case
- Yes.
"To revolution" was on it.
- What did you promise her?
- To find it.
- I didn't like her at first sight! if only..
- Shut up!
So, if we don't find her son, we are not
getting out of here.
Yep...
Does anyone remember his name?
I do - Sokolov. Dmitry Sokolov.
Yep. Infantry
Yep.
I'm here for you.
Why do you look like beggars! Clean yourselves up!
- Where are the rest?
- Working out punishment.
In 5 min you all must be at the office.
- Cpt. Zhorin is waiting for you.
- Special Unit.
He is interested in your nightly swims.
May I ...  ask a question,
do you remember a soldier: Dmitry Sokolov?
You're too late. 7 days ago their group did not return.
There are 2 versions here.
Are there any other Sokolov here?
Not in our division.
Ok guys, get yourselves in order.
- Hello.
Hello
Cutting to the point...
- Did you go to the lake at night?
- Yes.
Decided to go for a swim, wash up?
You don't look stupid, at least most of you.
Did you know about Germans being very close?
No
Strange ignorance, - everybody knew except you.
Tell me soldier, did you find anything suspicious on the way to the lake?
Not really.
any German posts by any chance?
- It was too dark.
- Do you remember the way?
- It was dark.
- We remember the way very well, Cpt.!
What?... Hello.
Had a nice chat? Turns out you're
making wheat moonshine? Please do share.
Listen, Demin. It's true they say "idiots are lucky".
Made it to the lake and nothing.
- And we have mine fields, barb wire, secrets...
- Oh!
And these go through and nothing.
As if they are really guests from the future.
Smart guys.
Did you ask them about that .. future?
Not yet.
Soldiers, listen for your orders:
tonight you'll go into German base,
capture and bring back an officer
Leader of the group will be corporal Emelyanov.
Roger that!
Ok, when you come back with an officer,
then we'll talk about your past, present and your bright future.
ID's..
comrades.
- Guys, do you remember our digging?
- Quiet!
Shut up idiot!
Did you see where he put our IDs?
To that same safe.
And the dude in leather coat.
So, it turns out we digged ourselves out.
And how many of us did we dig out?
4 soldiers, officer in leather coat and a nurse.
So check it out: IDs in the safe,
our assignment, then advance.
What time is it?
6:42
The time on that watch was 6:42
Huh?
Ok, even if we accept that we digged ourselves out
nobody will touch us until the attack for sure.
But we have to escape before the attack.
How will we know when the attack is?
The attack in this region was at
6:00, August 23, 1942
So we have left only ...
62 hours
Great!
No, we have to get out of here.
And what do you suggest?
To fulfill our promise.
We need to find that damn cigarette case.
We need to find Sokolov.
If he's scout, we have to go there and find his tracks.
At least it's a lead.
SPEAKING GERMAN
Come on
Let's go
Ok
Get down
CANS NOISE
What a bastard.
I'm listening, lieutenant major
Can we talk in private?
Nina, I... talked to the head office...
They are transferring you to the
main hospital
So you can go pack right away
I already told you "NO", lieutenant major.
Why are you keep calling my rank.
- I, by the way, have a name
- I don't need your name
The attack is soon, that's what we have to think about
we don't need to
And about the attack ..
Nothing to think about, we'll .. all of them
how was it ..
"we'll do them all"
What?
another words: We'll win
he's a "winner" now
Nina, so will you transfer or not?
I've already arranged everything
No. Sorry
Go, the commander is waiting for you
Lesha, please forgive me.
Forgive me.
Here it is, damn foxhole
Here is the 2nd one
SPEAKING GERMAN
Come on faster!
- Tie hands.
- Yep.
- I think the guys didn't make it
- Where?
SHOTS FIRED AT THE FRONT LINE
- Why aren't you sleeping?
- Can you hear?
Still didn't make it
They will
Give me all grenades!
- Drag him faster!
- What about you?
I'll hold them as long as possible.
- You'll get killed
- It's unknown yet. Why are you trying
to have my funeral so soon?
Do you need a special invitation?
Fulfill your orders! Go!
Filatov, when does this war end?
may 9, 1945
I can't believe we'll make it.
Leave.
Go!
- Is he dead?
- Why are you even asking.
Go. Faster.
- Remember the way?
- Yes, we do
- I do too.
Damn rags, my feet hurt
- This was a successful mission.
- Except we didn't find Sokolov.
- Nope. Oleg, frisk him.
- Yep.
Here is your front line, show me your division.
Show me.
I don't know. I don't know how to read a map.
I never had to read maps.
You'll be shot in the morning in the name
of the glorious Germany..
Russian soldier - the Patriot.
Pretty, but boring.
- Who will win?
- Soviet Union in May, 1945.
Colonel, in 43rd you'll be captured but in 1948 you'll
return to Germany and become a great historian.
You're crazy.
You will write a book about WWII and
receive a great award.
You're delirious!
In your book you'll write about the fact
that right after your interrogate soviet scouts
you will be called to Berlin to receive
the medal, Mr. Kurt Bornhof
and you will not come back here.
You, three, after me!
Oh, pure Arian.
Listen, Cherep, maybe you can chat to your
people so they'd let us go, huh?
Very funny.
Why, they are like your family.
Who will sign the capitulation?
From the Soviet Union: Gen. Zhukov,
from the U.S. Gen. Patton
- from France...
- What?!
France?! These cowardly half-Jews
also won over us?!
Of course. It's a part of
anti-Hitler coalition.
Watch your step.
Damn, legs are killing me!
Didn't I tell you to watch it!
Drink.
You're brave soldier.
Eat.
I don't eat after 1st.
What about Hitler?
He shot himself in the office basement.
How is that possible?!
How can you win?!
You! Pig!
Do you have any idea what is German Military Machine?!
Mainshtein, Guderian, Paulus, Fon Klaist!
Here, in Stalingrad, from Autumn 1942 -
Jan 1943 will be massive battles
in which your famous Paulus will end up
in a very tight ring and will be captured.
and us, starting with Volga will start to advance,
and slowly, slowly,
slowly advance...
towards Berlin
- Guys...
- How is it?
Asked to pass.
Here
Take it.
- Won't eat, bastards
- Nice to meet you, local
- Filatov, Sergey
Sokolov Dima
What did you say was your name?
Dima, do you have a cigarette case?
- Yes, only it's empty
- Can I take a look?
Lets...
- Let me take a look?
- Here.
- What's that engraving?
- "To devotion to Revolution. By commander Budenny"
My grandpa gave it to me, when I was going to War
- Give back.
- Hey, stop it.
- Give back
- Give back the cigarette case
- Don't give back.
How did you find out about the cigarette case?
corporal Emelyanov told us.
Remember him?
Yes, great man.
- He saved my life
- Ours too.
He died.
- How? When?
- When he was covering our retreat.
- I'm so sorry.
- Feel sorry for yourself instead.
- It's war. who's feeling sorry for themselves...
- its true
- ...only fucking cowards.
Not everybody is a hero, like you.
- Who would know about that if not you.
- I'm not following you guys.
If you do, you'll shit your pants.
Especially when you find out that in 21st
century, skinheads will walk Moscow streets
dressed in black
with Nazi symbols, raising their hands yell:
"Hi Hitler!"
Are you fucked in the head?
- Huh
- What did you say?!
- Get off me!
- I'll strangle you bastard!
YELLING IN GERMAN
MACHINE GUN SHOTS
Bitch!
Tomorrow they'll execute us, and there will be
no right or wrong
Will be! There always be right and wrong.
Our path is right!
And never in Moscow will somebody shout "Hi Hitler"
Never, never, don't worry
Alright. Enough. We're short of time.
Got to get out of here.
I'm digging a way out here.
Nice! That's one hole!
- And where are we getting out?
- Guys, dirt is soft!
- There is a guard!
- Only one.
He's by the door. If we're quiet, he won't hear
Then what?
I saw, when we were lead to the interrogation,
there is a trench about 100 yards away
- But there are Germans there.
- Can't you jump over the trenches?
Who's going to figure out who you are in the dark?
They'll shoot of course, but that'll be up to you, guys
Why "you" and not you?
I can't. My leg ..
That bastard guard broke it when he was kicking me.
- Well, what's there?
- I think this is it.
Stop coughing.
Bitch, broke my tooth
GERMAN SPEECH
Ok, you first.
If he makes it through, the rest will too.
Come on.
Wait.
Here.
Give it to my mom.
Come on.
K-Kh-Kha
Oh God.
... "Sun's gong down" (Dima started singing)
"Hundred of young soldiers
from the Budenov's division
"went to gather intel in the steppes"
"they traveled a long time"
CUSSIN IN GERMAN
MACHINE GUN
If we make it back, no word about the capture
Freeze! Don't move!
Who are you?!
Scouts, coming back.
- You're going to get it!
- Go screw yourself!
Where are you all coming from?!
Listen, follow me, quick
Ok, we just got back from a mission
Stirred up the Germans, got back with
nothing, lost the corporal.
He was an great, he'll be missed.
But these buttheads came back in one piece.
Not a single scratch.
Magic.
Where, where the justice?
I'd like to know!
That corporal alone was worth a whole unit.
Right, good results are worth reporting up the chain.
Get out of here.
I'll call you back, we'll talk again.
Dear Nina
Could not help myself, how are you here without me?
You're back...
my baby
Alive.
Serezhen'ka, I knew that everything's will be ok
Nina, I'm very...
I ..
Let's go
Run-Run-Run-Run!
Over here
- It's certain now.
- Comrades, we attack tomorrow
Listen, Borman was right.
We do attack tomorrow.
If we attack, we'll get more what we asked for.
If we don't take off at night
It's interesting, Borman is all over Nina there
and we're here waiting to die
Stop whining?
Borman said, - we're going to the lake at night.
Let him say goodbye to the local talent
He's probably having a lot of fun, Right Beroev?
Sex, Sex is sooo nice!
Sex, Sex - without interruptions!
(Quote form a rap song in mid 90's)
Your two, go screw yourself.
Assholes!
Where are you going, retard?
Trrrrrrr-oi-ho!
Shoven Out!
Uaaaa!
Yeeehhh - Ha!
Yeha!
Yessss!
You're such a bastard, Borman.
Uuuuuu-hahaha!
Are you clumsy?
Love you
Nothing
- Come here
- Silly
Wait
Aaaaaooi oi!
Damn! My back!
Mama!
- Bitch!
- What do you think you're doing?!
I see... everybody is a boxer
Greetings, comrade Captain
Huh, I see.
What are you doing?
We're going to be court marshaled!
There, Here some more!
Excuse us, happens to everyone.
Don't pay attention, happens.
It even happens to old friends
We'll sort it out
- Hey, where are they taking you?
- Ah, Nina! Hello.
- To the basement, to be executed in the morning.
- What for?
For fighting
I see.
Who gave an order?
Lieutenant major Demin, and that
officer from the Special Unit
What are you looking at? Move!
Comrade officer!
Just wondering, why are Filatov and that one...
2nd soldier got arrested for?
Is that the proper way to address to address and officer?
On the other hand, what gives you the right
to ask an officer those kinds of questions?
Want to be locked up in the basement too?
Everybody's treating you too nice around here,
and you're taking advantage of it!
Arrested for fighting, disruption of order!
In a combat situation.
- Is that it?
- Questions?
Dismissed, Polyakova!
They'll be released in the morning
Why are you so worried about them
I have feelings, lieutenant major
- Whaaaaat?
- For whom?
That's my business.
Couldn't save the only pretty nurse...
Those guests from the future..
showed up... stole our woman
Who? Beroev?  or Filatov?
I think it's ... Filatov
He's the kind women like
That must be him
Looks like Beroev fell for Polyakova,
and Filatov kicked his behind.
That's the kind of order you're
running here, lieutenant major.
Ok, Where is this tough guys ... what's his name
Serduk!
On my way!
- Did you put the soldiers in the basement?
- That's right, I did it
- Now let them go.
- Both of them?
- No, only one!
.... Beroev.
Why him?
- Well.. he got beat up..
- Yep.
- ... his face is all mashed up..
- ... injured another words
- Yep.
- Here is one
- Where's Romeo?
- In the basement
Zhorin gave an order
Why's that?
For order disruption.
Did he kick your butt?
I fell from the tree
Yeah, right
- And how long will he be there?
- How am I to know?! I didn't put him there!
Dammit.
Well, looks like Berlin will make it without
our autographs
- What are you talking about?
- Look here, we got a newborn activist!
Quit skinheads, joined patriots
- He's contemplating here how he'll join the attack.
- Awesome
Really, awesome. I think I couldn't
Nobody will ask you
You'll get your 100grams of vodka and go,
for Motherland, fight real dudes this time
And you're not going?
Don't advise you either. Don't you get it?
We need to run to the lake ASAP
What about Borman?
What about him? Screw him!
- I'm not leaving without him.
- Me too.
Screw you too! I'm going alone then!
You can stay, and die
Don't flatter yourself, Borman has
the cigarette case
..  Filatov!
Maybe we should try to save Filatov from
the basement?
Are you mad? That Special Unit shit is only
waiting for a chance to whack without a trial!
All we can do is sit and wait
Do you get it? Sit and wait!
Serezha.
Serezha ... wake up, my baby
Good
There you go, come on
Good boy
Zhorin ordered to release you in
the morning .. it's dawn already
Serduk gave me a key so I can bring you food
He's tough, but a sweetheart
There, good
No, no, this way
Eat.
We advance soon, you’ll need your strength
Silly
Don't be scared, you'll survive
That I can promise you
Nina..
it is my time to leave.
No ...
Sorry ...
Forgive me.
Nina...
No
Forgive me, Please forgive me.
Why?
Silly
My love..
What were you singing then ...
What?
I forgot the words.
Can't recall.
- and I can't recall
- What was it ...
One moment
- Because I needed...
- Yes
- ... your love
- sometimes more than bread
- Yes
Because I thought ...
Of you...
Look, he's alive
We thought they wouldn't let you
We didn't go to the lake
So got to figure out the next move
Can't go to the lake, ours will shoot us
We only have 1 option, join the attack
And see what happens.
Let's stick together.
Comrades, who can play guitar?
Come on, com one. Our guy hurt his hand
- Guys, I found one!
- Yeeeeeah !
- Come on!
- Hit it !
- Here
SONG:
(Machine gun in hands,
Because he's a soldier)
(Medals shining, because it's way)
(Came back home, because he's a hero)
(Came back home ....  Alive)
(This silence, sun shine
Said there is no more death)
(sun shine and silence suddenly
announced - there no more war)
Follow me
Enough singing
Listen to the orders, soldiers.
Get ready to fight!
Get in position!
Fire!
YELLING IN GERMAN
Come on guys.
Fire!
Tanks are coming through. Get down!
Get down!
For motherland! For Stalin!
- URAAAAAA !!!! (Gooooo)
- Forward!
URAAAAAA !!!!
Ura! Guys.
Come on guys, Ura!
Ura! Guys
All together, Ura!!!
Come on guys, Ura!
Come on guys
Uraa! mother***
AAAAAA!
Mama. Mama
AAAA!
Uraaaa! Uraaaa!
AAA!
AAAAAAA!
Uraaaaa!
Jump!
Where! Where, stupid?!
One moment.
Forward!
- Uraaa!
Come on, go!
Uraaa!
Bitch !  Uraaa!
Gooo!
AAaaa!
To the trench!
Is that you, home boy?
- Are you ok?
- I think so
We got what we asked for.
We'll die.
I have no idea what artillery did,
All the foxholes are intact
comrade lieutenant major,
I know how to get to the foxholes
There is a little valley that leads
to German trenches
If we can make it, we can bomb the foxholes
How do you know that?
- That's the path we took when we went on our mission
Aaa! AAAAA!
Vitaly! Beroev! Down, quick!
- Do you have grenades?
- 2
- Take mine.
- Why?
- Because!
Noooo, I'm not going over there
What do you mean? Are you crazy?
I .. I will not go there
Do you want to get court-martialed!
Come on guys.. We can go forward
while that foxhole is active
Water
Bro, water.
Hey, soldier, are you alive?
Serezha!
One moment
- Nina...
- Shhhhh, it'll be ok
- It's ok...
- Aaaa!
- Shhhhh, quiet now
Emotions, sorry.
Don't worry, they'll stitch you up
Main thing your bone is ok
The most important thing in a man - is a bone
Humor - good.
- How much time has passed?
- What time?
- From the moment of the attack
- half an hour, no more.
What half an hour, at least 3 hours!
1st battle, every minute seems like eternity
- There you go. Better?
- Yes, better.
Stay down. I'll go look while it quiet down
There are a lot of wounded
Why did it quiet down? Did we take the front line?
- No
- It's not good
- Now what
- Now?
WISTLE OF FALLING BOMB
Now I'll go forward, someone will take care of you here
That's it
Love you
You need to move back, got it?
it's ok. it's ok
just a little more
one moment.
Alexander Vasilievich, dear ...
- comrade lieutenant major!
- Kolokoltsev, how did you get here?
- Come on, get in!
Commander was so mad,
Threatened to shoot everyone
If we don't establish communication with you
So I run the wire all the way
from our trenches
Good job!
"7th", "20th" is on-line
These foxholes won't let me through!
- Hey bro, are you wounded?
- No
So why are you heading back?
Changing positions.
I see. Come on join us, we got a perfect one
Got it, over.
So comrades, there will be another airstrike
in about 10 minutes.
If we don't take care of these foxholes
we're all going to die here
How could that happen
Alexander Vasilyevich..
Don't worry
...how did you manage, huh?
Hang in there
Nina.
Don't go there!
Get out of there!
- Nooo! Go back !
- Hang in there sweetie
One moment, I'll come back for you
Just got to make it to the office.
Nina! Don't go! Leave! Leave!
Little bit more! Hold him
Hey !
Come on
- Come on.
- All together.
- Hold it, hold it
Don't go there
Hang in there
that's it, that's it, that's it
Take him in
Leave !!!
Careful.
Hang in there
Don't!!! Don't!!!
Don't!!!!
No!!  HA ha ha ha! Nothing happened!!!
Nothing ha.......
- Beroev, ready?
- Me? yes, I'm affraid
Everybody's afraid, but we have to fight
Come on, everything depends on us now
God
Come on
Unit!!!!
Fire !!!
Boy it's hammering down
That's our fire. Hope we don't get caught
- What if we do
- If only ..
Oh mama, what if I'm pregnant!!
Crawl! or I'll kiss your ass
Vitally! Oleg!
Hey! Sergey is here
Where?
- Where we're going?
- Demin ordered to blow up that fox hole
...The one we stole an officer from
- You're wounded
- I know
- We got to get up
- Can't
Darn fox holes, can't stick a head out
AAAAA!
Aaaaaa!
Germans!
Aaaa!
Get down!
Awesome
Attack! Let's go comrades!
Forward!
- Let's go comrades!
- Uraaaaaa!
Do you need a special invitation?
Well?
- Aaaaa!
- Uraaa!
Forward!!!
Uraaaa!
Mother******* !
Come one, Go!
Uraa !
Uraaa!
Vitaly!
Bitch!
Vitalik! Vita...
It's nothing.
Chuga .. how could you..
Vitalik .. just dont ...
You hear me..
- Shhhhhhh.....
- Mama.
Yes, we got it Comrade "7"
Yes, they are running.
Alive! Alive!
You're alive, silly
Home! Home!
SHOTS FIRED, SCREAMING IN GERMAN
VOICE: EMELYANOV: Filatov, when is the end of war?
VOICE: FILATOV: May 9th, 1945
VOICE: BORMAN: Sorry officer, but we're your descendants
VOICE: SPIRIT: We're from the future
VOICE: NINA: My baby came back
VOICE: BORMAN: Forgive me, forgive me
VOICE: Nina: Why my love, silly head
(In cold and sadness tears are rolling from our eyes)
(Somewhere is whisper of your words)
(I'll never stop waiting, trying to bring back)
(To look back in our past)
(Simply to forget and to live)
(It's you and me, our eyes will speak for us)
(Forever our heart will keep that tender pain)
(You and me, time will show the path home)
(There is no escape, I run after you)
(You and me, our eyes will speak for us)
(Forever our heart will keep that tender pain)
(You and me, time will show the path home)
(Never)
(There is no escape, I run after you)
- THANKS FOR WATCHING ONE OF MY FAVORITE MOVEIS OF ALL TIME -