You can do it, champ!
Try it again, but easy.
Well done, that's it!
They say that every story
needs the words of its own.
For my story, I couldn't find
them for a long time.
It began when words
had dried up.
Well done! You're genius!
Last seconds of the game;
Come on, let's do it now!
Atta, boy!
Kajevic Jr. will do the
hook. Will he make it?
Is the gold in our hands again?
Kajevic, and he scores!
Kaja, the champion!
The motherfuckers were
close last night.
I was blown off the ground!
Enough for today!
-What do you mean, enough?
I'm in a hurry, man! I paid you
300 marks up front!
What's the rush, when
they're bombing us?
I'm in a rush all the time.
I'm a businessman!
They say you're doing better
than in the last war.
Which one? -In both.
People smoke more,
the enemy is stronger now.
Why? Do you think I should
fight? -God, no!
Just like the last time:
You rolling in mud,
me pushing cigarettes.
One man falls, another fills
his pocket. -Way of the world!
You telling me I'm not
patriotic?- By no means.
When I'm through, you'll
be a 100% fucking Serb!
Right! And you gotta do
more work and talk less.
Up your ass!
-Up yours!
What did the doctor say?
The bombs scared the kid,
so he's a bit.silent.
Did he prescribe any medicine?
-He'll get over it. -When will
he get over? -lf he hadn't been
here, it wouldn't have happened.
Hey mom, take the kid to
the other room.
It's my fault I let the kid
stay here...
when they're bombing us!
-They could have hit anywhere.
They could have hit your place.
-But they didn't.
You're bad luck. You simply
attract disasters. -Absolutely.
Since I attracted you.
I take him to spend one night
here because my mother's ill.
So what? -Whenever I rely
on you, it all goes wrong.
Everything went wrong since
you took him and left me.
I've felt a 100% percent
better since I left you.
Listen, Tijana.
He doesn't feel better!
You heard what the doctor
said: a happy family life!
That's what he needs. And you
and me, we'd manage somehow.
He needs safety, normal life -
that was what the doctor said!
No drinking with the jerks!
-Nor staying with your mom!
If my mother weren't that ill.
I would take both of them
to Italy!
And he would start speaking
right across the border?
I would start singing!
Come on, move your ass!
I said, get up!
Move your ass over here!
Your sis says you're on it
again. -Everybody's talking.
Let them babble!
It isn't true, dad! -I don't
give a shit about your life.
But if they talk again that my
son's smoking weird tobacco,
I'm gonna beat the shit
out of you.
I swear by my mother's...
-Leave you late mother alone!
She was a wimp,
just like you are.
She's lucky she didn't
live to see what I see now.
Watch what you're
doing, wimp!
I'm sorry, bro.
-Piss off!
Siske! Hey, Siske!
Hi, Zuba!
What do you want? I told
you not to come back.
I want you to do that butterfly
for me. -I told you I won't.
I've got money. -I don't
care about your money!
You know what that
butterfly means?
That's what whores have on them.
Maya and Beba have it.
-Because they are whores!
Oops, sorry!
I didn't see you there!
You're on now.
-I am.
Do I know you?
-My mom lives here.
Pavlovic?
The little Pavlovic girl?
Do you remember me?
We were in the same class.
I don't think so. -My father was
in the army.
So, we'd moved to Sarajevo.
Turcinovic, remember?
Turca? Oh, yes.
How did you say we called you?
-Call me Josie now.
I gotta get back home before
the alarm. -Hang on!
Pick one of those.
-I have a boyfriend.
He doesn't like to wait.
-Come on.
What's your boyfriend's name?
-Ufonja. -Oh, Ufi!
What are you doing with that
guy? -None of your business.
Well, it is.
You pretty, he an asshole.
I'm gonna tell him that.
-Oh, I'm scared shitless!
I'm off. Ciao!
Hey, Josie, hang on! Don't miss
your big chance, Josie!
I hope they won't bomb
here again.
They blasted everything.
There's nothing left.
I'm gonna die waiting
for a taxi here.
You're gonna die rushing.
-Somebody's gotta rush,
and that somebody is me. 'Cause
you are the legend of the 'hood.
Almost a great player.-We didn't
get along in normal times.
Why don't we try it now?
Take me across the river.
-Yes, if you pay for the fear.
Be a good boy, honey.
And listen to your daddy.
Take care of him, Kaja,
please. -OK, Tijana.
I'm gonna bring him some clean
stuff tomorrow.
Need any dough now? -Sure,
for some ice cream and beer...
How much do you need?
-I'm only kidding.
Buy something for Jovan.
-I don't need it.
If you wanna go across
the bridge, let's get moving.
They're gonna blast the bridge
while you're kissing.
And I've already had a bath.
Hey, sis, please don't!
I can stand the bombs, but
when someone starts crying.
Where's your kid?
-Upstairs. Asleep.
Hey folks, this summer's
gonna suck bad.
Why do you think so?
-The bombs are dropping
and you ask me why!
-It could be worse.
It can always get worse here.
But it can never get better.
When it was better here?
-Ten years ago.
We went to Sutomore,
on the coast.
They bombed Sutomore...
-That was yesterday,
and we were there
10 years ago.
And 5 years ago, we were
camping in Greece. -It was cool.
Sure, you were with Tijana
we only had our hands.
And, last year. -What the fuck
happened last year?
A basketball tournament here.
The dudes from the city came.
Here, on our court?
We can play here even now, but
we can play "The Lost Brigade".
We beat the shit out of them
didn't we? -We sure did.
We were mean.
-You are a mean player.
Zuba, Come on!
And you're bragging 'cause
we've beat some suckers.
Remember those upstarts
in expensive gear?
They didn't know shit.
-We're naturals, man.
Cut the bullshit, you jerks!
Look at yourselves!
There's no Sutomore,
no Greece for us.
We can't go across the border.
All we can get here are alerts
and that shit falling on us.
That's what I said:
it's gonna suck bad.
Let's rebuild it?
-What?
The court.
Why, we get rid of the mess,
lift the basket.
And there's a new court!
-You're nuts, man.
That basket probably weighs
3 tons. Who will lift that?
It can be done in three days,
I promise!
You really are smart, man!
Rebuild the court!
Well, unless a bomb
razes us to the ground.
Or unless our anti-aircraft
take cover in here.
Or unless they decide to
send their troops 'cause
they have nothing
better to do,
or unless we starve to death,
or unless we get drafted.
Then perhaps we'll mend
that court some day.
I'm gonna get some sleep.
This war is fucking boring.
What's wrong with him?
-He's nuts or something.
They are early tonight!
-I'll see you.
Come on, let's go!
Hey, champ!
Let me tell him something,
mom, please.
Are these bastards bothering
you? lgnore them.
You gotta sleep. We're gonna
practice the hook tomorrow.
You'll master it a 100%.
Dad will clean up the court
and coach you.
But you gotta sleep, get some
rest till tomorrow.
Come on!
Zuba!
-What's up?
An earthquake? Another bombing?
-I want my butterfly.
Fuck the butterfly! You need
a pimp, not a tattoo.
You're a bastard.
-I know.
Why didn't you come downstairs?
-Where? -In front of the house.
Everybody's there.
Kaja's giving a speech.
He's probably organizing
a fucking May Day parade.
Fuck! This guy is out
of his mind!
So, what do you say?
Who can guarantee they
ain't gonna blast us again?
People start to relax, and
they come back and boom!
Gonna fly high in the sky.
-Bye-bye new court, bye-bye!
OK, what now?
Got a better idea?
You wanna spend the whole
summer in the shelter?
I just said:
"Let's rebuild the court!"
I don't say it's a big deal.
It's nothing much, but.
Have you ever been fucked
when you did what I said?
We've always been fucked
when we did what you said.
Come on, fuck off.
We can do it, really!
I say you can't! What's your
fucking bullshit, Kaja?
These are dangerous times.
You gotta try to survive.
Make yourselves useful;
go sell some cigarettes for me.
You know when you're
gonna rebuild it? Never!
Wanna bet?
-Against who?
Me.We're gonna make
it in 3 days.
What are you gonna bet?
A slice of pie? -Deutschmarks.
Oh, marks!
OK, I'll bet you 500 marks
you won't make it. -500 marks!
You could buy a used car!
Too much!
Suck my cock!
-Stop swearing, fucker!
You can't collect 500 marks?!
Hey guys, can anyone lend
me 300 marks?
No small change, man.
-I left them in another suit.
I'll give you 300 marks.
-Very generous!
Atta boy! You're my hero now!
You heard him, chicken?
Looks like it's getting
serious now.
Why are you putting him on?
-Cut the crap!
OK, no more kidding.
500 marks till Monday.
Here's my hand, yokel!
-Fuck you, oaf! -Cut, Kaja.
You're cool.
And I was a bastard some time
ago! -You just pretend.
I know it, I keep telling
everyone.
You just pretend you're bad, but.
- I'm cool? Sure, I'm cool.
How come I didn't see it
a minute ago?
You gave him 300 marks.
-I don't care about 300 marks.
I just wanted to see
the fucker's face.
What do you blame him for?
-All, but that's another story.
They're never gonna make it.
They know it and you know it.
Shitty kids.
If they survive this shit,
that will be their big success.
You belong to the young
batch of their breed.
A chick with little brains,
who'll graduate 'cause
the teachers are starving.
Your friends are whores
and you hope that I'll do you
that butterfly to help you to
a better start as a hooker.
How can you say that?!
-What? -Things like that.
Because it's true. -It is not.
-Yes, it is. -No! -Yes!
Hey guys,
we gotta drink to it!
You gotta toast before
each big effort.
And then, tomorrow, slowly.
-It's no rush, man.
No work on Easter.
-We'll work when it gets cold.
Hey, Jovan! Come over here.
Take this to your dad.
When your dad was playing,
Djordjevic was on the bench.
Jovan!
There goes the beer!
-Honey...
Are you OK? For sure?
Hi, Tiki.
Hello, everybody!
Everything as usual?
We stick to our ways. -Where
have you been all this time?
Hi! -Hello!
We're rebuilding the court.
It's a lot of work.
-That much work could kill you.
We're just getting things ready.
I talked them into it.
Jovan's having a great time.
Cool, but I gotta go. I brought
some clean stuff for Jovan.
How's your mom?
-A little better.
I'll try to catch a couple
of hours tomorrow.
We can make a barbecue.
The guys always ask for you.
-I'm touched.
I thought, something
like a beach party.
Good, old times, remember?
-Jovan, see you tomorrow, honey.
Hold on!
Kaja, please try not to let him
get hurt, OK? -I'll try.
See you!
Jovan the champ!
Now you know it's yours
and no one can take it.
We'll make the court
tomorrow, Jovan.
It's gonna be the best in town.
You know who's gonna play here?
Rebraca, Bodiroga and Djordjevic
against Siske, Turca, me
and you. Yeah.
You know how tall this
Rebraca is? As a mountain, son!
Daddy's gonna put you
on his shoulders and
you're gonna slam-dunk
above Rebraca's head.
We're gonna beat the shit
out of them, you'll see.
Mommy's gonna cheer for us.
You know she likes to
cheer, for the winners.
She's gonna yell:
"Kaja, Jovan, Kaja, Jovan!"
The whole 'hood's gonna
support us and we'll win.
Fuck!
Let's go! Time to go to bed.
Fuck, they're giving us hell!
Don't they know that Divac
is a Serb? - So what?
Would you bomb Michael
Jordan's country? -I would
if I had the weapons.
-Give us the sausages.
See you, guys!
-Hey, grab a sausage!
Any news, old man?
Just the bad ones.
-Bad or worse?
The worst.
That's what I like about you; you
know how to cheer up people!
Can't you keep the noise down?
Hey, where have you been?
Sobering up, like everyone else.
Can't I have some peace and
quiet? -Yeah, sure, why not?
No way!
Hey, come on, quick!
Come on, let's give it a push!
Hey guys, where's Misa?
His mom is a bit scared.
-She worries a lot, you know.
Hey, kid.
-Leave me alone!
Are you kinda angry with me?
I don't need your tattoo.
I need nothing from you!
Everything around you is
filthy. It makes me sick!
Me too.
Hello, is that you, Tijana?
He's OK, still sleeping.
It wasn't that bad last night.
Some soft bombs, they say.
I'd hang them all in the
center of Belgrade
both the NATO guys
and our warmongers.
God forgive me!
He woke up.
Probably heard it's you.
Would you like to say
something to mom?
Jovan, are you there?
Mom will drop by
to play with you, OK?
We're going on a trip soon.
Then mom will be with you
every night.
You should see him
listening and nodding.
OK, Tijana, bye.
Say hello to your mother.
Give her my best.
Woe is me,
when kids have kids!
Maybe we're not angels,
but we're not the worst people.
Why, we aren't done yet.
Blisters already?
-Delicate skin, eh, Siske?
I didn't lift anything heavier
than a joint in years.
Check him out! Atta, boy!
Are we gonna build the best
court in town, or are we?
Come out on your terrace
And hail the Serbian race!
Come out on your balconies
To hail the champions!
God help us!
Why don't you cut it out?
-What's up, old man?
We're just cleaning up the mess.
-You'll suffocate us!
As if the terror from
the sky weren't enough!
That guy in the AWACS can
tell time from your watches.
Do you want to have
them bomb us again?
What did you say?
They'll bomb us again?
We're just cleaning up.
You can close your windows.
I know you well, Kajevic.
You made even little Misa
come downstairs!
What's the matter, old fart?
No one made me do anything!
If you want to clean, why don't
you clean the shelter?
I cleaned it up this morning!
-Did you hear it?
She cleaned it up!
We're no rats to spend the
whole summer in the shelter.
Don't argue with him,
just screw him!
Misa, come back inside!
I'll tie you to the bed!
And you want to play while
the bombs are falling on us!
Why don't you join the army
and serve your country?
What are you yelling for?
Who's yelling?
What are you two doing?
-Working. -Drinking.
Beer?! In this heat?!
You need booze when it's hot!
Wanna some booze? -Better have
one for us. -For you? Sure.
And for the two of you? OK?
What about you? -You don't drink
anything for me. -Never mind.
I'll drink for you too.
Come on!
I knew it!
What's up, guys? Looks like
some rusty kind of job?
Don't worry, Kaja.
We'll fix everything up.
Hey, where do you think
you're going?
Don't make uncle Toza
pull out your ears!
Hey guys, it's snowing!
Let me see!
Who needs toilet paper?
Look what a lousy print!
Saving on us, motherfuckers?
If they were throwing out
dollars, we wouldn't mind.
You're right. Maybe they'll
throw those 500 marks for you.
Come on, guys,
back to work!
You'll never win your bet
if you don't work.
Hold on, your dad's coming.
You didn't say hi! -Hi!
I didn't see you come in!
You were working hard.
I can't believe it.
You didn't believe we were gonna
do it. -To be honest - I didn't.
I can't remember when
I saw you working last time.
Kaja's got
some surprises for you.
I must take a bath:
I reek like hell. - You do.
As if you've just come
back from the training.
Where have you been?
-Why?
Do you take your dumplings
with sugar? - Yes, thank you.
Staying for dinner?
-I'll stay the night.
Your mother has let me.
If you don't mind.
I do mind. It's an invasion
of my privacy.
But if you wash the dishes,
massage my back etc...
.then it's OK.
I can't stand another night
without him. Go take your bath.
Your athlete's torso's just
too much. -Ex-athlete's torso.
It's because of my mom.
A nurse is with her.
In case she calls.
Don't be embarrassed about
the mobile. We are family.
See how good you look when
you're doing some work?
Tijana, I'm a 100% OK!
I swear by my mother.
I'm not old yet. Look!
-You haven't grown up yet!
You're somewhere on Jovan's
level, believe me.
That used to turn you on, Tiki.
-It did, once, Kaja.
Why not again, Tiki?
-You had us!
Like a game won!
But you lost us.
The game is over. -I counted on
some overtime, but...
Hey, what are you doing? -Aren't
he dumplings great, son?
I let him spend 3 days
with you, and look at him!
Hey, what's the big deal?
-One kid's enough for me.
But two...
Too many and two much.
I forgot to tell you, son.
That friend of yours from
Spain, Djordjevic, called today.
Sasha called me? -Yes.
I didn't know you were in touch.
-What a nice guy he was!
Kaja used to play with him.
Then he moved away.
He's in our national team.
-Love is what counts.
The national team? You're in
it today, tomorrow you're out.
And what did Sasha say?
-He wants to recommend you
for a job in Italy. He asks if
we need anything.
They are early tonight!
I'll get some candles.
-Come on, honey!
Easy, Tijana. Don't panic.
-I just want to take him to bed.
Probably a graphite bomb.
There's a total black-out.
Cemetery candles!
-They're for dad's anniversary.
Let's go to our room, honey.
Mommy's gonna put
you in bed.
She'll tell you the story of
a boy, Peter Pan, who lived
in the Never-Never Land
and didn't want to grow up.
He was that kind of man.
Good night.
Danka, why did you start
lying in you old age?
Everybody lies today and
so can I. It's for your good.
Shame on you.
-Shame on you!
I've got no money,
No cigarettes,
I've got no wife
by my side,
I've got no home, no luck,
Nobody cares for me.
Oh, how I'd like to get stoned,
Any kind of drug would do.
I wouldn't control my brain,
I'd rather blast it with a gun.
Cigarettes are like food
When a man has no wife.
Did you grasp that Danka
was lying? -I did.
I like the girls
in summer dresses.
I kiss their backs.
I can feel the fragrance
of resin...
Tonight my ship found
her harbor.
If I were you,
I'd fall in love with me.
If I were you, I would.
But I'm not.
Sorry. I have things to do.
Oh, good morning.
There will be no tears today,
eh, sis? -Not today. I promise.
I can see it's a different
story. Love or something.
Something.
Love and war...
Hey, where are we going?
-Hey, wait for me!
How come your mom let you
out? -She can't play it cool.
Here it is.
This is it!
-You sure it's a basket?
It looks better than
the one we have.
A little rusty, but solid.
-As hard as my cock.
Let's try to lift it.
It's in one piece. -We'll die
hauling it to our court.
Come on, guys.
You can do it without me.
Where are you going? -I've got
a situation over there.
I'd like to have
that situation myself.
We won't forget this, Turca!
-Hey, Josie! Hold on!
I feel awful being here.
-A nice place for a walk.
Authentic Yugoslav ruins.
A must for tourists.
Come on, Josie. Come on,
let's take a walk.
The cafeteria was over there.
That crazy dentist's office
over there. Such a prick he was,
it's good they'd blasted it.
Are you afraid of radiation?
-Yes, terribly.
Don't you feel that something
radiates between the two of us?
I'm sick.
-Hey, check this out!
Probably meaning: "Hey,
wanna play three on three?"
"Let's have a ball" means
"let's have some fun".
It can also mean.
-Sure, sure it can.
Your English is perfect.
-You fool!
Let's sit down. Come on.
I was in Sarajevo when
the shellings started.
We ran a little,
we fought a little.
Did some funny
and crazy stuff.
When I came here,
I thought: "It's over."
And look at me now:
Under fire again!
Is that why you're all smile?
You've seen it all before?
I finally grasped that
nothing's too terrible.
If you look at it the right
way, anything can be fun.
Nothing has to be really
terrible. You see?
You're not cheerful;
you're crazy. -Same thing.
What now? -What now?!
Let's weld the basket!
How do you mean to weld it?
With your nails?
Let's bring the cables,
the gear.
What cables? It's a black-out.
-The power's back.
I know what we need.
Misa, come with me.
We'll be right back.
Hello!
-Hi!
What are you doing with the
tools? Dad's gonna kill you.
If you rat on me,
I'll shave you with this stuff.
Let's go!
Where are you going?
This is the safest place.
And you think that's funny?
But, we love each other.
-You're nuts.
Josie.
Josie, hold on! Josie!
I'm gonna fuck you bad
because of this, aggressors!
Let me show you something!
Hold it! - Don't you see
what you're doing? - So?
That's not the way to do it.
You used up the electrodes.
I'm gonna get some new ones.
What are you doing?
We're doing the court.
I thought you knew it.
Doing the court?
-Yes.
Looks like you've
been welding? -Yes.
I can imagine how well
you welded it!
You know, it's gonna be
a real basketball court.
I thought this situation was
gonna make you grow up!
You're just fooling around.
-What do you want, old man?
When you're not working,
you just sit here, smoke,
and you can't wait to
pick on me!
What was it I did to you?
Come on, tell me!
God did it to me; to let
me have a son like you!
I've grown up in ruins.
But I had balls all my life!
I gave you everything,
to your mother and you!
Was it my fault your
mother died?
Was it my fault you
became such a wimp?
Fuck you, old man!
You'll never gonna
have what we had.
We've built everything
and you can't even make
a fucking basketball court.
Hey, Marlboro!
Look how the works progress
and get your 500 marks ready.
When he gives me that dough,
we're gonna party till dawn!
That's the right height.
It's OK.
Looks pretty low to me.
-It looks too high to me.
No, it's fantastic. -It's too
high. -Come on, ask Kaja.
It's OK, it's cool.
Don't sit on the ball
son, come on.
The height is right,
but it looks somewhat.
like it's crooked.
Anything looks crooked
after a bottle of brandy.
You're a very interesting
man, neighbor.
OK, let's check the height.
Come over here, son.
Come on, shoot!
It's 3,05 m. I guarantee.
Give me five, son! -Ufonja.
Wonderful.
But now you'll have to take
it back to where you found it.
What do you mean, back?
-The basket. It belongs to us.
You shouldn't have touched it.
That's stealing.
What are you talking about?
Since when it belongs to you?
Just a heap of rusty iron.
-Who are you to say that?
You stole our basket! You
know what they do to thieves?
What? What?
-OK, I see.
You came here because
of the chick.
Ufi. I know you came
here because of Josie.
And she chose a better,
prettier and smarter man.
I don't give a shit for that
slut. I want the basket back!
Why don't we settle this
the civilised way? -How?
I mean, I'm gonna beat
the shit out of you!
Hold on! Cut that!
Jovan, give me the ball.
Let's play three on three
up to 21 . OK?
So, what do we do after
we win?
Well, if you win you can
take the basket with you.
If you lose, it stays here. You
can even drop by to play.
No way! -Why? You don't
dare, do you?
Fuck you!
He can't do it. -What you mean,
he can't? Hold him!
Where's the other basket?
That's the problem!
You gotta fly to win!
We started, we started!
Fuck you!
-No, come on, get away!
What the fuck is it?
Cover him Turca, please!
That's right! Do it, man!
How are you, guys?
-Hey, hello!
Just another foul like that.
Do it!
Didn't I tell you it was too
low? -How you welded it.
I'm gonna weld your mouth!
Victory?
I'm buying beer! -First dibs!
-And cigarettes!
How are you, Tiki?
You were good.
You can still score.
Well, not like I used to be...
What are you doing here?
-I came to see you play...
Are you putting me on?
-I gotta go before the alarm.
Wait, wait... Do I look alittle
like I used to? -Just a little.
You sure are hot for me!
-Come on, dream on!
Bye bye.
Here's some coffee for you.
-Thank you.
No, thank you. I'm having
beer. -A strange taste.
The water is two days old.
A little stale, smells of pipes.
Thank you, we're having beer.
-No, thanks.
What about Josie?
-No problem, buddy.
I wanted to dump her anyway.
She's become a bore.
Fucking hysterical:
"They're bombing us!"
Just go ahead and cope with her.
I'll try. I have a way with
women's hearts. -Do you?
They're bombing us again!
Let's split!
Danka, Danka,
come on, quick!
Did Tijana call? -Yes, she's
arrived home. -She has?
Here's the vest.
Here's the bag. Quick!
Mihailo!
Misa!
-I'm here, mom.
What's the matter, mom?
And then Hercules jumped
on Pegasus and flew back.
Try to catch some
sleep now, son.
He isn't afraid of anything,
grandma's treasure!
Kaja, there's a game on TV.
-I'll wait till he's asleep.
Can we agree on the idea
that the quality of one's life
can be measured on the scale
of fulfillment of his ambitions?
One smoke and you
got stoned, man!
My grandfather was a farmer.
That's what he wanted to be.
My father is a laborer.
He always wanted to be one.
What about me? -That's what I'm
asking. What about you?
Is my wish gonna come true?
-What would you like to be?
A lover.
You'd better try to be
a laborer or a farmer.
Come on, grab yourself a beer.
Here you are, Turk! You're
the big tiger here, right?
I'll bet you a 100 marks
they will blast the bridge.
Are those 500 marks ready?
We already played on the court.
It's OK, Turk, it's OK.
Suck my cock!
Josie, where have you been?
It's me, Turca, the pretty one?
Didn't you see me?
Don't worry, it'll be over
soon. Don't worry.
Get away from me!
-OK, I'll get away.
We're gonna suffocate!
We're all gonna die here!
Let me go! -I'm off.
Where to?
-Out of here!
Where do you think
you're going, woman?
Come back here!
-Let me go!
What's wrong with you?
-Let a bomb kill us all!
I can't stand this any more!
I'm sick!
Hey, Josie, remember my scar?
You know how I got it?
Do you know how? -How?
We were running away
from Sarajevo. Behind the zoo,
where the nuthouse is.
Their snipers are here,
our snipers over there.
I take a look to the left and
spot a cherry tree.
Branches overloaded with fruit.
I feel like I could die for
a cherry. I say, what the hell,
and set off toward the tree.
As soon as I put the first
cherry in my mouth,
they open fire!
I thought I was done.
I haven't touched a cherry
for five years since that day.
What does this have
to do with cherries?
Nothing. Important thing is
that you don't get scared.
And I never got to try
cherries again.
Here's some water.
What have I got
from my life, guys?
How many girls did I have?
Nothing!
You want me to count
them for you? Watch now.
There was one in Makarska,
on the beach.
One in Titograd,
while I was in the army. Two.
Have a seat, Seka, please!
-The tally's three and a half!
I ain't counting heavy
pettings in the doorways.
Nothing for my potentials!
I have a whole life to live!
Seka, come and sit here.
You're pretty, you see.
But you look sad.
Are you OK? Come on, tell me.
Zuba hasn't come down.
Probably screwing some
chick upstairs.
While we're wasting time here.
Are you OK, son?
Don't be afraid, please.
Are you alive, Zuba?
-Fifty-fifty. It depends.
What's the matter? Are you OK?
-They razed their basket.
I was right,
they ain't gonna make it.
I though you didn't care.
-I don't.
Move you legs, son.
Leave it that way, ma.
I'll clean it up.
I gotta call Tijana first.
She isn't answering the phone.
Where were you?
I've just called.
Take it easy, please!
Calm down, Tijana!
-Just hold me, Kaja, please.
You never know
when to hold me!
I was trying to call
all night long.
I was worried about
you and Jovan.
Let me look at your hand.
I don't know what to do, Kaja.
Does it hurt?
What if he never speaks
again? -It has to sting a bit.
I'm staying here! We
should all stick together now.
Did they bomb near you?
-Worse than ever.
How's your mom?
-Shivering and trembling.
A neighbor's with her
while I'm here.
You gotta go, Tiki.
-I can't.
Be reasonable, please. Don't
you see they've run amok?
It's getting worse all the time.
What about the Italian visas?
-I can't think about that now.
We must think about it!
-Just shut up and hold me.
What's up, champ?
Wanna pee?
You don't need a butterfly.
You need something else.
And what have you got?
Me? Nothing, 'cause I
don't believe in anything.
What about me?
Do you believe in me?
You? -I don't care
for that butterfly.
What I really wanted
was to be with you.
I don't know why;
you're ugly, boring and fat.
And I still wanted you.
So? Do you hate me now?
-I can't hate you.
I don't know how to do it.
-You can learn to hate.
Go home now. Come on.
Did mom teach you
the numbers?
Do you know what number
was on dad's dress? -Seven.
What did you say?
Jovan, what did you say?
Come on, say it again,
please!
Come on, son.
Come on, say it again!
Danka, he spoke up! - What?
-He said "seven"!
Jovan, is that true?
Hello, Tijana! -Yes? -You
know what happened? -What?
Jovan spoke! -Oh, come on!
-Honest to God! -How?
He just said "seven". I asked
him what my number was.
He said "seven". -Don't make
things up. -I'd never do that.
Let him tell you himself.
Come on, tell your mom.
Tell her what you.
Tell her. Come on.
No, he won't do it now.
But he really did it. Really!
OK, Kaja. I'll call you.
-OK.
How are you, Toza?
-Who is it, son? -Toza.
I'll bring 500 marks for you.
-It was a mistake, they say.
Mistake, my ass!
I'm sorry. -I know you have
a heart of gold.
I'll bring the money.
-Hang on.
What do you say: let's
forget about the bet?
Why? -I love to win,
but not with their help.
Without them,
you'd have made it.
Then you should give me
500 marks. -Turk. you know.
Come with me,
I'I lget you the basket.
Jovan just spoke.
Welcome to our modest
celebration!
It's your court,
Turk, after all.
I'd have missed anyway.
And, suck my cock!
Let's go, guys! Let them idle,
but we've got work to do.
You, Kaja?
-Me?
It's OK, buddy.
Just don't be late, please.
Why are you fooling around?
This country's in war,
and you're fooling around!
Go fuck you! Do it quick.
Yes, buddy, I was waiting
for you 1 5 days.
Do you have a cigarette?
-I'll call you later.
What's your name?
-Seka.
Come on? Seka? I'm Toza.
-Pleased to meet you.
Are you from the 'hood?
-Yes, I live here.
I've never seen you before.
A cigarette, eh? -Yes.
Take this.
-All of them?!
Thank you.
-Thank you.
What's the matter with you,
you drunken swine?!
Wait until I come upstairs to
tattoo your fucking brain!
I'll come down and stick
those cigarettes up your ass!
OK, I'm waiting for you! I'm
sick and tired of you, jerk!
What's up? Leave me alone!
-Come here!
I gotta go home.
What did you do with him?
-None of your business!
It is! Get in here!
He just gave me cigarettes.
-You don't know him.
I'm sick of your lecturing!
Sorry. - What for?
-Everything.
Her name was Jelena.
-Whose? You sister's?
She was 1 7.
Just like you are now.
I was drafted and
our grandma died
and my best friend
managed to dodge the draft.
I thought it was a good thing;
he would take care of her.
And so he did.
What happened?
He took her to Amsterdam.
He came back; she did not.
And you don't know what
happened to her? -No idea.
Maybe she's OK.
-Then she'd have called.
Why don't you ask that
friend of yours?
Toza?
I wanted to kill him.
When I stuck a gun barrel
in his mouth, he told me
she ran away from him
with some criminal.
And I believed him.
Am I the only one
whom you've told that?
Yes, though everybody
knows it.
Come on, pick out a card.
Remember which it is.
Why don't you tell me
what card I picked out?
How the hell do I know
what card you picked out?!
I've got something for you.
-Really?
Cherries!
They may start shooting
from somewhere. -They won't.
Yes, this is the great quality
of these guys.
The awkwardness, poor play.
Yes, yes, all these misses!
Come on!
Here's your inquisitor!
-Yes.
Come on, shoot!
Come on, hit it!
Would you like to play?
-Move your ass back home!
Come on, hard hats, would
you like to play? -Why not?
OK, but let's play a men's
game! -OK.
OK, let's play three on three,
up to eleven points.
It's one - nil.
Ciao.
-Hi.
Balls, kid!
Come on, bro, that's it!
It's 1 1 - 8.
Let's go to my place.
-He plays well, your kid.
I coached him.
-The kid's got balls.
Did Tijana call, mom?
What did you say?
-Did Tijana call? -Not yet.
Looks so calm tonight.
-I don't know why they're late.
Hey, what are you
doing, champ?!
Would you like to
massage your dad's back?
Come on, step on me.
Yes, that's it!
Hey, take it easy!
How come you're here so
early? -I came to take Jovan.
We are leaving.
Where to? -To a safe place.
Far away from here.
What will happen
to Kaja, Tijana?
Hey, bravo!
Where were you, Tiki?
A bit early, aren't you?
I came to pack his stuff.
-Champ's going home?
No, I'm taking him to Italy.
I've got the visas.
Hey, hold it, son. Hold it.
Where are you, honey?
Pity you weren't here yesterday.
It was great.
Everybody came out.
As if the situation was normal.
Have you seen the court?
-What are you talking about?
I'm taking him to Italy and
you're talking about the court!
You should have seen him!
He started to speak.
I wanna say,
I finally did something.
It isn't much,
but it's something.
I did something for Jovan.
I did it to make him
think of something else.
Are you still talking about it?
-You should have been here.
Everything was abnormally
normal, like ten years ago.
I thought that this thing
has made us.
somehow closer after all.
-Kaja, I still love you,
but it won't make me stay.
-Why is it your only way to tell
me that you love me?
Why?!
Hello, taxi! Please send
a car to 4th Boulevard No. 70.
In three minutes?
Yes, thank you.
So, you managed
to get the visas?
I thought we might talk
some more about it.
Kaja, you said it yourself.
Jovan should live a normal life.
This place won't be normal
even in ten years time.
Jovan!
Hey, honey!
Come on out of there,
please.
Honey, we're gonna take a trip.
Across the sea. Eh?
Come on, sweetheart.
Don't you wanna go with
your mommy?
Hey, champ,
please don't hide there.
Do you know how you
become a real champion?
When you come out
to play when it's hardest.
And win.
When Djordjevic and
the guys come to play here,
I'll let you know, so that
mom can take you here.
You know?
OK?
Come on!
No son, it's your ball.
Take it with you.
I'm overloaded.
I can't take this one too.
It's my present for him,
Tijana.
I made you some lemonade and
sandwiches for the trip.
Jovan likes grandma's
sandwiches the best.
You shouldn't have.
Come on, honey.
Listen, Kaja, you really did
miracles with that court.
You really surprised me.
But I need greater miracles
to make me stay here.
What shall I do?
I'll practice to work
great miracles.
Hey, champ.
Come on.
Tijana!!!
What is it, honey?
-Seven.
What are you doing here? You
wanna stay here all day long?
Nothing. Everything is OK.
Lousy weather. A hard day
for both NATO and us.
You're a nice guy, Turca?
Has anyone told you that?
Chicks mostly.
Let's have a beer together,
come on.
No, I'll stay here for
a while to cool down.
Bye.
I know.
Dad was buried on Thursday.
The ceremony was a quiet one.
A lot of people died
in these days.
Zuka and Siske didn't fight
any more.
They didn't talk too much,
either.
They were just sitting
in silence.
Turca talked Josie into
going with him to Greece.
They made it across the
border and left the country.
He promised to teach
her to laugh again.
Misa was the first
to get drafted.
Many others were called-up
after him.
Come on, private.
Go there and grow up.
See you.
It's you. Looks like you,
doesn't it?
I couldn't have done it better,
I was looking at the mirror.
No one plays any more.
I couldn't sleep because of
the noise from the court.
Now I can't sleep
because of the silence.
When are you gonna
finish that tattoo?
Never.
Come on, you try.
I'd surely have missed.
Tijana went to Italy
and she got married later.
I started speaking again,
but in Italian.
But I've never forgotten
my mother tongue.
Translation:
Review:
Olivera Maric
Distribution:
CINEMA DESIGN