NINE LIVES
The story of Jan BaaIsrud
In the spring of 1 943,
Jan BaaIsrud met his destiny.
AII his friends met their deaths.
More than 1 00 countrymen
heIped Jan BaaIsrud survive.
This fiIm can't teII everyone's story
and does not mention any reaI names.
BaaIsrud himseIf,
has supervised this production -
- so it wouId meet his one and most
important note: Thanks for Iife!
Sorry to drag you
aII the way up to LapIand.
- Don't wear Mr. BaaIsrud out.
- I'm in fine shape now.
I have greetings
from London and ShetIand.
- How much do you know?
- Nothing.
We thought we had Iost everyone.
Then you showed up here in Sweden ...
Your feet seem so Iarge.
They were bigger
when I first came ashore.
They want a compIete report.
I don't know if I can ever give
a compIete report.
Everything stiII seems so unreaI.
We were Norwegian soIdiers.
We had crossed over from ShetIand.
A cargo of weapons and expIosives.
SuppIies for Northern Norway.
Those are the facts
that are easy to mention.
And that shouId suffice
as an introduction.
- That's it.
- Stand by.
Yes, this is the pIace.
A. HANSEN
SHOEMAKER
Who are you?
- Are you aIone?
- My wife is asIeep.
What do you want
in the middIe of the night?
- Our shoes need haIf-soIing.
- We heard you were the best.
And that we couId trust you.
Who said that?
Who are you?
Hansen. The shoemaker.
- Who is the enemy?
- Who are we?
The Germans are the enemy.
They took ...
Leave!
Go away!
- You don't want to taIk to me.
- What does he mean?
- Now you Iisten here, Hansen ...
- I'II expIain everything.
- Don't wake my wife!
- What do you need to expIain?
They took the Hansen
who was here before me.
What did you just say?
Don't worry.
I'm afraid myseIf.
AII shoemakers up north are
caIIed Hansen. I'm from down south.
I took over Hansen's business when
he was arrested. I won't say a word.
I'II forget you ever came here.
Won't even teII my wife,
aIthough she Ioves the King.
I don't think you are agitators.
It happens ...
I mean ...
They try to trick us. Send out peopIe
in Norwegian uniforms, -
- with EngIish cigarettes,
to find out who has contact with ...
I know of someone
who has contact with ...
I've known for quite some time.
You want to taIk to Konrad.
The fisherman.
I'II caII him.
You can find him yourseIves.
His is the onIy boathouse
north of here.
We apoIogize for coming
to the wrong house -
- and waking you up
in the middIe of the night.
Just don't mention this to a souI.
- And never cIaim we were agitators!
- Two can pIay at that game.
- This is taking too Iong.
- Think something's wrong?
- Bring the smack aII the way in.
- Is it deep enough?
- Can we forget Hansen?
- He's just afraid, poor man.
- He'II caIm down.
- Is the fIoor strong enough?
- Eight tons of dynamite.
- PIus fuses.
It wiII hoId.
Let's get to it.
Konrad?
Do you know what you're doing?
Yes.
Do you?
Take care of Hansen right away,
and we'II be sure.
Don't be Iate.
Skipper, get the crew ashore!
Into the boat!
Keep the boats out of the way!
Move out!
- ShouId I Iight it?
- Yes.
- How Iong wiII it burn?
- Two minutes.
50 seconds.
40 seconds.
AII cIear?
Prepare to board.
30 seconds.
Row!
Now!
- Dammit!
- Row!
Steer with your oar, Per.
Row!
Sigurd!
Get your feet up.
Thank you, Tua.
It's a good thing I know
how to handIe heIpIess men.
Take it easy.
I'm the midwife around here.
Nothing to worry about.
Where are you going?
Those are stiII wet!
Have you Iost your mind?
I am a dangerous man
to have in the house.
Ask for Henrik across the mountain.
Give him my name.
I never give any names.
Stop!
Who are you?
- I said, who are you?
- Let me sIeep.
- Where is Henrik?
- I am Henrik.
Then I can sIeep here.
- Who sent you?
- EngIand.
- You're Iying!
- It's the truth. We came by smack.
- I heard about that boat.
- What did you hear?
- I wouIdn't teII an informer.
- Did you hear that everyone was ...
You are one man too many,
if what I heard was true.
Heinrich!
Heinrich ...
No, no ...
You can never be carefuI enough.
He has sIept for nine hours.
Let's find out who he is.
YeII for him to get up.
Aufstehen!
You're from EngIand, aII right.
Good pronunciation.
You scared the Iiving dayIights
out of me.
- Is this an isIand or the mainIand?
- An isIand. But I have a boat.
We Ieave tonight.
- I have boots.
- You can't ski in sea boots.
It's a Iong way to Sweden.
- No need to expIain anything to you.
- You aren't the first.
Grit your teeth.
Frozen fIesh doesn't bIeed.
Just watch out for gangrene.
Eat. We have to hurry.
Mum says, there's pork at the bottom.
I'II find it.
Prepare the boat, boy,
and put the skis on board.
Had the midwife
deIivered that baby yet?
You can't fooI me. The stump of your
big toe is in one of her diapers.
Keep going!
Look out!
Stop!
No!
Jan?
- Jan?
- Wait!
Wait!
- Do we know him?
- No.
- Yes, I think I know ...
- He's bIeeding.
The Germans are going from house
to house. Hide him in the barn.
- Can you take him aIone?
- Yes.
- Have you hidden the radio?
- Yes. Are they far off?
They're coming this way.
I'II warm some food.
Have they been here?
They've been to my pIace.
- Making a midnight snack?
- It's for the caIf.
- You shouId be at home, grandpa.
- I shouIdn't have moved back north.
Go home, grandpa. It's Iate.
I had to come up here
to mind the future, my chiId.
You're going to feed the caIf
with a spoon?
Yes.
He's very iII.
He'II Ieave soon.
Grandpa can be trusted,
but oId peopIe taIk too much.
- What's that around his neck?
- The bandage from his foot.
- It's stiII beating.
- Can you open his mouth?
He needs a doctor tonight.
- ImpossibIe.
- We have to feed him something.
I'm most worried about his Iegs.
Go inside, in case someone comes.
Find some ointment and bIankets.
The Iadder has some weak rungs.
And get grandpa out of here!
Wir müssen bedtime.
- We are safe now. Go home.
- That's what I aIways hear.
When we grow oId,
and there is troubIe, -
- onIy the youngest need us.
- They have faith in us.
- Don't be ridicuIous, grandpa.
Damn!
If he is who I think he is, he needs
to cross the mountains to the border.
It wiII take time
if we have to puII him.
We can be back
before the Germans miss us.
Then the boys in MandaIen can
take over. No Germans up there.
- There's no ointment Ieft in town.
- But more than enough curiosity.
His Ieg is bIue.
Try the doctor again.
He isn't back.
How Iong do you dare wait?
OnIy untiI tonight. He has to Ieave.
There's stiII Iife in him.
What if he isn't who you think?
You and I can take that chance,
but we're invoIving many others.
If I can vouch for him
after taIking to him ...
Then we'II aII vouch for him.
- He's awake.
- Has he said who he is?
Are you hungry, too?
- What's the matter, Agnes?
- I think he's bIind.
Can't you see me?
- Who are you?
- That depends who you are.
Not a bad answer.
Thank God! There's Iife in your Iegs.
It hurts Iike heII to begin with.
That's a good sign.
I was afraid
you had Iost aII feeIing.
The doctor's stuck
up in the mountains.
But I'm sure
everything wiII be ... fine ...
If you fire now, you'II hit me.
- Where am I?
- Where are you from?
From the mountains.
Where am I?
With good peopIe
if you are a good man.
- What's this pIace caIIed?
- FurufIaten.
Can we put that gun away?
- Do your eyes burn? Not your feet?
- No.
I had to escape into the mountains.
I know who you are. That was a week
ago. No wonder you're snow-bIind.
That makes 2 km a day.
I'II get you a new bandage.
Do you know me now?
Here's my wife with breakfast.
Snow-bIind. It wiII pass.
- Touch her, too.
- It's enough if she speaks.
Open wide.
- I aImost got seasick.
- You sure got your hair washed.
- What's that in your hand?
- My cIock.
- It's a snowbaII.
- One snowbaII a day from now on.
- Leave some snow on the fIoor.
- We'II be ready to go in two days.
- Are we going up high?
- 1 000 meters. We're at five now.
I'II be fit enough to waIk on my own.
You won't have to carry me
a kiIometer into the mountains.
- You're so quiet.
- No ...
- Martin ..?
- Yes.
- Is there much Iight in here?
- Just a candIe.
WouId you Iike a drink, Jan?
Do I need one?
- This is how we Iook.
- Let's Iook at the remaining nine.
The doctor is coming in a coupIe
of days. Don't worry about your feet.
It probabIy isn't as bad
as you think. The ointment heIps.
Were's the drink?
- CouId you Ieave a knife for me?
- The doctor's coming tomorrow.
Not if the wind picks up.
You won't make it across the fjord.
Don't taIk nonsense. You're bIind
and you made it across the fjord.
- Leave me a knife.
- Why do you need a knife?
- You have a gun.
- I have seven rounds. I need nine.
- Promise to wait untiI tomorrow.
- I'II wait as Iong as I dare.
- Why is Martin out in this weather?
- He went to Iook after the boat.
- Does he need a doctor for that?
- The doctor has a boat, as weII.
The doctor had his bag with him.
Is his boat sick?
- Come to bed, Martin.
- I just stare at the ceiIing.
- He has a week's suppIy of food.
- His feet ...
- You'II have to carry him. Rest now.
- There's onIy one thing to do ...
Cut it off before it spreads.
Martin!
- I've taken on too much.
- No, it's getting caImer out.
- Are the skis in the boat?
- Yes. Don't forget the ice axes.
Ready, OIe? Do you have
what the doctor gave us?
- Yes, but you'II be the surgeon.
- You have to give him the shot.
Yes. He won't feeI anything.
- When wiII you be back?
- Tomorrow afternoon.
- Be carefuI on the way down.
- The cIimb wiII be the worst part.
- So many men?
- Ask Agnes.
Cheers, grandpa!
- What did he say?
- He's going out for moonshine.
I toId him he'd better be carefuI,
if that's what he's up to.
Is it any wonder
I'm proud of that boy?
Hurry!
Martin!
My God!
- He spared me that job.
- We have to bandage him.
He's awake.
He must have nine Iives.
And he'II need them aII.
- Did you hide the boat?
- I did my best.
- How far to a Swedish hospitaI?
- Two days, if we are Iucky.
They'II know more in MandaIen.
Know this:
We want him across the border.
The Germans know
that he must get to Sweden.
But that is aIso aII they know.
Right now he is on his way up
the other side of the mountain.
Forward!
Here in this room I have pounded
common sense, BibIe history -
- and the ABC's into your skuIIs.
Spit in your hands now, boys,
and show me it wasn't for naught!
Has this oId teacher
taught you anything?
- Ivar?
- I'm doing what I did in schooI.
You were a sIow Iearner
back then, too.
- Have we agreed on a meeting point?
- Where is it?
- You can't miss it.
- Germans!
I heard something crack.
Was it the sIed?
No, thank God.
It was just my chest.
- Jan has passed out again.
- Turn the sIed around.
He has a nice view.
Let's go again.
Is he passing out again?
We have to turn the sIed around.
AII the bIood's gone to his feet.
We made it, Jan!
There's no one here.
CaII out, boys!
Martin!
Spread out and Iook for them.
Where I'd Iike to be a guest
where my heart feeIs best
and the cIosest of ties are found
I remember, I remember ...
Keep singing, chiIdren!
They're going from house to house.
They've been to my house now.
Sing chiIdren.
I'II go see the Lapps.
They're our best chance.
What if there's an inspection
whiIe you are gone?
Sing chiIdren!
Drop by
my wife and chiIdren tonight.
As spring dawned anew
my deep Ionging for you
made my cry and cry again ...
PIease, Martin. Get Amund home
before darkness faIIs.
The others wiII fix some food.
As Iong as I have aIcohoI,
you won't get rid of me.
I'II come and Iook for you, tomorrow.
I'II send a card from Sweden.
Anything eIse I can do for you?
Light a fire if you hear woIves.
Don't forget the password, Jan.
- HeIIo, gentIeman.
I'm sure he's here.
Wait for me!
In this weather,
I'm sure they've taken him.
I promised I wouId check on him.
It's strange to think he onIy heard
my voice. He never saw me.
- WeII, aren't you vain!
- I'm so gIad it's over, Martin.
GentIeman!
Over here!
Yes!
GentIeman!
Here!
Here ...
I'm sure he's around here.
Just a few more minutes.
Wait!
He has to be here.
- Don't forget to buy stamps.
- HoId it!
My pack is fuII of empty bottIes.
I just wanted
something to fiII them with.
We aren't done yet, grandpa.
AII the worse for you.
- What do you mean by that?
- What you're doing isn't safe.
PeopIe are taIking. PeopIe have
seen traffic crossing the fjord.
AII I've done is promise
some peopIe Iiquor.
One Iiter for FoImar,
one Iiter for Andrik at the store.
Two Iiters for OId Erik
down on the docks.
He enjoys a drink. One Iiter for ...
- Have you been teIIing peopIe ..?
- Quiet! Both of you!
It must have been tough,
since Amund broke three ribs.
Who has a stiII?
I need 5-6 Iiters.
Take this.
Now open that.
There's your Iiquor!
Never forget
the most important detaiIs, son.
It'II be my job
to keep peopIe's mouth shut.
You rascaI!
I'm sorry, grandpa.
Martin, you can save yourseIf
that trip up the mountain.
A Lapp is driving the ''caIf''
across the border today.
How do you know that?
Go out and cIean up,
and stop asking so many questions.
About those bottIes ...
I just happened to have a stash.
Over here!
No, I think over here!
Try to Iocate him.
Look over here, on this side.
This way.
Come on! Let's go!
That must be the right side.
Are you sure there's no use?
There are other Lapps.
They cursed us in Norwegian,
Swedish and Finnish.
- So the trip was a faiIure.
- It won't be this time.
- The wind's picking up.
- EspeciaIIy up in the mountains.
- Berteus, go back home.
- Why?
Five young chiIdren,
are five good reasons.
- My youngest has pneumonia.
- Go, Berteus.
Ready, boys?
We have to turn back!
Don't pack any more
than Martin needs.
I'm adding some for Jan, too.
He's been up there a week now.
I know. I'm doing it anyway.
They're away fishing.
I'II go aIone this time.
- Where are you going?
- With you.
Stop her.
A new storm is brewing.
- A new storm is brewing ...
- They tend to.
You reaIize
I'm going to get a dead man?
Yes, Martin.
You go up.
Now you can see, Martin.
He's dead.
No, you can't kiII this oId fox.
Jan!
He's aIive!
Dig! I'II get the backpack.
Tomorrow we'II have 1 00 reindeer
foIIow you across the border.
- You have more Iives, Jan.
- Let's go teII the men.
Now your cIock is right again.
OnIy one more.
I get such bad manners from this.
You have food and Iiquor
in your sIeeping bag.
Don't forget to Iight a fire
if you hear woIves.
Go!
I knew you were pretty, Agnes.
HeIIo, gentIeman!
Agnes!
God, how I have waited for you!
There's stiII Iife in you, honey.
There's Iife in him, too, grandpa.
The Lapps don't beIieve me.
TeII Martin we'II get him tonight.
He was expecting you today.
Don't screw it up.
And on the ninth day ...
On his ninth Iife ...
Hurry!
There he is!
We have to turn back!
We'II try again tonight.
No! Oh, no! Don't come!
No!
I'm moving. See?
Like this, and Iike this.
I count. I counted. I have counted.
I am. I was. I have been.
I am Jan.
Jan BaaIsrud.
I used to Iive outside OsIo.
My father is stiII aIive,
as are my brother and sister.
My mother is dead.
I am, as you can hear,
in fuII command of my senses.
And I want some truffIes.
Waiter! My truffIes!
Not troubIe, truffIes!
Headwaiter?
Do you see that man?
Show yourseIf!
Here come the paIIbearers
to take him away!
Here they come
to Iower him in his grave!
Over here.
That's it.
There are few mourners
when you're far from civiIization.
Oh, go away!
Ivar!
Reindeer tracks, Ivar, everywhere!
Go! Get across the border!
Go!
SubtitIes:
SDI Media