[ music ]
CHRIS NICOLA:
Every cave I enter has a secret.
[ water dripping ]
Down there, in the darkness,
there's always a mystery to unlock.
Some people are afraid of the dark.
Sounds echo seemingly from nowhere.
But there are no monsters down here.
[ grunting ]
Back in what we like to call
"prehistoric times,"
people escaped beasts
by hiding in caves.
What was so surprising
about this cave
was that its secret wasn't prehistory.
It was living history.
ESTHER STERMER: Here we are in the
Grotto underground, buried alive.
Who could tell
how long we need to remain?
CHRIS:
I'm a New Yorker.
I work as an investigator
for the state of New York.
But my passion is caving.
I travel the world, exploring caves.
[ birds chirping ]
It was in 1993,
right after the breakup of the Soviet Union,
[ dog barking ]
that I first came to Ukraine.
[ man speaks native language ]
[ man speaking native language ]
CHRIS: I wanted to research my
Eastern Orthodox family heritage,
and I wanted to explore
Ukraine's legendary gypsum caves.
Gypsum caves don't occur
that often in nature.
They're very rare.
And some of the biggest caves in
the world happen to be gypsum caves,
and they're
located in western Ukraine.
[ water dripping ]
I was traveling through the second
longest of the gypsum caves,
the 77-mile-long Priest's Grotto cave,
when I turned a corner
and stumbled over some objects.
There were the remains of stoves.
Trenches had been dug to make
earthen tables and earthen benches.
And I'm not an archaeologist,
but I could tell
that these things were aged.
You start to move some earth around.
You find medicine bottles,
buttons, a lot of buttons,
and a lot of fragments of leather shoes.
And one shoe was a lady's shoe.
What's a either very small
woman or child's shoe,
doing in that cave?
Those objects were someone's life.
I had to find out
the story of who lived there.
I began to map all the objects.
Each object was
a piece of the puzzle.
I started asking people
in the nearby town about the cave.
In the early '90s,
a lot of Ukrainians
were still hesitant
to talk to Westerners.
I'm rather outgoing,
and I smile a lot, I like talking.
Oh, no, no.
People were very hesitant.
Nobody smiled.
It may have been as soon as '94, '95
that someone said,
"Maybe some Jews lived in the cave. "
CHRIS:
[ speaking Ukrainian ]
Again, there's a language problem.
I'm trying to find out,
"What do you mean,
maybe some Jews lived in the cave"?
This was my first real lead.
I began to research
the history of the Jews in Ukraine,
and I discovered
that before World War II,
Ukraine was home to one of the largest
Jewish populations in all Europe.
My Eastern Orthodox ancestors
probably had Jewish neighbors.
ESTHER: We were living
in the town of Korolowka...
my husband, Zaide, our children, and I.
There were 500 Jews living in town.
Ukrainians and Poles
lived on the bordering streets.
The Jews traded with them.
It had gone on like this
for many years.
My two granddaughters were
the newest addition to our big family.
[ all speaking native language ]
With my grandmother,
when you came
to my grandmother Esther,
you had to produce.
It wasn't playtime.
She was a businesswoman.
[ speaking native language ]
My other grandmother picked me up,
kissed me, hugged me,
but she didn't do that.
The time that I spent with her
had to be productive.
She used to have the newspapers
delivered from Warsaw,
from Czortkow, from Lvov.
SAUL STERMER: She was reading
what happened in 1938 in Germany
on Crystal Night,
when they burned all the synagogues.
She said, "It's bad.
We have to run away, if we can. "
One day, she finds in the paper
that Canada would accept Jewish farmers.
ESTHER: We prepared our documents...
my husband, Zaide,
and five of our six children.
My oldest son, Nissel,
who had been in the Polish cavalry,
my younger son, Sam,
and my middle son,
the carpenter, Saul,
and my two younger daughters,
Hannah and Yetta.
My oldest daughter, Henia,
and her husband, Fischel Dodyk,
had decided to remain in Korolowka
with my granddaughters,
Sonia and little Sima.
[ speaking native language ]
[ photographer counting down ]
[ camera shutter clicks ]
SAM STERMER: And we had an interview
with the Canadian consul.
They examined us,
and we were accepted.
And my father sold the land
and the houses, everything...
the beds and whatever we had.
In 1939, on 8th of September,
we were supposed to go.
It was reserved places on a boat.
Stefan Batory
was the name of the boat.
The 1st of September,
the war broke out,
and we got stuck there.
SAUL: My mother said,
"Black clouds are coming. "
SONIA: Soon as the Germans came in,
they made a Judenfrei.
They made Jewish people
to be in charge
of the other Jewish people.
SAM: They would tell us
they're gonna register
all the people between 10 and 50.
SONIA: And they're starting to say
that we have to go to the ghetto.
My mother, she said,
"Boys, make some bunkers, hiding places. "
And we made those places.
We made about six places.
[ soldier speaking German ]
Gestapo!
[ speaking commands in German ]
[ footsteps approaching,
muffled voices ]
[ soldier speaking German ]
I used to sit with my finger
on my mouth,
and I knew I was
not allowed to speak.
I wasn't allowed to whisper.
I was never allowed to cry.
I would have given out everyone.
So we were prepared for them.
We even prepared sand for the women
to throw at them in the eyes
in case they come in.
[ soldier speaking German ]
Somehow, I figured out,
that my grandmother...
is a strong lady.
And if I'll be
where my grandmother is,
maybe I'll survive.
[ soldiers speaking German ]
We were pretty good till...
till Sukkos '42.
They surrounded the city,
and they went from house to house,
and they took away 900 people.
More than half of the Jewish people
they took away to Belzec,
to the concentration camps.
And the rest had to go
to the ghetto.
My mother said,
"No, we are not gonna go to the ghetto.
"We come to the ghetto,
and two days later, we are gone. "
"Nissel," she said
to my older brother, Nissel,
"you go and look for a place.
"You go in the forest there
and dig a hole somewhere tonight. "
My uncle Nissel
went to Bilche Zlote,
and he said, "We should go to Verteba,
to the Grotto. "
ESTHER: In the center
of the Bilche Zlote Valley
was a very extensive cave,
which had attracted speleologists
from all over Europe.
We had no choice.
We tried to stick
the family together.
That was our goal.
My cousin, Sol Wexler,
was with us.
YOUNG SOL WEXLER:
There were three of us...
my mother,
my younger brother Leo, and I.
My father had gone to New York
before the war broke out,
but we got stuck.
We began transporting here at night
wood, kerosene, candles, food, and water.
We set up close place,
not far from the entrance.
My mother said,
"We take everything with us. "
We had everything there.
We were equipped.
[ sawing ]
SAUL:
We start building up some beds.
Piece of wood here, nail it,
two pieces of board.
We bend those sides,
and we brought in
some straw, some hay, anything.
SONIA:
We came to Verteba.
[ gasps ] My God!
I've got a playground here.
I would make-believe
I'm living in a castle,
and it was wonderful
not being in a bunker.
My grandmother was
very worried I shouldn't get lost.
You know,
the cave had so many mazes
- going this way and that way.
- Sima?
- You just had to take the wrong turn...
- Sima!
and I was a very little girl.
[ rock clinks in cup ]
SAM:
It was warm. It was dry.
And we had pillows and covers,
and we had food.
SONIA:
My father and my grandfather
and my Uncle Nissel
all bought badges.
They paid off the Ukrainian police,
and they were allowed
to buy back a horse and wagon
from the peasants.
They were collecting scrap iron
for the German government,
but they were free.
SAM:
So they could stay in our house.
They were driving around all over.
Nissel and my father
and Sima's and Sonia's father
brought in food
and water and whatever we needed.
I used to explore.
That was my thing.
I used to walk around
in every hole, in every place.
SAUL:
Sam says he could see.
Maybe his eyes are different.
I couldn't go from here to there.
I wouldn't move.
We didn't have no water there.
So we used to have drips
used to come in.
I used to go with my grandmother
to get some drippings.
A glass of water
was for a family for a day.
I was once so thirsty,
I got out from the cave,
I said, "Even if they kill me,
I have to go to a well somewhere. "
And I was drinking
almost all the pail of water.
I was so thirsty.
I didn't have water for a few weeks,
just a little bit sometimes.
ESTHER:
Nissel was our most important contact
with the outside world.
One day, Nissel told us we
had to hide more deeply in the Grotto
because peasants
were being seized for labor,
and they might want
to come here to hide, too.
SAM:
Verteba was an open place.
You were exposed.
Nissel said, "If they come in,
"and you don't have
another exit to get out,
"you're all doomed. "
SOL: We used up
all of our time and lighting supplies
looking for a second exit.
My cousin Saul
was always the leader.
I was inside a manager.
[ laughs ]
I was... Anything, I was doing.
We come on one place,
and I see a pile of earth.
In a cave, everything is stone.
I came over.
I took my shovel.
[ shovel scraping ]
And we see between
the two stones that it's soft.
- [Nissel calls out ]
- Nissel?
SAM: Nissel used to come in for two,
three days and dig.
[ Nissel speaking native language ]
If he was digging two hours,
he made more progress
than me in four hours.
Beautiful ground
and very soft to dig.
I was digging
three, four feet in a day.
SAM: And I helped.
Whatever they needed...
they need light,
they need a shovel.
I wanted to show that I, too,
am one of the boys.
SAUL: One day, I was at the top,
and I felt... I see, like, topsoil.
And I look up, and I see a star.
[ panting ]
[ laughs ]
SAM: We were so lucky.
You could come out in the middle
of the road somewhere.
We come out on a field.
[ Saul laughs ]
SAUL: And then I made,
with a 2 x 4, like this,
a frame all around
and the top covered with dirt.
Then they went in the village,
and they took a couple of chains
from the bells.
So high... It was about five stories high.
- [chains clanking ]
Fifty feet high, maybe.
SAUL:
The chain was hanging down.
When you walked up,
you hold onto the chain.
ESTHER:
After completing the second exit,
we began to move back
to our new living quarters,
which was
a cave completely remote.
It was all wild and primitive.
The ceiling was so low
that we could not walk upright.
The families were
now quite scattered
and far apart within the cave.
The atmosphere was not as joyous
as it was when we came in.
ESTHER: Every morning,
Saul and Sam would go outside
to see if there were
any signs of strangers around.
One day, Saul came back, shaken.
He told us someone had actually made
steps to descend into the Grotto.
[ speaking native language ]
SIMA:
The next thing that I truly remember...
and it was horrendous
and stays with me all my life,
even if I want to push it away...
was when the Germans came by.
Hersch Barad
was right next to the entrance.
[ shouts ]
[ shouting in native language ]
And my mother right away
stood up and said to the kids,
"Hide any place you can. "
[ Esther speaking native language ]
I grabbed the ax.
[ soldiers speaking German ]
[ speaking German ]
[ shouts ]
My mother pushed me under.
There's no room for her to go in.
[ soldier yells in German ]
[ soldiers speaking German ]
[ woman screams ]
SAM: I stood on the side,
and I said to my cousin,
"Let's kill at least one of them. "
When I saw that he's not moving,
I threw away the ax.
I said, "I don't want to see
when they kill me. "
- [ soldier speaking German ]
- [ woman screams ]
[ soldiers speaking German ]
[ screams continue ]
[ Esther speaking native language ]
All of a sudden,
I hear my mother.
"We live here like rats.
"We don't mix in politics.
"We are women and children. "
SAUL: "What, are you afraid that
the Fuhrer is gonna lose the war?"
Can you imagine a Jewish woman
to mention the name Fuhrer?
And he says to my mother,
"Don't be afraid. "
SAUL: "We'll take you out,
and you go in a camp. "
My mother says, "I know what kind
of a camp you have for us. "
SAM: She told him. She opened up
his eyes, it looked like.
I see, hey, they're not killing.
After that,
I lost my fear completely.
I started to dress with a jacket.
- [ soldier speaks German ]
Now I took my time.
He didn't like that,
but what the heck?
I had nothing to lose.
SIMA: My mother knew
they were gonna march us out,
and that I needed my shoes,
and she didn't want to bend down
to pull out the other shoe,
because she felt that the German,
with his machine gun,
may bend down with her together
and may see my sister
hiding underneath.
- [ soldier speaking German ]
- SONIA: "Don't worry," he says.
"I can kill her right here.
Don't bother with the shoe. "
My mother starts begging him.
[ commotion,
Esther speaking native language ]
SONIA: Hersch Barad pushed out
my sister's shoe.
[ soldier speaking German ]
[ heavy footsteps ]
[ Leo pleading in native language ]
[ soldier speaking German ]
[ child crying ]
[ soldier shouts ]
[ Leo pleads ]
[ shouts in German ]
SOL: I could hear
the noise in the distance,
as they were leading them away,
and the awful wailing
of my little brother.
[ pleading continues ]
[ soldier speaks German ]
As soon as they turn around,
I was sticking to my mother.
She went like this.
I knew the cave in the dark...
[ soldier speaks German ]
and I ran, and I ran right, left,
and lied down under a rock.
[ soldier speaking German ]
SAM: My mother slipped
into a hole in the side.
[ soldier speaking German ]
[ speaking German ]
[ silence ]
SONIA: I know
they took my mother away.
I'll never see her again,
and I'll never see my sister again.
All of a sudden,
I hear somebody saying...
[ speaking native language ]
"Where are you?"
WOMAN: Sonia? Sonia?
[ speaking native language ]
SONIA: My Aunt Yetta
came looking for me.
[ Yetta speaking native language ]
[ speaking native language ]
SONIA:
She says, "Don't be afraid.
"Whatever will happen to me
will happen to you.
"I'll take care of you. "
I... I don't know what happened,
or I'm sure I got very scared.
But I don't remember nothing.
[ all speaking native language ]
[ panting ]
When I didn't hear them no more,
I ran in straight in the exit.
Saul was scared,
and I kept pinching him. Nothing.
I was finished.
[ all speaking native language ]
[ chains rattling ]
SONIA: I'm holding onto a chain,
and I'm walking up the steps.
[ woman speaking native language ]
SONIA: People are screaming,
"Open up the exit!
Open up the exit!"
[ young woman crying ]
But there's nothing.
They can't do it.
They can't do it!
[ woman and girl pleading ]
[ boy speaking in hushed voice ]
[ overlapping voices
conversing and calling out ]
[ women pleading ]
[ woman pleading ]
[ girls pleading ]
[ overlapping voices ]
Everybody started to run
in different directions.
We were like wild people.
ESTHER:
It was very cold.
Each one of us ran
with no destination in mind.
I tried to speak to Saul...
- [ speaking native language ]
but he couldn't reply.
[ panting ]
SOL: We were
only paces away from the guards.
We could hear them talk
about discovering us.
We crawled to the village,
to the Mirawald barn.
Mrs. Mirawald had hidden
Hannah once before.
[ knocking on door ]
[ speaking native language ]
What a mother.
Oh!
SOL: That night, I lay there
and thought of Mother and Brother.
The Gestapo had turned them over
to the Ukrainian police.
[ door closes ]
SIMA: I remember when
they put us into that prison room,
and they put us down on the ground.
They didn't feed us.
My mother kept saying,
"Don't worry, my child.
"You'll see. You'll see.
We're gonna be fine.
"Your father's going to take us out.
"We're going to be okay. "
[ Henia whispering ]
She was just trying to comfort me
because I knew at that age,
I knew we were going to be shot.
I knew that.
I was home already.
I was, uh...
When I ran away, I came,
and I went straight to the bunker.
My father and Nissel and Fischel,
they ran to the Ukrainian police,
and they made a deal with them.
500 something... I don't know...
gram or something, gold.
The men had to bring
five bodies to replace ours,
because should
the Germans come back
and want to see
where the bodies were that were shot,
he protected himself.
He said, "I want to have two children,
two women, and a man. "
[ shovel digging ]
SONIA: And they found two
women and a man,
but they couldn't find any children.
So my father
said he's not stopping.
He's going to look
in another place
where he thinks
there were some children.
I mean, that was the only way
that they were going to save our lives.
The policeman insisted on that.
[ woman crying ]
SIMA: The Ukrainian policeman said,
"Just lie down.
"I'm gonna shoot five times
in the air,
"and then you're
just gonna run away. "
[ woman crying ]
[ gun cocks ]
[ gunshot ]
[ gun fires twice ]
[ sniffs ]
SIMA: We just got up,
and my mother started
to look why they didn't get up.
And that's when we realized
that they were shot.
[ speaking native language ]
ESTHER: When the chief of police,
who was a stranger in the district,
learned that Sol Wexler's mother
was from Bilche Zlote,
he decided he would
not be able to free her or her son.
The peasants might see them
and report back to the Gestapo.
[ speaking quietly in native language ]
SOL:
We left early the next morning.
It took us a full day
to reach the Stermer bunkers.
As long as I live,
I will remember my cousin
Sol Wexler's eyes,
searching for his mother and brother
and how guilty I felt that his mother
and brother are not there.
[ wind howls ]
SAM: He came into our house
after he killed my aunt
to collect the gold and the silver.
Got a whole bundle,
and he went away.
And after that,
we were in big trouble.
We had to hold off
all the Germans.
Anyone gonna be spotted
gonna be shot.
[ somber piano music ]
CHRIS: I kept coming
back to Ukraine every year,
hoping to uncover the story of the
people who had lived in the cave.
Western Ukraine was one of the worst
places for Jews during the war.
Less than 5% survived here.
1.5 million Jews were executed
without going to the camps.
It was a personal extermination.
I figured that if a group of Jews
had lived in the cave,
there were probably no survivors.
ESTHER: Outside,
the sun warmed the fields,
which were beginning to turn green.
All was awakening to life,
but we sat there
like condemned men.
There was no place
on Earth for us.
SOL: Every night, I had dreams
of my mother and brother.
And sometimes,
in the middle of the day,
I would imagine seeing them
while still wide awake.
We were hiding,
and Nissel was going around to look.
My mother says,
"Nissel, you got to find a place.
"We cannot live like this. "
SAUL:
Nissel went to Munko Lubudzin.
He lived in the forest
in a little house.
- Munko... [ speaking native language ]
- And he says...
SAM: "I need a place for my family.
"Maybe I can make some bunker,
hiding place in the forest, a hole. "
He says, "You know what?"
"I was once hunting a fox,
and he ran in a hole.
"And I come there. I didn't go in.
"There's a hole. Try this hole. "
This was the 1st of May,
a Sunday, 1943.
[ speaking native language ]
And we look on the right side.
It's an opening.
We got down,
and we start sliding in.
[ water dripping ]
As we were walking,
we took corridors.
We took a long passage,
and we started walking.
The main room that you walk in,
I think you could drive in
with a couple of trucks.
Before was a smaller room,
then was, like, arches,
and you walk in the second.
And I touched a little stone.
It rolled down, and I hear...
[ water splashes ]
We go down,
and I put my two hands like that,
and I taste the water.
Such sweet water.
[ man speaking native language ]
SAM: So this is the place.
We have water. We can live.
We went home with good news.
ESTHER: They had found
the best place imaginable.
No human being had
ever set foot there.
Thirty-eight of us descended
into the cave.
The men told us to slide down
into the mud.
[ young girl whimpers ]
SIMA: Somebody was standing there,
and they kept pushing you.
You know, they were
maneuvering you to go down.
You slid in the mud.
We talked to our mother and said,
"It's very hard,
"and I don't know if you'll be able
to squeeze through the stones. "
ESTHER: I tried to get through the rocks,
but it was impossible.
They maneuvered my body
and placed me wherever they could
until, finally...
Boom! She's inside.
We got our mother inside.
We came, and we were very hungry,
and we were wet.
And I remember I had, like,
the chills, you know?
We came there almost
without food.
No food.
By the time we came
to the second cave,
everything was lost in the first cave.
[ water dripping ]
SAM: Nissel was
with my father in business,
so he knew everybody,
and everybody...
He was a very likable guy.
SAUL: There was no bank.
There was no money.
There was no nothing.
But the only thing...
if you have a few things, you trade.
SAM:
The miller was a friend of Nissel's.
SAUL: And he bought
a hundred kilos of flour.
SAM: This Ukrainian guy was supposed
to go pick up the flour.
They made a deal with him.
[ man speaking native language ]
And he's to meet Saul and Nissel
in the field there.
They made an appointment.
They came there.
The guy's not there.
We were waiting and waiting,
and we see
it's almost daylight,
so we went back to the cave.
SAM: So the next night,
they went to him.
SAUL:
We didn't go by the door.
Forced a window, and we got inside.
[ men speaking native language ]
"Don't ask questions.
Give us back the flour. "
SAM: Finally, he says,
"Okay, I got some here in the corner. "
So he gave a third of it.
We decided we need a stone
to make our own flour
the guy took away from us.
SAM: So, a couple days later,
Nissel and Saul went to his house.
And we went in his barn,
and here's the stone.
SAM: That stone
they can hardly lift, right?
SAUL: Nissel carried it home
with us on his back.
[ Nissel speaking native language ]
[ groans ]
SAM: Once they got the top stone,
they made a bottom stone.
Grind a little bit flour
and a little potatoes,
and you used
to go to the kitchen and cook.
SONIA: Each family had one man
or two men
that would go out and get food.
If they brought in a bread,
they brought in the bread for their family.
These were the rules.
SIMA:
The women never went out.
Only the men went out.
[ people conversing quietly ]
SOL: When it came to food,
each family was separate.
My uncle, Zaide Stermer,
was hiding above ground.
Nissel and Saul were now
heads of our family.
My father was
in a very small village,
and he had a very good friend.
He was afraid, plain and simple.
He was just afraid, you know?
We knew one thing.
We have to go.
We have to do
what has to be done.
We have to go out,
no matter what.
If there's no food here,
that's the end of it.
[ animal squawks ]
- [ speaks native language ]
- SAM: Nine uniforms.
I put on a shirt
with a pair of pants.
I felt like a hundred dollars!
[ laughs ]
[ speaks native language ]
It was so much fun.
[ insects chirping ]
SAUL: To cut wood was
the most dangerous thing.
It was so noisy.
You start cutting and knocking
and sawing.
You could hear it.
You could hear it
to the police station.
So, we were standing there
and cutting wood.
This guy came over.
He knew us.
He was like... grew up with us.
[ whispering in native language ]
- Some people said, "Take him in alive. "
- [ men conversing in native language ]
And some people said, "Kill him.
He can go to the police. "
[ man speaking native language ]
SAM: And then the decision
was to let him go
and to trust him.
We trusted him.
They came with the shovels
and with the digs,
and they, I bet you they threw
in there maybe 25 loads
till they filled up the hole.
They say, "That's gonna
be the end of them. "
[ panting ]
SAM: Mendel comes running in.
"The villagers covered the hole.
"That's it.
We're gonna die here. "
SOL:
We thought we were finished.
They knew about us.
We didn't have another exit.
ESTHER:
We would all die of hunger here,
a fate worse than strangulation.
SAUL: "It's terrible!
"We can't go out!
We're gonna die here!"
I said, "Wait a minute. "
The second cave was all over stone.
Only in the front...
SAM: There was, like, a little room
there when we came in.
And there was a boulder.
And on top of that boulder
on the side...
SAUL: I see some earth.
SAM: Three days and three nights,
we were working,
everybody in shifts.
[ grunting ]
We made another exit.
We made sure
that they couldn't come in,
because who wants to slide in,
in a wet hole feet first?
You don't know
where you're going.
There was a man
always standing with an ax,
and if they would have come in,
they had to
come with the feet first.
They would have chopped off
their feet.
[ men conversing in native language ]
SAM:
We trusted one man, Munko.
And Munko used to tell Nissel
all news.
ESTHER:
There was talk in the village
that my daughter Hannah
was hiding out
in the home
of the Mirawald woman.
She had been there ever since
they had discovered our first cave.
When my grandmother heard that,
she said to my Uncle Nissel,
"You go and bring her immediately. "
[ conversing in native language ]
SAUL: And Hannah came out,
and she looked so nice... so clean!
[ conversing in native language ]
The next day,
the Ukrainian police came,
and they turned the house
upside down looking for Hannah.
If they would have found her,
they would have surely killed her.
Then the priest came,
and he said that nobody
should keep a Jew.
He preached that they should get
rid of all the Jews.
So the farmer came home.
He says to my father,
"You have to leave. "
[ speaking native language ]
SAM: He says, "Run. "
[ speaks native language ]
We had no friends.
ESTHER:
All the family was now in the cave.
Every time the men returned
from the outside,
they had bitter news.
The police and their helpers
had boasted
that they had discovered
a bunker in the forest
and killed very many Jews.
Among them were our best friends.
There were 24 people in the bunker.
[ man singing in native language ]
My grandmother
kept a calendar in her head.
She knew day by day
which day it was.
And when the holidays came around,
my father was the hazan,
and he knew how to pray beautifully.
All day in Kippur,
we didn't sleep.
We would fast,
and he was praying.
[ singing continues ]
[ man praying in native language ]
[ insects chirping ]
SIMA: When the men used to go out,
it was very, very frightening.
SONIA: The women would sit,
but they wouldn't talk,
because nobody wanted to...
to say it out loud
that they might not come back.
Everyone thought about it,
but nobody said anything.
SAM: If I didn't go out
with Nissel and Saul,
I was sitting there
and waiting for them to come back.
Somebody else would try to come in,
I would stick him.
ESTHER: On the evening
of the 10th of November,
my sons, Nissel and Saul,
joined by my husband, Zaide,
went to buy grain and fuel.
SAUL: Some people in our cave,
they had, let's say, a gold chain.
They cut little pieces,
and the deal was made.
And we had to stay over the barn.
It was so cold.
So, we tell to our father,
"Why are you gonna stay here?
"It's cold. Go back to the cave. "
What me and Nissel did together,
my father was completely
a different person.
[ speaking native language ]
So he went back.
This was, about, should I say 12:00.
About 2:00, he's back.
He says,
"As I was walking to the cave,
"somebody was yelling,
'I'm gonna shoot!"'
He run away.
And the police is near the cave.
We are here,
the family in the cave.
We wouldn't be able to go in.
They wouldn't be able to run.
Everything is over.
We're gonna all die now.
Nissel said,
"Let's go and have a look. "
Then I say to Nissel.
I say, "What if we both croak?
"What do you think?
Are we gonna fight somebody?
"Stay here. I'll go myself. "
And I tell him,
"Listen, if they kill me,
"you're still gonna do something.
"But if they kill you, the family
cannot survive without you there. "
[ whispering ]
[ speaking in native language ]
And Sam was there.
Said, "Everything is all right. "
[ clicking tongue ]
[ speaking native language ]
We were all inside, and I hear
somebody's walking there.
Everybody's inside.
How come somebody's outs...
All of a sudden,
we hear shooting.
SAUL: Pow! Pow! Pow!
They're shooting.
[ gunshot ]
SAM: Nissel picked up a big boulder,
put in the hole.
He was such a powerful guy.
[ Nissel speaks native language ]
Nobody had a brother like I had.
There were no brothers like that.
[ water dripping ]
ESTHER:
Long ago, people believed
that spirits and ghosts
lived in caves.
Now we could see
that there were none here.
The devils and evil spirits were outside,
not in the Grotto.
SOL: It was decided we would
stay underground for two months.
Let them think we were dead.
Do nothing.
SAM: Everybody slept.
There was no lights, nothing.
We slept 18 hours a day,
maybe more...
maybe 20.
[ wind whistling ]
SAM: And we stayed in,
and there came the big snow.
SAUL:
Blowing snow and everything.
SAM: The police came,
and they looked,
and they saw no tracks.
"Nobody comes out here.
"They must have somewhere
another exit. "
But we didn't have nothing.
Christmas Eve we can go out.
They for sure, the police,
they were thinking,
"They're not gonna be around here. "
My uncle Saul made a sleigh,
a collapsible sleigh.
Went out in the forest,
and I brought in
two young, little trees.
- [ water boiling ]
- And I cook and I cook.
And then I took it out,
was steaming.
Bend, you tie down,
and let it dry for a day,
and here I have
one side already, huh?
Was not one nail in the sleigh.
Nothing.
[ grunting ]
SAUL: I look at Nissel.
He was yellow...
not shaved and marked all over,
like a wild man.
I thought to myself,
"Maybe I look like that, too. "
I took the sleigh,
and I go with Nissel to Bilche Zlote.
And we load up the grain,
250 kilos or even more, grain.
[ grunts ]
And we start to pull.
We can't even move it.
Said, "What do we do?"
Nissel says,
"I'm gonna go to Bilche Zlote. "
[ Nissel speaking native language ]
And I was waiting
in the meantime.
I was so damp, so cold...
terrible.
Suddenly, I hear...
[ imitates horse ]
I look around.
I see somebody's on a horse.
[ laughing ]
[ blows ]
SAUL:
I see Nissel come on a horse.
He brought a horse!
[ Young Saul speaking native language ]
Say, "Nissel,
where is the harness?
"You forgot the harness!"
He says,
"I'll go back for the harness. "
I said, "Don't go for the harness.
We're gonna make harness. "
[ speaking in native language ]
And we go with this horse.
Oh-ah!
And it was real chutzpah to go
and to steal a horse.
Mendel Dodyk came out.
"People eat horse meat!
"Let's kill the horse!
Have meat!
"It's a fat horse!"
He says, "It's a beautiful horse.
"I'm not gonna
let this horse be killed,"
and let it... let it run away.
ESTHER: Food had become
increasingly difficult to procure.
We had to consider every bite.
We ate only often enough
to keep alive.
And I used to say to my mother,
"I know, Mommy, that
I'm not supposed to have more food,
"and you keep giving me food,
and I keep eating and eating,
"but I know that I'm still hungry. "
But I didn't ask for more.
I just told her how I felt.
[ water dripping ]
SOL:
Food started to be missing.
They started accusing me.
I denied it.
I felt guilty and ashamed,
but I had nobody.
[ stones scraping ]
SAM: I used to grind the flour.
And Sol, he helped me grind.
But we grind the flour
in the dark.
We never used no light.
I speak to him.
I said, "Sol, Sol. "
There was all flour all over the face.
- [speaking angrily in native language ]
- It was terrible.
He ate up the flour for the family.
Very naive.
He was, uh...
He didn't act smart.
SOL: That day,
I got the first of many beatings.
They warned me,
if they ever catch me stealing,
they're gonna throw me out.
SONIA: He was hungry.
I think he was hungry
out of loneliness.
ESTHER:
A new problem came to plague us.
The underground lakes had dried up.
SAM: The water was going
down and down.
It dropped maybe 15 feet
when we were there.
[ raised voices arguing ]
SOL: There were fistfights
and arguments.
[ argument continues ]
[ baby crying ]
SAM: We knew that if the Russians
don't come in 1944,
in the winter,
there's no way
that we can live there forever.
For how long?
For another year? No.
SAUL: The Ukrainian police,
they would come after us,
and they would stay there,
and they would get us.
Suddenly, we hear...
[ imitates gunfire ]
My brother was in the army.
He says...
"You see that fire?
That's the front. "
They were going over with tanks.
When we got out,
we'd see a tank there,
a smashed rock here.
[ machine gun fire ]
You go out.
You go outside,
and who knows what's outside?
I think at one point...
I don't know if it's true or not...
but I think
they took lots at the end.
Who's going to be
the first one to go out?
SOL: We didn't know
who was outside,
the Russians or the Germans.
So they sent us to go to the woods,
where Munko lived.
[ distant machine gun fire ]
He said, "The Russians are here,
the Germans are here,
"and we are in the middle. "
We were stuck outside the cave.
It was an hour before
they realized we were missing
and pulled us back in.
[ wind howls ]
[ siren blares in distance ]
CHRIS: After working
on this for nine long years,
I had finally run out of leads.
As interested as I was in finding out
if this legend or rumor was true,
I came to the realization that perhaps
not all puzzles are solvable.
Then, one winter night
in December,
I just came back
from an expedition,
and I was tired,
and I was greeted
by 40 or 45 pieces of junk mail.
And I think it was
the last or next-to-last one
when something caught my attention.
"Jewish cave survivor. "
And I froze.
[ horns honk in distance ]
It was from a fellow
who identified himself as Ed Vogel,
the son-in-law of Sol Wexler,
who survived the Holocaust
by living in a cave
in western Ukraine for over a year.
And Sol was living
less than seven miles away from me.
He sat me down
and started to tell me his story...
how he lost his mother and brother,
how he survived underground
for over a year and a half.
My cousin, Sol Wexler,
called my uncle, Saul Stermer,
and he told him
that there is a man,
and his name is Chris Nicola.
Those are remains
of the branches that came outside.
Yeah, yeah.
That was...
That was this morning.
This morning.
[ music ]
CHRIS: And then I learned
Esther Stermer
had written the survival story down
and listed the family names.
That's when I remembered
the chamber in the cave
with all the writing.
It hit me like a brick wall.
"Stermer," "Salomon,"
"Wekselblad," "Kurz," "Dodyk. "
Among all these words
were their names.
We were in the right place
at the right moment.
That was our luck.
And maybe that's
why I wanted to go back
and to say thank you
to the cave.
[ all conversing in native language ]
SONIA: It's with us.
We try not to show it,
but it's always with us.
And here I am, back after 67 years!
Oh! [ laughs ]
SIMA: My Uncle Sam and my Uncle Saul
have fantastic memories.
"Well, this piece of land
belonged to this family,
"and this piece of land
belonged to our family.
"And this piece of land
belonged to the Dodyk family. "
Then I stop for a second.
I say, "Hey, where are the people?
"Where are the people?"
I know this...
I knew all the names.
"This is Rolenstock,
and this is Schneider, and this is... "
Right through all the people,
and nobody there.
SAM: Where are the people?
This was
the most painful thing to come.
Very painful.
[ dog barks in distance ]
[ birds chirping ]
SIMA:
Going back into that prison room,
that was my hardest day
of my trip to Ukraine.
I saw everything that happened,
and it's almost
like I heard my mother
speaking to me in my head.
We didn't speak.
We didn't tell people
too many times.
If we spoke about the cave,
we spoke it amongst ourselves.
We didn't tell it to others,
because it was just too incredible.
CHRIS: It would be hard
for experienced cavers
to endure a year underground...
not just by the environmental
conditions,
but also mental conditions.
They discovered one
of the longest caves in the world,
and they broke the record
for uninterrupted, sustained survival.
These were amateurs,
that ranged in age
from 2 years old to 76.
They went into the cave
not equipped,
but through trial and error,
being able to think
out of the box,
they turned themselves
into world-class cavers.
We thought that getting
into Priest's Grotto
might be too difficult for them.
Sam is in his 80s,
and Saul is 91.
But Sam insisted on trying.
Okay.
[ men conversing indistinctly ]
- Okay?
- We're doing good
Okay?
SAM: Yeah, listen,
I'm very disappointed,
because I wanted to go in
and be in the place
where we lived.
Listen. Listen.
The Ukrainians will tell you
there's something special
about this cave.
Once you open the door,
you can feel something.
The cave knows you
and your brother were here.
- Oh, yeah, the cave knows!
- It knows.
- Yeah, yeah.
CHRIS: What did your mother write
in the beginning of the book?
What did she write
about why she wrote the book?
Because she wants
maybe someday grandchildren
and great-grandchildren come
and to see what we went through.
And who's standing
right alongside you?
My granddaughter
and my brother's grandson.
It was my first bedtime story...
everything about the cave.
SAUL: My granddaughter...
she got out.
Beautiful... a nice, tall girl.
Said, "This is my granddaughter,
came to my cave. "
This was worth a million
to see that.
The first day,
when I walked down,
and I came, and I looked down.
I could see it now,
the way it looked.
CHRIS: Nice and slow, Saul.
Guiding Saul through
the passageways of Verteba
was quite an experience.
I felt like I'm going
back in time.
And in my mind,
I'm thinking that
he's seeing things
the same way he did 67 years ago.
You better watch my cave here.
Don't break nothing.
CHRIS: When it was Sam's turn,
his energy level was unbelievable.
SAM: Fine. I'm fine.
CHRIS:
He was so eager and energetic,
he was pulling me
through the cave.
CHRIS: We're gonna continue
going straight.
When I went into Verteba...
I... I... I saw everything
in front of me.
I saw the people.
Look, this is where
they were cooking.
SONIA: And I was happy.
This is where they were cooking.
Look. Don't you see,
it's all smoke here?
SIMA:
When I was five years old,
one-third of my life
was spent in caves.
I think we slept here.
I think this is where we...
See, Sam?
When it gets dark...
- Yeah.
- and they put just a candle,
you're gonna see the same change.
[ lights click off ]
SAUL:
Now I know where I am.
Let's close down the lights
for a minute.
Ahh. Now I feel good.
The cave was fighting for me.
I should be alive today.
Those stones...
Those stones put up a fight.
SONIA:
I was safe in the darkness.
I feel safety in the quietness,
and sometimes, you know,
you're still
the child that is in the Grotto.
SAM: The Russians...
they bombed the Germans,
so we stayed inside,
and we told this guy
that if the Russians come in,
he should put a note
and put it on a string
and put it down in the hole.
[ clanks ]
One day, I come out,
and there it is.
Oh, what a noise.
Everybody was yelling
and crying and...
and we were liberated.
[ birds chirping ]
You can't imagine this feeling,
how beautiful it is outside.
SIMA: I said,
"Close the candle, quick!
"It's too bright.
"I can't see. "
I forgot that there was a sun.
[ music ]
Not one person came out
to greet us and say, "Hey. "
These were neighbors...
"We're so happy that you're alive. "
SAUL: And we had a dog
before we left,
a beautiful German shepherd.
This dog, if he could say,
"Where have you been?"
SIMA: There are miracles,
and there aren't miracles.
Depends how you want to believe.
There had to be miracles for us.
CHRIS:
I feel like I did something good.
I went to Ukraine
looking for my family's story,
and I found someone else's.
We beat the odds,
and they didn't get us.
SAM: We are not heroes,
just survivors.
We fought.
We were fighters.
ESTHER: We were masters
of our own fate in the cave.
There was no one
to whom we owed our safety
or upon whom we depended.
After our men came in
from the outside
and scraped off the mud
which clung to their clothing,
they were free men.