OFFICIAL ENTRY
1969 FESTIVAL OF THE ARTS
DAIEI STUDIOS
FIRES ON THE PLAIN
You idiot!
The hospital sends you back
and you obey?
There's no room here
for consumptives like you!
Go back!
Tell 'em you have nowhere to go.
They'll have to take you.
Why can't you
grasp the situation?
We landed to the west
under enemy fire
to reinforce units
at Tacloban.
We lost two-thirds of our men.
Our artillery was sunk in transit.
We tried to reach Burauen airfield
by crossing
the central mountains,
but without artillery,
it was impossible.
The enemy's counterattack
forced all companies
to fan out across the valley.
You know all that.
We brought 12 days' rations
from Ormoc.
You really think there's any left?
Soldiers are taking turns
foraging for food.
You're coughing up blood
and can't even lift a sack of potatoes.
In the thick of war,
your comrades gave you
five days' food to take to the hospital.
Three days later you returned,
saying they'd
pronounced you cured.
TB cured in three days?
With five days' food,
you should've stayed that long.
I sent you back to complain,
but the doctor claimed
it wasn't five days' worth,
and it was all gone anyway?
What kind of imbecile are you?
I don't begrudge you the food.
If you could work like the others,
then no problem.
This company's shrunk
to the size of a platoon.
But we still have to eat!
The unit has split into three groups
taking turns foraging
for yams and bananas.
They eat what they find
and bring some back for the others.
Then the next group goes.
Like goddamn beggars!
This is the Imperial Army!
It's a disgrace,
but what can I do?
We all have to pitch in.
You're nothing but a burden.
You should be ashamed!
All I can do
as your squad leader
is send you back to the hospital
before everyone starts hating you.
If they don't admit you,
sit there until they do.
If they still refuse,
then you must die!
You weren't given
a hand grenade for nothing.
If they send you away,
blow yourself up.
That will be your final duty.
I, Private First Class Tamura,
will return to the hospital.
If they do not admit me,
I will kill myself.
Good!
Now buck up and go!
Don't bother reporting
to the commander.
I, PFC Tamura, will report
to the hospital as ordered.
Fall in!
It's not easy for the squad leader.
He can only order the men
to dig air-raid shelters.
They don't even have shovels.
Just sticks
and old worn-out pans.
I fill out
supply requisitions
with nowhere to send them.
The enemy doesn't even
bother with us anymore,
yet we still dig air-raid shelters.
You're better off at the hospital.
The company CO can't help you.
I'm sure he heard
the squad leader's hollering.
Here are some rations.
I'm grateful.
Kill yourself only if you have to.
Damn it, I'm starving.
Hey!
Where are you going?
I didn't think
anybody was around.
This is the entrance
to our camp.
Where there's an entrance,
there have to be sentries.
It's so hot
we went in the shade.
Where are you going?
I, PFC Tamura,
am reporting to the hospital.
The hospital again?
I won't be returning
to the company.
Why not?
It seems there's no room here
for sick men like me.
Who said that?
The CO?
The squad leader?
Who knows who's better off anyway,
you or us?
They'll order us to attack soon.
But will the hospital take you?
I'll stick it out until they do.
Don't give up.
Produced by MASAICHI NAGATA
Based on the Novel by SHOHEl OOKA
Screenplay by NATTO WADA
Cinematography by SETSUO KOBAYASHI
Production Design by TOKUJI SHIBATA
Music by
YASUSHI AKUTAGAWA
Starring
EIJI FUNAKOSHI
OSAMU TAKIZAWA
MICKEY CURTIS
HIKARU HOSHI
MANTARO USHIO
MASAYA TSUKIDA
KO SUKIDA
YOSHIHIRO HAMAGUCHI
ASAO SANO, SHIN DATE
YOSHIO INABA, JUN HAMAMURA
Directed by KON ICHIKAWA
Good day, sir.
Good... day.
This way.
Please come in.
This way, sir.
Please eat.
What's this?
That's salt, sir.
Is this your house?
No, sir. My house is
on the other side of the river.
Please eat.
What's that?
Yams for my parents
and siblings
out working in the jungle.
Would you like some yams?
You mean those?
No, these aren't for you.
But wait a moment,
and I'll get some nearby.
God, it stinks!
That bastard!
The hospital!
I'm saved.
You idiot!
They throw you back here
like a baseball.
Go back and tell your leaders:
This hospital's overflowing
with seriously wounded men.
There are only two doctors
and seven medics.
I don't care if you're coughing blood.
If you can walk, you're not a patient.
Tell 'em that!
What kind of degenerate
comes in for something so minor?
But you've come a long way,
so if you've brought food,
you can rest here
for a few days.
I have no rations, sir.
Sir, no excuse, sir.
Those are 26cm guns.
Ormoc's getting hit
with long-range shells again.
You back again?
Looks like
another new man arrived.
He wasn't here this morning.
There are three new guys,
including you.
Only one went away.
Pops, that one had crazy diarrhea.
He left 'cause guys
with diarrhea don't get fed.
Shape he's in, he'll be dead
'fore he even walks a mile.
No point staying here.
You can say that again, pops.
They've still got rice.
We might as well eat too.
Gimme your yam.
I'll steam it with mine.
No appetite?
Or out of yams?
You've got malaria.
You can't even move.
They really should admit you.
Wily bastard.
Everything's falling apart,
and the fucker's steaming yams.
He got lots of tobacco from somewhere.
Wraps it around his belly.
He traded some for yams
at the hospital earlier.
He could return to his unit
but stays to do business here.
He helps us out.
You jealous?
You think
if you side with him,
he'll give you half his yams?
He's a tightwad.
Won't even give you one.
I have my own.
You've got it good.
I've only got one left.
Don't worry.
I won't ask you for yours.
We've been chucked out of our units.
No point fighting now.
I hope the Yanks
take us all prisoner.
They'd kill us.
Nah, they think being a POW
is honorable.
They'll say,
"You guys fought hard,"
then fill us up
with corned beef.
Thanks.
Go ask your buddy for some.
Didn't you say
you had some yams?
I won't forget your kindness
as long as I live.
That won't be long.
That's for sure.
I'll swipe some hospital food tonight
and pay you back in the morning.
Don't.
You'll get caught.
Don't you feel sorry
for the patients?
What's wrong?
Looks like
he pissed himself.
Tell us when you gotta pee.
We'll hold you up.
It's hopeless.
He won't last long.
You're all deserters!
A career soldier,
as gung ho as ever.
- Fucking bastard!
- What's going on?
Stealing yams!
Where's the candle?
Hold him down!
Son of a bitch!
- Is he a patient?
- No, one of the squatters.
Drop dead, you worthless shit!
We're gonna chase
you all off tomorrow!
Aren't they shelling
your company?
Looks like it.
We may be in danger here too.
What's that smoke?
Beats me.
I saw lots of smoke
on my way here yesterday.
Black smoke
everywhere I went.
This morning it's over there.
Pops, you think
it's some kinda signal?
Smoke signals?
The Yanks wouldn't use
anything so primitive.
Maybe it's guerrillas.
Hey, get moving
or you'll be killed!
He's dead.
They took
almost everything!
I was told to die,
and I intend to.
So why run?
There was no need
to fill my canteen.
Some of you may still be alive.
But I won't come to your aid.
I'll be dead soon myself.
Then we'll be even.
MANY DAYS PASSED...
AND MANY NIGHTS
What's that?
A village.
That must be the cross
on the church.
I'll be killed if I'm caught.
So why do I want to go there?
Is that the cross I saw?
Japanese soldiers!
Hello.
Don't!
Don't kill me!
Salt!
Japanese soldiers!
What unit are you from?
PFC Tamura,
Murayama Company, Koizumi Corps.
Murayama Company
was wiped out at Albuera.
I was in the hospital.
I came here alone.
Where's your rifle?
I lost it in a valley.
Some soldier you are.
Your company, sir?
Oshima Company.
We got cut to pieces at Burauen.
We were to join a paratrooper unit,
but only 30 of them landed alive.
They ran our direction
in the jungle
and got our company
blown apart in the bargain.
We sure were relieved
to find this yam field yesterday.
Yams?
Are there any left?
Stop slobbering.
There's lots left.
But you better hurry.
A plane was patrolling here earlier.
Let's clear out.
It was a gift from the gods
to find so many.
They'll tide us over
until Palompon.
Sir, are you proceeding
to Palompon?
All troops on Leyte
are ordered to assemble there.
All units are retreating
for evacuation to Cebu.
I didn't know.
You going too?
Yes, if you would be so kind.
I haven't heard
such fancy talk in ages.
We never offered
to take you along.
You look sick.
Can you keep up?
I'll do my utmost, sir.
We've been to hell and back.
Even ate human flesh in New Guinea.
Come along,
but careful you don't get eaten!
What have you got there?
It's nearly bursting.
It's salt.
Salt!
Talk about luxury!
What do you say?
Share some with us?
We'll take you along.
We won't eat you.
I was kidding.
Yes, I'd be happy to share.
Thanks!
How about a little taste now?
God, that's good!
Let's go split it up
in the shade.
There's a hut over there.
- Ashes from a signal fire!
- Signal fire?
Guerrillas use them
as smoke signals.
I saw black smoke
everywhere.
So did we.
What guerrillas?
Don't get all worked up.
It's just farmers
burning corn husks.
Looks like they just
harvested this field.
Back home my family burns
piles of rice hulls.
What's all the fuss?
They're just fires on the plain.
Where'd you get it?
Down in a village.
A village?
It's pretty far away,
by the sea.
You went there alone?
That was brave.
Wasn't it dangerous?
It was deserted.
Looked like
the Americans had been there.
Seems wandering Japanese soldiers
had also attacked a few times.
The villagers had fled.
There was a pile of Japanese soldiers
killed by the villagers.
Anything else?
- Such as?
- Food, of course.
- Just salt.
- That can't be all. You look everywhere?
Just in one house.
I'll bet there's more food.
Why don't we take a look
on the way?
A man ran away.
Guerrillas may be there now.
What?
Something sounds fishy.
You just said it was deserted.
Two villagers returned for salt.
That's how I found it.
So one ran away.
And the other?
I don't know.
Only one saw me,
and he ran away.
Well, you gave us salt,
so we'll take your word for it.
No time to dawdle.
Get your yams.
We'll wait here.
Sir, there's a hut and a field here.
Maybe even chickens.
Isn't it safer to stay here?
Wanna spend your life here?
Be my guest.
But you never know
when the Yanks might come.
I'm not gonna take that risk.
I got you one.
Is this really
off a dead soldier?
Where else?
I too looked far and wide,
but inexplicably I couldn't find
a single dead soldier with a gun.
You don't know how to look.
So I got one for you.
Take it or leave it.
Just shut up and take it.
Thank you very much, sir.
Any troops here
from Shimizu Company?
Get a load of him.
Not a care in the world.
What do you mean?
Resting against a tree trunk,
his things in a neat row,
hands clasped on his chest.
Just waiting to die.
Take a look.
His tidiness is admirable.
No, I won't look!
I refuse!
Need tobacco?
One leaf for three yams.
Okay, two.
Sell it to the officers.
The division staff is behind us.
Is that true?
Is it true or false?
Can't know until they come,
can you, dumbass?
Hey, Tamura, you still alive?
You too?
Your beriberi got cured?
- Yeah, but I'm being bled dry.
- How so?
- By that awful bastard.
- What awful bastard?
Yasuda. He and I banded together,
so I'm selling his tobacco.
But the son of a bitch
can't move at all.
Which one is Yasuda?
Tamura, is it?
You look better.
I'll bet you have
a lot of food on you.
Must be tough
getting around with that leg.
I can walk a little
if I lean on Nagamatsu.
And I can't eat
unless I let him.
That's right. We gotta reach
Palompon before my tobacco runs out.
Who would buy tobacco now?
Are you kidding?
Men can't live without tobacco.
The worse things get,
the more they need it.
We're selling a lot.
- That's not true, pops.
- You're just a bad salesman!
Soldiers would trade
their last yam for it.
Look, the officers!
Hurry up and catch 'em!
I'll trade you that for a yam.
Fool! Wasting your time
trading tobacco!
Hurry up and get
to Palompon, you idiot!
Get the food before you hand it over!
How many times I gotta tell you?
That's the first time
that happened.
It'll happen again.
Be more careful, you ass!
I'll be going now.
I can't take it anymore.
Leave him then.
I'd starve if I did.
I can't even steal his tobacco.
He keeps it wrapped around his waist.
Only gives me a leaf at a time.
It's true.
You'd best get to Palompon
as soon as possible.
Yasuda's not going.
He plans to surrender
to the Yanks.
You plan to surrender too?
I'll cross that bridge later.
I'll just do
whatever Yasuda does.
Is that how we'll end up?
What's that?
Just look!
No shortages for them, I'll bet!
All fat as pigs!
First time I've actually
seen the enemy.
We've heard 'em
but never seen 'em.
We never saw
who was shooting at us.
Running left and right,
dodging their shells -
it all seems a little funny now.
See that house
beyond the main road?
The road forks there.
The road to Palompon
runs through the forest
at the foot of the hill.
We gotta get to that forest.
But that means crossing the road
and the open field.
Hey, you, stay down!
We'll all be better off
once we're in Palompon.
They'll let us watch
the officers cross over to Cebu.
Is that you,
squad leader, sir?
Hey, not so loud!
You still around?
Yes, I ran into some comrades.
I apologize for my long absence.
No apology needed.
I almost gave up hope
of ever meeting up with you again.
It'll be tough crossing that road.
How you gonna do it
with no shoes?
I'll be all right.
Will we be crossing at night, sir?
Ain't it obvious?
That marsh is pretty deep.
How deep you think it is?
Can't tell from up here.
Is it the best place to cross? Well,
everyone's here, so I guess it must be.
It's knee-deep on this side,
but shallower on the other.
You seem to know a lot.
You crossed it already?
Don't believe me
if you don't want to!
He's nuts,
getting mad over nothing.
Come here a minute.
You got any salt left?
Yes.
The squad leader ate mine.
Could you give me
a little more?
Thanks.
Let me give you some advice.
You've been following
the squad leader like a lost puppy,
but I wouldn't, if I were you.
He's treated us like dirt
since we landed in New Guinea.
We stay 'cause he's seen combat
and stays cool under fire.
He'll let you tag along
until he's taken all your salt.
Then he'll toss you on your ass.
Did you really eat human flesh
in New Guinea?
Better just think
of that as a joke.
I'm his subordinate so I'm stuck,
but you're free.
I know it's scary on your own,
but you'd be better off.
I understand.
All right, then.
No more tagging along.
What were you guys
whispering about?
Thinking about surrendering?
Now's your chance.
Once we reach Palompon,
we may not see any Yanks.
Look, there's a friendly-Iookin' one.
A chaplain.
It says "traveling chaplain."
Is that right?
You know English?
No wonder he looks kind,
if he's a chaplain.
Hey, assholes!
Just try and surrender!
I won't let you!
You should be ashamed!
Lag behind and I'll know
what you're up to.
You're going to Palompon,
like it or not!
Just look at your faces!
The enbankment!
We're safe! What a relief.
Asshole!
Let go of my scabbard!
Keep quiet!
Don't get so close!
Tanks!
I'm hit!
I think I left my gun over there.
I don't think
I can make it to the forest.
He's alive.
He's smoking.
I surrender!
Is Palompon this way?
Yes, but there are Yanks on the way.
We can't get past.
It's been raining forever.
Hey, are you dead?
The earth's revolving, you see.
That's why the sun sinks,
sonny boy.
Brother,
where did you come from?
The Pure Land in the West.
Buddha is Amida...
one is one...
two is two.
I clasp my hands in prayer.
Hey, let's get out of here.
No need.
A plane is coming for me
from Taiwan.
An autogiro.
It's supposed to land here.
Mr. Airplane, come for me!
Please take me home!
I'm a Buddha!
Save us, O merciful Buddha.
It hurts!
What kind of birds are those?
They're not birds.
They're flies.
The flies are buzzing.
You're kinda stupid, aren't you?
What, you still here?
Poor guy.
When I'm dead...
you can eat this.
Come back!
You can eat me!
I wouldn't do it.
I didn't do it.
I'm dreaming again.
Someone's watching me.
Tamura, is that you?
Nagamatsu?
Come on now.
It's water.
I can't chew.
My teeth fell out.
My gums have gone soft.
- What's that?
- Monkey meat.
- Monkey?
- Shot him in the forest.
- I saw a hand.
- A hand?
What hand?
It's rolling around out there.
Didn't you know?
- Nope.
- Over there.
All right, I get it.
Some soldier got his hand shot off.
What happened to your buddy?
Yasuda? Alive and kicking.
You guys been here all along?
Yup. We couldn't make it
to the Ormoc highway.
Wouldn't have
gotten past anyway.
Yasuda's leg
keeps getting worse.
Says he can see
to the kneecap.
He won't show me though.
It's noble of you
to look after him.
Me?
We're from the same outfit,
and it's Ionely on my own.
And he's got tobacco.
Still?
He traded me some
for the monkey meat.
Crafty bastard
never smokes any himself.
Can you get up?
I don't know.
Is this the direction
you came from?
Yeah. It's not exactly a hut,
but further in I have a place to sleep.
- You got any bullets?
- Yeah. I use 'em sparingly.
Did you mistake me for a monkey
and almost shoot me?
You gotta be kidding!
It's Tamura.
I didn't recognize him at first either.
He's changed so much.
Tamura?
What happened to you?
I collapsed.
Nagamatsu found me.
Isn't the war over yet?
Like he would know?
He's been drifting around
just like us.
You got any food?
Not a thing.
I've been eating
grass and leeches.
- No rifle either?
- No.
Oh, yeah.
I have a grenade.
A grenade?
Wait. No, I don't.
I must've lost it.
What a waste.
Could've thrown it in the pond
to get some fish.
- Don't you guys have any?
- We used ours.
All we've got now is his rifle.
He hunts monkeys with it.
Only thing keeping us alive.
- How many pieces left?
- Not many.
- I said how many!
- What difference does it make?
We agreed we'd only eat three a day.
Now let's have the tobacco.
Okay, but we've got
another mouth to feed.
You'd better find another monkey.
Who's gonna share with Tamura?
It oughta be you.
You brought him here.
He can't chew anyway.
I don't need any.
It's softer cooked.
He said he doesn't need any.
Why force him?
Fool!
Don't tell me he came here
in order not to eat.
I'll eat some
when my teeth are better.
You bet you will!
I'll see to that!
What are you so mad about?
It's just monkey meat.
You're right.
You're damn right.
Have some leaves.
Thanks.
Leave some for us.
Chew and then spit it out,
or you'll get the runs.
I'm not worried.
I've been eating raw grass.
Hey, Tamura.
What's so great about smoking?
It's poison to the system.
Smokers are a bunch of idiots.
Isn't that right?
I really don't know.
Here's some water.
Ready to hit the sack?
- Don't you sleep here?
- No, over that way. You coming?
I'm okay here.
Come on.
It's not far.
He said he's all right here.
Yasuda's leg
starts hurting at night.
His moaning won't let you sleep.
Let's go.
Why can't he stay here
if he wants to?
Your bed is quite far.
Not really.
I wish it were further.
- Why not sleep where he does?
- Don't tell him where I sleep.
He says his leg's a wreck,
but he can walk, I tell you.
I don't sleep there
'cause I don't want him
stealing my rifle.
- Why would he?
- You'll see.
I brought you here
'cause I trust you.
Me?
Careful he doesn't
steal your grenade.
But I don't have -
Yes, you do.
- How'd you know?
- I can feel it.
I really thought I'd lost it.
I know.
I used to keep it in my pocket.
I said I know.
- I forgot I moved it.
- I believe you already!
You're good at that.
Watching the fire is Yasuda's job.
It's hell to restart if it goes out.
- It started raining.
- Is that my fault?
How you gonna catch
any monkeys?
They might be around,
even in the rain.
I'm going.
- I'll go with you.
You can't walk.
Wait till you're better.
I'm still sleepy.
I'll take a nap at Nagamatsu's.
You can sleep here.
Come over here,
out of the rain.
You won't get wet.
I'm glad you showed up.
Nagamatsu's gotten real uppity.
Fights me on everything.
He'd be dead by now
if not for me.
I taught him to shoot monkeys.
Are there that many around?
I haven't seen any.
It's not like the place
is crawling with 'em.
They don't come out
in the rain, do they?
The rainy season's winding down.
It seems to have stopped.
I think I'll take a look around.
Where's the pond where you said
I could use my grenade to fish?
That was a long time ago.
It's a long ways away.
I thought you lost your grenade.
It was in my haversack.
It could've gotten wet in the rain.
Let's see it.
A 99, isn't it?
Properly set, too.
It's still good.
Give it back.
I'll look after it for you.
You'll get it wet.
Give it back.
Nagamatsu's gonna be angry.
Did he say something?
He said not to let you have it.
- Then why did you?
- I wasn't thinking.
Too bad.
It's too late now.
Give it back.
All right.
If you want it that bad,
you can have it.
Just put that thing away.
You catch on quick.
He got one!
Come back here!
Stop. Don't.
I get it.
- Did you see?
- Yes.
The monkey got away.
No telling when I'll find another.
There's one right in front of you.
Where's your grenade?
- I don't have it.
- You don't?
You just thought I did.
- What happened to it?
- Yasuda took it.
What? You idiot!
After what I told you!
I wasn't thinking.
I've got no choice now.
I've gotta kill him
before he kills me.
We gotta get him to use it.
He'll throw it when I shout.
When he does, run.
Yasuda, I got a monkey!
Stupid son of a bitch
fell for it!
That's strange. The stream's
dammed up, just like I left it.
This is the only place
around with water.
It flows from here
to the forest below.
Where'd the bastard go?
It's been three days.
He didn't have much water.
No telling how long
the old bastard can hold out.
- Let's just get out of here.
- No.
We're out of food.
We'll kill him and cook him up,
then surrender to the Yanks.
No one will know I ate "monkey meat"
if I don't say anything.
You know the way to Ormoc, right?
I don't remember.
Why don't you just
kill me and eat me?
I could've done that long ago,
but I've got no hankering
for TB germs.
I'm sick of the whole thing anyway.
That old shit talked me
into all this,
but enough is enough.
That asshole's bullying
gets on my nerves.
I won't be happy
till I finish him off.
- There's smoke rising.
- Is it a signal?
No, a prairie fire.
I hear they're for burning corn husks.
I'm gonna go see.
- Don't be a fool.
They're farmers.
Forget it.
They're not Japanese farmers.
Let's head
for the Ormoc highway.
The Americans won't make it
easy to surrender.
You'll be fine
as long as you're with me.
I'm not surrendering.
You go on alone.
Stop talking nonsense.
It's him!
He's finally come out.
Nagamatsu! Tamura!
I was wrong!
Let's make up!
Come on out!
I've got a fire going!
We've got one too!
Come out!
You can have all my tobacco!
We've had enough
of your tender mercies!
I'll just kill you and take it.
Don't think
I've got it on me now!
It's hidden away nice and good!
Let's be friends!
He's a clever bastard.
Hold on, Tamura.
Don't do it.
I know what you want.
There are farmers around that fire.
I know it's dangerous to go there...
but I want to see people
leading normal lives.
THE PHILIPPINE FRONT
FEBRUARY 1946
THE END
Extracted and Adapted by i0n for KaraGarga '07