THE TRAVELLING PLAYERS
A film by Theo Angelopoulos
The play you are about to see
in five acts
is Spyridon Peresiades'
immortal idyll
''Golfo the Shepherdess'',
with a superb cast
of famous actors,
both seasoned players
and others who are young.
The love of Golfo,
tragic and profound,
deep in your heart
will resound.
In the fall of 1952
we returned to Aegion.
A few veterans,
but mostly younger actors.
We were tired.
We hadn't slept for two days.
LONG LIVE MARSHAL PAPAGOS!
THE SAVIOUR OF THE NATION
If we don't want to see
our streets
If we don't want
another Red December...
We must all rally
around the Marshal.
With your vote you can make
this coming Sunday,
the 16th of November 1952,
a historic day.
A day of victory for
the national forces.
This is why you must vote
for Papagos.
By voting for him you vote for
the only national candidate.
For the man who led our
army to victory...
against the communist
rebels in 1947-49.
A vote for the Marshal
is a vote for peace,
prosperity, law and order.
Tomorrow afternoon...
The Minister of Propaganda
of the Third Reich, Goebbels,
accompanied by Ioanis Metaxas,
our National Leader,
will pass through our town
on his way to ancient Olympia.
The National Youth
Organization
invites everybody
to welcome him,
suitably and respectably
dressed for the occasion. ''
Ioannina
Lefkada, Xanthi...
Leave it, father.
I'll do it.
Write down the dates too.
You will come back.
No matter how many years go by,
you will come back,
full of remorse,
to ask forgiveness.
One night in shame
you will come back.
It won't come out!
Why is everyone happy
and smiling, father?
Why don't you get
your little bastard.
Dammit!
Because on a golden day
like this, my child
the black tears stopped,
old wounds were healed.
The wheat grew tall.
And the stones turned into
flowers and golden streams.
Left turn!
Forward march!
Why? Didn't you like it?
You will come back.
No matter how many years go by,
you will come back,
full of remorse,
to ask forgiveness.
Broken-hearted,
you will come back.
Why is everyone happy
and smiling, father?
Why is the sun so bright today?
Why is the day so clear?
Because on a golden day
like this, my child
the black tears stopped,
old wounds were healed.
The wheat grew tall
and the stones turned into
flowers and golden streams.
You, this way.
In room 15, the others in 17!
The day has come and in the
dawn the morning star has set.
The peaks are drenched in
sunlight and nightingales sing.
Partridges bathe in the streams
but the proudest partridge
of them all,
the beautiful Golfo,
has not appeared.
But here she comes!
Good day to you, Tassos.
Good day to you, Golfo.
They might be watching!
No one can see us
save the birds of the forest.
And the birds?
Not like that... scared... the
way your mother would say it.
No one can see us
save the birds of the forest
and the surrounding peaks.
And the birds?
From the beginning, comrade.
- Good morning.
Hello, mother.
Don't look at me.
I look awfuI in the morning.
I'm on a 48-hour pass.
We leave for the border
in a couple of days.
At least you don't hate me
like your sisters.
Still the same obsession!
I knew you'd come.
- Again?
- I dreamt about it.
No, this was something
different.
We were in a garden.
It was summer.
You were three or
four years old.
The air was fragrant.
Someone was singing.
No, it was Mr. Kokinos playing
the violin. Remember him?
Then, I don't know
what happened.
You ran to me.
Hid between my legs.
I held you tight
untll you started to sink
inside me
and disappeared.
I got up then.
Mr. Kokinos was still playing
the violin.
But I couId feel you inside me.
Good day to you, Tassos.
Welcome, beautiful partridge,
for whom my eyes pined.
Good day to you, Golfo.
Orestes! Orestes!
Orestes!
How are you, father?
I am rotting!
The daisy told me
that you don't love me.
That you no longer adore me.
You cannot melt away
my sadness,
however sweet your caresses...
having great power.
And the earth was illuminated
with his gIory.
And he cried out
in a mighty voice saying:
Babylon! Babylon the great
has fallen!
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow morning...
for the border,
from what they say.
Then we'll soon be
at war here, too.
One night I crossed the river!
There can be no doubt for
any Marxist, that a revolution
is impossibIe without
revolutionary conditions.
What are the characteristics
of revolutionary conditions?
When a crisis breaks out
in the rullng classes
and indignation of the
oppressed classes emerge.
When the misery
and suffering
of the oppressed classes
take a more acute form.
When as a consequence of
the above mentioned conditions
there is a great increase in
the activity of the masses
who in times of peace quietly
allow themselves to be robbed
but in revolutionary times
are forced by circumstances
and the crisis in the rullng
classes
towards independent
historical action.
We must explain to
all governments:
We know you are the armed force
against the proletariat.
We will march against you,
in peace, whenever possibIe,
with guns when it becomes
unavoidable.
Feasts! Bread! Gallows!
Tell me, girls...
How are you doing?
Where are you going?
Here comes Golfo
and there's Tassos, too.
Come in and see them.
Outside don't wait,
the play is great!
Don't debate,
it's already eight!
Tell me, you guys...
How are you doing?
Where are you going?
Here comes Golfo
and there's Tassos too.
Come in and see them.
The day has come and in the
dawn the morning star has set.
The peaks are drenched in
sunlight and nightingales sing.
Partridges bathe in the streams
but the proudest partridge
of them all,
the beautiful Golfo,
has not appeared.
But here she comes!
Good day to you, Tassos.
Welcome beautiful partridge,
for whom my eyes pined.
They might be watching!
No one can see us save the
birds of the forest
and the surrounding peaks.
And the birds?
What is it?
What's wrong, Golfo?
How can we be together when you
run from the eagle's shadow.
I thought it was the shadow
of a man.
Don't be afraid.
Only God is here to see us
and surely it is His wish
that we love each other
faithfully and honourably.
Look around you Golfo at
the clouds around us
which like a mist, like a
blanket thrown from heaven
shield us from mallcious gossip
and indiscreet eyes.
You are my only thought,
my only dream...
And truly I pray for you
and light a candle
to the Virgin Mary.
You will come back.
No matter how many years go by,
you will come back,
full of remorse,
to ask forgiveness.
One night in shame
you will come back.
When you reallze
you were mistaken,
broken-hearted
you will come back.
In the meantime the Turks
occupied Karahissar.
It was August 1922.
The front was breaking up.
Our soldiers arrived,
threw down their arms.
The Greek Army no longer
existed. Disaster had struck.
I managed to board
an Italian ship,
swimming all the way
from Aghia Triada.
Thank God there were
the Italians.
They had designs
on Asia Minor too
but they were more human,
and bringing them to
Greek soil.
Whlle the French, the Americans
and especially the British
who helped cause the war as
it served their own interests
showed the worst conduct.
I boarded that ship
with nothing on but my pants.
Finally, we arrived
in Keratsini.
I was so hungry.
I longed for spaghetti
cooked in oil.
I kept saying to myself:
I wish I had something to eat!
I jumped into the sea.
The others jumped too.
He gave me an old shirt
to wear.
I set out for Piraeus with
a man from Chios.
We reached a country tavern
where they were cooking beans.
There was a couple inside.
I asked for some water.
''Where are you from?''
they asked.
''We are the first refugees
from Asia Minor,'' I replied.
''Sit down,'' said the couple.
''Give them something to eat. ''
We ate a whole portion
of beans.
They also treated us
to some retsina wine.
It turned out that they
were royalists.
And some nonsense about
the last king of Byzantium.
I said: ''I've eaten, I thank
you, goodbye!'' And we left.
I was furious.
We spent the night
in a church in Piraeus.
All the refugees
had gathered there.
I slept in a pushcart.
In the morning
I told my companion from Chios:
''We'll go find work. ''
''Where?'' he said.
''Wherever we see a smoke
stack, we'll go. ''
We finally saw one.
I was barefoot.
I asked the guard
at the factory:
''Excuse me, we are refugees.
Are there any jobs for us?''
''Come in,'' he said.
They gave us 2 drachmas a day
and a place to sleep.
It was better than nothing!
In the meantime I wondered
what had happened to my famlly.
I saw an old neighbour.
How are you?
He was the brother of
Vassilis, the actor.
''Your oldest brother was lost,''
he told me.
''Your father, mother and
the kid got off at Mytilene. ''
I searched heaven and earth
to find them.
But I never did.
Black is the night on
the mountains,
On the cliffs, the snow
is falling.
In the wilderness,
in the darkness...
on the hills, on the rocks,
on the paths...
The Greek draws his sword!
At 5:30 this morning,
28th October, 1940.
the Italian Armed Forces
attacked our frontiers
along the Greek-Albanian
border.
Our forces are defending
the land of our fathers!
Our show tonight
is dedicated...
to this first army communique
and to victory.
The day has come and in the
dawn the morning star has set.
The peaks are drenched in
sunlight and nightingales sing.
Partridges bathe in the streams
but the proudest of them all,
the beautiful Golfo,
has not appeared.
But here she comes.
Good day to you, Tassos.
Welcome, beautiful partridge,
for whom my eyes pined.
They might be watching.
No one can see us save
the birds of the forest
And the birds?
What is it?
What's wrong, Golfo?
How can we be together when you
run from the eagle's shadow.
I was terrified.
I thought it was the shadow
of a man.
Don't be afraid.
Only God is here to see us
and surely it is His wish
that we love each other
faithfully and honourabIy.
The daisy told me that
you don't love me...
that you no longer adore me.
I did it!
At first they didn't want
to take me.
I said: ''Take me even
as an auxiliary. ''
In the end they took me.
Undress.
Are you coming?
where everything in life
is fleeting.
Come and place a kiss
on my hair.
If we don't want to see
our streets
smeared once again with the
hammer and sickle.
If we don't want another
Red December...
We must all rally around
the Marshal.
the 16th of November, 1952,
a historic day.
A day of victory
for the national forces.
This is why you must vote
for Papagos.
A vote for the Marshal
is a vote for the only
national candidate.
For the man who led our
army to victory...
against the communist
rebels in 1947-49.
His victory will mean peace,
prosperity, law and order.
Is this where you said the
Englishman was hiding?
You!
I was terrified.
I thought it was the
shadow of a man.
You made me drunk,
you made me mad.
I lost my head.
I don't know what to say.
Oh, God! They'll kill
each other!
And I'll scratch your eyes out,
you and that witch.
Take this bread
and cheese, child.
I'll go and tend my sheep.
Are you still standing,
you ingrate!
Kneel and ask forgiveness
from that angel!
is Spyridon Peresiades'
immortal idyll
''Golfo, the Shepherdess'',
with a superb cast...
It looks like the Englishman
managed to escape at night.
We have information he was
hiding on stage last night,
disguised as a woman.
Informer!
Bitch!
I came from beyond the sea,
from Ionia. And you?
Fire!
I can feel your daughter
watching us like a dog.
Why don't you send her away?
Anyone who doesn't like it
can leave!
I escaped from prison
with six others.
When the front collapsed, they
handed us over to the Nazis.
The resistance movement
is growing, Electra...
I got a message from Orestes.
I'm leaving for the mountains
to find him.
How many ships have floundered
in your eyes blue as the sea.
Ships whose only purpose
was to dock
in love's harbour.
In your mischievous blue eyes,
my wildest dreams,
my sweetest dreams
were swallowed up,
hurllng against the rocks
of your heart.
Never before in my life
have I ever seen such eyes,
so blue, so large, so bright.
Tell me, you girls...
Where are we going?
What are we eating?
How I love the girls...
a bit of thigh,
a bit of breast...
come to the cafe..
with a wonderfuI play.
Such lips and eyes.
Such firm young bodies
you'll never hope to find
anywhere.
Everyone outside!
Me, comrade!
It's the partisans!
Turn off the lights!
They're gone!
Now is the time to forge
the publlc order...
and our democratic liberties!
Countrymen, let us unite
with the national army
and our allies
for the liberation of Greece,
under the leadership
of a government of
National Unity.
GOVERNMENT OF NATIONAL UNITY
FREEDOM TO THE PEOPLE
And now happy at last,
free from fascism!
We can all go home, brothers,
together, all together,
now that the occupation
is over.
Enslaved people,
tortured people,
the wind of freedom is
blowing. Onward!
And all together let us cry:
Onward, brothers!
THE WIND OF FREEDOM IS
BLOWING. ONWARD!
AND ALL TOGETHER LET US CRY:
ONWARD, BROTHERS!
Partisans, soldiers of
the People's Army!
Break the bonds of slavery!
The bell of freedom is ringing!
Let all the slaves rise up!
THE BELL OF FREEDOM IS RINGING!