And you've come here
directly from Normandy?
Ja wohl, ja, ja.
And how is the morale
of the combat troops?
It's excellent.
You mean that?
Ja, ja.
Please.
Ah. That's where the attack
against the Fuhrer took place...
right in there,
only three weeks ago.
The bomb was placed
under the table.
It was in a briefcase.
The generals thought
everyone would be killed,
but the Fuhrer was safe,
thank God.
General Jodl is waiting.
Please.
General Jodl.
Heil Hitler.
Very pleased to see you again.
The Fuhrer wants to see you
immediately.
Be careful
when you shake his hand.
Oh, then he was wounded.
Not badly;
merely a scratch.
Nothing serious.
Nervous?
Ja.
Quite naturally.
...mein Fuhrer.
Noch nicht, mein Fuhrer.
Thank you, mein Fuhrer.
Ja wohl, mein Fuhrer.
Herr Choltitz, at last.
I am so glad they sent you here.
You can't imagine.
As you know, I've been appointed
your successor.
Paris is now a fortress city.
I am in full command,
and unfortunately,
it will not be
an easy assignment.
Now, allow me
to introduce to you
some of my staff officers.
Colonel Jay you know already,
General von Boineburg,
Chief of Staff,
and my adjutant...
he will serve you well.
Please report to me at
6:"0 tomorrow morning
at my headquarters
in the Hotel Meurice.
At 7:"0, I want all the officers
for a staff meeting
at which we will study
a plan for the defense
of the city of Paris,
street by street.
Is that clear?
Ja wohl, Herr General.
Then I won't disturb you
any longer, gentlemen.
My God.
Gentlemen, you have heard
which way the wind's blowing.
Well, what's wrong with you?
Are you drunk?
Have you forgotten
how to salute?
Look at this uniform.
It's disgusting.
It looks as if
you've been sleeping in it.
Why don't you mind
your own business?
It is my business...
I am an officer,
and you are a soldier
in the Wehrmacht.
That's my bad luck, isn't it?
Haven't you heard?
We've lost the war.
Germany's finished. Kaput.
We've had it.
Stand up.
Papers.
What you need is
a few days in prison.
You're a disgrace to Germany.
Museum is closing.
All right, we are closing.
Sorry, monsieur, we're closing.
The exit's right there.
Closing time, monsieur.
Ja, I'm leaving.
600 rifles to free Paris.
Where are the arms
and ammunition
promised by General De Gaulle?
They'll arrive very soon.
Soon? We need them right now.
I should get a message
this evening.
London will tell us when
the Allies will arrive in Paris.
If they don't decide
to go around the city.
We'll have to wait if they do.
Tell that to our men.
Bernard Labe could tell them,
and they would listen to him.
But he's in prison.
We have to free him.
I know only one way.
This is the center of Warsaw.
It was here
that the Polish terrorists
first fired on German troops.
As a result, the Fuhrer ordered
the complete destruction
of the city.
A lesson not only to the Poles,
but to the world.
Your husband's alive.
In Germany?
No. In Paris.
He's to be transferred
to the prison at Fresnes
with a large group
of political prisoners.
Fresnes.
That means they'll
send him to Germany.
Yes.
Warsaw no longer exists.
And it will never exist again.
So perish all enemies
of the Reich.
Enough of these horror pictures!
Keep quiet, I want to watch.
If you like it so much,
why don't you
go to Germany?
I didn't do anything, I swear.
I'm telling you, it's a mistake.
Day after tomorrow
at Place des Vosges.
That's how we're planning
to set them free.
That's premature.
An uprising can't succeed
without support from the Allies.
In that case,
they'd better hurry.
In the last four years,
I've changed my address
ten times.
I've changed my name.
Today, our men are like me.
Impatient to come
out in the open.
Impatience was never
a good argument for anything.
German morale is low.
We ought to strike right now.
De Gaulle is in London.
If he were in Paris, he'd
see things differently.
For the Germans, the
Resistance is an enigma.
Soldiers without
uniforms or training.
They're convinced that
we've got them outnumbered.
That's to our advantage.
Anyway you measure,
the decision can come
only from the National
Council of the Resistance.
Yes, we know that.
So call a meeting,
but I'm sure they
will agree with me.
Think what happened to Warsaw.
If you start too soon,
you'll find
you've only liberated ruins.
My name is Eller.
I was just parachuted
from London.
Thanks, that's a good job.
Please, Sister, would you
go get the last messages
while I'm decoding this one?
The Allied high command
has decided to bypass Paris.
They're going
straight to the Rhine.
This is terrible.
As General De Gaulle's
military delegate,
you are ordered to avoid
an uprising at all costs.
But how can I possibly control
all the other groups
of resistance?
What can I say to them?
Just be patient, relax,
and one of these days
the Allies will show up?
We must convince
the Allies to help us.
Amicol, do you think
with a bit of pressure
from intelligence service
they might change their plans?
My friend, all I'm supposed
to do is to get information.
And I do, believe me.
The decision
is part of strategy.
They must save
all of their fuel
to push their way to the Rhine
and before Hitler
can regroup his troops.
There's only one solution.
I have to go to London.
Then in your absence I will do
everything that is in my power
to avoid an uprising.
You can't prevent it
without any help.
Bernard Labe.
Only he can help us now.
Would you please do me a favor
and get me a cup of coffee
before I collapse?
I'm afraid you'll have
to collapse.
With the new commander,
no more coffee breaks.
It's all work and no play.
Austerity till victory.
Just on the front.
Let's not exaggerate.
Reporting for duty,
Herr General.
You are seven minutes late
this morning.
I'm sorry, Herr General.
Issue a proclamation
to the population
of the city of Paris.
Print it immediately.
Should any civilians shoot
at a single German soldier,
the entire block
in which the shot was fired
will be razed to the ground.
Do you have such a good memory
you don't need to write down
what I'm saying?
Yes, Herr General.
I mean, no...
I mean, no, Herr General.
Number two...
issue an order to disarm
the entire city.
Number three...
I want a plan
for the destruction
of important strategic points
in case we're forced
to fight in the city.
To ensure our defense.
Number four...
a plan to destroy
the entire city
in case we're forced to withdraw
and retreat to the Rhine.
Destroy the entire city?
Ja.
Any objections?
But is Paris of any
strategic importance?
Is there any point
in turning the city
into a heap of rubble?
Cable Berlin...
ask for the arrival date
of Captain von Ebernach
and his demolition squad.
Also the arrival date of Karl.
"Also arrival date of Karl. "
What is his last name, sir?
Hmm?
Oh, ja.
Here, look at this.
That's Karl there.
No, not this one.
Here, look.
A giant mortar.
A beautiful toy.
When old Karl spits out a shell,
a city block is erased.
You see that man?
Gives you an idea of the scale.
Ja?
You have lovely children,
Herr General.
Ja.
When you're finished,
report back to me.
Ja wohl, Herr General.
Tomorrow morning, the Gestapo
will transfer Bernard
to Fresnes.
He'll only stay there
two or three days.
Oh, if I'd only known.
Do you realize it was
the morning the Gestapo
arrested Bernard
that I found out
he worked for the Resistance?
He never knew I was
working for them, too.
Each of us kept it a secret.
You might as well
tell me the truth.
Were his responsibilities
important?
His district
covered all of Paris.
More than that,
he had respect and admiration
of the entire Resistance.
Now there's talk
of insurrection,
and your husband
is one of the few men who
can influence Colonel Rol,
persuade him to wait.
Bernard is very important to us.
Then... you've got a plan?
Can you get Bernard out?
I have to go away
on a mission.
I'm afraid you have
to do it without me.
How? Tell me.
Go see Nordling,
the Consul General of Sweden.
He's already negotiated
for several prisoners.
The cost is high, 20 Germans
for every Frenchman,
but it's our only hope.
Nordling.
I'll go see him.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
See you after your dance class.
Pardon.
And where are you going, Madame?
I must see Consul Nordling
right away, sir.
No, that's impossible.
I'm sorry.
- It's very urgent.
- Can you come back?
It's important.
I've got to see him.
Have you an appointment,
Madame?
It's a matter
of life and death.
No, no.
Well, I'm very sorry,
but I must ask...
It'll only take a few minutes.
Now, I promise.
Please let me see him.
What's going on here?
Herr Consul Nordling,
my name is...
She's trying
to force her way in.
What can I do for you, Madame?
Oh, Mr. Nordling, I'm
terribly sorry to disturb you,
but my husband is
in the prison at Fresnes.
Madame, there are 2,980
political prisoners in Fresnes.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Oh, but Bernard is a
very important leader
in the Resistance.
Bernard Labe.
His work is important.
Bernard.
Bernard Labe.
Races horses,
has the lovely place
in the country?
Yes.
I've been there.
Madame Labe,
you-you don't remember me.
I came with a large company.
You were very charming.
I... I particularly
remember the lunch.
There was a marvelous mousse.
Mr. Nordling, you're speaking
of another century.
Oh, please, what can I do?
Well, the Germans, so far,
have refused
to exchange political prisoners.
However,
there's a new commander,
and it's... just possible.
Oh, will you see him?
Can you see him?
I...
I will give anything.
Money, anything.
Trout.
What?
It was a mousse of trout.
That day at the lunch.
- Oh.
- Come on.
Where are they being sent?
Across the Rhine.
Buchenwald.
Oh, Buchenwald,
oh, Buchenwald.
They're sending
the French prisoners
to Germany, and we stay here.
Why the easy way
when they can make things hard?
Papers, please.
These are the plans
for destroying
the most important factories.
Herr General,
the Swedish
Consul Nordling is here.
He wishes to see you
immediately.
No, I can't now.
I gave specific orders
that my conference
with Captain Ebernach
was not to be interrupted.
Consul Nordling insists
it's very urgent.
He'll have to wait.
Ja wohl, Herr General.
Are these the plans
of the factories?
Ja wohl. Over 200,
Herr General.
The bridges. 48.
The electrical works.
The reservoirs.
The gas works.
In five minutes, the entire
city's totally destroyed.
How long will it take your men
to place the explosives?
48 hours.
Good.
Herr General,
are we also supposed
to destroy
the historical monuments?
The Notre Dame?
The Louvre?
Everything.
But not before
you receive my personal order.
Ja wohl,
Herr General.
This is the greatest
assignment
the Fuhrer has ever
entrusted to me.
To destroy an entire city.
Well...
we've had enough practice,
haven't we?
Ja wohl, Herr General,
but never on such a scale.
You're right.
With Paris, the eyes
of the world will be upon us.
But don't forget, huh?
You are not
to begin any demolition
without receiving written orders
from me.
I understand, Herr General.
That will be all.
A beautiful city, Herr General.
Ja.
I suppose so.
But we are soldiers,
not tourists.
Send in the Swedish Consul.
Ja wohl, Herr General.
- Herr Consul.
- General.
What can I do for you?
General...
it is my desire
that the prisoners
camps be conducted
according
to the Geneva Convention.
In order that we may
avoid such massacres
as have already
occurred in Cannes
and Fresnes.
That's a political concern,
not military.
What happened?
I have a signature.
You do?
I can't believe it.
We have a chance.
Hotel Majestic.
- Oh...
- The prisoners...
Oh, that's marvelous.
...may be turned over
to the Red Cross
if I can get a countersignature
from the military governor.
51 is the first bus.
47 is the second bus.
49 is the third bus.
64 is the fourth bus.
Very well.
We shall hold
the remaining prisoners
until the Red Cross arrives
to take them into custody.
Thank you, Major.
Excuse me, I-I wonder,
do you happen to have
a bit of brandy?
I'm feeling... rather faint.
It must be the heat.
I'm sorry, Consul General.
I do not drink spirits.
But here's some water.
Water's far better
for your system
than fermented grain.
I couldn't agree with you more.
Major...
I believe that some prisoners
are already
at the railroad station
preparing to leave.
Ja.
2,45", to be exact.
Isn't that a list?
There must be some way
to stop them.
They are no longer
under my jurisdiction.
Once we deposit
them at the station,
they belong to the SS.
We don't have trains
to repatriate
our own wounded home.
And these SS pigs find them
to transport prisoners.
There must be some way
of releasing these prisoners.
From the SS?
Well...
I suppose you can always try.
I have my orders,
which I have conveyed
to your group leader.
I advise you to listen to him.
Very attentively.
To avoid any misunderstandings.
Is that clear?
Uh, group leader.
Group leader!
Tell your men what
they can expect.
They say that
we'll all be executed
if anybody escapes.
So there's no use
trying to run away.
They'll catch you,
and shoot the rest of us.
Papers?
I want to see the Kommandant.
The Kommandant?
Let him pass.
Herr Kommandant.
I have an order from the...
Inside.
Inside!
For God's sake, will you stop
waving your damn papers
in front of my nose?
I don't care in the least
what's stamped on it.
Herr Kommandant...
I have orders
to send these pigs to Germany.
This has been signed...
Bernard!
I've got the papers!
You are free!
Bernard!
Bernard, I've got the papers!
You are free!
Bernard!
- By general...
- General who?!
General this, General that,
General here, General there...
General damn! Since they
tried to kill the Fuhrer,
I don't care about
generals anymore.
They're all traitors.
What are you doing here?
How did you get past
the roadblock?
What is this?
What's going on?
Why can't you keep any order?
Who is that woman?!
Herr Kommandant,
she is under my protection.
- Swedish?
- No, but...
Then get her out of there!
Bernard!
Bernard, you are free!
No! No!
Bernard!
Bernard, no!
No! No! No!
No, Bernard, no!
No!
Bernard!
The Germans have disarmed
the police stations
at Saint-Denis and Duniere.
As a protest, the entire
police force has gone off duty,
but the Commissioner of Police
ordered them back
to their posts.
Will they obey the order?
No. No.
I can't give any
orders to the police,
but our operation would
certainly be much easier...
if the police
were to stay on strike.
Yes?
It fits in with our plans.
The Resistance units
of the police
will decide tonight
when they meet
with the other sections.
I'll be at the meeting.
I'll talk to them.
The leader of the
student Resistance
was contacted by an
agent called Serge.
He said he could get them
rifles and ammunition.
How was the student contacted?
By one of his friends.
Says he works
for intelligence service.
A favorite trick of the Gestapo.
It's out of the question.
All arms and ammunition
must come through us.
Yes, but when?
Very soon.
A little patience.
What did Rol say?
We have to cancel it.
It's too risky.
But that's crazy.
I know Captain Serge.
He can be trusted.
No. It's no.
Oh, but I swear,
he told me that...
- It's no use, Paul.
- He promised!
It's no use, Paul.
Colonel Rol says no.
But when are we going
to fight back?
Very soon, very soon.
Just be patient.
You come for the ammunition?
I'm Captain Serge.
We were sent here by Francois.
Good work.
You're the first ones.
It's all right; it's Serge.
Cigarette?
Thanks.
- Cigarette?
- Thanks.
Cigarette?
Oh, merci.
Thanks.
Oh, there they are.
They're friends of ours,
from the same street.
I'm Captain Serge.
I'm Diane, Catholic Youth Party.
Young Communists.
Here's our driver.
- Hello.
Listen,
it's ridiculous,
all of us meeting
in the middle of the street.
A perfect way to get caught.
Come on, let's go.
The ammunition is in a garage.
Why don't you follow me?
Yes, all right.
Hey, what
are you waiting here for?
Hurry, let's go.
Have you got the merchandise?
I've got a big surprise
for you, Konrad.
There are at least "0.
How's that?
Bravo.
Don't move.
All of you stay in the truck.
Hands up!
Nobody move!
All right, boys, game's over.
Get into position.
The rest of you, back.
Get them out.
Out!
Aah! No! No! No!
No, no, no!
Not me, not me!
Aah!
Come on, get out!
They killed all of them?
All of them,
and no trace of this Serge.
Apparently a Frenchman
working for the Gestapo.
I tried to warn them.
The poor kids.
And the strike?
How about the police?
It's done.
They've voted.
Good. And now
it's up to us.
Next time, it will be
more than posters.
Over there.
Tear them down.
All of them.
Damn French swine.
Any news of Chaban?
The only thing I know is
that he's left London.
Will the Allies head for Paris?
I know as much as you do.
Pierreflot, you are late.
I am sorry.
They are all over town.
"Paris fights back. "
Hmm, Colonel Rol's been busy,
hasn't he?
Mm-hmm.
Apparently,
the liberation has begun.
We should have acted first.
Look here, you represent
General de Gaulle in Paris.
What do we do now?
We don't have very much choice,
do we?
You sent for me?
What is the latest report?
We have received word
from Chabon.
He has returned to Paris.
Chabon's returned.
I must see him before curfew.
We'll call a meeting of the
National Committee tomorrow.
We must move against
the Germans before Rol.
We must take the
prefecture of police.
It's the nerve center of Paris.
Between now and tomorrow?
The list!
Claire.
Yes?
Mademoiselle, please
take this list of names
to the mailbox.
The section heads
will have all night
to notify their agents.
Yes.
May I help you, mademoiselle?
Oh, la, la.
Don't bother.
But curfew is starting
in a few minutes.
Permit me.
Ah.
It's not, it's not
working so well.
I think it's broken.
I'm sorry.
I have to go home now.
In that case, permit me
to take you in my car.
Why, it's very nice of you
to help me.
Oh, you simply have no idea
how helpful you really are.
Where were you?
What are you doing in uniform?
Well, I saw a circular saying
that we should go back to work.
But that's a lie.
The National
Liberation Committee
announced they'd dismiss
any policeman
who puts on his uniform.
Look at us,
we're not in uniform.
The orders are to go
to the prefecture
But that means they're
trying to divide us.
Let them try.
Well, you mustn't come here,
Monsieur Labe.
Things might get dangerous.
That's just the point.
I thought that you might
need a chaplain.
Yves Bayet, all your
instructions arrived last night.
Everything's working out
as we planned.
That's fine. Perfect.
Can I talk to you a minute?
Yes, I'll see you later.
Say, do you think that...
Quiet.
Quiet!
In the name of the Republic,
and of General De Gaulle,
I'm taking possession
of the prefecture of police.
I never gave orders
to take the prefecture.
Looks like somebody else
gave the order for you.
Tell our men to go into
action immediately.
I'll see what's happening.
Mama!
Take a look down there.
Oh, thank God it's all over.
Jean-Pierre Guillom,
do you take Lillian Ceverat
for your lawful wedded wife?
I do.
Lillian Ceverat, do you
take Jean-Pierre Guillom
for your lawful wedded husband?
I do.
Then it is with great pleasure
that I pro...
Take off that sash, monsieur.
You're no longer mayor.
Then we can't be married?
The ceremony will continue.
Congratulations
and best wishes to you both.
Monsieur Luizet, in compliance
with instructions
from General De Gaulle,
I'm handing over the prefecture.
- Bayet.
- Yes?
It's Joliot Curie.
You mean... ah.
Ah, excuse me, uh...
Joliot Curie.
Bayet.
Delighted.
Take me to the wine cellar,
please.
- The wine?
- That's right.
Go and show the professor
the wine cellar.
It's across the courtyard.
Thank you, monsieur.
Don't mention it.
Empty all the wine bottles
in the cellar.
Careful.
Easy with the suitcases.
They've got acid in them.
We'll make beautiful
Molotov cocktails.
Even the chateau margot
and the champagne?
Yes, except the magnums,
they're too big.
The gasoline,
the gasoline, hurry.
Attention.
This is Colonel Rol talking.
I have a message.
As chief of the F.F.I.
for the region of Paris,
I want to congratulate you all.
Thanks to you, the Germans
are on the defensive.
That's just the beginning.
But there are far
too many of you here.
All of you, except "00, go back
to your district headquarters.
We will give you further
instructions in due time.
The essential thing is,
the Nazis see us all over Paris.
All right, go on.
I see Colonel Rol's found us.
Well, what counts is that
we made the first move.
From now on, we are all
in the same boat.
We are off to a good start.
The courthouses are occupied,
at least 80%.
That's good work.
Now I'm going to check up
on the police stations.
Colonel Rol, I have ten men,
what shall we do?
Take a position
on the riverbank.
But I have no rifles.
Well, go back to bed.
Don't shoot.
Wait till he gets closer.
Quick, the ammunition.
The rifles.
One for me.
Come on.
Here.
Quick.
Go on.
Well, what do we do with them?
Put them in the cellar.
I'm very sorry.
They didn't tell me we weren't
allowed to drive across Paris.
You French, I'll kill you all!
I'll kill every one of you!
French pigs.
Take me to the Hotel Meurice!
Hotel Meurice!
What's wrong?
What's wrong? What's wrong?
What are you waiting for?!
My men are being burnt alive!
Come.
Have three tanks lined up
in front of the prefecture
right away.
And keep firing at it
until every one
of them surrenders.
What's more, alert the Luftwaffe
at Le Bourget.
We'll need their support.
That will be all.
No. Stay here.
No, let me go.
Listen to me.
Come back.
Monique!
Watch out!
They're going to shoot at us.
Here come the tanks.
Tanks?
- Here come the tanks.
- Where are they?
On Quai St. Michel.
They're encircling us.
They sent a couple of shots
through the windows.
Three men were killed.
Quick! Did you get
the code through?
- Yes.
- Hurry, Mademoiselle.
- Get down.
- Watch out!
Open up!
It's the Red Cross!
Open the door!
Damn it!
Just when I was going
to get my phone call.
The German...
Hello. German tanks are firing
on the prefecture.
Hello.
Hello? We must have
reinforcements.
Send every man who's available.
At Ile de...
Hello? Hello? Hello?
At Ile de la Cite.
You must...
you must attack the enemy
from behind.
Hello?
Hello? Can you hear me?
Hello? H... Hello?
What did you...
Hello. What?
There's another call.
I'm sorry. Quickly.
He's wounded.
- Hurry! Hurry!
- Badly.
It's the Mayor of Paris,
but he's wounded.
- Hello, hello.
- He's been hit.
Germans attacking.
Send reinforcements.
Hello? Yes.
Oh, quickly, quickly.
A doctor before he dies!
Diane.
What are you doing?
Don't you see he's dead?
What do you expect us
to fight with?
Pen knives?
We've called all over town
for ammunition.
They want us to give
up the prefecture.
But that's impossible.
Physically and morally.
Absolutely impossible.
Now that we're here,
we're staying.
Quick, hurry up!
So, that's the thanks I get
for freeing those
political prisoners.
And now that rebel at the
prefecture wants a cease-fire.
Ha!
Never.
We exterminate all of them!
I promise you that by tomorrow
they'll be no prefecture,
no cease-fire, no palace.
We leave that
to the Luftwaffe.
And if a bomb should miss?
A few bombs always miss,
but others will hit the target.
It's the law of averages.
A bomb that misses...
could hit...
Notre Dame.
Ste. Chapelle.
That's a thousand years
of history
turned to dust.
You're not the first one
to tell me that.
Yesterday morning,
the Mayor of Paris was here,
Monsieur Titinger.
Titinger?
And he said the same thing.
But what can I do?
I am a soldier,
and I must obey the orders
I was given by the Fuhrer.
General...
your enemy...
is the Allied Army,
not the people of Paris.
What you really care about
is the defense of the city.
Hmm? Am I right?
Arrange for a cease-fire,
and you'll have time
to prepare that defense.
Report from the prefecture.
Our men are losing ground.
How's it going in Noilly?
Heavier resistance
than we expected.
Order the Luftwaffe into action
over Paris.
Herr General, the Allies
have air superiority.
If we try daylight bombing,
we'll lose the last planes
that we've got left.
Then attack tomorrow morning
before dawn.
The divisions from Denmark...
have we had any word of them?
No, and I'm doubtful
that we'll ever get them.
Then...
You, you will accept
a cease-fire?
I must hold the bridges,
and time is running out.
With a cease-fire,
I could gain time.
But you do the negotiating.
I don't want to be involved
with it, understand?
Of course.
But if those people
dare to shoot
at even one of my men...!
Don't worry, General.
History will be grateful
to you...
for having saved a...
very beautiful city.
Hello.
Susan?
Yes.
I'm fine.
I wanted to hear your voice.
Yes.
The children, how are they?
Give them a kiss.
Of course I do.
Don't worry, I will.
Yes.
No, no, don't worry.
No, please.
I don't even have any bullets...
We won! They're pulling out!
They're running away!
No, don't, please.
You mustn't.
Cease fire.
A cease-fire
has just been concluded
with the German Commander
of Paris.
The National Committee
of Resistance
issued an appeal
to all citizens of the Republic
not to engage
in any further reprisals
or demonstrations of any kind.
In exchange,
the German occupation forces
agree not to attack
public buildings
now in the hands
of the Resistance.
Furthermore, they agree to treat
all French prisoners
according to the laws of war
in the Geneva Convention.
Cease fire!
A cease-fire
has just been concluded
with the German Commander
of Paris.
How do you like that?
What's going on?
Those double-crossers
used my name
to order a cease-fire.
Now that the Germans
are running,
we're not going to quit.
I'm afraid we'll have to quit...
no ammunition.
We'll find some.
Thanks to the cease-fire...
Thanks to the cease-fire
we have already won,
first of all,
official recognition
of this committee
and of our forces in Paris.
Furthermore,
we can avoid certain defeat,
a crucial point.
You know perfectly well
the prefecture
would have been taken
in an hour at most.
- And you know why, too.
- Yes.
Where was the ammunition?
Our delegation has demanded
time and time again
that the Allies give us arms
and launch a spearhead on Paris.
We haven't received an answer.
I met General Patton myself.
He didn't say it
in so many words,
but it's clear that the Allies
intend to capture Paris
by encirclement.
It is up to us
to remain where we are.
There's no choice.
We must keep
the gentleman's agreement
we made with Choltitz.
Choltitz.
With Choltitz, gentleman.
That's right. Choltitz.
I'm only concerned with saving
the lives of our men and
avoiding unnecessary killing.
For us, it's only a matter
of deferring all combat
until such time
as the balance of forces
swings in favor
of the Resistance.
I see.
We sit on our behinds
until the arrival of the Allies.
That is treachery!
It is you who are traitors!
It is impossible
to discuss anything seriously
under these conditions.
I'm leaving!
I propose we put it to a vote.
Raise your hands
if you're voting
in favor of a cease-fire.
All those who oppose it?
The cease-fire
is rejected by one vote.
I will abide by the decision
of the majority,
but for tactical reasons,
I must request that our decision
to resume fighting
not be announced
before tomorrow, ":00.
Halt!
We must put on
a show for them
so act with authority.
Leave it to me.
Get out!
Hands up!
We are representatives
of the Resistance.
A cease-fire was concluded
with the General
in command of Paris
through the intervention
of the consul of Sweden.
We are checking to make
sure that it's respected.
We shall see.
Major, a briefcase.
Terrorists.
I'm sorry, this is serious.
Very serious.
You're obliged to respect
the conditions of the truce.
You have to liberate us.
Go on, get in.
Quickly, get in.
They could be telling the truth,
but I can't afford
any more trouble.
I think I'd better check up.
I'm turning this over
to the Gestapo.
I'll take the women in my car
and you the men in yours.
Yes, sir.
Go on! Both of you.
I decided the only thing
to do was to execute them,
but then I thought you might
want to speak to them.
Gentlemen.
I suppose you know
the Swedish Consul,
Herr Nordling.
Thanks to his efforts,
we arranged a truce
which, up to now, has cost the
lives of 200 German soldiers.
As a representative
of General De Gaulle's
provisional government,
I protest!
Against our arrest
in the midst of the cease-fire.
We are just
contacting our people
to make sure they respected it.
In your car, my guards
discovered a proclamation
that was designed to provoke
the city of Paris to revolt.
I don't see how you maintain
you're respecting the cease-fire
and then make
vicious attacks on our men
right in front of our faces!
I'm a member of the French
Government in Exile
and I won't permit you to
question my word of honor!
The circular in the car
was a proclamation
that had been revoked.
In that case, why did your men
shoot at our soldiers?
You command an army of regulars.
When you give an order,
your men obey it.
The Resistance is
an alliance of many movements,
and I don't
control them all.
The Communists, for example?
Our ranks include both
Communists and anti-Communists.
Now we're all battling
against a common enemy.
You can make among yourselves
all the politics that you want!
Only you must not shoot
at my soldiers!
If you would like
to finish these incidents,
stop sending out your patrols.
Herr Consul...
since these men
were taken prisoner
after the cease-fire
went into effect,
I place them in your custody.
Thank you, General.
Are you an officer?
Officer in the Reserves.
Well, then...
Get these men out of here
before I change my mind.
Careful.
Well...
now we're going underground
and I mean literally.
We've taken most of
the police stations
and post offices.
Good, but remember,
no matter what
as long as the Germans
are in Paris,
the orders are
to keep fighting.
It's right through here.
We'd better hurry.
He'll be calling any minute.
Hey, Maurice.
Here, German sweaters,
underwear.
Ah! It's about time.
We're freezing here.
Take one.
Here, give this to Jean.
It's time.
Ja. Ja.
Everything's in order.
Heil Hitler!
What's going on?
The German watchman.
Every day for the last two years
he's called
to make sure everything's
all right in the sewers.
Hello? Hello?
This is the main sewer station,
Place de la Concorde.
A Nazi tank is still patrolling.
Nothing else to report.
Everything's all right.
Somehow, we've got
to make contact
with the Allied Command.
I thought you
were sending Veret.
He was killed.
He didn't even reach the front.
That makes six men we have lost.
And so we'll have
to send out a seventh.
Maurice, you know the region?
I- I'm from Marseilles.
You know Normandy?
I've been there on vacation,
but I can't say I know it
very well.
That leaves it up to you,
I guess.
Will you do it?
Of course.
Dr. Monod has a car,
a safe-conduct, everything.
He told me that
you might get through
by pretending
you're going to inspect
the hospitals in Normandy.
Sounds good.
Good.
but after you've
contacted the Americans...
If I contact them.
Good morning.
These are your papers.
You're assisting me.
I'll let you drive the car.
Uh, tell me,
know any medical terms?
No, nothing much.
Well, I'll have an intern
at the hospital at Versailles
come along with us.
It will help.
A good motor.
Ah. Old Marcie gave me
a real gasoline.
- For you.
- Yes, who is it?
It's a man.
I can't hear him.
Hello. Yes? Yes?
It's Mantes! Yes!
The Americans are in Mantes!
Listen.
Y- You can hear tanks.
Listen!
Here, listen!
I can't believe it!
Hospital attendant.
There, you see?
Und he?
He's been assigned to us.
Why, yes, he's my assistant.
We're going to visit
one of my patients
at the sanitarium
in Neufchateau.
The doctor and his assistant
have an emergency call,
and they'd like to go
to Neufchateau by car.
Hey, what's going on
over there?
Turn everybody back.
The curfew begins in "0 minutes.
Go on!
I'll have every one of you shot!
Halt!
Turn around!
What are you doing here today,
Monsieur Cocteau?
Good evening, monsieur.
It's nearly curfew.
Matter of fact,
we've come to see you.
Oh, fine.
It's a pleasure.
Is it all right?
Of course. Certainly.
I'll open the gate.
Follow me.
So, that's your real name?
I hope you gentlemen
will be comfortable.
Good night.
Thank you, monsieur.
According to the farm boy,
it's only 11 kilometers
to the front.
He's willing to show me the way.
It's safer to go at night.
You mean you trust a farm boy
you never saw before?
Why, you won't even make
two kilometers in this rain,
and with those shoes.
What if you meet
a German patrol?
You can't say
you are on your way
to give a sick cow
some medicine.
Listen, my friend.
To me, it's madness
to ask the Allies
to parachute arms
into a city like Paris.
You realize... guns dropping
all over the roofs,
in the streets?
You know very well they might
fall into anybody's hands.
But after all, it's my mission.
Well, instead
of asking for weapons,
say they should push
immediately for Paris.
Impossible. My orders are...
Well, then,
if that doesn't work,
you must try and speak
to Leclerc, all alone.
Why, returning to Paris...
it's been his dream
for four years.
Ooh.
I shouldn't have eaten
those pig's feet.
To think I'm a doctor.
They always
give me heartburn.
You'll never make it,
believe me.
The woods are crawling with SS.
The roads are all blocked
for ten kilometers.
What do we do now?
The morning's wasted,
and we still can't
get around the Germans.
Come on.
Major Georges.
Of course, that's it. Why not?
He's the head of the Resistance
in Corbeil.
Hurry.
No, no, give me the
ration ticket tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
Here, Pierre.
Take your bread.
There. Good-bye.
Good-bye.
Thank you very much.
The Americans are
at edge of the woods.
Then it's all right.
Good.
Well, I'll leave you here.
I must return to the hospital
as soon as possible.
And the Germans?
The Germans?
At the other end of the village.
They've occupied a farm
with guns behind
each stack of hay.
Believe me, with them
you mustn't use tricks.
You must show force.
It's the only method.
Let's go.
Is he the one?
Yes, it's him.
He wants to go over
to see the Americans.
Well, we can try.
Seymour!
Watch the store.
I use them because
of their uniforms.
The Germans have respect
for uniforms.
Conditioned reflex.
I'll let you know
when I get back.
I'm going, too.
You need support.
Go on.
Albert...
Yes or no?
Watch out for the machine guns.
Ready?
Ready.
Stop!
This is a good spot.
All right.
Hey, go on.
The Americans
are across the field.
Well, good luck.
Thanks.
Get going.
Let him go.
If we shoot him, we'll give away
our position to the Americans.
Hey...
where did you come from?
I come from Paris
with a message
for General Eisenhower.
Here's the new call to arms.
Fine.
Where did you find
that tin hat?
I stole it from
a German sergeant
while he was taking a nap.
You should've picked
one that fit you.
Hey, why don't you bring
a pillow along, too?
Here are the bullets.
Take them over to Colette.
I stole them from the bakery.
They had plenty.
We start out of Deburre,
fly over Paris,
back to the airfield,
then start over again.
Herr General Field Marshal.
Please leave us alone
for a minute.
It is quite clear that
you are no longer able
to keep order in the city.
And we've also learned
that you've negotiated
with the terrorists.
Herr General Field Marshal...
It's not your business
to meddle in politics.
Why did you make the panzers
leave their post
at the prefecture?
I thought it more efficient
to attack with the Luftwaffe.
Then please explain why
you didn't use the Luftwaffe?
Because of the superior
air strength of the Allies.
I discussed it with Major Hegel
of the Luftwaffe...
I warn you,
you must restore order
by any method, however drastic.
Ja wohl,
Herr General Field Marshal.
If you don't follow my orders
you know what
the consequences are.
Ja wohl,
Herr General Field Marshal.
Heil Hitler.
Hell Hitler.
General Field Marshall Model.
Draw up a plan
for the bombing of Paris.
Okay. Major Gallois.
I've been sent by Colonel Rol,
the head of the
French Resistance for Paris,
to tell you that we have
seized half of the city.
And now we want you to...
You want what? Hmm?
We want you to help us.
The situation is this:
we hold all
the official buildings.
After one day's truce,
fighting has started again,
but we are short
of arms and ammunition.
The Germans will find out
sooner or later,
and when they do,
their reaction may be terrible.
Especially if they receive
reinforcements
from the east, as we are told.
They may destroy Paris.
So we ask you
to send us one unit
to liberate the city
immediately.
You're a soldier,
I'm a soldier,
I'll give you
a soldier's answer.
First, we're not in the business
of liberating cities,
not even capitals.
Our business is to destroy
the German army.
We can end this war
in three months
if we keep moving fast.
Second, Major Gallois,
don't you think
that I would like
to help you people?
Can't you see what my
position is right now?
Third, we can't change plans
that have been
scheduled for months.
Final victory depends upon it.
Our plans don't include
feeding four million
Parisians, hmm?
I'm sorry, Major, it's no dice.
I'll report our conversation
to my superiors in Paris.
Sit down.
Orderly!
Yes, sir?
Open up a bottle of champagne.
- Champagne.
- Yes, sir.
Are you tired?
No, sir.
May I ask you a...
a personal favor?
What is it?
I want to talk to a French
officer, General Leclerc.
Mmm. Leclerc?
That impatient lion.
You mind traveling all night?
Of course not.
Good.
Here's one for the road.
Akerns?
Yes, sir.
Get a jeep and a driver
for this man and see
that he gets to Laval.
He needs to see General Leclerc.
Thank you, sir.
You got a long trip
ahead of you.
Half the brass in Europe
is at Laval, you know?
Hello? Hello?
General Bradley, please.
Good trip, huh?
Brad?
What the hell's happening
in Paris?
Colonel Lebel, Major Gallois.
Colonel Lebel,
General de Gaulle's liaison,
assigned to General Bradley.
General Patton telephoned
to say you were en route.
Who?
General Patton.
You saw him at the front.
That was General Patton?
Yes.
General Leclerc is not here
but, um, I...
I told the Americans
you were coming,
and they are very anxious
to see you.
In fact, General Sibert
will interrupt a staff meeting
to hear your report.
This is our last chance
to convince the Allies
that they must go on
straight to Paris.
It's up to you now.
Yes.
We're listening, Major.
The Resistance
and the people of Paris
now control most of the city.
We wanted to welcome you
to a liberated Paris.
But we cannot hold out
indefinitely.
We need your help.
The Germans have
no organized units
between your advanced
lines and Paris.
From the military point of view,
it would be a-a mistake,
almost a crime,
if you didn't take advantage
of such a favorable situation.
It... it is only a question
of time, gentlemen.
The Germans will counterattack,
and they have precise orders
to destroy Paris.
Hundreds of thousands
of Parisians
will be... slaughtered.
The French people
will never forgive the Allies
for not coming to their aid.
Never.
You're very eloquent.
As a matter of fact,
what you told us
is exactly what
General de Gaulle's
been telling Eisenhower.
I'm contacting Bradley
immediately.
You must send us a unit a once.
You can tell General Leclerc
that I may have
some news for him.
Leclerc? Is he here?
Yes, he arrives in a few hours.
Anyway, congratulations.
I think you made
a good impression.
Come on,
let's get something to eat.
You must be hungry, eh?
Please.
Here we can talk quietly.
Have a seat.
Your cease-fire
didn't work out as you planned.
The situation
is worse than before.
The Allies have crossed
the Seine near Mantes,
so if our information
is correct,
they'll encircle Paris shortly.
Then I must take
drastic measures
and begin the demolition
of the city.
Really mean to destroy the city?
If that cease-fire of yours
had worked out...
We did our best.
Nobody can control
the Resistance now.
If de Gaulle were here...
Why doesn't anybody
get in touch with him
and ask his help?
With de Gaulle?
It's the only way Paris
will ever be safe
from destruction.
The Resistance is going
to force my hand otherwise.
This is the final order
Hitler gave me.
Destroy the entire city
of Paris.
Herr Consul, do what you can.
I've issued this for you:
a pass that will get you safely
through the German lines.
Why are you doing this?
Herr Consul, if I thought
that the destruction of Paris
could win the war for Germany,
I would set the city
on fire myself.
But...
...we've lost the war.
Then...
why has Hitler ordered
the destruction of Paris?
Because he's insane.
I know it.
I saw him in Rastenburg.
There are two SS officers
waiting for you.
Did you find anything?
No, Herr General.
Force of habit.
Well?
It concerns a mission
that's rather delicate.
Well, isn't that
the specialty of the SS?
Delicate missions?
Vice Minister Himmler
has recently learned
that the Louvre
has a very valuable tapestry.
A what?!
A tapestry.
It's, uh...
it's called the, uh...
...the Bayeux Tapestry.
11th Century.
It shows the Norman
invasion of England.
The Vice Minister
would like us to bring it
as a gift for the Fuhrer.
Huh.
Instead of the real invasion
of England.
I don't find that
so amusing, Herr General.
Well, gentlemen,
you can have the tapestry.
We were certain we could
count on you, Herr General.
Only the Louvre is in the hands
of the Resistance.
But the Louvre
is just over there.
Ja. The only question is,
will it still be there when
we get through blasting it?
But why don't you try
to bargain with the French?
Go with a white flag
in your hand.
You never know. They could
give it to you as a present.
Gentlemen, good day.
Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler!
We represent the ministers
of the Provisional government.
The cease-fire
has at least permitted us
to occupy the buildings.
But we must make
one more step
toward installing
the new government
by holding a meeting
of the new cabinet.
Let's say, at 6:00.
Right.
Then we'll have to
take the Maintenon.
Pierrelot will
take care of that.
The Maintenon?
Maintenon Palace.
Ah.
Traditionally, that's where
all cabinet meetings
take place.
I don't think there are
any Germans there,
but I understand that
a group of collaborators
are still occupying
the building.
Do you think they'll try
to keep us out?
We know that some of
them are against us.
You never can tell.
Take "0 men along with you.
That should do it.
"0 men, huh?
Well, I guess
I better get going.
Claire, start telephoning.
All right.
Gentlemen, see you at 6:00
for the cabinet meeting.
At the Maintenon.
Where else?
Hello? Is Marcelle in?
He's not there?
- Well?
- Nobody can go with you.
Did you reach Maurice?
He can't leave the office.
The Germans are guarding
the street.
And Joliot?
At the town hall
it's the same thing.
Well, I'll go alone.
I'll go with you.
Over there.
Go on.
Hurry.
Pardon, monsieur.
Yes?
Do you know where
the Maintenon is?
Over there, monsieur.
The Prime Minister's house?
Oh, no, no, I'm sorry,
across the Seine.
Rue de Varenne, yes.
Go on.
Rue de Varenne?
Oh, there's
a sentry box in front.
You can't miss it.
And be careful.
They're shooting everywhere.
We'll get ourselves killed.
Come.
What do we do now?
Eh...
Let's go.
What do you want?
The officer in command.
Major, there is
someone to see you.
I'm the officer in charge.
What do you want?
I have come to take
possession here
in the name of the Provisional
Government of the Republic.
Monsieur Le ministre, I've
always been for the Republic.
I place myself at your disposal.
Thank you, Major.
Detail, fall in.
You forgot to put armbands on.
Attention!
Close ranks.
Present arms.
The staff welcomes you,
Monsieur Le ministre.
Thank you.
Take me to the Council Hall.
If Monsieur Le ministre
will follow me.
Who are you?
Switchboard operator.
Go back to your switchboard.
And you?
Chief librarian, monsieur.
Return to your library.
The meeting starts
in two hours.
How many will you be,
monsieur?
Around "0.
Very well.
The Prime Minister's desk.
Ah, monsieur, I've seen
governments come and go,
but nothing like the last one.
They took
everything they could.
Even the silverware.
And here is the Council Hall.
Not bad.
Would you please provide
some pencils and erasers?
And ink and scratch pads.
In other words,
the usual preparations
for Council meetings.
Good.
And we will also need
rooms for the night.
Bedrooms.
I assume
Monsieur Le ministre
will the want the Green Room
for his personal use?
The Green Room?
It's always reserved
for the Prime Minister.
My, my.
Hmm, adequate.
Excuse me.
I know exactly how you feel,
my son.
But no emotion.
The facts.
If you don't march
immediately on Paris,
they'll destroy the entire city.
The situation is
as serious as that?
I'm afraid so.
You must begin
your drive on Paris...
tomorrow.
I should personally
like nothing better.
And I'm doing all I can
to convince headquarters,
but you can't push an
armored division around
like a wheelbarrow.
We've just fought
a battle at Argenton.
We're very far from Paris.
I could make it.
But I would have to receive
the orders today.
And if not?
If not?
We'll see what we can do.
General de Gaulle will end up
by convincing the Allies.
And now, tell me everything.
Well, where's General Bradley?
If he's not here before 7:00,
it's going to be too late.
I've got to get that order
before tonight.
Ah, here he is.
Well, I got the news
I was waiting for, Sibert.
Where is he?
You win.
The decision has been made
to go into Paris,
and the three of us
hold the responsibility
for that decision.
I, because I'm giving the order,
you, General Leclerc,
because you are going
to execute it,
and you, Major Gallois,
because you brought us
the information
that led us to that decision.
Thank you.
How do you feel, Major?
Hmm? Oh, I haven't slept
in three days.
I promise you
a full day's sleep.
But right now
I'm sending you down to G-2,
and tomorrow you can
join General Leclerc
at Ramboullier.
Rebius?
We're moving on to Paris.
Is that your son, Lieutenant?
He was two then.
And now he's four years old.
I've never seen him.
Off your behinds!
We're marching on to Paris!
I'd better
shave off my beard
before my wife sees it.
This is it.
We're going to Paris!
Dampierre!
That way, there.
Where are you going?
To Paris!
Paris?!
Well, you've still got
a long way to go.
I have an aunt who has
a restaurant in Montparnasse.
We can eat off her
for ten years.
Is that near the Bastille?
Not the Bastille.
I said Montparnasse,
peasant.
They signed off, sir.
Fine. Message finished.
Two German panzer divisions
have started out for Paris.
Call all the other units.
We must notify them.
Go on, quickly, quickly.
Orders from the General.
All units accelerate.
Where is Leclerc now?
They're moving,
they're going all out
but they're still more
than 50 kilometers away.
Mm. That's about "0 miles.
You know,
we can't run the risk
that German general
might just suddenly
change his mind
and destroy the city.
So Leclerc has quite
a job on his hands.
Tell Hodges to keep
the Fourth Division ready
just in case.
Look, the Eiffel Tower...
that's on the...
the right side of the river,
right?
The Right Bank?
The left.
Well, okay, if the Eiffel Tower
is on the left...
...that means that the Louvre
is on the right, yeah?
And the Chambre of,
what do you call it?
Of Deputes.
Now, look, will you
just knock it off
and quit bothering me?
Yeah, but you've been to Paris
and I haven't.
Boy, I never thought
in a thousand years
I'd get to see Paris.
Yeah. See Paris and die.
No, that's... that's Naples.
What do you think
happens when you die?
You go to Naples.
Funny.
Start unloading those
bazookas there, Sergeant.
We going into Paris, Lieutenant?
Yeah, we're moving out.
Oh! The telephone's working!
We can call Paris!
We can call...
Hey! The telephone's working!
We can telephone Paris.
Hey, Maurice,
the telephone's working.
You can call your house.
Madame, please.
Put a call through for me
to Elysees "-2-2-6.
It's my parents.
My mother, Madame Bovera.
Tell her I'm coming
with the Black Berets.
You've come a long way?
Yes.
Sahara.
Sahara?
Mama!
It's Mama.
It's me, Henri.
Put-put the champagne
on ice.
We're coming!
How much do I owe you?
May I?
Of course.
Hello?
C'est beau l'accuell...?
Hold on, please.
Here you are.
Hello?
Hello, it's me.
It's me!
But it's true,
I tell you, it's me!
I say it's me. Me!
Tell her your name,
it'll be quicker.
Huh?
All right, who are you?
Georges.
All right. Hello. It's Georges.
I mean, I'm not Georges.
I mean, yes, it's Georges.
I'm calling for Georges.
But he can't speak.
He's too excited.
Hey, Georges, we're leaving!
He's in Arpageon.
Tell her we're on the way.
On the way.
He's on the way.
Yes, and I give her a kiss.
He gives you a kiss.
He loves you.
I love her.
Good-bye, Madame.
Where have you come from?
From Paris.
Here are the locations
for the mines.
Uh-huh.
Fine.
Then we move
on to the next site.
One hour and it's all finished.
They're going to have
such a show of fireworks,
they'll think the whole world
is burning.
We are going home
to Berlin!
We are going home to Berlin!
We'll be back for Christmas!
Wait a minute, stop pushing.
General Leclerc
asks me to tell you
that they're on the march...
to hold fast!
Hey, believe it or not,
we're passing right
in front of my house.
I live on the corner.
Our kitchen is just
above the restaurant,
and I used to get
my cigarettes
at the shop across the way.
You know,
I said to my wife,
"I'll be back.
I'm going to get
a pack of cigarettes. "
The funny part is,
I didn't go back.
I signed up with De Gaulle.
What will you
tell your wife?
I've got the pack
of cigarettes... Camels.
All right, on your feet.
Hurry, hurry.
What is it now?
You can come out.
Oh, about time.
What's going on?
You've got work to do.
Oh, work.
Yeah.
Hurry.
It's a tank.
55 meters. Direct target.
First, they put you in jail.
Then, they want you
to defend it.
Fire. Fire.
What are you doing there, Daum?
We're joining
the regiment, sir.
That's stupid.
Yes, but those are the orders.
You should never
obey stupid orders.
Sir, they tell me
there is a clear road ahead.
Good. You're starting
immediately for Paris.
Don't worry about
the Germans. Just go.
Don't stop for anything.
Tell the Parisians we're coming.
We'll be there... tomorrow.
Very well, sir.
Go on.
Daum!
Didn't I tell you
to clean that up?
There was no time, sir.
In Paris we have
to look our best.
Hey!
Who are they?
They're Germans.
No, they are Americans.
Get away from the window.
Juliet, come inside. Juliet!
Why, they're American.
The Americans?
It's the Americans!
The Americans.
No, they're French!
Oh, they are French.
They're French!
I can't believe it!
Say, what's the shortest way
to the town hall?
It's very simple, Captain.
You take the Avenue de...
Take the Rue de la Piscine.
Thank you. Thank you.
Why are the bells
ringing like that?
Herr General...
They're announcing our funeral,
my dear Fraulein Irma.
Would you connect me
with General Spiedel?
Put a call through
to General Spiedel.
Why do you look
so surprised, all of you?
You thought a miracle
would save us, huh?
None of you seems to realize
what's happening...
in Russia, in Germany...
or even what's happening
now in Normandy.
After the past few months,
I don't think anything
could surprise me.
General Spiedel.
Good evening, Spiedel.
There is something
you should hear.
Bells?
Ja, they are ringing.
They've been silent
for four and a half years.
They're ringing to announce
the arrival of the Allies.
And now will you send me
those divisions
you promised us
almost a month ago?
Unfortunately, no.
Our reserves
are completely exhausted.
Ja, then, dear Spiedel.
I would appreciate you
doing a favor for me.
See that my family
doesn't suffer.
Thank you. Ja.
Hmm. Napoleon's tomb.
All his victories:
Marengo,
Austerlitz,
lena,
Freidland,
Wagram,
Moscow.
Moscow...
Von Choltitz here.
The Fuhrer wants to know
are you ready to proceed
with the burning of Paris?
Of course, General Jodl,
of course.
All the charges
have been placed
under the Louvre
and the Eiffel Tower.
What are you waiting for?
Why the delay?
What's holding you up?
All the demolitions are set
for the fortified bridges,
for all of the waterworks.
Then I see no reason
for you to delay any longer.
Give the order
for total destruction.
The minute that
all our occupation units
have evacuated the city.
It should've been done already!
The Fuhrer wants
the city burned now!
Is that clear?!
Do you know where my son is?
What's his name?
Maurice Bovera.
Don't know him.
Where are the Black Berets?
Over there.
Thank you.
Colonel Fabien.
We are ordered to support
your attack on the...
Careful!
Lieutenant Delafu Chartiere.
Second division.
The only way to get those Nazis
is to climb up there.
You see?
All right.
Marco, Jacques, you cover us.
- Yes, sir.
- Ready?
Lieutenant Pierre
Delafu Chartiere.
Second Armored Division.
My respects, Madame.
Oh, please, after you.
This way, please.
Oh, wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
You mustn't force it.
Careful.
They're over there,
across the street.
Better step back, Madame.
I want a man at each window.
Yes, sir.
Ooh, careful.
Prepare the grenades.
Right here.
You, you got everything ready?
Careful, my roses there.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, please, please, Madame.
Oh, don't you
worry about me.
Oh, don't worry...
Make sure they
don't see you, huh?
Jacques,
the incendiary grenades?
Ready, sir.
Good.
Marco, ready?
Ready, sir.
When I give the order,
hit them with everything.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Ready.
Go on.
Perfect.
Fire.
Cease fire.
Close it carefully, huh?
Madame, thank you
for your hospitality.
Gentlemen, would you pick up
the cartridge shells?
Very well, sir.
My respects, Madame.
Madame.
All right,
we'd better get going.
Madame.
We made it.
We're in Paris.
Yeah, we haven't made it yet.
We got to cross
that bridge first.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Excuse me.
Ecole Militaire?
Oh, right.
It's there, to the right.
To the right,
Ecole Militaire, right?
Yes.
Please.
Come on. Come on.
Hey!
We've waited
four years for you.
But America's only been
in the war for three years.
So what?
We knew you'd come.
What's wrong?
Yeah, well,
he's already got a date.
But I don't.
The Captain's looking for you.
There's a tank over there.
We've got to knock it out.
Stop.
Bombs are here. Come.
Over here.
Excuse me, sir.
Do you happen to have
any bazookas here?
Yeah, yeah.
It so happens we do.
Make it fast.
Cover me, Charlie.
I'm going off with this guy.
Okay, but watch yourself.
We're on
the Left Bank, right?
What?
Uh, the... the Left Bank.
Yeah, Boulevard San
Michele over there.
Jardin Luxembourg there.
Yeah.
Yeah, the Latin Quarter.
And, uh, that's not
a nightclub either.
That's... that's where
the students live, right?
Yeah, I'll explain later.
You see that door?
- Yeah.
- Okay, let's go.
We got it!
Yeah.
Hey, let's drink to it.
Yeah, yeah.
First bar we find?
First bar we find.
Okay.
Oh, that was a bull's-eye.
Give us whatever you've got.
Quick.
No, not this one.
Come on, have a drink.
We'll open up
a good bottle of Bordeaux.
I've never tasted wine
till we got to Normandy.
Well, do you like it?
Yeah, I like it.
Hey, I hear there's
a war going on.
Oh, come on,
give me a break, will ya?
You know,
this is exactly the way
I thought Paris would be...
a little place like this,
checkered tablecloths...
red wine.
Come on, Grandpa,
you've done your share.
Pardon.
Yes, come back tomorrow.
Hey! Psst! Psst!
Get back inside, for God's sake!
You'll get yourselves killed!
Get back!
They're coming nearer!
Get ready to fire!
"00 meters!
Don't stay together!
Francoise! Francoise!
Get over here!
Hurry!
Go get that machine gun!
What are you waiting for!
What's wrong?
It's jammed.
One of the tanks got the panzer.
All right! Let's go!
Good luck to you, Corporal.
I'll be glad to get back
to my wife.
She's been waiting six years.
We all have families.
A panzer!
Near the obelisk!
Fire!
Got it! With the smoke shell!
He's going to shoot at us!
No time to reload!
Ram him! Ram him!
A panzer.
Our first in Paris.
Ah, those cowards.
They ran away.
All right, all right. Let's go.
Let's go.
Come on!
Let's go. Back up.
That's right.
We made it at last.
There it is.
Now all we have to do
is get inside.
That's not going
to be so easy,
Lieutenant.
Well, someone's
got to do it.
All right, men, let's go.
Joliot, you and your men
guard the entrance.
The others, Gully, Herman,
come with me. Inside.
Do we shoot?
Why else are we here?
For a picnic?!
Back, everyone!
A grenade. Quick!
In the interest of saving lives
and after a token resistance
to preserve our honor,
I'll surrender the city.
I remain, Herr Consul Nordling,
gratefully yours...
And so on and so forth.
And see that
all this is packed.
We're about to be
prisoners of war.
That's if we're lucky.
That'll give me
a chance to read
War and Peace at last.
Colonel, I would like
to thank you, too.
Get out, all of you, one by one,
with your hands up.
All of you,
take care of them.
Where's the General?
Herman.
So, Colonel,
where's the General?
Who? The General?
- Yes.
- He's upstairs.
Will he surrender?
He will surrender,
but only to an officer
of the regular army.
Show us the way.
They are here.
Lieutenant Henri Karcher,
army of General de Gaulle.
Lieutenant General von Choltitz,
Commander of Paris.
Are you willing to surrender?
Ja.
Unconditionally?
Then you are my prisoner.
Give us your arms.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Major Larorie.
General von Choltitz,
you have engaged in battle,
you have lost.
In the name of General Bayet,
I ask you to give me
some of your officers
who will ride in Jeeps
carrying the white flag
so we can convey
the order of surrender
to those still fighting.
There are already
too many killed and wounded.
General, will you follow me?
Karcher, you're in charge
of the others.
Yes, sir.
The moment has come.
Come on.
Where are you taking me?
You've surrendered
to the French army.
Now you're going to sign
the act of capitulation.
Hello, Papa?
This is Lieutenant Karcher.
Your son.
In spite of your pessimistic
view of my military career,
I'd like to announce
that I've just made prisoners
of the general
in command of Paris
at the Hotel Meurice.
He surrendered to me.
But I'm still very bad at drill.
Go on! Go on!
Go on! Oh...
We made it.
We won the race.
Where are we?
In front of Notre Dame.
What's it look like?
Just like they said, big.
And beautiful with...
two towers.