This film is based on a real story.
On August 15, 1945, Korea was liberated from Japan. The 38th Parallel set the barrier between the Communist North, and the U.S. held South.
June 25, 1950 marks the beginning of the Korean War. It was the first full-scale conflict since WW2, and the region around Pohang saw fierce clashes between South Korea's 3rd Infantry Division and North Korean forces.
For the past 40 days, South Korean forces have only been retreating. There is nowhere else to fall back, all they can do now is wait for the arrival of the Allies in the Nakdong River.
August 8, 1950
Hey, hey!
You over there.
Take this ammo to Giganpo's position.
What?
People on the roof above!
Captain
There's been 3758 strikes.
How is it on that side?
25 pointers, I need assistance immediately.
Fire! Fire!
To the front!
How many are left?
It's the last one.
Captain
What happened to the artillery support?
f17
They're back in the rear.
Just fall back! That's an order!
It's too late, it's all over!
Kang Daewi, listen to me!
We can do it, Captain!
Hey, Kim Jun Seop.
-Yes.
Take three support plantoons.
Yes, sir.
No matter what happens, you have to keep going.
-Yes, sir.
Hey! Let's go!
Hey, Kim Jun Seop.
Yes.
Be careful.
We need a medic! A medic!
Don't run, hold your ground!
Hurry, medic!
Over here!
You got the medic, right?!
More ammunition!
Reloading!
Fire! Fire!
I said run, not stand!
Here.
Stay behind.
Let's go!
Stick to the wall!
They're coming!
Reporting two platoons!
Captain, we've lost contact.
Try again.
Yes, sir!
Captain, Lee Myung Gook.
Still haven't ripped through them?
The rest have begun to retreat.
It will be taken soon.
It will only take five minutes for the 766th Vanguard Troops to win.
We'll start attacking Pohang.
Let this land be free!
Let this land be unified!
Kill everyone.
Charge!
Captain, please send reinforcements! We're being pushed back!
We're in trouble!
Charge!
Yes
Yes, that's right.
Commander
Nakdong River positions have moved to the front
according to Captain Wi's orders.
Hey, comrade Lee,
why am I going there?
I'm going straight to Pohang.
It's an order from the Central Commander.
It's only a suggestions by amateur pencil pushers.
What do they know about war?
Are you ignoring his commands right now?
Comrade, who is in a higher position?
I'm asking who is in a higher position!
The top commander...
Since I left Pyongyang,
I am the top Commander.
Since August, all the orders for Busan
have been directly from me.
Bugwan.
-Sir!
We will take the 766th Vanguard Troops straight to Pohang.
What are you doing? Do it now!
If you cut off the bridge, the refugees will be blocked off.
Then what will we do?!
It's a direct order!
The medic has arrived, so no need to worry now.
We'll give you morphine, wait a little longer.
Move the corpse.
Can you hear me?
It looks like your hearing is gone.
Does it hurt?
What is your name?
You don't even know when you got hurt, do you?
I guess you don't want to talk.
How's Kim Jun Seop?
He's been killed.
Those bastards.
Why aren't you sending in support troops?
Why have you stopped supporting artillery?
Kang Daewi.
For the past 40 days, we've only been retreating.
I'm tired of retreating.
When were the allies supposed to arrive?
Where should we run to now?!
Do we go all the way to Busan?
Then should we go in the ocean afterwards?
Kang Seok, stop it now!
Leave him.
I know.
Seeing men killed right in front of your eyes,
I know it frustrates your heart.
There were no support troops left to send.
Artillery support fire was unavailable because the 4th unit was being wiped out.
It was a vicious fight.
We have three divisions
committed in the Nakdong River area.
Whether it's 5 divisions, 12 divisions, or 15 divisions,
I have to focus on the Nakdong River perimeter.
That is an order from the higher ups.
The Nakdong River battle is going to turn into a bloodbath.
We can no longer retreat or push back,
because this is our last line of defense.
Then where are the Pohang units supposed to be?
Attention!
The Hakdobyung group, move with the other groups!
Move quickly!
Move faster, guys! Let's go!
Were you by Kim Jun Seop's side when he died?
Yes.
What's your name?
Oh Jung Beom.
Catch!
Hey, nice work here!
What is it?
On the charge of attempted murder, that guy,
is heading to a juvenile jail center.
While he was heading to a juvenile jail center,
he said he wanted to fight since
he's a student soldier too, but...
Do you want that kind of guy?
I don't know what else to do.
Particularly, this bastard.
He looks a little old.
You're sure he's a student?
He is.
There's a unit of students that are meeting over there.
Run over.
Don't worry about that guy.
Don't you dare run, you bastard!
His parents were killed by Communists.
That's why he hates it when you talk about communists.
Please sign this.
New HDB recruits, 68 people. 3 existing recruits, total of 71 people.
End of this group!
The first three, come forward.
Give an M1 rifle, with 250 rounds each
to the new recruits
Right now?
From the left line, one person come forward at a time.
Next line!
New HDB recruits, find your places.
Move quickly!
This is so cool!
Men, from this point on, you are now all HDB troops.
HDB troops are divided into two sets.
The head commander will be Oh Jung Beom.
Excuse me!
What is it?
Why are you making him commander?
Do I hear an objection?
Captain, how about a vote for the position?
That's right. Let's act democratically.
Let's do an eating contest!
If it's an eating contest, then I have confidence too.
Be quiet! Do you think this is a joke?
A commander should have combat experience.
I'm sticking with Oh Jung Bum.
From now on, this place will be your position.
Right now, we have three divisions...
committed in the Nakdong area.
Are you saying you want us to defend this place?
Just us?
That's right.
Is there any reason to defend Pohang?
Pohang is a minor strategic base.
Then why don't we abandon Pohang?
Even though this place is not as important, if the enemies get through Nakdong River,
it's over.
According to the information we already have,
this place is relatively safe compared to the Nakdong area.
Oh, how long do we have to defend this place?
The allied forces will arrive on Wednesday.
Only until then.
Let's not go. Can we just not go?
It's an order from the upper command.
We... follow the orders we're given.
Excuse me. If...if...
the communists attack, what do we do?
What do you mean? We can just kill them all!
Hey man, you can't even shoot a gun, and you want to kill them?!
Shut up, I can learn!
I'm guessing we can't run?
Fight, fight until the end!
HDB troops are soldiers, are you not soldiers?
You are the country.
Believe in yourselves.
Here.
Your arm.
You need to take care of your wound.
Remember that.
The power supply.
First turn it this way, then turn it on. Then afterwards, tune it.
Then after tuning, adjust the sound frequency.
Then match the sounds.
What is this?
It's not the frequency, it's the power.
There's no time, I have to keep moving.
You're in charge.
Dae Wi Nim.
What?
Have some confidence.
If anything happens, you can contact me on the radio.
I can't be the top commander.
I've never even held a higher rank before.
Lead with your heart.
If you have a pure heart and good intentions,
everyone will follow you.
If you make them cross the river
it will take two days to get there.
18 hours more because of bridge damage.
Totaling to about three days.
The remaining boats will not be
enough for everyone.
There are roads beyond those mountains,
it would take us half a day to get there.
But we might be ambushed there.
Comrade Commander,
Regardless of this,
should we just follow orders
and continue down Nakdong River?
This, Comrades, is why I say that theories are useless in the battlefield.
Think about it.
If the enemies have a safe crossing,
We're going to have to destroy it.
Is there any way to cross the river?
Take the 766th Vanguard Troops,
and order them to swim across the river.
Yes, I understand sir.
Swim and cross the river.
Tell the tanks to turn around.
Swim and cross the river!
766th Vanguard Troops, prepare to cross!
Cross! Swim and cross the river!
Hey southern comrades, hurry up and show your faces.
Hey, what is this?
Give me one you bastard!
Sir!
Attention HDB troops!
HDB troops!
From now on, divide yourselves into two divisions and...
What are you yakking about?
Speak up, I can't hear you at all.
From this point on the first division,
will bury the corpses.
Is there food?
If there is, can you give us some?
Mr. Bachelor?
You guys... have you ever stabbed someone?
Have you stabbed any communists?
I'm not burying any corpses.
Do we have to do those kinds of things? Huh?!
We're here to kill those communist bastards.
Not to bury corpses!
Isn't that right?!
Right, right!
Yeah, that's right!
You still have to listen to the commander.
It's the orders of Kang Seok Dae!
Orders?
Why should we listen to them?
If you don't, you'll be shot.
By who? You?
Shoot me?
What are you looking at, bastard?
Move out of the way!
Hurry, take it, take it!
One...Two...Three!
One shot has to shoot like 100.
I've trained 8 times before going to war.
You all have only one chance.
So, what did I say?
One shot works like 100.
One more time!
One shot works like 100!
Form up! Line up!
Watch closely.
You saw it?
If you do it wrong,
you'll lose a finger.
Prone position!
Load your weapon!
Fire!
Wow!
Kap Jo,
there's so many people here, and they want us to
survive for half a month only with these?
If this bastard wouldn't eat so greedily, we'd have enough for one month.
Hey, this week is a luxury
where I don't have to pay for snacks!
Kap Jo!
What?
Later at night,
That bastard, Mr. Bachelor, should we
beat him up later on? Who are we, after all!
Who are we?
We are orphans. The bastards.
We are the hoodlums, the bastards.
Kap Jo can barely read.
Shut your mouth, asshole.
Even though our captain is "Mr. Bachelor", Kap Jo, you're even better.
Yep.
Wow, it's awesome!
Kap Jo, this is a hand grenade, right?
Give it to me!
Is it real?
Of course, you idiot.
This thing can go "boom"
and blow up an entire market.
It'll explode?
Yeah.
Wow...
You can blow up everyone with one of these!
You'll disappear without a trace.
Don't move!
Hey!
Hey hey hey!
I said don't move!
Don't joke about that!
Ahhh...jerk.
What is this?
Idiot!
Throw it away you idiot!
Throw it away!
Throw!
Run away!
Stay still you idiot!
Now there are
no more potatoes.
We have nothing to eat besides the corn outside.
Don't worry, we'll get you food.
Wang-pyo, let's go get our tools.
Stop right there.
Butt out.
What?
That's an order.
An order...
Another order?
If the North attacks, how are we going to fight with these guys?
Our soldiers are counting on us to cover them.
That's why we have to fight with strength.
Mom, I want to see you.
Today, I fought with the Armed Forces of Pohang.
Everyone else left to the front of the Nakdong River.
Now, there are only 71 of us.
Mom...
I hear children in the next room laughing
It's been a long time since I've heard laughter.
To keep those children laughing,
Please watch over them.
Hey! What kind of bumpkin dance is that?!
Poongchun,
let's show them how it's done.
Ahhh, in front of these kids.
Charleston Swing
Kap Jo, Kap Jo, Kap Jo!
It's 10 o'clock. All of you, go to sleep.
Platoon 1, what are you doing?
Is this a picnic?!
We're in the middle of a war.
Hurry and get up!
The M1 is heavy, isn't it?
None of these guns are heavy.
But what kind of gun is this long?
These guns were made in the U.S.
If you shoot it,
it will go far.
Should we shoot it?
Just try it.
And you'll wake up everyone.
But Hyung...
I want to eat my mother's spicy cabbage stew
and anchovy soup with some spicy radish.
Think of how delicious it would be.
Then why are you with me now, you moron?
Are they U.S soldiers?
If they're our allies...
They won't shoot at us.
So they're the enemy?
Yes, tell the platoon to form a circle.
Okay.
Brother, I need to go pee.
Hold it in, you idiot!
Can't you do it later?
Get down!
Get down, get down!
The wind feels nice.
What do we do...
Yeah I know...
We hardly ever eat....
We're not going back after this?
It'd be good after we finish this tour...
Although if I could, I'd go back to my hometown right now.
Ceasefire!
Should I check it out?
Stop shaking and talk!
Looks like we hit the jackpot.
Mother...
Why aren't you shooting him, moron?!
Hey, should I do it?
Mom, I killed a North Korean soldier today.
I was told that North Koreans
are monsters with horned heads.
But, those words from his mouth...
he was looking for his mother.
Mom, why do I have to be at war?
These complicated and painful feelings...
I think your heart would sink
if you knew about them.
Hey, it's finally cooked.
Is this corn?
No matter what, I don't think this is going to work.
Aren't the Communists spread out everywhere?
Why are we defending this school?
Post sentries around the school.
Commander, do you think we can use these?
Who knows?
Let's take it.
Hey, look at him.
Hey. stop smoking cigarettes.
Mind your own business.
Why do you act so bossy?
You're not the platoon leader!
Do you want to die?
Just like that.
Those were imported smokes, you idiot!
In the woods, one cigarette smells like 10 cigarettes.
The nerve of this bastard...
Get down!
Where are you?!
Who is it?!
Get down you idiot!
Wang Pyu...
Wang Pyu!
Shit!
I'll kill you bastards!
Kap Jo!
Get back here, it's dangerous!
Get down!
Fire!
Pung Cheon, go over there!
Throw your gun away!
Please!
No!
Kim II-Sung is leading the Republic of Korea!
Put down your guns and surrender!
Kap Jo, don't shoot. That's an order.
That's a North Korean soldier.
The enemy that does not surrender will die!
For the liberation of the South Korean people!
Don't shoot!
Shoot.
Shoot, you moron.
Commander,
you heard him!
You heard the communist, you should have shot him!
Sir, you're here?
How many casualties?
16 are dead, 5 are injured.
Shit!
Shit! Don't touch me! It hurts!
Hang on!
Just hold on!
Why can't you hold on?
Shit! Go away!
Bear with it!
Wang Pyu, that idiot.
I knew that he was looking for me.
He was a member of my gang, but
he always got himself hurt, stabbed
and injured on his own.
Crazy bastard.
Do you have a cigarette?
This is a zippo lighter I stole from someone.
Do you want it?
It's fine.
This is Cuckoo's Nest.
Come in, over.
Nest here, we encountered the enemy!
Cockoo's Nest here, we have encountered the enemy!
Yes sir, I was
reporting the situation, but...
Could I speak with Captain Kang Suk Dae?
Is this the captain?
How are you?
This is the radio operator, Jae-Seon.
Who?
Yesterday, we encountered the enemy.
We killed 12 communist soldiers.
16 men were killed by communist soldiers.
The rest escaped, others were wounded.
Hurry up and come back.
The communists have attacked 2 times.
What?! Put the commander on line!
Oh Jung-Beom speaking.
Those scumbags are tying us up!
We don't know when we'll be back!
Give me a status report every 30 minutes!
I'll call for reinforcements!
Don't be afraid and wait!
Hold out for two hours!
It's two hours!
What did he say?
Is he coming over?
He said he's sending us reinforcements.
Until then, I'll figure something out.
From the sound of the bombs, it's no joke.
We're being beaten like children.
We're like kids robbed of our own country.
Well that's too bad.
Get out!
Fire!
Reload!
The North Korean army now has the 766th Vanguard Troops
and 5 divisions.
They are attacking Pohang.
We need more reinforcements.
Where do you want to send the troops?
Don't you see?
The Nakdong River is a bloodbath!
Only the lives of those student soldiers are valuable?
Everyone's life is precious.
But we have to stay here defending to the end!
If the Nakdong River falls, then it's all over for us!
You're right, save them all...
Save everyone!
All the parents and families too, do you want to?
Stay with your unit, there's no one we can send.
How many doctors are there?
All of them are gone, even the nurses.
How many trucks went out yesterday?
There are 15.
You're lying, it's 20!
You son of a bitch!
I didn't count them, I just gave an example!
Please, continue, Political Commissar Comrade.
Are we done yet?
Comrade Cho Yeon.
Sir!
Get me a cup of water.
Give it to the student soldier.
Give it to him.
In order to gain the enemy's trust, you have to be compassionate.
To gain the loyalty of the people and strengthen our political party.
Indeed, you must be merciful.
What do you mean by that?
Follow me.
Stand up!
Political Commissar Comrade,
he's gone through enough.
Hey, Kap Jo!
Hurry up and get ready!
Hold it, hold it!
Dal Yong!
Hey, who's the commander here?
You're the commander, student Oh Jung Beom?
Who are you?
I am...a Korean People's Democracy worker.
General Pak is here with 5 divisions and the 766th Vanguard.
Our troops,
in exactly two hours will attack here at 12:00.
This place is going to be occupied.
If you surrender and raise a white flag there...
All of you will be spared.
That is compassion, my students.
Our comrades
held by U.S. imperialists will be liberated.
And we will unify Korea together.
Also...
Now comrades, be responsible for the unification
of our country, because this is within our army's power.
At 12:00, let's meet then.
Comrade...
I hope nothing bad will happen.
Jak Jeong Wan.
Did the 4 divisions of the
enemy change movements?
Reinforcements have been constantly on the front lines of the Nakdong River,
as Pohang does not detect the movement of enemy.
Gang Dae We, did you hear that?
Pohang can be reinforced.
Yesterday, they engaged the enemy twice.
Please, let me take some soldiers.
I'll defend it, no matter what.
Follow me.
Attention!
Hey, get your ass over here.
Ask if you have any backup troops.
Sir, is there any backup you've got there?
There's a severe shortage of U.S. troops.
Even at the Nakdong River front, there is a severe shortage.
I'm afraid it's not possible to send any troops any time soon.
There is a shortage with the US troops. He said it's going to be difficult to send support.
Follow me.
Open them up, now.
This is the new line of super bazookas.
It will make it that much easier
in stopping those North Korean tanks.
He said that with the new super bazookas
it's going to be much easier to stop North Korean tanks.
Thank you very much, sir.
Everyone, listen well!
On the Nakdong River front line,
There, they're fighting and dying gloriously!
Jung Dal Young, this moron, is a coward.
Traitor!
Coward!
He sold out the land
on which we all eat.
This traitor
needs to be killed by our own hands!
Do you guys hear me?!
That's right, that's right!
I don't feel so good...
Why don't you
just kill me, can you do that?
Just wait a bit.
The captain will rescue us and bring us food.
Brother, still...
The kimchi stew that I used to eat. I want that too..
Hey, Dal Young!
This asshole, he's a traitor!
Stop it you jerks!
Damn it!
Stop it!
You're still holding a grudge...huh?
Put that gun down.
If you run away, you can live.
To the People's Army....
Even if you go, we can still survive.
Damn you.
If you're going to run away, run away quietly!
I'm going to run away?
Kap Jo, Kap Jo!
Come here, you asshole!
Yes, you coward!
Do you really want to die that much?!
Go and die like a dog!
I'm going to live greatly,
then die!
Stop it!
Hey, let's go!
You guys aren't going?
I sure as hell won't!
We're going to go at them and fight them
even with our bare hands!
Let's go!
Let's move out.
Comrade Commander!
They have not raised the white flag.
Comrade Commander, why are you delaying?
Let's attack now.
In order for our soldiers to attack, they need an order.
With Pohang unprepared, we should attack now.
Why are you delaying it?
We can end the war by August 15th if we attack, can't we?
If you have already killed a soldier,
in your fellow soldier's eyes, you are also a soldier.
Comrade Commander, no matter how young he is,
whoever holds a gun there is the enemy.
The student commander there,
is inexperienced and weak.
Are you listening to me?
I would have killed them already,
if they were real soldiers.
What?
Comrade Park.
Without the Central Party's orders, you freed an enemy prisoner
who should have been shot!
One more word.
And I'll send you back to the Central Party in a casket.
Mom,
The undergarments you bought for me, I put them on now.
Why didn't I think about it before, I don't know.
Mom,
Maybe I might die today.
There are so many enemies around us.
It's just that things aren't going well. I'm not saying it's the end, at least not yet.
I found it!
Assemble the troops 1km away from the school.
Wait for my command.
Do not fire until ordered.
Then attack.
If I die fighting,
I hope I won't be hungry ever again.
Reinforcements are coming from the river soon.
We are going to hold out for the next hour.
We will all join forces and fight.
Fight!
The Captain told us
HDB troops are student soldiers.
We are student soldiers!
Hooray, People's National Liberation Army!
Hooray!
Hooray! Hooray!
Do you need some help?
Thank you, comrade!
You have strong muscles, comrades!
Are you ready?
Fire.
Why isn't it firing?
I didn't follow instructions.
Fix it right away!
This is Cuckoo's nest, over!
Nest here, come in, over!
I followed what you said, but it's not working!
Pardon?
Chang...The Platoon leader said
use your feet.
Kick it.
It's falling here!
Stop!
Everyone stop!
Why, that's...
What the hell are you doing, are you trying to kill us?
Move it.
Cannonball!
Comrade Commander...
Medic! Medic!
Fire!
They repay my kindness with mortars?
Those bastards...
Fire!
I'm going to kill you all.
I'm going to kill every single one of you!
All those students were preparing earlier!
We should have attacked earlier!
2nd platoon, 2nd platoon!
Fall back into the classrooms!
Move it!
766th Vanguard of the National Liberation Army!
Yes!
Dear General Kim Il Sung demands our victory!
Charge forward!
Open fire!
2nd platoon!
Shoot!
Cuckoo! Respond!
Cuckoo, over!
Cuckoo?!
Get down!
Everyone inside!
Fall back!
Everyone, get back! Get back!
Hey Jung Beom!
I'm not finished yet!
Kap Jo! Kap Jo!
Carry the machine guns inside!
It's the tanks, let's go!
Tanks! Tanks!
Hurry up!
Tanks!
Shit!
I want to go back home.
What about you?
I'm going to die alone.
When we go back to this school
you should go and study well.
I'm a student soldier.
This sorry kid
couldn't even do well in school.
However, now...
Look.
From a kid into a student soldier.
That's great.
We're both student soldiers.
Let's go!
Watch out!
Go quickly.
You're better at fighting than me.
You're braver than me.
Go quickly.
Hurry up and go!
The reinforcements are coming soon...
The machine guns on the rooftop!
Meet me up there!
Move quickly, quickly!
And get the molotov cocktails!
Hey!
Jung Beom!
Watch out!
Stop...stop!
You're not going home?
We're going to sacrifice our lives for this school.
Both of us.
Screw that! I'm not going to school today!
Comrade Commander!
What is that? We're being attacked from the rear!
You got us into this mess!
You are a traitor!
All troops, retreat!
Hey, comrade...
You talk too much.
1st unit, move forward!
To the left!
Jung Beom, reload this!
Hey comrade...
I wish it didn't have to end this way.
You fought amazingly well.
But what can you do?
You were born in South Korea.
I was born in North Korea.
Time to put you out of your misery, Comrade Oh Jung Beom.
You bastard...
I'm so sorry...
...then turn it on. Then afterwards, tune it.
Then after tuning, adjust the sound frequency.
Then match the sounds.
What is this?
Frequency.
It's not the frequency, it's the power.
I told you, first you have to turn power off.
Hey, Jae-seon, come over here!
Thank you.
You're blocking me you idiot!
Sit down!
I said sit down.
Ready? I'm about to take the picture.
One... Two... Three!
This movie was based on the true story of Battle of Pohang Girl's Middle School, which took place on August 13, 1950, fought by 71 student soldiers in the Republic of Korea's 3rd Corps.
Those 71 student soldiers delayed the North Korean's advance for 11 hours, giving time for South Korean and UN troops to counterattack later on.
Subtitles brought to you by -71 Into The Fire Team- at Viikii.net