Name is John Carter, US
special forces Intel
Long range reconnaissance op. Why am
I telling you this? I don't know.
Maybe it's not important, but
someone wiser than me once told me:
"You can tell a lot about
a man by what he does"
I run a single man
operation, deep in country.
Territory so remote, that even
the site of a lone jar-head
is considered more of a
novelty than a threat.
My missions are classified, as
I'm sure my story would be.
Except no one would believe it.
- New folks?
- Many people pass through this area.
- It's not shearing season and the
poppies haven't been harvested yet.
- You've been here for too long.
- I'll drink to that.
I used to know your father. He used to
stand up tho these kinds of people.
My father died because of your people.
You Americans, Russians, everyone
wants a piece of what we have here.
There are too many hands
reaching into the barrel.
Soon you will see there's
nothing left to take out.
There is nothing
left here for you.
That's a very nice speech
but you truly believe that your wife
and son will be safer once I'm gone?
- Maybe not be my wife.
- That's funny.
She likes you, you
should take her with you
She's too heavy, I can't carry that much.
I'll give you a cart.
I don't know who they are. They have a
camp outside of town and they need trucks.
They seem to have a lot of money,
but no one is getting in their way.
Except the prostitutes.
Then your wife is doing pretty good.
Hey!
Let him go.
What is so funny?
The look on your face when I blow
up all your opium and those trucks.
- How do you know this is opium?
- You're right.
- Why don't we find out.
- The American doesn't joke.
Look, I let go of this, and you
can say goodbye to everything.
Let him go.
Thank you John Carter.
I owe you one.
- You said you wouldn't hurt them!
- Lower the gun. You don't want to do this.
Lower the gun.
Trust me, you don't wanna do this.  Don't.
Don't!  It's a loaded gun.
Please.
- Get out of the way little sheep.
- Ahh!
Mongrel!  I shall shoot both of you!
Don't!
Don't do it.
Listen to what I'm saying.
You don't want to do this.
You don't wanna take part in this OK?
You just wanna get outa here.
Go on and live your life.
That's it.
I'm not authorizing this unless I have
your full assurance that this procedure
will not have adverse affects.
We've had a 100% success rate so far.
Surgeons tell me most in your condition,
don't even regain consciousness.
You're probably wondering
what your prognosis is...
You're not expected to
make it through the night.
All of your major
systems, are failing.
But that's OK ...
because we have this.
The entire data to reconstruct
you, atom by atom, lives on this.
16 GB of flash memory stick.
Now, you don't have to answer this now.
Because you already signed the papers,
we don't need your permission.
Just wanted to let you know, if you were
concerned this procedure isn't working,
Don't worry.
We've tested it out previously
on a human subject.
And from all signs, that
test was a success.
Teleportation.
That's right.
You are the perfect candidate
for this operation.
It was funny the other
day when you said Mars.
Quite prescient really. We
are sending you to Mars.
Not the Mars that you
thin, this is Mars-216.
a small planet in the orbit Alpha-Centauri.
The fourth planet out from its sun.
Our scans show an exceeding possibility
that this planet could hold life.
We certainly believe it has an atmosphere.
We haven't been able to penetrate to its
surface, but you'll do that for us.
Do you have any questions?
I don't think he can speak.
He's trying to tell us something.
I think he's ready to go.
- Is he one of your kind?
- No.
I believe he's an assassin.
Or else, why would he have
gotten onto your ship?
- We should finish him.
- But he is unarmed.
It does not take weapons
to kill, my princess.
- Avert your eyes.
- No!
He can do us no harm now.
You are making a big
mistake, my princess.
Than I shall suffer
the consequences!
The decision is made.
Very well my princess.
Did you just call me your "princess"?
A thousand pardons,
I meant... Your Highness.
While I am grateful for
all you have done,
Only one man shall ever
call me "his Princess."
And that man will be blessed.
Time will tell.
This is either a really good sign,
or a really, really bad one.
Um...
Well...
I'm really sorry about what
happened, to your egg.
It seemed to me like you guys were
having such a good time and laughing,
maybe we can uh ... smash
some more together.
Ok.  Forget about that.
I'm from a planet called Earth.
Well, actually from Virginia really.
My name is John Carter.
[Alien Language]
Okay.
Actually, let go.
Okay come on.  Leg go of my arm.
Okay!
I get the idea.
[Alien Language]
Same to you buddy.
What do you want me to do?
You want me to ... jump?!
Bunch of idiots.
You want me to jump.
Okay, you can loosen this
up, give me some slack.
You wanna jump?
Okay.
[Alien Language]
How about some lunch?
Enough!
You want me to jump again?
I'm not gonna jump.
Okay.
Just do it!
[Alien Laughter]
Hey look,
But I'm hungry.
Food.
I need to eat some food.
You know ... food?
Okay.
How about some water? Drinking water.
Liquids.
Great, that's it.
Good, thank you.
[Alien Laughter]
You guys are a riot.
Shouldn't you be in school?
Food?
Food, yeah I-
I'll eat I'm hungry.
That's very kind of you.
Thank you for uh, the hospitality.
It didn't come from your body ...
did it?
Forget it, I had to ask.
I'll try it.
It doesn't smell so bad.
I'll give it a shot.
Okay.
It's not so bad.
I was expecting worse.
Not bad at all.
Yeah, I'll take some more.
What is that?!
No, no, no, no, no!
I'm not eating that
no matter what!
I don't know what that is
and I'm not eating it!
No.  No, thank you, I'm full.
Those are bugs, insects.
You see we don't eat that.
I'm not gonna eat
it, no matter what.
You're not gonna eat that are you?
Yeah, I'm glad you liked them.
They're good right? Yes. I don't,
I don't eat bugs for dessert.
Thank you.
Ok!  Alright!
You have to work on your hospitality.
Hospitality.
Why am I sounding like this?
Now that we have your attention,
allow me to introduce myself again.
I am Tars Tarkas.
This is Sola.
I'm... John Carter.
- There was something in that bug, right?
- Yes.
The Jubilee Beetle allows
all to communicate.
Interesting.
They taste like crap.
Crap?
Never mind.
I have a lot of questions for you.
And I for you.
Thank you.
Am I free to go?
You have earned you position amongst us.
As our tradition,
You are offered the things of the
warrior you defeated on the first day.
You may have his quarters,
and his retinue of slaves.
Well, I'm not in need of any slaves.
Maybe some of his possessions.
Did he have something I could possibly use?
He did have a lot of debts.
Oh.
Well, I should have
killed that big fat guy.
Tal Hajus!
Do not speak of him with those tones.
Well pardon me.  I know he's...
your supreme leader.
But when the shit hit the fan, he
was the first one to split town.
You see many things John Carter.
Yeah, I like to fight with
people that wanna stick around.
Time may come when things
like that are settled.
We have a saying here on Barsoom.
The slowest road to a destination,
is often the most rewarding.
You will love golf.
Golf?
Everyone to the station!
What's going on?
This does not concern you.
Under no circumstances interfere.
I can not promise that we won't
confuse you for the enemy. Ha!
Fire!
Look out!
Aim for the pilot!
He's flying that craft!
Fire!
Aim for the Pilot!
Hit them better.  Come on!
Ready the hooks!
Ready,
Heave.
Heave!
You missed it!
It's getting away.
Bring in the Tharks.
Mount up!
We can't let them get away!
Bring all the survivors to me.
- Stay away from us!
- I'm not here to hurt you.
But you attacked the ship before.
I've never been here.
- Then you are a madman!
- You've seen me on this ship?
I have.
Please tell me what happened.
Sab Than said you were
here to kill the princess.
No, I'm not here to kill anyone.
I'll make you a deal. Help us or those
Tharks will desecrate our bodies!
If they find us, they
will do horrible things!
Please, there's not much
time you must help us!
Just take us away from here and
I'll tell you what you wanna know!
Our bodies can not fall to them.
No! Take her first please.
Thank you.
When I die, please bury us together.
Here, take some water.
Can you tell me who that woman was?
She's Dejah Thoris princess of Helium.
They must not capture her!
You also must promise one other thing,
If you find her, you must
not let her marry Sab Than.
- Who's that?
- He did this to us.
Do you know who I am?
No.
I am Kantos Kan.
Master engineer of the
royal pumping station.
We were en route to change out the crew.
Okay alright.  Take it easy.
Take it easy!
Remember this. Day by day, night by
night we keep the air clean and bright.
Day by day, night by
Can you tell me what happened on that ship?
When I was there.
The princess...
Damn.
Hey.
Wait a second, that's not the
way to treat a rescuer now.
I doubt those are your motives.
And I am in no need of rescue.
Look, I don't know
if you noticed,
but there's a hundred
of those guys coming
down here to get you
so we have to go.
What do you want of me?
Look, I will explain later but
we have to get out of here.
Why were you on my ship?
Your ship? I was there
to help Kantos Kan.
- You've seen Kantos Kan?
- Yeah, I spoke to him.
- You're lying.
- Look, I will explain later.
- Are you coming with me or not?
- Stay back!
How can I trust you?
I'm the only friend you've got.
I promise I'm not going to give you
up to a bunch of bloodthirsty Tharks.
You will thank me later.
The prisoner's mine!
On behalf of all Tharks,
for performing bravely in battle
and for capturing one so
important, the Princess of Mars,
We award you this fighting harness.
You are now Jeddak.
Among Tharks.
Let me explain.  It's not what you think.
I'm still on your side.
That was her pee bucket.
I should be honored,
she is the princess.
Good thing you haven't
been feeding her much.
Let me ask you something. When a
princess gets to uh, to Hajus
What's gonna happen?
The people of Helium have inflicted
many wounds on the Tharks.
Tal Hajus will reflect on this.
One might think that the princess
could be a bargaining chip.
A way to advance the cause of
the Tharks on this planet.
But, Tal Hajus does not think like this.
He will most likely send her to her death.
But not before torturing her horribly.
It is his way.
How did Tal Hajus become supreme leader?
Like all of us, Tal Hajus
earned his rank through battle.
He fought his way to his position.
Killing all those before him.
He moved up as you are.
And I.
Do you think you could abscond
with her, and that cage?
Surely someone
must have the key.
I thought so.
You're not gonna throw
anything at me are you?
I forgive you.
You do?
I see now that you're
with these savages
because you're too ashamed of
yourself to live amongst men.
I've heard of ones like you.
You don't feel that you
deserve to live in society,
don't feel that you deserve anything good.
So you just lurk around the edges,
never really accomplishing
anything in life.
Never even having a family.
Excuse me?
I forgive you.
See these people, these Tharks,
As bad as they seem, they have honor.
How can there be honor in
holding someone in a cage?
You got a point there.
But, they're telling me your people
are trying to eliminate them.
Not true.
Not all of my people resist them.
Certain factions, wish
to have them contained.
Okay, that's kind of savage.
Mars is a delicate balance.
My people,
We run the air pumping stations.
Without which, all would perish.
They don't respect that.
The raid our villages.
We supply the air that keeps us all alive.
We keep the air clean and bright.
How do you know that?
You must leave now, the
spiderlings are approaching.
- You have to let the princess go.
That is not up to me. We
must leave now. Come on!
It is bad to be caught out in the open.
We must move.
I'm not going until you
let the princess go.
I can not my friend. It would be
too much temptation for you.
I will give you this.
If I am killed by the spiderlings,
you can have the key!
It'll be OK.
Maybe they won't
be able to see us.
They hunt for vibrations.
They don't have eyes.
Give me one of your rifles.
Duck!
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
- This can't be good.
- Looks like a scout.
Back to back!
Shit.
Give me the key!
There you go my princess.
How much longer till we get to Tal Hajus?
Maybe a day.
You know, I was thinking that's
not such a good idea. You know?
After we were attacked by the spiderling.
one could possibly image that we...
got separated.
That the princess...
was lost.
But that is not what happened.
One could possibly imagine
Then I would be derelict in my duties.
There's times where
dereliction is one's duty.
You guys have a lot to
learn on this planet.
Thanks!
Next time, better warn me.
You're lucky one of my me didn't shoot you.
You're lucky I didn't miss.
We have a long ride ahead of us.
I will make you a deal.
If you promise not to run away
with Mr. Carter here,
I will allow you to remain out of the cage.
And why would I run off with him?
We Tharks may be ... different,
But we are not unperceptive.
Your kind,
So simple in their behavior but,
You don't even know what motivates you.
I'm certainly not motivated
to be anywhere near him.
Like a leaf floating
down the stream,
you are unaware of the current that
runs beneath, plotting your course.
You the leaf,
think you control your motion.
My only motivation is
to return to my people.
forget this experience, and all of you.
That will be for Tal Hajus to decide.
Let us go!
- Is that our destination?
- No.
That is a structure of her kind's making.
What is it?
They say it cleans the air for us.
It is used to control us.
Making us believe that without
them we could not survive.
So, you don't even think it works.
They say that one man can operate it.
We have a saying, "to plow the
field, it takes more than one Thark"
How can one man run a machine that
filters the air of an entire planet?
It can not be true.
The Royal station.
We have to go there. Kantos Kan
and his wife should be there now.
Please, we must go.
I know nothing of them.
What happens if they didn't make it?
Our mission was to deliver a
replacement crew to the station,
Kantos Kan and his wife.
So it is true. Two people could
run a big machine like that?
They don't have to run it,
It operates without humans.
A royal pumping station
official is appointed for life.
Their job is to monitor the machine,
make necessary maintenance,
and if there's trouble,
start the backup system.
They are a fail-safe.
the job of maintaining the
royal planetary pump station,
is the most important
job in this planet.
If something were to
happen to the machine,
and no one were there
to start the pump
our planet would die.
Well I think this calls for a detour.
What do you say we go and
investigate the pumping station?
At least to see if Kantos
Kan made it there.
We will not deviate.
The princess may believe her words
are truthful, but they are lies.
It comes down to me from my elders.
That pumping station does not work!
Look at it, breath the air!
Do you really believe in your
heart that the air you breath
comes form that machine?
We stay the course.
We are here to see Tal Hajus. We
have with us the princess of Mars.
Oh great leader!
What is this you've
interrupted my day with?
- I have brought you the princess...
- So it is the Princess of Mars.
You are as ugly as I have been told.
I cannot see how your kind worships you.
But don't worry. When I am done
with you, I will make you pretty.
Your royalness.
The grasshopper speaks! Jumping
bean I barely noticed you.
The princess, as ugly as she may be,
was intercepted.
We intercepted the princess
on her way to do business
which may affect all of us.
What could that be?
The princess was en route to
the royal pumping station.
For years, her kind has used the
pretense of the royal pumping station
to keep my kind in
check, to subjugate us.
To keep us here
in this wasteland
while they hoarded the
fertile grounds to the north!
They keep us in fear. And yet
with her delivered to us,
we now have an opportunity
for our answers.
Answers to what?
The air you breathe,
is it not still fresh?
She never delivered her cargo
to the station. Did she not?
Therefore, as we all
suspected, it is a sham!
The machine can operate without
the hand of man of Thark.
It is but a precaution we keep it occupied.
If something were to happen, we
are the only ones who can fix it.
I am sure that such speeches sway
the masses at home, but not here!
Your words reek of lies!
Your royalness, I think you're
being too harsh on the princess.
Who are you to tell me what I can do?
I am John Carter of Mars.
Jeddak of the Tharks.
Captain of the arms.
A Jeddak grasshopper?
Who could have bestowed such a
position upon you, a human?
It was I your highness. John Carter
showed great nobility and courage.
He fought bravely in
the spiderling attack.
I see before me three abominations.
One, Dejah Thoris princess of lies!
Two, John Carter, made
Jeddak against Thark rule
and three, Tars Tarkas, loyal warrior
who broke from Thark tradition.
No one but I can confer the position of
Jeddak upon another; especially a human!
Tars Tarkas, you have served me well.
For this offense I will
relieve you of your command.
Remove yourself from
my throne at once!
I will find a place for
you amongst my servants!
John Carter, as told you
are a great fighter.
I will allow you to use your
gifts in the fight pits tonight.
Dejah Thoris, horrible princess
Your fate I will savor.
For all those years that
you subjugated my people
for so long with your malicious lies
I will see to it that no words will
ever be issued from your lips.
Lips that I will not
waste I might add.
Let my will be done!
This doesn't look too good.
I have a task for you. But first
prepare the animals to ride.
I've seen you before,
on the Princess' ship.
If I'm lucky enough to
meetcha in the arena,
I'm gonna kill you.
Not if I kill you first.
Sarka!
I'm so happy to see you my friend.
What are you doing here?
You Americans are so easy to bribe.
I think I was dying. I told them were
I kept 10 million All my profits.
If only they could keep me alive.
Then the spook agent came. NSA/CIA?
I gave them everything.
No!
They even promised me amnesty
if I was successful.
The I came here.
What were you doing with the princess?
It was fate.
We were destined to be together.
We were both on the ship together,
when I was teleported.
Bingo!
You told them I was an assassin didn't you?
You're a soldier, a killer.
I'm gonna have fun killing you.
You were lucky once.
It won't happen again John Carter.
You're dead.
What is wrong with you Tharks?
Don't you guys have reality TV?
That's how it's going down huh?
shit
I'm not gonna fight him.
We have to fight!
I'm not gonna fight you!
I want you to know, that
you were honorable.
I was glad to have you as part of my squad.
If we don't fight,
they'll kill us both.
Since I beat you, then
I'll be commander right?
If I were commander. When you
defeat a Thark in Battle,
If you were to defeat Tal Hajus,
then I'd be commander right?
If I could defeat him, yes.
You just don't quit do you?
A Thark may never concede a fight.
Have it your way then.
Come with me.
What about John Carter, Tars Tarkas?
I have my orders, we must leave.
There is no time.
Your absence will be discovered
It's my lucky night!
We will have to finish this
at another venture Carter.
Why is that?
I have someone else I need to meet.
She is a bit more important.
Oh I'm sure she'll be pleased.
knowing you're coming after
you slaughtered Kantos Kan,
Have you learned nothing?
If you have a superpower,
you should keep it hidden.
It's time to end this.
I challenge you for
leadership of the tribe.
Do you accept the challenge?
Only I can issue such a command.
Do you accept the challenge?!
Die!
You are unfit to command!
Who amongst those witness to
this, denies my right to command?
Where's the princess?
She went with Sab Than
to the pumping station.
They took off in a flier.
Do you have another flier?
I'll meet you there!
What happened to Kantos Kan and his wife?
I'm afraid the Tharks got them.
But how did you survive?
It wasn't easy, I was
captured, just like you.
But the flier, how did
you manage to get it?
The Tharks had it. They
shot it down like yours.
And you were a prisoner of Tal Hajus?
Yes.
Did you see John Carter?
I did.
Is he alive?
No, he died in the arena.
If it is any consolation,
he helped me escape.
He told me it was a great honor to
have served you in your journey.
If he survived, he would have
liked to have been your servant.
He said that?
A rough translation.
That's funny, I
thought he hated me.
No, furthest from the truth.
He felt about you the same way I do.
Like what?
I love you.
My heart can only go to one person.
And I want to be that person.
- But it has already gone out.
- To who?
It does not matter, he's dead now.
I have no more heart to give.
It can't be.
We can talk about this later.
Right now we have to find the
current keeper of the station,
assess the situation.
Hello?
Is anyone there?
- Good day.
- Atol Nard?
Princess.
Is everything OK in there?
This is highly unusual.
Let us in!
Who are you?
He's with me.
Princess. Thank you.
Your highness.
Please, we're here to assess the station.
Everything is in fine working order
princess. No parts need replacement.
Everything is as it was 700
years ago, when I began.
Is this man my replacement?
No I'm sorry, they were killed.
So this is it, this
is the heart of it?
Yes this is all of it.  Hydrogen fusion.
Do you know what this is?
I wouldn't touch that.
But you know what this is.
Something... you shouldn’t be touching.
If you know what this is, I don't
think you'll come closer to me.
What do you want?
I want an answer ... from her.
I want you to be mine.
Will you be with me?
I cannot.
My heart belongs to another.
No!!!
You're an idiot.  They have a backup.
I don't need you. I just
needed to know where it is.
I can see you.
Sarka!
Not there either.
Sarka
Sarka!
You're insane.
By my calculations
it will take only 4 hours
for the atmosphere to
leach off this planet.
That is 4 hours longer
than you will be alive.
You always sucked at math Sarka!
You were a shitty opium
dealer, a shitty tea seller
And now, you're a shitty
destroyer of worlds.
Come on.
I can't believe you're
doing this, over a girl.
It's not really you.
The Sarka I know is motivated
by money and power.
You might be loosin' it.
You're right.
The girl means nothing to me.
She is immaterial. With
you out of the way,
let's say dead. I shall
restart this pumping station.
But only after Th people of this
plant make me their supreme ruler,
and bring me tribute.
With this impenetrable
station as my base,
I shall have the best
bargaining chip ever.
The air supply. It is
better than drugs.
That's if you can
activate the machine.
It is a simple mechanism.
Maybe not for these primitives.
They will give me whatever I want.
Just to keep from asphyxiating.
You're forgetting one small thing.
And what is that?
I'm gonna kill you.
Heave!
Go on, push.
Push.
You can do it.
Heave...
I was with Kantos Kan when he died.
He was saying ...
Something... day by
day, night by night ,
I know.
You do?
Oh, Ok.
Is that it?
Is that the controller?
That's it.
Okay.
Come on.
Is it working?
Try harder. Come on,
it's not working.
That's it.  Go on!
That's insane!
Go on.
Faster, faster, faster!
You did it!
I never told them anything.
For them the experiment was a failure.
They didn't expect me to survive, but I
guess I was tougher than they thought.
If they knew the truth, it would be over.
Humans would overrun
the savage planet.
One fighting man from earth
was enough for Barsoom.
They sent me back to active duty.
So now I wait,
Biding my time till the day when I
shall return to the red planet and...
the princess of mars.