Captain, I've come from Tobruk.
I've a message from General Lederer.
And these cigars with compliments.
Major, I have orders.
Your men are to leave for Tobruk.
Tobruk? Why, that's crazy!
- Those are my orders.
That's an active war zone! Prisoners
of war are to be sent to a safe area.
Tobruk is now ours.
I assure you it is safe.
The Geneva Convention
has explicit rules...
We also have those rules. Your side
was notified about this movement.
Heil Hitler!
You will do that too. So prepare!
We leave immediately.
- And what if we refuse to go?
We will leave you here.
Then you will see there are
worse things than dysentery.
Merrihew!
- Sir?
Pack it.
- Yes, sir.
Captain, the girl. She is crazy.
She is speaking of an airplane.
I will see to her.
Italian whores don't impress me!
Speak English, you Kraut!
What is the problem, Signorina?
- Why am I not leaving to Tobruk?
Special air transport calls for
special authority. - I got!
Courtesy shown the bearer
will greatly oblige General Banducci.
Yes, I know of your position
with the General. - Position?
You are very attached to his staff.
He's molto grande, il Generale!
You only piccolo Captain.
Italians are stylish warriors. I wish
they'd keep their women on a leash.
Any other jokes?
Yes.
You will travel like the rest of us.
How is that?
- In a truck. Continue packing.
Amsterdam. The Hollanders.
They make good cigars, no?
Very nice. - Cured dry as the Sahara.
Rommel himself smokes these.
You know Rommel? - Yes.
He loves the Sahara. We all do.
By "we",
I mean the professional military.
I'm not a military man, Captain.
War holds no romance for me.
The side effects are repulsive.
- Here there are no side effects.
No women, no children,
no towns to get in the way.
Just men, my Doctor.
Just men?
- Yes...
Halt!
Get out of the vehicle!
Give orders to leave the vehicles!
Yes, sir!
Follow the vehicle cautiously.
He's alive, Captain.
Dead or alive?
- Dead. They stink already.
Search the dead and the cabin.
Bring me all the papers!
The man is suffering from exposure
and dehydration. He needs treatment.
Give it to him.
We camp here for tonight.
Use the trucks to make a camp.
Pitch the tents.
We will stay till 4 a. m.
Corporal, your pulse
and respiration are quite normal.
You're shamming. Why?
I'm Foster.
Your ID tag reads Weatherly, J.D.
That's my cover. I'm Foster.
Captain, 53rd Combat Engineers.
You don't know?
- What? - 8th Army Intelligence.
I've never had contact with
Intelligence, 8th Army or otherwise.
You are Major Farrow, aren't you?
- I'm Tarkington, Hugh. Medical Corps.
Where the hell is Farrow?
- Who?
Those prisoners in the convoy
are the 5th Commandos, aren't they?
No, that's my outfit,
the 15th field hospital unit.
God damn it to Hell!
The moment he is conscious
bring him to me for questioning.
It may be a little while, Captain.
I'm afraid he's in shock. - Yes...
We continue now with a report
from CBS London and Edward R. Murrow.
This is London.
The loss of Tobruk will make
supplying Malta even more difficult.
And the battle for Egypt
may even now be underway.
At the moment, all that can be said
is that Parliament and the press
are looking for someone to blame.
There's no question
about the conduct of British troops.
Their bravery deserved victory
but they were defeated.
But Rommel is fond of the unorthodox
and speculation is futile.
Rommel is being
reinforced through Tobruk.
Tell me! Are you
a member of the 5th Commandos?
Get him out of here.
Quite a performance.
What in the name of God is that?
Don't worry, she's real.
Belongs to an Italian general.
Any more? - No, she's the only one.
Signorina Vivian something or other.
English pigs!
She's the only passenger...
- What happened to the 5th Commandos?
That's an interesting question.
To ask it makes this the bloody
muck-up of all time. - Who are you?
Sergeant MacKenzie, 5th Commandos.
- 5th Commandos? Any others here?
Well, we're it.
Ed Brown, Bill Wembley,
Dan Garth and Reilly.
We were left behind when
our unit was moved. Acute dysentery.
Except me. I got a bad tattoo
from Alexandria. - And the others?
Shipped to a prison camp in Tunisia.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
I don't see why that's a surprise.
- Did he brief you? Major Farrow?
Only what he had to. He told us
we were going to Tobruk as prisoners.
On the way, we'd scuttle
the German guard and take over.
Your credentials say you're an expert
on the harbor guns at Tobruk.
If it's any comfort, we had 50 men
trained to blow them to Hell.
You said
he only told you what he had to.
Any idiot private
could spell it out, sir.
Rommel is building up supplies
in Tobruk for his next attack.
He controls the air. The only way
to clobber Tobruk is from the sea.
To clear the way for Navy
those guns have to be knocked out.
That's it, isn't it?
- That's it.
I don't think it concerns us.
- It does. How many men do you have?
Whatever nonsense you have in mind
you're not involving my men.
At 1700 hours tomorrow, one of
our planes will attack the convoy.
The purpose was to create confusion
so the 5th Commandos could take over.
A deliberate air attack?
- Nevertheless, the pilot will strike.
To scrub this mission
I need a radio. The only way I can
do that is by taking over the convoy.
And then?
Then we drive back to British lines.
A long way through enemy territory.
But with wheels and guns
and fuel and a little luck...
Who knows? One further question:
Where is the medical kit kept?
I know the truck it's on.
But why, sir?
We need weapons
in order to acquire better weapons.
I'll see to it, sir.
- Good, good.
I accept that you are dedicated,
Captain. You will do what you must.
But without me or any of my men
that don't want to be involved.
Sir, I'm a Quaker. I'm in the Medical
Corps as a conscientious objector.
I cannot help you in a mission
where I would have to kill someone.
Sergeant...
The next morning, the Hitler Youth
marched at the Berlin Stadium.
In spite of rain and fog,
132,000 came to greet their Fuehrer.
Everything you are,
you are through me.
And everything that I am,
I am through you.
And because the German nation's
master race
in its pride and confidence,
bravely and daringly
demands leadership,
the people
in ever-growing numbers
pledge allegiance to our leadership.
Sieg Heil!
Isn't that a Luger?
- No, it's a Walther. Automatic.
Beautiful.
Really something, eh lads?
What are you doing in the box?
What are you doing back there?
My arm hurts bad.
Very badly. I need medicine.
OK, take the medicine.
ETHER
The people of Germany
rejoice in the knowledge
that the eternal need to flee
has been replaced by
an eternal sense of belonging!
Any of you chaps got the right time?
I make it nearly 5 o'clock.
1700 hours?
How about a tea break, for instance?
- Or a beer break? - Is that a Rolex?
Yes. English. Rolex.
- Rolex?
Rolex is not English.
It's a Swiss watch. - Yes.
How much? - Maybe I'll make a deal
with you if you play your cards right.
It's a Swiss watch. - That's right.
- How much do you want for it?
How much?
1700 hours.
Spread out!
Stay there!
Foster, you goddamn boy scout!
My God, help!
Too bad about the radio, sir. - Yes.
Make up a burial detail
and post a guard over the prisoners.
Do you know of the Geneva Convention
concerning treatment of prisoners?
There's more to the Africa Corps
than uniform, much more.
You all will be shot as spies!
I wish I could shoot you myself!
You won't be buried, Superman.
We'll leave you for the vultures.
The burned-out truck is hopeless.
The others are ready to roll.
Feed the men.
- The Germans too, sir? - Yes.
I haven't found any papers, sir.
- I've got them. - Are they in order?
Official passage for British prisoners
with Africa Corps escort to Tobruk.
MacKenzie...
- Sir?
We're a long way from our lines.
Let's get going. Now.
There's been a change of plan.
- Change of plan?
The radio has been blown to bits
so we stick to our original operation.
The next step is an airdrop
of weapons and explosive devices.
Do you propose to raid Tobruk with
a hospital unit and 4 sick commandos?
No, I'm going to blow up their guns.
The device involved
could be carried in your medical kit.
But the delivery requires men.
The truth is it's a suicide mission!
No. The Navy picks us up.
I've no more desire to die than you.
What about them?
They remain here.
- Alive.
Here comes our supply drop!
Look sharp, lads! On the double!
Cut those supplies loose
and bury the chutes. Hurry it up!
Here's some more, fellows!
Get moving! Get over here!
Get a move on now,
we haven't got all blooming night!
Get them in, cowboys!
I give you my word, alright?
What about the girl?
- She stays with us.
She's an integral part of the convoy.
On the official bill of lading.
She's yours, Doctor. All yours.
- Mine?
I don't care if you cut out her
tongue. She's your responsibility.
But the prisoners live.
- Alright. Deal.
Right lads. Over the side.
You grip the rope with the right hand
and pay it out with the left.
Hold it tight but let it out slowly.
Easy does it. Pay attention,
your life depends on it.
You're not rolling pills now.
We'll teach you how to be Commandos.
Careful.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine...
Listen carefully. This weapon can
hurt you as much as the enemy.
This cylinder contains Napalm,
the other contains compressed air.
You release it by pulling this valve.
The air comes up here.
You pull the trigger. And here
is a thing called an "increment. "
This thing spins around and
operates like a cigarette lighter.
Don't get forward!
Never get in front of the machine!
Hold it up away from you. Put your
finger on the trigger. And press!
I'd hate to lead them into
a real brannigan at this point.
But they're better than I expected
and, well, we'll play it by ear.
Silence. Quiet.
Quiet. Silence. You know silence?
- Silence.
What about that girl?
- She's going to be difficult.
She's unpredictable, sir.
- He's right.
We'll run into Nazis in 100 miles. If
she blows the whistle, we've had it.
There must be something we can do.
Pity you're not helpful. - Pardon?
- Eating out of your hand in no time.
Doc, you're supposed to know
about women. - Not this kind.
I can picture your patients
in Harley Street very clearly.
An emotional appeal doesn't work. I
dare say she has a price. - No doubt.
I gave in on the prisoners.
I hope we don't have to pay for that.
As far as the girl goes...
- Let me try again.
There's very little time.
- There's no time, Captain.
For God's sake... Hold it!
Alright, get out!
Two full Panzer divisions.
What the devil are they doing here?
Never mind. My men are ready.
Let's attack!
Fork to the left, the sea and Derna.
Our Tobruk road lies straight ahead.
Suspicious, our standing here, sir.
- Yeah.
Your other German-speaking man?
- Garth. - He rides in the rear.
You come along with me.
Shall I take care of her, sir?
- No, she's in the clearance papers.
You said she's my responsibility.
Well, I've got something.
Too late for that. - I'm a doctor.
She'll be taken care of.
What's the problem?
The Italian lady. Where is she?
- She's there.
Corporal!
She belongs to one of
Mussolini's generals. Understand?
Yes...
We'll take the road to the sea.
- No, that area is off-limits.
You'll continue on to Tobruk.
- We'll camp here. - That's allowed.
Park there.
Park there!
When I suggested we attack the Jerrys
I was venturing a little joke.
Two Panzer divisions...
I don't understand that.
Maybe Rommel's waiting for the right
time. - Rommel waits for nothing.
They might have come from Derna.
No, that's the 11th and 21st Division.
Reps camp! Parts. Repair shop.
- They could do that in the field.
Fuel!
Rommel must have a fuel dump nearby.
Heavily camouflaged.
- Underground? - Where?
A Panzer division without fuel is
scrap. If we could immobilize two...
But it's all... You've got no radio.
No way of communicating...
Communicating?
How you do go on, Doctor.
If I locate the bastards
I'll blow them sky high.
Maximum security installation.
How do we get in?
If you get past the road block
you can ask Rommel.