Art Festival Production
© 1966
Subtitles Provided by SuperHappyFun.com
Translated from french
The Red Angel
(Akai Tenshi)
Original Story by
Yoriyoshi Arima
Photography by
Setsuo Kobayashi
Music by
Sei Ikeno
Starring
Ayako Wakao
Shinsuke Ashida
Yusuke Kawazu
Directed by
Yasuro Masumura
My name is Sakura Nishi.
I left Japan for China
in May, 1939.
I was assigned to the
Tienstin Army Hospital.
Nurse Taniguchi
and you four, surgery.
Nurse Nishi and you three,
general medicine.
Nishi.
Half of your patients are serious.
The rest are not.
They're mainly TB and
mentally ill patients.
Some aren't sick at all.
Be careful.
Many can demonstrate a fever
by agitating the thermometer.
Mental patients who've recovered
pretend their sick.
They prefer being here
to manning the front lines.
Seeing through their lies
is your job.
You'll be with them
every day.
Understand?
Outwardly it's just like
a military hospital in Japan.
But in fact it's a field hospital.
You're new here?
Where was your last post?
After graduating I spent three
years in a Tokyo Hospital.
Born in Tokyo?
Me too.
From the Kiba area.
So, your family is
in the lumber trade?
Grandfather was,
I don't remember.
Why not?
Father died before
I was born.
Mother also, when I was two.
An aunt raised me.
How old are you?
I'm 24.
I'm Pvt. Sakamoto, also from
Tokyo. Be good to me.
Tokyo, eh?
Damn it!
I wish I was back there.
Nishi, time to make
your rounds.
Stop it!
I'll scream!
Go ahead.
Let me go!
No use fighting back.
Everyone's bored.
They'll enjoy the show.
I reported everything
the next night.
I see.
Pvt. Sakamoto again?
You're his third victim.
He isn't fully recovered,
but this can't go on!
Hello, nurse.
I'm being sent back to
the front line.
A death sentence.
Congratulate me.
Thanks for everything.
Good luck.
I really enjoyed it.
Next time it's my turn.
Stuck here all day.
A man needs a woman.
My next posting, two months
later, was even worse.
Hell couldn't be much worse.
It was a front line hospital.
FIELD HOSPITAL
Bullet wound.
He's dead.
Surgery.
Amputation.
Dead.
Put my foot back on!
Forget it, son.
Amputation.
All right, son.
We'll stop the pain.
No saving him.
Surgery.
Help me!
Please!
Control yourself!
Separate the dead.
Amputation.
At the thigh.
Anesthetic?
Just local.
He's a kicker,
hold him down.
Idiot!
Get back here!
Mother!
All right, he's ready.
I'll sew him up.
Get me a bandage.
200 operations over
three days and three nights.
Lt. Okabe, the surgeon,
the medics and nurse,
all went without sleep.
Arm next.
Hold him down.
More and more men
were brought in.
Many died before surgery.
Some died during surgery.
Others died after the operation.
They all went to the morgue.
Get their tags or we
won't know who is who.
There was a mountain of tags.
It was the end
of the third day.
His pulse is strong.
He's lost too much blood.
He's a goner.
Nurse Nishi.
It's me, Sakamoto...
Save me, please!
I'm sorry
about what happened.
I don't want to die!
I want to live!
I'm begging you!
Don't leave me!
Nurse Nishi!
Please don't let me die!
Don't kill me...
Doctor.
He needs a transfusion.
Anesthetic.
Only colonels and above
get blood transfusions.
I know this man.
Please, Doctor.
How do you know him?
He was my patient in Tienstin
for a while.
He's not kin,
or even a friend?
No, sir.
We're swamped. These others
have a better chance.
If you come to my quarters
tonight, I'll do it for you.
Thank you, sir.
Just this one!
I didn't want him to die.
I didn't want him to think
that was my revenge.
That I'd deliberately kill him.
The transfusion didn't work.
By the end of the shift
he was dead.
What's up?
No pulse.
His pupils are dilated.
He's been gut shot,
it kills them every time.
What a waste of
precious blood.
We'll take him out.
Throw him in the pile.
One more dead!
Who is it?
So, you really came?
Were you joking?
No, I meant it.
Pour me some wine.
The spoils of war.
The man we gave
the transfusion to died.
That's no surprise.
It would've been a miracle.
I'm sorry I caused you trouble.
Don't play favorites
with the patients.
Soldiers aren't human beings!
They're just weapons.
Why did you operate if
you knew he'd die?
Before I was drafted,
I was a specialist surgeon.
But here, I'm no doctor.
I have to decide
who will live.
Sometimes I long
to be a doctor again.
I knew he'd die but
I did my best anyway.
The last vestiges of
my professionnal pride.
made me go through
the motions.
Have a drink.
You'll sleep better.
Yes, sir, I will.
How can I save
truckloads of them?
Ruptured blood vessels,
smashed bones...
Loss of blood or
gangrene gets most of them.
We've no blood
and very little medicine.
So I cut off their arms
and their legs...
Even those who don't need it...
They say that I'm an
expert at it.
I've cut off hundred of limbs.
I've crippled hundreds of men.
God knows how many.
But you had to save
their lives.
You think they believe that?
They'd be better off dead.
What I'm doing is wicked.
I either let them die,
or I cripple them. That's all.
Am I a doctor?
It's a wonder I don't
go mad.
The war's to blame.
Not you.
The war, eh?
As we attack,
our lines get longer.
The enemy turns around
and attacks our rear,
where our defense are weak.
China's too big.
It's a stupid war.
But that's the Army's problem,
not mine.
Get undressed.
I can't get drunk
in front of a nurse.
That's an order!
Yes, sir.
There's no tomorrow
on the battlefield.
We live from day to day.
What happens today,
whatever we do, fades tomorrow.
You need not worry.
Now come here!
What's your first name, Nishi?
Sakura.
Sakura?
Cherry blossom?
Just think,
if you live long enough,
you will become a 60 or 70
year-old Sakura.
Cherry blossom only last
a few brief days.
I love my name.
I'd like to live up to
my name.
Who named you?
My father.
He died before I was born.
In photographs, he looks like you.
Enough wine.
I need a shot now.
It's all in that drawer.
What kind of injection?
Never mind.
Just do as I say.
Yes, sir.
It's morphine, sir.
Hurry up. It's almost dawn.
There's no time.
I just want to sleep,
to just forget everything.
Nishi, will you stay here until
I fall asleep?
Summer nights are cold here.
If you're cold,
you can share my blanket.
I was exhausted.
I only wanted to sleep.
Next!
Awake?
It's noon.
You've slept for ten hours straight.
Get some more.
I must go.
They'll manage without you.
I said you're exhausted.
Doctor!
What?
Did anything happen?
You think that I tok
advantage of you?
You undressed me.
I didn't touch you...
Not that it matters.
What does that mean?
You wouldn't understand.
I'll go back.
We nurses went back
to Tientsin
in a truck with the sick
and wounded.
By that time, I couldn't get
Dr. Okabe out of my mind.
Perhaps I had begun
to love him.
"TIENTSIN MILITARY HOSPITAL"
How was the front line?
Do I smell?
What of?
Blood and gore. I almost
scrubbed my skin off but...
Your imagination. That's how
you become a real nurse.
Matron, what is Dr. Okabe
really like?
he's a fine officer,
an excellent surgeon.
You're in charge of
surgery this time.
Nurse, can you help
me urinate?
In a moment.
Why were both of your
arms amputated?
The left one was blown off.
Gangrene set in on the right one,
so the doctor...
Thank you.
Which doctor?
Dr. Okabe. He cought the tetanus
in time. I survived.
How long have you been here?
Six months. My wounds have
healed, but...
You can't return to fighting.
Going home? Have you a wife?
I shipped out two months
after we married.
You want to go home, then?
Yes.
But, for some reason, I can't.
I only bother the others here.
Home will be better.
Pvt. Orihara's almost
fully recovered.
He hardly feels any pain.
Why wasn't he sent home?
I wonder. But that is
not our problem.
We're short of beds
as it is.
It's best for him, and for us,
that he goes home.
Nishi, that's quite enough!
It's not your place to
make those kind of decisions.
Yes, ma'am.
I just feel sory for him.
Nurses do not have feelings.
It's your duty to keep
quiet and do your work.
I've given up.
I don't think I'll ever go home.
Never?
Thanks.
Not that I think that
the war will last forever.
Why can't you go home?
A soldier who'd lost both
legs was finally sent back.
They kept him hidden.
He can't even see his family.
They'll probably keep
him institutionalizd forever.
That's my fate, too.
But why?
If people saw me...
they'd know how terrible
war is, and hate it.
Some would think we're
losing the war.
The Army brass
wouldn't like that at all.
From time to time,
I wish I was dead.
You poor man.
It must be agony.
But I'm used to it now.
The one unbearable thing...
What is it?
It's...
No, never mind.
It's nothing.
Let's wipe you down.
Nurse Nishi, would you mind
doing it at night?
Why? I can't show you
any special favors.
I don't want the others
to see me.
Tonight, after taps.
Please.
Let's do it now.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Nurse Nishi...
Can you come every night
from now on?
If you want me to.
Please. I'd like you to.
You nurses...
...take care of our meals
and everything.
With never a frown.
It's our duty.
But there's one thing
that no one does for me.
Do you follow me?
Nurse Nishi,
I'm a man too.
I'm crippled but
I'm still healthy.
The others all can
manage somehow...
but I have no hands.
I'm helpless.
It's starting to drive
me mad.
Do you understand?
Yes, I learned about that
at nursing school.
Nurse Nishi, please save me.
Touch my body.
I beg you.
Have you asked the other
nurse such a thing?
No, ma'am I've never asked
anyone before.
Only you.
Nurse Nishi, I'm just filth.
I'm a hateful man.
I'm going to die without
ever seeing my wife again.
Nurse Nishi, please help me!
Medicine, everything
was scarce.
Poor Dr. Okabe could only
amputate arms and legs.
However trivial, I decided I'd
try to ease his burden...
...in my own way.
Nurse Nishi, am I asking too much?
Not at all.
Thank you.
You're the only one who
cared to save me.
You poor, unfortunate man.
Nurse Nishi, please
let me kiss you.
Just once is enough.
Sakura
I want to touch your body.
I don't mind, but...
Since I lost my hands...
...my toes have become
very sensitive.
I can feel with them
just like my hands.
So...
So?
Please.
Let me put my fot
between your legs.
Please!
Alright.
I'm glad.
I'm very hapy.
Go out for a walk?
Yes, he can manage.
I think it
will be good for him.
But all alone?
I'll escort him.
I'm off today.
I see.
All right, then.
We can't do much
else for him.
Have him wear a coat...
...so his arms won't be
too obvious.
Treat him to something nive.
What is it?
Where are we going?
Let's find a hotel.
Just leave everything
to me.
Let's take a bath together.
Together?
I'll wash you.
You can look at me all
you want to.
Do anything you like.
tell me anything yo want
me to do for you.
Why are you doing
this for me?
No particular reason.
I have no arms...
...but I can do things
to make up for it.
But this won't happen again.
It's the last time.
Yes.
Probably.
Remember it.
I'll never forget
what happened today.
I'm truly very happy.
Nishi, Private Orihara
commited suicide.
How?
He has no arms!
He jumped from the roof.
Fractured skull.
He died instantly.
I can't believe it.
This was found
under his pillow.
Used his mouth to
write it, I guess.
It's to you.
I haven't told anyone else.
Sakura, I'll never meet anyone
like you again.
So, there's no point in living.
Thank you and
good-bye, Orihara.
Will you inform his family?
He'll be listed as
killed in action.
And receive a promotion to
Private First Class.
I believe I killed him.
I tried to help him,
but I tortured him instead.
It does not concern you!
in war it's each for himself
or there's no surviving it!
Forget him as soon as you can.
There's too much to forget.
I can never forget.
Pvt. Sakamoto and
then Pvt. Orihara.
I killed them both.
A month later...
...we five nurses were transfered
back to the front lines.
I'm back again.
Been keeping well, sir?
Again?
It seems you and I are fated.
You've been promoted.
Congratulations.
The more people we kill...
...the more stars they give us.
It's a strange life.
Is there a major battle.
Yes, Chang Kai-shek and his
allies made an attack.
Our army is stretched
very thin.
They were cut to pieces.
The wounded are arriving in droves.
You have experience.
I'll have you removing bullets.
Can we manage?
We have to!
A handful of Japanese soldiers
are pitted against all of China.
It's no easy war.
The wounded will increase...
...we're badly undermanned here.
You'll have to work
twice as hard.
If not, good men will die.
Yes, sir! We will, sir!
The wounded are arriving, sir!
Be right there.
Water!
Give me water!
Be careful!
No dead in here!
The bullet is still in there.
Remove it.
We began operating...
...and did so for two days
and two nights.
I, alone, removed 160 bullets.
Can't save him.
He's cut to pieces.
He's lost too much blood.
Do you know why
the enemy did this?
No, sir.
He swallowed this.
It's a secret code.
A communications man.
No time to burn it,
so he swallowed it.
They cut him open
to get it.
While he was still alive?
Yes.
A fine soldier.
You did your duty well.
A hero's death.
He's dead. sew him up
and ship him out.
Shrapnel in the lower back.
I'll have to operate.
Anesthetic.
I've changed my mind.
Close him up.
Next patient.
Why did he stop?
A waste of anesthetic.
Something different
about him today.
The third night, after all of
the soldiers had been treated.
Nishi?
Yes, sir.
Come in.
Sit and have a drink.
May I ask a question, sir?
What is it?
Why didn't you operate
after the anesthetic?
Officers need not explain
to lower ranks.
I'll explain, though you probably
won't understand.
Why's that, sir?
You're a woman, but you have
no marital experience, right?
What's marriage got
to do with it?
He was wounded in the sacrum.
Here.
All the sensitive nerves...
...that govern sex are
located there.
If I operated on those
damaged nerves...
...what would be the result?
He'd lose his masculinity.
Forever!
It made me think.
If it doesn't fester,
he has a chance to live.
If a good doctor operates
back home...
...he may leave the nerves intact.
So, I changed my mind.
I see.
I have no confidence
in the work I'm doing here.
It's all wrong.
I kill those who'd recover,
men better off dead, live as cripples.
But...
to men, becoming impotent...
...is worse the being crippled.
I'm tired. Give me
a morphine shot.
I want some sleep.
Stay until I fall asleep...
...like you did last time.
Hold me, if you want to.
Yes, if I'll do, sir.
I wouldn't ask anyone else.
Will you stay 'till morning?
Don't worry.
You'll be safe with me.
I won't even touch you.
Why not?
These days, I have no interest
in woman at all.
We're in different worlds.
I only want to sleep.
But why, sir ?
You really want to know?
Yes, I do.
Alright, then.
I'll tell tou.
Since I started using morphine...
...I'm not a man any more.
I haven't been for a long time.
You have a wife, don't you?
She died three years ago,
so it doesn't matter.
Please stop using morphine.
Why?
I want to be in your arms.
What?
I think I love you.
I want you to touch me.
You love me?
What a strange girl.
You ressemble my father.
A substitute, am I?
No! I really love you.
Sorry, I can't give up
the morphine.
Why not?
I'm a doctor.
But I can't do anything here.
Without the drugs,
I can't go on living.
It's the same for soldiers.
They kill and pass it off
as patriotism. That helps...
There are so many things
that I'd like to forget.
Nishi, it's no use talking.
Just give me the shot.
Then get into bed.
Yes, sir.
I missed you.
I really did.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
You swine!
Letting maggots hatch!
What's the matter?
He removed a bandage
and let flies settle on it.
Now it's festered!
Why did you do that?
He was afraid of being
sent back.
He wants to be sent home!
What if you lose your leg?
It's better than dying!
My wife gave birth
after I shipped out.
I've never seen my son!
Dr. Okabe wants to see you immediately.
I'm off to the front lines.
One doctor, two nurses...
...and three medics.
We leave tomorrow morning.
Were you ordered to?
Yes.
It's a tough battle.
Only one doctor there...
He can't cope alone.
It's an emergency.
So, it's goodbye for a while.
Please take me with you.
It's too dangerous.
You could be killed.
No! I don't want
to leave you!
Why not?
I love you!
Love?
Do as you like.
But don't expect a life together.
This is war.
We could die any day.
I wonder.
The only way is to regard
everyone as strangers.
So stay.
Matron said that too.
But I refuse.
It's an order!
I refuse!
You disobey orders?
I do.
A traitor to Japan.
I'm afraid of one thing
more than anything.
That is working and dying
apart from you.
Don't worry. I'll be back.
Wait for me.
No, please take me with you.
You're stubborn.
Who else, then?
Nurse Tsuruzaki.
Sh's new and inexperienced.
I'll take care of her.
Even further from Japan.
It doesn't bother me.
Ever nearer to death.
I don't care.
Are you ready to die?
The cherry blossom
has such a short life.
The sooner the better.
Halt!
Is Dr. Okabe here?
Yes. What is it?
Your new orders, sir.
Go ahead.
You're to stay with us
until further orders.
We're in your hands.
We'll escort you there, sir.
Good man.
We're here, sir.
Excuse the men, ma'am.
It's their first sight of
Japanese nurses.
They're ecstatic.
Time to head back.
I'm Lt. Ishida, in command
of this outpost.
Please be seated.
Our headquarters are
fifty kilometers from here.
The enemy has begun
a massive attack.
They broke through our lines.
We've been cut off.
I see. So that's why our
journey was cut short.
Yes, sir.
The enemy are better
equipped and outnumber us.
We're unable to break through.
We're surrounded?
Yes, they're attacked twice.
A mobile squad helped
fight them off.
Just one platoon here?
Yes, equipped with four
light machine guns.
That's all we have.
Any civilian Chinese?
A handful of children
and the elderly.
Doctor!
A 'comfort woman'
has diarrhea.
I suspect cholera.
Please examine her.
Attention!
It's cholera all right.
She's badly dehydrated.
Quarantine her and give warm
water for 48 hours.
She may pull through.
How many comfort women here?
Two more, sir.
They may have it, too.
Isolate them.
Disinfect this hut thoroughly.
It's off limits to the men!
Cholera?
That's one more enemy.
Is there nothing we can do?
No drug beats cholera.
Just isolation and disinfection.
Idealy, raze the vilage
and withdraw.
That's impossible.
This is a strategic point.
We're ordered to...
...hold it at any cost.
In any case, the cholera
must be contained.
Otherwise we all die.
Issue the men an
acid gargle before meals.
The soldiers want the women
who aren't sick.
Here they are.
Back to your cribs.
No! They're in quarantine.
How about you, then?
Much more fun!
Stop it! Nurses aren't
comfort women!
You're hungry, aren't you?
Hungry for a man!
I'll pleasure you.
You animal.
This is the front. We either
kill men, screw women...
...or eat rations. That's all!
We get what we can
while we're still alive.
You idiots!
You want to die of cholera?
Get out!
You doctors get your pick
of nurses. We don't!
Twelve men and two
comfort women are infected now.
That's seven dead.
How does it look?
There will be more.
The problem is that we lost
half of our fighting strength.
If they attack,
we'll be wiped out.
Sir, all of the remaining
Chinese civilians
have slipped away.
Afraid of the cholera?
No doubt some spies too.
Spies?
They musthave introduced
the cholera virus.
They fed something to her.
So the enemy knows
out exact disposition?
Yes. Expect an attack any time.
Contact HQ.
Ask for reinforcements.
We can't, sir.
Our radio gear is down.
Send a courier.
To certain death?
We're surrounded.
No one could through alive.
We're expecting a truck
tomorrow morning.
We'll just have to wait.
What's the matter, sir?
I've caught it.
Sergeant, a signal!
That's bad.
They'll attack tonight.
The doctor's asking for you.
Go at once.
Take a break, nurse.
You're worked all night.
We'll take over.
Nurse Tsuruzaki.
Nishi?
Yes, sir.
Nurse Nishi reporting for duty, sir.
What's the latest count?
Four new cases, sir.
If I catch it,
I'll give it to you.
Same thing if you get it.
Why did you summon me, sir?
It's time for my shot.
I refuse.
But I need it.
Nishi, that's an order!
Morphine is only for the most
critical of patients.
I'm starting to suffer from
withdrawal symptoms.
Soon the fits will come.
I don't want the others
to see me half-crazed.
Please.
Go get the morphine!
If you don't quit now,
it will effect your brain.
Your heart will weaken,
and you'll die.
I'm better off dead.
It's also the drugs
that are keeping us apart.
Please give it up.
What would I gain?
You'd gain me.
You're a woman.
Yes, the woman who loves you.
How do I quit?
Please do as I say...
...as if I were a superior officer.
You're ordering me to quit?
I'll tie you up and
do what I have to do.
Tie me up?
Yes.
We're caught between cholera
and the enemy.
This could be our last night.
Be my superior officer tonight.
Do what you must.
But don't let anyone in.
The Captain is down
with cholera.
I'll take over the command.
I expect an attack tonight.
Man your positions!
Just tonight...
They'll attack tonight.
The truck comes tomorrow.
We must not surrender
the village!
Nurse Nishi...
Nishi.
You had it though...
I'm over it now.
Untie me.
How long was I thrashing?
Five hours.
Two more have got it!
Please love me as a woman.
Please love me.
I can't.
I want to be a real woman.
Not just a doll.
Make love to me.
I can't.
I'm not a man any more.
No! That's all in your mind.
Without the morphine,
you can.
Nishi, touch me.
That's what I am.
Do you understand now?
I can't love you.
No, you're all right.
Hold me close,
as tight as you can.
It's no use.
Don't give up.
You can do it.
No. I'll never return
to my old self.
You can.
I know you can.
It's Oh-One Hundred Hours.
Not long ntil dawn.
Hold out till then!
Their small arms
don't frighten me.
But, if they bring in mortars,
were all dead.
I can't hardly believe it,
Nishi.
Nurse Nishi has won.
I'm myself again.
It's like a miracle.
Please say that you love your
Sakura cherry blossom.
You want me to say
that I love you?
I want you all to myself.
You already have.
Your heart, too.
Not in wartime, no.
There's only fleeting pleasure.
Not for me.
I don't want to be
a passing fancy.
I want to be your trus lover.
I want no heart
to offer you now.
Then I'll look for it.
It's Oh-Two Hundred Hours, already.
Another three hours
and we'll be safe.
They like to attack at dawn!
Be alert!
Sakura.
I love you. Now I can say
it truthfully.
I'll never let you go.
Tonight we reached
our greatest ecstasy.
Though by tomorrow,
we may be dead.
You don't mind that?
This is all that's important
to me now.
Get me the wine.
It's my last bottle.
Let's drink a toast.
I didn't know that military
women were so sweet.
Military women?
I mean you nurses.
Put on my uniform.
Becoming?
Yes, wonderful.
a fine officer!
The boots.
Would they salute me
if I went out?
First, they'd laugh.
The sword and gun.
I'm afraid not.
Dr. Okabe,
pour wine for your superior.
Here, Major.
Sergeant!
-What is it?
-The enemy!
I prefer being a woman.
Then let me give you
some pleasure.
I can hear your heart thumping.
It's the wine.
Nishi.
I wish we'd met in
Japan in peacetime.
They're attacking.
The enemy.
There's no escape.
Will you die with me?
Yes!
By your side.
I'm 40 years old.
A long life,
yet short too.
I guess this is the end.
I can die happy.
Because I love you.
Your mark, Sakura?
I'll give you one.
Where?
The same place as yours.
Thanks to you,
I can die like a soldier.
Don't cry for me.
Enemy attack, sir!
Follow me!
Stay here!
Head down!
Hold your fire!
It's still too dark.
Don't waste ammo!
Wait 'till they're close.
What's the situation?
We're surrounded, sir.
They're using mortars
to soften us up.
Before they attack.
It doesn't look good.
But it's an hour 'till dawn.
There's a slim chance!
Good!
We're soldiers, too!
Orderlies and nurses will fight!
Fire!
Give 'em all you've got!
Pull yourself together, nurse!
Protect your patients!
Here they come!
Dig in!
Sergeant's dead, sir!
I'll take command.
Fight! fire at least
one shot before you die!
I'm scared!
You'll fight!
I'm too scared!
Come back!
Go get her!
She's gone crazy!
No, that'd be suicide.
I've killed yet again.
She's my third victim.
Nogami!
Somehow, I survived.
Not even a scratch.
Anybody still alive?
Halt!
Who goes there?
Army nurse!
We're reinforcements.
We routed them. You're safe now.
Stay back!
We have a cholera epidemic.
Cholera!
Send medical personnel
immediately.
Any other survivors?
I don't know.
The cholera and the fighting
took most of them.
I understand.
Wait here.
Nurse Tsuruzaki!
Forgive me.
This is how I will
end up, too.
The bodies were stripped
of their clothing.
Weapons, clothing, boots...
They took everything that
they could possibly use.
Doctor!
Dr. Okabe!
The End.