Last on Roots:
- Master made me head trainer today.
- That nice.
I'll pit them birds
until I can buy myself free.
You'll stay and fight chickens.
It don't matter how much I saves.
You're mine, George.
Can't you get that
through your thick skull?
It got through that time.
- You'll be worse.
- Killing massa?
- That's no more than killing a dog.
- No, damn it! No!
He's your daddy.
Don't know about you,
but I want to win and be champion.
If Speckled Red wins...
...I'll set you free.
The bird of Sir Eric Russell
is the winner!
Don't want no crying.
None of you all.
Your husband and your pappy
and I'm telling you now.
A few years. That's no time at all.
Be back.
I'm married to a free man,
George Moore.
I ain't about to live
with no slave ever again.
War, boys, it's war!
Are we gonna whup them Yankees?
I believe you want a whipping.
You won't do nothing...
...because I won't let you, Brent.
Captain's brother has been missing.
If any of you seen him, speak up.
You ain't seen the last of me, nigger.
"To all commanders in the field,
from General Robert E. Lee:
After four years of arduous service...
...marked by unsurpassed courage
and fortitude...
...the Army has been
compelled to yield...
...to overwhelming resources.
I need not tell the survivors
of many hard-fought battles...
...who remained steadfast
to the last...
...that I have consented to this
result from no mistrust of them...
...but feeling that devotion
could accomplish nothing...
...that could compensate for the loss
that attends the continuance.
I determined
to avoid the useless sacrifice...
...of those whose past services have
endeared them to their countrymen.
You will take with you...
...satisfaction coming
from consciousness...
...of duty faithfully performed.
And I earnestly pray that
a merciful God will extend you...
...his blessing and protection. "
It's over, folks. The war is over.
God save the Confederacy.
Freedom. Freedom.
We's free!
Freedom!
Free! We's free!
Freedom! Freedom!
Hey, we're free! We're free!
Freedom!
- Who that, Rufus?
- Lewis, from the Harvey place.
- What was he bellowing?
- Something about freedom.
Free?
- Nigger must be crazy.
- Yeah, must be.
Come on, mule. Come on!
Lewis, what you standing around for?
We's free.
- Who say that?
- Came over the telegraph.
The war's over. The South gave up.
Slavery's no more!
- You be fooling with me, I'll...
- Not fooling you.
I's here to tell you.
It is the God's truth.
Free?
- Mama?
- Yes?
Why you look so sad?
This is a celebration.
Thinking about your dad.
Wishing he was here.
Don't fret. Chicken George
be coming back...
...now that freedom's come.
You come dance with me instead
of slaving at the table.
Come on, just one dance.
I guess I don't have
to ask if you've heard the news.
I don't know what it means,
what it'll do.
I guess no one does right now.
I'll try to hold on to the farm.
I'm not sure how.
You all may want
to go off on your own.
But you can stay if you want.
I can't pay you anything.
Everything I have is tied up
in the crops.
Maybe you could
farm some of the land...
...and share the crop with me.
We all have to think about what to do.
I don't know what it means.
Say hello to your mom for me.
What'll it be, Harry?
Well, let's see now.
- I need...
- Mr. Brent.
I been waiting a long time.
- I'll take care of you when I'm ready.
- I was here first.
Now look here, you no-account black.
It's all right, Evan.
I'll drop by a little later.
No need for that now.
Well?
Loaf of bread and a bag of grits.
Thirty-six cents.
Hello, Evan.
Senator! Doggone,
it's good to see you!
Like old times.
I thought you was in England.
- I've just returned.
- Did you see that? Did you see?
You won't believe how they carry on.
Can't even call them niggers.
At least, not to their faces.
Well, I wouldn't fret, Evan.
Let the "niggras"...
...have their day.
- What you mean?
The same thing as old Uncle Richard
told me as a boy.
Old Brer Rabbit, when he can't
get through one way...
...he change his way...
...and by and by,
he get where he want to be!
I get you now, sir! I get you!
That's right. We is free at last.
All right. We is free at last!
- Yeah! We's free!
- Free.
Ain't got no more massas.
Nobody going to whup us again.
Nobody gonna abuse our women.
No... .
That's right.
Freedom taste good, don't it?
- Yeah, I can taste it!
- Baby!
Well, maybe it taste good...
...but it sure ain't gonna
fill our bellies.
How is we gonna feed our children?
How we gonna find shelter?
Now we is free,
what's we gonna do?
I say we go
where the pickings is better.
Yeah, yeah.
Go where? Do what?
Well, I don't know right off.
- Must be someplace.
- You is ignorant.
- Bone ignorant.
- Here now.
Ain't your fault, we's all ignorant.
We is just what
the massas wanted us to be.
None of us been taught to earn
our keep in the white man's world.
We gonna leave, we better learn...
...how to do for ourselves first.
Well, what you say, Tom?
What you say we do?
I say we stays here...
...and farms, like
we been doing all our lives.
Not for Harvey.
It gonna be part
our own land for our own selves.
Our dirt we farms!
Well, now, hold on a moment, Tom.
All I knows...
...all I ever seen
is this plantation...
...and that little town of shops.
I want to see the world, Tom.
What is freedom
if you can't go nowhere?
Of course you can go.
That the whole idea of freedom.
You wants to wander for a while,
ain't nobody gonna stop you.
Same for all of you.
But maybe we don't have to go.
Maybe now we can find
what we wants right here.
I say we gotta give freedom a chance.
And here is as good a place
to start as any.
Besides...
...what's our daddy gonna do
when he gets back and we's all gone?
How we know he coming?
All them years he been gone,
and no word.
He coming back because
he say he gonna come back.
Your dad ain't never
said nothing in his life...
...he don't mean. Hear me?
Just asking, Mama.
I don't want to hear
no more about leaving.
Ain't nobody going nowhere
till my man come back.
We is a family...
...and we is gonna stay a family.
Tom? Martha and me sure would like
to throw our lot in with you.
If you wants us, of course.
Wants you?
You just try getting away.
And you'll hear hounds baying
at your heels before long.
- Come with me.
- Where we going?
I's gonna spark you in moonlight.
Yes, you is! That gonna be some
sparking with two young ones.
Don't argue with me. Just come along.
Damned if I'll give
my niggers any part of my farm.
It's been in my family
over a hundred years.
I'd as soon sell out
to some carpetbaggers.
I'm with you. The niggers
is putting on enough airs...
...without owning land.
They can all own land,
far as I'm concerned.
- What you saying, Archie?
- Their graves.
They can own them all they want.
I respect your sentiments,
but we gotta be realistic.
Somebody has to work our land
and niggers are done as slaves.
I don't like it either,
but I got no cash for wages.
I got to parcel out shares.
I'll never owe a black nothing
except a whipping.
I always pay my debts.
You are living in the past.
You can't go around whipping blacks.
Feds won't allow it.
He's talking sense, boys.
There'll be a judge here,
and the Army'll back him up.
We ought to string up a few of them.
Just to set an example.
Now you're talking.
There's more minus than plus to that.
It sounds good...
I'll tell you about plus and minus.
"Plus" is what
I come out of the war with.
I come out "plus"
a Yankee ball in my knee.
Come out "plus" a limp
I'll have the rest of my life.
And I'm "minus" my brother, sheriff.
And I'm telling you
no white man killed him.
No white man killed another in the
last month of war. Niggers did it!
Every step I take,
every time my leg twinges on me...
...I recollect who's responsible...
...for the "pluses" and "minuses"
I gotta live with now.
I recollect who done it to me.
Niggers!
Well, gentlemen,
I think I'd better leave now.
I'm bound to uphold the law.
Gave my solemn word to do that.
It seems to me that the law
ain't what this meeting is about.
Just a minute, sheriff.
I'm going with you.
Senator.
These men respect you,
and surely you're not for violence.
I agree that misdirected violence
is dangerous, Mr. Jackson.
What do you say?
We ain't heard from you.
What should we do, senator?
It's my intention to acquire property.
A great deal of property.
If it was anybody but you,
I'd say you was plumb crazy.
The land ain't worth
a horse's apple without slaves.
Our niggra, under the misguided
new business arrangements...
...is to receive a share
of crops he works.
But before that profit is paid...
...his costs are deducted:
Grain, tools, wagons,
mules, horses, feed.
Somehow he never manages
to catch up on the costs, right?
It doesn't matter who works land.
What counts is who owns it.
Property is power, always.
Whoever has the land has the people.
I guess you know what you're doing.
Be assured I do.
By and by, Brer Rabbit,
he gonna get where he want to be.
Tom! Tom!
Where've you been with the water?
We got some thirsty mouths.
- Tom!
- Reeny?
What? What is it? What?
Rufus just came in from town.
Telegraph say...
...a white man killed
President Lincoln last night.
Shot him in the back of the head.
He's dead, Tom.
Still daylight left to work.
Did you hear her, Tom?
- Lincoln's dead!
- I heard. I know he's dead.
It won't be for nothing!
I won't let his dying be for nothing!
Tom? What is it?
To your cabins, everybody. Quick!
- Tom?
- I don't know.
You keep out of this, Harvey!
Lewis! Tom! Come on, come on!
Let's get a line here.
Get some water on this!
Jesse, come on, come on!
Everybody! Hannah!
The barn's on fire!
- Everybody move.
- Come on. Hurry up!
Pass the bucket. Pass it.
Move it, move it, everybody.
Buckets! It's getting bigger!
Hurry, before it spreads!
Get the bucket! Back! Get back!
- Back! Watch out!
- Faster, faster!
Free at last.
I don't understand it.
I just don't understand it.
We won't let them get away with this.
We worked too hard to raise our crops.
Nobody gonna ride
in here and trample...
...everything we got in the world.
We ought to get guns and fight back.
Who we gonna fight?
Damn! I don't know.
We can't let them do this.
They won't let us live here.
We should get out!
No! We ain't gonna do no such thing.
We's staying because
we has a right to stay.
This changes nothing.
It means there's some rebs around
don't know the war is over.
They won't push us off our land.
We is free men.
Besides...
...they won't get away with it.
- What you mean?
Look here.
- I don't see nothing but hoofmarks.
- Right.
- What's so special then?
- Nothing.
Hoofmarks are all the same.
But suppose they weren't?
Suppose each hoofmark had something...
...that set it apart.
- What you getting at, Tom?
- Those nightriders, that's what.
Stands to reason...
...these riders
is some of our neighbors.
Also, most of them bring
their horses to me for shoeing.
Now suppose every horse
I shoes me from this day on...
...I put a little special mark on it.
Maybe here.
Then we'd have a way of knowing
what horse the shoe belong to.
And if we know where the shoe fits... .
Why are you selling?
The place got run down during the war.
I parceled shares to the niggras...
...but nightriders came.
You don't know who?
No. They've been rampaging through
the country, destroying crops...
...scaring the niggras half to death.
Last week they tore up
everything I planted.
I don't have the heart
for farming anymore, senator.
I'm sorry to hear about
your troubles, Samuel. Very sorry.
But business is business.
In anticipation of our discussion,
I had this contract drawn up.
$5000 isn't much
for a man's life work, senator.
I couldn't agree with you more.
Unhappily, that's quite
beside the point.
You've indicated that the place
isn't in the best of condition.
And in all good faith, 5000...
...is the best I can manage.
Think about it. You might wait
for a more satisfactory offer.
We both know there won't
be any better offers.
I'll accept.
Good. That's it, then.
There's just one other thing.
My niggras owe me for seed.
A couple hundred dollars.
They've worked hard.
I wanna wipe the slate clean.
- Consider it done. Here's my hand.
- Thank you.
Ain't you done yet, boy?
Yes, sir, Mr. Drake. I's trying, sir.
Got to fix it just right.
I guess that's about it.
Much obliged, boys.
Lila.
It's time, Lila.
Lila... .
Oh, Sam, how can we? All those years.
I know, honey.
There's nothing we can do.
I'm gonna miss this place,
and you folks.
I'm sorry I had to sell,
but I didn't have much choice.
The new owner will come
in a few days to talk to you.
Meantime, I suggest you put
in your new crops.
I'm sure you'll find Senator Justin
a decent man to work for.
He agreed to wipe out your debts
so you can start from fresh.
Mrs. Harvey and I want to thank you
for your kindness...
...and your help over the years.
Goodbye and good luck to you.
Goodbye, Mr. Harvey.
Mrs. Harvey.
Now, what's the matter with y'all?
Where's your manners?
Say goodbye to the Harveys
and wish them well.
- Bye, Massa Harvey.
- Bye, massa.
You was better than some, massa.
Now that we know who they is,
I say let's kill them!
No.
Why not? I didn't know you was
particular about killing whites.
There will be no killing.
We go to the law.
White man's law?
That's right.
Sorry I'm late. I had
to help Martha with some chores.
- What we got to do...
- What's that white man doing here?
What white man?
They's only one white man
in here as I can see.
Old George?
When the killing starts,
like holds to like.
You got no call to talk like that.
He can't help it he white.
I don't care. I want him out.
And who is you to
be giving orders around here?
I ain't the only one
that feels that way!
I ain't listening to nobody
say a word against Old George!
No, Tom, it's all right.
I ain't one to tarry
where I ain't wanted.
Old George...?
Now I say we ain't going to no law!
I say we even up our own tally!
Lewis, you best sit down and shut your
mouth. You said enough for one day.
You're lucky that Mama
weren't here to hear you.
I said, sit down, little brother.
I ain't finished with you
about Old George.
We gots to go to the law,
don't you see?
Ain't supposed to be
no white man's law.
Only supposed to be one law.
- The law!
- You daft, Tom?
You try to set the law on whites,
they gonna lynch you.
Maybe, maybe not.
But we got to find out, don't we?
If we don't give the law a chance,
freedom ain't worth a damn!
Who going into town with me
to see the sheriff?
You is a plumb stubborn fool.
- Damn you!
- What are you so all fired up about?
Why you got to be the one to step
forward? You ain't even the oldest.
Why you got to be
the big man every time?
'Cause I wants to look my daddy
in the eye when next we meet.
'Cause I want our children
growing up in freedom.
'Cause too many suffered
to bring us this far to go back.
'Cause somebody got
to stand up, Irene.
Is that so?
Well, somebody got to mind
his wife and babies too.
Now who gonna do that after
they shoots you or hangs you up?
- Irene...
- Oh!
- Don't go!
- Irene.
- Oh, please. Please.
- I gots to.
Oh, Tom. I'm so scared.
Tom... . I don't want them
to hurt you.
I ain't nothing without you, Tom.
I's scared too...
...but I just can't not go.
I hate you for doing this.
I'd give anything, say anything,
do anything to make you stay.
But I's proud of you, Tom Harvey.
Oh, I's terrible proud of you.
- Now... .
- What?
There's only one thing.
I am going with you.
- You's talking crazy...
- I'm going.
- Woman, you is...
- Yes, Tom?
One fine woman.
That's what you is.
You's one fine woman.
Well, well, well.
You are one smart man, Tom Harvey.
Fancy you figuring out
something like this.
There's no doubt about it.
You got them dead to rights.
You did good coming to me, though.
Had you told anybody else about this?
Just my kin.
What you gonna do, sheriff?
I'm gonna get after them, Tom,
but I gotta handle this careful.
This is not just locking up
some Saturday night drunk.
I gotta study. I got to figure out
how to handle this.
I tell you what I want you to do.
You go on home and just go on
about your business.
Best that folks don't know you got
anything to do with this.
Yes, sir. Take care of it, then?
Well, I guess I got to, Tom.
I guess I got to.
- Tom?
- I think we done right.
- I think the law is the law.
- What happened?
He heard me out,
and he going after them.
What you two doing here?
Well, you one crazy fool.
But you still our brother.
- You sure?
- He going after them. Don't worry.
Yeah?
Can I come in?
Sure.
You all right?
I sorry about what happened.
You knows how we feel about you.
Yeah, I guess I do.
After last night, I guess I do.
Don't go on like that. Lewis got
no more sense than a bee...
...when his blood's up.
Don't mean nothing.
If Lewis didn't mean what he said,
why ain't he here?
He come around. He just needs
more time to collect himself.
Well, Tom.
I guess maybe I need some time too.
Well, sure you do.
- George?
- What?
Maybe we been here long enough.
Maybe we best be thinking
of striking out for ourselves...
...while we still young enough.
I'm sure you've been concerned
about what'll happen...
...now that Mr. Harvey has left.
Let me reassure you
that nothing is going to change.
Mr. Harvey's agreement with you
will be honored.
You'll receive a percentage
of the crops you raise.
Well, what do you say to that?
It's very kind of you, sir.
But if Mr. Brent gonna be in charge,
I don't think my people wanna stay on.
Well.
You're free to go, of course.
Just as soon as you pay up your debt.
What debt?
According to the farm's ledger,
you was advanced $235...
...in seed, grain and supplies
against future crops.
But Mr. Harvey said he fixed that.
Told us we was free and clear.
The agreement's on file
at the county clerk's office.
I didn't see
that in the deed of sale.
Now you work hard on your share,
it'll reduce your debt considerably.
$235 dollars ain't all that much.
But in the meantime,
don't nobody try leaving here.
This is a legal matter
and the sheriff will lock you up.
Senator, sir?
Is this what you wants?
I thought I made it clear, boy.
Mr. Brent speaks for me.
Mr. Johnson.
We're wondering what your plans are,
now that Mr. Harvey's left.
I ain't got no special plans.
I'll just go on working my share.
That won't do. Me and the senator,
we got feelings...
...about whites sharecropping
with niggers.
Why should a smart boy
wanna work like a field hand...
...when there are
other opportunities to consider?
We need someone to keep his eye on
things, make sure the work gets done.
The job's yours if you want it.
I ain't much about overseeing.
I'll pay you a good wage and if
it works out, maybe your family...
...can move into the main house here.
Now that's fair, ain't it?
- All right. I'll do it.
- Good boy, Georgie. Good boy.
We'll settle the details later.
Senator?
I think that's everything
for now, Evan.
I'm looking forward to a long
and happy association.
You'll find me a fair man
to work for...
...if you're willing
to meet me halfway.
Next time I'm here,
I expect to see all these darkies...
...out in the fields
where they belong.
I want you reporting to me regular.
I do hope you're gonna
behave yourself, boy.
I surely do.
Oh, howdy, sheriff. Come on in.
Howdy, Evan.
You know, Evan, we've been friends
for a long time.
I want you to know that.
I know that, Charlie.
What's got into you?
And I'm on your side.
You understand that, don't you?
Sheriff, you been drinking?
No, I don't think
I could get drunk tonight.
No. Why? Why can't you get drunk?
I know who every single one
of them nightriders is.
I got proof I'm gonna turn over
to the Federal Circuit Court judge...
...when he comes next weekend.
- You got what?
You heard me, Evan. I got proof.
Tom Harvey gave it to me.
I don't want to know what I know.
But I know it for a real fact...
...unless somebody does something.
I'm sworn to do something that'll
make me a hated man in this county.
Unless somebody does something to make
Tom Harvey pull back his evidence.
Do something like what?
Evan, I'm sick enough as it is!
At myself, for letting it go this far.
Do I have to lay out the plan too?
No. No need for that.
You've done enough, sheriff.
You've done enough.
I guess I'll just have to see...
I don't wanna know another word.
I'm an officer of the law.
Sometimes an officer of the law...
...just ain't got no choice in some
things. You understand what I mean?
Won't nobody misunderstand, sheriff.
I'll see to that.
Well, thank you, Evan.
I'm much obliged to you.
Good night, Evan.
Tom Harvey!
We want you, nigger!
Tom. Tom!
Get yourself out here, boy.
Or we're gonna burn your kinfolk.
Tom.
Move.
Now!
George.
They's six of them, Martha. Six!
Why should I? Like holds to like.
That's what they told me, ain't it?
Ain't it?
Thought you was smart going
to the sheriff, didn't you?
This here's a bad nigger!
Talking about the law instead of
doing his work, paying his debts.
So we're gonna teach him
how to be a good nigger!
It's best you study hard what's gonna
happen, so you won't make mistakes.
Because you ain't never
gonna leave here! Never!
All right! Get on with it!
Damn it! Now you leave my nigger be!
Stay out of this.
Boy needs a lesson.
- What's he done?
- He's fixing to set the law on us.
All right, he's got it coming!
But you put me in charge here
and nobody whips my niggers but me!
Let him do it.
- Why you stopping?
- No use. He's senseless!
It don't matter.
He'll remember when he wakes up.
If he wakes up. Now get on with it.
Looks like you're on top of that!
Make sure you teach him
how to be a nigger now!
- Tom! Tom!
- God, let him be alive!
Oh, God, let him be alive!
Please. Help him.
Let him be alive.
Irene? Irene. I'm sorry, Irene.
I was just trying...
...to make them think
I was doing their job.
You ain't got nothing to be
sorry about, Old George Johnson.
You just saved my man's life!
You just saved my man's life.
I'm sorry, Old George.
I was wrong. Dead wrong.
- Let's get him inside.
- He'll be all right.
- He's gonna be all right.
- Easy.
- Careful now. Be careful.
Oh, Tom.
What we gonna do? What we gonna do?
Ain't nothing we can do.
We ain't never gonna get away
from here. Never!
At least not alive, anyway.
All my fault.
I should've let y'all go
when you wanted.
- Instead of...
- Now you just hush, Mama.
Don't you go blaming yourself.
We stayed here because we wanted to.
Tom? What we gonna do?
Get my boy out of here.
I don't want him to see me like this.
Martha.
Lewis?
Yeah, Tom?
Take that shovel
and dig up the floor...
...under Bud's bed.
- What you want me to do that for?
- Do it!
Bud, don't worry about your daddy.
He's gonna be fine.
He's a strong man.
Ain't none stronger.
He'll be up and around in no time.
I'm gonna kill
those white men someday.
- You shouldn't talk like that.
- I'm gonna kill them.
Bible says it ain't right
to kill people, Bud.
Do it say it right
for them to whip my daddy?
It don't say that neither.
Then I'm bound to get them.
Which ones, Bud?
Couldn't see their faces.
I'll find a way
to get the ones who done it.
Suppose you make a mistake?
Suppose you hurt white folks
that ain't done your daddy no harm?
I'll do what I gotta do.
Then I guess you might as well
start with me.
I didn't mean you.
Well, I sure am white.
I'm white as a cotton ball.
If you start hurting whites
for being white...
...then soon you'll get
to me and Old George.
I don't wanna kill you.
That's what happens when you
hurt folks for their skin color.
You won't be any better than them.
I hate them. Hate them!
Hate them for what they done...
...not because they's white.
Me and mine is white.
But we love you...
...just like our own.
If you'll let us love you.
Oh, Bud.
Oh, my poor little Bud.
This is a cavalry officer's pistol.
Got "J.B. " carved in the handle here.
Lord God!
- It be Jemmy Brent's. Put it away.
- Give it to me.
Husband, what is you thinking of?
They catch you with that gun,
they gonna kill you.
I only knows one thing:
Ain't nobody ever gonna whip me again!
Ever!
Someone's coming!
Blow out the candles.
Open the door slow, whoever you is...
...or I'll blows you apart.
You don't wanna do that, son.
Not unless you gonna make yourself
an orphan child.
Daddy?
My man.
Grandpa.
Chicken George!
What's this?
I got news for you.
The old chicken-fighter
has come home to roost!
Look at you.
Good thing you come home
after dark, George.
Why you say that?
I's so old and ugly I might scare you
to death in God's proper light.
I don't see you with my eyes...
...I sees you with my heart.
- So I is old and ugly?
- What you talking about?
Was a time when you used to
look at me with your eyes.
All right, I'll look at you now.
Come on.
I say come on around here.
You still is beautiful, Tildy.
You still my beautiful woman.
Sure, time has left a few tracks
in its passing...
...like it's done me.
But you got a sprinkling
of moonbeam in your hair. Look.
And your eyes... .
Your eyes still have that
little girl looking out of them.
I feel like
a little girl tonight, George.
Been so long.
It's just like the very first time.
What's going on here?
Tom whipped, and this
Evan Brent in charge.
Nothing that won't keep till morning.
Hush now.
Brent and his like done stole
most our lives away.
Let's keep this one night
for ourselves.
Oh, my sweet, sweet Mama.
Yes, indeed. The family sure owes
a lot to these two birds.
With the money they won me,
I bought us some land in Tennessee.
Land so rich and black
you can plant...
...a pig's tail and a hog will grow!
Daddy...
...ain't you heard a word we said?
We can't go to Tennessee,
can't go nowhere.
You mean Brent and his bunch?
I wouldn't worry about that none.
I been in worse situations in the war.
What you getting at?
All right.
Let's look at it
like it was a military operation.
Here we are,
surrounded by the enemy...
...outnumbered, outgunned...
...and half our troops
is women and children.
On the face of it, it looks bad.
Look like we in a hopeless position.
And that's our one strong point.
Don't sound like
no strong point to me.
Way I figure it...
...Brent and this senator must be
feeling mighty smug.
Like they got us
where they want us.
Toeing the line, scared to death.
Well, from now on...
...we gonna do everything we can...
...to make sure they go
right on feeling that way.
Clumsy fool!
Look after Mrs. Randall.
I wanna see what's going on out there.
You dumb black boy.
Can't I trust you to do nothing?
I want every grain of that
back in the sack!
I's trying, Mr. Johnson.
You ain't trying hard enough.
I don't want no sacks full of dirt.
Those darkies...
...they was bad enough under slavery,
but now they's useless.
I's done, sir.
What are you waiting on, boy?
Get the rest of the sacks
out of there!
Would you move your black backside?!
Move it! Move it!
- Well, George.
- Oh, Mr. Brent.
I see you've learned.
I wasn't too sure about
overseeing them darkies...
...as you well know,
but I wanna tell you...
...it beats farming all to hell.
- I wanna thank you.
- That's all right, son.
Just don't you let up.
Don't you worry.
I keeps on them all the time.
You'll do, Georgie, you'll do.
Oh, please, sir.
Please.
We don't want no more trouble.
If my man goes up
in front of the judge...
...they'll kill him, sure.
I got two little babies, sir.
Now what we gonna do
if they kills my man?
Oh, please, sir.
You mean Tom wants to
forget this whole thing...
...and drop the charges?
I swears to God you won't never
hear from him again.
Well, you seem like a good girl...
...so I'm gonna do something
that I hadn't ought to do.
This is your husband's property.
You do with it what you want to do.
God bless you, sir.
I think that's about everything
he asked for.
Thank you, sir.
Just a minute there, boy.
I ain't done with you yet.
- Yes, sir?
- Fetch me a dipper of water, nigger.
Yes, sir.
I do believe that's the sweetest water
I ever tasted.
Yes, sir.
Fetch you some more, sir?
No.
But I sure did appreciate it.
You're shaping up into a good boy.
Thank you, sir. I's trying.
You can run along now.
You see that uppity Tom fetch me
a dipper of water, nice and polite?
- Yes, I did.
- Did my heart good.
Charlie tells me Tom's wife was in...
...begging to have them charges dropped.
We can rest easy
about the Harvey place.
- Yes, it looks that way.
- Something troubling you, senator?
It's been my experience
one should not depend...
...on an unbroken series
of fortunate events.
This idyllic behavior is either
to conceal furtive activity...
...or a tribute to George Johnson's
ability to work a miracle.
- Johnson seems to have things in hand.
- I do not reject the miracle.
I simply think
it should be put to the test.
- Have you been to the farm yourself?
- Not recently.
I've been busy at the store.
A little drive out there, unannounced,
might teach us something.
Stop lollygagging.
Put your backs into it!
You think this is a picnic?
I got my eye on you.
You put your black back into it,
or I'll do it for you!
Good day, senator. Mr. Brent.
Hello, young man.
Wanted to see
how you're getting on.
Ain't as far long with
the planting as I'd like to be.
We's cleaning up
what the nightriders did.
But things is coming along.
It's coming along.
- Massa Johnson?
- Lewis, what is it now?
We'd like you to look
at the fence we's fixing.
Go on back and keep working,
and I'll be there directly.
- Thank you, sir.
- Go on, now.
The blacks, they just
like little kiddies.
Can't do nothing on their own.
I guess we ought to get
back to town.
Seems like Mr. Johnson's
got his work in order.
Be seeing you, George.
- You keep after them, you hear?
- Don't you worry none.
Good day, senator.
Oh, Mr. Brent!
Mr. Harvey's mules
is on their last legs.
They ain't hardly pulling
worth their feed.
If I could have me six young mules...
...I could plant another 1 00 acres.
Senator?
I think Mr. Johnson's enterprise
ought to be encouraged.
I'll get them out here
as soon as I can. Anything else?
No, I think I got
everything I need now, sir.
- I'll get six mules out tomorrow.
- I'm much obliged.
Mr. Brent!
You gotta come out to the farm.
It's Georgie!
All right, missy. Just calm down.
Tell me what happened.
Georgie had an accident.
I think his leg is broke.
- We better go get Doc Farrell.
- I went there first.
He's on his way. But my husband
want you to come.
He's afraid the darkies will
take advantage and run off.
- Mr. Brent, you gotta come.
- All right! Calm down.
It'll be all right.
Get back to your husband.
I'll ride out soon as I can.
Get! Get, you hear!
Over here, Mr. Brent.
How's he doing, doc?
He all right, Mr. Brent.
But you ain't.
What are you doing? Put that gun down.
We leaving this county.
We're making sure you won't stop us.
You been bamboozled, Mr. Brent!
Why, you dirty nigger lover!
Mr. Brent...
...it ain't I loves niggers so much...
...it's just I don't like you at all.
You're not as smart as you think.
That ain't the point.
The point is, we ain't as dumb
as you think we is.
Because if we's that dumb,
what's that make you?
We're taking charge. Drop that gun.
Think I'm crazy enough
to ride out here alone?
I didn't live through no war to walk
into an ambush with eyes wide open.
Boy...
...if you got any skin left
on that black carcass of yours...
...you're about to lose it.
Where's the rest of them
no-account niggers?
Believe I asked you a question.
- Did you hear me?
- No! Please! They're in the barn.
Come on out of there!
I know you're in there.
I'll be hard on you
if I have to go in there.
Break that door down.
Hold it right there, boss.
Now...
...I'd drop them guns...
...kind of nice and easy like.
Pick up the pop pistols.
Now, what if...?
This is the way my captain
used to teach us to think.
"What if the enemy figures out
your first plan?
What you gonna do?
Get yourself another plan! "
Who the hell are you?
I'm the daddy of these boys.
Don't you remember me?
You chased me out of the county once.
Now, all I wants to do...
...is leave the county peaceably.
Tie them up, boys.
Tom, he all yours now.
How do it feel, Mr. Brent?
To be tied up
like a hog for slaughter...
...waiting for your flesh
to turn to jelly?
What do you feel like to be
on the other side of the lash?
No, Tom... .
Please.
Time to go.
Get moving.
Get the children back there.
Sit down.
Maria Jane!
Come on up, Bud.
Got your young'uns, Tom?
My boy Tom has a good heart
and I admire his thinking.
If you bother me or mine ever again...
...I'll kill you.
- Let's go.
- No.
Not yet.
I know you's sorry to be leaving.
We got to get moving.
I been sitting here,
trying to remember.
Been living here maybe 1 4, 1 5 years.
I lost count.
I helped Irene birth
all the grandchildren.
Seen them grow.
I held her second baby in my arms
when she die.
We buried that sweet lamb
by the willow.
I knows every chink in every wall
the winter wind blow through.
I know...
...it hard, old woman, leaving.
Hard?
Chicken George...
...you is a foolish old man.
There ain't nothing hard
about being happy.
This ain't never been our home.
Never belong to us no way!
This here is Massa Harvey's
nigger quarters.
When we ride out of here, I ain't
never gonna think of it again!
Go on there, mule!
Let's move on.
Mr. Brent! Thank the senator
for these new mules.
We never could've made it
without them!
We's here!
This here our land.
Go on, mule, go on!
Hold up there.
You get down easy, honey.
Here's home.
Bud.
The first slave in this family
was my granddaddy...
...Kunta Kinte.
But he weren't always a slave.
Before he was a slave
he was a free man...
...in another country.
A country called Africa.
But then the slavers,
they catch him...
...when he went to find some wood
to make a drum...
...and they brung him to America.
To a place called Annapolis.
But Kunta Kinte...
...he never forget where he come from.
He never forget Africa.
He never forget
the words he spoke as a child.
How ko mean a fiddle...
...and Kamby Bolongo mean a river.
He never stop fighting against
his chains to be free again.
Not even after they cut off half his
foot to keep him from running away.
And before he die,
he give that dream of freedom...
...to his daughter.
Kizzy.
My mama.
And before she die,
she give that dream to me.
And I've tried to keep that dream
alive in all you children...
...till that day come.
Hear me, old African...
...the flesh...
...of your flesh...
...has come to freedom.
You is free at last.
We is free!
The family did settle
in Henning, Tennessee.
Matilda passed away
before Chicken George.
And he enjoyed life among
his children and grandchildren...
...until he died
at the ripe old age of 83.
The blacksmith, Tom,
and his talented Irene prospered.
Their daughter, Cynthia, married
a quiet black man named Will Palmer...
...who came to own
the town 's lumber mill.
They had a daughter named Bertha...
...who attended Lane College...
...where she met and married
Simon Alexander Haley.
In 1 92 1, the Haleys welcomed a son...
...the seventh generation descendant
of Kunta Kinte.
That boy was me, Alex Haley.
I never forgot those stories which
my grandmother Cynthia told me.
And in 1 963, after I had retired from
a career in the U.S. Coast Guard...
...I became obsessed with knowing
more about our family...
...more about its history.
It was a search that would take me
1 2 years to complete.
And those things that I learned,
I wrote in a book called Roots.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH]