[Man Panting]
Ca Lu, halfa click that way,
two-nine-zero.
- I say we go right up the middle.
- Negative.
One round flank up the hill, the
other one right through the swamp.
Heads, you get the hill.
Tails, you get the swamp.
Flip the motherfucker.
- See you in Ca Lu.
- All right.
[ Mouths Words ]
[Man Speaking
ln Vietnamese]
[ Vietnamese ]
[ Vietnamese Continues]
[ Shouting ]
Delta Two, what's your SITREP?
Over.
What do you got,
Gibson?
Nothing, sir.
Delta One, Delta Two, SITREP. Over.
Two-one, contact!
Contact way out!
[ Screams ]
Cease fil re! Cease fil re!
Go, go, go.
Let'sget 'em!
Come outta there!
Put your hands on your head!
Get on your knees now!
Come on!
Down, down.
Come on out ofthere!
Now!
Howmanyyouslopes are out here?
Huh? What'syourunit? What's in it?
Tuan, get over here!
Talk to these motherfuckers!
-Find out how many ofthem are here!
-[ Translating ln Vietnamese ]
Where are they? What's in it?
Talk to me, goddamn it!
[Tuan Continues]
Aah!
Two, this is One Actual.
Where are you?
[ Gunfil re On Radio ]
Uuh!
Other side ofthe tree line.
I'm in the water unable to withdraw.
Unable to withdraw! I'm calling
in a fil re mission on this position!
- Hurry up and drop that arty!
- They're all over!
[ Static,
Transmission Crackling ]
[ Man ]
Go left! Get out there!
Tell this man to get on that radio
and pull his men off Hodges.
Tell him to break contact
and move his men north of Ca Lu!
[ Translating ]
Tell him I ain't playin'!
Pull his men off Hodges now!
[Tuan Continues]
I ain't bullshittin'
with you.
Eitheryou call your men off
Hodges,
or this motherfucker's
dead and you're next.
- [Tuan Continues]
- Last warnin '!
Uuh!
Call your men
off Hodges now!
If he does, he can go.
He's got my word on that.
Ifyou don't,
I'll kill you where you stand.
[Tuan Continues]
[ Groaning ]
[ Vietnamese ]
[ Men Shouting ]
[ Groaning ]
[Man On Radio] Two, this is
OneActual: Youstill with me?
Crank off a pop-up
ifyou're still alive.
[ Grunts ]
You got a reprieve, you hear me?
You don't get to die today.
Yougotyour "HaiIMary: "
######[Blues Rock]
Hey! It's the colonel
with his coveron!
[Cheering, Applause]
All right!
Make way, make way!
- I guess the drinks are on me.
- All right!
At ease!
Listen up.
- ######[Stops]
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the reason we're allhere,
ColoneIHayes Hodges:
[ Cheering ]
He's calling it a career after
32 years ofdistinguished service.
All right, all right.
Colonel, we got you a gift
and a surprise,
so don't act like
you're not coming up here.
[ All Chanting ]
Speech! Speech! Speech!
Speech! Speech!
Speech!
[Cheering]
Hey, my man!
Good to see you.
You damn well better be. I came
halfway 'round the world for this.
Hey, get up here.
[Man]
Speech!
The sword, Colonel.
You know the story, Hayes.
Marine Lieutenant Presley O'Banion
defeated the Barbary pirates...
on the shores ofTripoli
in 1 805.
Out of gratitude, the pasha
gave him the Mameluke sword.
Marine offilcers have
carried one ever since.
It's the symbol
ofa warrior,
and you are a warrior.
- [Cheering]
- The best I ever served with.
This man's been riding a desk
for the past 28 years,
but not because he wanted to.
He knows how to fil ght.
It's in his blood. Ah-ooh!
[Man] What areyou
gonna do now, Colonel?
Well, uh-- Well.
Heh! No more wars to fil ght,
no more trials to lose.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- [Laughter]
So I expect I'll do
some teaching at V.M.I.
I will recon the local restaurants
in a concerted effort...
- to fil nd out what civilians eat.
- [Laughter]
Ofcourse, I intend to continue
serving my country...
by honorably depleting
the trout streams...
ofthe Southern United States
with my fly rod!
That's about it.
Let's get outta here.
- I missed you.
- Yeah, I missed you too.
How's the kid,
the smart Hodges?
You know, he studies more than
any two people. I never see him.
- You gotta filx that.
- Yeah.
- Got my orders.
- Oh, yeah? What?
Got command ofthe 24th
Marine Expeditionary Unit.
- Special Operations capable.
- Congrats. Huh! Congrats.
- Yeah.
- Outstanding.
All I gotta do is lash
'em together, take 'em to sea.
[ Quietly ]
That's, uh... outstanding.
You ain't missin' nothin', Hodge.
It's a whole new ball game.
No friends, no enemies,
no front, no rear.
No victories, no defeats,
no Mama, no Papa.
- Yeah.
- We're orphans out there.
It's funny, you know?
One guy walks out through a swamp,
he gets to come home to a desk.
Another guy drives up a hill
and he gets to still be doin' it,
all over the flip
ofa goddamn coin.
You know, that's--
It's funny.
You gave good service
to the corps, Hodge.
To think otherwise
would bejust plain crazy.
- You'd have gotten your command.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
[ Sighs ]
[Man On P:A:,
lndistinct]
What's up,John?
Terry, we've been ordered
to the Arabian Sea, GulfofAden.
This comes straight down Second
Division through General Perry.
The American Embassy in Yemen
is surrounded...
by a crowd ofdemonstrators.
The crowd isn't hostile,
but it's large enough...
to spook their government
into pulling their security forces.
Twenty-fourth Marine Expeditionary
Unit's gonna provide extra security.
We're gonna baby-sit, Colonel.
Just show our presence.
Remember, though, if it turns
hot, we're looking at an evac.
We got an ambassador and his family
there. Let me run you through this.
Here's your
potential L.Z.s.
Marines at the embassy advise we can
gain entrance through the back way.
Here's some stairs where you
can deploy your men to the roof.
These are your
over-watch positions.
I'll take them in
myselfquietly.
One platoon, TRAP team,
put everyone else on Ready Five.
My thoughts exactly,
Colonel.
[ Indistinct Shouts ]
[ Chanting ln
Native Language ]
[Chanting Continues]
[ Boy ]
What's wrong, Mommy?
The people are upset
about some things, darling.
- Are they mad at Daddy?
- No, they're not mad at your daddy.
Why are they yelling?
They're trying to get attention
so that people will listen to them.
Sir, state security analysts
are asking for an assessment.
Assessment? We're getting the hell
out of here. That's the assessment.
The Sixth Fleet marines
are in the air, sir.
Ifthey think I'm gonna
tough this one out, they're crazy.
Tell Mrs. Mourain to start packing.
We're going home.
Shall I indicate
we're ready to evacuate?
Ask them where the hell
are those helicopters!
The ambassador wants to know
where the choppers are.
You heard me.
Where the hell are the choppers?
[Indistinct
Radio Transmission]
[ Shouting ]
Lock and load!
[Bullets Ricochetting]
[Man On Radio] We're gonna
take a betterlookbefore we go in:
[ Grunting, Groaning ]
Wagon Wheel, this is Red Man.
I'm over the embassy.
This ain 't no baby-sit:
It's ugly down there:
[Man On Radio]
RedMan, Wagon Wheel:
Rogerthat:
Let'sgo forthe evac:
Put it on deck.
We're going in the north side.
[ Indistinct Shouts ]
There! Go!
- Captain Lee!
- [Lee] Yes, sir!
Nobody comes over those walls
or through those gates. Nobody!
One Alpha, secure all entries.
Tango and Bravo, on the walls!
- Move, move, move!
- Last man! Last man!
Pull back! Pull back!
[ Indistinct ]
Take cover!
- [ Childers ] You speak English?
- Yes!
Where's the ambassador?
He's topside! Go topside!
[ Man ] Take that corner!
Take that side! Move!
Aah!
Move, move, move!
Go, go!
Bravo Two, left!
Move, move, move!
Incoming sniper fil re!
Stay down! Stay down!
- Two blue, clear!
- [ Mrs. Mourain Yelps ]
- Who's Mrs. Mourain?
- I-l'm Mrs. Mourain.
- Where's the ambassador?
- He's in there. Are we leaving?
The helos are outside, ma'am,
but that's up to the ambassador.
Stay away from
the windows, please.
Duck! Ow!
Aah! Colonel! Please!
My God! Are the helicopters here?
What kept you people so long?
We're ready to evacuate, unless you
want to stay and run the embassy.
I want to go right... now!
We called hours ago!
All right, sir, come to me.
Stay calm and come to me.
- Stay calm: Come to me: Stay low:
- We're like targets!
- We're sitting targets!
- Follow Sergeant Mac. Go!
Come on! Down there!
Down there! Right there!
Right there!
Down there! Down there!
Go ahead, ma'am!
Go ahead!
Go ahead, ma'am, go ahead!
Come on, son. Come on!
- What's your name, son?Justin?
-Justin.
[ Sobbing ]
Come on,Justin! Come on!
-Justin, what's that you got there?
- A flashlight.
We're gonna ride in a helicopter.
Wanna bring that with you?
- Huh? Come on. Come on!
- Mommy!
Let's go, ma'am, go!
Go, go, go!
All TRAP Unit six,
stay low, stay low!
We got crap coming over the walls
and sniper fil re at 1 00 meters. Over.
Stay low! Sit tight,
sit tight, sit tight!
[ Continues, lndistinct ]
Colonel, we got three marines hit!
One is K.I.A.
One Alpha says they're gonna
try to breach the front gate!
- Tell them to wait out!
- Roger that!
- [ Indistinct Shouts ]
- [HelicopterBlades Whirring]
[Man]Put the missus on board
first: Get in there, Mr: Ambassador:
I'll personally recommend you--
Where's the belt?
- I'll personally recommend--
- Hold it!
Where areyougoing? What? Colonel!
Colonel, we can't wait here!
Come on! Let's get out!
Come on!
Let's go! Christ!
[Man] We're leaving
injust a fewseconds:
Let's go! Why are we sitting here?
Why are we sitting here?
-Sir, please! Look at me. Stay calm.
-Let's go!
She's free, sir!
Go!
Hope you know how
to fold this, sir.
Thankyou, Colonel.
I'll never forget this.
Sir.
Go!
[ Groaning ]
[ Panting ]
- [ Grunting, Groaning ]
- [Man]Krasevitch is hit!
Corpsman! Corpsman!
Shit!
Goddamn it!
Fuck!
Six, Red Man.
Engage hostile targets
as they appear.
Deadly force is authorized.
How copy? Over.
Red Man, Trans Six Actual.
Negative, negative!
Be advised, I have women
and children in my line offil re.
I got snipers in the buildings
at 400 meters. How copy? Over.
What is it about this order
you don't understand, Captain Lee?
Sir, are you ordering me
to fil re into the crowd? Over.
Yes, goddamn it!
Waste the motherfuckers!
Six out.
Engage! Engage!
Open fil re!
[ Screaming ]
Cease fil re!
Stay down! There may still be
snipers out there.
Cease fil re!
- Cease fil re, goddamn it!
- Everybodystay down!
There may still be snipers
out there. Stay down!
Get down!
[ Wailing ]
[Woman Screaming]
- Sergeant Mac.
- [Mac]Sir?
Contact all stations.
Mission complete.
Launch medevacs.
Dead and wounded out fil rst.
Aye, Colonel:
Allstations, this is RedMan:
Mission complete:
Move allmedevacs to L:Z:
Howcopy? Over.
[CarHorn Honks]
[Siren Blaring]
[Man]
The F:B:l: investigation shows:::
that all the bullet holes
in the embassy wall:::
came from directly across
the way, from thesnipers:
Any weapons or ammo found
among the dead or wounded?
No, sir: Nothing:
However, intelligencesuggests:::
this could have been
a terrorist operation.
Any proof?
This is a tape from
the embassy security system.
- Want me to thread it up?
- No. I don't want to watch videos.
I don't want to hear about
ammo casings in some building,
'cause here I got
83 dead people--
unarmed--
women, children, old men.
Another hundred or so
critically wounded.
Here I got an international
crisis of mega fucking proportions!
Bill, you know there have been
regular reports...
ofa terrorist
plot against this embassy.
This was a regularly scheduled
protest. It was every week.
It was the usual bullshit about
American presence in the gulf.
Have you looked at these?
I mean, I'm just assuming you have,
since they're on the front page
ofevery newspaper in the world.
It's not that the rest ofthe
world wants to hold us responsible,
we are responsible!
We can't even have
the appearance ofa cover-up.
That does not excuse us
from our duty, Mr. Sokal.
We sent Colonel Childers in there,
and the mission went to shit.
We can't go after the man
who carried out his orders...
and ignore the people
who issued those orders.
Childers ordered the slaughter...
of innocent women and children.
Get that straight right now.
I'll tell you
what we ought to get straight.
We lost three
United States Marines.
They lost 83!
Now, are we gonna go to war
with Yemen over it?
We're covering our ass all over
the Middle East right now, General.
Because ofyour man's
hotheaded miscalculation,
we are in danger of losing embassies
in Saudi,Jordan and Egypt.
We're in danger
of losing our presence...
with every moderate
in the region.
Now they're gonna scream
"cover up."
The screaming will get so loud we'll
be sending Marines back over there,
and the body count ofAmerican
dead is gonna be higher than three.
I see where you're going
with this, Mr. Sokal.
Will you be needing me
anymore today?
No.
No, that's fil ne, General.
Thankyou.
Good day to you, sir.
[ Sighs ] Where do you think
you're going with that?
- You don't want to look at it.
- Nobody's lookin' at it.
Why should the United States
be held responsible...
for the actions ofone man?
What ifthe crowd
had weapons?
What ifthis shows
they did fil re fil rst?
He could have fil red over
their heads, this moron!
Didn't he know where he was?
The Middle East!
He could have isolated
on the snipers.
He could have
avoided confrontation.
He could have done
50 fuckin' things!
Instead, he destroyed a fragile
trust, put his own men in danger--
Fuck this guy!
Forget this tape.
I don't want to watch it.
I don't want to testify about it.
I don't want it to exist.
[Men Shouting ln Distance,
lndistinct]
[ Women Together ]
Good morning, sir.
[ Together ]
Aye, aye, sir.
- [Man, lndistinct]
- [General]Assoon asit's time:
General, Colonel Childers
reporting as ordered, sir.
- Give us a minute, Skip.
- Yes, sir.
Colonel, it's my duty to inform
you that you've been charged with--
[ Sighs ]
You know the drill.
This is the Article 32
investigation.
You're facing
a general court-martial...
and charged with violation
ofat least three articles--
everything from "breach of peace"
to "conduct unbecoming."
But the bottom line-- 83 counts,
violation ofArticle 1 1 8, murder.
You issued an illegal order
to have your marines...
fil re into a group
of innocent civilians.
Murder, sir?
I'm the convening authority, so I've
gotta get this B.S. out ofthe way.
Sign here, initial here.
You're not a flight risk, so there
won't be any pretrial confil nement.
This court-martial convenes
in eight days...
by direct order of
the national command authority.
Doyou want me to call
Bob Bennett orone ofthoseguys,
or do you want to go
with base legal?
Terry, goddamn it,
we've been friends for20years:
You want to tell me exactly
what the hell happened out there?
I lost marines. The crowd
was hostile. They fil red on us.
They fil red fil rst, sir.
I want you to know
I did everything in the world...
to keep this from happening.
It'sjust out
of my hands now.
Thanks a lot.
When's the last time you
actually caught something here?
- Two years.
- [Chuckles]
- I really need your help.
- I'll help. Anything you need.
You want me to take the stand?
I'll be a character witness.
No, you don't understand
what I'm asking.
I want you
to be my lawyer.
[ Sighs ]
I'm a good enough lawyer to know
you need a better lawyer than me.
'Sides that, I'm short.
Two-nine plus one wake-up,
and I'm gone.
You need one ofthose
Washington cats.
I don't want some Starbucks
drinker who's never seen combat.
-I need somebody who's been shot at.
-Yeah, I've been shot at.
That's what I am--
a shot-up marine.
As a matter offact,
that's all the hell I am.
No, wait a minute.
I'm also a weak lawyer.
I'm a very weak lawyer--
and the government is gonna come
at you with everything they've got.
Major, Bill Sokal. It's a pleasure
to meet you. Come on in.
Let me introduce you.
Gentlemen, this
is Major Mark Biggs.
He'll be prosecuting
the Childers court-martial.
The marines put the major
through Stanford Law,
and he owes them a couple ofyears
before he takes over the world.
You know GeneraILowry:
I'dlikeyou to meet thegeneral
oftheJoint Chiefs ofStaff,
General West, and the secretary
of Defense, Mr. Wyatt.
Have a seat.
Make yourselfcomfortable.
What I gather from our esteemed NSC
advisor and secretary ofstate...
is that we've got a trial
in two weeks.
-Seems awfully damned fast.
-Everyone in this room will agree...
it's in the national interest that
this trial be moved along quickly.
The Article 32 investigation
was complete and comprehensive.
It all seems to point
in one direction.
Has he got a lawyeryet?
He's requested a military
attorney, Colonel Hayes Hodges.
Second Marine Division, Lejeune.
Any relation to
General H. Lawrence Hodges?
His son.
Larry Hodges was one ofthis country's
most distinguished offilcers.
What do we know about
Colonel Hayes Hodges?
He's a guy who got
blown apart in Vietnam,
then went to Georgetown Law
and became a cynic.
Is that about right, Major?
He was 67th in his class
at Georgetown, sir.
He doesn't take too many cases,
doesn't win too many.
He apparently went through an ugly
divorce, had a drinking problem,
- retiring in two weeks:
- Can we guarantee we get this guy?
Sir, if I may
say something?
I am not a hired gun.
I accepted this assignment...
'cause I believe in the merits
ofthe government's case.
I am not gonna stack the deck
against this guy.
I will try this case
on good evidence only.
I'm glad to hear it.
[Man]
Holdyourfire:
- Set that weapon down overhere:
- [Man, lndistinct]
[Man, Distant] We need
a couple ofcanteens up here:
[HelicopterBlades
Whirring]
- [Man]Party incoming!
- You can go.
You can go, goddamn it!
Go on! Dee dee!
Get the fuck out of here
before I change my mind!
Looks likeyou're going back
to the world, baby:
- Doc!
- [Man] Twenty meters out: Left!
- Right there:
- [Hodges]Anybody else?
[ Child Giggles ]
I got you now!
- Hey, buddy!
- Hi, Mom.
He looks fabulous.
- Happy anniversary, Mom.
- Oh, thankyou. So good to see you.
I wasn't sure you'd make it.
- You look wonderful.
- Thankyou.
- How's it feel to be retired?
- Um, crazy.
Good. Oh, you look great.
- Thankyou.
- Well, come see Dad...
- There he is.
- and all the family.
Hello, sir.
- Glad you could make it.
- Yes, sir.
[Laughter,
Crowd Chatter]
- [ Man ] Good to see you, Hayes.
- How are you doing?
Hey, kid. Hey, you.
Remember me?
- The old guy who looks like you.
- Do I know you?
- Yeah.
- Your voice sounds really familiar.
Here's a clue: I was married
to your mom for about filve minutes.
- Really? You sure? 'Cause I don't--
- Yeah. [ Chuckles ]
[ Chattering ]
- Well, is he guilty?
- Sir?
Your friend
Colonel Childers.
- Guilty ofwhat, sir?
- Come on, Hayes.
You served with him. Is he the rabid
dog we've all been hearing about?
I don't think
I should comment, sir.
Come on, Dad. This is family.
You can lighten up a little.
You know what we said
at the naval academy.
Even ifyou thought
you weren't responsible,
it went wrong
and you were there.
Since when have you
not had a comment?
Since Childers asked me
to defend him.
[Man]No: Oh, Hayes:
- [ Woman ] What?
- [Son]Excuse me:
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
Why would you do that?
Huh!
-Because he asked me, and I owe him.
-That's great.
That represents everything
that's wrong with the military.
Wisdom from the one person
in this family...
who has not elected
to serve his country.
Childers must have snapped.
It happens in combat.
I've seen it.
I'm sure you have too.
Thankyou for reminding me...
why we have the presumption
of innocence in America.
[ Scoffs ] What are you, Abraham
Lincoln? You can't hide behind that.
The guy murdered innocent women
and children.
- You hear that on television?
- And newspapers.
- It's all over the place.
- It's Mom and Dad's anniversary.
Don't take this case, son.
This man has trashed
the reputation ofthe Corps.
He's put us back 20 years.
Is this how you want
to be remembered?
I don't see how I can
turn him down. He saved my life.
Well, I understand that
as well as anyone.
But you don't repay him by
falling senselessly on a grenade.
The way I see it,
this man should fil nd himself...
- the best laywer in the country.
- Somebody better than me?
The guy's
a real marine, Dad.
I mean, ifthey
can do this to him--
just hang him out to dry--
they can do it to anybody.
Forget that he's my friend.
They can do it to anybody.
That means your medals
and your citations...
won't mean jack shit
when they come afteryou.
[MetaIClinking]
At least two of his own guys
are gonna testify...
that he didn't have
to open fil re, sir.
Nobody reports seeing any
weapons among the demonstrators.
- His psych eval was a disaster.
- What about embassy footage?
Cameras, fil lm, videotape,
home movies, shit like that?
No, I've subpoenaed everything.
The embassy got hit pretty good.
- Most of it was destroyed.
- [DoorOpens]
[Man Grunting]
Terry, you know Tom Chandler. He's
gonna help us prepare your case.
Colonel Childers, good to see
you again, sir. Um, all right.
First, we've subpoenaed all
the Article 32 investigator's notes,
the State Department's
notes on Yemen.
Major Biggs has already had
your head checked by their doctor.
I've got you an appointment
with ours.
- No.
- What?
No more multiple choice
questions about self-esteem.
We got the combat filtness reports.
He can forget the psych eval here.
That's a mistake, Colonel.
Listen, when I turned 1 8
I joined the Marine Corps.
I asked to be in the infantry.
- I asked to go to Vietnam.
- Terry.
I live for the privilege
ofcommanding troops.
I think it's the greatest honor
an American can have.
You know how many birthdays
and Christmases I missed,
spent rotting in jungles
or in the desert,
just so you could play
war at ROTC?
Childers! You gotta keep
your shit together here, man.
Your court-martial board
is gonna be made up of people...
who might've spent one day in
Grenada, maybe two days in Kuwait.
They're gonna be beach boys who've
never been anywhere near combat.
They're gonna be people
like Tom Chandler...
sitting right here in front ofyou.
That's who you're
making your case to.
We don't have anybody
to back up your case.
That's because
all my witnesses are dead.
- Okay. So what happened?
- He lost it. He snapped.
That's good.
We can snap him on the stand.
This doesn't happen in a vacuum.
Let's get a complete history
of Colonel Childers.
Talk to every marine
he ever served with.
My guess is
this has happened before.
We have to be careful here.
This guy is
the warrior's warrior.
A Navy Cross, two Silver Stars
for composure in battle.
He has no wife, no kids,
just the Corps.
He was our best.
That's why he was sent.
He's not on trial for the
good service he gave the country,
but for what he did
on the wallin Yemen, period:
Major, nobody wants to say it,
but it occurs to me we're trying
to set an example here.
So let's set it and show
the world we mean business.
The fil rst charge supports the death
penalty, and I say we go for it.
No more death.
I'll see that he never gets another
command and I'll put him in jail,
but I will not seek death for a man
who served his country honorably.
Idon't want it
brought up again:
We gotta show
Childers' state of mind.
We gotta prove he went out
with intent to kill,
and that is not going to be easy.
Whether a man is charged
with murder or hailed as a hero...
is sometimes a very thin line.
Our case is this: Childers receives
orders that a regularly scheduled,
Iawful protest outside
our embassy in Yemen is unruly.
He is to secure
or evacuate the premises.
There has been no violence
prior to his arrival.
Once there, Ambassador Mourain...
does not feel the situation
warrants evacuation.
- Childers ignores him.
- There wassniperfire:
They draw fil re from snipers
across the street.
Childers retaliates into an unarmed
crowd in front ofthe embassy.
A crowd ofwomen and children.
He shot the wrong people.
[Man On Radio]
Allright, here's what this means:
Murder-- Obviously, he couldget
up to the deathpenalty:
Conduct unbecoming an officer:
Max is dismissal
with a dishonorable discharge,
forfeiture ofallpay andallowances
andconfinement foroneyear:
[Woman] What about breach
ofpeace? What is that?
Breaching thepeace is minor:
That meansparticipating in an act
ofviolent orturbulent nature:::
that deprives the community ofthe
peace andtranquility it deserves:
It's sort ofthe militaryequivalent
ofthe civilian misdemeanor:
- No big deal:
- [ Chattering, Shouting ]
[ Man ] There he is!
You goddamn baby killer!
Baby killer!
You're disgusting!
I'm not answering any questions,
all right? Get out of here. Go away.
You fucking baby killer!
Fuckyou!
Who the fuck are you
to spit on this uniform? Huh?
You ever play blackjack, Colonel?
Not really.
There are no intangibles.
It's all odds, sir.
You know them, you'll beat
the guy next to you.
You know what cards have been
played, you'll beat the house.
Sometimes you just can't win
no matter what you do.
I saw your man on television
knockin' some zit-faced kid around.
You have to understand the kind of
pressure Childers has been under.
A man with that kind ofservice--
No, no thanks.
This was a rescue mission
that went bad. Nothing more.
You're aware, Colonel,
we could ask for the death penalty.
You're not serious.
Oh, I'm very serious.
In fact, it's been suggested.
What do you think would happen
ifa Yemeni killed 83 Americans?
He'd have a trial
that would last for one day,
and they'd take off his head.
Have a seat, Colonel.
Please.
So here it is:
You plead him out. Guilty.
He throws himselfat the mercy.
- We'll help him out at sentencing.
- How much help?
I'm not about to promise you
anything, but I'd say...
in the neighborhood often
to filfteen, out in seven.
Major,
do you know what the life expectancy
was for a second lieutenant...
dropped into a combat zone
in Vietnam in 1 968?
I don't have time
for 20 questions, sir.
Then what's all this shit about
the odds ofwinning at blackjack?
You got time.
Take a guess.
My guess is your man's going down
'cause he deserves to go down.
I got a question foryou, Colonel.
What happened at Ca Lu?
The battle ofCa Lu,
Vietnam.
You were there with Childers.
Something happened. What was it?
Fuckyou is what happened
at Ca Lu, Biggs.
Two weeks.
Life expectancy of
a second lieutenant...
in combat in Vietnam
was two weeks.
Sir, I need more time
to prepare this case.
I need your permission
to go to Yemen--
It's all here, Hodge. We did an
exhaustive Article 32 investigation.
This thing happened
3,000 miles away. I need more time.
Colonel, it's all here.
We had it brought from Yemen,
and it's not unusual to convene...
a court-martial
on short notice.
There could be witnesses, something
the investigators overlooked, sir.
Don't you think Colonel Childers
is entitled all consideration?
ColoneIHodges, ldon't care
ifyougo to China:
We have our marching orders,
and this court-martial...
will convene
at 0900 a week Monday.
- Now, is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
[Man Leading Cadence,
lndistinct]
[Men]
One! Two!
[DoorbelIRings]
- ...contact the sergeant?
- He's off-base, sir.
[DoorbelIRings]
Terry?
Childers?
Ohh.
Oh, shit:
It's okay.
- [Sighs]
- It's okay.
- I wasn't--
- No, no. I know.
It's okay. It's all right.
I know. Believe me, I know.
[ Sighs ] Can I leave you alone
with that thing in the house?
Yeah. I ain't goin' six
on you, Hodge.
I'm goin' to Yemen.
If I have to stickyour ass
in a hospital till I get back,
- that is what I will do.
- You don't have to do that.
Got your word on that?
[ Sighs ]
Oh, shit.
They take my uniform away,
they may as well shoot me.
You can live with it, bud.
Believe me.
I'm not gonna shit you.
They offered us a deal.
[ Sighs ] You plead guilty, it's
ten to filfteen. You're out in seven.
-What do you think?
-I think they're out to crucify you.
For a whole lot of reasons,
I say we take it and call it a day.
[ Sniffles ]
I did what they
asked me to do, Hodge.
I lost marines over there.
If I'm guilty ofthis,
I'm guilty ofeverything I've done
in combat for the last 30 years.
[Woman Chattering]
[Man]
ldon't know:
Colonel Hodges?
Captain Hustings.
I'm not in uniform and I'm not
saluting because ofthe snipers.
Please know that I'm saluting
on the inside.
I've got some Kevlar back there
with your name on it.
We're not the most popular team
in town right now, sir.
Hustings, are you a wiseass?
My mother prefers to
think of me as glib, sir.
Very well then. You will most glibly
belay all bullshit and drive on.
Roger that, sir.
I've lined up some people who were
at the scene, as you requested, sir.
- We can start tomorrow.
- Good.
- All right. Here we are.
- Oh. 0700.
Roger that, sir.
The old embassy was
a filfth century palace.
Gotprettyshot up:
We're moving the newone
to a bunkeroutside the city:::
behind about a mile
of barbed wire, sir.
- You want me to come with you, sir?
- Negative.
Stay with the vehicle.
Meet me at the hotel.
Yes, sir.
[ShutterClicks]
[ Shutter Clicks ]
[ShutterClicking]
[ Sighs,
Mutters lndistinctly ]
[Man Shouts
ln Arabic Language]
######[Drums, Flute]
######[People Singing
ln Arabic Language]
[ Shutter Clicks ]
- [ Shutter Clicks ]
- ######[Men Singing]
######[Singing Continues]
[ Singing ]
[ Singing Continues ]
[Man SpeakingArabic]
[ Arabic ]
Armed American marines,
they were shooting at his people.
They werejust trying
to defend themself.
Is he saying
the marines shot fil rst?
[ Arabic ]
Why were your police offilcers
ordered to abandon the embassy...
on the day ofthe riot?
[Man SpeakingArabic]
[ Arabic ]
It was a peaceful demonstration.
There was no reason to stay.
After the killing, were
any weapons found in the crowd?
[ Arabic ]
No. They picked up everything
that was left. No weapons.
[Man Outside
Shouting ln Arabic]
[ Arabic ]
Hey!
No, look. Now, wait.
Wait a minute.
- [ Shouting ln Arabic ]
- Wait a minute, fellas.
[ Shouting ln Arabic ]
Hey. Hey!
[ Panting ]
[People Chanting
ln Arabic]
[ Chanting ]
[GirISpeakingArabic]
[ Arabic ]
[ChatterContinues]
Hi. What's your name?
Do you speak English?
- You're a very pretty girl.
- [ Gasps ]
"Katchi"!
Is that your name? "Katchi"?
- May I help you?
- Yeah.
I was wondering
what happened to her?
She lost her leg.
Who are you?
I'm a lawyer with the United States
Marine Corps. What happened?
- A marine lawyer?
- Yeah.
Follow me, please.
[ Flies Buzzing ]
[Baby Crying,
Flies Buzzing]
There are hospitals like this
all over the city.
[Babies Crying]
Most ofthe people here
will die.
[ChildSpeaking
ln Arabic]
[Crying Continues]
[Gunshot]
Sir? Doyou want
something to drink?
Give me another one!
Open the goddamn door!
What's wrong with you?
Get yourselfa new lawyer,
you son ofa bitch. You lied to me.
I could not fil nd
one goddamn witness.
I couldn't fil nd
one goddamn shred ofevidence!
Not for our side
anyway!
You clearly opened up
on those people. What were they?
Rag heads, camel jockeys
or fucking gooks?
- You through?
- Yeah.
Get up.
- [ Panting ]
- Come on. Get up. Come on.
Look at you.
You went all the way to Yemen.
All you proved is
you're still a drunk.
You know what your problem is? You
never measured up to your old man.
- But I can't help you with that.
- [ Grunts ]
[ Yells ]
- [ Yells ]
- [ Groans ]
[Coughs]
[ Groaning ]
[ Yells ]
Stop this shit
before somebody gets hurt.
[ Grunts ]
[ Coughing, Laughing ]
[ Coughing ]
I lost every one
of my men at Ca Lu.
And I'll tell you
the fil rst thing I felt.
Joy.
Elation:
Gladto be alive:
I was glad it wasn't me, and
I fucking hate myselffor that.
That wasn't your fault.
We're in deep shit, bud.
Yeah:
It's fourth and 40, Hodge.
I need a Hail Mary.
[ Sighs ]
How?
[ Sighing ]
[Intercom Beeps]
Send him in.
[DoorOpens]
[DoorCloses]
I just want to make sure
we're on the same page here.
- Offthe record:
- Ofcourse, Bill.
Now, you didn't see any weapons
in that crowd, did you?
Well--
[ Chuckles ]
There was some shooting,
but l...
couldn't be sure exactly
where it was coming from.
Now, see, that's
gonna be a problem,
because we can't get on the stand
and waffle about the charges.
Waffle, Bill?
In your mind, Childers
was responsible, wasn't he?
I wasn't exactly there.
I had already evacuated.
You have to remember
he saved my life and my family.
This all happened after--
Does that mean the United States...
is gonna have to take the fall
for what he did?
I don't understand.
The investigating team didn't
fil nd any weapons in the crowd.
That's because they weren't
there until the following day.
The Yemeni government
cleaned up the scene,
but unfortunately that's
not something we can prove.
Nor can I testify about it.
It all happened afterward.
Yeah, but you can testify
about Childers' frame of mind,
his behavior
while you were there.
He saved my life.
Surely this will all come down
to what the tape shows.
The tape's inconclusive.
Hodges subpoenaed it,
ofcourse, but, uh...
it was a faulty recording.
- I see.
- Doyou?
If Childers isn't held
totally responsible,
then the United States
will be.
And just guess...
where the fil nger...
is eventually gonna point.
- Me?
- Where else?
You should've known
this was gonna erupt.
And ifyou didn't,
you were asleep at the wheel.
Either way, yourconduct
wasinexcusable:
Now, do you want to face a
congressional inquiry over this,
put your career at risk?
Think about it.
Thankyou, Bill.
[DoorOpens, Closes]
[ Retching ]
[ Panting ]
[Toilet Flushes]
[ Groans ]
[ People Chattering ]
[Bailiff]
Allrise:
Beseated:
Look closely
at this picture.
Why did a well-trained
fil ghting unit...
have to slaughter unarmed
men, women and children...
when their orders
were simply to protect...
and if necessary,
evacuate the embassy?
The answer is,
they didn't.
They were ordered to open fil re,
and that order came from one man--
Colonel Terry Childers,
who stands trial
here today,
a day ofsadness,
a day when America has
to accept responsibility...
for its failures and its
mistakes as well as its glories.
We will show you that the accused,
through his mind-set and actions,
ignored the rules
ofengagement...
and went far beyond
the scope of his authority...
to intentionally order
the murder...
of 83 innocent people.
[ Amplifiled Thumping ]
[ Clears Throat ]
I was the last one to enter the
courtroom this morning. I was late.
I was late because
I was in the head.
And I was in the head
because... I was throwing up.
And I was throwing up
because I don't know if I'm...
able to handle thisjob.
[ Chuckles ]
I believe that Colonel Childers
is innocent ofthese charges.
I just don't know if I have what
it takes to make his case for him.
I'm simply not on the same page
as Major Briggs, uh--
Major Biggs here,
as a lawyer.
We all know that.
So why did I take
thisjob?
I took this case because
Terry Childers told me...
I would have done the same thing
he did if I'd been in his shoes.
I took the case because I know Terry
Childers. His word is his bond.
He told me he did
what he had to do.
Now, I hope
I don't let him down.
We sent Terry Childers out
on a very tough mission.
And when it went bad,
and he did everything he could
to save the lives of his marines,
save the lives
ofthe embassy people,
you turn aroundnowand want
to blame the whole mess on him,
sendhim toprisonpossibly
forthe rest ofhis life:
That's not fair.
It's not right.
It is what made me sick
this morning.
It was a large crowd.
There was a lot ofcommotion.
The noise was very unsettling.
But it was
a peaceful crowd.
That is, until Colonel Childers
arrived and prevented me...
from pursuing
further avenues ofdiplomacy.
[Biggs]Did ColoneIChilders
forceyou to leave the embassy?
Yes. He charged in.
He... started
pushing us around.
He physically restrained me
from doing myjob.
[Biggs] What washis state
ofmindat this time?
He wasin a fury:
He was disrespectful
to me and my family.
Oh, that's bullshit.
It wasalmost, howshouldlsay,
a murderous rage:
[Biggs]
Doyou remember what hesaid?
Irememberhesaid
something like:::
"diplomacy is bullshit
at this point"...
andthat "nobody fucks
with theAmerican flag: "
- Those were his words:
- [Biggs] Thankyou, Ambassador:
No furtherquestions:
Do you believe...
that an American embassy
on foreign soil...
is sovereign
United States territory?
Asageneralprinciple, yes:
Do you believe Americans
have a right...
to defend that territory
if it's attacked?
Ifit is, in fact,
attacked:
Would you have expected
Colonel Childers to surrender...
to the attacking crowd
orto fight them?
I would have expected neither.
The colonel should have let me
address the crowd,
then he could have withdrawn
his marines.
Would you have expected him
to hold his fil re as he withdrew,
- even if he were taking casualties?
- To the extent possible.
So your order would have been,
"Hold your fil re to the extent
possible, Marines.
And to the extent not possible,
fil re away."
[Hodges]
Ambassador:
This photograph
is exhibit "C."
- What is that?
- It's a security camera.
Is it mounted
on the roofofthe embassy...
and pointed down to where
the crowd had gathered?
- I would suppose so.
- Yes or no, please.
Yes.
- Is it in operation 24 hours a day?
- I suppose so.
- Yes or no?
- Yes.
Do you suppose there is a taping
system attached to this camera?
- [Biggs] YourHonor:
- [Judge] Colonel:
- Yes.
- Where's the tape?
It is my understanding
that ifthere were tapes,
undamaged tapes, they'd have been
sent to the State Department.
Undamaged tapes?
Well, there was
destruction andlooting:::
after the killing.
Asyou withdrew, didyou remember
to take theAmerican flag withyou?
Didyou rememberto take
theAmerican flag, sir?
- Ofcourse.
- Where is that flag now?
I brought it home and returned
it to the State Department.
It was shot to shreds,
wasn't it?
By the snipers, yes.
[Hodges]
Yeah?
[ Children Shouting,
Chattering ]
Right! Go right!
Goal!
At ease, son.
Let me see. Which one
ofyou people is named Justin?
-Let me take a guess. How about you?
-No.
Then I'll have to make
another guess. I'll take, uh... you.
How'd you know?
Are you in the marines?
Yes, sir, lam.
Go on in the house, kids.
There are sandwiches in the kitchen.
Mrs. Mourain, I'm sorry
to botheryou at home:
-I'm Colonel--
-I know who you are, Colonel Hodges.
- Is thatyourboy?
- Yes.
Can I talk to you
a few minutes?
I don't think
that's appropriate.
I don't believe your husband
is telling the truth...
about what Colonel Childers did
in Yemen.
Kids, go on in the house.
There are sandwiches on the table.
- Let's go! Come on!
- [Children Laughing]
[ Chuckling ]
You should take that up
with my husband, shouldn't you?
Colonel Childers risked his life
so you could be here, ma'am,
watching these kids play
out these windows.
Does that botheryou?
I feel terrible about what
happened to Colonel Childers.
Can you tell me that he
manhandled your family?
Or that he prevented
your husband from doing hisjob?
Ma'am?
Can you tell me that?
No.
As far as I'm concerned,
he behaved quite honorably.
Will you testify to that?
- My husband's a good man.
- So is Colonel Childers.
I've been married for ten years.
You're asking me to throw that
away in an afternoon.
Yourhusbandandyou
andyourson:::
owe your lives
to Colonel Terry Childers.
We all have our priorities,
Colonel.
I can subpoena you, ma'am.
Please don't.
Don't put me up there.
I'm a very credible witness.
Now, ifyou'll excuse me.
You won't tell the truth
if I put you on the stand?
I don't know
what the truth is.
Colonel Childers is on trial for
what he did outside the embassy.
I wasn't there.
Were you?
[DoorOpens]
- [ Exhales ]
- [DoorSlams]
Captain Lee, you were in command
ofthe TRAP team...
and the second ranking offilcer
under Colonel Childers in Yemen?
- Yes, sir.
-Andyou were on the roof:.:
- ofthe embassy, wereyou not?
- Yes, I was.
Colonel Childers ordered you
to open fil re...
immediately after Sergeant
Richard Krasevitch was shot.
- Is that correct?
- Yes.
But Sergeant Krasevitch was not
shot by the demonstrators, was he?
Objection. How could we know
the exact fil ring position...
ofthe bullet that killed
Sergeant Krasevitch?
[Judge ] Sustained. Counsel
refrain from leading the witness.
[ Biggs ]
Did you at any time...
receive gunfil re from within
the demonstration itself?
Captain?
I can't remember any fil re
from the demonstrators,
to my knowledge that is, sir.
You killed the wrong people,
didn't you?
You should've been fil ring
at the snipers across the way.
- Isn't that correct?
- I can't answer--
- Objection. Calls for speculation.
- Sustained.
You shot at people who
were demonstrating peacefully,
who were not using
deadly force:
Your Honor, that's not
in evidence here.
Sustained. Major, I'm not going
to warn you again.
Captain, what were the words
Colonel Childers used...
when he ordered you to fil re
on the demonstrators?
I don't remember
the exact words, sir.
He orderedme
to open fire:
When you obeyed Colonel
Childers' order to open fil re,
did you believe it
to be a lawful order?
Yes, sir.
Otherwise it would have been your
duty to disobey. Is that right?
Yes, sir.
When your men opened fil re
on the attackers in the crowd,
did the snipers in the buildings
across the way cease their fil ring?
Absolutely, sir.
It went completely quiet.
It would seem, then,
that the two groups were
actually one working together.
Objection: Counselis drawing
a conclusion forthe witness:
Sustained:
Were you in a position
to observe Colonel Childers...
when everyone was evacuated?
Yes, I was.
What was the last thing
you saw him do?
- He went to the flagpole.
- Then what'dhe do?
He tookdown
theAmerican flag:
Was he personally
under heavy fil re at that time?
- Yes, sir.
- No more questions.
Captain, prior to receiving orders
from the accused to open fil re,
where was the point of greatest
concern for the safety ofyour men,
the crowd below or the snipers
in the buildings across the way?
- I'm not really sure.
- You're notsure?
Well, I guess--
Don't guess.
I'll repeat the question.
Was the point of greatest concern
the crowd below...
orthesnipers
across the way?
I would have to say
the snipers.
Did you feel an immediate mortal
danger from the crowd as a whole?
- I don't understand.
- You don't understand?
- No, sir.
- Let me help you.
Were you more worried...
you'd be killed by these people
or by these people?
I wasn't thinking about that.
Have you ever been under fil re?
You didn't see the crowd fil ring, but
you did take fil re from the snipers.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Ourclinic is not too far
from the embassy:
So I was one ofthe fil rst
to arrive there.
Did you see any weapons
on the bodies ofthe dead?
No.
Didyou remove any weaponsfrom
thepeopleyou were treating?
No.
Not a single weapon
anywhere among the victims?
No, no weapons.
In your opinion, is Yemen
a training ground for terrorists?
Not at all.
We met in Yemen.
You encouraged me to tour
your clinic in order to witness...
the suffering caused by
Colonel Childers' orders.
- Do you remember that?
- Yes.
I found an audiocassette
on the floor ofyour clinic.
It's marked exhibit "R."
Do you remember that?
- Yes.
- I found another one...
inside the embassy.
In fact, I found several others.
They're all marked exhibit "R."
Will you translate the writing on
the outside ofthat cassette?
"Declaration
of lslamicJihad...
Against United States."
These audiocassettes are used
for the purposes of religious...
and political propaganda due to
the high illiteracy rate in Yemen.
- Is that correct?
- Yes.
Will you translate
the words you hear...
on this audiocassette
for the court, please?
[ Man Speaking
ln Arabic ]
[ Stops ]
Dr. Ahmar?
"We call on every Muslim
who believes in God...
and hopes for reward...
to obey God's command."
[ Arabic ]
[ Stops ]
Dr. Ahmar, does it say
what God's command is?
"To kill Americans...
and plunder...
their possessions
wherever he fil nds them."
[ Arabic ]
- Go on, please.
- [ Man On Tape Continues ]
"To kill Americans...
and their allies,
both civil
and military,
is duty ofevery Muslim...
who is able."
- [Tape Continues]
- To kill Americans is a duty.
- Is that what it says?
- Yes.
- [Tape Continues]
- [People Murmuring]
Do you recognize
the speaker's voice?
- No.
- [ Tape Continues ]
Dr. Ahmar, in your opinion,
is this propaganda...
representative
ofthat demonstration?
No. I'm not a member
of lslamicJihad!
The crowd
wassinging songs.
I heard them from my clinic.
What was your reaction when you
learned that Colonel Childers...
had been selected
to lead this mission?
I was very pleased. The colonel
had a distinguished record.
- He's a nationally renowned war--
- How did you defil ne his mission?
We wanted to increase security,
but frankly,
ifthings got threatening,
we wanted an evacuation.
So you weren't looking
for confrontation?
No, that's what we wished
to avoidat all costs:
What was your reaction
to what happened?
I was stunned,
appalled.
Wasn't the severity ofthe problem
at the embassy understated?
Absolutely not.
We operated on the information
we had at the time.
I have here a State Department
report from Yemen.
It's exhibit "M."
Willyou readthe underlined
sectionsforthe court, please?
Certainly.
'January25.
Grenade thrown atpolice car:
January 27. Sixteen Western tourists
abducted by fundamentalist group."
- Go on, please:
- "February 6.
-A bomb explodes in a car--"
- You got today's Post?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Give it to me.
"Stungrenade thrown at newspaper
kiosk nearapolicestation:
March 1 3.
A military offilcer...
is seriously woundedby
Yemen's first::: donkey bomb:
Explosives were apparently
concealedunderthesaddle: "
[Hodges]
Thankyou:
Ihave anotherState Department
document, dated 17November:
It's from the ambassador
to you.
Will you read this
for the court, please?
"Dear Bill. Please, we must revisit
our previous conversation...
in that the security measures we
have taken are still inadequate...
for the protection
ofour mission to Yemen."
You have to understand that
when I received this letter--
Thankyou: Now, there are--
Well, are there::: cameras:::
-mounted on the roofofthe embassy?
-Uh, yes:
Are they designed
to observe and record...
activities in the public spaces
outside the embassy?
- Yes.
- Where are the tapes?
Uh, it's my understanding
the embassy was looted.
Maybe the cameras
were destroyed.
This is a photograph.
It is exhibit "D" for the court.
It's a picture ofa camera
on the embassy roof.
Does it appear
to be damaged?
No.
- Where are the tapes?
- I don't know.
Don'tyou think
the UnitedStates owes it:::
to Colonel Childers
for 30 years ofservice...
to fil nd that tape
and produce it here?
Objection. We don't know
anything about any tapes.
- This is pure speculation.
- Sustained:
This is a shipping manifest.
It's exhibit "O."
It is a list of items removed from
the embassy during the evacuation...
and shipped
to the State Department.
Will you read
line six, please?
"Videotape from security
camera, VHS, one."
You too busy to look at those
tapes oryou just didn't care?
Objection. He's badgering
the national security advisor.
Sustained. Counsel,
please proceed carefully.
- Where are those tapes?
- Objection! Asked and answered.
Oh. Yes, right. Right.
Don't you think it's funny...
that a tape that could exonerate
my client is missing?
I don't think it's funny at all.
Withholding evidence
is a very serious crime.
- [Biggs] Objection:
- Sustained: Counsel, rephrase:
Withholding evidence to frame
a United States Marine...
is no less evil than charging
my client with murder.
Where are those tapes?
Colonel, I turned over all
materials in my possession...
to Major Biggs.
Ifthose tapes showeda happy
crowd ofpeacefuldemonstrators,
we'd be looking at 'em.
Objection, Your Honor.
This is contempt.
Colonel,
this is your last warning.
It was a new security system.
The cameras were pointed down
at the crowd.
Tapes were recorded, and those tapes
were sent to the State Department.
Why are those tapes not here?
Objection, Your Honor.
I've seen no such tapes.
No further questions.
There are no tapes showing
the crowd fil ring weapons?
None that I'm aware of.
And the government has turned
over all of its evidence?
Ofcourse:
Colonel Hodges has gone
to some length...
to have you read security reports
illustrating violence in Yemen.
- Yes, he has:
- Here is today's Washington Post:
Will you read these headlines
that I've underlined...
from today's Metro section?
"Agent, kidnapper killed in
rescue of businessman's son."
"Bomb threat evacuates
Museum of Natural History."
"Officerchases truckdriver,
fires 38 times: "
"Husbandshoots wife,
himselfin street: "
Mr. Sokal, does this random,
unfortunate news mean we should...
allow Colonel Childers and his
troops loose in Washington, D.C.?
Don't answer that.
Thankyou, Mr. Sokal.
Present arms!
Order arms!
[ Bugle Begins ]
Take deep breaths, sir! You're
almost out of here. Stay calm.
I hope you know
how to fold it, sir.
Thankyou, Colonel.
I'll never forget this.
- [Shouting]
- [ Yells ]
[Explosion]
[ Shouting ]
[Screams]
Krasevitch is hit!
Corpsman!
Corpsman! Shit!
Goddamn it!
Engage hostile targets
as they appear!
- [ Shouting ln Arabic ]
- Waste the motherfuckers!
Cease fil re!
Cease fire!
[DrilISergeant]
Orderarms!
I was proud of my marines.
They showed
remarkable discipline.
Why didn't you fil re
at the snipers in the buildings...
instead ofat the crowd below?
Because I believed we were
in greater danger from the crowd.
- Was that crowd fil ring at you?
- Yes.
The demonstrators in front of
the building were firing atyou:::
- in addition to thesnipers?
- Yes.
Why didn 't anybody else
see that crowdfiring?
My men were
under cover on the roof,
except for Krasevitch
who was on an observation post.
And why isn't he here testifying
on your behalftoday?
Because he was killed in action.
He died in my arms.
So you were the only man left in
a position to observe that crowd?
Yes.
Where else have you been
in combat, Colonel?
Vietnam, Beirut,
Panama, Persian Gulf.
Can you identify that blue and
white ribbon on your uniform?
It's the Navy Cross.
Do you remember the citation
that accompanied that medal?
"For conspicuous gallantry in
the face of great personal danger,
reflecting great credit
upon himself,
the United States Marine Corps
and the Naval Service."
Your witness.
Colonel,
you gunned down
more than 80 people.
You wounded
anotherhundredorso:
Could this have been motivated
by a desire forretaliation?
I was protecting my men.
Sergeant Richard Krasevitch was
shot only a few feet away from you.
- Is that correct?
- Yes.
And right after Sergeant
Krasevitch died,
you ordered open fil re
on the crowd?
- Is that also correct?
- I was taking fil re.
There were weapons
in that crowd.
Well, you wouldn't shoot
unarmed people, would you?
No, I wouldnot:
Even in the heat of battle, you
wouldn't shoot an unarmed person?
No.
This is exhibit "F."
Will you please read
the following to the panel?
"Rules ofengagement governing
ground conflict in urban areas.
One: lf possible,
the enemy will be warned fil rst,
then asked to surrender."
Colonel, did you warn
the enemy?
We arrived in helicopters.
We were standing on that roofarmed.
Didyou warn them, either with shots
into the air orby a loudspeaker?
Did you ask them
to surrender?
No.
I'm sorry, no, you did not
warn the crowd?
Yes. No, I did not
warn the crowd.
Continue, Colonel:
Youseem to knowthem by heart:
"Deadly force
is the last resort."
- Go on.
- "Three:
When possible, try to arrange
for the evacuation ofcivilians...
prior to any U.S. attack."
Did you do that, try
to evacuate the innocent people...
before you slaughtered them?
- Objection. That is inflammatory.
- Rephrase, Major.
Did you try, following Section C
ofthe rules ofengagement...
for ground conflict in urban areas,
to evacuate innocent civilians?
- No.
[Indistinct Whispering]
Yeah, yeah.
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
I just have
one more thing, Colonel.
Did you have to repeat
your orders to Captain Lee?
- I'm sorry?
- You ordered Captain Lee...
to engage hostile targets,
and he advised you...
that there were women and children
in the line offil re.
- Is that correct?
- He couldn't see--
Yes orno, Colonel? Didhe
followyourfirstset oforders?
I don't remember.
Captain Lee is on record
as saying he hesitated...
and mentioned the snipers
in the buildings.
- Is his testimony accurate?
- I don't remember.
Let me get this straight.
You evacuate
the ambassador.
You go back to the roof.
Two ofyour marines are K.I.A.
A third,
Sergeant Krasevitch, dies.
You give your captain
an order which he doesn't follow;
in fact, he questions.
And then you said what?
[ Sighs ] I don't remember.
You don't remember
what you said next?
It was combat,
not some training exercise.
A moment later,
your men were shooting.
What did you say
to make that happen?
I don't know.
You must have said something.
Captain Lee reversed himself.
- What did you say?
- I don't know the exact words.
- Let me helpyou:
- Your Honor.
You said, "Waste the motherfuckers,"
didn't you?
- No, no, no.
- You didn't say it?
- It all happened so fast--
- You're under oath, Colonel!
Let me refresh
your memory.
This is exhibit "ry" a tape
recording made aboard...
the U.S.S. Wake lsland ofall radio
communications received that day,
including your exact words.
YourHonor, withyourpermission
I wouldlike toplay this tape:
Ifyou got it on tape,
then that's what I said!
They were killing my marines,
so, yeah, I said it!
"Waste the motherfuckers!"
- Are these "the motherfuckers"?
- Objection.
- Overruled.
- Yes!
- These?
- [Hodges] Objection!
Yes!
- These?
- [Hodges] Objection!
- Overruled.
- Yes.
Are these "the motherfuckers"...
- that you ordered to be wasted?
- Your Honor.
- Major.
- Yes!
The crowd in front ofthe embassy
had no weapons, did they, Colonel?
Objection. We found
no snipers' weapons either.
Yes, they had weapons!
You think there's
a script for fil ghting a war...
without pissing somebody off?
Follow the rules,
and nobody gets hurt?
Yes, innocent people probably died.
Innocent people always die.
But I did not exceed
my orders!
There are rules, and marines
are sworn to uphold them.
I was not going to stand by
and see another marine die...
just to live
by those fucking rules!
- [GaveIPounding]
- Colonel!
Your Honor,
I request a recess.
Major.
The government is fil nished with
Colonel Childers, Your Honor.
[Judge]Allright, Colonel,
you haveyourrecess:
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
[ Sighs ]
Why didn't you tell me
what you said?
- I didn't remember.
- "Waste the motherfuckers."
That's brilliant.
You didn't think that was important?
Why didn't you know
about the goddamn recording?
- You're supposed to know--
- I had a week to prepare this case.
I didn't realize
what a fuckup I'm defending.
- Well, now you know.
- Goddamn.
- [ Sighs ]
[ Sighs ]
-This is going to take us both down.
-How's that work?
You gonna spend the rest
ofyour life in prison too?
[ Both Sighing ]
- [ Sighs ]
- I'm sorry.
[ Exhales ]
- I really screwed up in there, huh?
- Yeah, you really did.
[ Chuckles ]
Whew!
- So what happens now?
- Shit, I don't know.
[ Sighs ]
I don't know.
Your Honor, the government
calls Colonel Bin Le Cao...
- as a rebuttal witness.
- Objection, Your Honor.
What are the grounds for
this rebuttal witness to be allowed?
Will counsel please
approach the bench.
- Who is Colonel Bin Le Cao?
- A North Vietnamese Colonel...
who fought against Colonel Childers
at the battle of Ca Lu.
What he has to say directly refutes
statements made by Colonel Childers.
- When was the battle of Ca Lu?
- 1 968.
This is uncharged misconduct. It is
not allowable under military law.
How do you know this witness
is going to charge misconduct?
I'm assuming--
He knows because he was
at the battle of Ca Lu.
- Is that true?
- Yes, sir.
On what grounds are you
calling your witness?
Colonel Hodges made Colonel
Childers' combat experience...
part of his defense.
Furthermore,
Colonel Childers testifiled...
that he never shoots unarmed people.
My witness hasan important
perspective on thatstatement:
I'm gonna allow
the witness.
[Biggs]
Doyouswearoraffirm:::
that the evidenceyoushallgive
in this case:::
shallbe the truth,
the whole truth:::
andnothing but the truth,
so helpyou God?
[Cao]
Yes, ldo:
Will you please state
your name for the court?
- My name is Bin Le Cao.
- In 1 968, you were a colonel...
with the North Vietnamese army,
B3 regiment, involved in a fil ght...
with American marines at Ca Lu
in the Quang Tri province?
Yes, I was.
Will you tell the court
about that battle?
We were aware that
small units ofAmericans...
ryere ryeryr
my company of men.
We found ourselves
behind your forces.
This was lucky for us
because we were outnumbered.
Do you recognize
this man?
Yes.
Didhe captureyou andyour
radio operatorthat day?
Yes.
Did he remove your weapons
and place you under armed guard?
Yes.
Didyou consideryourself
aprisonerofwar?
Yes.
Did he execute
your radio operator?
Yes.
You personally saw him shoot
a fellow prisoner ofwar?
Yes.
[Biggs]
Where didheshoot him?
[Cao]
ln the head:
Thankyou:
No furtherquestions:
[ Sighs ] Were your men annihilating
that platoon of marines?
Yes.
Did Colonel Childers force you
to call your men off?
Yes.
Do you believe his actions
were calculated to save...
- the lives ofAmerican marines?
- Yes.
Would you have done the same
thing Colonel Childers did...
ifthe situation
had been reversed?
Colonel Cao, would you have shot...
a captive American radio operator
in the head ifyou thought...
it would persuade Colonel Childers
to spare the lives ofyour own men?
Yes.
No more questions.
[Judge] This court is in recess
until tomorrowat 0900:
- We willhearclosing arguments:
- [GaveIPounds]
- General, goodto seeyou:
- Perry, good to see you too.
I want you to meet
my grandson.
Hi. Nice to meet
you, sir.
Thanks.
[Biggs] Colonel Terry Childers
is a decorated warhero,
a trusted leader
ofAmerican marines,
and I wish that was
all there was to it.
Unfortunately, there are
83 dead Yemeni citizens,
many ofthem
women and children.
Colonel Hodges would have you
believe that this crowd was armed.
He would also have you believe
that there is a videotape...
proving this to be true.
There is no tape
exonerating Colonel Childers.
There is no evidence
exonerating Colonel Childers!
Is Colonel Childers a man capable of
killing defenseless, unarmed people?
Is he capable ofordering
the execution...
of innocent
men and women?
Is he capable ofexecuting
P.O.W.s with his own hand?
Unfortunately,
we have shown that he is.
You have heard the sad testimony
of Colonel Cao...
who witnessed Colonel Childers'
barbarism fil rsthand.
You've even heard
Colonel Childers' own admission...
that his desire was to "waste"
them, regardless ofwho they were.
Now, we are faced
with the diffilcult prospect...
ofconvicting
one ofour own.
None of us wants to do this,
but you've heard the facts,
and it is unavoidable.
Colonel Terry Childers ordered
the senseless slaughter...
ofa peaceful crowd!
Now, asmarines,
we do notget the luxury
ofcovering up ourmistakes:
We must air them,
thereby ensuring
that they never happen again.
Thankyou.
That's sovereign
United States territory...
as much as if it were
in Ohio or Maryland.
Colonel Childers didn't
volunteer to go over there.
He was ordered to go there because
he was the best man for thejob.
We armed him.
We trained him.
We sent him over there to risk
his life to save other Americans.
And then ask him
not to return fil re?
There are over 300 bullet holes
in this building.
Colonel Childers didn't open fil re.
He returned fil re.
And he waited until after three
of his marines were dead...
and another lay
mortally wounded.
He waited until he was
personally under heavy fil re.
He waited until he saw
that crowd holding weapons.
Only then did he order
his men to return fil re.
Under the rules ofengagement,
a civilian pointing a weapon...
is no longer a civilian,
and the use ofdeadly force
is authorized...
in order to save lives.
It's not murder.
It's combat.
ColoneIChilders is
the only man alive:::
who was in a position
to see that crowd.
But the camera on the embassy
roof had the same point ofview.
The government
would have you believe...
there's no tape
from that camera.
I have shown you that that tape was
delivered to the State Department.
Do you believe that tape
got up and walked out...
ofthe State Department
on its own?
By not producing that tape,
the national security advisor,
Mr. Sokal, has brought dishonor
into this court.
Without that tape, lcannotshow
you that the crowdfiredfirst:::
and that Colonel Childers
is innocent.
But without that tape,
they cannot prove...
beyond a reasonable doubt
that he's guilty!
[Sighs]
Here's my case.
He's all I've got.
Thirty-two years ofservice,
thirty-two years of heroism
as a United States Marine.
Regardless of
whatyou decide here,
ColoneIChilders'career
asa marine is over.
He willneveragain
commandmen in combat:
The ambassador and his family
are alive today because of him.
And I know how
the ambassador feels,
because Colonel Childers
saved my life too.
I'm alive today because of him.
My son is sitting in
this courtroom because of him.
I'm alive today,
and I have a son,
because ofthe heroism
of Colonel Childers.
To ask this man to risk his life
for his country,
to ask this man to watch
his marines die in his arms...
and call it murder
when he's defending himself,
call it murder for fil ring back
when fil red upon--
To call it murder for saving
the lives of his countrymen...
under the most extreme
ofcircumstances, that's, uh--
My fellow Marines,
that's hanging him out to dry.
It's worse than leaving him
woundedon a battlefield:
That is something
you do not do...
ifyou are
a United States Marine.
And it is something that I pray
to God you won't do here either.
[ Sighs ]
- What'd you think?
- You're pretty good.
Yeah. Yeah.
- Dad, you were awesome.
- [ Chuckles ]
Thanks, son.
I'm very glad that I don't
have to sit on that panel, son.
You made it
awful tough on them.
- [ Ringing ]
- [Indistinct Chatter]
- 1 5,000 to 25,000--
- Excuse me.
[ Ringing Continues ]
I said no interruptions.
[Woman]l'm sorry, Mr: Sokal:
It's veryimportant.
Send him in.
Can we pick this up
after lunch, gentlemen?
Absolutely.
[Men Chattering]
[DoorCloses]
Close the door.
What is it, Colonel?
No matter what happens
to Terry Childers tomorrow,
I'm not going to leave
thisjob until I fil nd out...
- what happened to that tape.
- Good.
Think it'll ever turn up?
No.
I don't either.
Well, then there's nothing more
for us to talk about, is there?
You ever had a pissed-off
marine on your ass?
Is that a threat?
Oh, yes, sir.
[DoorCloses]
[Crowd Chatter]
- [DoorOpens]
- [Bailiff]Allrise:
Has the panel
reached a verdict?
We have, sir.
Colonel Terry L. Childers, this
court-martial fil nds as follows:
On the charge
ofbreach ofpeace,
the court finds
the defendantguilty:
On the charge ofconduct
unbecoming an officer,
the court fil nds
the defendant not guilty.
On the charge ofmurder,
the court fil nds
the defendant not guilty.
This court-martial
is adjourned:
Sentencing will be conducted
at a time to be determined.
- [ Gavel Pounds ]
- Thankyou.
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
[ Sighs ]
- I need one more favor.
- Yeah.
Teach me how to fly-filsh.
You are well aware that I know
shit about fly-filshing.
Oh.
Colonel.
You realize in light of
Colonel Cao's testimony,
we'll be pushing for charges
on the Ca Lu incident.
That was 30 years ago.
You're going to have
a hard time fil nding witnesses.
I thought maybe
you'd be willing to testify.
I'll make you a deal.
Ifyou can tell me right now
what the life expectancy was...
for a second lieutenant dropped
into a hot L.Z. in Vietnam in 1 968,
I'll tell you everything
I remember about Ca Lu.
- One week.
- Negative.
Sixteen minutes, Major.
Sixteen fucking minutes.
And that's all I remember.
[CrowdShouting]
[ Together ]
Sir.
[ Soldiers
Shouting Drills ]