Dépêchez-vous avec la malle.
Tenez mon cheval, voulez-vous?
(Coughing)
Merci, mon ami.
Mon général.
Réveille.
Richard, you're shaking.
Am I?
What's the matter?
(Sighs)
I'm going into battle today.
And I'm getting older.
You weren't old last night.
Where are we? It was dark when I arrived.
Behind that hill is the town of Toulouse.
Toulouse is the last town loyal to Napoleon.
If we take Toulouse,
Boney has to pack his bags and head for Paris.
And Paris will take everything that's valuable
and send him on his way.
You mean the war will be over?
If we take Toulouse.
And to take Toulouse,
we have to take that hill.
The war will be over!
We can go home,
buy a town house.
No, a country house.
Maybe both.
Both? And where do we get the money?
There's a lot of numbers here, Richard.
Let's see.
10,000 guineas.
And that piece of paper
gives you power of attorney over it all.
Which means you have complete control
over my money.
To do with it as you will.
You present that piece of paper at the premises
of Messrs Adam Hopkinson & Son,
Adelaide Street, London,
And they will give you 10.000 guineas.
You don't mean to die on me, Richard, do you?
Oh!
Dear Jane.
Richard?
If you love me enough
to leave me all your money,
you must love me enough
to make me a promise.
Do you?
It depends on the promise.
Promise this will be your last battle.
It bloody will be if I'm not careful.
Be serious, Richard.
Promise me that after this battle
you will ask Wellington to send you home.
Could do worse. I'm as tired
of these bloody battles as you are, Jane.
I want to go home.
Put my feet up.
We'll be so happy.
Yes,
we will.
Promise me you'll come straight back to me.
Break that promise, Richard,
and I promise
I'll be on the first boat back to England,
and you will never hear from me again.
I can't let that happen.
It would break my heart.
Would it?
Yes, it would.
You'd get all my money.
Colonel Ross?
SERGEANT MAJOR: Quiet in the ranks!
Oh, damn, damn, damn!
Five years I worked my fingers to the bone
for Wellington, cracking his codes and ciphers.
I beg him for a brigade, he gives me a brigade.
What am I to do with my brigade? I am
to support Colonel Wigram's brigade, Sharpe.
Colonel Wigram!
(Explosion)
Well, Ross?
Wellington wants you to take that hill,
and I hate you for it.
What are you grinning at, Sharpe?
Think I can't do it?
- What time is it, Ross?
- It's nine.
I shall be on top of that hill by noon.
- Sergeant major?
- Sir.
- Brigade will prepare to move off.
(Frederickson laughs)
Wigram's well connected, sir.
Wellington had to give him a chance.
You think he ain't up to it, Sharpe?
Why else would he send you in close support,
sir?
Did the communiqué say "close support",
Sharpe?
That's the way I read the order, sir.
Wellington wants you to give
very close support, sir.
Artillery! Covering fire.
SERGEANT MAJOR: Over here, lads.
On the double.
Come on,
be brave. Now.
SERGEANT MAJOR: Come over the top.
SERGEANT MAJOR: Come on.
Be firm now.
Sound the recall!
WIGRAM: Get back.
Guarding the Colors!
(Cheering)
Come on. Lads.
Let the buggers through.
I'll have you flogged! I'll have you flogged!
What are you staring at. Sharpe?
Bloody cowards ran away.
A bad workman always blames his tools.
Not my fault, Ross.
You did your best, Wigram.
Skirmishers!
Piper, play me a tune.
Général.
Distant bagpipes
(Knock at door)
Lady Spindacre to see you, ma'am.
(Sobs) Oh, Molly!
Oh, there, there!
You mustn't distress yourself.
He's in no danger, Jane.
Colonel Wigram is with him.
He's not worth the worry.
No soldier is.
What would I do without him?
I thought the same about my Reginald.
See, men are all the same.
You marry them,
you make a good home for them,
but as soon as your back is turned,
they're off to battle,
and before you can say Jack Robinson,
they're dead as doornails.
(Sighs)
My Reginald was no loss, though.
He didn't deserve me.
No. I married him a captain,
made him a major within a month,
and what does he do?
Gets himself killed by a common dragoon
at Vitoria.
(Gasps)
A wrinkle.
Well, it'll have to go.
Look at me, Jane.
Poor widow with a wrinkle.
Nothing except Colonel Wigram
between me and the poorhouse.
Or the whorehouse...
Why. What lovely notepaper.
JANE: That makes it worse.
Richard said if he was to fall in battle,
I was to take that paper to London,
and draw out his money.
It’s a power of attorney
Power of attorney?
Over a substantial sum?
10,000 guineas.
Richard, be careful!
See the breastworks?
Gunpowder'll weaken them.
See if you can get the grappling irons in.
Then open the gate
and let us into the fort.
Pint of rum for the first man
to get their grapnels in.
What do you say, Hobbes?
(Soldier screams)
Pint of rum, Hobbes!
WIGRAM: Close the ranks!
ROSS: Steady, lads. Steady, steady.
Keep it tight, keep it tight!
Steady, boys.
Sharpe, open that gate.
Open the damn gate!
SERGEANT MAJOR: Everybody. Up the hill.
Come on, Hobbes!
I'll have that pint of rum for you, Hobbes.
Come on!
(Explosion)
We're in.
Steady. Close the ranks!
Ross
ROSS: Keep 'em moving, Wigram.
Keep the buggers moving!
Go on!
ROSS: Come on, you blighters!
Pick up the Colors!
What do you mean, coming on a battlefield
with your buttons not done up? Eh?
Come on. You follow me.
Follow me!
Go through.
Commandant Maillot!
Commandant.
You'll be needing this.
Get up. Get up!
Pick up your glasses.
Now crawl back to Calvet.
(Screams)
CALVET: Repliez-vous.
Repliez-vous.
Repliez-vous!
Stop firing. Cease firing!
Well done, lads.
See if you can find some brandy.
- I'm getting too old for this.
- Me, too.
- Pat?
- Sir?
- Tell Jane the battle's won.
- Yes, sir!
- I'm coming home.
ROSS: Splendid work. Sharpe.
- Are you all right, sir?
- Oh. It's a scratch.
Just a scratch. I intend to celebrate
tomorrow night with a good bottle of claret.
I want you to do me the honor
of dining with me.
Bring your beautiful wife. Sharpe.
Sir.
Oh,
you'd better bring that filly of yours, Wigram.
- What's her name?
- Lady Spindacre, sir.
The merry widow, yes.
Be sure and bring your wife, Sharpe.
Beauty...
...and the beast.
What did you say, sir?
Steady on, Sharpe. Just a jest.
Wigram merely meant
you're not as pretty as your wife.
Absolutely.
What I meant is that Sharpe
is not as well-bred as his wife.
Some women prefer the rough to the smooth.
They enjoy having themselves degraded.
Your next move, Sharpe,
is to slap my face.
(Clears throat) Who is to be your second, sir?
You're a damn fool, Sharpe. Wellington
hears about this, you'll be on the first ship home.
Exactly what I promised my wife, sir.
Best I stay here tonight.
Tell Jane you gave me some billet duties.
Very good.
(Gasps)
Pistols at dawn, sir.
(Groans)
Never mind, Sharpe.
That gives us 12 hours drinking. Come along.
(Laughter and music)
The spoils of war.
I've finished fighting, Frederickson.
WOMAN: Come on. Darling. Over 'ere. Eh?
I'm going home.
I feel the same.
I would like to be finished too.
But first, I must have what you have.
What's that?
Marriage and money.
Or money and marriage.
You have both, Sharpe.
Which comes first?
Luck.
Luck comes first.
I'm going to need more than luck.
The only way to make a beautiful woman
blind to all this
is to entice her with golden guineas.
Oh!
You don't need gold to entice them.
What did you do when you were young?
Dirty old sod!
See?
Getting old, Sharpe.
The old dazzler isn't what it used to be.
I need a good woman.
A woman who'll let me take my time.
Yeah.
I've got a woman like that.
And I mean to keep her.
That was why Toulouse was my last battle.
No.
Your last battle is in six hours' time,
with Colonel Wigram.
Merci.
(Sighs)
Le Général Calvet m'a dit
que c'étaient vos derniers jours parmi nous.
- Camier! Hoche!
- À vos ordres.
Challon...
(Knock at door)
- Lady Spindacre.
- Oh, Jane!
(Sighs)
Have I lost him?
Lost him?
All the others are returned.
Oh!
You weren't told?
Major Sharpe is well.
Oh, Molly!
And preparing to fight a duel.
A duel?
What happened?
Colonel Wigram made a gallant remark
about your beauty,
which Major Sharpe misunderstood,
and called Wigram out.
No!
He promised me.
He gave me his word!
And broke it. The brute!
What can I do?
Teach him a lesson.
You told him if he fought again,
you'd be on the next boat from Bordeaux.
Now, bad enough he should break his word.
Now, don't you break yours.
There's a ship sailing at three,
and we can be on it.
We?
Oh, my dear Jane, you're my best friend.
You don't think I'd let you down?
Now, pack your bags,
and your power of attorney,
and in three days from now, we'll be in London.
Oh, I don't know, Molly.
How can I leave Richard without a word?
You're not leaving him,
you're teaching him a lesson.
And while he's busy learning his lesson,
we'll be in Bond Street,
buying you some dresses
that'll break his heart when he sees you next.
(Whispers) My fellow likes to fire last.
Shoot, damn you. Shoot!
He likes them to sweat a little.
What if I was to say I was sorry, Sharpe?
ROSS: Don't shoot. Sharpe.
You won't want to shoot him.
Not when you hear my news.
- What news?
- The war's over.
Wellington's won. We've won, Sharpe.
God!
I hope what you said is true, Ross,
because if it's not,
I'll go back there and I'll shoot him in the head.
Might've been better
if he'd shot you in the head, Sharpe.
There's no point beating about the bush.
Your wife found out about the duel.
What?
Yes, she's leaving for Bordeaux,
taking a ship for England.
(Groaning)
Oh, stop your whining, Wigram!
You won't die from a bullet up the bum.
You might spend the rest of your life
scratching your arse,
but that's what we're all going to do now.
- Now this war is over.
- He shot me in the arse, Ross!
Don't go on, Wigram.
What the devil are you doing here?
Major Sharpe, this is a warrant
summoning you to a court of inquiry
under the joint jurisdiction
of the British and French authorities.
Oh, don't be a silly sod!
It wasn't much of a bloody duel.
It's nothing to do with dueling.
What the devil has it got to do with?
Last night,
ten miles outside Toulouse,
somebody stole a coach containing the treasure
of the former emperor, Napoleon Bonaparte.
Two men were killed.
So? What's it got to do with me?
Where were you last night?
I don't know. I was drunk. Blind drunk.
Like every other officer in the British army.
- He was with me.
- All night?
This is a sensitive issue. Sharpe.
Treasure worth more than
a million gold sovereigns.
Lord Wellington's French allies claim it's theirs,
And they have evidence you took it.
I’m sorry. Sharpe.
Am I under arrest?
Lord Wellington wants... proof,
so he's set up a tribunal of inquiry.
If it finds there is a case against you,
you go to a court martial.
If the court martial finds against you...
...you'll be shot.
Who's in charge of this tribunal?
Colonel Wigram.
(Groans)
You wish to withdraw all of it?
All of it.
10,000 guineas!
It's a very large sum, if I may say so, Mrs. Sharpe.
Are you sure that you want it all?
She's quite sure.
Very well.
If you will sign the bottom of the page.
How would you like to be paid
the sum specified?
Notes, coins, bonds. Makes no matter.
We'd like it in this bag.
Oh, no, no, no, no!
No. That's quite impossible.
We do not have such large sums
on the premises,
but it shall be with you by noon. Ma'am.
Please be sure it's sent over on time.
Carruthers has your address.
I'm happy to have been of service to you,
Mrs. Sharpe.
- Ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Carruthers?
- Yes. Sir?
Put a letter in the post to Major Sharpe.
Tell him his wife has closed the account.
(Gavel bangs)
The purpose of this tribunal
is to enquire into the disappearance
of the personal treasury
of the late emperor, Napoleon I,
whose property now belongs by law
to His Most Catholic Majesty,
Louis XVIII, King of France.
Monsieur Roland represents the interests
of the new French administration.
Major Sharpe,
as there appears to be a prima-facie case
against you as perpetrator of this crime.
You may wish to appoint a lawyer.
Just get on with it.
I shall speak for Major Sharpe, sir.
Don't be a damned fool.
What do you know about the law?
The court recognizes that Captain Frederickson
will hold a watching brief for Major Sharpe.
Proceed, Monsieur Roland.
In December last year,
the emperor, Napoleon Bonaparte,
was persuaded
to contemplate the possibility of defeat.
His private treasury was packed in wagons.
And a permanent escort provided
under a hand-picked officer,
Colonel Maillot.
Two weeks ago, after the fall of Toulouse,
this treasury fell under the overall command
of a new officer,
a Major Ducos.
Ducos
May I take a moment of your time,
Monsieur Roland?
Where is Major Ducos and Colonel Maillot
at this moment in time, sir?
Major Ducos is missing and presumed dead
at the hands of Major Sharpe.
Colonel Maillot is at his home in Normandy.
Why is Colonel Maillot not here?
He was not willing
to travel into British-held territory.
But he has sent me this sworn deposition.
The script, sir - why is it so shaky?
Colonel Maillot was wounded
in the attack on the train.
He lost two fingers on his right hand.
- Did you see him write it, sir?
- No.
But it tallies with the evidence at the scene.
I bend two fingers.
Tie a bandage about it.
Voilá.
Anyone could have written that statement.
If this tribunal of inquiry
finds against Major Sharpe,
he will be court-martialed for murder.
You cannot shoot a man
with no more evidence than a scrap of paper,
which looks as if a spider has crawled all over it.
Habeas corpus.
Produce the body.
I want to see Colonel Maillot in this court.
Habeas corpus?
A fellow in the field artillery
gave me a law book to wipe my arse with.
But I read it instead.
I think, Monsieur Roland, we must insist
on Colonel Maillot appearing before this tribunal.
I will fetch him here myself,
but it will take two weeks.
Just one last question.
Why should Major Sharpe,
a rich man, want to rob the treasury?
WIGRAM: He was a rich man.
Major Sharpe's wife withdrew all his money
from Messrs Adam Hopkinson & Son
in London a week ago.
And... er how do you know this?
We intercepted a letter
from Messrs Hopkinson & Son
to Major Sharpe.
WIGRAM: This tribunal is now adjourned.
Major Sharpe will be confined to quarters
in the barracks at Bordeaux.
(Groans)
Oh, Molly, I'm so glad you went back
and bought this.
I wanted it so much when we saw it yesterday,
but it seemed so expensive.
How much do I owe you?
Good grief, girl, it's a gift.
No, Molly, I insist.
Oh, well. Three guineas.
Hmm.
But you must stop me the next time.
My dear Jane, it's your money.
You must learn to spend it
without looking over your shoulder.
No, Molly, I must mind my money.
I'm glad your friend found me this town house.
I'm very happy with it, but the rent is very high,
and we're spending so much.
And besides. Richard will be here soon.
Major Sharpe?
But, Jane, how?
He's sure to follow me,
as soon as Wellington gives him leave.
(Knock at door)
Come.
A Lord Rossendale, ma'am, from Horse Guards.
He says he must see you most urgent.
Shall I tell him to wait?
No. Show him in, Sarah.
Mrs. Sharpe.
I'm sorry to intrude upon you, madam.
I would not have done so
were it not a most urgent matter.
I regret to say that your husband. Major Sharpe.
Has been arrested.
Arrested?
On what charge?
Making away with the treasure
of the late Emperor Napoleon Bonaparte.
But my husband's a rich man.
Why should he do such a thing?
He's done worse, ma'am.
He murdered two men while taking it,
and mutilated...
Beg pardon. Ma'am. But it was bad.
He is in custody now,
and will most certainly be court-martialed.
Perhaps I should have broken the news
more gently?
Nonsense.
You were cruel to be kind, Lord Rossendale.
Major Sharpe has made her most miserable.
Brute!
Doesn't deserve a beautiful woman like this.
Shall I lay her on the couch?
No, take her to her bedroom.
- (Gasps) Don't let her drop.
- Don't worry, I have a good hold of her.
Smelling salts. Smelling salts, you stupid girl!
I shall have to leave you for a moment,
Lord Rossendale.
That girl will never find the smelling salts.
Be so good, Lord Rossendale,
as to take one of her hands and stroke it gently,
to restore the circulation of the blood.
Why, yes, of course.
She's taken every penny out of the account.
Why should she want it all?
Hats.
Hats cost a devil, I'm told.
Then she'd better buy a black one, with a veil.
They're going to shoot me, aren't they?
Yes, of course.
I've got to get out of here,
find this Maillot, find out the truth.
That's not a problem.
I gave the provosts a guinea
to get themselves some rum.
And human nature being what it is,
one little drop led to another little drop.
And...
(Clatter in other room)
After you, gentlemen.
DUCOS: Challon.
Romand, Hubert! Avec moi!
I can't understand it, Pat.
Why has she not written me
to tell me what's happening?
More than likely, she has written to you,
but how would a letter find us out here?
I want you to leave for England immediately.
I want you to give this letter to Jane personally.
Should I not know what's in it?
It says I'm sorry I broke my promise to her,
Patrick.
The rest of it's between a man and his wife.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Where will I find you?
Maillot's place in Normandy.
It'll take me and Frederickson
a few weeks to get there.
Traveling mostly at night.
You'll find us.
Paris.
Paris!
SHARPE: Normandy. We're nearly there.
Get down!
Merde!
(Dogs bark)
Lucille?
Henri!
MAN’S VOICE: Major Sharpe, Major Sharpe!
Major Sharpe!
Henri!
Why not speak English, like the other night?
You're mistaken, ma'am.
We were not here the other night.
My name is Sharpe.
Major Sharpe.
Curse!
He let you live. Be sure I won't be so soft!
SHARPE: Help me!
Help him!
Get him on the table!
What did you use?
Nails. He shot my brother.
I assure you, Madame, he did not!
I heard his name called - Sharpe.
You were tricked. We were all tricked!
Boil some water, quickly!
Oh, cursed!
Escaped?
The provosts will pursue him.
What will happen when they find him?
Perhaps you should sit.
Oh, John,
what am I to do?
Hold on.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Hold him fast.
Argh!
Got it.
(Fizzing)
Help me dress the leg.
I'll do it.
Let him sleep now.
Madame, I don't even know your name.
Lucille Dubert.
I thought your name was Maillot.
No.
Madame Lucille Dubert.
You are very beautiful.
Are you married, Madame Dubert?
No, I’m a widow.
You British made me a widow on the battlefield.
At Talavera.
I'm sorry.
And er...
would you like to be married again?
Married! I hadn't thought of it.
When my husband died, I didn't think
I'd find happiness with another man.
And now?
No, maybe
I'm ready to think about it again.
That will be all, Rudge.
You may be off too, Sarah.
Thanks, ma'am.
To you.
Me?
You at least have a wonderful future, Jane.
You're a rich woman.
When I first saw you.
I thought
you were the most beautiful woman in London.
But wealthy too...
Society will open its arms to you.
What good is that to me?
I'm still his wife,
for better or for worse.
Believe me, Jane, it was for worse.
You are a wife now.
You will be a widow soon.
Don't say that.
I'm sorry, Jane. I'm stating a simple truth.
When they catch your husband.
They will shoot him.
Nothing you or I can do or say will stop that.
You must go.
You mustn't speak of my husband like that.
Major Sharpe has become a murderer, Jane.
He's not the man you married.
He's become a monster
who mutilates the men he murders.
Don't leave me!
I'm not leaving you, Jane.
Jane...
Major Sharpe is still the same.
He has a wife, hasn't he?
How do you know?
He called it out in his sleep.
Jane.
He must love her a lot.
Love her?
If he does, he's a fool.
(Clears throat)
She left him.
You have good sight.
Most men your age need spectacles.
Not me.
I'm not that old.
You're so vain.
You were wearing these
before you broke the glass.
These are not my spectacles.
They belong to a bad piece of work.
A French major by the name of Ducos.
Ducos?
You know the name?
My brother cursed his name. I remember.
Ducos has made Sharpe a thief.
And now he has made him a murderer.
We have to find him.
"Monsieur Juliot, Paris."
He made these.
Surely this Ducos would go back
to get another pair?
Look after Major Sharpe for me.
And when I get back,
I should have something to say to you.
Something to say to me?
And what do I say to Major Sharpe
when he wakes up and finds you've gone?
Tell him he is to be best man.
You will remember that? Au revoir.
Best man...
Good man, better man...
Oh, merde!
Happy?
I love you.
I love my house. I love my life.
Miss Jane!
Harper!
Harper's here!
Jane!
I have a letter from your husband, Miss Jane.
Miss Jane...
Sarah!
Xavier?
You startled me, Major Sharpe.
How long have I been here, ma'am?
Ten days.
Have you been here every night?
Mm-hm.
Who is Xavier, ma'am?
My husband.
My late husband.
(Footsteps)
(Dog barks)
What are you doing in my house?
Who are you?
Apologies, Madame.
Major Salmon.
I'm here on the orders of the authorities,
searching for Major Sharpe.
I am alone.
We'd like to make sure of that, Madame.
He could be in hiding.
Major Salmon,
I am the mistress of this house.
I dust and clean every room
every day.
Do you think I wouldn't know
if there were a man hiding in my house?
If you say so. Madame Maillot.
We um...
came here because we were worried about you.
After all,
Major Sharpe...
...murdered your brother.
Then surely this is the last place
where he would hide.
Madame.
(Galloping)
Thank you.
You have a soft heart, but hard hands, ma'am.
Have you no servants?
What would I pay them with, Major Sharpe?
The Revolution took everything but the roof.
Napoleon took the rest,
including my brother... and my husband.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I make do.
But there are certain tasks
that are too much for me.
It helps sometimes
to have a man about the house.
Captain Frederickson will help you
while we're here.
He has gone to Paris.
Paris?
He's gone to see the man
who makes Major Ducos' spectacles.
He said I should take care of you
until he comes back.
You're doing that very well, ma'am.
Did he say anything else?
Yes!
I think Captain Frederickson
asked me to marry him.
He's a fine man.
He's a hero.
Like you.
Like my husband.
Heroes have short lives.
What is the matter, dearest?
Look what the morning post just brought.
It's a letter from Richard.
I can't bear it, John.
He asks after my health most tenderly.
And then, almost as an afterthought,
tells me his troubles.
This is Sunday.
There is no post.
As I thought. I locked this door last night.
So how did the letter get into this room?
He's been here!
In our bedroom!
Harper was here.
(Running water)
Voilá.
- Monsieur?
- J'arrive.
Dans rue de Richelieu.
Gaston.
I make lenses for the world, monsieur.
I am Captain Frederickson.
I served with Wellington's army.
I too would have been a soldier,
but for my eyes.
But now the war is over, we are friends,
n'est-ce pas?
Just so. That is what brings me here.
During the war,
I was taken prisoner by a Major Ducos.
Ah.
These are his spectacles.
He had two pairs. One of which he loaned to me
while I was his prisoner.
Hmm...
Major Ducos?
You know him?
Perhaps you might tell me where I may find him.
I would like to thank him for his kindness to me.
I... I have not seen him for a... for a year.
It is strange.
These are very special prescriptions,
and only recently
a Count Poniatowski of Naples
ordered such a pair.
Exactement.
Count Poniatowski?
Of Naples.
Thank you, Monsieur Juliot.
Richard?
Are you hungry, Richard?
I'm starving.
What is your favorite French dish?
Er...
coq au vin.
Because it's the only one you know?
No,
I like it cos it's got wine in it.
It's got chicken in it too.
I'll get the wine, you get the chicken.
You will take us to Major Sharpe,
and Major Sharpe will take us to the treasure.
How the devil can he do that
when Ducos has it?
Convince me.
Do you think if Major Sharpe and myself
had the imperial treasure,
I would waste my time in a shop
that makes spectacles?
You are convincing me.
A toast.
What shall we drink to?
To the death of Napoleon.
Oh, you don't know?
But then, how could you?
Know what?
Napoleon is gone.
He's in exile in Elba.
I can't believe it.
Then the war...
...the war is truly over.
(Sighs) What shall I do?
You have to go home.
Until my innocence is proven, I have no home.
To peace, then.
To peace
(Sighs) Peace.
I've never known it before.
I seem to have spent all my life
soldiering, fighting.
Never really thinking about the war finishing,
and what I'd do, where I'd go.
These past few weeks,
being here with you,
helping on the farm, it's been good.
You've been very kind to me.
I feel like I'm...
Your wife will be waiting for you.
Yes, I suppose she will.
Good night, Richard.
Good night, ma'am.
(Sighs)
(Footsteps)
Best I sleep in the barn, ma'am.
(Cowbells)
(Bleating)
Psst.
- It's me.
- Pat?
I've only just got back.
Let me have it, Pat. Let me have her letter.
Jeez, I looked everywhere for her, so I did.
Damn it, let me have her letter, Pat!
There is no letter.
When found her she didn't want to see me...
Where is she?
She's in London.
She's well. She's staying with her friend,
Lady Molly something or other.
- Who else?
- They're being looked after by Lord Rossendale.
We, he'll be a friend off Lady Molly's...
Tell me the truth, Pat...
Is my wife...
Is Lord Rossendale... Damn it! Are they lovers?
Yes or no?
No.
Good God, no.
Nothing like that. Sir. Nothing.
You're a damn poor liar.
But you're a damn good friend, Patrick Harper.
Beg your pardon, ma'am.
The door was hocked.
MAN: Dans le jardin d'mon père,
les lilas ont fleuri
Dans le jardin d'mon père
Les lilas ont fleuri
Tous les oiseaux du monde
Viennent y faire leur nids
GROUP: Auprès de ma blonde,
qu'il fait bon, fait bon, fait bon
Auprès de ma blonde, qu'il fait bon dormir
Auprès de ma blonde
Qu'il fait bon, fait bon, fait bon
Auprès de ma blonde, qu'il fait bon dormir
(All cheer)
What do you say to my plan?
We join forces, go to Naples,
and destroy Ducos?
Just like that?
We cross the frontier into a foreign country,
and fight Ducos
and the devil knows how many men?
I only wish to recover the treasure.
You. However,
need to save yourself from execution.
You have no choice.
Who's in command of this expedition?
How many generals do you see in the room?
None. Calvet.
It's like the French Revolution.
All men are equal, each man on his own merit.
We have the most merit.
- So you say.
- H do say.
What you need in Naples are skirmishers,
snipers, small-arms experts.
We've three such experts -
me, Captain Frederickson
And Sergeant Harper.
So, which one of you equals is in command?
- I am.
- What do you say to that, Captain Frederickson?
Major Sharpe is in command, General.
CALVET: How shall I divide the cheese?
By merit or by rank?
Who gets the biggest piece?
- You do.
- Because I am a general.
No, because bloody hate cheese
(Sighs)
Can I have a few words with you, Frederickson?
Official business, Major Sharpe?
Private business,
between me and you.
Save your breath.
For God's sake, Frederickson!
We've been friends for five years.
We were friends. That's all over now.
So, if you'll excuse me, sir...
For God's sake!
You think I set out to get myself shot?
Didn't you?
No, I didn't! I stepped into her sights.
Damn you, Sharpe! God damn you!
How many women do you want?
- William...
- I hope she breaks your bloody heart.
I will come back.
I'll be here.
Lady Molly Spindacre, ma'am.
Oh, Molly, I'm so glad to see you!
I got your letter. I came straight here.
Damn expensive journey,
I don't mind telling you.
- I'll make it up to you, I promise.
- Don't mention it.
What are friends for?
Now, tell me what's the matter.
Molly,
I'm so frightened!
Richard has escaped,
and is footloose somewhere in France,
sending his men to attack me!
We must leave England.
Leave England? For where?
America.
John has helped me invest my money there,
in cotton
And shaves.
We need money.
You have money. Lots of money.
We do, and we don't.
Most of our money is tied up in these projects.
And John had such bad luck with cards
before he met me.
It's a long story, Molly.
I need about 200 guineas.
Jane!
I haven't got two guineas!
Well, can't we take some things to Bond Street,
get our money back?
Take things back to Bond Street?
Don't be such a fool, Jane.
Buying jewelery is one thing,
selling it back is another.
But John said! Oh, I don't know what to believe.
I'll tell you what you can believe, Jane.
You're the laugh of London.
Rossendale's a reckless gambler,
and if you don't give him up,
you'll go down with him.
Molly, you're my best friend.
What will I do?
Do as I do
Dry your tears, make up your face,
wear your hair high, and your dress cut low.
Drop Rossendale.
What do you think I am, Molly?
A wh...
A whore? That's the word you're looking for.
I'm a whore, Jane.
An honest one. You are dishonest.
I just tell lies to the men in my life.
You lie to yourself.
- Where are you going?
- Where do you think?
Your money's run out.
I'm going back to France, to Colonel Wigram.
I've been away a long time.
It'll be hard work getting him back.
Hair high,
how dresses.
Laugh like a lady, and make love like a whore.
What will happen to me?
Oh, don't worry.
You have a better bust than mine,
and a much stronger stomach.
CALVET: That is where
Ducos and his men are hiding out.
We are here. We march around the bay.
No, across the bay
We'll steal two boats. We can attack tonight.
In Russia, I ate my own corporal.
Disgusting.
(Woman hums)
(Laughter)
(Music box plays)
(Giggling)
(Hums)
Dai.
(Tuts)
(Gasps)
Salope!
(Pants)
CHALLON: Calvet.
MAN: Oh là là!
CHALLON: Allez. Dépêchez-vous.
Venez vite.
MAN: Allez... De la poudre...
Ugh!
CHALLON: Allez plus vite.
MAN: On est prêt. Là.
CHALLON: Dépêchez-vous.
CALVET: Those ruins are like rabbit warrens.
Four men could hold off an army.
How many has he got?
Let's find out.
Look, can you get your men
to take these bloody white cross belts off?
- They stand out a mile.
- Remove their belts?
These are the Imperial Guard, my friend.
They have worn these belts
in every one of Bonaparte's battlefields,
from Austerlitz to Borodino.
They would sooner take off their skins.
Very well.
But you'll let us go up there first.
Soon as you hear a shot, you'll attack.
Frederickson, take the left.
Harper, you take the right.
En avant!
Marche!
(Click)
Get down!
Good shooting, Sharpe.
He stepped into my sights.
Yes, but you could have missed.
CHALLON: Merde. Remettez-moi ça sur la table.
Allez. Remettez ça.
Par ici!
Take me to Ducos.
Présent...
Feu!
Par ici.
SHARPE: Harper.
MAN: La porte, la porte!
MAN: Oh, merde!
Ducos! Where’s Ducos?
The gold, Gaston, the gold!
Mon général!
The bastard's gone to get help.
(Crashing)
Ducos
The war is over, Sharpe.
Apparently, not for you.
Let me offer you a choice.
You can die up there, or you can die down here.
If you make me come up for you,
you will die very slowly,
And very painfully.
If you come down here. With your hands up.
I'll shoot you like a soldier.
You have my word.
Your word?
I give you my word before General Calvet,
with whom I have no quarrel.
You're a damn liar, Ducos!
I say the same. You would shoot me too?
Why would you spare my life?
Why indeed?
Well,
you will have to take your chance.
Gentlemen, you have two minutes to surrender.
(Sighs)
What about this grasshopper gun?
It won't stop 100 men, spread out on all sides.
Spread out on all sides...
That's it.
Frederickson?
Fix me some powder charges.
For grapeshot?
Not grapeshot. Gold.
Non.
Make a choice Calvet-
you lose this box of gold, or you lose the lot.
Frederickson, you man the gun.
Harper, let's finish that bastard off,
once and for all.
Soldati, avanti!
(Gunshot)
SOLDIER: È oro!
Lasciate tutto questo!
Siamo ricchi.
Fire the next one away from the boats.
(All shout excitedly)
Vigliacchi!
MAN: Andiamo! Dai, dai! Qua!
Tonate indietro!
Did I get him?
Don't worry, he's done for.
Allez.
Fait attention!
Ça y est. C'est bon.
(All groan)
I came for the gold, and I got the gold.
What did you come for, Major Sharpe?
For my name,
and for revenge.
Ducos is dead. You have your revenge.
Am I misunderstanding something,
Sergeant Harper?
Ducos was only half his revenge, sir.
Cherchez la femme?
The other half is a woman?
Now you have it
Boats at the ready, sir.
Forget this other woman.
Forget your revenge.
I saw the way Madame Maillot looked at you
back at her château.
I already have a wife.
No, you don't.
Not any more.
Order.
This tribunal is now in session.
Major Sharpe, you may stand.
I adjourned this tribunal some three months ago
to allow Colonel Maillot to give testimony.
In the meantime, Major Sharpe escaped
and murdered Colonel Maillot.
I will now send him for court martial.
I have no doubt the penalty will be death.
Monsieur Roland,
is there anything you'd wish to add?
With the deepest respect, Colonel Wigram,
I must tell you that there is not a word of truth
in the case against Major Sharpe.
What's he saying?
(Murmuring)
Silence! What the devil do you mean by this,
Monsieur Roland?
This is the sworn testimony
of General Maurice Calvet,
the general who commanded Major Ducos
to take the imperial treasure to Paris.
This statement was given in my presence
two nights ago.
This testimony makes it clear
that this tribunal has no choice
but to discharge Major Sharpe
without a stain on his character.
MAN: Well said.
What about the murder of Colonel Maillot?
There was one witness to that murder,
Colonel Wigram -
Colonel Maillot's sister,
Madame Lucille Dubert.
She is in this court today,
and she is prepared
to testify to the innocence of Major Sharpe.
(Gavel bangs)
Do you wish to hear her testimony,
or do you take my word?
Yes, yes!
Before you adjourn this tribunal, sir,
I am instructed
by His Majesty King Louis Philippe
to say that France withdraws all charges
against Major Sharpe,
and expresses her deep regret
for any damage that might have been done
to the good name of this good officer.
(Murmurs of assent)
(Gavel bangs)
This tribunal...
...finds there is no case against Major Sharpe.
Accordingly, I...
I am closing the proceedings.
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Major, congratulations. Wonderful news.
- Oh, what wonderful news.
- Terrific.
Terrific.
Good shooting, Frederickson.
They stepped into my sights.
You could've missed.
Where to now, William?
Home.
Become a lawyer.
Barrack-room lawyer?
No,
bedroom lawyer
In five years' time,
every rich widow in Westphalia
will come to me if she has difficulties with her will.
Your woman is waiting for you, Richard.
(Woman laughs)
Come on.
We're going home.
MAN: Congratulations, Sharpe... Well done...
(Screams)
(Wind whistles)
There's nobody there, Jane.
(Sighs) Nobody at all.
(Sighs)
What's the matter?
I had a letter from Molly this morning.
Richard has cleared his name.
He's free to come home.
He'll have his revenge on us, John.
Will you go
Or will you...
This time tomorrow, you will be in England.
I'll be back.
I know
Would this moment last for ever?
Kiss me now
And leave me never
Oh, farewell