(Shouting in French)
Good lad. Good lad.
- We've got 'em going now.
- They're well away.
SOLDIER: Vite par ici!
(Women scream)
SOLDIER: Allez!
Where the hell have they got to?
- I can hear the drums.
- That's not exactly enough.
Rifles!
(Blows whistle)
Look at it. Clean through the whole bloody lot.
Argh.
Well, will you look at this.
SHARPE: Our absent friends.
REDCOAT: Look at it all!
REDCOAT: Come on.
SHARPE: Sergeant, come here.
REDCOAT: Get out of my way.
- Where did you get to?
- Up at the top, sir, as ordered.
- And you sat tight?
- We was all set to move, just as soon as...
SHARPE: But you didn't.
- We would've done, sir...
You were to head them off.
Clear orders to block their way. They were done.
They'd have surrendered.
Hundreds of prisoners.
Did you take money?
- What's he saying?
- Were you paid to do it?
I was not, sir.
The only money I'd take off a Frenchman
is like this.
Wait for me!
REDCOAT: Come on! Come on!
They were saving themselves.
Well, you know, dead men gather no loot.
Brave soldiers of the South Essex Regiment.
Get your men together, Sergeant,
we're going back to camp.
No, sir.
- What did you say?
- I refuse your orders.
- You shouldn't have done that.
- You took the king's shilling, Sergeant.
He can have it back!
I were no bigger than him there.
This is better. I've got lots more stashed.
We all have.
So no more orders, Sharpe.
- Major Sharpe.
- Not from you, Sharpe,
nor no bugger else.
- We're off, ain't we?
REDCOATS: Yes!
- The provosts'll get ye.
- We'll be off where they can't.
With the wild fellas in the hills.
- They'll sell us women, grub and booze.
REDCOAT: Yeah!
So bugger the King and his shilling!
- (Redcoats cheer)
- It's your last chance.
I think it's your last chance to join us.
Look at your men, Sharpe.
The whole, horrible dirty bunch.
Look at him there,
the scaly licking his chops.
Sergeant Rodd.
Private Rodd.
Deserter Rodd.
SHARPE: When the provosts catch you.
It'll be 200 hashes.
And then you'll hang.
Anybody?
(Redcoat sniggers)
REDCOAT: Look at that. Look at that.
Ooh, look at that.
Cor, look at this.
HAGMAN: I am a deserter
And this I shall say
The generals they thrive
While the men rot away
They sit drinking fine liquor
And brandy and all
Whilst we to the front
And like good soldiers fall
- I hate that song.
- Oh, aye?
- What's up wi' it?
- It's on the side of the deserters.
It's only a song, lad.
- Do you think the provosts'll really catch them?
- They catch a lot of them.
- The provosts are muck.
- Private Skillicon! (Tuts)
No, no, they are. They're thief-takers,
so that makes them thieves themselves.
Skillicon doesn't say much,
but when he does you have to listen.
Sing that song again.
Oh, Private Skillicon
Hark to his fame
Ha ha!
Provosts all run at the sound of his name
So come all you bold chickens
And you guinea cock fowl
You'd best watch your feathers
Skillicon's on the prowl
That'll do it now, lads.
(Chickens clucking)
I can hear dinner.
(Horse whinnies)
Good day. I take it you're provosts.
And what do you claim to be?
Riflemen.
Half your equipment's French.
It's better.
What on earth's that?
It's a seven-barreled volley gun.
Made by Mr. Nock of London.
I gave it to him.
He's the only one that can handle it.
And you are?
Major Sharpe. South Essex.
And you?
Lieutenant Ayres... sir.
Provosts catching looters, eh?
Yes, sir.
Brave work
Better than fighting.
AYRES: Soldier.
- Wait a minute.
AYRES: What the hell are you doing?
- They haven't gone.
Who's missing?
On. Lease. Lease.
Oh, Skillicon!
- This one of your men?
- I'll deal with him, Lieutenant.
No, you won't. He's going to hang.
- Sir, it's a wild chicken. Just a wild thing.
AYRES: Wild?
Nobody lives here. It's deserted.
He's a looter.
Hang him!
I'll tell you where there's looters...
Stop!
You're not going to hang him.
Oh, yes. And you will watch it.
Let him go, Lieutenant.
- Are you mad?
- I said let him go!
Have your thief, Major.
He took my chicken.
You stupid bastard.
- Why did he hit me?
- If he hadn't, I would have.
You've landed him in the shite. Grab your rifle.
Go on, grab your rifle.
You'll be lucky to save your neck.
(Redcoat shouts orders)
SOLDIER: Come on, lads.
Come along. Come on.
Richard Sharpe.
Major Munro.
Now, you've not to enquire what I've been doing
since we last met because it's secret, as usual.
And I shan't enquire what you've been doing
because I know already.
You're in black trouble, laddie.
- How bad is it?
- I could use words like "dire" and "dreadful",
but that’d cheer you up
Major Sharpe, sir?
His Lordship will see you now.
I won't bloody apologize.
If it's an order, you will.
You'll grovel, cringe, squirm and toady
to Lieutenant Ayres.
He screamed his head off to the provost marshal
and the provost marshal screamed his head off
to my lord.
Major Sharpe.
- Sir.
- Did you threaten Lieutenant Ayres with a rifle?
Yes, sir.
Some years ago, you saved my life.
I was glad to, sir.
I shouldn't like to think
you'd trade on my support.
Never, sir.
Evidences for impending courts martial.
Four score of them for my attention.
Am h to add another?
If you must, sir.
I often envy Napoleon, do I not, Munro?
You're wrong. He's losing, you're winning.
Still, he has the Imperial Guard
and disciplined soldiers.
I have the scum of the Earth.
They fight well, sir.
Oh, yes - thieves, drunkards, jailbirds.
I've drilled them into heroes.
But when the battle's done,
they turn back into drunken vagabonds.
They rape. Plunder. And run.
Not all, sir.
- Yours just kill wild chickens.
- And now I'm to invade France with them.
Well, I'll line the roads with provosts
to keep them in order.
Provosts Major Sharpe
For any infraction, to hang them on the spot.
And if any man defies my provosts,
or, worse still, should turn a gun on one...
Apologize to Lieutenant Ayres.
Very good, sir.
He's waiting.
Disgraceful, Sharpe. Disgraceful.
All I have to say, and in particular to you, sir,
the Provost Marshal,
is that my behavior was utterly inexcusable.
I imperiled Ayres' authority
And overstepped my own.
I apologize
Oh, you do?
Yes, sir. Unreservedly, sir.
I very much regret my part in it, sir.
As I'm sure Lieutenant Ayres does his.
I do, sir. Yes, I do.
What have you got to regret in this, Ayres, eh?
Is there more to this than meets the er...
Gentlemen, I'm sure honor is now satisfied.
- Feel better?
- Shamed.
- I'd not go through it again.
- You were lucky, man.
His Lordship wanted you chopped up in bits.
Did you not notice?
- Was it enough?
- For what?
France. When it happens,
I want to be in it, not stuck in some...
As the Lord disposes.
The one above, not him in Headquarters.
I can't pray.
Washed in the blood of the Lamb, ye should be,
not just the blood of the French.
- Where are we?
- Eh, sarge, know the way?
Sarge?
Do you know the way, or what?
Which way now, then, sarge?
If we keep the sun on our back s
during the heat of the day...
- We bloody die.
...we'll be going north.
Keep that on!
- Why, sarge?
- We don't want them to think we're frogs.
- Who?
- Anyone we run across.
But if it's provosts, they'll have us spotted.
- That's right.
- Nah, the provosts don't come this far.
All right, lads.
RODD: Act friendly.
Er...
Buenas tardes, amigo.
Amigos. Inglés.
You talk English?
Sarge...
RODD: Drop your guns. Drop 'em.
Amigo...
Si, amigo.
Say we want food.
Er... coma,
por favor.
And water.
Agua.
Casco
Oh, my God.
Dorme, dorme, mio Patrizio
Que tu mamá ya va bien
- I've done nothing. I've done nothing.
- Sergeant!
SKILLICON: They'll hang me.
What's going on here? Sir?
- I'm arresting him for looting.
- Does Major Sharpe know?
This doesn't concern him. Nor you.
- Bring him away.
- No! No!
- Lads, they'll hang me!
- Have they the right?
- He was asleep, sarge.
- Find Major Sharpe.
This time they'll hang him, surely.
- But Sharpe...
- It's for Mr. Sharpe. Don't you see?
(Somber drumming)
HARPER: Poor Skillicorn...
- Will they really do it?
- I've seen the gallows.
This is not for my baby.
HARPER: He's bloody useless. But...
- He's one of mine.
- No, don't.
It'd just suit them.
I don't like to watch death agonies
deliberately imposed.
PROVOST MARSHAL: Ht's for the example.
- He stole a chicken.
One chicken, ten thousand chickens.
The crime is the same.
In a short time, sir,
you will lead your army into France.
I need hardly remind you...
- Indeed you need not.
- A hostile population.
Any excuse to rise savagely.
I take your point.
I took it a long time ago, without your help.
I'm corrected, my lord.
I should mention, sir, that the provosts
have recovered many deserters.
A figure of 237
- in the past week...
- 242.
Good.
Punishment?
For now, just hold them in detention.
Very good, my lord.
He'd string up my whole army.
Aye, well, sir, he's bitter against sin.
When we go into France, Munro, it must be
to liberate it from a wicked regime.
- I believe that profoundly.
- Aye, but will the French believe it?
When they learn we are not come
to rape, steal and pillage.
And when will that be... sir?
(Soldiers mutter)
SOLDIER: Did you see that?
WOMAN: Is it in there he is?
Somebody say.
Bess?
Oh!
Oh, Arthur!
This is my cousin - Mrs. Nugent.
- How on earth did you get here?
- You mean, all the way from Ireland?
On a boat. What else?
And we found a man to show us the way.
Where's he got to?
And...
You know who this is, don't you?
Grown up a lot. Still my baby.
Ellie?
Cousin Arthur!
Er... you'd best come inside
and explain yourselves. Leave the rifles.
- Oh, they're not loaded.
WELLINGTON: See to the horses.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Well, I've never seen him sweat like that before.
- Poor old Nosey.
- I weren't looking at him.
I was looking at the young lady.
- Lovely.
- Mm.
Mm!
- Try this chair, miss.
- A cushion.
- Thank you.
- Perhaps something to drink. Some lemonade?
That would be a blessing. I'm parched.
And then you'll want to get on with your war.
Shove us in a tent or something.
Bess, why are you here?
- Uh?
- Dada.
Will. My husband, Will Nugent.
We've come to find him.
Er... he wrote to me.
And you got him his commission.
Oh, Dada was so pleased.
I'm afraid I don't quite er...
Perhaps after Madrid?
There were so many changes.
Ah, yes, yes, I do recollect.
He was directed to the preparation of maps.
And... er... yes. Quite an artist, old Will.
Always was. And now?
We think he might be lost.
This is war, madam.
Not killed lost.
- Sort of... mislaid.
- We had a letter from him.
MUNRO: How on earth did he manage it?
It's mostly enquiring about the dogs, but...
Oh, but... there's stuff here. Look.
Rumors about a vast hoard of treasure
somewhere in these hills.
- Typical Dada.
- (Bess giggles) When he gets the notion...
Bess, what is it that you want me to do?
To mount a search for him?
Well...
I'm about to order the invasion of France.
To suspend it while we find Will Nugent would be
interesting but might be criticized in London.
- You mean you won't help?
- Cousin Arthur...
we've come all this way.
And now you're going all the way back.
Both of you.
As soon as it can be arranged.
But tonight... you shall be my guests.
Oh, Ma, look at my dress.
It's all squashed to bits.
I can't wear this.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Can you do something with it?
Sí, señora.
Give her these, too - my petticoats.
- Could you do these as well? Thanks.
- Por supuesto.
Miss Nugent.
- Yes.
- Major Richard Sharpe.
Are these your rifles? We've had them cleaned.
- Oh, there was no need.
- I think there was, miss.
I mean, no hurry.
Unless to put a bullet through cousin Arthur.
The General.
He's kicking us out.
You traveled here alone?
Just a guide and a servant.
I'm glad you had these.
They're American. Made in Pennsylvania.
- None better.
- Speaking as a rifleman.
- Yes, miss.
- (Laughs)
I'll see you tonight, at my cousin's party.
- Doubt it, miss.
- Are you on duty?
I er... I'm not exactly in his favor at the moment.
Ah, well...
You're like me.
You could come as my escort, Major Sharpe.
Will you?
- Well, I er...
- We could talk about guns.
(Bess laughs) He's so funny!
(Laughter)
Don't worry, my dear, you'll travel back
under proper protection. More port here.
I Can’t spare any provosts, my lord.
- There's no need. I'll send some older men.
- How old?
On their way to discharge,
so they don't pester young Ellie.
But, Miss Nugent,
suppose you had run into trouble?
- She'd have seen them off.
- With that Yankee popgun?
Coon gun, that's what they call 'em.
Tiny little bullets.
But deadly accurate.
You were lucky, ma'am.
Two females on your own.
- If you'd run into any Frenchmen...
- Or guerrillas...
Even worse - savages.
I've found French soldiers
they'd nailed to doors alive.
Our horses are very fleet.
So are theirs.
She's a lady,
which is why she's got a lady's gun.
Which is a rifle.
What about that, Major Rifleman Sharpe?
You're drunk, Mr. Ayres.
So should you be by now.
And I stick by muskets.
Ayres.
Back in Ireland, I go shooting quite a lot.
With a lady's gun.
Just as well I'm a lady, Lieutenant.
What sort of game?
Mostly rabbits.
Rabbits!
I can knock the head off 'em every time.
If it comes close enough.
Come here, little bunny rabbit,
look down the spout.
Every time.
- At 100-yard range.
- She never misses.
Better be careful, Mr. Ayres.
I smell a wager.
(All chant) A wager! A wager! A wager!
A wager. A wager. A wager. A wager.
- Is he truly your best man?
- He surely is.
That man could shoot a pimple off your nose
without breaking the skin.
Will you run the book, sir?
I will not.
This is sinful gambling and I'll have no part of it.
I'm here to see fair play.
It is only sinful, sir, when you lose.
- I'll make the book.
- Ahn. Well said.
Put two shillings down.
Put me down for 20 guineas.
Miss Nugent, to make up for last night -
I was a bit bosky -
I lay 50 guineas on you.
Sergeant, 50 on the girl.
You have it.
MAN: Ten guineas on Miss Nugent, please...
How about you, Major?
Will you match me in guineas?
- No.
- That's the way, laddie.
Set them an example.
Then you're free to shoot.
Go on, Major. Instead of this scruffy creature,
prove yourself.
Not who's going to win,
but who's going to lose, eh, Major?
Good luck, sir.
- Scruffy creature!
- Clean yourself up.
MUNRO: Change of contestant.
MUNRO: Take your positions, both.
I like to lie flat.
COOPER: Crikey, just look at her, will you?
(Whispers) Sharpe.
Ten shots apiece. Fire in your own time.
Targets set at 800 yards.
Miss Nugent, bull at four o'clock.
God save Ireland.
Major Sharpe. Bull at two.
- That'll do.
- She'll better that, just wait.
Miss Nugent, dead center.
Yess! Major j
you're off-center at five.
Dammit, I should have wagered a hundred.
- The book's still open, sir.
- Right, then, raise it.
An even hundred you have, sir.
Major, center...
four.
Miss Nugent... another bull.
(Laughter)
Miss Nugent, bull's-eye again.
When Arthur hears of this,
he'll want you in his army.
Oh, be quiet, Ma.
Major Sharpe, also bull's-eye.
Miss Nugent. Center at seven.
Major. Center... bull.
Major Sharpe. Bull's-eye.
Miss Nugent. Bull at ten.
Number nine coming up.
Miss Nugent... bull's-eye.
Major... a bull.
Last shots. Contestants... all square.
Miss Nugent, bull's-eye.
Ah, no... no, not quite.
Center... nine o'clock.
Major Sharpe...
miss.
- Bravo!
RIFLEMEN: Miss?
HAGMAN: Aye. Miss.
Oh, shite.
Damn. Damn. Damn.
Bad luck, sir. Take another shot?
Well, my lucky day.
Oh, well done, Ellie. Great match.
Congratulations.
Did you not forget this?
- Look, Miss Nugent...
- Ellie.
Go on, shoot.
Hold everything.
All bets still stand.
HAGMAN: At Miss Nugent's request.
Major Sharpe is to refire.
Center, bull's-eye.
Center shot takes the match.
(Ellie chuckles)
Oh... I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
Your hundred guin... (Laughs)
REDCOAT: Where do you want them, Corporal?
- Over there.
Mind out the way. On the double.
Get these on top.
Mad for the drink, so he is.
Swills it down like a tinker on a fair day.
Don't you, hm?
- Would you like to hold him, ma'am?
BESS: Oh!
Oh, he's beautiful.
He's not just any old baby, ma'am.
- He can comprehend five languages.
- (Bess hums)
Can march 50 miles a day,
can strangle wild beasts,
- play a bugle with one hand behind his back.
- Harris.
I think he's just fine the way he is.
- (Baby whimpers)
- (Bess hums)
May I?
(Baby whimpers)
Shh. Shh.
Guard! My lord's tent.
Guard of Honor, at the double!
(Shouting)
- What's going on?
- No idea.
HARPER: To do with the big offensive. Maybe.
SHARPE: Maybe.
Or maybe not.
HARPER: Jeez., he's a queer hat on him.
It's what's under the hat.
HARPER: Any notion who he is?
SHARPE: They call him Eh Casco.
What rumor says about him...
I never put much faith in rumors.
In this country, Pat, rumor's always right.
I told him you know of his reputation
as a powerful leader of partisans,
feared by the French.
So much so that they will not enter his territory.
Que temen tanto que no entran en su territorio.
What exactly is his territory?
Where?
Cuál es exactamente su territorio? Dónde?
Lejos. En las montañnas.
In the far hills.
That's all he'll say. Sir.
Yo no mato ingleses.
I do not kill Englishmen.
Well...
that's a relief.
Not for the Scots.
Solo los capturo cuando huyen de usted.
He takes our men when they run away.
I think he means deserters.
Ah. How many?
- Cuántos?
- Cincuenta y dos.
He's got 52.
So, what does he propose?
Is he going to turn them in?
I fancy not. Nothing so simple.
Qué propone?
Se los entregaré.
A cambio de armas.
He wants to trade them for guns.
I thought we should come to that.
Baker... rifles.
Do you know what Baker rifles are?
- They're in use with my rifle regiments.
- Baker rifle.
How many?
- Cincuenta.
MUNRO: Have you got that? 50.
That's about one gun per deserter.
Would ye contemplate it?
Oh, yes.
I can spare the guns.
And it'll help these fellows
to damage the French.
- Damage?
- Look at the eyes, Munro.
Besides, I want those deserters.
This breastplate must be three centuries old
at least.
He must have looted a museum.
Make the arrangements, Munro.
(Soldier shouts orders)
Major Sharpe, sir?
- What is it?
- Compliments of my lord, sir.
Will you attend upon him forthwith?
- Is this an order, sir?
- Well, of course. You have some objection to it?
I'd hoped to retain my present command
for the invasion of France, sir.
- (Sneers)
- Outrageous. You want to take your pick?!
No, sir. Just do my duty, sir.
Which is as I've just described to you.
Exchange of rifles for deserters. Understood?
Yes, sir.
Where's the rendezvous, sir?
We don't quite know yet.
MUNRO: It'll be worked out stage by stage...
In secret.
This um... El... what? Casco.
- Hm?
- If he does produce the deserters. Then what?
- We'll look after them, sir.
- Oh, no.
Oh, no, you will not.
That's the duty of my provosts,
under an officer of mine.
Any suggestion who that might be, sir?
- What?
SHARPE: Is he listening outside. Sir?
COME IN!
Sir.
HAGMAN: If anybody wants to know my name
My name it is young Johnson
I have my orders from the King
To court all the girls that are handsome
To court them all, both old and young...
I haven't brought my men.
They won't be needed, will they?
They've got no duties here, Mr. Ayres.
Are you nearly done?
That's for me to say.
Carry on, lads.
AYRES: Why do they stare so?
(Chuckles)
You hanged one of them, Mr. Ayres.
You might do it again.
You're a man to watch.
A word.
We shall be the only two officers.
We can't have enmity between us.
Can we not?
- It's hard to talk to you.
- It's quite easy.
Just start like this:
"Major Sharpe, I believe you are ignorant
and illegitimate and wounded all over,
but I forgive you.
My daddy's rich and fiddled me
into the Bow Street runners - oh, sorry, provosts.
So I'm a nice person."
They say you saved Wellington's life.
Do they? You don't have to believe it.
- And captured a French Eagle.
- You needn't believe that either.
Isn't it true?
We're going to dangerous places, Mr. Ayres.
A horse can slip and go over a cliff.
- And when you do...
- Let me go.
Go and tell your tales again.
Major Sharpe, I offered you my hand.
We should put things behind us.
Set out in good will,
a cheerful parting from our friends.
- And Ellie.
- Ellie?
Have you told her yet?
The man you hanged...
the man who stole a chicken...
I punished him myself... like this.
That should've been enough for him.
Is it enough for you?
Then here's my hand... just as you wanted.
Smooth.
Very, very smooth.
Lovely finish. Try it.
This one's a beauty.
See? Can I trade it for mine?
SERGEANT: Come on. We haven't got
much time. Get those horses loaded up.
SOLDIER: Yes. Sergeant.
SERGEANT: Hewitt. Give him a hand.
Ma, look at this.
Excuse me, excuse me. What is happening?
That'd be a bit of a secret, ma'am.
You're under orders?
BESS: Sergeant. Perhaps you can help me?
Where are you going?
Are you allowed to tell us?
Over the hills.
The fact is, we don't know ourselves yet, ma'am.
Oh, Major Sharpe.
- I was just about to say goodbye
- Nobody else is going. Is it only...
Just us.
A sort of special mission, all of a sudden.
Into the hills?
Mrs. Nugent,
I shouldn't really be talking to you about this.
- Well, I just want to know...
- Anyway, you'll be gone when we get back.
Maybe you could look in
on Ramona and the baby when I've gone.
Yes, we will. Won't we, Ma?
Ma.
If I don't find you here...
Would you come to Ireland and find me there?
Never mind me. Just come back.
- Suppose the French did try it?
- A counterattack through there? Impossible.
- Marshal Soult's a fine, mad officer. He might.
BESS: Let me see my cousin.
GUARD: You can't go in.
- Will you take your hands off me?
- Madam!
Does blood mean nothing to you?
Blood?
For the Lord's sake. I'm your kin,
come all this way to throw myself upon you,
- to seek help.
- You burst in...
And you've mounted an expedition to go
exploring in the hills without a word to me.
- Expedition?
- Major Sharpe is ready to leave.
Now, Bess. That's nothing to do with...
You may have no concern for Willie Nugent,
but my husband is a fine man.
- He deserves a great deal from us.
- Calm yourself.
For God's sake. There's enough black sheep
in our family to fill a field.
Whoring and swindling and...
But Will isn't one of them.
And as for your wife, Kitty,
- and her tribe...
- Bess, what is this for?
Let me go too. To find him.
No. You will not.
You will be removed from here tomorrow,
in the opposite direction,
disarmed and obedient.
Show this lady out.
- He's very quiet.
- What?
Your man, Lieutenant Ayres. He's very quiet.
Well... I just had to er... explain a few things.
Oh, right. There's nothing like a little bit
of explanation to promote understanding.
I remember having to explain something
to a fella in Ballyshannon once.
You know... I nearly half killed him.
HAGMAN: Sir!
Sir, we're being trailed. About a mile back.
- French?
- I couldn't make out.
Rifles, make ready!
My God, it's them. It's the women.
Rifles... stand easy.
Stand easy.
Major Sharpe, we're joining you.
- But I thought Lord Wellington...
- I talked him around.
Look, you just can't...
SHARPE: I need a written order.
- We have one.
I’d better see it
BESS: Of course...
You have it, Ellie.
No, you have it. I saw you pack it.
ELLIE: I think. Um... wait a minute.
(Sighs) Oh. Oh, no. I think I've left it in the tent.
ELLIE: I'm sorry.
I wish you hadn't done this.
We won't be a burden.
There'll be danger.
We can look after ourselves.
Aye.
But there's danger you can face up to
and danger of another kind.
I've smelt it once or twice.
It's rank. It's wretched.
And it's not of this world.
Sergeant Harper's a religious man.
- He'd have a word for it.
- You mean evil?
Something...
Something very wrong.
You're trying to scare us.
Well, you can't.
BESS: We'll go alone.
- Ellie...
We'll find Dada.
When first I deserted
I thought myself free
But the provosts they caught me
And hanged I shall be
So take heed of my fate
Less yourself you might see
For now the king's duty lies heavy on me
Miss Nugent.
Forgive my curiosity.
I'd like to hear about Dublin society.
He wants to know if we're really in it, Ma.
Well, yes, we are. Such as it is.
We're Anglos. Not like the real thing.
Unlike the sergeant here.
ELLIE: He's a real Paddy.
Oh, I'm a real Paddy, all right.
A Paddy who dreams of an Irish Ireland.
Free from outside influences.
Thank you, Sergeant.
But I fear it takes a war
to bring a man to his senses.
You know, I should be at home,
minding the cabbages.
- That'll do.
SHARPE: Forget society. Just watch the French.
- What do you mean?
- Look to the left.
AYRES: I see.
ELLIE: Just three.
- No, four.
SHARPE: So. Be ready.
And be calm.
And we'll head towards those trees.
- (Horse whinnies)
- I said calm, Ayres.
Here they come!
(Shouting)
Get back!
MAN: Get in the trees!
Sabers, vite!
Avance.
- Stay back, ladies!
- No fear.
Chargez!
MAN: Are the horses all right?
Are you all right?
SHARPE: My God. You did well.
She saved me.
A clean shot.
He's so young.
He's a boy.
SHARPE: They all are. Conscripts.
- Half trained.
HARPER: Cooper's hurt.
It's not too bad.
Would you have a look at him?
A woman's touch.
- Are you all right, Mr. Harper?
- Oh, I'm fine. It's only a scratch.
Bugger.
- (Cooper sighs)
- Well. Mr. Ayres.
How shall we report this?
A skilled defense or a valiant action?
I'm not very experienced.
First rule - always get a girl
between you and the enemy.
I killed him.
I never...
I never did that.
Not a sign.
They've quit.
Where's Ellie?
Ellie?
You proved yourself.
No.
That's when a woman has a child...
...and she's made a new life.
- Yes, I know.
- But if she takes a life... it's wrong.
Do you see? It's wrong.
Oh, God.
(Sobs)
(Ellie pants)
AYRES: Major Sharpe.
There's something I ought to say.
- I feel it my duty to...
- Yes?
...make sure we're heading the right way.
We are. That all?
Yes.
I saw you with Major Sharpe.
Oh, yes?
Would you marry him? That's the question.
Oh, Ma, it wasn't...
I just needed him then.
- More than your mother?
- Yes.
Something five or six miles away.
Look s like a tower.
Ayres, those bloody men of yours.
Get them to help - and the same goes for you.
There it is.
SHARPE: The watchtower.
Look. Over yonder, sir.
- Had trouble, Sharpe?
- We met a few French.
Aye, I saw.
And I saw these ladies.
I got my cousin's permission.
Aye? Not while I was there.
Later.
His lordship must be growing
more persuadable.
Now, we must prepare for our guest.
(Thunder rumbles)
Now, Mrs. Nugent, I wish most profoundly
that you were not here. Nor you, Ellie.
I came to find my husband.
A needle in a haystack, ma'am.
- And it's rotten hay.
- I tried to tell them.
I've been finding out more. Guerrillas
come in all kinds, we make use of them.
Now these…
Out there, in their hills, they have no god.
- They have something else.
- They're heathen?
Ah.
The story goes: There was a great shipwreck
hereabouts - long, long ago.
A galleon
bearing treasure from Mexico
to the King of Spain.
Not only gold, but idols for him to see.
Even people
- from that terrible hand.
- Treasure?
Oh, that catches your ear, laddie.
Well, if it's still there, nobody's found it yet.
- Will heard of it, too.
- You said... a terrible land.
The Aztecs of Mexico were a high civilization
and entirely evil.
How could that be?
Their religion was based on human sacrifice.
They cut the living hearts
- from their prisoners.
MUNRO: That'll do.
AYRES: Thousands.
- Or they skinned them.
- I said that'll do.
They even had a god of flaying.
Xipe Totec. The Flayed God.
Stop gloating.
I came across it in my studies.
Rather amusing.
Major Munro, you didn't mean
there could be anything of that here?
Tush, no.
Well... maybe a taint...
turned into foolish nonsense.
- These folk are peasants.
- And that's all?
I'll maybe set a few braw missionaries on them...
- when I've the time.
- (Rustling)
- He's coming up now, sir.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
- Out of sight, ladies. Go with the sergeant.
- No. I want to see this fellow...
- Do as I say.
...question him.
- If he'd ever come across Dada...
- I insist.
He's alone.
(Horse hooves)
Buenas noches, señor.
Tiene los rifles?
Dentro de dos días, haremos el cambio.
The exchange takes place in two days' time.
We'll be there.
- Oh, ask him, please.
- Quiet.
Señor... señor...
Por favor...
Perdóne me...
Have you seen my husband?
Un inglés.
Capitano Will Nugent.
EL CASCO: Un mensaje francés.
El mensajero quiso dárselo a usted.
- What is it?
- It's a French dispatch.
They must have intercepted a messenger.
They do sometimes.
Oh, my God! It's Soult.
- Marshal Soult?
- Plans for a counteroffensive.
My lord must see this.
Get me my horse.
I think he said something about... the messenger.
Ellie, what is that?
It's made of some kind of skin.
(Thunder rumbles)
HAGMAN: By hell, I'm bloody drenched.
It's just as bloody wet in here.
BESS: Thank you, Sergeant.
- All in a day's work, ma'am.
SHARPE: Horses in here.
Get their loads off and all under cover.
What there is of it.
(Shivers)
(Stamping of hooves)
(Rasping cough)
Are you all right, ma'am?
I think so.
What is this place?
It's a house of God, ma'am.
But he hasn't been looking after it too well lately.
No.
(Sighs) Don't go.
Stay.
Casco
I don't want to think about him.
Just you now.
What about me?
Do you have a wife somewhere?
I had.
She...
She was shot dead.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I hate this land.
Come on. Up, you lazy buggers.
- (Moaning)
- Come on. Up!
Where's my lord?
- My lord.
- Munro, I thought you were far off.
I think you ought to see this.
Marshal Soult.
Was I right?
By God, you were.
- Halt the column.
OFFICER: Halt the column.
I misjudged him. He's quicker than I thought.
The man's a genius.
I think not. We can't have two geniuses
in the Peninsula.
- No, sir.
- Still. He'd have knocked me about.
And roundly. Too.
General staff assembly in ten minutes.
OFFICER: Very good. Sir.
Blood on this.
Aye, well.
The messenger would have succumbed.
Buenos días, señores.
We've got it all here as promised.
Have you brought the English soldiers?
- Harris, can you help?
- I'll try, sir.
Dónde están los soldados ingleses?
Aquí están.
He's says they're here, sir.
- Well, let's see them.
- Tráigalos.
Todo bien.
(Horses whinny)
SPANISH SOLDIER:
Venga, por aquí. Con prisa!
Rápido. Pa' lante!
- Dos por allí.
- Ten cuidado, rápido.
Cuidado. Rápido.
- Vale. Parados aquí.
- Quietos. No os mováis.
SHARPE: You men.
I'm Major Sharpe, South Essex Regiment.
I'm here to collect you.
You're going back.
Major Sharpe, sir.
You know me.
Ah, yes... I remember you.
Yes, sir.
My name's Rodd, sir.
Sergeant Rodd, as was.
Please, sir, don't let him...
I told you. I'm in charge.
Lieutenant Ayres, do your duty.
Get this rabble out of it.
Come on, move it out!
(Men mutter and groan)
AYRES: Come on.
Sergeant, the rifles.
SOLDIER: Adelante!
- The horses as well?
- Just get it done, Pat.
(Horses whinny)
I think we've finished, señor.
(El Casco imitates a bird cry)
(Cries)
Go on now, señor.
(Crying continues)
- (Clattering)
- Esto es parte de botírn.
Yo no lo quiero.
Says he doesn't need it.
That's ours, sir.
- They took everything off us.
- So it's your bit of loot, is it?
Get these off, sir.
- Better not.
- Sit down.
- We want water.
MEN: Yeah.
MAN: Water.
PROVOST: Sit down. Be quiet.
RODD: Here's some grub.
MAN: Over here!
MAN: Sergeant.
(All shout at once)
MAN: Please, water.
RODD: They starved us.
RODD: They grabbed us a few at a time.
We guessed they'd swap us.
- A wonder they didn't kill us.
- We're English.
So King George saved your skins, then?
What? Why did you say that?
It's just a manner of speaking.
MAN: Give us the water.
- Oh! Oh, yeah.
- Of course. Yeah.
- Was anybody killed?
Um... they caught the Froggy.
He was a messenger.
- What happened to him?
- I don't know.
They took him away.
They were supposed to be somewhere
up in the hills.
Caves, I heard.
- They're frightened to talk.
- Not surprising.
- Well, they're safe now.
- Safer.
Mrs. Nugent, we're leaving. You too, Ellie.
Oi! Can I have a scrap of baccy.
- Anything else, sir?
- No. That'll do me.
- Just a pipeful to keep me going.
- Let me see that.
Baccy?
Ma. Ma, it's Dada's.
It's the one I gave him.
- Where'd you get this?
- I found it.
- Where?
- I don't know. It was week s ago. On a road.
- Somebody must have host it.
- They did.
I never stole it.
- This is Dada's.
- Where was this road?
Out that way.
I just thought if I could get to the sea,
maybe buy a boat...
Get home.
Look, if you just give me some time,
I might remember.
- I could try And remember.
- He'll say anything.
- This is proof.
- An old pipe?
- I saw Dada make those marks.
- We're leaving now.
So pack up your gear, both of you.
Ellie...
- Take charge of it, Mr. Ayres. Make it official.
- On your feet, you scum!
HAGMAN: Forty I got for selling my shirt
And forty for selling my blanket
if ever I 'list for a soldier again
The devil shall be my sergeant
Poor old soldier
If ever I 'list for a soldier again
The devil shall be my sergeant
- Perkins.
- Sir?
Run and help the ladies. See to their horses.
Yes, sir.
Mrs. Nugent, Miss Nugent. It's time to leave.
Where are you?
Oh, no.
Sir, I can't find them. I think they've gone.
Damn.
Gone without a word.
They must be mad, off on their own.
- What do we do now?
- We're finished up here.
Those men go back to camp as planned.
Up to you, Lieutenant.
Right, sir. And then you search?
For Goods sake, yes
Those bloody ignorant female fools.
- Are you not going with them, Mr. Ayres?
- My men are brutes. They'll manage.
And recovering my lord's strayed relations
is an urgent duty.
You find anything, Hagman?
Nothing, sir. Ground's too hard for tracking.
Nothing, sir. I've looked hard everywhere.
Bugger.
It's just the girl, isn't it?
Mr. Ayres
- Don't tell me we're hunting the old duenna.
- Have a care.
How many times have you ploughed her?
Look...
I might decide I don't have a use for you.
(Horse whinnies in distance)
- Horses.
- (Distant chattering)
Not just horses - men.
- (Horse whinnies)
- I'd say French.
- What is it?
- Shh.
(Distant chattering)
- (Chattering in French)
HARPER: Ht's the same hot.
SHARPE: This time. We'll take them.
(Whispers) Cooper, Harris, Perkins.
Anglais!
(French soldiers shout)
En garde, monsieur.
SOLDIER: Allez, allez, allez!
- Hundreds of bloody bushes, he pisses in mine.
- We should have bloody had him.
Major.
SHARPE: That's not one of them.
That's a partisan.
HARRIS: His obituary. I think.
"A daily report
of Lieutenant Jean-Luc Barbier.
Our prisoner
has rendered himself to his wounds."
- Not very good French.
- Is that all?
No, there's more.
It seems to be... about Aztecs.
Let me see.
"But he confessed much.
I will not call them guerrillas. They are savages.
They persist in a belief they are descended
from the ancient Aztec people of Mexico.
This is to excuse their wanton savagery."
Let's hear it.
"They inhabit certain secret caves.
There they worship death."
Mother of God.
"Their leader is known as El Casco.
Only the English. Who have no religion.
Will have dealings with him...
...to supply guns."
What have we done, sir?
AYRES: Listen.
"I intend to discover this nest of savages
in the caves and destroy it utterly."
Oh, yeah? Him and whose army?
The fighting rabbit, eh?
He's got the right idea.
Jean-Luc Barbier.
Forms his letters like a young kid.
I nearly split him.
- Do you think they're the ones who attacked us?
- Why don't you ask them?
(Sighs) Oh, Ma.
(Bird caws)
It's his sort of place.
What do you mean?
If it was back home,
he would have stopped to paint or draw.
Poor Will.
Why poor? He's alive.
I know he's alive.
WELLINGTON: You men have committed crimes
under army haw.
Enough to have you court-martialed And shot.
As the Provost Marshal has correctly demanded.
However, in a few week s
I enter the heartland of the enemy.
I need every man who will follow me
and fight for me.
Are you such men?
ALL: Yes!
Go back to your regiments.
Wear your new red coats with pride.
And I'll see you in the land
of Napoleon Bonaparte.
ALL: Yeah!
- Well?
- It's true, sir.
And Sharpe's gone after them.
Damned women. I knew it.
What now? Mount a full search party?
Leave it to Sharpe.
Dismount, Mr. Ayres.
- What's happening?
- I'm giving you an order, that's what. Get down.
- It's my horse. I'm entitled...
- I will not have you ride when better men suffer.
Are we going round in circles?
- No.
- Oh, good. So, we're just lost, then?
(Distant gunfire)
Rifles.
- Baker rifles.
- (Distant gunfire)
A l'attaque!
- That was gunfire.
A long way off.
(Sighs)
We shouldn't have done this.
- Do you want to go back?
- Back? How?
A couple of stubborn fools.
We shouldn't be here.
Yes, we should.
Ma! Look at this!
It's Dada's.
It's Dada's. He was here.
He was here in this very spot.
Now we’ve got to go on.
Of course.
BESS: We'll stay on this riverbed.
Will'd be keen on it -
for the picturesqueness, you know.
- Ma.
- What is it?
(Crackling and rustling)
(Twigs snapping)
Who is it? What do you want?
- Are you loaded?
- Yeah.
Get past them and go.
Get out of my way!
MA
Ma... Ma... Ma.
- Ma.
- Ellie.
Oh, no. Ma?
Ma, Ma, no (Sobs)
(Wails) No!
(Wails) Ma.
(Man screams in terror)
(Man screams) No. No. No.
(Sobs)
(Tortured screams) No. No.
No.
(Tortured screams)
(Man screams in distance)
- (Screaming continues)
- My God.
How many is that?
- Four?
- Five.
But I've no wish to be counting.
- I don't want to seem clever...
- Be as clever as you like.
Whoever they are... I think it's a sacrifice.
(Moans in terror)
Dada.
Oh, Dada. Dada, we've been looking for you
all over the place, me and Ma. We...
(Moans and mutters)
Huitzilopochtli... god of war.
Tezcatlipoca...
- Tezcathipoca... god of the smoking mirror...
- Dada.
Tonatiuh... god of the sun.
Xipe Totec...
the Flayed God.
Dada. Dada, who am I?
You know me.
Coathicue...
...lady of the serpent skin.
Oh... Dada.
(Twig snaps)
Please... I wish to make surrender.
- I know that face.
- Yeah, so do I.
You fought with me, monsieur... and ran.
Oui. Je le regrette.
Mais... I wish to be your prisoner.
Please.
- They have killed my men.
SHARPE: Who?
- The partisans?
- Oui, les guérillas.
Et puis... they cut the hearts out of them.
Les cœurs.
Their hearts?
They have also... une femme anglaise. Jeune...
Ellie.
What have they done to her?
Take me to her. Now. Vite!
Go on.
(Nugent hums)
Ma is dead.
They killed her.
(Humming continues)
It was here that I saw.
Monsieur, you will now redeem yourself.
Pour la gloire.
You will lead two companies of French infantry
to the attack.
Two? Where are they?
- You are not serious, monsieur?
- You will make a diversion.
Une diversion. You will cry out orders,
And so will my men.
And fire your rifles. All of you.
To draw them away.
Entendu.
Mon brave.
Harper.
(Humming and chanting)
Pour...
spit...
and ram.
(Men chatter)
I'm coming with you.
Attrapez tous!
BARBIER: Deuxième compagnie.
Faites avance.
Troisième compagnie!
(Gunfire continues)
Charge á la baïonnette! Pas de prisonniers!
(Woman screams)
SHARPE: Ellie.
- She's fine.
Ellie.
It's me.
Richard.
What's happening?
They've run. Every last one of them.
Be sure.
Harris, take Lieutenant Ayres out and bury him.
Perkins, Hagman, go on guard.
They've done well... including the Frenchman.
Is that...
- Ellie?
- It's Dada.
Xipe Totec.
Our Lord, the Flayed One.
He can't even remember Ma.
Ready, sir.
Let's do it.
The mind's a very funny thing, you know.
I had an uncle once
who thought the fairies were after him.
- What happened to him?
- They got him.
All set?
For you to do, sir.
(Hisses and fizzles)
Richard... it was here Ma was killed.
Rifles... search!
- Ellie?
- Dada.
Oh, Dada! Dada?
But he knew me then. He did.
- He will again.
- He's on the mend. He'll be fine now.
Tragic about your poor mother, my dear.
I'm most grateful...
to this young man.
He saved us all.
It's what he does. Isn't it, Sharpe?
One last thing, sir.
Loot recovered, sir.
Mostly gold. Some silver.
Is that all there was?
Yes, sir. That's all.
# When evil stalks upon the land
# I'll neither hold nor stay me hand
# But fight to win a better day
# Over the hills and far away
# O'er the hills and o'er the main
# Through Flanders, Portugal and Spain
# King George commands and we obey
# Over the hills and far away