#Oh my life #
#Is changing every day #
#In every possible way #
#And oh, my dreams #
#It's never quite
as it seems #
#Never quite
#I know I've felt
like this before #
#But now I'm feeling it
even more #
#Because it came
from you #
#Then I open up and see #
#The person falling
here is me #
#A different way to be #
#I want more... #
- Hey, Avram.
- Hi!
Excuse me, ladies.
Excuse me.
Thank you so much.
- My wife paid you, right?
- Yeah yeah.
- Good.
- Have a good weekend.
- You bet. Ciao.
- Ciao. Ciao.
#And they'll come true #
#lmpossible not to do #
#And now
I tell you openly... #
Maida! Maida!
I'm picking up Slavko now,
could be a bit late.
Don't worry.
I'm going with Amela and the girls.
- I'll see you there.
- Ciao!
Hey, did you put
the beers in the car?
Yes, your beers
are safe!
Oh Bruno,
I'm sorry!
It's okay. It's okay.
How is business?
Good!
Yeah, it's very good.
#Oh my life #
#Is changing every day #
#In every possible way #
#And oh, my dreams #
#It's never
quite as it seems #
#'Cause you're
a dream to me #
#Dream to me. #
It's all there.
I'm sure it is, Emir,
but I'll just count it.
Okay, see you
next week.
Mr. Selimovic,
good morning.
I told him he should go
to the police.
Yes, and end up paying them
more than I pay Zijah.
He never listens.
- Your tickets.
- You boys should be out there
competing in Barcelona.
No Yugoslavia,
no team.
I just want
to be at the Olympics.
Mr., Mrs. And Miss
Selimovic.
Slavko Stanic and...
- still doesn't know who he's taking?
- Slavko?
He doesn't know what he's
doing in three hours' time,
never mind three months!
Thanks.
Ciao, Natasha.
- Ciao.
- Have a good weekend. Yeah, ciao.
Where is it?
Here?
No!
Hey, look!
It's here.
- Hey, Vlado!
- Slavko!
You make me
late, huh?
Barcelona!
- Now the weekend begins.
- Yeah.
We're gonna
have a great time.
- We should have got that watermelon.
- I told you.
No, I think that's my cue
to call it a day.
Just can't seem
to keep my hands still.
I hope your patients
don't hear you say that!
Okay, back
another 25 meters?
- Are you kidding?
- Yeah, come on!
- Miso!
- No!
So have
some bread.
- Stop it!
- What's happening up there?
They're
shooting olives.
Back here.
22, 23...
- You need some beer.
- Mm-mm.
No, I mean,
come on.
You got it.
- For you.
- Thanks.
- Nadja!
- Hey, Lejla! Amela!
- Maida, come on!
- Amela!
- I'm here!
- Come! Food.
That's too much for you?
Come, sit.
Eat, eat.
What?
Okay,
so I see you later.
What do you
think of her?
- She's coming to Barcelona with me.
- That's six you've got coming.
Is it six?
- Mama, do I have to eat the potatoes?
- Yes.
Slavko, if you're looking for someone
to take to the Olympics...
Vlado, that's not nice.
Why don't you ask Natasha
if she wants to go with you?
You know, the girl
from the travel agency?
Natasha!
Come on, I'm not
looking for a wife!
- Ah, she's a nice girl.
- That's what I mean.
Natasha!
What's going on here?
- I don't know.
- What are they doing?
- What's going on?
- You must show me your papers.
I don't have
to show you anything.
You're now in the Serbian Republic
of Bosnia. Your papers!
Since when?
It was declared by Radovan
Karadzic this morning.
Don't be ridiculous.
Karadzic has nothing to do with us.
- Drive on.
- I must see your I.D.
- Your nationality?
- Yugoslavian.
Good night.
Idiots.
I can't believe these soldiers.
What do they think they're doing?
Get out!
Get out of the car.
It's okay, I'll deal with it.
Give me that thousand.
- You're not giving him money.
- Just let him deal with it.
Slavko Stanic,
Serbian from Banja Luka,
now living in Sarajevo.
These are friends of mine.
- They're just taking me home.
- I see.
I was going to buy some
of Napoleon's best Cognac
to celebrate the news.
- Why don't you celebrate with me?
- I think I will.
- Okay, take care. Bye.
- You too.
Okay, let's go.
Pow!
Vlado...
what if Maida and Amela had been traveling
back on their own?
I mean, with me, okay,
I have my Serbian I.D.,
but two Muslim women
on their own with the kids,
- it's worrying.
- They'll be gone in the morning.
The U.N. Can't allow
that to go on.
Eh, I hope
you're right.
Good night,
sweetheart.
- Good night.
- Sleep well.
Are you sure you've got everything
for school tomorrow?
- Yes, Mom.
- All right.
- Good night.
- Don't stay up all night.
- I won't.
- Night.
- Be a good girl, Lejla.
- Thank you for the weekend.
- It's a pleasure. Ciao!
- Night!
I have to put it first of all
in this hand, okay?
But... it's gone!
- Oh...
- Wait a minute, where is it?
- Oh it's here!
- No, it's too fast!
Come on, music off,
lights out.
- Bye. Good night.
- Sweet dreams!
And no talking
late, okay?
I'm going to bed.
- See you later.
- Good night, Slavko.
Good night, Maida.
Ah, for me?
Wow.
I had them all stuffed in a drawer,
so I thought...
Where shall I hang it?
- So young.
- Mm-mm.
- That was Budapest, right?
- Yes.
600 meters.
Good shooting.
I knew you'd have
to include that one.
So why now?
I just wanted you
to have it.
- Let's drink.
- Yeah.
When Bosnia's parliament
voted for independence
from Yugoslavia, Bosnian Serb
leader Radovan Karadzic
warned of
violent consequences.
Now Bosnia is independent
and there's growing concern
that violence, even open war,
could erupt,
fueled by old ethnic hatreds
that are again emerging
as Yugoslavia
disintegrates.
In Sarajevo, many believed
peace would prevail.
Muslims, Croats and Serbs
have lived comfortably together
in the Bosnian
capital for decades,
forging friendships
and intermarrying.
But the mountains
that ring Sarajevo,
where the winter Olympics
were held just eight years ago,
are now controlled by Bosnian-Serb
militias with heavy weapons.
One kilometer or a kilometer
and a half from Sarajevo.
But we don't shoot.
We try just to keep peace
and not to... to control
the surroundings of Sarajevo.
You could take Sarajevo
tomorrow, couldn't you?
Anytime.
We could take it anytime.
Lejla, what are you
doing in there?
Bosnian-Serb politicians
still talk peace
and they're denying a report
that Muslims and Croats
are now being forced at gunpoint
to leave their villages.
- I'm trying to find my book.
- Can't achieve anything by war.
We don't want to take
the others' villages
or the other towns
or to impose any revolution.
We just want to be free,
to be as independent as the others.
But many Sarajevans don't
believe Karadzic wants peace.
Fearing the worst,
they're abandoning their city.
- Found my book, Dad.
- Hmm?
- Found my book.
- Good.
You had it!
Ready?
- Bye, Mama.
- Thank you for having me.
Bye-bye.
Bye-bye, Lejla.
Stay whenever you want.
- Bye!
40, 50, 60.
Okay.
Come on.
That'll be
17 Deutsche marks.
- Do you think we should be leaving?
- I don't know.
I mean, I can't
leave the hospital,
but maybe I should be getting
Amela and Lejla away.
See you later.
I'm sure that a lot of what is happening
is because people are getting
on the bandwagon and creating chaos
just to make an easy buck.
And it's our fear
that they're living off!
I think it's important
to let them know
that we will not be
frightened out of our homes.
Yes, I know...
but it's not that,
Mr. Selimovic.
My boyfriend's Serbian and
he's been called up into the army.
That's why we're
going to leave.
- I see.
- He doesn't want to fight.
No, I can understand that.
- I'll keep your job for you.
- Thank you.
Of course.
My car.
Hey!
Abandon your homes
or be murdered.
What can I do?
Who can I report it to?
Nobody's interested!
In Zvornik,
people are fleeing
with only the clothes
they're wearing.
There are reports of young men
being murdered or taken hostage.
- Panic is gripping Sarajevo.
- Look! It's Zijah!
Do you know how much
he's charging for one can of petrol?
200 Deutsche marks!
...is to buy it from the gangs
that are running the black market
- that's suddenly developed.
- Hey.
- Hey, that's our car!
- It can't be.
It is, look! They're
selling our new car on TV.
- Hi.
- Would you believe it?
For keeping your husband
up late last night, Maida.
That is outrageous.
That is outrageous!
I should have taped it.
What's happened?
Zijah! He stole my car
this morning.
And he's just been selling it on TV, just
now! It's just been on!
Talking in a high voice
isn't going to bring it back.
No point in having a car.
They won't let anyone
through the roadblocks.
- We got through last time, didn't we?
- It's different now.
- Have you been called up?
- Yeah.
So what are you
going to do about it?
I go tomorrow.
Why?
He's been called up.
You don't have to join
Karadzic's army.
There are plenty of Serbs who are
draft dodging. Miso isn't going.
Miso's a doctor.
And I wouldn't want
Miso in my army.
- What will you be doing?
- Cadet training.
And if they start firing
those guns on the hillsides,
where are you
gonna be then?
- Wherever they're not pointing at me.
- Firing them?
He said he's
cadet training.
- I have nothing to do with artillery.
- Perhaps you should have.
Then you could tell
your commanding officer
to take his tanks
off our hillsides.
I don't like guns pointing at me!
Some idiot might set one off!
You can't get sucked
into all this, Slavko.
Those guys calling themselves
generals are madmen.
They call me Muslim.
They call you Serb.
We're Yugoslav!
You have to get out.
What they got you doing?
Training kids to shoot on us?
I can get you three
plane tickets out of the city.
You're family to us.
You belong to Sarajevo,
not to those idiots in the hills
living out their stupid history books!
- How much?
- What?
For the tickets.
I can hear.
- 10,000 Deutsche marks.
- 10,000 Deutsche marks?
Where to,
New Zealand?
Vienna.
10,000 Deutsche marks
for Vienna?
That's cheap.
People are paying twice that price.
- How much are you getting out of it?
- Hey.
Maida, l...
I don't get anything.
I just want you
to get out of the city.
And what the hell
would we do in Vienna?
- Be refugees?
- No no no no no.
We are not
going to be refugees.
That is third world stuff!
This is Sarajevo, not Somalia!
We're Europeans,
for God's sake!
You can go to Stockholm
and stay with Anders.
We can't arrive
on Ander's doorstep and say,
"Hi, we're refugees. We'd like to move into
your house for the next 20 years."
Vlado spent 15 years
building up his business.
And I have worked overtime
every week to live the live we do.
So nobody is going
to take it away from us now!
The moment
we walk away,
we lose everything.
This is our home.
I think you should leave.
I'm just trying
to warn you, Maida.
Listen to me.
We don't get
our wage until...
unless we start fighting.
A lot of angry soldiers, Vlado.
That's why you should
take those tickets.
You may have everything
to lose, we have nothing to lose.
You know the most important
thing in the world to me
is that you, Maida
and Nadja are safe.
Yeah.
See you around.
Sarajevo is now cut off
from the rest of the world.
Encircled by Bosnian-Serb machine guns,
artillery and tanks.
If they fire just one of those guns
up on the hillside,
they will have destroyed
themselves.
It's just like what
happened in the Gulf.
The Americans will come...
pow! Straight at 'em.
But the only response
from the Bosnian-Serb
leadership today was silence.
Nadja!
Nadja! You okay?
- Mama!
- You're okay away from the windows.
Come on!
Get our things.
Okay.
Shh-shh.
- Come on, Nadja.
- No!
Hop on Daddy's back.
Maida!
They're stuck
in the elevator!
There's nothing we can do!
Come on! Come on!
Come on.
We should make a run
for Miso's.
- I don't want to go anywhere.
- We can't stay here.
Come on,
come on.
Let's go.
Stay close.
Go on.
Nadja!
- Leave it!
- What?
Nadja!
Come inside!
Go on.
Hey, listen.
They're going to frighten us
out of our homes, aren't they?
That's what they're doing.
Who are you calling?
Slavko.
I need to find out
about those tickets.
I think
I should do that.
Lejla?
Never ever go out
on your own again.
Make sure either me
or your dad are with you.
- Do you hear?
- That goes for you, Nadja.
Not until
those tanks are gone.
And don't ever
use the elevator.
Here, try this on.
The lines are down.
From their dominant positions
on the hills rising
above Sarajevo, Bosnian-Serb
gunners can precisely target
most of the streets
and buildings in the city.
Snipers are now operating
from positions along the front lines,
shooting anyone
in their sights.
And for the people
of Sarajevo,
there is no escape from a city
that's become a shooting gallery.
The roads out are closed and the airport
is held by Bosnian-Serb forces.
They overran it yesterday
using tanks to crush
any opposition.
Now Sarajevans
must either surrender their city
or try to defend it.
Okay.
What's he doing now?
If you want to control
the black market, start an army.
That's what he's doing.
Zijah's militia...
opportunistic mother...
This is the magazine.
This is how... where you load it.
Then you get
ready to shoot.
Put the safety...
always be careful.
Dear Lejla, my best friend
ever in the whole world.
This is my first report to you
from the front line.
The electricity and water
are still off,
but Dad has found some
useless plastic stuff
to put across the windows.
Old Teddy has got
a cut on his nose,
but otherwise,
the Selimovic family is just fine.
Where are you sleeping?
I'm not allowed
in my bed anymore...
and Dad says we're not
going down to the basement
because he thinks
we'll be safer where we are.
Great! Let's hope he's right
or we're dead!
I'm sorry!
- Where are you going?
- Get an ambulance, quick!
Young Malik's out there
with a rifle.
He doesn't have
a chance.
Nadja, come away.
Malik, no time
for mistakes.
Like that.
You're going to be
on the front line at Dobrinja...
Chetniks shooting at you.
That should do it.
I'll be all right,
darling. I will.
I'll be back, okay?
Come here.
Hey hey! Over here!
First house!
- Vlado!
- Nebojsa!
- Good luck!
- Thanks!
Everyone's in.
Okay...
the Serbs are
way back.
Back here,
no problem.
So, Avram, Samir,
Malik and Dusko...
Nevinova Street.
Malik...
Malik, come on!
Forward,
for God's sake!
Malik, get forward,
you idiot!
You have to get
forward into the house!
Malik!
Vlado, get the kid
to the house!
Sarajevo's suburbs
have become battlegrounds.
Civilians are being
caught in the crossfire.
Here in Dobrinja, the fighting
is particularly vicious.
It's a predominantly Muslim district next to
the Serb-controlled airport.
Its streets are now
a killing zone.
Nine of the 25 men in just
one unit defending Dobrinja
have died in
the last few days.
One of the many tragedies
of this conflict...
Home leave.
People who were once friends
are killing each other
and the international community
appears powerless.
- Nadja.
- Thank you.
- Hello?
- Vlado, how are you?
Slavko!
- I tried calling you!
- How are Maida and Nadja?
Yeah, they're here.
They're fine.
Good.
I'm really glad to hear that.
Where are you?
Well out of it.
Where?
I told you you should
take those tickets.
Yeah... yeah, you were right.
I can still
get you out.
It may be your last
chance, Vlado.
You've got
to take it this time.
- Go on.
- Go and see Natasha.
- You know, from the travel agency?
- Yeah, of course I know her.
I've given her details
of a route you can take
and a special pass to get you
through the checkpoint.
It's totally safe,
but you have to go today.
Vasa Slava Street,
"C" Block, 340.
You've got that?
340 Vasa Slava Street.
Lieutenant Stanic, sir.
Okay. For God's sake,
Vlado, you go this time!
Okay, okay, I'll come.
Promise me now.
You get the hell
out of there!
You should take
Nadja and go.
On our own?
I can't leave now.
I'm needed here.
Cross the mountains
on our own?
- What if it's a trap?
- He wouldn't do that to us!
He wants you
to be safe!
- I'm not going anywhere without you.
- No.
I won't go anywhere
without Lejla.
We stay together, Vlado.
Okay, let's see
what we have.
Good shooting.
Mm-hmm.
Good.
What are you trying to do,
shoot his thing off?
Come here,
I'll show you.
Okay, you are now
trained snipers.
Tomorrow, you'll be going
to the front line in Sarajevo...
- One, two and out.
...to the districts of Grbavica,
Dobrinja, Nedzarici,
Alipasino Polje.
Men, women, children...
You keep a little breath inside you
to keep you still,
and then you will become one
with your target.
You see a target,
you fire.
Your job is
to terrorize, okay?
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir!
I'd rather my team didn't shoot
in Alipasino Polje.
Why, you have
friends there?
We all have
friends there.
But we are Serbs.
You're fighting
for our families.
You are shooting for everything
and everyone we have lost,
for all our suffering.
Meet Slavko Stanic,
the best shooter in Yugoslavia!
Tomorrow, his boys will show us
what they can do in Sarajevo.
- Hi!
- Happy birthday!
- Chocolate!
- Good to see you.
- So how does it feel to be a teenager?
She hates being older.
- Hello!
- Come on in!
Okay...
Oh look,
this is great!
- You guys want beer?
- Fantastic!
- Sure.
Nadja, can you put this on the piano,
please? Thank you.
- Where did you get all this stuff?
- Don't ask.
How much did it cost,
that's the question.
- You have to celebrate a birthday.
- Our pièce de résistance.
- Pizza!
- Oh thank you!
One with tuna,
and one pepperoni special.
- Look at that, Lejla!
- Maida, you want beer?
- Eat, everybody!
- Yeah, come on! Go for it!
- So...
- What?
Have you heard
from Slavko?
- Yeah, he called.
- Yeah?
In fact, he offered us
an escape route.
Escape route?
What sort of escape route?
Yeah, a route
out of the cities.
Said he had some friends
on a checkpoint. Nadja.
- Thank you, Dad.
- So...
- when are you going?
- Piece of pizza for you.
No no, we didn't take it.
It was just for that day.
Are you crazy?
Why the hell not?
We have dying people
dumped in the corridors
of the hospital every day
and we can't treat them!
This is only the beginning!
Vlado did tell us
we should leave.
It was me who said no.
I wanted us to stay together.
Of course you did. Vlado should
have said, "Thank you, but go!"
For God's sake, Vlado,
we're talking about survival here!
If anything happens
to any of us...
- you know what I'm talking about.
- The children...
- Nothing matters more than survival.
- You want to survive?
You have to fight for it.
That's why I have to stay.
Sure, but Nadja doesn't,
Maida doesn't.
What reason on earth could
there be for keeping them here?!
You could have
taken my car.
You could have taken
Amela and Lejla with you.
I would give anything
to get them out! Anything!
I'm sorry.
Let's cheer
to the birthday girl.
Thank you.
Cheers!
Hey, how much does it cost,
an hour for a woman?
My friend's getting
desperate over here.
100 Deutsche marks.
Then tell your sister
I owe her 50!
You maniac!
What are you trying to do, kill me?
Hello, best friend ever.
Me again.
I spend half my life
waiting for a mother
- and here I am, waiting for her again.
- Come on, let's go.
Go on.
- We'll go by the market, okay?
- Okay.
Here, take this.
- Wait for me, Lejla.
- Come on now.
- Can we stop by Nadja's on the way?
- No.
I want to come
back and do the laundry.
I want to give her the tape.
Have the batteries not run out
on that thing yet?
- Where are the wheels?
- Oh, Jeez, I've forgotten them.
Would you go back and...
it doesn't matter. I'll get them.
- You wait here.
- Yes.
Okay.
Oh come on,
where is it?
Lejla, have you
seen the cart?
- No, Mom.
- You had it last.
Okay, where's this...
Hello, best friend ever.
As I was saying, I spend half my life
waiting for my mother,
and here I am,
waiting for her again.
I was going
to use this tape...
I'm not going insane.
I'm fine.
There we go.
Lejla.
Come on, Lejla, it's not funny.
Lejla, come on.
Let's go.
Come on.
Lejla.
Lejla?
Lejla!
Come on, Lejla!
No no, Lejla!
No, God, no.
Please, God, no!
Lejla!
No! No, please,
God, no!
No!
- Get her inside.
- No! No!
Okay.
- We must call Miso.
- He's at the hospital.
- I'll call him for you.
- No, I don't want him to know.
- You have to, Amela.
- No!
There's a sniper in the empty
building at the far end.
That's what's happened.
They must have taken the building.
She'll be all right.
She's going to be
all right.
Vlado.
Get back!
Maida's just called me.
Will you please
get out of here?
Yeah.
- Oh, Miso, I'm so sorry.
- Just get out of here.
I don't ever want
to see you again.
They can't bury her
at the cemetery.
Why not?
It's full.
And no one will go to Bara
because of the snipers.
Hello, best friend ever...
I'm not staying here
to see my daughter murdered.
Where are you going?
Across the city.
An apartment in Kosovo.
It belongs to a couple who've left, so we
can use it until the end of the war.
Hello, best friend ever.
It's me again...
Miso got it
for Amela and Lejla,
but now Amela wants
to be near the grave.
He found it for them
the morning she was shot.
Why do you tell me that?
I'm just telling you
that he's managed to...
No, you're not! Will you stop
playing that freaking tape?!
She'll play it
if she wants to!
You're only telling me that because that's
what I should have done.
No, I'm not.
He heard about it...
And he! He's only doing this
now to show me up!
Do you think showing
you up is on his mind
the day he's buried his daughter?
Every time, you get it wrong!
Oh, what do I get wrong?
Miso understood
the situation all along,
from the beginning and you never did!
You were blind!
And who told you to take that route out
when Slavko phoned?
- It was too late by then!
- Miso didn't think so.
How could I leave you
when you are on the front line?
- You're leaving me now!
- If you can't see why I'm going now...
No, I do.
Go on, do it. Shove off.
Yes, I will!
What a good man
he is, huh?
What humility on the day
he's burying his own daughter
to think of you
and Nadja.
- Yes, he is a good man.
- I mean it!
How the hell can he
still be a good man?!
Go away.
- Nadja...
- Go away!
Leave me alone!
Hey!
Help!
How are your boys doing
in Sarajevo?
They're okay.
You got to keep
an eye on them.
Don't worry,
I'll keep them sharp.
This is easy.
We can bomb every
Muslim's house in Bosnia.
But there'll be no Serbia,
unless we take Sarajevo.
So, which house you want?
Pick any house.
We'll save one for you.
Hah.
Hey hey,
stop stop, back!
Back up.
Say goodbye.
What happened to my family
was 10 times worse than this.
Get them out of here.
To all our families.
- I'll take this house.
- Of course.
Okay, we leave this house.
Let's go.
We have poor snipers.
- They are targeting the apartment on...
- What are you telling me for?
To do something about it.
Why?
Are your sales going down?
Everybody in the estate
has to use the streets
some times during the week.
And all the victims are people
going to the water truck.
Is this it?
Okay.
What else do you need?
There's no one shooting at us
from inside the estate.
They've got to be
in those buildings over there.
You're looking
for anything...
any change
in light or shadow...
cigarettes smoke,
anything.
Okay.
They've got
to be there somewhere.
Help!
Nothing.
Get forward!
Sofia!
Stop!
You stay here.
She's moving.
Dino, bring that car
over here.
You have to be seeing
at least one of them.
We're not seeing anything.
Get them into the car.
You find these
murderers, Vlado.
- Do you know where Dr. Kovacevic is?
- I really don't know, sir.
Miso.
Okay.
I need your help.
The bodies of two women
shot in the head
in Alipasino Polje were
brought in this afternoon.
- Can you give me an autopsy?
- Give you an autopsy?
Who do you think you are?
I need to find out
from where they were shot.
You think we have time
for autopsies?
Miso, please,
any information, anything.
Look, I'm doing
what I can.
You have to wait in reception
like everyone else.
Malik!
How are you?
Vlado, hi.
I am okay.
Thanks.
Girl, 13!
Mr. Selimovic?
- Mr. Selimovic.
- Here.
Please, follow me.
Okay...
the bullet entered the front
of the cranium here.
There is a clean hole
in the outer layer
and a shattering
of the inner layer,
but it got no further
than the brain.
The diameter
of the wound...
Wouldn't the bullet normally
pass through the head?
Don't you know that?
You're the one
who does the shooting.
Aside from which part
of the body you are hitting,
I would have thought it depends
on the distance the bullet travels.
The bullet passed
through Lejla's head,
if that information
is of any use to you.
Therefore I would surmise
that this bullet was
at the end of its trajectory.
Therefore shot
from a long distance.
You've had
your two minutes.
- The bullet.
- What?
That killed her.
That's five...
600 meters away,
shooting
through buildings.
Everyone killed has been shot
in the head. It's not possible.
I couldn't do it...
but it's possible.
Can't you get at him
from here?
I only get one chance.
If I miss he'll move.
It's another 15 days
looking for him.
- You see that bus on the Serb side?
- Yeah.
Now if I get a position
behind that,
I can reach him going
into the building at the back.
The only way to get behind
that bus is crossing the road.
We go under the road.
Okay.
I was wrong.
I couldn't get
an angle on him.
- Is Natasha here?
- No.
- Where is she?
- She doesn't live here.
- I know she lives here.
- I don't know who you mean.
- Where is she?
- Please, I don't know.
Freaking liar!
Freaking liar, where is she?
Please, I don't know.
Tell me one more time
that you don't know her,
and I will take you
to Zijah
and I will tell them
you are an informer.
Please, no.
Sit down.
Now you tell me the truth...
and you'll be okay.
So is she your girlfriend?
She's my sister.
Go on, take it.
Do you know Slavko Stanic?
Did Slavko invite Natasha
to go with him to Barcelona?
To the Olympics?
He did, didn't he?
I hoped he would.
We were all
going together...
my wife,
my daughter,
Slavko,
your sister.
Is she with him now?
Slavko...
he's as a brother to me.
He means as much to me
as Natasha does to you.
What do you want me to do?
- I have to go and see them.
- It's impossible.
- You just tell me where they're living.
- They're up in the hills,
across llidza. It's impossible
to go there now.
Draw me a map.
Well, how about that?
Come on in.
Ohh, I was hoping
you'd make it.
Come in, come in.
How did you know
I was coming?
Natasha's brother called on the C.B.
If you had called me yourself,
I would have told those boys on the hill to
hold firing until you were over.
Come in.
Natasha!
Get some water and
a towel for our guest.
Give me that.
Come in.
There she is.
Isn't she beautiful?
- Hi.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now pay homage
to the athletes and officials
of the 172 delegations
which have taken part
in the games of the 25th Olympiad.
- They are the stars of the ceremony...
- Thanks.
Why have you come here?
Oh, to drink...
to talk, hmm?
Is that true?
Yeah.
Of course it's true.
We've never been apart for so long.
So, ah, what are you
having to drink, hmm?
Cognac, whisky, beer, gin, what do
you want? Anything you want.
- Nothing for me.
- Of course, you're drinking.
No no, not tonight.
You're my guest now,
and tonight you're drinking.
Natasha, whisky and ice
for my very best friend.
Hey! And the olives.
Why didn't you shoot me
up on the hill?
- Why didn't you shoot me?
- When?
Just now.
Isn't that why you're here,
to kill me?
That's your job,
isn't it?
Since your factory closed,
your new job?
Ah, come on,
we should be celebrating.
A game of chess!
Sweetheart, let's have
the chessboard, hmm?
Whose turn to start?
Okay, you're white.
I'm going to bed.
If you're staying,
I'll see you in the morning.
Yeah, good night.
Hmm. Good night, sweetheart.
See you later.
I've never met a girl
like her before.
Someone who dreams
the same as me.
I don't have to explain
things to her,
the way I feel or I think.
She loves me.
I tell you, Vlado,
I'm crazy about her.
This is not me
playing games here.
First time I ever
felt right with the world.
#It's a very very
very good show #
- # A! #
- # E! #
- # I! #
- # O! #
- # U! #
#A-E-l-O-U! #
So we finally made it
to the Olympics.
You're killing women and children
on your own streets.
This is war.
You know, you were up on that hill
like a little rabbit, a sitting target.
I could have had you
just like that.
But you know
I'd never kill you.
Do you remember that night in Odessa
after we won the pairs?
Yeah, down on the beach.
It was a bottle of this.
I want you to leave
with Natasha tonight.
We never did find out
who took our clothes.
You're not listening to me.
- I heard you.
- Slavko, you've got to stop.
50 years ago, my family was taken
from their home, a house like this,
- by Croats and Muslim fascists...
- Yeah, I know what happened.
We all know what happened.
But didn't we learn anything together?
We were friends.
How can you...
find happiness
when you're shooting
on your own people?
I've got my happiness now.
Lejla is dead.
You know that?
Yes, she was shot
in the head by a sniper.
That wasn't me.
Whoever he was,
he was trained by you.
Natasha! Natasha!
Pack everything we can get in the Jeep.
We're leaving tonight.
- Why?
- Don't ask.
But where are we going?
Just do it.
We're going away.
I've been wondering how you've been
doing these last weeks...
- worried, huh?
- Why, of course.
You've spent a lifetime
worrying about me.
Where will you go?
You can stop worrying
from now on.
We're finished, Vlado.
No, I want you to call me
and you let me know where you are.
You do that, please.
You said it yourself...
"It's too late."
I hate anything to end.
I know you do.
And I've had a lot of tired days
because of that over the years.
Been worth it though.
- You go inside, yeah?
- Okay.
Slavko!
No!
No, no!
Fatigues, flack jacket,
bulletproof vest.
It's all Israeli,
we get what we can find.
Brandy, two bottles...
French.
So... you got him.
Well done.
Yes, sir, can we help you?
What's going on?
We have decided
to come to work.
There hasn't been any post for two
months. What're you talking about?
This is our job.
If we want to come to work,
then we will come to work.
And no one's
gonna stop us.
How did you get here?
- Walked.
- From Kosovo?
Yes.
So what time
do you finish?
3:00.
Are you trying
to chat me up?
I'll come outside.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I saw Amela last night.
And they're gonna give Lejla a proper
burial when they get the chance.
She said Miso
wants you to be there.
Hello, best friend ever.
I went in the morning
to get water.
There was shooting by the water truck,
but no one was hurt.
Zelijko was crying
when I told him about you.
So you see,
he didn't hate you.
That's all
I can think of today.
I'll be better tomorrow.