- Please, gentlemen POWs, have something to eat
- Calm down, calm down
There's enough for everyone, no need to push
Have your fill
Hogs
Hogs.  Vasiliy Stepanych, check out these jerks stuffing themselves
Why jerks?
Hunger is a strong motivator
Enough, pigs!
Enough, enough!
There are still many more hungry.
And you stay
This cattle
Bydlo, they will be in camp podyhat
You are true soldiers
and I offer you to fight alongside us.
No, not for Great Germany.
To fight against the Bolsheviks
for Russia,
After Germany's victory, someone must run Russia?
So you will be the ones to run
free Russia,
So said your General Vlasov
You?
No
Stick it where the sun don't shine
You?
Screw you
I'm with the rest of us
You?
I'll go
If it's against the Bolsheviks, I'll go
Name?
Captain Sazonov
I welcome,
your courageous decision.
You can go
that way
And I'll go,
I hate those communists, Christ-killers
Name?
Nikolai Sergeevich Yevseyev
You can go
That way
Enough
Liquidate these ones
I've said before, your dumb experiments
don't come to anything,
you tell them they are real soldiers
And I respect them.
So you found your cause?
Shut up, bitch
Sorry, guys, sorry.
Don't. No need to cry
You're an officer's wife, you don't have the right
I know.
Take care of Sasha
Vera,
you'll wait for me.
I promise you, I won't forget you
Don't promahnis
I'll try, for you
Their boots need to come off
Get them off
Hey, bros!
What brings you here?
What about you?
I told you, my own reasons
Oh, cool
We don't know where we're going,
which way is east, which way west, hell if you can figure it.
You can hear artillery to the east, that's the way to go
Yeah, you can hear it to the north and to the south, too.
War all around.
And who do you belong to?
Goryanov's 117th Brigade, Rifle,
202nd Regiment.
And you?
I'm from the 32nd rifle corps,
Khomichev -- he's from the 93rd Rifle Division, 96th Regiment
I'm from the 37th Division, 101st Regiment. I commanded a battalion.
Bros, have you got a crumb to spare?
Whatever's over there; we finished off the last breadrolls yesterday.
We've been going on what berries we could find,
Our stomachs are sticking to our spines.
Yes, we also live here on mushrooms
Iz you, all in krovischi,
The commander of each?
See two sleepers, Major.
Not occupant, he would wash the wound
Is there any water?
Have to go get it.
Where? And? They'll spot us right away.
Yeah, to hell with them, too,
I heard they had orders not to get held up,
not to get bogged down in local fighting.
To make straight for Stalingrad.
And where did you hear that?
When we broke out of the encirclement,
we grabbed one Fritz.  He said it.
Well look at this guy. On your head be it, let's go, guys.
Bitches... still laughing
Guys, can we take a break, I can't go any longer.
And through you can not, from now zhahnut
machine, rest.
No, well, what a bunch of pussies. Eat.
Let them eat instead of shooting, and thanks for that.
And what else happened? Tverdokhlebov?
Vasily Stepanovich.
They scattered into the forest,
I can't remember after that -
I was unconscious almost the whole time.
Alright then.  Better if you tell about the execution.
I've already told you about that.
Go into more detail.
How is it that they shot you, and you are here, alive.
Shooting wasn't enough
Not enough?
You ended up with
Two bullets, in the chest and in the arm.
Just got lucky, apparently?
Depends on how you look at it.
I Don't you understand Comrade Investigator.
Citizen Investigator.
Sorry, Citizen Investigator.
Well see here, former major, you've painted me a fabulous picture,
Taken prisoner how? Concussion. And you don't remember how you were hit?
Executed, and crawled up still alive from the grave?
Miraculous.  If only.
You do not believe me?
I do not.
I have to listen to so many wild tales here, my ears are swollen.
Pletete seven West to the heavens and all the forest.
And where is the proof, where are the concrete facts?
What will happen to me?
You yourself admit you were captured?
I was.
Now this is a concrete fact.
And you have read Comrade Stalin's order number 227?
I read it.
So now you see who you are?
You are an enemy of the people. You have betrayed the homeland -- you follow?
...which is, at this moment, in danger.
Now think, what should be done with you.
I came back to my own side.
That depends on where you're looking from. You went to your own or to the other.
Maybe you were sent back on a spying mission.
And everything else is just a beautiful tale.
Executed, remained alive.
Came back to your own side.
So you'll shoot me again?
That depends on you, Tverdokhlebov.
Confess, tell the whole truth, bare your soul,
you'll do a stretch in chervonets
But be a stubborn mule,
shlepnem, soul for miles.
Do you realize how many tale-tellers come through here??,
Tens so of thousands.
A river of people.
And you, flea, write them all up as traitors?
What did you say?
Kopytov!
Work him over some.
Then you'll cooperate.
Och, they've knocked your conscience out of you.
They tried.
Careful.  Head.
Easy, easy.
What happened next?
And what next? We got out of the encirclement.
"We" who?
Whoever was still alive,
Fomichev was with me the whole time,
Kobylko,
Yes.  Out of the whole regiment, less than a hundred were left.
Who can confirm this?
The same Fomichev and Kobylko
Others bailed out on the road back.
Many were killed when we broke through the front.
Alexei Loshilin,
Ignat Boiko,
Ivan Stekolnikov,
Can't remember them all.
That's enough.
But in his testimony Loshilin writes that
you encouraged Red Army soldiers to surrender into captivity.
It was over, you told them, the war was already lost,
continuing to resist would be too expensive.
Who, Loshilin?
Yes. That can not be.
Here. Read.
Here&#39;s creation.
Well, that Dubinin?
Are we going to tell the truth, or tell some more tales?
Burykin
Give your tale how you fell prisoner.
We fought to guard the battalion.
Holding our position, the Germans came down on us.
I was knocked flat.  Came to with three automatics pointed at me.
And what did you do?
What would you have done, with three rifles in your face?
And if there weren't three Germans, but a whole company, what then?
What then?
You were ordered to protect the battalion,
and you hid quietly -- the Germans would have easily wiped out half the battalion from your position.
You should have screamed, "Germans!".
Warned your own.
And then they'd have massacred me.
Massacred, of course.  But you would have warned the battalion?
But you're a coward?
I'm no coward,
but to think for a few seconds?
But should you think if you are a Red Army soldier?
Who are you then?
You are a coward and a traitor.
So you'll write all of them up as enemies of the people? Sychev?
Well, what kind of enemies of the people are they, goddamn it?
Spies, saboteurs.
Here's this Tverdokhlebov, also a saboteur?
He lies expertly, Comrade Major, spins a fine yarn.
Piss off.  I'm saying what actually happened.
Are the wounds still on your body?
Yes indeed, they are, two bullets.
Like I said, just what happened.
The front is catastrophically lacking men -- you understand this, Sychev?
Yes Sir, Comrade Major, I understand.
The fuck you understand.
All people have flaws.  Before the Soviet Government,
anyone might commit a crime, but an insignificant crime.
And you want to have them all shot.
I tell you, we need people on the damn front.
So let them redeem their guilt before the motherland
with blood, on the front.
Do you get me, Sychev?
Perfectly, Comrade Major, I do.
It took long enough.
Like talking to a giraffe.
Well now, Citizen Vasily Stepanovich Tverdokhlebov?
How are you feeling?
Your wounds have healed?
Thank you
I'm ready to be shot now
Why do you say that?
The authorities not only punish, but also give opportunity.  To redeem your guilt before your homeland.
There's a war going on, Major, and you are being given
the opportunity to redeem your guilt with blood.
Will you command a penalty battalion?
Certainly, there are men for it?
And I've been demoted.
We don't have enough officers to fill our officer posts.
Yes, and who the hell wants to command penal rabble?
We understand each other. We can violate the statute.
You can yourself?
I am ready to, Citizen Major.
Sure, then. Fine.
In the penal battalion, you will have the chance
to redeem your guilt through fire.
ATTENTION PRISONERS!
THE FASCISTS DREAM OF DEFEATING US,
AND HAS THROWN ALL MANNER OF NEW SOLDIERS TO THE FRONT.
THE PARTY AND THE SOVIET GOVERNMENT,
SHOWING GREAT CONFIDENCE IN YOU,
OFFER YOU THE POSSIBILITY,
TO REDEEM YOUR GUILT WITH BLOOD, TO PUT YOUR CRIMES BEHIND YOU.
Cram that up their asses sideways.
WHOEVER WANTS TO GO TO THE FRONT, TAKE THREE STEPS FORWARD.
Commies are scraping the bottom of the barrel,
they see their German counterparts, and can't stop them.
What, they've run completely out of soldiers, and now they're dragging zeks to the front?
Shut your yap, they'll hear you.
Нехай listen.
So they'll be fighting under guard, too?
You can fight I thee two krasnoperyh
with machine guns guard.
Check it out, all the politicals stepped up.
Sheep, screw 'em.
Enthusiasts
On the front, if your rifle misfires,
you'll bring your sentence on yourself.
shooting without justification,
remember what I'm saying
You hear?
No one will repeat this
Look, PAHAN went up
Ah well, let's go
You do in the law, Glymov
you never worked, and now you want to go to the front,
Tired at Nara shaft, sides otlezhal.
povoevat smallness hunting.
There smallness not work,
Glymov there, the whole will have to reel.
But it will have as much.
ATTENTION PRISONERS
In RODINA OPASTNOSTI
FASHIST MECHTAET U.S. POBEDIT
And BROSAET AT FRONT OF ALL THE NEW NEW
ORDY THEIR SOLDIER
YOU PARTY AND THE SOVIET POWER,
OKAZYVAET OGROMNOE CONFIDENCE
WHO IS IN FRONT HOCHET, 3 STEP FORWARD
Sheeting present the rounds here,
all seen? Understandably?
Next, push trigger lock and paste.
In the kind Hitler Kaput.
That is so clear?
Let us for the work rebyatki.
In response, understood?
And this much garbage?
In response, I&#39;m ready!
Молодец.
We as a chemist.
For example, 200 times to collect and disassemble.
How much?
You че afonorel, commander?
I said 200 times to collect and disassemble.
What would kill, a student must,
zeki my home.
Yes, to fight, not to steal.
And how do you think?
And you where citizens?
And we are for civil war, these closures do not
one hundred times before and collected.
And that same machine-guns and know?
As our stepfather know.
And what does not immediately say?
And many among you?
Enough,
look affairs, who for 58, almost
all into civil war.
Then free, was the only on the shooting.
The rest continue.
That&#39;s fortunate 58 - m.
And wait, wait.
Another.
Please.
Yes as long as you want.
Play yourself.
Two desyatochki, you do not dance.
Bankers point
Remove shoes, a citizen of the Chief.
Who else wants to try the gypsy happiness?
The brave citizens who bravely.
Let&#39;s try-ka.
What puts at stake?
Muhlyuet devil, not caught.
A catch that muhlyuesh,
otorvu head, understand?
Oh, uncle, your threats to cause me
spiritual trembling.
Castillo saharok, and you what?
But these chic shtiblety.
In tactical calculation, the blind can see
The Germans rvutsya to kavkazkoy oil
pererezhut Volga
take Grozny, and Baku
an end to Stalin
twice as two
In the history of Russia many times happened
twice two,
and derived from,
Russian Cossacks in Paris
Your words would be, yes gentlemen in the soul,
Only now, and I think we
God does not help
In October, all grains under frequent vygrebli
daughter under the new year died of hunger,
then the son of god to tidy o,
then old mother,
then wife,
one remained, well, that lie and wait for death?
Pozega his house that he would not get svolochi.
And went, just where the eye.
morning and took me on the road
kolkhoz was accused of setting fire to property
deskat my house for the time,
already belonged to the kolkhoz, and I did not have
set fire to his right
You tell me, Fedor
what the Antichrist, collective farms invented?
This is the Antichrist,&#39;m Lenin and Stalin
A teperechya, so I of the Antichrist
Germans must defend?
Sam volunteered for the eggs you nobody pulled.
Why volunteered?
As explained
Calling the land,
it is one my all, land.
From the first battle claws would tear
What is OGPU? About Lord, Help Ubezhat,
And vice versa? Poymayut head Otorvut conviction.
And can I as a call,
I can not kill people.
Chudniv Petya hear me, for armed robbery
sitting, but can not kill people?
Bratcy Hey!
че you doing there?
Well ka stop immediately
Well you what, teeth zhmut or second extra eye?
What you urki, under the monastery want to fail?
A shooting?
Idi suchara, rye razrisuyu.
What you two guys, the rules of our lives forgotten?
Give zhelezku.
Nothing, enemies of the people, we still felt
At night all porezhu, creation shameful
Knives and grinding, surrender,
or now all pourodaem
I have a svolochi into civilian
in three minutes to let flow
does not roll, your first bullet
I NOZHI ZATOCHKI ZDAT!
What will do with goner?
I thought so,
vykinut them out of the wagon should be,
that would be excessive noise was not
Poskubalis little short, it is
Such a life, our very hard
I thought so.
And I thought, you have to judge Glymov.
It is that whether you are going to judge me?
Why? The Tribunal.
Tribunal?
The Tribunal, also on тож award,
shtrafbat and front
No fuss, Baukin,
at the front poglyadim who first
farewell to the life
Let&#39;s emissions poured, ploughed bear
OH that volunteers shtrafniki
nalegay at kulesh until goryachenky.
And those which, sleep or something?
Eternal sleep
How eternal, be them, and then until the evening
remain hungry
Dead, they did not understand that right?
How dead?
Well instigators who fights?
I ask who instigators?
I can not say.
Can not or do not want?
I do not want.
What this will give?
Like what?
Instigators will judge tribunal.
And that the tribunal award?
Shooting.
The extra corpses.
People at the front needed.
The killers bedspreads?
Yes there, one third of the murderers,
Does that I recruited them to the volunteers?
Ty was appointed senior,
and all will respond.
And in other cars, quietly and peacefully?
Yes, no,
Counted 36 corpses,
Front doedem yet to even be added.
Yes of horseradish at the front where you need?
If you are now under lock bring?
You&#39;ll see the same as the Germans, just in
sdadites prisoner,
if not even earlier drapanete.
I do not drapanu,
and the prisoner did not pass.
So many of these in your car?
Enough.
With fast I doubt it.
Your right,
doubt or believe.
And you me my rights do not recall
do you remember about your.
My right to die on the battlefield,
want, do not forget.
I will come back soon, this heinous error,
Masha
You do not worry,
wait
What emissions?
Yes because it
but may be given here?
There will, in that place,
Bast Shoe even imagine what something sostryapay.
Article what?
I?
Fraud
So thought.
You have 58?
Quite true.
He was arrested in 1937?
It is true in 37
As you name?
Muranov Anatoly Petrovich
partorg, ball-bearing
plant in Moscow
Shtrafniki Attention!
I am your battalion commander
Hear?
They shot cannons and machine guns,
there by the blood flow,
People are dying there,
defending the homeland,
and now you will protect her,
Remember all that before,
who you were before,
Forget!
Now you look at Homeland mother,
looks with hope
I recall!
For failure to order shooting on the ground!
For violation of military discipline, shooting!
During the demonstration cowardice, shooting!
And except for the shooting, yet there is something?
Citizen commander?
The weapons will when?
Or bare hands, will fritsev soul?
The weapons issue on the front,
And when will zhrat?
Will also feed on the front.
Battalion!
On the left!
A step, Go!
What do you have eyes drills, kombat?
Finish bucket Orders
Vedro vodka
Oh, we thee kombat and navoyuem
Guys, song!