[MUSIC]
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
HI.
CHRISTOPHER.
PLEASE TAKE A SEAT.
SO, I'M GLAD YOU MADE IT.
DID YOU GET LOST?
YEAH.
SORRY I'M A LITTLE
LATE BUT I GOT CONFUSED
BY THE ROAD SIGNS.
OH, I UNDERSTAND.
SO, HOW IS YOUR GRANDFATHER?
HE'S LOST THE BATTLE I'M
AFRAID, TEN DAYS A.
I'M SO SORRY.
I HOPE HE DID NOT SUFFER.
NOT AT ALL.
WENT OUT IN HIS SLEEP THE
WAY HE ALWAYS SAID HE WOULD.
I'LL MISS HIM.
HE WAS SUCH A GOOD MAN.
HE ALWAYS SAID THE
SAME ABOUT YOU.
YOU KNOW THANKS FOR
MEETING ME AND DOING THIS.
JA, WELL I ALSO HAD TO
COME BACK ONE LAST TIME.
SHALL WE GO SIR?
LEAD THE WAY.
[CAR MOTOR]
JA, THIS IS IT!
DO YOU FEEL LIKE
TALKING ABOUT IT?
YOU MUST'VE HEARD IT
FROM YOUR GRANDFATHER
A THOUSAND TIMES.
YEAH, BUT NOT FROM YOU.
VERY WELL, IT WAS DECEMBER
OF 1944 AND ALL OF EUROPE
WAS RAVAGED BY WAR AND IN THE
GRIP OF A WET AND
BITTER WINTER.
[SUSPENSEFUL SYMPHONIC MUSIC]
[SUSPENSEFUL, INTENSE PIANO
MUSIC OF SILENT NIGHT]
[FOOT STEPS SLOSHING]
(OLDER MAN NARRATING)
I HAD ONLY RECENTLY
TURNED 12 YEARS OLD
WHEN ON CHRISTMAS EVE
I SUDDENLY FOUND
MYSELF IN THE MIDDLE
OF WHAT WOULD BECOME THE
FAMOUS BATTLE OF THE BULGE.
WAR DOES NOT STOP
FOR HOLIDAYS.
FIGHTING RAGED EVERYWHERE.
AND THE COUNTRYSIDE WAS
LITTERED WITH BODIES -
DECREPIT.
[FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING
GERMAN CALLING FRITZ]
(OLDER FRITZ) BUT MY MOTHER
WAS NOT THE KIND OF PERSON TO
LET EVENTS CONTROL HER.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
[SOLDIERS SPEAKING GERMAN]
(OLDER FRITZ) IT WAS THE SEASON
OF GOODWILL TO ALL MANKIND.
YET THERE SEEMED
NO END TO THE WAR.
NO END TO THE
FIGHTING, SUFFERING.
[BIRDS CAWING]
(OLDER FRITZ) WITH FOOD
AND BASIC SUPPLIES ALMOST
IMPOSSIBLE TO FIND.
AND OUR HOME DESTROYED IN
A BOMBING RAID MY MOTHER
MADE A MOMENTOUS DECISION.
SHE DECIDED THAT
WE WOULD SEEK REFUGE IN OUR
FAMILY'S OLD HUNTING CABIN.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
(OLDER FRITZ) AS I ENTERED
THE LONELY, EMPTY SPACE I
HAD NO IDEA IT WOULD BE
THE MOST MEMORABLE
CHRISTMAS OF MY LIFE.
[GENTLE SYMPHONIC MUSIC
'HARK THE HERALD ANGELS SING]
[HUMMING]
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
KINDLY GO AND GET YOUR BOOK.
IN ENGLISH, FRITZ.
ENGLISH.
I DO NOT SEE WHY I
MUST LEARN ENGLISH.
FRANZ ULMER SAYS THAT ONE
DAY SOON WE WILL CONQUER THE
WORLD AND EVERYONE WILL HAVE
TO SPEAK GERMAN.
REALLY?
AND HOW DOES HE KNOW THAT?
HIS FATHER SAYS SO AND
HE WORKS FOR THE FUHRER.
FRANZ ULMER'S FATHER
IS A MINOR OFFICIAL
AND HE KNOWS NOTHING.
BUT THE FUHRER
KNOWS EVERYTHING.
HE DOES NOT KNOW EVERYTHING.
HE SIMPLY FORCES OUR PEOPLE
TO BELIEVE THAT HE DOES.
MOMMA, YOU MUSTN'T
SPEAK LIKE THAT.
YOUR BOOK, FRITZ.
[WIND BLOWING]
"WELL " SAYS BUCK,
"A FEUD IS THIS WAY.
A MAN HAS A QUARREL WITH
ANOTHER MAN AND KILLS HIM."
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
ANY AMERICANS, MOMMA?
JA.
BEFORE THE WAR.
MANY AMERICAN TOURISTS
WOULD COME TO VISIT.
WHAT WERE THEY LIKE?
JUST LIKE US, I
SUPPOSE, ONLY DIFFERENT.
I SAW AN AMERICAN ONCE,
WHO HAD JUMPED FROM
HIS BURNING AIRPLANE.
THE SHOEMAKER SHOT HIM.
HE SAID IT WAS HIS DUTY.
THAT WAS NOT HIS DUTY.
THAT WAS MURDER.
DID NO ONE TRY TO STOP HIM?
WHY?
THE AMERICAN HAD BEEN
TRYING TO KILL US.
[SIGHS]
DO NOT WORRY, MOMMA.
AFTER CHRISTMAS, WHEN I
AM CALLED TO DO MY DUTY,
I WILL NOT SHOOT THEM.
I WILL TAKE THEM PRISONER.
FRITZ, YOU ARE NOT
BECOMING A SOLDIER.
OH YES, WILLI ERNST HAS
ALREADY BEEN CALLED UP AND HE IS
ONLY TWO MONTHS OLDER THAN ME.
LISTEN TO ME FRITZ.
WE ARE NOT GOING
BACK TO TOWN.
AND YOU ARE NOT JOINING
THE HITLER YOUTH
AND CARRYING GUNS.
BUT MOMMA, IT IS
MY DUTY TO - PAPA?
PAPA!
[DOOR BARGES OPEN]
[GASPS]
PLEASE DON'T HURT US.
WE ARE ALONE.
[BOOK DROPS]
ALL CLEAR, SARGE,
BED BACK HERE.
STAY WHERE I CAN SEE YOU.
UNDERSTAND?
NOT A SOUND.
[MOANING]
EASY SOLDIER - EASY.
WE BETTER CLEAN
THIS THING OUT.
GET ME SOME HOT WATER AND THE
FIELD DRESSING FROM MY PACK.
AND KEEP YOUR EYE ON
THOSE TWO OUT THERE.
HEY, HEY, HEY,
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
WHERE YOU GOING?
AH, I HAVE HOT
WATER ON THE STOVE.
I'LL GET IT.
[SOLDIER MOANING IN BACKGROUND]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH, TOO?
JA!
YOU LIKE HUCK FINN?
WHAT ABOUT TOM SAWYER?
JA I LIKE THAT
BOOK VERY MUCH.
I LIKE TOM.
HE'S A SMART BOY!
HUM.
SMART ?
THAT'S RIGHT.
TOM'S ALWAYS ON THE MOVE.
WHAT ELSE YOU READ?
MOBY DICK.
THE LAST OF THE MOHICANS.
NO KIDDING.
THOSE ARE GOOD BOOKS.
WHAT ABOUT MEIN KAMPF ?
NO!
IT'S A LOUSY READ ANYWAY.
HERE YOU GO.
THE LADY'S TAKING
CARE OF THE HOT WATER.
IT'S ON ITS WAY.
WHADDYA MEAN SHE'S
TAKING CARE OF THE WATER?
SHE'S HEATING IT UP.
YOU LET HER HEAT IT UP?
IT'S JUST HOT WATER.
ARE YOU FORGETTING
SOMETHING HERE, PRIVATE?
WE'RE AT WAR WITH
THESE PEOPLE.
I KNOW BUT, SHE'S -
BUT WHAT?
HAVEN'T YOU SEEN ENOUGH
BY NOW TO KNOW THEY
ARE NOT TO BE TRUSTED?
YOU WANT THEM TO DO
SOMETHING FOR YOU, YOU KEEP
AN EYEON THEM AT ALL TIMES.
DID YOU?
HUH?
DID YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THEM AT ALL TIMES?
NO.
THEN HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHAT SHE PUT IN IT?
IT IS HOT WATER.
JUST HOT WATER WITH A CLEAN
CLOTH TO CLEAN THE WOUND.
WE WON'T BE NEEDING
YOU ANYMORE.
LET ME GIVE YOU A
PIECE OF ADVICE RASSI.
IF YOU WANNA MAKE IT THROUGH
THIS WAR ALIVE, THE ONLY
PERSON YOU TRUST IS WEARING
THE SAME UNIFORM AS YOU ARE.
NOW GET OUT OF HERE AND
DIG SOME SULFUR PACKS.
WE TO DISINFECT THIS THING.
(SARGE) EVERYTHING'S
GONNA BE FINE.
SOLDIER!
MAY I ASK YOU HOW LONG
YOU INTEND TO STAY HERE?
I DON'T KNOW MA'AM.
THAT'S SOMETHING YOU'RE
GONNA HAVE TO TAKE
UP WITH THE SERGEANT
I TAKE IT YOU ARE LOST
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
HERBIE TOOK A HIT.
WE CARRIED HIM FROM THE LINE.
THEN THE SNOW CAME IN.
AND WELL, HERE WE ARE, AH.
THERE'S NO SULFUR PACKS.
(SARGE) THERE'S GOT TO BE!
YOU KEEP LOOKING!
THEN YOUR UNIT
IS NOT VERY FAR.
NO MA'AM.
CAN'T BE MORE THAN - THOSE
ARE THE KIND OF QUESTIONS
YOU SHOULDN'T BE ASKING.
(YELLING) SARGE! SARGE!
THEY'RE BEHIND THE WALL!
NO! NO I...
(SARGE) RASSI, GET IN HERE
AND GIVE ME A HAND.
NO SULFUR PACKS, SARGE.
DAMN IT!
WELL HOLD HIM DOWN
WHILE I CLEAN THIS
THING OUT, WOULD YA ?
HERBIE!
IT'S OKAY!
IT'S ME!
IT'S JIMMY!
JIMMY !
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
WE WERE HIDING BEHIND
THAT WALL, REMEMBER?
AYE?
THEN THE KRAUTS STARTED
SHELLING AND YOU GOT HIT.
HIT?
LEMME SEE.
NO, NO!
LEMME SEE !
NO, NO.
YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE HERBIE.
HERBIE, YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
ITS OKAY, THE SARQE
IS TAKING CARE OF YOU.
SARGE!
SARGE?
AM I HIT BAD?
IT'S ALRIGHT, HERBIE.
EVERYTHING'S
GONNA BE ALRIGHT.
JUST RELAX WHILE I CLEAN
THIS THING OUT, ALRIGHT.
YOU SEE - SEE - IT'S
GONNA BE - IT'S GONNA BE.
IS THERE ANY
SHRAPNEL IN THERE?
I DON'T THINK SO.
I'M NO MEDIC BUT IT
LOOKS LIKE THIS THING
WENT CLEAN THROUGH.
LUCKY IT DIDN'T
SEVER AN ARTERY.
YOU'RE SURE THERE'S
NO SULFUR PACKETS.
I TOLD YOU, WE'RE OUT.
PERHAPS THIS WILL HELP.
IT IS DISINFECTANT.
SARGE, IT'S BURNING.
IT'S ALRIGHT.
THE WOUND WILL HAVE
TO BE CLOSED SOON OR
INFECTION WILL SET IN.
WHAT ARE YOU, A
NURSE OR SOMETHING?
NO.
ONLY A SCHOOL TEACHER.
ONLY?
THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
THINK AGAIN, RASSI.
IN THIS COUNTRY THEY
TEACH THINGS THAT DON'T
BELONG IN ANY SCHOOLS.
THE LITTLE TYKE OUT
THERE HAS ALREADY BEEN
FILLED FOR HIS JACKBOOTS.
WHERE IS THAT KID ANYWAY?
HE'S JUST OUTSIDE -
BRINGING IN MORE FIREWOOD.
GO OUTSIDE AND FIND THAT KID.
AND BRING ME MY CARBINE.
RIGHT.
IT'S OKAY.
(WHISPERED) NO.
DON'T LEAVE ME.
ALRIQHT.
IT'S OKAY.
ALRIGHT.
IT'S ALRIGHT.
IT'S OKAY.
SARGE!
YOU'D BETTER COME OUT HERE!
WHAT IS IT?
THEY WERE RIGHT THERE.
LADY, I'M NOT EVEN
GONNA COUNT TO THREE.
UNLESS YOU TELL ME
RIGHT NOW WHERE HE'S -
I WILL NOT TOLERATE
WEAPONS IN MY HOUSE.
YOU CAN HAVE THEM
BACK WHEN YOU LEAVE.
WHAT?
IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T
NOTICED LADY, THERE'S
A WAR ON AND YOUR HOUSE IS
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF IT.
THAT MAKES IT A SHELTER FOR
MY MEN - A BASE OF OPERATIONS
- A HOSPITAL - A BARRACKS -
A BUNKER AND WHATEVER
ELSE THE HELL I SAY IT
IS UNTIL I SAY IT ISN'T.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
RASSI, GET OUTSIDE
AND FIND OUT WHAT THE
KID DID WITH THE GUNS.
BEAT IT OUT OF HIM
IF YOU HAVE TO.
NO.
YOU STAY HERE WITH ME!
[WIND BLOWING]
HEY.
WHAT'S UP BUDDY?
GETTING MORE
FIREWOOD, ARE YOU?
EH?
THAT'S A -
THAT'S A GOOD MAN.
WHERE'D YOU PUT THE GUNS?
LOOK YOU KNOW THIS IS
NOT GONNA WORK, SO DON'T
MAKE ME GET ANGRY AT YOU.
JUST TELL ME WHERE
YOU PUT THE GUNS AND
WE CAN STAY FRIENDS.
DAMMIT KID, NO GAMES
(YELLING) WHERE DID
YOU PUT THE FRIGGIN GUNS.
[BIRDS CAWING]
OF COURSE, SOME PLACE SAFE.
THANKS, PAL.
WE ARE NOT FRIENDS.
WE WILL NEVER BE FRIENDS.
I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
WHY NOT THEN?
YOU ARE AN AMERICAN.
YOU WISH TO DESTROY OUR
COUNTRY AND THE FUHRER.
REALLY?
AND WHERE'D YOU HEAR THAT?
ON THE RADIO.
NO KIDDING.
( CHUCKLE)
WELL, YOU'RE RIGHT
ABOUT THE LAST PART.
IF I COULD GET THESE HANDS
ON THE FUHRER'S NECK, I'D
RING IT LIKE A CHICKEN.
FEEL GOOD ABOUT IT TOO.
BUT I'M NOT YOUR
ENEMY, HE IS.
BUT HIS DAY OF RECKONING IS
COMING SOON, AND THAT'LL BE
A GREAT DAY FOR ALL OF US,
INCLUDING YOU, EVEN IF
YOU DON'T KNOW IT YET.
AND DON'T BELIEVE EVERYTHING
YOU HEAR ON THE RADIO.
SOME THINGS THEY
SAY JUST AIN'T SO.
COME ON.
GIMME THAT.
ALRIGHT?
[INTENSE MUSIC]
INSIDE!
COME ON.
GET INSIDE!
(WHISPERED) OKAY.
COME ON.
AND NOT A WORD UNLESS
I SAY SO, ALRIGHT.
(SHOUTING) HALT!
HALT!
FREEZE RIGHT THERE!
DON'T MOVE!
(WHISPERED) DAMN!
PUT YOUR WEAPONS
DOWN OR I'LL SHOOT!
YOU STAY HERE AND KEEP QUIET.
LET ME GO.
SO YOU CAN TELL THEM
THAT WE'RE UNARMED.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I COULD HAVE SHOUTED
IT OUT ALREADY OH
PLEASE, IT'S MY SON.
PUT YOUR WEAPONS
DOWN OR I'LL SHOOT.
TELL THEM TO PUT THEIR
GUNS DOWN OR I'LL SHOOT.
TELL THEM DAMMIT!
YOU HEAR ME -
PUT THE WEAPONS DOWN!
[SPEAKS GERMAN]
I UNDERSTOOD PERFECTLY
WELL WHAT WAS SAID FRAU
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
AMERICAN SOLDIER,
LET US TALK.
YOU ARE ALONE AND
THERE ARE THREE OF US.
THINK AGAIN HERMAN.
I GOT THEM COVERED
FROM IN HERE RASSI.
GOTCHA SARGE.
PUT THE GUNS DOWN BEFORE
THIS THING GETS UGLY.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
SO, MY FRIEND, IT SEEMS
YOU HAVE AN INNOCENT YOUNG
BOY BACK THERE WITH YOU.
SURELY YOU DO NOT
WANT HIM TO GET HURT.
WHAT DO I CARE?
HE'S ONE OF YOURS ANYWAY!
NO!
NEIN I NO!
STOP THIS ALL OF YOU!
STOP THIS MADNESS!
YOU HEARD HER.
PUT YOUR GUNS DOWN.
ALL RIGHT THEN.
GOOD!
THAT'S REAL GOOD.
GOOD.
(YELLING)
DON'T MOVE! DON'T MOVE.
FRITZ.
STAY THERE!
GET THE GUN OUT HERE SARGE!
ALRIGHT GET IN THE HOUSE!
GET YOUR MEN IN
THE HOUSE, NOW!
GO ON.
VERY CLEVER.
VERY CLEVER INDEED.
AND VERY CLEVER OF YOU FRAU.
I SAID NO GUNS INSIDE
THE HOUSE, SERGEANT.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
GET OUT OF THE WAY.
NO.
NO GUNS.
I SAID MOVE ASIDE LADY!
YOU MIGHT BE DEAD NOW
IF IT WERE NOT FOR ME.
SHE'S GOT A POINT
THERE, SARGE.
SHUT UP, RASSI.
NOW MOVE OUT OF THE WAY!
WE'RE GOIN' IN.
IF YOU WANT THE COMFORT
OF MY HOME, IT WILL
BE ON MY CONDITIONS.
THE GUNS REMAIN OUTSIDE.
LET'S GET SOMETHING STRAIGHT.
THIS LADY HAS OFFERED US
ALL SHELTER FOR THE NIGHT.
HER ONLY CONDITION IS THAT
WE LEAVE THE WEAPONS OUTSIDE AND
CONSIDER THIS NEUTRAL TERRITORY.
ARE YOU OKAY WITH THAT?
JA.
VERY WELL.
I GUESS WE HAVE A DEAL.
THANK YOU.
FRITZ, TAKE THESE AND PUT
THESE WITH THE OTHERS.
GOOD BOY.
[OMINOUS SYMPHONIC
MUSIC 'SILENT NIGHT']
WELL MERRY CHRISTMAS,
EVERYONE.
WELL!
SINCE YOU ARE ALL
GUESTS IN MY HOUSE, LET
US INTRODUCE YOURSELVES.
I AM ELISABETH VINCKEN.
AND THIS IS MY SON FRITZ.
SERGEANT RALPH BLANK - AND
THIS IS PRIVATE JIMMY RASSI.
LIEUTENANT HANS KLOSTERMAN -
THIS IS SERGEANT MARCUS MUELLER
AND PRIVATE PETER HEINRICH.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
WHAT WAS THAT?
YOU GOT SOMETHING TO SAY?
HE SAYS YOU ARE TROUBLE.
HE'S GOT THAT RIGHT.
NOT IN MY HOUSE.
DO YOUR MEN SPEAK ANY
ENGLISH HERR LIEUTENANT ?
JA, THE SERGEANT, BUT
NOT PRIVATE HEINRICH.
THEN MAY I SUGGEST THAT WE
ALL DO SO IN ORDER TO AVOID
ANY POSSIBLE CONFUSION.
VERY WELL, THEN.
(HERBIE) SERGEANT.
THAT'S ANOTHER ONE OF MY MEN.
HE'S BEEN HIT.
I GUESS IT'S TIME WE PUT
THAT DEAL TO THE TEST, HUH?
STAY HERE RASSI, ALRIGHT.
(HERBIE) WHERE ARE WE?
SARGE I'VE BEEN HIT.
PERHAPS ONE OF YOU HAS
SOME MEDICAL KNOWLEDGE.
THE SOLDIER IS
VERY BADLY WOUNDED.
WELL, LET US SEE,
SHALL WE SERGEANT.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
[GROANING]
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
A SERIOUS WOUND!
THAT'S RIGHT!
88'S!
STAY WITH ME HERBIE.
STAY WITH ME.
SARGE!
LISTEN, I'D LOVE TO SIT AROUND
AND CHAT WITH YOU ALL, BUT
UNLESS YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING -
I SEE!
SO - WOULD YOU KINDLY
HEAT THIS UP FRAU VINCKEN?
JA!
THE COLD SPARED
HIM INFECTION.
BUT WE MUST CAUTERIZE
THE WOUND OR HE MAY
SLOWLY BLEED TO DEATH.
MEDIC?
WOUNDED - THE WALKING
WOUNDED ASSIST THE DOCTORS.
THE EASTERN FRONT.
THE CAUCASUS.
AND NOW HERE.
YOU?
NORTH AFRICA.
ITALY.
NOW HERE!
JOIN THE ARMY, SEE THE WORLD.
[HERBIE MOANING]
JA !
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
IT SEEMS YOU HAVE CHANGED
SIDES, FRAU VINCKEN.
ARE YOU AWARE OF THE
CONSEQUENCES OF SUCH AN ACT?
I AM NOT SIDING WITH ANYONE.
ON THE CONTRARY, YOU
HAVE HELPED THE ENEMY.
AND THAT IS AN
ACT OF TREASON.
THEY FORCED THEIR
WAY IN WITH GUNS.
I THEN AGREED TO LET THEM
STAY, ON CONDITION THAT THEY
LEAVE THEIR WEAPONS OUTSIDE.
THAT HARDLY SEEMS TREASONOUS
TO ME HERR LEUTNANT.
( WHISPERED) NO.
BUT YOU COULD HAVE WARNED
US THAT THEY WERE UNARMED.
YET, YOU DID NOT.
( WHISPERED) NO I DID NOT.
BECAUSE I WAS AFRAID THAT
YOU WOULD START SHOOTING.
AFRAID FOR MY SON.
I HARDLY THINK THE PRESIDENT
OF THE PEOPLES' TRIBUNAL
WOULD CONSIDER THOSE
MITIGATING CIRCUMSTANCES.
AND WE KNOW HOW HERR
FREISLER DEALS WITH TRAITORS.
HERR FREISLER'S COURT IS
A PERVERSION OF JUSTICE.
ALL ITS JUDGMENTS ARE
FOREGONE CONCLUSIONS.
IF ONE CAN BE DEEMED
A TRAITOR FOR REFUSING
TO RENOUNCE ONE'S MORAL
OBLIGATIONS, THEN
I AM INDEED GUILTY.
NOW IF YOU WILL EXCUSE ME.
CAREFUL, FRAU VINCKEN.
THE AMERICANS HAVE
NOT WON THE WAR YET.
[SCREAMING]
ONE LAST TIME!
BE TOUGH FOR ME!
BE TOUGH.
ONE LAST TIME.
NOO!
[SCREAMING]
ARE YOU TOUGH?
YEAH.
THAT RIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S DONE.
THAT'S IT BUDDY.
THAT'S IT.
HE WILL PROBABLY BE
UNCONSCIOUS FOR A WHILE.
I'LL BE DAMNED!
THE BLEEDING'S STOPPED.
JA!
BUT WE NEED TO DISINFECT AND
DRESS THE WOUND PROPERLY.
WE WILL TAKE CARE OF THAT.
THANK YOU SERGEANT MUELLER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I'M JUST TRYING TO DO
WHAT I THINK IS RIGHT.
MY ELDEST SON PAUL
DIED AT STALINGRAD.
HE WAS SHOT AND BLED TO
DEATH BECAUSE THERE WAS
NO-ONE THERE TO HELP HIM.
NO-ONE SHOULD HAVE
TO DIE LIKE THAT.
I - I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
BUT WHAT I MEANT WAS WHY
WOULD YOU BRING YOUR BOY
HERE AT A TIME LIKE THIS?
OUR TOWN IS UNDER
CONSTANT BOMBARDMENT.
IT IS MUCH SAFER HERE.
CLOSER TO THE FRONT LINES.
YOU KNOW THEY'RE GONNA COME
RIGHT BY YOU IN A DAY OR TWO.
THE SOONER THE BETTER.
IS HE GONNA BE ALRIGHT?
JA!
THANKS.
IT WAS A NOBLE INITIATIVE
SERGEANT MUELLER.
LET US HOPE YOUR EFFORTS
WILL BE REWARDED.
THE PATIENT IS BETTER I HEAR.
HE'LL SURVIVE.
DAS IST GUT!
ONE OF OUR UNITS WILL BE HERE
SHORTLY AND THEN HE WILL RECEIVE
EXCELLENT MEDICAL ATTENTION.
I WOULDN'T COUNT ON YOUR
BOYS GETTING HERE FIRST.
BUT YOU ARE ALREADY
BEHIND OUR LINES.
NOT FOR LONG.
WISHFUL THINKING SERGEANT,
BUT WE SHALL SOON RESUME
THE OFFENSIVE AND HAVE YOU
RUNNING BACK TO THE ENGLISH
CHANNEL JUST LIKE WE DID TO THE
FRENCH AND BRITISH AT DUNKIRK.
ONLY THIS TIME
WE WON'T MAKE THE SAME
MISTAKE, I ASSURE YOU.
I DON'T THINK SO.
THIS OFFENSIVE WAS
YOUR LAST GASP.
NOW THE WAR'S ALMOST
OVER AND YOU KNOW IT.
WE'LL BE RUNNING ALRIGHT.
RUNNING AS WE KICK
YOUR SORRY BU -
GENTLEMEN! GENTLEMEN!
I REMIND YOU OF
OUR AGREEMENT.
YOU'LL KINDLY LEAVE
YOUR WAR OUTSIDE.
YES, OF COURSE.
DO FORGIVE ME FRAU.
I SHOULD HAVE REALIZED THAT
THE SERGEANT AND I WOULD HAVE
A DIFFERENCE OF OPINION
ON SUCH MATTERS.
I THINK YOU AND I WOULD
HAVE DIFFERENCES OF OPINION
ABOUT A LOT OF THINGS.
MAY I SUGGEST, THAT ON THIS
HOLIEST OF NIGHTS WE TRY
INSTEAD TO DISCOVER
WHAT WE HAVE IN COMMON.
A NIGHT OFF
SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
THE WAR'LL STILL BE WAITIN'
OUT THERE FOR US TOMORROW.
THEN IT IS AGREED.
YEAH.
GOOD !
WELL THEN IF YOU WILL ALL
BE PATIENT I WILL PREPARE
US SOMETHING TO EAT.
MA'AM.
MA'AM, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO DO THAT.
YEAH!
WE CAN TAKE CARE
OF OURSELVES.
ACH, IT IS NOTHING.
ONLY A LITTLE POTATO SOUP.
BUT WE HAVE LEARNED TO BE
GRATEFUL FOR SMALL THINGS.
FRITZ, THE DISHES.
PLEASE.
WELL THEN I GUESS IT'S
GONNA HAVE TO BE POT LUCK.
HEY, COME ON YOU
GUYS ANTE UP.
WHAT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
LIEUTENANT ?
DIDN'T YOUR MOMMA TELL
YOU, "NEVER GO TO A DINNER
PARTY EMPTY HANDED."
AH, YES!
OF COURSE.
HEINRICH, MUELLER,
YOUR RATIONS PLEASE.
EVERYTHING ON THE TABLE.
[MOANING]
NOW WE REALLY CAN HAVE
A CHRISTMAS DINNER.
THAT'S THE IDEA!
SO, LET'S SEE
WHAT WE GOT HERE.
LIEUTENANT KLOSTERMAN'S
GENEROUS CONTRIBUTION, HUH?
FOUR SLICES OF RYE BREAD, A
PIECE OF BRATWURST, AND AH,
A JAR OF PICKLED ONIONS.
HMM!
KIND OF SPARTAN LIEUTENANT?
PRUSSIAN ACTUALLY.
I DO APOLOGIZE.
THIS IS ALL I HAVE TO OFFER.
WELL, IT'S A START!
LET'S SEE WHAT
SERGEANT MUELLER'S GOT.
OKAY, FOUR SLICES OF RYE
BREAD, A PIECE OF SAUSAGE,
AND - HELLO, WHAT'S THIS?
COOKIES!
COOKIES?
THE MIGHTY WEHRMACHT
MARCHES ON COOKIES?
[LAUGHTER]
MY WIFE MADE THEM.
SHE SENDS THEM
WITH EVERY LETTER.
WELL THAT'S VERY
GENEROUS OF YOU SERGEANT.
PLEASE OFFER YOUR WIFE
OUR THANKS AND AH,
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT,
PUT ANOTHER ORDER
FOR ME, HUH.
JA.
OKAY, PRIVATE HEINRICH,
YOU'RE UP NEXT.
LET'S SEE WHAT WE'VE GOT
HERE; SIX SLICES OF BREAD,
A PIECE OF SAUSAGE AND -
NOTHING.
NO WIFE TO SEND YOU
ANY COOKIES THERE,
PRIVATE HEINRICH.
HOW 'BOUT YOUR MOMMA?
ER WILL WISSEN OB DEINE
MUTTER DIR MANCHMAL
SACHEN SCHICKT.
MEINE ELTERN SIND IN
EINEM BOMBENANGRIFF .
UMGEKOMMEN.
HE SAYS BOTH OF HIS PARENTS
- I THINK I UNDERSTOOD.
TELL HIM I'M SORRY.
ER SAGT DASS IHM
DAS LEIK TUT.
JA!
VERY WELL.
WHAT ABOUT YOU AMERICANS.
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
COME WELL PREPARED.
ALWAYS!
BOY SCOUTS MOTTO!
SO LET'S SEE WHAT OUR
SERGEANT HAS TO OFFER HERE.
DON'T LAY IT ON TOO THICK.
JUST GET ON WITH IT.
RIGHTO, SARGE.
JUST THE 'MENU DU
JOUR, NO EXTRAS?
THAT'S YOUR DEPARTMENT RASSI.
WELL, HERE YOU GOT A
FINE EXAMPLE OF AMERICAN
MILITARY CUISINE.
YOUR STANDARD
ISSUE K RATIONS.
HMM?
ONE CAN OF MYSTERY MEAT.
ONE CAN OF BAKED BEANS, HMM?
SOME WHEAT CRACKERS.
PEANUT BUTTER.
AND A PINEAPPLE PUDDING.
[ LAUGHING]
THIS IS EXACTLY WHY THE
WEHRMACHT WILL PREVAIL.
WHAT WILL YOUR POOR SOLDIERS
DO SHOULD YOUR ARMY EVER RUN
OUT OF PINEAPPLE PUDDING?
ASK FOR BANANA!
BESIDES YOU HAVEN'T
TASTED IT YET.
SOUNDS TO ME LIKE YOU
MIGHT HAVE TO GET USED TO
OUR CATERING LIEUTENANT.
I THINK NOT!
WHAT ABOUT YOU PRIVATE RASSI?
IT'S YOUR TURN.
WHAT HAVE YOU BROUGHT?
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
A LOT OF SUPPLIES.
MUST BE MY, UH,
ITALIAN ORIGINS MA'AM.
IF I'M GONNA DIE, IT'S
NOT GONNA BE OF HUNGER.
HE'S ALSO AN A-1 SCROUNGER.
NEGOTIATOR IF YOU
DON'T MIND, SARGE.
WELL THANK YOU ALL FOR
YOUR CONTRIBUTIONS.
FRITZ, FINISH SETTING THE
TABLE, AND THEN COME AND
HELP ME IN THE KITCHEN.
DU AUCH, PETER.
HELFE MIR MIT DIESEN SACHEN.
ALLOW ME TO HELP
ALSO, FRAU VINCKEN.
FRITZ, WIE ALT BIST DU?
TWELVE, SIR.
SORRY SIR BUT,
MY MOTHER INSISTS THAT I
SPEAK TO YOU IN ENGLISH.
JA, OF COURSE.
WE MUSTN'T LET
OUR FRIENDS THINK WE ARE
CONSPIRING AGAINST THEM.
TELL ME FRITZ, WHERE IS YOUR
FATHER, IN THE WEHRMACHT ?
YES SIR, HE'S IN THE ARMY.
ANY BROTHERS?
SISTERS?
MY OLDER BROTHER SIR.
HE WAS KILLED AT STALINGRAD.
HE DIED FOR HIS COUNTRY.
THERE IS NO GREATER HONOR.
NO SIR.
AND WHAT ABOUT YOU?
ARE YOU READY TO SERVE IN
DEFENSE OF THE FATHERLAND?
YES, SIR.
I SHALL JOIN THE HITLER YOUTH
AS SOON AS MY PAPERS ARRIVE.
AH, DAS IST GUT.
SO YOU HAVE NOT
BEEN CALLED YET?
NO SIR.
I SEE.
WELL, I SHOULD
LET YOU CONTINUE.
(FRAUN) FRITZ, DARLING, WHEN
YOU ARE DONE YOU AND PETER CAN
BRING IN THE DISHES.
DON'T GET TOO COZY HERE.
WE'RE STILL AT
WAR REMEMBER THAT.
I'M SURE YOU WOULDN'T
LET ME FORGET THAT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I MIGHT ACT FRIENDLY,
BUT LET'S NOT GET
CARELESS, ALRIGHT ?
NO, BUT THEY DID MAKE A DEAL.
LIKE THE ONE THEY
MADE WITH STALIN?
OH THIS REALLY IS A FEAST.
AND WHAT IS THIS?
'TRUFFLES DU PERIGORD'.
OH DEAR, THIS IS A LUXURY.
WHAT I WOULD GIVE TO
BE OUT IN THE FOREST ON
A COOL OCTOBER MORNING,
LOOKING FOR TRUFFLES.
WILL WE EVER DO THINGS
LIKE THAT AGAIN?
JA.
ONE DAY.
WHEN THIS CURSED WAR ENDS.
ALL THIS INSANITY.
HOW DID WE EVER
GET FOOLED INTO GOING
ALONG WITH ALL OF THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT WE WERE ALL
GUILTY, I SUPPOSE.
I KICK MYSELF FOR NOT
HAVING DONE SOMETHING SOONER
WHILE THERE WAS STILL TIME.
JA!
NOW IT IS TOO LATE.
SPEAK OUT NOW AND
THEY SIMPLY TAKE YOU
OUTSIDE AND SHOOT YOU.
I KNOW THIS FROM
PERSONAL EXPERIENCE.
NOT YOUR HUSBAND I HOPE.
A FRIEND.
ANOTHER SCHOOLTEACHER.
MY HUSBAND IS WITH THE ARMY.
HE'S A BAKER.
HE IS WELL THEN, I HOPE.
I DO NOT KNOW.
I HAVE NOT HEARD FROM
HIM IN OVER TWO MONTHS.
JA, WELL COOKS ARE
USUALLY FAR BEHIND
THE LINES YOU KNOW.
WE NEVER LET ANYTHING HAPPEN
TO THEM, CAUSE OUR FORCES
ARE RETREATING SO FAST NOW.
I'M SURE HE JUST HASN'T HAD
TIME TO SIT AND WRITE YOU.
JA, JA.
THAT MUST BE IT.
ARE YOU LATE FOR
SOMETHING, PRIVATE ?
LATE?
YEAH I'M LATE.
I HAD A WHOLE LIFE
PLANNED UNTIL YOU
GUYS INVADED POLAND.
SORRY FOR THE INCONVENIENCE.
BUT THE THREAT OF A
POLISH ATTACK LEFT US
WITH LITTLE CHOICE.
WHAT A LOAD OF MALARKEY.
A BUNCH OF YOKELS ON
HORSEBACK MUST HAVE BEEN A
REAL THREAT TO YOUR PANZERS.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
ISN'T THERE SOME PLACE
ELSE YOU'D RATHER BE?
I DO NOT THINK OF THIS.
I AM WHERE IT IS
MY DUTY TO BE.
AND IF YOU DIE?
IT WOULD BE AN HONOR FOR ME
TO DIE IN SUCH CIRCUMSTANCES.
DEATH IS NO RIGHT MATTER.
WELL, IT IS TO ME.
I PREFER THE ALTERATIVE.
I WOULD NOT EXPECT
YOU TO UNDERSTAND SUCH
THINGS PRIVATE RASSI.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE GETTING
PERSONAL, LIEUTENANT.
WELL LET'S JUST SAY THAT
IT IS UNFORTUNATE THAT OUR
FORMER ITALIAN ALLIES DO NOT
HAVE THE SAME IRON
RESOLVE AS WE GERMANS.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR
FRAU VINCKEN I'M GONNA
LET THAT ONE SLIDE.
BUT BE CAREFUL.
DON'T GET ME STEAMED.
AT LEAST THEY HAD THE
MOXIE TO GET RID OF THE
MEGALOMANIAC THAT WAS
DESTROYING THEIR COUNTRY.
TOO BAD YOU DON'T HAVE
THE RESOLVE TO THINK FOR
YOURSELVES AND DO THE SAME.
SUPPER IS SERVED.
HURRY, GENTLEMEN, UND
BRING SOMETHING TO SIT ON.
DANKA.
GIN I WOULD
ASK YOU ALL TO JOIN
ME IN A SHORT PRAYER.
LORD, WE GIVE THANKS FOR THIS
FOOD AND WE ASK YOU IN HIS
NAME TO PUT AN END TO THIS
WAR AND TO BRING
COMFORT AND PEACE TO
ALL ITS MANY VICTIMS.
AMEN.
PASS YOUR BOWLS!
WAIT A MINUTE!
IT SMELLS DELICIOUS.
JA.
[LAUGHTER]
VOILA!
AH!
TWO OF BORDEAUX'S FINEST.
OH, WELL YOU
ARE CERTAINLY FULL OF
SURPRISES PRIVATE RASSI.
JIMMY.
YOU CAN CALL ME JIMMY.
OR PERHAPS I SHOULD
SAY WEIHNACHTSMANN?
WHAT?
OH, VAS IST DAS ?
UM - SANTA CLAUS.
SANTA CLAUS
( LAUGHING)
I WONDER WHAT ELSE
DO YOU HAVE IN THERE?
OH, THE NIGHT
IS YOUNG, MA'AM.
NO ELISABETH,
CALL ME ELISABETH.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
LUGGING THESE BOTTLES
AROUND WITH YOU?
SINCE D DAY?
YEAH.
JUST ABOUT, SARGE.
AH, THEY'RE HERBIE'S.
BUT I DON'T THINK HE'LL MIND.
HEY!
TO OUR HOSTESS HUH, WHOSE
COMMON SENSE, DECENCY AND
STUBBORNNESS HAVE MADE THIS
EVENING POSSIBLE.
MAY SHE SOON LIVE IN
THE PEACEFUL WORLD
THAT SHE DESERVES.
(ALL) TO ELISABETH.
THANK YOU.
[GLASSES CLINKING]
NOW MAY WE EAT?
[HERBIE MOANING]
PLEASE SIT.
I WILL CHECK ON HIM FOR YOU.
THAT'S ALRIGHT, LIEUTENANT.
HE'S MY MAN.
I CAN TAKE CARE OF HIM.
LET HIM SLEEP.
HE'LL BE FINE.
THEN EVERYONE, YOU MAY BEGIN.
OH YOU DON'T HAVE TO
TELL ME TWICE, ELISABETH.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYONE.
(ALL) MERRY CHRISTMAS.
I HAVE NEVER UNDERSTOOD
THE AMERICAN FASCINATION
WITH BASEBALL.
(OLDER FRITZ) THAT WAS
WHEN IT STRUCK ME WHAT
MY MOTHER HAD DONE.
SOMEHOW THESE SOLDIERS WERE
NOT SO FEARSOME ANY MORE.
THEY COULD HAVE BEEN
FAMILY OR FRIENDS.
AND IT APPEARED
AS THOUGH MY MOTHER'S
WISH WAS COMING TRUE.
AS IF THE END OF THE
WAR WAS BEGINNING
RIGHT THERE AT THE
DINNER TABLE OF
ELISABETH VINCKEN.
[SYMPHONIC CHRISTMAS MUSIC]
(OLDER FRITZ) BUT THE MEAL
WAS ONLY THE BEGINNING.
CHRISTMAS IS THE
SEASON OF SURPRISES.
THE EVENING CERTAINLY HAD A
FEW SURPRISES LEFT IN STORE.
ELISABETH, THIS IS THE
BEST MEAL I'VE EVER HAD.
(LAUGHING)
SURELY YOU
EXAGGERATE A LITTLE.
NO?
( CHUCKLE)
NOT AT ALL.
NA-HUH.
AS THEY SAY,
EVERYTHING IS RELATIVE.
WELL RELATIVELY SPEAKING,
THIS MEAL WAS DELICIOUS.
RIGHT GUYS?
(ALL) YEAH!
THANKS ELISABETH,
IT TASTED GREAT.
HOW ABOUT YOU, LIEUTENANT?
DON'T AGREE?
WHAT?
AH YES, OF COURSE
THANK YOU FRAU VINCKEN.
IT'S UH, IT'S VERY GOOD.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY QUIET
DOWN THERE HERR LEUTNANT.
IS SOMETHING BOTHERING YOU?
NO!
THINKING.
THAT IS ALL.
WELL, THERE'S NO LAW
AGAINST THAT IN THE
THIRD REICH I SUPPOSE.
NOT YET !
[LAUGHTER]
AND WHAT WERE YOU
THINKING ABOUT?
YOUR FAMILY?
ACTUALLY I WAS.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
THAT YOU WERE HOME?
DECEMBER OF 1942.
AH, FOR CHRISTMAS?
FOR MY OLDER
BROTHER'S FUNERAL.
HE WAS A PANZER COMPANY
COMMANDER KILLED IN RUSSIA.
WE WERE ALL VERY
PROUD OF GUNTER.
HE BROUGHT GREAT
HONOR TO OUR FAMILY.
ONLY TWO MONTHS BEFORE HE
HAD WON THE IRON CROSS.
LIKE MY FATHER AND
UNCLE IN THE GREAT WAR.
AND NOW I AM THE ONLY SON.
SO, I MUST CONTINUE
THE FAMILY TRADITION.
THAT'S QUITE A
RESPONSIBILITY TO BEAR.
MAKES ME KIND OF GLAD MY OLD
MAN WAS JUST A STONE MASON.
MY FATHER WAS ALSO
IN THE GREAT WAR.
OH, HE WAS A HANDSOME MAN,
UNTIL HE MARCHED OFF TO THE
SOMME AND HAD HALF OF HIS
FACE BLOWN OFF.
WHAT WAS LEFT WAS
A HORRIFYING SIGHT.
FROM THAT POINT ON MY MOTHER
WOULD NOT ALLOW ANY MIRRORS
OR ANY SHINY SURFACES
INTO OUR HOME.
BUT OUR PAIN WAS
NOTHING COMPARED TO HIS.
HE WOULD
DRINK CONSTANTLY, UNTIL HE
DRANK HIMSELF UNCONSCIOUS.
AND THEN HE WOULD HAVE
NIGHTMARES AND SCREAM
AS IF BEING TORTURED.
HE FINALLY SHOT
HIMSELF IN OUR PARLOR.
I WAS TWELVE, AND IT WAS
HIS THIRTY-SECOND BIRTHDAY.
DO NOT TALK TO ME
ABOUT THE HONOR OF WAR.
(CLEARS THROAT)
WELL, UH LET'S SEE WHAT
WE HAVE FOR DESSERT HUH.
LET'S SEE, WE GOT,
WE GOT EIGHT COOKIES,
COURTESY OF FRAU MUELLER,
AND PINEAPPLE PUDDING, EH?
PRIVATE HEINRICH.
SOME PINEAPPLE PUDDING?
JA, FUR SIE !
DANKE!
PRIVATE CITIZEN VINCKEN ?
DANKE.
ELISABETH, WOULD
YOU LIKE A COOKIE?
NOT YET, THANK YOU.
ANYBODY ELSE?
WHAT?
ARE YOU KIDDING ME ?
COME ON.
HERE.
YEAH.
ME TOO.
BELIEVE ME THEY
ARE DELICIOUS.
UMM - UMM - SANTA?
WELL, I THINK
WE SHOULD HELP GIVE
ELISABETH A HAND -
NO. NO.NO.NO.
EVERYONE RELAX.
NO, NO REALLY.
NO, NO, NO.
I WILL TAKE CARE
OF EVERYTHING.
IT'S NOT A PROBLEM.
OKAY.
SARGE, I'LL TAKE THAT.
OH OKAY.
WELL, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
GOINQ SOMEWHERE, SERGEANT?
YOU GUYS MIGHT BE ABLE TO
HOLD IT IN ALL NIGHT, BUT
I GOTTA GO TO THE LATRINE.
JA!
I TOO MUST RELIEVE MYSELF.
FRITZ, DARLING!
WHEN YOU ARE DONE
YOU AND PETER CAN
BRING IN THE DISHES.
I SUSPECT I KNOW YOUR
SECRET, FRAU VINCKEN.
I HAVE NO SECRETS LIEUTENANT.
ARE YOU SURE?
THIS IS A UNIQUE SITUATION,
BUT TEMPORARY, I ASSURE YOU.
TOMORROW WE SOLDIERS
MUST GO BACK TO WAR.
BACK TO OUR OPPOSING SIDES.
WHOSE SIDE WILL YOU
BE ON, FRAU VINCKEN?
OR MORE PRECISELY WHOSE SIDE
WOULD YOU LIKE TO BE ON?
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY?
JUST THAT I KNOW
WHY YOU ARE HERE.
IT BOTHERED ME WHY A MOTHER
WOULD BRING HER SON UP
THROUGH OUR LINES WHILST A
GREAT BATTLE IS RAGING.
USUALLY CIVILIANS
GO THE OTHER WAY.
BUT NOT YOU.
WHY?
BECAUSE YOU HOPE TO
GET THROUGH OUR LINES
TO THE AMERICAN SIDE.
AND WHY WOULD I
DO SUCH A THING?
FOR FRITZ!
YOU SEE IT OCCURRED TO ME
THAT THROUGH EVERY TOWN
WE WENT THROUGH BOYS MUCH
YOUNGER THAN HE WERE
ALREADY BEARING ARMS.
BUT NOT HE.
WHY NOT?
HOW IS IT THAT HE IS THE
ONLY BOY HIS AGE WHO HAS
NOT RECEIVED HIS
CALL-UP PAPERS YET?
OR HAS HE?
I MAKE NO EXCUSES.
I HAVE ALREADY LOST ONE
SON AND POSSIBLY A HUSBAND.
I WILL NOT SEE MY ONLY
REMAINING SON GIVE HIS LIFE
FOR A CAUSE I NO LONGER
BELIEVE IN.
WELL I THINK THIS
IS THE LAST OF IT.
EXCUSE ME, LIEUTENANT.
SO GUYS, WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO DO ABOUT DRESSING UP THAT
NAKED CHRISTMAS TREE HUH?
WE DON'T HAVE
ANY DECORATIONS?
NOT YET!
LET ME SEE WHAT I CAN FIND.
WELL, COME ON.
LET'S GO.
COME ON.
LET'S GET TO THE TREE.
COME ON PETER.
DANKE.
CIGARS AND PINEAPPLE PUDDING.
A FEW KILOMETERS FROM
HOME AND YET WE BARELY
HAVE ENOUGH RATIONS,
AND AMERICA IS AN OCEAN AWAY
AND YOU HAVE EVERYTHING.
WE HAVEN'T EVEN STARTED
BREATHING HEAVY YET.
THAT KID THERE, HEINRICH.
HOW OLD IS HE?
TURNS FIFTEEN NEXT SPRING
IF HE SURVIVES THAT LONG.
WE NOW FEED CHILDREN
TO THE MEAT GRINDER.
WHAT ABOUT THE ONES
THAT DO SURVIVE?
HOW ARE YOU GONNA
MAKE THEM KIDS AGAIN
WHEN ALL THIS IS OVER?
I DON'T KNOW.
AND YOUR BOY IN THERE.
THE WOUNDED ONE.
HOW OLD IS HE?
TWENTY ONE.
HE'S AN OLD MAN IN THIS GAME.
HE MAY EVEN GET
TO BE A LITTLE BIT
OLDER, THANKS TO YOU.
IT IS DIFFICULT HUH, NOT TO
GET CLOSE TO THE GOOD ONES.
HERBIE?
WORST SOLDIER I'VE EVER SEEN.
CAN'T CLEAR HIS
WEAPON - BUNCHES UP
WITH THE OTHER GUYS.
CAN'T PUT HIM ON THE
POINT 'CAUSE HE'S
ALWAYS DAY DREAMING.
AH, YOU NEVER DAY
DREAM, SERGEANT?
SOMETIMES IT IS
WHAT KEEPS ME ALIVE.
OH HERBIE DAY DREAMS
ALL THE TIME, AND THAT
CAN GET YOU KILLED
(SIGHS)
BEEN WITH ME SINCE DAY ONE.
HIM, MEATBALL PRESTIANNI,
WINKIE KAHLER, JOHNNY SIMONE.
A GREAT BUNCH OF GUYS.
CAME OVER TOGETHER IN
'42, OFF A TROOPSHIP,
ONTO A LANDING CRAFT,
INTO NORTH AFRICA,
ITALY, NOW HERE.
ALONG THE WAY I LOST EVERY
ONE OF THEM EXCEPT HERBIE.
WORST DAMN SOLDIER
I'VE EVER SEEN.
WHAT IS IT, SON?
MY MOTHER WANTED ME TO TELL
YOU THAT WE ARE DECORATING
THE CHRISTMAS TREE.
WOW!
WE BETTER GO
INSIDE THEN, HUH.
I SEE YOU ARE NOT A
TRADITIONALIST, FRAU VINCKEN.
OH NO?
HOW'S THAT?
THE LIEUTENANT IS REFERRING
TO THE FACT THAT IN OUR
COUNTRY THE CHILDREN ARE NOT
PRESENT FOR THE
DECORATING OF THE TREE.
THAT'S A BUM DEAL.
THEY MISS HALF THE FUN.
YES.
BUT AS WE ALL KNOW
OUR HOSTESS PREFERS TO
DO THINGS HER OWN WAY.
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
IF THERE WERE MORE OF YOU
LIKE HER, NOT ONE OF US
WOULD BE HERE RIGHT NOW.
( CHUCKLE)
I'D BE BACK IN
BROOKLYN IN MY MOTHER'S
KITCHEN, SIPPIN' VINO,
(CHUCKLE)
GETTING MY HAND SLAPPED FOR
MOOCHING HER SPAGHETTI SAUCE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT LOOKS PRETTY GOOD!
THERE'S SOMETHING
MISSING THOUGH, HUH?
SOMETHING FOR THE
TOP OF THE TREE.
YEAH, THAT'S
RIGHT LIEUTENANT.
SOMETHING SHINY, EH ?
RASSI, WHAT YOU DOING ?
JUST FOR TONIGHT, SARGE?
OH, WELL.
IT LOOKS WONDERFUL.
(ALL) MERRY CHRISTMAS ...
FROLICHE WEIHNACHTEN.
^ [SINGING SILENT
NIGHT IN GERMAN] ^
JA.
WUNDERSCHON, PETER.
SCHON PETER, SAIER SCHON.
HE WAS IN THE CHOIR.
AT COLOGNE CATHEDRAL.
HUM.
NO KIDDING.
WITH A VOICE LIKE THAT HE
COULD MAKE A STATUE CRY.
WELL
(CLEARS THROAT)
I GUESS IT'S TIME TO
HAND OUT THE GIFTS, HUH?
GIFTS?
REALLY?
DIDN'T I TELL YOU SANTA
WAS GOING TO BE HERE, HUH.
PETER, CHOCOLATE, HUH?
DANKE!
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S FOR YOU.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, ELISABETH!
NOW, WHAT'S THIS?
(SNIFFING)
FRENCH SOAP .. OH,
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THANK YOU JIMMY.
MY PLEASURE.
SORRY GUYS.
NOTHING FOR YOU.
I'M ALL OUT.
I THINK MAYBE I'VE
GOT A LITTLE SOMETHING
FOR ALL OF US.
HUH?
YOU SON OF A GUN!
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
HOARDING THAT?
I WAS SAVING IT FOR
THE END OF THE WAR.
BUT I GUESS
CHRISTMAS CAME FIRST.
[INTENSE MUSIC]
WHAT'S WRONG, LIEUTENANT?
WHERE DID YOU GET THAT?
I TRADED FOR IT.
TWO ZIPPOS AND A
CARTON OF CIGARETTES.
LIAR!
I TOLD YOU I TRADED FOR IT.
LIAR.
YOU TOOK IT FROM THE
BODY OF A GERMAN SOLDIER.
EASY LIEUTENANT.
TO TAKE CIGARETTES, A
WATCH OR EVEN MONEY.
THAT IS ONE THING.
BUT TO TAKE A
SOLDIER'S MEDALS.
HIS HIGHEST HONOR, IS
THE MOST DISHONORABLE
THING IMAGINABLE.
BACK OFF, LIEUTENANT!
BACK OFF !
YOU NO SENSE OF DECENCY?
DECENCY?
I DON'T NEED ANY SERMONS
FROM THE LIKES OF YOU!
(YELLING)
WATCH OUT, SARGE!
I GOT HIM.
MOVE AWAY FROM HIM SARGE!
I GOT HIM!
HERBIE, TAKE IT EASY HERBIE!
GIMME THE GUN.
SARGE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
HERBIE.
IT'S ME NOW GIVE ME THE GUN.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
FOR CHRIST SAKE, HERBIE,
WOULD YOU GIVE ME THE GUN?
BUT SARGE -
[GUNFIRE]
YOU OKAY?
HERBIE! HERBIE!
IT'S OKAY. IT'S OKAY.
I'M SORRY.
SARGE.
IT'S ALRIGHT.
IT'S OKAY.
I'LL TAKE THAT, LIEUTENANT.
YOU GAVE YOUR WORD.
NOW GIVE ME THE GUN.
WHEN THEY FOUND MY BROTHER'S
BODY IT WAS STRIPPED NAKED
AND THROWN TO THE GROUND.
WHEN THEY FOUND MY BROTHER'S
BODY IT WAS STRIPPED NAKED
AND THROWN TO THE GROUND.
LIKE THE CARCASS
OF AN ANIMAL.
THEY TOOK EVERYTHING,
INCLUDING HIS MEDALS.
(WHISPERS) HANS.
(PETER MOANING)
PETER!
HE IS LUCKY.
IT'S JUST A GRAZE.
NOT TOO SERIOUS.
I WILL TAKE CARE OF THIS.
COME PETER, COME.
COME ON.
LIEUTENANT!
I'M SORRY I CAN'T TELL
YOU THE NAME OF THE
SOLDIER IT CAME FROM.
LIKE I SAID, I TRADED FOR IT.
HEY, FRITZ, IS PETER
GONNA BE ALRIGHT?
JA!
YOU AND I STILL FRIENDS?
WE'RE FRIENDS.
FOR EVER?
FOR EVER!
FOR EVER'S A LONG
TIME, YOU KNOW.
FOR EVER!
THAT'S A GOOD MAN!
HEY, YOU SEE THAT
BRIGHT STAR UP THERE!
JA!
SIRIUS.
THE BRIGHTEST
STAR IN THE SKY.
HOW'D YOU KNOW THAT?
MY FATHER.
HE LOVES TO STUDY THE STARS.
ME, IT WAS MY UNCLE ENNIO.
HUH.
WE USED TO SPEND ALL NIGHT ON
HIS ROOF WITH HIS TELESCOPE.
BET YOU DIDN'T KNOW IT'S
NOT ONE STAR BUT TWO?
JA!
I DID.
SO CLOSE TOGETHER,
THAT IT LOOKS LIKE
ONE FROM DOWN HERE.
YOU'RE A PRETTY
SMART GUY, HUH?
JA!
DO YOU KNOW HOW FAR IT IS?
NOT EXACTLY.
BUT I KNOW IT'S
ONE OF THE CLOSEST.
8. 7 LIGHT YEARS.
( WHISTLES)
MAKES YOU FEEL
KINDA SMALL, HUH?
JA!
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
A LITTLE HUMILITY
IS A GOOD THING.
UM - GUESS IT'S TIME
FOR A LITTLE SHUT EYE.
HUH?
(SIGH)
JA!
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
ARE YOU IN CHARGE
HERE, SERGEANT?
YES SIR.
WELL, YES SIR AND NO SIR.
WELL WHICH IS IT?
ARE YOU OR ARE YOU NOT THE
SENIOR MAN HERE, SERGEANT?
WHAT THE - WHAT THE
HELL'S GOING ON HERE?
ARE THESE GUYS
YOUR PRISONERS?
WELL, NOT EXACTLY SIR.
NOT EXACTLY?
WHAT THEN?
WELL NO, SIR.
I SUPPOSE YOU COULD SAY
THAT WE'RE ALL GUESTS HERE
- GUESTS OF THIS LADY.
GUESTS?
YES SIR.
PRIVATE RASSI AND I GOT
LOST IN THE STORM, TRYING TO
EVACUATE ONE OF OUR WOUNDED.
HE'S IN THE NEXT ROOM.
WE STUMBLED ON TO THIS
CABIN IN THE WOODS.
FRAU VICKEN HERE WAS
GOOD ENOUGH TO INVITE US
IN, SHARE FOOD WITH US.
AND THE KRAUTS ?
THEY SHOWED UP LOST
A SHORT WHILE LATER.
AND I SUPPOSE FRAU VINCKEN
FED THEM TOO, RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
( LAUGHING)
WELL, WE GOT ONE HERE
FOR THE BOOKS, SERGEANT.
IN THE MIDDLE OF A DECISIVE
BATTLE YOU TAKE OUT TIME FOR
CHRISTMAS DINNER WITH THE ENEMY.
I'M NOT SURE HOW THAT'S
GONNA SIT WITH YOUR
BATTALION COMMANDER.
UNLESS OF COURSE HE'S
AROUND HERE TOO SOMEWHERE.
NO.
SIR!
NO!
WELL, I HATE TO BREAK UP
THE PARTY SERGEANT, BUT
THERE IS A WAR TO BE WON.
WHERE ARE YOUR WEAPONS?
OUTSIDE, SIR.
FRAU VINCKEN MADE US
ALL LEAVE THEM OUTSIDE.
IT WAS HER CONDITION
FOR LETTING US
IN TO TAKE SHELTER.
OUTSIDE?
YES, SIR!
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
CAPTAIN WALTER DIETRICH AT
YOUR SERVICE, SERGEANT ?
BLANK.
SERGEANT RALPH BLANK.
WELL SERGEANT BLANK, LOOKS
LIKE YOUR FRIENDS HAD QUITE
THE CELEBRATION LAST NIGHT.
WHAT'S WRONG, SERGEANT?
CAT GOT YOUR TONGUE?
I HEARD ALL ABOUT YOU GUYS.
BROUGHT UP IN THE STATES.
PERFECT ACCENTS.
ALL YOU NEED IS A SET
OF FATIGUES AND YOU CAN BE
DROPPED BEHIND OUR LINES TO
DESTROY AND SABOTAGE AT WILL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
CLEVER ISN'T IT?
YOU GUYS JUST NEVER PLAY
ON A LEVEL FIELD, HUH.
AH, COME ON SERGEANT,
DON'T GIVE ME THAT CRAP
ABOUT RULES AND FAIR PLAY.
THIS IS WAR NOT A BALL GAME.
MAYBE THE GODS OF BASEBALL
PREFER A LEVEL FIELD.
BUT THE GODS OF WAR PREFER
THE SIDE THAT IS THE MOST
DARING AND RESOURCEFUL.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT WE'D BE
ON THE SAME SIDE IN THIS.
IT'S TOO BAD PRESIDENT
ROOSEVELT DOESN'T THINK
LIKE MR. LINDBERGH.
YEAH!
TOO BAD FOR YOU GUYS.
THE DAY'S SOON COMING WHEN
YOU'RE GONNA GET YOURS.
WELL, YOU'LL NEVER SEE
THAT DAY, SERGEANT.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
WHAT WAS THAT.
SARGE?
IT SURE AS HELL WASN'T
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
CAN IT BLANK!
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
MAMA ! !
[SPEAKS GERMAN]
HERBIE.
(WHISPERED) HEY.
HOW YOU FEELING, SOLDIER?
I DREAMT I HEARD
SHOUTING, SARGE.
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE FINE.
WE GOTTA GET GOING NOW, BUT
YOU'RE AT A FRIEND'S HOUSE.
HER NAME'S ELISABETH.
SHE'S REALLY NICE.
SHE'S GONNA TAKE CARE OF
YOU TILL OUR GUYS GET HERE.
NOW YOU JUST STAY
HERE AND RELAX.
THAT'S AN ORDER, ALRIGHT?
WHATEVER YOU SAY, SARGE.
HEY HERB.
JIMMY NO MUSS.
NO FUSS.
YOU GOT IT.
I'LL CATCH YOU BACK
IN BROOKLYN ALRIGHT?
OKAY.
YOU SURE YOU DON'T
WANT TO COME WITH US?
IT'S GONNA BE
OVER SOON, ANYWAY.
HOW ABOUT YOU, SERGEANT?
GO WITH THEM!
GO!
SAVE YOUR OWN LIVES.
IT IS NEARLY OVER!
LIEUTENANT, ALL THE PINEAPPLE
PUDDING YOU COULD EAT.
THANK YOU, BUT IT
IS NOT POSSIBLE.
IT'S ONE CRAZY WORLD, HUH?
JA.
HERE YOU MIGHT NEED THIS.
THANKS.
WHAT ABOUT THE KID?
[BIRD CAWING]
HE WILL DO WHAT YOU TELL HIM.
WELL, GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
GOOD LUCK, LIEUTENANT.
PRIVATE RASSI.
FRAU.
I GUESS THIS IS IT.
THANK YOU ELISABETH!
YOU KEEP YOUR HEAD UP AND
YOUR EYES ON THE STARS.
JA.
TAKE CARE, BUDDY!
ELISABETH, THANK YOU.
TAKE CARE OF
YOURSELF JIMMY.
ALL RIGHT YOU.
LET'S MOVE OUT.
COME ON PETER.
MAYBE YOU CAN TEACH
ME SOME GERMAN, HUH?
(OLDER FRITZ) IT WAS
JUST AFTER EIGHT O'CLOCK
ON CHRISTMAS MORNING.
LATER THAT DAY AN AMERICAN
PATROL CAME BY AND THE WAR
FOR US WAS FINALLY OVER.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE THAT
IT ALL HAPPENED RIGHT HERE.
IT TRULY IS AN AMAZING STORY.
THEY WERE AMAZING PEOPLE.
I GUESS SO.
BUT YOU NEVER SAW
MOST OF THEM AGAIN.
NO.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE GERMAN SOLDIERS.
AND AS FOR THE AMERICANS
- WELL I MET SERGEANT
BLANK ONCE IN MARYLAND.
BUT YOUR GRANDFATHER WAS
THE ONLY ONE WITH WHOM
I HAD REGULAR CONTACT.
AND NOW PERHAPS I
SHOULD GIVE YOU THESE.
YOU HAD THESE ALL THIS TIME?
HE INSISTED I KEEP
THEM FOR LUCK.
I THINK YOU SHOULD HAVE THEM.
THANKS.
WELL I GUESS WE
SHOULD GET GOING.
JA.
STILL KEEP YOUR
EYES ON THE STARS?
OH YEAH.
EVERY TIME I LOOK UP
AT SIRIUS IT REMINDS ME
THAT WITH GOOD INTENTIONS
EVERYTHING'S POSSIBLE.
LIKE THAT NIGHT WHEN BECAUSE
OF ONE WOMAN A GROUP OF
MEN CAME TOGETHER AS BITTER
ENEMIES PARTED
AGAIN AS FRIENDS.