Welcome to Melbourne,
I bring you General
MacArthur's compliments.
Thank you, sir. I am Colonel Mason.
These gentlemen are Major
Arthur and Captain Lawrence.
How do you do? How do you
do? I'm Lieutenant Schwartz.
These are Lieutenants
Armstrong, Leonard,
O'Doul,
Bacelli,
Bollenbacher,
and Emerson.
I'm very happy to know you
all and thank God you're here.
We're sorry we haven't
a big welcoming committee
but we're trying to avoid
calling attention to your arrival
since we haven't heard
from the other girls yet.
Not even the girls on the other plane?
No word as yet.
Did any of the others get off?
We were told there were
10 more by submarine,
but we haven't heard
from them since they left.
Aren't there any more? They said
everyone was to be ordered off.
Everyone was ordered off,
but we could only get about
20 before it was too late.
The rest of the girls are in
the hands of those filthy...
Then we should have stayed.
You were carrying out your orders,
and your further orders are to
proceed immediately to the hotel,
where the Red Cross has warm
baths and clean clothes for you.
And my further, though
unofficial, orders are
you are to have your heart's
desire, anything you want.
And what do you want most in the world?
A tomato. A nice, big, red,
cool, round, juicy tomato.
Colonel, do you happen to know
when we're supposed to go home?
On the very next transport.
I thought there were eight of you.
Davy... I mean, Lieutenant
Davidson is just being brought off.
I wore a 6-A before
Bataan and I'm gonna get...
Say, what do you know? I've
forgotten how to walk in these things.
You better sit down
before you break your neck,
or else get a bigger size.
High heels. The things
we do to trap men.
Boy, this is sure a relief.
I know people mean well, but it's
nice to be by ourselves again.
Yeah, it gets embarrassing being
called a heroine all the time.
What is a heroine, anyway?
I don't know. Somebody
who's still alive, I guess.
If anybody calls me a heroine again,
I'm gonna let them have a
tomato right in the puss.
Ethel, you'll bust if
you eat another one.
I've lost 35 pounds in this
campaign and I got to get it back.
Keep them coming every 15 minutes,
if it's not too much trouble.
No trouble at all. It's
an honor and a privilege
to be serving a group
of heroines like you.
No, you can't!
This will do right
here, nurse. Yes, sir.
How is she, Major?
The closer we get to
home, the worse she gets.
What do you think's wrong?
It's simple.
When people don't
want to live, they die.
Oh, no.
I know we did the wrong thing.
She didn't want to
go, she wanted to stay
and when we got her on the
plane, she just collapsed.
If it were a mere physical
collapse, I'd know what to do.
Frankly, I'm desperate.
I wonder...
I wonder, perhaps, if you can help me.
We'll do anything, Doctor, anything.
It's not going to be easy.
I hate to ask you, even.
I know how much you all want to
forget what you've been through.
But I only have one hope left.
This letter is addressed to her.
It came through on the
last plane from Mindanao.
Who's the letter from, Major?
Signed by somebody called "John".
Oh, that's...
Just a moment, please.
I want you to tell me
everything you can remember,
things that might not even concern her.
You never know. It might
have its place in the pattern.
Well, the first time I met
Lieutenant Davidson was last November.
We were all ordered to
embark from San Francisco.
I remember it was cold and drizzly,
and I had been staying
with Rosemary Larson.
It was her hometown,
and her family had come down
to the dock to see us off.
Goodbye, Mrs. Larson, and
thanks for a wonderful time.
I don't know when I've had better.
You should have stayed
around a little longer.
I'd have made a real hep cat out of you.
I don't know about the "hep".
Look, Mama, why don't
you go? You'll catch cold.
I won't. I want to see you go.
Let Mama stay, Roselein.
You'd think I was going away for good.
Davy. I'm sorry.
Can I see you for a moment?
This is Lieutenant O'Doul.
All present and accounted for now, sir.
Well, thank you.
Are orchids regulation now, Lieutenant?
They're not mine. A friend
of mine gave them to me.
I see. Well, good luck,
Lieutenant, and bon voyage.
Thank you, sir.
Davy, you've gotta help
me. I'm in a terrible jam.
What's the matter? Two of
my fiances came to the dock.
Two?
You know how hard it is for me to say
no when somebody asks me to marry him.
I thought it would be easy
for you to say no by now.
Golly, it's all in fun,
but if these two Irishmen
ever meet up with each other...
I parked one of them over at the gate...
There you are, darling!
I've been looking all
over for you, Joan.
Well, I've been looking
all over for you too, dear.
You wait here. I'll be right back.
Don't forget to write, dear!
What does she mean,
don't forget to write?
Letters. You know, from the post office.
Well, she's not leaving yet.
Oh, Captain! Captain, will you
hold this for me just for a second?
Well... And this, here.
But we haven't had a
chance to say good-bye yet.
There's lots of time to say good-bye.
Say, who wrote that?
Who wrote what?
"Whenever a snowflake leaves the sky
"It turns and turns to say 'Good-by!"'
Haven't the faintest idea.
Do you know the rest of it?
The rest of what? The poem.
No, never did.
Well, it goes,
"Whenever a snowflake leaves the sky
"It turns and turns to say 'Good-by!"'
Good-bye. No, Captain,
I remember the rest.
"Good-by, dear clouds,
so cool and gray!"
And it goes something and
something "on its way".
What does?
The snowflake.
How's that look?
It looks great. You're pretty. Thanks.
Davy, I want you to meet my mother
and dad, and my brother, Georgie.
Hold these, Georgie.
Bye, snowflake. Thanks.
Mother, this is Lieutenant
Davidson, our senior officer.
How do you do, Mrs. Larson?
I think we better be going.
Please, please. This is her first
time away. Take care of my baby.
Now, there's nothing to
worry about, Mrs. Larson.
I will worry. Is it not
so, a mother must worry?
Yes, I suppose so.
The days will be lonesome now.
The two years will go like wildfire.
Yes, the years are short.
It's the days that are so long.
Now, don't you worry. I'll take care
of Rosemary. She'll be all right.
May God save you and keep you kindly,
and stand between you and harm.
Thank you.
Thanks again, Mrs. Larson.
I like you. You eat so much.
Goodbye, Mama.
Where's my cake? What
have you done with my cake?
Frederick, her cake. I have it here.
Roselein! Roselein!
Now you've got me crying.
Good-bye.
But, darling, I did
look all over for you.
Joan!
Where did you go? Well, I...
Captain O'Rourke, I want
you to meet Captain O'Brien.
You two should know each other.
There you are, Captain.
I just remembered the end.
The end of what? Well,
you know, "The Snowflake".
Fine.
"Good-by, dear clouds,
so cool and gray!
"Then lightly travels on its way"
Yes.
Well, come on, Joan.
Good-bye. Good-bye.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, dear.
Good-bye!
Good-bye! Good-bye!
Thanks, pal. I don't know
whoever said the flesh was weak,
I find it very strong.
Say, you'll catch cold, leatherneck.
Who, me?
Never had a cold in my life.
We were to be stationed at Honolulu,
and although the boat was a slow one,
we enjoyed every minute of it.
It was hard to believe it was December,
what with the tropical sea,
blue water and flying fish.
Hiya.
How's your cold, leatherneck?
It's not a cold. It's just
a running nose. Running...
You better not take too much of
this tropical sun, you'll get burned.
Who, me? I never burn.
Best tan you ever seen.
Don't you ever get
tired of writing letters?
Uh-uh.
All doctors.
What's the date?
It's Sunday. We had chapel.
Sunday the what?
Sunday the seventh.
Thanks. I'll just head it, "Eighteen
shopping days until Christmas".
Maybe he'll take the hint.
Pearl Harbor.
Most of us didn't even know what
it was, let alone where it was.
So instead of landing at Hawaii,
we were ordered to join a
convoy somewhere in the Pacific.
None of us realized what
the whole thing meant.
Sweet Genevieve
The days may come, the days may go
But still the hands of memory weave
That blissful dream
Of long ago
I'll open for two. For three.
I'll see you. I'll stay.
I'll pass. Go ahead, bet.
Well, I would. You should see...
But you're not playing,
Elsie. Two, please.
I know it's not much of a convoy,
but somehow those other ships
make me feel more comfortable.
It would be awful to be out
here on the ocean all alone.
These will do.
I'll have three, please.
Do you think Pearl Harbor could
have been very much, Captain?
Well, there's no official word yet.
Still has to be proved that an
airplane can sink a battleship
for my dough.
We probably won't see
very much of the Jap fleet.
Is that Marine trying
to get your attention?
Hmm? Oh, him. He's just a
friend of mine from Kansas
who wants to show me his clippings.
He used to play football, I gathered.
Football? Who is he?
I really don't know.
Let's find out, shall we?
Hey, Kansas, come on in.
Hi.
This is Captain Saunders,
Captain Lawrence.
How do you do?
They thought they'd like to see
your scrapbook. Read it to us.
Here with them? Yes. Go ahead.
Yes, sir.
Read about your greatest
single personal exploit.
Oh, well...
What position did you play, Kansas?
Well, I sort of fooled around
at fullback. Used to play...
Carry on.
Yes, sir.
"One of the most thrilling
gridiron battles of the year,
"when a light, underestimated
Kansas team defeated Notre Dame..".
Notre Dame? I thought Kansas
played only high schools.
No, sir. They play colleges.
Go ahead. Yes, sir.
"Though at the end of the first half,
"Notre Dame held a comfortable
14-to-nothing margin..".
Very comfortable, I'd say.
Yeah. Margin...
"Nonetheless, in the second half,
"when the highly touted
'Weeping' Walachek,
"despite an injury,
was sent into the game,
"the Kansas Cyclones
scored three touchdowns
"in 10 minutes on runs of..".
Say, I remember that game!
That was a terrific upset.
Did you play on the team
with "Weeping" Walachek?
Well... He's me.
Well, why didn't you tell us who he was?
I still don't know who he was.
"Weeping" Walachek.
Yes, I know, but why "Weeping" Walachek?
Sort of a habit, I guess.
Everybody knew that
until he got good and mad
and started to cry, he couldn't play.
Then zowie! Touchdown.
Let me see that book.
"The last race..".
Come on, let's get on with the game.
Just a minute, Joan, I wanna...
Where's that Army game?
Right over here. I'll find it for you.
"Weeping" Walachek. What do you know?
The card game, hmm?
Just a minute, Joan, be
with you, just a minute.
Hey, here it is.
I remember that game. Boy, what a game!
Boy, did you wreck the Army.
Yeah, well, it was just after that game
that I sort of figured I
better join the Marines.
Cigarette, miss. Sorry.
What's the matter with me? Have
I got dandruff or something?
I really can't tell
out here in the dark.
That's not what I mean.
I know what you mean.
Look, why won't you ever let me see you?
Officers are not supposed to
fraternize with enlisted men.
I don't want to
fraternize. I just wanna see you.
And pass the time of day?
Well, it'd be better than nothing.
Sunburn.
Well, just stop your maneuvers
before you make contact
with the main body.
Don't you like me?
I like you.
That's just sort of, "So what," huh?
That's right.
Look, Lieutenant, if
it's something I've done,
or if I just plain annoy you, I'm sorry.
I won't bother you anymore.
Don't go. I'm just being childish.
I sure would like to meet one guy,
though, who doesn't make a pass.
Well, when you do, you
better begin to worry.
You're not so dumb.
I just talk dumb.
But why can't men and women be pals?
'Cause only men and men are pals.
All right. Come on. Get it over with.
That's... Better.
Incidentally, I'm warning you, Kansas.
I melt at a very low temperature.
Well, then, I'll try to be pals.
Okay and when you can't
stand it any longer,
from time to time I'll let you kiss me.
This one of those times?
Nope!
Okay, let me know.
Golly! What's that?
Subs, I guess.
We picked up a number of
survivors from the torpedoed ships
who were suffering from shock and
burns from the oil in the water.
They were pitifully few, but more
than we could accommodate in sick bay,
so we turned the salon
into a temporary hospital.
For a while we were so busy, it
kind of took our minds off the war.
One of the survivors, only slightly
burned, was a nurse from the other ship.
Her name was Olivia.
We tried to be friendly, but
she didn't want any part of us.
So we didn't want any part of her.
There you are, Olivia. I'm glad
it was no more serious than that.
Happy to see you up and about again.
Thank you.
Olivia, I'm glad to see
your bandage off. Let's see.
It's fine.
You're a very lucky girl. Lucky?
Why, yes. We didn't get many survivors.
That's one way of looking at it.
Why did that boat leave
after Pearl Harbor?
I realize we need supplies
in the Philippines, but...
I don't know, and I don't
ask a lot of questions.
I see.
Incidentally, your orders came
through. You're to join our unit.
Here are a couple of extra caps.
I've sent your new issue
to Room 10 on C-deck.
You'll bunk in with Miss Bacelli.
She's already mentioned it to me.
She doesn't want me to.
Oh.
All right, I'll talk to her.
Let me have your scissors, Bacelli.
Tony, what's this about Olivia?
I just don't want her around.
But why? What's the matter?
Oversupply of gall.
Her gall bladder needs draining.
What she needs is a
permanent anesthetic.
'Course, if it's an order,
she can come in with me.
Never mind, I'll get someone else.
Joan.
Joan, do you mind
Olivia bunking with you?
What did I do to get punished?
I'd do it myself,
only Rosemary's still a
little homesick and frightened.
That Olivia, I'd like to give her
an injection and leave the needle in.
But, okay, if I'm the victim.
Thanks. I don't know why I'm so nice.
Look, I'm perfectly all
right. When do I get up?
When you're told. Now, take
your shirt off like a nice boy.
What for?
Because I've got some
brand-new diapers for you.
Beautiful. Tell me, do you think I can
get my initials embroidered on those?
Sure. What are your
initials? D.O.P.E.? Here.
Great. This is going to be fine.
What's that for? A bath,
I'm gonna give you a bath.
Oh, no. No female's going to bathe me.
One of those.
Miss Davidson. Miss Davidson.
The patient's supposed to have a bath,
and he refuses to let me give it to him.
All right, Miss O'Doul.
Thank you, nursey.
Lieutenant John Summers. Mmm-hmm.
With the medical unit. Mmm-hmm.
Fine. A doctor and you
won't let a nurse wash you.
I'm not a doctor, I'm a technician.
I was associate professor
of Chemistry at Hawaii.
I see. A professor.
Well, that explains it.
What are you doing?
You're going to have a
bath, and don't be coy.
I don't care how dirty I may be.
You reek. I can still smell
that oil you were swimming in.
No female's going to bathe me.
Your mother did.
Only until I was big
enough to knock her down.
All right now, which is it to be,
the sheet or your arm?
Angels of mercy, huh?
You're a bunch of wrestlers.
What's the matter?
My head.
Feel dizzy? Yes.
No feeling in your hands and feet?
Yes, that's right.
You're lying.
When people get to know you
awfully well, what do they call you?
Lieutenant.
Oh.
All right. Turn over
and get your back done.
This isn't as humiliating as I thought.
Hey, that's nice. Do it again.
Get down.
Since you like this so much, I'm
gonna let you do it every day.
That'll be such fun. Now turn over.
Here.
Most of the patients were up
and about by Christmas Eve.
We'd been on the high
seas for almost a month,
and the people were
getting kind of jittery.
So the Chaplain
arranged with the Captain
to have a little Christmas party.
Joan, I think you were
with Janet that evening.
Maybe you could tell what
happened better than I.
Well, I remember we
all decided to dress up.
I wanted to make an
impression on Kansas,
and the only snakey thing
I had was a black nightgown,
which, with a few trimmings, did for me.
Hey, Rosemary, give me
a hand, will you? Sure.
Davy, aren't you dressing for the party?
I don't think so, dear.
How about here? Is that all right?
This is for Lieutenant Davidson.
Thank you.
Doesn't Rosemary look nice? Yes.
Where'd you get that sash?
Just part of an old surgical
gown I dyed with mercurochrome.
It's nice.
And he's never seen you out of uniform.
Who?
Who do you think?
You mean Lieutenant Summers?
It's still formal with you two.
Well, you better get informal
with him, or other people will.
He's a pretty cute guy, you know.
Pretty soigne, huh? How
does it look, Rosemary?
Haven't you got anything simpler?
Simpler? Well, I have some
other things in my musette bag.
I don't know if you'd call them simple.
Come on in. It's over there someplace.
This ought to be about
right, the locket.
That isn't mine, it must be Olivia's.
Let's see. I don't think she'd mind.
I like it!
Hello, Olivia.
Take that off.
Well, I only want to wear it tonight.
I said take that off.
What do you mean, snooping
around in my things?
She didn't. I found it...
Say, who do you think you are?
You wanna play rough!
Davy! Davy!
Stop it! Stop it!
She started it and I don't
get slugged by anybody!
Stop it! Now, I order you to stop it!
What are you, a couple of
children? Now what's up?
Sorry, Davy.
It was my fault, Davy! By mistake,
I opened Olivia's musette bag.
She had no right to open it.
She said it was a mistake.
Now I don't care whose fault
it was, you were both wrong,
you realize that, don't you?
I don't want to have to
take any official action.
Look, I know we're
all nervous and jittery
on a boat going nowhere, getting nowhere
but we've got to hang on a
little longer, that's all.
I don't want this to
go outside this cabin.
Now, forget it and shake hands.
Sorry, Olivia.
All right, Joan.
Joan's just impulsive. She
didn't really mean any harm.
Come on. Why don't
you go up with me? Hmm?
It may be our last party in a long time.
Leave me alone, can't you?
Silent night
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
Round yon Virgin
Mother and child
Holy infant
So tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly peace
Merry Christmas.
May I have your attention, please?
Thank you. I'm sure we're going
to have a lot of fun here tonight.
Now, before we begin, I personally
want to thank the Chaplain
for producing this
seagoing Christmas tree.
Thank you.
All right, Reverend. It's your party.
Thanks.
Before we get on with it,
there is something in my heart
that I would like to say to you.
This is the night before Christmas
and because it is, you must
forgive me for being sentimental.
We're a sentimental people,
and I think we're proud of it.
Despite the fact that our
enemies deride us for it,
it makes us the stronger.
It is ironic even to try to talk
about the spirit of Christmas
when war is flaming
throughout the globe,
but we believe in this great truth.
And so all I want to say in
the tragedy all about us is,
have faith.
Not a blind faith,
but faith in those things
in which we believe.
We must have such faith in those things,
such faith in ourselves,
such faith in mankind
that we are tough about
the things we believe in,
so tough that we will fight to the death
to make those tender
and sentimental beliefs
like Christmas a reality forever.
Now, God bless us, everyone.
And let me wish you a merry Christmas!
How about some music?
Hey, Kansas!
Why don't you come on in?
All the rules are off
tonight. It's Christmas.
Yeah, a fine Christmas. No mistletoe.
All right, if it means
that much to you, here.
Merry Christmas!
See? What'd I tell you?
Get my present?
Yes, thank you.
Well, what's mine in return?
My thanks.
I suppose I'll have to be
satisfied with just that.
You realize this is the first
time you've been in my arms?
I've been in lots of arms.
Yes, but these are mine. I
want you to get used to them.
Say, Kansas, you know,
we've never danced together.
Wanna? Can you?
Sure. I used to fool around
a little bit. Used to...
Say, don't waste that.
Pretty hot stuff.
What's the matter with you, Davy?
Why?
You seem to be smiling all over.
Good heavens! Aren't you in bed yet?
Believe it or not, I was
on the top deck with Kansas
singing Christmas carols.
Can I bunk in here, Davy?
Did you have another row with Olivia?
No, but she's scary,
she just lies there and
stares and never goes to sleep.
It's like sleeping in a graveyard.
Okay, you take my bed.
I'll try it for the night, anyway.
Thanks, pal.
Has she ever opened up? Ever
give you a hint of what's wrong?
There's nothing wrong. She's just
naturally a frozen-faced ghoul.
Are you asleep, Olivia? No.
Do you mind if I turn on the light? No.
Is it all right if I bunk in here? Yes.
What's the matter, Olivia?
Something's hurt you.
Why don't you talk about
it, get it off your chest?
You can forget I'm
your superior officer.
It's none of your business, so don't
forget you are my superior officer.
Maybe if I knew what was
eating you, I could help.
Nobody can. I don't want anybody to try.
I can do it myself.
Why did you lose your temper
when Joan... Put that down!
Do I go through your things?
I don't think we better talk anymore.
I'm beginning to get pretty sore.
All right, so you're beginning
to get sore, enjoy it,
but stop prying into things
that don't concern you.
Maybe it does concern me.
It concerns me that the morale
of this group remains high.
Until you joined up, it was.
But you're just a troublemaker.
But I don't really care
what's bothering you at all.
I don't like you any more
than the rest of the girls do.
I'm supposed to be a
nurse and that's all.
No, there's more than
that, now that we're at war.
Maybe you don't know what's up,
maybe you don't know
what we're doing here.
You think I don't know.
All right, I'll tell you.
I know what I'm doing.
I know why I'm here. I
know what I'm going to do.
I'm going to kill Japs.
Every bloodstained one
I can get my hands on!
Olivia.
That doesn't sound nice
coming from a nurse, does it?
We're supposed to be angels of mercy,
we're supposed to tend to the
wounded and take care of the sick.
We're supposed to be kind and tender,
and serve humanity in
the name of humanity.
What humanity? Jap humanity?
Olivia, be quiet.
No, you asked me. You wanted to know.
You pried into things
that didn't concern you.
You wanted to know what this is.
Look, look at that!
Do you know what it is?
I'll tell you, it's a boy!
Come in, both of you.
You wanted to know, too.
Today is Christmas, isn't it?
The time for cheer and good
fellowship and for peace.
Well, today's my wedding
day. You see that?
He and I were to be
married today in St. Louis,
and why weren't we?
Because he's dead. He
died that first morning.
They killed him. I saw him.
He was running across the field
to his plane and they killed him.
Sixty bullets! Sixty!
By the time I got to him, he was dead.
His face was gone! I
couldn't see him anymore!
Just blood! Blood all over!
Olivia! Don't.
Let me go! Let me go!
They must be punished and
I'm going to punish them!
Yes, dear.
He was dead. It was ended for him.
Livvie, darling.
I wanted him. He was all I had.
Yes, dear.
I loved him so much.
The next few days, we
really began to get jittery.
The Japs kept jamming our radio,
so we never knew what was going on,
and the rumor factory
was going full blast.
...all over Los Angeles.
Quiet, listen!
It seems Honolulu itself...
Say, Davy, we just heard on
the radio, we lost Honolulu!
Now, how could you hear
that? I heard it, too.
All it said was, "Blah,
blah, blah, Honolulu".
San Francisco's in flames. I know that.
Tony, turn that thing down.
You talk like a bunch of old
women. You know what I think?
I think you better all give
up thinking for the duration.
We haven't lost Honolulu,
and there's been no bombing either
in Los Angeles or San Francisco.
Who said so?
I just read the
communique the Captain got.
The truth is, Manila's
been declared an open city.
What does that mean?
It means we can't land there.
Well, then are we going back home?
We can't go back. The Army needs
what supplies we've got on board.
We've been ordered to a place
called Bataan, Bataan Peninsula.
It's in command of General MacArthur.
Well, if it's good enough for
a general, it's good enough me,
as long as they got plenty to eat.
I only hope it's got a decent
beauty parlor. My hair's a mess.
Hello.
Hello. Have you been trying to avoid me?
Frankly, I have.
Why?
Because...
Because I've been trying to avoid you.
Well, let's get away from here.
The noise of these engines...
I find the noise very reassuring.
Come on.
Now, I don't want to seem impetuous.
You don't?
All right, I do want
to seem impetuous, then.
But the point is, anything can happen.
Such as? The boat might sink.
It might.
If it does, we might
never see each other again.
That's possible.
Perhaps someplace in the hereafter,
but then I wouldn't have my body.
What's more important, you
wouldn't have yours, either.
That might be very interesting.
Well, I'll see you there sometime.
Wait a minute! I haven't
made my point yet.
After all, I'm not so bad looking.
I'm supposed to be very
intelligent, in fact.
I work hard. I make $5,000 a year.
Oh, you make $166 a month now.
Please, I mean this. I'm in
love with you, Lieutenant.
If only we'd met somewhere else before.
You'd have had a wonderful
time as I wooed you.
You think so?
I'm positive. I'd have
really been foolish.
I feel foolish enough now, but then
I would have spent sleepless nights,
bought flowers to lay at your feet,
flowers I couldn't
possibly have afforded.
I'd have been over meticulous
with you in taxicabs,
knowing, of course, you're
not that kind of girl.
At first, I think my dog-like devotion
would have made you pity me a little.
Then my fatal charm would
have snuck up on you,
and before you knew it, you'd be mine
in some dingy little French restaurant
where the wine wasn't too bad.
But with all that's happening,
I don't have to be
ridiculous for you to love me.
There's no time.
Out there this second, a torpedo
may be spinning its way toward us
and you've no time, either.
I think when you knew me, you'd
love me, but there's no time.
Don't you see, we haven't
got a second to waste.
You're right.
There's no time, no time
for anything personal.
Thanks for everything you said.
Maybe everything you say is true
and maybe you wouldn't have
had to do all those things.
I'd have stopped you the moment
I knew. You know now, don't you?
No, please, John,
don't make it difficult.
I've been trying to avoid you.
That ought to tell you something.
I can't love you, I won't
permit myself to. Why not?
Because I've got a job to do.
What's that got to do with
it? We've all got jobs to do.
I know, but our
responsibilities are greater now.
Nothing can stand in the way.
You do look a little foolish.
I wish we had met somewhere in
a dingy little French restaurant.
But maybe we will.
Good night.
Let me kiss you good-bye, then?
No. Just once?
Oh, no, please. Please.
What's the matter?
Listen, the engines have stopped!
Your life preserver.
Where's your life preserver?
I left it in the cabin.
Here, take mine, take it. No.
Darling, before anything
happens, tell me, do you love me?
No. You're lying. You do love me.
Yes. Well, say it then.
I love you.
Better get down to your stations.
What are the engines stopped for?
Run up to the Captain.
I'm sure he'd be delighted
to tell you over a scotch and soda.
Is it one of ours? Sounds like it.
It is. It's a PBY.
I guess Bataan can't
be so very far away.
We landed at Mariveles, a small,
snug harbor on Bataan Peninsula,
which the Navy used as
an emergency supply base.
Lieutenant Davidson? Yes, sir.
The CO wants to see you
immediately. Yes, sir.
This is Ling Chee.
How do you do? How do you do?
He's going to drive
you to your destination.
You leave right away, Mr.
Ling will take you to the CO.
Thank you.
It's good to be on land again.
Have you been in the
Army long, Mr. Ling?
No, I was editor of
the Chinese Advertiser
and I'm happy to say like Abu Ben Adhem,
my name led all the rest
on the Japanese blacklist.
Girls, this is Mr. Ling Chee
who's going to be with us
for the rest of the trip.
Now, each one find her own duffel bag.
Heap big war. Him near here, savvy?
I'm a Chinese,
Lieutenant, not an Indian.
The war is just beyond the mountains.
Sir, Lieutenant Davidson.
Colonel White.
I thought it might be
you when I saw the name.
My goodness, you've grown
into a beautiful woman.
Thank you.
Where was it? Shanghai.
I remember now. It was just
after you lost your dad.
Well, welcome to Bataan. Thank you, sir.
And you're in the Army, too?
Yes, and very happy. Happier
still that you're our CO.
I'm a terribly strict
disciplinarian, Janet.
Now these are your orders.
To proceed immediately to Limay,
our number one base hospital.
Now, here's Limay, this is
where you landed at Mariveles,
and over there is Corregidor,
and up there beyond Limay about
40 kilometers are the front lines.
Thank you, sir.
Pardon me, Colonel White, where
is the fourth medical unit?
The fourth unit? Let me see.
They were the first ones off they
disembarked early this afternoon.
They've gone. To what base, sir?
Base? They're based on the front lines.
They're probably there by now.
The technicians, too?
Well, there's nothing for
them to get technical with,
except maybe a stretcher.
Thank you, sir.
Hey, Joan!
Hi, Kansas.
Gosh, I've been looking
all over for you.
I just wanted to say so long.
Well, I'll be seeing you.
Kansas, are you scared, too?
You mean, you feel as if
you suddenly lost your belly?
Yeah. Me, too.
But that's just like in a football game.
You stand there waiting
for the whistle to blow,
and all of a sudden
your knees get like water
and you feel like throwing up.
Then, all of a sudden it toots.
Don't do that.
Then the first thing you know,
you're in there and
you're not scared anymore.
I hope so.
So long, Kansas, and don't get lost!
Who, me? How could I get lost?
Hey! Your gang went
in the other direction.
Well...
Thank you. Don't let
anything happen to you.
Who, me? How could
anything happen to me?
Look, don't say anything
else, except good-bye.
Good-bye.
Here's some gum. A little
farewell present for the girls.
Thank you. So long.
So long, girls. Good luck. Bye-bye.
You, too. See you later.
We arrived at Limay late that night.
It was a dusty little village where the
Army had established a small supply base.
But with the sudden change in plans,
the warehouses became hospitals
and headquarters for the nurses.
This was to be our home.
We were glad to be there,
and glad mostly at the thought
of a night's sleep on solid earth.
Hello. Are we glad to see you.
Well, the old homestead
hasn't changed a bit.
Easy, there. One at a time.
Captain McGregor? Yes?
Lieutenant Davidson reporting.
Well, you finally got here.
Hello, Ma. O'Doul, isn't it?
Yes, Fort Sam Houston. We used
to call her "Ma" at Fort Sam.
Her bite's much worse than her bark.
But I bark, too. Now, you
better all dive into your whites.
I'll get you some Gl tomorrow.
You can't wear whites here. The
nearest laundry is in Manila.
We need you right away.
Some of our girls have forgotten
what the word "sleep" means.
Chee, show them to nurses' quarters.
Now, get a move on, will
you? I'm glad you're here.
Thank you.
Captain? Yes?
Do you have any Japanese
wounded here? A few.
I'd like to handle them.
Do you know the language?
No, but I'm anxious to learn.
Well, I guess you can be accommodated.
I'll put you down for Ward 11.
Thank you, Captain. The name is D'Arcy.
And be careful of the foxholes.
Where are they? They're all over.
Well, can't you see them? No.
Well, then, how do you
know where they are?
If you fall in one, you'll know.
This is Ward 7. That's me.
Next to it is the children's
ward. That's for me.
See you later, kids. Good-bye.
And this is the surgery. Come
on, Rosemary, you go with me.
Good night, girls. Good night.
Over there is number three.
Number three? That's me.
Good night.
And this is Ward number 11.
This is where we keep the prisoners.
Why aren't the numbers in order?
We mix them up so as to
confuse the Japs and ourselves.
They certainly are confusing me.
I'm D'Arcy.
Patterson. I'm so glad you're here.
I'm sorry, but they all need their
dressings changed when you get around to it.
Run along. I'll take over. Thanks.
Night. Night.
Respiration all right here? Yes, Doctor.
Oh, here. It's just exhaustion.
The poor kid. Get her
to bed. We'll take over.
Where are your surgery masks?
Masks? We used them all up long ago.
You go on in. I'll have to scrub again.
I'm sorry. I can't understand you.
I'm sorry. I tore my glove. Help
me on with a new one, please.
I mean... I mean, hurry, please.
What is the case, Doctor? Cesarean.
Cesarean?
Oh, yes. You seem surprised.
I have a peacetime practice
as well as a wartime practice.
My name is Jose Bardia,
University of Philippines
and Johns Hopkins.
I'm Miss Larson.
Those are good hands for
surgery. We can use them here.
All right, Miss Larson.
You must forgive me if I
talk while I'm operating.
I'm so used to lecturing to my students.
Sponge.
Sometimes, I thank my stars
for my scientific education.
It makes me objective.
Broken bone, let's set it.
You know what to do. A baby to be born.
Breach delivery. Forceps.
Only three out of five live.
Live for what?
Don't people die fast enough
without destroying each other?
Is life too long?
Sponge.
No, we mustn't ask that.
That's not scientific.
I wonder how scientific those still
heaps out there on the battlefield feel.
Guns, machines, men, so much rubbish.
What was it in my student days?
Chemically, a man is worth
97 cents. Probably $1.05.
What, with the shortage
of parts and monopoly now,
the dead have risen in value.
Two for $1.98 on Dollar Day.
Doctor, the patient.
We've done all we can for her.
She will die soon of a bullet
wound she received two days ago.
When the baby started to come,
it was too much for her. Tie.
Now where were we in the lecture?
This little fellow we're about
to introduce to the world tonight.
What for him? I don't know.
They forgot to teach me
about spirit somewhere.
Ninety-seven cents worth of
body, but a priceless spirit.
May he be born to live in freedom.
And then Superman, with one
hand, held the streamliner,
and with the other one,
tore down the bridge
and thus saved the
life of his sweetheart.
My translator.
She wants to know if Superman
is so good, why isn't he here?
She would.
Tell her he just landed with
the Marines. We call him Kansas.
Miss Davidson? Yes?
Here's your list. Thanks.
I've assigned your girls.
I'll see you in the morning.
D'Arcy with the Japanese
wounded! What is it?
Olivia.
It's all right. I couldn't do it.
I didn't have the guts to, I suppose.
I couldn't kill even a wounded rat.
There's no reason to worry.
I was just a little silly.
Don't you think it would
be better if I took over?
No, not at all. There's nothing
wrong here. Is there, Olivia?
No.
You don't want anyone
to relieve you now?
No.
Right. I'll see you later.
We soon found out how right
McGregor was about wearing whites.
The next day the quartermaster
gave us some men's coveralls
as well as their shoes and underwear.
It seemed as if no man in the Army
wore anything smaller than size 46.
Look at that, how big this is!
She's in trouble.
Pull. Want some help?
The next couple of
weeks were misleading,
as the pressure from the
enemy got to be routine to us
and the wounded kept pouring
in from the daily engagements.
But the most terrible thing was our
medical supplies were beginning to run low.
You got morphine?
And the same food over and over,
carabao meat, tea and a bit of rice.
Occasionally, we got a mule steak.
It was so stubborn it
stuck in your throat.
Most of us slept in GI
underwear, except Joan,
who had clung desperately
to her black silk nightgown.
Good morning, sunshine.
Good morning, Joan.
Hello. Hi.
You know, she's gonna
wear that black nightgown
right up to the Pearly Gates.
She says it keeps her
morale up, and it does.
You tired? I'm numb.
And do my feet hurt.
If I didn't see mine from time to
time, I wouldn't know I had them.
You know that little Filipino scout
with the abdomen wound's
gonna be all right.
Swell. You're doing a grand job, Livvie.
Who isn't?
Thanks, Davy.
For what?
I can't say it exactly.
But for what you did,
setting me straight, I mean.
You set yourself straight.
You were so right in letting
me fight it out for myself.
I guess if you work long enough
and hard enough, you do forget.
Almost.
You wanna talk about him?
No. No point.
At least I don't want to die
anymore. I have too much to do.
You never did, really.
Yes, I did. There didn't
seem to be anything left.
I think I know how you feel.
Worried about your lieutenant?
I haven't heard a thing
since we left the boat.
Out, everybody, out! Emergency!
Oh, no, you take a nap. I'll
call you later. Come on, girls.
Emergency, Joan. What's up?
It looks like another convoy
of wounded. Come up to surgery.
Right.
I've got an emergency of my own.
There's no use, Colonel. I
can't take any more wounded.
I'm sure we have no more beds.
You've gotta do something, Ma.
I'll run over to the
jungle hospital tomorrow.
Maybe I can steal some there.
Hello, Colonel White. Hello, Joan.
How many empty beds have we?
We have none.
Schwartz, you better get over to
surgery. Yes, Captain McGregor.
Davidson, take over
in my office, will you?
Did I hear the name Davidson? Yes.
Janet, this is my son, Flight
Lieutenant Archie McGregor.
How do you do? Flying
with the infantry now.
How did that happen? We just
got caught with our planes down.
I've heard quite a lot
about you from John Summers.
John? Well, where is he?
In the mess hall. Thank you.
John! John!
Hiya, Davy.
Hello, darling.
Say, feels better without the whiskers.
You finished? Yes.
Did you get some sleep?
Best I've ever had.
You're a perfect sedative.
Well, let's call a taxi.
Where's the nearest nightclub?
No, you're going for a walk.
A walk I've taken so many times,
talking to you even
though you weren't there.
No taxis tonight.
Have you seen Miss Davidson?
Well, she finished her duty about
15 minutes ago and then said...
No, that wasn't her. We
haven't seen her at all.
If you see her, tell her I want
her to report to me immediately.
Yes, Ma.
This? It keeps up my morale.
This is it, the Bataan river.
You wouldn't even know
there's a war going on here.
That was the idea.
Darling, was it terrible up there?
It wasn't pretty.
We're so outnumbered. Sometimes
the Jap losses are 300 to one.
Still they kept pouring them in.
Their dive bombers are the worst.
Up and down every road
all day, all night.
Those Filipino scouts and our poor guys
sleeping on their
rifles and machine guns.
The bravest men I've ever even heard of.
They must be.
They don't give quarter
and they don't ask for any.
I can't figure it out.
Figure what?
Why they do it.
There's something other than
just fighting against the Japs.
These fellows aren't
a bit afraid to die.
That's our air raid signal. Come
on, there's a trench over there.
This is the only nice thing the
Japs have done so far in this war.
Oh, look.
You see, we have nothing but the best.
You know, sometimes I
thought you might forget me.
I tried to.
You did? What for?
Because you troubled me so much.
I'm sorry.
Everything that happens,
everything I do, you're part of.
I can't get you out of my mind.
Don't try.
I'm not going to anymore.
Here's the reconnaissance, I guess.
What are you looking
at me like that for?
I want to remember exactly how you look.
You know, sometimes, I couldn't
even remember the color of your eyes.
Your whole face was hazy.
That's when I look my best.
Thank God I had you to
think about out there.
I still don't think you should go back.
Hey, you know better than that.
I have a feeling that if you go
back, I'll never see you again.
Don't worry. Believe me, I'll
take care of myself for you.
Now promise you won't worry.
I promise. But I'll worry.
That's the all-clear.
Well, I guess we'd better get back.
Irma, what's up?
We've got orders to evacuate.
Are they that close?
I don't know. We've just been
told to clear out of here.
Captain McGregor, how close are they?
Where have you been?
I told you to report.
I wasn't able to get back.
But what I want to know...
Davidson, I discovered you went
out with Lieutenant Summers.
I'm warning you. If there's a
repetition of anything like this,
I shall order you to pack up and
recommend a dishonorable discharge.
As a girl whose people have
been in the Army all their lives,
you wouldn't want that to happen.
No, I wouldn't. Thank you, Captain.
Okay, then we'll forget
the whole incident.
Now, I've orders here
to evacuate the hospital.
We've got to be out by tonight
so we can destroy the base.
The demolition squad will
be here in eight hours
so that's how much time we've got.
After the patients have been evacuated,
you'd better get the surgery out.
I'll take care of that.
What are you doing
here? Come on. Look out!
Joan, they were out in the street.
Stay here and take her.
Listen, I'm gonna beat your brains
out if you don't stay around here.
My sister had... I
don't care what she had.
You stay here. Now, mind.
Hey!
What's the matter with you?
Do you wanna kill us all?
I've got some passengers for you.
But I'm in a hurry. They're in
a hurry, too. Get in there fast.
Here you are. Now, you
take care of your sister.
Take them away, Stevie.
Is this Superman? He'd better be.
Go on! On your way, toots.
On your way!
We've been ordered to evacuate,
we've got to get the
surgery to Little Baguio.
We can't leave yet, there are
more cases I know I can save.
But we've been ordered.
I know but I must have
a little more time.
Just a minute.
All right,
we're ready.
Hey, kids, see you later.
Goodbye.
I think we'd better be
getting along, Lieutenant.
I guess this is about it.
We've heard some rifle fire
not so very far back.
The demolition squad
isn't even here.
Sounds like a Jap
patrol has infiltrated through.
Come on, girls, get in,
hurry up.
I forgot something.
I'll be right back.
No, Joan! Come back here.
You haven't time!
Let's get started.
She'll be back in a minute.
Joan!
- Joan!
- Come on, Joan! Hurry up!
We've gotta get going!
I'm coming.
Hurry up and get in.
Get in the house!
Come on! Hurry up!
Get him in! Close the
door and put the light out.
Davy, I'm sorry, Davy.
Never mind that now.
Get down low, all of you.
He's dead.
Do you think they'll miss us, do you
think they'll send someone for us?
- Of course they will.
- What are we gonna do?
We'll get out
of this somehow.
I know what I'm gonna do.
If somebody doesn't come,
we'd better all kill ourselves.
But why? Somebody's coming,
Davy said somebody's coming.
I was in Nanking. I saw what
happened to the women there.
Keep quiet.
When the Red Cross protested,
the Japanese called it,
"The privilege of serving His
Imperial Majesty's troops."
It's an honor,
an honor you die from.
Stop that nonsense,
do you hear?
I've seen them fight
over a woman like dogs.
Stop it!
Here's a grenade.
Maybe we could get them...
Here, give me that.
If we threw a grenade
and missed,
it would mean sure death for
all of us, we might kill one...
Stop talking about killing.
Now, look. I want you all to stay here.
I'm going out
to start that truck.
As soon as you hear
the motor running,
make a dash for it,
it's our only chance.
Now don't be frightened.
I'm gonna throw this grenade
in the opposite direction
to try to divert
their attention.
Don't go, Davy, don't go. Be quiet.
One, two, three, four.
Livvie! Livvie,
come back here!
Come here!
Livvie!
Olivia!
Goodbye, Davy.
Thanks for everything.
Get back in the surgery!
No, it's our only chance.
We can't get through.
It's one of us or all of us.
Throw it away!
It's too late.
Goodbye, Davy.
Oh, no! Olivia!
Olivia!
Livvie!
Out! Everybody, out! Hurry!
After a nerve-wracking trip
through the jungle,
we arrived at our new base,
the jungle hospital,
which was officially known as
"Hospital Kilometer 163,5".
But it was no hospital at all.
It was just jungle.
The beds were placed
under canvasses,
which kept the sun off
the more serious cases.
But it was so overcrowded
that many of the beds were
just placed out under the trees,
which at least kept them
hidden from the Jap planes.
Nineteen wards were
set up in this way.
Each ward had a capacity
of 200 or 300 patients,
and this was increased
until we had
between 5, 000
and 8, 000 of them.
Most of the patients began
to be not wounded,
but men coming down
with malaria and dysentery.
A little one-cylinder engine
provided the electricity
for the main operating room,
which was just a tent
and we sterilized our instruments
in three large garbage cans,
one with soapy water
and two with boiling water.
We kept washing and rewashing the
dressings after they'd been used.
In our flight from Limay,
Rosemary had received
a nasty gash on the forehead.
But under the healing hands
of Jose,
she escaped
with only a slight scar.
And as the weeks went by,
we were so busy we had no time
to think about
what happened to Olivia
and even Joan seemed to be convinced
eventually that it wasn't her fault.
We were among the first to use
powdered sulphanilamide on open wounds.
It worked wonders.
We called ourselves "the
battling orphans of Bataan.
"No father, no mother,
no Uncle Sam. "
As we wondered
where the reinforcements were.
But even so,
we continued to hope.
Some of us got malaria, too,
fevers of 104 and 105.
But there was
no time for coddling.
The soldiers were
the patients.
How are you, Irma?
I'm all right.
Here, take your quinine.
There isn't time.
Take time.
Come on.
Here, take some water.
Guess I'd better
take some, too.
I don't know which
is the worst.
Davy was in charge
of the jungle hospital
as McGregor had her
headquarters at Little Baguio,
which was another base
about four kilometers away.
She had thrown herself
into her work,
with John constantly
on her mind,
although one never
would have known it.
The only contact
between them
was a little monkey John had
sent one day by a wounded soldier.
He quickly became
the pet of the company.
We called him Tojo because
they looked so much alike.
Give me those.
Hey, did you hear the news?
Supplies and reinforcements.
There's a big convoy on the way.
Friends, I want you to meet
my own private little army.
These guys' names are Joe.
Me Joe, too. Me Joe, too. Hiya, Joe.
Incidentally, these babies are the
sweetest fighters you ever seen in action.
Me Joe, too. Him Joe,
too. Yeah, me Joe, too.
I been over to Cebu and I
got some mail for all of you.
Hey, look what I got
a Sears, Roebuck catalog!
This big box is
for you, Rosemary.
I bet it's a cake. Remember
the cake we had on the boat?
You're the only one
who remembers,
you're the only one
that ate it.
Okay, Joe, see if you can find
yourself some chow. Pronto.
Hello.
Hi.
You big bum!
You always say
what I expect.
Isn't that nice?
Yes.
Say, what are you
doing here anyway?
I got some mail for you.
Thanks, pal.
They're open.
I guess those censors
must've run out of glue.
Kansas, have you been
reading my mail?
Well, I had to read
myself to sleep, didn't I?
You don't want to deprive me
of my sleep, do you?
Anyway, I didn't
read all of them.
Very dull, most of them.
Very dull!
I'm terribly sorry.
Except this Dr. O'Leary. He's
rather a cute guy, ain't he?
He is.
He writes with that
real literary style.
What's he to you?
Well, since you read them,
dear, you ought to know.
If it's a cake,
I hope it's chocolate.
It's a hat.
Who can eat a hat?
I don't care.
It looks good enough to eat.
Say, is there
any mail for me?
Davy, isn't it wonderful?
Well, it's pretty cute.
A little impractical.
No, I mean the news.
What news?
There's a convoy, Davy!
Are you sure?
Who told you?
Kansas just came back
from Cebu with the news.
Yeah, and that hat.
We're going to celebrate.
Davy, could I speak to
you for a minute? Yeah.
I thought you'd like to know Ma
McGregor's son's been wounded, he's here.
Serious?
I haven't seen him.
I was just told he was here.
Thanks, Irma.
It's tough on the old battle
ax. Only boy, isn't he?
Yeah. I think
I'd better phone her.
Davy. Davy.
John.
I told you I'd be back.
For a minute I thought
I was hearing voices.
How long are you
going to be here?
Till morning.
How are you, darling?
I'm all right.
You look pretty tired.
I'm sort of glad there
aren't 25 hours in the day.
The news is wonderful,
though, isn't it?
Wonderful.
I came over with Ma.
How's the boy?
His legs have
been amputated.
Both of them?
There was nothing else
they could do.
Here she is.
He's been calling for you.
How is he?
Hello, Son.
Hello, Mother.
How do you feel?
I'm gonna be all right.
Fine thing to waste
an $18,000 pilot
getting wounded
with the infantry.
A pain, in my toes. I got
a terrible cramp, I guess.
No, not that one, Mother.
The other one.
Oh, darling!
What's the matter?
Hey, what's the matter, Ma?
Lie down, dear.
No.
Lie down. No, I want
to see. I want to...
Ma, my legs.
Where's my legs?
Ma, they promised me.
They've taken away my legs.
Archie, darling.
No. No.
You all right?
Yes.
For a minute, I thought
I was going to be sick.
Hold me, hold me close.
I'm horrible, I know,
but all the time
I just kept thinking of you.
Hey, take it easy.
Nothing's gonna happen to me.
Nurse. Miss Davidson.
Ma.
"O sovereign Lord, who desireth
not the death of a sinner,
"We beseech thee to loose the
spirit of this, thy servant,
"and set him free
from all evil
"that he may rest with all thy
saints in the eternal habitations."
Do you want
a drink of water?
No, thank you, Davy.
Lie down for a moment.
No, it's all over.
He never saw his father,
and his son
will never see him.
He has a child?
Three months old.
It's a pattern that
will go on, I suppose,
until we do make the world
a decent place to live in.
Well, I guess
we can go now.
Thank you, Davy. I'm glad you
called me so I could be here.
I can't say anything, Ma.
What can you say?
What can I say?
I bore a son
and he's dead.
I bore a son, a healthy,
muscular child who was a good son.
It used to break my heart just to
look at him, he was so beautiful.
The handsomest son
in the world
and now I have
no heart to break.
Like his father, he died
for what he knew was right.
He was right, my son
and his father
and this time,
if we don't make it right,
my son and his father and all our
dead will rise up and destroy us.
I'm sending McGregor
to Corregidor,
so I want you and your staff to
report to Little Baguio in the morning,
take over in her place.
Yes, sir.
Do you know if there are any
nurses coming on the convoy?
What convoy?
What convoy? The one we've
been celebrating all day.
There isn't any convoy.
It's been sunk.
There've been
desperate measures taken
to get others through to us,
but only a few small vessels
have succeeded.
Not enough to mean much.
Is it as bad as all that?
MacArthur left tonight.
Left Bataan? He was ordered
off. He's gone to Australia.
But why?
Because he's needed more there
than he is here, I guess.
He didn't want to go.
Well, maybe I better
tell the others.
No, don't do
anything about it.
A good evening
of relaxation might help.
What they don't know
won't hurt them.
No, I suppose not.
Especially when
what they do know does.
Good night, Janet.
Good night, sir.
Little Baguio, which was
another hospital base,
was high up
in the Mariveles mountains.
It had been bombed
some days before we arrived.
The emperor himself
apologized for the bombing.
"So sorry."
When we got there, Davy
made us make a huge cross
with tarpaulins
in front of the wards.
She gave them the benefit of the
doubt, though even she didn't doubt.
Do you think
this will do any good, Davy?
I don't know. Perhaps we're only
providing them with an easier target.
I don't know whether that's
an air raid warning or mess.
Either way,
it's a warning.
Come on, kids,
let's go eat our slop.
What's the matter, Ethel?
I'm all right. Too
much rich food, I guess.
Who's in the children's ward?
Joan. She said she didn't
mind doing my shift.
Come on. You need some
rest. I'll take care of her.
Thanks, Patterson.
I don't know how she does it. Who?
Joan. She doesn't ever
seem to get any sleep.
I've never seen
anybody do so much.
I'm worried about her. Something
seems to be driving her on.
Go over and give her a hand, will
you, Sadie? I'll relieve you later.
That's really hitting
below the belt.
Davy! Davy!
What happened to her?
She fainted.
I've warned her.
Joan. Joan!
No, no, no. You stay down
there now. Sadie'll take over.
Nobody's going to take over
for me. I feel fine now.
Joan, don't.
What you need is some sleep.
That's what's wrong with you.
I can't sleep.
Well, maybe you can try.
I can't, I don't
want to sleep.
All I do is dream
about Livvie.
Now, Joan, you must forget
that. That wasn't your fault.
I know, it was nobody's fault.
But that's not it.
Don't you understand? I've got
to do what she'd have done, too.
But that's not the point.
I know what the point is.
When we joined the Army, I
don't know about the rest of you
but I had a feeling
that we might be in a war
and I don't want to feel when this is
over that maybe I could've done more.
You're just trying
to do too much.
What did we swear to when we joined
the Red Cross, do you remember?
"I solemnly pledge myself
before God
"that I'll devote myself to the
welfare of those committed to my care."
And it didn't say how many
or how much.
Joan, that's the way
we all feel.
Maybe we do a lot
of grousing sometimes,
but that's one of the
privileges we're fighting for.
Now, all I ask you to do is
lie down for an hour, or so
and then you can do
whatever you want.
Thanks. That's all I want
in my own way.
Come on.
Come on, now, you lie
down for a little while.
Thanks, Davy.
I feel better.
You know, that's the first time
in my life I've ever fainted.
Before the war, many's the time
I could've used a good faint,
but the guys I know would've
thought it was phony.
I wasn't taking any chances.
There's my dream hero.
Davy, don't say anything.
No, I won't.
Now what are you doing
down here again, you...
Kansas, what's wrong?
We're getting
the pants beat off us.
You're not quitting,
Kansas?
No, we're just making what's
known as a "strategic withdrawal."
Well, Kansas,
how bad is it?
The whole front line's
collapsed.
That bandage is filthy. Come on
in, Kansas. I'll change it for you.
Look, I know how short
you must be,
but have you got
anything to eat?
Yes, I've got some nice
southern fried monkey for you.
With ketchup?
No, with chili sauce.
I'm sorry to interrupt,
Colonel. What is it, Janet?
I just heard that
the front line's collapsed.
Well, you know there are lots of
rumors, thousands of them going around.
I don't think
this is a rumor.
Well, what do you want?
You've got to get
those girls out.
There's to be
no evacuation in Bataan.
But you've got to, they're
sick, every one of them.
They're only going
through the motions.
Give them a rest
so they can work.
You're doing more for morale
than anything else in this sector.
Just seeing you girls around
is almost enough.
If I were to evacuate you now, can't
you understand the panic would develop.
I know, Colonel... It's the
very thing the Japs would want.
If you leave,
the civilians would leave,
women and children
would clog the roads,
and there's a desperate
battle going on.
I'm sorry.
Of course you're right.
Don't worry, Janet. When the
time comes, I'll get you out.
Otherwise I'd never be
able to look my wife
or any other woman
in the face again.
I don't envy you, Colonel.
Oh, God. No!
Cut them down!
Get them under the bed!
Never mind those apes. Help me
with the children, Kansas.
Sponge.
Rosemary, take cover.
I can do this all right.
I'm not frightened
any longer, Jose.
Come on.
Come over here!
Litters! Litter bearers!
Get him into this ward.
Careful now.
What is it? It's a leg
wound. Lieutenant Summers.
I'll tell Davy.
Lieutenant Summers
has been wounded.
What is it?
A leg wound.
Thank you, Chaplain.
They're machine gunning.
They're strafing.
Beasts, the slimy beasts!
Chaplain.
They finished
the operation for me.
Rosemary!
It's the surgery!
Here, take this.
Davy, come back!
Rosemary!
Don't go in there.
Let it burn.
Your hand, Davy.
Your hand!
How is he, Chee?
His temperature is rising,
and the wound looks bad.
The fragment should be
removed immediately.
There isn't time.
We've been ordered off.
Ordered off?
To Corregidor.
Chee, get him into a truck.
I have to report to the
Colonel, but I'll be right back.
Yes, Davy. Litter.
I got everyone, sir.
We're ready to leave. Good.
Goodbye, Janet.
Aren't you coming?
No, I'm not.
But your orders. New orders
have just come through.
Have we surrendered?
We'll surrender
at 9:00 in the morning.
Oh, no. They haven't cut us off yet?
No, I think it's the demolition
squads blowing up our dumps.
Come on. You better go!
Joan, have you seen Chee?
No, I haven't.
I don't think he's left yet.
You haven't time, Janet.
Janet, do one thing for me, see that
those girls get through to the rock.
Yes, sir. We'll get through. So long.
Good luck.
But before we reached the main
road, everybody heard the news.
Panic developed,
and the roads were jammed.
Normally, it took two hours to get
to Mariveles, that day it took eight
and the Jap reconnaissance
saw what was happening,
so by the time we got there,
it was being bombed
and shelled without mercy.
- Hurry up! Get into the tunnel.
- Davy!
Thank God, you got through!
Did you pass Chee on the road?
No.
Where are the children?
Kansas found a shelter for
them. Get down, everybody!
Hurry up! Get in!
Come on!
Listen, we still have a few
minutes. Keep under cover.
If I'm not back, get down to the wharf
as soon as you hear the boat whistle.
Ling Chee! Ling Chee!
Ling Chee!
I've got to get some sleep. I'm so
bomb-happy, nothing else matters.
Stay here!
But I thought you said
I could have one shot.
Later on. You've been detailed
to watch over your little sister.
Hello.
Hi, Kansas.
I can't believe it. I just
can't believe it! What?
The Marines, they have
landed and been ordered off.
But it's not permanent.
It's not the end of the fight.
Yeah, but imagine it
happening to us, Americans!
All right, all out,
everybody!
We've been out
on our feet before.
Remember Valley Forge? That
was no strawberry festival.
Come on, kids, let's go.
So long. What do you mean, "So long"?
I gotta get the other kids.
Well, I'll help, too, then.
How soon are you pulling out? Now.
Well, I'll get the next boat. There
isn't going to be any next boat.
Well, go ahead, then.
Shove off!
Davy, no!
Davy! Davy!
Do you have John? Yes, in
the tunnel. I have a doctor.
John.
Where are the others?
You better go.
There's plenty of time.
All right, I'm ready.
We'll have to go in for that bomb
fragment. It may become infected.
That's not likely. It's probably
a piece of good American steel.
All right, nurse.
Will you help?
If I can.
Sorry, we have
no anesthetic here. I...
Is it out of order
if we hold hands?
No, go ahead.
It's all right, darling.
It's all right.
I think I've located it. I'll have
another try. Now, this may hurt.
Sounds just like a dentist.
Darling, no matter what happens,
promise me you won't let...
No, no, I won't, dear.
Just hold on, Lieutenant. Try
to think of something else.
I am. Ham and eggs,
hot cakes,
white bread, coffee...
Here it comes now.
Hold on.
It's all right, Doctor. Go
right ahead. He's fainted.
Get in there. Go ahead, kids,
up front, go ahead. Hurry up!
They can't understand a word
you're saying, you know.
I know, but they know
what I'm feeling.
Well, so long. What do you mean,
"So long"? Aren't you coming?
No!
You're gonna be a hero.
Yeah. Okay, you win. Shut your eyes.
What for? Because I'm
gonna kiss you goodbye.
I have a boat hidden
right here.
Take us.
Yes, hurry up. Get in.
Hey, any room?
Sorry, soldier,
but one more would swamp us.
- Can you swim?
- A bit.
Well, hang on and kick.
Thanks, lady.
Are you holding on, soldier?
Still with you, ma'am.
There's old Corregidor
answering them back!
You still with us...
Mind if we take one
minute's rest? My hands...
No, I can use it, too.
Look at those lights! It's so
regular. It seems like a message.
It is a message.
Three dots, three dashes,
three dots.
SOS.
And then Corregidor.
It spelled safety for us,
because everyone called it
the Gibraltar of the Pacific.
Especially so, since the Army
engineers had dug a series of tunnels
down under 400 feet
of solid rock.
The main tunnel
was called Malinta.
This was about
1, 000 feet long,
and in peacetime,
trolleys ran through it.
There were about 40 laterals
off the main tunnel.
The one in which
we were to spend
most of our time was called
the "hospital lateral".
Here, the wounded
were piled up
in double
and triple-decker beds.
Another was our quarters.
There were about 25 nurses
there when we arrived.
With us, the total came to 88 American
plus many more Filipino nurses.
Here, for the first time
in months,
we had a chance to wash
the Japs out of our hair.
For a few days we were even able
to get outside the hospital tunnel
for a little fresh air.
Air raid!
And then they started.
They plastered us
but good, constantly.
As they stepped up
their tempo,
things got tougher
and tougher.
The thunder of the dive
bombers was incessant.
The noise almost
split our eardrums.
The old story. Too little
food, dwindling ammunition,
too many people
and too many wounded.
Gradually, Corregidor felt
like and became a prison.
And though everything
else was giving out,
we thanked God
for the blood plasma
the Red Cross
had supplied us with.
Occasionally between bombings,
we went outside
and took our chances on a
shell rather than suffocation.
We listened hopefully
for news of home,
but the Japs jammed everything except
the commercials advertising food.
It makes a delicious salad
with whatever you have at hand,
pineapple,
strawberries,
or any of the plentiful fruits about us.
Cooled deliciously
in your icebox,
it will bring sunny
California to your home.
Shut that thing off!
What? No dive bombers?
It's not time.
They're still out to lunch.
There's no quinine left.
Well, what are we gonna do?
Nurse, what do you think
we're going to do?
They can take us off.
Why are we here anyway?
Why? Why isn't there any quinine?
Why isn't there any food?
Why aren't there any supplies?
Why are we waiting here
like rats in a cage
waiting for the man to come
and pour scalding water over us?
Why was nothing done? Why?
Take it easy, Davy.
I'll tell you why.
It's our own fault.
Our fault?
What did we do?
Because we believed
we were the world.
That the United States of
America was the whole world.
Those outlandish places:
Bataan, Corregidor, and Mindanao.
Those aren't
American names.
No, they're
just American graveyards.
Well, why don't
they get us off?
They can't get us off.
We've become what they call
"a delaying action."
That's what those 50,000 men
over there were.
They were merely
saving time.
I hope to God the people back
home aren't losing it for us.
Do you remember what the
Chaplain once told us?
It's our present.
We're giving them time.
Well, they're always
on time anyway.
Air raid!
Everybody in the tunnel.
I can't stand it any longer!
I've got to get out of here!
Tony!
Feeling better, Tony?
Much, thanks.
I'm sorry I blew up yesterday. Guess
I had a case of the heebie-jeebies.
Don't worry about it.
Those little outbursts are
about the only cold showers
we get around here.
Maybe you could use one?
What did you think I was doing
yesterday when I shot my mouth off?
I feel better, too.
Hello, Ma.
What you got there?
My grandson.
Oh, he's cute.
He looks just like...
Yes, he does.
Particularly at that age.
That's what I have
to live for.
Janet, can I speak
to you a minute?
What are you doing down here?
We discharged you a week ago.
I thought you knew
I was your permanent patient.
What is it, darling?
I just wanted to say
goodbye for a few days.
What are you talking about?
We sort of made up
a little party,
and we're going down
around Mindanao
to see if we can find
some quinine.
You can't go.
Why not?
Your leg.
You're still too weak.
I'm no weaker
than the rest.
John, you're not well yet.
We'll all be a lot worse
if we don't get some supplies.
When do you have to go?
We leave at 5:00 in the morning.
That's nine long hours
from now.
Ma, I want you to know I'm
going to break a regulation.
Is that something
new with you?
But I'm really going
to smash one this time.
I'm going to get married.
To him?
I'll get Chaplain Frank.
Can we get married here, Ma?
No. I don't know
about this, officially.
Better not in the tunnels.
I know, the bakery. It's still
standing, and they've a light there.
In the meantime,
I'll get dressed.
Dressed into what?
Maybe we could fix up
one of your skirts.
Just so the whole thing
isn't too confusing.
Dear God, we have
none of the things
which are usually used to
solemnize marriage in this one,
except the thing that you
prize most, sincerity of heart.
Amid all the boiling hatred,
both righteous and unrighteous,
two of your servants, Lord,
have found love
and desire to be wed
in Thine eyes.
Help me, Oh, Lord,
to consecrate this marriage.
And now, John,
wilt thou have this woman to thy
wedded wife, to have and to hold?
Wilt thou love her, honor her,
comfort her in sickness and in health?
And forsaking all others, keep
her till death do you part?
I will.
Janet, wilt thou have this man
to thy wedded husband?
To have and to hold?
I will.
I then pronounce you
man and wife.
God bless you both.
That's where you kiss, kids.
Okay, break it up.
Here's your wedding present.
It's the best I could do,
a bottle of wine.
Where did you get that?
The General. I told him
I needed to get drunk,
and he was so surprised
he gave it to me.
Some peanut butter
and bread.
It's a wonderful present, Ma.
This bit of jade.
It's some 2,000 years old.
Keep it.
For there are three wishes
that go with it,
good luck, long life
and an abundance of children.
Thank you, Chee.
Thanks for everything.
I have nothing to offer
except a bit of gum.
We'll take it.
Now, go ahead
and have your honeymoon.
Thank you.
Thank you, Chaplain.
God bless you both.
Good night.
Peanut butter.
I wonder if...
No, leave them alone.
Come with me, and I'll see
if I can dig some up for you.
Good.
I'm not going to eat anymore.
I'm going to save some.
Not me. This isn't
the kind of wedding cake
you put under your pillow
and sleep on.
The stars look
like street lights.
They are.
Haven't you ever been
to the Rainbow Room before?
That's the street below us.
I guess marrying you has changed
my perspective completely.
It's probably the wine.
I thought you were going to take me
to a dingy little French restaurant.
This is pretty classy.
Holy cats! You remember
everything I say.
I take you very seriously.
What is it, darling?
Did I ever tell you
about my place in the country?
No.
You know, I don't know
anything about you really.
I don't even know
if you have a middle name.
I have. It's Matathias.
Why?
An uncle. He left me this little
farm I was telling you about.
It's quite worth it.
Is it?
Yes, and you'd love it.
The time will come when you and
I will go out on a summer evening
when the grass is fresh
and the clouds white,
as if they'd just been washed.
The earth's warm and still,
and time passes quietly.
Everything's simple.
Just you and me and the kids.
Sons?
Daughters.
They're more decorative.
Let's get out of here
and go home.
Home!
I remember
a poet somewhere.
He said, "Home
is the place where
"when you have to go there,
they have to take you in."
You want to know something?
What?
I'm not afraid any longer.
Darling.
Darling, it's time to get up.
It's time to get up
and go to work.
You've only got
five minutes.
Fine time to go to sleep,
on our honeymoon.
It was a wonderful
honeymoon.
Here. Finish that up.
No, you.
Go ahead.
As my grandmother used to say,
"It'll warm your stomach up."
To you, honey.
To us?
Here's your breakfast.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Summers.
Yes, sir?
Just want to wish you
good luck.
Thank you, sir.
So long, Lieutenant.
So long, Davy.
Good luck, Chee.
Take care of him.
Don't worry, I will.
Wait for me here.
I'll be back.
I'll be right here.
What you doing?
This radio's
on the blink again.
What would you like better
than anything else in the world?
A tomato. I'd give
my left knee for a tomato.
Tomato and some Flying Fortresses,
wouldn't that make a lovely salad?
Yeah.
Why'd you ask me, Kansas?
Well, I got something for you.
Chocolate. Oh, gee,
Kansas, that's swell of you.
Where'd you get it?
Well, a raiding pile of Japs
tried to land last night,
and I got me a couple of them
and on one of them...
Kansas, how could you do
a thing like that to me?
I can't figure you dames out.
Chocolate is chocolate.
You're positively
disgusting!
And don't fiddle with that,
you'll get a shock.
Who me?
I never get shocked.
Look, don't you ever say
"don't" to me again.
There, you see?
Attention,
you fools on Corregidor.
This is the son of heaven's
birthday, our emperor Hirohito.
We wish you
to help us celebrate.
You will not object,
I am sure,
for you are the objector.
Banzai!
Air raid! Air raid!
Never a dull moment. This is
like living on a bull's-eye.
That was the worst
pasting we ever got.
I think they must have hit every
inch of the island that day.
Then suddenly, like magic, late
in the afternoon, it stopped
when they all went off to get drunk
to celebrate their god, Hirohito.
This quiet,
it's like the tropics you read
about in romance magazines.
They'll celebrate
all night long.
I hope they have the biggest
hangover the world has ever known.
Four thousand 100's,
$400,000.
I guess this is what
they call hot money.
Four thousand 20's.
$80,000.
Say, what goes on here?
They're destroying money.
Destroying money? Why, that's
the silliest thing I ever heard.
We ought to notify
the authorities or something.
They are the authorities. They're
from the finance department.
First time I ever even
saw enough money to burn.
All the nurses are wanted
at the mess hall.
Not for food.
Don't tell me.
No, right away.
Four thousand 20's.
That's $80,000.
Attention, everybody, please.
Colonel Clark has
something to tell you.
Thank you, Captain.
At ease.
This is a very
serious occasion.
It's not known how much longer
Corregidor can hold out.
I have here orders
from headquarters.
You nurses are to be
evacuated tonight to Australia.
You'll meet in front of the main
hospital tunnel at 9:00 tonight.
These orders are secret.
I want you to know
that in the name of General
Wainwright and myself,
there are no words high enough
to praise you all.
Good luck.
Captain.
Well look, Ma, couldn't another
one of the girls go in my place?
I haven't any family and...
Ma, I'd just as soon...
These are official orders!
I know what
you're all thinking,
but the entire nurse corps
has been ordered off.
You girls just happen
to be the first.
You can pack one handbag
or your musette, that's all.
There's just
one other thing.
These orders must be kept
secret, you're to tell no one.
I'll see you later.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Just cleaning house.
Irma.
Yeah?
Do you know anybody that could
take a letter out to the States?
It's to my mother.
Yes, I think I know someone.
I'll give it to him.
Thanks, pal.
I've got to get some fresh
air. I'll see you kids around.
Here, George. I found another
fountain pen, so you can have this one.
Thanks, Joanie.
Here, Joe. You've had your
eye on this for some time.
Okay, Joe.
I know we're short of
things to read here,
and I found some old
love letters of mine.
I'll just put them here, so you
have a kind of circulating library.
They're pretty funny. Maybe
they'll give you some laughs.
Who's there?
It's me, Kansas.
Hi, kid.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Sure.
Keep your mind on the gun, Chuck. Okay.
We've been
ordered off, Kansas.
I know. It's all over
the rock already.
Well, I came
to say goodbye.
Well, I'm glad
you did. Bye.
If you don't wait for me,
I'll break your neck.
Be sure you don't
break yours.
Give me a loan of your
handkerchief, will you?
And stop your sniffling!
Why don't you?
You know I can't help it.
It's a habit with me.
Well, I can't, either.
When you get back,
you should get some real ones.
I used to get mine
at the five-and-dimes.
Big red ones.
Remember? Bandanas.
Jeepers, what a place those five-and-dimes
are, everything in them, huh?
Yeah.
You might send me a dozen
of them when you get back.
Where, Kansas?
Here, where do you think? I'll
be here till Tokyo freezes over.
I suppose
if we were to surrender,
that you'd be
dumb enough not to.
Yeah, I'd be dumb that way.
Oh, Kansas!
We should have been doing
more of this in the campaign.
You and your wanting
to be pals.
I thought you were just
another guy on the make.
I was.
Gee, I'm glad I met up
with you, Kansas.
The pleasure's
been all mine.
You big blimp.
Well, so long, kid.
I'll be seeing you.
Goodbye and be careful,
don't get killed.
Who, me?
I never get killed.
There you are, O'Doul.
Well, I guess
that's everybody.
Good luck to you,
children, all of you.
Goodbye, Davy.
I'm not going.
You're not what? I'm not
going. I never intended to.
You heard the orders.
Now, I don't want any funny
business, get in that boat.
No.
Do you realize every
moment of stalling here
means that those planes
in the harbor are in danger?
That's not our artillery!
I can't go. I promised I'd be here
when he got back, he asked me to.
Now please, Ma.
I order you to go!
I won't take orders.
I'm not in the Army anymore.
When I married, I broke
regulations. It meant I was out.
You can't make me go.
Stop talking like
a hysterical schoolgirl.
I'm going to be right here
when he gets back.
He won't be back.
How do you know?
Tell me, how do you know?
There's been
no word at all.
They've considered them
officially lost for a week.
You're lying. You know
you're just saying...
Would I lie about that, Davy?
Would I?
No, you wouldn't.
But I know he's still alive.
He's out there somewhere.
I can't go, I can't!
Janet, if he's alive,
he'll find you!
Let me go,
I'm not going!
Down, everybody!
Davy!
Was she hit?
No, she's just stunned.
Get her in the boat!
She wasn't like the rest
of us. She never gave way.
But now everything
snapped at once.
When we got her on board the
plane, she never spoke again.
Maybe we should have
left her on Corregidor.
What's happened would have
happened some way or another.
Thank you.
Thank you all very much.
Now I think maybe I can try to
make her speak, to hear, at least.
Miss Davidson, we're
almost home. Do you hear me?
We're almost home.
Chair, nurse.
I have a letter for you.
"My darling, I'm writing this
from Mindanao.
"We leave in the morning
for an unknown destination.
"I write with no
so-called premonitions.
"As a matter of fact, I'm writing
this in a pleasant little bar
"on the outskirts.
"I've ordered two daiquiris,
"one for you
and one for me.
"I miss you.
I miss you all the time.
"It was such a short time,
wasn't it?
"And yet,
I remember every second of it.
"From the moment
you washed my back,
"and I could use
a good bath right now,
"till your face faded from view
in the darkness when I left.
"I think about you
all the time,
"and wish things
were different.
"Things will be different.
"I know that now because
there is good in this war,
"much as I hate it.
"This is not just
a war of soldiers.
"You weren't soldiers
in the strict sense.
"You were just kids from all
walks of life. All kinds of people.
"There's something new in
this war, something good.
"You could see it,
this new thing,
"even in their tired, hungry faces
as they took courage one from another.
"This is not a people's war,
because civilians also get killed."
"It's the people's war because
they have taken it over now
"and are going to win it
and end it with a purpose.
"To live like men with dignity in
freedom. This is the good I've found.
"There's a small voice
whispering around the earth.
"And the people are beginning
to talk across their boundaries.
"This voice will grow in volume,
until it thunders all over the world.
"It's what you said, and what
Jose said and what Rosemary felt,
"and Olivia.
"It's the rage
that made Kansas cry.
"It says,
'This is our war now,
"and this time
it will be our peace."
"I'm proud,
proud to have known you,
"proud to have
received your love.
"Already I've had a complete,
rich life in three short months.
"I'm enclosing a deed to that
little farm I told you about.
"It's now in your name.
I'll wait for you there.
"Or if you're there first,
wait for me.
"Thank you. Thank you,
my darling, for my life.
"Thank you for everything.
"Your devoted, and this is the
first time I've ever written this,
"your devoted husband."
John.