After five dark, anxious years
the sun breaks through .
The Dakota bringing home
Queen Wilhelmina . . .
. . . lands in a free country.
lt is a stirring moment
as the door opens.
Resolute and confident,
the Queen sets foot on Dutch soil .
After a warm welcome
by civilian and military a uthorities. . .
. . . Her Majesty lea ves the airport.
A jubilant nation greets
its So vereign Queen .
Her triumphant return
to The Hague .
Highlight of these first weeks
of liberation .
Without pomp, accompanied
by a single aid . . .
. . . Her Majesty passes
the cheering crowds.
Noordeinde Palace awaits her
at the end of the route .
Once more flying
the Dutch flag .
Children greet her with flowers.
As Queen Wilhelmina arrives
at her palace . . .
. . .the realization that the House
of Orange is home again . . .
. . .fills the hearts
of the Dutch people with jo y.
SOLDl ER OF ORANGE
Get inside freshmen !
Come with me !
Climb!
Hello , l'm Jack Ten Brink, sir.
Prick, you mean .
- Prick, sir.
- Up, Prick!
What do you think of Hitler?
Filthy e xhibitionist!
He builds good motorwa ys.
Are you for or against the sod?
Hitler's a bloody bastard .
Let him go !
Piss off!
Ma y l introduce myself?
Jack Ten Brink.
You might know the name .
My father's on the Council .
Two more shirkers.
l'm Jack Ten Brink.
- Ale x.
- Eric.
- Were the y hard on you?
- l've been here a while .
Someone made me sa y
Hitler is a bastard .
- Must ha ve been a Jew.
- Can we sta y here this long?
The y ha ve three weeks.
Enough time for a game of cards.
Freshmen to the dining room !
On your butts!
- Jesus, dinner time !
- The Council .
Everybody rise !
Down on the floor!
On your belly,
prick to the floor!
And sta y down .
Sit, sit, sit. Everybody!
And eat, eat, eat!
Bring them here .
Filthy shirkers!
You lot are in for it!
- Shirking , were you?
- No , sir.
- Perhaps you'd rather go home?
- l'd like to sta y, sir.
- Would you?
- Yes, sir.
Sing for us.
Hum along .
Off ke y!
And again .
Off ke y.
Again .
Mr. President,
this is a gra ve matter.
He's bleeding .
Hi , Eric.
Can you drink this yet?
Of course .
Hi , Esther.
l'll sta y put if you don't mind .
Eight stitches.
- Unbelie vable .
- What happened?
lt's a long story.
- We were . . .
- Not now, Eric.
- We're off to pla y tennis.
- No .
Tell us.
Well , it was the first e vening . . .
- Hello , ma'am .
- Good morning .
. . . puts it on my head
and starts hitting it.
Wham , wham . . .
. . . and l kept singing .
Eric, you ha ve a visitor.
The President.
Don't get up, Lanshof.
Your head after all .
Just a few stitches.
Telling your young friends
about university life?
- Well . . .
- l'd like a chat with you , Lanshof.
Please sit down , sir.
You were off!
Are you coming?
My apologies for last night.
lt was uncalled for.
lt was nothing . . .
lt was my fa ult. ls that beer?
Would you like some?
l intend to look after you .
There's a vacant room
at my place . Want it?
Yes, thank you .
Your health , Lanshof.
Your health , sir.
- Call me Gus in the future .
- Right, sir.
Prick.
Thanks.
- Good , l'll copy them .
- You should attend lectures.
Mr. Particular.
You sound like my mother.
- l missed you toda y.
- l was bo xing .
- Eric's at home .
- l don't blame him .
Shall we go up for a drink?
Let's surprise him .
On my shoulders.
Nico? Or are you afraid?
No .
Come along with us.
How's the sherry?
Disgusting .
- l've got something stronger.
- Nice .
Give us a hand .
Ale x!
Pull !
- Gus might like a drink too .
- Call him , will you?
Gus!
Who's slinking about?
Professor Ten Brink.
l don't slink.
l was at Professor Teilders.
A prelim .
l passed !
A present. . .
. . .from my old man .
- That's a good one .
- A Leica .
German .
Ex cellent make .
- Want some?
- No , coffee . l'm in training .
l'll order some .
- One coffee !
- Hello , chaps.
- A drink?
- Please , one .
Take my chair.
- How's your lo ve life?
- l can't keep the landlady off me .
- Good looking?
- A figure . . .
One coffee .
For this gentleman , Greta .
We'll take a photo .
Mo ve closer together.
l'm going to Germany for
a few weeks. Like to come?
No wa y. Trainloads of Jews
arrive here e very da y.
- l don't like swimming upstream .
- Cut it out, will you?
Don't mo ve .
Sit still . Watch the birdie .
lt's coming !
As the nun said to the bishop.
Glass, glass!
Four, three . . .
. . .two , one . . .
Your health !
- Eric's good .
- You're better.
- Yes, at tennis.
- You should've pla yed .
Guard duty.
Shut up!
Gus is a poor loser.
War!
- Jesus, war.
- Oh , the English . . .
We'll be neutral , as usual .
Don't be so damn stupid .
- What's with him?
- He's a Jew.
- l ne ver noticed .
- Prick.
- What was the score?
- Deuce .
Come on , Nico .
Turn off the radio , Robby.
Pencil !
Look, he can write .
Ma y 9th . . .
. . . 1 940.
What's the time?
- How's the army?
- A lot of wimps.
We could beat the Papuans.
Nothing will happen .
Do you mind?
Yes. A spot of war
would be quite e x citing .
Gentlemen , it's time .
Robby!
We must be off.
Nico will take us to the station .
Mr. Particular.
Coming with us?
She wants to sta y.
We'll get her home . Right, Eric?
- No problem .
- Well , Es?
l'd like to sta y a while .
We'll show you out.
See you ne xt week.
Let's get going , Robby!
Off we go !
Bye , darling .
Why aren't you in the army?
Bad e yes. Everything's
fuzzy at a distance .
But close up l see
e verything , perfectly.
Robby and l are getting
engaged ne xt year.
Congratulations.
- Lucky de vil .
- Who?
Both of you .
Want to dance?
Airplanes.
Are the y ours?
We don't ha ve that many.
Jerries.
Going to England .
Stop!
What do you want?
- We've come to volunteer.
- You must be mad !
- The y're Jerries in disguise .
- We're Dutch .
Ha ve them sa y 'sch' .
Germans can't pronounce it.
Sche veningen . Sche veningen !
Schele , schoonmoeder,
Sche veningen .
Let them through .
Eric, here .
We've come to volunteer.
Come back in ten da ys.
Officials!
We want to help.
Come back in ten da ys.
Ten da ys is quite reasonable .
- lt'll be o ver by then !
- The last war lasted 4 years.
Come back in ten da ys.
Come on .
Come on , Eric.
- See you in ten da ys!
- Or sooner!
Been to a party, ha ve you?
Yes, a party.
With schnapps and women?
Let's pa y and go .
A tip e ven . Decent of them .
A fifteen minute rest!
Lieutenant.
- My folks live here , ma y l visit them?
- Go ahead .
Come in .
- You can shoot the lot of them .
- The damn traitors.
Dirty fascist.
- Hello , Mother.
- Hello , Son .
Bunch of idiots.
Just beca use your mother's German .
Stupid . Stupid !
The y think the y can defeat Germany.
The y'll pa y when we get out.
The lot of them .
And how.
- You don't ha ve it so bad .
- We'll see .
Did you hear about the Queen?
She fled to England .
And you ha ve to fight.
German paratroopers!
Behind those wooden shacks.
- What's up?
- Paratroopers.
Look, there .
Check it out.
Co ver us.
Wounded .
Jesus, what are you up to?
There's a war on .
So what?
April fool !
That's Dirk.
There's a madhouse nearby.
l fooled you ! April fool !
Attention ! Salute !
What's going on?
False alarm about paratroopers,
General .
The war is o ver.
Rotterdam's been flattened .
Thousands of casualties.
We've surrendered .
Surrendered . . .
- But it just started .
- lt's o ver.
The politicians and collaborators
betra yed us.
But it's not our fa ult.
Holland can be proud of its army.
Men , l thank you !
Now what?
Line up!
l n position .
Put it down .
l n the water.
Go !
Come back, that's dangerous.
Do you want some more sand?
- Jerry slut.
- Mommy's bo y.
You're attracting attention .
lt's free .
There's Eric.
Outboard motor.
Gasoline .
Put some in .
- The forecast?
- Calm sea .
Good , or l'll puke my guts out.
Sure stinks.
Hope the Jerries don't smell it.
Screw it on tight.
Stand still .
He y, bastards!
Fine little boat.
Sherry from Pa , cheese from
my mother for the trip.
- Got the charts?
- Couldn't get them .
You said you would .
There's only one England
and it's there .
No , it's there .
Why aren't you coming?
Someone's got to do
the dirty work here .
You're just afraid .
Let's lea ve it at that then .
Your health .
Celebrating something?
Ale x!
- How about a swim?
- Good idea .
Ha ven't seen much of you lately.
At home . My parents
ha ve had a tough time .
Who hasn't?
Call in some time .
Ale x, l like you , but visiting
your parents is a bit much .
l'll see you around .
That's all we needed .
- The dirty fascist.
- Ale x is a fine fellow.
- l smell petrol .
- What time do we lea ve?
The beach will be deserted
in an hour.
l n two da ys we'll be in London .
Knock on wood .
- lt's a sturdy boat.
- One leak and you've had it.
What can go wrong?
The petrol !
Let's get out of here !
Hello , Robby.
How about that Robby?
Hangs the wash for his mother.
You'll ask the English
to come and get me?
- ls that it?
- l n code .
- Really?
- Yes!
l can hardly signal :
'Will London come for Mr. Lanshof?'
lsn't it dangerous?
lf l keep it brief. . .
. . .the Jerries can't locate it.
We hope .
- A potentiometer.
- Want to measure my potency?
Good morning .
l'll make contact.
- How do the y know it's you?
- l use a code .
l alwa ys begin with L-O-V-E .
Lo ve .
Guess why.
Go !
She's on to something .
lt stopped .
- Well?
- You can go .
- As a courier.
- Meaning?
Getting stuff from my group across.
That's fantastic.
When?
l'll let you know.
l magine , me helping you !
Not a big area .
Ne xt time he transmits. . .
. . . he hangs.
You seem to be very happy.
Did you tell Eric
about our engagement?
That's why you're
called LOVE .
- lt's a tennis term .
- What are you talking about?
lt's the best news
l've heard in years.
Let me know.
UNlVERSlTY EX CLUDE S JEWS
Read Volk en Vaderland .
Volk en Vaderland !
He y, look. . .
UNlVERSlTY EX CLUDE S JEWS
Read Volk en Vaderland !
- Here , we'll give you a hand .
- Thanks, l can manage .
We're here to help one another.
We've got nothing against Jews.
That's fine , thank you .
No , we're not finished .
Do you ha ve accident insurance?
You shouldn't ha ve
got in our wa y.
Just an accident. . .
Send the bill to Hitler.
What are you staring at?
lt was an accident.
Cheer up.
lt could happen to anyone .
Get those things out
of the water.
- l suppose you're a Jew too?
- Yes!
l'll kill you , you bastard .
l'll kill you .
Don't be so stupid !
l nside !
You'll get yourself in trouble .
- l won't let them do it.
- Go out the back wa y.
All the Jewish professors
ha ve to lea ve the university.
Yes, l heard .
First the professors,
then the students.
All the Jews will be
in the Polish salt mines soon .
Student bo xing champ
and nowhere to go .
You can go to England
instead of me .
How? When?
You'll hear from me .
Robby's e xpecting me .
What's John doing here?
He's taking my place .
What kind of madness is this?
Robby, the Jerries
don't like Jews.
l could've sent Esther.
Yes, you could ha ve .
Come on , we can't sta y here .
There it is.
To the boat!
We'll meet again .
- l n London .
- Hurry up!
See that you get this
to London .
Jerries!
Robby!
l'm stiff from the long trip.
The young one first.
Come along .
- Good morning .
- Morning .
- l'm sure you'd like some coffee .
- Smells good .
Uncuff him .
- Here you are .
- Thank you .
Would you like a cup too?
You seem surprised .
We've pro vided for you .
Sugar?
Don't l get anything with it?
With your second cup.
Egyptian cigarettes. . .
. . . but quite good . Take one , please .
l suppose you were e xpecting
English ones this morning .
Mr. Weinberg , you realize . . .
. . .we want some information from you .
l know nothing .
l was going to England to fight.
The war is o ver.
- Not for me .
- Yes, it is.
People died toda y.
Remain silent and more will die .
l don't know any of them .
Too bad .
Then l'll see . . .
. . . if those papers are dry yet.
Up!
The English don't send planes
for no reason .
Who or what did the y come for?
l know nothing .
You know nothing , do you?
You're tough , aren't you?
Bo x er's muscles.
Turn him round .
Do you ha ve muscles
on your kidne ys?
Enough , Breitner!
We don't work like that.
Ha ve you gone mad?
My dear bo y, l'm sorry.
Sit down .
Drink the rest of your coffee .
Drink.
Just tell me what you know.
Toda y's affair didn't happen
by accident.
l wonder who let the cat
out of the bag .
The information . . .
. . . could only ha ve come
from London .
Van der Zanden .
Do you know this person?
Van der Zanden . . .
He's our contact in London .
That's not true .
lt's an open secret.
lt's all for nothing , anywa y.
l suggest you talk.
Talk!
That's your trick.
Butter up a person . . .
. . . and then beat him .
l know nothing .
Breitner will continue
working on your case .
Speak up! Who was there?
Tell me their names!
l don't know, l don't know.
Sorry about that.
Tell me what happened .
We tried to get John o ver
to England , by plane .
The big time .
- But it went wrong , totally.
- What a pity.
The y got John .
LONDON BOMBl NG RE S UME S
lf he talks, l'll hang .
Amateurs.
Smirking , well-fed prick.
l'll hang .
So you come to me?
Gus, l need a place to hide .
Catch .
Ke y. . .
. . .to my front door.
Sta y as long as you like .
RUSSlAN FRONT COLLAPSE S
His lordship.
Prick.
You'll be safe at my place .
Hello .
Any around?
Up there .
lt's teeming with them .
The y're migrating .
A bea utiful sight.
l'll try to get a bit closer.
Bye .
ls that him?
- And he's not after the birds.
- Thanks.
My mone y.
You're a good patriot.
- ls that all?
- lt's the rate .
Well , if it's the rate . . .
Two beers.
You look pleased with yourself.
Will you take these to Nico?
Sure .
Photos of German bunkers.
What are you up to?
Be more careful .
Scared? Your health .
Your health .
Let me go ! Too late !
Take them awa y.
Let me go !
lt's nothing to do with me .
- The y must ha ve followed me .
- Nonsense .
- Shit. Why me?
- Risky business.
l hope l don't talk.
- Try to escape .
- How?
No talking .
Stop!
'The traitor is Van der Zanden
in London'
Come with me .
On toilet paper!
- You're Lanshof?
- Yes.
'Yes, sir.'
l'll be courteous when you are .
Did you write this?
Yes, sir.
What did you write it with?
With shit, sir.
You must be mad .
This is no wa y
to apply for release .
Perhaps l didn't ha ve a pencil .
Ne xt time l'll ha ve you shot.
You ma y go .
Where?
Home .
- You can't just let him go .
- l'm not.
He'll be followed .
Bait? A lure .
Exactly.
He might try to get in touch
with the resistance .
- Then you'll ha ve new guests.
- We ha ve the space .
Here , or in the dunes.
l'll lea ve it to you ,
Obersturmfuhrer. Goodbye .
Hello . Come in .
Let me take your coat.
- lt's a wonder you're home .
- That's for sure .
l stopped by a few times,
but you were alwa ys out.
- l'm back now.
- Yes, so l see .
Sit down .
lt's a bit of a mess.
l was working .
- Tea?
- No , l don't ha ve much time .
No need .
Robby is back.
Has he been awa y?
You know quite well .
He told me about the plane .
We can stop pretending now.
Yes. Where is he?
l n The Hague .
He wants to talk to you .
Come here .
See that man?
He tails me where ver l go .
Security Police .
- Robby wants to see you .
- l mpossible .
The y'd grab him too .
Ale x!
A friend of yours?
Yes, and so what?
Bloody bastards.
And the y call themselves Dutchmen .
How ha ve you been?
lt was touch and go .
That vet had quite a go at me
on the kitchen table .
Decent chap, though .
My transmitter is operating again .
Join us, Eric.
John is dead .
l've lost the taste for it.
You're scared .
We were betra yed by someone
called Van der Zanden .
- How do you know?
- John told me .
And he's in London .
We ha ve to pass that on , Eric.
Go ahead .
- You really disappoint me .
- Too bad .
- l'm being watched .
- Probably.
l'm a threat to e veryone .
We'll decide that.
l'll decide for myself.
Did you see Robby?
Then we can open the curtains again .
Fine .
That chap must be wondering . . .
Let him .
Ex citing?
lt's a bo y's book.
l'll be off then .
The curtains were a good idea .
The things you think of.
Here , your shoes.
Are you sure about this?
l want it to happen .
Sir. . .
Do you know where
Victoria Street is?
lf you turn left there . . .
. . .you come to a square . . .
. . .then you turn right. . .
Come along .
Good da y.
My compliments.
lt wasn't easy to find you .
- What do you mean?
- Your transmitter.
lt's on the garden shed there , isn't it?
- Do you smoke?
- No .
Do you mind if l do?
Thank you .
l ha ve a proposition .
Would you work for us in the future?
No !
Look.
Your fiance l belie ve?
l saw her at Lanshof's.
She looks Jewish .
Jewish . She'll go to
a Polish labor camp.
Not so good for the health .
Many people die there .
Let's go .
Won't you reconsider working for us?
Graduated?
Yes.
Congratulations, Eric!
You're the first from our year.
- l thought it would be you .
- l can't get finished .
Better hurry.
The university is closing .
Damn Jerries.
l've heard some
odd stories about you .
The resistance?
All o ver and done with .
l'm happy to hear it, Eric.
We must consider the future .
Let's go for a drink.
Degrees will count again
after the war.
There's Robby's fiance !
How nice .
l graduated !
Congratulations.
Flowers for you .
Come for a drink with us.
Wait for me .
There the y are .
Two gins. One with lemon .
So , a lawyer. . .
What are your plans?
- Take a holida y.
- On the Riviera .
That's impossible with the war on .
Jack, you're so wonderfully naive .
- Where are you going?
- To the bathroom .
Nico .
The y're after you .
You're telling me .
Still want to go to England?
Are you joking?
There's a Swiss ship sailing
tomorrow. The y'll take you .
ls it safe?
lt's a chance .
Nice of you .
You're putting us in danger.
Here are your papers.
Your name's Jean de Kuyper.
Here .
Shake it.
We didn't rent this bathroom .
l'm disappearing for a bit.