ISTANBUL UNDER OCCUPATION
THE NAVY OF THE ALLIED FORCES
IN THE BOSPHORUS
MUS TAFA KEMAL RETURNING
FROM THE SYRIAN FRONT
This looks very serious Sir.
What's all this?
They'll go as they came!
Anything else I can get for you Sir?
I'm looking for this man?
Do you know him?
I don't, but I'll ask.
Pass.
Mee too.
I raise you.
Hey guys.
Either play like men here
or else if you cheat again.
I'll trash the place.
Come on young man.
Where did you get that from?
I stake all.
Money talks here mate.
How can you bet with
only that much money?
All right.
Count this too.
My gun can buy anything here.
You scoundrels. Get up, up!
Go over there!
Do I look like a kid to you?
Hey, what's going on?
This is a robbery.
At least, it's an obvious robbery, Nico!
Hold your cigarette case!
You will not get away this Knock Out Ali.
You will pay for this.
If we meet again, then Nico.
Shit. Fuck off.
Sorry my Sali.
I'm sorry.
Come on go on, go on now ok ok
continue not important continue.
There he is.
Bismillah, bismillah.
Sorry. Brits after me.
If they ask point there, OK?
Take this. Thanks.
OK.
Went that way.
THE RESIDENCE OF THE FORMER GRAND VIZIER Our country is at an
important crossroads. Tevfik Pasha getting a vote of confidence...
...from the parliament will only
accelerate the enemy occupation.
You're right Pasha.
We're well aware of it.
Ever since I came to Istanbul...
...l've been talking to deputy members.
My aides are also lobbying actively.
According to general opinion, it looks difficult
for Tevfik Pasha to get votes of confidence.
It's extremely important for the
liberation of our country that you...
...become Grand Vizier again.
Frankly, my being Grand Vizier again
is not sufficient Pasha.
It is also a necessity that you become
War Minister in my cabinet...
...for the liberation of our country.
I will carry out any duty given to me with
utmost care and attention if it helps Pasha.
Now, with your permission, I have
to check the local situation.
May God help the people of this country.
This has been a nuisance for you.
Ohm... What a wonderful smell...
Otherwise at Selimiye everyday in the
mess it's tasteless.
Awful.
With your permission.
You see?
We have bothered yourwife
by talking shop.
That's bad.
Oh God... What's going on?
Who do you think you are?
Ssshht...
Come on wake up.
Oh...
Pull yourself together ha?
Now speak up, who are you? Speak.
Okay... My name's Jerar.
I'm the son of a Smyrnian
family emigrated from France.
I am a seaman, but I do acrobatics as well.
What do you want you bugger?
Huh?
You were stealing a boat.
I am a guard.
Tell the truth.
You were following me.
Okay. Look I'm the guard here.
As forfollowing you...
Ahh!
That's right I was someone called Guro
from the French...
Consulate is looking for you.
Guro?
Yes!
It seems this Guro has
got a score to settle.
He'll pay a lot in return for you.
Ok then...
I have a bit of business in Kalamis.
After that we'll go...
...and you will get your money, ok?
Eh no. No way. We all know
there must be an alternative.
I'll earn my money some otherway.
You are brave, man!
Let me come with you? Was it Kalamis?
OK? Let's make amends.
So be it. If you insist.
Ahh. You hit hard.
A yearlng Inslde me to dlstant lands...
Endless seas to you and to our love.
Away from a mlsty past,
I belong only to you.
May your love stay
In the waves of my heart.
In my endless dreams, I always see you.
Away from a mlsty past,
I belong only to you.
May your love stay
In the waves of my heart.
In my endless dreams,
I always see you.
What happened?
Nothing... it's nothing!
Yes! Something did happen.
And how!
Years passed but you still think of that
scoundrel!
...I know it!
I can feel it Just right here!
Now go down... Our guest is waiting.
GRAND ASSEMBLY
The result?
Unfortunately against us Pasha!
Gentlemen, The liberation will
not start in Istanbul.
Now we need to look at another option.
ISTANBUL MARCH 1919
In my home town I left my love...
Couldn't see her for flve years or more.
Couldn't come back from the blg flght.
No falth left to embrace her tlght!
I was surprised of course.
Mevlit?!
Where do these demons come from?
Where are you Mevlit?
Did you run away too when the
ships came to the Bosphorus, ha?
Fear cannot save you.
Istanbul will be ours soon.
Thrace too.
Keep calm... It's Okay.
Mevlit where are you?
Stop it. I'm here.
What do you want?
Well, well, well...
Tahtacizade Ali!
Are you back in Istanbul?
Aaa ok...
...once the navy disbanded
you lost your job.
What the hell is your problem
with Ottomans?
What will you gain
when the enemy comes to Istanbul?
They are your enemy not ours.
Ottomans are over.
Yes, now the big Greek era begins.
Are they?
Istanbul will soon be Constantinople.
You bastard. Now fuck off.
Bugger off!
Ali your beloved Defne too is under
a 100 kilo Greek with a hairy belly...
...moaning and groaning.
Sorry men.
Burgazli this should cover some damage.
Well done lad!
Goodbye! Sorry again!
Knock out Ali!
Wow!
If I tried acrobatics I'd be dead?
No man. I was in a clash again. Look at us?
British soldiers are all around...
...I suppose you're not aware?
The Brits are all over.
Am I not?
Because of them I couldn't eat today.
No shops open nothing...
That's why I went fishing for dinner.
Anyway, you weren't around.
I thought something happened.
Is there a time when nothing happens?
How is it?
Can we cross over?
As always.
I spent many years
and of course a lot of effort.
My God!
As an officer I travelled all over
the Middle East but I never drank...
...coffee as delicious as this.
There's no hurry.
We are still here.
What are these buggers doing?
Have the bastards started
the occupation here?
Thank you...
Catch him.
Shut up!
Damn it! It's not loaded! Run.
Jerar!
Where the hell are you?
Oh, God. What an acrobat?!
You go Ali... I'll follow.
You bastard!
This is enough, be quick more's coming!
Ok, ok.
Come on man.
Untie it.
Down!
Son of a bitch!
Wow! Looks like I owe you my life.
Come on man! There are more.
Come on.
Give it.
Did you see her?
May God be with you all!
You too.
How are you?
Not good master...
They put us in wagons in
Eskiþehir then left us here.
We've been dumped, master.
Where are you from?
Sivas.
You?
Van!
Erzurum!
You take this for yourway back home.
It was already a gift.
Thank you Sir...
Take it all, share it with yourfriends!
Thanks sir!
Not at all.
May God help you!
You too Sir.
What did you say bastard?
You're on Ottoman soil.
Is it right that you speak English here?
Identity...
Haaa... Identity!
Identity!
Hold on, where is it?
Yes, I'll give you an Ottoman one.
What's up? Can't you sleep again?
Normal! Nowadays things
happened that bothered you.
Of course... Someone who
falls in love can't sleep.
What do you think I am?
Yes, I might have
loved him in the past, but now I will not...
...do anything to stain my honor.
I'm yourwife, whether I like it or not.
Oh God! What's the hussy thrown now!
Enough cursing þsmail Bey!
This isn't a Tatavla brothel!
Once he leaves here, he
will go straight there.
No, I won't doctor...
Come on Nadya throw the dice...
Oh my God, For God's sake! Let's play!
It's the middle of the night.
The café's closed, go.
Osman bey knows me.
Open the door.
At this hour even for the Vizier,
I cannot disturb him. Go away!
I said 'open up' bastard!
Fuck of you!
Did a bomb drop then?
What is it?
Get me Osman Bey!
Bismillah.
Oi you! What's going on? What a racket?
Are you trying to destroy my business?
Someone barged in.
We'll throw'm out.
You go and rest Chief!
Who is he?
Who is this brave lad entering my
place beating my men single handed?
Ali! Knock Out Ali!
My son!
He is wounded.
Hurry, take him up... Kelle help.
Nadya take care of him.
Is this the guy you had trouble with?
Yes sir!
I am close to you Knock Out Ali.
Agh...
Be patient my lad.
Almost finished.
Wow, look at this.
Its like a boar bullet.
Doktor!
Yes...
Agh...
Now bandage... done. Aghhh.
You've knocked out this strong man.
This took long.
His endurance so far is a miracle.
Come on guys be quick.
They might get here.
Take Ali out by the back door.
I can get up.
No, not like that.
He can bleed internally.
Ok, ok. We'll think of something.
Damn it.
Oh God...
Osman bey, Brits are at the door.
Go keep them busy.
Ok.
Let's go downstairs.
Nadya you stay here.
We're closed closed.
We are closed man, closed now,
there are no customer.
The British mules don't understand.
Does any of you speak their language?
Open it!
You bastards. How dare you try to
enterwithout getting permission?
Shit... We're caught!
I'm fine.
What's going on here?
Remember that British general
I had the other day.
Yeah!
I kept his clothes, see, we used them.
Ali learned English quickly!
Well done my boy Keep on learning.
Kelle... Get the carriage.
We are going to Emirgan...
Who is this handsome man, Osman Bey?
This is Knock Out Ali. The bravest man
I know. You should have been...
...there the day I met him Nadya.
Surrender Osman. Otherwise we will
hang you here!
Hey, get off him.
Do you think it's right to attack people?
If anyone asks who did this,
tell them Knock Out Ali!
Then we came to Tophane.
I said let's work together he said no.
He didn't take my offer.
I insisted as a "loan"
he took 500 and left.
Rest.
He is tired... He won't wake up
for a long time...
I need this man Nadya.
Whatever you do make him well.
I found him at the right time.
I have many good men around but
this man is different Nadya.
It's like fire and gunpowder
together Osman Bey!
Hmm... Get him attached you ask whatever
you want. Now good-bye!
THE RAID OF THE PALIAMENTAND
THE ARRES TOF THE PARTYMEMBERS
I'm looking for him.
He is Ali, Tahtacizade Knock Out Ali...
Find this man for me... but alive.
If you manage...
...this will be yours.
These are... deputies... Asking for help.
We're in a difficult position.
We must get away.
We need you Osman Bey...
The British because of Armenians have
given orders to arrest MPs.
We have to go to Anatolia.
If not our end is the Bekiraga Squad.
I get it... Tonight a cart, with animal
skins, will set out for Bursa.
If you'll go with the skins,
I can send you.
May God be with you!
Are you ready to go?
We are sir.
Let's find a place to hide you.
Why does Osman Bey take money from them?
They're in a difficult position.
Is there anotherway?
He has men working for him,
there are so many orphans...
...under his care. Anyone with problems
runs to him. Money is necessary.
Don't forget his sick daughter in Italy, being
treated. He sends her lots of money.
Plus these men are rich men. Union and
Progress members. Running to Anatolia.
No need for money there.
Would they choose life, or money?
Yes, I suppose you're right...
Come on, sit down. Don't tire yourself.
Let me check yourwound.
Why do you run away like this?
From Mr. Guro!
Who is that?
Mr. Guro, my sports teacher at the Academy.
Would one run away from a teacher?
When necessary, he would!
Good... Keep your guard up. Nice punches.
You may even become...
...a world champion but... pass your French
exams or they'll kick you out.
Hey Guro... why don't I teach him French?
Who was Kolet?
Guro's young wife!
Oh!
Well, did she manage to teach you?
And How!
The neck...
The arm...
The leg...
Eye.
Eya.
Hand.
Hend.
Breast.
I know that!
Lips.
Again?
Yes! Of course!
Besides French Kolet taught me the
intricacies of the art of...
...love making. But one day...
Guro came home early...
Oh Shit.
I see...
You ran away to escape from him.
Why did you run away from the Navy?
In order to protect me from Guro,
I was assigned to the battleship Yavuz.
GERMAN WARSHIP GOEBEN
WHICH WAS GIVEN TO TURKISH FLEET
The Germans were in command of the ship.
We sailed to the Black Sea.
Before we knew what happened
Germans bombed Odessa...
That night they started celebrating.
Why don't you celebrate?
We don't see a reason to.
We had a victory today. We are allies.
You will have fun!
We bombed a city without warning.
Do you call this victory?
Shut up. I command you.
You cannot command me!
Stupid!
How dare he speak like this
and to an officer?
You bastard!
Don't get involved sir.
My trip is over sir.
When that was over I came back to þstanbul
and learned that...
...Guro is still here and looking for me.
God, this man really hates you.
Of course, he does...
Later I heard Kolet had hung herself.
And Guro is still trying to take revenge.
Jesus! You caused the woman
to commit suicide.
No...
You whore!
If you knew Kolet, you would know
she wouldn't do that.
She was full of life and
I was certainly not herfirst lover.
Okay, but you talk as if you were there.
How do you know? Were you there?
During investigations they found
Kolet's skull cracked.
Actually, her neck...
...should have been broken. Guro talked to
his powerful friends and got away with it.
So... first he killed his wife
now he is after me...
Don't worry, he can't find you here.
As long as it's obvious nothing frightens me.
Gube.
What's that?
Lip.
Yorgo!
What is it?
Who is he?
What about him?
A man called Guro at the French Consulate
is looking for him.
What will he do?
He will pay a lot if we take him alive.
Welcome. Is there a problem?
No no... No problem at all...
How can I trouble a beautiful woman
like you?
I wanted to see you.
My wife has been ill for years.
Your husband as well.
We have same problems.
Well, Dimitri Bey is not at home. And I have
to go to see a sick friend. So excuse me.
Ah, it's not important. I'll come again...
I'm sure you know a man who is
abroad feels lonely.
BRITISH COMMINICATION ROOM
MAJOR BENNET'S OFFICE
Welcome Kara Necati.
Understood?
Yes sir!
Damn it. I wish we could print this photo much
larger so that...
...British bastards see the bloody Greeks
Black Sea murders.
Kill the Turks!
Let's kill those bastards who spill
the innocents' blood. Off we go!
Pasha, as I saw in Friday's procession,
the Sultan looks hopeless.
This nation now needs a new leader.
My army in Erzurum is ready.
I will move my 20th corps to Ankara.
My soldiers are also ready.
Kazim, Ali Fuat! A strong army is vital.
However, our soldiers...
...are fighting for years. They are tired.
I heard that there'll be an opening...
for an Army Inspector up north.
By using this I hope to go to Anatolia.
Let's not forget, if we cannot convince this
great nation, we cannot succeed.
I mean first we must get strength
from all our people.
Gentlemen, Istanbul is under British
occupation for some time.
Therefore a number of secret organizations
sprang up. Among them we have...
...our organised police department as well as
those set up by minorities.
Organizations are not only official but also
underground. The Dardanelles hero...
...Mustafa Kemal Pasha is going to
Samsun as army inspector.
There will be secret meetings these days
where he will be staying.
Both occupying forces and minority
organizations may cause interference.
Osman Bey, that's your province.
You will ensure security in that area.
I will sir.
OFFICE OF THE DEFENCE MINISTRY You Ask for the
much authority Kemal Pasha... They won't accept.
Let us send our official request as we want,
if they don't approve, we can talk later...
Don't forget, a visa needs to be obtained
from the British Liaison Office.
I'm aware Pasha!
In that case you have some future plans.
General staff officers always make plans!
Wonderful man, eh good!
Is this enough?
Ok, enough.
Here comes Osman bey.
Ali! Come boy...
I will talk to you.
Kelle you go and get ready.
All right Osman bey.
Ali, you were here for a long time.
You don't know what's going on.
Nowadays, British scoundrels
increased pressure.
May be you are aware. We haven't been idle.
We have an important duty tonight.
We will protect Mustafa
Kemal's house with friends.
I need you tonight Ali.
Anything you say.
I owe you my life.
Kelle you take your men go to that corner.
Iskelet you go to the other corner.
Keep you eyes peeled.
No problem Osman Bey!
Welcome gentlemen.
Please take a seat.
There is an important subject
I want to share with you.
Ali I fear there is something wrong.
Let's go and check.
This way.
What happened? Is there a problem?
Why did you whistle?
No sir. I swear I didn't.
Very strange...
May all go well brother.
Thank you.
I'm looking for an address.
How can I help?
I found the key. Ok.
We left the house unguarded sir,
let's go back.
Don't leave here.
Gentlemen. As you know I was appointed
as inspector to the 9th Army.
And you all as my quarter officers
shall stay at my side.
What happened to the guards?
Maybe they went in.
Thh... I don't like this...
You wait here. I'll go.
Hey, be careful.
Don't worry...
Damn it.
The government in otherwords Palace
has assigned us the following.
Greeks in the Black Sea region
have been rebelling for some time.
The Turks living in that region have quite
rightly reacted and fought back against this.
Our duty is to restrain and hold back
the locals who are already giving...
Greeks a taste of their own medicine.
This assignment is a cover.
However it's duty.
But...
This mission...
It's only a way of getting to Anatolia
easily and with authority.
Gentlemen our country
is waiting for liberation.
What was that?
The noise came from upstairs.
Where man?
Jumped into the garden, hurry!
My God we're done for.
What happened here?
He fell down and killed himself.
This is Kara Necati.
Bloody British informer.
Who are you young man?
I'm one of Osman Bey's men...
The Patriotic movement Sir.
Well done boy.
Maybe you just changed
the fate of a nation!
This country will be freed by
brave men like you.
You will understand later.
Thank you Pasha!
Get rid of him. Leave no traces!
What have you done?
The Motherfucker.
Was apparently working
with the informer.
I wiped him out not to expose
you, me and the others.
But you shot him before he talked.
Never mind. The patrol will find him
and think t'was a street fight.
Kelle and Arab obviously cleared off.
Let us clear off too
before we get caught.
Come.
Kelle Who are they?
Don't know Osman bey.
Union and Progress members Osman bey,
they need to get away.
Have a nice day.
You too.
Welcome gentlemen.
Your'e welcome.
I'm afraid I can't help you. I am
being watched I cannot help you run away.
Nemrut Pasha cut off all roads,
they'll hang anyone they see.
We will pay what you want.
It is not about money Hodja.
I can't do miracles that's all.
You can't leave us like this.
I have to help my family.
You can't hand us over to them Osman bey.
Don't you understand Hodja?
All the roads are guarded by police.
At least take us to the other side.
I can take you to Tuzla.
Would that help?
Sure... Wouldn't it?
If they try to stop us later... God help us!
In that case, Come on let's go!
Don't be mad Ali.
I wouldn't want to oppose you, Osman Bey.
So please let us go.
With your permission.
As you like.
If you get caught, don't give me away.
We still have a lot to do here.
May God be with you.
You too Ali.
Don't worry, I'll be back.
What's going on?
Look here Dimitri.
We know you have weapons.
You will give us some.
We need fifty rifles and a thousand bullets...
Leave me alone you idiot.
What makes you so sure
that I've got weapons?
Don't bother your heart won't stand it.
The British officer is
always at your house.
What are you talking about?
Your precious collection?
Don't play with me.
Look here.
I sell weapons to Russians.
I have no weapons for you.
You will have my friend.
You'll see.
Just as the Armenian guerillas did,
obviously you want to have the Turks and...
...Greeks at each others throats.
We are all Ottomans.
Exactly what harm have they done to us?
You're talking too much, give us weapons.
Orwe'll be back!
Let's go...
Sir are you ok?
Hop hop!
What are you doing man?
You almost gave us a heart attack!
I was just being cautious when
I saw you with others.
I was watching you.
This time it's different Jerar.
We need to take them to Tuzla.
What for?
They are running away from the Brits.
One condition for my boat...
What's that?
I come too.
Jerar!
Don't argue man.
You never know what happens at sea.
I can't leave you alone.
Block head!
I wonderwho?
Ok then take this!
What's this?
This time it is not forfun man.
We have to be cautious.
Come on.
Come on Gentlemen,
may God be with us.
Enver Pasha ran to Germany but by
dealing with Lenin he will soon come back...
...with a Caucasian army to start
the "War of Independence" in Anatolia.
What a noble man you are.
Why don't you come with us!
No master. Believe me
I'm certainly not noble.
I am not good for anything anymore.
There isn't a front
I haven't fought on in Palestine.
We had no food, we fried
grasshoppers, ate tree bark.
You know Cemal Pasha's channel expedition.
I was there. We swam in a pool of blood.
That bastard Lawrence...
I still have the scar he made.
I mean there is no battle left
I haven't fought in.
We couldn't beat the enemy when Germans
were with us, how do you think we will now?
Look young boy, maybe we lost one war but
this doesn't mean Turks will give up.
Nowadays we have a navy minister,
Hamidiye hero Rauf bey...
...east front commander Karabekir Pasha,
Ali Fuat and Mustafa Kemal Pasha.
God... well gentlemen it's the end.
From here on you're on your own.
Come on have a safe trip.
May God help you.
No man I don't want money.
Its for the country.
May God be on your side.
Thank you.
Thank you too.
It's a trap! Lay down.
Ali!
Jerar!
Jerar...
Are you ok?
I'm fine. Ahhhh... fine.
Ok ok. Take care of the others.
Press on, press on ok press on.
Are you ok?
- I'm fine, I'm fine ok.
- Come on.
Are you ok man?
Serving our country was not meant to be.
This belt is full of gold.
Please use it for the
salvation of our Khalif.
May God bless you!
Ok man, don't exhaust yourself.
Let's go.
Ok, get a move on.
Hang on mate.
I'll take you to a doctor soon.
I'm okay, very good.
Stinging a bit, that's all.
Your hand. Press this press.
Ah...
Hang on ok.
I'm done with this.
There is one bullet left. You might need it.
Don't talk man, shut up,
you are bleeding badly.
Mate...
I am shot for the first time.
Never mind.
I'm proud to be dying for my country.
Braveman my braveman, hang on, hang on.
I can't believe this Jerar.
It was definitely an ambush.
I wonderwho told them.
Osman Bey? Nadya? Who?
We're living through a time when anyone
could be prepared to stab you in the back.
You're right mate, you are right.
We are close, hang on we are close.
Jerar? Jerar! Jerar?
My brother!
You were a true sailor, man.
Sleep peacefully where you belong.
Paper... Paper, the Dardanelles hero
Mustafa Kemal Pasha has landed in Samsun.
More power to your elbow!
Ali, my lad! Welcome.
Thank you man. I'm looking for Osman.
Have you seen him?
No... He wasn't here for a long time,
no one saw or heard of him.
Interesting.
Have you also been hiding away?
We get our energy that way.
Very well.
I'll wash my hands and
face to clear my head!
You prepare me a nice strong raki.
Right away!
Hey Turk! Give us some fish, raki...
Meze meze... haydari...
some meze as well... haydari...
Eat shit you bastards...
Hurry up...
Osmanli is finished!
No one has the strength to bring that down.
Speak my braveman, speak...
Please speak now.
Where did you find this gold?
Look how many days you've been beaten.
Make your life easierfor.
Miþon?
Yes...
Shut up... What am I to tell them.
If I speak, they'll hang me anyway.
They're starting again.
Bastard.
My God. Are you so stubborn?
Give them a name you
fool and save yourself.
Dimitri.
Dimitri?
I got the gold from Dimitri.
A merchant in Kadiköy.
Good choice man good choice.
What did he say?
Never mind. You did well.
Shit they are coming.
Don't look scared?
Shut up, shut up.
Why are they silent?
Be careful, he knows Turkish.
It's not the soldier's fault.
I thought you'd heard but obviously not.
My husband Dimitri passed
away a few days ago.
You mean he died?
Unfortunately...
...the day he gave you some
work, that same day he died.
May God have mercy on him.
Unfortunately.
I'm sorry.
They brought you here by mistake but
this is important.
Do you know this man?
Yes! He's Ömer, he worked
for my late husband.
Where did you find the gold?
My husband gave the gold to him.
I was there.
That's bad.
Because its already been registered.
We can't give it back.
The gold is not important.
Accept it as a donation If you wish I can return
the gold to you later over dinner perhaps.
Really it's not important.
Let us get you out of here immediately.
Thank you.
How could you give the gold?
Ali, I beg you.
I never stopped thinking about
you, every day, every hour...
You cannot know how it feels.
I was told you died in the war.
I was forced to marry a Greek.
I prayed for your soul for years.
You are alive.
Standing right here but
worried about a handful of gold.
My dear one.
Before this dream is over lets go away.
Ok ok but... I made a promise.
That gold... was the last request...
...of a man who died for his country. I was
going to buy weapons to send to Anatolia.
You were going to buy weapons?
Yes...
Dimitri left a bargeful of weapons behind Ali!
I don't get it.
Dimitri was trading in illegal arms.
Actually the cellar is full of gunpowder...
Take those guns, give them to whoever you
want. In place of gold.
You will be keeping your promise too.
Then, I beg you, let's run away immediately.
From now on I don't everwant anything to
remind me of my days without you.
Ayoung Greek is here, wants to see you.
Bring him.
What do you want?
I heard you were looking for someone
called Knock Out Ali.
Yes, do you know where he is?
This Knock Out Ali has a married lover.
I have seen him roaming around...
...the girl's house. I have been watching
the house for some time but Ali is not around.
However, there is a British Colonel
visiting very often. Named Scott...
...from the Selimiye barracks.
You may get information from him.
Look this is enough for
us to start a new life.
I sent Andon and Maria back home.
Let us go somewhere else too.
Don't worry we will go.
Don't leave the house until I come.
Ali...
...be careful.
Stop puffing up like a toad
and spit out your poison... Speak up...
There is nothing to say Osman Bey!
I couldn't get them to the other side.
I'm embarassed.
I was not surprised at all that you were
the only survivor out of the eight.
Since you know the exact details of the trip,
You have been following events Osman Bey...
Thank God, we have eyes and ears
everywhere. News travel fast here...
The gold in the belt? What about it?
Left in Mufti's belt orwhat?
Now you are coming to me to
get information from me.
I don't like it Ali, this is not yourway.
Forgive me Osman Bey...
Our country is in such a state...
Mufti told me to buy weapons with gold.
I bought them.
Now I have to get them to Anatolia.
Will you help me...
...get the weapons to Anatolia then?
I'm surprised you are getting involved in
these affairs... Wasn't it you...
...who said 'is it up to us to save this country?
I must admit, the last request of old Mufti
confused me Osman Bey.
Our country is invaded.
Mustafa Kemal went to Anatolia...
...with his friends as the 9th army inspector.
I cannot forget Kemal Pasha's words...
...of that night. Obviously Pasha
is after a fight.
Yes... Then read this.
Mustafa Kemal issued a statement...
"I swear on everything I consider sacred
that togetherwith our people...
...I will strive to the end with all my
being, for the independence of our country".
You see... I am aware
of developments too...
...as soon as possible.
I will do what is necessary.
Now... You get the weapons to me...
This way you will carry out
Mufti's last request.
Bloody whore!
Ahhhhhhhhhhh.
Nadya!
Ali... be careful...
What did you do man?
Why did you do it?
Stop Ali...
Let's hearwhat this is all about...
Stop stop spy... She was a spy!
She was sending wireless messages.
I caught her in time!
Come on guys, let's get out of here.
We have no idea who
she was in contact with.
I still think you shouldn't have shot her!
Agh...
I'll have her buried in a Christian cemetery.
Yes yes yes Mr. Ali.
I see you got used to guns.
No no no!
If you want your love alive,
you have to see me first.
Look Guro, let's deal man to man.
You want me.
First untie her then we can talk.
She is innocent.
I killed an innocent
person because of you.
You made me a murderer.
I can kill another one.
Are you ok?
We have to leave now...
Come here!
Ali here...
...run!
Gunpowder. Hold this.
Run to the door.
Run!
Are you ok?
Let's go...
Defne...
Nothing should separate us ever again...
Even death.
My beauty, I have to deliver those weapons.
You know that.
Look at me!
After the delivery... I promise you...
We will go somewhere,
I say I promise you!
Come on, they are waiting for us.
You will take the boat to Kurna bay
with Andon!
How come your alive again?
You were shot too but you're still alive,
why shouldn't I be?
You scoundrel!
Speak up, tell me who
brought you back to life?
Your mother!
If you don't want to die,
speak up or I'll shoot!
You asked for this, you bloody fool...
Where the hell have you been Ali!
I was beginning to worry.
Thank you, Kelle.
I put the weapons in a safe place.
Somewhere along Kurnaköy bay.
Good, I'll give you two men so you
can go and deliver the weapons.
That's not the way it's going to be
Osman Bey. Only you and I will go...
...no one else will come with us.
Why's that?
I'll tell you the reason on the way.
Okay then, have it yourway...
Usually I have my men follow me
like a shadow but...
...this time, if you insist, it'll be only
me and my revolver...
Kelle... I have something to do...
You take care of the place...
Ok, Osman Bey!
You certainly like taking precautions.
I like it...
If you only had a little
more patriotism in you...
...we could have done a lot together.
There are weaknesses in your
organization Osman Bey!
What are you getting at?
In my opinion Nadya wasn't the traitor!
Don't beat about the bush lad,
tell me what's on your mind...
Do you remember that night when you shot
and killed þskelet Musa near...
...Mustafa Kemal Pasha's chalet?
Well I saw him at a market place...
I killed him a little while ago. In otherwords,
he didn't die that night when you shot him.
Bugger me! You saw him fall to the ground
like a bag of shit didn't you?
Let's suppose we were wrong to
think he was dead then.
What would you say to the fact that
he drew his gun as soon as he saw me?
I really think someone is playing
games with you Osman Bey.
Please don't tell me that Nadya did this too...
Çopur Talat or Çengel could have done it...
Now can you understand why
I wanted you to work with me?!
It's very hard to find trustworthy
men these days.
The boat's there...
Osman, help me!
Osman bey, help me!
It's the end Ali...
Osman bey ha?
Hands up!
Vay Cukurcesmeli vay!
Osman Bey there are no weapons on
this boat. He's tricked us again.
Our British friends will be very annoyed!
Hosst!
Speak up Osman Bey, speak up...
Why are you doing this?
Ali... I know you don't owe me anything
but please do me one last favour.
In the name of God... You shot me Ali!
Let everyone think the British shot me.
Nobody knows I'm a traitor.
But I don't understand?
Ahh...
Why did you do this?
The British blackmailed me.
They found out I was a member
of the police organization.
They have taken my sick daughter
and wife hostage in Italy.
They didn't leave me any other option.
I was forced to help them.
I'm sorry Ali, I blamed so many people.
Shoot me and finish me off.
Was Nadya part of your cover?
She realised what was going on.
She was going to talk!
Come on, please shoot me Ali,
the British will be here soon...
Alright, I'll help you but first, tell me who
I should deliver these weapons to.
Go to Sile immediately... There's a midwife
at the healty center, called Müzeyyen.
She is a real patriot.
Give the weapons to her.
Go Ali, don't waste any more time!
Ok. Take this then and
do what you have to do!
There is only one bullet in it anyway.
Ali!
Shit, damned bastards.
Run away Ali, run away.
Very good, give me a kiss.
May God bless you.
Control the fever every 2 hours.
Welcome...
Good to meet you.
What can I do for you?
Midwife Müzeyyen, yes?
Yes!
Well we... we won't take up
too much of your time.
Come in please.
We have a bargeful of weapons.
We want to send them to Anatolia.
Who told you to come to me?
Cukurcesmeli sacrificed his life
today trying to protect the weapons.
Unfortunately we lost him during
a fight with the British!
Where are the weapons now?
On a boat anchored close to the shore.
But how much do you want
for these weapons?
Nothing!
Good! Let's get to work, we must unload
the weapons right away...
But wait a moment... I'd like to know exactly
where these weapons are going?
To Mustafa Kemal Pasha, Ali Bey...
You know me?
My lieutenant!
Welcome to our group!
That's that then... We can be on
ourway too can't we?
What's wrong?
I don't know how to say this to you...
I've been thinking while watching...
...these mothers, grandparents carring
hundreds of kilos on their backs...
Look at Lieutenant Recep...
He's already lost a leg to the war and yet
he's still struggling for...
...the freedom of his country.
...lt makes me feel there is something
more important than just us, Defne...
Surely our country...
What are you saying Ali!
Defne... I can't be that selfish and
go off to Vienna now. Now I understand.
This country will be freed by
brave men like you.
This Country needs one of us.
I have to join the war
efforts in anatolia.
Ali!
Please forgive me Defne!
I love you and always will.
So will I!
Give that to me. Take this.
Come on. Come on.
Ali.