This film is based on true events.
Surinam 1921
Okay boys, let it go.
- Not yet.
Do you want to cross the entire ocean?
- Fine with me.
What would you do in Holland?
- Study.
That 'll be the day.
Now let go, you little monkeys.
Stop now or l' ll sink your boat.
Let's row.
l' ll swim.
That's too far.
- So what?
Waldemar, come back!
Are you crazy?
He's crazy.
Dad!
Waldemar!
- Where are you going?
Brasil
-Why?
Can't make a living here.
- What about us?
You'll manage.
You're my son.
Where's mom?
-Inside.
Daddy is gone.
You swam in the river again!
Many kids have drowned there.
l' ll never drown, mamma.
The water is my friend.
My ocean swimmer.
Seven years later.
I will miss you all .
-l' ll miss you too.
Waldemar, this is
mother's dearest wish.
Yes, but five years is a long time.
Don't secretly marry my sister.
- She has to say yes first.
l' ll be back for the wedding.
You can come back after graduating.
I won't let you down.
If you screw up, we'll
canceI your allowance.
Don't open it before
you get on board.
Don't forget us!
And say hello to our cousin.
Goedereede, Holland.
Mom! It 's finished.
Why does daddy go to church twice?
He wants to be close
to God twice as often.
''My God...''
It 's a disgrace, on
the day of our dear Lord.
Our councilman isn't
blessed with such a wife.
Why don't they wave back?
They're not allowed.
- Says who?
Says God.
- Are you allowed?
I can do anything I want.
Why are you so quiet?
We're not quiet at all .
It 's so quiet I can
hear my own thoughts.
Do you want me to
read from the bible ?
l' d rather not.
The meat is getting cold .
I know a passage...
about a wife who has
to obey her husband.
Do you want me to shut up?
- Yes!
Now it's quiet again.
We're not quiet at all .
It's a riot here. Isn't it, Willem?
One big riot.
Or shall I talk to the water jug?
Hey, jug, did you lose your tongue?
I didn't lose my tongue.
I swallowed daddy's.
That way I can talk even more.
Mamma is funny.
- Daddy doesn't think so.
Can't you ever be normal
Look who's talking.
''My God, how I love you!
Tonight in the shed...''
The Hague
You have to go back.
I can't. The love is gone.
- That happens in every marriage.
What if every woman ran away?
-l' m not 'every woman'.
We warned you for Willem.
- Yes you did.
He abducted you
from that monastery!
Those nuns still pray for you.
Keeps them off the street.
-lmpertinent as ever.
Mom, please, I need a home.
You can't stay here.
And we can't lend you any money.
Why don't you say something?
Why should l
You do most of the talking.
No, Rika does.
She's just like you.
Mom, it's only temporary.
We warned her enough.
She has to take care of herseIf now.
Rika, wait!
What will you do now?
Find a home for me and my children.
- David Millar.
-Waldemar Nods.
When I arrived, all I had
was a stuffed crocodile
and a bow and arrow.
Quite a sight, wasn't it?
In Holland you're
always quite a sight.
- Do you know who I am?
- Yes, you're my cousin.
That's what they say.
Actually, l' m your half-brother.
- My half-brother?
-A bastard son of your father.
So having all his
mistresses pays off.
Why did you come here?
To fulfill my dream
of a better future.
So you're a dreamer.
But you'll find out.
-Find out what?
How it is over here.
-Is it that bad?
Nothing but poverty
for people like us.
You're late.
-The traffic was busy.
The children have gone to bed.
Show your cousin the guest room.
l'll heat up your dinners.
What will you study?
-Business administration.
Not aircraft construction?
- Not everybody is
flying high, Christine.
Is that what you do?
l'm financial director at
Royal Dutch Airlines.
Your Surinam certificates
won't be sufficient here.
You can't apply for our University.
You have to take
the entrance course.
The entrance course?
Eighty percent of your kind faiIs .
The question he often raised was
whether a mathematical axiom...
... could be applied to
philosophical matters.
- Black Peter, Black Peter!
- Shut up! That's not a reaI one.
Where can he go?
He has nobody else.
You said he'd be gone soon!
Send him away!
-I can't. He's my cousin.
Cousin, brother... it doesn't matter.
I want him out of here.
How lovely , Bertha!
It's so great you're all here.
Do we have to live here?
I want to go home.
So the women are working
while the men are playing?
How dare you ruin that ball ?
Everything in my
garden is my property.
Have you gone mad?
Remove that immediately !
Everything in your garden
is your property, isn't it?
What are you looking at?
l'm looking for this address.
They have a room for rent.
That's me.
But we're busy moving in.
l'm sorry. Maybe I can
come back some other time.
Or is the room no
longer available ?
No.
You can say yes.
Why would I say yes
if it's not yet rented?
It 's bed and board. And I also
do the cleaning and the laundry.
Come here, kids.
Would you mind if Mr.
Nods became our boarder?
What's a boarder?
-You'll find out.
My name is Waldemar.
Nice to meet you.
Do you wash yourself?
- Better than you.
Is daddy living all alone now?
He's got his job and
Jans takes care of him.
He can't be very lonely .
This is your new school
With the priests.
Not you, you're going
to the girls school.
Let me guess...
With nuns?
Bye.
Come in.
Here's your supper.
-Thank you.
Do you like your room?
-It 's very nice.
Children not too noisy?
-Not at all .
Food alright?
- Couldn't be better.
We hardly see you.
What do you do during the day?
I study, or I go to the beach.
How about joining us
for dinner tomorrow?
I don't want to bother anybody.
In Surinam it doesn't
rain as often as here.
But when it rains,
it rains really hard.
We call it sibibusi.
That's when the snakes come from
the soil to swim in the puddles.
Do you know what we
always used to do?
Well?
- Don't you like potatoes?
- In Surinam we always eat rice.
Rice?
I heard you're living
together with a black one.
So what?
-It 's my house.
- The rent gets paid, doesn't it?
- Everybody's talking about it.
- I hadn't noticed.
- It happens behind your back.
I don't care about everything
that happens behind my back.
I don't want his kind here.
Mr. Nods is a decent man.
He goes to college.
And he happens to be my boarder.
I don't want this crap.
You could at least try.
I said I don't want this crap!
Wim, don't be so rude!
Wim, what's the matter?
I miss dad.
But you'll visit him for Christmas.
He was so sad when we left him.
It 's all very sad.
It's a pity it has to be this way.
Yes.
I bought you something.
For me?
A Christmas present.
I thought... You love music so much.
It's beautiful
Wouldn't you like to stay a while ?
The house is so quiet
without the children.
You should get out more.
You're always in the house.
I never know where to go.
Or who to visit.
I really missed this.
Me too.
Mrs. van de Lans.
I couldn't stand it in the house.
Try and find another room.
Your presence creates tension.
For the kids?
- No, for me.
- I thought you needed the money.
I'll take another tenant.
A woman.
l'm sorry about your present.
l'll give it back to you.
Mrs. van der Lans?
You can call me Rika.
Rika...
Shall we do something fun?
- It's snowing.
- Yes.
I only know this from pictures.
You can't join us.
- Dirty nigger!
Come on, throw!
Bullseye!
Don't you miss home?
Not right now.
And when you're not in my bed?
I miss the sun.
And the river.
No people ?
My mother. But she's dead.
And Hilda...
Hilda?
Your fiancé?
No, she's my sister.
The eldest.
My younger sister is named Lilly.
Do you have sisters?
- Plenty of them.
And brothers too.
But besides Marcel I
haven't seen them in years.
Why not?
They banned me when
I married Willem.
Don't you miss Willem?
Not right now.
Can I have jam?
- Mom, are you alright?
- Yes, l'm fine.
How long?
About eight weeks.
Have you got the money?
Well , let's get this over with.
You will have to lie down.
A letter for you.
From Surinam.
- Damn.
- Bad news?
He doesn't want a divorce.
Does it matter?
Yes, Waldemar.
It matters a lot.
Wedding,
Hilda Nods and Jo Herdigein.
May 1929
Have you got a girlfriend?
Why are you asking?
Just because.
Just because....
A boy in my class said
something about men and women.
About what they need.
- Need?
Yes, to...
You know...
I understand.
So do you have a girlfriend?
No.
Wim!
Hi Bertha, hi Henkie.
Everything alright?
This hiding is driving me crazy.
I love you.
I don't care if the
whole world knows it.
And they will.
I'm pregnant.
Since when?
- Four months.
Four months?
What were you thinking?
This dumbo won't notice?
Of course I didn't.
I was scared.
I even wanted to get rid of it, but...
- Get rid of it?
Our child?
I don't know. What are
we getting ourselves into?
If they find out that we...
I get it.
- No, you don't get it.
Yes I do, Rika.
You're just like everybody else.
Can I stay here for a while ?
I told you.
Nothing but poverty.
September 1929
Let's go for a swim.
Why don't you join them for a swim?
I don't feel like it.
Because you're too fat?
Don't tell mom.
I don't see them, do you?
- No.
Wim, Jan!
Are you upstairs?
Everybody runs away...
I beg your pardon?
My kids are not the only ones...
I don't understand what you mean.
Mom is a damn traitor.
...where the children are.
That's good to hear.
We talked to your husband.
The children are with him.
I'm looking for Waldemar Nods.
Do you know where I can find him?
Waldemar is taking his
entrance exam today.
Oh, yes.
- Should I give him a message?
Yes, from Rika. Tell
him I hope he'll pass.
Dear Wim, I feel sad about
you and Jan running away.
I am not angry with you.
I just hope you'll be back soon.
Whose is it?
Do you know you'll lose
everything, if I want to?
No allowance. No children.
Do you realize?
If you only came to rub
it in, you'd better leave.
No, that was not my intention.
This is something
Wim didn't mention.
I was...
They offered me a job.
In Soerabaja.
It 's a beatiful place.
Also by the sea.
I beg you...
Please join me.
I don't want to continue like this.
I want to keep the children together.
Our children.
Let's try again.
Far away from this misery.
Away from Jans...
Yes, that too...
And you can bring your child .
I'm willing to forgive you.
I will legitimate your child
and raise it like my own.
If only you will join me.
Please?
Rika, I...
Is he the father?
Yes.
I can't accept this...
I can't accept that...
...my children will live
under one roof with...
With two negroes!
- I just don't accept it.
- That's more like you.
I'm going to destroy you, you slut.
I'm going to destroy you
to the ground!
Don't touch her.
I love you so much.
Please don't leave me.
Think! Blacks are drifters.
What if he goes back?
- I will raise the kids by myself.
- You will lose them all.
What?
- He already has Wim and Jan.
He will claim the other
two and I can't blame him.
No, he can't do that.
You can still give up this child.
I can arrange a way out.
There is no way out.
- Willem is mad as hell .
I am their mother!
He can't do this to me.
Look at what you did to him.
He started it, with Jans.
With the maid.
I have to find a lawyer.
He won't get them.
I need some money.
- I can't help you anymore.
I will stop paying the rent.
- No Marcel, please!
You have no one to blame but yourseIf .
- You can't. Not now!
What's the matter with mom?
She's upset because Wim
and Jan won't come back.
You passed.
Now you can go to university.
As soon as you've paid
the tuition fee.
- Tuition fee?
- 300 Guilders.
It 's a boy.
When they are babies,
they're still cute.
- What shall we call him?
- Waldy.
You're behind with the rent.
Give me some time.
I just had a baby.
With your decent boarder, I'll bet.
That's none of your business.
Exactly . Therefore,
I terminate the rent.
You can't turn me and my
children out on the street.
I give you one more month.
But only if you pay
the rent by tomorrow.
Where did you get those?
- Bought them for Henkie and Bertha.
We don't have money for balloons.
We can't even pay the rent.
Always be a king to
yourseIf , Waldemar.
No matter what you lose.
A letter from court.
- Is this the last evening?
- Yes, try to get over it.
How am I supposed to do that?
Write me whatever's on your mind.
If you don't I will feel so poor.
But you're already poor.
You make me feel rich.
Bye, my dear sweethearts.
Be good. Be kind to each other.
Don't fight. And please write me.
We have to go.
We'll see each other soon.
I'll write you.
See you soon!
How can I tell them l'm only
allowed to see them once a year?
No vacancies.
Sadly, that will be impossible.
There are two things
a plant needs to grow:
Sun and water.
These are our rainy days.
Hey little boy!
What's this?
The Egyptian exodus?
Nobody wants us.
I have some room left.
Here we are.
-Mister...
- Call me Sam.
I don't know how to thank you.
We all need a roof over our heads.
Podem entrar, vamos.
Let me take care of that.
- What about the baby?
- He's sleeping.
No sea so distinguished
as the sea of Scheveningen.
Only the Haute Vollée bathes there.
No beach is as charming
as the beach of Scheveningen.
It 's where the flower
of Holland flirts.
Now it's your turn.
We have no job for you.
No sea so distinguished
as the sea of Scheveningen.
It 's not filled with jellyfish
because they stay on the beach.
I'm looking for my
brother, Waldemar.
So you must be Hilda...
Or Lilly?
Hilda?
How did you find me?
Our cousin gave me your address.
- Please come in, I'm Rika.
- Not in this mess.
So what. We'll just ignore it.
Let's have some coffee.
Will the two of you marry?
- She needs a divorce first.
- Does she have more children?
- Four.
Four?
- What's her age?
- 37.
You are seeing a married
woman who's 17 years older?
Our father's mistress is
17 years younger than him.
That's accepted.
The reverse is not.
Ridiculous, don't you think?
You were mamma's Ocean Swimmer.
You were supposed to study and
return and make it big time.
You can't have that
future with that woman.
Her name is Rika.
I had very different expectations.
Me too.
Go with me to the Dutch Indies.
Jo has a terrific job there.
They need people like you.
You can still escape.
Who says I want to?
Do you ever wonder what
mamma would think of this?
She'd turn in her grave.
I'm cancelling your allowance.
Where is your sister?
- She left.
Is she coming back?
She's leaving tomorrow
to join her husband.
Where to?
- Batavia.
- How deep can we fall .
- What?
You shut the door in my face
as if I'm a piece of rubbish.
Are you ashamed of me?
Your silence tells me all
I need to know.
- I dropped out of college.
- So you're looking for a job?
I applied a million
times. But the crisis...
Yes, they have a good excuse.
I live with a baby and
a woman in a small room.
Most Surinam men would leave.
What about Waldy!
I grew up without my father.
I coped with it better than you.
- A job would be great.
- I'll see what I can do.
Good morning, gentlemen. This
is our new employee Mr. Nods.
Teurlings, will
you show him around?
Is that my place?
And who is Mr. Teurlings?
Waldemar Nods.
You must know somebody
who pulls the strings here.
Only last week three men got fired.
Can you explain to me
what I'm supposed to do?
Yes, what would that be?
I guess they never taught
you in the jungle , did they?
From your mother.
Do you think mamma misses us?
Why should she?
She has a new child .
Six years later.
- Where is daddy?
-In the sea.
Daddy, I'm scared.
Waldy, you should learn to swim.
You have to make long strokes.
Right.
Waldemar is homesick.
I'm not blind.
- Close your eyes.
- Why should I.
Close your eyes, Rika.
I have something for you.
Now you can look.
I've taken care of the money.
It's yours now.
Our own guesthouse.
It has to be ready in a month.
- Why so soon?
Because the children
will visit us by then.
We have our own house now.
Perhaps they can visit more often.
Where are Mimi and Greta?
- Fired.
You want me to help ?
I don't need any help .
- This house has 12 rooms!
Which I'm all going to rent out.
- What's wrong with you?
- This is daddy's room.
- It 's the best room.
- And if he returns?
Forget about it.
Don't you understand?
Just forget about it.
- Why should I?
Neutral territory, said the judge.
This is a guesthouse.
That's neutral territory.
This will cause a lot of trouble .
I can do anything I want.
Wonderful to see you again.
Come, we don't have much time.
- Why do you greet him?
- I know him, don't I.
Can't you see he doesn't like it?
Don't think for others.
Follow your own instinct.
That's easy for you to say.
Are daddy and Jans happy together?
- Where are you taking us?
- I want to show you my guesthouse.
That's not allowed.
Yes it is. It 's like a hotel
It's neutral
But you live there, don't you?
- Yes I do.
Most of our guests are performers.
I have a maid now.
Her name is Agnes.
I'm not allowed to be here.
I worked hard to finish it
so I could show it to you.
I now have my own house.
It has enough rooms
for you to stay in.
Aren't you proud?
It 's not what was agreed.
- Agreed?
That is completely unreasonable .
Is it normal for a mother to see
her children two hours a year?
Half of them don't even show up.
I wouldn't even
recognize Jan and Wim now.
They wouldn't recognize you
either, dressed up like that.
I want to leave.
I don't feel comfortable here.
Alright.
Let's go.
Where is Waldy?
We're playing hide and seek.
Shouldn't you look for him?
No. Stupid game.
...National Socialism and Fascism
are the future of the New Europe...
but above all , comrades,
you are Dutchmen.
Come in.
I wanted to show this to you.
Another certificate!
All you do at night is study.
German Commercial Correspondence.
Mark my words, that will be of use.
Am I in line for a promotion?
- Dutch people get priority.
I am Dutch.
Nods, you do a good job.
That's why you still have one.
...Men with a heart
filled with love...
As you have broken the arrangement
to meet on neutral territory...
... you will not be allowed,
for a period of two years...
... to receive your children
in the city of The Hague.
Willem, you can't do this to me.
Open the door!
Let's talk about this.
Bertha!
- Mom!
Please, open the door.
I can't see you for two years.
That's too long!
- Shouldn't we let her in?
- That's out of the question.
Wim! I'm still your mother!
I want to see you all !
I should have never
let you go. Never.
He's got a high fever!
He has double pneumonia.
We'll have to wait.
We are being punished.
Lord forgive me. Please cure him.
The hospital called.
Mamma has appendicitis.
- She's not dying, is she?
I'll go fetch a doctor.
Waldemar, when you go to Holland...
l' m not going.
Never leave the people you love.
I'll stay with you.
You will go to college.
I don't want to be alone.
l'm not sure I can manage.
You are your father's son.
You'll manage.
Even without me.
How is he doing?
You'll wake him up.
I can't face this any longer.
Daddy?
Hey, Sonny Boy.
Get well soon.
Dear Bertha.
Your father finally
consented to a divorce.
He had no other choice.
I will marry Waldemar and I
regret that you can not be there.
Don't be sad about
moving to Groningen.
Waldemar says distance
doesn't matter.
Every breath I take is for you.
My spirit is always with you.
Never forget that my heart
belongs to my beloved children.
Summer, 1940
Good day to you, madam, sir.
Do you have rooms available ?
No we don't. In summer we
serve tourists, not soldiers.
Of course we will pay well .
It 's an order Rika.
We don't have a choice.
I'm not taking orders from anyone.
How many rooms do you need?
Look at me!
Very nice. You are a boy scout.
- Yes!
What do you want to
be when you are older?
Soldier. I want to be a soldier.
With pistols . Like you.
Your mother should be proud of you.
Too bad the boy scouts will be
forbidden. Orders from the Führer.
You will have to
turn in the uniform.
What did he say?
That you have to be
careful with your uniform.
Hi mom.
Look who's here.
- My God.
- Hi mom.
This can't be true!
Jan! My son!
Please, come in.
To my children. Who are
all here, except one...
and whom I love so much.
And to God, who brought me
Bertha, Henk and Jan.
I think it was the
train that brought them.
How is Wim?
He works as a doctor in Friesland.
I regret I haven't
seen him for so long.
Don't say anything.
He takes after his father.
Jan is planning to be engaged.
Oh, how nice Jan!
With a Catholic girl
How does your father
feel about that?
He kicked me out.
You will always have a bed here.
May 1942
- That's the last one.
- This is ridiculous.
What do they want
with these labels?
So they can spot us.
What's next?
Will they brand you?
Rika... Next time you come by...
I'm afraid I won't be here.
Sam, do I have to worry about you?
You are my tower of strength.
I don't want to lose you.
So stay.
I'll stay.
Sorry to trouble you.
Please accept my apologies.
What does it say?
We have to evacuate our house.
Within three weeks.
That can't be true.
We are in a strategically
sensitive area.
Why does God need to take
away our home as well ?
Not God, Rika.
The Germans.
Why do you always take pictures?
As a memento. For later.
- So you can see how it was?
- Yes.
It's pretty here, isn't it?
Yes...
I don't want to leave here.
I didn't want to leave Surinam.
Couldn't you stay?
No.
Do you miss it?
Not right now.
You're here.
The Germans can
take my house, but...
I want something equal
in size in return.
You can't make demands.
Sure I can.
Here's a letter from church.
So you have five children?
Why are you hiding this?
It 's nobody's business
that we own these things.
If you don't want anybody to
find it, you need to hide it.
- Who's going to search for it?
- Nobody.
Mrs. Nods... Follow me, please.
Somebody wants to
take your confession.
- Mrs. Nods?
- That's me.
I'm seeking help. For people
who are having a hard time.
Who's not having a
hard time these days?
People who don't stand a
chance against the Germans.
Forbidden people in a forbidden
time, in a forbidden territory.
What do you want from me?
We're looking for rooms...
And you have a large house.
- It 's my livelihood.
- You will get paid.
Sixty guilders a month for
Jews, forty five for Dutch.
Give me some Jews then.
These people will stay briefly untiI
we transfer them to the countryside.
- People will come and go.
- I'm used to that.
There's a risk. If you get
caught you will be punished.
Punished? For housing people?
It's a strange world we live in.
You're not a priest.
Not even Catholic.
- But a Christian.
- Protestant.
I want to see your face.
I want to look you in the eyes.
My name is Paul Vermeer.
But you're just a boy.
I'm 24. Please call me Paul.
I'm Rika.
- Maybe you should think about it.
- In war you need to act.
- Life before philosophy.
- Exactly. They will be welcome.
You will have to be quiet. My son
doesn't know you'll be upstairs.
You need a lot.
It 's too obvious.
I have a guesthouse.
You don't have German
officers as an alibi now.
Walk, you scum! We want
our Jewish blood money!
Niggers shouldn't be boy scouts.
- Are you Mrs. Nods?
- Yes.
Can we have a word?
We had to pull him
away from this boy.
- I saw Sam!
- How is the boy doing?
He took quite a beating.
But he's a healthy Dutch boy.
He'll get back on his feet.
If I catch you
again, you go to jail
Got me? And another thing.
You're forbidden.
- What?
- Your uniform.
Don't bother. l' ll burn it.
- Why?
- As punishment.
Very good. We'll find our way out.
- What's that?
- The maid.
For Christ's sake what are
you... Waldy! Come back!
These people need to hide.
Otherwise they'll be caught.
Do you understand?
- So what about Sam?
- Nothing.
One year later
Do they think they can
win the war like this?
- You have to return to Groningen.
- Why?
It 's no longer safe here.
- What about you?
- Don't worry about me.
But I do. Especially now
we can see each other again.
I don't want to lose you.
I want to be with you.
And I want to be with you.
- Come with me, to Groningen.
- No, I can't leave here.
- Will you be careful.
- I won't let them destroy me.
Not a huge load of
laundry this time.
- Just a regular load?
- Regular?
A gentile in need of hiding.
- Somebody from the resistance?
- A deserter from the SS.
- That's odd.
- Why?
A resistance fighter
saving an SS member?
Ex-SS. He deserted.
- But he signed up first.
- He wanted some adventure.
He was 18. And naive.
- And he ran away when he felt like it.
- That's only human, isn't it?
It doesn't show much fortitude.
This boy will be shot
if they catch him.
But to have him share
space with with the Jews...
- I don't know... what do you think?
- Everybody deserves a second chance.
This is Gerard van Haringen.
He will be staying here.
Welcome Gerard. Have you
eaten? l'll go get a plate.
What is the reason you are here?
- Same as you.
- I doubt it.
You take the rope,
put it like that...
Really. Try again. Once more.
Hey, big boy scout,
what's going on?
Did you have a fight or something?
So what's up?
Nothing.
You had too much water in your head,
so you opened the floodgates.
That's much better.
What's going on?
I want to get my second star.
- After the war?
Yes.
But these knots drive me crazy.
- Is that all ?
- Yes.
If only you knew
how often I failed.
- Did you ever see me cry?
- No.
Come here, stand straight.
Are you a reaI boy scout?
- Yes.
- I thought so too.
You must keep one thing in mind:
a real boy scout never cries.
You hear me?
Never.
So repeat after me.
a real boy scout never cries.
A real boy scout never cries.
Louder!
- A reaI boy scout never cries!
Perfect. Now lift
two fingers and swear.
A reaI boy scout never cries.
Very good. You feeI better now?
Good boy.
I heard that all the Jews
that have to turn themselves in...
...are sent to camps in Germany.
Supposedly to work.
- To make themselves useful.
- But what really happens is this.
lmpossible .
That's hundreds of people .
Thousands. And the people who
help them are sent away too.
But they deserve it.
They know they're wrong.
So the Jews don't deserve it?
It was just their luck
to be born that way.
Waldemar should 've
been home already.
- Do you like it?
- Are you allowed to make music?
- Why wouldn't I.
- What if someone notices?
Well , then we just say it's him.
- Isn't that a German song?
- What?
I think you're
playing a German song.
- Could be.
- I'd rather not hear it.
- German songs aren't suspicious.
Still no reason to play them.
I can play the same melody
with different words.
I'm not singing
our national anthem.
# If all are unfaithful,
we remain true... #
# so that there will always be
a troop on earth for you. #
Dirty bastard.
Come Gerard,
let's go to my room.
Where were you?
It's past curfew.
I needed some fresh air.
- What's the matter?
- I'm scared.
Of what is going on all around us,
and even in our house.
What about Waldy, if
something happens to us?
- That won't happen.
- How do you know?
I want to go away.
What do you mean?
Away from this house?
Away from this country.
Away from Europe.
From this war.
I want to take you
and Waldy to Surinam.
But the borders are closed.
I'll talk to David. Maybe
he can arrange something.
Yeah... An airplane.
Mom!
Upstairs lads, that's where they are.
Here they are!
Hush, don't say a word.
Come on you! Hurry up!
You're coming with us.
Dirty nigger.
And take this brown shrimp too.
You don't belong here.
Hurry up down those stairs.
Filthy Jew.
Good work boys.
A big score.
Take them away.
Hey, Gerard.
A real boy scout never cries.
- Don't be scared.
- Shut up.
When we get out of here,
we go to Surinam.
- It's always warm there.
- We will swim in the river.
Shut up! Damn it.
Poor little resistance fighter,
did you hurt yourself?
We will make you talk, Jew lover.
Here, give this to daddy.
What do you have there?
Tell me, what do you have there?
Open your hands, immediately!
You. What do you have there?
It's clear you have something.
Show me your hands!
Give it to me.
Give me the money.
You're allowed to go.
Come on.
Do as he says.
Go to uncle Marcel.
No, I don't want to.
I want to stay with you.
I'm not going to uncle Marcel
Get lost.
Go home.
Sit down.
My name is Kees Kaptein.
The most successful
executioner of the Dutch Jews.
Does the name Kees
Chardon ring a bell?
No.
Maybe you only know him
by his alias. Paul Vermeer.
Never heard of him.
Why are you hiding Jews?
I'm not hiding anybody.
Those people live with me.
I run a guesthouse. All
paying guests are welcome.
- Even if they are hiding?
-It's not written on their forehead.
It's sewn on their overcoats.
Shall I give you some names?
Abraham Cohen, Joseph Polak,
Herman de Bruin, Dobbe Franken.
That all sounds very Jewish,
don't you think?
If you say so.
Stop lying.
Why did they stay in your house?
Everybody needs a
roof over their heads.
Mom said I should go see you.
- What happened?
- They are in prison.
- And our house is gone.
- Gone?
You can stay here.
Don't you worry.
That's not possible .
Think of my nerves.
Woman, at least for once shut up.
Start talking, you stupid bitch!
We know that Kees Chardon
alias Paul Vermeer
wasn't a decent lawyer.
He and a bunch of
morons helped Jews.
And you acted as his assistant.
A simple housewife...
Who would 've thought?
I have nothing to say.
Maybe we should change the rules.
Your little son...
I bet you really love him.
Shall we bring him and
give him the same treatment?
- I'll let you watch.
- You're sick.
Not as sick as you.
You live with a nigger.
A racial disgrace!
That's what we call it.
- Pick up her son.
- Não!
He's with an uncle, isn't he?
These walls have ears.
They're fetching Sonny Boy!
Clear off,
outside!
- Where is Waldy Nods?
- He's not here.
Search the store and the house.
I'm sure you understand we would
never keep such a cuckoo in the nest.
We get rid of them. Nobody wants
such a black nuisance around.
- Poor monkey. They're trash.
- Indeed.
It's getting too dangerous
for him over here.
I can go on for hours.
Until you drown.
How many Jews?
How come this
doesn't work with you?
The water is my friend.
Too bad it's your only friend.
Your family kicked your son out.
Why don't you sit for a while?
It hurts to sit.
- Did he give you a hard beating?
- With a curtain rail.
That's Kapi's trademark.
It can be worse.
- Vera had...
- No mom, don't mention it.
I have a daughter, she's your age.
I have five children.
Do you still have nothing to say?
Ah well . It doesn't matter.
You're nailed anyhow.
If you pick up enough people ,
there's always one who breaks.
In this case it was a young man
who truly understands our cause.
Gerard van Haringen.
What are you doing?
I'm practicing.
She's a pianist.
Every day without practice
makes you play worse.
Can you play Sonny Boy?
I think so.
Uncle Marcel
I want to go with you.
Don't leave me here!
A group of men has been taken away.
Your husband was one of them.
Dear God.
Where to?
Camp Vught.
The sentence against the group
of Kees Chardon is as follows:
Hendrika Johanna Nods
and Kees Chardon...
are sentenced for life because of
extensive Judenhilfe and conspiracy.
Give me something to write on.
Camp Vught
Move on. Get back in line.
He's still alive.
He's still here.
Waldemar.
Move, you piles of shit, move!
Concentration Camp Neuengamme
- Four languages?
- Yes, four.
Dutch, French,
English and German.
- Polish?
- No sir, no Polish.
That's too bad.
But you've passed.
Four languages.
Unbelievable .
You can work here.
Finally someone who
appreciates my certificates.
Dear Waldy,
How are you?
A letter from your uncle Marcel.
A letter from my father!
- What does he write?
- That I should do my best in school
Otherwise he'll come home
and slap me on my behind.
They don't have a clue
what's happening here.
Concentration Camp Ravensbrück.
9 september 1944
Dutch women, keep
courage. Ahoy ahoy.
Why do you need all this food?
I keep it out of the Krauts' hands.
And I sell it.
- Some potatoes, please.
- Do you have anything to pay with?
- No jewelry?
- No.
Those wedding rings will do.
Here, take this one.
You should stay out of this.
You are an idiot, you know that?
They'll lose those
rings eventually.
Why not to me?
Everyone makes money from the war.
Do you really think your parents
were hiding Jews for free?
Paul
Paul Vermeer!
- Waldemar.
- You're still alive.
Yes.
To give up is to give in.
In what section did they put you?
Outside.
The salt mines.
This labour is far
too heavy for you.
They should have me do it.
Doesn't matter, Waldemar.
Here we are all slaves.
Dear Waldy, First of all
I wish you a happy 1945.
Fortunately I'm healthy. It can be
bitter cold here, but I'll manage.
I'll manage.
Have you heard from
mamma in the meantime?
No news from mamma
out of Ravensbrück.
I miss you both.
Our rainy days.
The Führer has died.
Faith has stricken us hard.
I'm very sorry.
What to do with you now?
We now have a new Führer, Dönitz.
The enemy advances.
There is only one way out.
Over water.
Lübecker Bay
Our liberators!
Stupid Britts!
It's us!
The whole ship is burning.
I need a smoke.
Only Germans.
No prisoners on board!
Only SS!
No prisoners!
Somebody's swimming.
- That man is black.
- Nevertheless he is a good swimmer.
Where is he going?
To the other end of the ocean?
He's swimming for his life.
When will you shoot?
On the count of three.
I'm ready.
One...
Two...
Three.
We're good soldiers.
We'll win this war!
A letter from your uncle .
What does he write?
That's he received a
letter from a pianist...
Oh céus...
Poor, poor boy.
- Good to see you.
- You've grown a lot.
- Where am I going to live?
- With your grandparents, for now.
Until my father returns.
We haven't heard from your father.
I've got something for you.
It's from your mother.
In the train. Goodbye dear children.
Bye father and mother.
Goodbye dear brothers and sisters.
A big kiss for everybody.
I'm going to Vught,
to my dear husband.
Please pray for us.
Have faith. I'll be brave.
Your loving mother, Rika.
Months later, Waldy received word that his
father had died in the Cap Arcona disaster.
It was a mystery to him how
such a good swimmer could drown.
Sixty years after the war,
he learned the true story when a new book
about his parents revealed
previously undiscovered facts.
According to the pianist's letter,
Rika died of dysentery in early Macrh, 1945
Hilda and Jo Survived
a Japanese prison camp.
They returned to Holland
and gave Waldy a home.
Willem was upset at the news of Rika's death.
One year later he married Jans.
Bertha was the only one
who stayed in contact with Waldy.
His haIf -brothers could not cope.
MarceI kept searching for Waldemar
but eventually had to give up hope.
On ApriI 16, 1945,
Kees Chardon (PauI Vermeer)
died of exhaustion in a
labour camp near Neuengamme.
Of all the arrested Jews, only Dobbe
survived the concentration camps.
Gerard van Haningen was sent to Dachau.
After the war he moved
to a West Frisian Island.
Because of this, Waldy never set
foot on any of the Frisian Islands.
Kees Kaptein was tried
and executed for his war crimes.
Waldy became a journalist. He married
and had children.
He lost his parents but kept afloat.