Honey, I'm calling my baby honey
Never
Oh, my baby honey
He is my special food
It's strange that he never ask for me
I only give him honey
No matter when to use
I flied to his lips
millions of time like a bee
Because to me, even chocolate candy cannot
compare to his sweetness
- Gisela, I have to leave
- What are you leaving for?
- Gisela
- Oh, I see
Come on, let's go
- Ok, meet you at the English park
tomorrow noon at twelve
- in front the cabin by the lake?
- Yes, Hans really should
give me a phone call
- I'll remind him
- Has he calm down now?
- You shouldn't have yelled at him
Everything will be fine
Finally, you should have arrived earlier
Hurry, let's go
- Is this all?
- the rest has not arrived yet
"German people are shocked by soliders who
fell into the abyss of death at Stalingrad
330,000 fellowmen are forced to
death and extermination step by step
by the great strategies of our strategists
meaninglessly and irresponsibly
Little Sophielein, if you can help Willi
he must be very happy
This is the stamp, and this is the address
Thanks
What to do with the rest?
I'll go deliver them at the college tomorrow
- Are you crazy?
- Willi, did you forget the female
college students demonstrating
at the Germany Museum a few days ago?
- almost succeed
- Gestapo have been in the
first ground alert for this
- Hans...
- Don't forget our slogans are everywhere
Hans, before we have any new envelopes
we can hide the rest under the board
No need. There is nothing left.
Lack of paper
It's already pretty dangerous
to write slogans on walls at night
But compare with giving out flyers
at campus in the day time...
Do you want to die?
We have to make our best efforts,
cannot wait anymore
Let's bring along the whole city!
It's the most tense moment
of the Stalingrad warfare now.
Nazi's secret agents are all over the campus!
If bolshevists come now,
just to kill them all...
- At least we can kill them once for all
- If I were you
I won't hope Soviet Union
comes before Americans
Don't you hate bolshevist the most?
Hans, are you crazy?
Don't go to deliver them in colleges!
I'll go when they are having classes,
nobody will be in the hall...
I'll come out soon, entering from
the front gate and get out from the back one
- It's too dangerous!
- Willi...
I will take all the responsiblity
if anything happens.
Won't embroil others
You are going to walk through Schwabing
with a big suitcase?
Let's me take this
Hans, I don't think
we should embroil Sophie in this...
If we were to be checked,
it would be easier for a woman to pass
She is right
Alright, let's go
Alex, meet me in my place at twelve tomorrow
- Starting from tomorrow, no wait?
- We can wait, but Nazis won't
Thanks
Don't work too late
- Goodnight
Dear Lisa,
I'm listening to Schubert's Trout Quintet
I feel schubert's inspriation
is flowing in air
I can hear the happy tweedle of birds
and little creatures
The piano constantly repeats
the same thematic rhythm
just like a clear, crystal creek
oh, they make me so enchanted
Wish I can hear from you soon
Best wishes, yours Sophie
Not sure if mom still have some jam?
This brand they only sell turnip juice now
Not conspicuous enough, right?
- We bring the light of hope
into colleges today
- Yes
Good morning!
- Good morning
- We are going to a neurology hospital,
you want to come along?
- Sophie is going to Ulm by bus.
I will be there soon
- Hurry up
Hurry, hurry up
- There are some in the case, Hans
- What?
- No one is up there, wait a second
- I'm going with you
Freeze! Stop!
Stop right now!
You...don't run...stop!
- You are under arrested! Stop, damned
- What's wrong?
- You are under arrested!
- Ridiculous, how can you arrest us randomly!
- You are the only people upstairs,
come with me
- We were coming out from
the Department of Psychology
- You are handing out fly sheets
- Nonsense
Let go of him,
it's me taking off those sheets
Good you admit that. I'm going to report you
You come with me, both of you!
Believe me, even in my college you cannot
get away if you are doing that
"German people are shocked
by soliders at Stalingrad..."
Come in!
So many? Unbelievable!
- They are all here?
- Yes!
You can go now!
Schmid, write a report
We will catch them all
There...there
This college student seems to
have something in his hands...
Quick, give it to me!
Look, there is one more fly sheet
Give it to me!
Or you want me to do it myself?
They should be put together
- I'm Mohr, national police.
Long live Hitler
- Long live Hitler
This two, they are under arrested for now...
- These are the documents I took over
- It's me took these two guys...
Do you have any ID?
- Ms. ophia Magdalena Scholl?
- Yes
- Mr. Hans Fritz Scholl?
- Brother and sister?
- Yes
Female
21 years old...
so, you want to resist Reich that...
has already taken the whole Europe?
when the guy noticed be watched by me
he started ripping the paper in hands
an unacquainted classmate
handed it over to me forcedly
I ripped it 'cause I don't want
to bring any trouble
- Is this your case?
- yes, it's mine
Take it!
I've given the order to close off the college
any teachers and other personnels
shall not leave the school
Sure! certainly I will stay too
- go back and tell Alex to leave me alone
- Quiet!
Scholl, Hanz, get in the room
to Maller for inquest
follow me, madam!
come here please!
unlock cuff!
Thanks
Let's begin
sit down
Sophia Magdalena Scholl, from Ulm
born on May 9, 1992 in Forchtenberg
Christian, and your father?
Robert Scholl, mayor of Forchtenberg
- any professional nursery education before?
- yes, I have
currently live in Munich,
NO 13 Franz-Joseph ST.
- landlord's name is Smith?
- yes
- any criminal record?
- none
you have admitted right
in front of the dorm administrator
that it was you...
who spreaded the fly sheets from balustrade
the fly sheets were on the marble handrail
I spreaded them casually
when I was passing by
why?
it's my nature, see anything,
move anything ...that's it
I admitted it then and there
and I knew ...
I made a stupid mistake
I am very regreted,
but things can not be changed anyhow
Miss Scholl,
you spreaded fly sheets in college
and it has violated
Kriegssonderstrafrechtsverordnung
do you want to know the punishement for
quislism and collaborationism?
- it has nothing to do with me
- imprisonment, labour reform...
- or execution
- it has nothing to do with me, definitely
- cigarettes?
- no, thanks
- but you do smoke, right?
- occasionally
perfect for this situation
just coincidence
why did you bring an empty case to school?
I planed to go to Ulm by car
pick up my clothes in house
- the clothes were taken home
for washing by my mother
- back to Ulm?
it's not weekend now
you want to take that long trip back home?
- yes
- just for some clothes?
not only for the clothes,
I also want to visit a friend
she just had a baby
- and, my mother was sick
- why didn't you wait till weekend?
so you skipped classes?
why did you go home so hurry?
because my friend suggested going to Hamburg
so I want to get back before weekend
I planed to take 12:48 train
and I already made the appointment with
my sister's friend in Heltz Station
you can ask him
- his name?
- Otto Aicher
he started from Solln
and reached Munich at 12.... 11:30
- Aicher, start with an "e"?
- start with "a - i"
you didn't put clothes
in the case to Ulm for washing?
no, I wash my own small clothes
as for the big ones,
no one is needed for washing yet
so, it means you don't need clean clothes yet?
but just now you were saying...
you expressly bring an empty case to home
for washed clothes?
I was thinking that since I went back to Ulm
I should bring next week's clothes too
so you want to go back to Ulm
why did you still come back to school?
I had an appointment with a friend
her name is Gisela Schertling
we planed to have lunch together
in the cabin at british park lakeside
at 12 noon
didn't you go to Ulm?
I desided that today temporarily
I came back to school
to cancel the appointment with Gisela
why did your brother accompany you to the school?
didn't you just come to cancel the appointment?
Hanz and I often go to school together
Hanz wants to go to neurosurgery school
dorm administrator said, about 11 o'clock
you two were on aisle of the third floor
- what were you doing?
- we were on the way searching for Gisela
she was in Pro. Huber's philosophy class
- but that was on 2nd floor
- yes, we were there 10 minutes early
so I took my brother
to psychology department for a look
most of my classes are in 3rd floor,
psychology department
where did you see the fly sheets?
you mean the paper? everywhere
- and you did not even take a look
and see what it written?
- yes, I did, but only a glance
- my brother told a joke about this
- a political joke?
no, he said it wastes paper,
he is just like me
not interested in politics
several days ago,
when a district principal gave speech
in Germany Museum
a bunch of female college students made trouble
were you there?
No
- everybody should be there while in the speech
- I don't attend any politics
what do you think of the speech
given by district principal
as he mentioned...
girls should think about
how to give birth for leaders
while not fooling around in college
He said the ugly one
can marry to his adjutant
This is a taste problem
What you did in university
Already make you a suspect,
I seriously advise you
Don't be hesitate any more
to tell the truth
I deny that I have any connection
with this leaflet
Except the joke I made,
I understand that
The suspicion for us
before you finds the real wrongdoers.
- But my brother and
I has nothing to do with this
- Do you really think?
You can hide it before me
when answer the question?
What do you think?
All I told you are truth
Mrs Scholl, my co-worker did not
Find anything leaflet in that case,
you brother's Confession
also proved what you said
You can relax now
I never worried
Let the recorder come in
I will let her to record my statement
You have to listen carefully
If there is any conflict with your affidavit
You must tell me right away
- Are you clear, Mrs Scholl?
- Yes
Although this will be kept
in your criminal record
But, we will see
Maybe you still can go to Ulm
according to the plan
It is over
Metternich! Retirement certificate
Hail Hitler
Mr. Sch¨¹rmer, follow me
You students think you can be here
Fool us?
Please hand out your jewellery, watch
We already made up our mind to
Use our lives to resist
Do not consider the world surrounding us
- No matter understand the necessity
of this war or not
- Necklace and pendant
The time for a full scale war already comes
Follow me
Let us say farewell to fear
and meaningless hesitation
In this fight with fate
Abide our rule: clean my leather coat
But do not make me wet!
(Means the law deprive citizen's right
for consultation in 1935)
- Please take off you cloth and give it to me
It is great danger
We must put into huge effort
If you still have any illegal stuff, give it me
I help you throw them in to toilet
I am also a prisoner
Now, that time is coming
I have nothing
Please take off your gloves
OK, let's continue
Tomorrow will knee down
to thank us our acceptance for him
Ladies, get in, hurry, hurry,
I want to listen to the lecture
Do you know how my brother is now?
Your brother already had it
He is waiting with other men up there
You are the main suspect
Because you have the case
Leaflets are threw down by your too
Do not admit anything!
I admitted nothing
How long have you been here?
One year and five days
They caught one of my letters, I quoted
Words that Ludwig-Thoma criticizes Hitler
- Even though, you still work for those people
- They order me to do this
The reason why I am here
Is to prevent you to commit suicide
- Why are you again Nazi?
- My brother and I are communist
Even my brother has a very
senior position in an insurance company
I admire the selfless help in communist party
People have to do something
Scholl Sophia, go with me!
I hope, we never see each other, good luck!
You too, good luck!
Wait here
OK, Mrs, your release paper
You are lucky this time
Please speak up
Understood
Follow me, follow me
You can take off your coat
Sit down
Your father was put into jail for 6 weeks
Because you call our leader is
God's punishment for human being
He was arrested for the crime of conspiracy
Also his license was revoked too
I want to know. You join Hitler Jugend
What do you dad think about that?
My dad never influence
our political preference
Typical democrat
Why do you join Hitler Jugend?
Because I heard that
Hitler will bring our nation glory
Good luck and fortune,
everyone will have job and bread
Everybody will enjoy freedom and happiness
- You are single?
- I am engaged
With Fritz Hartnagel
He is a commander of eastern front
Stalingrad?
Yes
- When was the last time
you see each other?
- Half year ago
Have you seen this gun before?
My brother had a gun like this
He was sergeant in army
Why do you have 190 bullets in your drawer?
9mm bullets?
They are also my brother's
When was the last time you buy stamps?
- About two week ago
- Where did you buy,
and how many did you buy?
Leopoldstrasse street, post office 23
Ten 12 cents and five 6 cents
I can't remember exactly
- Only those, you did not buy more?
- No
Have you seen these stamps?
No
- Are you sure you never seen them?
- Never
This was what we found in your brother's room
Why did you never mention...
Your brother has alot stamps?
Your question is when and where
I bought stamps recently
one hundred and fourty?
who needs that many of stamps? for what?
what you need to send out?
compliment to friends and relative,
we are in touch.
- so, your have seen those stamps?
- I am just guessing.
you found those from
my brother's place, not mine
is this your typewriter?
it was in my brother's room,
we borrowed it from landlord.
- she lent to us to type something.
- what thing?
An essay about philosophy and theology
- not for typing those handbills?
- No
An essay about philosophy and theology?
something like...
"Hitler could not win this war,
only keep it going"
or "a criminal cannot give Germany victory"
or "federation is the future of Germany,
freedom of speech, freedom of religion"
Hans didnt write those
- You wrote those?
- No
- but you believe this kind of world order
- I don't care about politics, and I won't
anyway, we compared all those writing,
and all those bullshit
are done by this typewriter,
then at the beginning of this month,
they are sent to different addresses,
include Munich
I have no idea about this
sit there!
watch it!
all those bullshit were from
your brother's place
and your were there
and he was planning to destroy all those bills
Have you seen those paper before?
- No
- keep your lie, but read this for me.
"two hundred thousands German died...
- just for one war opportunist"
- Does this remind you something?
Is it similar to other six handbills?
Take look at the handwriting
- I dont know
- Listen to me!
this part of evil speaking comes from
a guy named Christoph Probst
He is a friend of your at lnnsbruck.
We found his letter.
Exactly same handwriting!
Probst£¬is also a student in iatrology
love family and mountains of motherland.
An other do oneself proud bastard
Never understand people are dying at battlefornt.
who is in, beside you,
your brother and that Christoph Probst.
- who did those bills?
- please stop slandering me?
You held back all those evidence from your home
Even I asked you to give me the truth
I just admit what I really did
how about listen this,
your brother, was just like you,
how to explain those evidence
"the military plan failed at eastern line...
U.S.A and british military force
increased unpredictablely.
I conclued that we could not win this war
after painfully thinking in long time...
I believe that avoiding
the meaningless death...
and keeping the integrality of Europe
the only way is finish the war
as soon as possible, in the other hand, ...
I also have deep fear about the way
we treat the occupation area
and people in the area"
that is just his political point,
not exculpation to your slander
this is ...
...disorganizing army
and betraying our country!
I dont believe my brother said that!
So you think your brother was lying to us?
Before my brother talk to me personally,
I won't believe that he said those
Eickemayer Studio
you heard about it?
Yes
Eickemayer is at Krakau in recent few months,
he gave the key...
of studio to us, let us take a look
the fingerprint on the copymachine...
they are your brother's
your brother has admited
he designed,
copyed£¬and handed out
all six kinds of handbills.
He tried to make me believe that, he sent out
five thousand handbills in Munich at one night
you lived with your brother
you were all in the hallway this morning
and you still want me believe
that you have nothing to do with this?
you think all these slander
are meaningless? Just admit it!
You and your brother made
and sent those handbills!
YES! and I am proud of it!
what will happen to me and my brother?
You should think about
this at beginning£¬Miss Scholl
- Our relative will be embroiled?
- I can't decide it
- I have to go to washroom
- Not now!
Who draft out these?
- Me!
- You are lying£¬Miss Scholl!
Juse few weeks ago...
we did the writing check
from the report,
we are sure they are from a male.
Your brother is the author and the planner!
- who mailed out these handbills?
- my brother and I
excuse me, I have to go to washroom
Locher!
Washroom!
follow me
Hurry!
open the handcuffs, it hurts!
What are you doing with them?
you know, Miss Scholl?
there is no leeway...
you know it, next door to the left
Who wrote these banner"Step out! Hitler!"...
"FREEDOM"...
and a crossed NSDAP badge,
University£¬Ludwig street
Marienplatz£¬Kaufinger street
and Schwabing everywhere
my brother and I
Your brother said after he got arrested£º
"go back home...
tell Alex£¬dont wait for me"
Schertling was right there
He was telling Schmorell to run away?
Hans had a appointment with Schmid,
he didnt want him wait for nothing.
- You mentioned about your plan to Schmorell?
- No
- and Graf?
- why are you keep lying?
- I did not
here
this is your confession!Sign it!
Locher!
take her out!
I heard about Mohr told Locher:
this kind of people...
is what Germany needs
but we have to re-educate them
Maybe they will try to
rebuild your world view
but I will tell you, they may just wait
- why?
- even the bosses are impatience
a lot people think allied forces will
get into Germany in eight to ten weeks
after that£¬sooner or later£¬
Germany will be liberated
If my mother know I am under arrest
She won't stand the shock
She is over 60,
and she is sick all the month
If Gestapo goes to my house...
she my get in jail cause us...
and your father?
He is 10 years younger than my mom,
he always bring us the immaterial power
your mom is not alone.
Thanks
"we are not silence,
we are the forgotten conscience
White roses let you cannot sleep in peace!"
- Who are "us"?
- My brother wrote this.
at the last line of 4th handbill£º
"please copy...
and pass around",
and here is about resist movement
- doesn't sound like couple peoples' crime
- We dont have organization
How much you know about Willi Graf?
Sergeant£¬he has same major as my brother
came to our house sometimes.
we knew£¬he helped you guys
copying the handbills at the studio
Maybe you found his fingerprint
- but he went to studio at other time.
- When?
Middle of January,
We were going to see Eickemayer' painting
that's the reason why
others' fingerprints are in studio
- who were there?Schmorell?
- Maybe, I dont know
I was just there at beginning,
then I went to concern
- Probst brought handbills to Salzburg and Linz?
- No
Hans didn't tell him anything,
cause he has wife and three children
here, you have to tell me the damn truth,
I am asking you.
Who is in?
Graf£¬Anneliese?
I totally met them about 10 times.
- what did you talk about?
- about lecture and science
- My impression of Graf is that
he has no interested in politics
- no interested£¬but knew the inside?
I have to say£¬Graf has nothing
to do with the handbills
- how about Schertling?
- Gisela met me several times.
we studied in same university,
and we knew each other before that.
- she is NSDAP
- as your saying£¬Miss Scholl
The member of resist movement is everywhere
in Germany they all look like
have no interested in politics
It is good for your, is't it? Mr Mohr
As our counting,
this so called "white rose"...
bought ten thousand papers in Jan...
and two thousand envelops
- who did that?
- my brother and I
only hundruds of handbills
for the 1st to 4th.
it makes sense.
But you wish I believe you two
copyed thousands of handills
for the 5 and 6th edition?
- then sent them out?
- we worked on them day and night.
I admire you£¬and you take class
at the same time?
yes£¬we were faking
there are lots of members
we knew£¬your brother£¬Graf£¬Schmorell
Furtw?ngler£¬and Wittenstein served
at eastern line before.
all the people got in university in Munich
any political movement between them?
My brother just told me
about innumerable death.
- but never talked about his comrade
- I don't believe you£¬Miss Scholl
At this period, everyone is careful
about their political speech.
Just like what you say in the handbill?
you found these address there?
copy from phonebook of German museum
let's take a look at Stuttgart:
Jan 27th and the morning after, totally...
sent out seven hundred handbills!
same day at Munich...
about two thousands handbills were sent out.
Just you and your brother
cannot done this job!
I took the fast train
to Stuttgart at 27th...
handbills were in a case,
when I arrived...
I threw half of them
into the post-box of station.
all the left I put
into the post-box at country side
your brother could't be
at Munich in Jan 20th...
when we found the addresses from phonebook...
he sent out an other two thousand handbill
in differnet place? who was helping him?
I wasn't at Munich
who support you money?
my father gave me one fifty each month.
my brother has pay from army
How can you afford your life and
all the handbills and postage?
everytime you trip to Ulm,
it took you 15 mark
- we borrowed some money from friends
- from who?
here, up left corner...
"E"must stand for income
- it is the backer's name after amount?
- Yes
your fiance were in?
- so he knew it!
- No!
everytime we borrow,
we give a pretence.
you can ask everyone
my brother and I are the only members
have you thought about
if you and your brother
assume all the crime,
what will happen to you?
We know every name!