Heinrich
Toyland
They are still practicing.
Don't you think they are getting better every day?
Yes, very good.
I'd give everything so he can play his whole life like that.
Probably tomorrow...
Quiet now above!
Stop that plink-plonk, jew scum!
You played very nice today. Very, very nice.
You won't catch me!
Hey, these are my notes.
Stay here.
Did you see my son?
N..
Why in a hurry, beautiful lady?
I can't find him.
There was nothing goin on here.
The Silbersteins left today.
Yeah, it's better for Heinrich.
And the bear?
Why was Mrs Silberstein so sad?
Because the Silbersteins have to travel soon.
Travel? Whereto?
To Toyland.
To Toyland? I want to go there too!
That's not possible, boy.
But i want to go to Toyland.
i sad No. Now eat.
Dad would have allowed it.
Hello, did you see a little, six years old boy?
Do you think i can keep the whole crowd apart?
But he is my son..
Jew?
So don't worry, madam.
We only brought jews to the station.
Have a nice day!
Heinrich?
Could you..
..keep a secret?
Downstairs in the corner,
i bumped into a rhinoceros.
With a real rhinoceros?
Then i'll tell you my secret.
I come along with you to Toyland.
Even my mum won't allow it.
Why can't i go with them to Toyland?
Because it's to far away.
I don't care!
Besides, the teady bears are huge there.
Bigger than Paulchen?
Much bigger.
Much, much bigger.
Come, lay down.
We are not afraid of that, right Paulchen?
Mum, could you please keep the light on?
Stop!!
Jew scum!
I'm looking for my child.
Where is your starlet?
Where is your star??
Not a jew?
I'm looking for my child.
My son has to be here somewhere?
Why didn't you say you will travel?
Forgot.
Anyway, i come with you to Toyland.
That's not possible.
But we are blood brothers.
We swore we will always stick together.
I will take along the notes.
Then we can practice whenever we want.
Name of the neighbors?
Silberstein.
Usually everything works fine here.
Your son wanted to go with them?
Because they are friends.
Wagon 3, Obersturmführer.
David!
Wait for me!
Heinrich, darling, we don't want to
play hide-and-seek.
Come to me, boy.
But i want to go to my friend!
I want to go to Toyland.
There is no Toyland.
Heinrich, come!
One moment.
Let us do that.
So handsome.
Like the mother.
Next time you don't scare your mother like that, promise?
We still need you.
Come, you'll go home.
Please excuse this trouble, madam.
Good Bye.
Scharführer, you have to explain how this mishap could happen.
Do we play again?