STALIN (Iron Man)
Subtitles translated by Arif chandio
SIBERIA 1917
My father had been exiled
Siberia for life
But history began to change
Russia was on the 3 rd year
in a bloody war with Germany
Tsar lost so many people that have
need and to fight for his enemies. he
But ... my father was not good enough
Joseph Visarionovici
Dzhugashvili, age 38 years
Born in Georgia in the province Gory
Exiled to Siberia ...
revolutionary activity
There was never
enlisted in the army
The subject has the following deformitatii:
Left hand with 2cm May
smaller than the right hand
Possibly a congenital defect
(congenital = occurred at birth)
2nd and 3rd finger from
welded and united left leg ...
... Sign of the devil ... Rejected!
My father was doing things,
to raise money for
Bolshevik Party (communist)
outlawed!
his favorite nickname was: Koba
Hunt during the day and night
play book with murderers and thieves
Our people are dying of hunger
Blamed on the Tar
And he was forced to abdicate
The new government has issued
all political prisoners
And the exiles my father
They were granted amnesty.
The wealth and nobility fled!
Koba are climbing, as
and Bolshevik leader Lenin -
My father's idol
Make your
Instead, make your place!
Sergei!
Many old friends were
there, as Srrghei and Olga Aleguia
Olga! How long was it
She e. ... Nadia!
Why are not there with
he? -I see him tomorrow!
Nadia would become my mother!
Olga, what a woman has come! ... Not yet
Thank you for
you have overthrown the tsar
But the great war still continues
You deposed the tar to them
continue the bloody war???
Nuuuuuuuuuuuuuu!
Did you overthrew the tsar as
peasants remain without land???
Nuuuuuuuuuuu!
Did you dethroned for tar. to
still die of hunger?
Nuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuu!
People ask
Peace, land, people ask bread
Prior to fulfillment
revolution, proletarian revolution!
It has been 6 months since blsevicilor
implemented for the end of the revolution ...
And install a communist government,
no one was allowed to own something
Tsar and his family were executed!
And a new war
started! Civil war!
Koba's favorite song, I thought
you forgot!-I remember!
Remember?-I remember
all you learned about it!
I remember how I saved
life when I drowned in the sea
Do not drown, water play, I was
caught by hand and you pulled to shore
I choked, and he swam to save me!
You were 3 years! -I remember!
Swan Lake!-Disc Nadia!
This is so old now!-But dedicated
May discuss theories with a
Greek-That I would love to hear
So Koba .. Not ... Stalin! -Stalin
-My new name! (Steel), but for.
you as a friend is always Koba!
-For Stalin!
-No! For Lenin!
Nadia became one of his secretaries
Lenin, a year later met with Stalin
Which was sent on the southern front
How did you go from the Secretariat?
It was your idea? What did you say?
How is civil war, I said
may be more useful?
Help! Help!
Stalin was pursuing him, him
look, to report about it!
- Not anything like that! It
help him!
So ... do you think Stalin needs
help from a girl of 19 years!
To assist you, to take notes-Who, but the
sal asked Stalin watch?
E Troska? Or Rumen?
Nadia believed that Stalin would
change Russia was right
You have a notebook and a pen
here, ready? -Da.-Write!
In ac. Stalin said compartment will
best for stabilizing Frontlit S
You decide, it will require! -But
just to collect supplies
Do not get involved in military activities?
-Stalin disobey orders
only if they agree with
-Always become a leader!
-Not always, no!-Yes!
Dad always said that you like
you! What else says?
You're a hero, daring robberies orgazizezi,
Knowledge, you are a giant among men!
I was humbled on a bed, son of
shoemaker and a woman of domestic
-You are unusual, surrounded by a
Aura .................................
-I was 15 when I wrote that
Look at you, our great commander!
Look at you, Commissioner
national chosen by Lenin himself!
Kalin Vorosevlov, this is Nadia
Alilujeva, daughter of Sergei
Nice, the mother's eyes
Your! -Greetings from Bolshevik to?
- Kulinkov, kavalencici-I
who are "Yes, you trust them?
Troska is, you? Troska's Commissioner
war, and Red Army commander.
-You agree with Troska or not?
-Not all! Welcome!
So you agree that we must be
vigilant? "Yes, absolutely, great vigilance!
Here's a list of officers, suspects,
call here soon!
-Trosky, should be informed!
-Trosky would not understand, we give!
- All officers on your
are here, as you asked Koba!
- What is the reason? I
fought for you bastards.
-Barge "not" to dive, be
f.atent would pierii all, be f.f.atent!
-24 Former and honest officers were suspected treason
... unfortunately they drowned accidentally
We will replace, with individuals
Reliable, This is Murder!
Murder, murder, he says it was an accident,
Officers were held on a boat that sank
And who put the boat? Officers
irreplaceable to kill! Stalin!
-Sky's call back soon!
-Stalin is a trusted companion!
Replace it, or resign!
Or Troska or Stalin!
-Troska or Stalin ... I understand
must be Troska and Stalin!
We need both! Trosky
not my father never forgave him!
They began to avoid each other even when
lived in the Kremlin with other communist leaders.
There my parents have celebrated wedding.
-Are you still so young!
-You were younger than me when you ran with my dad!
-Yes, but would have to see it when your father!
-It was so beautiful, an idealistic young revolutionary!
-Just like Koba
-Koba is not your dad
-you think it is too old?
-It is a Georgian, and no one except you Georgian
Now you do not agree!
But I want to be with him!
Be happy for me! For us!
Nadia, Nadia, Koba Username:
-Jesus is not come this far!
-Joy, joy eternal!
What joy. Nikolai always optimistic!
Yes always see the good
things, something that November 2 share!
French champagne, Nikolai
do the honors! Yes, Nadia health!
Unfortunately we could not get the
crystal Swarosky!-health, long life!
-Where you going?-Trosky
-kemenev, is a inrtelectual
Dad, do not have education and their manners were looking
top of him and he knew, were on his side Trosky
Trosky was the son of a prosperous landowner, which
enjoy all the privileges of wealth
And was regarded by many as a survivor
Lenin a French novel
- It's a better story, not far from
here Stalin and Nadia is married!
-You why you were not
invited? -Else?-NO
Get her up on your secretary!
-You unchanged, we have to work tomorrow, revolution, a request!
Will be there, but not early!
I could to do this
Long years ago,
My mother was mostly new Soviet woman,
continued to work chair and pregnant
Comrades, you have stopped doing history, for
that no one here to register?
-Do not worry, whatever will be written!
-Comrades, we have an agenda today, the Secretariat!
-How to improve work?
What is wrong with his work?
-Function of the structure go faster!
Practical problems of organizing the party!
Various problems that have to deal
members, description, etc., the Secretariat dealing with it.
-New is our easy to political office, all
you have to do is to think
-I think we should elect one of
November the Secretariat, the Secretary-General ..
So we have a direct connection with
subsidiaries, How have you comrade Trosky
I do not flatter myself with work, flateaza
a donkey, it flateaza Stalin
Please, please, no personal remarks!
Comrade Sinoviev? Are you interested?
-Il propose the Stalin-else?
-Yes Stalin?-Agree comrade. Stalin?
If nobody will do it! YES!
-Can I change the subject comrade. Lenin?
-Please!
-The war ended, he began a new era, the police should be held accountable
But all do what they want, all terrorizing the world.
True!-Tov.Buharin I think is right!
No brutatitate should be allowed, although
no revolution is not possible without the terror!
-What are you doing?
A drawing!
Just gave me so much power!
Control all regional leaders!
I do not know, neneorciti! Trosky,
Trosky, refufuza king Jews refuse!
You know what they gave me a reward for doing
up? A country house! know whose it was?
-Zubagov-Zubagov? -bastard against
I organized atacul.Trosky refuse!!
-What is it? All right?-Men! -What you
says to go to Georgia?
To break some heads of impreuna.Uni
Our old friends drive instead of their bows.
They need a kick in the ass! Come, All
what you need is a good pair of boots
Let go touch! Dad was something I
went to Tbilisi to work at a boot factory.
Shoemaker that he wanted to be, I ran, I came
home in a couple years ... I fought like hell.
But ... I never did
boots for someone not ... but you port!
And you know what is the best thing about
them? Boots hit a man in the head!
-It 's something pozarta boots
Sergei, wear boots!
-A healthy boy!
Vasily, gonna say
Vasily! Koba, Koba where?
-What happened?
-Koba, Koba's Lenin has just had a stroke!
-Can I talk to him?
-For when you ask permission?
-V.Ilici?-If you are asked to send
telegram that? ... for Secretary General
-It 's a copy?
-You urm.membri severely punish the Georgian Central Committee
-Where did that? -I know they came
in a fight but slapped the man!
-Your claims hit! - He insulted Sergo!
-Um Party member not attack another member!
- Not allowed!
- You have pain?
-No, no, it's nothing, it's an order
Sergo's to apologize!
E Georgian, he ... - I mean committee
Control-Who gave you the letter, who, who?
Sergo's come back Ordana immediately!
Immediately! -Com. they watch the story?
They want to turn against me, to divide
Party! Doctors said vau to rest to be calm
Calm, so why you stressing bastards, the
what? It will kill that's why!
But I will not allow it, I have a purpose, a mission
Put it on comrade. Lenin back on his feet!
-It can lead us again.
-I call the doctors! Job
that nobody wanted
Dad put the party leadership Securitate. Surround
ruthless people, chosen for loyalty to him.
Gaganovici, was one of them! E
arranged, we will know about anyone sound!
-Who arranged that? -Myself!
-Who knows about this? -Anyone?
-Make sure!
-Koba, Comrades!
Koba-know, as Lenin is ill
-Country needs leadership
-And Trosky is about to become a
-Lenin Of course not listen to another opinion
Yours in particular-Not even our Perera
-We thought you can turn to Lenin!
- Healthy, strong, able to solve our problems
difficult! - November, we could manage! -In the spirit!
-November???
-You (Stalin), I, and Zinovin!
-How many legs has a seat?
three
-Yes, that can not stay on 1 or 2
-Okay, okay
-What make way now?
-Let me take stupid!
-Trosky, comrade Lenin wants to see, said to be
to stand up against Stalin's not too late.
Nothing, ma'am. A little indigestion.
- We must help the
Lenin now! -Hands!
-Where is it?
-Do not be upset!
What fai?
-I read some of my essays!
-They went again to f.interesant
I see now how stupid I was then
-I made? -Yes! ... Read
official reports ... -Doctors say ...
-Answers to your face, make it about you
And organizational, yes ... but doctors say
-It was not tired
-Do not get tired, reading: reports, newspaper
-Newspapers? -Yes real newspapers, not paperwork
they have chosen you for me
-Not one scrap for Lenin
cribs full of good news
-You raised money just to get you out of policy?
-It will help healing
-Nooo, I are out policy!
-No!
-So you do not know what's happening in the country, n
I allowed to read their own newspapers
Leave it to your comrade Lenin read
fairy tale that abureli that damned abureli
It's not that you do well, we need you,
for your healing, leadership comrade. Lenin
How comrade. Lenin lead ...
if you is denied access to information
- It will help ... doctors orders
- Doctorileor orders? -Yes
-Not Stalin's orders? -NO-situation
in Georgia, you're georgiaan, you ...
-One should not be
worry! I help
-Why did you call Troska, crazy bitch,
I think that to know ... what you want, kill him?
-Lenin is dead!
Intelesm Dad, how much they complain
Russians new god, now that religion was illegal
Was the idea of him smelling the
Lenin put him in Red Square to the
-Com. Molotov, where e Com. Trosky? Parca had to
sal find him and bring there, what happened?
-I found ... I said to imormantarea
was yesterday but was too far to reach
-You lied, why? -You
said he did not want him here!
-Not one to admit this to anyone it or not?
-Yes
-Then why are you telling me? You
some Molotov to reach a far
Leaving us, comrade. Lenin ordered us
inaintre to look and be pure
A major requirement for the party
Leaving our comrade. Lenin urges us
To remain united: Party!
Together swear to it
honor the word! Tov.Lenin!
I had a quarrel in the morning
-About what?
-Nikolai!
-What, like I like?
-Nikolai, I
offered a job at a new magazine: Culture and Revolution!
Joseph, said that next. thing that I will waste
time are some peasants as a useless poets
-And you said are useless? -I said no
are useless-I said it is far from useless
-Russia cultural needs-exactly-then
I put my arms around him and apologized!
-Then you make love
It's a terrible thing like the death of Lenin,
That it happens now, who will lead?
-Joseph said the strain on the back or
-Who?
-Time to incepem.Sena!
-Yes
--
Charming flowers, their life is too small
-What happened?
-Phone, call ... they found a letter
What letter???
A letter which Lenin trimiso the Committee
center to be opened after his death!
What say? -I know nothing
about it? -No, nothing?
Working with Lenin's nearest you, you have
heard anyone speak about it!
-Lie?
-They do not know anything about it!
He reached bitch: Trosky
You called success!
Trosky, Karmaniev, Zinoviev
Those, 3 small kids
-Do not say that!
-Mice!
If the committee is Georgian
an understanding with them, then ...
Com. Lenin also wrote: Stalin is too
brutal and these become intolerable
From one that has the function of
Secretary General therefore proposed comrade
To consider the removal of Stalin
ac.pozitie and the appointment of another person
May patient, more loyal, more
caring and less ...
Trosky Tro .. ... .. sky instead Trosky
Stalin to be Trosky, talk!
-Do it, you only can we get rid of
Stalin! -It 's too stupid to know what to do
Please, please! For each one of us cuv.lui
Lenin had a purpose and a different meaning!
But in the period in which comrade. Lenin did not
could lead fell per new actions. task!
Com. Kazemiev, Zenovia and Stalin
to provide collective leadership!
Our experience makes me happy to
I say: The statement comrade. Lenin is wrong
So aim to keep it on Stalin
the item or-This is outrageous
-Lenin was sick! -Lenin was right,
should listen to him talk Trosky
-To say that Lenin had
right-betrayed you!
Yes, comrades are cruel to those who hate
party, I hid it and not hide it now
It's good to be kind, but you must know when
I am free to be cruel to keep my job
The 2 times I tried to quit and 2
times I was told to rasman the current position.
I obey the party's obligation
me to stay on my position.
Trosky has wasted the last chance to stop
underestimated the human father that you consider a donkey
-I am James!
-Your son!
-I know!
-What are you doing here?
Came to Moscow to study!
-It is better here in Tbilisi, I mean schools
-think you can come here without me???
-Get out, go, outside, go
-I gave your son a camera
-No, no, no, do not worry, it will be fine!
"Why Joseph? Why? I never
You said you were a child, why?
When his mother had died 2 months, not
have you seen since then, why?
You hated it? -Don 'You Baby?
-He was a young woman georgian
-Uneducated, religious ...
-So do you love?
-She was young, I was young
-Not even talked about it!
-Nadia's dead!
-Yeah, the door is closed, the room is sealed?
-And you do not ever think to
it? Voldemort is dead-And if I die?
-Do not say that-If you die,
Vasily abandon him?
-I 've abandoned
James, I left with his sisters
-Who has a
Vasily let him?
-Get your
mind-n cap!
-Another child?
What child?
-The port that you are pregnant!
-Are you pregnant?
-Why did not you say, the
what? -I should, but ...
Leave it to James to stay!
Joseph???
-Look
conspirand at them? E Trosky vs me, me vs. Trosky
-I guess I get to
top ... You attack me first
-Comrades, do not
I let them do that, friend of Lenin's Trosky
My Tatl, comrades stop it!
-E Trosky, Lenin's friend, Father
My! It's incredible what happens!
1801-Alexander 1 has banned the use of torture
Word said torture is a disgrace brought mankind
-James helps to prepare for. exams
-You agree with Alexander?
-Are you or disagree?
To have a discussion: to say to you
a military commander, not to be but ...
Say ... you hold a prisoner with inside information
vital that your master can save lives ...
It's stubborn, does not want to
talk, you spit in the face
-What are you doing, James?
-I ... .. do not know
You let people die? James?
-What about it?
-Torture is bad!
-My son ... incereci to
teaching him the idiot that irreversible,?
-Mr. a copy of Lenin's Testament
-How did you asked!
-Printed letters of a printing
drought in Leningrad (St.Petersburg)
-Stalin is too cruel ... and
What role Zinobie here ..
-Zinobie???
-Do you think this could happen without the complicity of?
-Temporary maneuver!
Sergo, I guess you could ...
Maybe you could persuade the members
Congress to get rid of: Zinobie
Find a replacement! A Communist
good, eye-catching personality
But ... who?
-Kirov???
-Kirov?
-Have you worked with him in the Caucasus?
-Yes, she knows how to move things.
-A good man, the world is like! Read
books, likes music, a good friend.
-Very good Sergo, very good! Why not me
-I thought it about it? Very good.
-Tov.Kirov!
-Com. Kirov!
-Tovarsi!
-Good to see you!
-You killed you Inns?
-From a single fire!
What distance?
-10 Meters
-Wait, wait ... were you at 10 that?
-I believe that ... who would do that?
You could do it?
You do you not?
-You go to Leningrad to
it replaces Zinobie! Go and Sergo and Gagaovici
I rely on you!
10 feet !!!!!!!!!
Shot that
from 10 meters Zigoda
10 feet who could believe this?
You have to admire a man like
this, and to supervise
Go to Leningrad and be watching
they. The customized on it, especially the Kirov
My parents, my brother Vasily and I,
was on my way south to house winter
And stopped in every state, the father can
muscles show party local authorities
Convened there
Regional party boss
Lavreti Beria
-What to do?
-Yields have been good ... I
fields seen from the train
-The state required peasants to work for the good townspeople!
-There is trouble in my district!
-But grain is not delivered, why?
-That 's because the peasants were told that
if prices are expected to get better
To become rich at the expense
others who he said that, who?
-Com. Stalin, I'm not sure that you understand the situation!
-The state offers low prices, unreasonable!
Party officials do not understand
peasantry, come to villages threatening
Peasants complain that the then NDA Buy
grain not receive anything in return!
-There is nothing for them to buy!
I asked, what to do and I
You gave answers? NOT only complaints
You gave me a solution, not
so I give you a mine:
You will begin selling all provisory
Wheat in existing ppreturile
Whoever refuses, it will
be confiscated grain!
-You bring everyone you poune in
before the law based on art.107 of the Penal Code
What you must remember contain
severe penalties, for any type of speculation
They are indicative of your, this
measures will be applied to all your U.R.S.S.
Thanks for your ideas!
80% of the population were farmers who lived in
remote areas and isolated from the control of the party
For dad, it
represent a real danger
Those that could not control them
could later become foes
And you could cut your throat when you
barbiere are, or you drown in a pit.
-I have children, understand me!
-Comrade, please!
Lavrenty Beria, entered the house
Our first date for that year!
-Zvidana I had to
see him often, always, I'm scared!
-It 's a pervert!
-Beria?
-Sergo, met in Georgia, even
before becoming party chief
He kidnapped a girl, one raped her,
forced her to marry him
Lead by around one ever sees
she loves and says: Bring thio here!
Then he says: "If you do not want to be
something happen to you or your family ... "
-Sergo, he hates! -Why not
Joseph says something? -He said
-And your husband said, "See
your own business "just
A talk I with him
-Declare war on the peasants, forcing them
to give up their own land
And collective farms to move to state
Already they hoard seeds you go
-There will be famine!
-Bukharin're too bland!
-There are reports that some villagers have been shot,
without trial, thousands are sent to LAGRA: Why?
You have to starve to feed the country for
cities? Politburo's never agree
-I know everyone's position
-But Lenin, Lenin always said that the party must debate
-Do not try to
bring him to Lenin in Lenin that Bukharin guy
-I 'm going back to Moscow
What happens to Nikolai?
-Joseph not to stand against anyone cushion
-As you know Trosky sent into exile not forgive, not
Remember, Sena does not trust anyone, not even Sergei
Sergi, mine? The oldest
Friend, you imaginzi things
He hates his own son: James, you humiliate, not
single people are creatures of his close
This evil pervert
Beria, not coming here again
Gaganovici Molotov or Rosilov them.
-He loves you!
-That one is ...
-James
-What happened? -He wants to
married, do not leave.
-Why? Who? Jewish-And-E?
-So? Want to marry a Jewish
-How can you say that?
-How do you feel that?
-Bring a doctor, fetch a doctor and take
Vasily it on here
-Stupid, not even to shoot
I able
James survived, but
my mother's soul was hurt
-Nadia? What is in
Leningrad? -I left!
-Nadita not understand!
-No, you do not understand!
-I see, Of course I understand
Want to call us?
Not yet, no!
You had an argument?
He became suspicious of all
the world is vicious and cruel!
May have some time
heavy Koba! Not Koba, e Stalin (Steel)
Of course it's Stalin, should be
Where Stalin as Russia if not Stalin!
E, is wrong with you? S good to others, you
said many times that he likes children
-E else?
-I
- No, of course not, it loads all the selfishness pb
peasants, saboteurs ... country is in crisis needs you
-Sergei! -Don 't
can desert her husband
-Are you tired, stay here a few days
-Okay, well you call me explain to you're tired ...
-You need time
Nadia, think carefully and calmly
-If not come back, what will happen to him?
-With each of us!
-You wife of Comrade Stalin
-You Children's
You do not understand, there are an average person
-Probably ingrijprat it you do not know where you are
-Hello?'s OK!
-It 's your husband wants to talk to you!
-Koba, comes
-If you go to Moscow, says
Comrade Stalin's what happens
Tell him that we took all the land,
all food, all life
We sent away, comrade
Stalin does not know
Tell him, tell Comrade Stalin
-Beria, no bother your wife, i stay on track
-You say that's a wonderful dancer, telling it to show us
-Don 'opri.canta, sing!
-Nadia, hope you come
-So you back, uh, uh
-I have a message for you
-My wife delivers messages!
-From an old woman
-My wife delivers messages from the old woman
-The train stopped at a station, on one side was a
scary train, wagons full of people deported
Dead bodies thrown himself, a
station, many others are?
A woman running at me and begging me
tell Stalin, Stalin's great that people are dying of hunger
If only they knew the great Stalin, and would save people but
here you celebrate the 15th anniversary of the revolution
Comrade Stalin and his friends feeding
while starving his people
-For that was the revolution?
-Sing, sing!
-I 'm so calm!
-I loved the Seine, I loved! ... Not forgive me
Never one to punish me, punish everyone
-Maybe you should go for a while
-Where, where Stalin's wife can go?
A die of hunger, or a camp so I send in a
a camp
-No, I would do that!
-No, you think Nuuuuu???
A talk I with him
-No, just watch
-Protect
yourself, take care
-You go somewhere, you're right
-I will go with you-NO
-We are friends, but you have to go
only, to go alone, just leave
-You are right
-You take care of everyone but I'm gone!
-Depends on you for that
Sena, I love you!
Koba, Koba!
-Cover
-a.
-I
He told Nadia to let empty inside
-Deasta not come to imormantare?
-My friend has buried heart today!
Heart-He buried his heart with a
lying country known to have died of appendicitis
-Yeah, baby, yeah killed
a, yes killing millions in the country and give our eyes are closed
-Who are we, what are we now?
Why have you betrayed? Why?
Tatl my hunger called and sold in a fairy tale
grain to other countries would have save his own people
He used the money to our country of peasants industralizeze
day and night, people were forced to make our country great
Stalin greatest!
All I knew was that my mother was
dead for 2 years And we missed it
-Wake up, wake up
Sleepyhead them!
-Wake up-Hey, why not me
servant brings tea? Why?
-E went to a wedding!
-You got it!
-Thanks!
-Not just us who we
feel threatened, is the world!
We need a strategy
new, must unite the world!
-Are you an idealist so Bucharin!
-Where is the bride? This is for the bride!
-Ana Mikalovna
-For years waiting to be old enough to drink it.
-Thanks Uncle Sergei-and this is
pt.tine Nikolai! What, what is it, a fox!
I had this creature in baatia
deserted, but he looked right in my eyes
Here is a renaissance said, would
I need to take as a gift
-If he was dead enough
-Yes ... as you have won the girl!
-I l
I won him, and it was not easy, I pretended to be younger than him
So I will make a toast now!
-Nikolai, gentle and beloved husband, who believes in the good of the people, for good
-To Nikolai
-Another guest
-Bucharin, congratulations, I
Forgot Congratulations!
-Daddy!
You thought Nikolay to marry her,
and Stalin not know! Nikolay, Nikolay!
It amazes me again with all you love
Nikolai, loves Stalin, Lenin loved
Girlfriend, my girlfriend Nadia, loved it!
It's not right?
The beautiful bride, and will wish to
both the greatest happiness!
Kirov, I want to talk
Should we go to Leningrad? -To
what? -There are people who want your head, believe me!
-People that I suspect not, believe me!
People raised on you!
-Have you placed a man of yours
in Leningrad? -The Central Committee
-Central Committee without consult me
sent a man to the NKVD (KGB) in Leningrad
Would have a deputy, can 2 people
-Thanks comrade. Stalin must go back to Leningrad
Kirov was a popular man, people were returning against
Dad and saw Kirov their best chance of rescue
My father knew a
Yes yes! Um time!
-E Stalin!
That summer my dad
reorganized national security
And appointed chief Yagoda
Dad had many homes, but one in which
most was sitting next to Moscow
It was a fortress, with walls and guards, my father started
to spend most of their time behind ac.ziduri
-Charlie Chaplin
Yagoda, Charlie Chaplin!
Each film had seen in Russia
be approved personally by the father
He loved most American films,
musicals, movies mafia, comedy
Charlie Chaplin was his favorite
-The material prepared gentlemen?
-Yes, Koba!
-You can go, that's not interesting Svetlana!
-And how to go back without me?
-Oh, no
you worry about me. Dad, go, go!
-L
I met comrade. Kirov last night ... a very popular not?
-Is-You worked
together in Leningrad-Yes
-It is a charismatic leader, always exceptional, and always insistent decisive
-Yes
Do you think it's aware of that?
-Aware of what Comrade Stalin?
-The conspiracy was
it make him general secretary in my place!
-It is difficult to know comrade. Stalin
-It 's your job to know!
-Get in the car comrade. Kirov, even
fire curtains, for safety
-For safety
buddy, I got you
-Com. Medved, NKVD
-You were responsible for security comrade, Kirov?
-Yes, tov.Stalin!
-Com. Nikolai, why, it
You killed the comrade. Kirov, why?
-I, I ... -Do not lie, do not
you can lie on comrade. Stalin!
-Do not have acted alone, so who you
helped?
-Comrade Yagoda
-No, no, not him
You never saw comrade. Yagoda before today!
Never-l
You never saw comrade. Yagoda before today, is this true?
-Else you hired to kill comrade.
Kirov Zinobie one of his men, correct?
-But, do you remember who ..
need help to remember!
Wife and mother are arrested
not want to be free?
You send in her
a new place, a new house, a new bodyguard, will be f.comfortabil!
But what you have to
remember me?
-What did you say: names, places
all what you think!
-Get confession from him!
Grisham-Come, come with me!
First Kirov is killed by a murderer
staff that acted alone!
-Now I say it's probably a conspiracy -
it was a conspiracy-Whose?
-E as the burning Reichstag, do
even blame the Nazis and communists
-What?
"Why not come to me?
-Fox has her mind, even a red
Has now become a murder him criticisms
father or his policies became treason
-Bukharin and my daughter, beautiful
his wife and ... fox
He called fox-Grisham, your name Zinoviev
-It is a common name!
-Yes of course!
But Bukharin and allow the
fox named after you!
Admit it!
-Maybe .... but not me
said never-Admit it!
-Yes-Yes, he called
fox for you
-Yes, Bukharin and
fox named after me!
See, it's easy to tell the truth, so you
what all i remember comrade. Yogoda and Yezov?
-Are too good to you?
Koba let me tell you of our common experience
the police Tsar was mild compared to ...
-Where is the Tsar now?
-Koba us know, we fought side by side in the old regime!
I fought side by side with you
-Under the leadership of Lenin himself
-How do you think you conspired with Trosky, to
kill comrade. Kirov
-Traitor!
However, tell us how
Comrades Zinobie, Kamenev ...
Together with Trosky ...
How do you find these 'confessions',
as were obtained?
-You can say Koba
Can not understand law!
-Highly important
crimes ... among children
-Children 12 and over are subject to all
measures punishments criminals, including
-Including death, including death
-Tell tov.Kamenev about
evidence against son
Your son was under surveillance,
near Vila comrade Stalin near Moscow
-Trying to kill
Stalin-Can, is only 14 years
-Evidence-Inventions-Evidence
-My son never ...
How can you ask us to say that
Yachim was Hitler, who would believe that?
-Anyone hear or read your confession, and
everyone in the world will hear, read and think!
Showtime
You have to be closed
Wagons full of comrade.
old that you want? Gheizov ..
-If we agree, promise or
Another old comrade will not be executed!
Their families will pati-nothing
Family, is important
-And as our lives!
Of course, if you sign!
-Koba
He said that our family does not
will suffer, we said, promised ....
-We have been promised life if you confess
Tov.Stalin has revoked the promise
-Shut up!
-Be brave, that man aratele
were you when I was with Lenin
-It is impossible-I
killed ... and I said
To keep one. Toast for. Nikita Nikita
Khrushchev new head of Moscow!
You beat a long way from
Ukraine, Nikita for you!
-For Nikita!
Show hands again !..., dirt under nails will come to
believe that Stalin's mass comes from mud under nails
-How bad!
-Coming from the field!
-Look
ac.domni you to have clean hands and manechiura done, look
These hands do not work, hands
These are the hands of a gentleman, raise your nails
-All the hands of the Lord and
looked, peasant origin, Nikita
-For Nikita!
-Do it on the other, on the other,
Zinobie take him on again!
-I am surprised that you have not seen
their execution, Zinobie and Karmeniev!
-M very happy!
-Oh, I do not have what it takes!
-N would be the first execution I
assisted-No, but you're still a pharmacist
You are good to do poisons, death
slow, plots, conspiracies, to assist!
Yezou will replace
Take them back to Moscow!
-Fucking bastard ... will
come and your turn
-Hany, Hany: Kamenev and
Zinoviev, were shot
Not only them .. and I heard a
rumor, I was involved and me! -What?
-How can it?
-In these days all is possible!
Com. Old grudges, one after altulti comrade., and
involve other and trying to save
-If Lenin would have lived
-Sss, watch
-Yes, yes, all these strange things that I have
have happened, he knows I understand why he was killed Kirov
I saw the empire or a table
conspirators accused of conspiracy around the world
-Mandate evacuation of an hour!
-But, how can my books, work
my wife, our baby
These are orders
my outside ... one time!
-Hello?
-Nikolai, what are you doing?
-Are you there, I am Koba, how things
-Are released!
-House is full of soldiers
-Well, give him the fuck out!
-Put your phone now mn
their boss! -For you, tov.Stalin!
-Hello, who gave you orders
those, who, who? -Com. Yezov!
-Com. Yezov??? Com. Yezov is an idiot, get
from there, go now, out, out!
-You say that Stalin has
Yezov sense of humor?
-I came to drink with your husband?
-You wait!
You gave flowers to the grave
Nadi, yesterday? -Give Thanks
-For you, open
a!
-Nikolai Bukharin is an enemy of the people, so no
one of us is nesuspicios
-Yes ... yes .... yes
-You know what happens?
-No?
-I thought so, they are
Dangerous times Sergo
-We become stronger, hell
Our enemies can not accept something
Enemy agents infiltrated everywhere, including on
high position, doing its best to destroy our economy
And wanted to pursue it after
Stalin's murder of Kirov's assassination
-We need your help Sergo
-Il's
-I want to declare against Bukharin!
-Bukharin?
-Yes to oppose him, using the Sena against Analarina, you are in a knot
a rope, Bukharin trusts you
A davada of your friendship by Stalin
State proves your loyalty
-You want me to renounce the Bukharin, as you can judge him
and shoot him, why go through all this?
Do it simply, our great
leader defends Soviet people, Look!
-Do it you! Shoot
Bukharin yourself on!
Have the courage! -Put it down, I
seen guns, I'm not scared!
-Put
it down!
-So it will
denounce the Bukharin-No
-When your own brother you
He denounced you?
Sergo brother confessed to you, you gave
order as Commissioner of heavy industry
For acts of sabotage
and smuggling is a fact
-My brother confessed?
-I have to admit, there have been too many accidents, too many
You let my brother being beaten, tortured,
Bring him to Moscow, I want to see you both!
-Too late!
-Too late?
-Too late
-Bastard!
A kill us all! -Sergo, Sergo, not
no, no tov.Stalin shoot him!
If you do as a country in chaos, would invade fascists would take
country and you go down in history as the man who betrayed Russia
And people ... people you would
Ask yourself why did you kill
Everyone who wears your name
family will be torn to pieces
I will eat your heart, you will drink blood
No, do not you shoot tov.Stalin
-I think you'll shoot yourself!
And we will call a heart attack ... the comrade.
Argenichitze occurred following his exhausting work!
Hero of Soviet Union: The
May the glorious dead
And we will bury you with all honors
Near the Kremlin walls,
near Lenin's tomb
Nobody will ever find that
You betrayed the party and country!
And your family should be
saved, honored this promise
-Promise? -S all
Sergo you have left!
-Wait, you were a
seminar you recognize words
Chair when they sinned as I have dark
trial and suffering soul with guile as
-E in the Book of Job
The power of God, perished in
breath of His nostrils they are consumed
Dad, he kept the word of the day
this, Sergo imormantarea received a hero
His ashes were deposited into the wall
Kremlin and escaped unharmed Sena
-Dad
-Since my daughter has become leads the door?
-Com. leads the
doors! Where did that dress?
-It 's too short! Cover
your knees!
And look at your feet ... is empty
Change your dress, when you go to cmparaturi !!!!!!
-You were at his imormantarea
Sergo, why? -It felt good!
-A to call a doctor!
-Koba, say something, do not bother!
Gonna lose you too, so
Take care, Sergo, had!
-Tough life!
-Yes, we take a flight, as on a branch pasariele
-As a branch pasariele on ... sorry
me is an old woman not understand anything
-So how is it that suddenly you have a lot of enemies???
-Olga!
There are people I know of one life, are
army officers, party members loyal
-Friends, heroes of the civil war, what happens,
what happens? Why these people die? Can you tell?
-And why everyone who knew my daughter, everyone who loved
Nadia
Disappear, are arrested, who's
destroy, are you?
-For God!
What we will arrest them all?
-Yes, why not?
-Koba ... shut up
woman, shut up?
Why shut-up? I said you had said. Now, let
him to kill me and me
You duso on my face to
suicide, committed suicide because of you
It's much better now, you look much, much more
well is much better, tov.menajera!
My Princess!
-Accused Bukharin!
-Accused Bukharin, you heard the testimonies of others
witnesses that was part of conspiracy dintr0o
Under the great traitor
Trosky, to overthrow the Soviet regime
For this purpose, numerous acts of terrorism, have
were committed including the assassination of Sergei Kirov
And even a plan
assassinate him tov.Stalin
What miserable bunch of traitors!
I heard in the office: what
miserable bunch of traitors!
Confession is good for their souls
-And now Bukharin
The highlight of our game
We all heard what you did, you talked
with him, a plot to kill Sergei Kirov
-I
I can not imagine why he said that there was also a discussion
-I know nothing about any
scheme-kill the Kirov
-Not
did you do to give, how could you fail?
-Korol, Korol said you said ...
You had months and months ...
-Get it on my hand for a night, it was a
are to confess it's the King of England
-I
have done my duty, I did everything you asked, even my own deputy, myself busy mother of his
-Officials, commanded you, plotting against
Stalin, and you assume you're not involved?
-Involved in what? Yourself you did kill them
operators of power to get new people
-Yes, yes monster, but want to
tell me you left delibert people to be persecuted, killed
-What did you do Yezov? How could you
pay for your terrible crimes?
-To Com. Stalin!
-I beg to
spare my wife and child
On March 12, 1938, without warning, the military
German crossed the border with Austria
There was just a total invasion test
And Hitler triumphantly entered in Vienna!
-Abnormal development-think? Not know ... gotta
admire Hitler stuie wants and not afraid to get it
-I scare the British and French
but not on Comrade Stalin
-It is a fascist, wants to destroy us, one always says
-There are a lot of things you do with all
-I think now Hitle looked eastward, and
says: That is Stalin, can work with it
-So it arranged?
-I am personally concerned
-A z5s something? -He
required to give you that!
-Koba, why you needed
of my death, why?
-What you know about Trosky, as we
to slip through your fingers?
-E in Mexico City, and that house was turned into
a fortress
-Why do not you get rid of it?
Jacob grew to SC. military and joined the army all
in a vain attempt to win approval of the father
-You have a niece!
-You want to become a gunner!
-Yes, do you mind if I call?
-I hope you do not dust our lines!
-I will do my duty!
-The full length of the central comandamentu
Lieutenant like you can order division
-I will do whatever is asked of me!
-James!
-So what is the situation here?
Germans attack all
-Panzerele (tanks) them, we
lines were broken, they control the skies aviation
I lost 1000 planes apropare
-1000, How can that be?
-Most was destroyed ala ground
-On the ground???
-Despite warnings and recommendations
were left on the ground in paragraphs into lines
-No, counterattack: here, here, here, here
and here!
-You do not understand the situation, our front collapses,
retreat to try to avoid to be captured
-No catch, no withdrawal without
teaching, attack! Beeeeria! Beria!
-Bring the troops of the Security, shoot
anyone who tries to pull
-Shoot our people???
-Yes and I will shoot you too stupid inconpetent!
-Koba! How can you say that? Who killed
the best of our generals?
40,000 of our finest officers
called them enemies of the people, he shot
Who trusted Hitler?
Who said that we will attack?
Voroshilov? Nu.Ai was you. Was it you!
Comrade!
Koba!
The past 10 days
We are waiting on you, no one
can do nothing without you
Koba, we love you!
I call on you!
Comrade Stalin!
Save us!
Save Us
tovarare! Save us!
Klim!
-I
could kill!
- How can? No
Stalin's orders!
Comrades, citizens, brothers and sisters
We are united in a patriotic war against
an enemy that trying to make people
-Your son ... Jacob was taken prisoner
The slaves of the Germans!
I resist, and we will annihilate the enemy!
We will show no mercy
Hitler will go the way of Napoleon
To defeat, to despair
And to his death
-N
I have no son named Jacob
No
What do I expect???
Only I saw my dad
during the war
When he learned that James was killed when
evadeza try a German camp
It never told me Germans
came to the gates of Moscow
And surrounded Stalingrad
When finally I sent back
27 million of us died
Only at the end of the war, the imormantarea
grandfather, my father again reviewed
It was the first time the family
We met after years of good
-At least Sergei knew! I did
everything I could: the best doctors
Died of silence, not cancer
-Si
the closed mouth while his friends, his companions were imprisoned, killed
-You
your mouth shut! What did you old bitch?
-Look
Go to my son, generally, I believe it You can stay on your own feet Vasily
-And you Svetlana? Not use that as an excuse to
bring your husband around Jew by
What iai learn? You made my son a
drunk! And ... my daughter really need to say ...
-What could I expect? You
You taught his daughter to be her loyal husband ??????
And you tried to turn him
against me! Sergei, but he knew me!
Sergei I knew
On drunk, put him in jail a
time, wake him curse My family ... you are!
Soviet Ukrainian thank
our great liberator tov.Stalin
The best friend of all children!
Soviet bielorusieni thanks great
Our leader: geniulul tov.Stalin pt. victory
No, thanks comrade. Stalin for a victory
We all know that Stalin did not beat the Germans
-Tovarare, to be serious
No, thanks tov.Stalin
for our victory!
Our thanks
go to the great Russian people
Your victory is a statement to the world
the Russian people believe in a better future
And it's ready to sacriificile
necessary to obtain large building ...
In the winter of 1950
father sent for me
I hear you leave And as the memory
is suspicious of everyone around him
Now he wants to see me, and
pt. first time his nephew: Joseph
-Go
Go to Grandpa!
-His eyes are a Jew
-Look who is man?
-Someone who ensure that everything is okay!
-It puts so many questions!
-Why?
-Because they are things that need to know
-Why, why Why, why, why?
A real Jew, a? Ha, haha
Car-always something, for squirrels, see?
-Look, it feeds you, keep a
so! Nurtures it, feeds it!
Why you look-that?
-I want to release Anna Bucharin!
-It is a beautiful red-tailed, right?
Do not touch a bite!
-Mind your own business, you have the slightest
idea of what you talking about? -Is harmless!
-What you know about harmless, what the hell knew?
-I know people disappear ... again
-Enemies ... take your mother speaks
-N
have no connection with the Soviet Union Enemies ...
-Grandpa's cute!
For a man your age,
have a remarkable constitution
It is said that men from the Caucasus, they say
that is, I can ride a horse, or a woman
But still, you had problems with balances
Blood pressure and ...
is dangerously high
What you recommend?
-As little work as possible!
-Fruits, vegetables, vitamin injections!
-No injections!
-O to write a prescription
-No recipe, my own cure!
-Go, not work, rest
you, not what was said and Lenin?
-Thanks Gutterman, you can go now!
-Taste-a Lavrenty (beer)!
-I do not like soup!
-Taste
a!
-How is your dad spends
time with a bunch of old people boring?
-Where you going?
-Home
-No, I stay, I promise I will
become interesant.Ia place!
-Have you eaten? Lavrenty ... have fun
Fun at the expense of Nikita!
-Dance Nikita!
-Oh no! -Dance!
-Do not be shy, dancing
-Come on, we know you're very good
-Lavrenty not stay here!
-Let me me
drew breath
-I aged!
-No, no!
-No, no, no, no, to live forever!
-Yes,
It may be necessary!
Who would come after Stalin? Who
may follow after Stalin?
-None of you deserve, so
I will get rid of all of you
-Soup they eat ... is poisoned
You can see that I have not touched mine
-Dad
-Kidding, Koba ....
-No, no ...
-You must kidding
-Now you see ... fun
-You all ... what do you think s
would happen?
Without Stalin!
Svetlana ..... Come!
Come here! Close the door! Come Here!
I loved your mother! Beautiful!
She was silly, she does not understand
sitautia What happened, what to do
He heard of some people
And turned against me
He became my enemy
And then I betrayed Suicide
You killed yourself! ... To start
plotting against me ... why
-It was your fault ... you
has cost
You just like her ... listen to my enemies
they're full of venom, as has also
So how did she leave
You turn against me
I know who I am, and a
to have great care of them
You do not know what you think: I know
Stalin knows ... I know what you think
What are you ... who you know fuck all
-Get out!
-Dad
-This is a picture for you!
-Thanks!
-Too bad he died
..... My time has come .......
Here's a piece
Come with us, please!
-Are you a doctor, right? Well catch
her hands properly
-I 'm sorry ...
-Bleeding in the brain ... not ...
maybe ... ... Please
-Let
him to suffer!
-Asshole fucking
-I
You asked ... why Beria expected to call one days until the doctor?
-If m
I asked?
-We try to take power
will be as bad as before
-You said it
bad-I said
-You said, right? But what will
said after Stalin died?
-About what?
-Its crimes!
What crimes?
-Millions ...
-Nikita, you're too sentimental, talking too much, who are we to
judge him by Stalin?
-Without it we would have a Tier 2 country, now look
at us
Controlled half of Europe, all
China, We have the atomic bomb
Order will be honored without
Stalin We would have taken 20 years plus
-I believe that
-No purges, arrests, murders ...
Without Stalin, I could be a big country
-How to History asked Stalin?
-Dad? Dad?
-Stop
you please ... not see that he died???
Without you all the tar is lost
At 3 months after the death of Stalin, Lavrenty
Beria was executed by his former associates
3 years later, Nikita Khrushchev began the public
to reveal the nature and extent of Stalin's crimes
Svetlana Alliluyeva is alive
and lives in England (1992)
Iosiv Stalin's crimes have caused the deaths of tens of
million (approximately 50) of Soviet citizens (and others)
ENDING