Colonel Claus von Stauffenberg.
Attention.
Explain to.
Long live our sacred Germany.
Fire.
Is it all began?
- Hurry up. Forward.
Loge 19. We are too late,
but can you for this one time...
The Führer is there too.
You should only go after the break.
Oh, it's just begun.
And the best music is loud.
Make an exception for an officer
who, like the Führer loves to Wagner.
Be quiet and stay behind the curtain.
Just after the break may visit your place.
There he is.
Do you see those eyes.
He really enjoys full teugen.
He loves that music.
And he loves soldiers.
- Me too.
That bodes well
for our future.
Will you marry me?
- What?
Not, It is not so difficult. Will you marry me?
- You're not all there.
Can I make an offer?
Dear Nina, we are
so far encountered by land...
that we have two days right
Poland and left move the masses.
The country is desolate,
just sand and dust.
It is inconceivable crowd.
Many Jews and mixed blood.
A nation that is only
under the knout feels good.
Everywhere you see sad poverty
and dining.
The thousands of prisoners will
our economy a disservice.
We knew that a campaign against
Russia would not be easy.
This kind of slaughter.
- Henning, you exaggerate.
Here things happen, Claus,
just behind the front line...
that my imagination to go upstairs.
Your troops do not believe you found
if you tell them.
Tell him what you saw.
She was suddenly tonight
to my door, exhausted and confused.
Can you get that letter in your unit
question? He is faster than in Berlin.
It is a woman...
Child. Small child. Man.
Old man, is difficult.
Move, move. Walk.
Come on, dirty jew.
Command to stop. Undress.
Please, don't.
Beautiful woman, old man.
Everybody cries.
Very little.
So small.
Lots of crying.
My baby. So many crying.
Nothing child, please.
In her village, in Krupka,
that is not so far away...
has a German unit
citizens from their home.
Children, elderly, women,
men. She received a Execution by shooting.
912 people, almost the entire village.
These were her parents
and her brothers and sisters.
There are also other villages.
Not in this area over 30,000
why people have to be made.
Unbelievable.
They are people like us.
I think that breeds hatred intolerable.
They took us as liberators.
I hear they are still welcome.
There is only one possible solution.
Hitler must go.
Now? While the war is in full swing?
We have sworn an oath.
He has already sworn a hundred times
trampled.
Time is running out.
Dear Nina, there are days that you never
most of his memory is erased.
Times when we doubt
to everything we think and do.
I've never been so serious doubts
to my profession and my life now.
East Prussia, 1943
That bastard.
What is a bastard Hitler. I hope
klojo ending in hell.
He knows not what he says
if he is drunk.
He let hundreds of thousands of people
die in the bloody Stalingrad.
However, it stops cold.
He is so almost anything.
General, and kept to himself. He is also
still head of the intelligence service.
And you should not yell.
It should be just,
otherwise I explosive.
Which is insensitive bastard
only with themselves busy.
His people can not give a damn him care.
- Now it is enough. Can you help me?
Yes, of course.
Who are you?
You're right.
Die-Russia military exercise is considered
's disaster. And also in humanitarian terms.
If you knew what officers
the intelligence service such as hear...
You can not better
discuss somewhere else?
Come on.
Dear Nina, with open eyes, I see
our country towards its downfall.
But I can do nothing against.
My work in the General Staff
is meaningless.
I would like to move to the front
in Africa. I can not just different.
Tunisia, April 1943
Where are you from?
- First Lieutenant Farber.
I had to sign with you. You would have
give to me a unit command.
It seems you hear a Swabia.
- You sometimes?
Yes, from Lautlinge. And you?
- From Böblingen.
It is not true. Go sit still.
And you want a unit of me?
- Yes, that's why I'm here.
We can no longer
the hero will pass the time.
Our African adventure is over.
Outwards. Come on.
Put die, boy.
We have a front Swabia.
So it is good.
Tell me something. And keep breathing.
All right, just keep breathing.
Wait. Not dead, boy.
Therefore, Why don't you listened to me?
See 'm. See you again.
I go to the new command post.
- I wait until everyone has passed.
Yesterday, we had gone here.
I'm sorry. Order from on high.
What do you see?
A doctor.
Where am I?
- At the hospital in Munich.
We have in each case
To view can save.
We are pleased that you are still alive.
Wait a long time. LN
Africa has almost given to you.
Hello, Claus.
What have they done to you?
In the land of the blind
one-eyed man is king.
I can not even wegwissen your tears.
On this arm you do not hand more.
That has been amputated in Tunisia.
And my wedding ring?
They have thrown away the manual.
The ring is still on.
I have to do something against this guy.
I had a lot to do.
You have to be healthy again,
nothing more.
Can I my gloves
not off, Henning?
Then there are fingerprints on.
- It's for your own safety.
Write the following. First:
'The Führer Adolf Hitler is dead. "
"An unscrupulous clique...
- What types should I?
'The Führer Adolf Hitler is dead. "
That you can not do.
- We must. We have no choice.
If this message reaches the press,
he is already dead.
Are you afraid?
- My hands shake just a little.
You had promised me that you would do.
I do too.
Okay, first sentence.
'The Führer Adolf Hitler is dead. "
Exclamation.
"An unscrupulous clique of party leaders...
has the opportunity
taken to benefit...
to the violent conflict front
in the back to attack. "
That is not true.
Maneuver distraction. They may
not know who is behind it.
Since there now
great danger...
The rich government,
to maintain law and order...
decided to take action.
The SS.
And the papers?
- Too late.
Exit and follow me.
Put your arms on edge.
Who is that?
Do you live here?
- I would have known.
What is that answer?
I'm Colonel Henning von Tresckow
and that is Lieutenant Von Stauffenberg.
ln order.
Come on.
Shoot immediately
as they try to flee.
Surround the house
and blocking all exits.
That was a lot.
- Come out and fast.
Keep the windows in the cellar holes.
What is it?
I'm afraid.
I'm terrified of the gallows.
We burn all drafts
and hide the typewriter.
I know. It is highly dangerous
what we do. For all of us.
You can now go on logging.
I can not. And I do not.
The kids want you
good night wishes.
Who first?
Good night, Daddy.
- Good night, Valerie. Sleep good.
Excuse me...
- No. Another time.
Who told you that?
Grandma.
- You know my mother still.
God will protect you.
And now to bed.
Good night, big boy. Come over here.
Men may embrace each other.
Sleep good.
Where did you get that gun for?
In the event that.
Burn it. They should not
fall into the wrong hands.
Anything else?
- Are you mad?
What time does your train?
- According to 't track booklet to 00.10 hours.
Then it will do so. Germans
are very punctual, even in the war.
You exaggerate.
- Perhaps.
I am the only
to my senses to do.
Why?
- You may guess three times.
I can not tell you.
I may not agree.
Not anymore?
You tell me anything.
We turn around to the topic
as a cat to the hot broth.
You're something. I do not know what
and therefore I'm upset.
Do you trust me?
It has nothing to do with confidence
to make it comes to your security.
So the hero you want to hang out.
I want an end to the war make.
Do you also turn out to me?
To your children?
Very often.
Can you imagine
that we do not want to lose?
You're my man. You're with me
married and not with the Empire.
It is also about us.
- To us, it has long anymore.
It is about duty, honor and morality.
I got my belly full of them.
You are so changed.
If I see you so, I think:
That's my man anymore.
He is just as fanatical
as those beyond.
They trot through their hatred and others
trot in their desire shipment.
I was always so proud of
that you was different.
That is now over.
You're just like her.
What we do here, Nina,
we do for Germany.
Thing to do for me. Only for me.
Do not die.
- I will see to that.
Swear. With a handshake.
I will do everything I can.
I think that is not enough.
I can not promise you.
Then go back to Berlin
and do not let what you can.
You demands the impossible from me.
- You also mine.
Are we like each other?
You want to own something.
Actually not.
Take care of yourself.
Sorry, I guess I
coupá me in the wrong.
Can you still my wife 's call, Alix?
- I will.
General Fromm would like to speak
in his office.
I do so.
I expected another call.
By Alix von Winterfeld.
I would like Mrs speak.
I will pass on to the colonel.
Until horns.
Your wife is with the children away,
your mother said.
And unfortunately not available.
Come inside.
Would you like cognac?
- Not daytime.
The highest boss wants from us
a proposal on new troops.
I do not know
where I should get away...
but you'll think of something solid.
I can not go this time.
I have no time and honestly
I am also in no sense.
Civil defense siren again?
That would be the 20th.
The day after tomorrow. July 20.
And now in the shelter.
Are you not coming down?
Tomorrow is another execution
of Tristan and lsolde. Are you coming?
Is there a chance
that we get help from the British?
They demand the unconditional
surrender of the Germans.
For them, we are also traitors,
Like our own nation.
Well, we do it without them.
Even Hitler's enemies
we get no help.
Your decision is therefore common.
It must be done, and done now.
I put everything on the game,
even my life.
And I expect you to support me,
with all the consequences.
All sectors in the army
are aware.
If it succeeds in Berlin,
the others do too.
What happens when things go wrong?
- It may just not go wrong.
It can really all directions.
- That is true.
Expects you still visit?
This way.
What is it?
- I have the whole end apart.
I thought I was by the Gestapo
followed. Fortunately that was not the case.
This is Margarethe von Oven.
She was once the secretary of
Tresckow. She is on our side.
The story goes that the headquarters
of the Führer could result.
This week.
- Who says that?
That rumor doing the rounds.
- We must act quickly.
And another thing.
Tresckow stuck on the Eastern Front.
He had been pleased to see.
I had the next pass.
The attack should immediately
take place. At all costs.
I think that too.
If it goes wrong, we must
still trying to commit a coup.
It is not about the practical usefulness...
but we must world show
that we have tried.
And that our lives are
are prepared to give.
He said that literally.
You must immediately get out of Berlin.
Tonight yet.
No, not now.
- I beg you.
Get up. It is five hours, boss.
Yes, thank you. I am al
Think of the briefcase.
- I already have gestruikeld.
I do myself.
Stop just two shirts in my bag.
I do.
It's going to be hot again.
Is there one broken cases?
Good morning.
Here is the bag
and an extra shirt.
I just throw the tank full. We must
on time at the airport.
English explosive.
Who shall decide on our fate.
Why should you execute the attack?
We got you here so urgently needed.
Best guy, nobody wants
the dirty work.
We are here.
Lieutenant Haeften is already waiting.
Rangsdorf airport, 7 hours
We have unfortunately delayed.
- Why is that?
Hanging low fog and poor visibility.
- How late are we?
About an hour.
I will bag on the plane explain?
- Fine, yes. Be cautious however.
Is that the bag with the...
Your papers are here. How long
is flying to Rastenburg?
Two hours, depending on the wind.
Could it be...
that we never see each other?
- Yes, you can.
In the worst case.
I have huge respect for you.
For your courage.
Call Nina again.
Tell her...
Tell her I love her.
For the rest nothing.
Give me the bag with the paper.
It can also accidentally explode?
Dear Nina...
Rastenburg, East Prussia, 10:15
Kretz ensign.
I bring you to Wolfsschanze.
You can 't lose sight of.
- No second.
I have the text for your speech
given topic.
See you at noon in Keitel
barrack. The discussion is for an hour.
I will promptly on time.
Already 's been here before?
- Five days ago.
I have no problem with Jews.
That can not, because I know there is none.
Colonel Stauffenberg, heil Hitler.
What do you think of that?
Good morning, gentlemen.
- Anyway the best answer.
The Russians bars me worry.
- They are also right on our doorstep.
Say that but not against the Führer.
- That he knows well Thursday.
You have not had breakfast, I think so.
Breakfast for the colonel.
And soon a little bit.
Thank you, but I have no hunger.
The shoot lunch urge in,
So lay ahead but a bodempje.
And how are you in Berlin?
- Half the city is in ruins.
Willy Fritsch apparently at the last
air attack to have collapsed.
Well, in any case
it's a beautiful summer.
I think the worst mosquitoes.
- They are still disastrous than the Jews.
Just do not start again
about to whine.
Go ahead, I come true.
We gotta go. I believe
General expects Buhle us.
My adjutant von Haeften.
Lieutenant-General Von Thad.
Commander...
- Lechler.
Am I too early?
- We are on the way to Keitel.
Can Haeften somewhere waiting for me?
In the guest stay then.
John, bring the adjutant of Colonel
Stauffenberg to the guests stay.
I must say, Field Marshal...
that no troops there soon
more available.
There are up to fifteen divisions
deployable against the Russians.
The losses of the army, we can
do not respond.
Your enthusiasm is praiseworthy, but
if you can not talk against the Führer.
Keep your foot on the losses.
Saving the nerves of those poor guy.
With Keitel.
Yes, I know.
We gotta go.
- Already?
The agreement begins a half hour earlier.
Has anyone told you that?
No, unfortunately not.
How much time do we have?
- Ten minutes. So no hurry.
And think of what I said.
This is no ordinary war.
Where can I quickly
another shirt collection?
That can happen in my bedroom.
Here. If you want to help...
- I only need my adjutant.
Go ahead, I come true.
-We have to wait. There is time enough.
That never succeed.
- I love this. Do you have the ignition?
What do you want?
A quarter. Both.
We certainly need to play.
Both inflammation.
The tongs, give me the tongs.
If the wire breaks, it's over.
Is the acid-free?
I can not see.
Acid is released.
- Well, the second ignition.
What is it?
- Fellgiebel asks whether you call back.
I do later. Anything else?
- John Major is to wait.
We are coming to.
The guy is a disaster.
Check the equally fast.
And then pack. However cautious.
And what am I doing this?
A kilogram is enough. Take it.
- What you want? We are in a hurry.
I am al Hurry up.
God be with you!
- With all of us.
With just to hand that not.
- Keitel is already assumed.
What should you say?
- I want to help you.
My arm is still there.
- Gentlemen, we are not.
Little weird, right?
Every day there is bad news,
both the east and the west front.
Why can not hear the Führer?
He must know
how the situation there is?
Keitel part I think not.
Schenk just ready wine.
Heusinger is already busy.
Then, we're too late.
I want as close to the Führer
so I miss nothing.
I hear bad.
- I will.
The northern forces are
almost up to Ostrow along.
He is chief of general staff
General Fromm.
He introduced the new positions again.
The danger that the Russians,
in the area of the central forces...
which consists of 15 divisions,
draw in this direction.
So they cut
Northern troops that have...
Retreat is fundamentally wrong.
Let 's see. Here.
If we attack them from the side...
- I gotta call.
then we surround them and not to us.
But go quietly away.
I propose that the northern troops
Duna to return to bags.
Thus we strengthen the central...
Call for Superior General Fellgiebel
Stauffenberg. He is on the post adjutant.
Go for it.
General, I connect you through
with Stauffenberg.
I got you connected.
You can 'm record here.
Is it all end?
- No, I come right back.
That does not matter anyway. Yes, I wait.
Did you see me?
But not here.
And how are in the east?
- It is all according to plan.
There are problems with the car.
Apparently there is no...
Do not panic, it explodes here
more often a mine in the prohibited area.
Occasionally there accidentally kicks
an animal. And your car is underway.
I saw him though when I arrived.
- Well, you now have two cars.
Oh yes, one more thing. The commander asked
or you also continued to lunch.
Set at the height Berlin
and disconnect from all connections.
Let nothing leaking.
Keep it secret as long as possible.
Do you think he...
I bring you back.
- We are in a hurry.
You forget your hat and...
- Keep your mouth. And drive it.
Nurses, this way. The Führer.
I have to go to the airport.
Have not you heard? There is something
exploded in the headquarters.
I know, but we have a hurry.
Führer command.
But driving.
We have another one is needed.
This is insufficient.
Halt.
- Take your position.
You can not go.
There is alarm just beaten.
I have to go to the airport.
There may, until further notice
no one in or out.
We have no time.
Our unit leaves for hours.
Warrant warrant.
I commend you barricade
away and immediately.
I love me my instructions.
- This is unbelievable.
Can I use your phone?
- Always.
I call the commander for u.
With Kolbe, surveillance South. Colonel
Stauffenberg is here next to me.
He wants the commander speak.
- With Stauffenberg.
Möllendorf Oh, you're it.
We are stopped.
Alarm, yes. I've heard.
Also nothing more.
I miss my plane shortly
if not this sergeant...
You know, sir, that...
Yes, on your responsibility.
Airport Rastenburg, 13.15 hours
It is our success.
Not yet. Still a long way.
God, give me new strength.
Fellgiebel has fixed
already called to Berlin.
The man who wore them out...
Have you seen m?
That was Hitler.
- It was his mantle.
The face covered, like a dead man.
You do not survive such a bomb.
Even he did not.
Berlin, airport Rangsdorf, 15:40
Strange. Where is everybody?
And no pantserwagen.
Schweizer is true?
That was it agreed?
Yes, I'm just landed.
"Today in raids
of the jets did it happen...
what interests me in this oppressive hours
pijnigt incessantly. "
I go to the Bendlerstrasse.
Call Olbricht minute.
And make sure they send a car.
I needed fresh air.
She knew nothing of.
- Has Fellgiebel or not call?
That, but it was
a rather odd message.
There is something terrible thing happened.
The Führer alive.
That may not. These idiots have
in those two hours Thursday not done.
That is unbelievable.
Enter the start signal to Walküre.
Right now.
Hitler is dead, no doubt about it.
- Are you really sure?
Do you think I lie?
-It claims no one, but...
The air shed is made.
- A large cloud of smoke and screams dire.
Hitler was on a stretcher
wear away.
The bomb exploded two meters
next to him. He must be dead.
I'm convinced.
- Why is Walküre only now started?
We Taste in the dark.
We only got that call.
Come to Fromm.
I wait on you here, for all
security. I hear there are not more.
It is therefore failed.
- Adolf Hitler is dead, General.
Keitel claimed just the opposite.
The Field Marshal
highest in person.
Keitel is lying again 's. I've seen
Hitler dead that they took from the shed.
It is over.
- That does h.
General Fromm,
I myself have placed that bomb.
You?
- Hence launched Walküre.
Who gave his consent?
- Mertz von Quirnheim and me.
This is terrible. You give wholeheartedly again
that you have committed high treason.
Bartram, get immediate
Colonel Mertz.
The attack was carried out and did it.
Now it is important to quickly...
Stop with that nonsense.
Your attack failed.
Do you have a gun?
- Where do I need?
You must commit suicide.
You simply have no other choice.
I do not foster suicide.
- There is work to be done.
If we do nothing,
is our homeland to the sharks.
Did you participate in this coup?
- That you knew right?
I knew nothing. Absolutely nothing. And
such insinuations I am not served.
Did you launched Walküre?
- That 's right, yes. ln your name.
Then you're all three arrested.
Bartram, close them down.
You have nothing more to recommend here.
From now on we share the tune.
You have therefore not yet the courage
to join us to join.
I will make short shrift with you.
Give me your gun.
To do anything, General.
Otherwise you're dead.
I thought you were smarter.
You'll regret it.
There is a lot to regret
in this country. But this is not.
Plug him in the room next door.
And let him watch.
Grab his arms off
and make the phone defective.
Comrades. Soldiers.
I am deeply shocked.
I've just heard...
that our beloved Führer Adolf Hitler...
no longer alive.
Has just been launched
for the emergency Walküre.
We should form a united front.
We received the order for the government
hermetically district to close...
and to any disturbances
The order is restored.
I call on everyone
absolute obedience.
As to the front.
Why is the first sentence
crossed out?
The orders are secret. I do not know...
- Who has crossed out?
There must surely someone contract
Links have given?
The radio sends a communiqué.
- Is the radio still is not busy?
Apparently not.
- Make it happen.
We send the orders by integral.
Stop them there. You get
the orders of us. Hitler is dead.
Beck wants to hear from your mouth.
The dictator is dead, General.
I saw it happen before my eyes.
You do not survive such a bomb.
-Keitel otherwise.
That is a mystery to me.
- A riddle leads to confusion.
What we tell the people as Himmler
Hitler or Goebbels not declare death?
Well, what you also the world
make for me Hitler is dead.
And we act accordingly.
For you, the successor to Fromm.
But I honestly feel
me not so comfortable in that role.
Where Stauffenberg is?
- Second floor left.
All division leaders, yes.
Fromm immediately to the office.
I search colonel Stauffenberg.
- That's me.
SS leader Pifrader. I come on behalf of
the head of state.
You are therefore of the Gestapo.
Can I ask a few questions
under four eyes?
I got just one.
- It is a serious matter.
That I agree with you.
Give your arms off. Your adjutant too.
What do you want from me?
- I love you.
Close the door. Fast. Keep them.
- Get him in his leg.
I got m. The gentlemen are
disabled.
Close the gate off
and put extra surveillance down.
Six men with me.
We conclude that SS on it.
A second unit for the entrance.
Silence. I request you to be quiet.
I give the floor to our new
Head of State, General Beck.
Ladies and gentlemen,
This is a historic moment.
The military situation
that you all know...
is practically hopeless, on all fronts.
Each day new losses
reported. New defeat.
We want peace at last.
Where did he talking about?
- I know a lot.
... that all our energy to
turn and even our lives to car.
I ask you to us
to help and support.
In my opinion he does not count.
- Lntegendeel. Come on.
This is a coup.
- Without me.
We must equip
and the counter-attack going. But how?
I know
how we can come to weapons.
Berlin office of the commander,
18.00
Are you here for a reason?
- There is not anything here, Major.
Why? We follow the orders on.
- But not those of the Führer.
What do you mean by that?
I just come in from Dr. Goebbels.
He asks you to him want to come along.
It is rather a warrant.
I really do not follow orders of
a minister. Even though he called Goebbels.
Okay, I'm going to do to him.
With Mertz.
No, you can 'm not speak.
Follow that up.
Further instructions may be added.
That is not true.
By maintaining the power
arbitrariness and revenge out of the question.
Did you know?
- Yes.
The people must
the difference with the arbitrariness...
of the current rulers understand.
On the radio
the communique read.
today was...
a bomb attack committed.
These were some of the most seriously injured:
Lieutenant-General Schmundt,
Colonel Brandt, assistant Berger.
Slightly injured
Colonel General Jodl...
and the generals Korten, Buhle,
Boden Schatz, Heusinger and Scherff.
Furthermore, the admiral Voss
and Von Puttkammer...
sea captain Assmann
and Lieutenant-General Borgmann.
The Führer remained unharmed, a few
burns and bruising after.
Keitel was therefore right.
- He is right to work gone.
He will later today the Duce
for a longer receive maintenance.
Shortly after the attack, the state -
Marshal by the Führer to visit.
They lie.
They lie that it is printed.
Berlin, palace Goebbels, 18.55 hours
Nobody should look like or is
without my permission.
If I 'n quarter'm not back,
you must storm the house.
The building is surrounded. Two-man
to the right, two men left.
Minister, you wanted me to speak.
- Finally.
What is happening in the city?
And why is my house guarded?
Warrant from on high.
Immediately after it was disclosed
that our beloved Führer is dead...
What are you talking about?
The Führer is not dead. He is alive.
Lives the Führer?
That may not be true.
With Dr. Goebbels.
I need urgently the Führer speak.
Heil, Führer.
Next to me is one Major Remer...
that the government must monitor district.
They have him point made
that you no longer alive.
Major Remer, you hear me?
Do you recognize my voice?
As you wish, Führer.
Are all your doubts now
removed?
No doubt. He told me
the order given throughout Berlin.
Now we
from another keg tap.
Two units of the 5th Company
go to the Bendlerstrasse.
Did you get that machine gun
previously could not load?
Shoot straight away if they resist.
About ten minutes, this
all gone.
We can not go back.
Not anymore.
That coup must succeed today.
If not, then we all die.
I know for sure.
And maybe even our families.
The hatred of this man is
just as immoderate as himself.
We go by.
Yes, of course. I am so used to.
If you have not received orders?
Dan can come any time.
Can you just sign this?
He is so.
No, those orders are incorrect.
You only need to execute our orders.
Commander of the reservists, yes.
I do not know.
I only know that Hitler is dead.
In Paris, the SS disarmed.
Also in Vienna everything runs according to plan.
No, that statement is a fabrication.
Have you been off the radio speech?
- Yes, that was off.
No, with Stauffenberg.
Hayes, you're it.
I can still count on you, huh?
Yes, you must persevere.
Everything is here in full swing.
Field Marshal.
Chief is
Field Marshal von Witzleben.
He has been out of service, but...
- He supports h.
The attack was carried out and...
- What a mess.
I thought you did not.
- Since I had all reason.
I had promised to come
although that is useless.
Fromm asked whether he be back
his chamber may return. He is hungry.
He swears nothing improper to do so.
- Good, but keep him in the eye.
Come over here.
This is completely absurd.
The attack failed and the uprising is
beaten down. This takes nothing out.
Walküre runs.
In Paris the SS is already disarmed.
Hitler alive,
No one doubts there anymore.
With a handful of people you can not
against that man and the state begin.
Understand that anyway.
You can not even
reliably mobilize troops.
You let Major Remer
besiege the government district.
That man is a Nazi to the bone.
Solution to the problems
in the east. Sixty divisions...
He throws it wiped out.
Stieff has already been covered.
Fellgiebel too.
And now he is.
They just give to the effervescent.
It is not such sponsors continues.
But there was Tresckow.
Mertz, you need to hear this.
This is signed by Keitel.
'The Führer has to Himmler
appointed commander of the army.
Orders of Fromm, Witzleben
Hoepner are invalid or hence. "
You know what that means?
- We must immediately destroy.
That nothing will change even more.
Unfortunately not.
Help me out.
Faster, hurry. Pacific horns.
The coup perpetrators should not brands.
Here are the guns.
That should be faster.
Not make such a fuss.
The hand grenades.
Are you for or against the Führer?
Do you have a weapon?
- Are you for or against the Führer?
We are now married eleven years.
As long as he is in power.
Not much for a marriage.
Four children, I have begotten
and the fifth is coming.
And he?
He has, in the same period
destroyed almost the whole of Europe.
That is sure.
He would eventually get equal?
That may still not allow God?
I'm at the end of my Latin.
Tell my wife...
I for a case where I die for
fully endorse.
Any opposition is nipped in the bud.
I must ask you:
Are you for or against our Führer?
What should you do?
Make you outta here. Get out.
It occurs
since Stalingrad a disaster...
Are you for or against?
That is the only thing I want to know.
I can not me behind him scissors.
- Then, I have unfortunately arrest.
Do what you think you should do.
Mertz has nothing to do.
lntegendeel.
Unfortunately, the attack failed.
Give me your weapon.
- We are also officers, like u.
You've had your longest time.
- You have the Führer vowed faith.
You had to be ashamed. We go
to Fromm. You are with us.
Freeze. Stauffenberg, stop.
- Grab 'm. He can not escape.
Do not shoot. Are you crazy?
Don 't shoot.
Put the weapon on the ground.
- Reverse.
Doe quickly close that door.
Delia, call my wife again.
We have finally lost.
- It's over.
You must immediately all the incriminating
burning material.
They may find nothing. All names,
especially the names. Help them, Werner.
I am sorry,
but there is nobody at home with you.
So no goodbyes.
They have left us in the lurch.
Far too much.
I had a dream.
I have dreamed
of a German peace-loving people.
Guided by the best forces
from all walks.
A nation that law and justice
above all suggests...
that this war far eschews...
and that nothing else wants
than live in peace and freedom.
The game is off, Colonel.
Will you go to my office.
Now here I am again the lead
in hands. Is there something?
Well, gentlemen, that was it.
Now we turn again to the rolls.
I verordonneer you for your weapons
to issue and immediately.
We have no weapons.
We are not criminals?
You guys are much worse: traitors.
I accuse all participants
of high treason.
High Treason
our Führer Adolf Hitler.
You have faith
to the Führer vowed.
But that you have failed to do.
An officer may
no more serious crime.
In the name of the Führer
and as the highest court of the army...
I condemn you to the ball. The verdict
will be immediately implemented.
Dear Fromm,
your assessment is fair.
And perhaps necessary.
But I do not want
be shot dead.
We have so long together in the army
served. We were friends for so long.
That has nothing to do.
- Yet I beg you.
Yes, I beg you:
Let me again
I own that your verdict execution.
Give me your gun. Please.
Just do it, Beck.
But it could be over.
That is not so easy, Fromm best.
This senseless death...
Only one extra,
where there are already so many went for me.
But now it is my own death.
Is it already happened?
- Stay where you are. Help that man.
Get him off that gun.
Go on, hurry up.
God be merciful to him.
Can we talk about it?
Please, Fromm.
Can anyone than this poor guy
out of his misery?
Pridun, done that job on.
Hoepner, I think it
really terrible.
Choose you for the same fate as Beck?
- I do not feel guilty.
I think in any case not that I
a bullet through the head must hunt.
I can defend me and let me also
do. Even compared to my family.
Well, then I arrest you
Would anyone still write something?
A few final words.
I want something in the paper
entrust. Please.
Here, you go
sit at this table, Olbricht.
So we always sat facing each other.
Shoot it, so the
for the others not too long.
Are you ready, Olbricht?
Lieutenant Schady to death
convicted and executed are:
Colonel Mertz von Quirnheim,
General Olbricht of infantry...
who colonel whose name me
forgot, and the first lieutenant.
Consummation down the verdict in the garden.
And bring General Hoepner
to Moabit prison.
All participants have at my command
acted. Their take no blame.
I am the only one who is guilty.
- Take him to.
You, you and you: you.
Stay away from that man.
- Do not dawdle too.
Hurry, go through.
Come on, those cars parking here.
Come on, traitors.
Schweizer, it's all over.
What are you doing here? Is that your car?
Row behind the others.
And do your light on.
Is there something? Come on.
General of the infantry
Friedrich Olbricht.
Attention.
The heart sees more than the eye, said
Tresckow. I will never forget.
Explain to.
Fire.
Colonel Claus von Stauffenberg.
Attention.
Explain to.
Long live our sacred Germany.
Fire.
A very small clique
ambitious and unscrupulous...
and also unwise
and criminal officers...
Full smeedde
me to eliminate.
And together with me
the whole top of the German army.
The bomb, made by Colonel Stauffenberg
was placed...
exploded at two meters
away from me.
It struck a number of
my loyal employees injured...
and there was one death.
Eastern Poland, July 21, 1944
Schlabrendorff best.
A man leads only
a virtuous life...
if he is prepared to give his life
to provide for his conviction.
Say that to my wife.
After the attack were hundreds
people killed, so Fromm.
Nina and her children
have survived.
But until May 1945 were
yet millions of people dead.