Al-Qahhar
Try to hold your breath.
Just once.
If you can breathe,
So you can hold your breath.
Hold it!
Do you hear me?
Not.
Nothing!
Mullah said that after two weeks
you can talk and hear.
Today
This is the sixteenth day.
Still nothing.
What can I do?
Pray from morning to night,
I can not stand it.
I must talk about
with Mullah.
Mom!
I'm coming!
What do you want?
There are more than bananas.
We'll buy it.
Pissed.
I'll get the serum.
Agree?
Girls, come.
We're gonna get.
It happens, it happens!
Bibi!
Come on, let's go!
Bibi! The Water Bearer
has not yet happened?
Not.
Come on!
Quickly.
Here are your drugs.
You, my sister,
should pay me ...
The pharmacist refused.
We need money too.
We will do like last time.
With sweet-salty water.
You will hold two or three days.
I must go see my aunt.
Asking for money.
I go there, okay?
Why I ask permission!
Who is it?
What do you want?
I come to see my aunt.
Your aunt? She's gone.
Where?
- I do not know.
- Where?
I do not know.
My aunt is a party.
She had not warned me.
Nobody knows where.
I have nobody!
She does not know what happened to us.
What we will become!
Do not leave me alone.
Do not abandon me.
Your brothers are also parties.
With your mother.
Your brothers,
so proud to see you fight.
Your mother would have sacrificed
for a lock of your hair!
They are all gone
instead of supporting me.
The cowards!
They did not want to know
why you were injured.
They did not know that you fought
due to insult,
just because a man told you:
"I spit
in your mother's cunt! "
Someone in your camp!
You get insulted,
and you think you shot
in the neck.
A fight
so absurd!
They are all gone.
The cowards!
Come back!
Back to God's love.
My God, help him,
help him!
He fought so long
for you,
and thou forsake him like that!
Mullah will not come tonight.
He is afraid of stray bullets.
The water carrier, either.
I hope he is still alive.
Mom, it's dark.
I'm afraid.
I do, do not be afraid.
I'm here.
Mom, I'm thirsty.
Me too.
Mom too.
We're out of water.
Mom, you were talking to?
With your father.
Why Dad is angry?
But no,
it will be if we bother.
Who is it?
It's me, Mullah.
Hello, my sister.
I come to prayer.
- Not today.
- Why?
Since yesterday
I am unclean.
What?
Impure!
I have my period!
- And Eve also.
- Okay, okay.
It was a Tuesday, right?
A Tuesday?
Maybe ... possible.
I'll come back in 2 or 3 days.
If you want
your husband heal, pray.
God bless you.
Dad?
You sleep?
Remove it!
There's a fly!
Yuck! Removes it.
Dad, tell us a story.
But what do you do?
Out!
There is a fly
in the mouth of Dad!
What they did?
I hope
they did not hurt you.
Wait, I want to see something.
Not yet healed.
Whether it is long!
Do you feel anything?
It hurt you?
No,
it does not make you evil.
You do not suffer.
How is it possible to live
with a bullet in the neck?
It is you who are injured
and it is I who suffers.
Brothers,
the enemy will attack our homes.
Come to the mosque!
The venerable commander
will give you weapons
to protect your family
and your honor!
They have distributed weapons!
They will fight.
They are happy.
Arise, you'll be killed!
Come on, get up!
I do not know what to do with my brother.
He does not want to ask
his foot down.
For God's sake, be careful!
What did you do to him?
The poor!
Okay?
It's better here, right?
You see.
They are behind this wall.
The Water Bearer
is not yet past.
The war is still not over.
There will be retaliation tonight.
I can not leave you here.
It should get you to the cellar.
It is impossible.
Your head should not move.
If only a stray bullet
you could complete.
I'm going down.
I can not leave
the only girls.
Do not move!
Otherwise, I'm buggered!
Do you hear me?
- What he has in his mouth?
- I do not know!
Where is your weapon?
There are no weapons.
It was completed before us.
It does not need an alliance.
Dig into the other rooms.
Neither of the watch.
Come on! Come on!
Do you hear me?
We will cut your tongue?
I'm talking about!
You're dead?
Guys, where are you?
What do you do?
Look, he has a wife.
- I know.
- How? He spoke?
He took his ring!
We're going!
Where is his wife?
There is nobody at home.
I think I know.
- This is one of ours?
- I think so.
This is a good Muslim.
It was not bomb the whole neighborhood
for nothing!
Come on!
Mom ... you see?
But what is it?
Returns.
Your alliance?
Your watch?
Someone came?
Thieves?
They searched the house?
Bibi djan!
Bibi!
Have you seen someone enter
home?
O King of goodness!
It is time to return
I cry my loneliness
The king came.
He caressed me.
Do you have bread, my daughter?
I gave all my bread to the king.
But where are they?
- Your husband, your son?
- There they are.
In the house.
They are angry.
They talk to me.
To you, they will talk.
- Where are they?
- Come ...
Viewing!
My heart is impatient
of your absence ...
My daughter ...
the king caressed ...
I can not.
I can not stay here!
Come on, girls!
Prepare your business!
We're going!
We're going right away!
I have to find my aunt.
Go to hell!
- My doll!
- Stay there.
You again?
- I beg you, tell me.
- I've already answered you!
Tell it to me or I will not move from here.
I'm still here!
Thank you.
We go.
Standing!
Well, I'm going.
I back tomorrow.
You can go.
I was lucky.
Finally I found my aunt.
She lives north of the city.
I did a great deal
of his life.
You knew I was married?
Yes, it seems.
My parents married me
a very rich man,
but stupid.
Two years later, we realized
I was sterile.
I was useless.
My husband sent me
with his parents.
To become their servant.
When my father knew
I was sterile,
he had fucked me every night.
One evening, I cracked,
I could not go.
With its own deck,
I had hidden under my bed
I cracked his skull.
He died on the spot.
I fled.
I did believe
I had killed myself.
I disappeared.
I left the children.
She gave me some money.
I think ...
that ...
I can do anything for you.
They say that our neighborhood
is the front line.
They will destroy everything here.
You knew that, right?
You knew very well.
But you did not tell me.
You knew.
His brothers also knew.
That is why
they are all gone.
You know why
they have not taken you?
Your husband was alive.
Because you were alive.
Si ..
you were dead,
one of your brothers have married me.
Maybe they wanted
your death.
They could fuck me ...
finally.
Your brothers have always wanted
Me.
Three years when you were absent,
when I washed,
they looked at me
through the window of steam.
I could hear them gasp.
They masturbated.
I do not know what I'm saying.
I'm sick.
For once, you listen to me.
You never listen to me.
We've been married ten years.
How long
we lived together?
Two years?
Three years?
You were never there.
Even marriage!
Like all heroes,
you were absent.
The engagement,
in your place, there was your picture.
I was proud.
Proud to be at seventeen,
the bride of a hero!
Your mother said:
"Victory is coming soon!
"My son will come back!
"Victorious!"
When she saw
that victory was still far
she probably said:
"Leave as long as a bride
"With his parents is dangerous.
"She must marry."
That's why you got married
with his dagger.
I married
with you,
without you.
In the meantime,
I had to sleep with your mother.
She watched over my virginity.
The day of your return from the front,
when I saw you
for the first time,
I remember well,
as if it was yesterday,
you were like today.
Not a word, not a look.
You sat next to me,
indifferent.
But I
I watched you on the sly.
I knew nothing of men,
husbands ...
I observed the lesser
of your actions.
But you,
you still thought the war.
I wonder
if you noticed me that day.
I must go.
I talked a lot.
I have to take care of the girls.
The only example of married life,
it was my parents.
What an example!
The only thing that interested
my father in life,
it was his quail,
its quail fighting.
I often saw him
kiss her quail,
but never my mother,
sisters,
me
ever.
He always sat cross-legged,
he took her hand in a quail
and raised the bottom of her stomach.
And with the other he caressed ...
for hours.
Even if there were visitors
he continued.
If he lost the fight, quail
he was mad.
Once he returned,
he sought any pretext
to fight.
As if it was our fault.
He beat my mother,
my sisters.
I hated her quail.
, He was so proud.
It seemed
he lived for them.
I remember
I was nine or ten years,
it was very cold.
I saw my father
put one of his quail
in his pants.
Go away!
Long, I imagined
the men had a quail
between the legs.
One day, he had to win
lot of money for a fight.
Finally, I guess.
He had bought a quail
very expensive.
For weeks,
he has driven.
But he lost.
Finally, you are!
Hello. Can I?
- You brought your quail?
- Yes, I came up with.
Your quail on the lam!
That's it, you've lost!
Come on, give me the money!
He relied too big.
But he had no more money
to pay.
He then gave my older sister
to honor his bet.
My sister is a party of twelve
with a man of forty.
I was scared
the challenge to become a bet,
me too.
I was very scared.
Guess what I did.
A cat came to our garden.
One day
I pulled
quail from its cage,
I gave the cat.
He swept into a corner
to eat quietly.
I followed.
But the cat rebelled.
He scratched my face.
Here, there.
You never asked me
this scar.
Why am I telling you all this?
I never wanted
anyone to know,
not even my sisters,
not even my aunt.
It is because of you.
It is you who push me to speak.
You hear what I say.
I'm sure of it!
You just want me to talk,
I'm telling you all.
Go to hell!
Forgive me, my God.
Leave us.
What has happened?
Are you scared?
Fear?
No, I have a strange feeling.
I feel ...
A bad feeling?
An evil feeling?
Evil?
Not.
Since he is sick
and I told him everything,
I feel ...
issued.
It's weird, right?
What you say
reminds me of my childhood.
My father spoke of a stone.
On a magic stone and legendary.
He said: "If you find
this stone, and lay it before thee,
"Talk to him about your suffering
of your secrets.
"The stone listens.
"Whatever you dare ever
tell others,
"You say to the stone.
You talk to him ...
"She listens to all your secrets.
"It means everything.
"And one day,
"Stone broke.
"It falls to pieces.
"And that day, thou art loosed,
"Freed from all your pain."
What's her name?
The stone?
The stone of patience.
Yesterday, I wanted to give you.
I felt
you wanted it too.
This idea comforted me,
relieved me.
But this morning, I realized
it was not your death
which relieved me.
It was something else.
This is speaking,
talk with you,
reveal my secrets,
will reveal all my secrets.
You're still alive
only listen to me.
You live for three weeks
with a bullet in the neck.
You live to deliver me
of all my suffering,
all that I have on the heart
ten years of marriage.
For ten years!
You've aged so fast!
I never kissed you.
Never.
And now ...
I can do anything
with you.
I can do anything.
I can talk to you all,
everything.
My stone of patience.
Do you remember the first night?
Without a word, you're thrown out on me,
excited ...
distraught.
Your mother
we watched.
She was dying to know
if a virgin was deflowered,
if it could
have a grand-son or not.
A few months later,
when she saw
I was not getting pregnant,
she started to moan,
thinking that I was sterile.
Sterile!
At any time, she was looking for me.
She harassed me.
She pushed you
to take a second wife.
And you ...
You do not know what I had to do
that you keep me.
If you had known,
you would have killed me.
I did not want
you leave me.
If you had left me,
everyone would have driven me
my father, my mother,
everyone.
I have so many things
to tell you.
Someone is in the yard!
They bury the neighbors
in their garden.
My sister?
Hello, my sister.
Hello.
Are you okay?
I'm alive.
How is your husband?
He's alive.
They will still run
rockets.
Do not go.
God bless you.
Tonight again,
they will bomb.
I have to go.
There militiamen everywhere.
They searched the houses.
If they find you,
they will finish you.
The basement is flooded.
I will not let them kill you.
Your head!
Wait.
I will not let them kill you.
Between!
Sit!
Are you alone?
Not.
God is with me.
And you there, it's me!
Between!
What's going on?
This ... SSEZ ... fire.
What?
Until when?
I ... I do not know.
Will guard,
we camp here tonight.
- Go!
- Ci .. cigarette.
Here! Go!
Go!
Alone,
you're not afraid?
You have one?
No, I am a widow.
Do you have children?
Yes.
Two daughters.
Where are they?
My aunt.
That only you doing here, then?
I ...
I work.
I have to earn my living,
I have two little girls to feed.
What is your job?
I sell my body.
What?
My body.
I sell my body.
I did not understand.
I sell my body ...
for the pleasure of men.
Shame on you,
shameless, debauched.
- You have no shame?
- What?
- From what you say.
- What I say or what I do!
No chats with me.
Do you understand?
You are Muslim or not?
Muslim, why?
I'll stone myself,
on the spot!
Insolent!
Cursed is your father!
You soiled the name of Muslim!
All are killed,
and thou harlot.
I'll kill you!
Cursed be thy father, bitch!
Bitch!
Forgive me.
Enough,
are you bickering elsewhere
Well, what was I saying?
Ah, yes!
You did well to say that,
otherwise they would have raped you.
Come between.
- That's what I thought.
- You did well.
They never violate a whore.
You know why? Because ...
what kind of man
does not put his dirty thing
a hole that was used
hundreds of times.
But
raping a virgin,
it is their pride.
They show their manhood.
They are the strongest.
Stay here tonight.
I fear that lack of serum.
Take tea then.
I wanted to go with you.
Stay with you.
I'm afraid it will happen again
a misfortune.
The girls are safe
with my aunt.
They like my aunt.
Every night,
it tells a story.
What they would do here?
There is no water or electricity.
Stop!
I have so many things
to tell you.
I will tell you maybe everything.
I do not know how
you're going to take
that thou shalt say.
Tomorrow I'll tell you everything.
Agree?
I'm tired.
I must sleep.
Who are you?
- This is ... this is ... how?
- What do you want?
What?
This is ... com ... well?
This is ... this is ...
how?
But I'm not a whore!
It's over?
Shut ...
shut up!
It was your first time?
Arise now!
So ...
let me get up.
You are here?
The poor,
it made me think of you.
His heart was pounding.
You were as clumsy as him.
I did not know what to do.
I had no idea
what to do.
I thought it was
as you did.
I felt nothing,
only pain.
After I started
to please me alone.
Some nights
when you were sleeping, I stroked.
One night, you woke up
wondering what I was doing.
I said
I had a fever.
I was hot and sweaty.
You sent me to sleep
with children.
My aunt was right to say:
"Those who do not know
make love, make war. "
Mullah came again.
I have lied to him.
I told her
I still had my period.
That he was not pleased.
He went to bitching.
The poor, he became a coward.
To you too, I lied.
For our first night,
you thought it was blood
my virginity.
But I had my period.
I you had hidden,
on the advice of my aunt.
I was a virgin, but I was afraid,
fear of not losing blood.
Get out!
Come on!
Go play in the garden.
- What are you doing?
- You see!
It's time.
Remove it!
It's been three days
you make me run!
A little modesty, anyway!
You're kidding!
- You can deliver me from the water?
- Okay.
I have a little money,
I bought the serum and eye drops.
I bought to eat too.
I'll wash the cloth.
I return.
What do you want?
This boy did pity me.
At one point, I had a laugh.
He thought I was mocking him.
He almost left.
You know why I laughed?
Because my aunt.
I had talked about this boy,
his stuttering
and enjoys too fast.
My aunt told me:
"Advise him
"Kiss with her tongue
and talk with her tail. "
As soon as I remembered
this sentence
I laughed!
I immediately thought of you
and I stopped laughing.
It should not hurt
young with that, it's dangerous.
They think only of their tail
and nothing else.
Well, it happened.
Water carrier!
The toilet!
They are empty!
The boy learns quickly.
It is not like you.
It accepts
everything I tell him.
It does not upset.
You have killed me
if I told you that.
All that mattered to you,
it was your soul.
Your soul, your honor.
What about me? Nothing.
A piece of meat.
The boy,
I take her hand.
I put on my breasts,
between my thighs.
He lets me do.
I guide.
Where is the rosary?
Why would I say that?
The other women
never talk about it!
Never.
But I ...
I owned ...
by a satanic spirit.
The Koran?
You have not seen the Koran?
I was at what sura?
Peacock feather?
Where is she?
It holds all my secrets.
Forgive me.
I should not talk about it.
Today
I wanted to tell you everything.
I have not succeeded.
Someone repaired the gate.
Last night I had a dream.
I gave birth to a boy.
His face was wrinkled,
like my grandfather.
It's you!
Good ... hello.
Hello.
Today, I can not.
Not today.
Seu ... only ...
No, no.
I can not.
- Today I can not.
- I ...
re ... pa ... re the portal.
Oh, it was you.
Thank you.
I ... can ... enter?
No, I said no,
I have to work.
A ... mi ... minute.
I know we can do it quickly.
But I have work.
I expect someone else.
Seu ... seu ...
only ...
speak.
Go.
What do you want from me?
I told you
I could not today.
I need to see someone else.
Well, tell me.
The com ... Commander ...
of ... the other ... daytime
What you have on the body?
What is it?
This is ... a ... burning
of ... one ... cigarette.
Who did this?
The ... commanding
that ... is ... came another ... day.
I ... also have in my back.
That bastard,
this son of a bitch ...
The commander
who spit on me,
who wanted to kill me.
You know what he did to that boy?
It was an orphan.
He found it in the street.
The day he puts a Kalashnikov
hands
and evening bells
feet.
His body is covered in burns.
His chest,
his back.
It burns
with the barrel of his rifle,
and cigarettes.
The bastard!
The son of the damned!
Allah tells Muhammad to say:
"If I knew the hidden meaning
"I have done my goodness,
"And dismissed me wrong."
One day the Prophet said to his wife:
"Oh Khadija
soon I'm going crazy.
"I am possessed.
"I hear voices
coming out of the stones.
"At night, I approach a monster."
So Khadija asked:
"Let me know
to the next occurrence. "
And one day, the Prophet said:
"Khadija, I see."
Khadija then took off her veil
and asked Muhammad:
"You can still see?
"No, I do not see him."
Khadija said:
"It was not a monster
or a jinn. She was an angel.
"A jinn would have had no respect
for my hair.
"He would not have fled ..."
What bothers
in this story?
The Prophet says:
"If I knew the hidden meaning
"I have done my goodness
"And dismissed me wrong."
So what?
Evil could reach
Prophet?
My daughter,
The Prophet was a man,
sent by God,
like a hundred thousand other
Prophets.
Khadija, what she wanted?
Khadija?
She did not want
the Prophet feels ...
spellbound.
She wanted to open her eyes.
She wanted to tear
its illusions.
She wanted ...
Muhammad reaches
his prophetic truth.
This is it, Khadija
that would have been the Prophet.
Today, everything is calm.
They might be up
curfew.
I can stay late.
I am very tired.
Last night I did not sleep well.
Who is it?
Someone just dropped it.
It is crazy.
He lost his head.
I should have killed him the first day.
I could not.
It does not bother you
if I tell you about him?
That I welcome here?
I am under no illusions.
Do not worry.
I know it can be awful,
like you.
You too, if you come back to life,
you will return the same animal.
No?
Or maybe you will change.
You will change.
I'm sure.
You will smile to me.
You kiss me.
You take me in your arms.
You make me love
as I want.
You love me.
Because now
you know all my secrets.
You and I
it is no longer the same.
What do I do?
My God, what do I do?
God, help me!
The Koran!
Where is the Koran?
Someone took it.
My God!
Help me.
I'm going crazy.
No, no.
No, I'm not crazy.
Neither mad
or bewitched
or possessed.
I do not need anyone.
Person.
I thought it would be
hard to tell,
or even impossible.
But no.
Now, with you,
everything is possible.
You can do anything,
it all.
Where to start?
For our first daughter.
When I was pregnant, I prayed
to a miscarriage.
This child was my secret.
It was my secret.
At delivery, I wanted
stifle between my legs
but it gave me opium.
I was stunned, I could not.
Seeing that it was a girl,
I was reassured.
A girl would not betray
the secret of his mother.
You know why
I did not want this child?
It was not you.
The second either.
I was not sterile.
You, you were.
Nobody knew.
Your mother does not want to know.
Do you remember?
She wanted you to take
another woman.
What would I become?
My aunt came to my rescue.
I asked his advice.
She found the solution:
tell your mother that there
a healer who works miracles.
Oh, all the money spent
by your mother!
She told you nothing.
Each time, she said:
"This is your last chance."
After several consultations
home, I got pregnant.
You want to know who it was?
It was my aunt mackerel.
You want to know the miracle?
I tell you?
He put me in a dark room
with a man blindfolded.
Absolute Black.
The man had no right
talk to me
or touch me.
We have never been naked.
I never saw his face.
I think he was young and strong,
but without experience.
My aunt gave me advice
to guide.
The first time,
nothing happened.
At first,
I cried softly.
Then I screamed and vomited.
They drove me to the room.
I did not want to return.
Gradually, it was fixed.
I accepted,
with a ...
guilt.
When I was pregnant, your mother
clung to the healer.
She told
he worked miracles.
She often bought her
talismans.
For the second, I do not know
if it was the same man.
Still in the dark.
You?
You came back to life?
My stone of patience.
You came back to me!
The stone of patience.
You broke!
I brought you,
me
myself.
I became a Prophet ...
who performed a miracle.
Adaptation: Nahal Tajadod