CHRISTMAS 1941
Midnight.
In his castle of Stargard, Pomerania;
Captain von Stegel of the 15th armoured
division, is about to leave
once again his mother,
wife and son.
It's his third war Christmas.
What is his destination?
He doesn't know it yet.
The same night
at the same time in London,
a British family introduces the Christmas
pudding to corporal Théo Dumas,
from the 1st Free French Division.
Corporal Théo Dumas is distracted.
He thinks about his bar-tabac
in Montmartre.
With his European champion's gloves
hanged behind the bar.
In Ablis, west of Paris.
A grandmother says goodbye
to her grandson.
He's off to England.
François Gensac isn't a warrior.
He's 30 and he's always get bored.
He's hoping for a change.
At the same time, a small boat is taking
out of France a eight men group.
They have different reasons
to leave occupied France.
This medical extern got only one
but that's a good one:
His name is Samuel Goldmann.
At Bayonne's prison,
people are thinking.
There's a lot of thinking going on
in prison on Christmas Eve.
This one mostly thinks that
he's been sentenced to death
and that if the escape
he's planning fail,
he will be executed in two days.
TAXI FOR TOBRUK
10 months later, in Libya
inside Tobruk
occupied by the troops of Rommel.
What the fuck is he doing?
Come on, let's go.
Everybody down!
Come on, quickly!
It was like if the lieutenant was
feeling he wouldn't make it.
Was he bashed up a lot?
You know what kind
of funeral oration he was up to:
muscatel in Pleurnel,
but we're not there yet.
Yeah, I know; I maybe moved
a bit from the road,
but I got us out
of the mess, thought.
And I can guarantee you we'll be
in El Alamein tonight, in our beds!
If you keep going, corporal,
and if my notes are right...
we're not heading to El Alamein anymore
but to the Cape of Good Hope.
- And he has stripes on his jacket!
- Do you want them?
- How far did we move from the road?
- I was saying the Cape of Good Hope
to avoid offending you but we're
actually rushing to the South Pole.
Come on, slow down with that!
We just have to change direction.
We've got petrol, water and meat.
We're only 700 kms from our lines
and we can do 1000;
it's a piece of cake.
Of course, if we forget planes, tanks,
land mines and other trifles!
If a superior invites you for a ride,
my friend, just enjoy it
or you'll see you'll end up
under arrest.
Yeah; one day you'll be surprised
to end up having your arse kicked.
Hey...
Is this thing over there on the map?
No, it's not.
Morons.
And what about this one?
It's maybe a friend.
- Don't touch that.
- You bet!
Don't touch that, God damn it!
If it's a Kraut, let him thing we're
Krauts too; they've got British cars too.
Cool it, take it easy!
- We've got a brain with us!
- That's for sure.
Don't screw it.
- Messersmith 109.
- The one who doesn't turn left
and has messy machine-guns
according to Paris-Soir.
I got him!
I got my Kraut, guys!
Jesus, everybody out!
The radio and water!
He won't make it to Tobruk.
I mean the Kraut.
- I better like not answer you back.
Dumb people like you should wear a sign.
You'd deserve the council of war.
- I hear people.
- Try to catch the base.
And you, get our position.
In three hours time,
a plane could be here;
if Mr Arsehole don't shot him down.
We can copy but we can't transmit.
The oscillator burned out and
we don't have a spare one.
- How's that!?
- We didn't bring one.
Jesus fucking Christ; so you all
don't give a shit about nothing, huh?
So we're gonna croak because
you didn't bring a spare oscillator!
That's a bit rich!
That really is!
- What's wrong with your leg?
- It's nothing, just a burn.
It looks bad. Put your hanky on it
to keep it away from the flies.
You know flies...
Now or later...
So you don't even try anymore?
You just don't give a shit.
What were you saying?
- We were speaking about flies.
What?
You don't know what is it
to die of thirst, general?
I studied it, it's really groovy.
First, your tongue will puff up.
Swallowing will become painful.
Then will come hearing troubles,
and next vision troubles.
That's the standard progression.
Spasms will come later,
just before agony.
That's the moment when
the flies will attack.
What about speaking
of something else?
Why? That fit the present situation
and I'm a doctor.
That's funny.
I often thought about death.
Mine, of course.
I use to figure it around 70 years old,
with an add in the medical magazine.
Doctor Samuel Goldmann
died of a heart failure.
And I'm gonna die here.
Of thirst, like a geranium.
Is that it? Then, on your feet.
If you forgot something,
you'll tell us on the way.
Let's go.
Just from you to us, don't you think
that's the end of the road?
We've got no car and no water and
we're 700 kms away from our lines.
- We're gonna make it.
- How?
By foot!
You fool, tomorrow your feet
will be big like this!
Feet, tongue, spasms...
you really won't spare us anything!
- You'll see!
- Then if I can't walk, I'll crawl!
I'm gonna get through
that 700 kms no matter what!
- No matter what!?
- No matter what!
And even if I can't, the only way to find
a patrol or something is to walk!
Then you'll walk, but without me!
We'll both give up, you'll see.
We're all gonna give up.
Sure, go ahead: give up!
I heard that one so many times:
"Just give up, Dudu".
But that was always the other guy
who fell on his arse.
- Boxing is not exactly the same thing.
- Yes, it is!
There's only two options:
croak here or walk.
I am walking! And you too!
No.
Sorry, corporal; I haven't been
a hussar for 11 months
to end up a footsoldier.
- What does it mean?
Just this: I accept to die but
with the less effort as possible.
I'm gonna stay here,
smoke my last cigarettes and wait.
I let you crawl on the sand,
your tongue panting.
I'll be seating when
the flies will find me.
Come on, my brave men!
I'd rather die for the desert's fertilisation.
"Tomorrow on the tombs, the wheat
will look better.", like the poet said.
Gensac was a name and now
it's gonna be a fertiliser brand.
Colonialism is changing.
- And they call that a commando!
The orators commando!
Come on, let's go,
they're getting on my tits.
- Dudu!
- Shit!
Doctor, I think the Neanderthal man
is screwing us.
A walking brute goes further
than two seated highbrows.
Dudu...
Are we stopping because of me?
Him.
It's not because of someone.
Théo...
I can't take it any longer.
Do as I do:
think about something else.
Do you think those tracks
lead to somewhere?
Yes.
That's the only thing
we should think of.
I've got hearing troubles:
I hear music.
Me too.
Aren't you?
I've got lazy ears.
But if you both hear music, dummies,
that means there's really music!
Leave that!
Guys, that's the last metro.
We come back with it
or we don't come back.
Which one you pick?
The one facing us.
I'm taking this one...
And you?
- I don't care!
- You take the one on the right.
- Fine with me.
- You take the one in the middle.
- Yeah.
Don't screw it, guys,
there will be no second sitting.
Ready?
- Ready.
No!
Hurry up, scumbag!
They'd piss less if they
weren't drinking so much.
Wait, I lost mine.
Now, for Christ's sake!
There's some leftovers, guys!
You'd better hurry up!
Come on, cool it!
Does "hauptmann" mean "captain"?
- Ja.
Ludwig von Stegel, 1912...
Hey guys...
Do you know he's terrific?
Do you think they'll let me
take him home?
Hurt?
He wanted to play with his radio...
When you do stuff like that,
you get your paws caught.
Ask him who he was speaking with.
Don't mind us, Her Hauptmann;
just say it if we're bothering you.
La Haye's agreements
are protecting you...
Ask him if he has friends around.
I had those ones.
You'll obtain no information
from me.
But you can yap in French, bitch!
I don't yap, I speak.
Even if I'm only a private,
allow me an advice, captain...
if you really want to be ironic,
you'd better talk to the corporal:
he won't touch you, you're not
in the same weight division.
But with him, you'll have your arse
kicked before sunrise.
In a blink.
We won't touch you but can you
give me your officer's word
you won't try to escape?
The laws of war allow me to give you
my word and not keep it.
Okay.
But as we have 700 kms to do together,
I'd like to clear the situation.
If everything's all right,
I'll hand you over to the military police
but if you try something sneaky,
I'll plug you.
You've my word in both case.
Understood?
What means "something sneaky"?
Well. Come here,
we have some mechanical work to do.
You two, tell me how much water
and petrol we've got.
We're carrying the Tanganyika, general:
at least 30 litres of water.
Tanganyika or not,
draw up the rationing.
Shit, we just came out of rationing!
30 litres for five and
at least 20 hours of road,
don't figure on having a bath!
Did you say for five?
I can see only four of us.
Where is the fifth?
He'll drink and eat
the same as us.
Otherwise, plug him now.
Go ahead, we're looking at you!
What are you waiting for?
Go ahead!
Excuse-me, father. I didn't realise
I'd join the Salvation Army.
Let me laugh!
I'm a Jew.
What does it mean?
I thought you could
speak German?
I didn't learn it in a garage.
It could be faster if we'd ask him.
Yeah, faster...
If you're hurry to look like a sucker,
I've got all the time.
Stop it, they love to show
how brave they are anyway.
Hop in. In France,
we don't shoot our prisoners.
For sure,
we don't have much of them.
Gentlemen... The bar's open.
The container's opaqueness
allowing to cheat,
don't forget God is watching you.
- Drink up, I'll handle the wheel.
- Veterans first.
Here.
We're really drinking
too much, guys.
- You can skip your turn.
- I'd rather have a dilation.
You could say thank you.
I can put 20 more litres,
do I feel it up?
Yes, then you'll come
to help me with the meal.
I should only handle technical matters;
but if I let them do...
Is it the same for you?
- Sometimes.
- Are you coming from El Alamein?
- Yeah.
Without an officer?
We had one.
During the shootings,
he wasn't hiding in the car.
At what age they start
paying you your pension?
Can't you change the bloody record?
Why? They started it.
And I have plenty more to say.
It looks bad.
You could use an antiseptic.
I'll clean it anyway.
- It would annoy me to be amputated.
- Don't talk crap.
It would annoy me because of tennis.
Do you play tennis?
- I never had time for that.
Grant, examination, faculty,
examination again, internship...
I was a hard-working boy.
Careful, deserving...
revolting.
But I had only two choices:
be a doctor or fixing old cauldrons.
From father to son,
the Goldmann are tin workers.
If your grandfather isn't a banker,
where's the use of being a Jew.
Is it painful when I press around it.
- You bet it is.
It's so stupid not
to have Mercurochrome.
You're gonna enjoy that
but you can scream if you want.
You can count on me on that.
You know what they say in Cairo?
When you find a dead body
you can't identify in the desert...
You check his pockets:
if there's a can opener, it's a British.
If there's a bottle opener,
it's a French.
How could I knew?
Jeez...
If it was me, I would have been bawled out...
- What?
Nothing. I didn't talk to you.
By the way, Sam; you could also
take care of his hand.
His hand?
It's better be cautious,
joints are very fragile.
We never know.
Here you go.
I want to take you back
in good shape.
We're doing what it takes for that.
Let's see this hand.
Don't worry: there's nothing broken.
- What do you think?
I didn't use all my strength.
- Of course!
Now that you're feeling better,
don't forget you're in charge of the radio.
Yes, Sir.
I'd prefer if the buddies know
we're using a German car.
And is that grub ready or what!?
- Just a sec.
I'm so hungry, guys.
So?
- I don't know why
but it's worst than last night,
I can't copy anything.
Then just keep trying.
Hey, listen that.
"Violent combats are on.
The statement transmitted by
the Cairo this morning says that
the 8th army, with the help of
the air force, had launched last night
from El Alamein
a general offensive..."
"The decisive battle is on.
At the time we're transmitting,
Rommel's forces are
drawing back everywhere."
We just have to call them, they'll take
care of us after the war is over.
I want to have a closer
look on this, right now.
- I thought you were hungry?
- Not anymore. You get the wheel,
I'll get the compass.
You come with me.
I heard the situation isn't good
for you, my good man.
You'll forget about it...
Everyone on board.
En route to El Alamein.
Halt!
If you don't mind...
the wounded ones first.
We've been suffering,
we have rights over you.
Step in, my dear colleague.
- You really have some nerve!
That's how things are going:
soon, just any scratch will
be convertible into cash.
What's wrong?
The news are good.
I mean, for you.
Yeah.
Looks like home is getting close.
Do you have someone
waiting for you?
Are you married? Any children?
Yes.
So you're a father.
I'm a son.
That's my daddy I'll meet.
Yeah. Right now,
my dear father is in Vichy.
Legality is running into his veins.
If the Chinese invade us,
he'd become a mandarin.
If the niggers were taking over,
he'd stick a bone in his nose.
If the Greeks...
Let's skip this one...
So depending on things are gonna turn,
I'll be the Gaullist delinquent
or the purifier hero.
Watch out,
you're swerving to the south.
- You asked me to.
- Then it's because of their shitty compass.
Our is way better.
- It doesn't matter anyway,
you just guide me as you feel it.
Halt!
What did you say?
Halt.
Why halt?
- Stop, if you prefer.
- I don't prefer anything,
I'm the one who says
when to stop.
You won't reach
El Alamein like this.
You're gonna get stuck
in the soft sand.
- Soft sand yourself.
- Let him talk.
May I?
We have to by-pass this zone.
We have to do a "S".
Like this.
Then let's do it.
- It's over 100 kms detour,
we'll have it for the petrol.
- Yeah, we'll run out of petrol.
I don't see a solution.
What would you do
if you were in my shoes?
I am not in your shoes.
But I know that...
I would go here.
Siva's oasis.
You'll find all the water
and petrol you want.
- And we'll find your buddies too.
- You really have some nerve, Bismarck.
- A funny boy we have here.
- We had Siva's control yesterday but today?...
Radio Cairo said we are
drawing back everywhere.
If you don't trust
your own information...
Captain von Stegel, you really think
we're a bunch of morons.
We can take you directly
to Tobruk if you prefer.
In what floor do you live?
I'll can also run a bath for you.
Come on, Sammy, step on it.
Hard sand or soft sand,
El Alamein is straight ahead.
- Don't let the engine heat up.
- I'm spinning.
Use the intermediates.
Didn't I teach you that?
Yes, Sir; you taught me that.
Take the wheel if you can do better.
- You'll get stuck in the sand.
- I can stop if you want.
That moron's gonna get stuck.
That's it, I was sure
this would happen, didn't I?
- Me too.
- Try to go backwards.
Easy on the pedal.
Don't step on it, just caress it.
Get off and change
the gearwheels if you want.
I must really love war
to make it with that!
Get your shovels, gentlemen!
Pushing is maybe enough,
we need to know on what we're going.
On soft sand.
Hey... You speak German,
say him fuck for me.
What about taking a shovel?
- No.
- It could makes you tired.
This is not the point.
No French officer prisoner
is forced to work.
As an officer, I just ask for
the implement of an admitted rule.
Somebody needs a good kick
up the arse, guys.
- He's right: he doesn't have to work.
- And me?
You're not a prisoner so you dig!
I could use some water.
Same here.
Come on, guys,
that's the labourers round.
Special service.
Is it cool?
Like a southern rosé.
Maybe a bit too iced.
I'm not sure what La Haye's
agreements are planning for this type
of situation but I'll check it out
when we'll arrive.
Maybe a retroactive round will come.
Regulations are regulations.
Come on guys,
we're almost there.
Push!
Come on.
It won't start.
Let's do it again.
How much does it use?
30 litres.
- That's enough only for half of the way.
- I know that!
But if we go to Siva, we'll bump into
his friends and if we go straight
we'll run out of petrol.
There's no way out.
Having tasted what dying slowly could be,
I'd rather try something new.
- You're gonna be spoiled!
- You can count on it.
Well...
If He can remember we're representing
civilisation, God will maybe help us!
I think I noticed He'd rather help
big armies over smallest ones
so we'd better
not expecting too much.
Yeah...
But Siva isn't that big
and we first need to find it.
We're doing you a favour so what about
guiding us with the compass?
My pleasure.
Come on, guys, let's go.
Who's that?
Would you mind going
at the back?
Handle him.
Not like this, here.
Do we hook on the wagon?
Yeah.
But don't be overzealous.
We must land on it
just like in candyfloss.
"Hello ladies and gentlemen,
we're just passing through."
Okay?
- Yes.
Let's go.
Your road is a bit busy for me.
Do you know a better one?
What I dislike is their military police.
You know, they just have
the same one we have.
Some MPs are really twisted.
They'll be there if you're pilfering.
Slow down.
Can you make up your mind?
- We've got motorcyclists on our back.
- Do you think they'll give us a ticket?
- Let them pass.
- What if they stop?
Then we'll see.
What are we doing?
If you don't plan to take off,
then keep on driving.
See what I see, big chief?
Damn it, Samuel!
So they busted you too?
Samuel... Don't you recognise me?
- Hurry up, for Christ sake!
What a bloody moron!
Is he recovering?
Slowly.
- Théo...
- Yeah?
Did you noticed I didn't touch
a single hair of his head?
You speak of La Haye's agreements...
But that's the second time
you smashed his face!
Feeling better?
Get off and help him to walk a bit
but hurry up, we've got no time to lose.
I'll evaluate the situation.
Don't take this personally,
Théo is a brute born from the war.
In medical terms,
they call that a paranoiac,
in military terms a corporal.
- Is that brandy?
- Three stars.
- Show me that.
- No, no...
You took the car to the German army:
it's war.
But the bottle...
is mine.
It's maybe time to give him
another wallop.
Where did you steal this?
I bought it.
When was the last time
you went in Paris?
A year ago.
I transited there
three months ago.
I hope you enjoyed it.
What about speaking
of something else?
Why? It's instructive.
A nice garrison town, isn't it?
"Beaucoup plaisir, promenade,
jolie mademoiselle..."
I lived two years in the student residence
across Montsouris Park.
The left bank is nothing
except for the stadium.
At night, I used to go to eat
rue Monsieur Leprince.
- At the Chinese's?
- At Adèle's.
Is the tour over?
I've been listening this "Paris this,
Paris that" crap for two years.
The nice cheap bars,
the saturday night balls,
the place du Tertre and so on...
Soon, one of you is gonna show a metro
ticket and pictures of Notre-Dame.
For me all this is gone; there's
no more Paris and that's it.
Are you insensitive to nostalgia,
corporal Dudu?
No, but I don't think backwards,
I leave that to pussies and crayfishes.
- Bravo!
- I'm glad to hear that!
Scratch a boxer and a philosopher
will come out of it!
There's a sleeping Plato
in every Dudu.
Do you know what Plato is telling you?
Did you notice, captain, the friendliness
between noncommissioned officers
and privates we have?
That's what they call democracy.
We share joys and sorrows.
We share everything
...but the brandy.
And they are supposed to be
out of equipment...
What are we doing?
We move. Come on.
Do you really want to stay here?
That's the beginning
of the end, guys.
We've got 200 litres
of petrol with us!
Everybody down!
After you.
They are bombarding from high,
they must be Canadians.
Those morons are gonna
dump one of these on us!
Don't insult them,
they are our allies.
Don't try to run,
that would be stupid.
Don't worry, Dudu,
we're here.
Wow, my man...
so it's not only about
making prisoners...
We could use a coachbuilder.
- Let's just hope it starts.
- Shit, my beret.
- Don't move, I'll get it.
Listen to this...
Remind me to buy myself
a Mercedes.
Special service for the labourers.
- Here.
- Hurry up!
You can hold your brandy.
Bravo!
Get off by this side.
Slowly.
If it overturns, we won't be able
to put it back on its wheels.
Look at this...
Maybe I can handle this.
Maybe, yes.
Hold here.
- What?
Here!
Wait, while you manoeuvre it,
we'll prop it up.
- With what?
- With that!
If the car overturns,
we'll be crashed under, great idea!
The greatest idea I had
was to let you drive.
I wouldn't say anything
if I was you.
Ready?
Come on.
Stop, it's okay.
He's running away,
shoot on the tyres!
With what?
- Jesus Christ, I told 100 times
to never get off the car
without your weapon.
Give him yours.
Come closer, gentlemen.
Hands on your neck.
- We look smart.
- Who's at fault?
"Who's at fault?, Who's at fault?"
- We won't be here if you had let me do.
If the other one didn't overturned
the car, we wouldn't be here neither.
"It's not me, sir, it's the other fellow."
You're worst than kids.
"Concord between the French
has never been needed as it is today."
A field marshal said that.
- Come on, not today!
Okay.
I said hands on your neck.
Don't you understand French?
Take the front seats.
Corporal, you take the wheel.
On your neck.
En route to Tobruk.
Where do you think
it's gonna take you?
To Tobruk. Fourth floor.
I'm sorry, corporal,
but I can't wait to take a bath.
Don't answer, just drive.
I can't watch
the four of you.
Corporal...
- What?
Tell him there's no grenade
under the seat.
What could I do
with a grenade?
I don't know but don't do
anything stupid.
I think we're stuck in the sand.
I couldn't have done
better myself.
Get off.
Everyone.
Dig.
No.
You won't drink anything before.
We don't care,
we're not thirsty.
Good.
I'm not in a hurry.
- We neither.
Step back.
A southern rosé.
Don't you want some?
Good night!
Hey, captain!
En route.
If someone told me there
were snails in the desert...
Not as good as the grey ones,
but quite okay.
No one can contest that
you improve on acquaintance.
That's true: ace driver...
chef...
What were you doing
in civilian life?
I never was a civilian.
Since 1939, you military people haven't be idle.
- Since 1938.
Do you think it's funny?
Very.
I think like him.
An officer who doesn't like
to fight is a crook.
You are making war thought
you say everyday how stupid it is.
You should had stay home.
That's a funny one!
He is a professional soldier
but I didn't ask to come.
They sent me a notice.
So what?
You didn't had to answer.
Sammy, replace me with him,
I'm out of breath.
To my point of view
the best part of war
is the victory parade.
The boring part is
everything before.
We should cash our enlistment money
and parade right after.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
If you don't like war
why sign treaties with countries
that always fight war?
Sign a treaty with Switzerland
or Luxembourg.
My dear Ludwig, you don't know
the French well enough.
Our freedom complex
goes back to 1789.
That's why we slaughtered
half of Europe.
Ever since Napoleon
crushed Poland,
we've refused to let
anyone else do it.
It would make us feel frustrated.
That was a long time since
you didn't talk nonsense.
Yes, I was missing it.
Yet it's because of the Polish
they sent me to Norway.
Can you understand that?
You were in Narvik?
Nice little seafront.
- I know very well.
- Is this coming from there?
Yes.
The only things I brought back
are frostbites.
From Narvik, I went to England
instead of going home.
Why? I'm still wondering...
If you want to make friend with him,
just pretend
you believe it was patriotism.
It was ambition.
The petty bourgeois mind,
the lunchbox security.
You won't get me like this,
you bunch of dummies.
And there's the double pay. For the
noncommissioned officers it's not bad.
The more it last,
the more he fills his pockets.
It won't be okay if you start
speaking dough, guys.
I'm the only one who'll
end up sunk by all this.
-How's that?
- You know it perfectly.
Ludwig doesn't.
You know I'm not
a professional soldier.
I had a job you don't do for long
and it was my last years.
When I think that 15 days
before the declaration of war,
I was suppose to box with Gustav Rudin.
A fellow citizen of yours.
Only 15 days before
and on top of the bill.
- On top of the bill!
- Perfectly, on top of the bill.
And they would have had
to add more chairs.
That's what I left behind me, only to have
my arse kicked in the fjords!
That would maybe have had
the same thing on the ring.
Kidding me?
It was a piece of cake.
- How do you know?
- The fight was fixed.
Don't you think they're
a bit dumb, captain?
- We must admit we have some good laugh.
- Yes...
Here, have another one.
Shit.
It seems some were
in trouble here.
It's no longer a minefield,
it's a fairground.
Anyway we've been through this
on the way, we'll do it again
on the way back.
That's how things are going.
Who was driving the first time?
- Me.
Then it's you again.
Let's go!
"Let's go!". That's a funny one.
The first time we had marks, and a map.
- Where is it then?
- In Tobruk...
With the lieutenant.
Boys, I'm okay to try,
but I can't guarantee anything.
Because the landscape
is pretty different.
You can believe me.
There's no hurry
to blow ourselves up!
Take your time,
we're not in a hurry.
Anyway, they'll say
we've been sightseeing.
If anyone dares
to tell me that!
Do you mind?
Do you know he's a good guy?
Of course I know it.
What can I do about it?
You were right.
At war, we should always kill
the people before to know them.
Let me sit, Dudu.
Look at the specialist.
You still love that, do you?
I'll never get use to land mines.
I'd like to know who's the moron
who invented them.
Leonardo Da Vinci.
I'm lost.
Some marks are gone.
I don't recognise the place.
- No... You'll remember!
- I'm telling you I'm lost!
I'm lost, I can't help it.
There's only one solution.
Get back in our tracks.
And go round the minefield.
Why?
Are you afraid?
Yes.
Thanks.
No...
Don't touch.
How far is the other road?
It's a 120 kms detour.
Let's get back to it.
Don't worry: you'll be in
the hospital in one hour.
And us, under the shower.
Oh shit, I forgot...
What can we do?
We could suggest him for
the Croix de guerre.
Let's go.
How far is El Alamein?
About 15 kms.
Stop.
I have to give an injection,
otherwise he won't be back with us.
What would you do if
you were in my shoes?
What you're gonna do.
Take François to the hospital.
Yes but...
And you?
This situation is so stupid.
You already said he's a good guy.
What's your point, let him go?
No...
But we could think it over...
Just a supposition:
while we drop François at the hospital,
he could get away
from our watch.
It's only a supposition.
What does it mean clearly?
It means I'm really fed up of all
those military codes of conduct!
Is that clear like this?
Say, Ludwig...
Yes.
I feel like Dudu is gonna hate you,
he really loathes problems.
My case is not a problem.
To me neither,
but have a look at them!
Dudu forgets the frostbites from Narvik,
the other one the two years
he spent in the pen.
They evolve into the sublime.
But me, I don't forget anything.
I'm the nasty one, the spiteful one.
I don't like being a cuckold.
When I started reading Hegel,
you guys were already on "My kempf".
The French always
are a book too late.
That's why I'll sort good and
bad German later, with a clear head.
But as long as my head will be
under a kepi, I'll stick to clichés.
And I see only one for you.
When you have a prisoner,
you keep him.
Exactly. We were five when we left,
we're five to come back.
The account is good.
I don't want to bother you...
but I don't think
you'll stay five for long.
You're in Samuel Goldmann's hands,
a leading expert, so don't speak
of what you don't know.
You'll be on your feet
in one week.
And you'll shag your nurse
in two weeks.
For a start, we'll put you
in a terrific room.
And after?
I wanted to be put under
the Arch of Triumph...
Too bad there's already someone.
Send the guy back to his family
wouldn't be a bad idea.
But send him back on the other side
so we can keep on fighting each other,
is it that great?
Shit, a Kraut.
He really has some nerve!
Load it.
Ready.
Hey, guys...
Sam!
Guys, answer me for Christ's sake!
Hey, you bastard,
can't you take off your hat?
Excuse-me,
I was thinking of something else.
Translation and timing:
Aquasantajoe
For Cinemageddon, July 2010