Colonel Armstrong, M.G.
Colonel, you'll fly to
Seoul at 18OO hours.
You can rest in the lounge until that
time right over here through the door.
- Roger.
- Saville.
Major, you'll sleep here tonight. We'll
fly you to Seoul tomorrow at 1OOO.
From there you'll go by
bus to the 54th Group...
...at K 13.
- Thank you, sir.
Martini, please. Very dry.
Pardon me, Major, but
aren't you Cleve Saville?
- Yes, I am.
- I'm Gifford, the Club Officer.
- You wouldn't remember me.
- I'm sorry.
I was only a lieutenant in
your old wing in London.
Really?
- What 's your assignment?
- 54th Fighter Group.
They're the rough ones.
You'd like to be flying with them?
- I am.
- I just thought...
I haven't a desk job yet,
I'm glad to say.
A 54th pilot is here for a
weekend. Yeah, there he is.
Lieutenant Abbott!
Lieutenant?
How are you? This is Major Saville
who is assigned to your group.
I'm Carl Abbott, Major.
- It was nice to have seen you.
- Thank you.
- You want a drink?
- Just got one.
Give me a double bourbon. And
fill the Major's up when he's through.
I have sinus trouble
and it 's torturing me.
- Wait, you're Cleve Saville.
- That 's what the man said.
This sinus I can't think.
We've been expecting you.
The guys are already trying
to get in your command.
- It may be a different war...
- It 's a lousy war!
It may be a different war, but
nothing else has changed.
You still find things out for yourself.
What command?
- Squadron. Col. Imil said so.
- Imil?
Dutch lmil. That sinus!
I must have another drink.
Kevin, put one on the fire.
He's our Group Commander.
- He flew with you?
- Oh, sure! I remember him.
- We were in the same flight in London.
- He goes way back too.
The hero of 44. The first of the
jet pilots. A killer. A hunter.
He eats two steaks at dinner.
The world is too small for him.
A pilot needs confidence and
he has enough for all of us.
- When do you report?
- I fly to Seoul at 1OOO tomorrow.
That 's my flight. Do you wanna have
dinner with me? I'm meeting a girl.
- Not if you have a date.
- Major, I want you to come.
- Okay?
- All right, thanks.
We'll have just one more and we'll
go. Kevin, you're neglecting me.
Tell the driver I'll be back.
- Lt. Abbott 's table?
- Yes, sir. Someone is waiting for him.
No, I'm not staying.
He'll take care of you.
Do you... speak English?
Fairly well, I think.
In a place like this,
I expected you to be Japanese.
Thank you for interest, but
I am waiting for someone.
Yes, I know. Lieutenant Abbott.
I came to tell you
he won't be here.
It isn't like Lt. Abbott
to send a substitute.
I'm not... but neither
is it a bad idea.
- Where is Lt. Abbott?
- He's outside in a cab.
- I'll go with you.
- Allow me.
Thank you.
- Carl? Carl?
- Don't waste your time.
It wasn't the doubles at the club, it
was the triples on the way over here.
- Why did you let him?
- Would you care to repeat that, please?
I'm sorry.
I'll drop you off before
taking him back to the field.
I would'nt like anyone
to see him this way.
In the barracks there is nothing
odd about a man being poured into bed.
I know, but I want to take him
with me. Will you help me?
Ok.
Where are we going?
My name is Saville.
Cleve Saville.
- Do you fly with Carl?
- Not yet, but I'm assigned to his group.
Do you know when
he returns to Korea?
Ten tomorrow morning.
Same flight as mine.
- It 's kind of you to help me.
- I'm a kindly soul.
There. On the sofa will do.
Does he always
knock himself out?
Not like this. In the beginning
he almost never drank.
- He's scared.
- How do you know that?
I've known many pilots. Too much
booze is a sign. Headaches, too.
He thinks he's a bad flier because
he hasn't gotten any enemy planes.
He's had over 3O missions.
If he were bad, he'd be dead.
- He thinks he's just lucky.
- Maybe he is.
A man can't hit that hard
and fight jets. Not for long.
I want to help him,
but I don't know how.
Fighter pilots don't want to be helped.
They're stubborn.
You don't tinker with a man's fear.
He does that for himself.
- Is there anything else I can do?
- Would you like some coffee? It 's hot.
Hot coffee? You really were
expecting the guy, weren't you?
Of course.
- Nice place.
- Thank you.
- You're not in Japan long?
- A few months.
- Did you tell me your name?
- Christina. I'm usually called Chris.
- More coffee, Major?
- No, thank you.
If only Carl could feel the
war was more important...
that what he's doing
has a bigger meaning...
...I don't think it would be like this.
- The war has a bigger meaning.
But it came too soon after the
big one to sell anybody on it.
- You're not sold on it?
- I'm air force. I don't have to be.
No, I suppose not. A professional
doesn't ask questions.
We're not paid to ask questions,
we're not blind sheep either.
We can get out, or we can
wangle any sort of duty.
I'm over age for combat,
but I managed to get here.
- You wanted combat?
- Sure.
- Why? Do you like the war?
- It 's the only war I've got.
- I see.
- I doubt that you do see.
Why? I've seen men going to
Korea from World War II...
trying to recapture a feeling of
importance the other war gave them.
I know the kind of men you mean.
It isn't like that with me.
The war permits me to do
what I do best: Fight planes.
- What about you?
- What do you mean?
I bring a drunk home for a
mysterious girl, a very pretty girl.
I discuss my private business
and all I get in return is coffee.
But I thought you knew...
I mean, when you came into the cafe.
I'm sorry, Major.
I'm Lt. Abbott 's wife.
But he said he was
going to meet...
No, I didn't know it.
I guess I've been stupid.
I hope I haven't also been rude.
No, you haven't.
Well... in any case,
thanks for the coffee.
- Will he stay sober tomorrow?
- Who will stay sober?
- Who are you?
- A man with egg on this face.
It 's Major Saville, Carl.
Yes! Major... surely.
What happened? I haven't
been in any trouble, have I?
No, no trouble, lieutenant.
Good night.
- I'll see you tomorrow on the plane, sir.
- Sure. Tomorrow.
- Good night, Mrs. Abbott.
- Good night, Major. And thanks again.
How are you?
I'm sorry, honey.
I got with a bunch of guys.
You know how it is.
I ran into Major...
what 's his name?
- Saville.
- That 's right. Saville.
He's a big man. He and lmil...
old buddies. Killers!
What do you know?
Saville!
- The major with the confetti?
- Yes, that 's Cleve. Come on.
- Hello, Cleve.
- Colonel lmil!
- I'm still Dutch.
- Thanks, Dutch.
This is Monkey Moncavage. Maybe
you've heard of him. He has 11 Migs.
It 's a well know name.
Glad to meet you.
- Pleasure, Major.
- Knock it off!
- Knock it!
- This is Cleve Saville.
We flew together when a pilot
had a hangover for breakfast.
He's a big hunter.
He's the Iceman.
He's worth knowing, but don't fly
with him unless you want action!
Come to my office.
You're gonna like it here.
It 's only 24 miles to the shower!
This is my home
away from home.
We've seen worse.
- This junk is heavy.
- Do you really need that?
It 's a little flash.
It makes me look younger.
I've got to keep up
with these jet jockeys.
There's a lot of good men
lost in this stinking war.
- Did anybody tell you it 's stinks?
- Nobody, but everybody.
No guts.
It 's a war you can't feel.
There is nothing simple about it.
Except dying. That 's always simple.
I forget what this war's about.
- More?
- Not for me, thanks.
They tell you crummy these
Chinese Mig pilots are?
We have statistics.
They loose thirteen to our one.
Sure, thirteen to one.
What they don't tell you...
is that when one is good,
he's too good.
Casey Jones, for instance.
You heard of him, haven't you?
- You're kiddin'.
- I'm not kiddin'.
A Chinese pilot
named Casey Jones?
His plane has the
numbers 7-11 on his fuselage.
Don't ask me why.
Maybe he's a crap shooter. Look.
The Migs are based in Red China,
here across the Yalu River.
We've got orders never to
cross the Yalu, but they can.
- Still?
- Still.
They fly strung out in a line.
Bandit men, they call them.
If a bandit train takes off with
Casey Jones at the throttle...
one of our air groups can
count on losing two pilots.
I've lost seven good men
to that China boy...
seven good men
and a couple of aces too.
Old Casey hasn't been around
lately, but he'll be back.
So never underestimate the Mig pilot.
You're liable to run into one.
It sounds interesting.
I thought it would be. Would you
wring out an 86 in the morning?
If you think it 's necessary.
Not for me. But I guess you
haven't been up for a while.
No diplomacy, please. If you want
to see me fly an 86, I'll show you.
No offense. Routine.
- Sure.
- Glad to have you with us.
Dutch... good night.
- Major Saville?
- I'm Saville.
I'm going to fly with
you this morning.
- I know.
- My name is Corona. Like the cigar.
- Glad to know you.
- Yes, sir.
- My call is Cobra, right?
- Right.
- You'll fly the one marked FU-14O.
- Shall we get on with it?
- You had much time in an F-86?
- Enough, I think.
You'll need it. There'll be a
surprise waiting for you up there.
What 's that?
Col. Moncavage went up a while ago.
He'll test you in mock combat.
- Dutch's orders?
- He gets his kicks with surprises.
- Thanks for telling me.
- I'm a friend to Man.
K- 13, this is Cobra.
Ready to go with two.
You're clear for take-off, Cobra.
Glasses, man.
- Will this be exciting?
- That 's what I'm gonna find out.
It would've been
great 1O years ago.
Ten years is long ago.
Where are they?
Right up there.
Bogey at five o'clock, Cobra.
Moncavage is getting
into position.
Moving to six o'clock.
Watch yourself.
I'll break left
and take him off.
He did it! He pulled a high-speed
scissors and got on his tail!
Get out of there, Saville.
Get out of there!
You're too close.
Saville,do you read me?
Break off.
Break off!
Maj. Saville, this Col. Moncavage.
Sorry,colonel. I didn't know
it was you. Moving out.
The Iceman cometh.
Aren't you too old
to be playing games?
- Maybe I'm retarded.
- Lf you're nice...
I'll give you a squadron
after you've been indoctrinated.
- All I need is four planes.
- All right, then Flight Command.
How long will indoctrination take?
I'm pretty smart.
It 's usually three weeks...
but we give a bonus for old age,
maybe just two weeks for you.
How many hours did
you have in an 86?
- I said "enough".
- Enough is enough.
When you pick your flight would
you pick me? If you can stand me.
- I'm sort of obnoxious.
- I've got a pretty strong stomach.
You sure made a fool
out of the Colonel.
Will you cash this, please?
Thank you.
- Hello, Major Saville.
- Hello, Mrs...
Thank you.
- There. Now we'll star over again.
- Hello, Major Saville.
- How are you, Mrs. Abbott?
- Chris.
Four dolls. You must
have many girls at home.
No, my brother
has many girls.
- Next, please.
- That 's you, Major.
Air Express, please.
You are back in Kyoto very soon.
Hasn't it only been ten days?
Several of us came to pick
up some planes to fly back.
- I see. How's Carl?
- He's fine, I suppose.
US$ 3.35, please.
- US$ 3 and...
- 35 cents. 1,173 yen.
- Carl's fine. Don't worry.
- Thank you.
It was nice seeing you again.
Goodbye.
Chris?
Look...
I have nothing to do.
If you are free, could we have lunch?
Thank you. But I can't.
- There are things I must do.
- What?
You're right.
I haven't anything to do.
Do you know of an interesting
place where we can go?
I can't recommend
my hotel's food.
There is a place I like very much,
but it 's some distance.
- I have the time if you have.
- We'd need a car.
- Rent one right there.
- I'd better warn you.
- It will probably be pre-1941.
- That 's all right. So am I.
Carl's in Kyoto, isn't he?
I guess I'd better admit it.
Yes, he came in with me.
Don't feel bad. I would have
known it sooner or later.
I gather he often acts like this.
You like being stepped on?
I'm trying to understand it.
Wouldn't it be easier to
go back to the States?
That wouldn't answer anything.
Let 's not talk about it now.
All right.
Staying in the service after the
war took the least resistance.
I chose foreign duty...
teaching pilots in France, Turkey
and Greece... marking time.
Until another war.
Until another something.
It just happened to be another war.
Now...
...let 's talk about you.
- What would you like to know?
Just start somewhere
and end somewhere.
All right.
I lived in Oslo, Norway.
I was 16 when the war in
Europe ended. I had no family.
There was a little money so
I went to Paris to study art.
My paintings looked like
a bad cross between...
Rembrandt and Picasso.
I went to NY to study art.
My paintings improved.
It looked like a cross of
Grandma Moses and Salvador Dalí.
I met Carl.
He was very charming.
- We were married and lived happily.
- Did you?
For a while.
Carl got his wings only after
World War II was over.
He was called back for this war.
I came to Japan to be close to him.
When I met him here I didn't know him
and he didn't know me.
That happens to
some men in a war.
They look at death so much,
soon it 's all they see.
That 's the reason I don't go home.
Some time he might need me here.
After the war, if he lives,
maybe we can start over again.
- When will you form you flight?
- Within a few days.
- Can you pick your fliers?
- To some extent.
- Choose Carl.
- He won't be safer with me.
It isn't that. He thinks he's the
only one who is frightened.
This is the problem between us.
He thinks I expect him to be a hero.
To be in your flight...
Cleve Saville's flight,
might give him confidence...
bring him closer to what
he thinks he should be.
You needn't say yes or no.
Just think about it.
He will give you his best.
What are you thinking?
I was being envious
of your husband.
It 's late.
All right.
- What now, Mrs. Abbott?
- Whatever, Major Saville.
I deliberately invited that,
didn't I?
- It seemed right.
- I thought so too.
It has been an altogether
lovely day.
I'm very grateful.
Do you want me to go now?
Yes. I've taken enough
advantage of you.
- Advantage?
- Just that.
And if I don't go?
I'm off balance.
Don't press me too hard, please.
- Good night, Chris.
- Good night.
Cleve?
Forgive me.
Forgive you?
Mrs. Abbott, I'm in love with you.
Hello, Lieutenant.
Hello, Major. I think I can get to
the house by myself this time.
I've just been out
with your wife.
It does her good to get out once
in a while. I'm busy at the office.
- We leave at 6:OO a.m.
- I'll be there if I have to crawl.
- I can crawl pretty fast.
- I'll bet you can.
Surprise!
You're not surprised.
- Did the killer Cleve tell you?
- Accidentally.
He didn't know I hadn't seen you.
Why should he lie for you?
That 's right.
Nobody owes me anything.
Very friendly of Saville to
pay attention to my wife.
We met by accident
and have lunch.
What do you think of him?
- Must you drink now?
- What do you think of him?
What 's the matter?
You must have some idea.
- Is it so important?
- Maybe. What do you think of him?
I think he's a very lonely man.
Lonely?
He doesn't need anybody.
Imil calls him "the Iceman".
He's like death: No feelings,
no nerves, no fear...
Why do you tell me this?
I don't know.
Forget it.
Carl.
Do you think I'm comparing
you with Major Saville?
Aren't you?
- I don't know. I might be.
- Sure.
I couldn't blame you.
I've tried not to interfere.
I've tried to understand...
but you've got to let
me mean something.
I want to be your wife again, even
for the few hours you can spare me.
You've got a big problem, haven't you?
It isn't a big problem,
but it 's our problem.
That 's right.
I guess you're right.
I'll think about it.
I swear to God...
I'll try to think about it.
- Major. You're in and off in a hurry.
- I have a different kind of contract.
They're paying me by the hour.
How do you like that?
Steady as a rock. No nerves.
- Maybe they're numb.
- Maybe they're dead.
- Evening, sir.
- Hi, Corona, Abbott.
How does it happen? I'm to fly
with such select company...
...with you, Major, and Corona.
- Col. Imil made up the flight.
- Will you join us, Major?
- Thanks.
- Gently. Don't rock the boat.
- Are all those yours?
It isn't fair to stack up another
man's beer cans. I have integrity.
I'm the most accomplished
beer stacker in the squadron.
I don't have many
Migs to my credit...
but I can match my can beer
stack up against anyone's.
You say Dutch made
up the flight, Major?
That 's right.
I thought my wife might have asked
you to honor me with your command.
- Why should she?
- She's got my interests at heart.
She believed: "To keep in sickness
and in health, until death..."
She believes a soldier's wife
should follow her man into battle.
I'm not interested in what
you think about you wife...
but in what happens to
me in the Yalu River...
with a drunk pilot
flying my wing.
If you want to fly,
don't drink another beer.
- What if I don't want to fly?
- I'll be happy to oblige you...
by reporting your
alcohol content to lmil.
I guess I don't owe my
wife a vote of thanks.
- Good night, Major.
- Good night, Lieutenant.
I've met his wife a few times.
She's all right.
There's only one thing I can
say fot that guy: He's got guts.
Everytime he takes off on a mission,
he's scared, but he goes anyway.
That 's what counts...
when you go anyway.
Nobody makes you fly.
He could dog it. Nobody cares.
Nobody cares but Abbott.
- Give me some cigars, will you?
- Yes, sir.
What 's your name?
I've been buying cigars here for
weeks and you don't know my name?
- Charlie!
- I ought to be shot at sunrise.
Pell. P-E-L-L.
- Pell. Eight cigars.
- What do you mean? Six.
Six. You can't
blame for trying.
- Major Saville?
- That 's right.
- I'm Ed Pell.
- What about it?
- I'm assigned to your flight.
- Meet Lt. Corona. Same flight.
- How are you?
- Glad to know you.
- When do we get a mission?
- We have the morning mission.
Briefing at 5 o' clock.
Don't you ever read the schedule?
I just left Indoctrination. 5 is
all right with me. "George".
- What?
- "George".
"Tom" and "George". "George" means
"okay" and "Tom" means "not okay".
- Right, pal?
- You got it, man.
You're not experienced, eh?
Enough to know rude young guys
with big cigars in their faces.
You're the ace from
World War I?
I got my wings in the
Battle of Gettysburg.
Man, that 's real "George"!
A cigar?
- No, thanks.
- How about you that?
- You want a Corona, Corona?
- It 's gonna be a long winter.
Not so good, eh? "Tom".
- Where you from?
- Peoria.
- Peoria, what?
- Illinois. What do you think?
I didn't know. I was asking.
I'm sorry, but everybody
is picking on me.
- Do I look like I have bugs on me?
- Have you an itch?
A silly question
gets a silly answer.
- Sir.
- Sir. Am I gonna fly on your wing?
- You're on Corona's wing.
- I could be safe in the infantry.
I'm really good, Leader.
You'll give me a shot at a Mig, eh?
- You'll get a shot.
- You guys are all right...
we'll murder them.
Thanks, Major. Good night.
We'll jive at 5, eh?
- Good night, Lieutenant.
- Later.
You're too wide,
Cobra Four. Bring it in.
Yes, sir, Major.
That 's your position.
Stay there.
A wing man must cover his leader.
Don't forget.
Yes, sir, Major.
Whatever you say.
Why can't the Migs come to us
sometime? We always chase them.
They can bail
out near home...
Stop talking, Cobra Two.
This line's for business.
We're coming over enemy territory,
Cobra Flight. Test your guns.
Cobra Flight, fuel check.
Cobra Two,3OO gallons.
Cobra Three,320.
Cobra Four,295.
We'll make one more sweep
to the river and then go home.
Four bogeys at 3
o'clock, Leader!
You're sure? We know of no
bandit activity in this area.
- Leader,I see them too.
- Roger. I see them now.
4 bandits on parallel course. Maintain
present heading. Drop your tanks.
What are we waiting for?
Cobra Lead,
I can't drop my tanks.
I'll decoy, Abbott.
Follow me down.
- Three, what are we waiting for?
- Let's go,Pell.
Get away, Cobra Four!
I got one! Do you see him?
Affirmative, Cobra Four.
I see him.
Where is Corona?
Where is number 3?
Just hold still.
I'm hit! Cover me, somebody!
The Migs are crossing the river.
Break off. Are you okay, Cobra 3?
I'm burned up, freezing to death
and down to 15O gallons of fuel.
Let 's go home!
- Cobra Four? Where are you?
- Fouro'clock wide,Lead.
What are you doing out there?
Get back into formation.
You won't forget
my confirmation?
You'll get your mark.
You'll get your Mig.
Cuckoo,Daddy-o.
I'm losing power.
I must be hit in the engine.
Abbott, see if you can
persuade Pell to go home.
Roger,Leader. Cobra Four,
close it up and let's go home.
My pressure is fluctuating.
My controls are stiff. Look me over.
You've got some holes behind
your gear and in yourtail.
We'll drop down
and head for home.
Blow your canopy off
and eject over the base.
She won't blow. I'll have to fly
her down. Somebody can chop me out.
May Day.
This is Cobra Leader.
Go ahead.
K- 13,Cobra Three is coming in
shot upwith a jammed canopy.
- We have a Mayday!
- Did you read me,K- 13?
We'll be ready for you.
Bring him in on the alternate runway.
Get those trucks running!
Tower, tell Dutch we have a May Day.
- Who is it?
- Corona. He's going to try to land.
- What 's his fuel?
- We don't know.
Tower, this is Cobra Leader.
Do you see us?
I've got 'em.
We see you. Send Corona down.
You land on the main runaway.
- You're by yourself, Cobra Three.
- Aren't we all? Okay, Leader.
Good luck,Seegar.
You look about right. Your gear's
down okay. Speed okay. Relax.
Don't anybody get excited.
I always walk away.
Get your nose down, Corona!
Ease it down!
Drop the nose!
My controls are locked!
All I want to know is this: Where
were you when Corona needed cover?
He was cutting through Major's
line of fire chasing his Mig.
- I didn't see the Major's plane!
- Why did you leave your element?
- I asked Corona for permission.
- I didn't hear that.
You're trying to bug me
and I'm not going to take it!
At ease, Lieutenant!
I said, at ease!
Did you hear Pell
ask permission?
Because he didn't hear
doesn't mean I didn't ask.
All right, that 's all.
You and Lt. Abbott can go.
- I'll talk to Major Saville.
- I want to hear anything said about me!
Are you too stupid to understand
you've been dismissed?
- Okay!
- What did you say?
Yes, sir.
I've been dismissed.
- What do you think about him?
- I can't use him.
Look at this record.
"Air to ground gunnery:
First in his class.
Air to air gunnery: First.
Tactical combat: First.
First... first..." And on his
first mission he gets a Mig.
- At the cost of one of ours.
- That could've been...
a misunderstanding.
Maybe Pell did ask permission.
He's a liar.
I can't ground a man
on what we only think.
It 's your decision.
I don't want him in my flight.
Nobody else will want him either.
There's another way to handle this.
Make Pell your element leader.
Then you've got no worries.
Somebody else can cover him.
You want me to praise him?
Say: "You killed your leader...
...l'll make you leader"?
- Nobody's praising him.
I've got one thought: Get Migs.
That 's my job.
This little stinker
can get Migs!
If he doesn't get killed first,
he'll be an ace.
I won't stand in his way.
Let somebody else wipe his nose,
not me... not my flight.
Yes, in your flight.
I couldn't find a better place!
Most of these boys are risking their
lives because it has to be done.
But you're different. You like the risk.
It 's how you get your kicks.
When you risk your life it 's
to see if it 's your turn to die.
Let 's not pretend you care about
the death of another pilot.
I remember you
from the old days.
You were just like this boy.
Way out, all by yourself.
You're two of a kind, you and Pell.
You can handle him.
Make him your element leader.
That 's an order.
That 's all, isn't it?
Yes, sir. Thanks for the
review of my past history.
Past history?
Current events.
Men like you don't get
any better, just get older.
As you say, Colonel.
Major! How about it?
Did you sink me?
Thanks. You're all right.
I thought you'd defend me.
- You did?
- Sure.
I figured you were a guy who
would take care of his men.
- I am.
- I know.
And that poor guy, Corona?
Tough, eh? How about that?
- How about that?
- What was that for?
For "that poor guy, Corona".
- Should I said I lied?
- That might do for a starter.
Okay, I'm lying.
Corona burned on account of me.
Now, you tell me something.
How will it help for me to admit it?
- You think it 'll help Corona?
- No, but It helps me.
You're my new element leader.
I didn't want any doubts about you.
I'm stuck with you, but if you
fly with me you'll fly right...
unless you want a lump of hot
lead in the back of your head.
You dig, Daddy? "George"?
Yes, sir.
Major!
- You have nothing to worry about.
- I'll buy that when I see it.
You're right, that does look
like two other painters.
It 's fine for me to say that,
but not for you.
You're not answering
your phone.
I knew you were here. I thought
it wouldn't be wise to see you.
You could've told me
that on the telephone.
Perhaps that 's why
I didn't answer it.
You're very attractive,
Mrs. Abbott.
Thank you, Major.
Is Carl all right?
- He's not in Kyoto.
- I haven't heard from him.
He's my wing man.
That was nice of you.
He wasn't pleased?
He suspected you
had helped him.
- I don't seem to do anything right now.
- Maybe you ask too much of yourself.
I have that same jalopy parked
outside. Shall we use it?
This folder it 's a...
it 's a"what to see" folder.
Put out by the Air Force.
It says there's a lake near
here with scenery around it...
boats and things like that. Perhaps
you might want to look at that.
No. It 's not necessary. I'll
go with you. Give a minute to dress.
- Am I being foolish?
- No!
There you are.
They frighten away the bad
spirits and please the good ones.
In the East, they have
a saying for everything.
"In my house when the
wind sings, love dwells".
This should have happened
before I met Carl.
Now it 's out of time,
out of place.
The time is always now,
the place is always here.
- But not like this. Not like this!
- Is there any other way?
- I don't know.
- Would you give him up?
No.
But you said yourself your life
was going nowhere. So is mine.
I can't desert Carl.
- Then what 's left for us except...
- All right...
all right, if it will mean
anything to you at all...
No, you're right.
It 's out of time,
out of place.
Cleve!
Will you...
A woman is a strange
and wonderful thing.
I'll wager you'll ask
me to look after Carl.
I'll look after him, Chris.
Good night.
Hail to the Ace of Aces,
the Achilles without a heel.
How are you?
I used you absence to
a good advantage.
I haven't had a drink of water
in three days, and I feel fine.
Good.
Did you hear about the
return of Casey Jones...
starring Col. Moncavage
and six orientals?
Yeah, I heard about it. How do
you know it was Casey Jones?
He had the same 7-11
painted on his fuselage.
He took Moncavage
out with one pass.
He got close and
exploded him, like that.
His wingman killed Johnson and
the rest of our birds came home...
on a wing and a curse.
Would you do a favor
for an old friend?
Maybe. What is it?
If we run into Casey Jones,
would you let me take him?
- You and Pell have got enough.
- That 's not the point.
- You think I'm not good enough, right?
- No, I don't think you're good enough.
So don't you get any ideas.
You stay on my wing.
Thanks, pal. I love you dearly.
See my wife?
- She called on you, I guess.
- No, it was the other way around.
- It 's a nice gesture. Thanks.
- Think nothing of it.
- Cleve.
- Yeah.
You want to compare notes?
So... the Iceman has got
a melted spot, eh?
But aren't we a bit confused?
Wife's lover slugs husband.
Oughta be the other way around,
shouldn't it?
Wouldn't you be worried
flying beside me?
All I've got to do is drop
back and press the trigger.
That 's all you've got to do.
Don't worry. I have another idea.
I'll make you a deal, Cleve.
I get a chance at Casey Jones if
we meet him... you get my wife.
Up and even.
What do you say, old Cleve?
- Excuse me, Major.
- What is it?
Col. Imil wants to see all
Flight Commanders.
Thank you.
Well, Cleve?
What 's it like in that
tortured mond of yours?
Exclusive.
It 's reserved only for me.
I'll show you what I mean.
The enemy has cut
through this bulge.
We have 18,OOO
men in this pocket...
Marines, Blackwatchs, the Turks and
the Greeks. They'll hold the pocket.
Sometime about O3OO hours,
a flock of C-119's will leave...
to parachute supplies and
reinforcements into the pocket.
We'll use all our planes to give
them the most protection we can.
The Migs will be swarming
up there like bees.
It 's no accident that Casey Jones
has reappeared.
They're probably using
all their best pilots.
We must stop them.
That 's all. It 's simple.
You'll get your time over
target in briefing. Goodnight.
Viper and Rattlesnake
go to the Chinnampo area.
Cobra Flight, break off.
That 's the Sunanju River.
Roger, Phyton.
Keep it close,Four.
I'm having engine trouble.
We won't risk it.
Break off and go home.
Roger,Leader.
Good hunting.
- Fly spare, Pell. Don't get into trouble.
- Roger, Leader. I'm a cautious kid.
- Cleve, did we make a deal?
- No chatter. Maintain silence.
- This is the day. I fell it.
- Knock it off.
- Planes at one o'clock low!
- I've got them.
- Phyton, this is Cobra.
- Go ahead.
Bogeys at 2O, OOO feet
coming into target area, heading 1-4-O.
See what you can cut out of them.
We'll take on the rest.
Roger, Phyton.
Cobra Flight, drop tanks.
Cobra Two! Come in, Two!
Where are you, Abbott?
He was hit, but he bailed out.
Cleve, above you! It 's the crap shooter!
Phyton, this is Cobra.
- I read you, Cobra. Go ahead.
- Do you need us?
We've had a tactic shoot here.
The remaining Migs have fled.
The drop is under way.
- Pell, where did Abbott eject?
- To the north,I think.
Let 's take a look.
Swing around to the left.
Leader, I only have
14O gallons of fuel left.
I have 17O. I'll look awhile.
You break off and go home, Pell.
Rescue can't send a chopper in
this far.
- Did you hear me,Pell?
- Yes, sir.
- Then you heard me say,go home.
- Breaking off.
Easy, Carl. I've got you.
I followed you,
so court-martial me.
Get out of that yellow gear.
He got it bad, eh?
- Can you use that automatic?
- I'm a killer, man.
You go on ahead of us.
That way, to the south.
- Let 's make a stretcher.
- We must get out of here first.
Come on, let 's go.
- Who's next?
- Mrs. Abbott.
Send her in, please.
You may come in now.
This it Lt. Abbott 's wife.
Major Dark.
Won't you sit down?
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
I've known other wives who've
had this appointment. I know why.
- Is Carl dead?
- He's missing.
- How long has it been?
- This it the fifth day.
He was been parachuting
into enemy territory.
He's alive?
If he wasn't hit and his fall
was good, he may be all right.
However, if he is,
he's almost certainly a prisoner.
I know that 's not very comforting,
the Red prison camps...
being what they are, but there
is a chance that he is alive.
Is there no way to find out?
The information we
receive from the Reds...
through neutral channels
is seldom accurate.
If his name isn't on the prisoner list
that doesn't prove anything.
I see.
Did you know Lt. Pell
or Major Saville?
- Saville was the flight commander.
- I know Major Saville.
They were searching for your husband.
They are also missing.
- That was my fault.
- I don't think that 's quite possible.
I asked Major Saville
to look after Carl.
Of course. But that 's a phrase that
we all use: Looking after someone.
I don't think it would be just
a phrase to Major Saville.
Thank you, sir.
If we get any news,
I'll get in touch with you immediately.
Thank you.
Mrs. Mason.
This is Lt. Mason's wife.
Major Dark.
Won't you sit down?
Cigarette?
- Take it.
- Man, we could start a war.
Keep a close watch.
Eat this.
- Where's yours?
- I've had mine. Eat it.
They must make this
from Stalin's socks.
- Cleve.
- Yeah.
None of us are going to
get out of here unless...
Unless what?
Unless you and Pell let them find
me and go on by yourselves.
They don't take
wounded prisoners.
You'd get a gun butt right
between the eyes. Now eat it.
Let 's get out of here before they
star tracking us in the mud.
I got it.
Let 's go.
Set him over here, Pell.
Forward a little bit.
- How is he?
- I don't know.
Look! We're not going to
move outta here for a while.
I'll stand the first watch. Why
don't you sack out for a few hours?
"George".
Have you any of those
Chinese butts left?
Where are we?
Lmjim Baptist Mission.
We're close to the lmjim River.
That means... That means
we have a long way to go yet.
Not as long as it was.
I'm not going to make it.
You've stopped bleeding.
You'll make it.
The crows could be pecking
at me in that tree right now.
You could be in Kyoto...
and she's be free.
Why did you do it, Cleve?
"I could not love thee,
dear, so much...
Ioved I not honor more."
Is that it, Cleve?
You have a soul under
that tough hide.
Cleve.
"The pure in heart".
Who would guess it?
You don't belong in
this stinking world.
Bandage... have you
got a bandage?
- What 's up?
- They're friends.
We don't know what you're
saying, but that sound great.
He's trying to say
they're Christians.
A Bible!
How about that?
We understand.
We... understand.
- What 's happening?
- We'd better get out of here.
Let 's go!
Over here.
Look! If you want to do something,
we'll do it my way.
This way.
See this hand grenade.
Now!
- Where'd you take it?
- Arm.
- All right, let 's go.
- Easy.
Easy.
How about that?
You ready, kid?
Can you pull this
thing by yourself?
I'll go on ahead.
You know, Pell?
You would be a nice guy...
if you'd shave once in a while.
Mother of Athens!
You're Greeks!
- There are you going?
- Right here, Sargeant.
Is the boy in the cart alive?
Yes, he's alive.
Have you a cigarette?
- Is that boy sick, too?
- No. He just fell asleep.
Yes, Mrs. Abbott,
would you please follow me?
You may have 1O minutes with him.
You must not encourage him to talk.
Lt. Abbott? Your wife's here.
- Hello, honey.
- Hello, Carl.
- I'll be back when your time is up.
- Thank you.
Sit down, honey.
Not there.
I'm being taken to San
Francisco next week.
- I know. They've told me.
- What will you do?
- Don't try to talk.
- Chris... what will you do?
I've been in a dark place.
Lying here...
...l've come into the daylight again.
- What are you trying to say?
I'm trying to say that...
I remember how it was
with us before the war.
I want it to be
that way again.
I've waited until...
too late to say that, haven't I?
Got a match?
- You cuttin 'em up again, pal?
- Yes, man. I got my tenth.
- When're you coming back?
- I'm in a weakened condition.
I might even arrange to die.
Isn't he the fang?
The Old Skipper sure is the fang.
How do you talk to him
without an interpreter?
I use smoke signals.
What 's "the fang"?
- I forget, you don't get around.
- Knock it off.
You're getting a medal for Casey
Jones, to add to your collection.
It 's gonna make me top heavy.
Don't object.
Somebody must be a hero.
- Am I in your new flight, Skipper?
- You've earned your own flight.
Not me. I'm scared. I want to
be in a safe flight. Like with him.
- Suit yourself.
- How about it, Skipper?
Don't call me "Skipper",
you read that.
- Surely, daddy-o.
- Blow.
Blow? "George"!
Later.
I have to ask you a question.
I have to ask it. What happened?
- Didn't Pell tell you?
- He said you're both shot down.
- Pell was. I wasn't.
- Pell was lying? That 's all right.
Anybody can run out of gas.
I didn't run out of gas.
Orders are to get yourself and
you plane back if possible.
A man could be court-martialed
for disobeying.
I could have returned safely.
I had to ask you, but you didn't
say have to tell the truth.
I don't want any favors, Dutch.
I don't deserve them.
You know...
You think you got a man dead to rights,
then he throws you a curve.
You, for instance.
I thought I had you all figured out.
Now, I'm not so sure.
Maybe a man is never what
you think he is.
Maybe he isn't even what
he thinks he is.
Anyway, I'm accepting Pell's report.
If you consider that a favor, too bad.
Here's your matches.
- Hello, Chris.
- How are you?
I'm fine. We're unveiling
the arm in about ten days.
- You saw Carl?
- Just now.
Then you know he's
being sent home.
I know. Will you go
back to Korea?
This is the only war I have.
- When are you leaving?
- As soon...
I'll leave as soon as
I can, I suppose.
- You suppose?
- As soon as I can arrange passage.
There's the warning bell for
the visitors. You must leave.
Cleve, if I...
Whatever you're about
to say, don't say it.
Thanks. I was about
to be very childish.
Goodbye, Mrs. Abbott.
Goodbye, Major Saville.
C APTIONS BY VIDEOLAR