- Janek!
- Here I am, Baron.
Come on.
Rub hard.
- Everybody here?
- No, Baron. Not everybody.
Who's missing?
Mr. Bruckmann
and Hauptsturmfûhrer Aschenbach...
who still have to arrive from Oberhausen.
And the old man? Baron Joachim.
Come on, talk.
Baron Joachim is in his apartment.
He's getting dressed for dinner,
and so are the others.
- And my son?
- Can't you hear him?
Gunther.
- What do you want, Thilde?
- Come.
Come.
What do you want?
See.
Just like last year, Thilde.
No more, no less.
Yes, but last year
I was part of the audience.
Instead, this evening it will be different.
- I hope I don't forget my part.
- It will be a grand debut.
Tomorrow, your name
will be in all the newspapers.
All right. Thank you. All right.
A little compromise today and tomorrow...
and one fine day
we won't even be able to find our chairs.
Yes, dear.
I'm almost ready.
You know how Uncle Joachim
insists on punctuality...
- especially this evening.
- Please, help me.
- Darling, stay still.
- Thank you, dear.
You see, one can't always be saying "yes."
They're not reasonable people.
The more you give them to eat,
the more ravenous they become.
Darling, it's 40 years
that Uncle Joachim's been at the helm...
and always with equilibrium and firmness.
Equilibrium. You've used the right word.
A favor to the Liberals,
one to the National Socialists.
A favor to me, and one to Konstantin.
Herbert, you're not being fair.
Joachim is certainly not soft with that...
- particular gentleman.
- Because he's a snob.
If Hitler wasn't the son of a customs agent
and a servant...
Joachim would have already
thrown himself in his arms.
Yes, but you must admit
he took your advice...
and didn't give a mark
to the National Socialists.
That's only because he's so miserly.
- The children?
- You'll be hearing them soon enough.
They must be so nervous.
- Come on, Herbert. Let's go, we're late.
- Thank you.
- Come, darling.
- Yes.
"Now I can feel
"now I can feel them in my little heart
"But there are too many
and I can't repeat all of them
"If you wish to read them
"come closer
"Put your head on my breast
and listen carefully
"listen carefully"
Happy birthday.
Best wishes for your birthday.
Come here. I thank you.
I thank you, too, my little dear.
- Happy birthday, sir.
- Janek.
- Listen. Do you hear them?
- Yeah.
Ever since she was born, she was told,
"You are the most intelligent...
"you're the richest, the most envied,
you're the Baroness von Essenbeck."
How can I ask her
just to become Mrs. Bruckmann?
The wife of an ordinary executive
of the steelworks which bear her name.
An ordinary executive
is not exactly the right term.
You have Uncle Joachim's confidence.
And Herbert and Konstantin
would never make a decision without you.
- Doesn't that mean anything to you?
- Something.
But it's not enough for Sophie.
I've made a career for myself,
but I'll always be one of her employees.
If we decided to get married tomorrow...
old Joachim would lose
that confidence and liking for me.
He likes to believe
that she's the inconsolable widow...
of the adored son, the hero.
Idiot!
He'd probably sack me on the spot,
you know, Wolfe.
No, Frederick, you're wrong.
Today, not even his 10,000 slaves
working in his mines and factories...
not even his money, his castles,
have enough power to put you out...
because we have the power...
and we want you to remain where you are.
If anything,
we want you to climb even higher.
Over whom should I climb? Herbert?
Though the fact that Herbert's
got to climb down is no news to anyone.
His hostility towards
the National Socialists is too apparent.
- But Konstantin...
- Konstantin?
Does he have that much effect on you?
Well, he's a member of the SA.
He has connections with Rõhm.
Our large industries
will need men like you.
And our chancellor
has a weakness for big industrialists.
In any case,
it wasn't Konstantin I had in mind.
"Can you feel?
Can you feel how much I love you?
"Then I don't have to write it down
for you"
Do you think they would agree
to an encore?
I think even more than one,
so don't risk asking for it.
Then I will give up the idea.
That was beautiful.
Wonderful, my dear.
You were perfect, Thilde.
Come, sit down. Thank you so much.
Thank you. Bravo.
Very good.
You are the first to hold yourself back.
You seem to be ambitious,
but you're only a social climber.
Sophie wouldn't be happy.
You worry too much
about Herbert and Konstantin.
And you forget, there's somebody much
more important than they are: Joachim.
You must realize that today, in Germany,
anything can happen...
even the improbable,
and it's just the beginning.
"Personal morals are dead.
"We are an elite society
where everything is permissible."
These are Hitler's words.
My dear Frederick,
even you should give them some thought.
Tonight, for example.
Wonderful, my dear. Perfectly good.
I've so enjoyed it. Thank you so much.
I know it doesn't matter to you,
but your son is really talented.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening.
I'm sorry. Telephone.
A little silence, please. Silence, please.
In Berlin, the Reichstag is burning.
Stop! Did you hear, stop it!
The fire started half an hour ago.
A conspiracy, no doubt.
But I think
they've already arrested the guilty one.
A Dutchman.
A member of the Communist Party.
Communist, of course!
A grave Communist crime
against the new government.
Reich scum!
They could've chosen another day
to burn the Reichstag.
Right, Grandfather?
They ruined your birthday.
It was my headquarters in Berlin.
They still have not been able
to put out the fire.
The Berliners are on the terraces
enjoying the spectacle.
Perhaps I shouldn't be here.
The SA have been confined
to their barracks.
Keep calm, Konstantin.
The coup d'état has failed.
Whatever your battleground is,
it's not Berlin...
or at least it never has been until now.
In any case, the fact that we've uncovered
the leaders of this conspiracy proves...
What conspiracy?
It's clear it's only a pretext.
That's far-fetched, Herbert.
Herbert's theories are always far-fetched.
It's a deliberate provocation.
It can only be somebody
who's against the government.
If there is anyone who doesn't need
a parliament to govern us...
it's your chancellor.
Herbert, please.
All Germany knows
there's a list of proscribed people.
Now's the moment to get rid of
all opposition without trial and publicity...
with all Europe looking on!
The internal order of Germany
cannot interest Europe.
What internal order?
The kind that allows his friends
to enter homes and kill?
Herbert, please.
Didn't your Gõring
promise the enemies of the Third Reich...
- enough rope to hang themselves?
- You're losing your head, Herbert.
Gõring refers to the Communists.
Perhaps you're a Communist, too.
Today it's the Communists.
And tomorrow?
Don't worry about tomorrow.
At this very moment,
there's someone in Berlin...
who's already doing the worrying.
- Isn't that so?
- Well said, cousin Sophie.
Our only worry should be the
celebration of Uncle Joachim's birthday.
Even if this is not a night
like all the others.
Happy Birthday
For a long time...
I have intended telling you...
what I am now about to say.
The dramatic events...
which occurred in these last few hours...
force me to overcome any hesitation...
and uncertainty...
and go ahead.
In all these years...
you know that I have had only one object:
To hold on to
the unity and prestige of our firm.
For that reason,
I always tried to adjust our work...
and our structure...
according to the circumstances.
During the Great War, during peace...
during...
crisis.
Now, in the face...
of these recent dramatic events...
I maintain...
that it is more than ever necessary...
to protect the Essenbeck Steelworks...
from eventual political pressures...
or from...
even greater risks.
You must admit
that I never yielded to this regime.
And everybody knows I never had...
and never will have a rapport
with that... gentleman.
Nevertheless, in the interests
of the factory...
our production activity...
compels us to keep in daily contact...
with these people.
This is why I feel an indispensable need...
to have at my side a man...
in favor of the regime...
- who can guarantee us...
- All right.
My resignation
has been ready for some time, Joachim...
if this is what you're asking.
I am forced to do it, Herbert...
against my will
and without strong conviction.
- But the steelworks...
- Yes.
Right or wrong,
they must always come first.
That has always been your creed.
You sent your son to the slaughter,
so you could say:
"The Essenbecks put children and cannons
into the world with the same sentiment."
And with the same sentiment
they'll be buried.
Forgive me.
I congratulate you, Konstantin.
You'll be the vice president
that we deserve.
Come, Herbert. Please.
I hope I don't follow in the footsteps...
of my predecessor.
Agreed, Frederick?
"Children, the young ones
are coming out of my ears
"A man, a real man
"Children, the young ones
are coming out of my ears
"A man, a real man"
If it suited him, Aschenbach
would stab me in the back. I know that.
But not this time. He's on my side.
On our side, Sophie.
Herbert was right.
They did set the Reichstag on fire.
Coming here in the car tonight...
Aschenbach was perfectly clear in his own
mind that it was going to be successful.
We talked about you and about me,
about Joachim, about the steelworks.
And underneath all that...
he was saying:
"Tonight, you will be
given a special opportunity.
"It's up to you to decide
whether to take it or not.
"Whether to be with us or against us."
You understand what that means, Sophie?
I can't believe they'd put Joachim's name
on the proscription list.
He's much too important
to the steelworks.
For Herbert, perhaps, it's probably over.
Strange things
will happen tonight, probably.
And the only losers will be the onlookers.
I feel as if I've been given
a special mission.
And if I accept it, if I take that chance...
they'll give me all their help.
And there won't any more be a Herbert...
or a Konstantin, or a Joachim.
I will be in command.
I will make decisions. You and I, Sophie.
What have you decided?
It would be the first decision I'd taken...
without consulting you.
You did well, Frederick...
even if I will never know
how to push you enough.
Go, and go to the limit.
None of them are worth
even half of what you are.
You did well to wait,
or to say yes, to thank them.
But now you must make it pay!
All the times
that Herbert tried to push you aside...
that Joachim looked down on you...
and Konstantin, with his protective air,
always trying to help you...
to offer you a hand. He's the worst of all.
Don't be afraid, Frederick.
I'm not afraid.
All we have to do now
is to convince your son...
- that I can do the job.
- I'll take care of Martin.
I know Martin's desires.
He has no sense of values.
The steelworks or a Rolls,
it's all the same to him.
We will throw him the bait. Leave it to me.
- I've won!
- Yes, you've won.
- Where's Erika?
- Erika, come!
- I've won, you can come out now.
- Erika! Where are you?
- Here I am.
- There you are, you naughty little thing.
Come here. Now it's your turn. Come.
Put your hands over your eyes. Like that.
Now count up to 100, out loud.
One, two, three...
four, five, six...
seven, eight, nine...
ten, eleven, twelve...
thirteen, fourteen...
Erika. Come!
Drink! Let's not talk any more. Drink!
- I will not leave my school.
- You'll leave that dirty hole!
You'll come with me to the factory.
I'll drag you if necessary.
But I swear, in 10 years,
you will be in a position of command.
In a position to even throw me out.
At the cost of breaking
that damn cello over your head.
You're getting to be like your mother.
The same delicate stomach!
Never wanted to put her foot
inside the factory.
The heat of the ovens made her giddy.
- Listen, Papa, I have decided...
- I'll decide for you.
I know. You can't bear me.
But even I don't ask that you love me.
On the contrary.
I don't intend to leave that seat...
to that eager Frederick, neither to Martin.
I'll tie you to it...
when your time comes,
and God help me if I don't.
Those bastards have poisoned your mind.
But we'll tear
that school of yours to pieces...
including all their bloody damned books!
Gunther!
- Erika.
- Do you want her to find us quickly?
Come in.
All right.
As I foresaw.
Before daybreak, Herbert will be arrested.
Poor Herbert! And to think
that we're so close to the border.
Will there be a trial?
Is there a specific charge?
I don't believe
such formalities are necessary.
We just have to be careful
of their substance...
and the substance is this:
Before the flames of the Reichstag
are put out...
the men of old Germany
will be reduced to ashes.
Nevertheless, a semblance of legality...
can also be useful sometimes.
But now you must excuse me.
I'm tired and would like to retire.
If you need me.
But to leave like this, like thieves.
We are not the only ones, Elizabeth.
Every day there are a lot of people who
have to leave for other parts of Europe.
We are among the more fortunate.
At least we know where we're going.
- We have friends.
- But when?
The time it takes to get ready
and hand over the office at the factory.
It's all over, Gunther.
It was our fault. Everyone's, even mine.
It does no good to raise your voice
when it's too late...
not even to save your soul.
All we have done
is give Germany a sick democracy.
The fear of a proletarian revolution...
which would have thrown the country
to the Left was too great...
and now we can't defend it any longer.
Nazism, Gunther, is our creation.
It was born in our factories,
nourished with our money.
I know what you're thinking:
That I shouldn't run away...
- and perhaps you're hating me for it.
- No, Uncle Herbert.
- We'll keep in contact, won't we?
- Yes.
It's so late. What are you doing?
- Where's Thilde? Do you know, Erika?
- I don't know.
Thilde!
Herbert, they're here.
They've come to take you.
You haven't a moment to lose.
- Elizabeth.
- No!
Herbert, you haven't got
a moment to lose. Hurry!
- Don't go.
- Hurry!
- You're mad to take that. Give it to me.
- No!
I'll get rid of it for you. Now hurry.
Herbert! Darling, quickly.
- Take care of the children.
- Go, my love.
Herbert, don't. This way.
Open!
You, too, recognize this weapon?
Yes.
The weapon apparently
belongs to Mr. Herbert Thallman.
Should we continue
with our investigation?
Let's leave it to the legal authorities.
Mr. Thallman has taken a file
of compromising documents...
concerning the most recent research
in the steelworks.
It could be very useful outside the Reich.
He cannot make any concrete use of it.
"To the prosecuting attorney.
"February 18, 1933.
"Subject:
"The incrimination
of Herbert Thallman, fugitive...
"for the first-degree murder...
"of Baron Joachim von Essenbeck."
I know what you are feeling,
my dear Martin.
But you can't, from one day to another...
assume such a big responsibility...
without feeling, let's say...
afraid.
But neither I nor Frederick
will leave you alone.
We say, however...
that you have all the time
to continue your studies...
and to take in hand
the problems of the firm.
They aren't small problems, believe me.
Meanwhile, Frederick and I
will keep the business going...
as we have always done in the past.
I had really hoped
that you wouldn't have to assume...
the presidency of the steelworks...
under such tragic circumstances.
But unfortunately...
I still wanted to say that...
Grandfather was right.
In these times, our plant...
Yes, after all...
either it is in agreement
with the government...
or else our business, our advantages...
I don't pretend to be a businessman,
not even a politician.
However, this I know, too...
it's a matter of fact of special production.
There are technical problems.
Good.
Very good.
You've even made a crowning speech.
Now, however, don't exaggerate.
Let's try to give this meeting...
a rather more familiar tone?
- Joachim's intentions...
- I beg you, Konstantin!
Martin has not finished.
He's still saying something.
Let's listen.
Uncle Konstantin,
I will respect all of Grandfather's will.
He has nominated you vice president,
and it's fair that it should be so.
But I think that in a moment like this...
I think, yes, in a moment like this,
the presidency...
above all, needs a technician.
What kind of a joke is this?
It's not a joke.
Enormous interests are at stake.
And Martin thinks...
As far as I know, it's the first time...
Martin ever used his head to think.
I inherit the major stock,
and it's up to me to decide.
It is up to me to decide!
I nominate Frederick Bruckmann...
president of the administration...
and general director
of the Essenbeck Steelworks...
and all its associated member groups.
Frederick Bruckmann.
I pulled you up like this
from the nothing that you were.
Herbert's pistol...
Aschenbach's testimony,
the arrival of the SS.
Too much fantasy, Konstantin.
You come with me.
Today, you, too, learned something.
Things you are not taught
in a school like yours.
Come.
Don't have any illusions.
This war has just begun.
Gunther, come!
To the first model, with the hope
that we will quickly hear its music.
Will this entertainment last much longer?
Your place is here, Martin.
You can't leave now.
All right, sir.
Mr. Bruckmann.
I don't understand...
I knew your father
at the French Front in 1916.
A true Essenbeck, and a heroic officer.
I know.
The General Staff is quite firm
on this point. Either Rõhm goes or we go.
It's naked extortion.
The SA is a knife at the throat
of the high finance and the Reichswehr.
Consequently, it'll be necessary
to stop the flow...
of the heavy artillery
into the barracks of the SA.
Is that your personal opinion?
It is the opinion of the general staff.
And also of the Chancellor,
if you don't mind my saying so.
The army is the army,
and the SA is the SA.
We are not concerned with internal order.
And we will not divide
our traditional duties with others.
Traditional duties?
I'd like to know
where the Prussian generals were...
when we cleaned up Germany
from top to bottom!
- This country will never be clean enough...
- I beg your pardon.
Gentlemen.
No one doubts the merits
of the attack formations, dear cousin.
We ourselves would not be here
without the work of the SA.
But heavy arms are not needed
for public order.
All you have to do is look around.
Germany is the most orderly country
in the whole world.
It's a pleasure
for the American and English tourists.
What more do you want?
And so, gentlemen, we're all agreed.
Not one single machine gun
leaves this place...
unless it is requested by the general staff.
We are close to the elections, Frederick...
and we must win them at all costs
if we want them to be the last.
But you know that takes a lot of money.
Essenbeck is late.
Joachim's stubborn hostility has created
this disagreeable state of affairs.
All the other industrialists
have paid their quota...
Excuse me. It is difficult to set aside
such a large sum of money...
without juggling the balance sheets.
This is a corporation...
and as you well know,
Konstantin can be a problem.
If Konstantin wants
to become a problem...
well then, I say that a problem
always can be resolved.
Don't you think so?
"The state cannot but crush
the innocent little flower...
- "if the flower obstructs its path."
- I am not the state.
I've done everything I was required to do,
and I will involve myself no further.
Come on now!
Don't take me up on every word.
They are words of Hegel, you know.
He'd turn over in his grave...
at the idea of Konstantin being
compared to his innocent little flower.
Don't you think I could go? It's late.
Yes, go, Martin.
Thank you. Goodbye.
You will answer for everything
that may happen here.
Remember that.
ESSENBECK CAST-STEEL FACTORY
H. ESSENBECK
Emmer Street, please. Drive quickly.
- She's not here now. She's gone out.
- Thank you, I know.
Thomas and Heinrich Mann,
Walter Rathenau...
Erich Maria Remarque...
Arnold and Stefan Zweig...
André Gide...
Helen Keller...
Margaret Sanger...
Jack London...
George Bernard Shaw...
Émile Zola...
Marcel Proust.
Come here.
I had to open it. I'm sorry.
I'm obliged to read the mail,
specially foreign correspondence.
Herbert Thallman is my uncle.
It's absurd that I can't receive...
Listen to me, von Essenbeck.
If your uncle had good sense,
he wouldn't write to you here.
Where would you like him to write to me?
He needs help.
- You read that yourself, didn't you?
- I don't want to know anything.
I don't want to be involved in it.
I only want you not to drag our institute
in this mess.
And then, I can't believe...
I refuse to believe what your uncle writes.
- I ask permission to leave.
- Go.
And get your hair cut, von Essenbeck.
Yes, sir.
Yes, I believe that's all of it.
Request for renewal, tax deposit, stamps.
- Reason for the trip?
- Vacation.
Vacation. Going alone, Mrs. Thallman?
With my children.
Thilde, age eleven. Erika, eight.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Do you intend joining your husband?
No.
Perhaps you don't know where he is.
We are always well-informed, you know.
I can't see the difficulty.
We only wish to leave.
Has someone caused you some difficulty?
No, not exactly.
Do you know that your husband
has committed murder?
That's absurd. A disgrace.
Are you sure? Then why don't you
convince him to come back?
- He could prove his innocence.
- But I don't know where he is.
What have the children or I
got to do with it?
Is there some charge, perhaps, against us?
We don't want to leave, just to get away.
- Is someone forcing you to leave?
- No, they're stopping me.
Who's stopping you, Mrs...
Thallman. Elizabeth Thallman.
Perhaps you mean to insinuate.
Answer. Don't be afraid. Answer.
- Good morning.
- Your friend is not at home.
Yes. Okay. Thank you.
She had to go out.
She said she would be back late.
All right.
Lisa.
Look what I've brought you.
Do you like this little horse?
- Yes, thank you.
- You can ride on it. Do you like it?
You can caress it. Try it, Lisa.
- It's all yours. Do you like it?
- Yes.
You must take care of him.
You know, he likes you very much.
He really does.
Lisa!
Lisa, why don't you answer me?
- You're a wicked girl, Lisa.
- No!
What do you think you're doing?
I've told you not to waste time.
You never do any work.
You stay here and play all day.
Look at the disorder in here.
Stop crying, or I'll really give you
something to cry about.
I told you to stop. Didn't you hear me?
Start cleaning up the room.
And the plates need washing.
Come on now. Get to work!
Martin.
It's you.
- I didn't expect to find you here.
- What's the time?
- It's 2:00.
- 2:00.
It's so late.
I had a lot of work to do tonight.
Help me, I implore you. Help me.
I know you're the strongest,
and you can prevent me from going.
But I don't see what's the point.
You can't still be afraid of Herbert.
Yes, before maybe, but now!
Now his papers aren't worth anything.
No one's going to listen to him.
Germany can do as she wishes.
You yourselves can do anything you like
in the whole of Europe.
Nobody's going to lift a finger
against you. So why keep us here?
Oh, yes, because one day
we might remember.
We might say to ourselves what we know
about you, about everyone.
But do you think that day
is going to come, Sophie?
No, it's not.
Herbert still deludes himself.
I don't anymore. You never believed it.
So why? Why keep us here?
Just my presence here
must be unbearable to you...
because it makes you remember
when you want to forget.
I too, I only want to forget.
So let us go away, Sophie. Let us go.
Just one word, one word from you.
One word is enough.
Go. Leave. If this is what you want.
Don't fool yourself, however, Elizabeth.
Don't dream of coming back one day
to find a Germany...
which was so dear to your heart.
It's finished, that Germany. Forever.
There will be no other Germany
but this one.
And you will not be able to escape it
or avoid it.
For it will spread before you know it,
all over Europe, and everywhere.
Hauptsturmfûhrer Aschenbach.
Baroness von Essenbeck.
Lisa.
Come.
Come, I'll show it to you.
Why were you crying the other day?
I heard you, you know.
Did someone hit you?
Your mother?
Does she do it often,
on your little tiny ass?
Why?
Stop it, Martin.
Stop it, darling. I've got to go.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to pose.
To pose?
No, stay with me.
I'm late.
I've got to go, darling.
Didn't you have enough?
I'm late, darling. I've got to go.
Stop it! Please!
Where the devil is that dress?
Darling, please.
Stop it.
That's enough, Martin.
If you want to be of some help,
why don't you tidy up this room a bit?
Look what a mess you've made.
And that stupid little girl is ill.
- Who?
- Lisa.
I've got to pay for her doctor as well.
What's the matter with her?
What's she got?
How should I know? Can't understand it.
She's got a high temperature.
Last night she was delirious.
I'm so late.
Martin, what's the matter with you?
Why don't you do as I told you?
This room is in such a mess.
Now, I really must go.
Darling, when you leave,
lock the door, please.
Goodbye.
Lisa.