CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
TURNER ENTERTAINMENT GROUP
AND U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
HOW DO YOU FELLOWS MANAGE
TO LOOK SO COMFORTABLY, VICKERS?
WE MAY LOOK IT, SIR,
BUT WE'RE NOT.
THEY SAY THE FIRST 40 YEARS
ARE ABOUT THE HARDEST UP HERE
ON THE FRONTIER.
AFTER THAT,
YOU GET USED TO IT.
REALLY?
[MAN SHOUTS]
TROOP, HALT!
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
[BUGLE SOUNDS]
[MAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
PEARSON?
ONE OF THE LEAD HORSES
OF THE SUPPLY CART
HAS BROKEN A LEG, SIR.
[VICKERS]
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
CARRY ON.
GIVE ME THE GUN.
SORRY, SIR.
WELL, OF ALL
THE IMPERTINENCE.
THAT VULTURE--
HAPPENS TO BE
A ROYAL FALCON,
ALMOST CERTAINLY
BELONGING
TO HIS HIGHNESS
SURAT KHAN, SIR.
OH. OH. OH.
FORGIVE ME.
I DON'T KNOW. THEY LOOK
PRETTY MUCH ALIKE
IN THE DISTANCE, SIR.
A QUITE A NATURAL
MISTAKE TO MAKE.
A DEVILISH AWKWARD ONE.
HARDLY AN INGRATIATING WAY
FOR A HOME GOVERNMENT MAN
TO PRESENT HIMSELF
IN A DELICATE MISSION
TO THE SURAT KHAN.
OH, I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
AFTER ALL, YOU MIGHT
HAVE MISSED HIM.
OH? OH, YES, YES.
TROOP,
WALK MARCH.
[BUGLE SOUNDS]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HIS HIGHNESS
IS AWAITING YOU.
HIS HIGHNESS SURAT KHAN,
AMIR OF SURISTAN,
OFFERS A PRAYER
OF GRATITUDE
THAT YOU
HAVE BEEN PRESERVED
IN YOUR JOURNEY
AND PLACES HIS HOUSEHOLD
AND ALL IN IT
AT THE DISPOSAL
OF THE ILLUSTRIOUS ENVOY
OF HER MOST
GRACIOUS MAJESTY
QUEEN VICTORIA.
MAY I EXTEND HER MAJESTY'S
WARMEST GREETINGS,
AMIR SAHIB?
PERMIT ME TO PRESENT
CAPTAIN GEOFFREY VICKERS,
CORNET JAMES RANDALL,
CORNET CHARLES BARCLAY,
CORNET LAWRENCE PEARSON
OF THE 27th LANCERS.
VICKERS...
IT'S GOOD TO SEE THE FACE
OF AN OLD FRIEND AGAIN.
ONE OF THE BEST MARKSMAN
IT HAS EVER BEEN
MY GOOD FORTUNE
TO ENTERTAIN,
YOU KNOW, SIR HUMPHREY.
YOUR OWN HUNTING SKILL,
AMIR SAHIB,
COMPELS ME TO DEPLORE
MY POOR MARKSMANSHIP.
[CHUCKLES]
YOU BRITISH...
SO ADEPT
AT DIPLOMATIC GRACES
THAT EVEN MY OWN RACE
BOWS TO YOUR FINESSE.
GENTLEMEN...
I WOULD BE
INCONSIDERATE, INDEED,
TO INSIST ON ANY LENGTHY
COURT FORMALITIES.
SHALL WE DISPENSE
WITH THEM?
[SIR HUMPHREY]
DELIGHTED.
[CLAP CLAP]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
YOU'RE WELCOME,
VICKERS.
THANK YOU,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
I REGRET AS DEEPLY AS YOU,
SIR HUMPHREY,
THAT SO FAR
THE NEGOTIATIONS
SHOULD HAVE PROVEN
SO BARREN OF RESULTS.
WHILE IT IS REGRETTABLE,
WE MUST REMEMBER
THAT THE TREATY
BY WHICH
YOUR FOSTER FATHER
RECEIVED ANNUALLY
A SUM OF MONEY
FROM MY GOVERNMENT
FOR HIS EXTRAORDINARY
SERVICES
CEASED AUTOMATICALLY
TO EXIST ON THE OCCASION
OF HIS DEATH.
FOR MYSELF, I SHALL
DO MY HUMBLE BEST
TO ACCEPT WITH GRACE
THIS SUDDEN WITHDRAWAL
OF FINANCIAL SUPPORT.
AND MAY I NOT
ADD FURTHER
THAT MY GOVERNMENT
LOOKS FORWARD HOPEFULLY
TO CONTINUED FRIENDSHIP
WITH ITS NEIGHBORS,
THE TRIBES OF SURISTAN?
OF COURSE, I SHALL ENDEAVOR
TO CONVINCE THE NAWABS
AND MALIKS OF SURISTAN
THAT THE ACTION
OF THE BRITISH GOVERNMENT
IS NOT TO BE CONSTRUED
AS UNFRIENDLY,
CALM THEIR NATURAL
RESENTMENT,
AND CURB ANY ACTIVE
REPRISALS THEY MIGHT
SO EASILY CONTEMPLATE.
I AM CONFIDENT
THAT YOUR HIGHNESS'
PRAISEWORTHY EFFORTS
WILL BE REWARDED
WITH SUCCESS.
LET US HOPE
THAT YOUR CONFIDENCE
IS JUSTIFIED.
YOU KNOW, SIR HUMPHREY,
CONFIDENCE IS
AN ADMIRABLE QUALITY.
WE SO SELDOM
APPRECIATE IT FULLY...
UNTIL IT IS WITHDRAWN.
[PEARSON]
YOU KNOW, THE FIRST TIME
I WAS IN BENGAL,
I SAW A FALCON
BREAK A LAMB'S BACK.
BEASTLY BIRDS.
YES, I THINK
I'LL SEND ONE
BACK TO MY FAMILY.
JUST THE THING
FOR A MAYFAIR
DRAWING ROOM.
ANCIENT SPORT
OF KINGS--FALCONRY.
THE APPEAL LIES
IN ITS CRUELTY.
I'D TAKE A POTSHOT
AGAINST A TIGER
IN LONG GRASS ANY DAY.
THEY'RE MAN-EATERS,
YOU KNOW.
ONLY A SAVAGE
WOULD PREFER
THIS SORT OF THING.
[SIR HUMPHREY]
AHEM. QUITE SO.
QUITE SO, VICKERS.
WHY, YOUR HIGHNESS,
I MEANT, OF COURSE--
NO, NO, NO, NO.
I DARESAY YOU'RE
PERFECTLY JUSTIFIED.
HOWEVER, THE SURISTANIS
ARE AN ANCIENT RACE
OF PEOPLE.
THEY CANNOT SO EASILY
FORGET THEIR ANCIENT
TRIBAL WAYS OF LIFE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I TRUST YOU'LL
ACCEPT MY APOLOGY.
OH, PLEASE,
PLEASE, PLEASE.
BORIS.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GENTLEMEN, LET US
GO IN TO DINNER.
UH, BY THE WAY,
SIR HUMPHREY,
YOU WOULD DO ME
THE HONOR IF YOU
AND YOUR GENTLEMEN
WERE TO JOIN ME
TOMORROW MORNING
AT A LEOPARD HUNT
I'VE ARRANGED.
WE START AT SUNRISE,
THE TRADITIONAL HOUR.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MEN SHOUTING]
[ELEPHANT TRUMPETS]
FINE FELLOW--
THE KHAN.
THERE'S A MAN
WHO CAN TAKE A LOSS
WITH GOOD GRACE.
YES. I DON'T THINK
I COULD LOSE £150,000
A YEAR WITH GRACE.
GREAT SCOTT,
VICKERS!
NOBODY BUT
THE HOME GOVERNMENT
WERE SUPPOSED
TO KNOW ANYTHING
OF THE REAL REASON BEHIND
THIS DIPLOMATIC VISIT
OF MINE.
SORRY, SIR, BUT UP HERE
ON THE FRONTIER,
THERE AREN'T
MANY SECRETS AN OFFICER
IN MY POSITION
DOESN'T GET TO KNOW
SOONER OR LATER.
BESIDES, I'VE COME
TO KNOW THE KHAN
PRETTY WELL.
THEN YOU MUST KNOW
THE SITUATION HAS BEEN
A DEVILISH, DELICATE ONE.
HOWEVER, I AM
QUITE CONFIDENT
THAT HE WON'T TRIFLE
WITH OUR FRIENDSHIP.
BESIDES,
THE MAN'S A GENTLEMAN.
ANYONE CAN SEE THAT.
YES, OF COURSE, SIR.
YES.
ANYONE CAN SEE THAT.
[DRUMS BEATING
AND MEN SHOUTING]
[GROWLING]
[GROWLS]
YOU HAVE THE HONOR,
SIR HUMPHREY.
THE KHAN WANTS
YOU TO TAKE
FIRST SHOT, SIR.
HUH? OH. OH.
THANK YOU. SPLENDID.
[GUNSHOT]
MISSED HIM
BY A HAIR, SIR.
BAD LUCK.
[GUNSHOT]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FINE SHOT, SIR.
[SIR HUMPHREY]
EXCELLENT MARKSMANSHIP, SIR.
[SURAT KHAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[ELEPHANT TRUMPETING]
[SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GROWLS]
[LEOPARD GROWLING]
SAHIB.
[MEN SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ARE YOU HURT,
YOUR HIGHNESS?
NO, NOT AT ALL.
BRILLIANT SHOT,
VICKERS.
IT WAS WORTHY
OF YOU.
IT WAS A LUCKY ONE.
I SHALL NEVER
FORGET IT.
MY GRATITUDE
WILL BE ETERNAL.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
WELL, GOOD-BYE,
DARLING.
GOOD-BYE, DEAR.
NOW, REMEMBER,
YOU SIMPLY MUST BE
BACK EARLY
IF WE'RE TO BE READY
FOR THE GOVERNOR GENERAL'S
BALL TONIGHT.
OH, THE BALL, YES.
I SUPPOSE YOU FEEL
QUITE CAPABLE
OF TAKING CARE
OF YOURSELF
AMONG ALL THESE--
OH, HOW SILLY.
A RESPONSIBLE LADY
OF MY YEARS IS
PERFECTLY SAFE ANYWHERE.
YES, I SUPPOSE SO.
WELL...GOOD-BYE.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GOOD-BYE.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ELSA, I'M SO GLAD
YOU WERE ABLE TO COME.
YOUR MESSAGE SAID
IT WAS URGENT.
IT IS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
MY BROTHER ARRIVES
IN CALCUTTA TODAY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
WORD CAME THROUGH
FROM HEADQUARTERS
LAST NIGHT.
NOW YOU'LL UNDERSTAND
WHY IT WAS SO URGENT
FOR ME TO SEE YOU.
GEOFFREY'S
COMING HERE.
ELSA,
THERE'S SOMETHING
I MUST KNOW.
YOU DO LOVE ME,
DON'T YOU?
OH, PERRY.
I KNOW WE BOTH TRIED
TO BE LOYAL TO GEOFFREY
BY HIDING
OUR REAL FEELINGS,
BUT NOW HE'S
COMING BACK, AND WE
CAN'T GO ON PRETENDING.
YOU DO LOVE ME,
DON'T YOU?
OH, PERRY, I'VE TRIED
SO HARD NOT TO,
BUT I DO LOVE YOU.
I KNEW IT.
BUT I'M STILL ENGAGED
TO GEOFFREY.
WE MUST TELL HIM
THE MOMENT HE GETS HERE.
I MEAN, I MUST TELL HIM.
IT'S MY RESPONSIBILITY.
AND WHEN HE KNOWS
HOW WE FEEL, HE WON'T
STAND IN OUR WAY.
BUT SUPPOSING
HE DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
HE WILL.
DARLING, I KNOW HIM
BETTER THAN ANYONE.
I'VE GOT TO TELL HIM.
IT'S THE ONLY DECENT
THING TO DO.
YES.
YES, IT IS.
I MUST BE GETTING
BACK NOW.
FATHER WILL BE
WORRYING ABOUT ME.
YES. YOU'RE RIGHT.
WILL I SEE YOU
TONIGHT AT THE BALL?
YES, PERRY...
TONIGHT.
IT'S ONLY NOW THAT
THE STRATEGIC IMPORTANCE
OF THE SITUATION
BECOMES APPARENT.
THE SAFETY OF
THE NORTHWEST FRONTIER
HINGES ON LOHARA,
WHICH IS THE BASE
FOR THE THREE
ADVANCE GARRISONS,
OF WHICH CHUKOTI
IS THE MOST IMPORTANT.
THEREFORE, TWO
OF OUR ABLEST OFFICERS
MUST COMMAND AT LOHARA
AND CHUKOTI.
I'VE HAD TO
TRANSFER WOODWARD
BECAUSE I'M AFRAID
HE'S TOO WELL ON IN YEARS
FOR AN ACTIVE COMMAND.
YOU SEE, WITH
SURAT KHAN JUST ACROSS
THE SURISTAN BORDER
IN A POSITION TO MAKE
THE APPROACH TO THE PASS
UNCOMFORTABLE,
I FEEL CONFIDENT
THAT WITH YOU,
CAMPBELL, AT CHUKOTI
AND YOU, WARRENTON,
AT LOHARA,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO HANDLE
ANY AGGRESSIVE COMPLICATION
THAT MAY ARISE.
CAPTAIN VICKERS,
SIR.
YES, SIR.
OH, SHOW HIM IN.
JUST A MOMENT.
CAPTAIN VICKERS,
27th LANCERS,
REPORTING FOR DUTY, SIR.
[MAN]
BEEN EXPECTING YOU,
VICKERS.
THE WAR OFFICE
IS SENDING YOU ON
A VERY IMPORTANT MISSION.
OH, SPLENDID,
SIR.
YOU'RE GOING
ON AN EXPEDITION
TO BUY CAVALRY HORSES
IN THE TATAR COUNTRIES.
OH.
DOES THAT MEAN
WE'RE PREPARING
FOR WAR, SIR?
WHATEVER IT MEANS,
YOU'RE TO DELIVER
THE HORSES YOU'VE PURCHASED
TO OUR FLEET AT BATUM
ON THE BLACK SEA.
FROM THERE,
THEY'RE TO BE SHIPPED
TO THE CRIMEA.
THAT CLEAR?
YES, SIR.
OH, WARRENTON, CAMPBELL,
YOU KNOW VICKERS.
[CAMPBELL]
YES, OF COURSE.
GEOFFREY, MY BOY,
HOW VERY NICE
TO SEE YOU.
GLAD TO SEE YOU,
TOO, SIR.
HOW DO YOU      HOW DO YOU DO,
DO, SIR?        VICKERS?
HAVE YOU SEEN ELSA?
NO, NOT YET, SIR.
HOW IS SHE?
SHE'LL BE VERY HAPPY
TO SEE YOU, I KNOW.
I CAN HARDLY WAIT
UNTIL I SEE HER EITHER.
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
GOOD MORNING.
OH, CAPTAIN VICKERS.
YES?
YOUR BROTHER IS HERE, SIR,
INSIDE WITH SIR CHARLES.
OH, YES. THANK YOU.
YES, SIR.
[PERRY]
GEOFF.
PERRY!
BY JOVE,
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU,
YOU OLD DIPLOMATIC
GLOBETROTTER, YOU!
IT MUST BE
MORE THAN A YEAR
SINCE WE LAST MET.
COME IN HERE, GEOFFREY.
IT'S QUIETER. I HAVE SOMETHING
IMPORTANT TO SAY TO YOU.
I BET YOU HAVE. I HAVE
AT LEAST A MILLION
THINGS TO SAY TO YOU,
EVERY ONE OF THEM
OF VITAL IMPORTANCE.
WELL,
LET'S GO INSIDE.
NO. I CAN'T JUST NOW.
I GOT A VERY URGENT
APPOINTMENT.
TONIGHT AND TOMORROW,
WE CAN TALK
OUR HEADS OFF,
BUT JUST NOW...
SEE YOU LATER.
SO, YOU SEE, IT DEPENDS
ON YOU, GENTLEMEN.
AND I THOUGHT I WAS
WELL-ACQUAINTED
WITH THE SITUATION.
BUT I DON'T QUITE
UNDERSTAND
SURAT KHAN'S
PRESENCE IN
CALCUTTA, SIR.
AND THIS DANCE THAT
THE GOVERNOR GENERAL
IS GIVING
IN HIS HONOR
AT THE GOVERNMENT
HOUSE TONIGHT.
FLATTERY IS
THE FOOD OF FOOLS,
BUT NOW AND THEN,
YOUR MEN OF WIT
WILL CONDESCEND
TO TAKE A BIT.
I SEE. FLATTERY
AND FRIENDSHIP,
SO TO SPEAK.
SURAT KHAN, DEVILING US UP
ON THE FRONTIER,
SEEMS TO BE DOING PRECISELY
WHAT THE RUSSIAN CZAR
IS DOING IN THE BALKANS.
YOU'VE READ
THE NEWS DISPATCHES
ABOUT THE COSSACKS
PLUNDERING OUTLYING
TURKISH VILLAGES.
MMM. IT'S AN OLD TRICK,
YOU KNOW--
DEVILING YOUR NEIGHBOR
INTO A WAR.
ONE WOULD ALMOST
THINK THAT THERE'S
RUSSIAN INFLUENCE
AT THE BACK
OF SURAT KHAN,
WHAT WITH RUSSIA'S
VITAL NEED FOR
OPEN-WATER SEAPORTS,
AMONGST OTHER THINGS.
YOU'LL ACT ONLY
ON ORDERS FROM SIR BENJAMIN.
I UNDERSTAND, SIR.
I WANT YOU
TO UNDERSTAND, ALSO,
THAT IT'S IMPERATIVE
THERE SHOULD BE
NO INCIDENT
THAT COULD CAUSE
A FRONTIER WAR
AT THIS TIME.
WE MUST MAINTAIN PEACE...
AT ANY COST.
[MAN SHOUTING COMMANDS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MAN]
MAJOR GORDON
AND MRS. GORDON.
SIR ARCHIBALD McMURRAY.
LADY McMURRAY.
MISS VERONICA McMURRAY.
SIR CHARLES MILLER
AND LADY MILLER.
[WARRENTON]
YOU REMEMBER
MAJOR BARRETT.
OH, MAJOR BARRETT.
AND,
LADY PELHAM,
MY WIFE.
GOOD EVENING.
AND THIS, MY DEAR,
IS COLONEL CAMPBELL,
WHO LEAVES TOMORROW
TO ASSUME COMMAND
OF THE CHUKOTI GARRISON.
COLONEL CAMPBELL,
I AM PLEASED THAT
WE HAVE MET AT LAST.
BENJI,
KINDLY STAY HERE.
MY DEAR,
I WAS JUST GOING--
TO THE REFRESHMENT ROOM
TO GET A DRINK. I KNOW.
THEN YOU'LL BE
UPSET ALL NIGHT.
HERE. TAKE A PILL.
LIFE WITH YOU IS
JUST ONE BLASTED
PILL AFTER ANOTHER--
UH, MY LOVE.
HA HA HA! JUST LIKE
A CHILD--BENJI.
NO IDEA OF WHAT'S
GOOD FOR HIM.
I HEAR YOU HAVE
A BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTER,
COLONEL.
YOU MUST LET ME TAKE HER
UNDER MY WING AT ONCE.
ABOUT TO BE MARRIED,
ISN'T SHE?
THAT'S SPLENDID.
YOU MUST LET ME CHOOSE
HER TROUSSEAU.
YOU'RE A WIDOWER,
ARE YOU NOT?
I AM,
LADY WARRENTON.
WELL, I ALWAYS SAY...
BENJI.
YES. I KNOW.
TAKE ANOTHER PILL.
[GEOFF]
ELSA, DARLING.
YOU LOOK SO LOVELY.
I'M SORRY I MISSED YOU
AT THE HOUSE.
[ELSA]
I'M SORRY, TOO, GEOFF.
[GEOFF]
WHY, IT'S BEEN SO LONG,
I HARDLY KNOW
WHAT TO SAY TO YOU.
WE'LL HAVE PLENTY
OF TIME NOW, THOUGH.
I HATE THESE SEPARATIONS.
[ELSA]
YOU DIDN'T TELL HIM,
DID YOU?
[PERRY]
I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE.
[ELSA]
HOW I HATE THIS DECEPTION.
[PERRY]
ELSA, DARLING,
THEY'RE WATCHING.
[MAN]
HIS HIGHNESS SURAT KHAN,
AMIR OF SURISTAN.
COUNT IGOR VOLONOFF.
HIS EXCELLENCY
THE WAZIR OF SURISTAN.
THE NAWAB OF DAJAL.
TAKE CHARGE,
MY FRIEND.
I'M ON DUTY.
TAKE CHARGE
OF WHAT?
[WOMAN]
MY! HOW YOU'VE CHANGED.
[RANDALL]
FOR THE BETTER, I HOPE.
[WOMAN]
I ALWAYS LIKED THE CAVALRY.
MAY I HAVE A WORD
WITH YOU, SIR?
HMM? CERTAINLY.
SURAT KHAN'S
JUST ARRIVED.
WELL?
HE'S GOT
A COUNT IGOR VOLONOFF
WITH HIM.
AH, VOLONOFF. THAT'S
A JUICY, CLEVER GESTURE.
OSTENTATIOUSLY FLIRTING
WITH RUSSIA, EH?
TWO STRINGS TO HIS BOW.
AH, WELL, WE'LL SEE.
OF COURSE, IT MIGHT BE
JUST A COINCIDENCE.
THE SUN MIGHT RISE
IN THE WEST.
WELL, I'LL FINISH
MY DRINK.
I HAVE
A COWARDLY AVERSION
TO MEETING REPTILES
SOCIALLY
TILL I'VE HAD
AT LEAST ONE SHERRY
AND BITTERS.
GOOD EVENING,
SIR CHARLES,
CAPTAIN VICKERS.
GOOD EVENING,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
SIR CHARLES MACEFIELD,
MAY I HAVE THE PLEASURE
OF PRESENTING COUNT VOLONOFF?
CAPTAIN VICKERS,
COUNT VOLONOFF.
HOW DO YOU DO?
IT'S VERY PLEASANT,
YOUR HIGHNESS,
TO FIND YOU
IN THESE FRIVOLOUS
SURROUNDINGS.
WELL, SIR CHARLES,
SINCE YOUR KINDLY GOVERNMENT
HAS SPARED ME THE BURDEN
OF DISPENSING ITS ANNUAL
APPRECIATION TO MY COUNTRYMEN,
I AM BLESSED
WITH MORE LEISURE.
AH, WELL,
COME WITH ME.
I'LL PRESENT
SOME REALLY AMUSING
PEOPLE TO YOU.
THERE'S
MY DAUGHTER NOW.
SHE'S ENTRANCING.
ELSA IS A FINE GAL.
AND THE GALLANT
YOUNG CAVALIER
WHO HOLDS HER SO TENDERLY
IN HIS ARMS--
HER FIANCE, OF COURSE.
OH, CERTAINLY NOT.
BUT SHE IS ENGAGED.
YOU SAID SHE--
TO CAPTAIN
GEOFFREY VICKERS
OF THE 27th.
THAT'S MERELY
HIS BROTHER,
A DIPLOMAT OF SORTS,
SECONDED
FROM HIS REGIMENT
FOR DUTY
WITH THE POLITICAL
DEPARTMENT.
OH, DEAR.
HOW SILLY OF ME.
THEY DO SEEM TO BE ENJOYING
EACH OTHER'S COMPANY.
[PERRY]
LET'S GET AWAY FROM HERE, ELSA.
CHARMING...
AND MOTHERLESS.
WELL, AS I ALWAYS SAY,
COLONEL, IT'S NEVER TOO LATE.
I MUST START LOOKING AROUND
RIGHT AWAY
TO FIND A SUITABLE WIFE
FOR YOU.
REALLY, OCTAVIA.
YOU MUST BE A LITTLE
MORE GUARDED--
KEEP QUIET, BENJI.
COLONEL CAMPBELL HAS
JUST BEEN BEGGING ME
TO FIND HIM A WIFE.
WHAT PARTICULAR QUALITY DO YOU
MOST ADMIRE IN A WOMAN?
THE QUALITY
OF SILENCE.
NOW, COLONEL,
YOU'RE FLATTERING ME,
JUST AS
DEAR LORD MELVIN DID.
ONCE WHEN WE SAT
NEXT TO EACH OTHER
IN AN INTOLERABLE
GUILDHALL BANQUET,
"LADY WARRENTON,"
HE SAID,
"YOU HAVE THE POWER
TO DRIVE MEN MAD."
I CAN BELIEVE THAT.
FORGIVE ME.
WHAT A DULL DOG
THE COLONEL IS.
HASN'T A WORD TO SAY
FOR HIMSELF.
BENJI.
[PERRY]
I LOVE YOU
SO MUCH, ELSA.
YOU LOOK
SO BEAUTIFUL.
I--I CAN'T STAND
THIS ANY LONGER.
WE'VE GOT TO
FIND A WAY TO TELL
GEOFFREY TONIGHT.
YES, YES.
I KNOW, I KNOW.
WE SHOULDN'T BE SEEN OUT HERE
TOGETHER. YOU KNOW THIS PLACE
IS FULL OF SCANDALMONGERS.
BUT I HAD TO SEE YOU
ALONE.
WE CAN'T GO ON
DECEIVING GEOFFREY
LIKE THIS.
DARLING, I KNOW
HE'LL UNDERSTAND.
HE'S A GREAT FELLOW.
HE'S HUMAN.
IT'S JUST BECAUSE OF THAT
WE MUSTN'T HURT HIM ANY MORE
THAN WE CAN HELP.
LET ME TELL HIM
IN MY OWN WAY. AFTER ALL,
IT'S MY RESPONSIBILITY.
WHEN HE KNOWS
HOW WE REALLY FEEL,
HE CAN'T THINK
THAT WE'RE IN THE WRONG.
WRONG?
IT'S ONLY WRONG
IF WE DON'T TELL HIM.
LET'S FACE THE TRUTH.
WE'RE IN LOVE
WITH ONE ANOTHER.
WE ALWAYS WILL BE.
[COLONEL CAMPBELL]
ELSA.
YOU WILL RETURN
TO THE BALLROOM
AT ONCE.
MAY I SAY, SIR--
I AM NOT INTERESTED
IN WHAT YOU HAVE
TO SAY.
THERE CAN BE
NO EXCUSE FOR A MAN
WHO IS SO DISLOYAL
AS TO TRIFLE
WITH THE AFFECTIONS OF
HIS BROTHER'S FIANCEE.
I FORBID YOU
TO EVER SEE OR SPEAK
TO MY DAUGHTER AGAIN.
I AM NOT BEING
DISLOYAL, SIR.
ELSA AND I
LOVE EACH OTHER.
LOVE?
CHEAP INFATUATION.
YOU DESERVE
A GOOD THRASHING.
PERRY...PLEASE GO.
AND AS I DOUBT THAT
YOU HAVE THE COURAGE
TO INFORM YOUR BROTHER
OF THIS TREACHERY,
REST ASSURED
THAT I SHALL TELL HIM.
MY BROTHER KNOWS ME
TOO WELL TO ACCUSE ME
OF TREACHERY, SIR.
ELSA, I'LL SEE YOU
AGAIN BEFORE YOU LEAVE
FOR CHUKOTI.
ONE MOMENT,
CAPTAIN VICKERS.
EVEN THOUGH
YOU'VE BEEN SECONDED
FOR THE POLITICAL
SERVICE,
YOU STILL RETAIN
YOUR ARMY RANK.
WELL, SIR?
THEREFORE, YOU
WILL DO AS I SAY.
IF NOT, I SHALL
HAVE YOU RECALLED
TO ENGLAND
FOR GROSS
INSUBORDINATION.
VERY WELL, SIR.
[CLICKS HEELS]
ELSA, I AM
AT AN ABSOLUTE LOSS
TO UNDERSTAND
YOUR ATTITUDE.
FATHER, I LOVE HIM.
YOU REALLY BELIEVE
YOU LOVE?
I SEE.
NOW I UNDERSTAND
THE STRANGENESS
OF YOUR BEHAVIOR
FOR SOME TIME PAST.
BUT YOU
MUST REMEMBER...
THAT YOU LOVED
GEOFFREY WHEN
YOU ACCEPTED HIM.
HE'S BEEN AWAY
A LONG TIME,
AND NOW
THAT HE'S BACK,
YOU MUST REALIZE
THAT THAT LOVE
IS STILL THERE
AND THIS IS
MERELY A PASSING
INFATUATION.
I WISH
YOU WERE RIGHT, FATHER.
I'VE FOUGHT AND FOUGHT
AGAINST IT,
BUT I LOVE HIM.
ELSA, MY DEAR,
I'VE TAKEN CARE
OF YOU
EVER SINCE
YOUR MOTHER DIED.
LET ME KNOW WHAT
IS BEST FOR YOU.
GEOFFREY'S
A SPLENDID FELLOW,
LOVES YOU
WITH ALL HIS HEART.
YOU CAN'T
WANTONLY HURT HIM.
OH, I DON'T WISH
TO HURT GEOFFREY.
OF COURSE YOU DON'T,
MY DARLING.
THERE, NOW.
DRY YOUR EYES.
LET'S FORGET THIS
LITTLE INCIDENT,
AND PROMISE
WHEN YOU MEET HIM
TONIGHT,
YOU'LL TREAT HIM
AS THOUGH NOTHING
HAS HAPPENED.
I'LL TRY, FATHER.
THAT'S A GIRL.
COME.
WILL YOUR HIGHNESS
EXCUSE ME?
WHY, OF COURSE.
SOME BEAUTIFUL
LADY IS WAITING,
NO DOUBT.
YES, NO DOUBT.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
[CLICKS HEELS]
MY GOOD FRIEND
THE GALLANT
CAPTAIN VICKERS
ONCE SAVED MY LIFE,
AND AS YOU KNOW,
IN MY COUNTRY,
SIR CHARLES,
FRIENDSHIP CAN BE
CLAIMED BY FRIENDLY
ACTIONS ALONE.
YES. IN THIS
TREACHEROUS LIFE,
IT'S DIFFICULT
TO KNOW WHICH IS FRIEND
AND WHICH IS FOE.
BUT IN THE END,
ONE FINDS OUT,
AND THE WISE MAN
ACTS ACCORDINGLY.
YES.
AHEM. YES.
ARE YOU STAYING LONG
IN CALCUTTA,
YOUR HIGHNESS?
A FEW DAYS, I FANCY,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
THE, UH...
UNLESS WHAT,
YOUR HIGHNESS?
I SOMETIMES THINK,
SIR CHARLES,
THAT A GREAT
GOVERNMENT RESEMBLES
A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN,
WHO, INTOXICATED
WITH THE POWER
OF HER OWN BEAUTY,
IS APT TO
WITHDRAW FROM
A SINCERE SUITOR
THE FAVORS SHE'S
ALWAYS GRANTED,
AND WHEN SHE FINDS
THIS SUITOR
CONSOLE HIMSELF
WITH ANOTHER BEAUTY,
REGRETS
HER COLDNESS.
INTERESTING. AND WHAT
DOES SHE DO THEN?
SHE CLAIMS THE PRIVILEGE
OF ANY BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
AND CHANGES HER MIND
BEFORE SHE'S LOST
HER SUITOR FOREVER.
DO YOU NOT AGREE?
THE ONLY GREAT GOVERNMENT
I'M ACQUAINTED WITH
IS SINGULARLY MASCULINE.
IT MAKES UP ITS MIND,
AND ONCE HAVING REACHED
A DECISION, ADHERES TO IT.
I'M AFRAID WE'RE
LOSING OURSELVES
IN A FLIGHT
OF FANTASY.
[CHUCKLES]
YES. PERHAPS. YES.
OH, GEOFF.
PERRY, OLD LAD,
HAVE YOU SEEN ELSA?
LADY WARRENTON,
THIS IS MY BROTHER
GEOFFREY.
HOW DO YOU DO?
YOU ARE THE FIANCE
OF THAT EXQUISITE
CHILD. AM I RIGHT?
YOU ARE RIGHT.
CAPITAL.
I CONGRATULATE YOU,
BUT YOU MUST KEEP AN EYE
ON THIS VERY ATTRACTIVE
BROTHER OF YOURS.
I SAW MISS CAMPBELL AND HIM
DANCING TONIGHT.
THE LOOK IN HIS EYE
WAS ANYTHING BUT DIPLOMATIC.
AHA.
BENJI!
MR. VICKERS,
NEVER MARRY A MAN
WITH AN INDIAN LIVER.
LADY WARRENTON,
I WON'T.
BENJI!
THANK HEAVENS.
OH, GEOFFREY,
THERE'S SOMETHING I WANT
TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT.
OH, THERE'S ELSA NOW.
WAIT A MINUTE, OLD BOY.
ELSA, DARLING,
I'M SORRY I MISSED
SO MANY DANCES.
YOU KNOW HOW
THESE DIPLOMATIC
AFFAIRS ARE.
SHALL WE DANCE NOW?
I'D LOVE TO.
DO YOU MIND, SIR?
NOT AT ALL.
LOOK AROUND YOU.
WHY?
HERE
IN THIS ONE ROOM,
YOU CAN SEE EVERYTHING
THAT MAKES THE WORLD
GO ROUND--
RICHES, INTRIGUE,
AND ALL THE SEEDS
OF MUTINY, WAR,
AND HATRED.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT ALL
MEANS TO ME?
WHAT?
NOTHING.
JUST NOTHING.
YOU'RE
THE ONLY THING
THAT'S REAL HERE.
ALL I KNOW IS
THAT I'M HOLDING YOU
IN MY ARMS
AND THAT...
THAT
YOU'RE SO LOVELY.
OH, GEOFFREY.
ELSA...I LOVE YOU.
[WHISTLING]
HELLO, OLD LAD.
GLAD YOU CAME IN
AND WAITED.
I HAD TO.
MIGHT HAVE MISSED
YOU COMPLETELY.
I'M OFF AGAIN
TOMORROW.
ARE YOU GOING
WITH THE CAMPBELLS
TO CHUKOTI?
NO. WORSE LUCK.
I'M GOING UP
ON THE ARABIAN
FRONTIER
TO BUY A PACK
OF HORSES.
WE NEED PLENTY
OF THEM, YOU KNOW,
AND GOOD ONES.
SOUNDS
LIKE TROUBLE
ON THE BALKANS.
YES. THAT'S
WHAT I THOUGHT, TOO.
I TRIED TO SOUND OUT
OLD MACEFIELD ABOUT IT,
BUT HE CLOSED UP
LIKE AN OYSTER.
HOWEVER, IT MUST BE THAT.
HE TOLD ME TO HURRY,
AND WILL I.
YOU CAN IMAGINE WHY.
GEOFFREY...I...
I'VE NEVER
THANKED YOU FOR ALL
YOU'VE DONE FOR ME.
OH, NONSENSE,
OLD LAD.
YOU'VE BEEN A SUCCESS.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
BUT SOMETHING'S
HAPPENED.
I KNOW
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
WELL, WHAT?
I'VE FALLEN
IN LOVE WITH ELSA.
OH, I'M SORRY, OLD LAD.
HOW ROTTEN FOR YOU.
YES, BUT, GEOFF,
ELSA'S IN LOVE WITH ME.
I DON'T THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
I DO, UNFORTUNATELY.
WE TRIED NOT TO.
HONESTLY, WE DID,
GEOFF.
I SEE.
MIGHT I ASK
WHAT YOU INTEND
DOING ABOUT IT?
HAS ELSA TOLD YOU
THAT SHE LOVES YOU?
HAS SHE PROMISED
TO MARRY YOU?
YES, BUT NOT
IN SO MANY WORDS.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
YOU'RE LYING.
THIS IS SPLENDID.
AFTER SNIVELING
TO ME ABOUT HOW
GRATEFUL HE IS,
MY BROTHER COMES
TO ME AND TELLS ME
HE'S STOLEN
THE AFFECTIONS OF
THE ONE PERSON I LOVE
MOST IN THE WORLD.
BUT NOT CONTENT
WITH THAT,
YOU'VE GOT
THE EFFRONTERY TO
COME HERE AND LIE.
YOU CAN'T
BELIEVE THAT.
LIE AND LIE.
LISTEN...
YOU'D BETTER
GET OUT.
TAKE YOUR DIRTY INTRIGUE
SOMEWHERE ELSE,
BUT GET OUT OF MY SIGHT
AND STAY OUT.
VERY WELL,
BUT LET ME
TELL YOU THIS.
I'VE ALWAYS
LOOKED UP TO YOU,
WORSHIPED YOU
AS A KIND OF GOD.
I FIND YOU'RE RATHER
A LITTLE MAN.
AND AS FAR
AS I'M CONCERNED,
YOU AND OLD CAMPBELL
AND THE WHOLE BLASTED ARMY
CAN GO TO BLAZES.
OH, GOOD MORNING,
SIR.
OH, GEOFFREY.
EARLY VISIT, HUH?
YES, SIR. I JUST HAD
MY ORDERS, AND I'M
SETTING OUT.
I THOUGHT I'D
COME ALONG AND SAY
GOOD-BYE TO YOU.
JUST TO ME?
WELL, SHALL WE SAY
THE FAMILY?
ELSA'S STILL IN HER ROOM,
BUT I'LL CALL HER.
TELL MEMSAHIB SHE'S WANTED
IN THE STUDY IMMEDIATELY.
CAPTAIN VICKERS IS HERE.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
YOU HAVE
A VERY DIFFICULT JOB
AHEAD OF YOU.
YES, I THINK SO.
BUT I'M SURE
YOU'RE EQUAL TO IT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
SO GOOD-BYE.
GOOD-BYE, SIR.
COME BACK TO US
SAFELY AND SOON.
THANK YOU.
OH, GEOFFREY.
WHAT'S THIS I HEAR?
ARE YOU LEAVING US
SO SOON?
YES, I'M AFRAID SO.
I SUPPOSE THIS IS
WHAT'S KNOWN
AS THE LUCK
OF THE ARMY.
THEY SHOW YOU
A BRIEF GLIMPSE
OF PARADISE
AND THEN
TAKE IT AWAY.
I SUPPOSE, IN TIME,
I'LL LEARN
TO BE GRATEFUL
FOR EVEN A FEW HOURS
WITH YOU.
HOW LONG WILL YOU
BE AWAY?
OH, A MONTH, TWO MONTHS.
HARD TO SAY.
THERE'S SO MUCH TROUBLE
GOING ON EVERYWHERE,
WE'VE GOT TO BE
READY FOR IT
WHEN IT COMES,
BUT AS SOON AS I
COME BACK THIS TIME,
WE'RE NOT GOING
TO LET THE ARMY
OR ANYTHING ELSE
INTERFERE
WITH OUT HAPPINESS,
OUR MARRIAGE,
ARE WE, DARLING?
OF COURSE NOT,
GEOFFREY.
RIGHT.
IT'S A BARGAIN.
GOOD-BYE, MY LOVE.
I'LL HURRY BACK
SO FAST.
OH...
ELSA,
THERE'S SOMETHING...
I THINK I OUGHT
TO TELL YOU
BEFORE I GO.
IT'S RATHER SILLY,
BUT LAST NIGHT
AFTER THE BALL,
PERRY
CAME TO SEE ME.
HE'S IN LOVE
WITH YOU.
YOU KNOW, HE'S
QUITE IMPULSIVE,
AND HE SEEMS
TO BE TAKING THIS
PRETTY SERIOUSLY.
I WAS VERY STUPID
ABOUT IT.
I LOST MY TEMPER
COMPLETELY.
NOW, OF COURSE,
I COULD KICK MYSELF,
BUT I DON'T
WANT HIM TO BE HURT
MORE THAN NECESSARY,
YOU KNOW?
YOU NEEDN'T WORRY, GEOFF.
I SHAN'T BE SEEING PERRY
IN ANY CASE.
FATHER'S BEING SENT
TO CHUKOTI,
AND, OF COURSE,
I'LL GO WITH HIM,
AND PERRY
WILL SOON FORGET.
YES, OF COURSE HE WILL.
THAT'S JUST LIKE YOU,
ELSA, TO UNDERSTAND IT
LIKE THAT.
I MUST GO NOW.
THINK OF ME A LITTLE
WHILE I'M AWAY.
I WILL.
GOOD-BYE
AND GOOD LUCK.
GOOD-BYE, MY LOVE.
THEY'RE MOVING
ALONG FINE.
HOPE WE MISS
THAT STORM
BEHIND US.
HOPE WE MISS
ANY OTHER SORT OF TROUBLE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND, SIR,
WHY THESE NORTHERN TRIBES
ARE SO HOSTILE.
SINCE TURKEY'S DECLARED WAR
ON RUSSIA,
ALL THESE FELLOWS KNOW
THAT ENGLAND AND FRANCE
ARE BOUND TO COME IN
ON THE SIDE OF TURKEY.
YES. IT'S ALL
VERY COZY.
THESE TRIBESMAN
ARE GOING
TO SYMPATHIZE
WITH THE RUSSIANS.
THAT'S IT,
SO IF WE WANT HORSES,
WE'VE GOT TO PAY
THEIR PRICES...AND LIKE IT.
TROOP, COLUMN LEFT!
RANDALL!
ROUND OUT THAT HERD,
AND LET'S MAKE A START
FOR BATUM.
IT'S 60 MILES TO BATUM.
WE HAND THE HERD
OVER TO THE CAPTAIN
OF THE TRANSPORT FLEET THERE
AND THEN BACK TO INDIA!
THAT'S NOTHING TO BE
SO CHIRPY ABOUT.
YOU'RE DOOMED
TO BE MARRIED SOON,
YOU KNOW.
A MORE PLEASANT DOOM
NEVER FACED
ONE OF THE QUEEN'S MEN.
THIS SICK SENTIMENT.
YOU OUGHT TO BE
DRUMMED OUT OF THE SERVICE
FOR THAT REMARK.
[MAN]
DON'T MIND
HIM, SIR.
I DON'T.
WHERE'D YOU COME FROM?
BE GLAD YOU CAME ALONG
FOR THE RIDE.
IT'S THE SORT OF THING
YOU'D ENJOY--
A REAL PICNIC
WITH EVERYTHING
BUT RED ANTS,
AND I'D RATHER HOPED
FOR SOME ACTION.
[GUNSHOT]
TROOP, HALT!
HERE'S YOUR ACTION.
RANDALL, STAMPEDE THE HERD
THROUGH THAT GORGE.
TROOP, WHEEL MARCH.
GALLOP!
TROOP, DISMOUNT!
TAKE COVER!
GET IN YOUR POSITIONS!
INDEPENDENT FIRE
AS SOON AS YOU'RE UNDER COVER!
[SCREAMING]
WE'RE OUTNUMBERED.
WE CAN'T HOLD ON
MUCH LONGER.
RANDALL, TAKE COMMAND.
IF I'M NOT BACK IN AN HOUR,
TRY TO BREAK THROUGH FOR BATUM.
KEEP FIRING
AS LONG AS YOU CAN.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
NEVER MIND ABOUT ME.
YOU DO AS I TELL YOU.
HUDSON,
YOU AND BURKE
FOLLOW ME.
YES, SIR.
HERE. FASTEN THIS
TO YOUR POMMEL.
NOW, RIDE OFF DOWN THERE
AND DRAG THIS BUSH
BEHIND YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
TRY TO RAISE ENOUGH DUST
TO MAKE THEM THINK
HALF THE BRITISH ARMY'S
COMING UP TO RELIEVE US.
HURRY!
[YELLING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ALL RIGHT, BOYS.
FOLD UP YOUR ARMY.
[MEN]
THEY'RE RUNNING!
[MEN REJOICING]
[MAN]
PEARSON, PEARSON,
THERE'S SOMETHING
TO TELL YOUR
GRANDCHILDREN ABOUT
IF YOU
LIVE LONG ENOUGH.
[ALL TALKING AT ONCE]
THERE'S A BAD FELLOW!
IT'S MY TURN.
LET ME
HAVE A SHOT
AT HIM.
WAIT TILL HE GETS
ROUND THE ROCK.
HOLD IT. WAIT.
[GUNSHOT]
CAPTAIN VICKERS!
GEOFFREY, AM I
SEEING THINGS?
WHAT HAPPENED?
THEY THINK THERE'S
A RELIEF FORCE
COMING UP
TO SUPPORT US.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY,
SIR.
THANK HEAVEN
I MISSED YOU.
YEAH. LUCKY
FOR ME YOU WERE
AIMING AT ME.
GOOD MORNING,
GENTLEMEN.
I'M MORE THAN PLEASED
WITH THE BRILLIANT SUCCESS
OF YOUR EXPEDITION.
CONGRATULATIONS,
MAJOR VICKERS.
MAJOR? WHY,
THANK YOU, SIR.
I HAVEN'T SEEN IT
IN ORDERS YET.
YOU WILL TOMORROW.
CONGRATULATIONS,
CAPTAIN RANDALL.
THANK YOU, SIR.
SHALL I SEE IT
IN ORDERS, TOO, SIR?
YES, OF COURSE.
SIR.
I'M AFRAID YOU'LL HAVE
TO WAIT A BIT, PEARSON,
BUT GOOD WORK
ALL THE SAME.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU ALL SAY
ABOUT GOING BACK
TO CHUKOTI?
WE NEED
SEASONED OFFICERS
UP THERE.
I WOULD LIKE IT IMMENSELY,
PERSONALLY, SIR.
HE'S GOING TO BE
MARRIED SOON, SIR.
SO I UNDERSTAND.
WELL, WE'LL SEE
WHAT WE CAN DO
ABOUT GETTING YOU
AN EXTENDED LEAVE
LATER ON.
WHY,
THANK YOU, SIR.
WELL, THANK YOU,
GENTLEMEN.
PERRY.
[PERRY]
YOU SENT FOR ME, SIR?
PERRY, YES. SIT DOWN.
MAKE YOURSELF COMFORTABLE,
WON'T YOU?
THANK YOU, SIR.
THE VICKERS ARE
AN OLD ARMY FAMILY.
YES, SIR.
I KNEW YOUR FATHER
AT ZANDA, PERRY.
YOU AND YOUR BROTHER
GEOFFREY HAVE COME
ALONG ADMIRABLY,
THOUGH AS BROTHERS,
I EXPECT YOU'VE HAD
YOUR LITTLE DIFFERENCES.
HMM?
YOU KNOW,
BROTHERS RARELY AVOID
THESE LITTLE THINGS...
BUT THEY'RE
USUALLY TRIFLES.
TRIFLES, SIR?
CERTAINLY.
DON'T YOU THINK SO?
WELL, THAT IS, IT'S
RATHER DIFFICULT
TO EXPLAIN,
BUT, DON'T YOU
THINK, SIR,
WE'RE ENTITLED
TO SETTLE
OUR OWN PROBLEMS
IN OUR OWN WAY?
YES. YES, PERHAPS SO.
NOW, GOVERNOR GENERAL
DELHAUSSY
REQUIRES THE PRESENCE
OF A POLITICAL MAN
ON THE FRONTIER
TO HANDLE THE SURISTANI
SITUATION.
I'VE SELECTED YOU.
YOU MEAN I'M TO GO
UP TO CHUKOTI, SIR?
NO. YOU'LL BE
STATIONED AT LOHARA.
CHUKOTI WILL BE
THE SPEARHEAD OF ANY
POSSIBLE MILITARY MANEUVERS,
BUT YOUR DUTIES
WILL BE THOSE
OF AN OFFICIAL OBSERVER.
IS THAT FINAL, SIR?
I MEAN, THAT I'M
TO GO UP TO LOHARA?
FINAL. YOU'LL HAVE
SO MUCH WORK TO DO THERE
THAT YOU WON'T HAVE TIME
TO THINK OF ANYTHING ELSE.
YOU'LL LEAVE
WITH A CARAVAN
IN THE MORNING.
THAT'S ALL.
YES, SIR.
I UNDERSTAND, SIR.
PERRY. I'M SORRY
ABOUT THE WAY THINGS
HAVE GONE, OLD LAD.
ELSA CAN'T LOVE
BOTH OF US,
YOU KNOW.
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
WELL, THEN...
LOOK HERE, GEOFFREY.
WE MIGHT AS WELL
GET THIS THING SETTLED
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
WE'RE NOT FRIENDS,
SO WHY PRETEND WE ARE?
ALL THE CARDS
ARE STACKED ON YOUR SIDE--
OLD CAMBPELL'S FOR YOU,
THE FACT THAT YOU
GOT THERE FIRST,
EVERYTHING.
I'VE ONLY ONE CLAIM--
ELSA HAPPENS TO LOVE ME,
AND ONLY ME,
AND AS LONG
AS THAT'S TRUE,
I'M GOING TO FIGHT ANYONE.
PERRY, I KNOW
YOU'RE WRONG.
WE CAN'T LET
SOMETHING LIKE THIS
COME BETWEEN US NOW,
AND BESIDES, YOU--
I'LL GET OVER IT.
I KNOW.
WELL, GET THIS
INTO YOUR HEAD.
I'M OLD ENOUGH TO KNOW
MY OWN MIND AND ELSA'S.
I WOULDN'T
HANG ON TO ANYONE
WHO DIDN'T LOVE ME. I--
[MAN]
THIS IS WHERE WE
TURN OFF FOR CHUKOTI. VICKERS!
COMING.
PERRY, OLD LAD--
THERE'S NOTHING MORE
TO SAY.
[MAN]
TROOP, COLUMN LEFT!
[BUGLING]
[MAN SHOUTING ORDERS]
EYES LEFT.
HALT!
REPORTING OUR RETURN
FROM CALCUTTA, SIR.
GOOD, MAJOR VICKERS.
ANY CASUALTIES?
YES, SIR.
ONE MAN WOUNDED.
WE WERE FIRED ON
SEVERAL TIMES,
BUT WE EXPECTED THAT.
DID YOU RETURN FIRE?
NO, SIR.
I'M GLAD YOU DIDN'T.
SIR BENJAMIN'S ORDERS
ARE TO MAINTAIN PEACE.
PRETTY DIFFICULT ORDERS
TO FOLLOW, SIR,
PARTICULARLY WHEN
THEY'RE FIRING ON US.
YES. WHEN YOU'VE
BEEN SOLDIERING
AS LONG AS I HAVE,
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND
IT'S BEST TO FOLLOW
INSTRUCTIONS REGARDLESS.
YES, SIR.
BY THE WAY,
IT WOULD BE DISGRACEFUL
FOR AN OFFICER
TO APPEAR BEFORE HIS
COMMANDANT'S DAUGHTER
IN SUCH A CONDITION.
RUN ALONG
AND CLEAN UP
AND COME BACK
TO MY OFFICE.
YES, SIR.
TROOP,
FACE LEFT ABOUT!
WALK MARCH!
ASK MISS CAMPBELL
TO COME TO MY OFFICE
IMMEDIATELY.
HALT!
FALL OUT THE OFFICERS.
PREPARE TO DISMOUNT!
DISMOUNT!
DISMISSED.
CAPTAIN SAHIB!
PREMA!
UP YOU GO.
THANK YOU, SAHIB.
LOOK, I BROUGHT YOU BACK
A NEW SALUTE.
WATCH.
HOW DO YOU DO IT?
LIKE THIS.
TRY IT ON THE GENERAL.
WELL, MISS CAMPBELL
LEFT WITH THE FIRST PATROL
THIS MORNING, SIR.
CONFOUND IT!
WELL, UH, YES.
THAT'S ALL.
WHY DIDN'T ELSA
TELL ME OF THIS?
THAT GIRL'S
A COMPLETE MYSTERY
TO ME. OUTRAGEOUS!
SHE KNEW
PERFECTLY WELL YOU
WERE ARRIVING TODAY.
PARDON, SIR?
ELSA LEFT FOR LOHARA
THIS MORNING.
LADY WARRENTON
MIGHT BE ILL, SIR.
SHE MIGHT HAVE SENT FOR HER.
NOT THAT I'M AWARE OF,
AND WHAT IF SHE WERE?
THAT'S NO EXCUSE.
[LADY WARRENTON]
YOU DON'T MEAN TO TELL ME--
WELL, YOU MUST HAVE HAD
A LONG AND TIRESOME JOURNEY.
A NICE CUP OF HOT TEA
WILL REALLY REFRESH YOU,
MY DEAR.
I'LL NEVER FORGET MY
APPALLING HONEYMOON TRIP
WITH DARLING BENJI.
YOU REMEMBER, DEAR?
BENJI!
YES, DEAR? BE WITH YOU
IN A MINUTE, DEAR.
HERE'S SOME NICE COLD WATER
TO TAKE WITH YOUR PILL.
I THOUGHT I MIGHT
DRINK A LITTLE TOAST
TO OUR DELIGHTFUL GUEST.
KEEP ME AWAKE ALL NIGHT?
WELL, YOU'RE WRONG AGAIN.
I HOPE
YOU AND SIR BENJAMIN
DIDN'T MIND MY COMING
UNINVITED LIKE THIS.
CERTAINLY NOT.
DELIGHTED.
MIND?
WE'RE ENCHANTED.
BY THE WAY, HOW IS THAT
RAVISHINGLY HANDSOME
FIANCE OF YOURS?
YOUNG VICKERS.
DUE HERE TODAY.
NO, BENJI,
YOU'RE ALL MUDDLED.
ELSA IS ENGAGED
TO THE OTHER BROTHER,
GODFREY.
GEOFFREY, DEAR.
SOME CAKE?
NO, THANK YOU.
SO THE BROTHER IS COMING.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
THAT IS A COINCIDENCE.
MY DEAR, YOU REMEMBER
THE APPALLING BALL
IN CALCUTTA?
WELL, I WAS CONVINCED
THAT YOU AND HE WERE, UH...
SO TO SPEAK.
[SIR BENJAMIN]
PAY NO ATTENTION TO
MY WIFE, MISS CAMPBELL.
SHE HAS TWO OBSESSIONS
IN LIFE--
GIVING ME PILLS
AND SCANDALOUS INTRIGUE.
CAPTAIN VICKERS,
SAHIB.
THANK YOU.
LADY WARRENTON.
GLAD TO SEE YOU,
VICKERS.
SIR BENJAMIN.
ELSA! WHY,
THIS IS A SURPRISE.
HOW ARE YOU, PERRY?
[SIR BENJAMIN]
GOOD TRIP,
MY BOY?
DON'T BE ABSURD, BENJI.
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS A GOOD TRIP IN INDIA.
ONE EITHER TRAVELS IN
COMPARATIVE DISCOMFORT
OR IN COMPLETE DISCOMFORT.
MINE WAS COMPLETE.
YOU TWO CHILDREN
WANT TO BE ALONE, I KNOW.
YOU MUST TELL ELSA
ALL ABOUT GODFREY.
GEOFFREY, DEAR.
ALL ABOUT YOUR BROTHER,
THOUGH, WHY YOU'RE NOT
GREEN WITH JEALOUSY OF HIM
FOR ANNEXING THIS ADORABLE
CREATURE, I CAN'T IMAGINE.
COME, BENJI.
OH, PLEASE DON'T
DISTURB YOURSELF,
LADY WARRENTON.
ELSA AND I
WILL TAKE A STROLL.
SHALL WE?
YES.
NO, NO, NO.
NOT OUT THERE.
NOT ON THE VERANDA.
THERE. IN
THE SUMMER HOUSE...
WHERE THE BIRDS
ARE SINGING
AND THE FLOWERS
ARE BURGEONING.
ACROSS THE VERANDA
AND DOWN THE WALK.
REALLY, OCTAVIA.
YOUR CONSTANT INNUENDOS
ARE INTOLERABLE.
YOU FULLY EMBARRASSED
YOUNG VICKERS
AND THE CAMPBELL GIRL,
NOT TO MENTION ME.
WHY CAN'T YOU RESIST
POKING YOUR NOSE
INTO OTHER PEOPLE'S
PRIVATE AFFAIRS?
IS NOTHING SACRED
TO YOU?
YES, BENJI, DEAR.
YOUR LIVER.
IT'S WONDERFUL OF YOU
TO COME HERE LIKE THIS.
WHEN I SAW YOU JUST NOW,
I COULDN'T BELIEVE IT
POSSIBLE.
WHY DID YOU
TAKE SUCH A RISK?
I HAD TO.
I'VE TRIED TO FORCE MYSELF
TO FORGET YOU.
I'VE EVEN TRIED
TO HATE YOU,
BUT I LOVE YOU.
I ALWAYS HAVE,
AND I ALWAYS SHALL.
DARLING.
POOR FATHER.
YOU SEE, HE'S RIGHT
FROM HIS POINT OF VIEW.
HE MADE ME PROMISE
TO TRY TO GET OVER IT.
I DID TRY...
FOR THREE MONTHS,
BUT I FAILED,
SO I THREW AWAY
ALL COMMON SENSE
AND CAME HERE TO YOU
TO MAKE SURE THAT--
THAT YOU'RE READY
TO FACE EVERYTHING WITH ME.
MY LOVE FOR YOU
IS EVEN STRONGER,
MORE A PART OF ME
THAN EVER.
I WAS SURE OF IT.
TOMORROW I MUST GO
BACK TO CHUKOTI
AND TELL
FATHER AND GEOFFREY
THAT WHATEVER HAPPINESS
THERE IS IN ME TO GIVE
MUST BE GIVEN TO YOU.
PARADES, LEFT!
TROOP, HALT!
[BUGLING]
STABLES. COMING?
PARADE LEFT,
COLUMN LEFT. MARCH!
REPORT THE RETURN
OF THE CONVOY, SIR.
VERY GOOD.
SIR BENJAMIN'S
COMPLIMENTS, SIR.
YOU'VE HAD A SCRAP.
WE WERE FIRED UPON
BY THE SURISTANIS
IN KOHRUD PASS.
WELL, YOU HAD
YOUR ORDERS?
YES, SIR. MY PATROL
WITHDREW IN GOOD ORDER,
BUT WE LOST A MAN--
LANCER WENTWORTH.
WENTWORTH?
THAT'S ALL, BARCLAY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
WELL, SIR. THE KHAN--
THAT IS, IF I MAY...
YES, OF COURSE.
GO ON.
WELL, YOU SEE, SIR, WE RAN
ACROSS A CARAVAN COMING
DOWN FROM THE PASS.
THERE WAS A HINDU MERCHANT.
HE'D JUST BEEN
TO VISIT THE SURISTANIS,
AND HE HAS IT ON GOOD AUTHORITY
THAT THE SURISTANIS ARE
PREPARING FOR AN ATTACK.
AN ATTACK?
YES, SIR.
ON CHUKOTI.
OH, COME,
COME, NOW, BARCLAY.
THE KHAN WOULDN'T DARE.
YOU MUST BE MISTAKEN.
THAT'S ALL.
YES, SIR.
SOLDIERS...
OLD WOMEN, THAT'S WHAT.
I FEEL
THAT BARCLAY'S
INFORMATION
IS ACCURATE, SIR.
WHAT, YOU ALSO?
ALL RIGHT.
PRESUMING IT IS.
WHY THIS GARRISON?
WHY CHUKOTI?
ANSWER ME THAT, VICKERS.
THE KHAN'S
WISE ENOUGH
TO KNOW, SIR,
THAT AN ATTACK
ON CHUKOTI NOW
WILL IGNITE
THE ENTIRE FRONTIER.
WHY,
THE INFERNAL SCOUNDREL.
THEN HE MUST KNOW
THE HOME GOVERNMENT'S
FEELINGS ABOUT A BORDER WAR.
THAT'S IT EXACTLY, SIR.
ALSO THE FACT THAT
ENGLAND'S ABOUT TO
GO TO WAR WITH RUSSIA.
ATTACK NOW, SIR.
STRIKE THE FIRST BLOW,
AND YOU'LL CRUSH HIM.
VICKERS,
YOU WILL PARADE YOUR MEN
IN FULL MARCHING ORDER,
READY TO MOVE OFF
AT ONCE.
YES, SIR.
[BUGLING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GOOD-BYE, MARY.
COMPANY...MARCH!
TROOPS ARE READY
TO MOVE OFF, SIR.
[CAMPBELL]
STAND AT EASE, GENTLEMEN.
I HAVE RECEIVED
THE FOLLOWING FROM
GENERAL HEADQUARTERS--
"TO THE OFFICER
COMMANDING CHUKOTI
GARRISON,
"UPON RECEIPT
OF THIS ORDER,
"YOU WILL DISPATCH
ALL AVAILABLE MEN
UNDER YOUR COMMAND
TO BRIGADE HEADQUARTERS,
LOHARA, TO TAKE PART
IN MANEUVERS."
MANEUVERS?
AT THIS TIME, SIR?
SIR BENJAMIN'S ORDERS, VICKERS.
HE KNOWS MORE OF THE SITUATION
THAN WE DO.
MAJOR JOWETT,
YOU WILL BE IN COMMAND
OF THE TROOPS.
CAPTAIN CARY,
CORNET GORDON,
CORNET BARCLAY
WILL GO WITH YOU.
THE REST OF YOU
WILL REMAIN
IN THE GARRISON.
THOSE ARE MY ORDERS
FROM SIR BENJAMIN.
THAT'S ALL, GENTLEMEN.
BEG YOUR PARDON,
SIR.
YES. WHAT IS IT?
SENDING THE MEN OFF
TO LOHARA
ON MANEUVERS NOW
LEAVES US WITH
HARDLY ONE COMPANY
OF INFANTRY HERE.
OBVIOUSLY, IT'S
STRATEGIC TO PUT ON
A DISPLAY OF FORCE
FOR THE SURISTANI
TRIBES.
MORE EFFECTIVE
THAN BULLETS.
BUT THAT LEAVES
CHUKOTI ALMOST
ENTIRELY UNDEFENDED.
BOLDNESS. THAT, MY BOY,
IS THE ESSENCE
OF STRATEGY.
BUT THE WOMEN
AND CHILDREN, SIR.
JOWETT'S WIFE
AND CHILD, ELSA,
THE SEPOYS'
FAMILIES.
NOTHING TO WORRY
ABOUT.
WE HAVE PLENTY OF MEN
LEFT HERE
TO DEFEND THEM.
WE HAVEN'T
ENOUGH MEN LEFT.
YOU CAN'T TAKE--
MAJOR VICKERS,
YOU'VE HAD YOUR ORDERS.
I'VE HAD MINE.
THAT'S ALL.
YES, SIR.
PARADE RIGHT!
FORWARD MARCH!
ELSA.
OH, IT'S YOU,
GEOFFREY.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO STARTLE YOU.
YOU LOOKED
VERY FAR AWAY
JUST THEN.
WHAT WERE YOU
THINKING OF?
OF A PEACEFUL
COUNTRYSIDE,
OF SOFT GREEN DOWNS
ROLLING TO A BLUE SEA.
I KNOW. ENGLAND.
NO HOT, BURNING SUN.
NO ETERNAL TREACHERY
WAITING
FOR THE UNKNOWN.
ENGLAND.
IN EARLY SPRINGTIME.
ASCOT, CRICKET,
PUNTING
ON THE THAMES.
WE'LL SEE ALL THAT
TOGETHER ONE DAY.
JUST NOW IT...
SEEMS RATHER LIKE
AN INTANGIBLE DREAM.
LITTLE LIKE YOU,
ELSA.
YOU SEE...
I WAS RATHER HOPING
YOU'D BE HERE
WHEN I GOT BACK.
I WAS AT LOHARA.
YES, I KNOW.
YOUR FATHER TOLD ME.
THERE WAS SOMETHING
I HAD TO FIND OUT,
SOMETHING
I HAD TO BE SURE OF
BEFORE I SAW YOU.
YOU FOUND OUT?
YES.
GEOFFREY, YOU WANT
TO MAKE ME HAPPY?
MORE THAN ANYTHING
ELSE IN THE WORLD.
THEN YOU MUST KNOW
EVERYTHING.
I CAME
BACK FROM LOHARA
DETERMINED TO
TELL YOU THAT--
[BULLET RICOCHETS]
MAJOR SAHIB!
TOWER GUARD SHOT!
SURISTANI.
MAJOR SAHIB.
SOUND THE ALARM!
TURN OUT THE GUARD
DOUBLE QUICK!
VICKERS,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WE'RE BEING
ATTACKED, SIR.
SURISTANI?
YES, SIR.
CONCENTRATE
YOUR STRENGTH
ON THE MAIN GATE.
SEND 15 MEN
TO THE EAST WALL.
ORDERLY!
OPEN FIRE AS SOON AS
YOU'RE WITHIN RANGE!
CORNET!
YES, SIR!
TAKE 15 MEN
AND MOUNT
THE EAST WALL!
[BABY CRYING]
RAPID FIRE!
WE'RE LOSING
TOO MANY MEN, SIR!
YES. WE'RE HOPELESSLY
OUTNUMBERED.
WE'D BETTER ABANDON
THE WALL BEFORE
IT'S TOO LATE.
THE BARRACKS, SIR.
WE CAN HOLD THEM OFF
FROM THERE
AND GET THEM AS
THEY COME OVER THE WALL.
GIVE ORDERS
TO ABANDON THE WALL.
BUGLER, SOUND THE RETREAT.
TAKE COVER IN THE BARRACKS, MEN!
TAKE COVER IN THE BARRACKS!
QUICK, MEN!
GET ALL YOUR WOUNDED
TO THE MEDICAL OFFICER!
GET THE DOORS
AND WINDOWS!
[GEOFFREY]
BARRICADE THE DOORS
AND WINDOWS!
ELSA, GET ALL
THE WOMEN AND CHILDREN
AWAY FROM THE LINE
OF THE WINDOWS, QUICK.
[WOMAN SHOUTS]
MAMA!
RANDALL!
YES, HERE.
TAKE SIX MEN
AND REINFORCE THE REAR.
ISSUE MORE AMMUNITION
ALL AROUND. QUICK.
YES, SIR. FIRST SIX MEN,
FOLLOW ME.
THIS WAY. HURRY!
HOLD THESE WINDOWS
AND COVER AN ATTACK
FROM THE STABLES.
MAKE EVERY SHOT TELL,
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
AMMUNITIONEER,
READY TO INTERCHANGE RIFLES.
VICKERS,
HOW MUCH AMMUNITION
HAVE WE LEFT?
PLENTY, SIR.
THAT'S THE LEAST
OF OUR TROUBLES.
IT'S WATER THAT'S
THE MAIN PROBLEM, SIR.
WATER AND THIS HEAT.
WE'VE GOT TO REACH
JOWETT AT LOHARA.
SOMEONE'S GOT TO
GET THROUGH TO THEM.
NOW IS YOUR CHANCE.
THE MOON'S GOING
BEHIND SOME CLOUDS.
NOW, DON'T FORGET.
WHEN YOU REACH
THE RIVER,
CUT A NATIVE BOAT
LOOSE,
AND THE CURRENT
WILL CARRY YOU DOWN
TO LOHARA.
THAT'S
EASY ENOUGH, SIR.
I'LL HAVE THE TROOPS
BACK IN NO TIME.
THAT'S THE SPIRIT.
NOW, WITH
ANY LUCK AT ALL,
YOU SHOULD GET OVER.
THERE'S
VERY FEW MARKSMEN
HOLDING THE WALL.
LOOKS PRETTY CLEAR.
YES.
GEOFFREY, LOOK.
YOU WOULDN'T MIND
GIVING THIS
TO MY FAMILY
JUST IN CASE?
LOOKS LIKE
A PRETTY CHEAP ONE.
DOES IT GO?
IF YOU WIND IT UP.
YOU'RE AN IDIOT.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL GIVE IT BACK
TO YOU TOMORROW.
THANKS, OLD PAL.
GOOD LUCK.
COME, MY BOY.
OVER YOU GO.
GOD BE WITH YOU.
THANK YOU, SIR.
[GEOFFREY]
YOU READY?
YEAH.
HE'S OVER THE WALL.
IN THIS CHANGING MOON,
THE KHAN WON'T DARE
TO MAKE ANOTHER ATTACK.
THANK GOD FOR HIS
EVERLASTING MERCY.
YOU LOOK
AS THOUGH
YOU COULD DO
WITH
A FEW HOURS'
SLEEP, SIR.
OH, YES.
PERHAPS YOU'RE RIGHT.
SUN'S UP, SIR.
YES.
WE CAN'T HOLD OUT
MUCH LONGER, SIR.
[MAN]
MAJOR VICKERS, SIR. LOOK.
THEY'RE GONE.
THEY'RE GONE, SIR.
[GUNSHOT]
PEARSON,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
ARE YOU MAD?
BUT DON'T YOU
SEE THEM?
THEY'RE COMING
OVER THE WALL.
THEY'RE
COMING THROUGH
THE COMPOUND.
I CAN'T STOP THEM.
SHUT UP! STOP!
I--I--I--
SHUT UP!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT,
OLD FELLA.
PULL YOURSELF
TOGETHER.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
[SOBS]
THE WALLS ARE
ALL DESERTED, SIR.
THAT'S VERY STRANGE.
POSSIBLY SOME SORT
OF A TRICK.
RUN UPSTAIRS
AND LOOK AROUND
CAREFULLY.
WHITE FLAG, SIR.
WHAT?
THEY'RE COMING
TOWARDS US NOW
OVER THE HILL.
WHAT THE DEVIL
ARE THEY UP TO NOW?
WE'LL SOON SEE.
REMOVE THE BARRICADE.
OPEN THAT DOOR.
HIS HIGHNESS,
SURAT KHAN,
AMIR OF SURISTAN,
SENDS GREETINGS
TO HIS EXCELLENCY
THE COMMANDANT
OF CHUKOTI
AND HUMBLY
PROPOSES A TRUCE,
WITH A REQUEST
THAT YOU WILL SEND
MAJOR VICKERS
TO DISCUSS
THE TERMS.
EXCELLENT.
HE'S PROBABLY MISSED
A BOAT FROM ITS MOORINGS
AND SUSPECTS OUR MAN
GOT THROUGH
AND IS READY
TO TREAT WITH US.
I'D BETTER GO, SIR.
YES, OF COURSE.
WE ACCEPT HIS HIGHNESS'
SUGGESTION
ONLY ON THE CONDITION
THAT WE HOLD YOU
AS HOSTAGE
PENDING MAJOR VICKERS'
SAFE RETURN.
I'M SURE HIS HIGHNESS
WILL BE GRACIOUSLY
PLEASED
AND WILL UNDERSTAND
YOUR NATURAL CAUTION.
VERY WELL.
YOU'LL ACCOMPANY ME
AS ORDERLY.
YES, SIR.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
I WELCOME YOU,
MAJOR VICKERS.
MAY THE GODS
OF COURAGE AND WISDOM
CONTINUE TO BESTOW
THEIR BLESSINGS ON YOU.
YOUR HIGHNESS,
I MUST SUGGEST
YOU COME STRAIGHT
TO THE POINT.
REALLY?
YOU PROBABLY KNOW
BY NOW THAT WORD
HAS REACHED LOHARA,
AND THE ENTIRE
BRIGADE'S
ON ITS WAY HERE.
HOW INTERESTING.
OH, IT PAINS ME
DEEPLY
TO HAVE TO DISILLUSION
YOU ON THAT SCORE.
IF IT'S THAT SEPOY
YOU MEAN--
YES.
CAPTAIN RANDALL.
OH, SO IT WAS
CAPTAIN RANDALL
WHO SO IMPRUDENTLY
ATTEMPTED TO PENETRATE
THE LINES.
POOR FELLOW.
HE PAID THE PENALTY
FOR HIS FOOLISHNESS.
HE'S...HE'S DEAD?
OH, MY FRIEND,
LIFE IS SWEET AND DEAR
WHEN ONE CANNOT HAVE IT.
THAT'S WHY I SENT
FOR YOU.
I'M OFFERING YOU
YOUR LIFE.
MY LIFE. WHY?
YOU SAVED MINE,
AND I SHALL NEVER
FORGET IT.
YOU WILL BE GIVEN
A HORSE AND SAFE CONDUCT--
YOUR HIGHNESS,
UP TILL NOW
THE HOME GOVERNMENT
HAS CHOSEN
TO DISREGARD
SUNDRY UNFRIENDLY
ACTS OF YOURS.
BY WITHDRAWING
YOUR FORCES NOW,
YOU'LL BE MAKING
A FRIENDLY GESTURE
WHICH WILL ALMOST
CERTAINLY LEAD
TO THE REOPENING
OF NEGOTIATIONS
IN CALCUTTA.
YOU'RE NOT FIGHTING
A SINGLE OUTPOST.
YOU'RE FIGHTING
THE ENTIRE
BRITISH ARMY.
YOUR LOGIC,
MY DEAR MAJOR,
IS OVERWHELMING.
NO, MY FRIEND.
I DO NOT THINK
YOU SERIOUSLY BELIEVE
THAT I'LL ACCEPT
YOUR OPTIMISTIC
SUGGESTIONS.
AFTER ALL, HAVE YOU
NOT AN ENGLISH PROVERB
TO THE EFFECT
THAT POSSESSION
IS 9/10 OF THE LAW?
THEN I TAKE IT
THERE'S NOTHING MORE
TO BE SAID.
ON THE CONTRARY,
IF WE ARE OPEN
AND HONEST
WITH ONE ANOTHER,
THIS MATTER CAN BE
SETTLED REASONABLY.
ANY SUGGESTION
YOU MAKE MUST
GUARANTEE THE SAFETY
OF THE WOMEN
AND CHILDREN.
THEN THE OBVIOUS
SOLUTION WOULD BE
AN EVACUATION.
EVACUATION?
YOU MEAN SURRENDER?
HARDLY. I AM
PERFECTLY WILLING
TO GRANT THE GARRISON
A SAFE ESCORT
TO LOHARA.
WHY, I'VE EVERY
REASON TO SUPPOSE
THAT WILL BE
PERFECTLY
SATISFACTORY.
WHEN I WENT TO SCHOOL
IN ENGLAND,
I LEARNED YOUR CHARMING
CUSTOM OF SHAKING HANDS,
SIGNIFYING THE COMPLETION
OF A BARGAIN
BETWEEN TWO GENTLEMEN.
OF COURSE, THE GARRISON
WILL HAVE TO LAY DOWN
ITS ARMS.
WHAT? BUT WHY?
AS A FRIENDLY GESTURE.
THAT'S UTTERLY
IMPOSSIBLE.
IT PLACES US
ENTIRELY
AT YOUR MERCY.
AHEM. WE UNDERSTAND
THEIR FEELINGS,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
VERY WELL, THEN.
WITH ARMS.
I'M SORRY.
I WON'T AGREE
TO YOUR TERMS
UNDER ANY CONDITIONS
WHATEVER.
TAKE MY OFFER
TO YOUR COMMANDANT.
THE DECISION IS HIS.
IF MY TERMS
ARE ACCEPTABLE,
INSTRUCT YOUR COLONEL
TO RAISE THE WHITE FLAG.
YOU SHOULD KNOW
THE BRITISH
NEVER SURRENDER,
YET THEIR GUNS WILL
BE USELESS TO THEM,
IF I MAY ADVISE
YOUR HIGHNESS.
I SUSPECTED YOU HAD
A PLAN.
PRECISELY.
IF COLONEL CAMPBELL
ACCEPTS OUR TERMS--
AND HE WOULD BE
EXCEEDINGLY UNWISE
NOT TO--
IT WOULD BE
VERY SIMPLE.
I WISH YOU'D
THINK IT OVER
AGAIN, SIR.
I FEEL
WE'RE MAKING
A GRAVE MISTAKE
IN ACCEPTING
THE KHAN'S TERMS.
IT PUTS US ENTIRELY
AT HIS MERCY.
WELL, WE'RE PRACTICALLY
AT HIS MERCY ALREADY.
I'M SURE YOU'RE
QUITE MISTAKEN
IN YOUR SUSPICIONS.
CAN YOU GIVE ME
ANY TANGIBLE REASON?
NO, SIR, EXCEPT
THAT THEY OFFERED ME
A HORSE
AND A SAFE CONDUCT
FOR MYSELF ONLY.
NO, I SEE NO REASON
TO MISTRUST HIM.
BESIDES,
I'VE GOT TO THINK OF
THE WOMEN AND CHILDREN.
THAT'S JUST IT, SIR.
WE CAN'T TRUST HIM.
WELL, WE'VE GOT TO
GO THROUGH WITH IT.
ALL RIGHT, GET TO THE FIRST
AND SECOND BOAT THERE.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GET THE PEOPLE
LOADED INTO THE BOATS
AS SOON AS YOU CAN,
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
AND YOU TAKE
THE LEADING BOAT
TO LOHARA.
PUT THAT STRETCHER
ON THE RAFT THERE.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[BABY CRIES]
CAREFUL! DON'T
OVERLOAD THAT BOAT!
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SCREAMING]
OUT OF THE BOATS.
QUICKLY, NOW!
MASSACRE!
HE'S SAFE.
MY DEBT TO MAJOR VICKERS
IS PAID.
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
DRIVE THE REST OF THEM
BACK INTO THE GARRISON!
DOES IT FEEL
BETTER NOW?
YES, MUCH.
THANK YOU.
WE SHOULDN'T
HAVE TRUSTED HIM.
THOSE POOR
LITTLE KIDS.
HORRIBLE.
WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO THEM?
HE CAN'T MURDER
THEM ALL.
NO. THAT WOULD
BE TOO MUCH,
EVEN FOR
THE KHAN.
HE'LL HOLD THEM
AS HOSTAGES.
THAT'S WHY WE'VE
GOT TO GET TO
LOHARA FOR HELP.
IT'S
OUR ONLY HOPE.
LOOK.
IT'S OUR CHANCE.
"...BEEN OUR REFUGE
FROM ONE GENERATION TO ANOTHER.
"THOU TURNEST MEN
TO DESTRUCTION.
AGAIN THOU SAYEST, COME AGAIN,
YE CHILDREN OF MEN..."
[MAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
"THE DAYS OF OUR AGE
ARE 3 SCORE YEARS AND 10,
"AND THOUGH MEN BE SO STRONG
"THAT THEY COME
TO FOURSCORE YEARS,
"YET IS THEIR STRENGTH
THEN BUT LABOR AND SORROW,
"SO SOON PASSETH IT AWAY
AND WE ARE GONE.
TURN THEE AGAIN, O LORD..."
[SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MAJOR VICKERS!
WHAT ON EARTH
ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT?
WELL, WHERE
DID THIS HAPPEN?
JUST NOW, SIR,
DOWN BY THE RIVER
AT THE NORTH GATE.
WHAT'S THE MEANING
OF ALL THIS?
MISS CAMPBELL!
GEOFFREY!
ALI!
TELL LADY WARRENTON
MISS CAMPBELL
NEEDS HER HELP AT ONCE.
MY DEAR.
GO WITH CATARO.
SHE'LL TAKE YOU TO
MY WIFE AT ONCE.
GEOFFREY, MY BOY,
THIS IS TERRIBLE.
HOW ON EARTH
DID IT HAPPEN?
CHUKOTI, SIR.
THE SURISTANIS
ATTACKED.
HOT WATER AND CLOTHES.
GET SMELLING SALTS.
MY POOR, POOR CHILD!
I THOUGHT
THE BEST THING
WE COULD DO
WOULD BE TO TRY
AND REACH HERE
FOR HELP.
CHANCES ARE, WE WILL
GET THERE IN TIME?
YES, IF WE HURRY.
CAPTAIN BARNES.
REQUEST MAJOR JOWETT
TO REPORT TO ME
AT ONCE
AND SOUND ASSEMBLY.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
THE KHAN MUST BE
HOLDING THE WOMEN
AND CHILDREN.
YES, AS HOSTAGES,
OF COURSE.
WE'VE NO TIME
TO SPARE.
PACK THE SEPOYS
IN THEIR OWN
TRANSPORT WAGONS.
WE'LL BRING THEM
ALONG WITH US.
GEOFFREY, YOU GET
YOUR ARM ATTENDED TO
AT ONCE.
I'LL BE WITH YOU
IN A MINUTE.
DO YOU MIND
IF I COME ALONG?
NO, OLD LAD.
WE'LL NEED YOU.
HALT!
THAT'S STRANGE!
THE WHITE FLAG'S
STILL FLYING.
THERE ARE NO
SENTRIES ABOUT.
SHOWS EVERY SIGN
OF BEING DESERTED.
WHAT DO YOU
MAKE OF IT?
WHO KNOWS, SIR?
MAJOR JOWETT?
TAKE FORWARD A DETAIL
IN SKIRMISHING ORDER.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
THE LAST SIX SECTIONS
DISMOUNT
AND ADVANCE
IN SKIRMISHING ORDER!
I WONDER IF
THIS IS ANOTHER OF
THE KHAN'S TRICKS.
FIRE A SHOT.
[GUNSHOT]
NO SIGN OF LIFE.
TROOP, FORWARD. GALLOP!
OH, YARA! PREMA!
MEZANTI!
THERE SHE IS
ON THE STEPS, SIR.
NAN!
JOHN.
[CRYING]
YARA...
YARA, COME.
THEY'RE DEAD! THEY'RE ALL DEAD!
CAN'T YOU HEAR ME?
THEY'RE DEAD, I TELL YOU!
THEY'RE DEAD! GONE!
PREMA!
[SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
PREMA.
MY LITTLE BOY'S
GUN.
HE WANTED A GUN
TO KILL SURISTANI.
SURISTANI KILL HIM.
PREMA, MY BABY.
DO YOU HEAR ME, PREMA?
PREMA!
COLONEL CAMPBELL,
SIR,
UP OVER THE WALL.
SO THAT'S WHY
THEY ABANDONED CHUKOTI.
WE'VE GOT TO FOLLOW
SURAT KHAN.
HE CAN'T BE FAR OFF.
IMPOSSIBLE.
THEY'RE MOUNTAIN FIGHTERS.
WE DON'T STAND A GHOST
OF A CHANCE AGAINST THEM
IN THE HILLS.
BUT WE CAN'T STAND HERE
DOING NOTHING!
BY HEAVEN, WE'LL NEVER REST
TILL HE'S BEEN MADE
TO PAY FOR THIS.
INDIA WILL BE TOO SMALL
TO HOLD HIM.
[MAN]
THESE BOOKS WANT TO BE STORED
AND THE CASES
MADE READY FOR TRANSPORT.
[MAN]
AND ALL THE OFFICIAL PAPERS
IN THIS BOX HERE.
YOU'LL REPORT
TO THE COMMANDER IN CHIEF
ON ARRIVAL AT BALAKLAVA.
GOOD LUCK, WATSON.
THANK YOU,
SIR.
MAJOR VICKERS,
OH, GEOFFREY,
MY BOY.
REPLACEMENTS
FOR THE 27th HAVE
REPORTED FOR DUTY, SIR.
GOOD, THEN YOU'RE READY
TO EMBARK.
NEVER BEEN TO THE CRIMEA,
HAVE YOU, GEOFFREY?
THEY TELL ME IT'S
A PESTILENTIAL HOLE.
SEEMS VERY STRANGE
TO ME, SIR,
THAT THE WAR OFFICE
SHOULD BE SENDING
THE 27th TO SEBASTOPOL
TO FIGHT THE RUSSIANS.
POOR DEVILS,
HAVEN'T THEY BEEN
THROUGH ENOUGH ALREADY
AT CHUKOTI?
THE RUSSIANS?
PEOPLES DON'T WAGE WAR
AGAINST OTHER PEOPLES,
GEOFFREY.
ENGLAND IS FIGHTING
THE TYRANNY OF THE CZAR.
THE 27th LANCERS
ARE FIGHTING SURAT KHAN.
SURAT KHAN.
IT MAY INTEREST YOU
TO KNOW THAT AFTER
THE CHUKOTI MASSACRE,
SURAT KHAN FLED.
YES, I KNEW THAT, SIR.
INDIA WAS TOO HOT
TO HOLD HIM.
THE WAR DEPARTMENT
HAPPENS TO KNOW
THAT HE TOOK REFUGE
WITH THE RUSSIANS
AND IS WITH THEIR FORCES
AT SEBASTOPOL.
THIS IS WORTH KNOWING.
NOW YOU UNDERSTAND
WHY THE 27th LANCERS
HAVE BEEN ORDERED
TO SEBASTOPOL.
EVERY MAN WILL HAVE
A CHANCE FOR VINDICATION,
NOT ONLY FOR HIMSELF
AND FOR HIS REGIMENT,
BUT FOR EVERY SEPOY
IN INDIA.
NOW, YOU BETTER
GET ALONG, GEOFFREY.
YOU HAVEN'T TOO MUCH TIME
TO GET YOUR KIT READY.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
YES. COME IN.
WHY, ELSA.
GEOFFREY,
I HAD TO COME.
WHY, WHAT'S
THE MATTER?
PERRY IS GONE.
GONE? WHAT
DO YOU MEAN?
TO THE CRIMEA.
HE WAS ORDERED
BACK TO HIS REGIMENT,
AND HE SAILED TWO DAYS AGO
WITH SIR BENJAMIN
ON THE FIRST TRANSPORT.
OH, GEOFFREY,
HE'LL BE KILLED.
I KNOW HE WILL.
YOU LOVE HIM,
DON'T YOU?
I DO.
I CAN'T HELP IT.
A LONG TIME?
I THINK,
SINCE THE FIRST DAY
I MET HIM.
I TRIED TO TELL YOU
THAT DAY WHEN I CAME
BACK FROM LOHARA.
YOU NEEDN'T EXPLAIN.
I THINK I'VE KNOW IT,
REALLY, IN MY HEART...
FOR SOME TIME.
I'M SORRY, GEOFFREY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WHY, IT CAN'T BE HELPED.
QUITE A NATURAL THING.
HE'S A GRAND LAD, ELSA.
HE'LL MAKE YOU VERY HAPPY.
YOU'LL BE GOING
BACK TO ENGLAND,
I SUPPOSE.
YES. I THINK SO.
OH, YOU'RE LUCKY.
WISH I COULD GO, TOO.
WELL, I MUST FINISH
THIS STUFF UP.
GEOFFREY, ARE YOU GOING
OUT TO THE CRIMEA, TOO?
YES. LEAVING
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
MAY I HELP YOU PACK?
OH, NO, THANKS.
I'VE BEEN GIVING MYSELF
A CRICK IN THE BACK
ALL THE MORNING AS IT IS.
ELSA, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT PERRY.
HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SEE THAT HE IS.
GOOD-BYE...
AND BLESS YOU...
BOTH OF YOU.
GEOFFREY, WILL YOU
TAKE HIM A MESSAGE?
WHY, YES.
TELL HIM...
THAT I THINK HIS BROTHER...
IS THE FINEST MAN
I'VE EVER KNOWN.
SIR CHARLES
MACEFIELD'S
COMPLIMENTS
TO GENERAL SCOTT.
THERE ARE
NO NEW ORDERS.
SOON AS THE WAR
COUNCIL'S OVER,
I'LL NOTIFY HIM.
WE MUST ATTACK
SEBASTOPOL.
GENERAL CANROBERT'S ANXIETY
IS PERHAPS PROMPTED BY THE FACT
THAT OUR SUPPLIES
ARE RUNNING LOW.
LORD RAGLAN
UNDERSTANDS
PERFECTLY.
CAN'T YOU SEE,
LORD CARDIGAN,
THE BALTIC FLEET
IS USELESS?
THE TURKISH FLEET,
I REGRET TO SAY,
HAS BEEN DESTROYED
BY THE RUSSIANS
AT SINOPE.
THE RECENT STORM HAS WRECKED
NOT ONLY THE RUSSIAN FLEET,
BUT THE LARGEST
OF THE FRENCH MAN-OF-WAR.
YOU UNDERESTIMATE
OUR RESOURCES, GENERAL.
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
WE HAVE SEBASTOPOL
UNDER SIEGE,
AND OUR FORCES HAVE
THE RUSSIANS AT BAY,
SO TO SPEAK.
BESIDES, SO FAR,
NO REAL OPPORTUNITY
TO ATTACK SEBASTOPOL
HAS PRESENTED ITSELF.
ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
I'LL MAKE A NOTE OF IT.
LORD RAGLAN
CAN'T BE DISTURBED
WHILE THE WAR COUNCIL'S
IN SESSION.
TAKE IT UP WITH
SIR CHARLES MACEFIELD.
YES, SIR.
WAIT.
ALL RIGHT. CARRY ON.
YES, SIR.
MY PLAN TO WITHDRAW
THE LIGHT BRIGADE
IS PERFECTLY CLEAR
TO ALL OF YOU GENTLEMEN.
BE GOOD ENOUGH TO ISSUE
THE ORDERS, SIR CHARLES.
VERY GOOD.
I THINK THAT'S ALL
WE HAVE TO DISCUSS.
SOME PAPERS
FOR YOUR SIGNATURE, SIR.
HMM?
WELL, THESE
ARE NOT IMPORTANT.
PRESENTLY WILL DO.
SIT DOWN.
I WANT YOU
TO TAKE A DISPATCH.
GENERAL HEADQUARTERS,
ARMY OF THE CRIMEA.
FROM HIS EXCELLENCY,
FIELD MARSHAL
THE EARL OF RAGLAN, K.C.B.,
COMMANDING...
THE MAJOR GENERAL
SIR BENJAMIN WARRENTON, K.C.B.,
NO. 1174.
ON RECEIPT OF THIS ORDER,
YOU WILL WITHDRAW
THE LIGHT BRIGADE
TO A POINT
3 KILOMETERS SOUTHWEST
OF ITS PRESENT POSITION...
BY ORDER.
LIGHT BRIGADE'S
MOVING BACK, SIR?
YES.
WHAT'S SURPRISING
ABOUT THAT?
VOLONOFF COMMANDS
THE RUSSIAN
ARTILLERY POSITION
ON THE HEIGHTS
ABOVE THE VALLEY
OF BALAKLAVA.
SURAT KHAN'S
WITH HIM.
WE KNOW THAT.
DON'T YOU THINK
THE MEN OF THE 27th,
THE MEN FROM CHUKOTI,
OUGHT TO BE GIVEN
A CHANCE TO ATTACK THEM?
I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL.
EVERY BRITISH SOLDIER
WOULD GIVE HIS LIFE
TO AVENGE
THE CHUKOTI MASSACRE,
BUT AT THIS MOMENT,
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
MAY NEVER BE
ANOTHER CHANCE, SIR.
YOU MUST KNOW
THAT THE RUSSIANS
HAVE THEIR STRONGEST BATTERIES
SITUATED ABOVE THE VALLEY.
IT WOULD TAKE
AT LEAST FIVE REGIMENTS
FOR THE ASSAULT.
OH, NO, VICKERS,
IT'S SUICIDE.
THAT VALLEY,
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
IS A VALLEY OF DEATH.
IT WOULD BE
WORTH IT, SIR.
600 MEN ATTACKING
THE RUSSIAN CENTER
WOULD KEEP
THE ENEMY OCCUPIED
WHILE THE COMBINED
FRENCH, TURKISH,
BRITISH FORCES
ATTACK SEBASTOPOL.
SEBASTOPOL TAKEN,
THE CZAR MUST SUE
FOR PEACE.
YES. THE ENTIRE
CRIMEA SITUATION
HINGES ON SEBASTOPOL,
BUT THIS IS NO TIME
TO CONSIDER PERSONAL
FEELINGS, VICKERS.
YOUR PLAN IS
ADMIRABLY DARING,
BUT THAT'S JUST IT.
IT'S TOO WILD.
NOW, I WANT YOU
TO DELIVER THIS ORDER
PERSONALLY
TO THE COMMANDER
OF THE LIGHT BRIGADE.
IS THAT CLEAR?
YES, SIR.
WHY, WHAT'S UP, VICKERS?
WHAT? NOTHING.
YOU DO LOOK RATHER ODD,
YOU KNOW.
CONFOUND YOU, BENTHAM.
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS,
WILL YOU?
I'M SORRY. YES, SIR.
NOW, GENTLEMEN,
THESE BATTLES
ARE THE FINEST
OF TWO AND A HALF MONTHS.
WE'VE LOST HUNDREDS OF MEN,
APART FROM THOSE WHO DIED
FROM THE COLD AND SICKNESS.
IT IS, THEREFORE, IMPERATIVE
THAT UNLESS--
ORDERS FROM GENERAL
HEADQUARTERS, SIR.
YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
GENTLEMEN.
HIS EXCELLENCY'S
COMPLIMENTS.
THANK YOU.
WELL, HOW ARE THINGS
OVER AT HEADQUARTERS?
THEY'VE BEEN
PRETTY DULL HERE.
I BEG YOUR PARDON, SIR.
THAT'S FROM
THE COMMANDER IN CHIEF.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
WELL, SIR.
"UPON RECEIPT OF THIS ORDER,
THE LIGHT BRIGADE WILL ADVANCE
AND TAKE THE ENEMY POSITION
ON BALAKLAVA HEIGHTS."
IT'S COME AT LAST.
YOU EXPECTED IT?
FOR WEEKS, VICKERS.
FOR WEEKS.
SO YOU THOUGHT
GENERAL HEADQUARTERS WERE
THE ONLY ONES IN THE KNOW,
BUT I, TOO, KNEW
THAT SURAT KHAN
WAS WITH VOLONOFF
ON THE BALAKLAVA HEIGHTS.
THE 27th--
THE MEN KNOW, SIR?
CERTAINLY NOT.
THERE'D BE NO HOLDING THEM.
DO YOU MIND
IF I TELL THEM?
YOU MEAN
YOU'RE COMING WITH US?
OF COURSE.
IT'S MY REGIMENT.
BESIDES, THIS
IS MORE THAN JUST
A FIGHT FOR ME, SIR.
AND TO ME, TOO,
MY BOY.
DO YOU THINK THAT I'VE BEEN
ABLE TO SLEEP SINCE
THAT AWFUL DAY AT CHUKOTI?
AND NOW, AT LAST...
WOULD YOU MIND IF I
SPOKE TO MY BROTHER
HERE IN YOUR OFFICE?
CERTAINLY NOT.
ORDERLY...
GO TO
CAPTAIN VICKER'S BILLET
AND REQUEST HIM
TO COME HERE AT ONCE.
[MAN]
YES, SIR.
GENTLEMEN, WE HAVE
ACTION AT LAST.
COME WITH ME.
I TRUST ALL THE UNITS ARE
READY TO MOVE OUT AT ONCE.
OH, I--I THOUGHT
SIR BENJAMIN SENT FOR ME.
NO. I SENT FOR YOU.
I WANT YOU
TO TAKE THIS DISPATCH
TO GENERAL HEADQUARTERS
AND WAIT THERE
UNTIL FURTHER ORDERS.
WAIT AT
GENERAL HEADQUARTERS?
BUT I'VE HEARD
THE REGIMENT'S
MOVING FORWARD.
IF I HAVE TO WAIT
AT GENERAL HEADQUARTERS,
I'LL BE OUT OF THE FIGHT
ALTOGETHER.
YOU'LL DELIVER IT
PERSONALLY TO
SIR CHARLES MACEFIELD.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
I BELIEVE YOU'RE TRYING
TO KEEP ME OUT OF THIS
DELIBERATELY
BECAUSE OF ELSA.
NO. NO. ELSA'S GOT
NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
YOU'RE NOT
IN THE DIPLOMATIC
SERVICE NOW, YOU KNOW.
YOU'RE
WITH YOUR REGIMENT
AT THE FRONT.
YOU'LL OBEY MY ORDERS
IMMEDIATELY.
IF I REFUSE?
YOU'LL BE
COURT-MARTIALED.
I SEE--
DISGRACED EITHER WAY.
VERY WELL.
BUGLER, SOUND ASSEMBLY.
MEN OF THE 27th,
SURAT KHAN IS ON THE FIELD
WITH THE OPPOSING
RUSSIAN FORCES,
THE SAME SURAT KHAN
WHO MASSACRED
THE WOMEN AND CHILDREN
OF CHUKOTI.
OUR CHANCE HAS COME.
SHOW NO MERCY.
LET NO POWER ON EARTH
STOP YOU.
PROVE TO THE WORLD
THAT NO MAN CAN KILL
WOMEN AND CHILDREN
AND LIVE TO BOAST OF IT.
MEN OF THE 27th,
OUR OBJECTIVE IS SURAT KHAN!
FORWARD!
13th DRAGOONS,
PARADE LEFT!
WALK MARCH!
11th HUSSARS, FORWARD!
[BUGLING]
CAPTAIN VICKERS,
SIR.
SHOW HIM IN.
DISPATCH, SIR.
PERSONAL. URGENT.
THANK YOU.
"THEY'LL ATTACK
THE BALAKLAVA
HEIGHTS."
THIS IS INSANITY.
GENERAL WARRENTON
IS ATTACKING
THE RUSSIAN ARTILLERY.
THEY'LL BE SLAUGHTERED,
ALL OF THEM.
ORDERLY!
I MUST ISSUE ORDERS
AT ONCE
FOR THE CHATEAU
D'AFRIQUE AND
THE HEBREE BRIGADE
TO SUPPORT THEM.
LET ME TAKE IT, SIR.
TAKE YOUR
FASTEST HORSE.
THE LIVES OF 600 MEN
ARE IN YOUR HANDS.
YES, SIR.
27th LANCERS,
FORWARD!
13th DRAGOONS,
8th HUSSARS,
FORWARD!
7th HUSSARS,
4th DRAGOONS,
FORWARD!
WALK MARCH!
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
THE BRITISH LIGHT
CAVALRY
ARE
ADVANCING AGAINST
OUR POSITION.
WE'LL CUT THEM DOWN
BEFORE THEY CROSS
THE VALLEY.
NO DOUBT.
INSTRUCT BATTERY
COMMANDERS IN
POSITIONS 37 AND 22
TO OPEN FIRE
IMMEDIATELY THEY
COME WITHIN RANGE.
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
[BUGLE SOUNDS]
THEY'RE DEPLOYING
THE CHARGE.
SEE FOR YOURSELF,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
WHAT A TACTICAL BLUNDER.
FOOLS. WHY, THEY'LL RIDE
INTO CERTAIN DEATH!
CHARGE!
THEY'RE CHARGING!
WHAT MADNESS.
[SHOUTING COMMANDS]
ONWARD, MEN! ONWARD!
WHY, THEY'VE BROKEN
THROUGH THE FIRST LINE
OF BATTERIES.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE!
STEADY, MEN!
HOLD YOUR LINE!
ONWARD, MEN! ONWARD!
INSTRUCT COLONEL PLATTOV,
14th CALVARY, TO PREPARE
THE COUNTERATTACK.
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
STEADY, MEN! PRESS ON!
INSTRUCT 14th CALVARY
TO ATTACK!
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
GENTLEMEN,
EVERYONE BELIEVES
THE 600 WENT
TO THEIR DEATH
AT AN ORDER FROM ME.
CONFOUND IT, MAN.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
A MISTAKE.
I'LL STAKE MY LIFE.
YOU NEVER ISSUED THAT ORDER.
IT WAS
A MAGNIFICENT BLUNDER.
THAT ONE INSANE CLASH
TURNED THE TIDE IN OUR FAVOR.
BUT THERE WAS
A MISUNDERSTANDING,
WASN'T THERE?
THE ORDERS YOU GAVE--
WERE RECEIVED
AND CARRIED OUT.
BELIEVE ME, GENTLEMEN,
I FULLY APPRECIATE
WHAT YOU'RE TRYING
TO DO FOR ME,
AND I'M SORRY I HAVE
TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
YOU'RE SHIELDING SOMEONE.
YOU'RE A BLASTED FOOL,
GOD BLESS YOU.
FOR CONSPICUOUS GALLANTRY.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
TURNER ENTERTAINMENT GROUP AND
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
PUBLIC PERFORMANCE OF CAPTIONS
PROHIBITED WITHOUT PERMISSION OF
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE