Fegele. Fegele.
Ah. Ah.
Fegele?
Hmm.
Olive.
Drusilla.
Richard.
Susan.
Suzie.
For a black-eyed
little Susan, eh?
What's this then?
America.
No.
England, dear.
Shall I have that?
Let me have that,
shall I?
Uh, would you
give it to me?
Can't I have it?
It's for her own good,
mind, because it will
only make her upset.
There. That's better
then, Suzie.
Isn't it?
Nice and clean.
Where are you from?
Where is she from?
She don't know.
She can't speak.
Maybe she don't
speak English.
She's a gypsy.
Gypsy.
Raggle-taggle gypsy.
Stop it!
Gypsies! Come and have
a look at the gypsies.
All things bright
and beautiful
All, all
Things.
All
"Tings"
Things.
Things. Things.
Bright.
Things
Br--
Bright and beautiful.
Bright.
Canish.
No!
No more of that!
Now, you're in England now.
So you speak English,
don't you?
They wouldn't let me
speak Welsh, either.
But it did me
the world of good...
in the end.
You see, Suzie,
you've got to
learn to fit in.
Am laid
In earth
May my wrongs create
No trouble
in thy breast
Remember me
But
Forget my fate
Nice, dear. Very nice.
But I'm afraid a nice voice
is not quite enough.
You see, our girls are famous
on the continent for their legs.
And other things.
- Why are you here,
actually, dear?
- I want to go to America.
Ah, I see.
Another one.
Well, I suppose Paris is
a step in the right direction.
And there's no harm
in dreaming, dear.
I like a bit of ambition
in my girls.
Which way?
Here.
We'll follow you.
I don't know
where we're going.
we should go out tonight.
I'll show you how to have fun.
Listen. Do you
speak French?
Um, not really.
I can teach you some
very important words which,
you must know, are amour--
So you live
all by yourself,
you poor little duck.
Oh, this is, you know,
not too bad.
There's plenty of room.
In Moscow there would be
three families in here.
- What are you doing?
- I'm saving.
- What for?
- To go to America.
Suzie, you take my advice.
Buy yourself a nice dress...
and you will find a rich man
who will take you there, hmm?
I have a plan.
I will help you
find little extra jobs.
What kind of jobs?
Oh, cabarets, parties.
Oh, Suzie, it's easy if you know
the right people. And I will
stay here with you, yes?
And we will share everything,
everything. And...
maybe we will have
money left in our pocket
at the end of the week.
It's a good idea, yes?
Hello.
- Something is missing.
- Like what?
Huh? The food.
My friends.
Even the cold.
This is nothing.
Winter was winter
in Moscow.
But that's all finished with.
Forward.
Forward. We must always
look forward.
Isn't that true, Suzie?
This is my father.
That's your father, yes.
Abramovitch.
But this is in Russian.
Why didn't you
tell me before?
Suzie?
You don't
understand Russian?
Abramovitch.
Ah.
So, he was a Jew.
Silence. Silence, everyone.
Please, mes amis.
Tonight we're lucky to have
the guest star of Felix
Perlman's new opera company.
So please welcome Dante Dominio
who has kindly agreed
to sing something for us.
The best.
The best--
You are fantastic.
I just had to
say that to you,
that's all.
Ah, the girl with the horse.
Oh, yes, but I don't
usually do that.
Oh, no?
No, no, no.
I'm a dancer, actually.
Ah, really?
Trained dancer.
Uh-huh. Where?
Uh, from Kirov.
So, you, uh,
liked it, then?
Oh, yes!
You are--
You're sublime.
I can't imagine, myself,
how it must be to--
to be on the stage
at the same time as you.
You know, just somewhere
in the background listening,
in the chorus,
for example.
Felix.
This, uh,
young Russian lady...
should come
to your auditions.
And I have a friend.
She can sing.
Oh, is that so?
Say has a lovely voice.
La bella bambola.
She's very talented.
Eh?
So you sing too?
No. l-- A little,
little bit, but I dance.
Suzie, there you are.
There.
Hold it! Hold everything.
Hold it.
Felix, you really
want me to stand here?
Not over there, huh?
No, over there, Dante.
Here you block the entrance
of the horse.
The horse?
It-- It looks good, Dante.
"It"? "It" looked good?
Felix, tell me.
Is this, uh, opera
or a spectacle?
I see no contradiction.
Allora,
I put another way.
Do you want the public
to look or to listen?
Both, Dante, both.
The eyes and the ears.
Ah.
It's opera for the people.
And the people need
to be entertained.
I came to Paris to sing.
Strangely, I believe
the public are coming
to listen to me,
not to look at scenery
or horses.
But then what
do I know, huh?
Mmm. I am just
a foolish singer.
Hello.
Ecola.
La bella bambola.
Hey.
Mm-hmm. Lola.
Lola. Bellissima.
Now you are here,
with us, huh?
Yes. Thank you very much.
Bellissimo.
Yes, it's a great,
great aria.
You see, Verdi,
he understands that...
the voice can express
the highest ideals for man--
his search for strength
and glory...
and beauty.
Madonna.
No, but what is it like
to be a star,
to have everybody
looking at you
all the time?
I was not always
where I am now.
Really?
Oh, no.
When I was a child,
we had nothing, nothing.
But that is incredible.
We were immigrants.
Allora, from the south
of Italy to the north.
It was cold?
It is the people.
They look down on you
if you come from the south.
How terrible.
And because we were poor,
we all lived
in one little room--
the whole family.
No. The whole family?
That must have been
so difficult for you.
Come on.
No.
Did you see
how he looked at me?
You see, Suzie,
there are rules
of how you get your man.
Rules? What rules?
Well, first,
you must play hard to get.
If it is too easy,
he loses interest. He must
feel that he is, uh, a hunter,
and you are a beautiful
wild animal he is hunting.
It's a primitive instinct,
you see.
Second, if you want to make
a man want you,
and only you,
you must smile.
And you must listen.
You always listen.
Mmm. He needs attention.
Men, you see, they are very,
very fragile.
And third,
you must look good.
Very good.
Actually, that's probably
the most important thing of all.
You know, without my looks,
I would never have
got out of Russia.
Never. Will you tell me
something frankly, Suzie?
Do you think...
I should get my hair
bleached some more or
should I leave it like this?
Hmm?
So what do you think
explains the rise of Fascism
in your country?
An artist must be
above politics.
- Don't you agree, Felix?
- So they say.
But, you know,
there has been "caos."
- Come se dice "caos"?
- Chaos.
Chaos. Chaos and confusion
in my country.
Mussolini believes
in order and organization.
He understands that the Italian
people must regain back...
their self-respect.
By putting on black shirts
and marching up and down
in one of those rallies?
Ah, you intellectual, huh?
For the working man,
the rallies are about
dignity and strength.
The lighting, the music,
the choreography creates
an atmosphere.
- Magnifico!
- Mussolini most certainly has
a great sense of theater.
Certo. Certo, huh?
And everything he does,
huh, is big.
Yes. Yes.
You could learn something,
Felix. He really knows how
to reach his public, huh?
Felix, thank you
very much.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Let's go.
They're just gypsies.
So you, uh,
sleep here, hmm?
And your, uh, friend...
sleeps over there?
Da.
This is, uh,
how it was...
for me.
Yes.
This is, uh, how it was.
My mother and a baby
in one bed.
And my brothers and me
in the other.
End to end.
The sacrifices my mother
made for me.
But why?
Why did your
little friend, huh,
refuse my invitation?
It's here.
It's too big for you,
the room?
Perhaps soon there'll be
not two, not three, but four
occupants in the residence.
Would you say that again,
Madame Goldstein?
So now I understand
why you didn't seem like
the other English girls.
Eat.
Thank you.
Isn't it gorgeous?
Did he
buy that too?
Yes.