MOSFILM
ART STUDIO THREE
THE ASCENT
Based on the novella Sotnikov
by Vasili Bykov
Script
Yuri Klepikov, Larisa Shepitko
Director
Larisa Shepitko
Cinematography
Vladimir Chukhnov
Hurry! Hurry!
Germans!
Punishment squad!
Stay calm!
Rybak! You too!
Get to cover!
Everyone into the woods!
Into the woods!
Pick her up!
Ammo!
Sotnikov: Boris Plotnikov
Rybak: Vladimir Gostyukhin
Village Elder: Sergei Yakovlev
Demchika: Lyudmila Polyakova
Basya: Victoria Goldentul
Portnov: Anatoli Solonitsyn
Stas': Nikolai Sektimenko
Village Elder's Wife: Maria Vinogradova
Sotnikov, let's move out!
I'll cover you!
Move out!
I can't —
Rest.
Just a moment. Just a moment, dear.
We'll get you something to drink,
something to eat.
Krotsky —
What?
Get it out.
Get what out?
Whatever there is left to eat.
Well, that was good going.
So where are the sleds?
We should move on.
Then we'll be okay.
We need to get out of here
and find something to eat.
Then you'll be the one to get it.
We have to stay here a while.
You know the Kurgaev farm?
Kurgaev? I do.
He's got a woman there.
Hey, you. Watch it.
Make a run over there. Be quick.
This is us.
Here's Dubovoi's camp.
- What about the wounded?
- And the children?
The families need to be delivered safely.
And without food, you yourself know —
It's still a long ways to Dubovoi.
A long way to go.
How about finding a boar?
We could feed everyone.
Pack up.
What, alone?
Take someone with you.
Stoptsov.
What kind of help could I be?
Right.
Matyushenko.
- They're calling you.
What's going on there?
This weapon's jammed.
But I could go.
Whatever you say.
No. Fix it so it shoots by morning.
Fine.
Is your weapon in order, Artillery?
All in order.
Kolya!
Say hi to Zosya!
Eat some snow. It helps.
Damn! Won't go away.
Can't do anything about it.
Why didn't you stay?
Someone else could've come.
Who?
We're in deep now.
Used up the last of the ammo
on some patrollers.
Doesn't matter.
Once we get to Dubovoi, we'll have plenty.
You shoot pretty good.
Good eye.
Are you really from the artillery?
- Really.
A regular soldier then.
Not quite.
How's that?
I taught math.
I graduated from the teacher's college
in Vitebsk.
Math? That's good.
Walk in my footsteps.
It'll be easier.
I've been meaning to visit her
for a while now —
- Who?
- Zosya.
My Zosya's there. She's terrific.
You've got girls on your mind.
Why not? It's not all just about war.
No, it's not like that.
Zosya and her folks are like family to me.
They hid me when I was wounded,
and with the Germans all about.
You were surrounded?
They saved me, didn't give me away.
They knew who they were hiding —
a company commander, after all.
A regular soldier.
When we were parting,
Kurgaev gave me his short fur coat.
Then they sent me off to the partisans
as if I were their own son.
Are you kidding?
No hard feelings at all.
Even though they knew
about Zosya and me.
You know,
she came to me on her own.
I wasn't even thinking about it.
I was sleeping.
And in the morning,
I hear someone breathing heavily.
I felt heat sweeping all over me.
Damn. I would've married right away
if it wasn't for the war.
Is it still a long way?
We're getting close already.
See what I mean?
Talking makes the road shorter.
I don't know about you
but I can't stand
these lone assignments.
Even the easiest ones.
I'd rather make a hundred attacks,
as long as I'm in the ranks.
But at night, the forest —
It's hard, you know.
Maybe —
Maybe they... had time to get out.
Tell you what. Go on back.
I'll go on
another couple of kilometers.
Can't go back empty-handed.
What the hell?
I said I'd go alone.
You'll freeze without a hat.
- Hats don't grow in the woods.
In the village, every man has a hat.
So I should snatch it
from someone, you say?
Snatch it?
There's always a way to talk to people.
You just need to know how.
Here. It's warmer than nothing.
- No, don't.
Cut it out. Don't be fussy.
It's nice and warm.
Want some?
Go ahead, eat.
Actually, thanks for not leaving.
When there are two —
Well, let's move on.
Where is this damn village?
Are you the headman?
Well?
Anyone else here?
Just us.
Any Germans in the village?
Germans? No.
There's only a policeman left behind.
Got a cow?
Yes.
So far.
You should eat something.
I've got something hot here.
Fine, but make it quick.
So you work for the Germans.
Do they pay much?
I haven't asked for anything,
and I haven't gotten anything.
He's an old man.
He did a stupid thing.
- Keep quiet.
Take your hat off.
- Your son?
- Our son. Our Tolya.
Is he with the police too?
No, for God's sake!
He's at the front.
We don't know if he's alive or not.
Yeah.
You're a disgrace to your son.
You sold out.
Put your Bible down.
Well!
Gripping like a —
Let's go.
- Son. Son, dear —
- Keep quiet.
Move it.
- Our Father.
- Wait!
Don't! Have mercy on the fool!
Son, dear.
He's going to shoot him.
You should've thought of that earlier.
You think he wanted to be
a German headman?
They threaten him every day.
Shouting.
Putting a gun to his head!
Son, dear, let me out.
Let me see.
Let me see what's happening.
Son, dear —
Son! What are you —
What's with you?
- Nothing.
You're sick with fever.
Your friend's calling you.
He's sick.
Here's some dry raspberries.
You can make tea someplace.
Something to drink.
- No, thanks.
Why not?
Go on.
And shut the door.
What, you're letting him go?
The hell with him.
Sorry.
I'm no help today.
Why the hell did you come then?
You asked already.
"Asked."
Those other two wouldn't come, and you —
Stop it! Stop it already!
Where are we?
I didn't notice.
Are we going the right way?
I think so.
Faster!
So you want to take me alive.
Just a second.
Damn it.
There.
Now you won't take me.
Sotnikov.
Where are you hit?
- In the leg.
Let's go.
I can't.
Come on.
What is it?
Does it hurt?
What's with you? Help.
One moment.
Grab on.
This is the end of it.
Where to now?
It's all lake.
Wait here.
I'll look around.
Looks okay.
There's a cabin close by.
It looks empty.
Sotnikov, what's with you?
You'll see.
Maybe —
I'll take you there.
We'll get warm.
And then —
I'll stay here.
Yeah. You know, that'll be better.
I need to go. The boys are waiting.
I'm frozen.
It's all right.
It's all right, brother.
I'll come back for you.
Then we'll move you.
I'll really come back for you.
Kolya. Everything's fine.
I was only afraid to die
out in the open field.
In the night, alone like a dog.
In the woods, it's not frightening.
The main thing
is to get used to the thought:
Is this to be the end?
Go on in.
Are you alone here?
Yeah.
Where's your father?
He's gone.
Your mother?
She works for old man Yemelyan,
earning money for food.
I see.
Any Germans in the village?
No.
They came once and took our pig.
They took it away in a truck.
What's your mother's name?
- Demchika.
- So you must be Demyan, then, right?
They also call Mama "Polgeniya."
Are you partisans too?
What do you need to know for?
You're just a kid.
Say, is there any hot water?
There is. Wait.
Bring us some.
Maybe you've got some food too?
Mama boiled potatoes.
Do you have any bread?
Leonik ate it all yesterday.
Here's some, a treat.
Thank you.
Scram!
That's Mama.
Mama! We've got partisans here!
Hello, ma'am.
What's this about?
We were waiting for you.
What for?
There's no bread. There's no butter.
Galya, take Katya.
No hens to lay eggs!
We're being nice to you, woman,
and you're angry with us.
If I were angry with you,
you'd be out of here.
Galya, I said take Katya!
I'll punish you!
When's the last time you saw Dyomka?
How do you know about Dyomka?
We know him.
He's wounded.
The bullet's still inside him.
We'll have to get it out.
Forget it. You can't get it out.
They say there was crying
over by Lesiny all night.
They say a German got shot.
Who says?
The old women always talk.
The old women?
The old women know everything.
Get out of there.
All right. That's that.
But now what?
That's the question.
How should I know
what you should do?
You see?
He can't walk. That's for sure.
You got here, didn't you?
Quit it, Rybak. Let's go.
Hold on!
Germans.
They're heading this way.
In the attic! In the attic!
In the attic! Go!
Hello, Prava. How are things?
See any strangers?
Like I've got nothing better to do
than to look for strangers.
- Seen any or not?
- No.
Invite your guests into the house.
They're inviting everyone to the cemetery,
and you call them "guests".
What did you say?
You're gonna get it.
Hurry up! Don't stand there.
Can't you see they're cold?
Make up something to eat.
Who stole our pig?
You shameless bastard!
And you're a Red Army bitch!
Maggot!
German scum!
Bitte, come inside.
I tell you there's no one there!
- Where's the ladder?
- We never had one.
All right, if you don't want to —
Come here!
Come here! Red bitch!