It is the opportunity
of a lifetime, Admiral Canaris.
A wonderful chance to show
what the Abwehr is capable of.
Wouldn't you agree,
Reichsführer Himmler?
After the miracle you have effected
in rescuing II Duce, anything is possible.
Our own glorious
Sturmbannführer Skorzeny
merely shares your instinct for daring.
We cannot expect less from section
three of our beloved Abwehr. We will not.
Well, our Führer was in rare form today,
I must say.
Do you really think so?
I, for one, thought his proposition
to you rather challenging.
So is harpooning a whale
with a sewing needle.
May I remind you that only yesterday
Il Duce was surrounded
by his own troops on Gran Sasso -
a virtual prisoner -
and today he is our honored guest.
Oh, yes, a daring raid
faultlessly executed.
Congratulate your Sturmbannführer,
Skorzeny.
Coming from another man of daring,
such as yourself, Herr Admiral,
- I'm sure it will be doubly appreciated.
- This, erm... new plan of our Führer's.
This... This pipe dream.
It is exactly that, you know.
I would have thought a feasibility study
at the very least was in order.
Surely the Abwehr can handle that?
If it had been proposed to your SS...
The SS was created to lead, Herr Admiral,
to be the very soul
and conscience of the Reich.
And since national victory
is now inevitable,
I would advise us all to look
to our own... personal victory as well.
Heil Hitler.
- Morning.
- Good morning, Herr Admiral.
Oberst Radl - send him to me at once.
I've notified Oberst Radl of your arrival.
Thank you.
Come in, Radl.
- Herr Admiral.
- Come and sit down.
Your meeting went well? The Führer
had something specific in mind?
A simple exercise in logistics.
Nothing very complicated.
He merely wants Winston Churchill
brought from London to Berlin.
And we are ordered
to make a feasibility study.
Today is Wednesday.
By Friday, he will forget it.
But Himmler will not.
Reichsführer Himmler approved?
Only of my being put on the spot.
That meeting!
You should have seen it, Radl.
There was Hitler -
first ranting, then cajoling.
And then perfectly rational.
Then raging and stamping like a...
Like the ringmaster of some freak circus.
Goebbels, hopping from one foot
to another like a... like a schoolboy.
Bormann - a vulture...
perched in the corner -
watching, listening, never speaking.
And Mussolini... Mussolini!
An automaton, Radl.
And I looked round that room,
and I wondered...
am I the only one who can see it?
And if so, what must I look like to them?
Herr Admiral, the feasibility study...
Will be a total
and unnecessary waste of time.
Make it immediately.
Why not put a bullet through your head,
it's quicker.
And others need the brandy.
You had an appointment
for an examination this morning at ten.
You had another two weeks ago
and another two weeks before that.
The Admiral and I were discussing
a special project for our Führer.
In spite of your skills as a doctor,
I believe my health was better
served by keeping that appointment.
You didn't chain-smoke to remind me
what a stubborn ass you are, Max.
You'll be flicking your own ashes
on my grave soon enough.
Not if you stop
this idiotic self-destruction.
And die in May as opposed to October?
If I am to die, let me die in peace, hm?
Heil Hitler.
Complete for the last month.
If Herr Oberst could give me
a rough idea of our problem?
I can be quite specific about it.
The Führer has instructed us
to kidnap Winston Churchill.
Good God!
Well, Karl,
do at least a feasibility study on it.
Something which might
fit our needs came in yesterday.
Just a mention,
as far as I remember. If I may, sir?
Here it is. From codename Starling.
A village in England
called Studley Constable.
How do we receive reports
from this Starling?
From the Spanish Embassy in London
by diplomatic pouch, also by radio.
Exactly where is Studley Constable?
The east coast of England.
Er... county of Norfolk.
Let's have a look at the place.
- Larger scale.
- Jawohl, Herr Oberst.
Ah... here.
Ah, Herr Oberst.
Isolated coastline, very rural,
wide beaches, salt marshes.
Ideal.
Now, a man to lead it, Karl.
Crash-landed, 1940- glider assault.
Albert Canal, Belgium,
dropped into Crete, '41...
Wounded taking Máleme airfield...
Knight's Cross.
Led volunteer assault group of 300,
special action, Leningrad.
Stalingrad Knight's Cross
with oak leaves and swords.
January this year, dropped into Kiev
with 167 surviving in unit,
to get two cut-off regiments
out of Russia.
- Oberst Kurt Steiner.
- And has the language?
Educated in England.
Third time in the last month,
despite Göring's personal guarantee.
Are you familiar
with the works of Jung, Karl?
I am aware of the works of Jung,
not familiar, Herr Oberst.
A very great thinker. A rational man.
And yet he speaks of something
called synchronicity -
events having a coincidence in time,
creating the feeling
that a deeper motivation is involved.
- Ja, I understand that, sir.
- Take this affair.
The Führer makes the absurd suggestion
that we emulate Skorzeny
by abducting Churchill.
We have to make a worthless
report on the prospects.
Suddenly, synchronicity
rears its disturbing head.
- Ja. I see that.
- We receive a routine report
with a brief notation that next month,
after visiting a local bomber command,
Churchill will spend
a weekend in a country manor
less than seven miles
from a deserted coastline.
At any other time,
this report would mean nothing.
At this particular time,
and in that particular file...
...it becomes a circumstance
which titillates.
A coincidence to... tease us.
Surely Herr Oberst
doesn't believe it can be carried off.
A wink from a pretty girl
at a party results rarely in climax...
but a man is a fool not to push
a suggestion as far as it will go.
Find this man.
He's been out of Germany too long.
Los, los, weiter. Schnell!
Los, los!
Hans...
Hans!
Let's stretch our legs.
Los, weiter!
Stay on the train.
No one allowed off the train.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Sir, you must remain on the train.
If memory serves me,
the Polish army surrendered in 1939.
- Sir?
- Who are these people?
- Oh, Jews, sir.
- Jews?
We are razing the ghetto to the ground.
Burning them out. They put up a fight.
Oh, how? With umbrellas and crutches?
Halt! Halt!
- I'll take the prisoner now.
- Prisoner?
What is...
- What is your name?
- Brana.
Good luck, Brana.
Identify yourself.
Oberst Kurt Steiner.
Commanding
the 12th Parachute Detachment.
A salute is customary
to a general, Herr Oberst.
Even to one of SS.
You didn't seem quite so
discriminating a moment ago.
I have nothing
for or against Jews, personally.
But I've seen too many
good men die for cause,
to watch a girl be killed for sport!
Straub was doing his duty...
He's like something I might pick
up on my shoe in the gutter -
very unpleasant on a hot day!
If you have the dubious honor
of commanding this slaughter,
I'd advise you to keep him
downwind at all times.
That is, if you can tell the difference.
For God's sake, Kurt.
What am I to do with you, Herr Oberst?
You're a military hero,
awarded the Knight's Cross for gallantry.
Yet responsible for the attempted escape
of an enemy of the state,
abetted by the mutinous conduct
of your men.
By rights, you should all
be court-martialled.
Difficult decisions are the privilege
of rank, Herr Gruppenführer.
But, as for my men...
they seem to feel a certain loyalty to me.
I, er...
don't suppose you could
content yourself with my head
and overlook their part in this thing?
Huh?
There you are, you see, Hans?
It's infallible.
I can always tell
a thoroughgoing bastard when I see one.
- Herr Oberst?
- In here, Karl.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Herr Oberst.
The material arrived from Starling.
It is truly excellent.
Starling is to be commended.
Ja. Ja, this is good.
What news of Oberst Steiner?
We're having difficulty
tracing him, Herr Oberst.
He's in Germany, but as to exactly where,
we've hit a roadblock, you know?
Even rumors of a court martial,
but we'll find him.
I'm sure. And now...
Here... a possible undercover operative.
I have decided on this man.
He's lecturing here in Berlin.
Send for him immediately.
- Yes.
- Oh, and Karl.
Send this message to Starling.
Yes, Herr Oberst.
- Where is Herr Oberst?
- In the map room, Herr Admiral.
This message has been sent out.
Did you originate it?
I did, Herr Admiral.
"Very interested
in your visitor of 6th November.
"Would like to drop some friends in
to persuade him to come back with them.
"Your comments expected by usual
route with all relevant information."
You've exceeded your authority.
You were told to prepare this feasibility
study, not embellish a joke.
With your permission,
it is no longer a joke. It could be done.
In my opinion, it should be done.
What if Churchill prefers to die?
What if abduction
becomes assassination?
No one specified dead or alive.
God in heaven!
Kill Churchill
when we've already lost the war?
I'm sure you've done a good job,
very thorough.
But this operation could make
the Charge of the Light Brigade
look like a sensible military exercise.
Drop it.
Herr Oberst?
He has arrived.
Come in,
Colonel... Radl, isn't it?
The top o' the morning to you.
It's not Irish whiskey,
but it'll do to be going on with.
Better for you to drink than me.
I have the feeling
I might be needing it. May I?
Ja.
The last time I was invited
up here to Section Three
someone persuaded me
to jump out of a Dornier.
5,000 feet above Ireland, in the dark,
and me with this terrible fear of heights!
You're planning a holiday to England,
are you?
They say that Brighton's
lovely this time of year.
- W-What the Christ is that?
- They're Russian.
I took to them in the Winter War.
They're probably all that
kept you awake in the snow.
Here... and here.
Now...
- I had a proposition for you, Mr. Devlin.
- You had?
Have.
- I'm working, you know, Colonel.
- At the university.
For a man like you,
that's like a thoroughbred racing horse...
finding himself...
- pulling a milk cart.
- You've got a way with words, Colonel.
You want me to go back to Ireland?
Well, I can't. They'd arrest me...
No, no. We don't want you to go back.
No. You're still a supporter
of the Irish Republican Army?
Soldier of, Colonel. Once in, never out.
But you're here in Germany
and not England, why?
I don't like soft target hits.
I don't want to live in Bayswater,
mixing up explosives
in my landlady's saucepan
to blow up a couple of passers-by.
My fight is with
the bloody British Empire
and I'll fight it on my own two feet.
If it's some rabid fanatic you're after,
I'm the wrong man.
Am I right to assume your aim
is total victory against England?
No, that's your aim.
My aim is a united Ireland.
I appreciate the distinction
but Germany must win the war first.
Pigs might fly one day but I doubt it.
Mr. Devlin.
- I want you to go to England for me.
- I barely know you.
To assist in the kidnapping
and safe return to Germany...
of Winston Churchill.
Give me another Bolshevik
firecracker, will you?
I think I fell asleep in the snow.
Herr Oberst.
Good evening, Herr Oberst.
I am Sturmführer Toberg of the SS.
Reichsführer Himmler
presents his compliments
and requests you to bring
the plan designated "Eagle".
When is that to be?
Now, Herr Oberst.
You seem nervous, Herr Oberst.
Please relax. Sit down.
May I smoke, Herr Reichsführer?
No.
A masterful job.
Thank you, Herr Reichsführer.
But, you know, some people
would say that such an operation
could make
the Charge of the Light Brigade
look like a sensible military exercise.
Have you heard that phrase before,
Herr Oberst?
I don't immediately recall,
Herr Reichsführer.
I know all about your plan.
I know what is written
on every single page.
Even the one you haven't got yet!
The court martial
of Herr Oberst Steiner and his men.
The arrogance of this Steiner is dazzling.
An unusual man this... er, this Steiner.
Intelligent, ruthless, a brilliant soldier...
but above all, a romantic fool.
He threw away everything -
rank, career... the future.
He is presently serving
in a penal colony on the island of...
er... Alderney.
All because
of some little Jewess
whom he'd never
clapped eyes on before!
You know he's a veteran of
five successful commando raids?
Six, I believe.
Educated in England.
Speaks the language perfectly,
without an accent.
The ideal man for the job,
eh, Herr Oberst?
- If you think so, Herr Reichsführer.
- And so do you.
But the Herr Admiral Canaris
doesn't think so.
My loyalty to Herr Admiral...
Is exceeded only by your loyalty
to the Führer himself. Isn't that so?
I was sure of it.
Now, this Churchill business...
Our Führer wants it seen through.
You have considerable autonomy
in running your office.
You ought to be able to use it
as an excuse to prevent Canaris
from knowing what's going on.
What kind of authority would I have
to carry such a project through,
Herr Reichsführer?
Aloud, if you please.
"Herr Oberst Radl is acting
under my personal orders
"in a matter of the utmost
importance to the Reich.
"All personnel, military and civil,
"without distinction of rank,
will assist him in any way
"that Oberst Radl sees fit to demand.
"Adolf Hitler."
So you see, Radl,
under the terms of that document,
even I find myself
under your personal command.
Good luck.
I can only envy your inevitable
success in the matter.
- Heil Hitler.
Major Neuhoff, Commandant
of the island of Alderney.
- A distinct pleasure, Herr Oberst.
- Read this, please.
I see, Herr Oberst. What is your wish?
Terminate the penal unit here.
That applies to Steiner,
von Neustadt and the 29 men.
18, Herr Oberst. There are only 18 now.
The men are required to ride the
larger torpedo craft into enemy shipping.
- The torpedoes detach, of course?
- Of course.
- Most of the time.
- Burial detail,
the usual letters of commendation.
And get the names right this time.
- Thank you, Herr Major.
- But...
Thank you, Herr Major.
- Herr Steiner?
- Yes, I'm Steiner. What is it?
My name is Radl.
Well, what is it? I have two men to bury
and no office to make small talk in.
Your credentials are hopelessly
impeccable, Herr Oberst.
What can I do for you?
Lead a raiding party to England
to kidnap Winston Churchill.
You don't seem impressed.
I haven't seen your plan yet.
Here.
While he's making his decision,
I'll go to that pub and think about mine.
The only time this plan makes
any sense to me is when I'm drunk.
- You are in command here?
- Oberleutnant Koenig, Herr Oberst.
These configurations
seem somewhat abnormal for an E-boat.
That's because she's a converted
British MTB, Herr Oberst.
Captured making a drop
off the Dutch coast.
- Morning.
- Sir.
You're familiar
with the east coast of England?
For five years I was First Mate
on a cargo ship out of England.
This could work, you know?
It will. It is a direct order
from the Führer himself.
I stood opposite Adolf once.
When he gave me this.
Oh, I forgot. One of those.
You're an officer.
You swore an oath, you have no choice.
Of course I do.
I'm going to die here anyway... eventually.
You forget, Radl, that I'm under
suspended sentence of death.
Officially disgraced.
I do not retain my rank...
only my authority, because of the, er...
peculiar circumstances of this job.
I offer you a chance
for reinstatement of rank
and vindication for you and your men.
My men need no vindication.
- You said it could be done.
- It's possible.
Of all the world's leaders,
Churchill is probably the least protected,
unlike the Führer.
Steiner, is thumbing
your nose at the Führer
more important to you
than the lives of your men?
31 of you a few weeks ago.
How many are left?
Sixteen.
You owe them this last chance to live.
Or to die in England instead.
I will put it to my men.
They are entitled to know.
Only the destination for now - revealing
the target would be going too far.
I will put it to my men.
Steiner.
It may not win the war,
but it would make them think
about negotiated peace. Hm?
A negotiated peace?
I will put that to my men also.
God bless all here.
- Give us a glass of your strongest.
- Gestapo.
So that's how the Gestapo dress
in Berlin these days?
- Gestapo?
- Drink?
I haven't sucked my thumb in years.
I wonder if you'd do it for me?
- Sir?
- Suck it.
Now, about your Mr... er, Devlin.
A man of considerable resource
and guile, I assure you.
Tell me something, Mr. Devlin.
Just why are you coming along?
Can't you tell? I'm the last
of the world's great adventurers.
Sweet Mary, Mother of God.
Tough bunch of lads in there, Colonel!
What did he say?
Steiner insisted on
the unanimous consent of his men.
I'm not surprised.
If they agree, you'll leave tonight
for Southern Ireland.
- Close to the Ulster border.
- Tonight? What about my papers?
Your Irish passport and British
medical discharge have been provided.
Starling's found you a job.
You'll be a... marsh warden,
whatever that is.
It's a marsh warden.
What about the money?
- £10,000 first...
- No, I asked for £20,000.
10,000 has been deposited
in Geneva as per instructions.
Ten more
upon completion of the mission.
You think I'd sell out?
You've been so expensive
to buy in the first place.
You are going to jump in those clothes?
I might look a little bit silly
going down, Mr. Steiner,
but I'll be a lot safer
when I land on the ground.
There's an old poem which,
translated from the Irish, says,
"I realized fear one morning
"To the blare
of the fox hunters' sound
"When they're all chasing after
the poor bloody fox
"It's safer to be dressed like the hound"
You're quite literary.
If the truth be known, Colonel,
I'm a bloody literary genius.
- Your complete instructions.
- Right.
All of it - everything? No cyanide pill?
I couldn't conceive of a situation
which would force you to take one.
It's a little trick I learned
from my uncle in Belfast.
In the Middle Ages they would
have burned you for that.
Goodbye, Mr. Devlin.
I will see you in England.
I'll be there.
- How do I jump out?
- Release your safety belt.
I turn the aircraft upside-down,
you drop out.
Has it occurred to you that
the signature on your authorization
could just be a forgery?
Why not fly to Berchtesgaden
and ask him yourself?
Let's not bother the man.
Mrs. Joanna Grey?
- That's right.
- Liam Devlin.
I could do with a cup of tea.
It's been a hell of a journey.
Come inside.
That's a neat trick.
We're both Irish, your wolfhound and me.
- What's her name?
- Patch.
Oh, Patch, is it?
Sit down, Mr. Devlin.
It's lovely, the countryside, isn't it?
You'd hardly know there was
a war on. Patch!
They're living
in a fool's paradise.
They lack the discipline
the Führer has brought to Germany.
These are papers you'll need.
I'll give you the ones they gave to me.
You know Sir Henry
is away for some time
and only the servants
are in the manor house?
Does anyone else know
Churchill will be here?
Only Father Verecker.
Your duties, in the main,
will be merely gamekeeping.
You've got a motorbike parked outside
and you can have this shotgun.
It is loaded.
- You know the way to the cottage?
- Down the road, the pub's on the right,
and I go through the manor house gates,
to the end of the lane.
Here's the keys.
Oh, petrol for the motorbike -
the ration allowance is only
three gallons a month.
I hope I won't be here that long,
Mrs. Grey.
They sent you over rather late.
Churchill arrives the day after tomorrow.
Colonel Radl sends his apologies,
there was nothing he could do about it.
This should be more than enough
for the vehicles we need.
I assume your contacts are reliable?
You take after me.
By the way, I would advise you
not to use stolen commercial petrol.
It contains a red dye...
Which comes out if you put it
through a gas mask. May I?
Oh, by all means.
To the English Enterprise.
I think you and I will get along famously.
On the contrary, Mr. Devlin.
The success of the mission depends
entirely on the distance we keep.
Morning.
Walk on.
Good day to you, cailín.
- God save the good work.
- Oh, watch your back!
- My back?!
- Mr. Devlin.
Mr. Devlin, is it?
Mrs. Grey told us about you
at the last WVS meeting.
You're the new marsh warden.
And you're with
the Women's Voluntary Service.
I help out.
When I have the time.
Sort of erm... servicing the troops, is it?
I don't mind.
Miss, I do believe you're
a little bit of a tease.
Children tease, Mr. Devlin,
and I am almost 19.
Go on. Go on.
God bless all here.
Can I have a glass
of your strongest, please?
- I'm George Wilde, the publican.
- Liam Devlin, marsh warden.
That's Arthur Seymour
and over by the fire, Laker Armsby.
Will you join me in a drink?
- A pint of bitter.
- Pint of bitter. Sir?
I buys me own.
Coming in here
with your shotgun and motorbike,
buying drinks for us estate workers
who content themselves with less.
It can only be because of my good looks.
Make fun of me
and I'll squash you like a slug.
Arthur!
You walk soft around here.
You keep your place...
and stay away from Molly Prior.
If I've caused any offence, I'm sorry.
Arthur, get out!
Today I leave, boy, but from now on,
when you see me, you leave.
One and nine, please.
- Good day, Father.
- Oh, good afternoon.
Liam Devlin - I'm Sir Henry's
new marsh warden.
- I'm just introducing myself around.
- I'm Father Verecker.
This is my sister Pamela, she's up
from Mildenhall on a weekend's leave.
- Your sister? How do you do?
- How do you do?
I'll be back for tea, Father.
- Goodbye, Mr. Devlin.
- Goodbye.
We have a small
if loyal congregation here, Mr. Devlin.
I look forward to your adding to it.
- You are Catholic?
- Oh, yes, Father.
- Did you come for confession?
- Oh, with apologies, Father,
this poor soul is well past redemption.
God forgive me, but this confessional
could do with a few spicy revelations.
Don't forget the words of our Lord,
Mr. Devlin - "The last shall be first."
In that case, I'm assured a place
at the head of the line.
Where did you find this?
A DC3, captured almost intact.
- Gericke.
- Herr Oberst.
- Will it be ready in time?
- No problem.
Where did she go? Eh?
All right, my friend.
What kept you?
"What kept me," is it?
Why, you little devil!
My God, and I'll know you till
Doomsday, that's for sure.
- What does that mean?
- It's an expression from where I come.
- You use these?
- No.
Good for you. They stunt your growth.
You with your green years
still ahead of you.
Almost 19, eh?
- What month?
- February.
- 25th?
- 22nd.
But I was right, you're a little fish.
We should get along well -
me being a Scorpio.
Never marry a Virgo.
Virgo and Pisces never hit it off.
Take Arthur, for example.
I think he's Virgo, watch it with him.
Arthur? Arthur Seymour? Are you crazy?
No, but I think he is.
Pure, clean, virtuous...
and not very hot - that's a Virgo.
Ah, it's a terrible shame
from where I'm lying.
You'll have a weight problem
if you don't watch your food.
Bastard!
Are you laughing at me?
What else would you have me
do with you, Molly Prior?
Don't answer that.
How do you know my name?
George Wilde told me at the pub.
Oh, I see!
- And Arthur, was he there?
- You could say that.
I get the feeling that he looks upon you
as his personal property.
He can go to hell - I belong to no man.
Your nose turns up.
And when you get angry,
your mouth turns down at the corners.
I'm sure you could find a hundred things
wrong with me... a thousand!
But you wouldn't throw me
out of your bed on a wet Saturday night.
That's men for you -
anything's better than nothing.
Wait! Come here!
You don't know the first thing about me.
Because if you did,
you'd know that I much prefer
a warm autumn afternoon
under the pines...
to a wet Saturday night, any day.
The sand has a terrible way
of getting where it shouldn't be.
Get out of here, before I let
my mad passion run away with me.
Go on, get! Get!
They told me all Irishmen were crazy...
now I believe them.
- I'll be at Mass on Sunday, will you?
- Do I look like I will?
Yes. I think you do.
Oh, Devlin, you bloody idiot.
You never learn.
Never bloody learn.
It is out there, Hans.
160 miles west.
We've been on tough ones before.
The kidnapping
of the British prime minister.
If successful, will be a shot in the arm
for German morale.
But I agree. It won't stop the bombers
from making their daily runs.
The men considered that
before they agreed to go.
The men, as I once remarked
to a certain Gruppenführer in Poland,
feel a loyalty to me.
Which, God help me,
I may merely be taking advantage of.
You tell me, Hans.
Is it a legitimate mission
or have I simply agreed
to an elaborate way of killing myself
and taking all of you with me?
There is Radl's point -
of a negotiated peace.
Hm, a negotiated peace.
I laughed when he said that.
But supposing he's right, hm?
But then negotiated on behalf of whom?
On behalf of the men who lead us
or on behalf of Germany as a whole,
as she will be one day?
The Gruppenführer from Poland will be
part of the Germany she will be one day.
So, by God, will we.
Mother of God.
Look at that now.
- What kept you?
- Very clever.
After I came back to make sure
you put the pie in the oven.
- But then I suppose you've eaten.
- Just get the pie into the oven.
That's better.
- What's this?
- Trinity College, Dublin.
- Football?
- Art and literature.
- What are you reading?
- Some poetry.
- Read it.
- "Read it", is it?
- It's a foreign language.
- Irish, the language of the kings.
It's very beautiful.
Liam - is that Irish too?
- Yes.
- What does it mean?
- William.
- No, I think I prefer Liam.
- William is so ordinary.
- Jesus, Joseph and Mary heed me.
- What does that mean?
- It means that if you don't get the pie,
I won't be responsible.
Oh, I do like you, do you know that?
From the first moment I saw you,
Mr. Devlin, sitting astride your bike.
The pie.
- Pie's not ready yet.
- How did you get it here?
- This morning.
- Oh.
- Read.
- "Read", is it?
Give me that book over there,
the blue one.
Sit down.
I'll read you the end of this.
"And then I asked him
with my eyes to ask again yes
"and then he asked me would I yes
"to say yes my mountain flower
"and first I put my arms around him yes
"and drew him down to me so he could
feel my breasts all perfume yes
"and his heart was going like mad
"and yes I said yes I will Yes."
- Is that Irish too?
- Yes.
Himmler sends personal wishes
for success from the Führer himself.
You've altered the parachutes. Why?
Unfortunately, we have high tide
at first light when we must drop.
So we may land in the surf.
These slots enable us to guide the chute.
It's experimental and the landing
velocity is high, but we have no choice.
I assume they've been tested.
Jawohl, Herr Oberst.
I have one request.
A demand, actually.
Blackmail at this point, hm?
We are not spies
and will not be treated
as such by the British
if anything goes wrong.
We will wear our own uniforms
under the Polish outfits
and if necessary, we will fight
and die as what we are -
German paratroopers.
Max, it is not a subject for negotiation.
- In that case, agreed.
- Thank you.
Hello, Liam.
My compliments on the dress.
It's a great improvement.
Why pick on me?
Because you're lovely, because
you could never fall in love with me.
But I might... just for spite.
It wouldn't matter -
I could never fall in love with you.
I'm bad for you, we've no future.
I'm not telling you that
to make you want me more. It's the truth.
I'm here - your turn to leave.
Oh, God.
Arthur, did I ever tell you
about the uncle I've got in Belfast?
Of course I didn't.
He was a bare-knuckle boxer.
I'm just telling him about the Holy Trinity.
You know it?
Footwork, timing and hitting.
And a little bit of dirty work.
"Learn these," my uncle would say.
"You'll inherit the earth like the meek."
You never know when to lie down.
Liam!
Well, Arthur, looks like
he bought you a drink after all!
I told you not to come here tonight.
I wanted you to come home
to a proper fire.
When I went to the wood bin
I found those.
Now put it back, there's a good girl.
What is it?
What does it mean?
Molly, my own sweetheart,
I love you dearly,
but any more games like this
and I'll give you
the thrashing of your life.
Size ten. Was I right?
Silk stockings.
Real silk.
Where did you get these?
You can get anything...
if you know where to look.
Black market.
That's what it is.
Why can't you be nice and normal?
Would you have me in my grave
so early?
Now go get the tea.
Or do you want to report me
to the police?
Oh, Liam.
It's perfect...
but which way is England?
You. Tell Oberst Radl who you are.
Kapral Andrzej Jankowski.
You.
Kapral Stanislav Kunicki,
as you very well know.
Get back in line.
I'm very much impressed.
You know, it all started as a joke,
an insane joke.
I hope that Winston Churchill
appreciates our sense of humor.
- Good luck, Steiner.
- Thank you, Max.
'Falcon, this is Eagle.
Are you receiving me? '
Eagle this is Falcon, receiving you.
'What are conditions over the nest? '
Visibility good, cloud cover low,
wind freshening.
'Eagle out.'
Well... what do you think his game is?
Black market... or worse?
There's two army trucks outside
without numbers on... yet.
This... German.
It's worse!
Arthur, if you love me,
don't breathe a word until...
I'll have that bastard
arrested within the hour.
I've never meant to tease you.
I know I have, but I never meant to.
- You lying tart.
- I love him, Arthur.
What you do to him, you do to me.
You can both rot in hell.
Stop, Arthur!
I won't let you go!