THE ASSAULT
Far into the Second World War...
live Anton Steenwijk, his parents
and his brother Peter...
on the edge of Haarlem.
It's January 1945.
Almost all of Europe is liberated...
celebrating, eating, drinking
and making love.
But here in Haarlem
it's still war.
And winter.
The winter of starvation.
You always bring so many earthworms.
- From my bird cemetery.
I bury all the dead birds
that I find.
Open it.
I have my hands full.
What you put into Mother Nature,
you will also get back.
The banisters and the door
of the visitor's room.
The whole house will go.
My dad stokes the stove
with novels.
The heavy ones should weigh
the most.
Anton, you're forgetting the soup kitchen.
- Oh, yuck. Let Peter do it for a change.
Peter can't do it.
Imagine if there's a sudden raid.
We will go together, alright?
I have to go anyway.
I may not be on duty, but
it impresses people.
Hello, Mr. Aarts.
Hello, Madam.
Karin, Tonny, wait up.
Can you hold up for a moment?
You sure walk fast.
Do you mind if I walk with you?
- Of course not, Madam.
Then allow me to carry your bag, Madam.
There walks the Aarts woman
with her husband.
They always treat you like dirt.
- A little, yes.
Surely because he's in insurance.
That doesn't amount to anything in a war.
Hello, Mrs. Aarts. Hello, Sir.
Nice weather, isn't it? For January.
Stir first. I want some of that
thick stuff from the bottom.
Of course, nurse.
And for my neighbours the same recipe.
I wish you'd go with us every day.
Hey, boys. Get out of there.
Are you mad?
Bunch of slobs.
Did you see how they greeted me, those Aartsen?
Pathetic.
Hey, it's your friend.
Hello, Anton.
Hello, Fake.
Say, do you know him?
Do you know that bastard?
That Ploeg is the beastliest
killer of whole Haarlem.
And you are greeting him, Tonny?
I only greeted Fake.
He's in my class.
Would you like a biscuit?
- Yes please, Mr. Beumer.
Home-baked from bean flour.
By Mina Bakgraag.
Do you like it?
Do you still have vacation?
- The school is closed. Coal scarcity.
I'm sure you don't have a problem with that.
Bye.
- Bye.
Listen. 'At the World Exhibition
in New York, a cylinder was buried...
containing a complete summary
of our technology.
Such as the Lord's Prayer, movie sequences,
novels and a 1938 lady's hat.
The cylinder will be opened again
in 5000 years.'
That's in the year 6938, dad.
I wish they'd buried that Homer
along with it. The damn translating.
I don't want to hear you say such things.
I think that's sensible.
Then the people of 6938 will understand
their present day much better.
Those who don't know their past,
don't understand their future.
Remember that, Tonny.
Can we? The table is set.
Not so quick. And chew,
that's the best for you.
What's wrong, mom?
- What is it, dear?
A button.
Not even made of bone. Even the buttons
in the soup aren't any good.
Does it hurt, mom?
The crown is broken.
No dentist anymore who can
do anything about it.
What are you doing?
- I'm putting in a clove.
It takes away the pain.
I remember that from my grandmother.
It helps right away, boys.
If we'll just finish our meal,
we can play a game later on.
See you tomorrow.
Same place, same time,
same nothing.
Peter, your translation.
As when through rain and melted snow-
swollen rivers...
streaming down from the hills...
into a valley cavity
their tremendous mass of water...
originating from abundant
sources...
join in their hollow bed...
and far away in the mountains, the herdsman
hears their dim-thundering roaring...
That's how the screaming sounded...
and the laborious battle of soldiers
getting in a fight.
How beautiful.
- Yes, very.
Especially if you work on it for 1.5 hours.
You don't realize that yet.
A traditional education.
It will be of use to you for
the rest of your life.
With the exception of some small
matters: Perfect.
Wie lacht niet, die de mens beziet.
What does that refer to?
- Nothing.
Sunt pueri pueri pueri
puerilia tractant.
'Children are children, and
children do childish things.'
We will go to bed soon.
- It's not even curfew yet.
We don't have a lot of carbid anymore.
- I want green.
You think you will win sooner then?
- Yes.
We will see about that.
- Well, are we still playing?
Let's throw and see who starts.
- Me.
Someone is shot.
- Peter, here. Stay here.
It's Fake Ploeg.
- Tonny, move away from that window.
Dead as a doornail, if you ask me.
- Ploeg?
Look.
God damnit.
- Hey, calm down a little.
The Krauts will get us now.
We didn't do anything.
- They don't care.
What are you going to do?
- Put him at Mrs. Beumer.
Better the old woman than us.
- How dare you?
Why should he lay at our place then?
- You say something, Willem.
A few seconds later
and he would have laid at her place.
Yes, but that's not the case.
He wasn't laying here either,
yet that's the case now.
I'm gonna put him back.
- You're playing with your life.
Not me, you.
Stay here.
You're all crazy.
Retards, all of you.
Hold it, don't move.
Hands up.
What's that?
Are they shooting at Peter?
Where is he?
- Round the back.
Peter.
Peter, sonny boy?
What should we do now?
Maybe he hid himself somewhere.
Why don't you wake up finally.
They're shooting at Peter.
Maybe he's already been hit.
Forgive me, Thea.
Forgive me.
It has gone well for so long
and now at the last...
Anton, put on a coat.
God, where is that boy?
Maybe at Korteweg. That's where
he ran to with Ploeg's pistol.
Did you really see that?
- Just when he walked away, he grabbed it.
He wouldn't...
I'm going to Korteweg.
Be careful, there's the guy
who was shooting at Peter.
Get inside, mom.
Yes, I'm closing the doors.
Open it.
- Open the door immediately.
They have the key...
Three men go upstairs.
The rest spread out.
Papers, quickly. Everything.
- We have nothing to do with it.
Shut up.
Ethica, more demonstrata geometrico.
Benedictus de Spinoza.
Is that right?
Are Jew books being read here?
I...
- Take off your hat when you talk to me.
I am principal clerk
of the court.
Shut up, Jew friend.
Where is the fourth one?
My 17-year-old son, scared
by this terrible event...
suddenly left the parental house
without saying goodbye.
He went in that direction.
You don't say, Mr. principal clerk!
He did?
Suddenly? Really?
Absolutely.
- Take them.
Tonny.
- Mom.
Wait here.
Here, take this.
Come.
Are we locking up kids now, too?
- No bullshit, open it.
Will my parents be brought here as well?
- That's a concern of the Germans.
Where should I leave him? They're all full.
- With the one in cell six.
The SD said Einzelhaft would go there.
- I'm the guard commander.
Try to get some sleep,
it's only for one night.
Sir?
What brings you here?
- Madam...
They set our house on fire.
- When? Just now?
Yes, a man was shot in
front of our house.
I mean, not at our house. At the neighbours...
- Jesus.
Were you home alone?
- No, with my father and my mother...
and my brother... He escaped.
He wanted...
What now?
Come.
Come sit here with me.
Ok now?
My name is An...
- Hush, I don't want to know that.
I'm not going to tell you my name either.
But one thing you should never
forget for the rest of your life.
What?
Don't forget that the Krauts
set your house on fire.
Who did it, did it.
And not someone else.
I do know that, I saw it with my
my own eyes. The Krauts.
Yes, but they will say that the
illegals are responsible for it.
They know that if you kill such a
lout, there will be reprisals.
Do you know the name of that guy?
- Ploeg.
Softly.
Fake Ploeg. A bastard, he was with the
police. His son was in my class.
Did you see him? Was he really dead?
- Dead as a doornail.
You know, if the illegals
wouldn't have done it...
that Ploeg would have killed
a lot of other people.
Why are you crying now?
It's all so horrible.
The world is a hell. It's hell.
I'm glad it will all be over
soon. I've had it.
What will be over soon?
- The war. The war, of course.
The Americans are at the Rhine
And the Russians at the Oder.
How do you know that so well?
Dark, isn't it?
May I touch your face for a moment?
What's wrong?
- It's nothing, never mind.
Are you in pain?
- It's nothing.
Trust me.
I've seen it even darker recently.
No way.
- Yes.
I was with a friend
till long after curfew.
I went home at night.
I thought no one would see me.
I've lived in that neighborhoud for 25 years.
I walked that road hundreds of times.
I thought: I'll get home.
But suddenly I didn't know
where I was anymore.
I was afraid that I would
be walking in the Singel.
I was crawling on my hands and feet,
but that didn't work out either.
I waited until it was bright.
Did you cry?
- No, I didn't. But I was scared nonetheless.
I was there for a long time.
The silence I disliked the most.
It seemed as if I was all alone
on the planet.
Then what?
What do you think? I was right at my own
house. Five steps and I was in.
I stayed with my uncle in Amsterdam...
- Hush.
What was that?
I don't know.
Let's think about other things
while we still can.
What do you mean?
- Well, as long as we're still here together.
You will be released again tomorrow.
- What about you?
I might not.
We've talked about the dark.
Can we talk about the light now?
Yes, after darkness comes light.
I wanted to write a poem once
in which I compared love to light.
The most beautiful light I know,
is the light just after sunset.
A person who loves someone,
radiates such light.
There's a man who loves me and
so he's radiating that light.
Me too, because I love him too.
Even though he doesn't know that.
He thinks not...
but I love him.
He's married and his children
need him. Just like your parents.
Where would they be now?
- They are propably held somewhere as well.
They will be released tomorrow.
And your brother too.
He took the pistol of Ploeg.
Would the Germans mind?
Jesus...
Come here.
Unbelievable. You put him
with that saboteur?
Have you gone crazy?
That communist whore is going straight
to Amsterdam. Euterpestraat.
You may count yourself lucky that
she hasn't been rescued already.
Or else there would be some
heads rolling here.
What is this nonsense?
Who ordered this?
Someone from the Sicherheitsdienst.
I bet he wanted to arrange some
things in Heemstede.
Play santa after the war as
a friend of the resistance.
The Gestapo will be interested in hearing this.
Where does that blood come from?
It's not mine.
Damnit. It's hers then.
Get a doctor. We still need her.
Hurry damnit.
Damn Dutch. No wonder so
many of them get shot.
Chief inspector Ploeg.
Biking in the dark.
Stupid idiot.
The boy stays here.
Tomorrow he'll go back to his family.
What's this?
- He will stay here tonight.
Mr. Korteweg.
I have something for you.
A lard sandwich.
Do you like it?
Wash.
Her blood.
You to family in Amsterdam.
For the moment.
All papers are ready, understand?
There, and now clothes for the trip.
There.
Papers.
Take cover.
- Hurry, get out.
Get out.
Get up. The bastard will come back.
Hurry, damnit.
Schulz is hit.
Careful.
- He's still alive.
Slowly.
Come on. Hurry, you.
Wait here.
This boy must be brought
to police headquarters.
Now this. Come.
Take him to police headquarters.
He must be coming from headquarters?
Move on, general.
That was still missing.
We're getting reinforcements, general.
I want to see his papers.
Pull out the crap first.
He looks like a mug from the
Bialystok ghetto.
Give the boy coffee and cookies.
- There are no cookies today.
After an assault in Haarlem...
- There, I think you'll like that.
In which
chief inspector Ploeg was killed...
the SD ordered to kill the Steenwijk
family and 19 others.
The 12-year-old son Anton Steenwijk...
staid in prison that night at
the Heemstede police station.
Isn't that just amazing?
He was in a prison cell with a saboteur...
then he was brought
to the Ortskommandatur.
Have they gone crazy?
Aren't there any orphanages
in Haarlem?
From there he was brought to
Amsterdam, where his uncle lives.
I can't believe it.
The place was bristling with fighter planes.
Have they all gone crazy
in Haarlem? Unbelievable.
Lousy organisation.
Go ahead and laugh about it.
Take this.
Let the uncle come here.
Uncle Peter.
Come, let's go.
I left my coat.
- Let's go.
After the liberation, Anton staid in
Amsterdam, living with his aunt and uncle.
The night of the attack seems
indefinitely long ago.
The Russians and the Americans...
allies
in the war against the fascism...
are opposed to each other.
The East-West conflict begins.
War in Korea.
Anton doesn't meddle with politics,
no more than he does with his past.
After his final examinations he
studies medicine.
Just in 1952, Anton goes back
to Haarlem for the first time...
because a friend passed for his
Master's degree dental surgery.
Hey, Steenwijk. You're here after all.
- Gerrit-Jan, congratulations.
Am I still on time a bit?
- A bit. Join us.
As I said before,
you are of course spoilt boys.
You're only thinking of ways
to stay out of the army.
They don't even want you.
- Listen, lout.
If you'd only have an ounce of guts,
you'd voluntarily report for Korea.
That's where the barbarians pound on the
gate of the Christian civilization.
The fascists were nothing compared to that.
Why don't you go yourself and drive into
their brains with your weird shoe?
Nice ball.
Just like the university, Korea is
being run down by bastards.
Let's drink to the downfall of
all red fascism in all countries.
I should join them.
- There are former SS members in the legion.
They will get exemption
from prosecution then.
You are behind the times.
In Korea they can make up.
Zeker zacht ei staart thans
peinzend in de verte.
Yes, you Steenwijk.
And? What's your conclusion?
- How do you mean?
Dodge it or check in? What should we do?
I'm getting another beer.
Are you having a good time?
- I'm doing my best.
Good. Though you're looking
rather shitty, young man.
Yes, I think I'll just go around the
square for a moment. Excuse me.
Hey, damn Steenwijk.
The registration bureau is that way.
Tonny.
Tonny...
- Hello, Mrs. Beumer.
Tonny, boy. I...
Come here.
Just look who we have here.
Anton.
You know: Tonny.
How are you doing, Kees?
- Fine, Mr. Beumer. Thank you.
You too?
Do you want coffee?
We were just going to have our evening coffee.
Thank you, Madam.
- Please sit down.
Will you be sitting there?
That's not very comfortable.
This used to be my fixed spot when your
husband used to read with me. Remember?
Shall I help you?
- No, it's alright. It's almost done.
And the coffee was already done.
Why have you never dropped by before, Tonny?
It's the first time that I'm visiting
Haarlem again.
Oh, yes?
You're just as tall as your father.
I recognized you immediately.
We've talked about you so many times.
Say, he's very ill lately.
Just act as if you don't notice.
That you never came back before.
Someone was standing and watching at
the opposite side a couple of times.
Who was it?
- I don't know.
A man with an old coat
and a lady's bike.
Biscuit?
- Thanks.
Does Mr. Korteweg still live here?
- Him?
He moved right after the liberation.
Gone.
Nobody knows to where.
He didn't say farewell either.
Karin neither.
That was very strange.
Right, Bert?
Do you remember that the sanitation
department came by to pick up the fish bins?
Aquariums.
Those were terrariums, for his lizards.
- Yes, glass objects.
He was a very unhappy man.
After the death of his wife,
he came by a couple of times.
The Aarts people are still living there though.
And still pretty much to themselves.
They will never just come by and have a chat.
Just recently the Groenevelds asked...
they are living
in Korteweg's house now...
if Mr. Aarts wanted to sign as well
in order to get those weeds removed.
That bare and ugly spot
gives such a mess.
Where our house used to be?
I do understand.
Life goes on.
You are such a smart boy.
And so gentle.
You're just like your brother Peter.
Peter was just as gentle.
I saw that night how he still tried
to help that wounded man.
That bastard, that Ploeg.
And to us he always was just
as sweet.
Always such a good heart.
What are you going to do?
- Put him at Mrs. Beumer.
Better the old woman than us.
- At Mrs. Beumer?
Why was Ploeg shot in front of
your house?
It might just as well have happened
at our place. Or at Korteweg.
My husband always told me
that God saved us.
But then why didn't He save you?
And then your husband said: God didn't
because we are heathens.
Why your father?
I can still see him in front of me,
with his bowler and his umbrella.
And your mother.
They never hurt anyone.
Gherkins are like crocodiles.
What they must have lived through.
Your uncle did tell you that, right?
When your mother attacked
that guy of the SD?
They were killed like animals.
- Mrs. Beumer, I ehm...
Tonny, it's all so terrible.
I surely understand that you...
No, it's not that.
I was just...
Is this really the first time
that you are in Haarlem again?
Then you should visit the monument.
Monument?
Yes, it was unveiled by the
mayor three years ago.
Down the street there.
We really hoped that we would see you again.
My husband was still in good shape back then.
Didn't you get an invitation then?
- Oh yes, I think I have.
Shall I go along with you?
- Well, I'd rather...
Yes. Of course, Tonny.
You want to be there alone.
Bye, Tonny.
When he starts working as a houseman
after his Master's exam...
the distant winter of starvation fades away
more and more into the shrouds of time.
1956. During the 20th Party Congress in Moscow...
Nikita Khrushchev reveals
the crimes of Joseph Stalin.
During the same year:
Revolt in Budapest...
knocked down by
Russian tanks.
In Amsterdam masses of
people are gathering...
at communist institutes.
Anton's room is around the corner.
Here, I'll screw you up.
Communist. Dirty bastard.
Communist.
Hello, Ton.
Hello, Fake.
Wine? Beer?
Beer.
Student, I presume?
This chair sucks.
- Otherwise, it's highly modern.
Come, sit here.
You haven't changed a bit.
- That's what I hear more.
I knew it was you right away.
I needed some time.
I haven't seen your father that often.
What are you studying?
- Medicines.
I work in a shop of domestic
articles. Repairs and the like.
At Haarlem?
- Haarlem...
Did you think we were still living
in Haarlem? In Den Helder.
Did you come all the way from Den Helder to...
- Yes. Strange, isn't it?
How did you get into plumbing?
You finished grammar school, right?
After the war my mother was
put into an NSB camp.
I was sent to the
Bisschoppelijke Nijverheidsschool.
I'm not even Roman, god damnit.
What did your mother do then?
- She was married to my father.
When she was released, we were
lucky enough to stay in Den Helder.
I went to technical school.
- Why not grammar school again?
You know nothing, do you? You.
What are you really thinking?
My mother became worker.
From five till nine at the morning
and five till nine at the evening.
We got our food that way. My sisters and I
couldn't go to grammar school from that.
Now she's in the hospital.
One leg is already amputated, the right
one is yellow with brown stains.
Water is dripping out and they don't
know what it is, so they say.
There, are you happy now?
Doctor.
That's the difference, isn't it?
Your parents get shot and still
you are studying medicines.
But my father gets killed
and I'm repairing geysers.
But your mother is still alive.
And your sisters too.
Besided, isn't there a difference between
how they both died?
What difference?
My parents were innocent.
- My father was too.
I only know what was told to me.
- Exactly.
But if you see the difference between us
that way, I don't understand that stone.
Then you should just become a communist.
The communism
is the worst of all.
That's what you see now in Boedapest...
where the urge for liberty of an
entire nation is being smothered in blood.
You're just memorizing
headlines.
Sorry, smart doctor. There is a mass
slaughter going on. Better now?
Haven't you read the papers?
About the horrors that are committed
there by Mongolian soldiers.
What do you mean, Fake? Is it
time now to gas the Mongols?
No, bastard.
Look at that scum.
My father was right.
Everything they say about communists
now, he was already saying in the war.
And it's those damn communists
who killed him.
You defend them.
They knew all along of reprisals and still
they shoot him in front of your house.
And has the war ended 1 second earlier by it?
My family wasn't killed by communists,
but by friends of your father.
Are you saying that it's my father's
fault that your family was killed?
Fake, you can still love your father
without having to justify things?
Just say honestly: He was wrong, but
he was my father and I love him.
Wrong? Wrong? Was he so wrong
about the communists?
Those outside thing exactly the same
way about it. Just look at it.
And he never knew about the Jews.
He picked up the people from their homes.
That's what he always did.
During Colijn he had to shoot at workers.
He never wanted to do that again.
That heater will go soon.
Do you know when my father became a
member of the NSB? In September '44.
When all those sham fascists
fled to Germany.
Action had to be done,
so he thought.
And for that belief, they shot him.
Not for anything else.
If they wouldn't have done that,
your parents would still be alive.
Perhaps my dad would have done time
in prison for a couple of years.
Surely the name of your father should have
been written on the monument then as well.
What monument?
- For the 29 hostages and my family.
Should they have included
'Fake Ploeg' there too?
God damnit.
When your house was set on fire,
we received the news about my father.
Have you ever thought about that?
I did about what happened to you,
but did you think of me too?
God damnit.
Fake.
I just wanted to say to you that
I will never forget that moment.
What moment?
The moment you just greeted me and
weren't ignoring me like all the others.