Arabic Voice: “You must not approach this building..
there is a bomb out there..
Please evacuate the area..
You must all escape immediately…
there is a bomb out there..
Don’t stop…Stopping is not allowed."
Arabic Voice [ Repeating Warning ]"
- Go, go.
- We're going right.
Stop traffic up there. Let's go!
Approaching.
I think we have touchdown.
THOMPSON: A little to the right.
SANBORN: Going to the right.
Oh, hello, mamma.
Now push it in.
- I can't.
- What do you mean, you can't?
- Pretend it's your dick, man.
- How about I pretend it's your dick?
You'd never get in if you did that.
[ LAUGHING ]
- Here. Let me have a shot.
- All right, give me a sec.
No, come on. Time's up. It's my dick, man.
Go.
You fucker.
SANBORN: Got that?
THOMPSON: Yeah.
There we go.
- Oh, look at that.
- Nice 155, huh?
- Yeah.
-155?
It's going to do some fucking damage.
Okay.
SANBORN: Hey, Eldridge,
looks like we're going to need a charge.
ELDRIDGE: Oh, I got that.
I figured four blocks, that'll give us
about 20 pounds of bang, total.
That blast is going to roll straight out there.
The shell will probably kick out there,
and most of the shrapnel
is going to shoot straight up
in a beautiful umbrella pattern.
Yeah.
We're gonna get some smaller pieces
and shell fragments this way,
but we'll be okay
if we're behind the Humvee.
- Bring the bot back. We'll load it up.
- No problem.
Bot is moving.
SANBORN:
Let me know what you got, Eldridge.
- Good to go.
- All right. Wagon's set up. Bot moves.
- Uh-oh. We got goats, guys.
- Heads up. Goats.
- Watch out.
- SANBORN: Blow them little bastards up.
- Oh, shit.
- Shit.
- Oh, fuck.
- Wagon's having a bad day, boys.
- Did you build that?
- ELDRIDGE: No, the U.S. Army did.
All right. Looks like I'm going down there.
You don't like waiting around
this beautiful neighborhood?
Oh, I love it.
So, if everything looks okay
when I get down there,
I'm just going to set it up and we'll BIP it.
Give these people
something to think about.
Want them to know
if they're going to leave a bomb
on the side of the road for us,
we're just going to
- blow up their little fucking road.
- Sounds good.
- Craving a burger, is that strange?
- Not for you.
No, okay.
- Helmet on.
- Happy trails.
- Fans on.
- Blaster One. Can you read me?
Roger that, Blaster One. You're good to go.
You're looking good, Blaster One.
[ PANTING ]
It's nice and hot in here.
THOMPSON: 150.
Roger that, 150 meters.
Hi. Where are you from?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where are you from?
- California?
- Hey, get out of here, man.
- Where?
- Hey, this ain't a fucking meet and greet.
Now get out of here. Now.
Go.
- You making friends again, Sanborn?
- All day long.
[ PANTING ]
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-five meters.
Roger that. You are now in the kill zone.
- Thanks for reminding me.
- That's what I'm here for, baby.
THOMPSON: Okay.
- Okay, the dets are good.
- Roger that.
Okay, I'm laying on the charge.
Nice and sweet.
I'm good to go. I'm coming back.
- Five meters out.
- Five meters. Roger that.
Hey, Sanborn.
You know what this place needs?
- I'm listening.
- It needs grass.
- We gonna start our grass business?
- That's right, man.
I'm going to sell the grass,
and you're going to cut it.
It's going to be called Sanborn and Sons.
[ LAUGHING ]
We'll be rich.
I like that. Crabgrass, St. Augustine, man.
I'm a scholar on this shit.
How about this? You sell it, I fertilize it.
[ LAUGHING ]
THOMPSON: Twenty-five.
SANBORN: Twenty-five meters. Roger that.
Sanborn! Butcher shop, two o'clock,
dude has a phone!
- Why is Eldridge running?
- Make him put it down!
- Put down the phone!
- Come on, guys. Talk to me.
- Drop the phone! Drop your phone!
- Shit!
- Hey, burn him, Eldridge. Burn him!
- Put down the cell phone!
Eldridge, burn him! Get out of the way!
- Drop your phone!
- Tell him to put it down!
Go get it! Stop him, Eldridge!
I can't get a shot.
Thompson!
Anywhere's good.
- MAN: Is that everything?
- Yeah.
[ HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ KNOCKING AT DOOR ]
Yeah?
Come in.
Sergeant James.
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
- J.T. Sanborn, my man.
- Oh, hey. Hi. How are you? Will. Call me Will.
Welcome to Bravo Company.
Welcome to Camp Victory.
Camp Victory?
I thought this was Camp Liberty.
Oh, no. They changed that about a week ago.
Victory sounds better.
All right. Well, good.
At least I'm in the right place, right?
- Yeah.
- Well, while you're here, can you
- help me move this thing real quick?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, no problem.
Maybe you shouldn't take this down.
You know, we get a lot of mortars at night.
You know, the plywood on the windows
help with the lateral fray coming through.
- That's why it's up there.
- Yeah, well,
it's not going to stop a mortar round
from coming in through the roof, you know.
Besides, I like the sunshine.
Hey, uh, I'm sorry to hear about Thompson.
- I know he was a good tech.
- Yeah, he was.
He was a great team leader, too.
Yeah, I'm not trying to
fill his shoes or anything.
You know, I'm just going to do my best.
Appreciate it.
All right. Cool.
Well, home sweet home, right?
[ HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING ]
ELDRIDGE: Aren't you glad the Army has
all these tanks parked here?
Just in case the Russians come,
we have to have a big tank battle.
I'd rather be on the side with the tanks,
just in case, than not have them.
Yeah, but they don't do anything.
I mean, anyone comes alongside a Humvee,
we're dead.
Anybody even looks at you funny,
Pretty much the bottom line is,
if you're in Iraq, you're dead.
How's a fucking tank
supposed to stop that?
Would you shut the fuck up,
Owen? Please?
Sorry. Just trying to scare the new guy.
I saw a little bit in Afghanistan, too.
Should get your eyes on the road, Eldridge.
Copy that.
[ HORNS HONKING ]
SPEAKING ARABIC: "Move..move"
Move.
SPEAKING ARABIC: "Move..Hurry up"
[ HORNS HONKING ]
Soldier [ speaking Arabic ]: "Move..move"
The Iraqi in the car [ protesting ]: "Shame on you.."
MAN ON RADIO: Blaster One,
this is Victory Main.
Have you reached your 20, yet? Over.
Where the hell are the guys
that called this in?
[ RADIO SQUAWKING ]
Victory Main, Victory Main,
this is Blaster Mike.
Interrogative, do you have
an update on position? Over.
MAN ON RADIO: Victory Main.
Figures to follow.
3-4-5-3 is your grid. Over.
Well, that's exactly where the hell I am,
and I don't see anybody in fatigues.
MAN ON RADIO: Give us a second
to confirm grid. Over.
- Watch your feet.
- MAN ON RADIO: Set visual is 3-4-5-3, grid.
Over.
Got the Humvee.
Friendly!
Ah, here we go.
- They abandoned their vehicle.
- We got an empty Humvee over here, James.
Yeah. Yeah, I got it.
Let's move.
Friendly.
- Morning, boys.
- Sir.
Don't tell me the bomb's in here
with you guys.
[ LAUGHING ]
Let's step out,
and I'll show you what's going on.
- All right.
- Down on that block 20 meters,
this side of the mosque,
east side of the street, our informant says
he saw a pair of wires
going into a rubble pile.
- It's a possible IED.
- Yeah.
- I trust this guy. I know him.
- Okay. I'll handle it.
- Do you want to talk to him or...
- No. Good. Keep your boys back.
We'll be good. Thank you. Specialist,
- bring up the Humvee.
- What's going on?
I'm going to break out the suit.
- What about the bot?
- I'll take care of it.
Well, don't you want us
to get the bot down there,
see what it looks like?
- I'll handle it.
- It's kind of tight down here, James.
All right, here we go.
Ready?
Good?
You know,
you don't have to go down there, man.
- We already have the bot halfway out.
- I'll be all right.
First day, figure you want to
take it easy, right?
- How's it looking, Eldridge?
- Good to go.
Let's do it.
- Got tools?
- Got tools.
All right. Let's rock and roll, man.
[ LAUGHING ]
- He's a rowdy boy.
- He's reckless.
Blaster One, what's going on?
Blaster One! What are you doing?
Blaster One, this is Blaster Mike.
What's with the smoke
on the side of the road? Over.
SANBORN: Hey, James, can you hear me?
What's going on with the smoke
on the side of the road? Over.
- JAMES: Creating a diversion.
- From what? Is there a threat?
Eldridge, get up on the wall. Move!
Tell me what you see, Specialist.
All right. I got him.
He's walking down range.
James, the smoke is killing my visibility.
Where are you in relationship to the IED?
Are you within 100 meters yet?
Hell, I don't know, Sanborn. I'll tell you
when I'm standing over it, cowboy.
[ CAR HORN HONKING ]
Take cover!
ELDRIDGE: Oh, no.
A car stopped in front of him, Sanborn.
Shit. James! James, come back, now.
EOD just pulled a nine on a haji in a car.
- Do you want me to send backup?
- JAMES: I got it.
- Sanchez, Harris.
- Negative! Negative!
Stand down.
The blast will come up the block.
Stay clear around the corner.
EOD has the situation under control. Over.
JAMES: Where you going?
SOLDIER: Hold your fire, on my command.
Want to back up?
SOLDIER: Get out of the car!
Get out of the car!
What the fuck are you doing?
Back up.
Hello?
[ MAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Brother..Get out of the car..or else they'll kill you..For God's sake get out.."
Want to get back?
Shit.
It's that way.
Back.
SOLDIER: Three, four rounds fired. The nine
is now pressing into the haji's forehead.
- Taxi's moving.
- Eldridge, get him out of here. Come on.
- Get him out of the car!
- Stop! Stop the car!
Get out of the fucking car!
Get on the ground! On the ground!
- Get down there.
- Stay down.
Well, if he wasn't an insurgent,
he sure the hell is now.
[ LAUGHING ]
Roger that. That's real funny.
Found something.
Hello, baby.
Got you.
All right.
All right. We're done. Good to go.
- Good to go.
- Come down, Specialist.
Roger.
[ GRUNTING ]
Uh, got a wire. Hang on.
Where are you going?
- Secondary.
- Shit.
Take cover. Get in the wall. Get in the wall.
Oh, boy.
[ EXHALING ]
That wasn't so bad.
First time working together.
What do you think?
Hmm, I think us working together
means I talk to you
- and you talk to me.
- We going on a date, Sanborn?
No. We're going on a mission,
and my job is to keep you safe,
- so we can keep going on missions.
- It's combat, buddy.
Hey. It's just 39 days.
Thirty-eight if we survive today.
Hey, it's Mr. Be All You Can Be.
- What's up, Doc?
- Not much. How are you?
I'm good.
Got a question about that song, though,
Be All You Can Be.
What if all I can be is dead
on the side of an Iraqi road?
I mean, I think it's logical. This is a war.
People die all the time. Why not me?
You got to change the record in your head.
You gotta start thinking about other things.
Okay. Stop obsessing.
Right now, what are you thinking about?
You want to know
what I'm thinking about, Doc?
- Yeah.
- This is what I'm thinking about, Doc.
Here's Thompson, okay. He's dead.
[ GUN CLICKS ]
He's alive.
Here's Thompson. He's dead. He's alive.
He's dead. He's alive.
Yo, what's up, my nigger? What's up, man?
What's up?
You cool? Come on.
You want the cool shit?
Man, come on, come on.
It's the tight shit, man. Come on.
Wanna buy DVDs? Wanna buy DVD?
Fuck you. Come, come, please, please.
New releases. Look.
Hey. Hello, hello. Want to buy DVDs?
Very good. Very good.
- How much?
- One for 5 and two for 9.
- Three for 12.
- Three for 13, and I don't give you tax.
- Very good, man. Look.
- No tax?
All right. What do you got?
What do you got?
You know, you smart shit.
You not like those stupid fuck-face...
Yeah, I'm a smart guy, huh?
You're a smart kid.
Give me your best one, okay?
- Here, this the best one.
- This is a good one?
- Yes. The best shit, man.
- Okay. Here you go. I'll take one.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you.
Want a cigarette? Get out of here.
You shouldn't smoke.
Thank you. Take it easy.
I need to talk to you about something
before we go out again.
What's that?
- Yesterday.
- Mmm-hmm.
Wasn't cool.
Yeah, I know. You'll get it, though.
You'll get it.
- So, you're a ranger, huh?
- Yeah.
I was in Intelligence seven years
before I joined EOD.
We ran missions in every shithole
that you could possibly imagine.
So, I'm pretty sure I can figure out
a redneck piece of trailer trash like you.
Looks like you're on the right track.
See you out there, man.
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Get out of the building.."
Come on, let's go. Move it. Move it.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC OVER LOUDSPEAKER, REPEATING THE WARNING ]
SANBORN: Shit. Get out of the way. Move.
Hello.
- Where is it?
- It's behind the wall.
- All right. See any wires? Any smoke?
- No. I didn't look.
- All right, so how do you know it's a bomb?
- The car has been parked illegally.
The suspension is sagging.
There's definitely something heavy
in the trunk.
Right. So, why don't you walk over there
and peek inside
and tell me what you see?
You want me to go close to it?
[ In Arabic ]: "You bull shit!"
Yeah. No. I don't. No, I'm kidding.
I'm kidding.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Hey, move.."
ELDRIDGE: Shit. It's coming from over here!
Blaster One, you there?
Blaster One, you hear me?
Here. Go!
Shit.
Let's go, guys.
- Sarge.
- Yeah?
- Let it go.
- ELDRIDGE: I got top cover.
That's a negative, Specialist.
Eldridge, you stay with me.
- Sanborn, you take top cover.
- Shit.
Blaster Mike in position.
What do you got?
I got a through and through to the chest,
but I got him stable.
- He's not going to make it.
- If we leave here in 15 minutes,
- he's got a survivable wound, sir.
- He's not going to make it.
[ SHOT FIRING ]
Oh, God.
- What's he doing?
- I don't know.
What are you doing?
There's enough bang in there
to send us all to Jesus.
If I'm going to die,
I wanna die comfortable.
I need my kit and my cans, yeah.
- What's going on down there, Eldridge?
- I'm getting his kit and his cans.
Cover me, please.
Kit and cans.
Got a lot of det cord, electrical.
All right, I'm gonna look
for the initiating system.
Well, it's not in the back seat.
I don't think.
All right. It's not in the back seat.
Got a young man on the roof,
your nine o'clock, keep an eye on him.
Roger that.
It's not in the front seat.
It's not in the door.
Not on the floors.
Not in the glove box.
If you haven't found it yet,
it's probably under the car.
Yeah. No wire leads under the car.
It's all in here somewhere.
- Hey, Sanborn.
- Yeah.
You got eyes on some guy
with a video camera?
- No. Where?
- He's right at my 12 o'clock. You see him?
He's pointing the fucking thing right at me.
Shit. Negative. I don't see him.
Hey, Sanborn. He's right at my 12 o'clock.
Look, 12 o'clock!
Roger that. I got him.
ELDRIDGE: Getting ready
to put me on YouTube.
- Little shady.
- Yeah, he looks shady.
- Keep an eye on him.
- Okay. So, what's the play?
Be smart. Make a good decision, over.
[ MURMURS ]
Got more wire that
leads fucking nowhere.
Fuck!
- SANBORN: Hey, James, how you doing?
- I'm wonderful. How are you?
You know, we've been here a while.
- We need to get out of here soon.
- Uh-huh.
We got a lot of eyes on us, James.
We need to get out of here.
Roger that. I'm going to figure this out.
SANBORN: James,
we need to get out of here.
- James, do you copy?
- Fuck it. I get it.
Fuck me.
[ LAUGHING ]
[ VOICES FROM GROUND ]
- Hey, how's it looking in there, soldier?
- All clear.
James, the evac is complete. We can leave.
Let the engineers handle this mess.
- We moving?
- That's affirmative.
[ SQUEAKING ]
- Interesting.
- What's up with James?
- He's not answering me.
- Yeah. I think he removed his headset.
Will you tell him to
put his radio back on, please?
Hey, James! Sergeant Sanborn is asking
if you'll please put your headset back on.
Uh, that's a negative.
That, yeah, that's not going to happen.
Shit.
I got eyes on three guys
at the minaret at six o'clock.
- SANBORN: What the hell is he doing?
- I don't know what the fuck he's doing.
Looks like he's checking the oil.
They're communicating
with your cameraman.
- This is real bad, man.
- Get behind the Jersey barrier.
- I can't see James from here.
- Get down now!
We can go!
Bastard.
[ EXHALING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
We're done.
Sanborn, let's get out of here.
JAMES: Whoo!
That was good.
- Hey, James?
- Yeah, yeah.
Never turn your headset off again.
- You the guy in the bomb suit?
- No, sir. Sir, that's Sergeant James.
- He's right here.
- Hey, James.
- Yep.
- Someone's here to see you.
Oh!
You the guy with the flaming car,
Sergeant James?
Afternoon, sir. Uh, yes, sir.
Well, that's just hot shit.
You're a wild man, you know that?
- Uh, yes, sir.
- He's a wild man. You know that?
- I want to shake your hand.
- Thank you, sir.
Yeah. How many bombs
have you disarmed?
- Uh, I'm not quite sure, sir.
- Sergeant?
- Yes, sir.
- I asked you a question.
- Eight hundred and seventy-three, sir.
- Eight hundred and seventy-three.
Eight hundred and seventy-three!
That's just hot shit.
- Eight hundred and seventy-three.
- Counting today, sir, yes.
That's gotta be a record.
What's the best way to go about
disarming one of these things?
The way you don't die, sir.
That's a good one.
That's spoken like a wild man. That's good.
Hey, what's up, man?
Hey, wait a minute. Look who it is.
I want my 5 bucks back, buddy.
$5 for what, man? You crazy now?
Yeah. The DVD you sold me was crap.
You crazy, man. That's impossible.
It's Hollywood special effects.
No. It was shaky.
It was out of focus, buddy.
- What, you want donkey porn?
- It's crap.
Girls on dog? Gay sex?
Man, anything you want. You're gay?
I hook you up, man. Come on.
- All right. What's your name?
- Beckham.
- Beckham, like the soccer player?
- Yeah, man. It's like the soccer player.
- Now give me my ball.
- Are you a soccer player?
Yeah, man. I'm best of the best.
I'm better than Becks.
- You play goalie?
- Yes. I play goalie.
Good. I'll make you a deal.
If you can stop the ball,
I'm going to give you 5 bucks.
- But if you can't...
- $5, man? What about 10, 20?
If I score... Listen to me.
If I score, I'm going to keep your ball.
- Deal?
- Deal.
Get up there. Go on.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Go..go.."
- Let's see what you got, hot stuff. Come on.
- Are you ready?
- On three. Ready? One, two, three.
- Yeah.
[ LAUGHING ]
Shit.
Come on. Where's the $5? Man, come on.
All right. I got you. Good job, dude.
- There's 10.
- You're an EOD?
[ Bomla..bomla..! ]
- That's right.
- It's fun, no? It's cool? It's gangster.
Yeah?
Yeah, I think so. Tell you what.
I'm going to buy... Let me see
if I have enough money, yeah, 5.
I'm going to buy another DVD, okay?
But if it's shaky, look at me,
or out of focus, or any way not 100%,
I'm going to chop off your goddamn head
with a dull knife.
How do you feel about...
I'm just kidding. I'm just kidding. Here.
[ LAUGHING ]
You're a good kid, man.
You're a good kid, aren't you?
CAMBRIDGE: Owen. Hi.
- Hey, sir.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Good.
- What's wrong?
- Brakes are squeaking.
Don't trust the mechanics around here,
you know?
- So, how you doing?
- I'm good. I just want to check the oil.
Yeah, it's good to sleep, eating well.
Feeling pretty squared away, actually, Doc.
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
So, you getting along
with the other soldiers in your unit?
Yeah. My team's great.
My team leader is inspiring.
- You being sarcastic, soldier?
- No.
He's going to get me killed,
almost died yesterday.
At least I'll die in the line of duty,
proud and strong.
You know, this doesn't have to be
a bad time in your life.
Going to war is
a once-in-a-lifetime experience.
It could be fun.
And you know this
from your extensive work in the field, right?
- I've done my field duty.
- Where was that? Yale?
Look, you don't want me to come around,
I won't come around.
These talks are voluntary.
Look, I'm sorry.
I appreciate what you're saying. I do.
I appreciate our sessions together,
but you need to come out
from behind the wire and see what we do.
Well, if the circumstance calls for it, I will.
Just like every other soldier.
Fire in the hole! Fire in the hole!
Fire in the hole!
Firing now.
[ WHOOPING ]
- Ready for second det?
- Ready.
Fire in the hole! Fire in the hole!
Fire in the hole!
JAMES: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hold on a second.
God damn it.
- I think I forgot my gloves down there.
- What?
I forgot my gloves. Hang on.
[ CLEARING THROAT ]
SANBORN: You know, these detonators
misfire all the time.
What are you doing?
I'm just saying shit happens, they misfire.
He'd be obliterated to nothing.
SANBORN: His helmet would be left.
You could have that.
Little specks of hair charred on the inside.
ELDRIDGE: Yeah. There'd be
half a helmet somewhere, bits of hair.
Have to ask for a change
in technique and protocol,
and make sure this type of accident
never happen again, you know?
You'd have to write the report.
- Are you serious?
- I can't write it.
No. I mean,
are you serious about killing him?
ELDRIDGE: Twelve o'clock, I see an SUV.
SANBORN: Roger that.
ELDRIDGE: I got four armed men.
They're in haji gear.
JAMES: All right. Go slow and easy, man.
We're in it now.
SANBORN: All right.
Careful now, guys. Careful.
- Eldridge, you stay on that 50.
- I got them.
Put your gun down. On your knees.
Down. Put the gun down, now!
- Put up your hands.
- Get down, motherfucker.
Put your gun down now!
Put your gun down!
Advance, advance.
Hands high!
- Eldridge, cover!
- I got you.
Pistol off your hip, now.
What you want me to do?
Keep my hands up or take off the pistol?
- Keep your hands up.
- Okay.
Easy, easy.
Got it!
Can I touch my fucking head now?
Slowly.
We're on the same fucking side, guys.
Oh, Jesus.
TEAM LEADER: You guys are
wired fucking tight, you know that?
JAMES: Right. Well, this is no place
for a picnic, right?
- What are you guys doing here?
- We have a flat tire. Can you help us?
Sure, yeah. You got any spares?
We have spares,
but we used up our wrench.
How do you use up a wrench?
Well, the guy over there with the red thing
on his head, he threw it at someone.
[ LAUGHING ]
- All right.
- Thank you.
- This is Chris. This is the wrench man.
- Hello, wrench man.
- That's Jimmy.
- You know, you can shoot people here.
- You don't have to throw a wrench.
- Fuck off.
Take a look at this.
I picked these guys up in Najaf.
Nine of hearts, that's one.
And the other, Al Rawi, jack of clubs.
- The same guys?
- TEAM LEADER: Yeah. That's them.
Does he need a little help there?
What's the problem with the tire? Come on.
No good, boss. This wrench is too small.
All right, solutions? Anyone?
I think there's another wrench in the back
of the Humvee, if you wanna check.
- I'll give it a try.
- All right. Let's do it.
TEAM LEADER: How long you guys out here?
JAMES: I don't know, Specialist,
what do we got?
ELDRIDGE: We have, uh, 23 more days.
SANBORN: Oh, God.
We have 22 days after today, sir.
But no one's counting, right?
This trip never finishes.
Contact left.
Sniper!
MAN: Take cover.
TEAM LEADER: Chris, take the 50.
Jimmy, head back into the...
You got it.
Nice covering.
Lay it down! Lay it down!
Charlie, go! Go, go, go, go, go!
- Shit!
- SANBORN: Rock and mortar.
TEAM LEADER: They're on the sides, Charlie.
Take this one.
- Get the van and the go bags, Jimmy.
- Got it.
- What are we shooting at?
- I don't know.
- Fuck. The packages are gone!
- MAN: They won't get far on foot.
Bring them in, Sergeant, those fuckers.
I'm out 500,000 fucking quid.
[ LAUGHING ]
I forgot, it's 500,000 dead or alive.
Okay. Jimmy, give me the Barrett.
Can't see a thing.
Come on!
Chris is shooting wild.
Gotta conserve the ammo.
OLDER MAN: Hey, Chris, can you hear me?
Hey, Chris! Can you hear me?
Chill out on the 50.
Roger that.
- Fifty's down.
- He shot Chris.
OLDER MAN: It must be coming
from that building.
I can't see anything.
Movement on the roof.
- Yeah?
- Three meters higher.
I'm going to adjust.
My anchor fell out.
- Fuck, fuck. We need some help.
- He's dead.
- We gotta get out of here now.
- Damn it.
This is Alpha Nine. We're in deep shit.
- I'll get on the Barrett.
- Go, go, go, go.
- Yeah, we're taking incoming fire.
- JAMES: Go, go, go, go.
No, Sanborn. Sanborn don't go up there.
JAMES: Go, buddy. Stay low!
Stay low! Stay low!
I have two KIA... Correction, three KIA.
Our grid last lock stat...
- JAMES: Stay low!
- Can you get me some help?
MAN ON RADIO: Roger that, Alpha Nine.
Give me your post. Over.
- Behind you.
- Yeah.
OLDER MAN: MGRF 5-5-4-2-9-7-3-4-2-0.
MAN ON RADIO: Alpha Nine,
this is Big Dog Seven.
You're gonna have to sit tight. Over.
Just breathe easy.
JAMES: I've got movement.
SANBORN: Yeah.
On the ridge of that house.
- About 850 meters.
- See it.
By the window. You got target?
Got it.
All right, you're a little left.
Just breathe easy.
[ GUN CLICKS ]
I'm out of ammo.
Hmm?
Eldridge, we need ammo.
- Where is it?
- JAMES: Check on the dead guy, man.
It's on the dead man.
- Eldridge!
- I'm looking.
- We need that ammo, man.
- All right, man.
Here.
Thanks.
- All right. Same target.
- Got it.
- Fucking jammed.
- Let me see.
[ GRUNTING ]
Fuck.
Shit. The blood's making it jam.
Eldridge, shit.
You gotta clean the blood off, man.
It's making them jam.
Specialist!
- Clean the blood off.
- Okay.
Clean it. Clean it.
- You gotta clean it, man.
- How?
Spit and rub.
- All right.
- Spit and rub, buddy. Spit and rub.
It's not working. It's not coming off.
Just spit and rub. Spit and rub, man.
Here, take it out. Take it out.
Use your Camel. Use your Camel.
Where is it? You all right?
Here, use that.
Just breathe, buddy. Come on.
Just breathe in.
You got it. You're doing good.
Here, just squeeze. Got it?
Rub that ogive baby.
Come on, you got it. Here.
You're doing good, man.
You're doing real good.
- Got them?
- Yeah.
Hey, I'm going to keep you safe, buddy,
all right? Now let's get these bastards.
Scan your sectors. Scan your sectors.
Kill that fucking asshole.
Son of a bitch.
Nice, he's down.
Second one is out of range.
Twenty meters to the right of the building.
- I got him.
- Fire when ready.
He's moving. He's moving. He's moving.
To the building. Follow him. You got him?
Got him.
JAMES: He's down.
Good night. Thanks for playing.
Window, at the window, at the window.
He's still there.
Left window, left window. Got him?
Got him.
He's down.
[ COUGHING ]
[ SPITTING ]
- JAMES: Hey, Owen.
- Yeah.
Can you grab a juice
out of the pack, please?
Sure.
SOLDIER: I think we're out.
- Got anything left to drink?
- You could try that one.
Here.
Thank you.
[ SIGHING ]
Drink. Drink it.
JAMES: Things are real quiet.
SANBORN: Yeah.
JAMES: I don't like it.
- Hey, Will.
- Yeah?
At your six o'clock,
I see movement on the bridge.
- Right on the tracks.
- Well, handle it.
- Should I fire?
- It's your call, buddy.
Good job.
Hey, Sanborn.
I think we're done.
[ HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROANING ]
- Okay? You all right?
- Yeah.
That's what you get for hitting
your fucking team leader, motherfucker.
- Come on, man.
- I'll be right back. I gotta piss.
Owen. Another round, boy. That's an order.
Well, yes, sir, Sergeant James, sir.
You're not very good with people,
are you, sir?
But you're a good warrior.
Give me your mug.
- There you go, sir.
- You acquitted yourself well
on the field of battle today, Specialist.
Cheers.
I'm too old for this shit.
- I was scared.
- Yeah?
Well, everyone's a coward
about something, you know.
You're good. You're real good.
SANBORN: Just what do we have here?
Will has possessions.
- I didn't know you owned anything, Will.
- Let's see what you got here, Will.
- Who's that?
- That's my son.
[ LAUGHING ]
He's a tough little bastard. Nothing like me.
You mean to tell me you married?
Well, you know, I had a girlfriend,
and she got pregnant, so we got married.
We got divorced.
Or, you know, I thought we got divorced.
I mean, she's still living in the house,
and she says we're still together,
so I don't know.
What does that make her? I don't know.
Dumb for still being with your ass.
[ LAUGHING ]
Hey. She ain't fucking dumb, all right?
She's just loyal.
She's just loyal. That's all.
How about you guys? You got...
You got a girl? What do you got?
My only problem is the girl I do like, I can't
stop her from talking about babies, man.
Give her your sperm, stud.
Go on. Do it.
Come on, chicken shit.
Just give it to her, man.
- No. Hell, no.
- Make babies.
I know when I'm ready.
I ain't ready for that yet. I know that.
Well, well...
- What do we have here?
- Components.
They're, you know, bomb parts, signatures.
Yeah, I see that,
but what are they doing under your bed?
Well...
Ah-ha!
Here we are. This one.
This one is from the U.N. building.
Flaming car. Dead man's switch. Boom.
This guy was good. I like him.
Relay... Ah! It's this guy.
This one, y'all,
is from our first call together.
This box is full of stuff
that almost killed me.
And what about this one?
Where's this one from, Will?
It's my wedding ring.
Like I said, stuff that almost killed me.
[ LAUGHING ]
You know, I just think it's really interesting,
you know, to hold something in your hand
that could have killed any one of us.
Damn that. It's all shit from RadioShack.
- ELDRIDGE: It's interesting.
- I think it's interesting, too.
Well, I think you hit me harder
than I hit you, motherfucker,
therefore I owe you a punch.
- Now get your ass up. Come on.
- You know what? He's right.
Let's go. Come on.
Come on.
All right, hold on, boys.
We need some rules.
Sanborn, no face shots.
- There's gonna be a face shot.
- Sergeant James, take off your shirt.
- Yes, sir.
- What happened?
- My momma dropped me when I was a baby.
- Looks like frag scars.
Let it go, Eldridge.
- Come on.
- All right.
Nice and big.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
- You like that, huh?
- That's all you got?
Come on.
Bring some. Come on.
[ MOANING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
[ WHOOPS ]
God damn!
That's gotta hurt.
[ COUGHING ]
- You all right, man?
- Yeah.
- He's all right.
- Get up, bitch.
Get up, bitch.
[ EXCLAIMING ]
- What do you got now?
- Get the fuck off me!
- What do you got?
- Get off me, you motherfucker.
What do you got? Come on, Sanborn.
What do you got? He's a wild one.
We got a wild one.
- Let go.
- That's right.
- Come on, Sanborn.
- You get off me, you shit.
- Ride on him!
- Get off me.
I'm riding him. Whoo!
- Come on, guys.
- Come on, Sanborn.
- Get off me!
- Hey, hey, hey.
[ LAUGHING ]
I'm just kidding, motherfucker. Shit.
You're all right, Sanborn.
You're all right, man.
Owen, get this guy a drink. Come on.
- You got him?
- Yeah, I got him.
- Right here.
- All right.
- I'll see you later, man.
- Get home safe. All right.
Come on, big boy.
Damn, boy, you need to get on a diet.
He hurt his knee. Carry on.
Come on, man. Steps.
Come on. Step, step.
Jesus.
All right, lay down. Lay down.
- Get some rest.
- Hey, James,
you think I got what it takes
to put on the suit?
Hell, no.
Good night, boy.
[ SIGHING ]
Whoa.
- Morning, Colonel.
- Morning. Mind if I ride along?
I'm sick to death of sitting
behind a desk all the time.
It'd be a privilege. Hop in, Colonel.
Hey, Doc.
Not to insult your intelligence, sir,
but if the shit hits the fan,
please don't fire out the Humvee.
The round will just bounce around
and someone might get shot.
I don't like getting shot.
Understood, Sergeant.
ELDRIDGE: It's a pretty standard mission.
We're just here to pick up
some unexploded ordnance.
Sergeant James is gonna
go see what the deal is...
All right, guys.
...and hopefully we're gone
in a couple of minutes.
- We've gotta gear up.
- For what?
Security hasn't gone in.
We'll just go in quiet. Radios off.
- Roger.
- Roger that.
- I'm glad you came.
- Stay safe. All right.
[ GLASS CRACKING ]
Psst. Psst.
- Clear.
- Hey, cigarette's still smoking.
It's all our shit.
Motherfucking goldmine.
Watch out for trips.
I got something.
I know this kid. His name's Beckham.
He sells DVDs.
You ever see a body bomb before, man?
It's fucking disgusting, man.
Let's get out of here.
Eldridge, why don't you grab all the C4 and
det cord you can get your hands on, okay?
Let's get all this ordnance out of here.
And we're just gonna...
We are gonna blow the place, got it?
- Roger that.
- Let's blow it.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Peace be upon you"
- "Peace be upon you" too. Welcome here.
What are you doing?
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "We want to take these stones"
Yeah? Putting the stones in to move?
Yeah. That's really wonderful,
but it's a little unsafe today.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Thank you..God bless you."
Yeah, it's a little unsafe.
So, maybe... I don't know,
I'm thinking maybe we should move?
No?
[ Arabic Speaker ]: "No problem!"
[ COUGHING ]
Fuck.
- You all right?
- Yeah. You?
Yeah.
[ EXHALING ]
- ELDRIDGE: You all right, man?
- Yeah.
No one in or out, okay?
Cancel the det. Cancel the det.
- Fuck is he doing?
- I don't know, man.
I don't know.
[ GRUNTING ]
- I'm coming out.
- SANBORN: Roger that.
Hi.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Peace be upon you."
- Where are you from?
- New York.
- The Big Apple.
- I'm from Iraq.
CAMBRIDGE: I love it here.
This is a beautiful place.
But it's not too safe here, okay?
So I think we need to move, please?
ELDRIDGE: You think it's that little base rat?
- SANBORN: No, I don't.
- You positive?
Sure. Hey, I don't know, man.
They all look the same, right?
I don't know. Will seemed sure.
That was weird.
Very weird.
Please, just move.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Move from here"
Move. Move.
Thank you. Move on.
Move on. Thank you.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "That the peace, the Americans brought here."
I'm sorry.
Will's very weird.
I mean, he keeps bomb parts under his bed.
I bet you he won't keep
any of these parts under his bed.
Bye-bye.
Yeah, bye-bye. Bye. Thank you.
Hey, Colonel. Let's go.
So long. Thank you.
ELDRIDGE: IED.
- IED, IED. Fuck.
- Cambridge!
- What happened here?
- Clear it.
- Jesus!
- JAMES: Get back! Get down!
SANBORN: Stay back.
Stay back, Sanborn. Keep them back.
Is anyone hurt?
Cambridge! Fuck. Fuck.
Where's Cambridge?
- Cambridge, come on. We gotta go.
- Shit. I think he's dead.
We got to find Cambridge. Doc!
- Eldridge. Eldridge.
- Doc!
- Eldridge!
- Eldridge, come on, man. Come on.
- Doc!
I just saw him. He was walking right here.
He's dead, okay? He's dead. Okay?
It's all right, man. You're all right, buddy.
You're all right.
[ PHONE RINGING ]
Hello?
Will?
[ SIGHING ]
Hello?
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Peace be upon you."
- "You're Welcome"
Hey, let me ask you a question.
What happened to the little kid
that used to work here?
Sorry, man. English... I, no English.
No English. You no speak English now.
Okay. Little kid. Beckham is his name.
He sells DVDs.
DVD. One DVD, $5.
Jesus Christ.
- $5.
- Excuse me, soldier.
- You in charge of this area here?
- What's up?
You know this guy?
How do we know that
he's not giving intel to insurgents,
telling them where to drop mortars?
- I think he's just selling DVDs.
- Well, he's a security risk.
We should get rid of him.
What are you looking at?
He's just selling DVDs, man.
All the merchants are clear.
- By who?
- I couldn't do anything with him
without the say-so from my CO.
All right. Fuck.
Fuck.
[ EXCLAIMING ]
Change anything?
You speak English now, don't you?
- Okay.
- Drive.
- This is his house?
Beckham's house?
Wait here.
Fuck.
[ MUSIC PLAYING ON TELEVISION ]
[ DISHES CLATTERING ]
Shh!
You speak English?
English, French, Arabic.
Good. Open your vest.
Stay there. Stay.
Tell me what you know about Beckham.
- For whom?
- Beckham, 12-year-old boy, body bomb.
Stay right there.
- I don't know.
- You don't know.
But please, sit down. I am Professor Nabil.
- This is my home.
- Mmm-hmm.
You are a guest. Please, sit down.
I'm a guest. I'm just...
I'm looking for the people
responsible for Beckham.
You are CIA. No?
I am very pleased to see CIA in my home.
Please, sit.
Look...
[ WOMAN EXCLAIMING ]
Be careful. The gun can go off.
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "What is he doing here?"
- "Don't make a fuss!"..
- "Get inside..It's none of your business"!
- "Get out of here..." "Enough is enough"
- "What have you done?"
- ..."Get inside!"
[ CAR HORN HONKING ]
- U.S.A. friendly coming in.
- GUARD 1: Stop.
- GUARD 2: Get the fuck down!
- GUARD 1: Stop right there.
- U.S.A. friendly.
- GUARD 1: Halt.
GUARD 2: On your knees.
GUARD 3: Get down on your knees, now.
You will be shot.
- Don't move.
- Don't fucking move.
- Get the fuck down!
- On your knees!
- Down now!
- Open your jacket!
- Opening my jacket.
- Cover. Get him down.
- On the ground.
- I have a weapon.
- Don't fucking move.
- Get him down.
- Tower, hold cover. Searching.
- I have a weapon.
- Hands where I can see them.
- Gun.
- Like I said.
- Weapons clear.
ID?
- What the fuck are you doing?
- I was at a whorehouse.
All right. If I let you in,
will you tell me where it is exactly?
Yeah.
SANBORN: James, do you copy?
James, do you have your ears on?
James!
Yes, it's James. What's up?
- Hey.
- What's up, man?
Look, we have a tank explosion
in the Green Zone.
We have to do a post-blast assessment.
See if it was a suicide bombing,
and if so, how the fuck did he do it?
Okay.
Where'd you say you were again?
I didn't, Sergeant. Let's go.
What happened to your head, James?
You ready? Game face, buddy. Let's go.
- SANBORN: You ready?
- Let's do this.
- Rock and roll.
- Moving out.
Good night.
[ WOMAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]
[ SOLDIER SHOUTING ]
U.S.A. friendlies coming through.
[ WOMAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]
Make room, guys. Make room.
Hey, Sanborn. Look.
Grab the other arm. Grab the other arm.
- Grab the other arm.
- Sir, can I get a medic? Need a medic!
[ SIREN WAILING ]
[ FLARE GUN FIRING ]
JAMES: An oil tanker?
SANBORN: Yeah.
SANBORN: Pretty long flight, huh?
JAMES: Yeah.
[ MAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]
[ SOLDIER SHOUTING ]
[ CHILD SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Papa..papa"
JAMES: This is the edge of the blast radius.
Jesus.
- So, where's our triggerman?
- Burnt up in the flames, man.
Suicide bomber.
We'll never find a body in that shit.
What if there was no body?
What if it was a remote det?
A really good bad guy
hides out in the dark, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Right here.
The perfect vantage point
outside the blast radius
to sit back
and watch us clean up their mess.
ELDRIDGE: Wanna go out there?
JAMES: Yes, I do.
- I could stand to get in a little trouble.
- SANBORN: No, man. This is bullshit.
Look, you got three infantry platoons
behind you
whose job it is to go haji hunting.
That ain't our fucking job.
JAMES: You don't say no to me, Sanborn.
I say no to you, okay?
You know there are guys watching us
right now.
They're laughing at this.
Okay, and I'm not okay with that.
Now, turn off your goddamn torch,
because we're going.
Fucking shit.
[ FLARE GUN FIRING ]
JAMES: Now we know
where their oil tanker came from.
SANBORN: No shit. Same kind.
- We're close.
- Yeah.
All right, these alleyways
are probably set up in a grid.
We're going to need to split up,
flush them out.
Sanborn, you take one.
Eldridge take two, I got three.
Rally point at your intersection.
Ready, move.
SANBORN: Wait, rally point when?
Fuck.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Haste..haste.."
[ CHILD SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Papa..papa!"
[ GARBAGE CAN CLATTERING ]
[ MACHINE GUN FIRING ]
Shit.
[ SCREAMS ]
- Shit!
- You got contact?
Who was it? What's going on?
- What do you got?
- It's Eldridge.
JAMES: Go, go. Man down. Man down.
- Shit. Shit.
- All right. No, no.
- Negative, negative. It's not him.
- Shit.
- He's gone.
- It's not him.
Where'd they go? Where'd they go?
Tankers and troops are that way.
- Let's go this way.
- Fuck!
Fuck.
[ WHISPERING ] Use your torch. On three.
Ready? One, two, three.
- Fuck.
- Shit.
Softly, softly, softly.
On three. One, two, three.
[ GUN FIRING ]
JAMES: Now, now, now. Go, go, go.
Eldridge, you okay?
- Fuck, dude, I'm hit.
- Shit, he's hit, man.
They hit him in the fucking leg.
Shit. Come on, come on, come on.
- Am I dead? Am I dead?
- No, you're fine, man. You're fine.
- You're fine, man.
- That's right. Just breathe.
Hang on, buddy.
- Okay, I got it, got it, got it.
- You got it?
I'm gonna put some pressure now, come on.
You're all right.
[ SCREAMING ]
You're all right. Look at me, look at me.
You're all right, okay? You're all right.
All right, buddy. You ready to get up?
On three, ready? One, two, three.
Hey, what's up, man? Hey, man.
What's up, man?
Wanna buy some DVDs?
Wanna play some soccer?
Wait. What's up? Come on, man.
Wanna play some...
Hey, wait a minute!
Fuck.
[ SHOUTING ]
- Hey.
- JAMES: How you doing, buddy?
Doc says you're going to be okay.
My fucking femur is shattered
in nine places.
He said I'll be walking in six months,
if I'm fucking lucky.
- Six months ain't bad, huh?
- It's not bad? Fucking sucks, man.
[ SCREAMING ]
Take it easy, buddy.
You see that? You fucking see that?
That's what happens when you fucking
shoot someone, you motherfucker.
Sorry. Sorry, Owen.
Fuck you, Will. Really. Fuck you.
Thanks for saving my life,
but we didn't have to go out
looking for trouble to
get your fucking adrenaline fix, you fuck.
Hey, take care of yourself, Owen.
Come home safe, man.
- See you on the other side, man.
- All right.
Let's get out of this fucking desert!
SOLDIER: Don't move.
If you keep walking, we will shoot you.
Move him back.
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "If you move, they'll shoot you."
Keep that translator back.
- But the bomb was forced on him.
- Get back!
Don't move! Stay still!
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Don't move"
If you keep walking, we will shoot you.
If you keep walking, we will shoot.
Get that translator back, now.
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Stay still"
- TRANSLATOR: He's not a bad man.
- Clear.
Give him room. Give him room.
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Please, save me from that bomb"
"I know nothing about it"! "Please, save me, quickly"
Hey, what do you got?
He came walking up to our checkpoint,
said he had a bomb strapped to him.
But he's sorry. He doesn't want it to go off.
Then he starts begging us
to take it off of him.
- Right.
- Help this man. He's not a bad man.
SANBORN: He's not a bad man?
He got a bomb strapped to him.
This is a joke. He's trying to pull us closer.
Yeah, I got it. I got it. All right.
Look, tell him to open his shirt slowly
and see what's inside.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Open your shirt, so that he can see what's underneath"
Slowly. Slowly.
Slowly!
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Ok. no problem...but please save me quickly".."I swear it will explode"
Jesus.
All right, Sergeant, I need
a 75-meter perimeter. Get these guys back.
- Get them back.
- Give me 75 meters. Get back!
You tell him to get on his knees
and touch the sky, okay?
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Go on your knees and raise your hands up"
Slowly!
Get down!
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Quickly, please"
Okay. I need your radio.
Can't we just shoot him?
- TRANSLATOR: No, no, no.
- No.
He's a family man. He's not a bad man.
He's just asking for help, only help.
- Yeah, all right. Look. You get back.
- Only help!
- Like everybody else.
- He's asking for help!
You don't want to die, get back!
I got it.
[ MAN SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I don't want to die..Just save me"
- Listen. I know we've had our differences.
- Yeah.
Eldridge... Look, it happened, all right?
It's water under the bridge.
James, this is suicide, man.
That's why they call it
a suicide bomb, right?
[ SHOUTING IN ARABIC ]: "Guys, the bomb has been there for an hour...it will explode"
Let's do this.
TRANSLATOR: He says
the bomb may have a timer,
please hurry.
- We're good.
- You all right now?
Yeah.
- Go get them.
- Let's do it.
- See you.
- Watch for snipers.
Yeah.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I have a family and kids".."Please save me"!
JAMES: Get your hands up.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I have a family and kids".."I don't want to die this way"!
TRANSLATOR: He says he has a family.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I don't want to die this way"!
TRANSLATOR: Please help.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I have a family and kids"
Now, listen.
- TRANSLATOR: Please.
- Look.
It'd be a lot easier for me to disarm this
if I just shoot you. Do you understand?
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I have a family".."I don't want to die this way"..."Please take this off me"
All right. What's he saying?
He says, "I don't wish to die. I have a family.
"Please take this off me."
All right.
Tell him to put his hands behind his head
or I'll be very happy to shoot him.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Friends..it's going to explode"..."Look, it's going to explode"
[ TRANSLATOR SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Put your hands on your head"
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Put your hands up"!
Look, that's not what I said.
Tell him to put his hands behind his head
or I will shoot him.
[ TRANSLATOR SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Put your hands behind your head"
Listen.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Haste...put your hands on top of your head...he is going to shoot you"!
Listen, listen.
Yes? Yes?
Yes? You understand?
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Yes..yes"
Okay.
What do you got here?
TRANSLATOR: He has four children.
Shit.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Save me...hurry up, please"
All right, Sanborn, we got a timer,
and we got a lot of wires, man.
I'm going to need a little help on this.
Roger that. Tell me what you need.
Bolt cutters. But you gotta get down here
in two minutes,
- or we're all fucked.
- Roger that. I'll be there in 30 seconds.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Hurry up, please...save me..I have a family"
TRANSLATOR: He says,
"Please, I have a family."
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "Hurry up, please...save me..I have a family"
I know. I know. Just...
It's okay, you're all right. You're all right.
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: [ performing prayers before death ] "I swear that God is one, and that Prophet Muhammed is the Messenger of God"
TRANSLATOR: Says, "Please don't leave me."
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "O, God...O, God"
- You weren't fucking kidding.
- Nope.
What's this made out of?
[ MAN SOBBING ]
Shit.
SANBORN: Oh, man.
That's case-hardened steel.
[ GRUNTING ]
Shit.
- What's our time?
- We got two minutes.
- Shit.
- We're gonna need a torch to get this off.
Well, we don't have one of those
in the fucking truck, man.
- He's dead, man.
- Hold on. Let me think.
Just let me think. Let's handle this.
We're gonna...
It's okay. We got this. We got this.
Just... Shh! Okay?
I'm gonna look at the back.
It's just... We don't got enough time,
Sanborn. We don't have time.
I just gotta... I gotta get these bolts off.
No. We got a minute and a half, man.
We gotta get out of here.
- I'll handle this. Just go.
- Look, Will, come on, man.
Look, I'm right behind you. Just go.
Fuck him! Come on. Let's go.
- Sanborn, I got the suit. Just go.
- James.
Sanborn, you have 45 seconds.
You have 45 seconds, Sanborn, leave!
- He's a fucking dead man, Will!
- Go!
- Everybody get back!
- Go, go, go!
[ SCREAMING ]
We got one.
Go! Get back! Get back!
Shit, I can't!
There's too many locks.
There's too many. I can't do it.
I can't get it off. I'm sorry. Okay?
You understand? I'm sorry.
You hear me? I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
Get down now!
I can't help him.
Everybody stay down! Stay down!
[ SPEAKING ARABIC ]: "I swear that God is one..."
James! Everybody up and out. James!
[ GRUNTS ]
You all right?
No, man. I fucking hate this place.
Here, man. Have a hit.
I'm not ready to die, James.
Well, you're not going to die out here, bro.
Another two inches.
Shrapnel zings by, slices my throat.
I bleed out like a pig in the sand.
Nobody will give a shit.
I mean, my parents will care,
but they don't count, man. Who else?
I don't even have a son.
Well, you're going to have
plenty of time for that, amigo.
- No, man.
- You know.
I'm done.
I want a son.
I want a little boy, Will.
I mean, how do you do it, you know?
Take the risk.
I don't know. I just...
I guess I don't think about it.
Every time we go out, it's life or death.
You roll the dice.
You recognize that, don't you?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
But I don't know why, you know.
[ STUTTERING ]
I don't know, J.T.
Do you know why I am the way I am?
No, I don't.
Pizza. Pizza.
[ BABY SQUEALING ]
- Wow. You did some shopping.
- Yeah.
I got some soda. We done?
You want to go get us some cereal
and I'll meet you at the checkout?
Okay. Cereal.
Where...
Some guy drove his truck
to the middle of an Iraqi market,
starts passing out free candies.
All the kids come running up,
the families and stuff.
He detonates.
They're saying 59 are dead.
You know they need more bomb techs.
You want to chop those up for me?
Boing! Boing!
[ BABY LAUGHING ]
[ MUSIC BOX CHIMING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
[ BABY MURMURING ]
Yeah.
You love playing with that.
You love playing
with all your stuffed animals.
You love your mommy, your daddy,
your nature pajamas.
You love everything, don't you?
Yeah.
[ BABY MURMURING ]
But you know what, buddy?
As you get older,
some of the things that you love might
not seem so special anymore, you know.
Like your jack-in-the-box.
Maybe you realize
it's just a piece of tin and a stuffed animal.
As you get older,
there are fewer things you really love.
And by the time you get to my age,
maybe it's only one or two things.
With me, I think it's one.
- Welcome to Delta Company.
- Sergeant.
Subtitles by ARAVIND B
[by_agentsmith@yahoo.com]