I think it might be useful to clarify
a few things right off the bat.
By simple definition,
we are in the business of winning wars.
What else do you need an army for?
Take the Cold War,
we won without firing a single shot.
Why? Number one,
we just flat out out-spent them.
The Russians couldn't shovel money
into the fire as fast as we could.
Number two, and this is where
my command comes in,
technology.
Nobody shapes nature the way we do.
We take atoms and molecules
and make them into everything
from combat boots to bombs.
Bombs the other side will never see
until they're ploughing down their
chimney like Santa Claus from hell!
General?
What?
This is not the first time
you've been here.
We've been down this road before,
that is correct.
Several times, in fact.
I haven't been keeping count.
Let me refresh your memory.
You have before you a document.
I do.
The sensor fused anti-tank missile.
I'll be the first to admit that this programme
had its share of difficulties.
We did experience a glitch or two
with the thing, that much is certain.
But even a heat-seeking missile
can miss a target.
General, I see here
that you taped electric hotplates
to the surface of the vehicle to help
your heat-seeking missile find its target
and that the temperature
of the vehicle was so high
that it could have fried an egg at 20 feet!
Commence fire!
There was a verifiable deviation
of the standard test data accumulation.
There were other deviations,
were there not?
What about the Paveway bomb?
I'm not going to tell you
the Paveway never missed.
It missed by a mean distance
of five miles and nearly 50% of the time.
You know...
in baseball, a guy who hits.400
is considered pretty damn great.
In baseball the losing team
isn't killed by their opponents.
Be that as it may,
the Paveway is one hell of a bomb.
Laser-guided, state-of-the-art.
And it proved what?
That we have an effective weapon
as long as the enemy allows us
to build a two-storey crane
directly above their tanks?
We have had some spectacular successes.
- Such as?
- That's classified information.
General...
Let's move on to the next item.
The Bradley fighting vehicle.
What would you say the batting average is
for the Bradley, General?
It takes people with sophisticated knowledge
and expertise
to conduct these tests
and to interpret the results.
If the US Army acted on the advice
of every Tom, Dick and Harry
who had an opinion,
we'd wind up with a bunch of B-52s
powered by outboard motors.
- I fail to see your point.
- My point is...
that a lot of things have to come together
to create a new weapon,
and it takes teamwork.
Good, old-fashioned teamwork.
Colonel James Burton -
was he part of your team, General?
More or less.
Post, sir?
Sergeant.
Can you tell me how to get to 4E-624?
Forward into the escalator,
your left, two flights up to four,
your left, E-ring, your right,
proceed past corridor nine, face left.
Thank you.
It's no secret that
Colonel Burton had a rocky tenure,
that we didn't see eye-to-eye.
But it didn't start out that way.
No, no, no, no, no!
I spoke to General Hall.
General Hall spoke to General Jones...
...General Jones spoke to Admiral Watts.
Well, then, write it down!
That takes care of Spina in Rhode Island,
and Mays from Nebraska. Any Democrats?
No, forget him.
Because he's a scum-sucking Judas
who'd sell his mother for a handful of votes.
How about the Senate?
That son of a bitch.
After we papered his state with contracts.
All right, let's make the fuselage in Michigan
and the landing gear in Mississippi.
By all means, let's keep Congressman Groves
and his bloodsucking buddies happy.
- Welcome, Colonel.
- Thank you, General.
- You and I ought to get to know one another.
- I welcome the opportunity, sir.
- Fact is, I'd like to help you.
- Thank you, sir.
Your new job, under certain circumstances,
can turn into a real shit-burnin' detail.
You're gonna need friends.
I'd like you to count me as one.
I appreciate that, sir.
Air Force Academy,
Strategic Air Command,
MBA from Auburn.
Your commanding officer,
General De Grasso and I, are old friends.
He says for you the sky is the limit.
But then you draw the short straw.
I was assigned, sir.
Hell, it's a bum deal, whoever made it.
Every other year, somebody decides
we're spending too much money.
A bunch of pencil-necks get together
and come up with a plan.
This year, it's the joint
live-fire test programme.
Staffed from all the services.
So now we got the Army, Navy,
Air Force and Marines,
doing a circle-jerk over weapons testing,
and you get to hold the big dick.
I mean, who thinks up this nonsense?
Congress, sir?
And so it should, that's its job.
You'll never hear me criticise the Hill.
You'd think Congress has enough
of their own shit without wanting ours.
Well, I'm not anticipating any problems, sir.
Neither am I.
A man as clever as you
knows how to walk a minefield.
Howard Matheson.
Came here two rotations ago.
That marlin isn't all he caught.
I got him into SenCom and now
he's head of their missile testing.
- Blake Gelmore, you know Blake?
- No, sir.
Wasn't even a full-bird colonel
when he left for the private sector.
That was four years ago.
A few contracts later and look at him...
He could buy and sell both of us
a thousand times over.
- Lucky man.
- Smart man.
First-rate soldier, just like you. Knew
how to make the best of a difficult situation.
This new job of yours is tough.
It's going to require teamwork.
These are a couple of your projects
undergoing testing.
The UH-60 helicopter,
the AV-8B jump-jet
and the Bradley fighting vehicle.
All outstanding programmes,
all organised and ready to go.
I did a little homework for you.
I appreciate that, General.
You could return the favour by giving
the Bradley a little extra attention.
Attention?
We need it in the field.
The sooner the better.
Put it on top of all the things
in your inbox
so it'll get in your outbox
as soon as possible.
As a personal favour to me.
- Best of luck, Colonel.
- Thank you, sir.
- Colonel.
- Sir?
Next time you're told
to report to this office, be on time.
Yes, sir.
Sir.
Colonel James Burton,
I'm here to see the Bradley test.
- Straight ahead, sir.
- Thank you.
- There he is.
- That's the guy?
That's him, supposed to be real smart.
Squadron Officer School,
- Air Command and Staff College.
- First tour with the Pentagon?
He was at the Air Force lab
when Congress called.
He's a soldier, not just a manager.
- What do you mean?
- He's put in his fair share of flying time.
Looks like a fucking choirboy.
Maybe, but nothing goes into production
until he signs off.
Target is now in position...
Colonel Burton, JD Bach.
Welcome to the team. Ha-ha-ha!
- Colonel Bach.
- Good to see you.
This is Major Sayers, our chief tester.
Army Weapons Research Lab.
So how'd an Air Force guy end up
overseeing tests run by the Army?
- It could have been worse.
- How's that?
Congress could have appointed
someone from the Navy.
The range is now hot.
Commencing armour penetration tests
on the Bradley fighting vehicle.
Attention on the firing line.
Are you ready on the right?
Ready on the left?
Firing line is ready.
Firing detail, commence firing.
Cease fire. Cease fire.
- Ha-ha! Damn impressive armour.
- Congratulations.
All right, drinks are on me, gentlemen.
Joining us, Colonel Burton?
Congratulations, thanks for your help.
We couldn't have done it without you. Thanks.
- Say, Colonel, are you gonna join us?
- Well...
Shouldn't we take a closer look?
No, actually, safety precautions.
See, the fire team goes out first,
no one else is allowed near the vehicle
for another hour.
- Why is that?
- Any test involving a live round,
there's a freak chance
that something might blow.
We don't wanna lose you
first day on the job, Colonel.
- How about that drink?
- Sounds good, Major.
There'll be a phone call for you in your office
at 1100 hours. It's important you be there.
- Good morning.
- Welcome, sir.
- Morning.
- Morning, Sergeant.
- Good morning, sir.
- I unpacked a few of your things.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
- Family, sir?
- What's that?
- Family.
- Oh, that's my uncle.
- He was a flier in World War II.
- Hm.
Huh!
- What's that?
- The plane I learned to fly in, a T-28.
I used to take her up, slide the canopy back,
and fly for hours.
Just me and the sky.
Personally, I like the sky where it is -
with me on the ground looking up at it.
So, where you from, sir?
Just outside of Chicago.
Hm. And where would that be?
Normal.
Normal, Illinois, is that on the map?
Yes, Sergeant, it is.
Is it normal in Normal?
I think the word is uneventful.
You getting paid by the hour, Colonel?
No, I got an appointment.
I'II, um... take this, Sergeant, thank you.
Fine.
Mm-hm.
Colonel Burton.
Hello?
The test on the Bradley,
I hear you wanted a closer look.
How did you hear that?
When it comes to the Bradley,
follow your instincts, Colonel.
- Who is this?
- I can't tell you that right now.
Well, whoever you are, I don't take
unsolicited advice from people I don't know.
Just make sure you read
the fine print, Colonel.
Sir, Colonel Burton. Sir.
You're up early, sir.
I'm on my way to the office, Sergeant.
Thought I'd check out the Bradley.
Sir, isn't your office 40 miles that way, sir?
Yes, Sergeant, yes, it is.
Has anything been altered
on this vehicle since the test?
No, sir.
Are you looking for something, sir?
Just reading the fine print, Sergeant.
Just reading the fine print.
Stinger missiles, 50 cal tracers.
7.62 tracers.
25mm rounds.
- What's this?
- That was used on the Bradley, sir.
This writing, it's Romanian, isn't it?
Yes, sir, it is.
Sir, Colonel Bach and Major Sayers
won't be here until noon.
That's when our first test is scheduled, sir.
This isn't exactly an all-out test, Sergeant.
More like a little pop quiz.
I'm not sure regulations allow us to borrow
the door from the ammunition shed
for a pop quiz, sir.
Sir, regulations state that the ammunition shed
should never be left open, sir.
Duly noted, Sergeant.
Regulations also apply
to removing the door, Colonel.
Also duly noted.
Fire when ready.
Backblast area clear! On the way, sir.
Fire.
Come on straight... Hold!
You wrecked a door?
Colonel, the ammunition
used on the test on the Bradley
is the same as we used on this door.
Romanian - the most ineffective
ammunition in the world.
- No wonder the Bradley passed.
- This is serious.
- It is!
- Yes, you destroyed a door.
It was tested on
an armoured personnel carrier,
a vehicle to carry soldiers into combat.
This door is property of
the United States government.
The shell barely penetrated the door.
OK, but it's all bent.
How are you gonna put it back?
I'm not really worried about that!
- This door protects our ammunition.
- The ammunition doesn't work!
But we need the ammunition for our tests.
Look - I'll buy the Army
a new goddamn door.
You can't afford a door like that.
Did you see what it stood up to?
Exactly! Some spitball from Romania!
It was my understanding that only Soviet arms
would be used in these tests.
Well, yes, and Romania
is one of the Soviet blocs...
- Isn't it?
- Colonel Burton,
we've been testing
the Bradley for some time.
You may not be aware
of some steps we've taken.
The Romanian rocket is only 73mm.
That's less than the 85mm Russian.
A smaller diameter means
a smaller explosion and less shrapnel.
We're conducting tests
using ammunition of varying diameters
to determine the exact threshold
of the Bradley's tolerance.
So far it's held up against everything
we've thrown at it, sir - Soviet, Romanian.
Latvian, Lithuanian...
Like a rock.
My apologies.
You're new to the project.
There's a lot to catch up on.
You're right. So if you'll get me
the test reports, I can catch right up.
- How's that, Colonel?
- Send me the data,
I'll do my homework,
and we can push through.
We've got five years of test reports, sir.
- We have a schedule.
- Let's keep to it,
get the Bradley into production, ASAP,
what do you say?
Thank you, gentlemen.
This could blow the whole deal.
You've got to stop this
like you did with the last guy.
- Don't worry about it.
- Sir, he wants to see the reports.
- Just give him the reports.
- Are you out of your mind?
Now listen to me. Listen very carefully.
Give him everything he wants.
Every single piece of paper.
Everything.
- Sergeant?
- Here, sir.
What the heck is all this?
Everything you ever wanted to know about
the Bradley and weren't afraid to ask.
Every memo on every last nut and bolt.
I wonder which national forest
died for this project.
- You read any of this stuff?
- I hoped you'd have the Cliff Notes.
- I hardly know where to start.
- Maybe that's the whole idea.
I don't get it.
What?
- That.
- It's the Bradley.
Well, if that's the Bradley, then what's this?
- What's the date?
- 1968.
The question is, how did they get to that...
from this?
Gentlemen, our mission
was to design and implement
an infantry transport vehicle
that would be a worthy replacement
for the M-113 armoured personnel carrier.
We have met that objective and then some.
The Bradley armoured personnel carrier
will bring troops to a combat zone
swiftly, efficiently, and safely.
It will hold 11 men plus a driver,
and features a 20mm cannon,
which will provide
ample firepower and flexibility.
Lightly armoured, speedy
and solidly engineered,
our troops will arrive at the battlefield
in the finest American technology.
And at a million and a half per,
a real bargain.
Nice work, Colonel!
Outstanding!
Damn impressive!
So it was a big taxicab - drive guys
to the battlefield and go back home.
Mm-hm.
But how did it
end up with a turret on top?
Hm. Hm-hm-hm.
- This is all well and good...
- Something wrong, General?
There won't be anything left in the budget
for my scout.
I doubt it, Bob.
You don't need scouts -
you have radar, air-recon, satellites.
You always need a scout -
why couldn't this thing serve as a scout?
But it's a troop carrier, General.
This is a speedy vehicle. Why can't it be both?
For one thing, it's too big.
And you can't really see out much from inside.
- Sounds like a design flaw to me.
- Design flaw? No...
We'll just stick a turret on top
with lots of opticals.
But then, sir, it'll be even bigger.
What's your problem, Smith?
Not elegant enough for you?
The thing is, it's hard to do a "sneak
and peek" when you're over ten feet tall.
- He's got a point, Bob.
- We need a scout.
This is fast enough and it's funded.
- Actually, we're a hair over budget.
- Turn the Bradley into a scout
and we're gonna be selling them off
to some el presidente in no time!
Anything for surveillance
ends up south of the border.
That anti-aircraft gun,
who backed you up on that?
- You did, Bob.
- Who testified to Appropriations?
- I'm talking to Appropriations next week.
Do I sell you on my scout or do I not?
You did, Bob.
How about portholes along the side?
So the fellas can stick out their guns
and shoot people!
Good. And you know what, Colonel?
We already have the turret.
We oughta get the biggest bang we can.
I'm sorry - bang, sir?
You can't hurt anybody
with that pansy-ass gun!
Add on some firepower!
- Where do I fit the extra ammo?
- I don't know. Shift things around.
4400 rounds of machine gun ammo,
and you wanna add 25mm shells?
- The General wants his ammo.
- He can't have it unless he carries it.
- Can you squeeze it in?
- No.
Just squeeze it in!
We're not trying on Levi's here, Colonel.
Are you telling me that in a vehicle this size,
you can't fit a few rounds of ammunition?
Not in its current configuration, no, sir.
So, the configuration is wrong.
There must be something you can dump.
- Dump, sir?
- Something you don't need.
General, the interior is very spare.
Besides the ammunition and the men...
Leave one of the fellas behind.
Put the ammo where the men go.
Sir...
it is a troop carrier.
So, make a couple of extra trips,
what's the difference?
They want a transport
that doesn't carry men,
and a scout that's got a cannon
as big as a tank's.
- And portholes.
- Great, portholes!
To shoot at whatever
they can't hit with their cannon.
You don't have to buy it, just draw it.
- That's one hell of a cannon.
- That's the problem.
Why?
You go out on a battlefield
with this pecker sticking out of your turret,
and the enemy is gonna
unload on you with all they got.
But it's a troop carrier, not a tank.
You want me to put a sign on it -
"I am a troop carrier, not a tank,
please don't shoot"?
This was going to be so beautiful.
- Good work, Smith.
- Looks perfect.
- Thank you, sir.
- The thing is...
Yes, General?
Looks a little like a tank with that cannon.
Probably gonna draw more fire.
Actually, sir, that has come to our attention.
We know it's not a tank,
but will the other side?
I guess we could always thicken the armour.
Colonel Smith, could you explain
why you put those portholes there?
Yes, sir, as per your request,
so the men can shoot out at the enemy.
- You're joking, aren't you?
- Portholes? Are we in the navy?
Say... you think you could
make this thing amphibious?
Get the troops across a river?
No.
No, sir. No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Amphibious?
The Bradley's supposed to swim?
In theory, at least.
Amphibious troop carrier slash scout...
Slash tank.
A couple more months,
I bet this thing can fly.
What's this in the margin?
"Please help me,
"I am losing my mind,
"RLS."
Lieutenant Colonel Robert Laurel Smith,
head of oversight and development.
Aluminium.
- This thing's got an aluminium skin.
- Huh?
Anything fired at it will go through it
like a hot knife through butter.
We're using steel rather than aluminium.
Of course, steel is
much heavier than aluminium,
so it won't go as fast.
We can't lose speed -
it won't work as a scout.
It won't keep pace with tanks, either.
Armour's a reactive measure.
Let's think proactive.
Equip it with anti-tank missiles,
then it can blast those enemy tanks
before they fire.
What do you think, Colonel?
Fine.
- Anti-tank missiles?
- I don't know.
The men will have to wear
the missiles as hats!
I don't know, Jones.
That's why you get paid big bucks.
- Colonel, we're not talking about...
- A pair of Levi's. I know!
God damn it!
We are talking about 11 years
with nothing to show for it!
Except an ulcer the size
of the district of Columbia
and a career on permanent hold!
You see this?
I've been... I've been a bird colonel so long,
I swear I'm growing feathers!
If you have to design hats to haul
those goddamn missiles, then just do it.
Excuse me, sir...
Uh... ladies and gentlemen,
if I can have your attention, please.
If you'd all just take your seats.
Thank you.
We are pleased to present a scale model
of the new Bradley fighting vehicle.
Featuring scout, troop transport,
and anti-tank capabilities,
it carries six men.
How many was it supposed to carry?
- 11.
- The Bradley is outfitted
with sophisticated surveillance equipment.
It is also equipped with a rapid-fire cannon,
and an anti-tank rocket launcher.
Which means it's loaded with...
1500 shells and ten TOW anti-tank missiles.
So in summation, gentlemen,
what you have before you is...
A troop transport that can't carry troops,
a reconnaissance vehicle that's
too conspicuous to do reconnaissance...
And a quasi-tank that has
less armour than a snow-blower
but has enough ammo to take out half of DC.
- Fantastic.
- Congratulations, General Smith.
- General?
- Helluva job.
General?
Let's build it.
They're building it?
This is what we're building?
Please be seated.
This will be brief,
I'm needed at the Oval Office.
I want to show you
this morning's New York Times.
If you'd be so kind to turn
to the editorial page.
It essentially says that every weapon
we produce is overpriced junk.
Now, that's not news.
Critics have said it for years.
What was news to me
touched on our supposedly spectacular
"Sergeant York" anti-aircraft gun.
It says there when the Sergeant York
proved incapable of hitting airplanes,
we test-fired it at hovering helicopters.
When it failed to hit hovering helicopters,
we fired at stationary targets
and it missed those.
Now is this possible, General Keane?
There was a problem with the proximity fusing.
According to this, one missile locked
on to a ventilation fan in the latrine!
And destroyed the latrine.
Were we test-firing at latrines that day?
My first sergeant was in that latrine
and he's around to swear otherwise.
Why am I learning about this
in the newspaper?
It makes me look foolish,
and I am not a foolish man.
General Cushing, any problems
with the Maverick missile tests?
No, sir.
Admiral Morehouse, any problems?
- None whatsoever, sir.
- General Partridge...
- Sir!
- Problems with the Bradley?
No, sir, absolutely not.
Production is imminent.
Mr Secretary, I believe
the press is on a wild-goose chase,
looking for problems where none exist.
Let's hope you're right, General.
Because we do have problems.
Terrorists in Lebanon,
and Colonel Qadhafi in Libya,
and Sandinistas in Nicaragua,
and let's not forget our ongoing problems
with the Soviet Union.
Frankly, I don't appreciate calls
from reporters and congressmen
asking me why nothing
we are working on works,
and I can't answer them because
the men developing these systems
tell me everything is just peachy!
So, if you don't have problems, good.
If you do, get rid of them.
I want these weapons built.
If not by you, I'll find men who can.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Yes, I do.
Close the damn door, come on.
About these tests you've been
thinking about conducting on the Bradley.
I understand your concern,
but if you were an armoured warfare expert
instead of a flier,
you'd understand
the Bradley is a good vehicle.
4,000 Americans will be employed building it,
the Army wants it.
- Read the files...
- I've read the files, sir.
200 pages on the rear door,
250 pages on the paint job,
computer simulations of combat -
not a single test that indicates what
might happen if the Bradley takes a hit.
Which is why I've ordered
a full-up live fire test.
I want to equip a Bradley with
all the ammunition it would take into battle,
fill all the fuel tanks, and hit it
with a Soviet anti-tank weapon,
- to see how it'll hold up.
- Cancel it.
Sir?
I think we're having
a communication meltdown.
Whatever problems there are, we'll fix them -
in the field, after they're deployed.
- General...
- That's the way we're gonna do this.
Nobody takes your job
more seriously than I do,
but I also have a job -
to deploy that Bradley.
I want that rocket launcher
pointed at the Soviets.
Here.
Jesus.
Dismissed.
- Afternoon. Afternoon.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- Fanning!
- Yes, sir?
- What happened to you?
- Don't ask. What's this?
It was on your desk
when I got back from lunch.
Some ammunition for your Bradley battle.
Hm!
It's a British Army test report.
Top secret too.
Until it landed here.
General Smith, Jim Burton.
How did you find me?
You have very distinctive handwriting.
I've been reading memos on the Bradley
going back to 1968,
with your handwritten notes in the margin,
or... initialled by you.
- This handwriting?
- We should not be seen talking.
Look, you contacted me, General.
No. You received an anonymous leak
about which I know nothing.
The British found out that aluminium
gives off a toxic gas when hit by a shell.
Bad news for men
in aluminium armoured vehicles.
Couldn't we... couldn't we sit down
somewhere and actually talk?
If the Pentagon had their choice
of busting us or nailing a Soviet spy,
they would choose us in a heartbeat.
Who exactly is "us", General?
Some people who work in the Pentagon
are fed up watching billions of dollars
thrown away on defective weapons
upon which our troops stake their lives.
People like you, Colonel.
We are the enemy.
- To whom?
- To majors who want to be colonels,
colonels who want to be generals,
you bet we are the enemy.
To move up, you have to get things done.
You don't want to be the one
who drops the ball,
cos if you drop the ball,
no promotion, no star,
no cushy job with a contractor
when you retire.
Which is why, Colonel, everyone
attached to the Bradley will stop your tests.
General, I appreciate your interests
if not your methods.
Whatever disagreements
I may be having over the Bradley
will be resolved above board.
Now, if you have something to say,
I'm sure the Washington Post
would love to talk to you.
Me? The press? Are you crazy?
The Army is my life.
Like you, I work inside the system, and
you don't have a prayer of running your tests,
not unless you're willing
to sacrifice your career.
And if you think you're safe because
Congress gave you your job, think again.
Good day, Colonel. And good luck.
So why did you send me that report?
Sir.
- Nice to see you, General.
- Good to see you.
- Evening, sir.
So she whispered to me, "Why do you think
the General always stands at attention?"
- Sir, Major Sayers is in the library.
- Tell Major Sayers I'm busy.
He said the little prick
ordered tests on the Bradley.
What? I'll have his ass in a sling so fast.
Whose ass, sir? Major Sayers
or the little prick?
General, he knows about
the study the Brits did.
- What study?
- On aluminium.
Aluminium's used on the Bradley, sir.
When hit by a shell, it burns
and gives off a toxic gas.
God damn it.
We fought a revolution
so we could ignore the fucking British!
So why mess things up now?
- I thought you talked to him.
- I did.
- The man must be a fool.
- Can't you stop him, sir?
No, I'm not his commanding officer.
Some draft-dodging junior congressman
wanted more objectivity in the testing process.
Goddamn checks and balances.
General, with all due respect,
this isn't just a check, sir,
it's a full fucking body block!
If we don't get the Bradley out there now,
it'll be stuck in development forever.
Start production now.
Throw Burton a bone or two.
Let him run a couple of tests.
Yes, sir. General, actually,
he'd like to blow it up.
I don't give a fuck what Burton wants.
Let him do some piddly-shit stuff,
see if he can parallel park the fucker!
Just get it into production.
Am I to understand
that you were not in favour
of the tests Colonel Burton proposed?
Absolutely not.
Absolutely not, yes,
or absolutely not, no?
Absolutely not absolutely.
Are you questioning
his motives or his methods?
I have no reason to question
Colonel Burton's motives.
I can only speak to his methods.
Which, by anyone's definition
were somewhat peculiar.
There were other ways to find out
if clothing would catch fire
inside the Bradley when it took a hit.
Let's take the... the mannequin thing.
- Colonel.
- Yes?
- Phone call, sir. They said it's important.
- Very good.
- Dalton.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll meet you back at the firing area.
- Strip the dummies.
- Sir?
Strip the dummies, Sergeant, now.
Thank you. Let's go.
Fire when ready.
Backblast area clear!
- Out of the way, sir.
- Fire.
Hold it there. Let me see those.
Uh-huh. That looks good,
uniforms look good. Great, there you go.
Wait a minute, what's that?
That's part of our test, Colonel.
Wait a minute.
No one in my command
gave the order to strip the dummies
and put their clothes
inside a fireproof container
inside the vehicle while
Colonel Burton wasn't around.
You're a pair of clowns!
The insults that were traded that day
had no business
showing up in the test reports.
They were deleted from the final report.
All except Colonel Bach's unfortunate
reference to Colonel Burton's mother.
Temperatures were running high.
Apparently inside the Bradley as well.
There's a degree of uncertainty
involved in every test.
That's the point of doing tests -
to find out what happens.
If we knew what the results would be,
we wouldn't need to do the test.
And just because the tests
didn't always come out
the way Colonel Burton expected...
is no reason to assume that
anything devious was going on.
I ask you, General,
filling the fuel tanks with water
for a test designed
to check the combustibility
of those tanks - that wasn't devious?
If the tanks had been filled with fuel
there's a good chance
the vehicle would have exploded.
Isn't that the point?
If the vehicle had exploded,
we couldn't run additional tests.
I can't order up an unlimited number
of Bradleys just to blow them up!
Unless you're telling me
to spend more money.
General, I believe that efforts
were made to make the Bradley amphibious?
Yes, although how that's relevant
I fail to comprehend.
How many Bradleys
were lost during that experiment?
Lost?
The report says
four of the Bradleys sank during testing.
That is a matter of opinion.
It's not opinion, General.
Four of them sank.
Technically, yes.
General,
can we get back to the fuel tanks?
Come on. Good.
Sergeant, have the tanks
always been filled with water?
No, sir.
Only when the vehicle is being tested, sir.
What else don't I know?
Sergeant, I'm asking you a question.
What else don't I know about these tests?
The ammunition stored in the Bradley, sir.
What about it?
Sand.
That's affirmative, sir.
Tell me...
did the term "court-martial"
ever enter anyone's mind here?
- No, sir.
- Really?
That's truly amazing, Sergeant.
Here we are watching
water drip out of the gas tanks
and sand spill out of the ammunition
after a test that was done to figure out
whether or not the damn thing is safe!
And no one here even thinks
of the term "court-martial"?
Now why, if you don't mind my asking, is that?
We were under orders, sir.
Is acting on those orders
conscionable, Sergeant?
It doesn't matter what I think or do, sir,
because you desk warriors from Washington
will find a million different ways
to make the tests turn out
whatever way you want, sir.
I'm not here to manipulate test results.
- I'm here to learn the truth.
- You want the truth, sir?
We get a new white knight
every other year, sir.
Some guy just like you,
and you all start off the same.
Big speeches that turn to shit after six months
when your next promotion comes due.
And then it's business as usual.
Where did you pick up
this lousy attitude, Sergeant?
Right here, sir,
watching guys like you.
Well, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry to hear that.
Cos unlike you, I take my job seriously.
Really?
Well, maybe... maybe
you can explain to me, Colonel,
why the Bradley has been ordered into
production before you have done your job.
What is this?
100 Bradleys have been ordered?
I'm not gonna have it on my record
that the Bradley fell behind schedule
because of some goddamn tests.
Those goddamn tests could save lives.
The Bradley will save lives, Colonel,
by bringing men to the front line.
Do you know what would happen to those men
if the Bradley is hit and the aluminium burns?
I know all about the British study, Colonel.
And it is bullshit.
That thing could be a deathtrap.
- Says who?
- Says me.
Have you put people in there during the test?
- No, of...
- So you don't actually know anything.
And until you do,
all you're doing is wasting our time.
Are you suggesting Colonel Burton
had no reason to be concerned?
I am suggesting
that Colonel Burton and his tests
did not reveal anything
we didn't already know.
Except his own penchant for theatrics.
- Theatrics, General?
- Yes, theatrics.
Cheap theatrics at that.
Now the little prick has issued a memo
that stipulates that for the tests
he'd like to use sheep.
Jesus, we already started work
on the chassis assembly.
- Don't worry.
- If the sheep die
- we're gonna have to stop production.
- There are ways around it.
- Absolutely.
- Like what?
We could sic the animal rights people on him.
It is cruel and unusual treatment of sheep.
Rack of lamb.
Yeah, that would be me.
- Yes.
- Major Sayers just called, sir.
- When do they plan to run the tests?
- As soon as we send over the sheep.
"We"? I thought they were
in charge of the sheep.
They say it's being handled at our end.
The Surgeon General's office.
What does the Surgeon General
have to do with sheep?
- Excuse me.
- Colonel Burton.
- We were told you might show up.
- Who told you that?
Colonel Bach, he established this office
last week with the Surgeon General.
- You're trying to kill the Bradley.
- Who told you that?
I'm sorry, sir, all information
in this office is classified.
So, what is
"ruminant procurement" anyway?
That's what this office has been created to do.
- But what is it?
- Analysis and policy determination
for tendered research data
on the optimal test ruminant.
Such ruminants are to be...
You're talking about sheep.
You're in charge of buying sheep, correct?
We can't just go out and buy sheep, sir.
Why not?
We're doing a vaporifics test on sheep.
Vaporifics is all about what happens
when a warhead penetrates armour.
Lieutenant, I know what a vaporifics test is.
I'm the one who called for it.
Well, then you know we have to have
sheep specs before we can proceed.
Sheep specs, what is sheep specs?
Specifications!
Shorn or unshorn, rams, ewes or lambs?
Merinos or short hair?
Shorn merino ewes or unshorn merino lambs?
Bighorns or domestic?
Domestic shorn lambs or bighorn unshorn?
Just, how long will it take you
to get your sheep specs?
Not long at all, six, eight months, tops.
But then we'll require another eight months
to evaluate the data.
After which we can move
into prototype ruminant evaluation...
- How much?
- Well...
All right, bring it back.
Keep it coming. Keep it coming.
Keep it coming.
A little more. A little more.
Whoa!
Sir, Colonel Bach is on his way over here, sir.
I'm sure he is.
It sounded like a world-class shit-fit, sir.
I'm sure it is, Sergeant.
- Come on, move it.
- What are these sheep doing here?
- I bought them.
- You can't do that!
- Well, I did.
- There are no sheep specs, Colonel!
- I devised the specs, Major.
- What are they?
They're live and kicking,
and that's good enough for me.
Testing is a science, Colonel.
It needs controlled experiments.
- Just sticking sheep into a...
- All right, you don't want sheep?
Lennon, Chavez,
get the sheep out of there,
- and get in the Bradley. Dalton!
- Yes, sir?
Get in the Bradley.
- Sir?
- I need a vaporifics test, get in the Bradley.
- Everyone inside.
- Are you out of your fucking mind?
You think this is
some kind of joke, Colonel?
All right, we'll just use the sheep.
That's a terrific idea.
Use the sheep in the Bradley.
Go on, sheep.
Get in there... God damn it!
Backblast area, clear!
- On the way, sir.
- Fire!
Oh, God, Granger, don't breathe!
- What the hell happened?
- The damn fumes!
Stay back!
- How are you doing?
- I'm OK.
Jesus, just one tiny whiff...
Did you get a look inside?
Nothing could have survived those fumes.
Sergeant, where are the sheep?
Major Sayers said they had to be incinerated.
- What?
- They carted them away, sir.
Whoa! No! Whoa! Stop, stop, stop!
- Follow those sheep!
- Sir?
- Stop that truck, that's an order!
- Yes, sir.
Sergeant.
I need them, for autopsy.
To verify test results.
I see him, we got him, sir.
- Pay no attention to them!
- Sir?
Concentrate on the sheep.
Look out!
Move it!
Come on!
Damn it, what are you stopping us for?
- Stop the sheep!
- What's the hurry, sir?
Not one of the tests I've ordered
has been conducted according to plan.
And since my job...
Your job is to stop whining and serve
the United States as befits an officer!
My job is to oversee the joint live-fire
test programme and report to Congress.
In order to do that, I'm gonna have to insist
on a live-fire test of the Bradley
under combat conditions.
Listen to me, fly-boy,
you don't know shit about combat!
I know there are a lot of ways
to die in that vehicle, sir.
- Don't you preach to me!
- I want a realistic...
- The number one priority is...
- People first, vehicles second!!
Those are my priorities. The Army's
priorities seem to be the exact opposite.
You are way out of line here.
I won't sign off on the Bradley
without a live-fire test.
- Sir?
- Who is Burton's commanding officer?
General De Grasso, sir.
Get him for me now.
It's an economic move, Colonel,
you're being reassigned.
In the meantime, should I... continue
in my present assignment?
Your present assignment
has been eliminated, Colonel.
I didn't think my job could be eliminated.
- I was appointed by Congress.
- But you're paid by the Army.
If they can't afford you - and they can't -
you have no job.
Colonel, it's time to move on.
Let's not let this little blip on the screen
ground you permanently.
Would the Colonel ever consider
having a drink with an enlisted soldier?
Does the enlisted soldier
think the Colonel needs one?
- What are they gonna do, fire you?
- OK, just a little one.
You know what's really ironic?
General Omar Bradley was a brilliant tactician
and a great leader.
No ego, just did the job.
And he looked out for the morale
and the safety of his men.
And they go and put his name on this thing!
Talk about a kick in the ass.
The closest the brass ever get to a battlefield
is the first tee on a Saturday morning.
You know, Fanning...
I've been around long enough to know
that the Pentagon is not a charity,
it's cashflows and egos.
That's part of it, it's what helps drive it,
fine, but...
somehow...
somehow I always thought the men came first.
I always thought that the people on top knew
that it was about the soldier in the field.
You gave it your best shot.
- Did I?
- Yes, sir, you did.
Well, now it's somebody else's problem.
My problem is salvaging my career.
Which apparently is not beyond repair
if I'm a good little boy.
So, that's it.
That's it.
The man said, "war is hell".
He should've tried peacetime.
- You don't mind, do you?
- No, be my guest.
I don't believe in government waste.
- Burton.
- So they're moving you out?
Is there anything you don't hear about?
Well, how far are you willing to go
with this thing?
The question is...
how far are they going to send me?
You ought to take a trip to California
this weekend.
I'm not up for a vacation right now.
No one goes to Fresno
for a vacation, Colonel.
- Can I help you, sir?
- Colonel Burton.
I'm here to see the project manager.
- Colonel Burton?
- Yes.
Steve Johnson, project manager.
Hi, thank you.
All set, let's go!
What's going on here?
Who changed the specs?
The Israelis.
The Israelis? When?
When they placed their order.
- So these are for export?
- Yes.
- All of them?
- Yes, Colonel.
You're telling me we're manufacturing
two different versions of this vehicle?
The Israelis wouldn't take the Bradley
as designed, Colonel.
They wanted the fuel tanks on the outside,
reinforced armour,
a different ventilation system...
All right.
What about the specs for our Bradleys?
Exactly like the ones
you're testing, Colonel. No change.
- You think you were followed?
- Followed?
I drove for hours.
I don't even know where we are.
Maybe you'd prefer to meet
at the officers' club?
- When did the Israelis test it?
- They didn't have to,
they knew by looking at it
that it was a deathtrap.
So while we're sending our guys off to die,
the Pentagon brass is redesigning
the damn thing for somebody else!
They can't sell it overseas like it is.
Business as usual.
So maybe you'd like to keep
fighting the bastards?
I've lost my job, General.
They're moving me out.
So, they're moving you out,
you haven't been discharged.
Work from inside,
from wherever they send you.
And turn into you?
Passing anonymous notes
and meeting in parking lots?
You're great at sitting in the shadows.
Why don't you do something?
I can't.
- Help me!
- I have done everything that I can.
I've been fighting this for almost 20 years.
I'm not gonna go to the mat over this!
I... I've got too much to lose.
70,000 troops.
70,000 American boys
will ride into battle in the Bradley
if America fights another war.
We can't be a part of
sending them to their deaths.
One call.
- What?
- One call.
I'll make one call and that's it.
Sit down.
General Partridge, you've read
today's Washington Post?
- I have.
- And seen the story,
attributed to a highly placed Pentagon source?
Yes, and I am as distressed as you that
anyone in the Pentagon would stoop so low.
Leaks within the Pentagon
are how I get most of my information.
Are you suggesting that
the Pentagon is less than forthcoming?
Then perhaps you can explain
why I have to learn from the press
that the man in charge
of testing the Bradley has been fired?
- He wasn't fired, sir, he was reassigned.
- By whom?
By General De Grasso,
his commanding officer.
I'm as shocked as you are.
I guess there was some confusion
between the Army, the Air Force...
The sort of trouble you always get
with these cross-departmental
joint-testing programmes.
- Yes.
- Congressman Stratton is on the phone.
Sam, what can I do for you?
What article? Oh, that article.
No, completely untrue, inter-office SNAFU.
File it under creative journalism.
I'm looking into it now,
you'll be the first to know. Right. Right.
My best to Ellen.
General, I want a full update on the Bradley
- and I want it in writing.
- Right away, sir.
That is the last call
I expect to receive on this matter
from Congressman Stratton
or anyone else on the Hill.
Do I make myself clear, General?
Perfectly.
Colonel Burton, I want you to write
your report on the Bradley.
Sir? I was under the impression
that my job had...
Your job has been reinstated.
I want your report on my desk
by 1800 hours tomorrow.
- Yes, sir.
- Colonel, in case you are unaware,
as per the military manual, you will deliver
your report to me and to me alone.
Should a single copy be made public,
I will charge you with
subversion of military procedure
and have you court-martialled.
Stop packing, we're staying.
- How'd you do that?
- I didn't do anything.
- Do we have a rule book?
- A rule book, sir?
- A book with rules in it.
- What do you need a rule book for?
To play by the rules,
cos I always play by the rules.
Then why do you need a rule book
to tell you what the rules are?
I need a rule book to tell me which rules I...
Just get me the book.
You need anything else, sir?
Chinese food, No-Doz?
No, thank you, Sergeant, I'm fine.
Well, then, night, sir.
What sounds better?
"The Bradley has so far
failed virtually every test"
or "The testing program of the Bradley
"has been without any coherent standards"?
They both sound like something
the General wouldn't want in his report.
This is not just a report,
it's a deadly weapon.
Sir, an M-16 is a deadly weapon.
A report is just a pile of paper,
unless you plan to inflict
a lot of extremely vicious paper cuts.
Go home, Sergeant.
Good night, sir.
"The failure of the Bradley to incorporate
even the most elementary safeguards
"to protect the troops inside
raises questions about the integrity."
"The manner in which
the vaporifics tests were carried out
"suggests either negligence
or a failure in the chain of command."
"Had any troops been inside the vehicle,
as it is currently configured,
"they would have been killed
by toxic fumes, flames
"or by the overpressure created
by the expanding gas in the compartment."
"And as a result
of manifest deficiencies in every area,
"this office..."
"As a result of manifest deficiencies, this
office is advising the immediate necessity
"of live fire-testing under combat conditions"!
- Rewrite it!
- Sir?
Rewrite the fucking piece of garbage
so it smells like a rose!
Jesus Christ!
"The Bradley test standards
"have been consistently altered
"in extreme ways.
"The Bradley tests have been
extremely consistent.
"They have altered
"the standards
"for testing.
"Test after test has revealed
design flaws in the Bradley.
"The marginalised optimal performance data..."
"The marginalised optimal performance data
"suggests no vaporific shift at this time."
Ha-ha-ha! That's brilliant, Lieutenant,
that's abso-fucking-lutely brilliant.
Thank you, sir.
- But, sir...
- What?
What does it mean?
What do you mean, what does it mean?
You wrote it.
- Afternoon, sir.
- Good afternoon.
"The Bradley tests have been
extremely consistent."
This thing is exactly the opposite
of what you wrote.
How can they do that?
They're playing by the book, Sergeant,
and so am I.
Paper cuts...
vicious paper cuts.
"The characterisation in your report
is at best a serious misunderstanding
"of the testing procedures
on a vehicle as flawed as the Bradley.
"As noted in my original report,
the integrity..."
Jesus Christ! Who did this fucking thing go to?
The distribution page listed 198 names.
Court-martial the son of a bitch!
Lock him up now!
- We can't.
- We sure as hell can!
Burton's report was classified,
it was sent to you,
you revised it and sent it back to him.
He wrote a memo on your revision
which can be sent to anyone
remotely involved with the Bradley.
In this case, 198 people.
I will fucking kill him.
I will fillet him, draw and quarter him,
stick his head in a vice.
We can't touch him, sir. It's by the book.
Then you find something in that book
that'll help me fry the son of a bitch!
What?
Sir, the Washington Post is on the phone.
That was fast. Leaks don't usually
get to them till after lunch.
Yes. No, we cannot comment
on that right now.
Yes?
No, he cannot comment on that.
I'm sorry, but under military rules,
I'm unable to comment.
I... I can't comment.
No. No, no comment.
Sorry, goodbye.
I'm getting lockjaw from not saying anything.
Burton.
I... I can't comment.
Is there anything I can comment on?
Well, yes.
I've just received orders
that I am to report for duty in... Alaska.
Alaska is a prestige posting, Senator.
No, no, no,
I assure you that memo of his
had nothing to do with his being transferred.
Senator, I'm sorry, I've just been informed
Secretary Weinberger is on the other line.
I'll get right back to you.
I promise, thank you.
Sir, Weinberger is on two,
line one is the Times.
Three is the Wall Street Journal,
four is Newsweek,
line five is the House
Armed Services Committee.
What do they want?
Hearings, sir. On the Bradley.
Alaska?
- What?
- I said Alaska, General.
As I said in my opening remarks,
Madam Chairman,
a lot of things have to come together
to create teamwork.
- Good old-fashioned teamwork.
- Yes, you told us, General.
And Colonel Burton's not a team player,
he's a rogue operator.
I'm not a name-caller, Madam Chairman.
But if you wish to make that connection,
that would be your choice, not mine.
Did you ever say to Colonel Burton
"If I get one more call from the Hill
about your, uh, expletive deleted, reports,
"you'll be sitting on your brains"?
- Does that sound like me, sir?
- Answer the question, General, please.
I don't remember saying it.
Not that I wasn't provoked.
Two witnesses testified that you said
those words to Colonel Burton
outside the Pentagon pharmacy.
I have visited the pharmacy.
Quite a bit lately for antacids.
But I would never say
anything like that to anyone.
Let alone a fellow officer.
But what about your antagonism
towards Colonel Burton?
It's his report that I don't approve of.
Colonel Burton's report is fallacious,
misinformed, and accusatory.
And I have no use for an officer who is
more interested in grabbing headlines
than he is in defending this country.
I thought he was in Anchorage.
Madam Chairman, Colonel Burton's here.
The committee would like to call as witness
Colonel James G Burton,
United States Air Force.
- Madam Chairman.
- Yes, General?
Under the rules of military conduct,
no man can appear at these hearings
without the express order
of his commanding officer.
Unfortunately, General De Grasso
is on a tour in Germany.
General De Grasso has not ordered
Colonel Burton to testify.
You're quite right, but as Colonel Burton
has been transferred to Alaska,
he's no longer under
General De Grasso's command.
Am I correct?
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing but the truth
- so help you God?
- I do.
Looks like you've stirred up
a hornet's nest, Colonel.
It was never my intention, ma'am.
What was your intention?
Simply to do the job I was assigned to do.
The Army test reports do not make
the possibility of casualties a top priority.
In fact, General Partridge's
report on the Bradley
doesn't even mention the word casualty,
not once.
I came to the conclusion that
what was required was a live-fire test.
I requested such a test, repeatedly.
- Did you get that test?
- No, ma'am, I did not.
Why not?
I wanted more realism than Army testing
was accustomed to providing.
You want realism?
General, you are out of order!
Madam Chairman, in the interest
of resolving some of these issues,
I'd like to say something.
Please be brief, General.
Of course.
Colonel Burton wants more realism,
so let's talk about the real world.
The real world has enemies in it.
There are forces at work,
even now as we speak
with one objective in mind -
the destruction of this country.
We must not, we will not
allow those forces to prevail,
for if we do,
you can be certain that you and I,
and everyone else
will never again enjoy the luxury
of meeting in this building
to debate anything!
As I said at the outset,
we are in the business of winning.
That takes teamwork.
General, the teamwork you so prize,
I take it it was in full force
during the development of the Bradley?
Textbook!
Perhaps you'd like to tell us
how much has been spent so far
to develop the Bradley?
How much?
Well, you have the figures, don't you?
Of course.
14.
- More or less.
- 14.
- Million?
Bill... ion.
What did you say, General?
Billion.
Billion... with a B?
With a B.
$14 billion for designing
one armoured vehicle?
That's one way of looking at it.
Of taxpayers' money.
We are all taxpayers, after all.
We're in this together.
General, how many years
has this programme been running?
Bear with me, just a moment.
Um... er...
Let me... Ah.
Let's see. 12, 15...
- 17.
- What?
17.
Which is evidence...
of the enormous care my team takes
in the development of every weapons system
undertaken by the Pentagon.
Hm.
17 years.
$14 billion of the taxpayers' money.
General, I think it's time
the American public
gets the live-fire test
that Colonel Burton wants.
- Tomorrow's the big day, sir.
- Uh-huh.
I'll tell you one thing.
Every damn one of these nuts and bolts
has been taken off and put back on again.
This wouldn't be flame retardant, would it?
You think they made the men
trick this whole thing up?
It wouldn't surprise me.
Not a bit.
Room, attention.
At ease, gentlemen.
Looks like you've been working hard.
- Corporal.
- Sir?
Let me have one of those M-16s.
I wanna tell you a story.
You got a problem with that, Sergeant?
No, sir.
About a year ago,
I went to the veterans' hospital
to visit a friend of mine
from my flying days.
Only I took a wrong turn
when I got off the elevator.
Now, when I look back on it,
I think I was meant to go down that corridor.
Cos that's where I met Phil.
Thank you, Corporal.
- But, sir...
- Let me finish, Dalton.
I want to pass on something
I learned about the M-16 from Phil.
You all know the M-16 better than I do.
A lot of you used it in Vietnam.
But you were lucky.
In the early days of that war,
they sent guys off to fight
with M-16s that jammed in combat.
A little bit of dust, a little bit of rain,
and the gun was useless.
Maybe those early M-16s
weren't tested properly.
Maybe somebody somewhere
was more worried
about a production schedule or a promotion
than he was about those grunts
in some faraway jungle,
who might end up with
their stomachs in their hands.
But you don't know anyone
that happened to, do you?
No. I'm sure not.
Otherwise you'd be out there right now
making sure that that Bradley
is exactly - and I mean exactly -
the way it would be
under normal combat conditions.
With some of your buddies
riding inside, guys like Phil.
Only Phil has been in a coma
for the last 20 years.
Since the day his M-16 jammed
somewhere outside of Vinh Long.
But hell, you don't know the guy.
Or anybody like him.
Right?
Sir?
Over here!
- General!
- Good morning, sir.
- Everything all right?
- Fine, sir, just fine.
Keep coming. Keep coming. Keep coming.
A little more. Keep coming. Keep coming.
- Sergeant.
- Sir.
- Everything all right, Sergeant?
- Fine, sir.
- Thank you.
- Welcome, sir.
Welcome, Sergeant.
Jeez. Looks like some party.
Ladies and gentlemen, please be seated.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
distinguished members of Congress.
I think it's fair to say that
you'll be seeing enough from this test
to give you the basis once and for all
to form your own conclusion
about the sort of systemic excellence
we've been pursuing.
I will be giving the signal shortly.
When I do, I want you
to visualise combat conditions.
Imagine that the men firing that round
are the enemy.
And that the Bradley,
I don't have to tell you...
the Bradley is on our side.
Ladies and gentlemen,
distinguished members of Congress,
I give you your Bradley fighting vehicle.
Can you believe this?
Sergeant.
Everything's gonna go as planned, isn't it?
It will go exactly as it should, sir.
As planned, right?
Corporal, this is Sergeant Dalton.
Move the vehicle about five yards forward
and then clear out. Over.
Roger that.
For your further edification,
the Bradley can be fired accurately...
How much fuel is in those tanks, Sergeant?
Just enough to do those manoeuvres?
No more than it would have
if it was in combat, sir.
Seven TOW missiles fired
from a launcher mounted on the left side...
- And the ammunition inside the Bradley?
- Up to spec, sir.
- Whose specs?
- Manoeuvrable,
- and capable of keeping pace with...
- No! No!
Carrying infantry troops
needed to support tank operations,
more than we have in the test conditions.
And the hour is at hand.
All eyes front on the Bradley fighting vehicle.
The vehicle that will carry our boys to victory
for many, many years to come.
Backblast area clear!
Fire!
Who's the best, baby?
Dalton, Granger!
- Sir.
Could you explain, please?
We tried to tell you, sir.
You see, sir, when you gave us
that speech last night
we had already fixed the vehicle
back to the way it should be.
So you were...
- you were ahead of me.
- I don't know about ahead,
but we've been behind you
ever since you fried those mannequins.
And the sheep, sir. Man, that was epic!
I'm sorry I made you listen
to that lecture now, I...
Sir, you have nothing to apologise for, sir.
We had you figured wrong.
The men come first with you,
and you proved that.
It was a hell of a good speech though, sir.
Any time you want to give another one,
you know where to find us.
Thank you, men. Thank you, all.
Sir.