[marching boots get louder]
(little boy's voice)
Imagine it.
Imagine it someone came
and built a high wall
right around your neighborhood,
so you couldn't get out.
That's what the
Nazis did to us.
No one's allowed
out at night.
It's so quiet you can
hear someone cough
right across the other
side of the ghetto.
Everyone is scared.
Even my dad.
Even my uncle, who pretends not to be.
Every week, the Nazis come
and take more people away.
They call this "selection. "
You never know when a
selection is going to happen
or who they're
going to take next.
There aren't many
of us left now.
Only the strong
ones who can work.
Us kids have to be
careful in the daytime.
At night, I hide in the
loft so they don't find me.
My uncle gave me a book.
It's called Robinson Crusoe.
[children's voices
and laughter]
(first boy) I found
one. I'll give you 30.
(second boy)
No, it's 40, Avrum.
Thirty!
Starting now.
One, two, three,
(female voice)
Come with me.
five, six, seven,
eight, nine,
ten, eleven,
twelve, thirteen,
fourteen, fifteen,
[fading] sixteen, seventeen,
eighteen, nineteen-
[shouts in German]
(male voice)
Selection!
Selection.
(male voice) No one
leaves. Everyone keep working.
Women and children
this time, Stefan.
Where is Alex?
I n Bird Street playing
with the Gryn kids.
[taunting]
Alex, oh, Alex.
Stop it, Avrum.
You're hurting him!
Leave him alone! You're
hurting him I Leave him alone!
As in canned rat.
Come down, Avrum.
It's not sate.
Go on, Alex. Go get the
stinking rat yourself.
Go on, dodo. Go get the rat. Go on!
(German soldier)
Alright now! Get in line!
Hey, you!
Stop! Stop!
(Mrs. Gryn) Hide!
Selection! Hide in there!
(girl) Alex! Come on, Alex.
(Avrum)
Alex, come on!
Alex, come with us!
There's no time!
[crowd shouting]
(German soldier)
Hey I Come back! Hey!
Stop! Get back!
[whistle]
[barking]
(soldier)
Nothing here.
Let's go!
Come on!
Don't worry, Snow.
[indistinct]
(soldier)
Move!
Stay in line!
[softly]
Alex.
Alex!
How could
you sleep?!
I knew you'd come.
I knew it.
We won't take him to
the factory anymore.
(Boruch) The factory’s sate.
There are ways to get out.
I'll see that
he's alright.
Besides, I need a footrest. [chuckle]
He stays in the bunker with the Gryns.
(Alex) What about Mrs. Gryn's eyes?
What about
Mrs. Gryn's eyes?
She stares.
There, you see?
You expect the boy to stay
at a dirty slimy cellar
with someone
who just stares?
They've changed
the rules, Alex.
From now on, they catch
you with kids, [pfft]
you're on the next
train. You understand?
Now good night.
Myriam told me she said it
was like a holiday place.
"Myriam told
me, " huh?
So where are the postcards
from this holiday place?
Where are the letters?
Remember Aunt Lunya?
She couldn't fart without
writing someone about it.
[fart]
Boruch!
It sneaked out.
What do you want?
What are they doing to these people?
I don't know.
I don't know either.
Here. Take my own mezuza in
that tree of yours up there.
Keep it with you
at all times.
It will ward
off evil.
Mrs. Gryn too?
No more
staring eyes.
Thanks,
Uncle Boruch.
Don't mention it.
"We were shipwrecked. There
wasn't a house to live in.
"Or any food
or clothes.
At night, I thought I'd
get eaten by wild animals. "
You bake the bread
too heavy sometimes.
They are
killing us.
No one
knows that.
Now you don't have
your mezuza for protection.
Maybe Mrs. Gryn with her staring
eyes will come looking for you.
Oh, I live
in hope.
Yeah.
(singing) Mrs. Gryn, Mrs. Gryn,
I didn't know
you cared.
The first time
I saw you
all you did
was stare.
(both sing) Mrs. Gryn, Mrs. Gryn,
I didn't know you cared. [chuckles]
[factory whistle]
Just keep your head down, you old fool.
[three soft knocks]
Then there was my
great grandmother.
Your great-great-grandmother.
Such a woman.
Terrifying.
She could eat Mrs. Gryn
for breakfast, lunch and tea
and then [pt]
spit out the bones.
What is this
supposed to be?
A bowline,
like you said.
A bowline?
Hmm.
Now this, this
is a bowline, Alex.
How many times have I told you, huh?
Here, that's
a bowline.
There's mail
for you, uncle.
Hmm. What do we have
-[shout]
Alex, I told you not
to bring him in here.
It's against the law.
Besides, there's all kinds of gray mice
in this factory
and they're crazy.
They'll kill him and eat him
just as soon as look at him.
You're just
scared of him.
Oh.
[five knocks]
[engine revs]
[German spoken]
(German officer)
You, Jew.
Yes, you.
Come here.
How old are you?
59.
59?
Why aren't you working?
I'm the storekeeper.
Load it
on the truck.
[soft gasp]
[groan]
How old
are you, Jew?
59.
[shout] How old are you?!
[groan]
I'd eat that German officer's
boots with my naked teeth.
Not funny.
Ah. I'll feel better
when I get my medicine.
Stop talking for once in your life.
I need
my medicine.
This is not the
take [indistinct] stuff.
This is the best
Russian vodka.
Don't ask me how much I paid for it.
How much you pay for it?
Tomorrow you should stay
in the bunker with Alex.
Stay in the bunker
with me, Uncle.
I've got my
work to do.
This looks like a very
inferior brand, you know?
Right, if you
don't want it-
On the other hand-
(Alex) A man should never drink alone.
The boy is right.
A delicate palate like
yours shouldn't touch this.
I'll sacrifice myself.
Good.
(Stefan)
And now steady,
breathe out.
Now gently squeeze.
[click]
Hey, bullseye.
The bullets
didn't fall out.
Clip. It's
called a clip.
What does he want to be a marksman for?
Is the war
over already?
You should
have told me.
I'll watch
out for him,
I'll see that
he's alright.
It's not a bad idea
for a young man
to learn how to
shoot a pistol.
(German soldier) Come on. Out. Get out.
(woman)
No, no, please!
Wait here.
Wait.
You'll take
pneumonia down there.
You'll be safe,
you'll be outside.
(thin man)
[indistinct]
(Mrs. Gryn)
What do you care?
We need some
more penicillin.
Thank you,
Mrs. Gryn.
See you tonight.
(Alex)
Look, Yossi.
You can't bring that
filthy thing in here.
You scared
or something?
You know what
Momma said!
Hey, Yossi.
Look, Yossi.
Seek it. Seek it, Snow. Seek it.
Seek it.
[indistinct]
Alex, how many times have I told you?
It spreads diseases.
Put it in here!
Put it here!
Alex!
He'll get us
all killed.
[noises]
What happened
to the signal?
Mrs. Gryn. She was going to kill Snow.
Stop it, Alex.
You're starting to
believe your own stories.
Sorry.
Where's the rodent?
At home.
That's the
best place.
Go on.
(Stefan) What's he doing here?
I told you to stay
in the bunker!
(Boruch)
What's happening?
They're clearing
the houses.
They're everywhere!
[shouting]
[machine-gun tire]
[footsteps]
Someone talked.
Out.
Hey!
[whispers]
Jacob, isn't it?
I knew your father.
Move it.
[groans and moans]
[machine-gun fire]
(Stefan)
I'll take him.
(Boruch) No, we stick with the plan.
He comes
with me.
I don't want
no arguments.
We don't have
time for this.
You know what
you have to do.
Now go!
Good-bye!
Take this.
Stay with
your uncle.
Do everything
he says, hm?
Wait for me.
No matter
what happens,
I will come
back for you.
Wait for me.
They're closing
the factory.
They're clearing
the ghetto.
This time it's
all of you.
Good luck, Boruch.
[officer speaks German]
That one!
Bring him out!
[whistle]
Now, remember,
you stay off the street
and wait.
Wait.
How long for?
As long as it takes.
An hour, maybe a day. Just wait.
Your dad will come
and get you, Alex.
Remember that.
He will come for
you. Remember.
Alright. Alright.
Go with [indistinct].
Run now. Go.
Ohhh, no!
[screams]
No! Go back!
Go back!
[shots]
[speaks German]
[soldier shouts]
[German spoken]
[soldier speaks German]
Come, come.
[trickling]
[flushing]
Shh!
[flapping]
[coughing]
Snow.
Snow!
Snow?
[squeaking]
[squeak]
Rescued from the camps.
(Alex) "My man, Friday, threw himself
"at my feet
in gratitude
"for my having saved him from
the cannibals' cooking pot.
" I n a little time,
I began to speak to him
"and teach him
to speak to me.
" I let him know his
name should be Friday
"which was the day
I saved his life.
" I likewise taught
him to say master
and let him know that was
to be my name. " Got that?
Listen to Master Alex.
We call this bread.
Bread, good.
We eat bread.
You like?
[squeak]
[dog barking distantly]
[clatter]
[Alex gasps]
[classical music]
[barking]
Bye, Snow.
[clatter]
[plane flying overhead]
Seek it, Snow.
Seek it.
Yes. Good
boy, Snow.
Seek it.
Good boy, Snow.
Good boy.
I found them.
They're mine.
Go away.
(Alex) Please. I haven't got any food.
[clatter]
[German spoken]
[machine-gun tire]
[screams and shouts]
[loud footsteps]
(German officer)
And the rest.
Careful.
Steady.
A very inferior brand.
[gasp]
A man should
never drink alone.
[Alex giggles]
Oh, quite right.
[men laughing]
Dad?
Alex, my boy.
My brave, brave boy.
I knew
you'd come.
I knew.
Uncle Boruch!
You're alright!
(Boruch) It takes more than that.
Leopards can't
climb trees.
You listen to
your uncle Boruch.
One day, you'll be rich
and famous, just like him.
You've got to sacrifice
yourself. Remember.
[men's laughter]
Dad?
[door opens]
[door closes]
[undefined noises]
[loud noise]
[pots and pans rattling]
[male voice] Take it. Leave that.
What's that?!
[pigeons cooing and flapping]
Leopards can't
climb trees.
Ahh!
I didn't do anything.
You can't trust me
and I can't trust you.
What's your name?
Alex.
What's in the
sack, Alex?
Rope.
What's it for?
My dad.
Ha. Some dad sending his
kid out to risk his neck.
He couldn't
come himself.
Are you
Jewish, Alex?
No.
Tell me
the truth.
I'm Polish.
[speaks in Latin]
May the Lord
be with you.
And you say-hm?
[speaks Latin]
[Alex repeats]
Tongue.
Come on.
It's Latin. It means
"And also with you. "
I know. Of course I know Latin.
Of course you do. You're
a Pole and a survivor.
Now go on, go back to
your dad. Go on, move!
[children's cheerful voices
singing and laughing]
[cheerful chatter
and laughter]
Day one.
Just you and me.
And the cannibals.
[car door closes]
[speaks in German]
(German officer)
Where?
How many?
Twelve.
[German spoken]
(German officer)
Out I Out!
(male voice) We'll
do whatever you say!
[indistinct
loud voices]
[little girl coughing]
[German spoken]
[voices shouting]
[soldier speaks
in German]
[both speak in German]
[pigeons flap]
[tinkle]
[dripping]
[speaks German]
[loud explosion]
[child coughing]
[machine-gun tire]
[German spoken]
[weapon clacks]
[clacking]
[groan]
Henryk!
Who shot him?
Me.
Oh my God.
(wounded man) Freddy I [shout]
[truck engine
and German voices]
Come here!
Get down!
Come on.
Done alright
for yourself.
Do you have any more
ammunition for this?
Take it. It's yours, isn't it?
No?
What's this?
Hello.
What's your name?
Snow.
Snow? 'Cause he's
white, like snow?
You alright?
I killed him. I didn't mean to.
[weeps]
Hey, hey.
What are you doing here all on your own?
I'm waiting
for my dad.
How long has your dad been gone, Alex?
Thirty-six days.
[shouts and moans]
Some water.
Relax.
[gulps and chokes]
This leads
to the other side.
I'll go contact with the
Polish Underground.
A priest. I think
he can help us.
So I'm gonna go
find him, alright?
You be careful
on your way home.
Make sure Henryk gets plenty
of water. No champagne.
I'll see you in
a couple of hours.
[choking and screams in agony]
[muffled screams]
[screaming stops]
[undefined noise]
[horse clopping by]
[child's voice shouting]
[choking]
Sorry.
I had to.
You were making
too much noise.
[muffled noises]
[male voices speaking
in foreign language]
[male voice
whistles to Alex]
Hey, you!
(lady) Thank you, bye-bye, dear.
[coins fall to floor]
You must be rich throwing
your money about like that.
Bye bye,
Mrs. Takysky.
(Mrs. Studjinsky)
Bye, Stasya.
Yes?
Are you the
doc's place?
Is something
wrong with it?
It's a bit difficult
to explain out here.
[classical music]
What can I
do for you?
Are you sick?
It's not me.
It's my friend.
The authorities insist upon
hearing of anything suspicious.
[conversation
in German]
I watch you
play chess.
On the telephone.
Through the window.
How did you find
your way out?
Freddy showed me.
He hasn't
come back.
Friends of
the priest.
Don't talk so much. He doesn't
need to know these things.
Of course
he does.
Did you put some tinned beef in?
Yes, yes.
We're gonna make sure
your friend gets well.
(girl)
Hi Doctor Studzinski.
(doctor)
Stasya
(girl) Mustn’t pass on
stairs. It's bad luck.
(girl)
Oh, hello again.
I didn't recognize
you at first.
(doctor)
Come along, Alex.
What does that girl
know about you?
Nothing.
I promise.
I can't climb that!
I'll take your bag.
It-it can take
your weight.
(doctor)
Now, your treatment.
I'm trying to
get some more
but it's a lot of money
on the black market.
If he gets worse, he'll
have to come to me.
I can't afford the
risk. Now, you take that.
A lot of people rely
on me, you understand.
A lot of people.
[indistinct noises]
(male voice)
Stand back.
Stand back!
[tough boy laughs]
(tough boy) What do
you think you're doing?
Who are
you, anyway?
(tough boy) It's the little Jew fish.
He's mine, come here little Jew fish.
(girl)
Come on, Alex,
we should have been home
ages ago. Are you coming?
Mother will kill us.
You know how she hates
it when we're late.
(tough boy)
She's a Yid lover!
Thanks.
That's alright.
You're not from around here, are you?
No. It's a boat
ride from here.
Rough seas.
Sharks.
Do you go to the park on Sundays?
Yeah.
You know the little house?
Four o'clock? Bye then.
Hope your boat doesn't sink. [giggle]
[choking sounds]
You're better.
Where's Freddy?
He went for help.
How long?
Ten days ago.
[bird chirps]
(Alex) He built a house in a tree.
He found a rope
ladder on the roof.
He lived there
for a long time.
He made his
own weapons.
He caught things to eat.
Then he rescued Friday.
But it's just a boy's story. [sigh]
Maybe he could've
stayed alive
for a week
or two.
He could survive
forever if he had to
if no one came
to rescue him.
[laughs] Alright, I give up.
Look, I'd better
go home.
Me too. Dad will be
wondering where I am.
See you tomorrow?
Alright.
Bye, then.
Bye.
Come on, Snow.
Fetch it.
Go on.
Seek it.
[squeak]
Good boy.
[squeaks]
I didn't know
which ones.
You look like
a scientist.
Now you look
like a jeweler.
Oh, hello
young man.
What have you
got there?
Ohh, I thought
it was the Plaza.
It says here there's
going to be a war soon.
Not funny.
Last dose.
[sigh]
I'll tell
you something.
I could do with something proper to eat.
I could do with something to get
me on my feet. Something decent.
I'm thinking steaks.
Fried potatoes.
Now, get me something
proper to eat
or I'll eat that
bloody rat of yours.
What are you looking at all the time?
It says here-
Shh.
I'm reading.
"The dinner party
is the most formal
of all types of
present day entertaining. "
"When man Friday and I
arrived at the cannibals' camp,
"the very blood ran
cold in my veins
at the horror
of what I saw. "
"Your guests should not be
seated too close to one another. "
"There was an eerie silence
hanging over the hut.
There was no sign of
any of the inhabitants. "
"I arranged my guests
around the table so that-"
"Their bones were strewn about,
along with human skulls and flesh. "
"I decided a three-course
meal was quite in order. I-"
"-turned about to see a
cannibal shoot me with a-"
"-fruit and a selection of cheeses. "
[Alex laughs]
What are
you doing?
I've got
to get out.
You can't.
You'll never get down
that rope ladder.
I've got to
see a man.
I'll go. I can do it.
I can find him.
How's your Latin?
[speaks Latin]
Very good.
Think you could
learn some more?
[organ music starts]
(priest) You have come
to confess your sins.
[speaks Latin]
Just exactly what
does that mean?
I don't know.
Alex. The
little survivor.
How can I help
you, Alex?
The priest said the ghetto walls
are coming down any day now.
The walls coming down and
the Poles are moving in?
Obvious that the
apartment is going free.
But the war goes on.
I think you should
come with me.
[pebbles rolling]
This many will get so tat
they'll float away into space.
This many will get so thin
they'll slip down the drain.
This many will get reborn
as flees and get squashed.
Don't you want to know how
many children you're gonna have?
How many?
I'm not telling you.
You have to find
out for yourself.
Dad doesn't want
a corpse for a son.
I don't want a corpse for a friend.
This place
is finished.
It'll be swarming with
Poles and German soldiers
in a couple of days.
Face up to it.
Alex,
the chances are your
daddy is never coming back.
It doesn't matter,
does it?
He can make
his own decision.
That future of yours.
It's waiting for you.
Good luck.
[children shouting
cheerfully]
(tough boy) Look! Wait
a minute! Little Jew fish!
Come back!
Hey you, Jew fish, come here.
I'm sorry,
it wasn't me.
I didn't do it.
Please. I'm sorry.
[soldier speaks German]
[soldier shouts
in German]
Gestapo!
Run!
Hurry.
[foreign language]
[shouting in German outside]
[machine-gun tire]
[cries softly]
Can I come
in please?
What's it like?
To live in
an apartment.
More like
a cupboard.
You live in
a cupboard?
Well, under a
cupboard, actually,
but I have a bed
and a cooker,
and everything I need.
Really, it's fine.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Leaving?
We're going to my
uncle's in the country.
(female voice)
Stasya?
It's okay,
it's my mother.
You can't miss
the curfew.
You'd best
stay the night.
You'll have to be up early
in the morning though.
He could come with
us, couldn't he, Mama?
That's enough, Stasya.
Clear the table please.
Thank you.
[soft piano music]
[odd high
piano notes]
[both giggling]
You can come with us, if you want to.
We'll leave a message for your father.
We'll make sure he
knows where to find you.
Just came to
say good night.
See you
tomorrow then.
You will come with us, won't you?
Good night.
[squeak]
(man) Hey I Go on I Hey I Go on!
[crowd cheers]
[crowd wallah]
(tough boy) Tear it
down! The Jews are out.
[child laughs]
[cheerful children's voices]
[children scream]
[children talking]
(male voice) Out now.
It's dangerous in here.
Get this area closed off
before someone gets killed.
[loud noise]
Oh.
Wake up, Snow.
Snow.
[children laugh]
[weeping]
Snow.
Goodbye, Snow.
[slow pounding]
[softly]
Alex.
[indistinct noise]
Alex?
Dad?
Are you real?
Yes.
I'm real.
(Alex)
I knew you'd come.
(Alex) At first, it
seemed like a mirage.
A strange sort of
shimmering on the horizon.
Slowly, bit by bit, it
got closer and clearer.
Then, there it was.
The most beautiful ship.
Full sail, with
all its flags flying.
It was coming
to my island.
Coming to my rescue.
It was going to
take me home.
[classical music]