Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
VLADIMIR BUKOVSKY
Soviet dissident
NORMAN DAVIES, Historian,
Cambridge University
NIKOLAY MELNIK, survivor of the 1932/33
Famine | Potatoes, beets, cabbages.
Salted cabbages were taken
by the whole barrel.
All edible goods were taken away.
Everything!
VOLODIMIR SERGIYCHUK, Historian, University
of Kiev | When the food was taken away,
peasants were also forbidden
to seek it elsewhere.
To buy, exchange or earn.
BORISS SOKOLOV, Historian | They were dying.
And they were not allowed into the cities.
Special guard-squads prevented these
dying, starving people from
boarding the trains.
Many died right by the railways
leading to Kharkov, Kiev...
They entered a house and asked:
"where are your dead?"
There was only a half-dead
woman laying in the bed.
They said:
"Let's take her! She will die anyway."
"Why come after her tomorrow?"
She begged them: "Don't take me.
I am still alive! I want to live!"
MARIA ZAGUTS, survivor of the
1932/33 Famine | It was horrible!
They were all dumped into the grave.
The ground was moving.
This is a sacred place for me.
Because it is the resting
place of the Famine victims,
including my close relatives,
my grandmother.
PIERRE RIGOULOT, Historian,
Institut d'histoire Sociale, Paris
We must create a new man.
And a new life form
should appear!
FRANÇOISE THOM, Professor
of Modern History, Sorbonne
GEORGE WATSON, Literary Historian,
Cambridge University
VLADIMIR BUKOVSKY
Soviet dissident
FRANÇOISE THOM, Professor
of Modern History, Sorbonne
You must all know half
a dozen of people at least,
who are of no use in this world.
Who are more trouble
than they are worth.
Just put them there and say:
"Now will you be kind enough
to justify your existence?"
"If you can't justify your existence,
if you are not producing as much as
you consume or preferably more,
then clearly we cannot use our society
for the purpose of keeping you alive.
Because your life does not benefit us
and it can't be of very
much use to yourself.
Let's go and denounce them!
Then we can denounce even more
of them, the ones who are left.
Don't be afraid to do it.
ALEXANDER GURYANOV, "Memorial" society, Moscow | In the 1930s
the technology of murder and executions was introduced.
Every administrative region
had a designated area
where corpses were to be buried.
A person was taken down
a corridor to the "red corner"
There was the final ID check.
The victim had to identify himself.
Then he was led to that room.
When he entered, he was shot.
NICOLAS WERTH, co-author of
"The Black Book of Communism"
VLADIMIR KARPOV, former Soviet Colonel
Khrushchev asked to increase his quota!
He was allowed
to kill 7 or 8 thousand "enemies"
He asked:
"Please increase my quota to 17000."
MIKHAIL GORBACHEV, Soviet President | Stalin
was awash in blood! I saw the death sentences,
which he signed in packages.
Together with Molotov,
Voroshilov, Kaganovich and Zhdanov.
They were the five most active.
Molotov would always add:
change "10 years" to "execution".
Packages!
NATALIA LEBEDEVA, Historian
As a result, in 1937-1941,
11 million people were repressed.
11 million!
Can you imagine
the scale of repression
against their own people?!
VLADIMIR BUKOVSKY
Soviet dissident
SERGEY SLUCH, Historian | According
to all norms of international law,
the decision of the Soviet
Government to invade Poland
was a clear act of aggression.
Red Army in 1939
NORMAN DAVIES, Historian,
Cambridge University
Initially, Ribentropp's proposal
did not contain it.
However strange it may seem,
the initiator of this
secret protocol was Stalin.
But we denied it, because
it was so aggressive,
the Communist party
could not have signed it.
So, we denied it up to the last day!
ARI VATANEN, member of
the European Parliament
When Berlin made the decision
to stop using this base,
German Admiral Raeder
sent a letter to the Commander
of the Soviet Navy, Kuznetsov,
expressing deep gratitude for services
provided to the German Navy.
PIERRE RIGOULOT, Historian,
Institut d'histoire Sociale, Paris
VIKTOR SUVOROV, former Soviet Secret Agent
A delegation of Gestapo came to the USSR
to learn how to build
concentration camps.
It is in German...
Beria's signature...
Translation from the German:
Reichsführer SS, Chief of
the Security Main Office.
Berlin, Nov. 3, 1938.
With this warrant, my representative
Standartenführer SS Mueller is given
the authority to sign an agreement
in Moscow on coordinated activities
between the NKVD and
the Security Main Office of Germany,
on which we put high expectations
related to strengthening the peace
and security between our countries.
Gruppenführer SS Heydrich.
Attach to the main document.
Lavrenty Beria.
A secret agreement was signed
between KGB and Gestapo.
About collaboration.
They accused me of lying,
claiming that it was not true.
We could not have signed
such an agreement.
NATALIA LEBEDEVA, Historian | This contradiction is
amazing! While it is accepted that Stalin's regime
was criminal, exception is
made for the foreign affairs.
If a regime is criminal, then
it acts criminally in all areas,
including foreign affairs.
This should be accepted once and for all!
The NKVD will propose to
the Soviet Government
a program
to reduce the participation
of Jews in State bodies,
and to prohibit Jews
from the areas of culture
and education.
Chief of GUGB of the Commissariat
for Internal Affairs.
Beria.
Representative of the Chief of the
Security Main Office of Germany,
Mueller.
This was a real war.
A war against Jewish Fascism
within the country.
BORISS SOKOLOV, Historian | Because
being a Jew, Litvinov was not fit
for signing any agreement
with Germany.
NORMAN DAVIES, Historian,
Cambridge University
Stalin's police, the GPU has fallen
to the level of the Nazi Gestapo.
VLADIMIR BUKOVSKY
Soviet dissident
Politburo CK VKPb
took the decision
to shoot all prisoners of war
from these 3 camps.
Major Soprunenko who was
carrying out executions in Katyn
VIKTOR SUVOROV, former Soviet Secret Agent
...was decorated with the Medal of Honor.
But Serov,
the later chief of the KGB,
for the shooting of Polish officers,
he was awarded the order of Lenin,
the highest State decoration.
I swear to obey the orders
of the Commander-in-Chief,
Adolph Hitler.
But if among us there will
appear provocateurs,
we ourselves will deal
with them ruthlessly.
EMMA KORPA, GULAG survivor | And then
we dragged the sledges to the graveyard.
When my son was dragged,
the guards were not on duty.
Children were not
considered inmates,
so they were buried in
a civilian graveyard.
And when another child died,
I dragged him as well.
Then I got a chance to visit my son's
grave for the last time...
CHRISTOPHER BEAZLEY, Historian,
member of the European Parliament
INESE VAIDERE, member of the
European Parliament, Latvia
RITA PAPINA, survivor of the Soviet terror
We went out. There was a big puddle of blood.
We collected it in a glass jar.
Because it was our fathers blood.
It is hard to speak about it.
It is as if a scar was torn
and is bleeding again.
JANIS DZINTARS
Moscow, 2005
VLADIMIR PUTIN, former KGB
Officer One needs to acknowledge,
that the collapse of the Soviet Union
was the greatest geopolitical
catastrophe of the century.
Nobody wants to admit
that one's ancestors
were simple criminals.
ANDRÉ BRIE, member of the
European Parliament, Germany
WOJCIECH ROSZKOWSKI, member of
the European Parliament, Poland
There is this feeling of
inferiority, of national humiliation,
which was in Germany after WW1,
and we had it after the collapse
of the Soviet Union.
It is fertile soil for
these new Nazis.
This is exactly what
led Germany to Fascism.
Moscow, November 4.
"THE DAY OF NATIONAL UNITY"
Since Putin came to power,
there has been
a massive xenophobic
propaganda from above.
And people have begun to feel
hatred toward foreigners,
to people of other languages,
other religions.
The Russian mass media is working
against Russia and its people,
because it is in the hands
of the Jewish mafia.
Pick it up.
And clean up after yourself.
Do you speak Russian?
I am a deputy in the State Duma,
LDPR fraction. My name is
Nikolay Kuryanovich. I am a member
of the Security Committee.
I would like to greet
the national-patriots of Russia.
Glory to Russia!
We were arrested by
the Russian National Socialists.
Glory to Russia!
RADKO MLADIC, war criminal,
murderer of 8300 people
Glory to Russia!
Katyn.
Lviv.
Vinnica.
Tartu.
GIRTS V. KRISTOVSKIS, member of
the European Parliament, Latvia
MICHAEL GAHLER, member of the
European Parliament, Germany
www.moviesubtitles.org
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org