If you remember Pearl Harbor...
you'll recall that in the year that followed...
the Japanese were almost invincible.
Early in 1943, however, they were checked.
Stopped cold by the Marines
at Guadalcanal...
the Navy in the Coral Sea...
and the Allied armies in New Guinea.
This was a period of far-reaching decisions,
desperate strategies...
and incredibly daring counter-strokes...
not the least of which involved...
two bright young naval officers.
This bold, slightly improbable adventure
began with a message...
authorized by the Commanding General,
South West Pacific Area...
and flashed by top priority to the lone
carrier on patrol in the Coral Sea.
It was an urgent request
for a particularly qualified young officer...
to lead an extremely delicate missión.
It demanded a man...
a man of executive ability
and high intelligence...
and that innate quality that enables a man
to swiftly estimate a situation...
and make a wise decisión.
In bestowing that most thrilling
of all awards, an officer's first command...
the Navy knew it had a man that would ask
no questions and offer no excuses.
He would carry out orders regardless
of what obstacles fate put in his path.
Well...
Within the hour,
with high hopes and only a mild headache...
Lieutenant Rip Crandall was on his way...
to a secret anchorage,
a hidden harbor, so shrouded in mystery...
that it was known only as
"somewhere in the South Pacific. "
Here, the U.S. Seventh Fleet,
victors of the Coral Sea...
drowsed at anchor, licking their wounds
and dreaming of the great battles to come.
And here, the Lieutenant saw
his passport to high adventure.
Here, somewhere among
the flotillas of destroyers...
their vital supply and repair ships...
among stalwart battlewagons
of the Nevada class, carriers...
deadly cruisers of the Boise class, escorts,
and tenders of all classes...
he found the ship of his dreams, the Echo...
in, well, a class by itself.
While at first glance,
it might have looked like England's reply...
to the Boston Tea Party...
it had nevertheless had a distinguished
career in the copra trade.
The Navy had not only
gratefully received it from New Zealand...
as a sort of reverse lend-lease,
but had taken great pains...
to man it with a picked crew of specialists.
Dedicated, highly skilled seamen...
who chafed at inactivity here in this quiet
backwater far from the battle lines...
and awaited only the arrival
of their commander to swing into action.
Duck!
Bring that gear aboard.
Welcome aboard, sir.
What? Belay that racket!
You want the whole flotilla to hear us?
What is this?
Honors for the prospective
commanding officer, sir.
The officer in commissión
shall see that all honors and ceremonies-
This hulk is commissioned? As what?
- It's unclassified, sir.
- I can believe that.
Duck!
Sorry, sir. All right, bear a hand, there.
Let's get that thing in port and secure it!
- Johnson?
- Yes, sir?
I'm sorry, sir, but we've only been aboard
a couple of hours.
- How many men have you lost so far?
- None, sir, just a few cuts and bruises.
Don't forget Miller, sir.
Yeah. Yeoman Miller, sir.
Transferred to the hospital ship.
He's a real nut, sir.
I told him to look out for the hatch,
and he thought I wanted a match, and...
Thanks, Johnson.
You can take this man below
and show him where to stow his gear.
All right, sir.
What is all this malarkey
about this ship being commissioned?
It's true, sir. Admiral Hathaway
had me commissión her...
and sign her over to you.
The papers are in your stateroom.
My what?
Your cabin. You can go right ahead.
I'll bring your gear along.
Yes. Just leave it there.
Sir?
I'm sorry, sir.
I meant to warn you about these beams.
You gotta watch it.
- What did you say your name was?
- Tommy.
Sorry, sir. Hanson, sir. Ensign Thomas J.
Let's sit down.
My name is Crandall. Rip Crandall.
I know that. I'd have recognized you,
even if they hadn't told me.
You know me from someplace?
Balboa. The California Yacht Club.
You were getting ready
for the Honolulu race in '39.
What did you do? Crew for me? Or...
I tried to, sir.
You're not the kid
that fouled up the genoa jib?
Oh, gee.
I remember
I was a little rough with you that day.
- Didn't I chase you up the mast?
- Yes, sir.
You said I didn't know enough
to pour water out of a boot.
Boot. That was nice.
You were right, sir.
I nearly wrecked your ship.
But I've studied a lot about sailing
ever since. That's why I volunteered.
You volunteered? What? For this?
Yes, sir. I had a desk job here at the base...
and when Cmd. Vandewater
told me about this-
Vandewater? Not Wilbur Vandewater?
I don't know. Kind of slim, blond hair.
And a blackguard Nazi! That nose-
- Sir?
- What does he do here?
- Flight secretary to the Admiral.
- Yes, he would be.
You have to take him those clearance papers
when you've signed them.
- This ship's not officially yours until you do.
- lt isn't?
You're right. It isn't.
I'll get the ship's boat in the water
so you can take it.
Do that, Bill. Tommy. Wait a minute.
You got a copy of the Navy regs?
- ln the top left-hand drawer, sir.
- Thank you.
Anything wrong?
No. It's just that I do everything
by the book, you know.
Your gear, sir.
I already got that gaff secured.
The gaff. Chief.
Watch...
For your information,
it's not a gaff, it's a boom. The main boom.
Yeah. Sorry, sir.
Mr. Hanson has been teaching us.
The gaff is the...
The spar that, on this ship,
you would bend the head of the foresail to.
You didn't make your rate in sail?
No, sir. But do you think the rest
of these clowns know anything...
Beg pardon, sir.
My last hitch was on The Hamill,
the tender alongside, sir.
- And you volunteered, too?
- ln a manner of speaking, yes.
That is, no, sir.
You'd see it in my record anyway.
It was this, or else.
Else what?
Chief Svenson started his fifth hitch.
And the Chief's mess
gave him kind of a testimonial...
and I figured a party is no good
without entertainment...
and they got this girl dancer at the tavern.
I see.
Nothing like that, sir.
Her husband came with her.
Only...
Only it's wartime,
and unauthorized civilian personnel...
are not allowed on naval installations.
Particularly tenders, the skipper said.
So he gave me my choice of being busted
or grabbing the first ship out.
So, you volunteered. What, the first...
- The first ship out?
- That's what they said, sir.
- I've got to get out of here. Pardon me.
- Sir!
All clear? Lower away together.
If you don't mind, I'd just as soon
you didn't mention it to Mr. Hanson.
He really believes I did volunteer,
and he's kind of young and eager...
and you know?
Let go of the after fall.
Let go the forward fall.
Chief, your secret is safe with me...
because I'm not going to be around
to tell him anyway.
Leaving the ship.
I should have checked the caulking, sir.
It's okay, kid, it's nobody's fault.
Don't you worry about it.
But we'll get you ashore, sir.
Won't we, Chief?
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
Horse, slack your stern line.
Shark Bait, heave around on the bow.
Get that thing aboard.
- He can handle anything, sir.
- Yeah, I'm sure of that.
- He can't wait till we get to sea.
- Yeah, I'm sure of that, too.
- What's up, Chief?
- Brass, coming through.
Right this way, sir.
- Family entrance?
- Dock is on the port side, sir.
Show the Captain the quarterdeck, sailor.
Welcome aboard, sir.
With him in command,
we could sail right into Tokio Bay.
- I'd settle for just getting out of the harbor.
- He can do that blindfolded.
Yes, sir, but I don't think he's going to.
He didn't take them papers, sir.
He forgot them. He must have.
He's got to sign them. Can I still catch him?
Sir, you get them papers.
I'll see that you catch him.
Ahoy, the weather deck!
What do you want, Jack?
A new rubber band for the engine?
Got a special delivery for the dock.
Can you handle it?
Yeah. Hey, Boats,
throw the hook over the side.
Just put your foot in there
and hold on tight, sir.
Jack, don't forget to tell him
to get a transfer.
Yeah! You have to switch over
when you get up there, sir.
Okay, let's go.
Easy, Leahy! Take it up!
Okay, Boats, bring him up.
If you're looking for your brother, he's
in a scow on the other side of this monster.
No, sir. It's me, sir. Tommy.
The Chief had
the ship's crane put me on the dock.
That Chief. He's just full of ideas, isn't he?
What's the rush?
I promised I'd meet some guys
at the Officers' Club for dinner.
- I just thought I'd walk in with you.
- It's a little early for dinner, isn't it?
Yeah, but you know,
junior officers have to get in and get out.
I was hoping you'd have dinner with us.
I'd like the fellows to meet my new skipper.
Thanks, Tommy,
but I'm not your skipper yet.
You see, I haven't signed
those papers in your pocket.
Yeah. I figured you forgot them,
so I brought them along.
- You really didn't forget them, did you?
- You didn't think I did, did you?
I know the ship doesn't look like much, sir,
but it's no scow...
and once the men get to work on it,
you'll be surprised.
If it's on account of me, sir, don't worry,
you can get another junior officer.
Wait. Look, kid,
this has nothing to do with you.
It's just that I don't want to get stuck
on that ship, you see?
But it sails, sir.
And it might have an important missión.
Tommy, if it was the Vanderbilt yacht,
I wouldn't want it, kid.
Do you see all those ships?
That's only a fraction of the Japanese fleet.
Do you want to go
up against that in the Echo?
Yeah, maybe you're right.
I guess I'll have to give these
to Cmd. Vandewater myself.
I'll give them to Vandewater.
I'll take care of him. Where's his office?
Headquarters building.
Behind the tug mooring, sir.
Thanks.
Look, kid, I may end up
as your skipper yet...
but you understand
why I'm trying not to, don't you?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
How do we set up now, Maggie?
Cpl. Hathaway's office called at 17:00, sir.
Col. Harris at 17:05.
Briefing's at 18:30.
- That'll clear the deck, sir.
- Fine.
- Is Lt. Crandall still waiting?
- Yes, sir.
But I'm sure he understands...
that you have a full schedule
and won't mind.
No. Send him in, please.
Yes, sir.
Permissión to secure at 18:00, sir?
Permissión to... Sure.
And get me Admiral Hathaway, would you?
843.
Tell me, once you secure at 18:00,
what would you be doing, Maggie?
Keeping a date at 18:01.
With the base efficiency expert, of course.
Of course.
Stun the crows.
Flag secretary returning the Admiral's call.
Yes, sir. Got it right here, sir.
- Somewhere. Hi, I'll be right with you.
- Yeah.
Sir? Absolutely, sir.
19:00 in your quarters, sir. Yes, sir.
19:00.
What is 19:00, anyway?
7:00. I might have known
you had your finger in this.
All steamed up about my new command
and I end up in a Chinese junk.
What are you talking about, Rip?
- I thought you were at sea.
- I was, and very happy...
until I get orders transferring me to a grain
barge masquerading as a Navy vessel.
- The USS Echo?
- Echo?
Say, is that the racing sloop-
Joke's over.
I've been aboard this career-wrecker.
I was hoping you'd report here first,
so that l-
You could con me into it?
She's a brute, isn't she?
I'd liked to have seen your face
when you went aboard.
But it's no joke, Rip.
- This is an important assignment.
- You're getting funnier by the minute.
No, I'm serious.
Gen. MacArthur himself
wants her delivered to New Guinea.
Why?
You know, I asked him that same thing.
I said to him, "Doug," I said...
"why do you want that old hulk
sailed to New Guinea?"
- And he said to me, "Van, boy"-
- "Drop dead."
What's MacArthur got to do
with the Navy, anyway?
Say, you have been at sea.
Let's just say that he mentioned it
to Admiral Hathaway...
and Admiral Hathaway suggested
that I get with it or else...
and l, in turn-
You saw a chance to do a favor
for an old sailing buddy.
Rip, I swear it, your name popped out
of the lBM machine...
with five or six other ex-yachtsmen...
none of whom I would trust with a canoe.
And if you don't think it's a favor,
I heard about your fitness report.
That popped up, too?
You should get your
next promotion around 1980.
Come on. Now, look.
All you've got to do is slip up
inside the Great Barrier Reef...
run across the Coral Sea,
and take her into Port Moresby.
It's blue water all the way, prevailing winds-
Enemy planes, enemy subs.
400 miles of open water,
I got a crew of cherry pickers.
You beat me to Santa Barbara once
with five Sea Scouts.
But that's got nothing to do with this.
No. I picked you because you're
the only man I know who can do the job.
Now I get it. Now, what,
I sit on that bucket for the duration?
The ship's to be turned over
to the port detachment in Moresby.
What they'll do with it, I don't know.
That's their business.
All you've got to do is get it there.
You'll be flown back here for reassignment
the same day you drop the hook up there.
Now, why don't you just sign the papers
and get it over with?
Wait, a reassignment to what?
You'll have demonstrated your fitness
for command.
"D," maybe.
Maybe even a destroyer.
This is a chance half the guys in the fleet
would give their eyeteeth for.
How come I feel like I'm buying a used car?
How much time do I have to train, Van?
A couple of days, maybe.
- Or more. Let's see, to be in Moresby-
- Not a chance.
Now, look, Rip...
I don't want to have to lean on you,
but if I have to-
You'd have done it when I first walked in.
I don't have to take that ship.
Don't have to face a court-martial, either.
A prospective commanding officer
must first certify a ship in proper condition-
That applies to assuming command
in a naval shipyard.
Paragraph 1 does.
Paragraph 3 states elsewhere-
All right! For a direct commissión you got
to be a sea lawyer in a hell of a hurry.
Skipper had me memorize a page
every time I goofed.
Then you must know
the whole book by heart.
But Admiral Hathaway isn't that soft.
Good luck on your next duty.
Wait a minute.
Van, just give me 10 days to train.
Tell you what, give you an extra day.
That's impossible, and you know it.
I don't know anything,
except she's got to sail.
Under the second officer, if necessary.
The kid? But that's insane. He couldn't.
You know as well as I do
he doesn't have the experience.
Do l? Maybe this will give it to him.
- Did you talk him into it, sir?
- No, but I got him worried.
- Keep working on his conscience, mister.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Kid, what's with you and Vandewater?
Nothing, sir. He just told me to stand by.
There might be new orders
for the Echo tomorrow, sir.
What are you doing here, anyway?
I just came over from the Officers' Club, sir.
I thought, you not knowing the base,
I'd show you where it was.
I was hoping you might have
dinner with us, sir.
Sorry, I didn't mean to be so suspicious.
Thanks.
The new orders, sir.
Does that mean you got the transfer?
He's gonna talk to the Admiral.
- You'll get it.
- What makes you say that?
With your experience,
they'll have to give you a command.
Good officers are scarce.
Command? If Admiral Dewey
was still running the Navy...
I'd be a big man, but he ain't.
"lronsides" Hathaway is.
Where did you say that Officers' Club was?
Over there, in back of the shelter.
- I would like a double anything.
- Yes, sir.
Do you have any chit?
Have to get it from the mess officer.
- We're not allowed to take cash.
- Here, sir. You can use mine.
I couldn't do that to you, too.
I mean, it's bad enough that... Never mind.
This is the officer
I was telling you about, Arthur.
Lt. Crandall? This is a real pleasure, sir.
There's nothing too good for you, sir.
Mr. Hanson was telling me
you are going to command the Echo.
If you need an extra hand,
I sure would like a transfer.
If I were going to command the Echo...
I doubt that we would observe
the cocktail hour.
No, sir, he didn't mean that.
He's a real sailor.
Did two years as a deckhand before the war.
Right, Arthur?
Right, sir. The Old Escobar out of Frisco.
But that was power.
And there's nothing like sail,
is there, Lieutenant?
Coming right up, gentlemen.
You know, once the sea gets in your blood,
I guess you never get rid of it, sir.
Tommy, The Old Escobar out of Frisco
is the ferry to Oakland.
I've been on it. I wish I was on it now.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
Did Cmd. Vandewater say
who they'd get, sir?
No. I imagine they'll find somebody. Why?
No reason, sir.
I just thought, with you in command,
I'd get real practical experience.
I've been studying up
on seamanship and navigation-
Tommy, if you knew
I was gonna be your skipper...
you and Vandewater cooked this thing up.
No, sir. Not until I saw your name
on the orders this morning.
No pretzels.
Then what difference would it make
who got the assignment?
None, sir. Except I thought
I'd try and show you...
I wasn't as stupid as you thought I was.
In Balboa.
- I told you before. That was five years ago-
- Excuse me, sir.
The two gentlemen with the nurse
are waiting for you, sir.
Thanks. Won't you join us, sir?
I told them about you, too.
I see. And you primed them
full of the salty talk...
on how they were gonna sail with me, too?
What are you trying to...
I'm sorry. It's really nothing.
I've got a lot on my mind.
It's been a tough afternoon. You run along.
- I'm sorry. I'll join you later.
- Yes, sir.
Arthur.
Would you like me to freshen it up a bit, sir?
- You're gonna freshen that up?
- You can't fly on one wing, sir.
- Thanks, Jimmy. And don't bother to wait.
- Yes, ma'am. Thanks.
Coming through. Pardon me, gentlemen.
Do one of these.
Kid, I got one that will stop you.
Okay.
Do you know what it means
to miss New Orleans
And miss it each night and day?
I know I'm not wrong
The feeling's getting stronger
The longer I stay away
Miss the moss-covered vines
The tall sugar pines
Where mockin' birds used to sing
And I'd like to see
The lazy Mississippi
A- hurryin' into spring
The moonlight on the bayou
A Creole tune that fills the air
I dream about magnolias in June
And soon I'm wishing that I was there
Do you know what it means
To miss New Orleans
When that's where you left your heart?
And there's somethin' more
I miss the one I care for
More than I miss New Orleans
Wonderful, boy.
Tommy, you're magnificent. Wonderful.
Hanson, you were the... Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
We're just getting warmed up.
We should get back to the ship, sir.
We have to get the anchor watch set.
Ship's security.
Yeah, you're right. I'll just finish this.
Here he comes. I love your work.
From the time
we came in here this afternoon...
this guy's kept my glass filled with whisky
so you can shanghai me.
Where'd you get
"we gotta go back to the ship" business?
Will you fill me with the sauce and then...
No, sir. You left your gear over there.
And you haven't got a place to stay.
Until you're reassigned, I mean.
Right.
I could stay
at the Bachelor Officers' Quarters.
Yes, sir. I forgot.
I'll have them bring your gear over.
No, wait a minute, kid. I'm sorry.
I've been needling you all night long...
and you haven't done anything to deserve it.
It's just something is eating me.
Look, just chalk it up to the fact...
that I'm a heel, and you're much better off
that I didn't take command.
No, I couldn't do that, sir.
You have to do what you think is right.
- I'll have them bring your gear over.
- No.
Leave it there and I'll pick it up sometime.
Give me a chance to see the hulk again.
And you.
Thank you, sir. Good night, sir.
Take care of yourself, kid.
Miss Typewriter of 1943.
What happened to your efficiency expert?
Did he get his head
caught in a filing cabinet, I hope?
Never mind, old daddy's here.
Arthur. Old daddy's here.
Would you bring this girl
something tall and cool?
If you don't mind, Lieutenant,
I'm looking for an Ensign Hanson.
He's your date?
He gets around better than I thought.
This is official Navy business, sir.
I have some documents
which must be signed by 23:00.
There you go with those numbers again.
Ensign Hanson just left, ma'am.
I could try and catch him.
He left in a fast jeep. What documents?
I don't believe
that's any concern of yours, Lieutenant.
It's in connection with
Ensign Hanson's ship, the Echo.
I see. At the moment,
I'm still under orders to take command.
And if you don't mind, anything concerning
the Echo also concerns me.
Would you step into my office
for a moment, please?
Arthur! The wine.
Here we are, open for business.
Let's see the papers.
I understood you were to be reassigned, sir.
I don't think I should.
I haven't been reassigned yet.
Give me the papers.
I want to see the swindle
Vandewater's trying to pull.
This has nothing to do
with Cmd. Vandewater.
And I don't think Admiral Hathaway
would appreciate your terminology.
They're the acceptance
papers from the Echo.
The Admiral wants them signed tonight.
- By Ensign Hanson?
- By Ensign Hanson.
If you really need him,
his ship's down at the end of the dock.
- I can send a fellow over for him.
- You're a little over-trained.
If you're not careful,
I'll have you transferred to the Echo.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
He did it. He wasn't bluffing.
I think that Admiral
will have his grandmother made skipper.
Are they all in order, sir?
Right down to the fine print.
In that case, you can't have any objection
to Ensign Hanson signing them.
Where did you say his ship is?
- Bye, Arthur.
- Bye, sir.
Now, Lieutenant, look. I told you,
the Admiral wants those papers signed by-
- They will be. You got a pen?
- Yes, sir.
But they have to be signed
by the officer taking command.
I know that. Give me the pen.
Gosh, Lieutenant,
after the way you behaved this afternoon...
I wouldn't have thought a team of horses
could've gotten you on that ship.
Shut up.
Well, missión accomplished.
- Good work, Hanson.
- Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
I guess. Good night.
- Shark Bait, will you just try to stay with it?
- I'm sorry, Chief.
Good morning, sir.
Beautiful morning, Captain.
Horse.
You might have better luck... Chief.
You might have better luck with that thing
if you laid the gasket on the boom first.
- Yes, sir. Lay the...
- Gasket.
Under the foot of the sails there,
on the boom.
Yes, sir.
- Your coffee, sir.
- Thank you.
What was in that?
That was an egg, sir. And Mr...
I thought it'd settle the grounds, sir.
Something wrong with it?
Yeah. I thought I swallowed my tongue.
Mr. Hanson meant eggshells
in the bottom of the pot.
Not a raw egg in the cup.
What were you
before you entered the service?
I was a cook, sir. I've been one for years.
- I'll have another cup. With grounds.
- Yes, sir.
Shackle the foresheet to the traveler.
Good morning, sir.
This to that.
- This is supposed to be the winch?
- I beg your pardon, sir.
- Winch?
- Yeah.
No, sir. This is a spark plug, sir.
I was talking about the engine itself.
This is the power takeoff?
Beats me, sir.
Mr. Hanson just told me to get it running.
I see. What's your name?
Sparks, sir.
- Radioman, Second Class, sir.
- Yes, all radiomen are called Sparks.
I mean, what is your actual name?
That's it, sir. A.J. Sparks, Jr.
Funny, ain't it? I mean, being named Sparks
and making radioman.
It's very...
All I wanna know is
if this is the power takeoff?
I wrote my old man about it.
And he's A.J. Sparks, Sr.
But he darn near died laughing.
A fortunate thing he didn't.
Ship rigged and ready, sir. Request
permissión to send watch to breakfast.
I'd like to see the foresail set first, mister.
The foresail? Yes, sir.
Chief!
Set the foresail.
Aye, aye, sir. Stand by to set the foresail!
Chief, get a load of this.
- Man the fore halyards.
- Man the fore halyards!
- Stand by the foresheets.
- Stand by the foresheets!
Take this line and wrap it
a couple of times around the winch.
Get that line ready for running.
Come on. Get that other line clear.
Stand by to hoist away.
All hands, stand by to hoist away!
All hands, stand by to sink!
All right, break it up, you guys.
You got nothing to do?
Sir, the winch is still being repaired.
Shall we take it up manually?
No.
Have the men stand down.
I wanna talk to them.
Stand down.
Sir?
Stand easy.
That was pretty miserable, wasn't it?
No reason why it shouldn't be.
With the exception of
Mr. Hanson and myself...
none of you knows the slightest thing
about sailing.
Nobody expects you to.
However, this ship
sails for New Guinea Friday morning.
Once we're at sea,
any sailing order that isn't carried out...
sharply and efficiently
could cost any or all of you your lives.
Now, I can't make blue-water sailors
out of you overnight.
But you are all Navy men.
If you're willing to work 18 hours a day
for the next three days...
I think I can teach you enough to get by on.
But if you can't cut it...
if any one of you
thinks that he might endanger the lives...
of the rest of the members of this crew,
then put in for a transfer, and now.
There's no disgrace to it.
I'll be in my quarters for the next hour,
any man who wants to see me.
That's all. Dismissed.
Chief, I prefer that you
and Mr. Hanson remain on deck.
Let the men decide this for themselves.
What do we do if they all quit?
- Hello, Johnson.
- Yes, sir.
You didn't eat very much, sir.
I wasn't very hungry.
Not that there was
anything wrong with the food. I just...
Men eat yet?
Yes, sir. They ate real good.
- Kind of quiet, but real quick.
- What do you mean, "quiet"?
Sir, a couple of them said something about
seeing Mr. Hanson and the Chief.
They wanted to see Hanson and the...
Upper shroud, lower shroud, topping lift.
Jibstay, forestay, foremast, stow.
- How about that?
- Don't knock it. It works.
Gaff, foresail, gasket.
Callahan, standing or running rigging?
Blue standing, red running...
Running rigging, Chief.
Sheet or halyard? You.
Sheets, trims, sails, halyards, hoists.
Halyard, Chief.
- Which one?
- I don't know.
They'll know her by tomorrow, sir.
With your permissión, the crew'd like to
take another run at setting the foresail.
- Very well.
- Okay, Chief.
Aye, aye, sir. Stand by to hoist the foresail!
Shark Bait, throw up the...
- Gaskets.
Horse, stand by the foresheet.
Halyards to the winch!
Come on, you told me
you'd get that thing working.
Sure. When do you want it for?
Now, you idiot. You think you're back
in that service station?
Take up the slack.
- Set the foresail, Chief.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Stand by the mainsail. Engage the winch.
- Spark!
- I'm trying!
Hoist away!
Take it easy! You'll rip the mast out.
Slack it easy.
It's stuck. Heave!
It's stuck, sir.
- It's stuck, sir.
- Yeah.
Did you grease the mast? That's all it needs.
Don't worry about it.
You better bring it down.
Okay, slack it off and lower away.
Slack off and lower away!
It's still stuck. You get a man up on the rig
and kick the gaff jaws loose.
I'll go myself, sir.
One volunteer. You.
There's nothing to it, sailor.
- Yeah? Why don't you go?
- Move.
Can't we talk this over, Chief?
He's scared to death, sir.
If he doesn't do it here,
he'll never do it at sea.
Come on, boy. There's nothing to it.
You'll be all right, son.
Just take one step at a time, okay?
Take it easy. Now, don't look down!
Close your eyes.
Now, when you open them,
look straight ahead.
That's a boy. Just keep your eyes level...
and go on up one rung at a time.
You can do it.
That's it, sailor. Now, go ahead.
Now, I want you to go on up...
until you are level with the gaff jaws.
You know what they are?
- Yeah.
- All right.
When you get there, and when you're ready,
just reach out...
and see if you can kick them free
with your foot.
You understand?
That's the boy. When you feel it, I want
you to reach out with your right foot...
and kick the gaff jaws loose.
That's it. Reach out.
Don't look down!
Now, kick it loose.
Hook your foot in the shroud.
I can't.
Take another turn around that winch
and hold it fast.
Take it easy, kid, I'm coming.
I'm slipping. My hands are slipping. I'll fall.
Stop that! Wanna land on someone?
Got you.
Let go with your left hand.
Oh, boy.
I would've fell.
- lf you hadn't been here, I'd have let go.
- Never.
- Hang on, I'm going up and kick her free.
- Okay.
Hang on, kid.
All right, lower it away, Mr. Hanson. It's free.
All right, lower away, Chief.
Slow now, slow. Slow.
Pull what you got.
Wait for me!
That's my ship leaving.
Will you let me through, you guys?
That's my ship.
Wait a minute, boy.
What you got in the bag?
For Pete's sake, I'm gonna miss it.
It's leaving.
He's afraid of missing that?
Wait for me! Wait! Come on! Wait for me!
- I made it.
- Yeah. Nice going, sailor.
Now, bear a hand on the bowline.
We're just coming into the dock.
Say, you have got a few, haven't you?
He's a nut. But he's eager.
Here goes nothing.
- You'll be back before you know it.
- Just be sure I am.
The order's on my desk.
See they get processed, will you, beautiful?
Just pop them into that little lBM machine.
I'll square things with you
when I see you again next Friday night.
Are we getting
an lBM machine, Commander?
- My, that'd be-
- Yes, we might. Good luck, old boy.
Good landing.
You can take her on out now.
Aye, aye, sir. Stand by the line.
Not now, Johnson.
Chief, I want all this gear stowed
before we hit open sea.
Aye, aye, sir.
Come left, mister.
I said, come left.
You're cutting across the bow.
It's no use. She won't answer the helm.
Did you drop the centerboard?
Get up there and do it!
Go down and give me full speed astern.
- Sparks, back full quick!
- Back full, sir.
Not another one!
Come on with that centerboard!
Come on, you monster.
Centerboard down and locked, sir.
- Full speed astern, sir.
- Full speed ahead!
- Right, sir. Full ahead, sir!
Mister, will you get
a helmsman on that wheel...
and set sail, while I go below
and change my clothes?
Yes?
Shall I notify the Admiral's office
of the time of departure, sir?
Yes, please, Maggie.
While you're at it,
you might notify air-sea rescue...
to be on the lookout for a ship in distress.
- Now what?
- I think that Australian ship's saluting us.
They always cheered the Christians
before they threw them to the lions.
- You getting the sail up?
- Yes.
I'll be right up.
He's off to port.
- He's off to port.
- Sparks, kill that eggbeater.
- Yes, sir!
What are you doing here?
Thought you left an hour ago.
The weather report said winds
up to hurricane force in the Coral Sea.
I thought you might have a message.
- From that little boat, I mean.
- Ship.
They're under orders
not to break radio silence, remember?
You're really worried.
- Did you fall for that wild man?
- No.
Mind you, he was kind of cute.
Don't worry about him.
The rougher it is, the better he likes it.
He's having a ball out there.
Besides, the last aerial sighting
put them way up here.
They're probably beyond the storm
and just loafing along.
If I ever get my hands on that Vandewater...
Yes, sir?
Get this from the files immediately, please.
Now, then...
what's the report on that schooner
we sent to Moresby last week?
- The...
- Echo, sir.
She rode out a storm Tuesday night
and was sighted from the air yesterday.
From the position report,
they'll raise the New Guinea coast-
Don't guess, Commander. I want to know.
That ship is a vital part of joint operations.
- The Echo, sir?
- The Echo.
What do you know
about an officer named Foster?
Lt. Dennis M. Foster.
Why, nothing, sir. Should l, sir?
He's been assigned
to take the Echo to Cape Gloucester.
Cape Gloucester on New Britain, sir?
Why, that's enemy territory.
Very good, Vandewater.
It also happens to be an excellent place
to watch Japanese ship movements.
For the past six or seven months...
the Australians have had
a coast watcher there doing that.
Then, two weeks ago,
in the middle of a transmissión...
he went off the air.
Killed? Taken prisoner, sir?
I don't know.
But that's why the Echo
was sent to Moresby...
on a faint chance that it could take
in a replacement if everything else failed.
A sub couldn't drop the man off at night?
What was the Spearfish doing
in the Solomon sea last week?
Uncharted reefs will make it
impossible to get anywhere near the coast.
And an airdrop is out of the question.
No, it's got to be
a shallow draft vessel like the Echo.
The Australian replacement is in Moresby
waiting for the ship to arrive.
As soon as it does, this man Foster
is supposed to take command...
and try and make the run up
to Cape Gloucester.
I'd feel better if I knew more about him.
It's a ticklish job.
I'll get Lt. Foster's file out immediately.
I've got it right here.
He seems to be qualified,
and Capt. McClung picked him.
He commands port detachment of Moresby
and ought to know what he's doing.
He wants to hold Lt. Crandall
for a few days...
until Foster's familiar enough
with the ship to take over.
Tell him he can have Lt. Crandall
for as long as he likes.
Yes, sir.
Lt. Foster will not relieve Lt. Crandall...
until, in the opinion of the port captain...
Lt. Foster is fully qualified
to command the Echo.
That means I can hold Crandall here
as long as I like.
- That make you any happier about Foster?
- I've got nothing against the bloke.
He's just not the type
that I'd pick for a mate.
- He's a good officer.
- The best. A real sterling character.
But if you can have this Crandall bloke,
why can't he stay in command?
Because his job is to acquaint Foster
with the Echo, that's why.
Of course, we could try sending you
in again in another sub.
Now, wait a minute.
I'm crazy about Foster.
- Where is that flaming ship, anyway?
- Simmer down, Pat.
She'll be along.
On deck!
- What's that?
- I can make out a pier in the harbor, sir.
Nan. Easy. Roger. King.
That's her, Mr. Foster, the Echo.
I was afraid of that. A tub.
All right. Contact and please pass the word
to stand by for special instructions.
Aye, aye, sir.
There's a building at the shore end.
That must be the port detachment.
Fine. Sparks, ready on the engine.
Some navigation, mister.
Have the boatswain stand by to down sail.
- Sir!
- What's the trouble?
I wish I knew. I can't get it started.
I checked the ignition system,
the valves, the pumps.
- I'm going through the fuel lines.
- Can we take her in under canvas?
- No room to maneuver in there.
- We'd be going in in style.
In style?
As long as we don't end up on the beach.
How long is it gonna take you to fix it?
If I can find the trouble, not long.
But if I can't?
We have orders to get in as fast as we can.
Get with it.
Wipe that grin off your face.
This isn't as easy as it looks.
Keep the deck.
Hold that beacon in your port bow...
till I give the order to come about. Hold this.
No reason to get excited.
It's a tricky maneuver.
If you handle your duties as well
as you've been doing, we'll be all right.
There's one very important thing.
We'll be on the wind
when we fetch that dock.
I must come up fast, lose weight,
try to coast alongside, understand?
- When we start to luff-
- That's when the sails flap?
Right. I want every inch of canvas
down as fast as possible.
- Mister, stand by to come about.
- Man the sheets. Keep a close haul.
Tell the man up the crosstrees
to watch the gaff jaws.
- I don't want them sticking again.
- Aye, aye, sir. Guys, keep your eye on the-
- Somebody's firing at us.
- Over us, so far.
What did we do? Lose the war already?
- Who's responsible for firing on that ship?
- I was trying to warn them, sir.
They've not answered our transmissión
and don't know of harbor defenses.
She's already in the harbor!
Did it ever occur to you
she might be on a radio silence?
They're coming any minute.
Get down and warn him off.
Yes, sir.
- Where are you?
- I'm sorry, I can't get the engine started.
Get the transmitter.
I want to know who fired on us and why.
I can't do that either.
It doesn't put out without the engine.
- Sir!
- What?
There's a flashing light on the dock.
Take out the hand blinker.
Stand by to come about.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- All hands stand by to heave to.
- What's the matter with them?
- They're going right into it.
- Got them now, sir.
- Tell them.
What do you got?
"You are...
"approaching..."
Cancel it, they're already in it.
Tell them quick.
Cancelled. Restart, sir.
All they're telling us
is we're approaching a Navy dock.
"You are...
"in...
"a...
"fine...
- "area."
- lsn't that nice?
Must be the chamber of commerce.
What are they saying?
- Excuse me, sir. That "F" was an "M."
- That's different.
- "You are in a mine area."
- Mine area? Get directions, quick!
Lookout, keep your eyes peeled
for subsurface objects.
There's something there now, sir!
Dead ahead!
There they are! Two of them!
Dead ahead, sir!
- Orderly!
- Another one, sir. Off the port bow.
Man the back stage.
Go forward, get that centerboard up.
She won't answer the helm.
It won't make any difference
if we hit a mine. Go on.
- They request we move inshore, sir.
- Get back to that engine, quick.
Centerboard up and secured, sir.
Another one off the port bow, sir!
Another one at starboard.
They're out of it.
Tell them they're in the clear.
- We're all clear, sir.
- Roger.
On deck!
Low waters ahead, sir.
Lower away all sails, Tommy.
Drop that centerboard.
Sparks, put it forward.
Lower away all sails! Let's get this down.
The gaff jaws are stuck again.
Kick that gaff jaw free.
- Centerboard down, sir.
- Right!
You monster, come about.
- Sir, we're closing on the dock.
- What? Back full, Sparks!
Sir, we're gonna ram the dock.
No. Go forward and get ready
to let go of the anchor starboard.
Johnson, bear a hand on the anchor.
Cameo, grab that line.
Stop it up short. Tend that line.
Sparks, I said back full!
Excuse me, sir, she quit on me again.
Go forward and rig the fenders
on the port side.
Shark Bait, let go of the anchor
and hold it underfoot.
Man overboard!
Look out below!
Nice work, mister.
- What did you say, sir?
- I said, very nice.
Is that all for this performance,
or have you got an encore?
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
This is a centerboard ship-
A ship?
Why, I was under the impressión
that it was a USO Tour.
This is an official Navy ship, sir.
The crew is doing the best they could
under the circumstances.
This crew is doing the best they can?
I suggest you take this crew out
for about six months.
Who the hell do you think you're talking to?
This is my ship.
Anything this crew does is under my orders.
If you have any further remarks
about this ship or my crew...
you come aboard and make them to me.
- Throw the sails.
- Astern to.
Thank you for your invitation, Captain.
Since I'm relieving you,
that won't be necessary.
Whatever I have to say to this crew,
I'll say to them directly.
You're taking over?
As soon as you report your arrival
to the port captain.
I would be obliged
if you do that as quickly as possible.
Furl the sails.
Excellent, Lieutenant.
- At ease, please.
- Yes, sir.
You've done a remarkable job
bringing that ship up here.
Thank you, sir. I had a remarkable crew.
Yes, I saw them in action as you came in.
I'm sorry you won't be commanding them
on the missión.
Missión?
You don't think we brought that ship
up here just for the ride?
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
The missión is top secret.
You weren't informed, were you?
- No, sir.
- Come here.
Temporarily, the ship is being placed
at the disposal of the Air Force.
It's imperative that they get
one of their men ashore...
here on Cape Gloucester.
- ln New Britain? With the Echo?
- Yeah.
They seem to think
if she's disguised as a Navy training craft...
that she has a chance.
That's what they're doing to your ship now.
Camouflaging it.
And the Air Force will provide
what fighter cover they can.
Fortunately, that won't concern you, will it?
No, sir.
You've met your replacement, Lt. Foster?
- Yes, sir.
- Fine.
I have Admiral Hathaway's
permissión to hold you here...
until you can familiarize Foster with Echo.
- I know you're anxious to get back to town-
- That's all right.
It would take some time for the men
to get used to a new skipper.
It won't take more than 48 hours.
- I don't suppose you would be-
- Sir?
Yes, Davis, what is it?
Air Force reports enemy bombers
over the Solomon Sea.
They expect a raid in 20 to 25 minutes.
Mr. Patterson and the native corporal
are in the briefing room.
Shall I ask them to wait for the all clear?
- The Lieutenant and I will be over directly.
- Yes, sir.
Warn Echo. tell those
Air Force people to clear the dock.
Yes, sir.
They're going up to make the intercept.
Our ClC Room is over here.
Bogie 1 appears to be splitting.
Designated raids. One Abel and one Baker.
One Baker.
055. 43.
We know there's a convoy
building up here over BAM.
I'm fairly certain it'll take off
in the next 10 days...
run along the north coast of New Britain
and land troops either here at Madang...
or down here at Lae.
Lae, they'll land at Lae.
They'd be a month
coming over land from Madang.
We also know
that they'll be making a grave tactical error...
Mr. Patterson, that's right.
No Navy man would risk putting ships
through narrow straits like that.
They'd be a sitting duck
during an aerial attack.
- lsn't that right, sir?
- Absolutely, Lieutenant.
What Patterson is thinking of, though...
is this weather front
that's moving in from the central Pacific.
By the end of the week,
this whole area will be socked in so tight...
there won't be any chance
for aerial observation.
That's why it's so vital...
to get Pat in there to take the place
of that coast watcher...
who disappeared.
Tom Evans. Wasn't that his name?
Yeah.
Then we can hope, with Pat's help,
to get a visual sighting from the land.
Would it be difficult to drop Mr. Patterson
and the corporal by parachute?
If you ask me, it'd be flaming impossible.
I'd as soon go in with a brass band
and a neon light on my hat.
Besides, I don't like airplanes.
- Or air raids, either. Goodbye, all.
- Stick around a few minutes.
They'll be concentrating on the airstrips.
Yeah, and they might miss, too.
Don't you get any wrong ideas
about Patterson, Lieutenant.
If it weren't for him and the Australian
coast watchers who hid in the jungle...
when the Japanese occupied these islands,
we'd be in a bad way.
Both here and in the Solomons.
Patterson and that native corporal of his...
have spent the last six months
right here in the hills...
constantly in danger
from Japanese patrols...
and just as constantly sending us
our vital information.
So don't-
Now, they're entitled to sit this one out, son.
One Baker. 050.
One Baker should be overhead
in two minutes.
Very well.
You have air cover
as far as the Trobriands here.
Across the Solomon Sea,
you'll just have to pray...
that the enemy thinks
you're a native trading vessel.
That'll be two, maybe three days.
Right, Crandall?
I'm sorry, sir. This is the first time
my crew's been under fire.
I'm afraid it won't be the last.
No, sir. Let me see, three days, you say?
If you took off from here at dusk, and
you were sharp on celestial navigation...
it could be two nights and a day.
Foster is a qualified navigator.
Thank you, sir.
You have a few days
to acquaint him with the ship's peculiarities.
That won't be necessary. Thank you.
If this weather front does move down,
you'll have to do some dead reckoning.
Why don't you let me worry about that?
Pardon me,
but they're swinging in over the harbor.
Everybody but the duty section
should be in the slit trenches.
- What?
- Your own orders, sir.
Welcome to the club.
- Where's he going?
- To be with his ship, I imagine.
Quite a bloke, that Crandall.
Duck!
The port captain's here, skipper.
- Kind of soggy out, isn't it, Crandall?
- Yes, sir.
We could run up the coast for a few miles.
I can show the Lieutenant
how the ship handles.
That won't be possible now.
The size of that air raid shows
the Japanese are building up to something.
Air Force wants Echo underway
as soon as possible.
I see, sir.
Get underway as soon as
you've accomplished the transfer.
Bring your papers to my office.
We'll see about arranging air transport
for you to Australia.
Yes, sir.
After you, Captain.
Yes, come in, Crandall.
What're you doing here?
Why aren't you underway?
I request you to order Lt. Crandall...
to turn over the Echo to me
without further delay.
He's got me signing for equipment
I can't even find. He's...
Sir, he's getting underway.
He is?
No. He wouldn't do a thing like that.
Sir, he must be.
No, really?
He's taking it out himself, sir. See?
Yes, he is, isn't he?
My ship in that minefield again.
He knows where those mines are now.
Aren't you going to order him back, sir?
The Air Force would demand
an explanation...
for the delay, and-
Sir, this is a court-martial offense.
- What, Lieutenant?
- I said this is a court-martial offense, sir.
Yes, I guess you're right.
Still, he was assigned to me
for an indefinite period.
For as long as I needed him.
I'll tell you what I'll do, Lieutenant.
If he ever comes back from that missión...
I'll consider a court-martial.
Yes, sir.
This channel of yours
is less than 100 feet wide.
Is that the only break in the reef?
The only one I know of,
and I've covered over 100 miles of it.
- On deck!
- What is it?
Another enemy aircraft
on the starboard quarter...
closing in on us, sir.
You'd better get below, sir.
Same order stands!
Don't fire unless they fire first!
Hold fire.
Drop dead, you creeps.
- Blow a couple of gaskets!
- Yeah.
Looks okay, sir. They're waving back.
Dogs.
I hope that's the last of them.
This thing's starting to itch.
It is. With that weather front coming,
be lucky to make home.
Flaming shame if we didn't.
Run forward and tell cook
to barbecue poultry for dinner.
We need a decent meal for tonight's work.
We'll hit that front in one hour.
By midnight, it'll be darker
than 3-4 feet down a cow's throat.
- How will we see the reef?
- Nothing to it.
You can hear the surf pounding
on the reef for miles.
Fine. How do we know
how much water's under us?
That depends on the size
of the waves, don't it?
Don't worry, I can take you through there
with my head in a bag.
Yeah, you may have to.
Yeah?
Thanks for trying anyhow, Major.
Yeah, I'll be seeing you sometime soon.
No, sir.
He checked every squadron
that had a plane in the area today.
That's absolutely the last time
she was seen by anybody.
But that was at dawn this morning.
By late afternoon,
they should've been somewhere up here.
What about that observation flight
sent from there?
Canceled due to the weather.
You can bet the Japs
didn't cancel that convoy.
If we'd just gotten that ship underway
one day sooner.
Lower away all sails.
Stand by the engine.
I want full power going over that reef.
Tommy, take the deck.
Where did you say this inlet was?
- Straight ahead. Through those trees.
- Right.
At least the Air Force has been up here.
They sure worked that one over.
I guess so, sir.
Lead him.
I can knock that teacup
right out of his dukes.
Don't.
He may have friends,
like about 200,000 of them.
Just keep your eye on them. Don't get itchy.
You were going to glide
through the jungle like a ghost.
- This looks like Hannibal crossing the Alps.
- Take off.
I'm gonna be here a long time.
I like my comfort now and then.
You've enough for a hotel.
How far do the men have to lug this stuff?
The other side of that little hill up there.
I'll hide this stuff there
till I'm ready to move on.
It'll take them hours to get up there.
What am I to do?
Wait here like a sitting duck?
Who's gonna know?
You're tucked in here real nice and cozy.
The Japanese Navy never spotted you,
did they?
- Where are you going?
- You have to stay on the ship, sir.
- There has to be an officer with the patrol.
- Why don't you let the kid go?
Give him a chance to stretch his legs
and look at the countryside.
- Hanson, come-
- Thanks for the boat ride.
- I'll radio your regards to Capt. McClung.
- Thanks.
- I'll bring them back safe and sound.
- You better, or don't come back yourself.
On the bow.
- How do my men find their way back here?
- No problem.
Those masts of yours
stick up like a lighthouse in the fog.
Good on you, mate.
You.
Get out of here with those whites.
They'll spot you for two miles.
Come on.
Must have jumped him without his knowing.
- I'll have the boys dig a-
- Leave him.
Leave everything just where it is.
I can't have them know I'm here.
He had no family that I know of, Chief.
Quicker I'm out of this, the better I'll like it.
Let's go.
- A little different up here.
- It's beautiful.
- It's hard to believe.
- Your first stiff, kid?
- Yeah.
- There'll be a lot more of them.
No cup of tea, this war.
Chief...
Goroka will show you
where to dig my stuff in.
You'll have no trouble
finding your way back.
You've left a trail
as wide as George Street, Sydney.
- Will it give you away?
- No, it grows over in a day.
By tonight, we'll be a long way from here.
You're gonna stay down there
in the jungle?
Till the Japs get me.
Or our blokes come down
and run them out of here.
Don't worry about it.
Just reckon I'm crazy enough
to get a kick out of it.
That don't mean I wanna stay here for ever.
You do your best to keep the Navy moving.
Goroka, we go along now.
- Stay awake.
- I'm awake.
Give me some air, will you?
Coffee, skipper?
Shark Bait...
secure that boom crutch.
I want to move fast when they get back.
Yes, sir.
The crew will finish up.
There's nothing left
but pulling some brush over.
We'll be ready by the time you cool off.
You went to the wrong school, sir.
- Officers ain't supposed to work so hard.
- I needed it.
Chief, come here.
That's it, the Japanese convoy.
Lucky we got the old man
up here when we did.
He's still down in the jungle.
He can't possibly see it.
We've got to get back to the ship.
- All right, guys. Let's haul it.
- Come on, let's go.
Get going.
Sir, so the war lasts five minutes longer.
It'll be dark in an hour.
- Can I help you?
- I'm all right.
Sir, I saw the mast. They're right below us.
Go ahead.
Last time I ran like this,
four MPs were on my tail.
Rip! Listen up!
Wait a minute.
- Rip?
- Yeah, come in, kid.
We saw the convoy. It was...
Let him talk. Makes no difference now.
Tommy, I'd like you to meet
Capt. Shigetsu. UCLA, '38.
Bachelor of Science in Horticulture.
So, you saw our convoy?
Move over there where I can watch you.
- Not now, kid.
- No, later.
As you were saying, you saw our convoy.
Where were you
and what were you doing when you saw it?
My name is Thomas Hanson,
Ensign, United States Naval Reserve.
No use.
The good captain was just reminding me...
that Japan is not a signatory
of the Geneva Convention.
It really makes no difference.
We can classify you as a spy.
This is an aerial photograph...
taken of this ship
in the Solomon Sea yesterday.
You certainly weren't in uniform then.
Shall we get back to details of the missión?
Let's get back to the Rose Bowl game.
Okay, but Maj. Samada's gonna ask you
the same questions.
- Very educated man, the Major.
- Really? I'm Stanford myself.
In that case, it'll be my pleasure
to assist the Major in his questioning.
He's a big one.
I thought they were all little jokers.
Shut up.
What happened to you clowns? Asleep?
They were on us like tents.
We didn't have a chance.
It's for me. I'll get it.
Real brass.
Lay you eight-to-five he braces the sergeant.
- You'll rise when the Major enters.
- Sure, we will.
- You better.
- Okay.
Do me a favor.
It's there, right there. That's it.
I don't think they'd look good here
with the Major coming down.
Thank you.
Close the door.
I won't tell you anything more!
Good boy. Get the guns.
Get below. Prime that engine.
Give me back full when I yell.
- You want these?
- There are too many.
- What're you gonna do?
- Like I know! Get on the engine.
Chief, look aft.
Sarge.
Didn't I meet you in Singapore once?
I remember, you used to hang out
at that high-kickers club...
in Saigon, huh?
Duck!
Go, Tommy! Give it full,
and get up here on this machine gun!
Sparks, on the engine.
Chief, drop the centerboard.
Give me full ahead.
Duck!
See if you can get that machine gun nest.
Hang on to that gun, kid. Here we go.
You could've bet me we wouldn't make it.
Sorry, sir.
The engine flooded out going over the reef.
- Who needs it? Stand by to make sail.
- Aye, aye, sir!
Get this overboard
so we can raise the mainsail.
Port Moresby trying to reach us, sir.
Good. Get on that thing
and tell him what you saw.
- I can't transfer without the engine, sir.
- Fix it.
Look out, Rip!
Don't shoot.
Keep going.
- Rip, you all right?
- Are you kidding? I can't...
Move. Just make one little move.
Johnson, get the aid kit.
Let him handle it, sir.
- I can transmit now, sir.
- We'll contact them.
- lf you do, you kill your captain-
- Shut up, you crumb.
What do you mean?
You're still within range
of the shore battery.
The second you start transmitting,
they'll blow you out of the water.
Surrender. Your captain will be hospitalized.
- We have excellent Japanese doctors.
- Sir.
- Send it.
- It's insane.
You'll all be killed.
Can you stand by and let them destroy you?
- Let me plug him, sir.
- Shut up.
Enemy convoy seen
north of Cape Gloucester.
What's the matter with you,
you got four thumbs?
I told you so.
At 1600, heading west.
- Break out the life raft, Chief.
- Yes, sir.
Message received, sir.
Get that life raft over the side!
- How's he doing?
- I'm okay. Let's get out of here.
We're hit in the forward hull.
We're taking water fast.
- You abandon ship.
- Abandon ship!
Come on.
Aren't you gonna stay
and die for the rising sun?
You out of your mind?
He's got a pretty high fever, sir.
Can still fire flares.
Japanese nurses very good.
One more crack out of you
and you're in the water.
Sir, I hear a plane.
There it is!
It's a PBY.
Looks like UCLA blew another one.
On this same morning of 3 March...
projecting the course of the enemy convoy
from the slim information received...
the Allied forces in New Guinea put every
available aircraft in the air...
met the Japanese ships
and their air cover in the straits...
between New Guinea and New Britain...
and in a two-day running battle,
wreaked total destruction on it.
Of this little-known,
yet highly decisive battle...
Gen. Douglas MacArthur said:
"The battle of the Bismarck Sea
won a victory of such completeness...
"as to assume the proportions
of a major disaster to the enemy. "
And so it is recorded
in the history of Worid War II.
Of considerably less importance...
yet of vital interest to us...
is the fact that six months later...
in what was now
just a quiet backwater in the rear area...
a newly promoted Lt. J. G.
pulled alongside his first command...
and prepared to take over.
Belay that racket.
You want the whole area to hear us?
As a matter of fact, sir, yes.
- Stations for getting underway.
- Weigh her to side!
What did you say about going ashore
and speaking to the Admiral?
You weren't interested
in any more special missions.
I can let the man talk, can't l?