(HORSE WHINNYING)
(MAN SPEAKING GERMAN)
(MAN GRUNTS)
- SERGEANT: Permission to enter?
- CAPTAIN: Come.
SERGEANT: Where's the rest
of the company, captain?
Where do you think?
Moved out with the battalion.
I've been waiting here for you.
- You took your time getting back.
- I got lost in the smoke.
CAPTAIN: What happened to your gun?
Have you ever seen a
shell-shocked horse?
He stomped all over me and got my
rifle, knocked it to smithereens.
Well, I suppose horses have as much right
to go crazy in this war as men have.
SERGEANT: Oh.
What do you think?
CAPTAIN: What the hell is it?
SERGEANT: It's a "one."
First Infantry Division.
The Red One. You think General
Pershing will like it?
- Oh, sure.
- Got the idea from a cap of a Hun I killed.
- When?
- Oh, about an hour ago.
Did he yell out anything?
Well, the same old kaiser stuff, you
know, "The war is over," all that junk.
- Finish it.
- Sir?
Finish it.
The armistice was signed
at 11:00 this morning.
The war's been over for four hours.
Well, you didn't know it was over.
SERGEANT: He did.
ZAB: A quarter of a century
later, that piece of red cloth...
from the dead Hun's hat had
become famous all over the world.
It was the insignia of the
1st Infantry Division.
The Fighting First,
the Big Red One.
Twenty-four years later, the Big Red
One was fighting the Krauts again.
It was World War II this time.
We were invading North Africa.
SERGEANT: Hey, Griff.
Great! Thanks, sergeant.
ZAB: We were his rifle squad.
First Squad, 1st Platoon,
I Company, 16th Infantry.
He called us his wet-noses.
Griff, he was a hell
of a sharpshooter.
Johnson was a pig farmer
with hemorrhoids.
Vinci was a street kid who played hot jazz
on the saxophone, and that's me, Zab.
I thought I was the
Hemingway of the Bronx.
You really a book writer?
- Yeah.
- What book did you write?
The Dark Deadline.
- Never heard of it.
- Never read it.
It's an unpublished mystery novel.
I left it with my mother.
Why's a book writer a rifleman?
To come out with a war novel,
meathead. Why else, huh?
What about you, Griff?
You gonna be a cartoonist...
- ...for a big newspaper or something?
- Mm-hm.
Say, Griff. You do
everything left-handed?
Everything but shoot.
And play with my pecker.
(LAUGHING)
"Watch out, Vichy.
Here comes the Big Red One."
Vichy?
I always thought Vichy was
some kind of soda pop.
No. Vichy's the French,
fighting on Hitler's side.
Yeah, that's why we're wearing these
so they don't shoot Americans, huh?
We dropped leaflets so
they know we're coming.
But if they start a fight,
we'll have to kill them.
ZAB: We were in this war to
fight Germans, not Frenchmen.
We were kind of hoping they
were feeling the same way.
Put your rubbers on and
keep the salt water out.
Thanks, Griff.
I'll bet the guy that
invented these...
- ...never figured they'd be used on a rifle.
- I never could screw with them.
- How about you, Johnson?
- Not me.
ZAB: Over on the Algerian beach, French
soldiers were reading our leaflets...
and also wondering if
they were gonna fight.
The colonel is stupid not
to believe these leaflets.
We are no good. You,
me, all of us here.
Defending this miserable Algerian beach
for Marshal Pétain and Adolf Hitler.
I can't kill an American.
ZAB: There were four things
you could hear on the boat:
The waves, the engines...
an occasional muffled prayer...
and the sound of 50 guys all
heaving their guts out.
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH OVER P.A.)
MAN (OVER P.A.): French troops,
don't shoot. We are Americans.
Don't shoot. We come to fight Hitler,
not to fight with you. Don't shoot.
BROBAN: Hold your fire!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Yes, colonel.
- Open fire.
Not on Americans.
(GUN FIRING)
(GUNS FIRING)
AMERICAN SOLDIER 1: Medic! Medic!
ZAB: Nail him, Griff!
How the hell could you miss him?
Hell, he was close enough
to kiss on both cheeks.
What the hell's the matter with you?
I never saw you miss.
AMERICAN SOLDIER 2:
Medic! Over here.
(CHAPIER SPEAKING FRENCH OVER P.A.)
AMERICAN SOLDIER 3:
Sixteenth Infantry, hold your fire!
CHAPIER:
Americans, this is Captain Chapter.
General Tavernier is dead.
Americans! I surrender
my troops to your hands.
AMERICAN SOLDIER 3: Frenchmen,
we do not accept your surrender.
You surrender only to the enemy.
If you're Vichy, fight us.
If you're Frenchmen, join us!
(CHEERING)
ZAB: We were feeling cocky as hell.
Except Griff.
In the middle of the
battle, he froze.
It got to Griff.
He kept away from the rest of us.
Nobody wanted to use the
word "coward," not yet.
How come we're not pushing inland?
SERGEANT: Red Company's carrying
the ball. Take your malaria pills.
I wonder what they gave you in the
other war not to get a hard-on?
The same stuff you're wolfing
down now. It has saltpeter.
Griff's back.
I can't murder anybody.
We don't murder, we kill.
It's the same thing.
The hell it is, Griff.
You don't murder
animals, you kill them.
ZAB: The truth is, none of us had the
faintest idea what war was all about.
We hadn't met the Krauts yet.
(GERMAN SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
GERD: Communications Center
caught an American bomb.
These wet-noses found the phonograph
and one record undamaged.
Look at the faces of these
puppies, Schroeder.
They think the Horst
Wessel song is so...
Horst Wessel was a pimp who supplied
Hitler with baby faces like you.
He was killed in a brawl,
over a whore in Berlin.
(LAUGHING)
A poem by a pimp became the
hymn of Hitler's party.
Is that right, Schroeder?
Don't want to disillusion
these infants, huh?
You're getting soft.
Schroeder used to be tough. In Libya,
I saw him murder a German officer.
I didn't murder him,
Gerd, I killed him...
when he ran from a fight
with the British.
Murder. Killed.
It's the same thing.
We don't murder the enemy, we kill.
Everything is on the move.
Battalion is sending us
to the Kasserine Pass.
- We're going to choke on panzer fumes.
- Not me, Schroeder.
Let Rommel's panzer grenadiers
march behind those tanks.
But not me. I want no more.
I'm no damn Nazi fanatic like you.
Germany is through
singing for Adolf Hitler.
(GUN FIRING)
ZAB: Our brilliant
generals had figured...
that Rommel's push would come
at a place called Speava...
so they massed most of the
Allied forces over there.
But they sent our regiment
around the back way...
through a shit-hole called
the Kasserine Pass.
Our squad was on point.
We got an eyeful, all right.
The whole damned Afrika Korps was
coming through the Kasserine Pass.
Rommel had caught us
with our pants down.
SERGEANT: We got tanks, boys,
and infantry with them.
They'll be looking behind the rocks
for antitank guns, so let's go!
- ZAB: Oh, shit.
- SERGEANT: Let's go.
GRIFF: Sergeant, where are we gonna
run to? They'll spot us out in the open.
SERGEANT: We're not
running, we're digging in.
GRIFF: Digging in?
Are you crazy, sergeant?
SERGEANT: All right. Dig in and
let them roll over our heads.
GRIFF: Hey, they're
going off to the right!
ZAB: Guess again, jerk-off.
Look over there.
Jeez.
GRIFF:
Tanks! They're all over the place!
The war is over for you.
We won.
You lost.
You are in a temporary German
hospital in Tunis, sergeant.
Our doctors are very impressed
with your recovery.
You should be dead.
(SIREN WHIRRING)
We'd better get out of here.
You heard what that orderly said.
This is an unmarked hospital,
and they'd just as soon blast us.
Anybody here from the Big Red One?
SERGEANT: Sixteenth.
Eighteenth!
Where's that Big Red One man?
SERGEANT:
What happened at the pass?
You with the 16th?
You one of them goons?
SERGEANT: I Company, 3rd Battalion.
What are you doing wrapped
up in that Arab bed sheet?
- What happened at the pass?
- We counterattacked after you jokers ran.
We took Kasserine, Gafsa,
El Guettar, Tunis.
- We ran Rommel right out of Africa.
- You mean the Big Red One took Tunis.
We sure as hell did.
This is Tunis.
(GUNS FIRING)
You're right.
We took Tunis.
ZAB: The old bastard just
couldn't face being left behind.
He heard we were shipping
out to invade Sicily.
Where's the 1st Squad?
ZAB: Out of the original
12-man rifle squad...
the four of us were
the only ones left.
This invasion wasn't gonna
be like North Africa.
The beach would be
heavily defended.
So now at least, we could all go
to Sicily and get killed together.
(SERGEANT WHISTLES)
I gave the supply
officer a Luger for it.
By the way, what were you
doing in that Arab bed sheet?
They were shanghaiing
all the combats...
and noncoms and training
replacements for those rebel devils.
Where'd you steal it, stupe?
SHEP: My name's Shep, not "stupe." I got
it from the St. George Hotel in Algiers.
I understand you're
an Italian, Vinci.
How come they let a wop
in this man's Army?
I don't think a wop's
gonna fight a wop.
I think all you'll do is drink dago
red and sing "O Sole Mio."
(LAUGHS)
(SINGING "O SOLE MIO")
I like "O Sole Mio."
(GUNS FIRING)
ZAB: The creepy thing about battle
is that you always feel alone.
All you can see are the
guys right next to you...
and the bodies you
keep tripping over.
VINCI: Why are we always sent out?
It's the only damn squad
in the whole U.S. Army?
- ZAB: Where's the rest of the Army?
- SERGEANT: There are eight patrols...
checking the villages
for diehard snipers.
Anybody wants to transfer,
just let me know.
VINCI: I want to transfer.
SERGEANT: Okay, Vinci.
You're transferred to the point.
ZAB: You know how you
smoke out a sniper?
You send a guy out in the open
and you see if he gets shot.
They thought that one
up at West Point.
- ZAB: Are you okay, sergeant?
- SERGEANT: Why?
- You just let Vinci walk into a sniper.
- That's why he's here.
We got plenty of
wet-noses here too.
You really want to finish
that book, don't you?
That's why I'm here.
SERGEANT: Vinci made it.
Come on, Carlos, your turn.
Let's go. Come on!
(GUNS FIRING)
- Hey, Vinci?
- VINCI: Ho!
You know where he lives!
VINCI: Work to your right,
I'll go left. It's your ball.
Bravo! Bravo!
- You had him in the sights all the time.
- All the time.
You just wanted to see me sweat.
It's punishment for transferring me to the
point. May I rejoin the rear echelon now?
You are transferred
back to the point.
JOHNSON: Oh, my aching butt.
ZAB: By now, we'd come to
look at all replacements...
as dead men who temporarily had
the use of their arms and legs.
They came and went so
fast and so regular...
that sometimes we didn't even
get to know their names.
Truth is, after a while we sort
of avoided getting to know them.
I... I brought some water.
Do you know what they call you
four guys down at Battalion?
Sergeant's Four Horsemen.
I don't get it. You guys
lived through North Africa.
You didn't even get a scratch.
That's because replacements
keep getting hit instead of us.
You think...? You think
maybe I'll get it?
Why not? You something special?
I'll go get some, all right?
I'll... Excuse me.
Water.
You'll live, Smitty. You
did tripwire the mine.
They're not designed to kill
you, just to castrate you.
Castrate me?!
Hey, here it is. I found it.
- Oh, my God!
- It's just one of your balls, Smitty.
You can live without it.
That's why they gave you two.
SERGEANT: They're supposed
to be coming this way.
Hold it up.
I said, hold it up!
I'm eating.
Okay, let's try this.
Come on.
- VINCI: Keep an eye peeled for snakes.
- ZAB: Yeah, and bats.
VINCI: Bats? I love bats.
ZAB: Sergeant, what's the
word from Headquarters?
JOHNSON:
Yeah, what did the lieutenant say?
The lieutenant said that Hermann Goring's
panzers overran the 2nd Battalion.
If they break through
the division...
we're in the sea.
- ZAB: Where are they headed?
- VINCI: Right for us.
Our big guns will clobber them.
- They're still on the water.
- None of them have unloaded yet?
Not yet.
Patton's got tanks.
Still on the water.
ZAB: Jesus. We're sitting
in our own coffin.
ZAB:
We knew he wanted to run for it...
but we knew he wouldn't...
way before he did.
Anyway, the sergeant would've
shot him if he tried it.
(TANK APPROACHING)
(WHISPERING) He's taking a piss.
(EXPLOSIONS)
ZAB: Those American guns? I thought
they were still on the water.
SERGEANT:
It beats the hell out of me.
(GUNS FIRING)
- Relays! Relays!
- VINCI: Come on, relays!
SERGEANT: Radio!
Lieutenant. Yeah, 1st
Squad, 1st Battalion.
You're kidding.
Yes, sir!
You know who fired that artillery?
The United States Navy.
That was the crews of Savannah
miles offshore, all right?
Right. Can you believe that?
The U.S. Navy saved our ass.
Hey, where's our planes?
Why can't they spot that gun?
I don't know, but Battalion's got 20 patrols
out looking for it in this quadrant.
- They think it's an SP.
- ZAB: So why send us?
JOHNSON: That's right.
We got a break coming.
ZAB: The Army's made of the 1st
Division and 10 million replacements.
- Where the hell are they?
- Being stuffed with mattress covers.
Five to 10, when we get off this island,
we'll get our feet wet invading Italy.
You don't know geography well
for a writer. We're in Italy.
VINCI: No, this is Sicily. Here they
say, "I'm a Sicilian," not an Italian.
My old man was bo... Whoa!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS WITH JOY)
I figure close to 2500 bucks!
I'm sending every lira home.
Mussolini money's
good for one thing.
It's Victor Emanuel loot.
It's kosher.
- Who told you that?
- The captain.
Enlisted man can't send
home more than his pay.
- That's to discourage black marketing.
- But the lieutenant can.
It's for my old man.
Always wanted his own bagel shop.
- I didn't know bagels were Italian.
- Sure they are.
The pope eats gefilte
fish on Friday, don't he?
(MULE WHINNYING)
VINCI: It's his mother. He's
hauling her to the beach.
- SERGEANT: Tell him We'll bury her.
- VINCI: I did.
He'll put her next to his father.
She's decomposing already.
The sun's blowing her up.
(MISSILE WHOOSHING)
(EXPLOSION)
We've gotta find that SP.
Ask if he knows where the gun is.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Hell, he doesn't know what an SP is.
- You Knucklehead.
Tell him it's a self-propelled
gun with wheels.
He knows where it is.
The smart aleck wants to
make a business deal.
Shell out some bagel money.
He'll take us to the gun...
we get an ambulance to take
her to the cemetery in Gela.
He wants a casket for
his mother to sleep in.
And it's gotta have four handles.
All right, he'll get it.
Tell him we'll leave her in the wagon in
the shade if he leads us to that gun.
Either we take her with us or
we find that gun on our own.
JOHNSON: Boy! I don't know how long
I'm gonna be able to take this stink.
VINCI: Can it, Johnson, will you?
Talking about it only makes it worse.
(GUNS FIRING IN DISTANCE)
ZAB: Hey, sergeant.
Think this kid is leading
us into a bushwhack?
SERGEANT: Well, we're getting
closer to some kind of gun.
ZAB:
Can you see what it is, sergeant?
SERGEANT:
Yeah, it's an 88 all right.
On a Tiger tank, in a house.
They got women working
in front of her...
under a Schmeisser.
Yeah, makes a nice, peaceful
picture from the air.
What's-your-name, you stay behind.
When you hear us fire, you
take out the Schmeisser.
(MAN SPEAKING GERMAN)
(MOUTHING WORDS)
(LAUGHING)
(CHEERING)
ZAB: Those Sicilian women
cooked us a terrific meal.
Too bad they were all over 50.
We were more horny
than we were hungry.
A little mothering is good in any
war, but this beats them all.
There's not a man in
the whole village.
- Hey, Vinci.
- Ho.
Tell Matteo the meat wagon
is on its way for his mother.
Oh, and that the general is sending up a
casket, silk-lined, with six handles on it.
VINCI: Matteo! Matteo!
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
All right, Matteo,
it's okay. Thank you.
I told you, kid, a deal's a deal, right?
That's all right. That's okay.
No, no, no. I'm mucho gordo,
huh? That's okay.
Thanks a lot. You're
okay, Matteo, any time.
ZAB: It was the first time in ages
that we had all felt really good.
It lasted about an hour.
Then we got our orders to move out.
Where's my helmet?
The Krauts are gonna spot
that garden a mile away.
I like the smell.
ZAB:
North Africa was sand and rocks.
Sicily was rocks and sand.
England was green.
We hung around England for seven
months getting ready for D-Day.
Give me back my doughnut.
Then one day, we were
in the boats again.
LEMCHEK: How about it, Johnson?
- Who are you?
- I'm Lemchek.
Lemchek, remember? We been on
dry runs for this invasion...
for seven months in
England. I'm Lemchek.
How about what?
Will you swap with me?
Nope. Eleven is my lucky number.
Try Vinci, he might do it.
- VINCI: Do what?
- Hey, listen.
Swap numbers in the
Bangalore Relay with me.
My number two for your number 10.
- How much?
- Ten thousand dollars.
Ten thousand dollars! Where the
hell are you gonna get $10,000?
It's from my GI insurance.
I'll make you my beneficiary.
- Can you do that?
- Hey, I could put Eisenhower down...
for my beneficiary. I can
put down anybody I want.
Oh, Lumnuts, I am really shocked.
You know, you told me your
mother was your beneficiary.
What's the matter? Don't
you love your mother?
- I love my mother.
- Sure. I love my mother.
Sure, sure, I love my mother.
But she ain't number
10 on the relay.
Swap with him. He gets
hit, you get 10 grand.
- What if I get hit using number two?
- Ten thousand will buy a lot of bagels.
No, I like my number 10,
like Griff likes number eight.
Zab, nine. Johnson, 11.
The sergeant, 12.
It's bad luck to change numbers.
Don't worry, Lemchek,
you'll make it. You know why?
Only be dead Germans on that beach.
- Yeah.
- That's right.
- You sure? I mean, are you really sure?
- Sure, I'm sure.
You don't think I wanna
blow $10,000, do you?
He don't wanna blow 10,000.
Relax, Lemchek. You heard
what the captain said.
It's a couple of schnell battalions,
combat rejects defending the beach...
at Colleville-sur-Mer.
(GUNS FIRING)
First Squad!
First Squad, over here.
(EXPLOSIONS)
GRIFF: Son of a bitch.
SERGEANT:
This beach hasn't been touched.
Either our shells and bombs fell too
far inland or in the English Channel.
Vinci!
It's Lemchek.
You just blew 10,000 bucks.
Hey, throw me his helmet.
SERGEANT: Second Squad!
Those combat rejects sure
know how to lay down fire.
Those aren't rejects up there.
That's infantry.
ZAB: We couldn't move forward,
we couldn't move back.
Exit E-1 was blocked by a
huge barbed-wire tank trap.
Our Navy was supposed to shell it,
our planes were supposed to bomb it...
our bazooka teams were
supposed to blow it up.
If all else failed, we were the
last resort: the Bangalore Relay.
First Squad! First Squad!
Bangalore teams two and
three knocked out!
- What about our bazooka team?
- Dead.
- Bazooka team?!
- SOLDIER: Killed.
- Break them out!
- ZAB: Naturally, all else failed.
The Bangalore torpedo was 50 feet long
and packed with 85 pounds of TNT...
and you assembled it
along the way, by hand.
I'd love to meet the
asshole who invented it.
Ready!
Number one.
- Number two.
- SOLDIER: Dead!
Number three.
Number four.
Number five.
Six.
- Number seven.
- Dead!
Number eight.
ZAB: You'd better make it, Griff, you son
of a bitch, because my number's up next!
Nine!
Hang on.
Come on.
SERGEANT: Zab, tell the colonel.
Tell the colonel his
Exit E-1 is open.
Hey! Layton, 2nd Division, right?
Denham, 29th. Get some
coffees, boys, doughnuts.
We'll chew the fat later.
ZAB: Hey, come on. Throw the ball.
(JET ENGINE WHIRRING)
Just another buzz bomb
headed for London.
- Buzz bomb?
- Yeah, V-1 rocket.
How do you like the book?
- Damn good.
- Hey.
My mother sent it to
me for my birthday.
I'm Zab.
- Welcome to the 1st Squad.
- I'm Kaiser.
Nice to meet you, Kaiser.
That's my book.
- Your book?
- Yeah.
What do you mean, your book? I got
this from the Repple-Depple in St-Lo.
I wrote it, baby face.
And I printed it.
SCHROEDER: You, I don't want any
infantry around the panzer.
Put that dead panzer gunner
hanging halfway out the hatch.
Second radio man, here,
behind that man.
Put yourself in a good position.
ZAB: As we slogged through the
hedgerows and across France...
the sergeant began keeping to
himself. It was a little spooky.
He told Vinci he fought
around here in the first war.
He kept ahead as if looking
for some old ghost...
to rise up out of the mist.
Kaiser, your turn at bat.
JOHNSON: Would you look how
fast they put up the names...
of all our guys who got killed.
SERGEANT:
That's a World War I memorial.
JOHNSON:
But the names are the same.
They always are.
SCHROEDER: Enemy scout advancing.
SCHROEDER (OVER RADIO):
Give him a round-trip ticket.
I don't want any of you to
be where I didn't plant you.
No fingers on triggers.
One shot in panic and
we've lost what I want:
A platoon of dead Americans.
Don't twitch any muscle.
Look dead or you will be dead.
Give him a round-trip ticket.
KAISER: Nothing but a
bunch of dead Germans.
- SERGEANT: No dead dogfaces?
- KAISER: None.
Let's go.
SCHROEDER:
Enemy scout returning with patrol.
KAISER:
These dead guys give me the creeps.
ZAB: Shit, Kaiser, something's
always giving you the creeps.
KAISER:
How come there aren't any dead GIs?
SERGEANT:
Shut up. Keep your eyes open.
Just like I said, sergeant,
just three dead Germans.
ZAB:
But the sergeant wasn't satisfied.
He'd noticed something about the
piping on their collar patches.
They were different colors.
- SERGEANT: What color is that piping?
- White.
White's infantry.
Radio.
Get me the lieutenant.
- Lieutenant? Lieutenant.
- LIEUTENANT: Yeah, go ahead.
- Yeah, this is Sergeant Possum.
- Possum, right. Where are you?
We're at point 33,
Christ on the Cross.
You're in an ambush, huh?
Nothing here. Just a bunch of dead
Krauts and a knocked-out tank.
All right, sir, we'll wait for you.
Wish we could help, sergeant,
but you're on your own.
- What's that?
- Good luck. Over and out.
What?
Yes, sir.
Well, I'll be damned.
To hell with all officers.
He's afraid the platoon's gonna
get lost coming up here...
so we gotta go back and handhold
them all the way right here.
Well, I'll be a son of a gun.
Let's go.
Don't panic. Live
people are watching us.
It's a bushwhack.
(GUNS FIRING)
KAISER: I'm hit!
SERGEANT: Check for wounded Krauts.
You're pretty good at that, Johnson,
you should have been in the Medics.
JOHNSON: Yeah, I was one...
in Indiantown Gap.
- Where?
- Back in Indiantown Gap, Pennsylvania.
Never heard of it.
(MAN YELLING IN FRENCH)
JOHNSON: Is he dead?
(M UTTERS IN FRENCH)
ZAB: Johnson, you ever notice how no one
talks about home anymore, or women?
JOHNSON: Yeah, I noticed.
(WOMAN MOANING)
SERGEANT: On the double, boys.
There's a woman in there.
- GRIFF: Is she wounded?
- SERGEANT: Easy.
VINCI:
Wounded, hell, she's pregnant.
ZAB: Christ, she looks
like she's about to pop.
SERGEANT: That's what the man said.
VINCI: Jesus, sergeant,
what are we gonna do?
SERGEANT: Get the dead Krauts out
of the tank and get her in it.
Johnson, you're gonna
deliver a baby.
- What baby?
- Her baby.
Her husband said she's got labor
pains five minutes apart.
- Why me?
- You're qualified. Let's go.
(SCREAMING IN FRENCH)
JOHNSON: Hey. Her legs gotta
be propped up higher.
- Higher?
- Higher! And spread them apart.
Wide apart. Give me
some room, okay?
Face the bullets the other
way, away from her.
JOHNSON: Relax, would you?
SERGEANT: Okay.
Okay. Go to work.
- We need some hot water.
- What are you talking about?
- No time for hot water.
- Some rubber gloves.
Hey, Griff, break out the condoms.
I need a mask. I can't
get germs on the baby.
- There's more germs in this tank than...
- No mask, no baby.
That's fine. That's fine.
Give me a diaper pin.
Oh, the rubbers, the rubbers.
Easy, easy...
That's the United
States Army for you.
- JOHNSON: Take it easy, would you?
- SERGEANT: Put them together.
JOHNSON: Hey, look. Lady...
I'm a hell of a lot more
scared than you are, okay?
Just take it easy.
Get her hands away.
Okay?
Hey, Johnson, your dog tags.
Come on.
SERGEANT: I don't see the head yet.
You're never gonna see
it if she don't push.
- She gotta push, I think.
- What do you mean?
- I think she's gotta push.
- You don't know?
- I know. She's gotta push.
- You're sure?
- I'm sure.
- Yeah.
- Then do it.
Come on, damn it, push.
Push...
It's no use. She ain't gonna push.
We might as well write this kid off.
- Can't you push for her?
- No, she's gotta...
Look, how do you say
"push" in French?
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Hey, Johnson, look. You get the
head, I'll do the poussez-ing.
JOHNSON: All right.
Easy, lady. Hey, we all love you.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Hey, hey. I can see it.
I can see his head.
That's it. That's it.
Don't stop, lady.
Come on. Don't stop.
Keep it up. You're
doing great. Push.
Push. Push.
He's coming out. Great.
He's out! He's out!
It's a boy. A boy!
(BABY CRYING)
SERGEANT: Look at that.
ZAB: We got a bunch of medals...
not for delivering the kid,
just for killing Krauts.
ZAB: The whole German army was on the
run now. We were right on their heels.
In September, we slipped across
the Meuse River into Belgium...
ahead of the main American push.
The regiment figures there's a
railway gun chopping them up.
Forward observers in a
monastery right here.
- Why don't we shell it?
- Throw a couple of bombs on it.
SERGEANT: There's an underground
fighter living in there.
It's a woman, she's a killer.
Her name is Walloon.
She has a squad plan...
to wipe out the Krauts without firing
a shot or killing one civilian.
A woman in a monastery?
It's really not a monastery. It's an
asylum for retards and insane people.
I say division should bomb it.
SERGEANT: Killing insane people
is not good for public relations.
Killing sane people is okay?
That's right.
Let's go.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) The Americans are coming
The Americans are coming
Two men in the tower.
SERGEANT: Squad. Come on.
Bayonets.
Beautiful...
(LAUGHING)
I am one of you.
I am sane. I am sane!
ZAB: For a minute there before I dropped him,
I remembered thinking he might be right.
Now, when you're in a situation where
you can't tell crazy from sane...
that's pretty confusing for a soldier, but
it's good stuff for an aspiring novelist.
I mean, at least that's
what I kept telling myself.
ZAB: I'll be a son of a bitch.
My mother sold my
novel to Hollywood.
For Humphrey Bogart and
Edward G. Robinson.
Hey, hey. For how much?
For 15,000 bucks.
We got another Rockefeller
in the company here.
So, what you gonna do
with all the moola?
Well, first, I think I'm gonna
blow 1000 bucks on a squad party.
Only you guys gotta think of the damned
things you wanted to do to a girl.
Hey, Griff.
I'm working on it.
- Vinci?
- Hey...
Come on.
- I'll tell you in a minute.
- ZAB: Hey, Johnson.
I think I'd like the
most beautiful...
I know what I want.
Who the hell are you?
Kaiser. You patched me up
behind that tank in France.
- What tank?
- I was the one that liked your book, Zab.
Yeah, baby face. Yeah, so, what do
you want? What do you wanna do?
I want a big, zaftig girl...
stick her plump butt against
an ice-cold window...
Yeah?
And just hold it there.
What are you gonna do
with a frozen butt?
Thaw it out.
(LAUGHING)
It may take a while.
(EXPLOSIONS)
Three bursts. Making millions
of splinters, lieutenant.
- LIEUTENANT: They spot your position?
- They're not aiming at us.
They're just hitting the trees.
LIEUTENANT: They've got us pinned
down. Take them out for us.
- But watch out, they've got snipers too.
- Yeah.
Let's go.
Watch yourself, they still
got snipers out there.
ZAB: I can't see a goddamned thing.
(GUNSHOTS IN DISTANCE)
- Griff.
- GRIFF: Ho!
- Zab.
- ZAB: Ho.
- Vinci.
- VINCI: Ho.
- Johnson.
- JOHNSON: Ho!
Kaiser.
Kaiser?
KAISER: I'm hit.
SERGEANT: Where are you?
KAISER: Find me...
Did I kill that guy...
that killed me?
Yes.
ZAB:
We thought we'd push through...
but the Krauts regrouped
and counterattacked...
and bumped us back into France.
Lieutenant, we got tanks and
infantry coming at us...
at point 33. Three-three.
ZAB: We spent the whole winter freezing
our asses off just to take back Belgium.
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
JOHNSON: Kaiser, I'm beginning to
see what you like about big butts!
Sergeant, can you come here so we
can, uh, talk about it, you know?
I'm gonna like winning
this Purple Heart.
He was that close, that's where he
was. Easy target. Easy target.
So he asked me why
I didn't get him.
Everything's gonna be
okay. I guarantee it.
Okay, Zab, you know it's
time to take the hill.
- Take the hill.
- Wait a second. Excuse me, my dear.
Would you help the young
lady down, please, sergeant?
Okay, now let's see.
I...
I paid for this party...
so the hill will be took
when I say it's to be took.
- I beg your pardon.
- Well, okay, sir.
- Now, move.
- Yes, sir.
Come on, let's get on with it. Don't
forget your pieces. Let's go.
Keep your front sight covers on,
or else you'll get a rusty bore.
Let's go. Move it.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
ZAB: The party was kind of
a last big blowout for us.
The war was almost over and we were sure
we'd be sent back to the rear pretty soon.
As usual, we were wrong.
The sergeant hadn't told us yet, but we
were being sent to a place called Falkenau.
He knew what that meant. We didn't.
(GUNS FIRING)
I think you got him.
(GUN FIRING)
Jew?
Polish.
Czech?
Russian?
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
ZAB: He walked around
for half an hour...
before he could bring himself
to put the kid down.
That night, he buried
him in the woods.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
ZAB: Sergeant!
VINCI: Sergeant!
- Sergeant!
- GRIFF: Sergeant?
SERGEANT: Over here.
Where the hell have you been?
SERGEANT:
I'm not gonna tell you again.
- No lights at night.
- JOHNSON: Sergeant, the war's over.
Look, nobody's firing at us.
One minute after
midnight, official.
The war's been over for four hours.
ZAB: Hey, sarge, the dead
Kraut, he's still warm.
- You didn't know it was over.
- SERGEANT: He did.
GRIFF: He's still alive!
Sulfa.
Come on.
- Pills?
- ZAB: Right here.
Live, you son of a bitch.
You're gonna live if I have
to blow your brains out.
ZAB: Saving that Kraut was the final
joke of the whole goddamned war.
We had more in common with him...
than with all our replacements who got
killed whose names we never knew.
We'd all made it through.
We were alive.
I'm gonna dedicate my book to those
who shot but didn't get shot...
because it's about survivors.
And surviving is the only glory
in war, if you know what I mean.
(English - US - SDH)