[CHURCH BELLS RlNGlNG]
[SOBS]
KRALER:
Mr. Frank.
Mr. Frank?
Kraler.
Mr. Kraler.
Miep.
My good friends.
KRALER:
It is so good to see you home.
We had heard nothing.
I'm alone.
MlEP:
You must come home with us...
...and rest now.
-You must stay with us.
FRANK: No, I can't stay in Amsterdam.
Mr. Frank, this is your home.
-Amsterdam is your home.
-lt has too many memories.
Everywhere there's something, Miep.
Everywhere.
Even seeing you and Mr. Kraler....
I shouldn't talk to you
like this, after all you did.
Why, we'd do it again.
Everything's gone. The book....
They took everything,
except some papers.
We saved your letters and papers.
FRANK:
Please burn them.
Burn everything.
I told her...
...if I got back here,
I'd find her book.
Anne's diary?
It's where she left it.
"The 9th of July, 1 942. "
1 942. Is it possible, Miep?
Only three years ago?
"Dear Diary, since you and l
are to be great friends...
...I will start by telling you
all about myself.
My name is Anne Frank.
I am 1 3 years old.
I was born in Germany,
but since my family is Jewish...
...we emigrated to Holland
when Hitler came to power.
Things went well for us until the war
came and the German occupation.
FRANK AND ANNE:
Then things got very bad for the Jews. "
ANNE: You could not do this
and you could not do that.
We had to wear yellow stars.
I had to turn in my bike.
I couldn 't go
to a Dutch school anymore.
I couldn 't go to the movies
or ride in an automobile...
... or even on a streetcar.
And a million other things.
But somehow, we children
still managed to have fun.
This morning,
Father woke me at 5:00...
...and told me to hurry
and get dressed.
We were going into hiding.
I was to put on
as many clothes as I could.
It would look too suspicious
if we walked along carrying suitcases.
We were going to disappear...
... vanish into thin air.
I'm living a great adventure.
Three other people were coming
in with us. Father knew them.
We had never met them.
-Something's happened.
VAN DAAN: They had a 3 mile walk.
PETER: Mother.
-They've been arrested, I know.
VAN DAAN: Will you stop that?
-Mother. Father.
We're here.
VAN DAAN:
You see?
-Mr. Van Daan.
VAN DAAN: Hello.
-Mrs. Van Daan.
-Mr. Frank.
Peter. There were too many
Green Police on the streets.
We took the long way around.
Did you introduce yourself?
My daughter Anne.
My wife, Edith.
Margot.
Mr. and Mrs. Van Daan.
Oh, and this is our son, Peter.
So, now, please let us take off some
of these clothes.
KRALER: Good morning.
EDlTH: Good morning, Mr. Kraler.
FRANK: Morning, Mr. Kraler.
-Mr. Frank.
You're all here. That is good.
-We hoped to have everything in order.
-Please, don't even think of it.
We'll have leisure
to arrange everything ourselves.
-Brought sandwiches for lunch.
-Thank you, Miep.
The canned goods are here,
and your beans and potatoes.
-I'll get you ration books this afternoon.
-Ration books?
If they see our names on ration books,
they'll know we're here.
Don't worry. It won't be your names
that'll be on them.
[CHURCH BELLS RlNG]
ANNE: Father! The Westertoren!
-Anne! No!
You must never touch a curtain. Never.
No one must ever touch a curtain,
day or night.
If someone on the streets should
look up or someone should see...
...we would be lost. Remember,
it's not only our lives at stake...
...but Miep's and Mr. Kraler's.
-You have 1 3 minutes to get settled.
FRANK: Thank you.
Miep or I will be up each day
to bring you food and news.
Come, Miep, we must go.
-Goodbye.
FRANK: Goodbye, Mr. Kraler.
EDlTH:
How can we thank you?
I never thought I'd live to see the day
when a man like Mr. Frank...
...would have to go into hiding.
When you think of it....
FRANK: Goodbye.
PETRONELLA: Thank you, Mr. Kraler.
Goodbye.
EDlTH: Anne!
-It's all right, I have on three more.
PETRONELLA:
Excuse me, Mr. Frank.
-What do they mean, " 1 3 minutes"?
-Before workmen come.
Now...
...while the men are in the building
below, we must be quiet.
Every sound can be heard down there,
in the offices and in the workrooms too.
The men come at about 8:30.
They leave at about 5:30.
So to be perfectly safe,
from 8 a.m. until 6 p.m...
...we must move about up here
only when absolutely necessary...
...and then in stockinged feet.
We must not speak above a whisper
or run any water.
We cannot use the sink or even,
forgive me, the W.C.
The pipes go down through
the workrooms. No trash must ever be--
[SlREN APPROACHlNG]
[SlREN FADES]
No trash, which might reveal someone's
living here. Not even a potato peeling.
We must burn everything
in the stove at night.
This is the way that we must live
until it is over, if we are to survive.
Until it is over.
After 6:00, we can move about.
We can talk and laugh...
...have our supper, read, play games,
just as we would at home.
Now it would be wise
if we all went to our rooms...
...and were settled before 8:00.
Mr. and Mrs. Van Daan, you're upstairs.
I regret there's no place up there
for Peter. But he'll be here, near us.
-And where am l?
-You and Margot will be in there.
PETRONELLA: Excuse me, Mr. Frank.
FRANK: Yes?
PETRONELLA: Where do you sleep?
FRANK: This room is our bedroom.
Oh, no, no. You take the upstairs.
We'll sleep down here.
I've thought this out.
It's the best arrangement.
The only arrangement.
Edith? You must have some rest, dear.
You didn't close your eyes last night.
Now, go in the girls' room.
-Well, how about Anne?
-I feel fine.
I'm going to help Father.
This way, Mrs. Van Daan.
ANNE:
Excuse me.
Up here.
PETER:
Mr. Frank?
-Mr. Frank?
FRANK: Peter?
-I have time to get water for my cat?
ANNE: You've a cat?
Go ahead, but be quick.
-You only have about five minutes.
-He couldn't live without that cat.
I didn't know you had a cat.
I love cats. What's its name?
-Mouschi.
-What is it? Mouschi. A him or her?
-It's a tom. It doesn't like strangers.
-Then I'll have to stop being a stranger.
-ls he fixed?
PETER: No.
You ought to have him fixed,
to keep him from fighting.
MARGOT:
What a nice cat.
ANNE:
Where do you go to school?
-Jewish Secondary.
ANNE: That's where Margot and I go.
-Yeah, I know.
-I've never seen you around.
-I used to see you sometimes.
-You did?
Why didn't you ever come over?
Oh, I don't know.
I'm sort of a lone wolf.
You can't be a lone wolf here.
I wonder what our friends will say
when we don't show up today.
I had a date with Sanne.
Do you know Sanne de Vries?
-No.
ANNE: Sanne's my best friend.
She's thin like me.
They always yell at us:
"Anne and Sanne,
the skinny bananas. "
You took off your star.
PETER:
That's right.
ANNE: You can't do that. They'll arrest
you if you go out without your star.
Who's going out?
[PETRONELLA GRUNTS]
-Help me.
-I'm helping.
-What are you going to do with it?
-Burn it.
It's funny,
I don't think I could burn mine.
-I don't know why.
PETER: You couldn't?
Something they make you wear
so they can kick you around.
I know. But after all...
...it is the Star of David, isn't it?
Annele, it's almost 8:00.
Don't you wanna sit with us?
It'll be a long day.
No, thanks. This is fine.
You won't forget to take off
your shoes, will you?
Peter...
...it's nice to have you with us.
Yes, Mr. Frank.
See you later.
Did you know that he went
to the same school that--?
[CHURCH BELLS RlNGlNG]
ANNE: It's comforting that
Mr. Kraler and his secretary...
...are down there below us,
in the office.
Our protectors, we call them.
I asked Father
what would happen to them...
...if anyone found out
they were hiding us.
Father said they would suffer
the same fate that we would.
We are over an old spice factory.
You can smell the spices
all through the building.
[YELLlNG lN DlST ANCE]
[BELL RlNGS]
[FOOTSTEPS lN DlST ANCE]
[BOAT HORN HONKS]
ANNE: I read A Tale of Two Cities
through in that first day.
"It is a far, far better thing I do...
... than I have ever done.
It is a far, far better rest
that I go to...
... than I have ever known.
The end. "
It was the saddest book I ever read.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG]
[KNOCKS]
KRALER:
It is us, Miep and Kraler.
FRANK: Good evening, Mr. Kraler.
Good evening, Miep.
KRALER:
Good evening, Annele.
-Oh, Mr. Frank.
-Yes?
-This is the box you asked for.
-Thanks.
Oh, my dear friends,
you were all so quiet up here.
-I thought you'd gone out for a walk.
ANNE: Can you imagine me?
I didn't talk.
I hardly moved for one whole day.
Wish they could hear that
at school.
MARGOT: Mouschi!
ANNE: Mouschi!
PETRONELLA: Peter!
VAN DAAN: Peter.
ANNE:
Mouschi.
[MEOWlNG]
-Annele!
EDlTH: Annie!
-Peter, I'm warning you.
FRANK:
Please, quiet. Margot. Margot!
-What are these?
-You don't have to whisper now.
-There you are.
-He's such a nice cat.
PETER: Thank you.
MARGOT: You're welcome.
Annele.
There's a box there.
Will you open it, please?
Know how I'm going
to think of it here?
As a boarding house,
a very peculiar boarding house.
Father, my film stars!
I was wondering where they were.
And Queen Wilhelmina.
How wonderful.
There's something more.
Go on, look further.
A diary.
I've never had a diary.
And I've always wanted one.
A pencil?
I'm going downstairs to get a pencil.
-Anne, no!
-There's nobody down there.
Doesn't matter.
Don't go beyond that door.
-Never?
-Never. I'm sorry, Anne, it isn't safe.
-I see.
FRANK: lt'll be hard, I know that.
But always remember
there are no walls, no locks...
...no bolts that anyone can put
on your mind.
As a matter of fact,
just between us, Annele...
...being here has certain advantages.
For instance...
...remember that battle
with your mother about overshoes?
You said you'd rather die
than wear overshoes. Remember?
What happened?
In the end, you had to wear them.
Now, for as long as we are here,
you won't have to wear overshoes.
Isn't that good?
And the piano.
You won't have to practice it.
I tell you...
...this is going to be
a fine life for you.
ANNE: It's an odd idea for someone
like me to keep a diary.
Not only because
I have never done so before...
...but because it seems to me, neither I,
nor for that matter anyone else...
... will be interested in the unbosomings
of a 13-year-old schoolgirl.
Still, what does that matter?
I want to write, but more than that...
...I want to bring out
all kinds of things...
... that lie buried deep in my heart.
First of all,
I expect I should be describing...
... what it's like to go into hiding.
But I don 't really know yet myself.
I only know it's funny never
to be able to go outdoors.
Never to breathe fresh air.
Never to run and shout and jump.
Wednesday,
the 23rd of September, 1942.
The news of the war is good.
Stalingrad is still holding out.
The Russian offensive continues
in the Moscow area.
-It's safe now. The last workman has left.
-Whee!
-Anne!
-l' m first for the W. C.
-Six o'clock, Margot. School is over.
-Where are my shoes?
-Have you seen my shoes?
-What shoes?
-You're gonna be sorry.
-I am?
-Annie, dear.
-Wait till I get you.
I'm waiting.
ANNE: Stop! Peter!
-Annie! Peter!
ANNE: Peter, where are you going?
-Gonna give Mouschi his dinner.
-Peter!
EDlTH: Annie, dear...
...you shouldn't play like that with Pete.
That's not dignified.
Who wants to be dignified?
I don't wanna be dignified!
You complain I don't treat you like
a grownup, but when I do, you resent it.
I only want some fun.
I don't know what's the matter
with that boy.
Give him a little time.
He isn't used to girls.
Time? Isn't two months time?
I could cry.
And what about Miep?
She's usually so prompt.
[SlREN APPROACHlNG]
[SlREN FADlNG]
[HUMS]
-Margot, come and dance with me.
-I've got more work to do, Anne.
You know, we're going to forget
how to dance.
When we get out,
we won't remember a thing.
[SlNGlNG]
-Where is Peter?
ANNE: Where would he be? With his cat.
He hasn't finished his lessons, has he?
Peter.
-Peter!
-What is it?
Your mother says to come out.
I'm giving Mouschi his dinner.
You know what your father says
about wasting time with that cat.
-I haven't looked at him since lunch.
-I'm only telling you.
ANNE: I'll feed him.
-You stay out of here. And I mean out.
Is that any way for you
to talk to your little girlfriend?
Mother, I asked you...
-...would you please not say that?
-Look, he's blushing.
-He's blushing.
-Please, I'm not, but--
-Leave me alone.
-Like it's something to be ashamed of.
Nothing to be ashamed of
to have a girlfriend.
That's crazy. She's only 1 3.
So what? You're 1 6. It's just perfect.
Your father's 1 0 years older than me.
Mr. Frank, I warn you...
...if this war lasts much longer,
we're gonna be related.
-Mazel tov.
-I haven't seen my cat since lunch.
I'm giving Mouschi his dinner.
My little Mouschi.
I couldn't live
without my precious Mouschi.
You wonderful cat, you.
PETER: All right, Miss Quack-Quack.
-What's that?
-Miss Quack-Quack!
-You!
You talk so much
they call you Miss Quack-Quack.
You're the most
intolerable boy I ever met!
Quack, quack, quack!
-Quack!
-Ooh!
Anne, dear, you're hot.
-You're warm. Are you all right?
-Mother, please.
-You don't have a fever, do you?
-No.
You know we can't call
a doctor here, ever.
There's only one thing to do,
watch carefully.
Prevent an illness before it comes.
Let me see your tongue.
-Mother, this is perfectly absurd.
-Anne, dear, don't be such a baby.
Let me see your tongue.
Otto.
Anne, you hear your mother,
don't you?
Come on, open up.
Quack.
Annie.
-Otto.
-Anne.
You're all right.
I think there's nothing the matter
with our Anne that a ride on her bike...
...or a visit with her friend
Sanne de Vries wouldn't cure.
Isn't that so, Anne?
ANNE: I keep wishing that Peter
was a girl instead of a boy.
Then I'd have someone to talk to.
With all the boys in the world...
... why did I have to get locked up
with him?
[EXPLOSlONS lN DlST ANCE]
[FAlNT FOOTSTEPS]
EDlTH: Is it someone?
-ls it Miep?
It's strange we don't hear.
PETRONELLA: Maybe she got hurt.
-She'll come.
I wish she'd get here.
I'm going crazy without cigarettes.
Anne, you got "excellent"
in your history paper...
-...and "very good" in Latin.
-Yes, but how about algebra?
Well, I have a confession to make.
Up until now, I managed
to stay ahead of you in algebra.
Today, you caught up with me.
We'll leave it to Margot to correct.
-lsn't algebra vile, Father?
-Vile.
-How did I do?
-Excellent, of course.
Anne, please.
Your French composition today, Margot,
was just wonderful.
-Mrs. Van Daan, may I try it on?
-No, Annie.
It's all right, really.
But please be careful with it.
My father gave me this coat
the year before he died.
He always bought me
the best money could buy.
Mrs. Van Daan, did you have a lot of
boyfriends before you were married?
Annie, that's a personal question.
It's not courteous to ask
personal questions.
I don't mind.
Anneke, our house
was always swarming with boys.
-When I was a young girl--
-Oh, no, not again.
Shut up!
VAN DAAN & PETRONELLA: One summer,
we had a big house in Hilversum.
VAN DAAN:
The boys....
The boys would come buzzing around
like bees around a jam pot.
When I was 1 7....
Well, we were wearing short skirts then,
and I had such good-looking legs.
I still have. I may not be
as pretty as I used to be...
...but I still have my legs.
How about it, Mr. Frank?
All right, all right.
We see them.
I'm not asking you,
I'm asking Mr. Frank.
-Mother, for heaven sakes.
-Oh, I embarrass you too, do l?
Let me tell you something. I only hope
the girl you marry has as good.
Anneke, my father used to worry
with all the boys hanging around.
And he used to say to me:
"lf any of those boys get fresh,
you just say to him:
'Remember, Mr. So-and-So,
remember, I am a lady.' "
Look at you,
talking that way with her.
Don't you know she puts it
in her diary?
PETRONELLA: So what if she does?
I'm only telling the truth.
VAN DAAN: Haven't you finished?
-No.
-Oh, the thinker.
VAN DAAN: Leave him alone.
-I'm a dunce. A hopeless case.
PETRONELLA: Don't talk like that.
It's just you haven't got anyone
to help you...
...Iike Father helps Anne and me.
But if l--
Well, if we could help....
What about it, Peter?
Would you like to study with us?
Shall we make our school
coeducational?
Thanks, yes.
-Mr. Frank.
FRANK: Yes?
You are an angel,
an absolute angel.
Why didn't I meet you
before I met that one there?
I think it might be better if you went
into your room, Peter, to work.
Excuse me.
Peter, you listen to Mr. Frank.
Mr. Frank is a highly educated man.
VAN DAAN:
It's after 8:00. Where are they?
-At least one of them should've come.
-They'll come. Don't worry.
Don't tell me.
I know something's wrong.
Isn't it bad enough here
without you sprawling all over?
If you didn't smoke,
you wouldn't be so irritable.
-Am I smoking?
-You already smoked all the cigarettes.
-Miep only brought me one package.
-It's a filthy habit...
-...and this is a good time to break it.
VAN DAAN: Oh, stop it. Please.
You're smoking up all our money.
Will you shut up?!
And what are you staring at?
I never heard grownups quarrel like that
before. I thought only children quarreled.
This isn't a quarrel, it's a discussion.
I never heard children so rude before.
-l, rude?
-Yes!
-Annie, drink your milk.
-You've been spoiled.
What you need is a good spanking.
Remember, Mr. So-and-So,
I am a lady.
You're the most aggravating--
Why aren't you nice and quiet...
...Iike your sister, Margot?
Why do you show off all the time?
Let me give you a little advice.
Men don't like that in a girl.
Do you know that?
A man likes a girl who'll listen to him.
A girl who cooks and sews and cleans.
I'd cut my throat first.
I'd open my veins.
I am going to be remarkable.
I'm going to Paris...
-...to study music and art.
-Yeah, yeah.
I'm going to be an actress
or a writer or a dancer.
[GASPS]
-Look what you did.
ANNE: I'm sorry.
You clumsy little fool!
-My father gave me this coat!
-I'm so sorry.
All ruined, and what do you care?
You ruined it!
I could kill you!
I could just kill you!
Petronella.
Petronella, it's only a coat.
Only a coat.
Anne, you must not behave
in that way.
It was an accident.
Anyone can have an accident.
I don't mean that.
I mean the answering back.
You must not answer back.
They're our guests.
You don't hear Margot getting
into arguments with them.
Try to be like Margot.
And have them walk all over me
the way they do her? No, thanks.
I don't know what happens
to you, Annie.
If I had ever talked to my mother
as you talk to me....
Things have changed, Mother.
People aren't like that anymore.
"Yes, Mother. No, Mother.
Anything you say, Mother. "
I've got to fight things out for myself.
Make something of myself.
It isn't necessary to fight to do it.
Margot doesn't--
"Margot. " That's all I hear.
"Why aren't you like Margot? "
Everything she does is right,
and everything I do is wrong.
You're all against me,
and you worst of all.
[DOOR SLAMS]
I don't know how we can
go on living this way.
I can't say a word to Annie,
she flies at me.
You know Anne. In a half an hour,
she'll be laughing and joking.
And them.
I told your father it wouldn't work
with two families.
But no, no, he had to ask them.
Shh.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG]
[KNOCKlNG]
Every time I hear that sound,
my heart stops.
MARGOT:
It's Miep. Father.
FRANK: Yes?
EDlTH: It's Miep.
-Here's your list.
EDlTH: Thank you.
VAN DAAN: Is it Miep?
-Yes.
-At last, I'll have some cigarettes.
-Miep's here.
I can't tell you how sorry I am
about the coat.
Don't worry.
-Hello.
-Miep.
Mr. Kraler.
When Mr. Kraler comes,
the sun begins to shine.
-Dirk has had to leave.
-Dirk is Miep's fiancé.
He had to go into hiding in the country
to escape a labor call-up...
...but he has let me have
the radio for you.
-He shouldn't have.
-lt was too dangerous.
Look!
[MUSlC PLAYS]
ANNE:
Our blessed radio.
It gives us our eyes and ears
out into the world.
We listen to the German station
only for good music.
MAN ON RADlO:
The Axis forces in the Western....
ANNE:
And we listen to the BBC for hope.
MAN ON RADlO: --ceaseless attacks by
land and air forces are now in full retreat.
The 8th army continues
to advance.
PETRONELLA:
It's good.
All right, Peter. Now, let's see what
they have to say about the Nazis, huh?
Berlin.
[MAN ON RADlO
SPEAKlNG lN GERMAN]
Must we listen?
All right, Peter, that's enough.
The Green Police, they've found us.
MAN:
Hmm.
[FLOOR SQUEAKS]
Hm.
[HUMS]
Hm?
Hm.
[SlREN WAlLlNG]
[COUGHS]
[SlREN FADlNG]
[CLOCK CHlMES]
[EXPLOSlONS lN DlSTANCE]
[DOOR UNLOCKS]
MlEP:
This way, Mr. Dussel.
[AlR RAlD SlREN WAlLS]
[KNOCKS]
KRALER: It's Kraler.
MlEP: And Miep.
KRALER: Please open.
PETRONELLA: Bless them. They're here.
FRANK: Kraler?
KRALER: And Miep, yes. Open, please.
-Well, we had a visitor last night.
-We had a visitor last night.
-Y es, yes.
-A thief.
-lt was a thief?
-Did you hear him?
-Yes.
-He was right under you.
In the office right under here.
EDlTH: We did not know.
MARGOT: We thought it was the police.
-Are you sure, Miep?
-You were, of course, quiet?
We didn't move.
We hardly breathed all night.
-That is good. It was close.
-Too close.
He went through everything,
the desk and the files.
And he found the safe,
but he could not get it open.
He's looking for our ration card supply
from the underground.
-Somebody knows.
-They are in that safe.
They'll come back. You should get rid
of that safe. Get it out of here.
Yes, put a sign on the door:
"Burglars do not come back.
The safe is gone. "
-Jokes, yeah.
-Mr. Frank, I must talk to you.
-Of course.
-Maybe we should get rid of the radio.
Put it in the stove. Burn it.
If the Green Police found that radio....
Then they'd find her diary.
We'll burn that too.
Not my diary.
My diary goes, I go with it.
-Where is it?
-Mr. Van Daan.
If they find us, they might as well
find the diary, the radio....
-Usually, I try to bring good news.
-Yes, I know.
But something has happened.
A man came to me.
He told me that he has
a Jewish friend, a dentist.
He begged me, could I find him
a hiding place? So I have come to you.
It is a terrible thing to ask of you,
living the way you are...
-...but could you take him in?
-Well, of course we will.
-His name is Jan Dussel.
-Dussel. I think I know him.
EDlTH: I think it's fine to have him.
-Thank you.
But, Otto, where are we going
to put him? Where?
-There's so little food as it is--
-We can stretch the food a little.
PETER: He can have my bed.
-No, thank you.
Margot will move in with us,
and he can have her bed.
MARGOT:
I'll get my things out.
[BELL RlNGS]
Mr. Dussel.
Don't bump your head.
Come in, Mr. Dussel.
This is Mr. Frank.
-Mr. Otto Frank?
-Yes. Let me have your things, please.
Thank you, Mr. Frank.
I leave you in good hands.
Mr. Dussel, I must return your coat.
-What can I say to thank you?
-Mr. Kraler and Miep...
...they're our lifeline.
Without them, we couldn't live.
KRALER: Please. You make us seem
very heroic. It isn't that at all.
-We simply don't like the Nazis.
-I know, I know.
"Nobody's going to tell us Dutchmen
what to do with our damn Jews. "
We'll be up tomorrow,
see if they're treating you right.
KRALER: Goodbye.
DUSSEL: Goodbye, Mr. Kraler.
MlEP: Goodbye, Mr. Dussel.
DUSSEL: Goodbye, Miep.
-Welcome, Mr. Dussel.
-Thank you.
This is my wife, Edith.
Mr. and Mrs. Van Daan. Their son, Peter.
My daughters, Margot and Anne.
DUSSEL: Hello, Anne.
-How do you do?
-Margot.
Please, Mr. Dussel, sit down.
Thank you.
I'm dreaming, I know it.
Mr. Otto Frank here.
You're not in Switzerland, then?
Someone said that you had escaped.
-And you've been here all this time?
-Ever since July.
Did Mr. Kraler warn you
you won't get much to eat here?
You can imagine.
Three ration cards
among the seven of us.
Now you make eight.
DUSSEL: Mr. Van Daan, you don't realize
what's happening outside...
...that you should warn me
of a thing like that.
You don't realize what's going on,
right here in Amsterdam.
Every day, hundreds of Jews disappear.
They surround the block.
They search house by house.
Every day, children come home from
school to find their parents gone.
Hundreds are being deported.
People that you and I know:
the Hallensteins, the Wessels.
EDlTH:
Oh, no.
DUSSEL:
You get your call-up notice:
"Come to the station on such
and such a day and hour.
Bring only what you can carry. "
If you don't, they come drag you
from your home...
...and ship you off to Mauthausen,
the death camp.
We didn't know that things
had got so much worse.
Forgive me for speaking so.
Do you know the de Vries?
They're gone.
Sanne and I are in the same class.
Sanne is my best--
My best friend.
She returned home from school
to find her parents gone.
She was alone for two days,
and then they came and took her away.
Gone?
Yes, with all the others.
Oh, no.
People named Meyerberg,
they lived near us.
-Do you know--?
-We should put this off.
I'm sure Mr. Dussel would like
to get settled.
Would you take Mr. Dussel
to his room now?
ANNE:
If you'll come with me, Mr. Dussel.
Forgive me if I haven't expressed
my gratitude.
This has been such a shock to me.
I always thought of myself as Dutch.
I was born in Holland.
My father was born in Holland,
and my grandfather.
And now, after all these years....
If you will excuse me.
[MUSlC PLAYlNG lN DlSTANCE]
It's so different from what
Mr. Kraler tells us.
Mr. Kraler says that things
are improving.
I like it better the way Kraler tells it.
Good night.
-Say good night!
-Good night, Mother.
PETRONELLA: Good night, Mr. Frank.
FRANK: Good night.
Do you have any children, Mr. Dussel?
No, I never married.
-Have you no family at all?
DUSSEL: No one.
ANNE:
How dreadful.
You must be terribly lonely.
I'm used to it.
I don't think I could ever get used to it.
Didn't you even have a pet?
-A cat or a dog?
-No.
No, no, I have an allergy
to furbearing animals.
-Gives me asthma.
-Oh, dear.
What?
Peter has a cat.
-He has? He has it here?
-Yes.
We hardly ever see it.
-He keeps it in his room all the time.
-Yeah.
-I'm sure it'll be all right.
-Well, I hope so. Yes.
I hope I won't be too much
of a bother to you, Mr. Dussel.
No.
I seem to be able to get
everyone's back up.
Oh, I always get along very well
with young people.
My patients all bring
their children to me...
...because they know I get along well
with them.
So don't you worry about that.
Thank you, Mr. Dussel.
Good night.
I'll be back.
Good night, Mr. Dussel.
Be careful.
[CLATTERlNG]
[BELL CHlMES]
[MEN CHEERlNG FAlNTLY]
ANNE:
Sanne.
Sanne?
Sanne!
[LAUGHlNG AND SPEAKlNG
lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[GUN SHOOTlNG]
[SCREAMS]
Save me! Save me! No, no!
-No! Don't take me!
DUSSEL: Stop it! Stop it!
[LAUGHlNG]
ANNE:
Save me.
EDlTH: Hush, Annie, hush.
It's all right. It's all right.
Please, Mr. Dussel, turn on the light.
It was just a dream.
You're here, safe, you see?
Something must be done with that child.
Yelling like that.
Who knows who might be in the street?
She's endangering our lives.
Mr. Dussel, after all, Anne is not
exactly a trained frontline soldier.
Please, Mr. Dussel, go back to bed.
She'll be herself in a minute or two,
won't you, Annie?
DUSSEL:
Go back to bed. Hmph.
Excuse me. I'm going to the W.C.,
the one room where there's peace.
FRANK:
Go back to bed now.
EDlTH:
Would you like some water?
Was it a very bad dream?
Perhaps if you told me?
I'd rather not talk about it.
EDlTH:
Try to sleep, then.
-I'll sit right here beside you.
ANNE: You don't have to.
But I'd like to stay with you.
Very much, really.
I'd rather you didn't.
EDlTH:
Good night--
You'll be all right?
There's nothing that you want?
Will you please ask Father to come?
Yes, of course, Anne, dear.
She asked for you.
-Edith....
EDlTH: Go to her, Otto.
She's still trembling with fear.
[CRYlNG]
She wants nothing of me.
She pulled away when I leaned down
to kiss her.
They broke down the door and tried
to drag me out, the way they did Sanne.
Anne.
MARGOT:
It's just a phase.
All girls turn to their fathers
at this age.
They give all their love
to their fathers.
EDlTH: You weren't like this.
You didn't shut me out.
So....
-Do you want me to read to you?
-No, just sit with me for a minute.
Was I awful?
-Do you think anyone outside heard me?
-No. Now, lie down quietly so.
Like this. Now try to sleep.
I'm a terrible coward.
I'm so disappointed in myself.
I think I'm really grown-up...
...and then something happens,
and I run to you like a baby.
I love you, Father.
I don't love anyone but you.
-Annele. Annele.
ANNE: It's true.
You're the only one I love.
I've been thinking about it
for a long time.
FRANK:
It's fine.
It's fine to have you tell me
that you love me...
...but I'd be much happier if you said
that you loved your mother as well.
She needs your help so much.
Your love.
We have nothing in common.
She doesn't understand me.
Whenever I try to explain my views
on life, she asks me if I'm constipated.
You hurt her very much just now.
She's crying.
She is in there crying.
Oh, Father, I was horrible, wasn't l?
What's the matter with me?
Tell me.
Don't say it's just a phase.
Help me.
There is so little that we parents can do
to help our children, Annie.
We can only try to set a good example,
point the way.
The rest you must do yourself.
ANNlE:
I'm trying. Really, I am.
Every night, I think back over all the things
I did that day that were wrong.
Like putting the wet mop
in Mrs. Van Daan's bed.
And now this with Mother.
I say to myself, "That was wrong. "
And I make up my mind never
to do that again. Never.
I may do something worse,
but I'll never do that again.
I have a nicer side, Father...
...but I'm scared to show it.
I'm afraid people will laugh at me.
So the mean Anne comes
to the outside...
...and the good Anne stays
in the inside.
And I keep on trying
to switch them around...
...have the good Anne outside...
...and the bad Anne inside.
It would be what I'd like to be.
And might be.
If only....
She's asleep.
ANNE:
Thursday, the 29th of October, 1942.
Mr. Dussel and I had
a great battle yesterday.
Yes, Mr. Dussel.
According to him, nothing, I repeat,
nothing, is right about me.
While he was going on at me,
I thought:
"Someday, I'm going
to give you such a smack...
... that you 'll fly right up
to the ceiling. "
Why is it that every grownup thinks
he knows the way to bring up children?
Particularly the grownups
that haven 't any.
Monday, the 9th of November, 1942.
Wonderful news!
The Allies have landed in Africa!
MAN ON RADlO:
That measure of....
ANNE: Churchill spoke on the BBC
from London.
MAN ON RADlO: --which they have
so often meted out to others.
Ah, this is not the end.
It is not even the beginning
of the end.
No, but it is, perhaps,
the end of the beginning.
ANNE:
The air raids are getting worse.
The British planes come over, day
and night, on their way to Germany.
[EXPLOSlONS RUMBLlNG]
It's too much.
It's just too much.
Suppose they hit this house?
What will we do?
We can't go out in the street.
If they hit this house,
your worries will be over.
That big explosion,
an English plane fell right in this block!
Peter.
Peter!
FRANK: It's far away from here.
VAN DAAN: Please don't.
FRANK:
Just look at them.
Mrs. Van Daan,
this should be music to your ears.
-Music?
FRANK: Of course.
The more planes they send,
the sooner the war will be over.
-The sooner we'll be home again.
-I don't believe it'll ever be over.
Do you know what I'd like right now?
A cup of tea.
Oh, yes, please.
You can't have tea, then,
for breakfast.
If you have it now,
you won't have any tomorrow.
-I don't care.
-Neither do l.
Me too, please.
How about you, Mr. Dussel?
Tea now or tomorrow morning?
-Tomorrow morning.
-Sure?
Sure.
I'll take mine now.
The skylight!
FRANK:
Edith, come!
PETRONELLA:
Oh, Peter!
Peter! Peter!
Peter!
FRANK: "Praised be thou, Lord,
ruler of the universe...
...who's sanctified us
with thy commandments...
...and bidden us kindle
the Hannukah lights.
Praised be thou, O, Lord, our God,
ruler of the universe...
...who wrought wondrous deliverances
for our fathers in days of old.
Praised be thou, O, Lord, our God,
ruler of the universe...
...that thou hast given us life
and sustenance...
...and brought us to this happy season. "
Amen.
-Amen.
ANNE:
Monday, the 7th of December, 1942.
The Hannukah holiday
came early this year.
"We kindle this Hannukah light...
...to celebrate the wonderful deeds
wrought through the zeal...
...with which God filled the hearts of
the heroic Maccabees 2000 years ago.
They fought against indifference...
...against tyranny and oppression,
and they restored our temple to us.
May these lights remind us
that we should ever look to God...
...whence cometh our help. "
Amen.
-Amen.
"l lift up mine eyes unto the mountains
from whence cometh my help.
My help cometh from the Lord,
who made heaven and earth.
He will not suffer thy foot
to be moved.
He that keepeth thee will not slumber.
He that keepeth lsrael doth
neither slumber nor sleep.
The Lord is thy keeper.
The Lord is thy shade
upon thy right hand.
The Lord shall keep thee from all evil.
He shall keep thy soul.
The Lord shall guard thy going out
and thy coming in...
...from this time forth and forevermore. "
Amen.
-Amen.
May I have the hats, please?
Thank you.
Very nice, very nice.
-That was very moving.
-lt isn't over yet.
-Sit down!
VAN DAAN: Where are you going?
There's lots more.
Songs and presents.
-Presents?
EDlTH: Not this year, unfortunately.
But always on Hannukah,
everyone gives presents. Everyone.
-That's right.
-Like our St. Nicholas Day.
St. Nicholas Day.
No, not like St. Nicholas Day.
What kind of Jew doesn't
know Hannukah?
EDlTH:
I remember particularly the candles.
First one, as we have tonight.
The second night, two.
The next night, three, and so on,
until eight candles are burning.
When there are eight candles,
it's truly beautiful.
What I remember best are the presents
we used to get, eight days of presents.
Each day, they got better and better.
We are all here, alive.
That's present enough.
No, it isn't.
I've got something.