Archdruid Gutuart...
might makes law.
The wheel of destiny threatens
to crush us beneath it.
We are dying.
Tell us what we must do?
Every people, every tribe
needs its legend.
And every battle
needs a hero.
Behold.
The sign of the coming of a king.
The coming of a king?We
no longer have kings in Gaul.
-Perhaps then, the Romans.
-But they have no king either.
A hero must emerge
from the darkness.
He alone will keep the great wheel
from crushing us beneath it.
l must go to seek him out.
-Do you know the meaning of my name?
-Epona, the she-horse.
-No.
Vercingetorix, leader
of the great warriors.
Between a boy and a girl,
there should be something more.
Sorry.
-Are you a guest at the feast of May?
-Yes.
No, Y...
Well, maybe. Maybe l am.
And you my boy,
who are you?
l'm no boy.
l am Vercingetorix
A heavy name to bear,
leader of great warriors.
Not for the son of Celtill,
chieftain of Arvernes.
l am the daughter of Mosa, chief of
the Bellovaques. Who are you?
Nobody.
l am the seed blown by
the winds of fortune.
l am a spore that
may take roots.
-Spoken like a Druid.
-l'm just a poor minstrel.
ln fact, my finances might
greatly improve...
if l could gain entrance
to yonder feast...
by the grace of some noble guest.
Like yourself.
l would welcome you to Gergovia then.
Take my horse.
Thank you.
Tell my father l have sent you
and he will refuse you nothing.
Thank you, leader
of great warriors.
You give him your trust,
just like that.
He pleased me.
You please me too.
And don't forget if your brother
Celtill persists...
you must obey our laws...
and separate his soul
from his corrupted body.
Gutuart is wrong. There
must not be a king in Gaul!
The feast has not yet begun.
-You have no business here now.
-l'm returning the horse, uncle.
-What are you doing, my son?
-Showing Epona the city, mother.
Leticia, make sure there are
flowers on every table.
Come on.
Someday, you'll be my queen.
Your queen? l like
the sound of that.
But there are no
more kings in Gaul.
For the moment.
-For the moment?
-lt's a secret.
Follow me. My father is meeting
with all the chiefs of Gaul.
l welcome you, noble chieftains
of the other peoples of Gaul.
And particularly you, Dumnorix,
chieftain of the Eduens...
and Diviciac, your brother
and grand druid...
and our friends from the north,
the great Commios...
-and the valiant Mosa.
-Chief of the Bellovaques.
You also Gobannitio
my brother...
and you Calarix,
senator of the Arvernes.
Gutuart, our archdruid will be
present to witness our meeting.
Do you imagine yourself becoming
the new Brennus, King of the Gauls?
Have you forgotten that the Arvernes
have proclaimed a republic?
l haven't forgotten, Gobannitio...
that you want to become chieftain
of this aristocratic republic...
which makes the rich richer...
and the poor poorer.
But let us put aside these
petty rivalries.
We Gauls are trapped between
two great monsters.
To our North, the Teutons...
and at the South, the Romans.
Do you forget that it was you
who hired the Teuton mercenaries...
to conquer other lands?
-The Romans are no menace.
-For the moment.
What are you saying?
l'm saying you went to Rome to beg
Caesar to come to Gaul.
l say that the legions of Rome
will devastate our lands...
and destroy everything
in which we believe.
l say, better, Diviciac, the people
of Gaul united under a King.
l tell you, my brother...
rather a king at the head of Gaul...
than your secret pacts
with the Romans.
Let us unite and together expel
both the Teutons and the Romans.
ln great and glorious battles.
One day, l'll be your queen.
Here is the crown once worn
by the king of the Gauls.
Father, no!
Take your crown. Run!
Epona!
Give me that.
Vercingetorix, go.
This is between Arvernes.
Stay out of it.
Gobannitio!
No, my boy. Not that.
-l want to save my father.
-Of course you want, but you cannot.
-l must save my father.
-He has to accept his destiny...
and so must you.
According to our law...
we must separate your spirit
from your perverted body.
Foul reptile!
lt isn't the law that you serve,
but your own vile ambition.
And you my brother
are no better.
Farewell Celtill. The Eduens
will not be part of such treason.
Nor will the Atrebates.
Farewell.
You're more afraid to kill me,
than l am to die.
Hand me the torch, Gobannitio.
You're not worthy of sacrificing
your brother you betrayed.
His death belongs to him alone.
The magic of his death must
teach us the lesson of his sacrifice.
The greater the magic, the greater
the price that must be paid.
l will kill you, Gobannitio.
l will kill you.
Get up. Even if everyone
in Gaul is divided...
here, there is neither
tribe nor people.
No distinctive mark.
Drop that.
Get up! Hurry up!
Where are you going?
lt's time for me to do what l must.
l have a task to accomplish.
You're not ready.
Not yet.
Come with me.
l will introduce you to a master.
Rhia, l've brought you
a young friend.
Just try not to hurt him.
Draw a single drop of my blood...
and you can do
whatever you want.
-l thought it was impossible.
-lt is impossible.
Fighting must be a pleasure.
Look at me. Learn my moves.
Learn to anticipate each other...
provoke your partner,
entice your opponent to dare.
Capture his rage and make
it your own.
Lead the dance.
lf you know what you want,
your partner will want it too.
Attack again.
To be one with your sword, you must
empty yourself of all desire.
And when l'll learn to do that
will l'll have a drop of your blood?
When you achieve that,
you'll dispose of my life.
You must become a master druid.
l will become a master druid.
Then the game will be over, and you
will accomplish your destiny.
Did you see your death,
Vercingetorix?
No. l was king.
What does it mean?
The knowledge that comes to you
in dreams is yours alone.
A man's destiny is also his alone.
-Yes.
-Then l must follow it.
The greater your destiny the greater
the price that you must pay.
Since the flames consumed my
childhood, all l've done is study.
And now, l've been told
it's time to act.
Just don't abandon the path
of knowledge...
when you take the road of action.
Beware of this course of action.
For years our chiefs have been
victims of their own demons...
they have formed alliances,
and betrayed each other.
l'll show you where
this will lead you.
The Romans act without true
knowledge. See what they do:
a sword of stone right through
the living heart of the land.
You must travel this road
for a while.
So here our paths must diverge.
Look!
-Now, kick me in the ass.
-What?
They've seen my druid's robe!
So do what l tell you.
l'm a bothersome beggar. Kick me in
the ass and hound me into the woods.
Alright. Go away! Go away!
Come on.
-Go away!
-Please.
-And don't come back!
l'm sorry.
Where is the Druid?
What Druid?
-The man in the white robe.
-Oh, a beggar, nothing more!
Who would dare lay hands
on a Druid.
-Diviciac?
-You know me, Arverne?
You'd be a hard man to forget,
for the son of Celtill.
-We thought you were dead.
-Where are you going?
Gergovia.
Well, l am going to Bibracte
to meet the other chiefs of Gaul.
Would you like to join me?
For a while.
What keeps you here
so far from Rome?
The same thing that kept you
hidden in the woods...
and now sets you on my road.
Destiny!
Spoken like a Druid!
Actually, l was once a kind
of a druid of some kind...
a high priest of Rome.
lt cost me a lot of money.
Are you a druid?
-No, l chose another path.
-So did l. l choose to serve Rome.
Rome to which all roads lead:
bridges, aqueducts, roads...
the free movements
of goods and men...
and for the good of all
the civilised world!
So the selfless Caesar comes to Gaul
to bring civilisation...
to us, poor barbarians.
Yes.
One may be born as a barbarian...
but earns the right to call
himself a citizen of Rome.
Assemble your warriors. Join
me on my expedition to Britain.
Win fame, glory, and
Roman citizenship.
And half of everything you seize.
So, our paths diverge now...
but not too long l think.
Thank you for the horse.
l will return it.
Do you think he could win back
Gergovia by himself?
That boy!
Somehow, Gistus...
l do believe he could!
He never agrees with anything!
-Sure.
-No, no, please.
Look there, he's riding a
Roman General's horse!
-lt's beautiful.
-l wonder where he comes from.
Who are you? What do
you think you're doing?
Setting my house in order...
and avenging my father.
l come to offer you adventure.
l will lead all the warriors of Gaul
to invade the island of Britain.
l offer you glory and fortune.
l have the word of Caesar...
that we shall have
half the booty.
And to prove it,
he has given me his horse.
Half the booty.
Can you believe it?
You are welcome among us.
Ride at the head of our
Arverne troops...
and represent us proudly
before Caesar.
Why haven't your spies
found the archdruid?
l'm sure he's the one
who teaches them...
to believe in perpetual
changes.
He's my true enemy.
Mosa's daughter, Epona
might recognise me.
l salute you, friends...
and allies of Rome.
Dumnorix and Litavic,
chieftains of the Eduens...
Diviciac, Commios...
the valiant Mosa,
chief of the Bellovaques.
l liberated you from the Teutons
and l brought you peace.
Caesar offers pardon to those
who fought against him.
And his friendship to those
who will serve him.
Here, Britain, a rich land...
inhabited by barbarians
so primitive...
-that they paint their faces blue.
-And they go to war.
Let's invade Britain...
and half the booty is yours.
l can't go.
Why not?
l get seasick.
The gods are with us,
Dumnorix.
And l guarantee you the
sea will be calm.
Caesar accepts your children as
guarantee that you will be loyal.
Epona, princess
of the Bellovaques...
will take care of
the younger ones.
Dumnorix takes hostages.
He doesn't give them. Never.
-Yes.
This is what l want in
exchange for the booty.
No, Caesar. This
is an incredible total.
For the arms?
For the jewellery? For
the thousands of slaves?
You still owe us what you
borrowed to pay for the festivals.
Popularity is expensive.
l don't owe you anything
anymore.
But from now on,
you will owe me.
The taxes will be divided between
Rome and you and me.
-l need another four legions.
-To conquer Britain?
l'm sending the Gauls.
-l have to get rid of them.
-What cynicism!
Another word for politics!
Open the gates!
You were right about
Vercingetorix.
He has done it. He's here.
That's a gift of the gods.
And l knew it.
Another future victory...
for Caius Julius Caesar,
Proconsul of Transalpine Gaul.
For the moment.
A victory over the Britons...
will bring me no closer to
a triumphal return to Rome...
and Rome no closer to the
government it must have.
Julius Caesar,
King of the Romans?
King? Vercingetorix, no.
A king who founds a dynasty
is a hero...
but his son is a mediocrity, and his
grand son a half-wit or a monster...
and his great grand son
probably both. No!
l don't seek to destroy
the Republic.
-Only to rule it.
-A modest enough ambition.
When Alexander the Great was ten
years younger than l am today...
he had conquered the
entire civilised world.
At your age, he was dead.
All the more reason to hurry.
Dine with me tonight.
l'm sure you will find it
interesting.
l'm afraid we will never reach
Britain in such weather.
The Gauls only fear having
the sky fall on their heads.
And the Gaul who said
that to Alexander...
was struck dead
by lightening.
Take this Diviciac!
Listen to me.
So Dumnorix,
still afraid of the sea?
l guarantee that the sea
will be calm.
lt's not the sea sickness l fear,
but Caesar.
He offers us half the booty,
and that's not enough for you?
lt's too much.
-We must respect the pact
-lt was you...
you, my brother who made
the pact for the Eduens.
lt's not for me or my sons
to respect it.
Dumnorix!
What are you going to do:
Whatever l can.
Whenever l can.
l do believe that you
know each other.
l do?
Or have you forgotten the girl
you asked to be your queen?
Epona?
Your queen?
The King's wife?
When l met him in his village,
l was a little provincial girl...
impressed by the son
of a local chieftain...
who was even more impressed
with himself.
And what have you become, now?
A civilised and educated woman.
lmpressed by a Roman General who is
even more impressed with himself?
l am, after all,
an impressive man.
We are all impressive people.
You know...
sometimes l think...
that your father...
was ahead of his time...
-and he had very good ideas.
-To drive your legions from Gaul?
Too many tribes.
You have too many tribes.
And each chieftain has to
be elected every year.
That's a mess.
l want to govern Rome.
That's my destiny.
The destiny of the Gauls
might be to...
have a king...
chosen by Rome.
Why not a King
chosen by destiny?
-l knew you would come.
-You seem to know Caesar pretty well.
Caesar visits me often.
You're jealous?
l think often of the young
boy of Gergovia...
to whom l gave
a token of my fidelity.
Why do you think
he brought us together?
lt's always wise to assume Caesar
knows everything he should know.
Dumnorix doesn't trust him.
l trust him to be exactly
what he is: Julius Caesar.
l trust him as much
as l trust you.
What is that supposed
to mean Epona?
You are and will always be...
the leader of great warriors.
Ave! Dumnorix.
He stormed into our camp!
He massacred our soldiers
and then fled.
Continue loading the boats.
Your brother, l knew
he would betray me.
We should kill all the hostages.
No, please, don't
do that Caesar.
Dumnorix must be tried
according to our rules.
-l want to see him.
-Let me send Litavic after him.
No, l don't trust the Eduens
anymore, and l don't trust you.
Then send Vercingetorix.
He's an Arverne.
Well...
if that is your choice
No hostages are to be executed.
Bring him back...
alive.
Like the mercenaries of Rome...
you still wear your cloak
on your right shoulder.
l came to bring you back.
ls the silver-tongued Vercingetorix
trying to convince me...
or does the leader of great warriors
want to bring me back by force?
We might as well talk,
we can always fight to death later.
What order of Caesar did you come
to execute, riding his own horse?
To bring you back to be tried
according to our laws.
Your brother demanded it.
l'm very thankful, and
l am overjoyed to see myself...
being condemned by my brothers
in the camp of Caesar.
lf you don't come back...
the Eduen hostages will be executed,
and maybe others with them.
No, no, no.
What are you saying?
Even if he were furious,
and he must be...
Caesar will never kill
the hostages.
What Gaul would embark for Britain
if he executed his children?
-He will not do it.
-What do we do now?
l thought to offer you my horse...
and then together, let's go
to avenge the death of your father.
Have you never asked yourself...
who would set Eduens against Eduens,
and Arverne against Arverne?
Who profited the most
from the death of Celtill?
Vercingetorix, go!
Go!
Bring back to Caesar
what belongs to Caesar.
And give my tribute to him.
Your father was a good man.
l think we should go
to Gergovia, right now!
Let's go.
-What does this hand mean?
-That we have made an enemy...
and it would have been much better
to have him as a friend.
Throw the hostages into prison...
and lock Epona in a cell.
Let it be known that Caesar
will be grateful...
to the man who finds
Vercingetorix.
Close the gates!
You are banned from the city.
Caesar has put a price
on your head.
They massacred all of the druids.
But l came back to wait.
ls Gutuart still alive?
Brother and sister of the sword!
Now you can dispose of my life.
The game will be over soon then.
Stay here. Keep an eye on them!
We want Vercingetorix
as our war leader.
Senators, we command you
elect him chieftain of the Arvernes!
l will not be elected
by these cowards...
but by the acclamation
of my people.
Caesar cannot make me an outlaw!
He is my enemy and
l would be your king.
¡We want Vercingetorix
to be our leader!
Long live Vercingetorix...
King of the Arvernes.
ln the memory of my father...
l proudly accept.
People of Gaul.
Let us be what we must be...
a free and united people.
Together we will chase
the Romans out of Gaul.
They are our enemies...
and all who serve them,
traitors.
-Burn the reserves and the barns.
-You want to ruin us!
Do as l say or l'll
burn them myself.
Here little ones,
this is for you.
He's burning all of Gaul while your
legions are dying of hunger.
The men are starting to cast
hungry looks at the horses.
He's an intelligent leader.
He refuses to engage the enemy.
That's not a very glorious strategy.
But an effective one.
Let us return to
our own province.
Neither glorious, nor effective.
We will walk through the
fire and attack Avaricum.
Like the scorpion! l will follow
my own logic until death.
Let see which logic
Vercingetorix follows.
Evacuate the city...
or l will burn it to ashes
with your people still inside.
What right do you have, Arvern?
l can't let the Romans take Avaricum
with all its supplies.
l would burn Gergovia
my own town if l had to.
-Then, defend the city with us.
-The besieged can't win.
Because of our stupidity,
Caesar would snatch his victory...
from thejaws of defeat
in which l have trapped him.
One life for a city.
l offer you the innocent life
of my child.
lf you really believe it will
serve the cause of Gaul...
great king Vercingetorix,
kill him.
May he live to become a man
worthy of his mother.
May Avaricum survive
to see it.
-Let us fight a great battle!
-We should fight them now.
l'm going to Gergovia.
Did l do the right thing?
Or will l live to regret it?
You did what you thought
was right...
instead of what you
knew was necessary.
-Was that a mistake?
-Might does not make right...
nor does wrong.
But might is part of this world
of human conflict...
where we all are prisoners.
That's the real trap.
Your incomprehensible talking
does not help me.
Do you think so?
Now we will do what
Vercingetorix hasn't done.
Like the scorpion,
victory or death.
We'll kill all the inhabitants.
l want a blood bath.
Caesar, it's not necessary.
All the women...
all the elders,
even all the children.
Thanks to you,
they've all perished!
You abandoned them.
You refused to fight.
You are a coward.
And you would turn
us all into cowards.
You promised to lead us
to victory.
What victory? The one
he promised to Caesar?
You accuse me of treason?
Then kill me.
Yes, l betrayed Gaul.
Yes, l was a coward.
Your anger is my anger...
at myself.
Because l made one mistake.
l listened to you.
The city had to burn.
And would l had done it...
the inhabitants would
still be alive...
and the troops of Caesar famished.
But Caesar made
a worse mistake...
when he ordered this slaughter...
which horrifies and
revolts my heart...
and yours, and the hearts
of all Gauls.
Now if you think you've done me a
favour by giving me this command...
And if you think l'm no longer
worthy of this honour...
l'll hand it back to you right now.
Destiny.
That is destiny.
Disgusting!
lt was a real useless...
slaughter.
Useless?
Now we will have
a decisive battle.
l've found the secret
of the Gallic swords.
We march to Gergovia.
Position the catapults.
Load them.
-Hurry up!
-Why? There's no one there.
Form your lines.
Get ready.
Vercingetorix is surrounded.
He doesn't dare show himself.
Let's attack!
Your ally Litavic,
has just arrived.
On my word!
Hey, you men, we've
got something for you.
Look up here.
Come on, we're ready for you.
You're so shy!
Come taste this, please.
Take a look...
l mean to be the first.
Form a pyramid.
You'll get to see
what real men are like!
-Look what's waiting for you.
-Look.
You're shy!
Death to Caesar,
death to Caesar.
Kill them all.
Death to the Romans...
We're not afraid
of any roman!
Well they're your allies.
l just hope they're up to it.
The Eduens are with you.
Caesar has massacred Avaracum.
He's no longer our friend.
You, who has united us in this fight.
You are my brother.
Here.
That bastard Litavic!
May every single Gaul be cursed.
Let's attack!
Victory!
-Victory!
Vercingetorix,
King of the Arvernes...
leader of the great warriors.
What do you see after the victory?
l see all the peoples
of Gaul united.
United? Under the dark
desire of revenge?
No. l want to force Caesar back
on the same road he himself built.
lt is roads which use the pretext of
free movement of goods and men...
to accelerate the orders of
the empire...
which strangles us
to satisfy its ambition.
ln my father's memory, l will realise
the magic he wanted to create.
Chase the Germans and the Romans
out of Gaul.
Gauls...
l welcome you to Bibracte.
Vercingetorix has done what
no one has ever done before.
He has defeated the mighty Caesar
at the head of his legions.
-Six legions of them at least.
-Ten!
A Hundred! A Hundred!
Our women have proven that they
could take care of a hundred legions.
Shall we elect Vercingetorix
commander in chief of the army...
to get rid of the Romans
and the Teutons.
l don't want a battle...
even if we win.
And if we do...
Rome will not rest until
that victory is turned into defeat.
Maybe so.
To cut Caesar roads to the north
we should hire the Teutons.
You're crazy. They burned
your father for less than that.
That's not what they want from you.
Don't tell them such a thing. Listen.
What they all want now
is a final battle.
-We must continue.
-We will be victorious.
l took arms for
the freedom of all.
l pledge my life up to
the last drop of my blood...
no matter what sacrifice
destiny may call upon me to make.
Be with me and l will
lead you to victory...
into thejaws of death
with a battle song in my heart.
Now, let us choose our capital.
The capital should be Pabracs.
Why?
The Cadurques shall follow...
the orders of the Eduens.
The capital should be Genabum.
Genabum!
-l was very worried about you.
-l was never afraid.
l was locked in a cell alone.
l had time to think about you...
about Caesar, about his promises
and his lies...
but mainly about you.
And do you still trust the
leader of the great warriors...
who wanted you to be his queen?
At the time l accepted when
l was asked by the boy.
And now?
l'd be honoured to be asked by
the King of the Arvernes.
Not for you, for her.
Like everyone, l have come to humbly
bow before the conqueror of Caesar...
before he who had me liberated.
Wait, l want to talk to you.
Wait!
Between a boy and a girl,
there should be something more.
l only want you as my queen,
but...
But?
But what?
Well, l might be gone
for an eternity.
Since it's only that,
take me with you then.
No, l can't,
not to war.
My place is wherever
you will be.
-No. No, it's impossible.
-You think?
Try to stop me!
You are beautiful.
Go and warn the others.
l want to know what the Teutons
are doing here.
-Send out scouts.
-Yes sir.
We must hurry.
We need shelter.
Come on! Let's go!
He's here, he's here.
Allow me the honour of
giving you my bedroom.
Put it over there on the table.
Hurry up, please.
We are preparing the room
for the Bellovaque princess.
l thank you chieftain of Alesia
for your hospitality.
l am sure the staff of our commander
can organise his own quarters.
Go and help him.
Do it!
-What?
-Help him. Over there.
As they say, war is hell.
-l also want to be a great warrior.
-We'll talk about it later.
The army can retire;
we can manage on our own.
-You want to be my squire?
-Yes!
lt's good to be inside.
To us.
Do you know who the goddess
of Alesia is?
-No.
-No, who?
lt's the horse goddess Epona.
You crack yourself up,
Fancy Helmet.
Caesar is coming
to besiege us.
Too risky for him. He knows
we have an immense army.
He must know, but that's
what l believe he will do.
-We should leave here now.
-Leave here?
l thought you wanted one great
final battle, just like Caesar.
ls it what Gaul really needs?
No...
but now the die is already cast.
The battle you longed for
has already begun.
-We've got food for one month.
-Cut the rations in half.
Equal rations for the army
and for the civilians.
You must ride to the four winds...
gather a huge army of relief
and return.
lt is your challenge, make it work.
lf you want to win this battle, you
must return before the next moon.
You will be the hammer,
and l will be the anvil.
And please, remember.
Do not attack.
-What?
-Do not attack.
The Gauls will send
a relief army.
l know, and l'll be ready
before they arrive.
Caesar's fortifications worry me
and demoralise the army.
But not me. He won't
have time to finish them.
The Teutons are everywhere...
but our spies can't really find out
what they are really here for.
Caesar bought them.
There we are open
to the valley.
l'll let you pass if you tell me
where your archdruid is.
We don't know.
We don't understand him anyway,
so how can we tell you about him.
Strange!
You want to join Vercingetorix,
to aid him against me.
We don't interfere with
your world of strife.
Your Vercingetorix dealt me
some superb and unexpected blows...
and you enjoy it,
as much as l do.
To you, the prize of victory
is indispensable Caesar.
Without it, your life
is meaningless.
Druids. l have to establish
an absolute place to stand...
always the same, immutable.
l have to extend an empire
and to hold it together.
That is destiny.
Your words reduce
others to silence.
But when you have suppressed
all your adversaries...
there will be no more
combat, Caesar.
Your world will be irresistible
and your isolation complete.
l won't let you go to Alesia.
We must elect the general
of the relief army.
Time is short, Gauls! Vercingetorix
desperately awaits our coming.
Each of you take a ball to vote.
Each in turn.
Good.
Ten!
l said each in turn.
All our foragers who tried
to reach the countryside...
were massacred by the Romans.
And all the Romans who left their
camp were massacred by the Gauls.
Maybe, but this does not provide us
anything to eat.
Hey! When will this famous army
of yours arrive?
l'm saving the rat
for those traitors.
We'll cut their balls
and eat them...
if they ever get here,
the miserable cowards.
They will come.
Vercingetorix escapes us again.
The Gauls don't eat their horses.
They send them out because
they can't feed them.
But he has stayed.
Let's attack now...
while we still have our strength.
We must endure...
for the sake of the army of Gauls
coming to join us.
The fear of their coming...
keeps the Romans working night and
day to build their fortifications.
Listen, if they find themselves
fighting over our corpses...
what heart do you think
they will have for it?
Or you doubt their faithfulness
because they haven't arrived yet?
l'm sorry, you're right.
We cannot survive much longer
on the food we have left.
We must send everyone who
cannot fight out of Alesia.
They might have more chances
of survival in the countryside.
Don't send out the children.
l'll take care of them.
You're right.
The druids will help you.
They're all asleep.
The hammer will never
meet the anvil.
l will win this battle...
-if the army obeys me.
-What are you afraid of?
The deep silence of others.
Twenty balls for Litavic.
Twenty balls for Virido.
-Twenty balls for Commios.
-Pig heads!
The general has to
have the majority.
Twenty balls for Cassivelaun.
This is intolerable.
The leader must be me.
Me.
A Parisi!
Silence!
We've lost too much time
already.
There will be no leader,
but four equal generals
Yes, me.
Virido, Commios...
Cassivelaun, and me.
Our orders are still
not to attack.
Yes.
We can't stay here
doing nothing.
What is it going to change?
Spring will still come, grass
will still grow by itself...
and now Caesar is besieged
in his own fortifications.
And the Teutons won't attack...
if we stay well organised.
-What if they don't attack?
-Then we die.
lt's triumph or death.
And what will decide?
Destiny, Brutus.
Destiny!
-Hello.
-Hi.
Won't you play with us?
One toss, catch with one hand.
Those are the rules!
-lf l score the same, we play again.
-All right.
We're even!
Play again!
You said one toss,
with one hand.
No. The rules have changed.
You always change the rules.
l mean, you can't play like that.
He's right. You're even. He's
not playing to lose or to win.
He wants to keep the game from ending
because he wants us to stay together.
For me it's all over.
But you must go on
and fulfil your destiny.
And now you must not let
the great wheel of destiny...
roll over the people of Gaul.
Go to her. There will
not be many more nights.
Do not attack!
Carnix.
They haven't listened.
They're attacking anyway.
How stupid!
Caesar, they're attacking
from all sides.
As l always told you...
that's what happens if you don't
have a commander in chief.
Carnix. Carnix.
Carnix.
Carnix!
Yes!
You. You want to fight?
You want to die?
You want to live forever?
Then l will lead you,
and together...
we will become immortal.
Don't be afraid, Brutus;
Go!
And now unleash the cavalry.
He has always refused
the decisive battle.
l'm sure he's up to something.
And l don't understand what. l do
not like what l don't understand.
The final battle he never wanted
is a real massacre...
and Litavic is dead.
He wanted to hire the Teutons...
and we stopped him.
And now what are we to do?
Well, it's up to him.
We can only wait...
and see what he'll do!
When the people will not
follow where you lead...
you must follow them...
or walk alone.
You were right, the game
should never stop.
What does it matter
at the end...
to win what your enemy
will lose...
or to lose what he will win?
Where will it lead you?
As far as my energy will allow...
so the greatWheel of Destiny
will follow its course...
eternally moved by love,
as far as necessity demands.
l've always known that
l would always love you.
l will not have another queen...
but you.
He's going where nothing
more can be written.
The greater the magic, the greater
the price that must be paid.
l have only started
what l will never finish.
l come to offer you
the glory of your victory...
which Rome will
forever honour...
with inscriptions in stone
and eternal flames.
The light of my victory will make
my invisible past failures heavier.
l offered to make you a King.
So accept the surrender
of a King.
Caesar was never emperor of Rome.
On the ldes of March, 44 BC...
he was assassinated
on the steps on the senate.
His faithful Brutus
struck the fatal blow.
A few steps away, two years earlier,
at about two in the afternoon...
Vercingetorix, imprisoned
in the Tulianum...
was executed
by order of Caesar.
He did not win the Gallic war...
but for the first time,
he had united all its people...
who, still today live on
in our memory.