Directed by: Kim Han Min
1597 AD The Second
Korean-Japanese War
After 6 years of the First Korean-Japanese war, Yi Sun-Shin
was dismissed from his duty on suspicion of espionage,
and was taken to the
capital and tortured
On July, 1597, Korean navy led by Won
Kyun was destroyed by Japanese navy.
For the first time since 1592, Japanese
began to ravage Jeolla province of Joseon.
August 16th, the fort of Namwon, August
25th, the fort of Jeon-Joo were besieged
Now, the Japanese army was trying to take the capital
as they advanced further north with ferocity...
Yi Sun-Shin, at last freed, was
without any military title,
but doing his best to recruit soldiers and
collect weapons to prepare for the war.
Acquiring the 12 ships that have
survived in the battle of Chil-Chun,
Yi Sun-Shin settled his navy in the west
of the South Sea, at Jindo, Byuk Pa port.
At Uh-Ran port, which is only 100 miles away, about
300 Japanese battleships began to assemble...
The Admiral: Roaring Currents
Jindo, Byuk-Pa Port
12 days after the recommission
So,
When do you plan to have
us join the army, Admiral?
What do you mean?
- Captain Bae-Sul-Why, His
Majesty's command, of course.
His Majesty has commanded us
to join forces with the army,
so I'm asking you when
we are doing that.
Is that how you read it?
What?
Look here Admiral,
the enemy fleets have
already exceeded 200,
Are you aware of the fact that many of
our soldiers are running away already?
- Captain Kim Eok-Choo-In the last ten days,
about 50 soldiers have run away already...
I must ask you today, Admiral...
We have no idea when this enemy would show up
at our doorstep, and that could be tonight
So I'm curious, how do you propose
to fight against such enemies?
Let's heart it from
our young officers!
Do we stand a chance?
Do we?!
Don't be afraid to speak
up to your commander!
Admiral...
Please, enlighten us...
Aside from that one mere turtle
ship, do we have any other plan?
Watch what you're
saying to the Admiral.
How dare you!
I'm your commanding officer!
Shut the hell up and listen!
The hell you are!
You should be ashamed of yourself that you
ran for your life at the battle of Chil-Chun
Listen boy, it's because I ran for my life,
I was able to preserve those twelve ships!
If you don't know shit,
keep your mouth shut.
Admiral...
you know how futile
this battle is...
I saw it myself at Chil-Chun...
I saw how ferocious and
evil they have become!
100,000 of our men have died!
Do you intend to wipe out
the entire Joseon's navy?
You're dismissed, officers.
Admiral!
Your commanding officer
has just ordered you!
Let us go
It is important to repair the
ships and check on our soldiers.
Now!
Hae-Nam, Uh-Ran Port
(Japanese Navy base)
We must capture the king
of Korea and end this war.
We cannot let him escape
again like six years ago.
We must be quicker than
storm when attacking.
- Let's hurry up!
- Yes, General.
Can't let General Konishi
capture their king first.
I wonder why His Excellency (Toyotomi
Hideyoshi) is sending me a new officer...
telling me to just wait...
Are those Wakizaka's men?
Yes, it seems like they're returning
after spying on their camp.
How many times is this?
Counting the last night's surprise
attack, I believe... about three times.
But
I wonder who is this new officer
that is keeping you waiting?
Someone quintessential to
this battle, I'm told.
Apparently, there is no one better
to bring down Yi Sun-Shin than him.
Byuk-Pa Port, Admiral's Fleet
Considering insufficient number of your navy, it would be
beneficial for you to dismiss your men and join forces with army
- Father!
- What is he doing with his sword out?
- I overheard them saying they were going to kill us all!
- Of course they will!
Father! Father!
I swear to god, I will kill you!
No!!!
I apologize for using my
sniper on your prisoner.
It was just kind of hard to see.
Are you the new officer
that the chancellor sent?
They're lyo Navy from Ehime...
What navy? Everyone knows
they are pirates.
Let's go!
Junsa
Jindo Byuk Pa Port
(Joseon Naval Base)
-Dispatch Imminent-
The Japanese are
acting suspicious.
Their ships have already exceeded 200. They are
filling their ships with supplies and stolen horses.
If anybody dares to fight back, they kill him and cut his
nose off. They are also using kids as practice targets.
It's what they do when
they occupy a region.
Is it true that 250,000 Japanese soldiers
are coming down from Jeon-Joo area?
Yes, it seems true.
I've overheard them saying that Joseon navy is useless
and that they will soon be storming the capital city.
If we let them pass, then the
capital will surely burn.
Deliver this to Junsa and make
sure you bring back his reply.
Yes, Admiral.
The top part is finished!
Sweetheart
Another talisman?
I've done this
many times before.
You need not worry too much.
Anyway, I'll keep it safe.
Off I go
Take good care of
yourself, honey
Joseon Army Base (General
Kwon Yul's Camp)
- General Kwon Yul-He's
refusing to follow order again?
He believes it is the
right thing to do.
If he disobeys His Majesty again, there
will be no forgiveness this time!
Namwon fort and Jeon Joo
fort have fallen already.
Japanese army is
invading from the south
Moreover, their navy is trying to go around the South
Sea and attack the capital. What will happen then?
With a measly 12 ships, what does
he think he can accomplish?
Then why are you
asking us to join you?
How dare you! Do you not know Admiral's
health is in bad shape right now?
Who made him that way?
Why you... do you have any idea
what it is like over here?
That evil Kato Kiyomasa is at our doorstep
right now. at this point, every bit helps!
Stop him!
Please General, please give us weapons and
men. Right now Joseon Navy needs your help!
If you follow his Majesty’s
order, everything will be fine.
Do you truly intend to ignore
Admiral Yi's desperate plea?
How insolent! Arrest him!
General, please! General!
Admiral told me to tell you...
If you abandon the sea,
you abandon Joseon!
I've been waiting for half a day.
Is this how you treat your guest?
We've been too absorbed in our strategy meeting that we
forgot to greet our important guest. Please forgive us.
Anyway
Shall we hear from our pirate king on
how to capture the king of Joseon?
On our way to Joseon, I took
a look at their waterway.
If we go around Jindo
on a morning tide,
We can supply our army by night
and still take their capital.
It will only take a day and a
half to get to their capital.
That sounds nice
But Yi Sun-Shin is not
a feeble opponent
We should leave through the
big channel in front of Jindo
Take their capital
Afterward, I propose we join ground forces
and destroy Yi Sun-Shin together.
Why do you think
Hideyoshi sent me
Wakizaka?
What the hell did you just say? How
dare you call our chancellor by name!
I'll crush Yi Sun-Shin
with this hand
Or are you trying to let Konishi
take their capital first?
I apologize for our behaviors.
Please forgive me.
Please, have a seat, Kurushima.
I swear by my sword to
be feared by the world
With one swing, I paint
the world in blood
Mother....
Father, it's me.
It's nice to be with you
Yes...
Father..
Go ahead.
It seems like a good opportunity,
isn't it? Why don't you retire now?
We haven't been able to bring
grandmother home because of this war...
Hand your men over to General Kwon Yul And tell the
king you are too ill to carry out your duties.
You are angry at His Majesty.
He tried to kill you.
Aren't you upset?
Father...
We only have 12 ships left...
Can we even call ourselves
navy at this point?
Even if we could win
against all odds...
The King will
surely abandon you.
What do you fight for?
I fight for loyalty.
Loyal to whom? To
that... shameless king?
There is a saying
A warrior must follow his king
And the king must
follow his people
not the king?
There is no country without its people.
Without people, there is no king.
But people just want to survive.
There's nothing to expect from them.
Finish your meal.
It is precious.
Stay back! Stay back!
Admiral
You all will meet the same fate
Is... is this not
Captain Bae Hong Suk?
Oh god, Captain Bae...
What do we do?
Holy shit!
Get them out of here!
Get out of here!
Kurushima Michiyuki 25 years old
Were you the one who sent the heads
of the prisoners over to their side?!
I also sent their
noses and ears.
Do you have a death wish?
Why would you exacerbate things
by upsetting your enemy?
If they are worthy
opponents, then why not?
But
Are they worth it?
I told you, Yi Sun-Shin
is not a feeble opponent!
I suppose what I
hear is true then
That many of your men
secretly worship Yi Sun-Shin?
So I take it your failure
at the battle of Han-San
has got your balls shriveled?
What the fuck, you bastard!!!
I'll tell you one more time
Why do you think the
chancellor sent me?
It's because I am different than
those of you who fear Yi Sun-Shin
Don't be so quick to
pull your sword out
or your head will be
the first to roll
Since my brother Michiyuki had become the
chancellor's dog and joined this war
He paid it with his life
I suppose he protected me
from the chancellor's wrath
by volunteering to take
my place in this war
But he died at the
hands of Yi Sun-Shin.
In any rate, the
chancellor is old now.
At most, he has until next year.
That's why he is so
eager to end this war.
Joseon, which chancellor
desires so much...
will be mine soon.
That's why
Yi Sun-Shin must die.
Do you understand, Haru?
That is the only way
to avenge my brother.
What is going on?
Isn't that Oh Sang GU?
He must have been
caught running away!
Yeah that's him!
Admiral's coming!
He was caught running away.
My comrades who fought side by side
with me for years have all died...
I buried their heads today...
I'm so afraid...
I feel like it's my turn now...
Do we all have to die like them?
Are you done?
Military rule should be strict!
Do I make myself clear?
We're all screwed now...
He's not going to
change his mind.
Fine..
I'll find a way.
Myungryang Strait, Blood Island
This strait is narrow and shallow. That
is why the current is quite violent here.
That's where it gets its name from. (Literally translated,
Ool-Dol-Mok means the corner where water leaves crying)
Is this the place?
But Admiral,
If our enemy decides to come here, it must
mean that they find this place to be useful
Look at that strong current.
They will have our ships
surrounded in no time.
It does not seem very wise.
That is why we
need a turtle ship
If a turtle ship can destroy
the Japanese in the frontline,
and the rest of our ships
can fire cannons at them...
It takes half a day for the current to change. Will
turtle ship be able to withstand the attacks until then?
When the tide changes, the
current too, becomes mild.
But the sound....
is quite unusual.
Nowadays, it sounds
like a grown man's cry.
Problem is the whirlpool.
It usually does not sound like
that during high tide but
when the great high tide comes
and it makes sounds like that...
There almost always
was a big whirlpool.
It's going to be the great
high tide in about two days...
Do you hear that?
To me, it sounds like the
dead soldiers' cries.
Is that turtle ship
your only plan?
Plan isn't the issue.
The problem is
the growing fear among my men.
Is there truly no way
to overcome this?
What should we do if
we can't overcome it?
Is threatening them with
punishment the only way
To overcome fear?
Would that work?
Then
how do you propose...
I can probably use that fear...
Use... use fear?
Admiral... avenge us...
Admiral...
Please avenge us...
Avenge us...
You were alive...
I'm glad you came
Captain Choi... Captain Lee...
Please avenge us, Admiral...
Please avenge us...
Here...
Have a drink...
Have a drink and
stay for a while...
Hey...
Where are you going?
Captain Lee.. Captain
Choi... Hong Suk...
Please wait...
Where are you going
in such a hurry...?
Father!
Turtle ship on fire!
Admiral!
It's Bae-Sul's men!
It's on fire!
Save the ship!
He's over there!
Don't you all want to live?
Yi Sun-Shin is trying
to get us all killed
But I've found a way for us!
Don't throw away your
lives. It's not worth it!
So hurry up and...
Bring more water!
Admiral please.
It's dangerous, sir!
No! this can't be!
Let me go!
No!
No... no!
It's our turtle ship...!
Father!
It's all over now.
We were almost there..!
I must defeat them
with that ship...!
No...!
My lord!
Yi Sun-Shin's turtle ship
had just burned down.
What?
We sent our spies over to see what was going
on when we spotted fire from his camp
we were able to confirm that his turtle
ship has burned down to the ground.
That was his last
one, wasn't it?
Indeed.
Yi Sun-Shin no longer
has any turtle ship.
The road that we must
go on has no obstacles.
I sure can feel your power
in your calligraphy!
This should be our motto.
Let's go!
Junsa... Junsa where are you...
Cleaning before occupying...
Help me!
Catch him!
Catch that bastard!
Hey, help me!
Hey, don't go! Help me!
Walk faster!
One guy is missing!
Find him!
Walk!
Faster!
I'm useful. I can
row really well...
What the hell is he saying!
What the fuck?
Soo bong!
You little...
I'm sorry..I'm sorry!
Please don't kill me!
Calm down!
Whirlpool...
Turtle ship...
Father! It's Junsa's message!
Japanese plan to attack tomorrow morning.
They have about 330 battle ships.
Unfortunately, the new officer you asked
me to look into is someone I do not know.
All I know is that his name is Kurushima Michifusa and
that he comes from Ehime, where it is very much like here.
Good news is Wakizaka Yasuhiro
is leading the second battalion
I hope this helps.
I will join you as
soon as I return.
Let's go to Hae-Nam.
Sir?
We cannot fight here.
They are coming from behind us. We are
going to have to leave from Hae-Nam.
Let's go to war!
It's from General Konishi.
Why, he's hurrying me.
I am sure we will capture
their king first.
We are ready to go.
Tonight, Joseon looks
especially beautiful.
I like Joseon.
My Lord.
Report.
We are ready to go.
We've chosen Joseon prisoners
to serve in the lower deck
and we also amply prepared
gunpowder as well.
Yi Sun-Shin will not
survive this battle.
Let's go!
We don't even have any turtle ship this time!
And what the hell is this one-line-formation?
Has he gone mad or something?
I agree! Can't you hear that
sound? We'll die for sure.
We must think of something!
What is this plan of yours?
Are you trying to suggest that we
try and kill him like Bae Sul?
No, that is not what I mean...
Damn, I'm just anxious. We can't
even send a message to Lord Kim.
Let's go.
Go where?
I'll try to convince
the Admiral.
If I can't, I'll die tonight.
Your Majesty...
If you dismiss your navy now,
I am afraid our enemy will go around the yellow sea
and march straight to the capital city where you are.
My only worry is this.
I still have 12 ships
left to fight with.
If we all combine our
strengths and might
We can surely fight them off.
As long as I live,
they will not...
They will not dare
to invade us again.
Admiral... I have
something to say to you.
This battle is suicidal
This is suicidal!
Although you say we can fight them
off by luring them to Blood Isle
Without our turtle ship, it seems
unlikely that we could win
Please reconsider this decision
and think of the future. Admiral!
Admiral!
Is this really what you think?
If you can't reconsider,
then please have me killed.
I'd prefer to die by your sword.
If this is truly what you think
then, all right.
Assemble everybody in front
of quarters tonight.
Yes, sir!
Have you two brought
what I asked for?
Yes, sir!
Pour it!
What are you waiting
for? I said pour it!
- You heard what the Admiral said!
- Yes, sir!
- Burn it all!
Admiral! Please don't!
Admiral! Please!
Admiral, this is
not the way to go!
Stay back!
What a shame it is
that many of you
still wish to live!
We as soldiers
cannot and should
not avoid death!
You wonder, if we can survive
if we avoid this battle?
Do you believe you will
be safe if you hide?
Mark my words
I burn this place so that we could die
out there on that water, fighting
There is no place to go
no place to hide
Do not fear death
If you wish to live
you will find death
If you wish to die,
you shall find life
There is a saying
If one man does his duty
he can defeat thousands.
Is that not our situation?
Father...
How do you intend
to use this fear?
So this is Captain Bae's son?
Yes sir.
He's the one who brought Junsa's message
for you instead of Im Jun Young.
Luckily he escaped
because Junsa found him.
This was your father's.
Will you take it?
What is your name, son?
I am called Soo Bong, sir.
Your father and I fought side by
side for six years in this war.
I will not forget
you or your father.
I have a wish, sir
Go ahead.
I'd like to be part of your
crew. I want to help you.
If you promise to stay out of
harm's way, I will grant your wish.
Thank you sir
This is crazy...
Port of Hae-Nam
Mother...
This may be the last
day of my life.
I just hope my death
will not be in vain.
Admiral
You did well
I am Hae-Yi. I came to help.
You have my gratitude. Your
presence gives me strength.
Admiral!
Welcome back.
Sound the attack.
Sound the attack!
Depart now!
Myeongnyang Strait 8 AM
Set up the One-Line-Formation
The current is
strong. Row harder!
We must remain in
control! Row harder!
We cannot have our ship
fall back! Row harder!
Get rid of it.
- What is that?
- What the hell is that big black mass?
Other ships are falling back!
Soo Bong, I think we
boarded the wrong ship!
You didn't know this
was the main fleet?
That's what I'm saying! Why is
the main fleet going forward?
I will raise the communication
flag and tell them to come back!
Leave them be.
But sir...
Put the ship's anchor into the water and
get ready for a possible close combat.
Put the anchor into the water!
How come Yi Sun-Shin is not
putting up a command flag?
Look at his men. Even if he put
up one, would they listen?
Send the first battalion.
First battalion! Charge!
Turn the ship to the right side
and get the cannons ready.
Get the cannons ready!
Stop the ship and turn it to
the right side! Hurry up!
Captain Nah! Captain Song!
Aim all our cannons
at the front line
at the front line!
Aim it!
Snipers ready!
Fire!
It's speeding up!
Archers ready!
Now!
Fire!
Speed up and turn the
ship to the left!
Fire!
Watch out!
Now!
Yi Sun-Shin is attacking
the ones in the front
Kurushima's men are in chaos.
He's neither moving
nor backing down.
Wonder what he's waiting for...
How about we join forces
and attack together?
No. Let's wait.
Fear does not discriminate. It
can equally affect both sides.
Because they too, are afraid of
me because of their past defeats.
Fear does not discriminate...
Is that all? Is that
how you use fear?
If we can somehow transform
that fear into courage....
Send the second battalion
and push harder.
Second battalion, charge!
Kurushima is pushing hard.
He claims to be the expert
Let's wait and see.
Just wait and see.
The victory is ours.
They will be crushed.
The current is in our favor.
Admiral, the current has turned our ship so
much that it is interfering with our aim.
Cut the anchor and just ride the
current towards the Blood Isle.
Yes, sir.
Caught you.
Fire!
Bring me the pole!
Row harder! We cannot
let the ship get hit!
Admiral, we must put the
flag up and call them over!
We won't last long
without their help!
Captain, change the artillery
to smaller cannons.
Then prepare for close combat.
Soldiers, prepare
for close combat!
Charge!
Now!
Fire!
Charge!
Kurushima is winning!
Yi Sun-Shin tried to
hold as long as he could
But it looks like it's over
Fuck it, we're all fucking dead!
Admiral!!!
Admiral!
Take the rest of the cannons up on
this deck and move them downstairs!
Aim them at the enemy
ships' lower deck
can you do that?
We might die trying...
Just tell me you'll get it done!
Yes Admiral!
I'm counting on you!
Stack multiple cannons
and aim at their ships!
Yes sir!
Hurry up and go get the gunpowder
and cannons from the armory!
Soo Bong, no! It's dangerous!
Move all of these!
Hurry up!
Admiral! We are ready!
Soldiers get down!
Everyone get down!
Is that how you use fear?
If you can somehow turn
that fear into courage
That courage will be infectious
But father...
How can you turn such fear into courage
when they are so scared out of their minds?
I will have to die...
Could it be really over?
Whoa!
The main fleet is
alive and well!
They're alive!
Kill them all!
Damn those motherfuckers!
Wait, I wanna kill them too!
Let's go kill some Japanese!
Speed up, gentlemen!
Myeongryang Strait,
2 PM (mild current)
It's the whirlpool.
Yi Sun-Shin...
There's a reason why you
refuse to leave that Isle.
My lord, the current has changed and now
the whirlpool has become ferocious.
That's why on his side,
the current is mild.
From where he is, it will be easier
to aim at us. Do you see that?
Whoever gets that Isle,
will win this fight.
The battle would be
over in a heartbeat.
Before he settles there completely,
speed up towards his ship!
Sir, it's their main fleet.
Call our captains over.
Yes, sir.
You're mine now!
Admiral!
Captain Ahn!
I should be punishing you
accordingly for disobeying me
But since we are at war right now, You
must focus on fighting the enemy off
You must protect Blood Isle.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, Admiral!
Captain Song, we must
move to Mok-Joong port.
Absolutely, sir!
Move towards Mok-Joong port!
Perfect timing, sir.
Explosion will be massive.
Yi Sun-Shin's pathetic attempt
to lure us will not work.
Our main fleet will continue on
towards the isle as you commanded.
Sir!
There's a strange boat
coming towards our way!
Bring in the archers.
-Yes, sir!
Fire!
We must hurry! Pump it out!
Hurry!
What the hell?
Oh my god, I'm free!
Im Jun Young?
Junsa!
Gunpowder?!
He says that ship is
full of gunpowder!
Also, Im Jun Young
is on that ship!
Are they not answering?
Reload!
Sir, there is no answer!
Honey, wave something so
that they can see this...
You cannot let this
ship go to our Admiral!
Sweetheart, do it!
There you go.. that's my girl.
Let's wave something!
Sir, look over there!
There's a strange boat going
towards our main fleet!
- Prepare to fire!
- Yes sir!
Aim!
Fire away!
You did well...
I am glad I saw your
face one last time
See you on the other side...
Admiral, their main fleet
is approaching fast!
They're coming at us!
Row faster!
Yi Sun-Shin, you're finished!!!
Close combat!
Board their ship!
Kuroda!
Hurry up and get our ship ready!
Shall we back him up?
Everyone, we need your help!
Soo Bong! Soo Bong!
Yi Sun-Shin, I'm coming for you!
Sir! Our ships have
come to our aid!
Kimura!
Hurry up and follow them!
Sir, we can't! Our ships are
trapped in that whirlpool!
Aim!
Fire!
We must call for a back up!
You don't understand, do you?
They are not coming.
Should we send back up?
Yi Sun-Shin...
you...
Are you Japanese
or are you Korean?
Yi Sun-Shin!!!
Admiral, I'm sorry but our ship
cannot hold on much longer...
Admiral! We will get
you out of there!
Admiral! Our
officers are coming!
We must hurry before they
get into a formation!
Why aren't you speeding up?
The current has changed.
I know that! Tell
them to row harder!
It's all about speed
at this point!
Speed is the only way to win!
Speed up!
Don't let go!
When the hell can I
get off this ship?
It worked!
Sir!
Listen up!
No way
We're gonna crash!
What is this, a suicide mission?
What the fuck!
Please hold on... please!
That crash...!
It's the turtle ship!
Was that his plan all along?
They're running away!
Fire away!
Yi Sun-Shin...
Retreat!
Let's go back.
The current is back to normal.
We got 23 Japanese
soldiers here!
17 here!
We got 3 Japanese
officers and 9 soldiers!
Even if Japanese want to take
us, they can't! We're too good!
- Eat some of this
- I'm eating already!
You know, earlier I gave one of them Japanese
bitches death glare then they shit their pants!
I'm cool like that
I wonder if our descendants will ever understand
how much shit we had to go through for them?
If they don't, then
they're assholes
Now that we're alive and well,
let's go see our wives and kids
have some water!
Why, isn't this taro?
How wonderful it is to
be alive and eat this
Admiral!
What shall we do...
With all this hatred
between us...
Father
how on earth did you think of
using whirlpool as a weapon?
Father..
You said something?
I was asking you about the whirlpool.
It was such a good timing.
Heaven helped us.
If that is true, then couldn't it also
have turned out really bad for us?
Yes, that's true...
If it wasn't for the people
who came to save me.
You think people helped
us? Not the whirlpool?
What do you think? Which do you
think was more of a miracle?
1592 AD July
Han-San Island
That thing over there
What the hell is that?