Reason and motivation for this film were the
experiences of the student from Passau
Anja Rosmus, and her family.
The story my film tells is
at once fiction and truth.
I am not interested in the history
of a specific town in Germany,
but rather in the truth of
all towns in our country.
My film is set in Bavaria
because I live here.
Characters and actions are fictional.
Michael Verhoeven
We have been told in
ancient tales many marvels
of famous heroes, of mighty toil,
joys, and high festivities,
of weeping and wailing,
and the fights of bold warriors - of such
things you can now hear wonders unending!
OK. So... It all started with
the President.
- The President Dr. Karl Carstens
namely... - I'm sorry.
- Too much to the right.
- What?
Namely invited...
I'm sorry.
Too high.
The President Dr. Karl Carstens
namely invited
all the students in the Federal Republic
to an essay competition.
But... Actually it all
started much earlier.
WHERE WERE YOU BETWEEN 39-45.
WHERE ARE YOU NOW?
THE NASTY GIRL
A Film by
Michael Verhoeven
So... I am Sonja Wegmus,
née Rosenberger.
Behind me is the Cathedral.
Around me is my dear
hometown, Pfilzing.
Pfilzing is a lovely old Episcopal city
and lies on the Pfilz.
I was born there.
And my mother and my grandma
and all before that.
My father is a displaced person.
He came here from Silesia
only after the war.
My father is a teacher at Pfilzing
secondary school, St. George.
My mother is also a teacher.
At the same school as my father.
My mother teaches religion.
...as everyone saw, that in temple,
the church,
they were doing business.
He overturned the tables
with money and said:
Make not my Father's house
a house of merchandise.
That is my mother.
I was not born yet.
Here she already had the
first problems with me.
Good bye, children.
Goodbye, Miss.
Do you really want to further teach
religion in your condition.
But madam,
I still feel OK.
But it is quite obvious
that you're pregnant.
But I am married.
It's not about you.
It's about children.
They are asking questions.
- Good day.
- Paul, wait a minute.
Come here, please.
But it was of no avail.
My mother had to go.
The Catholic Church had an opinion,
that the children had to be protected
from the site of my pregnant mother.
When I arrived,
my uncle took us in.
This is my uncle Franz.
My mother's brother.
He is a cathedral vicar in Pfilzing
and lived in a monastery at the time.
You see, my father didn't get an apartment,
because he was a displaced person.
So we stayed with uncle
Franz in monastery.
Actually that was a seminary for boys
who wanted to become priests.
By that time my brother was born.
- Robert.
- Sonja, what were you thinking?
- Sonja.
- For God's sake.
This is Robert.
But then another sister
was born.
Lina.
Nothing to see there.
So, please.
As my father became a rector,
we moved to a small house in Petersbach.
The right one there,
that's us.
Directly opposite is the school,
where my father had class.
This so-called border...
- is called...
- The Oder-Neisse line.
Paul.
Be on time for lunch.
I won't reheat everything again.
I have a boy today
who must stay after class.
Not today, Paul.
What is it then?
What should have happened
on Friday already.
We're still living in the house today.
I had a wonderful and
secure childhood here.
And nature meant everything to me.
My mother taught us early,
that God's creatures are sacred.
Sonja, what are you doing?
Nothing.
A fish prefers to swim.
The child should be in kindergarten.
No way.
Now sit there.
Sure! So that she can get
all sorts of diseases there.
And meet God knows what
kind of children there.
Drop-outs and socialists. No thanks.
We were an ideal family.
My father was always allowed
to lead the prayers at mass.
An when he was standing in front
and all the people were listening to him
I was always proud and happy.
When I was about 12 years old,
there was always nice music on the radio
and I really liked to dance.
Sonja, come here.
Sonja, you're going home right away.
OK. OK.
I don't want to hear OK.
I liked being in school.
I went to convent school St. Ana.
Opposite was a classical gymnasium
for boys St. Eberhard.
Fuck the German shitty television.
At 30, 60 and 95 degrees...
Of course we had quite different education
system then at St. Ana.
- Good morning, ladies.
- Good morning, sister Leontina.
Yesterday we have learned,
that the English pronunciation...
Oh, my goodness.
Where are the curtains?
Rabenbauer.
I don't know.
Rosenberger.
They were brought to
the laundry yesterday.
Say it in English.
- The curtains were brought to the...
- Laundry. - ... laundry
Take your things.
Go down to the gym.
Please, hurry up.
We'll move to the gym room.
Hurry up.
The next day the glasser came.
And he put in milk glass windows.
Then we didn't have to go to the gym
anymore when the curtains were being washed.
My teacher was Miss Juckenack.
I liked her the most.
Although she always checked the
donation book first, before grading.
Haven't you prepared?
The Abtretter Gabi's father
always spent the most.
The correct answer would be:
Land is more expensive.
Spengler.
Listen carefully.
Please translate.
Army costs a lot, too.
The Spengler Hilde's father also
spent a lot.
But this year...
I expected more from you.
Rosenberger.
She liked me very much.
She never looked in the book for me.
That is Ablativus pretii.
Very commendable.
Ablativus pretii.
One day Miss Juckenack
came very excited.
Good day, Miss Juckenack.
- Is Sonja here?
- Yes.
Oh, I'm sorry to bother
you during dinner time.
Good day, Miss Juckenack.
- Let me take your coat.
- Thank you.
An essay contest, Sonja.
From the President. An essay contest.
In the whole of Europe.
She said I had to participate,
because it's such a commendable topic.
Freedom in Europe.
And no one has so much
freedom as us.
Sometimes even too much freedom.
- Don't you think so?
- Yes. - Yes, yes.
In the East. That's a different story.
She will write the right thing, Sonja.
Then I went to the town hall archives
and borrowed some books.
The head of the archives, Mr. Schulz,
helped me.
- Is it going well, Miss Rosenberger?-
- Yes.
I am not so sure about Greece anymore.
Should I count it towards
free democratic countries?
You are right.
That is difficult.
Because of the military junta.
- But it is in NATO.
- Yes, but a dictatorship nevertheless.
But through NATO it is a free
dictatorship, right?
In a sense.
Why don't you write, Greece is the
birthplace of democracy. That should suffice.
Yes, I'll write that.
I was very happy. I loved going
to school almost more than before.
Then something extraordinary happened.
Another thing.
Soon a young student teacher from Munich,
Mr. Wegmus, will take over
Math and Physics classes.
Rabenbauer, what is going on?
Please behave towards the new
teacher as it befits future ladies.
What is going on there?
We could totally make him uncomfortable.
We will always look him
directly in the eye.
Until he has to look away.
We could also look at his other parts.
And don't say a word.
No matter what he asks.
I don't understand that.
When we are asked something,
we must answer.
No, we don't, dummy.
That's the catch.
So, my name is Wegmus.
Must go.
(Muss weg.)
I hope we will get along well.
What topic did you study last time?
Rosenberger.
Contact electricity.
Contact electricity is
found in every day's life.
For instance when taking
off certain clothes,
it sparks.
Rabenbauer.
What happens when two bodies
rub against each other.
When two bodies rub against each other,
they must first get
over certain inhibitions.
- This were the gallows they say.
- Creepy.
What are you doing?
Come here.
You are supposed to pay for the candles.
Dear god, make him fall
in love with me. Amen.
You should pray better,
if you want it to work.
I made something for you again.
- For you, my dear child.
- Thank you.
I received most of the exams
we were supposed to take
a few days in advance.
Of course the teachers didn't
do favors for everybody.
But they did for those, whose
parents had spent generously.
Like Abtretter Gabi and Lettl Ramona.
I had to thank my uncle Franz
for the privileges I'd had.
My teachers adored
uncle Franz very much.
No, this isn't right.
Come, dad, help me.
I think it's disgraceful, that
children get exams in advance.
Come on, help me.
I'm surprised that you
participate in something like this.
I will complain to the school.
I should send this to newspaper.
Don't sin.
Hey. Hey.
You don't need to
accompany me to school, mom.
I'm old enough.
I’m nervous otherwise.
- May I drive you?
- Good day, Mr. Wegmus.
Is it on your way?
- Yes, I live nearby.
- Thank you. Come.
I could drive you more often.
My mother wouldn't allow it.
I have something for you.
It is the math homework for tomorrow.
It's the homework text.
Maybe you...
This is not necessary, Mr. Wegmus.
Thank you.
One day our postman
came with a big surprise.
- Good day, Mr. Kolodzieczik.
- Good morning, Miss Rosenberger.
A brief from the President.
For me?
You're joking.
No, no. It says here President's Office.
This belonged to the Poles.
Across the Oder-Neisse line
begins the...
...so-called GDR.
Mom!
Dad!
I won the first prize.
In all Germany.
The first prize, Mom.
A trip to France.
You see?
Maria! There's no way the
child can go to France alone.
Sit!
Dear tree,
you helped me so often.
Two years ago when I lost my purse
in the bathhouse and now again.
Thank you so much.
But now I want to ask
you for another thing.
Please protect Mr. Wegmus.
You know he has to leave Pfilzing now.
Make him return some day.
So that...
Rabenbauer Iris can marry him.
I saw you from afar and I just
wanted to say goodbye once more.
So, have a nice trip to Paris.
You too, to Munich.
Thank you.
After I take my final exam,
I will return to you, Sonja.
I mean, Miss Rosenberger.
I'd like to call you by your first name.
Me too.
I am Martin.
I know.
Sonja!
You are engaged now.
But don't tell anyone.
So I traveled to Paris
during summer break.
Of course I had to
call home every evening.
No, everything is OK.
Excuse me.
Yes, I've checked where
the fire escape is.
Certainly, I...
I've locked up already.
And here you discover the Eiffel tower.
Everybody had to describe
which country he'd come from.
And then I noticed,
that with me it's not that easy.
Est-ce que Pfilzing et dans DDR?
No. Pfilzing not DDR.
No. Not in the so-called DDR.
- Not German Democratic Republic.
- Not democratic?
- Bavaria.
- Pas Democratic Bavaria?
No. Oh, yes, yes. Democratic, yes.
Democratic Bavaria.
But... Christian Socialistic Union.
- Socialistic?
- No. No, no.
So, where do you live exactly?
- Te l'a dit. Elle vit en la Republic Federal
Allemand. - She said socialistic. - No, no.
My standards have changed in Paris.
When I came back to Pfilzing,
they honored me.
I received the silver
taler from the mayor.
Only very important people get it.
Follow Sonja's example.
- Congratulations, general.
- What did you say?
- Congratulations, Dr. Kogler.
- State of law is a higher cause...
- Congratulations, Miss Sonja.
- Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Congratulations, Mr. Mayor.
Now, Sonja.
- This is all thanks to you.
- Come now.
You know my brother?
Prof. Juckenack.
- Good day.
When I saw Prof. Juckenack,
I remembered a story
that he allegedly...
...in the 60s he adressed
highest authority
to campaign against the
printing of 50-Mark bill.
- ...highest authority...
- Not sure how it goes...
But I think people just
attributed the story to him.
Anyway in a certain position,
this banknote becomes something
very obscene looking in the mirror.
In the mirror?
Give it here.
Now look. Have you ever
seen anything so wonderful?
The money must be prohibited.
It spoils our youth.
Dear Dr. Juckenack,
I can't ban all 50 DM bills!
Come here.
Check this.
Would you like to prohibit
coffee drinking, too?
Anyway the 50-Mark
bill was not prohibited.
- Cheer up father. Play for us,
you play so nice! - Nicely wrong!
- How is that thing?
- With the bypass road?
Well, can I have that assignment?
Would you like to make the best offer?
I would have to know how
high are the other offers.
- That may be arranged.
- Good.
If I had known what a
celebrity you would become,
I would preserve your
appendix in alcohol.
Sonja got our worm-pills
from my late husband.
She was this little then.
Such a family is the best
breeding ground, isn't it?
Mrs. diocese councilor, Mrs.
pharmacist, Mr. principal.
Your Excellency.
I still see vividly, how this little girl
ran around our seminary garden.
After two years Martin,
I mean Mr. Wegmus returned.
He was an assessor!
Martin!
Martin.
Sonja.
You are still my Sonja, right?
Of course.
Such a kiss.
Because I'm fond of you.
One day Miss Juckenack came
to our house very excited.
- Is Sonja here?
- Good day, Miss Juckenack.
I'm sorry to bother you at dinner time.
- Good day.
- You know Mr. Wegmus, assessor.
- Yes, of course.
- Good day, Miss Juckenack.
- Good day.
- Would you like to eat with us?
- No, that's not necessary.
Bring a chair, please.
Please, sit here.
She explained that the President
announced another essay contest.
Topic: European idea.
Is there another topic?
Yes...
But...
My hometown in the Third Reich.
That's a nice topic.
I'll take it.
My hometown in the Third Reich?
What would you write about?
How the town fought
against National Socialism.
Especially the Church.
There's plenty to write about.
Very commendable.
...world without end. Amen.
- Good night.
- Follow Sonja's example.
- Yes, OK.
- Write only about positive things.
- Yes, of course.
Sleep well.
I already pictured winning
another first prize.
Maybe this time a trip to America.
The next day I started right away
asking acquaintances and relatives,
who experienced the era.
I first interviewed uncle Franz.
We, in the boarding school, didn't
notice much of the nazis.
And then suddenly there was a rumor,
that they arrested pastor Schulte.
Then they released him again.
But in his sermons he kept on arguing
against the racial laws.
And then they executed him.
Who?
- Mom, pastor Schulte.
- Yes, pastor Schulte.
He was a saint.
- Grandma, I can't eat anymore.
- Come now. Just a little piece.
Uncle Franz told me to go to Prof. Juckenack
if I wanted to know more
about pastor Schulte.
He is the one with 50-Mark bill.
He is the head of Episcopal archives.
But he has many other duties.
So I went to the church archives,
in Archiepiscopal ordinariate.
But strangely Prof. Juckenack didn't want
to know anything about pastor Schulte.
He talked only about Zumtobel,
who was a mayor in that time.
The only fully convinced Nazi was,
in my opinion, the mayor.
- Zumtobel?
- Yes.
He must have been very evil.
He got his deserved punishment.
He couldn't say anything
about pastor Schulte, he said.
The documents must be in Berlin, since
he was sentenced by People's Court.
And in the archives? Is there
nothing written about the times?
I'm sorry. We are just a
church library, theology.
Why are you writing about this anyway?
I would like to show, how the Church
remained honest in the Nazi era.
Well, I am sorry. Say hello to your
parents. And to your uncle, too.
I was disappointed.
But other people that I asked,
also always started talking
about Zumtobel right away.
And that he was evil.
Never mind, I thought to myself.
I'll go to the town hall archives
and find everything about Zumtobel.
- Is it going well?
- No.
I can't find anything that makes sense.
What are you trying to find?
Well. For instance about mayor Zumtobel.
That is filed as confidential.
It cannot be shown.
But I need it.
For my school essay.
You must get a permit
from Zumtobel's widow.
This is Zumtobel chocolate factory.
In all these boilers
a chocolate is stirred.
Maybe this smells nice.
This all belongs to Zumtobel family.
And Mrs. Zumtobel made an appointment
with me here in April 1979.
I thought maybe she still had
the documents from the trial,
that the Americans held for
her husband after the war.
That is you?
You want my permission,
to bring out all the dirt and all
the lies about my husband again.
I don't want to write about the lies.
I want only the facts.
My husband spent six years
in labor camp. Six years.
And he died of sadness.
These are the facts.
And others had a good time.
And now get out of here!
Now!
Zumtobel.
wasn't a bad type at all.
If it wasn't for him I would have
been arrested.
Because of the crucifixes.
- Which crucifixes?
- The school crucifixes.
They wanted to remove them
from the classrooms.
But I said no! No!
And then I gathered the women.
And then we went up to
the school building.
We were the first protesters.
- Really? You, grandma?
- Yes.
But then the police came
and arrested me.
But the district leader said,
send her home, she has 10 children.
Whose cat is that?
She's been straying around
for a while now.
I've asked everybody
about her already.
There's a hungry cat...
I remembered another person, who could
tell you something about pastor Schulte.
Dr. Kogler.
The one who received the silver
taler the same time as you.
He's a retired judiciary president.
I think he worked at the
People's Court.
He could tell you about Zumtobel, too.
I don't know. Mr. Kogler
shouldn't be taken too seriously.
Was he imprisoned after the war?
Why? He's a socialist.
I don't know anything.
I was in Berlin.
I have no idea what was
happening in Pfilzing.
In the difficult years.
Where in Berlin?
What is it to you?
I'm sorry.
- I thought maybe you were at
the People's Court. -So?
Do you think I could chose where
I wanted to work in those times?
I don't know.
And People's Court
only delivered justice.
And so did the other courts.
- Or do you think we were happy
convicting people? - No.
So, there was war.
Were you ever in the same situation?
And now go home.
And don't come back.
He can definitely help you.
You'll see.
Here is a cheesecake from
Sunday that must be eaten.
Yes, here is Dr. Friedfoll.
I'd like to speak to cathedral preacher.
Thank you.
- What do you want from a socialist?
- A socialist? God forbid!
Good day, Sir.
I have a request.
Cathedral preacher has just
returned from a fire drill.
- Good day.
- Sorry you had to wait.
Good day.
I have to wash my hands.
I keep myself fit this way.
Sit here, please.
- Reverend, may I.
- Thank you.
Reverend, cheers.
There is still somebody who knows.
What is the name of the woman
who lives near the school? Mrs...
Guggenwieser.
Yes, that's why the
Americans put her in jail.
Because she denounced pastor Schulte.
Pastor Schulte?
But she surely won't tell anything.
Why don't you just visit her? She lives
in an old people's home, St. Ansgar.
The Americans put me
in jail for 14 months.
That was something.
I didn't want pastor
Schulte to be convicted.
I only wanted him to shut up.
But they executed him right away.
The judge who sentenced
pastor Schulte to death.
Nothing had happened to him. The
Americans should put him in jail to.
Nothing happened to him.
And to the others also.
The brown Heinrich for instance.
I am tired now.
She'll recover.
In a couple of weeks.
These old people are tough.
The brown Heinrich?
No, never heard of him.
Wait, that must be Zumtobel,
his name is Karl-Heinrich.
Do you want to keep it?
I was impressed by him.
But maybe he was just quite stubborn.
Or just very proud.
Or vain about his decency.
I went to see Mrs. Guggewieser again,
to ask her about the brown Heinrich.
I didn't know anymore how to go on.
And I was also afraid at the time,
that Martin doesn't like me anymore.
Because I'd had so little time for him.
Rabenbauer Iris was
just waiting for that.
Anyway the deadline
for the essay expired,
and I closed the chapter.
I am just glad that the deadline
for your assignment expired.
I am not glad.
But I am.
You cared only about your essay.
- I thought you didn't like
me anymore. - Nonsense.
Pull yourself together, Eberhard.
Don't make such a spectacle.
- Somebody should bomb the place..
- Eberhard!
- Can I dance with your fiancée?
- Well, ask him.
Please come, Mr. Assessor.
Now the girls have their diplomas.
That's life. That's nature.
Sonja, come here.
What are you going to do now?
I'm sorry.
Miss Rosenberger.
- I'm going to study history.
- Very commendable.
She's interested in something particular,
namely Pfilzing in the Third Reich.
- May I have this dance?
- Sure.
Does this mean she will keep on prying.
She is just interested.
You voted against the bypass road?
Yes, because it is unchristian to
build this close to the miracle tree.
Didn't you plan to build a huge
furniture store there?
That has been rejected, then.
Everything is negotiable.
- This is Charly Zumtobel.
- Hello.
Sonja.
Take this ring
SILESIA IS OURS
and wear it as a sign
of my love and fidelity.
Follow Sonja's example.
Oh, my god.
Sonja.
- Are you hurt?
- No, no.
Sonja.
It so happens that right next door a small
apartment on the first floor became available.
Sit on the couch.
Sonja, you shouldn't carry
such heavy things. Come.
Then Sarah was born.
Very nice. Hold it.
Damn, I forgot to wind it.
Hold it. Sonja...
You should lift Sonja higher.
She is not Sonja.
She is Sarah.
Yes, little Sarah.
And then came Rebecca.
- You should lift Sonja higher.
- The child's name is Rebecca.
- Quite right. - Don't cry, Sarah.
- I just misspoke.
I was happily married.
And Sarah and Rebecca
brought much joy.
But sometimes I had a
feeling that I had failed.
That I wasn't there anymore.
Anyway the people of Pfilzing believed,
now she's over that
craziness. Thank god.
Now she remembers her
duties as wife and mother.
But I said to myself: No.
I'll just start all over again.
And I said to my husband, Martin,
I'm going to study at the university.
I started my studies.
Theology, German and history.
My parents were glad, because
they thought I would be a teacher.
But I just wanted to return to my topic.
I thought to myself, if
they didn't want my essay
I'll write a book.
I registered for classes
with Prof. Juckenack outright.
And then I visited him in
the editorial department.
Because he was also the chief
editor of Pfilzing Morgen newspaper.
A junior editor took me there.
You want to write a book about Pfilzing?
I've already started.
But you don't know anything.
I will study.
I want to learn from you.
Why do you want to write a book?
Do you want to be famous?
No.
I thought to myself that
something is hidden here.
- And now I want to know what.
- I have nothing to hide.
Zöpfel.
The young lady has all access
to the newspaper archives.
Look. I've found something strange.
Pfilzing Morgen. Wednesday.
November 2, 1936.
Typical Jewish gimmickry
A Jewish laundry salesman
conned two Pfilzing priests
out of 100 underpants.
The Hebrew profiteer
offered the priests,
to pay for the underpants
only at the end of the year.
Until then the merchandize was practically
given away because of the inflation.
The priests did their duty
and denounced the Jew,
who belittled the
government with this act.
He was sent to concentration
camp Hackeldorf.
- You are always studying hard.
- Good day, Mr. Zöpfel.
- Underpants?
- Yes.
The priests stated,
that the member of the Jewish race
put them in a state of trance
with physical contact.
Is there a name?
No, it only says,
member of the Jewish race.
- I mean of the priests.
- No.
So, there you have it.
I'm sorry.
Hackeldorf. Is that our
Hackeldorf, there by the Pfilz?
I cannot remember anything.
Mom.
Look what I found!
I am busy.
1940.
Dr. Juckenack.
We, German people, fight
today for our racial integrity.
Purity of the Aryan race
and its living space.
God is with us.
God is with our beloved führer.
This is strange, isn't it?
It is impossible that
Juckenack wrote this.
He was a member of the resistance.
Prof. Juckenack.
That could be anyone
in Pfilzing. Really.
But there was a concentration camp.
Hackeldorf, right.
We had no concentration camp.
Nonsense.
Concentration camp?
Just the opposite. There were people who
came to this base from concentration camps.
They were glad to be there.
They didn't have to go to
concentration camp from this base.
They worked a little.
But Prof. Steiert said in his lecture...
They were treated very decently.
There was a tall fence.
With barbed wire.
They were like animals in zoo.
And they begged.
Then I threw them some bread.
The guard told me it was prohibited.
And I would be put in jail if I did it again.
But I did it again and again.
I had three men in the battlefield.
So I thought...
...maybe someone will give
them something to eat.
One of the Nazi authors
started the so-called
host desecrations again
and spread the hate against the Jews.
In the 15. century
the Pfilzing Christians tortured and
cruelly killed the Jewish fellow citizens,
because a Jew allegedly stole the host
and pierced it with a knife.
Out of one host even blood ran.
Naturally...
Naturally such a legend had
a great effect in the Third Reich.
I cannot let you in.
I'm sorry. Please don't ask me why.
Suddenly I wasn't allowed to use
the Pfilzing Morgen archives anymore.
Allegedly because the newspapers
were being recorded to microfilm.
But then everything changed.
Namely, my former schoolmate
Lettl Ramona got engaged to the
grandson of district leader Zumtobel.
To Charly, who inherited
the chocolate factory.
And he had no objections against me
inspecting documents about his grandfather.
This is made from my
grandpa's old recipe.
Charly didn't care about the past.
He said, main thing is
that the business is good.
Charly said, the Americans
even offered his grandfather
to open a chocolate factory in USA.
That's why he didn't believe that
the old Zumtobel was a Nazi criminal,
like people said.
He was actually glad, that the
documents would come to light.
That's why he gave me his consent.
Here.
I signed it myself.
You see how grandmother is.
You made a big step forward.
Only...
This doesn't concern only Zumtobel.
After all, in these documents
there are intimate things about many
citizens and families of our city.
I cannot give you the documents.
I'm sorry.
Protection of privacy.
Do you know what I decided?
I will sue them.
I will sue the city of Pfilzing.
You're mad.
I will sue the city to
surrender the documents.
Come on, no normal person would do this.
What?
Sonja will do what?
She will sue the city.
- I think that's OK.
- Hold your tongue.
Hey, don't terrorize me.
I also think that's OK.
Yes, I...
think so too.
- We're going now.
- But don't come too late.
I've known Rosenbergers for years.
But I refused to represent
Sonja in court against the city,
because I don't think
this lawsuit is proper.
I told Sonja, when someone sues you,
I will always be there,
but in this case, no.
Good morning, Sarah.
Listen, I've been thinking.
Without a lawyer, this
doesn't make any sense.
- You don't stand a chance.
Not even this much. - Yes.
Just let me. I don't need a
lawyer. I prefer it this way.
But you cannot stand up
against the city alone.
But I have you.
Yes, right, but...
Say, hasn't the newspaper arrived yet?
Here is playback.
No, here...
- No, turn it to the right.
- No, to the left.
- Just turn it to the right.
To the right, that's it.
- Left is volume.
- Be quiet now.
...if you keep poking your filthy
noses in other people's business,
something bad will happen
to you and your children.
People who name their children Sarah
and Rebecca are not true Germans.
Jewish whore.
Colonists' cunt.
We made short work with
the likes of you before.
I am 18 years old and I
am German and proud of it
and you should finally stop...
Mrs. Rosenberger, listen...
But this is...
...your daughter is a spy for the East.
- We have evidence...
- But this is...
We will off you, Sonja Wegmus.
And your children too.
You won't have a minute of peace.
And one thing you should know...
This is the Rosenberger and
Wegmus answering machine.
Please speak after the tone.
This is a well-meaning friend.
Leave the city, pack
your things and disappear.
All of you.
Very commendable.
What did you say?
In the name of the law,
the following verdict is issued:
The defendant city of
Pfilzing is not to interfere
with the plaintiff's further research,
and will grant her access to all the
documents in the city archives.
Especially the Zumtobel documents.
- Follow Sonja's example.
- Oh, Mom.
Do you have a message for the public?
Are your motives of religious nature?
Does any party or
organization stand behind you?
- Do you fork for GDR?
- Are you inspired by Simon Wiesenthal?
Who? No, my grandma is my inspiration.
That is rubbish.
But you have to know where you come from,
or you don't know where you're going.
I'll give you the authorization.
With this you have unrestricted
access to the archives.
Thank you.
Personally, I had nothing against you.
You know that, right?
State agency for street naming?
Mangold cultivation from 1939 on?
Canine unit?
Evolution of hand grenade
in German armed forces.
I definitely haven't ordered this.
Where are the Zumtobel documents?
Don't ask me.
The Zumtobel documents.
They are checked out.
- Until when?
- Six to eight weeks.
You want the Zumtobel documents.
Yes, wait a second.
They are still checked out.
But you are next in line.
I specifically noted.
Put on hold in poison
cabinet for Mrs. Wegmus.
We call it poison cabinet.
But... It's on loan again.
Who to? I want names
and addresses this time.
Surely you wouldn't want me to
shout your name from the rooftops.
Yes. The documents are here now.
But here's the thing.
The documents are so old.
Too brittle.
They mustn't be touched anymore.
The problem is the documents
are too new. Personal rights.
You understand, right.
At least 50 years must pass after death.
The statute says 30 years.
Thirty.
Yes, but in the meantime
the city changed the statute.
Now it's 50 years.
Sarah, be still.
- Rebecca wants a bottle.
- Then make her one.
I must prepare for my physics classes.
And I must prepare a new complaint.
If I knew this, I would
never have married you.
We can change that anytime.
I was often at the end of my tether.
In my opinion Sonja overdid things.
And I also believe that
from a certain point...
From a certain points she
let herself get exploited.
I have asked her many times:
What do you have from this?
But no. She had to get the
documents no matter what.
I think Sonja has a
distinct sense of justice.
And people have always been asking me:
Why does Sonja do this?
And I have told them:
Why don't others do it too?
Lobo. Come here.
I sued the city again.
Because they lengthened the
obligation of secrecy to 50 years.
Because they didn't want
me to get the documents.
And I won the process.
The city had to change the statute again.
To 30 years like before.
But that didn't do me any good.
Because suddenly I was told, that
the documents cannot be found.
What does that mean?
Cannot be found?
They were lost going
through official channels.
But suddenly a coincidence helped me.
I would like to speak to
the head of the archives.
Mr. Schulz is not here. Someone
from Munich is substituting for him.
- A substitute. Go to the first floor.
- Thank you.
My name is König, a substitute.
What is this about?
I have an authorization.
Yes, please.
- Everything is in the poison cabinet.
- Poison cabinet? I see.
But it's already too late.
Oh, well.
Mr. König. Someone to see you.
I have to go to the archives.
I'll be back soon.
I can go if you want to?
Should I get you anything?
No, no.
I'll go.
But you have to show me your
pass. Do you have it with you?
You seem familiar.
Oh, well.
- What did you need again?
- Zumtobel.
And these tribunal documents.
- First name.
- Karl Heinrich.
Sign here.
- Name and address.
- Yes.
So, now...
I knew it. Now it's a matter of seconds.
I must copy as much as I can.
Indiscriminately, whatever I get my hand on.
First that, which is
the most prohibited.
- We are already closed.
- What?
Wait a moment.
What are you doing? This is not
to be copied. Can't you read?
- It says here, copying forbidden.
- Ok. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Would you please let me go ahead?
I have something urgent.
Excuse me.
Would you please let me go ahead?
I'm in a hurry.
Me, too. You see, Miss.
This is about my pension.
Do you need to copy anything?
Come with me.
Good day, Mr. Mayor.
I have something that I
wanted to send you. Come.
- Mrs. Brandl, Mrs. Wegmus-Rosenberger
will make some photocopies. - Good day.
Here you are.
By the way, Mrs. Brandl,
is the new archive's statute
prepared for Mrs. Wegmus.
This is now the new archives statute.
It is changed back like it was before.
- 30 instead of 50 years.
- Yes, I know.
It's a shame that it doesn't help you,
because the documents were lost.
Yes, I know.
You will receive this in the mail.
- Mr. Shulz's secretary is on the line.
- I'll take it in my office.
- How much do I owe you?
- Nothing for old friends.
That's it for today.
Listen, Karl. The top one goes
with return receipt. Don't forget.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Mrs. Wegmus-Rosenberger.
- Karl, where is the lady?
- What? Which lady?
- Where are the Zumtobel documents?
- Here.
- What did you copy in my office?
- Good day, Mr. Mayor.
Here.
Greetings, Mrs. Wegmus.
Good day, Mr. Kolodzieczik.
There is a surcharge of 1.20
Marks from the Mayor's Office.
They don't know how many stamps
they need. Should I send it back?
No, no.
This is very important.
Wait a moment.
The same day I returned to the archives
and demanded they give me the documents.
I brought some TV reporters
with me as witnesses.
Tell Mr. Schulz that the documents
are in the poison cabinet.
- If maybe he doesn't know.
- One moment.
Of course they knew very well,
that I had something from
the Zumtobel documents.
But what.
That they didn't know.
Thank god, the documents
have now reappeared.
Here you are.
And I brought even more.
- Thank you.
- See here. Zumtobel.
See.
Hey, Mom, look here.
Is he the one from the mall *BEEP BEEP*?
So he was also a Jew once.
Let me see. Yes, it was called
"Kaufhaus Hirsch" once.
- Yes, that I do remember.
- Only they never saw any money for it.
They disappropriated it.
Listen.
The Jewish businessman
Nathan Krakauer
was sentenced to jail
because he hurt
the government's reputation.
Against the Pfilzing priests...
The names are crossed out.
You cannot read them anymore.
Show me.
Here.
Listen.
He uttered that food
rationing could be next.
Bread and meat stamps
are already being printed.
That is your case, right?
Yes, Nathan Krakauer.
Wait.
- Are there no names?
- Just wait.
Take her.
Let me take a look.
Give it here.
You hold Rebecca.
Name directory.
See here, Krakauer.
See also Dr. Juckenack
and father Brummel.
- Is he the one with 100 underpants?
- Yes he is.
For god's sake.
See what it says here.
Experiments on humans...
10 years of hard labor.
- Dr. *BEEP*.
- Show me.
- Is that our Dr. *BEEP*?
- Pharmacist *BEEP*.
No, this must be his father.
I knew him as well.
He was always so friendly.
Experiments on humans...
But he wasn't put in jail.
I saw him wandering
around until his death.
- For medical reasons. See.
- Oh, I see.
It's a bomb. Run!
Go!
So, we're going now.
- But don't come too late.
- Ok.
- Professor.
- Yes?
I would like to study about
the fate of Jews in Pfilzing.
There is nothing to study there.
Oh, well. I still have to do some
research on the camp Hackeldorf.
And I wanted to ask you
do you know what happened
to Mr. Nathan Krakauer.
The one who that time bought 100
underpants from the two priests.
Unfortunately I can't tell
you anything about that.
How come?
But you were one of the two priests.
You put Mr. Krakauer
in concentration camp.
If you spread that,
I'll go all the way.
I will destroy you.
Mark my words.
I was actually frightened.
I had to think about my children, too.
And also...
I wanted to grow old someday.
Like my grandma.
And I wanted to have grandchildren.
Then I could explain to them,
how it was once.
I thought to myself:
No. It's not worth it.
This way the family life is destroyed.
So, the end.
Or not?
No, I will not give up.
Not a chance.
And then I went on with my work.
I had no time for my job.
First it was only the essay.
But then...
She said that this is
a social obligation.
What does a social obligation mean
if your own husband has to put
your children to bed.
- Good day.
Mrs. pharmacist, we need your wonderful
ear drops again for little Sarah.
For little Sarah?
These ear drops made by my late
husband are too good for you.
Then I went to Munich and gave
my manuscript to the publisher.
The book was printed in low volume.
Look. This is my book.
MY HOMETOWN IN THE THIRD REICH
It received a few very good critiques.
In Suddeutsche, in Zeit
and even in Welt newspapers.
But in Pfilzing Morgen
there was nothing.
Not a word.
Greetings, Mr. Wegmus.
A registered mail for your wife.
From Austria.
Sonja!
- Good day, Mr. Kolodzieczik.
- A registered mail from Austria for you.
There, please.
I was awarded honorary degree
from the University of Vienna.
Because of my brave accounting
of the recent history.
I had to go to Vienna to the conferment.
That was something.
And then the Swedish
royal Academy in Uppsala...
also conferred a doctorate on me.
I was pleased of course.
Doctor doctor.
And then Sorbonne in Paris joined in.
The press was very interested.
I was very much encouraged by all this.
And I searched further in the city.
For certain traces.
Then even the Pfilzing University
invited me for a presentation.
That was in winter 1983.
End of January. On the 50th anniversary
of the Nazi "seizure of power".
What I wanted to say
is that Pfilzing was a
city like many others.
With people who suddenly had a
chance to find jobs and who said,
before there was unemployment
and now we have jobs
and what happens to dissidents
and Jews is not our concern.
So Pfilzing was very
particular Nazi town.
But a town with resistance fighters.
Any questions?
You said you were writing a new book.
Could you tell us on which topic.
Jews in Pfilzing.
Thank you, Mrs. Wegmus-Rosenberger.
Permit me one more question.
In your book you mention the two
priests who denounced the Jewish merchant
for treachery, but you
didn't tell us their names.
But denunciation is
a serious accusation.
What is your allegation based on?
Where did you get this?
From Pfilzing Morgen
of November 2, 1936.
As far as I know, there
were no names mentioned.
But maybe chief editor Prof.
Juckenack would like to add something.
No. Thank you.
Couldn't this whole story
be just Nazi fabrication
in order to defame Jews and the
catholic church at the same time.
Not in this case.
Please.
Tell us the names.
No.
Will the names be
revealed in your new book?
No. I don't think so.
It deals with different topic.
It will involve completely different names.
Some people are in for a shock.
Everything Mrs. Wegmus said here,
is a disregard of such generous
people as pastor Schulte,
who gave his life for the cause.
And many brave members of the resistance.
Above all, Prof. Juckenack.
You shouldn't mention pastor Schulte
and Prof. Juckenack in the same breath.
He was the one.
Prof. Juckenack.
The one with 100 underpants.
This is unbelievable insolence.
You know very well, that
the American authorities
abstained from the lawsuit,
because it wasn't about groceries.
And they handled those.
But this man, Jew or not, was a crook.
Ask father Brummel.
That is the other priest that
you want to drag through mud.
Just because of father Brummel
I didn't want to say the names.
Father Brummel played at your christening.
You should be ashamed.
Maybe father Brummel would
like to address the accusations.
Please.
I took a vow not to
speak about this matter
until the day I die.
- Permission to speak.
- Please.
Prof. Juckenack who is depicted
as member of the resistance was everything
but the member of the resistance.
- This is a communist.
- They called him Brown Heinrich then though.
Yes, I am a communist.
My dear citizens!
Dear citizens!
Prof. Juckenack made a claim
for damages against the student
for defamation and slander.
Chief editor of Pfilzing
Morgen defends himself.
Slander suit against shameless student.
- We're going now.
- But don't come too late.
Come in, Miss.
Come in.
It is warm inside.
He always came to the camp on Sundays
and held a mass for Catholics.
And suddenly it was announced
that all the communists
will be sorted...
- Sorted out.
- Sorted out. Right.
Of course then they put them
in different camps where...
where people were being killed.
I was lucky though, because
the Americans freed me.
However they put me in
jail again after one year.
The Americans?
Why did they put you in jail?
Why? Because I was a communist.
I still fight today for recognition
of the politically persecuted.
I must take my heart drops now.
Excuse me.
But Miss, please drink.
I still need to find some
documents from that time.
For my rent, you see.
I can help you. I have
access to all documents now.
Thank you.
I can tell you, that we were
really afraid from Juckenack.
The Brown and the Black
did us harm together.
It is still the same today.
Please, strike that.
I'm just angry.
Could you testify in
court about Juckenack.
Yes, of course.
- Because he is suing me.
- What?
I have decided.
I'm going back to Munich.
You could come with me.
No, Martin.
You will have to go alone.
I will stay here.
I had to give up our apartment.
And moved next door
again with both children.
- Now it's like in the old days.
- Yes, stuffed.
Munich is a big city.
No one knows you there.
Almighty God,
bless our arms when the hour comes.
Be just, as Thou hast always been just.
- Lord, bless our struggle.
I had no other option.
I had to sue her,
to regain my inner peace.
But then Dr. Röder turned me down.
Naturally that was a big
disappointment for me.
In human terms.
I cannot legally represent a man,
who in the Third Reich hanged
an innocent Jewish citizen.
And these articles that he wrote.
All that came out just
now thanks to Mrs. Wegmus.
Suddenly Dr. Röder came over.
And said he wanted to defend me.
Because I am against
all kinds of racism.
You have to decide, Sonja.
No, I don't need you. No.
- So we're going now.
- But don't come too...
The day of trial was coming nearer
and nearer. And then it came.
I will watch the children tomorrow.
Thank you.
Come here.
This will bring you luck.
Certainly.
- Good day.
Just in case I brought my heart drops
and my nerve drops and constipation drops...
Ladies and gentlemen!
May I have your attention.
Silence.
Today's trial Prof.
Juckenack vs. Mrs. Wegmus
cannot take place.
District court judge Dr. Taffel
fell out of a tree while
picking pears yesterday.
I said to Sonja then, this
is a very dangerous situation.
Why did they abandon the trial?
Your opponents are beaten.
We don't know how they will react.
You have to be careful now.
- They held a church fest then.
- We are very concerned.
- Friendly countries.
- Public opinion.
- Well, the redemption.
- Or rather published opinion.
Good day, Mrs. Rosenberger.
Good day, Mr. Rosenberger.
- Good day.
Suddenly everything went back to normal.
I was again dear Sonja.
They dropped Dr. Juckenack
like a hot potato.
I was very sorry about that.
And suddenly everybody was on my side
and said, how I was right,
to do what I did.
And that they always said so.
A real happy-end.
I've molded Gloria before.
The princess.
And... Steffi Graf.
Or... even Mireille Mathieu.
Oh, yes?
We gathered here today,
to reward a fearless
struggle for the truth.
A woman who couldn't be bothered by
ever new difficulties and obstacles.
Follow Sonja's example.
And now I ask the new chief
editor of Pfilzing Morgen,
Mr. Hanspeter Zöpfel to say a few words.
Thank you. I won't make a long
speech, just like a journalist.
I only want to say this:
I hope that the artist,
Mr. Archibaldo Knips,
captured the essential, the typical in the
expression of this courageous young woman.
May I ask you,
Mrs. Wegmus-Rosenberger.
to reveal the bust now.
I won't let you turn me into a
bust and stick me in the town hall.
I am a living human being.
- Child, what is it...
- Nothing.
But I'm not falling for this.
Just because you're scared shitless,
because you're afraid of
what I might still find out.
Sonja, please be quiet now.
I won't be quiet. That
is exactly what they want.
Don't you see.
What are you implying.
But I'm not falling for this.
I'm not doing you any favors.
This is a rip-off. You don't want to
honor me. You just want to rip me off.
- I should be silent. I should shut
my mouth. - Please, Sonja...
- Yes, and shut it now!
- You ungrateful person.
She doesn't like anything in this country.
- So go to the GDR.
- Kiss my ass.
This is my homeland!
My homeland!
You assholes.
- Sonja, you are right.
- Stay with me, Sarah.
Dear tree, help me hide from them.
THE NASTY GIRL