(BIRDS CHIRP)
(ARTIE SHAW'S
'MOONGLOW' PLAYS)
NARRATOR: One evening
in the summer of 1941,
several months before
the United States would be drawn
into the Second World War,
in a little farming town
in Alabama,
a 16-year-old high school boy
named Glenn Dowling Frazier
discovered
that the girl he loved
was interested in someone else.
(CRICKETS CHIRP)
Frazier was so angry and upset
that when the owner of a
juke joint refused him service,
he stalked outside,
climbed onto his motorcycle,
and roared through the door,
shattering bottles
and smashing furniture.
As he raced away,
the bar owner chased him
down the street with a shotgun.
The next morning,
humiliated, scared,
and unable to face his parents,
Glenn Frazier went to
the nearest recruiting office,
lied about his age,
and joined the peacetime army.
He volunteered to serve
in the Philippines.
FRAZIER: When I volunteered
for the Philippine Islands,
I had no idea that we would
actually be at a war.
I was thinking
that probably Germany was
the most likely place
that there would be a war,
so in my mind, I thought it'd be
safe over there.
I never thought Japan
would be attacking us.
NARRATOR:
Over the next four years,
Frazier would find himself
in the midst of war -
desperate hand-to-hand combat,
a forced march so brutal
the world would never forget it,
and nightmarish prison camps
where simply surviving required
luck and bravery
and unshakable will.
Back in Alabama, those who loved
him would be told he was dead.
All Glenn Frazier would be able
to do was cling to the hope
that one day
he could come back home.
(ARTILLERY SHELL WHOOSHES,
EXPLODES)
(GUNFIRE, MEN SHOUT)
I don't think there is
such a thing as a good war.
There are sometimes
necessary wars.
And I think,
one might say, just wars.
And that, never...
I never questioned the necessity
of that war
and I still do not question it.
It was something
that had to be done.
NARRATOR: The greatest cataclysm
in history grew
out of ancient
and ordinary human emotions -
anger and arrogance and bigotry,
victimhood
and the lust for power.
And it ended
because other human qualities -
courage and perseverance
and selflessness,
faith, leadership,
and the hunger for freedom -
combined,
with unimaginable brutality,
to change the course
of human events.
(AIR RAID SIREN WAILS)
The Second World War brought out
the best and the worst
in a generation,
and blurred the two
so that they became, at times,
almost indistinguishable.
In the killing that engulfed
the world from 1939 to 1945,
between 50 and 60 million people
died...
...so many,
and in so many different places,
that the real number
will never be known.
More than 85 million men
and women served in uniform,
but the overwhelming majority
of those who perished
were civilians -
men, women, and children
obliterated
by the arithmetic of war.
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
The United States of America
was relatively fortunate.
More than 405,000 soldiers
and sailors,
airmen and marines died,
but that figure represented
proportionately fewer
military casualties
than were suffered by any
of the other major combatants.
American cities
were not destroyed.
American civilians were
never really at risk.
But without American power,
without the sacrifice
of American lives,
the struggle's outcome
would have been very different.
The American economy
only grew stronger
as the fighting went on,
and by the time it ended,
the United States would be the
most powerful nation on earth
and a once isolated and insular
people would find themselves
at the centre of world affairs.
The war touched every family
on every street
in every town in America -
towns like Luverne, Minnesota,
Sacramento, California,
Waterbury, Connecticut,
and Mobile, Alabama -
and nothing would ever be
the same again.
(GUNFIRE AND ARTILLERY FIRE
BOOMS)
HYNES: I'm not sure I can speak
about why human beings
in general go to war.
I think that's
a pretty large category.
I can only speak
about why 18-year-olds
from Minneapolis go to war.
They go to war
because it's impossible not to,
because a current is established
in the society so swift,
flowing toward war,
that every young man who steps
into it is carried downstream.
MAN: Luverne, Minnesota,
August 1941.
"Miss Aagot Rylund, who is
in town visiting her brother,
"knows what it is
to see vast sections of a city
"ripped to ruin by German bombs
"and she remembers the nights
that London burned,
"how she could read a letter
"by the unbelievable glare
of the far-off flames.
"She knows what it is to have
high explosive bombs blast
"their big craters
right outside the doorway
"of the shelter
in which she was sleeping.
"She has had
her best friends killed.
"Looking out
at the peaceful countryside
"from the Thompson porch,
she said it was hard to believe
"that the rest of the world
was at war."
Al Macintosh, 'Rock County Star'.
NARRATOR: Much of the world
was already at war
in the fall of 1941.
But for most Americans,
finally beginning to recover
from a Great Depression,
events overseas seemed
impossibly far away.
In Luverne, Minnesota,
the biggest town in Rock County,
in the state's
south-western corner,
the autumn harvest was
only a memory...
and its 3,000 citizens had begun
the long winter wait
until they could sow
their fields again.
Al Macintosh, the editor
of the 'Rock County Star',
lived at 517 North Kniss Avenue.
He was a newcomer
from North Dakota
who had turned down
big city jobs
to run his own small town paper.
He would soon find himself
trying to explain
the unexplainable
to his new neighbours.
Six-year-old Jim Sherman lived
with his family
at 503 North Estey Street.
SHERMAN: I think it was
a pretty close-knit community.
Uh, there was a saying that
if you don't want people
to know about it,
you don't do it - sort of thing.
And everybody knew pretty much
everybody else in town.
('AMERICAN ANTHEM' PLAYS)
NARRATOR:
Four miles south of town,
near the Rock River,
was the 120-acre farm
of the Aanenson family.
There they raised cows
and grew barley, oats, and corn.
Their middle son,
who would face the most fearful
odds in the skies over France,
was named Quentin.
QUENTIN: And literally, sometimes,
I would be on a piece
of farm machinery ploughing corn
and a lonely airplane
would fly over
and I would look up
and my spirit would soar.
That's where I want to be
sometime.
I want to live that way.
I want to do those things.
NARRATOR: In Sacramento, California,
the state capital,
Okies, refugees
from the Dust Bowl,
still camped on the edge
of town.
And worked the fields
and orchards and vineyards
of the surrounding
Sacramento Valley.
The city had been the gateway
to the California gold rush,
and the western anchor of
the transcontinental railroad.
Although it was home
to some 106,000 people,
Sacramento still seemed
like a small town.
Tom and Earl Burke,
who would be asked to sacrifice
everything for their country,
lived with their parents
at 3240 Lassen Way,
just north of town.
EARL: It was a tremendous town,
everybody knew each other.
All, all ethnic groups were
just perfect.
I mean it was, you, you could go
out on the streets at night
at 11:00, 12:00 at night
and, you know, you could
walk home in the dark.
Nobody locked the doors.
Nobody even thought of it.
It was a, a nice, clean,
little town.
BURNETT MILLER: The lower end
of town was rather colourful to us.
There were lots of whorehouses.
As you got up towards
the nicer part of town,
towards Tenth Street, uh,
the houses of prostitution
were quite fancy.
And, as kids,
we used to run down there
and run through the place,
just raising hell.
NARRATOR: 18-year-old Burnett Miller
lived with his family
in a comfortable neighbourhood
at 3643 West Lincoln Avenue.
He would discover,
in the last days of the war,
why it had to be fought.
Almost 7,000 Japanese-Americans
also lived in Sacramento
and the surrounding county.
Doctors, lawyers, teachers
and shop owners,
as well as some of the most
productive farmers in America.
Susumu Satow and his family grew
strawberries, grapes
and raspberries on their
20-acre farm, east of the city.
SUSUMU SATOW:
My mother didn't speak English.
My father spoke, uh,
broken English.
As a youngster, uh, at age
about eight, nine, I guess,
I used to walk down the railroad
track to a place called Mills.
And Mills had a semipro
baseball team.
And so I grew up in sort of a
baseball environment, I guess.
NARRATOR: In Waterbury,
Connecticut,
on the banks
of the Naugatuck River,
a skilled work force,
mostly immigrants
and immigrants' children,
turned out screws and washers
and buttons,
showerheads and alarm clocks,
toy airplanes
and lipstick holders,
and cocktail shakers.
Since the 19th century,
its citizens had proudly called
their town "Brass City".
Ray Leopold, the son of a Jewish
immigrant from Latvia,
lived on Route Eight on
the southern edge of the city.
Waterbury was a centre
for high quality craft.
Uh, there were individuals there who
could do one-ten thousandth of an inch
on anything and if there was
zero tolerance required,
they could do that, too.
OLGA CIARLO:
Well, Waterbury, where we lived,
there were a lot
of Italian people.
They had made a good business
for themselves
and were very well liked.
We had a wonderful neighbourhood.
We had parties
every single Sunday.
Every Sunday was a picnic
for us.
NARRATOR: The Ciarlo family lived
at 1032 North Main Street,
in the Italian section of town.
Their father had recently died.
His loss would be only
the beginning of their troubles.
And in Mobile, Alabama,
population 112,000,
the only real industry
was shipbuilding,
as it had been since the
Great War, a generation earlier.
Once a centre of cotton
and slave trading,
Mobile was best known
for its annual azalea festival,
and its leisurely Southern air.
John Gray and his family lived
on the south side of town,
near the L & N railroad tracks
at 407 Royal Street.
He would soon be asked
to fight a war for freedom,
though his own country's
definition of freedom
did not include him.
GRAY: Whites and blacks got along
pretty good,
as long as you had
the status quo.
But you could not, uh,
eat at the counter at Woolworth.
You'd have to go down to the end
and order your sandwich
and take it out.
Out to eat.
NARRATOR: Across town,
Katharine Phillips
and her family
lived at 1555 Monterey Place.
PHILLIPS: Daddy said Mobile
made its living
by taking in each other's wash.
And it was absolutely true.
The pace of life was slow.
On a hot summer evening -
of course there was
no airconditioning -
so Daddy would load us in
the car and we'd drive downtown
to Brown's Ice Cream and
he'd buy us an ice-cream cone
and then we'd drive out
to Arlington
and park out by the bay,
and all sit there
and enjoy the sea breeze.
And when we'd cooled down
enough, he'd bring us home
and everybody could go to bed
and go to sleep.
Or we sat on our porch
in the evening
and the children played
in the yard.
It was a wonderful way
to grow up.
And we were completely away
from the rest of the world
down in Mobile.
NARRATOR:
No-one in Mobile, Waterbury,
Sacramento, Luverne,
or anywhere else in America
was prepared
for what was about to happen
to them and their country.
DANIEL INOUYE:
Pearl Harbor was a Sunday
and, together with the family,
we were all getting ready
to go to church.
And the disc jockey's going on
with Hawaiian music,
and, suddenly,
he sounded hysterical.
For a moment,
I thought this was an act.
So I stepped out into the street
and, sure enough...
there are puffs and smoke coming
out of that Pearl Harbor area.
And so I called my father out,
said, "Look at that."
And, all of a sudden, three
aircraft flew right overhead.
They were pearl grey
with red dots.
I knew what was happening.
(ARTILLERY SHELLS WHISTLE,
EXPLOSIONS BOOM)
And I thought my world had just
come to an end.
(EXPLOSION THUNDERS)
(SIREN WAILS)
NARRATOR: At 7:55am,
on Sunday, December 7, 1941,
hundreds of Japanese warplanes,
launched from aircraft carriers
far out at sea,
attacked the American
Pacific Fleet
anchored
at Pearl Harbor, Hawaii.
(EXPLOSION BOOMS)
The attack took a terrible toll.
So terrible a toll
that the War Department
kept secret the exact details
for years.
(EXPLOSIONS BOOM)
Eight battleships,
including the USS 'Arizona',
three light cruisers,
three destroyers,
and four other naval vessels
were either sunk or damaged.
164 American aircraft
were also destroyed.
Most hadn't even gotten off
the ground.
And 2,403 Americans were dead.
Nothing like this
had ever happened
to the United States of America
before.
17-year-old Daniel Inouye,
the son of a Japanese immigrant,
was a senior at William McKinley
High School in Honolulu,
and a Red Cross volunteer.
INOUYE: A call came in
that we had casualties nearby.
One haunts me every so often.
It was a woman
clutching a child.
Her head was severed,
but here she was with her arms
around her baby.
And, uh...
So this is
what I had to pick up, at 17.
MAN ON RADIO:
One, two, three, four.
Hello, NBC. Hello, NBC.
This is KBU in Honolulu, Hawaii.
SIDNEY PHILLIPS: I was in a drugstore,
drinking a milkshake,
and this lady burst in
the side door and screamed,
"Turn on the radio!"
They were talking about
Pearl Harbor on every station.
MAN ON RADIO:
And London now awaits
Prime Minister Churchill's promise
to declare war on Japan
within the hour.
We knew this meant
we were in the war.
And we just...
all sat there quietly.
The radio kept giving the same
information again and again.
BARBARA COVINGTON:
I remember I was home eating breakfast
with my mother
and my two brothers.
I was the youngest,
and we were getting ready
to go to Sunday school.
I remember the fear
coming in my mother's eyes,
because she knew my brothers
were probably going to be
called, and they were.
LEOPOLD: It seemed so incredible.
2,400 innocent people
blown off the face of the earth
was an atrocity.
It was something
that had to be corrected -
perhaps the word
might be 'avenged'.
And, um...
we had to get busy with it.
NARRATOR: On December 8,
President Franklin Delano Roosevelt
asked Congress
to declare war on Japan.
Three days later,
Japan's allies, Nazi Germany
and Fascist Italy,
declared war
on the United States.
All across the country,
anxious Americans
asked themselves,
"How did this happen?"
For more than a decade,
they had had glimpses of a world
descending into chaos -
in their newspapers,
over the radio
and in newsreels
shown in movie theatres.
The Strand and the State
in Waterbury.
The Crest and the Alhambra
in Sacramento.
The Roxy and the Pike in Mobile.
And the Pix and the Palace
in Luverne.
NEWSREEL: For the first time,
we saw great cities squashed flat,
civilians bombed and killed.
NARRATOR: They had hoped
they could stay out of it all.
EMMA BELLE PETCHER:
You couldn't fathom across the ocean,
you know,
and you couldn't fathom
what it was really like.
But they would show
these newsreels,
and I'd sneak in the back of the
theatre and see these newsreels,
and they were horrifying.
NARRATOR: Throughout the 1930s,
country after country
had been held hostage
to the ruthless ambitions
of the leaders of
what would be called the Axis.
Benito Mussolini, the swaggering
dictator of Italy,
dreamed of restoring the ancient
Roman Empire and becoming
master of the Mediterranean.
Adolf Hitler built
his monstrous Nazi regime
and the mightiest army on earth
on the German thirst
for revenge -
revenge against the victors
of the First World War,
but also against those at home
who he claimed had stabbed
their armed forces in the back -
socialists, communists
and the Jews.
Above all, the Jews,
who he said were both
evil and subhuman.
The German people were superior
to all others, he assured them,
and he had been chosen to lead
them to their great destiny -
a Reich that would rule
over the Old World
and the New
for a thousand years.
(Crowd chants) Heil! Heil!
The fact is that I am a Jew.
I was aware of what was
going on in Europe,
perhaps a little more than the
average person might have known.
And I did feel that,
somehow or other,
that Hitler had to be stopped.
Not only for the Jews,
but for everybody in the world.
QUENTIN AANENSON:
We knew the war in Europe
was going to affect us
eventually.
After Czechoslovakia had been
taken over by Germany...
we knew that the war
was coming our direction,
one way or the other.
NEWSREEL: The beginning of
the Blitzkrieg, "the lightning war",
ripping deep into a nation
not equipped to meet it.
NARRATOR:
On September 1, 1939,
Hitler's forces stormed across
the border of Poland.
In response to the attack,
Britain and France
declared war on Germany.
The Second World War had begun.
Denmark and Norway fell.
Holland had surrendered.
Belgium was crushed.
French defences had collapsed.
And in June of 1940, Paris fell.
Adolf Hitler was the master
of Western Europe.
Then he set his sights
on Britain.
For more than a year,
she would stand alone
against relentless attack
from the air.
EDWARD MURROW ON RADIO:
Hello, America.
This is Edward Murrow
speaking from London.
They came over shortly
after blackout time
and opened the attack
with a veritable shower
of flares and incendiaries.
NARRATOR: When his plans
for Britain faltered,
Hitler had turned his attention
to the east,
ordering 3 million troops
in a surprise attack
on his supposed ally,
the Soviet Union,
setting in motion the worst
slaughter of the war.
Meanwhile, on the far side
of the world,
the military men who ruled Japan
in the name of the emperor,
believed their people
superior, too.
Their small, crowded
island nation had moved
from medieval feudalism
to the modern era
in less than a century.
And they dreamed of Japan's
becoming a mighty,
self-sufficient power.
With extraordinary brutality,
they had set out to seize
the resources of China.
And they coveted
the French and Dutch
and British colonies
in South-East Asia as well.
NEWSREEL:
From Shanghai to Nanking,
Japan still spreads destruction
from the skies
upon a score of Chinese cities.
Here is the result -
innocent victims of the savagery
that masquerades as modern war.
NARRATOR: Among the obstacles
in Japan's way
were the US Pacific Fleet
based in Hawaii...
and American military outposts
in Guam, Wake Island,
and in the Commonwealth
of the Philippines.
The Axis leaders were united
in their scorn
for the United States.
Its people were "timid,
undisciplined scum",
Hitler said,
"under the influence
"of Negroes and Jews".
He was certain
such a mongrel people
could never win a war against
his Aryan legions.
President Roosevelt had done
everything he could,
short of war, to combat
the aggressors.
Providing desperately needed aid
to Britain and Russia...
...demanding that Japan
withdraw from China.
Finally,
freezing Japanese assets
in the United States,
so that no American oil
could be used to fuel
further aggression in Asia.
For the Japanese militarists,
that had been the signal
to go to war with America.
They made General Hideki Tojo
prime minister.
He thought that by destroying
the US Pacific Fleet
at Pearl Harbor
in a single blow,
he could stun and demoralise
the country long enough
to become so dominant
in the region
that Japan could
never be dislodged.
American intelligence officers
had broken the Japanese
diplomatic code,
and knew some kind
of attack was coming.
(EXPLOSION, PLANE SOARS)
But no-one had known
where or when
until December 7.
GLENN FRAZIER: I was raised
in a real Christian family
and, as a result, killing was
not part of my training.
And, uh, that was a big hurdle
for me to get over
because I had been
taught not to kill.
NARRATOR:
Within hours of Pearl Harbor,
the Japanese had also attacked
the main Philippine island
of Luzon.
17-year-old Glenn Frazier
was now in the middle of a war
he thought he would
never have to face.
FRAZIER:
And when the war started,
and I was going
to the field hospital,
a couple
of Japanese planes - Zeroes -
bombed and strafed the hospital.
(GUNFIRE POPS,
BOMBS EXPLODE)
And as we were approaching,
a friend of mine and I -
uh, we got in the ditch
and one of the dive-bombers
came back and strafed us,
and dropped one bomb
and hit him direct.
And all I ever found of him
was his left foot in a shoe.
And when that Japanese Zero
turned his wings
right above the trees
and started to fly away,
I could see him
with a smile on his face.
And at that point, I had
no problem with killing people.
In fact, I got to the point
where I hunted them.
(GUNSHOT)
And if I didn't kill
a Japanese in a day,
I felt I didn't do my job.
(GUNSHOT)
NARRATOR: Glenn Frazier
was one of 31,000 men
under the command
of General Douglas MacArthur,
the best known soldier
in the American army.
A front line hero of World War I,
he was as self-absorbed
as he was courageous.
But the news of Pearl Harbor
had paralysed him.
He had had nine hours warning,
yet when the Japanese attacked
his airfields
in the Philippines,
most of MacArthur's planes
were still parked wing to wing,
easy targets for the enemy.
(BOMBS WHISTLE AND EXPLODE)
More than 50,000
Japanese soldiers
would soon be ashore,
converging on Manila
from the north and the south.
Neither the American troops,
nor the thousands of Filipino
reservists MacArthur called up
would be able to stop them.
The Americans were being
pushed out of the Pacific.
MacArthur eventually ordered
all his forces to retreat
onto the mountainous,
forest-covered Bataán Peninsula.
He withdrew with his family
and his aides
to the heavily fortified island
at the mouth of Manila Bay
called Corregidor.
Meanwhile, other Americans
in the Philippines,
innocent civilians thousands
of miles from home,
had been swept up
in the war as well.
(SIREN WAILS, BELL CLANGS)
SASCHA WEINZHEIMER:
The day Pearl Harbor got bombed
was the seventh.
But, in the Philippines,
with over the International
Date Line, it was the eighth.
Same day, and we were bombed
a few hours later.
And I had polio
when I was a baby,
so I used to go to Manila
three times a week
for physical therapy.
And this is what I was doing
on a Monday morning,
on the eighth, when the Japanese
started bombing.
NARRATOR: Sascha Weinzheimer
was eight years old
in December of 1941.
The daughter and grand-daughter
of wealthy farmers
with enormous holdings
in the Sacramento Valley
and in the Philippines.
As she would detail
in a journal,
she lived with her mother
and father,
her 3-year-old sister
and her 3-month-old brother
on one of the largest
sugar plantations
on the Philippine island
of Luzon.
NARRATOR: After Japanese bombs fell
near their plantation,
Sascha and her family
moved into Manila -
now with the army gone,
a neutral, "open city" -
joining other refugees
at the Bayview Hotel.
WEINZHEIMER:
The Japanese came in on 2 January.
That was the beginning of,
you know,
this putting the people
into camps and so forth.
And your life changed fast.
WOMAN: "The first thing I remember
"was looking across the street
towards the bay
"and seeing Japanese soldiers
and officers around the flagpole
"hoisting up the Japanese flag
"where our Stars and Stripes
had been."
(CHEERING)
"Soon trucks came rolling down
the boulevard yelling, 'Bonzai! '
"We were told to be calm
and keep away from the windows.
"Everyone was nervous,
especially Mother."
Sascha Weinzheimer.
NARRATOR: Japanese soldiers took
Sascha's father from the Bayview Hotel
to the walled campus
of Santo Tomas University,
which had been turned
into a civilian internment camp.
WOMAN: "After Daddy started
to say goodbye,
"I could just hardly stand it,
"and for the first time,
I was afraid,
"so I screamed
and held onto Daddy
"until I had to be pulled away.
"Then he ran out,
"and that was the last
we saw of him for a few months."
NARRATOR: Sascha and the rest
of her family found shelter
first in one convent,
and then another.
Wherever they were, the sound
of the guns from Bataán -
where Glenn Frazier
and his comrades
were still struggling
to stop the Japanese advance -
continued day and night.
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(LOUD, RUMBLING EXPLOSION)
(DUKE ELLINGTON'S
'PERDIDO' PLAYS)
SAM HYNES: You have to imagine
what it was like
to be a teenage, middle-class,
lower middle-class kid
in Minneapolis in 1941.
The chances for excitement
were fairly limited.
You could drive a car fast,
you could get drunk,
you could take a girl out
and try and get somewhere
and fail.
That's local excitement.
But to have an exciting life -
it was hard to imagine
what an exciting life would be.
And then, suddenly,
you could be, uh, a pilot
or a submariner,
or an artilleryman,
or any damn thing,
but you'd be...
It was something exciting,
and it was something adult.
All of a sudden,
you could choose,
just choose to be an adult
by writing your name.
I'm working for a bank in town
and delivering cheques.
I write my name,
and now, I'm potentially
a combat pilot, a fighter pilot.
Uh, an ace.
Or I'm the commander
of a submarine
going into Tokyo Bay.
These are incredible
opportunities.
You see, they're melodramatic,
exciting, like the movies.
And you might do it.
So that's terrific.
It has nothing to do
with patriotism.
It has nothing to do, really,
with who the enemy is.
It's the opportunity
to be somebody more exciting
than the kid you are.
(BENNY GOODMAN'S
'WANG WANG BLUES' PLAYS)
KATHARINE PHILLIPS:
I came home for my Christmas holidays,
and that's when I found out
that my brother Sidney
had gone down
and joined the Marine Corps.
And then, of course,
life really took on meaning.
SIDNEY: My father was
very patriotic, and...
I felt like really expected me
to join the military,
so my friend W.O. Brown
said, "Sid, let's go join
the navy in the morning."
And I said, "Fine."
And the recruiting office
was crowded
like you wouldn't believe,
so we walked up
to the head of the line...
...saw this marine
recruiting sergeant.
He came over and said,
"Do you boys want
to kill Japs?"
And we said,
"Yeah, that's the idea,
"but we're going
to join the navy."
And he said, "No," he said,
"You don't belong in the navy.
"You belong in the Marine Corps.
"You can't get
in the navy, anyway,
"because your parents
are married."
And we, uh, ended up
joining the Marine Corps.
KATHARINE:
So, Sidney joined the marines.
Daddy told Mother, "You might
as well sign the paper, Kate.
"He's going to go anyway."
He was only 17 years old.
So, the story in the family is,
the marine recruiting officer
crossed the street
any time in the next year
that he encountered my mother,
because she would give him
a piece of her mind
for taking her little boy
into the marines.
NARRATOR: Unlike the professional
armies of Germany and Japan,
the armed forces
that Sid Phillips and others
rushed to join
had been totally unprepared
to wage a world war.
In 1940, the US Army
had been smaller
than that of Romania -
only 174,000 men in uniform,
wearing tin hats and leggings
issued during World War I.
Then, in the fall of 1940,
Congress enacted the draft,
and every young man
in America began to worry
when his number would come up.
WILLIAM PERKINS:
Somebody got the greetings.
Long envelope, you know.
And when you opened it up,
it would say,
"Greetings, The President
of the United States
"and your neighbours
have selected you
"to be drafted
into the armed forces for...
"to protect the country,
etc, etc..."
And I was down
at a friend of mine's,
Howard Lopes,
and he got the letter,
and he opened it up,
and he was drafted.
And, so, boy, we just
laughed and roared,
and then I had to go home.
And when I walked in the house,
my grandma says,
"There's a letter up for you
up there."
And, uh, I... so, I picked
it up, and I looked at it.
And it said, "Greetings,
"The President of the United States
and your neighbours..."
I flew out the house,
run down the street, you know,
back up the street
where Howard lived,
and I walked in
with the paper in my hand.
Everybody looked at me,
and they had a good time
laughing,
because I had been drafted.
They knew.
I didn't have to tell them.
I just hold up... the letter up.
NARRATOR: Despite a growing chorus
of protests by black citizens
outraged at the idea
of fighting bigotry abroad
while it was tolerated at home,
the military continued to insist
on segregating African-American
servicemen into all-black units.
Even blood supplies
for saving the lives
of the wounded
were kept separate.
WILLIE RUSHTON:
I always thought that, one day,
our country would be better
for everybody.
'Cause I knew
I saw a lot of things
that my father had to go through
that I didn't have
to go through,
so I figured that
when my children come on,
we'd still have something better
than what I had,
so that's why I wanted
to go fight for my country.
I was fairly close
to being a pacifist.
I believed that there is
mostly negotiated solutions
to most problems of this sort.
But I couldn't fathom
that there was ever
a solution to the confrontation
that Hitler was giving
to us and the rest of the world.
I felt that I belonged
in the service,
um, because the threat,
while it was directed
at the entire rest of the world,
was particularly directed
at the origins that I came from.
(DUKE ELLINGTON'S
'ECHOES OF HARLEM' PLAYS)
If I didn't know it
at the particular moment I went in,
13 weeks later, after I had
finished my basic training,
I knew, expertly, how to kill.
Kill with a bayonet,
kill with a bullet,
kill with your hands.
Yes, I could kill.
HYNES:
I left Minneapolis for the service
on a dank, wet, cold
March Minneapolis evening.
My father drove me
to the station
in the car that he almost
never let me drive as a kid,
downtown, past all the...
places that had been the, uh,
stations of my childhood
and growing up,
to the Rock Island Railroad.
It was dark.
The long platform was dark
with hanging
arc lights at distance,
so that, as you walked,
it was dark, light,
dark, light, dark, light.
And at the far end
was a navy yeoman
with a clipboard
and a gathering of young men
or boys around him.
And we stopped,
and my father shook my hand.
It seemed very strange to me
that my father and I
were on handshaking terms.
Then he turned around and walked
back toward the entrance -
dark, light, dark, light,
dark, light -
and out into the street
and was gone.
And I turned to the yeoman
and went up
and said, "Present,"
when my name came up,
and I was in the navy.
NARRATOR: Nearly 50 million men
would register for the draft
during the war.
Some 16 million Americans would
eventually wear their country's uniform.
But during the days immediately
following Pearl Harbor,
it was still anyone's guess
where they would be sent
or how well they would fight
when they got there.