Hearken o' people...
the drum sounds the call
Now awake and arise
From your deep slumber
Awaken, now awaken
The Earth comes alive
as dawn heralds a new day
Rivers sparkle with new life and
hope rises in oceans anew
Awaken, now awaken
Be blessed, be blessed, be blessed.
May all be blessed
The towns are awake, the homes
are abuzz, every village is astir
Valleys awaken and so do their trees,
look, shadows are coming to life!
Be Blessed, be blessed, be blessed
May all be blessed
When dawn comes to bathe
at the banks of the Ganges,
dark night retreats before the
Sun's flashing sword
Sacred fires are lit for prayers.
Go now and greet your gods
He who asks, shall receive,
and sins of ages will be washed away
The market shakes off its slumber
and stretches to life
Landlord, trader, priest or soldier as per
your worth, your value is weighed
Singing songs of love and blessing the
Sufi wanders strumming his tunes...
May the doors of each man's fortune open
and may all be well in this world of ours"
Be Blessed, be blessed, be blessed,
May all be blessed
1857 A.D.
The entire Indian subcontinent
is ruled by...
a company. The British East India Company
The most successful business enterprise
in history
The Company has its own laws,
its own administration
lts own army
It controls the destiny of
one fifth of humanity
Get it over with
Mangal Pandey
Sepoy, 34th Regiment,
Native Infantry at Barrackpore
You have been found guilty of
mutiny and conspiracy...
to overthrow the government of the
Honourable East India Company,
by a duly constituted court martial
You have been sentenced to death
Well come on, hurry up
Mangal Pandey, do you have a last wish?
You cannot grant my last wish
Yet it will be fulfilled
Time's up. Hang him
Sir, the hangman...
he ran away
Yes sir, he refused to hang
Mangal Pandey
We tried to persuade him, threaten him
but... but he ran away, sir
Christ! This is nonsense
You... you hang him
That's not my duty, sir
Damn your duty, it's an order!
Move!
I'm a Brahmin, sir. It's against my faith
Send a message to Calcutta and
get another hangman
Until then, take him down
Take him down
The Earth will be scorched
Rivers of blood will flow
Millions will die
And I, William Gordon...
feel responsible for the inevitable
4 Years earlier,
on the mountains of Afghanistan
Fire
Infantry... charge
ATTACK!
Quick! Take them to base camp!
You did well, Captain
The Afghans are on the run
and we hold the pass
Pandey...
Gordon sir... no
Let him be
Captain Gordon
William, are you all right?
No don't... lie down
Here...
I want you to have my pistol
I've got nothing else to give you
Please
Take it
4 Years later,
31st December 1856, Calcutta
New Year celebrations at
the Governor General's palace
Who's that?
Lord Canning... Governor General.
- Not him, you fool
I mean, the chap next to him
Mr Lockwood, the Company auditor...
sent by London to investigate all the
monkey business going on in the Company
And next to him is Mr Kent
Bigtime trader
Some of the top Company officers
are on his payroll
My lords, ladies, and gentlemen...
pray silence for...
His Excellency Lord Canning...
Governor General of India
My lords, ladies and gentlemen...
as a servant of the
Honourable East India Company...
that has ruled the territories of Hindoostan...
for a hundred years...
I must profess pride and an equal humility
It is my privilege to recall...
that our forebears came
to these territories as traders
And we now find ourselves,
by the will of God...
masters of the entire Indian subcontinent
from Khyber to Comorin
What did he say?
The Company Raj completes
100 years in India
From traders they became rulers
My god! What is she wearing?
And we bring to India the benefits
of modern governance...
scientific progress, and, above all...
justice
Has he mentioned the Queen yet?
- No. He says they're doing us a favor
We have earned the love and
gratitude of the people of India
And we shoulder the burden of the
white man without complaint
Now...? - No
He says, we Indians are
grateful to them!
Now I call upon you to join with me
as I propose the loyal toast
Your mother must be turning in her grave!
Shame on you, Emily
Looking like a nautch girl!
- Do I look like a real nautch girl?
Captain Hewson, you must know
I am unfamiliar with the detail of the
attire of dancing girls
Ms Kent, the costume is perfect
Any nautch girl in India would
blush with envy
You keep the company of nautch girls,
Captain Gordon?
I pursue beauty wherever I can find it
Toast
The queen
The Queen... to the Queen
Oh! So sorry!
You black bastard
What the hell are you upto?
Sir, sorry sir. Please...
You, lift him
Hewson, that's enough
I'll teach you to touch a
white woman you black dog!
Forgive me sir, it was an accident
Enough sahib
Enough
The black dog will die
Miss Kent... on behalf of...
- It's not to me that you owe the apology
Come inside
Pull the fan
Faster
Harder, damn you
Kamla!
Oh god, one push into her paradise...
and I'll pull your fan in hell forever
The quartermaster showed
Gordon the new Enfield rifle...
that the Company was going
to introduce in India
Absolute beauties...
And speaking of beauties...
I saw you appreciating
Ms. Kent in a sari
Me... On the Company's pay?
Ah! But Kent is filthy rich
Vultures and merchants of arms.
The only ones to profit from wars, yes!
Amazing! The Company has connected
the entire country through wires
In a blink of an eyelid messages travel
from Calcutta to Delhi
Nonsense! Lmpossible!
It's got to be true! It's in the newspaper!
But how can messages get into wires?
I'll tell you. Easy! These whites have
mastered black magic
Yeah! Must've used a witch's hair
Yes and it's got an odd name too
...taelly - garaffe
What? Wow! That sounds scary
You bet your ass! We're all
in for a jolly ride now
Coming... coming...
I'm here now, my love
Here we are, I know you're hungry
You're dry
That white woman's baby
has sucked you dry
What's left for him?
Here, use this on your nipple,
it'll make him sleep
Don't you dare give opium to my baby
Hey, hey my baby, my love,
why are you crying?
Why are you crying?
Hush now, aren't you the son of a warrior?
Why is he always crying?
No nothing, it's just colic
Come on Veeru, we're late for the pit
Coming, coming
Come on, get him!
Scissor-throw! Give him the
scissor-throw!
Where's Mangal? - In the wrestling pit, sir
Captain sahib...
want to try your strength
against a black man?
Uh-oh, he's had it now!
Bravo Captain sahib, way to go!
Come on Mangal, don't spare him!
Why didn't you come today?
Tell me
I was angry
Angry? Why?
Hewson was killing that man...
and you did nothing
What was I supposed to do? Stand between
a fellow officer and a...
And a black dog!
Say it... say it!
You don't understand
I've spent half my life here,
the best part of my life!
What have I got to go back to?
You still did nothing
You're right, I should've stopped him
from whipping any black dog
I'm sorry, all right?
All right?
Now... are you still angry
with me huh? Huh?
All right, no... no
I'm beaten. You're forgiven
Bhang, my friend, elixir of the gods,
is Lord Shiva's favoured potion
Come on Mangal, have some bhang,
liven your spirits
Want to have some bhang, sahib?
- Er... bhang? Doesn't it, you know...
Don't worry, it doesn't bite or scold.
It's like a good mother
Strokes you, sings you lullabies
tells you stories...
and kisses you to sleep.
- Well, I'll have to try some of that
Because my mother certainly
never did any of that
Easy sahib, easy. You don't want two
stepmothers quarrelling in your head
Ration and roti, the Company's pay
Give us your life for a shilling a day
Shilling a day boys, a shilling a day
While the boom of the cannon
may blow you away!
Mangal... that's Hewson's horse
Come on
Bastards! Which bastard did this?
My silly heart can't contain its
excitement...
when everything gets going for
a nobody like me
May Lord Ram bless you, Mangal
Ram - Ram
AsSalaamu Alaykum Mirza sahib.
- Ram - Ram, Mangal
All well?
Oye! You cockeyed fool!
Can't you see?
A twisted rope is strongest,
a twisted eyesight, deepest
Don't touch me, you scoundrel.
You want to defile a Brahmin?
Come on, we're all untouchables now.
The Company reigns. All trash is equal
Mind your tongue, you dog.
- Dog? Me?
Who barks to guard the Company's loot?
You or me?
Oh! You deserve a thrashing, wait
And who wags his tail for the white man?
You or me?
And who's going to bite the new
cartridge dipped in animal fat?
Animal fat? - Yes. Cow and pig fat
That's used to grease the new cartridge
Into the mouth... bite... fire... boom!
Go straight to hell
Boom goes your faith, boom
goes your honour
Shut up, liar!
Silence
This is no fish market
Let one man speak
Mangal Pandey. Sepoy, 5th Company.
34th Native Infantry Regiment
34th eh? At ease
What is it?
Sir, we hear that the cartridge of
the new rifle is greased...
and must be bitten before loading.
- And what of it?
Sir, the grease coating is
made of cow and pig fat
The cow is sacred to the Hindus,
the pig forbidden to the Muslims
We can't touch such a cartridge.
It is sacrilege
Who is spreading this rot?
The news is all over, sir
Nonsense! No truth to it, my man
Hasn't the Company always
cared for you?
Now don't worry and go home.
Some mischief-monger is misleading you
There is no such cartridge.
There will be no such cartridge
Dismissed
Gather round... gather round,
gather round... gather round
The world's a marketplace, my friend
Gather round... gather round
Only shops from end to end
Gather round
You'll find it all here
It's all on sale
You'll find it all here - For a penny
it's all on sale - For a penny
All your heart's desires... - For a penny
you're sure to find here. - For a penny
Food and drink, trinkets and baubles...
for a penny, a penny, it's all for sale
Cloth and grain, friendship and love
Hey Gordon sahib
This is Miss Emily Kent.
Miss Kent, this is Mangal
Silks and muslin, satin, cotton,
priest and salvation...
rice and pulses...
All for sale
For a penny, a penny
Fortune-teller, healer, poet and tailor...
All for sale
For a penny, a penny
Honour and dignity, mango and pears,
crowns of royals, all mirrors and glass
All for sale... for a penny's worth
All battles and lies all music and noise...
All for sale... for a penny's worth!
Take her, take her...
at a throwaway price
Buy yourself a slave...
Look at this beauty, check out
her curves
Slave or servant...
wife or whore...
she's what you want...
and then some more
Make your bid. - Eleven
Stop kidding
Fifteen
Emily was surprised that though slavery
was abolished in Britain...
the Company allowed it in India.
Gordon explained that the Company
itself bought these girls...
for the pleasure of white soldiers It helped
prevent the spread of disease in the army
I have a gem here
Let me show you
Hands off, you pimp!
Bloody bitch!
Don't mess with me
She's a spirited mare eh?
Just waiting to be reined in
So who's going to be the lucky man?
Come on, let's hear it
Sixty Rupees
I think I've seen enough
Seventy
Eighty Rupees
That's better, eighty
Anyone else?
Quick! Or this meat will go to the whites
and you'll be left ogling
Wow, what eyes...
the entire Company Raj could
drown in them
What's your name?
Come on stand up... up
Let's get a look at you
Turn around
Packaging seems all right
All right?! By God she's a gem,
a real diamond
Okay then, let's call her that.
Heera (Diamond)
But she needs polishing
Get one thing straight, girl,
I am Lol Bibi
And I'm the boss here
Many trinkets like you decorate my shoes.
Got that?
And one more thing...
this is a pleasure house
exclusively for the whites
You'll have to work very hard
Men aren't easy to please,
no matter what their colour
That's true! Ask me, I have suffered
all the various shades!
One of the Company's biggest trades
was that of opium.
It forced Indian farmers to grow it,
bought it from them at a pittance...
and sold it in China at a profit.
When the Chinese Emperor resisted...
the Company waged a war against him.
To fight and die, Indian sepoys
were there after all.
And they called it the Free Market.
Captain Gordan,
You were meant to be singing too...
I'm afraid I'm unfamiliar with the song.
Not know it?
What are you, some sort of a pagan?
Didn't they thrash it
into you in school?
No sir.
They should've.
Which school did you attend?
Let me guess,
it wasn't Marlborough or Rugby?
No sir, my family are Catholics,
from Glasgow. I went to parish school
A papist! Come to think of it,
I haven't seen you at church.
I must have imagined you were
with your famous nautch girls.
Aren't they beautiful?
I picked them on our ride this evening
Ah, you must have ridden out
in the direction of Kashigunj?
Yes, I was astounded.
Acres of bright red poppies
Are they part of some religious ritual?
No, no. It's Company land.
Why does the Company grow poppies?
The poppy, Miss Kent
is the sole source of opium
The Honourable East India Company
forces Indian farmers to grow them
Opium?
- Indeed. Most of it is bought up...
by the Company at prices fixed by them.
And then shipped to China...
to help turn an entire nation
into opium addicts
But why?
It's the only thing
we can sell the Chinese...
in return for the tea and silks
that we Europeans are addicted to
I think Gordon, the ladies
ought to be spared this lecture
But the Chinese Emperor resists,
he no longer wants to trade in opium
So the company decides to
wage a war against him
And in this war it wants
Indian sepoys to fight and die
The circle is complete...
and we call it the free market
You abuse my hospitality
If I have spoken out of turn sir,
I apologise
After all I'm just a common soldier
It's a subject
you'd know more about than I
When Kent humiliated Gordon about his
humble beginnings...
Gordon couldn't stand for it.
William... I'm so sorry
- Emily, there's no need
Gordon liked Emily, but realized that
he did not belong in this elite circle.
When traders become rulers then
the common man pays the price
But now Nana Saheb will make
the Company pay
Really? How?
His minister, Azimullah, has returned from
England with Queen Victoria's letter...
which clearly states that Nana Saheb is
right and the Company is wrong
Futile. Nana Saheb has only a letter
while the Company has guns
But sir, the gun is a treacherous lover,
there's no telling whom she'll set
her sights upon!
What's up?
What the bloody hell is going on?
Broken axle, sir. Two boxes of cartridges
have fallen down
The new Enfield...
is the best rifle in the world
It will feel no different to your musket
A bit lighter
Accurate to a thousand yards,
five times the range of your
old Brown Bess
And now, the new cartridge.
It consists of gunpowder and a lead
You pick up the cartridge and
bite the end off, like so
You pour the gunpowder in,
followed by the lead
And then...
you ram the Johnny down.
Ram it down, tight
Then you're ready to fire
You... try
You... and you
Come on lads, look lively
Come on, it won't bark back
Corporal...
Yes sir? - What is the matter?
The grease, sir. We cannot put
the grease in our mouth
Then where will you put it, man?
Come on, be sensible
What's the matter, Captain?
It's the cartridges, sir.
The sepoys say they saw dogs
licking grease off them in the bazaar
They saw what?
Dogs, licking the new cartridges
The men believe they've been greased
with the fat of pigs and cows, sir
And are they?
The Company's supplier, sir.
I checked with him. And he assured me...
there was no truth to it
There you are, Captain White man's word.
Knock the superstition out of them
Still sir, shouldn't we be careful?
- You heard me, Captain
The Quartermaster claimed that
the cartridges were clean.
A white man's word was good
enough for the general.
He ordered Gordon to set
the soldiers' fears to rest.
The Company respects all religions
and will never break faith
And I, as an officer of the Company
give you my word...
that this cartridge is greased with
neither the fat of pigs or cows
Will a loyal sepoy please step forward
and volunteer to fire the gun.
What am I supposed to tell him now?
He has already done what he had to
We can't let this pass.
We must confront him with this
You think he'll listen to us?
- Here he comes. Talk to him
Aye Mangal, why did you
bite the bullet?
You're an outcaste now.
You'll pay for it.
Just because you speak a little English,
you think you're a bloody white man?
Now because of you,
they'll force us as well
Shut your miserable mouths
Gordon sahib said they're clean.
That's enough for me.
And what if Gordon sahib is lying?
Gordon sahib will never lie to me
That's fine, but what if the cartridge-story
turns out to be true?
Then I'll burn the company down
Now scram!
There. Look at that attitude
Gordon sahib, Will you tell me something?
Yes, Why not?
What is the Company?
Why do you ask?
I need to know
Company...?
A Company is an entity created entirely
for the purpose of making a profit
And what does it do?
- What does it do!
Well it buys and sells, anything.
Indigo, spices, opium
Love, honour, truth... anything
Yes but... who is the Company?
In your story of the Ramayan...
you have a character Ravana.
The chap with ten heads, right?
Well, the Company has thousands of heads...
all stuck together with the glue of greed.
You understand?
Hey, is that a Sati?
Come on
Gordon sahib, I don't think we should.
- Come on, it's a Sati!
Glory to woman who accompanies
her husband in death
Glory be!
Stop this
I said, stop this immediately!
Come here, come along
Sahib, you better leave.
These are sacred ceremonies
But Sati has been banned.
Burning a widow is a crime
Captain sahib, don't interfere.
You're tampering with our ancient customs
And you're tampering with my ancient custom.
I don't stand by and watch murder
Return the woman.
Or you'll regret it
You'll have to kill me first!
Come on!
Get him!
Lynch him
Anybody who dares touch
the sahib is a dead man
Sahib, save the girl!
I'll deal with these bastards
Go sahib... go... go
Oh God! A Sati!
But she is alive!
You're damn right she is!
But they will come for her!
It's a question of their honour
Return her, sahib!
- No one will touch her!
That's the law
What are we going to do
with her, Mangal?
Her relatives will surely kill her.
She has nowhere to go
Come out
Don't be afraid
You're safe here
No one will touch you
Come
How are you feeling?
Did you sleep?
What's your name?
I am going to work but don't worry...
I have posted guards.
You'll be safe
They will come... for me
Who?
Relatives
My husband was a powerful man,
lord of a hundred villages
I'm sorry you lost him.
Any children?
No, he was very old.
Sixty, when he married me
He had grown-up children
He was very sick
Sahib the village chieftain
has come to meet you
He says it's important
Go in... and don't worry
Sahib, don't play with our honour
What do you mean?
Return the woman to us
What? So that you can kill her?
That is her destiny
Not anymore
Don't involve yourself in matters
you don't understand
That will not be good for you
Are you threatening an officer of
the East India Company?
You listen to me!
You so much as set foot into
the Cantonment again,
and I will shoot you!
You understand me?
Do you understand me?
Now get out
In the course of his investigations
into corruption in the Company...
Lockwood raided the godown of
a Parsee merchant, Sorabjee.
Search the place
There is no need for all that, Sir
Search it. - It is all legitimate
The search uncovered
stocks of opium.
Sir, look at this
Seal the stock, arrest this man.
- Sergeant-major...
Mr Lockwood, you are a man
of high powers
But you've been here only
a few days, sir
You must try to understand
- Mr Sorabji you are aware...
that The East India Company has
a monopoly on the opium trade
It is obvious, you have been indulging
in your own private dealings
Mr Lockwood, I am acquainted
with you British...
and I have had dealings for years
with the Company officials
I will be very proud to make you
part of our arrangements
Are you offering to bribe me,
you blackguard!
Sir, I have the deepest respect
for you as a gentleman
I am simply trying to explain
how trade works in India
It could be beneficial to you.
- You mistake me sir
I'm here to bury corruption, not fan it.
- Corruption is a strong word, sir
It is our custom, as Indians,
to give small gifts
I must quieten your displeasure
and pay a fine. 300 pounds in gold?
Damn your eyes!
Three thousand pounds
Now?
Three... thousand... pounds!
India is rich, sir
Lockwood did not succumb to Sorabjee's
offer of a huge bribe.
Instead he forced Sorabjee to
name the villages...
from which he bought the opium.
Every man is reminded...
that growing, buying or
selling opium...
without the permission
of the Company...
is illegal and punishable
You have broken the law
Therefore by the order of
the Collector and Magistrate...
your land and property is
hereby confiscated!
But how are we to blame?
White sahibs tell us to grow, we grow.
White sahibs tell us to sell, we sell
Don't take our lands sahib!
Where will we go?
Have mercy, sahib
For god's sake, have mercy
Get your hands off
The Company is cruel!
Get out! Go away!
Our children will starve!
- Leave us alone
Fire!
No sir!
That's not necessary,
I'll deal with this
I said fire!
No... no... don't shoot.
- We're your brothers
What are you thinking?
Does this happen back home
in my village as well?
We're soldiers. It's our job to fight,
to kill
To kill an unknown enemy is easy.
But to kill people who are your own...
You were obeying orders, Mangal
That's our duty That is the price of
the salt we eat
Sometimes I wonder if there are more
important things in life than salt
I'm a slave to your charms
Your love for me is like...
a honey-dipped dagger
I'm a slave to your charms
Your burning gaze pierces
me like arrows
Where did you learn such deadly skill?
My heart's wounded...
but the pain is so exquisite
I'm a slave to your charms
Once I was a blossoming bud...
flowering in a garden of sunshine
No restless days,
no sleepless nights
I was innocent and carefree...
and then I met you!
Oh, what a price I'm paying
for having trusted you...
oh, what a price I'm paying
for having trusted you!
Your love for me is like...
a honey-dipped dagger
I'm a slave to your charms
She has already been promised
for the first night...
to the Company's senior officer.
You cannot take her sahib, I beg you
Out of my way woman,
I'm taking her
No, not for double the money, please
Her first night will be with me
and that's what she wants to...
don't you darling!
- Don't create trouble for me
Enough!
Did you not hear!
The woman said something. Leave the girl
One more word out of you and
I'll have you horsewhipped!
You're not going anywhere!
Bastard!
I'll get you for this, you nigger!
I'll teach you a lesson,
you son of a whore!
I say, leave him!
You scoundrels!
You're wrecking my shop
No! Not upstairs!
You'll destroy my rooms!
Who'll pay for the damage?
You still haven't told me your name
Jwala
Hey stop! - It's urgent
Where are you going?
- We need to meet Gordon sahib
Gordon sahib! He's killing Mangal!
- What... who?
Hewson sahib has gone to
the jail to kill Mangal Pandey
You dog! You dare assault an officer!
Say you are a dog
Say you are a dog!
You are a dog
Make the black bastard shit blood
Stop... stop it
Four men against one!
You cowardly bastard
You think you can kill this man
and get away with it?
The commandant won't take a
black man's word for it, will he?
Well, if he'll take a white man's
he'll bloody well take mine
You sir, you're no white man
Let's get out of here
Come on
Cheers to Mangal! Long live Mangal!
Next
Quick, lift it up. You wouldn't be here
if you were the shy sort
C'mon doc, quit peeping up skirts all day.
Treat a hero for once!
Isn't he the one who fought
with Captain Hewson?
No! He's the one who taught
him a lesson!
Come baby! I could teach you
a lesson or two myself
Oh dear! What a waste of energy!
Why don't you try your strength on us?
Yes! I've never tasted a hero
For you it'll be free. In fact,
we'll pay
Shut up! Go sell your bodies
to the whites... go
We just sell our bodies,
you soldiers sell your souls!
In the course of my investigations
I have discovered
that you have been compromising
senior officers,
falsifying accounts, in fact sir,
you have been cheating the company
I have done nothing
that others have not done before me
You have been smuggling opium
into China on your own behalf, Mr Kent
You have evidence?
Lockwood accused Kent of carrying
on illegitimate trade in opium...
and produced Sorabjee as evidence.
You wanted me to go to prison for you.
- No sir, you pay for your own sins
Mr Lockwood, you would persuade
a native to point a finger at me!
I'm just a puppet in his hands, sir
If you lay a hand on me...
the reverberations will reach
the House of Lords
Kent warned Lockwood
that taking him on...
Lockwood could be taking on
the House of Lords.
Anyone there?
Hukum Singh
I'm used to it, sahib
But I'm not
It's all right, come on
What are you doing?
Give me the gun
Give me the bloody gun!
I don't want you to go
I was just at Lol Bibi's...
your Juliet is really worried
about you, mate
She sent milk for you,
specially laced with turmeric
But I'm an untouchable and what
I've touched you won't consume
So I saved you the dilemma and
I drank it myself!
I want to meet her
Oh, so the fire rages here
as well
But how? You aren't a white man,
eunuch or an untouchable.
I want to meet her
What's your name?
Heera
What caste?
People on sale have none. Whoever pays
gets to choose my caste
Where are you from?
Don't know
As a child I was kidnapped, then sold
Since then, it's been one
sale after another
Want to escape?
Escape? With you?
You're badly hurt
Did you drink the milk I sent?
Ya
Lying to me?
Lol Bibi is looking for you
You'll get into trouble
Like the fish thrashes helplessly in a net...
so do I in your love
At the core of my being...
I feel an insatiable thirst...
and my every nerve is aflame
Oh tell me, lass, who's that
thief of your thoughts?
That philanderer, that scoundrel,
he sins in my head
Locking his eyes with mine...
he steals my sleep and peace of mind
That trickster... oh my rascal lover
Slowly but surely...
she falls in his trap
As the flames begin to lick her...
her veil begins to slip
That trickster
Oh my rascal lover
Oh tell me, lass, who is he?
Who's that thief of your dreams?
He's a soldier, a brave warrior,
who by my word, has stolen my heart
I didn't think at first sight that
he would possess me so
But my heart began to beat aloud...
and I knew I was lost
How I panicked...
and burned with shame...
when he took my hand and
pulled me close
Then clouds of desire gathered,
and burst forth with love's rain.
Oh that trickster
Oh you scoundrel
What's up Davar?
Damn you, Nainsukh!
You cockeyed scoundrel! Can't you find
someone else to bump into?
Who better than you, now that we're
both the same... untouchables
What nonsense, you swine!
Well, you've bitten the bullet
and licked the fat
You've lost your caste, you have
nothing left to lose now
Shut up... that's a lie!
Your "lie" is being manufactured
in a factory in Calcutta
Want to see for yourself?
Do you?
Come, my brothers, come
I won't stay silent any longer,
even if it costs me my life!
It's true about the cartridges.
See for yourself, pig fat and cow fat
May the devil stay away!
Is this your factory?
- Only in name...
the real owner is an Englishman
I am a god-fearing man, brothers,
I respect both Hindus and Muslims
Then why did you use cow
and pig fat?!
The Company would have used
crow fat if that was cheaper
Mangal...?
You lied to me!
I trusted you and you lied me
What're you talking about?
- I saw it with my own eyes
The factory, the cartridge,
the grease...
made with cow and pig fat
Oh God, no...
I'm now an outcaste
You know what it means to
be an outcaste?
My entire community will shun me
They will no longer touch me,
speak to me, eat with me,
or burn my body when I die
For them I am an untouchable.
I no longer exist. I am a nobody
Mangal, listen to me...
- You lied to me!
Listen to me, I didn't know!
They lied to me
You plunder our land, you abuse
our faith and now...
you want our Souls? Sahib... you've
enjoyed a black man's loyalty
Now taste his fury
Mark my words, Captain sahib!
This cartridge will explode
And it will bring to an end
the Company Raj
Take back you pistol, Captain sahib.
We're brothers no more
Don't...
If you are an untouchable then so am I
Mangal, we're all with you
A wrong done unknowingly is not a sin
That's what the scriptures say as well
This cartridge controversy
could spin out of control sir.
We have tried to introduce it twice,
in different regiments without success.
I would recommend caution.
Damn it we can't succumb
to such blind superstition
May seem like superstition
to us sir, but to the sepoys...
it's an extremely sensitive issue.
It strikes them at their core.
Gordon urged his senior officers
to respect the sepoys' feelings...
and withdraw the cartridge.
He was reminded that...
the country was ruled by a Company
which could not suffer losses.
Colonel Mitchell claimed that
his sepoys were loyal...
and would do his bidding.
So it was decided...
that a contingent from Barrackpore
be sent to Behrampore...
a hundred miles away... where they would be
forced to use the cartridge, by example.
Mitchell ordered the sepoys from
both the Behrampore...
and Barrackpore regiments...
to use the cartridge.
First company, first platoon,
step forward and pick up
your rifles and the cartridges
Subedar
What's the matter?
The new cartridge, sir.
The sepoys don't want to use it, sir
Damn it Bakht Khan
Now this is the Army
A soldier uses whatever arms and
ammunition he is asked to use
First company, first platoon,
step forward
Enough!
If you do not move I will blow you
apart with cannon!
Move the artillery forward
You will obey orders!
I will count till ten
One
Two
Three
Four
Five
Six
Seven
Eight
Nine
Fire...
Dismiss the parade sir.
This could turn serious
Do it sir
For god's sake,
do it before it's too late!
Very well, dismiss the parade
Parade... dismiss!
Looting the armoury was wrong
Now we leave them no choice
What choice did we have?
Mitchell was about to blow us up.
That was just a bluff.
He doesn't have the authority
But now he has an excuse
He'll attack us and claim that
he's putting down a mutiny
They're coming to attack our
homes with horses and cannons!
Don't panic. Get ready with
your weapons
Come on
This is your commanding officer
Unless you lay down the arms
which you have looted...
I promise you,
I will give the orders of fire
We don't want bloodshed,
Colonel sahib.
Withdraw your guns and go in peace
Surrender! This is your last chance
We are armed Colonel sahib!
We will fight
But sir, they are our own men
Not any more, can't you see
they are mutineers
Split up into four groups and
let each man carry two torches
Sir but we have no such commands
from the General
Don't you dare interfere with my authority
Please withdraw for now, sir.
Let me talk to them
All right do it, do it!
Listen up
This is corporal Bhola Tiwari speaking
Colonel Mitchell sahib has agreed
to withdraw the cannons
The English soldiers are
returning to their barracks
Please let them through
Fellow soldiers of India...
we have shed our blood
without complaint...
in the service of our foreign masters
For them, we have conquered
kingdom after kingdom
But in return...
what have we got?
Poverty, hunger and humiliation
Mangal, Gordon sahib is here
I'm not here on duty
I've come to speak with Mangal Pandey
Whatever you have to say,
you can say here. We're all friends
Give me a minute
Do you fully understand the implications
of what you're doing?
The Army will never,
never tolerate insubordination
You leave them no choice.
They will have to use force unless...
Unless what? Unless what sahib?
Unless we go down on our knees
and beg for mercy?
Swallow your cartridge and our honour?
Forget who we are and promise to
remain your slaves forever?
For too long our minds have rusted
in the service of foreign masters
All it takes is a little bit of grease to
make us remember who we are
I can understand how you feel.
I too feel angered...
when the Company is unreasonable,
when officers are unfeeling,
when rules are unfair,
but these differences...
must be resolved by reasonable means
This is the difference
Now what are the reasonable means?
News of the chaos at Behrampore had
reached the senior officers.
They were unhappy with Mitchell's
handling of the situation.
Mitchell is a fool
This shouldn't have been allowed
to happen.
I've come to beg you to reconsider, sir.
Please withdraw the cartridges.
You don't expect an army to succumb
to a rumour do you, Captain?
This is not simply
a question of idle gossip, sir.
Gordon once again urged that the
cartridges be discontinued.
But the officials paid no heed to him.
Instead, they cast aspersions
on his loyalty, and said...
he could share his bed with a
native, but not his loyalty.
The British were worried that there were
very few white soldiers in Barrackpore.
They decided to send for
Queen Victoria's troops from...
Rangoon to deal with the
rebelling sepoys.
And till Rangoon Regiment arrived...
they would stall for time
by ordering an enquiry.
I think we should accept the
Company's offer and return the guns
There will be only an inquiry,
no punishments
Let them save face
But we can win! For every British soldier,
we are seven sepoys
Even if we win Behrampore,
will it end the Company Raj?
So we take defeat without a fight?
Have we learnt nothing from the British?
Rushing into battle is futile
But if we plan well, we can win.
Our country, our honour... everything
But for now we need time
O' Messiah, lead us into hope...
O' Messiah, lead us into hope
In fervent worship, I seek you...
like a moth seeks the flame
O' most merciful, benevolent God...
hear my plea
Lead me to your light,
show me the way
O' most merciful, benevolent God...
hear my plea
O' Messiah, lead us into hope
My heart is uneasy,
sleep and dreams elude me
I turn and toss as a storm grows
in my breast
What is to happen next?
Where does this story go?
The world waits with bated breath
for the saga to unfold
O' Lord...
O' Messiah...
Why these hurdles, why this trial by fire?
O' most merciful, benevolent God...
hear my plea
Welcome, friends, welcome...
welcome to the noble path
We are emissaries of King Nana Saheb
I am Azimullah and this is Chief of the
Maratha army, Tatya Tope
Please be seated
What brings you to us?
You are aware how the Company has,
through treachery and force...
snatched our kingdoms from us
They took Delhi, Awadh, Jhansi...
Everyone is angry
Nana Saheb has united all the kings...
to fight against the Company
We're here to invite you to join us
Invite us?
What is it, some feast?
Your Rajahs and Nawabs have
gambled away their kingdoms
They've sold out to the company,
my friend
We have seen them grovel and
lay down their arms in front of us
What are they? Nothing
And you?
We are Hindustan.
The Company rules on our strength
The Company's native army
is the only force today...
with the numbers, the weapons
and the training to challenge the Company
And afterwards? Who will rule?
The people
Even in England, the Queen may be
on the coin, but the rule is of the people
The Company has always
won by dividing us...
by making us fight, king against king,
Hindu against Muslim
We have a common enemy... the Company
It's time to unite and fight against it
You want that we spill our blood to
throw the Company out...
and become your slaves again?
No! This is a fight for freedom
Freedom from our past,
freedom for our future
It is the need of the hour
that we bury our differences
We're ready to fight alongside the kings
But this revolution needs
a unifying symbol
And that can only be the
Red Fort in Delhi
If we agree...
to unite under the leadership of the
Mughal Emperor Bahadur Shah...
then we have a deal
But Bahadur Shah is 82 years old
Yes, he is old and infirm...
but fed up of the Company's excesses
He needs us and we need him
His flag will be our banner
We know the disposition, speed and
strength of the entire Company army
Barrackpore, Behrampore, Raniganj
Allahabad, Kanpur, Lucknow,
Meerut and Delhi
All large garrison towns
Three hundred thousand native sepoys
and only forty thousand British soldiers
If on the same day, at the same time,
all of us rise...
the Company won't know where to hide
In a single day, we disarm
every British soldier
And the Company Raj comes to an end!
Praise be to Allah!
Astrology predicts that the Company Raj
will end in a hundred years
And a hundred years, ends this May
Then let's fix the date
31st May
On that day, all of India will rise
and become free
It's Holi!
Holi is here, an explosion of colour
The bells ring out and drumbeats roll
The streets dance in drunken abandon
It's the season of joy, my love
You wretches! Where are you off to?
Look, Holi is here in a riot of colours,
painting one and all alike
Sorrows are lost, in new ecstasies
of blues, greens and reds
Look, Holi is here in a riot of colours,
painting one and all alike
Sorrows are lost, in new ecstasies
of blues, greens and reds
I am going to be coloured anew...
this year the hues look richer
No one can stop us now,
no one can hold us back...
No matter what... we are ready!
Look my love, I'm drenched in colours
And a little drunk, you sway
so mesmerisingly
How can I not let go and
enjoy this moment...
as you seduce me with your eyes?
- No one can stop us now
No one can hold us back...
no matter what... we are ready!
With a fistful of colours Lord Krishna
sneaks up on his lover
But Radha is quick as she is naughty
and gives it back as good as she gets
With a fistful of colours Lord Krishna
sneaks up on his lover
But Radha is quick as she is naughty
and gives it back as good as she gets
As the lovers unite and the colours mix
Radha and Krishna become one
Which is Radha, which is Krishna
who can tell them apart?
Under a blanket of colours
our eyes lock, our hands touch
We come closer and something
deep within me stirs
This spell of love, this joyous abandon,
can you ever escape it?
Don't ask that of me anymore
No one can stop us now,
no can hold us back...
no matter what... we are ready!
The insolent behavior of the sepoys
Had the British officials worried.
Just then, General Anson
received the news...
that Rangoon Regiment was afloat
and would reach on...
April 1st. Anson decided that when
the Queen's troops arrived...
the rebel soldiers would be disarmed
and their leaders hanged.
It would be such a lesson that no one
would dare rise for a hundred years.
Mangal, they're going to kill you
They've sent for the Rangoon Regiment
What... Rangoon Regiment? When?
1st April
How do you know?
Last night I was with Hewson
He blurts out a lot when he is drunk.
He said, once the Regiment gets here...
they'll disarm the native sepoys
and hang their leaders
I'm scared, Mangal! Save yourself...
and save me... from this hell
Mangal, I beg you
Let's run away...
anywhere
No
Heera, I cannot run away
The situation has changed.
We can't wait till May
But the kings need time to prepare.
- Time is what we don't have
One wrong move can ruin everything
Once the sepoys are disarmed,
who will do the fighting?
Your Nana Saheb? Or Bahadur Shah?
There's one way
We've received orders to march from
Behrampore on 21st March...
to reach Barrackpore on 30th March.
Rangoon Regiment arrives on 1st April
That gives us two days
The moment we reach Barrackpore,
we'll take over the cantonment
Then, before the Rangoon Regiment arrives,
we march to Calcutta.
There we capture Fort William
and hold on to it...
until the rebellion spreads
throughout the country
Done with selling your milk
to that white bitch?
Better that, than us starving
You bitch! Talking back to me?
Now their days are numbered!
- Yeah, in your dreams!
Wait and see, their time's up!
By the next full-moon... slaughter!
Where...? In Barrackpore?
Everywhere. All across India!
Memsaab, danger! Danger Memsaab!
Wait
What's going on, what danger?
Baba is like my own son.
I don't want anything to happen to him
Memsaab, you must leave!
- Why what's going on?
The sepoys say Company Raj will end
They've been saying that for a
hundred years. It won't happen
No! This time it's for real
Please take Baba and go back to
Englistan. Please
You've taken a great risk, Kamla.
Traitor! You dare to mutineer?
Now see what we do to your wife and child!
What date have you devils set for this?
30th March
Send dispatches immediately
Stop the Behrampore Regiment
from reaching here.
Contact Rangoon
The Queen's Regiment must get here
before the 30th.
Remember... your wife and child!
On learning the rebels' plans,
General Hearsey ordered that...
The Rangoon Regiment must reach
Barrackpore before 30th March.
Meanwhile, the Behrampore Regiment
must be stopped en route...
and prevented from reaching Barrackpore.
Halt!
Ah, Bakht Khan! - Why this halt, sir?
A storm is brewing.
We stay here till it passes.
But the Sepoys are tired... eager to reach
Barrackpore. They need to rest
Really? Well I'm afraid
they must rest here
I will go and explain it to them
That won't be necessary
What's up?
What happened?
White soldiers, a whole army!
What? Where?
On the riverbank, I saw it myself
Are you out of your mind?!
Believe me, I swear by my mother!
On the banks
Come on... the Brits are here!
The Rangoon Regiment has arrived.
Everyone to the Parade Ground. Quick!
Sound the bugle! Call everyone, quick!
This is not the time... - Blow the bugle
Mangal! What's the matter?
What's wrong with the Sergeant-Major?
Don't go out. It is bad luck to spill milk
It's an ill omen!
Something terrible is going to happen!
Please don't go
Don't worry, I'll be fine
Come on! The time has come!
Time to fight, time to be free!
What happened Mangal, what's wrong?
- Get your weapons. The Brits are here
The Rangoon Regiment has landed!
- But today isn't 1st April
They came early. We have to act fast.
Go get your guns! Quick!
To arms!
But Bakht Khan's men aren't here yet.
- We need to wait for them
We can't wait. We must attack,
and capture the cantonment before
the Rangoon Regiment moves in
Stop. Don't. You'll get us killed!
There's no time! Come on, move! Move!
No no, wait! He's gone mad!
Mangal your impatience
will get us killed!
And this hesitation will
kill the rebellion!
But Mangal, we are not ready yet
It's now or never!
What's wrong with you guys?
Don't you see, the moment we have
all been waiting for is here!
It's time to honour your pledge,
it's time to do or die
Pick up your guns and fight
Fight for your freedom
For once, fight for yourselves
Fight!
Come on!
What's going on here!
Who sounded the bugle?
Mangal, stop
Mangal... no...
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
A handful of sepoys is no match
for the Rangoon Regiment
That we shall see
Then you leave me no choice
Get the General
Sir, it's begun
The British Army
Rangoon Regiment
You are completely outnumbered
Drop your guns and surrender, or die
It's too late, Mangal. It's all over
All of India is looking at us
If we surrender now...
the rebellion dies before it is born.
We can't let that happen
I won't let that happen
They are far too many,
it's no use. Let's run
No... no...! - We can't win
We will win, even if it takes
a hundred years
Let's run Mangal... please,
or we'll all die!
Go
Spread the word
It has begun
Mangal the rebellion needs you!
The rebellion needs blood
Let it be mine
ATTACK!
Stop
Don't fire
Hold your fire
I want him alive
To the hospital! Quick! He mustn't die
Awaken, arise and be blessed.
May all be blessed
The towns are awake, the homes
are abuzz, every village is astir
Valleys awaken and so do their trees,
look, shadows are coming to life!
Nana Saheb, Barrackpore has risen
Soon the fire will spread all across
But Tatya...
Make up your mind Nana Saheb.
Seize the moment or perish
No hand can stem the fire that
rages in people's hearts
Eyes ablaze and spirits aflame,
no head will ever bow again
A changed people fill the streets,
marching into death's embrace
Greetings, Queen Lakshmibai.
- Welcome, Tatya
The time has come,
earlier than we expected
Good. Just what
I've been waiting to hear
Rising like a storm unstoppable,
stirring the land in it's wake
They swear to crush and finally
end this dark age of tyranny
I'm an Emperor only in name.
I am weak, what can I do?
A giant wave is rising, Your Majesty
If we don't swim with it, we'll drown
Awaken, arise and be blessed.
May all be blessed
He will live
There is still hope.
I have spoken to them
If you tender a public apology,
they will let you live
Just say that it was a mistake
and you're sorry that's all
Or they will hang you
I am not sorry for my actions
and I am not scared to die
So they cannot threaten me
or forgive me
Mangal...
I don't want you to die
This is my fault, I let you do this,
I passed on a lie
Gordon sahib, you did what you
could and I did what I had to
My blood is not on your hands
I've come to realise that what
I did and what I must do...
has nothing to do with
bitting a bullet,
and nothing to do with the
terror of becoming an outcaste
I... believed that Nainsukh was
born an untouchable
Now... we are all untouchables
in our own land
Gordon sahib, our fight is no longer
against grease on a cartridge,
it is for our dignity, our freedom,
our right to hold our head
as high as the next man
You, the lie, the grease...
I'd bite the bullet a hundred times
if it would give my freedom
Mangal for god's sake we have
to stop this thing,
or there will be terrible bloodshed
You don't understand
India is rising,
nothing and nobody can stop it,
not even my life
Mangal Pandey...
did you on the 29th of March
incite the other sepoys...
to rebel against the Company?
Who were the others involved
in this conspiracy?
On that morning, did you imbibe
any intoxicating drinks?
This one called bhang, for instance?
Let the record show that the
accused does not deny this
It's obvious that the accused
has no interest whatsoever...
in the proceedings
of this court martial. Therefore...
we shall have to rely upon
testimonies of the eye witnesses...
and the officers attacked and wounded
by the accused
You have known Mangal Pandey
for the past seven years?
I have known him sir,
as a brave soldier and a loyal friend
One of the finest sepoys
to serve under my command
Is it true that on the 29th of March
he attacked and injured you?
I cannot deny what happened sir,
but I would like you to look...
at the circumstances that led to
his behaviour, - Answer in yes or no...
Yes but the cartridge controversy
and the subsequent events...
Yes or no Captain
Just knowing
what happened is not enough
You have to understand
why it happened
Yes or no!
Yes
Is it not also true that
he subsequently murdered...
two of your fellow officers
and injured four others?
Yes
That will be all, Captain
No, that will not be all!
You will hear me speak damn it!
Has this company become so blinded
by arrogance and greed that...
it cannot see the danger
that stares it in the face?
We stand surrounded
by our own army
300,000 armed native soldiers
so disillusioned by our command,
that they are on the verge of mutiny.
And what do we do to pacify them?
We stoke the fire
of their indignation...
by laughing at their concerns
or suppressing them with brutality
But mark my words, if you hang
this man Mangal Pandey...
there will be rebellion,
bloody rebellion...
that will sweep
through this land like wildfire
A rebellion that will lead
to the end of this Company Raj
Captain, enough!
Gordon tried his best to save Mangal.
He warned that if Mangal Pandey was
hanged there would be a bloody rebellion...
That would put to an end the Company Raj.
But even this warning fell on deaf ears.
They failed to hang him this morning
They have called for a
hangman from Calcutta
They will hang him in public tomorrow,
and make a spectacle of his death
Hearken o' people...
the drum sounds the call
Now awake and arise
From your sleep of ages
Awaken, now awaken
The Earth comes alive
as dawn heralds a new day
Rivers sparkle with new life
and hope rises in oceans anew
Awaken, now awaken
Pay heed to this moment in Time,
though your eyes
disbelieve what they see
A man is leaving this world of man,
see his head held proud and high
Oh how fortunate is the mother,
who gave birth to such a son
So fearless, he shall never die,
even if life is taken from him
With such dignity does
this rebel take leave
every head bows in respect
On his lips the cry of freedom,
his heart's desire for all to see
His eyes see beyond the present,
the dream of his homeland free
You can kill a man but not his dream!
ATTACK!
And so began the bloodiest
rebellion in human history
The British called it a Sepoy Mutiny
But for the Indians it was the
first war of independence
An officer by the name
Captain William Gordon,
was recorded as having
joined the rebel forces...
and fought against the Company Raj
The rebellion was finally
put down after a year...
but it destroyed the East India Company
And the British Crown took over
the governance of India
Mangal Pandey in his death
became a hero, a legend...
who inspired a nation to
fight for freedom
The dream of freedom ignited by
Mangal finally came true 90 years later...
on 15th August 1947,
when India became free.