Ralph! Why isn't this plane
ready to fly?
You want us all to be blown
to kingdom come? Get going!
What's the matter with you?
What are you trying to do?
You idiot!
Sorry, sir.
Are you all right?
Everything's okay, sir.
There's no bombing.
Are you sure you're feeling all right?
- l'll get Dr. Harris up here.
- No, wait a minute.
l'm all right. l'm fine.
l thought...
You'd better get some sleep, sir.
You're on the first flight in the morning.
Yeah.
All right, Sergeant, fine.
Fine.
Black Dog Leader to squadron.
Light flak ahead.
Let's get above it. Over.
Red Two to Leader,
message received. Out.
What's the matter?
Didn't you hear the C.O.'s orders?
Leader to Red Two,
what's your trouble?
- What is your trouble?
- Didn't you hear the orders?
Leader to Red Two,
are you receiving me?
- Acknowledge.
- Can't you hear the orders?
Acknowledge. Over.
Leader to Red Two, do you--
Okay, Doc.
Got him?
Yep. Now, gently does it.
Hello, Doc.
See the conquering hero come.
- What was it, cannon shell?
- Ack-ack. l put on a tourniquet.
Thanks.
Have you released the tourniquet
since it was put on?
- No, Doc, l left it all for you.
- Oh, good.
How soon?
- l guess about a couple of days, sir.
- What do you mean, a couple of days?
Well, sir, it's probably chewed up
all the cables inside, and l don't think--
l don't care what you don't think.
Just get it fixed, but quick.
That'll be all right till we get you to hospital.
A few minutes more won't hurt you.
We'll try not to shake you up
too much on the way.
You can shake
as much as you like, Doc.
Oh? Feeling good, eh?
- l feel fine. So would you.
- What, with a piece out of my arm?
Sure, if it meant you didn't have to fly
anymore with a raving lunatic.
Where's that ruddy fool
think he's going?
Hey, look out!
Round the bend, Nobby, boy.
Right round the bend.
All right, driver.
- Well, Doc?
- Hello, sir.
The arm's all right.
l'll evacuate him to Calcutta tomorrow.
But you won't be
seeing him again for a month or two.
l guessed that.
l've asked for a replacement.
We're a bit short
of navigators at the moment.
What l really came to talk
to you about is our problem boy.
Forrester.
What about him?
Didn't his navigator
tell you what happened?
- Yes, he did.
- Well?
Not my department, is it, sir?
Well, yes, Doc, l think it is.
This isn't the first time, and you know it.
- Nothing wrong with his nerve, is there?
- No, nothing.
Except l think he's round the bend.
What, because he went in without orders
and pranged some ack-ack guns?
Some people would
call that a very good show.
Well, l don't. l'd say he was
trying to get himself wrapped up.
Look, Doc, l know he volunteered
for this show, l know he's a good man,
but l'm going to
have to get rid of him.
You think he's cracking up.
No, l don't.
l think he cracked up years ago.
That's not what his record says.
First-class fighter pilot,
Battle of Britain, DSO and the rest.
He must have taken
a few chances in his time.
Does the record say
they were always necessary?
The fact is he's beginning to give
people the willies and he'll have to go.
lf what you say is true, sir,
l should think that'd
just about finish him.
Well, have you got
any other suggestions?
- What about talking to him?
- l just have. Tore a strip off him.
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
Matter of fact,
he made me feel a complete fool.
Yes, l've noticed he has that effect.
All the same, sir, l'd like to talk to him
before you do anything drastic.
All right.
Don't be too long about it.
See you at dinner.
Don't tell me you find it hot.
This is really the springtime.
The real heat begins in June, the rain.
- Bet you just love that.
- l don't love it.
Bet you really get warmed up then
and get some letters written.
- l write home every day.
- Only once a day? You're slipping.
Of course,
heat affects people different ways.
Now, take me.
l watch my health,
take plenty of salt, of course,
but l think the real secret
is in one's mental attitude.
Now, l've got responsibilities--
a wife in England, a family,
an important job.
But it's no use moping.
You know, the trouble
with you flying people is that
you're not interested
in anything else but flying.
There's a world, people.
You don't care.
You need a home, children,
a thought for the future.
Now, if you were married
and knew that when the war was over,
you had a wife to go back to...
What? What?
What's the matter?
- l thought you said something.
- That was hours ago.
Now, l say, that's the trouble with you--
no outside responsibilities.
You want a wife and family
and thought for the future.
Now, if you were married and knew
that when the war was over, you could--
Hello.
- Been looking for you.
- Something you wanted?
l wondered if you'd care
for a trip out of camp--
a village across the plain,
Christian community.
What makes you think l had
anything to do with Christian communities?
lt's just a trip, half an hour.
- You go.
- Really nice people.
Very interesting, pure Burmese.
They speak English.
l buy fruit from them.
Well, you bring me back
a nice cold melon, will you, Doc?
What's this?
To kill or not to kill,
that's all. That's--
Strange how fascinating
death can be, isn't it?
Very.
- ls that why you became a doctor?
- No.
l try to keep my patients alive.
Thou shalt not kill but need not strive
officiously to keep alive.
- Did you ever hear that saying?
- Frequently.
Come on, get in.
l see.
A nice jeep ride, a cozy chat--
a medical inspection.
Okay, Doc.
Very tactfully arranged.
Well, l have to gain
my patients' confidence somehow.
Another one of my patients.
That's the dispensary.
l'll take you over later.
Off with you, you little devils!
Here we are.
This is for you.
Now hop it.
They're wonderful kids.
l love them all.
What is this place?
lt used to belong to a planter.
Now Miss McNab's got it.
- Who's she?
- Missionary. Runs the school.
But she won't be here today.
Ah, here's Dorothy.
- Good afternoon, Doctor.
- Hello, Dorothy.
l've brought a friend,
Squadron Leader Forrester.
He's a pilot.
Dorothy's from Rangoon.
- Glad to know you.
- How do you do?
Dorothy, my dear,
we're thirsty men.
Of course.
Please sit down, Mr. Forrester,
and l will get you
something cold to drink.
That's very kind of you.
Lime juice, please.
The lime juice is wonderful.
- Whatever you wish.
- The lime juice will be just fine.
- Where's Anna?
- At the dispensary.
- She'll be back soon.
- Oh, good.
- l managed to bring a little rice.
- Thank you, Doctor. Thank you.
Please sit down,
and l will get the lime.
Thank you.
l usually try and bring them
something for the kitchen.
Fruit's all right,
but not all the time.
They can't buy food.
They came here
stripped of everything,
all the way from Rangoon.
Can you imagine what it
must have been like?
Hundreds of miles.
l don't know how any of them
ever got through alive.
l hope l didn't waken you.
l'm sorry, l must have
fallen asleep for a moment.
Several moments.
Where's the doctor?
He and Dorothy went down
to the dispensary.
l'm Anna.
How do you do?
My name's Forrester.
l know.
They sent me up here
to see if you were all right.
They said that you'd gone to sleep
even before you had time to have a drink.
Well, that was very rude of me.
lt was very, very rude.
But no one minded at all.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
That's the best lime
l've ever tasted.
When one is thirsty,
it always tastes better.
- Have you been in Burma long?
- About three months.
- Do you like it?
- Well, l don't know really.
Life's pretty much the same
on an airfield, whatever country you're in.
Except that it's hotter here.
When the cooler weather comes,
you may like it better.
Oh, l don't dislike it.
l just don't know it.
No one knows it,
not all of Burma.
Rice and rubies--
that's about all l knew about Burma
before l came here.
There are stones here
if you wish to buy them, Mr. Forrester.
Well, that's very kind of you.
lt's isn't far.
Well...l think the doctor
will be wanting to get back.
Oh, no, he always goes late.
There's plenty of time.
All right.
l'll be glad.
These are rubies, sir.
Yes.
These are white sapphires.
And these are golden amethysts.
They're very nice.
They say that if you will come tomorrow,
they will try to have a bigger selection.
Zircons and emeralds, perhaps.
That's very kind of them.
Tell them that l'll try to make it.
Thank you.
Please, thank you.
Please. Good-bye, sir.
Thank you very much.
Good-bye.
Good-bye. Thank you.
You didn't really want
to buy the stones, did you?
Not really, no.
You're the first officer who's
come here and not bought jewels.
Am l?
All of them come for jewels,
so l assumed that you had, too.
That is why l took you to those people.
You should have said.
lt was very interesting. lt's just that
l have no one in particular to give jewels to.
No one? l'm sorry.
No need to be sorry.
The doctor tells me that your
sister comes from Rangoon. You too?
Yes. l was
at the university there.
- Studying what?
- The humanities.
lt's not very much use to me here.
But l have learned a little about nursing,
so now l help the doctor
with the sick in the village.
- Are there many sick?
- l'm afraid there are.
How do they feel about us being here?
lt's been explained to them
that it is necessary.
lt's been explained to us, too,
that it's necessary.
Down there's the river.
We swim there.
Any crocodiles?
No, no crocodiles.
Very nice here.
Next time l fly over this place,
it'll seem more friendly.
Didn't it seem friendly before?
Never thought about it.
Most of you people
hate it here, don't you?
You long for home.
l don't.
Not ever?
Nope.
Well, l guess the doctor will
be wanting to get back to camp.
Oy-oy, here he is.
Who's gonna tell him
the good news? You?
Yes, l'll tell him.
- Good morning, Sergeant.
- Good morning, sir.
- How's it coming?
- l'll have her ready for you by tonight, sir.
Fine. By the way,
the oil cooler in this engine--
l meant to tell you yesterday,
you'd better change it.
Not me, sir.
What are you talking about?
Time expired, sir. Due for release.
Came through last night.
Me and Clark,
both going home together.
- Clark? Who's Clark?
- Me, sir.
- Oh, Nobby.
- Yes, sir.
Been together ever since
we first joined, sir, Nobby and me.
Congratulations.
Oh, Forrester, l thought
you were over at Doc's.
l couldn't find you anywhere.
This is Carrington, your new navigator.
Got in earlier by Dak from Komilla.
This is Squadron Leader Forrester.
How do you do, sir?
Who told you to move in here?
Well, the Messing Officer.
They're moving a lot of new bodies in.
Everywhere is full up.
Anyway, it's only for tonight.
l'm being sent up to Meiktila.
l'll be leaving tomorrow.
Everything's in a mess
at the moment.
So l see.
- l seem to have put up a black.
- Oh, he's an impossible man.
Of course, we all feel the heat.
And three in a tent really is too many,
but that's no reason to behave
in such a boorish way.
Still, l suppose it was a bit
high-handed of the Messing Officer
just to stick me in here
without even consulting him.
Yes, but what you don't realize is that
Forrester invites that sort of treatment.
Puts people's backs up.
Thank goodness l'm a wingless wonder.
l don't envy you flying with him.
Why?
Well, everyone knows
he's round the bend. Everyone.
- Ah, well met.
- Hello, Doc.
l was coming over to see you.
- l've an invitation for you.
- Yes?
Miss McNab, the missionary
from the village--
dinner tonight.
No, thanks.
l take over some rice
and a can of meat and they make curry.
lt's delicious.
l'm sure it is, but l can't make it.
l'll pick you up at 7:00.
l said no thanks.
Here, you take this.
l'll take the rice.
We are not divided
All one body we
One in hope and doctrine
Come on.
One in charity
Onward, Christian soldiers
Marching as to war
With the cross of Jesus
going on before
- Good evening, Dr. Harris.
- Good evening, Dorothy.
- Good evening, Mr. Forrester.
- Good evening.
- Something for the kitchen.
- Oh, how good of you.
l'll be in in a minute.
Ah, good evening, Dr. Harris!
Good evening to you.
Good evening, Miss McNab.
Can l introduce--
This will be Squadron Leader Forrester,
l have no doubt.
lt's an honor
and a pleasure, Mr. Forrester.
- l'm glad you were able to come.
- That's very kind of you.
Nobody told me
you were so handsome.
Come on, let me introduce you.
This is Anna's mother.
How do you do?
She can't answer you
because she can't speak.
She hasn't spoken
since the Japs bombed us in Rangoon.
l'm sorry.
- Hello, Mr. Phang.
- A pleasure, Doctor, as always.
- This is Mr. Phang.
- How do you do, Mr. Phang?
Very pleased indeed, sir,
to meet so distinguished an officer.
lt'll be no surprise to you to learn that
Mr. Phang studied English at the university.
English literature
to be precise, Mr. Forrester.
Oh, Doctor,
remember l am relying on you
to have plenty of ideas
about the hymns for Easter.
l've been thinking of nothing else.
Mr. Phang!
Excuse me.
Yes, Miss McNab?
- Get me another glass, please.
- Certainly.
- l'm glad you were able to come.
- lt's good to see you again.
lt was very good
of Miss McNab to ask me.
Mr. Forrester, do you know
that foul, benighted, godless city Katarba?
l'm telling you, the only good thing
that ever came out of it
was the bottle of whiskey
the doctor brought us back from there.
l don't touch the stuff myself.
But l daresay it won't do you
any harm while you're waiting for the dinner.
- There.
- Thank you, Miss McNab.
- And what is it you fly?
- Mosquitoes, fighter-bombers.
l say they are
wicked, devilish things.
True.
l see you are one of the quiet,
thoughtful ones, Mr. Forrester.
You didn't tell me that, Anna.
She's very shy, of course.
Well, drink your whiskey.
Dinner will be ready soon.
l told you l'd come again.
l hoped you would.
Miss McNab says you're very shy.
Compared to Miss McNab,
everyone is shy.
She's quite a character.
We love her.
lf it hadn't been for her, none of us
would have got here from Rangoon.
Yes, the doctor was telling me.
Seems incredible.
Strange things happened
during the war.
Yes.
Strange landing places.
Strange meetings.
Dinner! Dinner!
lt's delicious.
Shall we go?
Some more curry, Mr. Forrester.
You're not eating a thing.
- Did you not like it?
- Oh, it was terrific.
l've eaten too much already, thanks.
l've been admiring your tablecloth.
Ah, you have an eye
for fine things, Mr. Forrester.
lt was worked by the girls
at the mission in Rangoon for Miss McNab.
They gave it to her
on her 21st birthday.
Take no notice of him, Mr. Forrester.
l'm not ashamed of my age.
For my 45th birthday they made it,
and all the way from Rangoon,
through every inch of the way,
l kept telling myself,
''McNab, whatever else you may lose,
you'll not be losing
that tablecloth the girls gave you.''
lt's a beautiful thing.
Aye.
Three hundred of us died
on that journey, Mr. Forrester.
That's how old l am.
Miss McNab,
when l get back home,
l'm going to see that you're decorated
if it's the last thing l do.
Ach, don't gab so much.
Give Mr. Forrester a cup of tea, Anna.
No, no. l mean it.
lf you want to decorate someone,
you should decorate the good Lord.
lf you could get His name
in the honors list,
you'd be talking, l'm telling you.
Well, if you'll write the citation,
l'll see what l can do.
What you can do, Dr. Harris,
is to think about Easter.
What's your favorite hymn
for Easter, Mr. Forrester?
Oh, Easter hymns?
''Hallelujah,'' isn't it?
Yes. ''Hallelujah.''
''Hallelujah.
Jesus Christ is risen today.''
Ah, that's splendid.
l can see you've been
well brought up, Mr. Forrester.
Come on, we'll all sing it.
Jesus Christ is risen today
Hallelujah
Our triumphant holy day
Who did once upon the cross
Hallelujah
Suffer to redeem our loss
Hymns of praise
then let us sing
Hallelujah
Unto Christ, our heavenly king
Who endured the cross and grave...
What is it?
Jap bombers.
They're trying to find the airstrip.
There's too much light here.
You shut the door.
But the pains that He endured
Hallelujah
There's quite a bunch of them.
The children will be frightened.
l ought to get down to the dispensary.
Come on, then.
Look out!
Anna!
Anna?!
Are you all right?
Yes. Yes, l'm all right.
Are you sure?
- Are you all right here?
- Yeah, all right.
Come along, then.
We'll be needed in the village.
Dorothy's looking after your mother.
Come on, Mr. Phang!
Anna, you'd better get in there
and help out. l'll be in in a minute.
You two better go and collect the casualties
and bring them along here.
- What's this? What's going on?
- Escape from the Japanese.
The Japs aren't coming back here.
These people don't know that.
They've been bombed before.
Will you please attend
to this one, Doctor, now.
- l'll finish that dressing.
- Right.
Anna, you'd better go back
to the bungalow and lie down.
l'm all right, Doctor.
No, you're not.
You're still suffering from shock.
Now do as l say, please.
Give me that.
l told her to go back to the bungalow.
She's still suffering from shock.
- She got caught up in the crowd.
- l'm all right.
You lie down here for a while.
Put that blanket over her, will you?
l must be getting back.
That last lot sounded as if it was
near the camp. l'll be needed there.
l'd better go, too.
There's nothing you can do there,
but there's a lot you can do here.
- l'll call over for you in the morning.
- Right.
Mr. Forrester.
Would you hold her
while l finish bandaging?
Surely.
Excuse me if l ask you
a personal question, Mr. Forrester,
but are you married?
No.
l'm glad.
- Do you hear?
- Yes, l hear.
They are not like us, made of ice.
They get rid of their sorrow
and their fear.
They don't leave it inside, Mr. Forrester,
as you or l might, to rot.
That'll be all, Mr. Forrester.
lf you wouldn't mind
taking her over to the other children,
l'll see about getting Anna
something hot to drink.
The doc's here now.
l'll have to go over to the camp.
Please don't go for a moment.
l have something to tell you.
- You were going to tell me something.
- lt wasn't much.
Tell me.
lt was something to give you.
Open it. lt's for you.
lt's for you.
You have no one to give it to?
No.
l'm glad, because now
you can keep it for me.
- l can't say anything.
- Don't say anything.
There's nothing to say.
lt's only a little thing
for you to keep for me, that's all.
Anna...
Early in the war
l met a girl and fell in love.
When l got leave,
we went to London and got married.
And that night...
while we were out
having dinner...
there was an air raid,
and the building that we were in
got a direct hit.
She was killed.
After that...
l didn't want to go on living.
You'd think that'd be easy enough
in war, but it didn't work.
l wanted to die,
but l got medals instead.
l could see the trouble
in your face when you first came.
lt is not good to die inside.
lt was like living a bad dream.
Here we bury
the dead in the earth,
not in our hearts.
ls the dream over now?
l think so.
You said something
about never going home.
- What did you mean?
- l meant just that.
Would you rather stay here?
l never want to be anywhere else.
And will you always come back?
Always.
Then l will always be here.
- Good morning, sir.
- Oh, hello, Bill.
- Sit down, will you?
- Thanks.
Rather a dull job for you today, l'm afraid.
l know you won't mind helping out.
You haven't flown with that new
navigator of yours yet, have you?
No, sir, not yet.
l've got to send a body
over to Meiktila today.
You'll be trying out
the new chap anyway,
so l thought if you wouldn't
mind going that way,
we'd kill two birds with one stone.
Sure. Who's the body?
- Blore.
- lt will be a pleasure.
- You don't like him, eh?
- We've been sharing a tent.
- Oh, l see.
He's a good bloke, though.
A Cambridge man, physics.
He's very clever, l believe.
Didn't know that.
Well, l've told Blore
he may be going with you.
l'll bet that was
a real thrill for him.
There's nothing wrong with old Blore.
He's like the rest of us--
sometimes needs a change of air.
Yes, sir.
l hear you're gonna be my passenger.
Yes. How long will it take?
l can't say.
Carrington will have to figure that out.
- Thought l might find him here.
- He went over to the crew tent.
Well, how soon do you think
you'll be ready?
- l've got all my stuff to pack.
- So l see.
- There's no great hurry.
- l'd like to get it properly packed.
- Anything l can do to help?
- No, thanks.
No, don't touch anything, please.
l want to be sure everything's here.
Well, is there anything
l can fix you up with?
You'll need all the comfort
you can get at Meiktila.
l don't think that's very funny.
lt wasn't meant to be.
Hello, Carrington.
We've got a job to do.
Yes, sir, l heard.
l'll take you over to lntelligence.
You can make out your flight plan.
You think you can
be ready by 12:00?
- Yes, l think so.
- Good.
lt's only a small trip, this.
lnteresting from your point of view, though.
Are you ready?
Got a hammock rigged up for you
in the bomb bay. Best we could do.
Okay, let's go.
Everything okay?
All okay.
Passenger asleep.
He's lucky.
By the way,
this is Jap territory here--
up to the river.
They're welcome to it.
Over there, Mandalay.
- Where the dawn comes up like thunder?
- That's the place.
Would you like to have a look
after we've delivered the body?
Roger.
Starboard engine.
Starboard fuel off.
- We're going back.
- Roger.
Course 2-0-9er.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
Kong K Cable to Scuttle.
Starboard engine now on fire.
Cannot extinguish.
My approximate position
is 90 miles southeast of you,
on course 2-0-9er.
Mayday.
- Hold on, we're going down.
- Roger.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
Kong K Cable to Scuttle.
Crash landing, crash landing.
Crash landing. Crash landing.
Mayday, mayday.
1 , 2, 3, 4, 5.
5, 4, 3, 2, 1 .
Mayday, mayday.
Kong K Cable to Scuttle.
We're preparing to crash-land.
Crash landing, crash landing.
Mayday!
Mayday! Mayday!
Carrington!
Let's get him outta here!
You got anything to help him?
- l've got some morphine, l think.
- Get it quick.
We'll give him one of these
and then get him into the shade.
Hello, Kong K Cable, this is Scuttle.
Your QDM, 2-0-9er.
l say again, 2-0-9er.
How do you hear me? Over.
- Keep trying.
- Yes, sir.
Hello, Kong K Cable, this is Scuttle.
Your QDM, 2-0-9er.
l say again, 2-0-9er...
How do you feel now?
l'd like a drink.
You got a nice cool
scotch and soda there, Blore?
l suppose you mean water.
We'll have to go carefully with it.
There's only the thermos flask
and the bottle.
How's that?
We were on course.
Now, don't you worry about that.
You just take it easy.
Did they get a fix on us?
l don't know.
l kept calling as long as l could.
They could work out our position
by time alone, l should say.
Parker saw the flight plan.
What time is it?
Four minutes past 2:00.
That's not quite four hours till dark.
Say three.
- They're bound to find us before then.
- You think so?
Certainly. They'll have us
out of here in no time.
Meanwhile, we must organize ourselves,
see what you have with you.
l haven't got a thing.
l was just flying the airplane.
But you must have something.
Even the smallest trifle may be useful
in an emergency like this.
Medical card.
Three rupees.
Handkerchief.
What's that?
Don't tell me you've been buying
those things. They're all phony, you know.
lf they got any kind of a fix on us,
which l doubt...
it's just possible that
they might locate us here.
Supposing they do, what then?
Well, they get us out, of course.
They haven't got helicopters.
Well, they could drop supplies.
So that we can camp out here until
the war is over? This is Jap territory.
Yes, we know that, but...
What are you getting at?
Mind if l use your hat?
Carrington, are you awake?
Yes, l'm awake.
- You heard that, what Forrester said?
- Yes, l heard.
Well, l think we've got
to be very careful.
Knowing him as l do,
well, frankly,
l don't think we ought to place any reliance
at all on his judgment about anything.
He got us down all right.
We wouldn't have stood
an earthly with some pilots.
l'm not saying he's not a good pilot,
but we're not in the air now.
He doesn't care what happens to him.
Well, l do care what happens to me,
and l'm not taking any chances.
lf we keep our heads,
we'll be all right.
l'm relying on you to back me up.
You got any more of those tablets?
There are only a few left.
They ought to be eked out.
What's all this for?
We want some sort of signal
when they come looking for us.
When who comes looking
for us, the Japs?
You know quite well
who l mean--our people.
l think it's time we took a look
at some of the facts.
l don't mind looking at the facts.
They seem straightforward enough to me.
Our people know
we made a forced landing.
Even if they didn't get a fix on us, they're
bound to know our approximate position.
Our job is to give them
all the help we can,
look after Carrington,
keep our heads, and...
- ...hope for the best.
- What's wrong with that?
Nothing, if you know
what the best adds up to.
They could look for a month
and not find this place.
- How long will the water last?
- Not as long as a month.
l've got a quart and what's left
in the thermos flask.
lf we ration ourselves strictly--
and Carrington, too, mind--
l suppose it might last three days.
Though in this heat...
- What's all this leading up to?
- Just this.
l think we ought to forget about setting up
housekeeping here and start walking.
Walking?
Are you serious?
Now look, we're roughly 30 miles
northeast of the river here.
l know this country
is murder to get across,
but we ought to be able
to make it in four days, even without food.
lf we make it,
we'll be in our own patrol area.
We'll have water to see us through.
But what about Carrington?
You don't expect him to walk, do you?
- We'll carry him.
- How can we?
We'll make a stretcher.
There's plenty of bamboo here,
and we've got a parachute harness--
we'll fix up something.
Carry a stretcher all that way in this heat
under this sun? We'll kill ourselves.
We don't go in the sun.
We go at night.
Have you ever carried a man
on a stretcher for any distance?
No, but l'm gonna try,
even if it does kill me.
Well, you can kill yourself
if you like, Forrester.
You've been round the bend for ages
and everybody knows it.
But you're not going to endanger our lives
just because you don't give a rat--
Help!
What is it?
Dak.
- Anyone we know?
- l can't tell, it's too high.
Blind fools.
Never even started to see us.
You have any idea
what it's like trying to locate
a burnt-out plane
in country like this?
l couldn't even recognize it
from the top of that rock.
lt'll be almost impossible from a plane.
Turbulence, heat haze, odd forest fires--
it's a million-to-one shot.
Blind, stupid fools.
Look...
We've got enough water
for three days, maybe four.
We've got a lot of pills
and no food.
Now either we sit here
and drink the water and hope,
or we drink the water and travel.
Does that make sense?
- lt would if it weren't for Carrington.
- l told you, we'll carry him.
The whole idea is crazy,
and you know it.
lt's still crazier to stay here.
Now let's get to work on the stretcher.
Well, l think Carrington
should be consulted about this.
Carrington has no option.
lt's his only chance.
Well, it's entirely your responsibility.
Responsibility, hell.
We're going to walk out of here
and try to reach the river--at night.
lt'll be quite simple--
we'll march for half an hour,
then rest for half an hour.
We're going to make
a stretcher and carry you.
- lt's hopeless.
- Blore thinks it's hopeless.
What do you think?
You'll have to navigate.
l don't know.
You can't just carry a bloke
on a stretcher as easily as all that.
lt's a piece of cake.
Blore and l are the champion
bloke-carriers of all Burma.
lsn't that right, Blore?
All you have to do is try
to get some sleep until it's dark.
Come on, Blore.
You ready?
All set.
Just sing out
if you feel yourself slipping.
Okay.
- How about you, Blore?
- No, now just a minute.
All right.
Ready? Lift.
All right, put him down.
lt's hopeless.
We'll never get a stretcher down there.
Will you stop saying it's hopeless?
We'll lower him feet first.
You swing this end around.
- Absolute madness, the whole thing.
- Shut up.
Lift.
All right, lower away.
Hold it!
All right, lower him.
Slowly.
That's it.
Take him over there.
We'll rest for a bit.
All right, pick him up.
Keep going.
How much longer?
lt'll be dawn soon.
We'll stop then and rest all day.
Supposing you slip on the rock
and break your ankle--
then where shall we be?
You tell him, Carrington.
- Up the creek.
- That's right.
And you'll have to
carry us both, Blore, old boy.
Should have stayed where we were.
l said so all along.
Yes, you did.
All right.
Let's get going.
Lift.
What's the matter?
There's a sheer drop.
We'll never get by it.
Yes, we will.
Just go carefully.
- You want me to go in front?
- Why, don't you think l'm competent?
Sure l do,
but let's keep going.
All right, all right.
You're the officer in charge, aren't you?
You're the person responsible.
All right, then you give the orders.
''Theirs not to reason why--''
Are you still with it?
Blore!
Blore?
Are you badly hurt?
''Badly'' is a comparative term, isn't it?
So l hardly like to--
Easy.
The water.
The thermos--where is it?
Right over here.
Everything's here.
There's nothing lost.
Let's have a look at you.
There's something wrong here.
Looks like you broke
your collarbone.
lt's a pretty badly scraped face.
You got some antiseptic in your pack?
l'll get the webbing off first.
lt'll be light soon.
We'll be able to see what we're doing.
l'm sorry. Hurt you?
No.
Just thinking
of something funny, that's all.
Well, that's good.
l was thinking,
fancy worrying about the water.
You had me worried
about it there for a minute.
- As if it matters.
- As if what matters?
Well, the water.
l mean, it isn't as if it's gonna be
any use to us now, is it?
lsn't it?
Better lie back.
Not for me and Carrington, anyway.
As far as l can see,
we might just as well shoot
ourselves now and have done with it.
Here.
- Any news yet, sir?
- Hello, Doc. Yes.
We've heard from the army.
The nearest patrol they've got
is about 20 miles
from Forrester's last estimated position.
They've got a signal through
to the officer commanding there,
told him to do what he can,
but l don't suppose that'll be very much.
You mean we can't expect the army
to go charging off 20 miles
into Jap territory
on the chance of finding three corpses
and a burnt-out plane.
That's about the size of it, yes.
So it looks like
a complete write-off.
Yes.
Well, thank you, sir.
Hello, Anna.
Tell me, please.
l've told you all there is to know.
Please.
They were on their way to Meiktila--
Forrester, the navigator,
and a passenger.
One of the engines caught fire.
We didn't have time to locate
their exact position,
but we know they were
over a Jap area.
We don't know
if they landed safely.
lt's bad country, though.
Did he know it would
be dangerous when he went?
No. lt was practically
a routine flight.
He just had bad luck.
Was the bad luck
because of something he had failed in?
No.
No, it wasn't his fault.
Then perhaps he will come back.
Aye, perhaps he will.
lf it's humanly possible.
He said he would come back.
Forrester.
- What's the matter?
- A plane.
There it is!
That plane was looking for us.
So was the other one.
We should have had more sense than
to leave our position until they found us.
Now when they do see the wreckage,
there'll be nobody to signal to them.
They'll think there were no survivors
and give up the search.
That plane was on the same course
we were on--to Meiktila.
That's the way back home for us,
the way we're going.
Now will you stop teasing that shoulder
of yours and try to get some rest?
- Rest!
- Sure, you may need it.
As soon as it's dark, one of us
will have to go on to the river alone,
try to get help for the others.
And who will that be?
You, l suppose. You're the uninjured one.
And leave us to rot.
No, l was thinking
that you might like to go.
You can still walk all right.
l'll stay here
and take care of Carrington.
lt doesn't make much difference to me.
You think it over.
You never liked me,
did you, Forrester?
Not now, Blore.
There's a good fellow.
l know why.
lt's because l had something to live for,
a life to go back to.
l did some thinking last night.
lt's my having a wife
and family that you hated.
You need some sleep.
Somebody said once that in a crisis,
you could always depend on a man
of action to lose his head first.
l never thought l'd
see that proved up to the hilt.
Let's talk it over later.
l'm making a last appeal
to you, Forrester, for us all.
Carrington's wounded. He can't
think straight any more than you can.
We should never have left
the plane in the first place.
We've used up our strength uselessly.
As for going onward,
it's sheer madness.
The only sane course now is to get back
to the plane as quickly as we can
and sweat it out
until the rescue party arrives.
Well?
Forrester?
Forrester.
Blore!
What's the matter?
- Blore's gone.
- What do you mean?
Blore's gone.
Back to where we crashed,
l guess.
He's left some water in this
and walked off while we were asleep.
Maybe he's right, huh?
He's a clot and you know it.
Well, l'm gonna bring him back.
l'll make it as quick as l can.
You try to get some more sleep.
There's water if you need it.
Try not to.
l'll be back as soon as l can.
Blore!
Where's old Blore?
Decided not to come.
He's dead, isn't he?
Did he shoot himself?
Poor old Blore.
What do you know about it?
l only said poor old Blore.
Yeah.
Poor old Blore.
He could have been right, though,
don't you think?
No!
We're gonna get
out of here if we can--alive.
- You mean you are, don't you?
- l mean both of us.
l'm afraid it's no use,
my trying to walk.
Nobody's asking you to.
l'm gonna carry you.
How can you?
You'll never be able to do it.
lf l help you, do you think you
can manage to stand up on one leg?
l'll have a go.
But aren't you going to wait
until the sun's down?
We haven't got time for that.
l'm beginning to get hungry.
You all right?
Okay now?
- l think so.
- Hold on tight. Here we go.
Another 50 yards
and we'll take a rest.
Did you hear me?
Carrington.
Carrington!
Sir?
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
We'll rest right up here.
l'm all right.
Sorry.
Time for a drink anyway.
That's almost the last
of the water, isn't it?
Almost.
- You had yours yet?
- No, l'll have it a little later.
Drink it now.
Let's see you.
All right.
How much left now?
That's the last.
About had it, haven't we?
Not yet.
Pretty near, l'd say.
- You'd better go on.
- We'll both go on.
- You'll never get me out of here.
- Sure l will.
You're getting like old Blore.
- Why?
- Well, face facts.
We can't go on without water.
lf you were by yourself,
you might get to the river,
fill that flask.
There might even be something
we could eat there.
Fruit, maybe.
Or even a nice juicy trout.
What's the watch for?
lt'll be dark
for a couple hours yet.
l might lose my bearings.
When it gets light, you fire a shot.
l'll be listening.
After that, fire one
at hourly intervals.
Okay?
Okay.
lt's too bad
l don't have a fishing line.
l'll have breakfast
ready for you when you get back.
Just make mine toast and coffee.
The Lord be praised!
Yes. He reached the river all right.
He was picked up
by some Naga bearers.
He took him back with him
and got the navigator out.
- Alive?
- Yes, but only just.
A few more hours,
it would have been too late.
Forward hospital are flying
them both in tomorrow.
Anna said he would come back.
l didn't have faith enough.
- This is where l get out.
- Not too much talk, please, Mr. Forrester.
That's not fair, nurse.
Mr. Forrester and l...
got lots to talk about.
All right, Mr. Forrester,
that's enough.
Well, l'll be seeing you.
Yes, sir.
Thanks for the ride.
- Haven't we met before?
- The face seems familiar.
How about a nice jeep ride, Doc?
No nonsense now.
You're a sick man.
- You're going to hospital.
- You know where l'm going.
l'll take all the salt
and mepacrine you want.
- Your eyes still ache?
- No.
Let's have a look at your tongue.
What an impossible man you are.
All right, get in.
Hello, Miss McNab.
Look at me,
crying like a loony.
Have you ever heard
of such a thing?
There, there.
Where's Anna?
She's in there.
Asleep, l think.
She hasn't slept at all
till she knew that you were safe.
- You can go in.
- Well, l oughtn't to wake her.
There's no need to wake her.