All boats from Brick.
Make them look good. It's the
first time they've seen PT boats.
All boats from Brick.
Nice going.
Brick from Rusty.
That ought to show them.
They maneuver beautifully, sir.
-A splendid-looking lot of men.
-Thank you, sir.
Gentlemen, we're late.
Those boats of yours
maneuver beautifully.
But in wartime, l'm afraid l prefer
something more substantial.
lt's wonderful the way
people believe...
...in those high-powered
canoes of yours.
Don't you believe in them, Rusty?
And l let you sell me that stuff
about a ''command of my own.''
You skipper the 34 boat,
don't you?
l used to skipper a cake of soap
in a bathtub too.
Secure from inspection.
Dismissed!
-Nice show today, fellas.
-Thank you.
Lieutenant?
Good evening.
l'd like you to meet some boat skippers.
Shorty Long, Lefty Aiken....
What the--?
l want you to meet Andy Andrews.
He just reported. Shorty Long.
-Happy to know you.
-Thank you.
Lefty Aiken.
Where's Rusty?
Looks like he's doing his paperwork.
-Andy!
-Hello, Rusty.
Lefty said you'd checked in.
What'll it be?
Beer.
Figuring your income tax?
No. l had to work out a smooth line...
...to convince the admiral
l belong on a destroyer.
So you're really quitting
the squadron?
Can't build a Navy reputation
riding a plywood dream.
What are you aiming at?
Building a reputation...
...or playing for the team?
Look, Brick, for years l've
been taking your fatherly advice.
lt's never been very good.
From here on in, l'm a one-man band!
Send in your request.
l'll forward it.
How about a beer, Rusty?
Five San Miguels.
Nice music.
Oh the monkeys have
No tails in Zamboanga
Oh the monkeys have no tails
They were bitten off by whales
Oh the monkeys have
No tails in Zamboanga
Oh he won't go back to Subic anymore
Oh we'll hoist the jib and spank her
And we'll pipe, ''All hands, up anchor!''
But he won't go back to Subic anymore
Lucky dog!
Small beer! Small beer!
Very small beer!
Milk! Sarsaparilla! Sarsaparilla!
Ginger ale!
Paint varnish and dash of red peppers!
Gentlemen!
l want absolute silence.
Boats here has a little speech to make.
l'm not going to make a speech.
Just got something to say.
Tomorrow our old pal Doc here
is going out.
He's being paid off after 30 years.
l know most of you kids got a ways
to go before you find out...
...what 30 years in the Navy means.
lt means service.
Tough and good.
lt means serving your country
in peace and in war.
So let's raise--
We interrupt this program
for an important announcement.
This morning, the Sunday calm of
Pearl Harbor was broken by the thunder--
So let's raise our glasses
and drink to Doc...
...with all the solemnity that
this occasion demands.
To Doc.
Sorry to have to interrupt you.
Ladies and gentlemen.
l have a very important
announcement to make.
This is official.
The Japanese have attacked
Pearl Harbor.
There are no details.
All Army and Navy personnel
must report to their posts immediately.
l repeat:
All Army and Navy personnel
must report to their posts immediately.
Let's go, Rusty.
Didn't you forget something?
Land where my fathers died
Land of the pilgrims' pride
From every mountainside
Let freedom ring
Hold it.
l don't know. l'm just doing
what l'm told. You know.
Any hot dope, Whitey?
Nothing yet, Brick.
That's probably where they'll attack.
Carry on.
We'll do our best, sir.
This just came in, sir.
Gentlemen.
You may assume that a state
of war exists between...
...the United States
and the Empire of Japan.
Govern yourselves accordingly.
My compliments, gentlemen.
Here are the orders.
Hooley.
Got anything for us?
What do you call that outfit again?
Motor Torpedo Boat Squadron Three.
No orders for you now.
Maybe tomorrow.
What do you want us to do?
Sit on our duffs?
l'll ask the old man.
Stand by.
Have one boat patrol the bay
and one stand by for messenger duty.
All boats fueled. Torpedoes will
be loaded within a half-hour.
Any dope?
Our orders are to stand by.
Those destroyers aren't standing by.
They went down that channel
like a rat race.
Somebody might have given
them orders to go.
You got 20 boxes of 50-caliber there.
Give 1 2 to Lefty.
Now hear this.
Unidentified aircraft approaches Cavite.
Unidentified aircraft
approaching Cavite.
Those are Jap planes.
Headed this way.
All boats out in the bay.
Follow me, and stand by for signals.
ls that another drill?
Can't be a drill.
All we get in this Navy
is drill, drill, drill.
Fire in the paint locker!
One formation.
Breaking off.
Heading up our way, sir.
Stand by to disperse.
All boats from 4 1 .
Stand by for scatter plan.
Thank them, Smokey.
Scatter plan Baker.
Execute.
Execute!
Good shooting, Smokey.
Recognize him?
lknew him well.
Shaved his father.
Get him, Junior!
All boats from 4 1 .
Return to base.
Pretty rugged, isn't it?
Let's go, Rusty.
We've checked everything, sir.
The storeroom's gone.
No torpedoes, no motors,
no spare parts, no nothing.
Wonder if they have
any torpedoes at Corregidor.
-Might be.
-l'll check on it.
Hi.
A little rugged.
You got wet clothes on
underneath that blanket?
Just scared.
You haven't got
a monopoly on that.
What are you looking at?
Just looking for the Arizona
to come steaming up to base...
...with her 1 4-inch guns blazing...
...and the best cook stoves
in the Navy.
Arizona ?
Arizona.
Some Army boys told us a Jap task force
is headed for Lingayen Gulf.
-Planes spotted it at sunset.
-Must be another landing.
Lingayen?
Give me those scissors, Doc.
That's only about
200 miles from here.
Two thirty-five.
Why don't we knock those babies off?
What with? A cake of soap
and a bathtub? Give me that pencil.
Mr. Brickley, the admiral, sir.
Right away.
Check your gasoline.
Feel better?
Take over.
Line up your engines, check all boats.
Step on it, men.
Fire in the paint locker.
-Yes?
-Brickley.
Mr. Brickley, sir.
You sent for me?
Yes, get a boat ready
to move my staff to Corregidor.
You'll run messenger trips
between Manila and The Rock.
Work out a schedule
with the Chief of Staff.
Cavite is finished as a base.
Move your outfit
to Sisiman Cove on Bataan.
ls that all, sir?
That's all.
ls it true that a Jap task force
is moving into Lingayen Gulf, sir?
Type that and send it.
Sit down, Brickley.
That task force will land.
You and l can't stop it.
Pearl Harbor was a disaster,
like the Spanish Armada.
Listen, son...
...you and l are professionals.
lf the manager says, ''Sacrifice,''
we lay down a bunt...
...and let somebody else
hit the home runs.
We know about those destroyers...
...out of commission,
tied up around San Diego.
We could use them here...
...but they're not around.
They won't be.
Our job is to lay down
that sacrifice.
That's what we were trained for.
That's what we'll do.
Understand?
Thank you.
All set, sir.
Secure your boats.
Secure the boats?
Shorty, take the admiral
and his staff to Corregidor.
Lefty, you stand by to run
a messenger trip daily at 900.
The rest of you
take your boats to Sisiman Cove.
You join us there.
Are you kidding, Brick?
Theirs not to reason why,
theirs but to do--
And die.
l don't want to be bored
to death running messages.
l'll see that you get
the more intriguing ones.
Does that help?
Any chow, Brick?
-Razor blades and toothpaste.
-That's a swell diet.
-What's the dope, Skipper?
-Jap transports landed up north.
They're giving Bataan the works.
-Good morning, sir. Any dope?
-No dope.
Good morning, sir.
A message just came in.
And Admiral Blackwell wishes
to see you immediately. Very urgent.
Thank you.
Probably wants us to carry
a message to Garcia.
Cross, stand by with that 4 1 boat.
Let's use those razor blades.
Chief, l want you to keep
sanitary precautions at all times.
Dig a big hole over there to put
the garbage in and what-have-you.
lk eep these pots and pans scrubbed.
Don't put anything in the bay,
whatever you do.
Holy smokes, cook!
You call that soup?
No, sir, that's dishwater.
Ensigns.
l suppose you're getting tired...
...of all this routine messenger
and patrol duty.
l know you're anxious to prove
your theory of the motor torpedo boat.
As you know...
...the Japs have Subic Bay.
They've got a cruiser at Fort Balanga
shelling our positions on Bataan.
We've either got to sink her...
...or pull out our troops.
Corregidor, Sisiman Cove, Subic.
The lines are here.
The Jap minefields here.
Their cruiser...
...there.
Sink her.
Excuse me, sir,
may l borrow that?
l think one boat,
don't you, Mr. Ryan?
No, l think two boats, Mr. Brickley.
Two boats, sir.
Shove off at dusk.
Good evening, gentlemen.
We haven't got enough
steel helmets to go around...
...so issue them to your gunners
and torpedo men.
l repeat again...
...do not open up on your radios
until you're sure they've spotted you.
Use your 50-calibers
to knock out the searchlights.
You said there'd be two boats.
Who's the second?
Rusty with the 34 boat.
That's all.
We'll shove off about 1 800.
l'll regulate the speed...
...so we'll reach the end
of this leg here in darkness.
All right, Andy.
All right, let's go, Mahan.
Sir.
Nothing.
-Sir?
-Not a chance, Shorty.
Copy that in longhand
and give it to Andy on the 34 boat.
Eager beavers.
What's the matter with us?
We have the best boat.
And my boat's the fastest one
in the water.
Seventeen-thirty.
Doc, will you take a look
at this finger?
Fellas...
...we finally got the green light...
...to sink a Jap cruiser
in Subic Bay.
Through those Jap mines, artillery
and past them patrol boats.
One of our boats ought to get back.
Any of you guys not on time
don't get to go.
All right, Shakespeare.
You got blood poison to the elbow.
You belong in the hospital.
When l get back.
-lf you don't want to lose it, go now.
-Put iodine on it and wrap it up.
Look, Doc, do me a favor.
lk eep your mouth shut about it.
Don't forget to put a pinch of salt
in that pancake batter.
You'll find jam under my bunk.
Give them that.
All set, Rusty.
-Your arm all right?
-Sure.
Everything's ready.
Okay, Slug, relax until time
to shove off.
Hey, Rusty!
Let me see that arm.
You're going to sick bay, fella.
You aren't afraid of a little
competition, are you, Brick?
Shorty, the 31 boat'll go
instead of the 34. Get her ready.
l won't lose a good exec
because you're out of your head.
Secure the boat.
Mulcahey!
For two bits, l'd punch you
right in the mush.
-You know the score.
-Right.
And have your torpedo man stand by
in case those circuits fail.
Wind them up.
Come on.
Let's go, Good Luck.
Corpsman! Corpsman!
This is a hospital.
Why don't you hire a hall?
Take off your hat.
lt's just a little cut
along the finger. l don't--
Shirts are hard to get out here.
So are artificial arms.
Anchors aweigh.
You've got a temperature
a little over 1 03.
Chew these sulfur pills.
What is this, shrapnel?
Where did you get it?
Cavite.
lt doesn't hurt.
lt doesn't hurt?
Did you ever hear
of blood poisoning?
lf you'd been a few hours later,
l'd have had to take that arm off.
Headquarters called.
Casualties arriving in two hours.
-How many?
-Over 200.
Double deckers.
Try and get some rest.
We've got work to do.
That young man is sick.
Get his temperature down
and get him to sleep.
Take a few minutes yourself.
You'd better lie down.
You have a temperature of 1 03.
So l've heard.
You Navy boys always run about
two degrees above normal.
Must be the time spent at sea.
What is your rank?
Second lieutenant.
l'm a j.g., so watch your language.
l thought you were a motorcycle cop.
Despite your gold braid,
you don't tell us.
We tell you. So lie down.
Unfasten your pants.
-What?
-Unfasten your pants.
Unfasten your pants.
Come right a little.
Right a little!
This should be the
minefields now, sir.
Left a little.
Left easy.
Steady as she goes.
-Any sign of Long's boat?
-Don't see him, sir.
-What's wrong?
-This gas was loaded with wax.
Sabotage.
-How long to get started?
-About 40 minutes.
Hurry it all you can.
Forty-minute job.
They're trying to pick us up.
Get that light!
Abandon ship!
The shore batteries got
the 31 boat, sir.
Stand by your torpedo tubes.
Stand by!
Fire one!
Fire two!
-Well, Cookie, we did it.
-Did what?
Been someplace?
We blew that Jap cruiser
into next month.
Recently?
Pick up any chow?
l forgot to tell you, Mick,
your laundry's drying. Came out swell.
You guys were late for breakfast too.
lt was wonderful.
Yeah, cupcakes with raisins.
Listen, bigmouth.
That ship was a big, converted
job with eight-inch guns...
...and we blew her
into kingdom come.
Tompkins.
-How?
-Machine gun in the belly.
Yes, and we lost the 31 boat too.
Our club on Bataan took another
rap on the chin last night.
Where is that Navy of yours, anyway?
On Central Park Lake?
They'll be along.
We won't see them till Christmas.
By then the Air Force will have
won the war, l suppose.
Only, where is the Air Force?
Enemy aircraft approaching.
Secure all ventilators and bulkheads.
Repeat: Enemy aircraft approaching.
Secure all...
...ventilators and bulkheads.
That's a nice kind of a girl
to have around...
...in wartime.
Or anytime.
She's...
...kind of cute too.
1 1 ,000 guys can't be wrong.
Pretty tough, huh?
Why don't you girls
get some rest?
Don't think we won't.
How about it?
Going to ask tall, dark
and obnoxious?
Got to look pretty
for that dance tonight.
How's the arm?
Okay.
Good. Would you like to
go to a dance?
Listen, sister, l don't dance.
And l can't take
time out now to learn.
All l want to do
is get out of here.
Now, wait a minute
before you start popping off.
l don't care if they
dance their dogs off.
Be reasonable.
Those girls need relaxation.
Something to remind them they're...
...women!
Sure.
They're not going to
remind me of anything.
All uglied up in those...
...potato bags.
-Hello.
Nice party.
Now that you're here,
why don't you stay a while?
Oh, no, l just came over to...
...thank you for...
...you know, sewing up my shirt.
But you do dance, don't you?
Good evening, Mr. Ryan.
Hello.
Think you better put
that arm back in the sling?
You might use it someday...
...for plowing, or
cutting out paper dolls.
Why the eager interest?
Professional?
lt's rather like back home,
isn't it?
The porch...
...hammock...
...fireflies.
Where?
lowa.
You know, tall corn.
Where?
Upper New York State.
You know...
...apples.
Those gun flashes...
...look like fireflies.
Every night...
...they come a little closer.
Hi, Rusty.
Sandy, this is Lt. Brickley.
-Miss Davyss.
-How do you do?
Hello.
Nice party?
Swell!
That big lug dance?
Wonderful.
Only stepped on her foot once.
What's up?
lt can wait.
Go ahead.
Andy did a pretty good job
on the cruiser.
All we've got left
is Gardner.
He's such a young kid for--
lt's tricky duty.
Why not?
Okay.
Just how bad is that hand?
The finger is open to the bone.
And there's still infection there.
Let's go talk to the doctor.
ls it healing?
Yes.
Come on, Brick.
Help me pour the heat on.
How'd it go?
Did you lose anyone?
No, sir.
Mr. Ryan picked us up beautifully.
l'm sorry, sir.
l'd rather lose my right arm
than the 33 boat.
Couldn't be helped.
Paid off.
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Andy got a 7.7
through both ankles.
Snake.
Take Andy's place on the 34 boat.
Aye, aye, sir.
That's tough luck, Andy.
How're they feeling now?
They don't.
You give us the word
if you need anything.
Sure.
We'll be over to see you.
The job's yours again
when you can take it.
l'll give you the nudge...
...about next week.
Wind them up.
You never saw nothing like it.
We blew that Nip out of the water!
-Two fish, right in the guts.
-Get this, Mick.
We started to run like this--
We had cupcakes for breakfast!
With raisins.
-Glad to see you aboard, Miss Davyss.
-Thank you. Good evening.
Gentlemen, l would
like to present...
...Mr. Ryan's guest, Miss Davyss.
This is a--
Wait just a minute.
Mr. Long.
-lt's a pleasure to have you here.
-Thank you.
-Mr. Aiken.
-How do you do?
How do you do?
Mr. Gardner.
-Nice having you here.
-Thank you.
-And Mr. Cross.
-Very happy to know you.
Dinner is served, sir.
Thank you.
Will you take my place
at the head of the table?
Miss Davyss took care of Rusty when he
was in the hospital at Corregidor.
She's now attached to the
field hospital at Bataan peninsula.
There are nurses
over here on Bataan?
A few.
Wasn't it mean enough
for you in Corregidor...
...without sending you girls over here?
Well, l asked for it.
Over here, l can talk to Rusty
sometimes on the phone.
By George, we're neighbors now!
Next time, bring the other girls.
We'll have a dance!
Be a good idea!
This is a lovely party.
lt's swell.
Thanks.
-Benny.
-Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Soup.
Hot.
Biscuits, very good.
Thank you.
Real jam, sir.
Soup, biscuits, jam.
l still say it's a swell party.
Now all we need is
an orchestra and a floor show.
Miss Davyss, you're in for
the biggest surprise of your life.
Dear old girl
The robin...
...sings above you
Dear old girl
It speaks of how I love you
The blinding tears are falling
As I think of my lost pearl
And my broken heart is calling
Calling for you
Dear old girl
Terrific! Wonderful!
lf you'll excuse me,
l have a lot of checking to do.
Surely.
Thank you very much for coming over.
lt meant a great deal to all of us.
Good night, Sandy.
Good night.
-Me too. Could l call you Sandy?
-Sure.
-Well, good night.
-Good night.
Thanks.
-Good night, Sandy.
-Good night.
l don't know when l've
had such a nice time.
And don't forget now,
we're neighbors and everything.
Good night, Rusty.
How's the chow?
Great!
Boy, if l had you
on the old Arizona...
...l'd make a pot roast
that'd make your hair curl.
Crying?
l'm not crying.
lt's just that they're
such nice guys.
You aren't kidding.
Mr. Brickley and Mr. Ryan.
Confidentially...
...the President has ordered me...
...and certain key personnel
to Australia.
Your boats will take us to Mindanao.
From there, an Army bomber
will fly us south.
You want to use
all four of the boats?
Yes.
Get them ready.
This is secret.
Repeat.
Secret.
You'll get the date when it's set.
Aye, aye, sir.
Just a minute.
l think you'll find all
the charts you'll need.
You know it's not going well
with us up here.
We get the news.
We're scraping up all we can
to form a naval battalion.
Can you spare any men?
We have two extra crews, sir.
l could use them, Brickley.
Yes, sir.
We're going to run south 600 miles.
There's bad weather out there.
lt'll be rough going.
lf any boat breaks down,
we'll have to let her go.
Expendable.
You know what that means.
First night's run...
...Cuyo lslands.
Hole up there during the day.
Second night's run...
...to Cagayan on Mindanao.
We still hold the airfield there,
but the Japs are moving fast.
lt's a question of how long
we can hang onto it.
Approach every landfall with caution.
Be prepared to fight or run for it.
But remember, your primary duty
is to get these people out.
Rusty will take the admiral
on the 34 boat.
And l'll take...
...the Army personnel with me.
We'll shove off at 2 1 00.
Motor whaleboat ready?
Whenever you are, sir.
Could Mulcahey take over my duty?
l'd like to go along and see Andy.
Yeah, sure.
We'll shove off at 2 1 00.
Easy does it.
Bring those boards up.
These drums will go overboard
on the first sea we hit.
Cross lash them.
Put them on right and tight.
That's exactly what
l've been telling them.
Let's do it how the captain
and l want it done.
We can take all we got, sir.
How's Mr. Andrews?
Doctor says he's good for
about eight or nine days.
Will you give him an aloha for me?
Just for two minutes.
Be cheerful and, you know,
give him the old one-two-three.
Yes, ma'am.
Hi, Brick.
Hello...
...fellas.
-Hi, Andy.
-Hi, fella.
How are you feeling?
What is this?
A PT boat convention?
lt's good to see you.
You look swell, Andy.
When will you quit stalling
and get back to work?
Any day now.
How's the chow in this hotel?
Wonderful.
Squab.
Steak.
-Mulcahey and Mahan say hello.
-Cookie too.
The whole gang.
-How's the 34 boat?
-Fine.
l suppose...
...Snake's been botching up my job.
He's no Andrews.
Say, l got some cigarettes here.
Go on, have some.
Thanks.
We're keeping him in condition.
-He's trying to take your place.
-Trying to is right.
We got a patrol to get ready for.
The job's yours
anytime you can make it.
-Thanks.
-See you next week.
-So long.
-Take it easy.
Say, Skipper--
Sit down, Brick.
That was a nice act you boys put on.
How did you get the word?
Scuttlebutt.
Here. l'll get it for you.
lf you get through...
...mail these, will you?
Sure, if there's any mail.
One to Mother.
One to Myra.
You know, she's at Lockheed.
l wrote out a will too.
That was a pretty good act
you put on yourself.
Any unfinished business
that you want me...
...to take care of for you?
Anything particular you'd like
to have me say to your folks...
...or to Myra?
l guess l've written
about all l had to say.
Sorry l couldn't do more
for the squadron.