TO BE OR NOT TO BE
Lubinski, Kubinski...
Lominski, Rozanski and Poznanski.
We're in Warsaw, the capital of Poland.
It's August, 1939. Europe is still at peace.
At the moment, life in Warsaw
is going on as normally as ever.
But suddenly,
something seems to have happened.
Are those Poles seeing a ghost?
Why does this car suddenly stop?
Everybody seems to be staring
in one direction.
People seem to be frightened,
even terrified. Some flabbergasted.
Can it be true? It must be true. No doubt.
The man with the little mustache,
Adolf Hitler.
Adolf Hitler in Warsaw
when the two countries are still at peace...
and all by himself?
He seems strangely unconcerned
by all the excitement he's causing.
Is he by any chance interested
in Mr. Maslowski's delicatessen?
That's impossible! He's a vegetarian.
And yet,
he doesn't always stick to his diet.
Sometimes he swallows whole countries.
Does he want to eat up Poland, too?
Anyhow, how did he get here?
What happened?
It all started in the General Headquarters
of the Gestapo in Berlin.
Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler!
- Colonel, we have Wilhelm Coetze here.
If you'd like to look into his record.
I hope he'll talk!
- He'd better.
Send him in.
- Yes, sir.
Wilhelm Coetze!
Heil Hitler!
- Heil Hitler!
And now, Wilhelm, I understand
you want a little tank to play with.
Yes, my father promised me one
if I got a good report card.
But our Fuhrer
heard about your report card...
and decided to give you
just what you want.
Heil Hitler!
- Heil Hitler!
You are going to tell your father
who gave it to you, aren't you, Wilhelm?
Sure, our Fuhrer.
And then maybe he will like the Fuhrer
a little better, won't he?
Sure.
He doesn't like him now, does he?
- No, he doesn't.
And sometimes he even says funny things
about him, doesn't he?
Well, he said they named a brandy
after Napoleon...
and they made a herring out of Bismarck.
And Hitler's going to end up as...
- A piece of cheese.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
How did you know?
- Well, it's a natural thought.
A natural thought?!
I hope you don't misunderstand.
I always, that is...
You see, Colonel,
I hope you don't doubt my...
Heil Hitler!
The Fuhrer!
Heil myself.
That's not in the script!
But, Mr. Dobosh, please.
- That's not in the script, Mr. Bronski.
But it'll get a laugh.
- I don't want a laugh here.
How many times have I told you
not to add any lines?
I want...
- You want my opinion, Mr. Dobosh?
No Mr. Greenberg, I don't
want your opinion.
All right, then let me give you my reaction.
A laugh is nothing to be sneezed at.
Mr. Greenberg, I hired you as an actor,
not as a writer. Understand?
No. What does the script say?
I make an entrance.
- And what do you say?
Nothing.
- Then say nothing.
Here am I sitting, waiting for my scene,
all eager to go...
and I have to wait and wait
to be driven out of my mood...
just because two little actors in the cast
want to enlarge their parts.
Mr. Rawitch, what you are, I wouldn't eat.
How dare you call me a ham!
Folks, I want everybody
to understand this.
This is a serious play,
a realistic drama...
Good morning, Dobosh.
- Good morning.
How do you like my dress?
- Very good. Very good.
It is a document of Nazi...
Is that what you're wearing
in the concentration camp?
Don't you think it's pretty?
- That's just it.
Well, why not?
I think it's a tremendous contrast.
Think of me being flogged in the darkness.
I scream, the lights go on...
and the audience sees me on the floor
in this gorgeous dress.
That's a terrific laugh.
- That's right, Greenberg.
You keep out of this!
That a great star, an artist,
could be so inartistic.
You must be out of your mind!
What do you mean by talking to my wife
like that? How dare you!
I'm sorry. I lost my temper.
Sweetheart, the dress stinks.
You're only afraid
I'm running away with the scene.
I afraid? Why should I be?
Of course not.
You're the best actor in the world.
Everybody knows that, even you.
- Don't be a prima donna.
Any chance to take the spotlight away
from me, it's ridiculous how you grab it.
Whenever I start a story, you finish it.
Should if I go on a
diet, you lose the weight.
If I have a cold, you cough.
And if we should ever have a baby,
I'm not so sure I'd be the mother.
I'm satisfied to be the father.
Mr. Dobosh, look,
if you'll just give me a chance...
Who made you up?
- I did, Mr. Dobosh.
What's wrong with it?
- I don't know. It's not convincing.
To me, he's just a man
with a little mustache.
But so was Hitler.
Wait, it's not just the mustache.
It's... I don't know.
I just can't smell Hitler in him.
- I can.
I know! I know!
That picture!
That's what he should look like!
But that picture was taken of me.
Then the picture's wrong, too.
Now, see here, Mr. Dobosh,
I'm a nobody and I have to take a lot.
But I know I look like Hitler,
and I'm going to prove it right now.
I'm going out on the street
and see what happens.
And that's how Adolf Hitler
came to Warsaw in August, 1939.
May I have your autograph, Mr. Bronski?
Bronski?
- Why, certainly.
Jospeh Tura i Maria Tura
in "Hamlet"
I know it would get a laugh.
Then Dobosh said to me,
"Bronski, you're going to play Hitler."
I thought that was the real start
of my career.
Don't worry, Bronski.
They can't keep real talent down forever.
And the day will come
when you'll play Shylock.
The Rialto scene.
Shakespeare must have thought of me
when he wrote this. It's me.
"Have I not eyes? Have I not hands...
"organs, senses, dimensions,
affections, passions?
"Fed with the same food,
hurt with the same weapons...
"subject to the same diseases.
"If you prick us, do we not bleed?
"If you tickle us, do we not laugh?
"if you poison us,...
do we not die?"
You'd move them to tears.
Instead, I have to carry a spear.
That's all we do, carry a spear.
Carry a spear in the first act,
and in the second act.
Carry Rawitch off the scene in the last act.
How I'd love to drop that ham
right in the center of the stage.
Would get a terrific laugh.
Hello, this is Mr. Tura.
Will you please order me a salami and
cheese sandwich and a glass of beer.
Right away, please. Thank you.
The audience is a little cool tonight.
- Not to me.
I know I'm giving a rotten performance.
I always do when we quarrel.
Say something nice.
- You faker.
I watched your scene with Polonius.
You were never better.
I'd give you a kiss right now,
but I'm afraid I'll ruin my makeup.
Darling, you were right this morning.
I felt so rotten after the rehearsal,
I went to Dobosh and told him...
when he advertises the new play
to put your name first.
Did you, darling? That's sweet of you.
But I really don't care.
That's what Dobosh said,
so we left it as it was.
But, darling,
you know how I feel about you.
Why I'd even...
Flowers?
- Aren't they beautiful?
Don't be casual. Who sent them?
I don't know. There was no card.
No card again? That's three nights
in succession. Who is he?
I'm sure this has nothing to do
with me personally.
This man probably loves theater,
an art fanatic.
Someone sitting in the gallery
night after night...
Just one of those poor boys
who can't afford a ticket...
but inherited a lot of flowers
and is trying to get rid of them.
Three nights in a row.
Even Shakespeare couldn't see Hamlet
three nights in succession.
You forget you're playing Hamlet.
- That's right.
Mr. Tura on stage!
Maria, darling,
I'm going into my big scene.
Joseph, sweetheart,
I swear I don't know who it is.
Thanks, darling.
It's true, Anna, I don't know who it is.
But I'm positive who it might be.
You mean that young aviator?
- Yes, he's very young.
He's in the second row again.
He gets better-looking every night.
Don't misunderstand me.
I love my husband dearly, and why not?
He's wonderful.
Only he gets so unreasonable,
so upset about little things.
Like the little thing in the second row.
Waiting for an answer.
"Lt. Stanislav Sobinski."
I was right, it is a young aviator.
Is he suffering very much?
- Yes, he had to break his silence.
He couldn't bear it any longer?
- No, he couldn't.
Poor little thing.
- He's just a mere boy.
Oh, no. - What's he want
you to do, adopt him?
He's dying to see me,
even if it's just for a minute.
Of course I won't. Definitely not.
Yet, I don't like to be rude to him.
I think it's a mistake to ignore people
who admire one and buy the tickets...
Darling, don't waste any more time
with excuses.
If you want to see him,
see him while he's still young.
Yes, I think I owe it to my public.
Dear Lieutenant...
Wait till you see him, Anna.
Unfortunately my time
is completely taken up.
But if you insist on seeing me,
come back to my dressing room...
when Hamlet goes into his soliloquy,
"To be or not to be."
How does it sound?
- Safe.
"O heavy burden!"
"I hear him coming.!
"Let's withdraw, my lord."
"To be, or not to be.."
"That is..."
"That is the question."
"Whether 'tis nobler in the mind to suffer"
"The slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune...
"Or to take arms..."
Thank you, Mrs. Tura, for receiving me.
If you knew how I was looking forward
to this moment...
And now you're probably disappointed.
- Mrs. Tura.
Please sit down.
- Thank you.
So you are the gentleman that sent me
those lovely flowers. Thank you.
Somehow, I pictured you quite differently
as a dignified old gentleman.
And now I see you...
I wonder if it was the right thing
to ask you back here.
You see, I never see strangers
in my dressing room.
But you are no stranger to me.
I've seen you in everything you've played.
I'll never forget how I laughed
when I saw you as Kiki.
Some people thought I was funny.
But you certainly weren't funny
when you played Lady Macbeth.
Thank you.
- I was really scared of you that night.
Of poor little me? I wouldn't hurt a fly.
Or a goldfish. By the way, how is he?
Who? - The goldfish.
What goldfish?
- The one you're so attached to.
You see, I read all your interviews.
Oh, yes, of course.
When I saw that picture of you
at the farm, behind the plough...
By the way, where was that?
- In The Chronicle.
No, I mean, where is the farm?
No, I think we've talked
much too much about me.
Tell me about yourself.
There isn't much to tell.
I just fly a bomber.
How perfectly thrilling.
I don't know about its being thrilling,
but it's quite a bomber.
You may not believe it, but I can drop
three tons of dynamite in two minutes.
Really?
- Does that interest you?
It certainly does.
I don't want to overstep myself,
but I'll take a chance.
Would you permit me
to show you my plane?
Maybe.
- When shall I call for you?
Tomorrow at 2:00 at my home.
No, I'd better meet you
right at the airport.
Goodbye.
I hope you forgive me
if I acted a little clumsy...
but this is the first time
I ever met an actress.
Lieutenant, this is the first time
I've ever met a man...
who could drop three tons of dynamite
in two minutes. Bye.
Bye.
Tomorrow at 2:00,
I'm gonna look down on Warsaw.
He's gonna take me up
10,000 feet in the air.
There's nothing wrong in that, is there?
No, not at all.
As long as Tura doesn't find out.
After all, what a husband doesn't know
won't hurt his wife.
It happened.
What every actor dreads.
What, darling? What?
Someone walked out on me.
Tell me, Maria, am I losing my grip?
Of course not, darling. I'm so sorry.
But he walked out on me.
Maybe he didn't feel well.
Maybe he had to leave.
Maybe he had a sudden heart attack.
I hope so.
- lf he stayed, he might have died.
Maybe he's dead already.
Darling, you're so comforting.
What's going on?
- Hitler's speaking to the Reichstag.
How do you do, Mr. Dobosh?
- How do you do, Doctor?
This is Dr. Voyawski
from the Foreign Office.
How do you do, gentlemen?
I'm afraid I have some bad news for you.
The government feels it would be unwise
to go on with this play.
What?
You mean, we cannot open tonight?
I'm afraid that's what it comes down to.
- But why?
We all have a right to know.
- I know the play has artistic value.
It has much more than that.
That's exactly what the government
is afraid of.
It might offend Hitler.
Well, wouldn't that be too bad.
Have you ever read what he says
about us? Do you ever listen to him?
I'm sorry, gentlemen,
but the order is final.
Joseph Tura and Maria Tura
GESTAPO
CHANGE OF PROGRAM
Tonight "HAMLET"
"To be, or not to be."
"That is..."
"That is the question!"
"Whether 'tis nobler in the mind"
"To suffer the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune..."
Anna, I'd like to speak to
Mrs. Tura alone.
Now look, Stanislav, I usually
tell my maid when to leave the room.
I have so much to tell you.
When we're in the plane, we can't talk.
When we're in the tearoom,
we can't do anything but talk.
When we're in the dressing room,
we must be very careful of my makeup.
You know, Maria,
the other day in the plane...
you didn't think I was watching
but I saw you looking at me.
It was a very sympathetic look, I thought.
I had the feeling you like me.
Was I wrong?
No, not at all, Stanislav.
Tell me, Maria. Be
frank. You still like me?
Well, of course.
You still like me, huh?
You think you'll always like me?
I don't see any reason why not.
That's wonderful.
What are we going to do
with your husband?
What?
- We must tell him, of course.
Tell him what?
That we love each other,
that we're mad about each other.
He has no right to stand in our way.
I'm sure he'll realize the situation.
So will Mr. Dobosh.
Dobosh? Where does he come in?
- You don't want to stay on the stage?
I wouldn't let you.
You're tired of it, anyway.
You want to live a quiet life.
You said so in The Chronicle.
Darling, you're really
going to enjoy that farm now.
You won't have to use that plough.
I'll buy you a tractor.
I'll build a swimming pool
for your goldfish.
You're really a darling...
but you don't realize
that I'm a married woman.
That's why I must talk to your husband.
But I love my husband.
No, you don't.
You're just decent, you're kind,
and you feel sorry for him.
Now, don't you worry.
It's a situation between men.
I'll wait here for him.
Stanislav, you must listen to me.
This is probably all my fault,
but you must understand that l...
Mrs. Tura!
- Stay out, Anna.
Mrs. Tura, it's war!
"Without any declaration of war...
"German troops crossed our border
at several points this evening."
Without a word of warning.
They'll pay before they're through.
We'll gonna fight them.
War. It's really war.
People are going to kill each
other and be killed.
Stanislav...
Goodbye, Maria.
Maria! Have you heard?
- Yes, it's war.
It seems impossible. It's incredible.
Does the audience know yet?
- No, I have to make an anouncement.
It's a conspiracy. That's it!
A foul conspiracy!
It's worse than that. It's a crime!
- You're absolutely right.
Walking out on me for the second time.
What are you talking about?
- Don't you understand? It's war!
It's an air alarm!
Close the window!
Hurry up, to the basement. Quick!
Anyway, we don't have to worry
about the Nazi play anymore.
The Nazis themselves are putting on
the show now. A much bigger one.
There's no censor to stop them.
Unhappy Poland.
Attacked without a word of warning
by a ruthless conqueror.
Warsaw destroyed
for the sake of destruction.
The curtain had fallen
on the Polish drama.
A tragedy with no relief in sight.
There was a Nazi tank
against every Polish hope...
and the people were
stunned and helpless.
There was no censor to stop them.
"If you prick us,
do we not bleed?
"If you tickle us,
do we not laugh?
"If you poison us,
do we not die?"
What a Shylock you would have been.
All I had to do was to carry a spear.
I wonder if we'll ever
carry a spear again.
Let's hope so.
But a new spirit had come over
the people of Poland.
Hate and more hate
was the answer to the Nazi terror.
Rebellion against suppression.
Determination to fight at any moment,
anywhere, everywhere.
The battle was on. "V."
"V" for "victory!"
Down with the Nazis!
Down with Hitler!
The Warsaw underground striking back...
sabotage, destruction.
But the real fight for Polish freedom
was led somewhere in England.
Young men of Poland
avenging their country...
the Polish squadron of the RAF.
Well, it's gratifying to see that
you still keep your sense of humor.
We are even much funnier over Berlin.
I only wish that I were young enough
to do for our country what you're doing.
Come on, Professor. One of your
radio speeches is worth 10,000 bombs.
When do we hear you again,
Professor Siletsky?
I'm afraid it might be
quite some time.
Why? What's the matter?
Nothing. I just happen to be going
on a little trip.
And anybody that buys a return ticket
these days is decidedly an optimist.
You are going
on a secret mission, Professor?
I see it's no use.
You boys are too clever for me.
Now I know. He's going
to Berlin to call on Hitler.
Not exactly. And I certainly hope that
Hitler doesn't call on me.
Well gentlemen, thank you for
honoring me with an excellent dinner.
Professor, are you going to Warsaw?
- That would be risking your neck.
After all, you boys risk your lives
every day, don't you?
So you are going to Warsaw.
Gentlemen, please, I
can't tell you any more.
I'm sorry that I even mentioned it.
But you didn't.
- We got it out of you.
After all, if I can't trust you,
whom can I trust?
And I know it will be buried right here.
Warsaw.
I'd give my soul to be there
for just one hour to see my mother.
If she's still alive.
I only wish it were possible
for me to find out.
Could you find out, please? My mother...
I understand exactly how you feel.
But you must realize...
I cannot possibly jeopardize
the purpose of my trip.
Why don't you tell me
where I can reach your people...
and I'll try my best?
Professor Siletsky? - Yes.
My people are fortunately
out of Poland...
but there is someone in Warsaw.
A lady? - Yes.
It's a very confidential matter.
I'd appreciate it if you'd tell her...
But don't tell her husband.
Now, I know exactly what to tell her.
Just say, "To be or not to be."
She knows.
A code message?
What's the name of the lady?
It's Maria Tura.
- Just a moment. I'll write it down.
What did you say the name was?
Maria Tura.
- T-U-R-A. That's right?
Don't tell me you've never
heard of Maria Tura?
Why? Should I?
Well, you lived in Warsaw...
Yes, of course. The name is familiar.
She's quite well-known.
Well-known? She's famous.
- Yes, indeed.
Here, it's the name of my brother.
I don't know if you
can read the writing.
MILITARY INTELIGENCE
V
- All right.
- Lieutenant.
- How do you do, sir?
- Gen. Armstrong.
Major Cunningham.
- How do you do?
Now what did you want
to see me about, Lieutenant?
I was thinking about coming here
for a couple of days.
I'm probably doing an injustice
to an important man.
Whom do you suspect?
You see, sir, the other night...
Professor Siletsky was addressing us
at the camp...
and I mentioned the name of Maria Tura
and he'd never heard of her.
Neither have I.
But he's supposed to be
a Pole who lived in Warsaw.
She's the most famous
actress in Warsaw.
Young man, there are lots of people
who are not interested in the theater.
In matter fact, there's only
one actress I ever heard of.
And I certainly hope
I'll never hear from her again.
Sir, Maria Tura's more than an actress.
She's an institution.
You couldn't buy a newspaper
without reading about her.
You can't buy a package of cigarettes
without her picture inside.
They name soap after her.
You couldn't move around in Warsaw
without popping into her.
I thought it was my duty to tell you
before the professor leaves.
He left already, didn't he?
- Yes, he was due in Sweden yesterday.
Just a minute.
How'd you know he was leaving?
He told us.
- Told you what?
That he was going to Warsaw.
- That seems incredible.
After all, we were all Poles together,
nobody saw anything wrong in it.
Otherwise, the boys wouldn't
give him the addresses.
What addresses?
- Of the relatives in Warsaw.
He took them?
- Yes, sir.
How could he do such a thing?
If they fall into the hands
of the Gestapo...
they can take reprisals
against all the families.
When does Professor Siletsky
get to Warsaw?
He probably took the boat
today for Lithuania.
And from Lithuania, that's uncertain.
I shall say, three or four days, sir.
How long will it take you
to fly to Warsaw?
About ...six or seven hours, sir.
You mind waiting outside a minute?
- Yes, sir.
I hate to believe it.
So do I, sir. We can't take any chances.
The fellow came here with
the highest recommendations possible.
And we checked again and again, sir.
This man is carrying instructions
to the underground in Warsaw.
If he delivers them...
to the Gestapo
instead of the underground...
it means, not only the death
of hundreds of people...
but the destruction of our organization
in Eastern Europe.
Of course. But I hate to condemn a man
on such vague evidence.
We're not condemning him.
When Siletsky told those fliers of his trip
to Warsaw, he wrote his own sentence.
Of course, he may be just a fool.
Then he's just as dangerous.
And I know Siletsky. He's no fool.
Well, sir, what are your orders?
Call in the young man.
- Yes, sir.
Now look here, Lieutenant...
as soon as you get to Warsaw...
go to Sztaluga 's bookstore...
and give him our instructions.
Sztaluga will then inform
the underground.
But if someone happens to be in the store,
don't mention anything.
Just ask for a copy
of Tolstoy's Anna Karenina.
And put Siletsky's picture on Page 105.
Now, is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
Ten minutes.
- All right.
Halt!
Too bad we missed him.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
Have you by any chance
Anna Karenina by Tolstoy?
I think I have.
Yes.
Here it is.
How much is it?
- 20 zloty.
That's much too expensive, I'm sorry.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
We'll take these stamps.
- How much?
Eight zloty 75.
Goodbye, gentlemen. Come again.
Professor Alexander Siletzki
- arrives in two days.
Monitor Railway station.
Gestapo cannot reach-otherwise
catastrophe. Take in
contact as soon as possible.
Yes, can I help you gentlemen?
We are looking for Mrs. Maria Tura.
- I am Mrs. Tura.
You have to come along with us.
I haven't done anything.
Why do they want me?
Just come along. Let's go.
205, 206.
Mrs. Tura is here, sir.
Yes, sir.
Let her wait in 206.
- Yes, sir.
Good evening, Mrs. Tura.
Good evening.
- I'm Professor Siletsky.
It's a great pleasure to meet you,
Mrs. Tura.
Won't you sit down?
Cigarette?
- Thank you.
I really must apologize for the manner
in which you were brought here.
When a man wants to see a lady
so badly...
he backs up his invitation with bane.
It's rather flattering.
That's very well put.
As a matter of fact, I'm not responsible
for your being brought here at all.
There's a charming young
man in England...
Gave me a message for you.
A rather strange message.
"To be or not to be."
You, no doubt know
its deeper meaning.
Yes, I have a vague idea.
I really...
Will you forgive me, please?
Hello? Yes?
How do you do,
Colonel Ehrhardt?
Yes, the trip was a little bumpy...
but I'm certainly glad that you sent
that plane to Sweden. Otherwise...
Whenever you wish, of course.
10:00 tomorrow morning
at Gestapo Headquarters
unless I hear from you tonight.
Very well.
I'm looking forward
to making your acquaintance.
Goodbye, Colonel.
I'm sorry.
- Well, I won't keep you any longer.
Thank you for the charming message.
- Mrs. Tura, you're an actress, aren't you?
- Yes.
Naturally, in the theater it's important
that you choose the right part.
Very.
But in real life, it's even more important
that you choose the right side.
The right side?
What is the right side?
The winning side.
I don't quite understand.
Here in Warsaw, there are a lot of people...
that we know very well
and a lot of people...
that we don't know quite so well and
would like to know a great deal better.
That's where you can help us, Mrs. Tura.
You want me to be a spy?
Now, come, that's rather a crude word.
I once played a spy,
it was a great success.
I had wonderful notices.
It was really an exciting part.
Wouldn't it be exciting
to play it in real life?
I got shot in the last act.
I suppose that happens to most spies.
My dear Mrs. Tura,
we would never dream of
subjecting anybody as
charming as you to danger.
All you'd have to do
would be to entertain a little.
For instance, invite certain people...
I can see myself giving a great banquet
in my one-room mansion.
Of course, they took my lovely
apartment away from me.
I assure you that can be
very easily remedied.
Life could be made...
very comfortable for
you again, Mrs. Tura.
Well. What do you say?
Naturally, it's all very attractive
and tempting.
But what are we going to do
about my conscience?
We've simply got to convince you
that you're going to serve the right cause.
I wonder if you really know
what Nazism stands for.
I have a slight idea.
In the final analysis, all we're trying to do
is create a happy world.
People who don't want to be happy
have no place in this happy world.
That makes sense.
We're not brutal,
we're not monsters.
Tell me...do I look like a monster?
Of course not, Professor.
You say that as though
you really meant it.
I do.
- We're just like other people.
We love to sing, we love to dance...
We admire beautiful women.
We're human. And sometimes...
- very human.
- I'm convinced of that.
Why don't you stay here for dinner?
I can imagine nothing more charming.
And before the evening is over,
I'm sure you'll say, "Heil Hitler."
I would like to accept your invitation,
but just as you want to represent
the Nazi case in the very best light...
I would like to represent the Polish case
in a more suitable dress.
I understand perfectly.
Please don't let me wait too long.
Au revoir.
- Just a moment.
I'm looking forward to it.
- So am I.
This lady is permitted to leave.
- Yes, sir.
This is a very difficult place to get in,
but it's much more difficult to get out.
I'm terribly frightened
and terribly thrilled.
Bye.
- Bye.
"To be or not to be."
I'm feeling much better.
I'm glad at that.
Who are you? How did you get here?
Parachute. I jumped from a plane.
Right into my bed?
How did you get into my apartment?
Your wife...
Isn't she back? I'm getting worried.
You're worried? I'm worried!
Not so loud, you
might endanger all of us.
After all, we're all in the same boat.
- Oh, the same boat?
Then let me ask you something
as one sailor to another:
What ill-wind blew you
into my slippers?
Siletsky is here!
- What?!
At the Hotel "Europe".
Just when I came to
the book store, they took me to him.
What'd you do at the book store?
- I warned them against Siletsky!
Siletsky here. Then everything's over.
There's still one little chance,
Siletsky hasn't seen the Gestapo.
Well, not untill morning.
- We have to get to him.
That's impossible. It's like an
armed camp. Soldiers everywhere.
Why did he send for you?
Does he know I'm here?
No, but believe or not, he wants
me to become a Nazi spy.
Who wants you to become a Nazi spy?
- Siletsky.
Who is Siletsky?
- A spy!
And who is he?
- Lieutenant Sobinski.
What are you doing here?
What does that matter?
Don't you understand? Siletsky's here.
It's unbelievable!
I come home to find a man
in the same boat with me...
and my wife says,
"What does it matter?"
But Mr. Tura, it's a zero hour.
You simply don't want me to waste time
giving you a long explanation.
No, but I think a husband is
entitled to an inkling.
All right. Siletsky wants me to have
dinner with him...
and if we don't get another idea,
I hate to think but,
maybe I'll have to kill him myself,
because only I can get to him.
You see, this all wouldn't
have happened
if Lieutenant arrived
before Siletsky.
But they sent a plane for Siletsky,
so he arrived before the Lieutenant.
Now, is that clear?
- No.
So, You're gonna have dinner with him?
That's our only chance!
Wait a minute.
I'll decide with whom my wife has dinner
and whom she'll kill.
Don't you realize, Poland's at stake?
Have you no patriotism?
Now, listen you...
First, you walk out of my soliloquy,
and then you walk into my slippers.
And now you question my patriotism.
I'm a good Pole.
I love my country and my slippers!
I hope your country comes first.
- So do I!
This is an emergency...
- Look...
I don't know much about
the whole thing,
but is this Siletsky a
real danger to Poland?
A catastrophe!
- He must be taken care of.
And he will be taken care of.
- Who's going to do it?
I'm going to do it.
- But how? - Where?
I'm going to meet Herr Siletsky
at Gestapo Headquarters.
And after I've killed him,
I hope you tell me what it was all about.
It took a bit longer than I thought,
I wonder if the effect was worth it.
I'm willing to die for our
Fuhrer at any moment.
Except for the next few hours.
- Thank you, Professor.
The last time I wore this gown...
It seems like ages.
And I haven't seen such food.
Caviar, it still exists.
Yes. On the winning side.
I must admit, you put some very
convincing arguments on this table.
It's nice being here, Professor.
I ordered a buffet. We don't want to be
interrupted by orderlies.
Naturally. After all, this isn't a fair State.
The best thing is to start
your training as an agent...
with a glass of champagne.
Shall we drink to a Blitzkrieg?
I prefer a slow encirclement.
You know, Professor,
I'm a little scared of you.
But why? You shouldn't be.
Maybe not. Maybe there's something
very gentle under that beard of yours.
I think you might have a boyish quality,
and yet I don't know.
Why don't you find out?
- I will.
Here, write your name
and I'll tell you everything about you.
The first time I saw
my husband's handwriting...
was on the marriage certificate,
then it was too late.
If you prefer... I'm
taking an awful chance.
But remember, if a fortune-teller
wants to stay in business...
she must only tell her client
what he really wants to hear.
Professor, if I'd known you made an "S"
like that, I wouldn't have come here.
You're a very determined man.
- Yes. Very.
But you have great charm, yes.
I only hope you live up
to that "Y," Professor.
You'll see.
Heil Hitler.
I am Capt. Muhm,
Colonel Ehrhardt's staff.
Please, come in.
Just a moment.
I'm sorry, there's been
a change in Colonel Ehrhardt's plans.
He'd like to see you immediately.
Yes, of course.
I'll be with you in a minute.
I'm so sorry.
- Don't tell me you have to leave.
Yes, but I'll make it as quickly as possible.
That's terrible. I came up here
with such doubts in my mind...
and now you're going to leave me here
just as the cause is getting me.
I won't be long.
Gestapo is so busy these days,
I'm sure they'll be glad to get rid of me.
I'm so sorry.
- Well, it can't be helped.
Just a moment.
What's your name?
Mrs. Tura.
- Whom were you visiting?
Professor Siletsky.
I'm sorry. Professor
left no instructions.
You'll have to wait until
he comes back.
But that's impossible.
Sorry. There is nothing I can do about it.
206. - Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Wait one moment, I'll announce you
to Colonel Ehrhardt.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye, Colonel.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Isn't this the gentleman
from England, Captain?
Yes, General. - It's a great pleasure
to meet you, Professor.
A very great pleasure.
You certainly fooled the English,
didn't you?
The British lion will drink his tea...
from saucers made in Germany.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
How did he ever become a general?
He's Gring's brother-in-law.
I'll announce you to the Colonel.
- Thank you.
He brought the papers with him.
Now remember.
Who were his helpers in England?
Soon as you find out call me,
I'll do the rest. - All right.
Now look Tura, you're playing for our lives.
- I know.
I'm going to do the impossible.
I'm going to surpass myself.
Don't. Take it easy and don't draw out
the scene please. Come on, let's go.
I hate to leave the fate of my country
in the hands of a ham.
Send him in.
Professor, please.
- Thank you.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Professor Siletsky, I'm glad to see you.
And I'm glad to see you, too.
Sit down, please.
- Thank you very much.
I can't tell you how delighted
we are to have you.
May I say, my dear Colonel,
that it's good
to breathe the air of
the Gestapo again.
You know, you're quiet famous
in London, Colonel.
They call you
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt.
Yes. We do the concentrating,
and the Poles do the camping.
Yes, indeed. Well, here's the report...
and that's the end
of the underground movement.
Let's see this.
Excellent. Excellent.
They're as good as dead.
I assume, there are no supplementary
documents still at the hotel.
No, that covers everything.
- Good.
And I'm sending the duplicate to Berlin
the first thing in the morning.
The duplicate?
Yes, of course, the duplicate.
If you ask me, it's a lot of red tape.
But since they want it, well, all right.
Naturally. You know, Professor...
Warsaw is a dangerous place these days.
But I suppose you have the papers
in the hotel safe?
No, they're locked in my trunk.
The whole hotel is a safe.
Yes, of course. Naturally.
I want to get the machinery started
on this report right away.
I'll be back in a moment.
- Very well.
All right, I'll get this wrapped up.
- No. He still has papers in his trunk.
Papers in his trunk?
I'll kill that dirty dog any how.
How are we going to
get into his hotel?
Get back there and keep him there.
We'll try to figure something out.
Alright.
Colonel, is there anything else
you want to ask me?
Lots. Sit down, Professor.
There are many things
I want to ask you.
So many things.
Anything you want to know,
I'd only be too happy to oblige.
Thank you.
So they call me
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt?
Yes. You know, Professor...
there's something I
wanted to ask you.
Yes?
That's the way it is.
A thousand questions on your mind...
yet you can't think of anything to ask.
But it will crystallize.
Maybe there's something
you like to ask me?
No, I can't think of anything, Colonel.
So they call me
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt.
Well. Excuse me a minute,
I'll be right back.
I'm running out of dialogue.
- We got it.
Here, check this gun.
Put it in your pocket.
Now, you take him
back to the hotel.
As soon as you're in his room,
hit his head with the butt of the gun.
Then, take his keys, open his
trunk and burn the papers.
And then you shoot him.
- All right. Just a minute.
What'll happen to me? They'll kill me.
We're going to keep our fingers crossed.
- Good.
Wait a minute.
You go to the hotel
and I'll cross my fingers.
Here, think of something else.
So they really call me
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt?
Colonel, unless there's something urgent,
I'd like to relax a little.
Relax? Oh, Mrs. Tura.
Tell me, how is Mrs. Tura?
Sit down, Professor.
You see, my Gestapo men
are very efficient.
I simply thought she might be
of some value to us as an agent.
And besides that,
she's very good company.
Very good company?
Colonel, if you'd like to meet Mrs. Tura,
I'd be glad to introduce you.
Well, thank you.
And if you should happen
to take a liking to the lady...
Maybe you'll even put in
a good word for me?
I'd be delighted.
Well, thank you.
Thank you.
Tell me, hasn't she a husband?
- Yes, but what does it matter?
Yes, what does it?
By the way, I believe her husband
is that great Polish actor...
Joseph Tura.
Of course, you've heard of him?
No, I haven't.
As a matter of fact, I never even heard
of Maria Tura before, either.
You didn't?
Then how did you get in touch with her?
It's rather a delicate story.
There's a young Polish flier in England.
I think his name is Sobinski.
Asked me to deliver a
message to her.
Well, that's very interesting.
What was the message?
I had to swear to this young Romeo
not to tell the husband.
That gives you a rough idea
of the message.
Yes.
It is a little rough.
- Seems they have a secret love code.
Am I boring you?
- No, I find it very interesting.
This young flier gave me the message,
and I couldn't make head nor tail of it...
and neither will you. But Mrs. Tura
seemed to understand it perfectly.
Well, what was the message?
"To be or not to be."
- To be...
To be or not to be!
- Colonel, it's nothing alarming.
It's only Shakespeare.
- That's what you think.
Professor Siletsky, you amaze me.
You, a Gestapo man, bringing a message
to a Polish woman from the enemy.
And when I say enemy,
I mean enemy!
You think they had a romance?
I couldn't swear to it,
but I don't doubt it. Do you?
No! And I'm going to find out
if I have to mobilize the whole Gestapo.
But, Colonel, I don't understand...
suppose these two did have a romance,
that's nothing you have to worry about.
The only person that has to worry
is the husband. That's all.
And that's enough!
I'm going to arrest this Maria Tura.
I guess you're right, Professor.
I've been with the Gestapo so long...
I get suspicious of everyone.
- And so do I.
So they call me
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt.
Coming back to Mrs. Tura.
- Let's forget about her.
There's nothing mysterious about her,
she's just a cheap, little...
I think I know what you mean.
Then I don't have to say it, do I?
Do you mind if I'm repetitious,
Colonel Ehrhardt?
Why? No, not at all.
As I said before, Colonel Ehrhardt...
the only one that has to worry
about all this is the lady's husband.
That great Polish actor,
Joseph Tura.
Well, that's none of my concern.
- But it should be, Mr. Tura.
Raise your hands.
Quickly, please.
Did you ever play a corpse, Mr. Tura?
What?
You're going to be one
unless you do exactly as I say.
Get to the door and tell your friends
to clear away from there.
I won't do it.
Turn around.
Get over there and face that wall.
Now, stay there.
Sure you won't change your mind?
I'll give you one more chance.
Farewell, Mr. Tura.
Long live Poland!
- What happened?
- I don't know, he must have gone out.
There he is!
Get him!
Get backstage. Raise the curtain.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Professor Siletsky?
- Professor Siletsky isn't here.
You expect him back?
- Yes, certainly.
Do you mind if I wait here
for the Professor?
No, not at all.
Thank you.
Good night, Professor Siletsky.
- Good night.
Good night, Professor.
Professor Siletsky?
- Yes?
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
I'm Capt. Schultz
of Colonel Ehrhardt's staff.
Well, I'm glad to meet you, Captain.
Mrs. Tura.
I thought you had left, madame.
You forgot to leave word for me
to get out...
But now I don't regret
that I've waited.
And how is Professor Siletsky?
Dead. Absolutely dead.
I had to take care of some business.
How about a glass of champagne?
No, thank you. I don't drink.
Cigarette?
- Thank you. I don't smoke.
Just like our Fuhrer.
- Yes.
Well, Captain, I'm terribly sorry
to have kept you waiting.
I tried to entertain the Captain,
but he seems to be the suspicious type.
I admit I was a little surprised
when I came in.
And I don't blame you.
Here the whole Gestapo has been working
for a long time, day and night...
trying to find out every little thing
about everybody...
and I arrive, and in a few hours
I find the most attractive lady in town.
You didn't know madame before?
Well, no. Not exactly.
But the explanation is very simple.
I just asked Mrs. Tura here
to deliver a message.
- Isn't that right?
- Yes. Yes!
There's a young flier,
a very good friend of the Turas...
and particularly of Mrs. Tura.
Isn't that right?
Yes. But he's no particular
friend of mine.
Nevertheless, a friend.
It was a code message.
Code message?
Mrs. Tura has nothing to hide
from the Gestapo...
but she has one
tiny little secret.
If her husband ever found out,
he would murder her.
By the way, he is that great
Polish actor, Joseph Tura.
You've probably heard of him?
- No, I haven't.
Professor, Colonel Ehrhardt...
Yes. I'm going to meet him promptly,
10:00 tomorrow morning.
There has been a change
in the Colonel's plans.
You're not going to take him away?
I'm sorry. But the Colonel is
expecting the Professor now.
Those are my orders.
Now...
Well, it looks like I'll have to go.
Excuse me a moment.
Sweetheart.
Darling.
Open the trunk.
Burn all the papers.
All right. What did you do with Siletsky?
- What did you do with Sobinski?
That's unimportant now,
don't you realize...
you're going into the hands
of the Gestapo?
Yes, the scene is
loaded with dynamite.
One little slip and I'm a dead man.
You know I'm never any good
unless I have my peace of mind.
Maria, be honest, be frank.
I've got to know.
Did you tell that fellow
to walk out of my soliloquy?
Sweetheart, darling, I love you.
Don't you know that? Don't you feel it?
If anything happened to you...
You think I can do it?
You're a great actor.
Nobody can play it but you.
You can, and you will do it.
Goodbye, darling.
Goodbye.
If I shouldn't come back,
I forgive what happened
between you and Sobinski.
But if I come back,
it's a different matter.
Yes?
- Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler.
- Professor Siletsky is here.
Have him come in.
Didn't you understand what I told you?
Did you arrest him? Why not?
You have no proof?
Now, that's a fine excuse. Arrest him, too.
Whenever in doubt, arrest him.
How many times do I have to tell you,
arrest him? Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Professor, at last we meet.
Please make yourself at home.
Won't you take off your coat?
Thank you. Thank you.
Colonel Ehrhardt...
I can't tell you how happy I am
to breathe the air of the Gestapo again.
Thank you very much.
Cigarette, cigar, glass of brandy?
No, thank you.
There was a sudden change
in my schedule.
Confidentially, big news.
A very old friend of yours is coming
to Warsaw. The Fuhrer.
I know you will be delighted
to see the Fuhrer again.
Who wouldn't?
- That's right.
How long since you've
seen him, Professor?
Too long. Much too long.
- Of course.
Tell me, is Berchtesgarden
really as beautiful as they say it is?
Yes, I think I can say
that without any risk.
But it isn't the architecture
or the landscaping...
it's the presence of the Fuhrer
that lends the real beauty to the place.
Naturally. Well, what news
you bring from London?
London? Oh, yes, London.
Colonel, you're quiet famous in London.
You know what they call you?
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt.
They do, do they?
So they call me
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt.
I thought you would react just that way.
Well, Professor,
let's have your information.
I think I can stand
a glass of brandy, after all.
Certainly. Brandy.
That makes me think of a very funny story
which is going all over Warsaw.
A story about our Fuhrer.
Now, how does it go?
Yes. They named a brandy after Napoleon.
They made a herring out of Bismarck.
And the Fuhrer's going to end up
as a piece of cheese.
Don't you think it's funny?
No. Neither would the Fuhrer.
I don't believe Adolf Hitler
will go down in history as a delicatessen.
Professor, I was only joking,
just repeating what I heard.
After all, I'll never...
Please don't misunderstand me.
See, I'm loyal. Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Professor, do you intend to tell
the Fuhrer about this?
Why should I ruin you?
- Of course, that's very nice.
I can promise you the Fuhrer
will never hear it from my lips.
My word of honor.
- Thank you.
Please, Professor, if you'd be so kind,
what about the underground movement?
What exactly are your plans?
- You want to know?
Yes, if you don't mind.
I have the key in my hand,
all I have to find is the lock.
It's better having the lock than the key.
How does it sound?
Promising. Most promising.
But tell me, what exactly
do you intend to do?
Well, let's get down to details.
- Yes, if you please.
There are no details. At least, not yet.
The important thing is...
I have the name of the leader
of the whole underground movement.
lf we play our cards right and carefully...
- I understand.
If you watch the shepherd,
you're bound to find the flock.
What's the name of the shepherd?
- Boguslaw Revanski.
Send Capt. Schultz in.
So, they call me
"Concentration Camp" Ehrhardt?
Capt. Schultz,
there's a man in this town...
What's his name?
- Revanski.
You mean, Bogoslov Revanski?
- Yes.
You don't have to worry about him.
- What?
We shot him two days ago.
Revanski shot? I refuse to believe it.
Don't you realize
whom you shot, Capt. Schultz?
I risked mz life to get the key man
of the underground movement...
and just when we were ready...
It's sabotage!
I resent that, Professor.
Why did you shoot him?
We have proof that this man was telling
some outrageous stories about the Fuhrer.
That's no reason to shoot him.
- I agree with you.
At least not right away.
So, you shot Revanski like that.
Would it have been better
to look him over first?
Why don't we look over people
before we shoot them?
I'm sorry, but you signed
the order of execution yourself.
Oh, well, I sign so
many every day.
I can't rely on my own people anymore.
Please, Colonel, maybe we can
still save the situation.
There's one other man.
A possibility. A good possibility.
Maximilian Pietrowski.
Maximilian Pietrowski?
Don't tell me you...
Yes.
Colonel, all I can say is, you can't
have your cake and shoot it, too.
It can't be done.
If they hear about this in England,
they'll give you the Victoria Cross.
I resent that, Professor.
- That's all, Schultz.
Yes, sir.
I didn't like the way Capt. Schultz
shifted the responsibility back to you.
Neither did I. You know,
there's always something wrong
with a man who doesn't drink,
doesn't smoke, or eat meat.
You mean our Fuhrer?
- No, please, Professor.
I hope you won't...
- Why should I ruin you again?
Thank you so much.
I suppose you want to go back
as soon as possible to London.
London? Yes, certainly.
- When did you plan to leave?
I'd like to get out as
soon as possible.
Under the circumstances,
that's best thing.
We have a plane leaving
on Thursday for Sweden.
I'll make a reservation for you.
- That's fine.
You better make that two
reservations. - Two?
See, my trip was successful
in one respect.
I made a discovery.
A certain Mrs. Tura.
She'll be the most valuable assistant
in London I've ever had.
Frankly, I don't believe
in women agents.
But you'll change your mind
if you meet Mrs. Tura.
Why don't you? Form
your own opinion.
If you say "no," it's no.
Alright. I'll call you at the hotel.
What was the lady's name?
- Mrs. Tura.
Her husband is that great
Polish actor, Joseph Tura.
You've probably heard of him?
- Yes.
As in matter of fact, I saw him on the stage
when I was in Warsaw,
once before the War.
Really?
What he did to Shakespeare,
we are doing now to Poland.
Goodbye, Colonel.
- Goodbye, Professor.
Group leader Ehrhardt
1941. Tuesday, 16. December
10:30 Maria Tura
I'm Colonel Ehrhardt.
Will you sit down, please?
Mrs. Tura, I sent for you.
- And I'm very grateful.
I can't make up my mind. Yes,
it sounds very intriguing and exciting...
Mrs. Tura, I have bad news for you.
Well, naturally, If you don't think
I'm the right person...
it will be disappointing,
but the cause must come first.
No, Mrs. Tura. It isn't that.
Prepare yourself for a shock.
Professor Siletsky is dead.
Dead?
- Murdered.
I can't believe it. It can't be.
When did this happen?
- We haven't found out yet.
I only got the report just now.
Was it at the hotel? - No. He was
evidently trapped somewhere.
The Fuhrer has just arrived in Warsaw.
The men are planning a great
reception for him tonight.
A kind of performance by the soldiers.
They opened the Theatre Polski.
They tried to arrange some scenery.
One of the props broke and out fell
the body of Professor Siletsky.
Who could have done such a thing?
Do you have any idea?
We are pretty certain.
You see, the bullet found in his body
came from a British service revolver.
Yesterday, the British landed
someone here by parachute.
So the only mystery left is,
where is this man?
Believe me, we're going to get him.
Well, I hope so.
- My poor Professor.
I had an appointment with him
this afternoon.
He was due here any minute.
Thank you very much. I won't take up
any more of your time. Goodbye.
Mrs. Tura, I want you to know
that your ties with us are not broken.
After all, you might be very valuable to us.
- Thank you.
It doesn't have to be London.
I might have something here in Warsaw.
Colonel, whatever you decide,
if you want me...
Naturally, I would have to know you
a little better.
That is my duty
and if I may say, my pleasure.
That's nice of you, Colonel.
But at the moment...
- It doesn't have to be today.
When you feel a little better,
maybe we can have dinner together.
Why don't you let me know?
- I will.
And don't take it too hard,
little woman.
I'll try not to.
- That's the spirit.
Mrs. Tura seems to be rather upset.
Naturally, it's very unfortunate
what happened to Siletsky.
After all, he died for the Fuhrer.
- Naturally.
Hello. Good morning,
Professor Siletsky. I have...
You will be a little late.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Will you please announce me
to Professor Siletsky?
The Professor left quite a while ago.
- He did? Thank you.
Was Tura here?
- Yeah.
Did he say anything?
- No, he just rushed in...
punched me in the jaw,
and rushed out.
Dobosh, you know what happened?
- Yes. It's all right, Joseph just left.
What do you mean?
- Well, he had some trouble.
Somebody must have grabbed his beard.
Don't worry, I fixed it up and
gave him an extra beard.
Just in case. You never can't
tell with Tura.
He's lost. They found the body in
the theater. They know everything.
What?! - What did you say?
Who opened the theater?
- The Nazis.
Who gave them the key?
- You idiot you, you shut up!
They're gonna kill him.
You've got to do something. Help him.
Rawitch, do something.
Everything is all right.
The Professor is here.
- We will be delighted.
Professor, please.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler. How is the Professor?
- Fine, thank you. How is the Colonel?
- Excellent. May I?
Tell me, Colonel, what was
your impression of Mrs. Tura?
Wonderful.
- I'm glad you feel that way.
Yes, indeed.
This is Capt. Mueller and Lt. Brundt
of our Special Investigation Squad.
Or what we call the Hotfoot Department.
How do you do?
- It's a pleasure.
How do u do? - How do u do?
It's a pleasure, I'm sure.
Professor, I think we should
have a good talk before you leave.
I have to take up a few things
with these gentlemen.
Would you mind stepping into
my living room?
He should have cracked by now.
Give him a little time.
Let him enjoy his goose pimples.
Colonel, do you really prefer
this procedure to our usual methods?
I would say with intellectuals,
the mental approach is more effective...
and much quicker.
But if he shouldn't turn out
to be an intellectual?
Then we try a little physical culture.
I don't want to hurry you,
but do you think it will be much longer?
Did you get bored?
- No, I tried to open up a conversation...
with your friend in there,
but he seems to be dead.
No. Really. Let's go and see.
It looks like murder.
If I'm wrong, Colonel,
please correct me.
There seems to be a slight resemblance
between me and your late friend.
Has that struck you, too?
- Definitely.
I have a terrible suspicion
that one of us must be an impostor.
Now that you mention it,
I think you're right.
Now, just for fun, Colonel, which one of
us do you think is the impostor?
I hope you won't
consider it impolite, Professor...
but there's a general feeling in this room
that it's you. Please forgive me.
Certainly. You mind if I play detective?
Go right ahead, Professor Siletsky.
Thank you.
Edmondson's London.
- The real Siletsky came from London.
The suit was bought in London.
You think it looks bad for me?
- Terrible.
His watch is still running.
Which means he was killed, since the real
Professor Siletsky arrived in...
This really looks bad for me.
I'm liable to get shot.
There's a distinct possibility.
There's no doubt
there was a definite purpose.
He wanted to look like me...
- Or you wanted to look like him.
That's right.
Our hair is cut alike and even the shape
of our beards is somewhat similar.
Not similar. Exactly alike.
How long did you know each other?
- I just meet him here.
Now you're lying. Plain lying.
You must have observed him
for several months.
It takes that long to grow
a beard of that kind.
Very good, Schultz.
- Excellent, Schultz.
Except you forget
I may be wearing a false beard.
Very funny.
No, Professor. I'll tell
you a better story.
Maybe he is wearing a false beard.
- I hardly think so.
Why don't you convince yourself?
Why don't you pull his beard?
I can't do it.
- No, you can't.
Too sensitive. You can murder a man,
kill in cold blood...
but you cannot pull a man's beard!
I can't believe it.
Schultz! How dare you put me in
this position? I can't rely on anybody.
You gave the order yourself...
- Shifting the responsibility on me again?
That's all, Schultz. Bye-bye, gentlemen.
Professor, I don't know how to apologize.
- You were only doing your duty.
If there's a slightest doubt in your mind,
why don't you pull my beard?
Please, Professor. No.
- Come on. Just once.
Don't rub it in. I assure you,
I never believed it for one minute...
but this Schultz...
And, Professor, if you see the Fuhrer...
You'd appreciate it if I didn't tell him.
I won't tell.
- Thank you so much.
Now, the important thing is to get you
to London as quickly as possible.
With Mrs. Tura? - Of course.
Anything you say, Professor.
Get me the airport.
- Where's Colonel Ehrhardt's office?
Heil Hitler. Colonel Ehrhardt?
- Yes, sir.
I'm in charge of the
Fuhrer's Safety Squad.
I ride with the Fuhrer this morning,
and in one hour...
I uncover a plot against his life.
Can't I rely on anyone?
But, General...
- Arrest this man.
No, General.
- This man's an imposter.
Are you crazy?
- He is Professor Siletsky!
Well? What do you have
to say for yourself now?
Here is a man with a beard,
and you didn't even pull it.
I never saw a more gross neglected duty
in my life.
General...
- I've no confidence in you anymore.
I'm taking charge of
this case myself.
There will be a reorganization here,
and your head will not be spared.
And furthermore...!
General, may I remind you of your
appointment with the Fuhrer?
Yes. You'll hear from me.
Take him out!
Piece of cheese?
Schultz!
I had a plane arranged and everything.
But Mr. Rawitch had a
burning desire to act again.
When Mr. Rawitch acts,
someone has to suffer.
Please, Mr. Tura. Forgive me
for trying to save your life.
Who really bust the whole thing up?
If you hadn't been so stupid...
and jealous of your wife.
- I hope it's true.
But it isn't.
- We'll talk about that later.
Friends...
- Romans and countrymen.
We know you want to play Mark Antony,
but that doesn't help us.
In 24 hours, they'll know everything.
Then we're caught like rats in a trap.
Just a moment. Hitler, of course,
will be sitting in the royal box tonight.
You remember two years ago,
we played Murder in The Opera House?
It was a flop.
- It might be again.
But we have to take the chance
to get out of here.
The situation is very similar.
There'll be soldiers in the
corridor guarding Hitler's box.
If we can get them away
for just one second...
That means we need a confusion,
a commotion among the Gestapo.
I have started a commotion
on every Gestapo man I've met.
No, we can't use you.
There'll be no ladies.
But... - Greenberg?
Yes, Mr. Dobosh?
If we can manage that Greenberg
suddenly pops up among the Nazis...
It'll get a terrific laugh.
- No, it won't.
Greenberg, you always wanted to play
an important part.
What do I have to do, Mr. Dobosh?
- lf you don't play it right, we're all lost.
And if you do play it right,
I still can't guarantee anything.
What do I have to do?
- All right, let's rehearse.
How does it look?
- Excellent.
Sobinski, it's time to go.
I'm ready.
Let's see.
Looks all right.
- Yes. He looks very good.
I'll pick you up about 9:00.
- Oh, darling. Goodbye.
If anything should go wrong,
if you shouldn't come back...
Then Sobinski won't come back either.
- Goodbye, darling.
I guess you want to say goodbye.
Go ahead.
This may be the last time
we'll see each other.
I can only say it was wonderful
knowing you, Maria.
Goodbye, Mrs. Tura.
- Goodbye, Mr. Sobinski.
Heil the Fuhrer.
- Heil.
How did you get here?
- I was born here.
What made you decide to die here?
- Him.
What do you want from the Fuhrer?
- What does he want from us?
What does he want from Poland?
Why all this? Why? Why?
"Aren't we human? Have we not eyes?
Have we not hands...
"organs, senses, dimensions,
affections, passions?
"fed with the same food,
hurt with the same weapons...
"subject to the same diseases,
healed by the same means...
"cooled and warmed
by the same winter and summer."
"If you prick us,
do we not bleed?
"if you tickle us,
do we not laugh?
"if you poison us,
do we not die?
"if you wrong us, shall
we not revenge?"
Lieutenants Lange and Schneider.
- Yes, sir.
Take charge of him and bring him to my
headquarters. I want to question him.
Men, I don't want a word to leak out
about this incredible incident.
Who's in charge here?
- I am, sir.
How could this have happened?
I don't know, sir.
- You don't know. That's just it.
That's how you safeguard our Fuhrer.
My Fuhrer, it is my duty
to advise you to leave immediately.
To the airport. We have to make a stop
on the way. I'll tell you where.
Greenberg, he always wanted
to play Shylock.
And he got his chance at last.
And he'll play it again.
Not in the corridor, but on the stage
of the Polski theater.
The railroad station.
- The underground is still alive.
Yes. We saved the underground.
Bronski, now we belong to history.
They might even erect a monument to us.
- They will.
I can see myself sitting on a horse
for the next century.
Yes, and sometimes when...
What's the matter?
- Nothing.
I am such a nervous wreck,
I'm imagining things.
Imagining what? - For a moment
I thought you were wearing a mustache.
I am.
- No, you're not.
Are you crazy?
Where's my mustache?
This is a catastrophe. We've got to find it.
I can't get out without it.
I've got to get Maria.
What did you do with it?
- My mustache!
We got to find it.
Good evening, Mrs. Tura.
I suppose you're surprised to see us?
I'm delighted, gentlemen,
but unfortunately I have an appointment.
We have several things
we want to find out.
Couldn't I see you tomorrow
at your office?
No, I'm sorry. It is very urgent.
The Colonel and I were talking things over.
Mrs. Tura, we consider you a women
of enormous appeal.
Thank you. But what's so very urgent
about that?
It struck me as rather peculiar
why anybody like you could be...
- attracted to Professor Siletsky.
You never can tell
about those things.
For instance, you're
attractive yourself.
Perhaps my taste is a little peculiar.
But I haven't Professor Siletsky's
distinguished beard.
That's what fascinated you so much.
- Yes, it did intrigue me.
Brought out the child in me.
I always felt like pulling it, but I didn't.
What do you mean by that?
- It was a false beard, you know that.
He fooled me and he certainly
fooled you, Colonel.
How do you know all this?
Gen. Von Seidelman.
- What do you know about him?
He asked me to his office,
and I had to answer a million questions.
He thanked me for
the information and...
Gentlemen, do you by any chance
suspect me?
Mrs. Tura...
- General thought everything was all right.
If Gen. Von Seidelman
thinks it's all right, then it is all right.
What are you trying to get me into now?
- Colonel, it was your own idea.
Shifting the responsibility on me again.
Good night, Schultz.
- Good night, Colonel.
This Schultz! Oh, Mrs. Tura, I'm so sorry.
I don't like to be impolite,
but I have an appointment.
Alright. I'll drive you there.
You don't understand. Someone is coming.
Someone is coming here?
- lf he should find you...
I am here on official business.
There is nothing to worry about.
Mrs. Tura, consider yourself
in the arms of the Gestapo.
Colonel, I'm a married woman.
- But you're expecting someone.
- Now I have to stay here.
- But, Colonel...
I have to protect your husband.
No, Colonel, you mustn't do this.
- Mrs. Tura, I'll give you a bracelet.
I confiscated a beautiful one today.
- I don't want a bracelet.
I can make life worth living for you.
I can give you extra butter rations.
I'll give you three eggs a week.
I don't want any eggs.
Colonel, please go.
Maria?
Why didn't you tell me?
- How could I? Don't you understand?
Haven't you any tact?
My Fuhrer!
Schultz!
Gentlemen, the Fuhrer wants to talk
to both of you himself.
The Lieutenant will take the control.
Yes, mein Fuhrer.
- Jump.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
Two very obliging fellows.
Now let's go to England.
First it was Hess, now it's him.
Everybody, a nice smile. Thank you.
And you, Mr. Tura. You played
the real hero in this amazing play.
I did my best and I was very ably
assisted by my colleagues.
Thank you, my friends,
for everything you did.
As little as it may have been.
I am sure England
will want to show its gratitude.
What do you desire most, Mr. Tura?
Well, l...
- He wants to play Hamlet.
After all, we are in the country
of William Shakespeare...
He wants to play Hamlet.
"Than is my deed
to my most painted word.
"O heavy burden!"
"I hear him coming.
Let's withdraw, my Lord."
"To be or not to be."
"That is..."