Yes, sir, I'll give Capt. Nolan your message
soon as he returns.
Get him now.
- Yes, sir.
- Do you hear me?
Get him now!
Oh, boy.
He's pretty burned up, isn't he?
The old man wants to see you, right away.
Oh, God, that's all I need.
Good luck.
Come in.
- Excuse me, sir.
- What's happened?
That was Admiral Dawes on the radio, sir.
- I mean, it was Admiral Dawes personally.
- So?
I told him what you told me, sir...
that you weren't in,
and we were still looking for Lt. Lawson.
- And?
- And that didn't seem to satisfy him, sir.
It doesn't satisfy me, either.
What about Lawson?
- He's nowhere on the base, sir.
- Look off the base.
Send out the Shore Patrol.
Bring him in, I don't care where he is.
Yes, sir. We've done that, sir.
If you've done that,
there's nothing else to tell me, is there?
No, sir, nothing else.
I just thought you'd like to know
what was going on.
Lt. Lawson!
If you're heading for the P.X.,
get us some more beer.
Anybody seen Lt. Lawson?
- Sam, where you going?
- I thought I'd have me a little grub.
- Wanna come?
- No, I ate already.
There he is!
Lt. Lawson!
Capt. Nolan wants to see you right away, sir.
- Who, me?
- That's right, Lieutenant.
Please, sir. Get in.
Yeah, I'll get in.
- What does he wanna see me about?
- I don't know, sir.
See you tonight, girls.
First come, first served.
You can draw straws.
Here we are, sir.
- Keep the meter running, boys.
- Yes, sir.
- The old man wanna see me?
- Boy, does he wanna see you.
- Yes, sir.
- Hi, John.
What's all the excitement?
They said you were looking for me.
Is that right?
By the way...
how'd you make out with that funny broad
at the club last night?
I was under the impression
that the funny broad was with you.
Hell, I brought her, but she really liked you.
That's why I left.
I wouldn't wanna appear ungallant...
but I think I'd just as soon
do without your assistance in that direction.
That's nice.
I thought I was doing you a favor.
Anyway, what's all the panic?
I was just getting ready to eat.
I have a job for you.
What, before I go on leave?
Yes, before you go on leave.
All right, as long as
I'm on that midday plane tomorrow.
Very gracious of you,
but it'll take a little longer than that.
Can't, John.
I got a four-weeks' leave coming.
- Later.
- Later nothing.
High noon tomorrow, I'm on that plane.
I'm gonna be in Frisco Sunday night.
We're flying you out of here this afternoon.
You'll be in the New Hebrides Sunday night.
The New Hebrides?
I've your orders here.
You'll report to a British Combat Unit
on one of the islands.
They need someone who speaks Japanese.
Combat Unit? What's that?
What the hell is that?
First you talk about postponing my leave,
now you're talking about combat?
There are three other officers
in the radio section.
Two of them speak better Japanese than me.
- They are all a lot older than you.
- That's good, they're mature.
But who picked on me?
I did. And it's not a question
of picking on you.
The British are organizing this for us...
and it's gonna involve
a certain amount of physical hardship.
We have to supply the man.
In my opinion, you're the man for the job.
No, John, negative.
Pick Antonelli, he likes all that military crap.
Not me, no.
I'm sending you, Lieutenant.
"Lieutenant"?
I'm Sam, don't you remember?
Sit down.
- Don't be...
- Sit down, Lieutenant.
I have to comply with an instruction
from higher authority.
A lot higher.
In order to do that, I'm obliged to make do
with the best possible personnel I have.
I know you're a long way
from being right for the job...
but only you begin to meet
the physical requirements.
Fortunately, they don't appear
to be concerned about much else.
So pack your things and report
to the Transportation Officer in 25 minutes.
You mentioned a Combat Unit.
I guess that means a bunch of limeys
running around...
playing soldier, getting shot at, right?
You may not remember this
or you may not be aware of it...
but I volunteered for the service
because as a language specialist...
I was gonna get a bar on my shoulder
and be able to sit by a radio...
and eavesdrop on those fiendish Orientals.
If they're gonna change those rules...
I just might have to resign that commission.
That's your privilege.
And if I do...
you'll have to send another officer.
Right?
The order specifies
"Japanese-speaking personnel."
If you resign your commission,
the Navy would be happy to accept it...
and send you out there
as a Seaman Second Class.
Would you like me to arrange that
for you right now?
Yes, sir?
- I can't win, can I?
- No, you can't.
Incidentally, this operation is something
the British are mounting for our benefit...
so it wouldn't hurt to show them courtesy.
- Courtesy?
- That's right.
You'll get along better if you don't
call them "limeys." That kind of thing.
I don't care
whether I get along with them or not.
Listen, you miserable bastard,
I'm not interested in your problems.
We lost two PT boats yesterday
not 2 miles from that bay down there.
I have to spend the rest of this day
writing to folks back in the States.
"Dear Mrs. Smith, a funny thing happened
to your boy last night. He got burnt up."
What shall I tell them?
"Too bad your kid couldn't be a bit smarter.
"If he spoke Japanese, we could've
gotten him a job sitting on his ass.
"When this mission comes along,
he'd say, 'Not me, buddy.'"
Go on, get out of here.
I don't have time for you.
From what I hear, the British
won't have time for your selfish...
I hope they get your goddamn head
shot off for you.
I'm sure we'll get along just fine, sir.
They're gonna love him.
Come on, scram!
- Toss it up, sir.
- You guys aren't in a hurry, are you?
You know something? I don't think
that clown's happy in the service.
Ain't it the living truth.
That bum wouldn't be happy anywhere.
Let's go.
Okay, back it in.
That's it.
A little to the left.
Hi.
- Boat's waiting, sir.
- What boat?
There's your boat, Lieutenant.
Thanks a whole lot.
Have a nice trip, Lieutenant.
Left, left, left, right, left!
Makes me a bloody foolish sight.
That's what.
Right, left! Keep those arms up.
Water's hard enough to come by.
Wash out those water barrels!
Get them off my square!
Keep those arms free, keep those heads up!
Go and get that man in the rear
or I'll keep dragging you all day!
Get those water barrels off my square!
Okay, bookie's off the course. No more bets.
Ready, set, go!
Connolly.
Your bleeding horse
is being left at the post.
That's not fair, Tosh!
Why not?
My jockey's only using his whip, ain't he?
If your bloke
doesn't wake his bloody ideas up...
you're gonna owe me two packets of fags.
He's right, Connolly.
Even you can run faster than that pig.
All the same, it isn't fair.
Away and pick your nose,
you mooning Mary!
But it isn't fair, Campbell. Look at that!
Objection! Steward's inquiry!
Gentlemen, objection sustained!
This bloody horse has been doped.
What the hell do you think
you're playing at?
Don't argue with the steward, laddie.
I've a mind to report you to the Jockey Club.
Leave him be.
I think his brains have come loose.
Yeah, you better watch it, Thornton.
All right, let's have you!
Cpl. McLean, get those men fell in.
Scott, right marker here.
One straight line, come on.
- Corporal.
- Sir.
Away and find Pvts. Rogers,
Currie, Rafferty, and Pvt. Riddle.
What's up then, Sarge?
Nothing to worry you.
- Good morning, sir!
- Howdy.
Commanding Officer apologizes.
He would have greeted you personally.
- It's okay.
- He's just come back from a reconnaissance.
Col. Thompson is waiting, sir.
If you'll come with me.
- Lf you'll come with me, sir.
- Right.
I'm excused duties, Sergeant.
Is that right?
Listen, laddie, we've had your stripes.
You make it necessary,
and I will personally crucify you.
You're on that list
because I put you there myself.
If you want a personal interview,
you can have it.
And you'll likely find yourself
facing a court-martial...
for self-inflicted wounds.
Do you hear me all right, laddie?
Yes, Sergeant.
Tosh, what's that then?
It's a bleeding Yank, isn't it?
No, Connolly, that's not a Yank.
That's Snow White.
And very pretty she is, too.
All right!
You've got bugger all to laugh about.
- You there, Hearne!
- Sir.
You're supposed to be
standing to attention!
This way, sir!
Col. Thompson will join you
in a moment, sir.
All right, attention!
Fall in!
One, two, three, four...
Good afternoon, Lieutenant.
Welcome to the New Hebrides.
Lt. J.G. Sam Lawson reporting...
as ordered.
I think we can let the Sergeant Major
deal with those.
Yes, rather an imaginative location
for a military headquarters, don't you think?
Yeah.
I sometimes wonder what kind of an artist
Gauguin would've become...
if he'd had the misfortune
to choose this place instead of Tahiti.
Yes, I think there would have been
a certain lack of inspiration.
Mind you, I don't know
what the natives were like here...
but there are none anymore.
I'm sure he would've found the current crop
of inhabitants singularly unappealing.
This part up here is all Japanese.
Not at all jolly.
And down here, we have our own group...
which I imagine he would've found
only marginally more agreeable.
Now, what we really have is the remainder
of a Brigade HQ Company...
consisting largely
of chaps from my regiment...
brought up to strength by
a rather bizarre variety of odds and sods...
who joined us
when we scrambled out of Singapore.
A lot of them were just as anxious to escape
the Army as they were the Japanese.
But I've no doubt
your chaps have told you about all this.
No, sir, my chaps didn't tell me anything.
Recently, though, the casualty rates
have been alarmingly high.
However, I'm afraid this little jaunt
we've organized now...
is going to change all that
because, amongst other things...
it's going to make it necessary for us
to penetrate all the way to their main base.
Sounds great. When do you leave?
As soon as we've briefed the men.
You'll be leaving
in about half an hour or so.
I'll be leaving in half an hour?
It doesn't do to let the men
brood about these things, you know.
Come in.
I believe you sent for me, sir.
Yes, Freddie. I wanted to have a chat
with you before I talk to the men.
- How are you feeling?
- First rate.
Good. Freddie's been on the sick list
the last few days.
I'm so sorry, I don't think you have met yet.
This is Lt. Lawson
of the United States Navy.
Lt. Lawson, this is Capt. Hornsby,
who'll be leading this patrol.
How do you do?
Glad you'll be coming along.
That makes one of us.
I guess this trip's unavoidable.
I shall be briefing the men in a few minutes.
Perhaps you'd like to get changed?
I take it you did bring some other gear?
This is all I got. What kind of gear?
It doesn't have to be
anything terribly formal.
- Sergeant Major!
- Sir!
Take the Lieutenant down to the stores...
and help him sort out something
appropriate for the occasion, would you?
Sir.
I'm afraid our laundry service
is a little bit primitive.
We've been reduced to using seawater
for everything but drinking...
so don't be alarmed if the kit you get
is a little bit manky.
"Manky"?
How's the grub?
It's a little bit manky, too.
See you later.
If you'll come with me, sir?
- You did say half an hour?
- Yes.
Yeah, I thought you said that.
What an extraordinary fellow.
He is an American.
Yes, but he does actually speak Japanese,
does he?
He says so, and I certainly
don't feel qualified to put him to the test.
You wanted to talk to me, sir?
- You said...
- Yes, of course. It's nothing really.
I wanted to be sure you feel up to it.
Good heavens, yes.
I mean, if you don't feel entirely fit yet,
I can equally send O'Neill.
No, sir, I'm fine.
Anyway, it seems to me
to be a marvelous opportunity...
to really hurt them, for a change.
Yes. Let's hope
they're not entertaining similar ambitions.
Stand to!
What the hell's that?
All guns and crews!
All guns stand to!
All guns commence fire!
Keep the men out of range
of the enemy, Captain.
You men, keep back. Stay in the safety zone.
Keep back in the safety zone.
Trevor's patrol?
Make sure they don't hit our lads!
They'll never make it.
Fire!
They'll be out of enemy rifle range soon, sir.
Are they out of range yet, sir?
They're out of range now, sir.
Keep your guns at ready.
Keep your eyes on that jungle.
Bloody mess.
Terrible bloody mess.
Medical Orderly!
Stretcher bearers!
A week from today...
the American Navy proposes
sending a convoy up through these straits.
We know that the Japanese
have no air reconnaissance in this area...
so barring any unfortunate encounters
with surface craft...
the Americans' presence in these waters
should remain undetected.
Undetected, that is, until...
early on Thursday morning...
when they will come within sight
of the Japanese coast up here.
In the normal course of events...
the Japanese
would communicate this information...
to their air and naval forces up here.
And within 24 hours, this convoy
would be pretty much at their mercy.
Is that clear so far?
Yes, sir.
Hearne!
Tosh.
- What?
- Him.
The movements and major policy decisions
of the United States Navy...
may be of limited interest to you...
but if you will bear with me
for just a moment or two...
I think you will find that it may be
worth your while to pay some attention.
- I am, sir.
- Good.
The object of our own operation
is simply to prevent news...
of the Americans' presence in these waters
from reaching the enemy's main base.
The Japanese transmit situation reports...
to their bases at Rabaul and Truk
on Wednesdays and Sundays.
If we were to destroy their radio...
before the transmission
on Wednesday night...
that is to say
before the convoy comes within sight...
of their coast here...
we should know that at least that part
of the mission had been successful.
This is where Lt. Lawson
of the United States Navy comes in.
Immediately prior
to Wednesday night's transmission...
you will destroy the Japanese radio.
Lt. Lawson will use
our own radio equipment...
to transmit the normal,
routine situation report in Japanese.
- Sir?
- Yes, Hearne, what is it?
Would the mission have to be abandoned...
if Lt. Lawson met with...
an unfortunate mishap?
Mishap?
Yes, I take your point...
but I think it's a little premature
to talk about abandoning the operation...
or of any mishap to the Lieutenant,
for that matter.
- Yes, sir.
- I hope your enthusiasm isn't catching.
I hope so, too, sir.
However, if it answers your question...
Lt. Lawson's part in this operation
is not, in fact, essential.
It is merely a way of gaining additional time.
Lf, for any reason, he should be unable
to transmit the message...
we shall still be doing a very considerable
service by destroying the Japanese radio.
Yes, sir.
We've never attempted to penetrate
this far into Japanese territory...
Bloody suicide mission.
Campbell.
Now's the time to shoot your other arm.
Knock it off.
Captain, I was wondering how come
Trevor didn't come that way or that way...
instead of down the middle like that?
- Mines, old boy.
- Mines?
Yeah. If the Japs ever sent
a sizeable force against us...
that bit of jungle over there
would be too close for comfort.
So we laid a mine field there...
and it worked a treat for a while
because it kept them out...
and our patrols could come and go
as they pleased.
Then one night
the Japs laid a few mine fields of their own.
It cost us seven men
before we discovered it.
Isn't there any other way out
of this target range?
Not if you're traveling north, Lieutenant.
I don't like to seem unduly cautious,
but wouldn't it be better if we left at night?
I'm sure the men
would be the first to agree with you.
- Wouldn't that make more sense?
- Indeed.
But if we're to reach the enemy camp
by Wednesday night...
we have what you might call
a rather tight schedule.
We had intended leaving last night...
but unfortunately, your people
were somewhat late in delivering the body.
You mean the whole operation's
been hanging on me?
I'm afraid so.
I'm sorry about being late, Captain,
but I wasn't driving that damn boat.
Patrol, attention!
- Carry on, please.
- Sir.
Sgt. Johnstone, stand the men at ease.
Stand at ease!
Easy.
Pay attention.
If we can get across that open ground
without attracting the enemy fire...
we can take it that the patrol encountered
by Trevor's men has withdrawn...
and we should be reasonably safe
until we've penetrated into the jungle.
Sgt. Johnstone and I will lead off.
The rest of you
will break up into three groups of four...
which Lt. Lawson here will dispatch
at intervals of 25 seconds.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
Cpl. McLean...
you and Signalman Scott will remain
in the rear group with the Lieutenant.
Hearne, the same applies to you.
As Medical Orderly,
you will be in the last group.
If there are any casualties on the way over...
you will not stop to render aid to anyone...
unless they are injured
within 200 yards of cover.
- Is that clear, Hearne?
- That's clear, sir.
Sgt. Johnstone,
prepare to move the men off.
Sir!
All right, get moving.
Over to the weapon pits.
- You hear that, Connolly?
- Move along.
Don't get yourself shot
till you get to the other side.
Why not?
Because Uncle Tosh won't be able
to look after you, that's why not.
All gun pits, stand to.
Come on, let's hurry up.
Give me three ranks!
Front rank:
Riddle, Thornton, Griffiths, Currie!
Center rank:
Rafferty, Rogers, Connolly, Campbell!
Rear rank:
Lt. Lawson, Hearne, Cpl. McLean, Scott!
Captain, what about the four guys
they left out there?
If we get across safely...
I imagine they'll pick them up now.
And if we don't?
I suppose they'll pick us all up tonight.
- Sergeant.
- Sir?
- You ready?
- Yes, sir.
Right.
Off we go.
Twenty-five, twenty-four...
twenty-three, twenty-two...
Get yourself out of here...
before you go, I've news for you,
you're on a charge.
A charge for appearing on guard duty
with your boot laces undone.
...seven, six, five...
You'll be on the Hebrides line-up.
...one, all right, go.
If you go out in the woods today
You better go in disguise
You're in for a big surprise
Shut up!
Stupid idiot.
Thornton, what's the matter with you?
My head's sore. I'm fair daffy.
I don't think that guy's playing
with a full deck.
What do you say, sir?
I think he's lost some of his marbles.
- What marbles are they, sir?
- Cuckoo.
- Cuckoo?
...twenty-four, twenty-three...
They wouldn't let him in the army
if he was cuckoo, would they, sir?
No, he's all right, old Thornton.
He's seen more soldiering
than you've had hot dinners.
He's all right.
Unless, of course,
he goes right off his rocker.
...seven, six...
Doesn't happen often.
...five, four...
- He's all right.
...three, two, one. Let's go.
Twenty-five, twenty-four...
twenty-three...
Don't walk in a straight line, you clowns.
Scatter, move to the left.
Come on, spread out. Use your heads.
That's great, sir.
The Lieutenant's obviously
done this before.
You don't have to be the Duke of Wellington
to know you don't walk in a straight line.
That's absolutely right, sir.
He's right.
...seven, six, five...
four, three, two...
He's right, you know.
...one. Come on.
All right, you men, back to work.
Spotted a relative, Campbell?
Up your pipe, you Cockney ponce.
Be quiet!
It's marvelous, this country living.
For pigs.
Look at my hands.
They look like chopped beef.
Excuse me, sir, is there something wrong
with your teeth?
We call it personal hygiene.
You ought to try it sometime.
You hear that, lads?
He reckons you're all a bunch of pigs.
Cheeky bastard.
May I have a light, please, Lieutenant?
Here.
Those two are getting pretty matey,
aren't they?
Why not?
Like you're always saying,
it's a matter of class.
I don't know about Snow White...
but old Hornsby's got about as much class
as a syphilitic road sweeper.
I really love this time of day.
- It always reminds me...
- It doesn't do much for me, I'll tell you.
I can see you're a confirmed city dweller.
My people farm, you know.
- We have this little estate in the Cotswolds.
- Is that right?
- Sgt. Johnstone.
- Sir?
- It's about time we moved off.
- Yes, sir.
Let's have Riddle out in front.
All right, Riddle, up front.
Why me again? I was back marker yesterday.
Keep it down, you chaps.
Because you're so bloody lovely, that's why.
Now don't argue! Get up front!
- Connolly, you kick off as back marker.
- Who, me, sir?
All right, sir.
Hang on here
until we've been gone a full minute.
Jap patrol, sir. Coming right down the path.
- Five of them, this way.
- Did they see you?
I don't think so.
Off the path, both sides.
Don't fire unless I do!
Captain, your field pack!
We did it!
Rogers, get your bloody head down!
Keep down, you bloody fool.
Rafferty! Rogers! Kill all those men!
Griffiths! Thornton! Pick up the rifles!
Come on, don't leave a trace.
You heard the orders. Get a move on.
Don't leave a trace. I said off the trail.
Tosh, over here.
Come on, clean it up.
That's right. Get it out of the way.
- Take him up that way.
- Tosh, hurry up!
Over in the undergrowth. That's right.
You'll be all right, Connolly.
Riddle, get off down the trail
and keep cover.
- Come on, Riddle, double up!
- Get them off the trail.
- I think Riddle's bought it.
- Damn.
Campbell, you get on up there.
If you see any more coming...
fire a warning shot
and get back here on the double.
- Yes, sir.
- Move it, Campbell!
Trying to work his ticket.
It's what you're doing, ain't you?
Trying to work your ticket, son?
- Hearne.
- What do you want, sir?
What about these two?
Bloody idiot. Put your hand on there
and keep the pressure, all right?
This one's got about five minutes.
This one will be all right
if we get him back to camp.
But we're not going in that direction,
are we?
No, sir.
All right, Sergeant...
do we have any other casualties?
The Yank says Pvt. Riddle's dead, sir.
- Is that all?
- No, it's not all.
Currie and Connolly.
- Both dead?
- No.
What the hell do you mean, idiot?
Can't you speak plainly?
Currie's dead!
Connolly's wounded.
Right, Sergeant, get these Japanese bodies
off the trail, please.
You heard. Get these bodies off the trail.
Come on, move!
And erase those bloodstains.
Never you mind.
Hearne's taking good care of you.
Come on, Rogers, get a move on.
I hear you're something
of a footballer, Connolly.
Before you know it, you'll be back home...
playing for the regiment, perhaps.
I don't know whether I ever...
You shouldn't have given up
smoking, Connolly.
You could've had a drag now.
Get those helmets.
I got his leg.
Take him up that way, towards the right.
Scott, give us a hand.
- Don't take all day, man.
- Yes, sir.
The helmet, you damn fool!
That pretty well cleans it up, sir.
It's been a great day at Hampden Park, folks.
Hornsby's Hotspurs: 5...
Japanese United: 3.
All eight of them scored by Hornsby.
What's he mean, all eight of them?
He means that Fairy Feet Hornsby...
deployed his forces
with such a masterly grasp of tactics...
half of us got ourselves shot
by the other bloody half.
No, it can't be.
Can't be? Go and dig the bullets out.
You won't find "Made in Japan"
written on them.
All right, Sergeant, let's be on our way.
Come on, men.
Rafferty.
Back marker.
Let's have a bloody good cry
And always remember
Come on, move it.
The longer you live
The sooner you'll bloody well die
Look at the mourners
Bloody great hypocrites
Isn't it grand, boys
Don't you know any other songs?
Aye, a few...
but at the moment, I happen
to be particularly fond of this one.
I wish you'd sing us one you hate.
Campbell, has it ever occurred to you
that if you had the other arm broken...
you'd be needing a friend
to button your fly?
Capt. Hornsby! Over here! Japs!
Where are you?
We're coming after you,
you bloody little ape!
Come on, Captain,
the bastard's getting away!
Get your blinking face here,
or we'll all be done for!
Hearne!
Come on, show yourself!
Two of them coming down there,
a lieutenant and a corporal.
I got the corporal. I winged
the other one, too. Could be dead now.
- Where did he go?
- Disappeared in there.
Hearne, see what you can do for him.
Corporal, take some men
and start combing the area.
- Four of you on the double.
- He's got to be in the jungle somewhere.
Campbell, you and Scott
take a look from this tower.
See if you can spot anything from up there.
Lieutenant, you better come with me.
- Come on.
- I can't go up there.
- You and your bloody arm.
- Go on, get on with it.
It's a bloody mile high.
What's up there, then?
Just some things
for measuring the weather or something.
It's like the stuff we've got back at camp.
Damn you, Hearne!
Shall I bring them down?
No, leave them.
If Hornsby sees them, he'll have us
lugging them all the way back to base.
Don't worry, Thorny.
Snakes love Japs.
You'll have to go to Woolworth's
and buy one, I think.
We're never gonna find him in this.
Let's get back.
It seems your friend
is on his way back to Tokyo.
- Hearne.
- What?
How about it?
- Can he walk?
- No, sir.
- But, surely...
- No.
Right, give him a hand. Come on, now.
What's the matter with you?
Can't you see that I can't put my foot down?
There's hundreds of these trails.
How're we ever gonna find him again
on our way back?
It's easy.
We're gonna scatter little white pebbles
through the forest...
just like bloody Hansel and Gretel.
Carry on, Gunga Din.
This thing weighs a ton.
Ease him down over there.
Sorry we couldn't have
the Rolls Royce for you.
Just thought you might need this.
Thank you, sir.
Good luck, Sergeant.
- Corporal.
- Sir?
There. Okay?
All done.
- Here.
- What's this, then?
- Salt tablets.
- I'd rather have a smoke.
- You short, then?
- Skint.
Hearne, we've got to go.
I'll see you Saturday, okay?
Yeah. Thanks.
Not for the cigarettes though.
You owe me them.
Don't you bloody forget it.
I won't.
And don't forget to loosen the tourniquet,
otherwise your bloody leg will drop off.
See you.
Enjoy your rest, Sergeant.
I reckon that makes you a Sergeant, Jock.
- Down there?
- Yes, sir.
All right. Hearne, Campbell, come with me.
Well, move yourself, Campbell.
I knew that little Nip had to be in there.
What?
- Cover me.
- All right.
They've gone. Let's move on.
Did you hear me? There's no one here.
Let's move on.
Look out!
It's not every day you get a chance
to kill an officer, is it, Lieutenant?
All he had was this knife.
What did you want me to do?
Wait till he threw it at you?
No.
No! It's me, Campbell!
What the hell do you want?
You asked for these, sir.
You idiot. You could've got yourself killed,
running up like that.
Come on, let's get moving.
Let's go.
Where are you off to?
You're still back marker, remember?
Bugger off, you Yank bastard.
I hope you bloody crash!
- How do you know it's a Yank, kid?
- You can smell them.
I thought all you limeys could smell
was our money.
Hearne, Lieutenant, Cpl. McLean,
come with me.
Keep them here a moment.
Rogers.
Can you see him?
Where the hell is he?
You might say he's all around here.
As a matter of fact,
you might even say he's got us surrounded.
That's right, Lieutenant. The bloody Yanks
are bombing us with old Army boots.
Land mine.
The damn fool should've known better.
Here, look at this.
It's a Chinese railway station, crabs and all.
Thornton, away in and find out
what time is the next train to Glasgow.
"Next train to Glasgow."
What's going on up there?
For God's sake, keep quiet. Keep moving!
Corporal, send in two men
to see if there's anyone in there.
Thornton, over there on the left.
Rafferty, over there on the right.
They kind of move sideways.
Must be Oriental crabs.
Lieutenant, will you join me?
They'll ruin your married life, won't they?
Here, give them a peck, Campbell.
A man ought to be close to his family.
Shut your trap.
All clear on the ground floor, sir.
Rafferty's up top.
Keep them things away from me.
Campbell, get rid of the crabs.
Why me, you dafty queer?
- That kid that got it back there...
- Rogers?
Yeah, Rogers.
Do you think he ever had time
to get himself laid?
Couldn't tell you.
Not my department really, is it?
I may be screwed up in a lot of ways...
but getting killed like one of these poor kids
isn't gonna be one of them.
That's what you say now.
But I'm sure when it comes to the point,
you'll be one of the first over the top.
Over the top?
I mean, you'll turn out to be a real fire-eater.
You wanna bet?
I'll give you 8-to-5.
And loan you the money.
You never get rid of those
with blue ointment, kids?
Time to relieve Griffiths, mate.
It's your sentry go. Griffiths, back there.
Takes a bloody bomb to wake him up.
An earthquake's more like it.
Here, Tosh, give us a light.
What the hell are you doing?
- Where'd you get these cigarettes?
- What's that to you?
- You stole them from Johnno, didn't you?
- Don't be bloody daft!
Where'd the blood come from then?
You did, you bastard, you stole them!
He's got no use for them now.
What's the matter?
- They're mine, that's what!
- Piss off!
- Don't "piss off!" me!
- Campbell, stop it.
Get out, Tosh! That's it. Out!
Cut it out, Tosh.
What's the meaning
of this disgusting exhibition?
I'll kill him!
He kicked me, sir. It's my arm, sir.
He kicked my arm.
Kick his arm?
I'll jam it down his bloody throat!
I gave Sgt. Johnstone these cigarettes.
Shut up, Hearne. Nobody's talking to you.
- I'm bloody well talking to you, aren't I?
- What did you say?
I said that he stole these cigarettes...
I'm not interested
in your grubby little cigarettes.
You bloody well should be!
Cpl. McLean, put this man on a charge.
Let's have no more of this nonsense.
Where does he think he is,
bloody Aldershot?
Hearne, it seems
you're not going to be satisfied...
until you've talked yourself
into some really serious trouble.
- Is that what you want?
- All I want is to get out of here.
If you had any sense, you'd know
we should've turned back a long time ago.
Thank you.
Have you anything to add to that?
Yes, I have, sir.
Your last patrol was a bloody shambles.
Getting this one shot up the ass
isn't gonna win you any medals.
So why don't you go home like a good boy
before you get the lot of us killed?
I don't know about you,
but I have better things to do!
Thank you. I shall cherish that bit of advice.
Corporal, this man is under open arrest.
When you get back to camp, you will
prepare charges for a field courts-martial.
Are you satisfied, Hearne?
Easy. Watch yourself, laddie.
That wee man's near daft enough
to have you shot.
All right, Corporal,
prepare to move off in five minutes.
Sir.
Rafferty, go and get Griffiths.
All right, front marker, move out.
It seems some of the men have just as little
enthusiasm for their duties as you do.
Maybe they didn't
volunteer for the assignment either.
No, they didn't.
Since this entire operation was
for the benefit of the United States Navy...
they probably find the object
of the exercise extremely remote.
Furthermore, they're just as anxious
to get home as you are.
Is that what you're gonna do now?
Go home?
Fact is, it doesn't matter how you feel
about something before the event.
You may very well feel it's a waste of time.
For all I care, you could be
a long-haired conscientious objector.
In that case, you should have had the guts
to say so in the first place.
Is that right?
The fact remains,
that once you're involved...
you have a certain responsibility
to the people around you.
They depend on you.
And that's something that none of your
sophisticated arguments can get around.
Do you understand what I mean?
Yeah, I hear you talking.
But you still haven't answered my question.
Scott!
Yes, sir.
All right, Corporal, move the men out.
...otherwise you'll wake up
Snow White and the Fairy Prince.
Don't talk so daft.
I just wanna get home like the rest of you.
Why don't we do that?
Why don't we all just bugger off home?
We could always say...
that old Fairy Feet and Snow White got lost.
Think. In six months' time...
the Japs will still be sitting
in this part of the jungle...
and we will still be sitting
in our part of the jungle...
and none of this
will have made a blind bit of difference.
You're joking, ain't you?
That's right, Scottie.
I'm always joking.
All right, this is it.
Who gets to stay up?
And we'll separate at this fork
in the trail here.
I shall take Lt. Lawson, Hearne
and Scott to deal with the radio shack.
Cpl. McLean will lead the rest of you...
to the southern section
where the barracks are concentrated.
Your job will be purely a diversionary one.
As far as we can see,
there's only one radio operator.
Ideally, we would put him
out of commission just before midnight...
and then keep quiet until the Lieutenant...
has sent his message
on our own transmitter.
If all goes well, we'll destroy their
transmitter immediately after midnight...
and pull back without calling
for any help from your people.
All right, let's be on our way.
Remember, any disturbance you hear
before midnight...
will require diversionary action from you.
If you hear nothing
after the one big explosion...
you can pull back
without revealing your position.
- Right?
- Right, sir.
Lieutenant, will you lead off, please?
Let's go, Scott.
Good luck.
Let us have you.
Come on, we've just got 15 minutes.
Get your fingers out!
I'm coming.
And remember, be quiet.
Sir.
Tosh!
Hearne, you stupid idiot!
- How is it?
- I'm just looking, sir.
Come on.
Oh, God, please. No.
How about it?
It's useless, sir.
There's at least three valves smashed.
- Valves?
- "Tubes" to you.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, sir.
Hearne, you bastard!
You did that deliberately.
No, I didn't, Mr. Hornsby.
You'll address me properly, do you hear?
Do you hear?
Yes, I hear you, sir...
and so will the Japs,
if you don't keep your bloody voice down.
I'm very sorry, sir,
but there was nothing I could do.
Dump that thing in the bushes!
We're late already. Out of my way.
- Any spares?
- No.
Go on.
Down there, under the hut.
Hurry.