A LOVE TO HIDE
Good as new, Mme de Marny.
Léopoldine.
Take this to madame's car.
Yes, Monsieur Jean.
Charming girl.
How's your brother?
Jacques is still in the sanatorium.
But he seems better.
He'll be home for Christmas.
Tuberculosis so young! Poor child.
I'll park the van and be up.
- For your brother. Don't forget.
- I won't.
Stop worrying, Mom.
A last delivery
and I'll be home for dinner.
If your father sees it...
Don't forget.
Up you go.
I'll lock up.
Sara?
What are you doing here?
What happened?
They killed them all.
Look at me.
You look better now.
You're not cold?
You're safe here.
What happened?
I got here last week.
With my parents and sister.
We've been housebound for 2 years.
Father lost everything.
The bastards took the lot:
factory, house...
Last month,
he said he'd found a smuggler.
One of his old foremen.
He gave him all he had left
and we came to Paris.
Tonight we should have gone
to Normandy then England.
Why did he do it, Jean?
Hadn't we given him enough?
I knew something was wrong
when I heard footsteps.
The smuggler usually came alone.
There were 5 or 6 of them.
They killed everyone.
My parents, my sister, everyone.
Yours was the only address I had.
Come on, don't be afraid.
This is a friend's house.
You'll be safe.
He's a great chap.
H is name's Philippe.
Tomorrow, 6 o'clock, same place.
Didn't you hear me?
- What were you doing?
- Sleeping.
This is Sara.
Do we come in or stay out here?
This is so risky!
Did the concierge see you?
- You can't trust anyone.
- And me?
Leave it out!
Look...
Sara's a childhood friend.
She's a Jew.
Her family's been killed.
What could I do?
I do German High Command's laundry
every day.
Think I'm proud of it?
- Now I can do something useful.
- Not just like that!
And you know how to hide Jews?
All you do is go back and forth
to the print shop.
If you won't help Sara, I will.
Stay here tonight.
Where is it?
I can't stay.
I'm expected home for dinner.
Philippe will look after you.
Eat something, then sleep.
Promise?
I'll be back tomorrow.
You seem to know Jean well.
We met on holiday in La Baule,
when we were kids.
We met there every year.
He was the first boy to kiss me.
Did you love him?
I think I still do.
Dear Jean...
It seems an eternity
to our next holiday.
Dad says I'm unbearable.
Know what I do every day?
I cross the day off on the calendar
and think of the next one.
Mom says it's because
I'm becoming a woman.
Every night I dream I'm yours.
I'm off. See you later.
Morning, Mme Lavandier.
In a sanatorium with TB...
Dad can't stop telling lies!
He'll end up believing them!
- Biscuits, soap... Is that it?
- All right!
Mom did her best.
I need to get out!
- Pass on the word...
- Only 2 more months.
Everyone's taking bribes!
Dad can cough up to get me out.
- He says you've to pay your dues.
- I haven't killed anyone!
Hey, calm down, Lavandier.
I was trafficking.
Like everyone.
Anyway...
Still kickboxing?
It's no good without you.
Any cute girls at the shop?
Not my type.
Bet they're mine!
Don't mind upsetting Dad
for the girls!
Stop.
- Sara's asleep.
- I don't care!
Can you stay here alone today?
We'll buy butter and eggs
to give you strength.
What for?
You've not eaten for 3 days.
I won't let you die.
- And if I want to leave?
- I refuse.
I'm all alone.
You have me. I'm here for you.
Do it for me, Sara.
Because I love you.
Do you swear?
I swear.
Coming, Jean?
Coming.
- Blast!
- What's up?
A puncture.
But the eggs aren't broken.
Let's walk. I've no repair kit.
Come on.
Why did you tell Sara you love her?
Because I do.
Not the way I love you.
But I've never felt this
for a woman.
She needs us.
I need you, too.
She won't get by without us.
Promise you won't let her down.
Promise?
I promise.
Will you kill them too?
- Why?
- Look...
Let me explain...
He sold out on us. Run!
I've nothing against Jews.
I help them.
And I wanted to help your father.
I used to work for him...
Shut up!
I can't...
You're a monster
but I can't do it!
You're filth.
Like the rest of your race!
Look! You haven't got the guts.
You bitch!
Where the hell is she?
The curfew's about to start.
In her situation
you don't go out without papers!
- Where were you?
- You put us all at risk!
Why couldn't I kill him?
What happened, Sara?
What happened?
I couldn't kill the smuggler.
Not even to avenge them.
Why am I such a coward?
You're not a coward.
Now hush...
Everything'll be all right.
It'll be all right.
Rise and shine, flower!
I want you to eat today.
Philippe's out getting bread.
There's some butter left.
So you'll eat, okay!
Here's breakfast!
Present for you!
- For me?
- Yes, for you.
A new ID card.
It's on official paper.
You were born in Alsace.
The civil list burnt
with the town hall in 1940.
You're now Yvonne Brunner.
Your new life starts today.
Where did you get it?
The less you know the better.
PROFESSION: LAUNDRESS
Hello, Yvonne.
No point wrapping Mme Cohen's,
she hasn't been in for 3 months.
This blouse'd suit me.
We won't see her again.
She must have taken off.
- That's stealing.
- Yvonne's right.
Even if she returns in 10 years,
her blouse'll be here.
Keep your distance
from that Yvonne Brunner.
I won't have the boss's son
dating an employee.
She's a friend.
And as she speaks German...
Don't disappoint me
like your brother.
I've decided to leave
the business to you.
And as future boss,
you must set an example.
You could've told me, Armand.
Have you thought about him?
You amaze me!
Hiding Sara Morgenstern
under Dad's nose. Some nerve!
I thought she'd be safe there.
Mom and Dad only saw her once
in 1936.
They don't recognize her.
If Dad knew he was hiding a Jew...
Him, a fan of Pétain!
Don't say anything.
Does she still love you?
I'll meet you when you come out.
Till then, be good.
Come on.
Monsieur Jacques, I'm so happy.
I was so worried about your health.
You look a bit pasty.
Bad weather in the mountains?
Hello, Monsieur Jacques!
It's not the return
of the prodigal son,
but of the black sheep.
You're an employee
like the rest now.
You'll obey your boss:
me, your father.
And when I retire,
you'll obey your brother Jean.
I'm leaving him everything.
Here!
Today's deliveries.
They're your job.
Jean will stay with me.
Get going!
This is Yvonne Brunner.
She helps Mom on the counter.
Yvonne what?
Brunner, sir.
Delighted. I'm Jacques.
The youngest.
I was in a sanatorium.
All right?
What did you eat inside?
Nothing. I lived on hate.
Come on.
Damn!
Help me up.
- One day I'll give you a beating.
- J ust try.
I missed our brotherly punch-ups!
You scraped me. Look.
M ind you, women love it.
I covered for you again
with Dad today.
What are you up to?
Disappearing, reappearing...
Not up to no good, I hope.
Stop the preaching,
St Jean of the Laundry!
Dad's cast you as the good guy:
perfect son, worthy heir...
But I have my role too:
black sheep!
I'm made for it!
I don't care what Dad says.
Even when he says
he'll leave you everything?
You didn't tell me!
I'll share it.
Spare me your pity.
You've never needed to fight.
So leave me alone!
I was almost happier in jail.
My family's awful,
even my brother watches me.
You here to weep or work?
How many addresses you got?
I didn't snitch
and I did a year inside.
So I'd like a token of gratitude.
How much?
30% on all we fence.
And first pick
of antiques and artworks.
Too greedy.
I have to grease the palms of cops,
of concierges, of Jerries...
All pigs!
15 %...
Furniture, yes, but no art.
O K, take note.
Marny. U nseen for 4 months.
8 rue Chaussée d'Antin. 3rd floor.
Strauss. 18 rue de la Boétie.
No sign for 2 weeks.
I've delivered there.
He's got masterpieces.
Moskovitz.
32 rue du Faubourg Poissonière.
Not seen since the last round-up.
Wait!
First to St Cloud
chooses the night out.
- I win, we go to Graff's.
- No way! And Yvonne?
- We're supposed to be a couple.
- Silly!
- Are you jealous?
- Me?
Just a bit possessive.
Because I love you!
Wait for me!
- Where are you going?
- To apologize for leaving her.
Hurry up. Remember I won
and we're going to Graff's.
My favorite boy!
Seen how well we're doing?
Since the competition vanished
we're now a free zone for queers.
I must see the Baroness.
He's a sinister one.
Did I shock him?
You've just arrived and Handsome
has already spotted you.
He is handsome, but he's all yours.
He's over me.
You dance with him.
He's Von Berg,
an influential officer.
Do it for me, as a friend.
Remember, thanks to men like him
Graff's is still open.
In this world
my only joy, my only fun is my man
I've given all my love
I've given all my heart to my man
And even at night when I dream
it's of him, of my man...
You can't count on me.
No more officiaI stamps
from the Prefecture.
But you're the Prefect.
Not for long. I'm finding it hard
to hide my disobedience to Vichy.
Don't drop us.
My superiors and inferiors
are gunning for me.
Believe me, I'll be more useful
in the underground.
Another thing. Don't come back.
It's too risky.
Notice anything?
New faces?
New? I know them all.
The bad boy in the cap is Durieux.
Vice Brigade.
Next to him is Rambrun. Also Vice.
The gray suit in the armchair...
One of them.
Look, he's taking notes.
Tell laundry boy to watch his step.
Go and rescue the rash young thing.
No hard feelings: you left me
for him and I'm protecting him.
It's a sign of love.
Are you looking for
a one-way ticket to the camps?
Have fun, sure,
but not with a German!
Enough.
The Vice Brigade is here.
You want to be in their files?
Don't treat me like a kid.
Anyway, what files?
Like the ones for the Jews.
I'd rather not dance with a Jerry,
but you were with the Prefect!
Aren't we a couple?
You're pathetic!
I'm going!
- Yvonne will be bored.
- Go back to her.
Be consoled. And screw her too!
You've got all night!
- Remember our first cigarette?
- I'll say.
I can still see your folks combing
the beach, fearing you kidnapped.
We were doubled up
behind the dunes.
It was rolled with corn paper.
It was so strong we turned green.
Remember?
I never thought it would end up
being a pleasure.
Or even a fond memory.
I'm sorry.
Is it me?
It's not your fault.
I'm in love with Philippe.
But you came back for me.
Your love disturbs me.
Your way of looking at me,
talking to me...
I'll never be all yours.
I'm not asking you to be.
I don't care if you're not all mine.
You don't care right now.
But once Philippe is home
and I go to his bed,
will you be able to bear it?
No. And it's understandable.
- It doesn't matter.
- It does.
Not if the one I've always loved
is with me.
With others too, but also with me.
I'd make you sad, Sara.
I love you too much to do that.
You're beautiful, desirable,
the only woman I could want,
the only one I could love...
But I'd ruin you.
I want you to stay beautiful.
I want you to be happy.
Nothing happened, Philippe.
Nothing ever will.
There's only you.
I'm so scared of losing you.
I love you.
Now listen to me...
The Baroness warned me:
we mustn't take risks.
Darlan has criminalized us.
Why? We haven't hurt anyone.
I know.
Who was that chap?
- Who's jealous now?
- I'm not. I'm worried.
I'm not stupid.
I know you made Yvonne's papers.
Where? At the print shop?
- Never you mind, dear.
- Well I do.
You don't need a Prefect ex
to know they're after resisters.
Don't mistake courage for rashness.
For Yvonne's sake.
Don't you agree?
Then you're rash too.
I may be "sweet Yvonne",
but inside I'm Sara.
I want to destroy the Nazis
So, I've been helping Philippe.
Don't worry.
I won't put her at risk.
You're resisting by hiding me.
We didn't want this war,
but it's ours. So be quiet.
You'll do what you want, anyway.
NO JEWS
It's either that or close down.
No work to do?
Mme Benaim!
Wait. Your laundry's ready.
- Here.
- How much?
Nothing.
Thank you.
Never do that again, do you hear?
Never!
Ten addresses today?
Business is booming!
How about that favor I asked?
I kept my word.
It cost me an arm and a leg!
10 pounds of beef
straight from Nevers,
via my brother-in-law!
You're too fat anyway.
Careful, it looks suspicious.
Wait!
- You're not walking home in this?
- I'm fine.
Jean's with Dad at the town hall.
I'll walk you home.
Thanks, but don't bother.
Don't upset me.
We're friends, right?
Come on then.
Thanks for walking me home.
- I'm going up...
- Wait.
This is for you.
Perfume, on rations?
Since when did women
start questioning gifts?
Sorry. I'm not used to it.
I even forgot to thank you.
Invite me up to apologize.
I can't, I don't live alone.
It's my cousin's place.
Great. I'd like to meet him.
Sara, in jail I dreamt of
a woman like you inviting me in.
Plus, I'm soaked.
I'll catch my death, Sara!
Look, my name's Yvonne.
- Yvonne!
- Sorry... Yvonne.
Evening.
Philippe, Jacques Lavandier,
my employers' youngest son.
Philippe Leroux, my cousin.
Can we go up to get acquainted?
Good idea.
- I've got a drop of hooch left.
- Great. Thanks.
I'll get changed.
I'll get the glasses.
- Pretty cousin, M. Leroux.
- Philippe to friends.
How is it a woman
from a rich family in Alsace
has a workman cousin?
A printer to be precise.
Family histories
are full of untold secrets.
Yours is no different, right?
I'm a workman, sure.
But Yvonne's a laundress.
It's wartime for everyone.
Some get rich, others lose the lot.
Bad time for the honest.
Are you one of our customers?
Yvonne insisted.
She thinks even workmen
should have clean linen.
It's lovely! It'd suit me
better than Mme Levy-Rosenthal.
She'd look like Mother Hen in it.
M ind you, we haven't seen her
for 6 months.
Take it. Bring it back Monday.
I doubt old Levy-Rosenthal
will be back.
Thank you, Monsieur Jacques!
I'm off then.
Enjoy your Sunday.
See you on Monday.
See you tomorrow.
Stop it! Are you mad?
Scared?
Stop!
Are you sick?
What was that?
You're a fag, a poof, a queer,
and I'm sick?
You revolt me! You know why?
Not because you're a poof.
Because you're a liar and coward
who passes himself off
as the perfect son!
I loved you.
You were everything to me.
And that makes no sense now.
Tell me I'm still your brother.
Please.
I couldn't tell you. I couldn't.
For years
I thought I was a monster.
I was 12 when I first tried
to talk about it.
To Father Kermadec in La Baule.
He said I should die of shame
rather than admit my perversion.
He showed me pictures so I'd confess
to sins I hadn't even imagined.
- Two demons on top...
- Shut up, I don't want to know!
I detested myself for years.
Hated myself, disgusted myself.
I was ashamed.
I tried to change.
To go with women.
It wasn't me.
Then I met a boy...
I realized it wasn't wrong,
I couldn't change.
Couldn't change?
You can choose!
Choose?
Did you choose your blue eyes?
Same here.
I didn't choose to love men.
Philippe Leroux and you...
How long has it been?
- 4 years.
- Jesus!
I can't believe it.
I didn't notice a thing.
I bet you laughed
when I talked about girls!
Tell me you forgive me.
Tell me, please.
It's not easy lying to my brother
who I love more than myself.
"Till death us do part"
still stands.
I thought you'd chickened out
in that brothel.
You were so proud of yourself.
You're a damn fine actor.
- Yvonne knows?
- Sure. She lives with him.
Doesn't stop her loving you
or making eyes at you.
To Jean!
Happy birthday, bro!
That's not all.
I've another surprise.
Jacques, you shouldn't have.
- Where'd he get it?
- Who?
Who? Your brother!
Champagne, beef, cigars,
not to mention records!
Black market, I suppose.
He's gone overboard as usual.
For me.
It's his way of showing
he loves me.
- If you say so.
- Stop.
Stop! What's got into you?
- Come on!
- Stop it!
You drive me nuts!
Seeing you with Jean!
Little looks...
I could kill you both!
Stop it! What's wrong with you?
She's all uptight.
What's wrong?
I treat her like a queen!
Why reject me?
You don't like real men?
Only poofs?
That's enough!
Now get out!
And stop talking rubbish!
We can't end the night on that.
Let's dance.
It's over.
No. I want to dance.
Yvonne's right. Dance with her.
I want to forget the war,
forget your brother and party.
I'll just watch.
If I don't fall asleep.
I don't want this to stop. Ever.
I can't love anyone but you.
Don't be silly, Yvonne.
If only you wanted to.
I'd be yours.
I'd give you children.
What? Who else will?
Philippe?
I'd do it for you.
I'd give you a son.
I'm not angry,
because you're drunk, Sara.
Sadly drunk.
I hope you've a good reason
for waking me up.
I need a favor.
Good God, a favor!
Now what is it?
Perfume for a dolly-bird?
A dress while we're at it?
Arrest my brother.
But why?
Because I'm asking.
I did a year without snitching.
I deserve it.
I don't disagree.
I just want to know why?
I love rotten families.
Rotten through with secrets.
And on what charge?
Say you got a tip
that he's in the Resistance.
It's hard to disprove.
Release him the next day.
Bring him to the laundry.
Tell him he's lucky
his brother has contacts.
Touching!
The bad apple wants to be a hero.
- Like Greek tragedy.
- Right.
It'll cost you a wad of addresses.
Tragedy's my wife's game.
He's at a friend's,
but he'll go home before dawn.
He passes the university.
Agreed? I get him released.
And don't hurt him.
Don't worry.
I'll just make the call.
I have to go.
Watch it. The curfew's still on.
Happy birthday again.
What are you doing?
Can anybody hear me?
Where are you taking me?
- I've done nothing to the Germans.
- Shut it! Who asked you?
Call my home. Lavandier.
Turenne 24-36.
They'll tell you I'm innocent.
Speak when you're spoken to!
U nderstand?
Easy. We're releasing him later.
- Why arrest him then?
- I'll explain later.
The reputation of the French Police
depends on us.
Well, ladies,
a nice evening of cottaging?
A bit chilly?
Your punter...
Isn't that Jean Lavandier?
Born 3rd October 1915,
Paris 3rd district?
He's in the poof file.
Cavorting with a Jerry officer.
I've got a case against him.
I'm innocent!
Who's that?
Your German cousin?
We know everything.
Witnesses saw you
feeling each other up at Graff's.
It's no time to be
a German officer's plaything.
I'm not his plaything.
I didn't sleep with him.
You're in the fag file!
You're the shame of the new France.
As you love Jerries so,
you can get to know them better.
He's never been this late.
God, I hope nothing's happened!
I could cover for Jean in the shop
and do the deliveries
this afternoon.
When did you start caring?
I nspectors Maurier and Cazenaud.
M and Mme Lavandier?
Is it about Jean?
He's being held for questioning.
What for? There's been a mistake.
I don't think so.
He's the lover of a German officer.
What's with this German officer?
You were supposed
to release Jean tonight!
Don't mess this up!
Mess up?
You played with fire and got burnt.
You should've known he liked
being occupied by the occupiers.
They'll occupy themselves
with him now!
How many addresses do you need?
Not even a hundred will do.
The Jerries don't care.
But try hard
and I'll put in a word.
A lieutenant-colonel
in the German Army.
Johann Von Berg.
You hit the jackpot.
I don't know him.
Our French friends
were most cooperative.
You met him at Graff's
on 30 August this year.
I didn't sleep with him.
We want to know
about your pillow-talk.
Arsch fickers like you,
dirty little bum bandits,
always talk during and after, right?
Don't try to protect dear Johann.
We know all about
your obscene, unnatural tryst.
I only met him once.
I didn't sleep with him.
If it's a lie,
why did Von Berg
put a bullet in his head?
He was a pederast!
A traitor!
All pederasts are traitors!
Did you go to his place
or to yours?
What did he say
when you sodomized each other?
This has gone far enough.
Only you can help Jean.
You know collaborators. Call them.
I did. No good.
Then I'll see what I can do.
Jean's being transferred
to Tourelles tomorrow.
We must know someone there.
It's a French jail.
Don't kid yourself.
It's French-run
but under Gestapo control.
He had an affair
with a German officer...
But it's a lie!
Easy does it.
It's no longer a question
of true or false.
Only the German officer
could save him,
and he shot himself
to avoid the camps.
I'm sorry.
Here. 32 addresses.
More later, as they disappear.
All I want is my brother.
Don't get your hopes up.
What must I do?
I might suggest poking your mother
to get a replacement.
But normal.
Not a fairy like this one.
Listen to me.
Your brother shames the nation.
Poofs dirty our race.
It's time for France, like Germany,
to cleanse itself.
Your rotten brother and his kind
need re-educating.
And if not, exterminating.
You're sick, Breton!
The stink!
Is it you?
You must be wondering...
Who turned you in? Why?
Well, sweetie,
family's not always what it seems.
Come in!
How can I help?
- My brother's here. Jean Lavandier.
- So?
I'm 4 months pregnant by him.
I work at his parents' shop.
He's wrongly accused
of being a pederast.
Mlle Brunner and I can testify.
He and I lost our virginity
in a brothel.
Has he offered to marry you?
Yes, sir. We're very much in love.
Our parents agree.
My mother signed this letter.
Grangier...
Bring prisoner Lavandier
and Captain Locarner to my office.
We'll clarify all this.
I'm sorry, but the prisoner
was moved to a transit camp.
He'll leave for Germany
this evening.
He's on the list.
It's a night train.
You can't stop there!
Here, take this.
I'll get him out.
They're only going to
re-educate him.
He'll be back once he's changed.
In about 3 months.
Silence!
I don't want him mentioned again
at this table.
Only get off if I call your name!
I said only get off
if I call your name.
In the truck. Move it!
You speak French?
- Where are we going?
- A labor camp.
What's that?
Like the yellow star,
but for German homos.
I'm from Alsace, I'm German now.
I must wear a pink triangle.
Pink for girls, to humiliate us.
Where are you from?
Paris.
You're lucky.
Frenchmen get blue stripes.
Better? We're going
to the same place.
But we're not all equal.
We homos with our pink triangles
are worse than dogs.
We die twice as fast.
So you're lucky.
I'm Rudy.
I'm Jean.
Isaac Levy, right?
You live in the 18th.
What are you doing here?
Where are you going?
Can I see your papers?
Yvonne Brunner...
- From Alsace?
- Yes. Eiswiller.
My fiancé and his family live here.
I work with them.
Here.
It's Yvonne!
Help me.
We'll put her in Jean's room.
Philippe...
He was looking at me.
- Why do they kill everyone I love?
- No talking. Rest.
What will we tell Jean?
She's boiling.
Water will bring her fever down.
It's Sara.
Sara Morgenstern.
Remember? Her parents
had a villa in La Baule.
You mustn't tell your father.
She'll stay as long she needs.
She's your fiancée.
She lives and works with us.
We'll do nothing
to attract attention.
Silence!
Re-education class.
Start running!
In you go, girls.
Dry yourselves off.
From Hans.
Your warrant officer's spoiling you.
Let it go. You know her.
I know she's a collaborator,
that's all.
Officer Stroeger.
If you'd like to go through
to my office.
I hope you bring good news
about Steiner's laundries.
Yes, the Aryanization Commission
seemed to appreciate your report.
Of course, there are
a few details to finalize.
Of course.
In only a matter of days,
Boulogne Laundries will be yours.
Yvonne, it's me. It's Jacques.
Can I come in?
How could you? They're killing Jean,
and you deal with them!
You disgust me. You're a pig.
I won't stay here
in the same room as you.
Don't talk to me like that.
Don't judge me!
I do it to find out where Jean is.
I pay for favors,
to get us out of this hell!
I'm sorry.
But I miss him so much.
Every day I think of him.
Every day I see his eyes
on that platform.
I can't take any more!
I miss him too.
Stay away! Don't touch me!
I'm all right now.
Don't go down or they'll kill you.
Hang in there!
Don't touch me! Keep away!
Do like them.
Never go near a pink triangle.
Don't talk to an arsch fickerl
Leave him!
Strip naked!
Kill me!
How many of you will abandon
your vile perversion
to become men worthy of the name,
ready to serve the Reich
and our great race?
So you won't be cured?
You refuse to be re-educated?
I'm an arschficker!
I like men!
You want to die like your comrade?
Then I'll send you to Dachau.
Our doctors will see to you there.
You'll change, you'll see.
No more.
We've nothing to celebrate.
I disagree.
We're free and alive.
It offends life not to enjoy it.
Let's drink.
To those we miss.
To life and hope.
We need to be happy.
We must fight for that.
A pleasure to meet a friend
spared by such painful times.
See, I didn't forget you.
No introductions?
- Let's go.
- I wouldn't if I were you.
One word from me and it's over.
Dining here with a Jewess
wanted for attempted murder...
You like taking risks, young man.
I have friends among the diners.
Let's not cause a scene.
- How much?
- Be reasonable.
You won't have enough.
I'm sure your young friend here
can do better.
If he can afford a meal here,
he can afford all Paris.
Tomorrow at noon.
The foyer of the Salle Favart.
I know a restaurant nearby.
There!
Thanks to your friend's sang-froid,
we'll all have a splendid evening.
I wish I'd killed him.
No fear, I'm here.
Don't worry.
A very old friend.
Work won't get done
with you looking out the window.
Not that it's my business.
You're engaged to the boss's son,
you can do as you please.
Are you hurt?
It's his blood, not mine.
I couldn't let him blackmail us.
You risk nothing now.
No one will hurt you.
Ever.
Wait, no questions. You'll see.
Explain.
Boulevard Malesherbes...
Saint Augustin...
Come and see.
Parc Monceau over there.
The classy area, Yvonne.
If you want, it's yours... Ours.
I can't.
I can't love any more.
Listen to me.
I'll do all I can to get Jean back.
But let me love you.
You know I'm dying to.
I'll make you happy, Sara.
I've love enough for two.
I'll love you like a man.
I want you to be mine.
Marry me.
I'm sure it's what Jean would want.
Hello, Herr Stroeger!
I have excellent news.
The Commission has accepted
your candidature.
You're now the official owner
of Boulogne Laundries,
my dear Jacques.
There is one formality...
The payments were made?
Just as you said, yes.
Half in Bern, half in Monaco.
I will say it wasn't easy.
Perfect.
You're a remarkable
businessman, old chap.
- Any news of my brother?
- Yes.
He's been transferred to Dachau.
A concentration camp.
From which there's no return.
From what I could learn,
he refused to be re-educated.
Don't let it upset you.
On the contrary,
thank the Fuhrer
for cleansing your family.
And for making it rich.
Live in the present, dammit!
If not for me, then for the baby!
You'll never take away my memories!
What is it?
The baby?
Come on, come on...
I didn't want to lose it.
It came early.
Our son's fine. He's out of danger.
It's a boy?
- Armand. After father.
- No. Jean.
To keep hope alive
and stop people forgetting him.
Yes, Jeannot...
Give him to Yvonne.
It's his bedtime.
It's his baptism,
we want to enjoy him.
Give him to Valentine.
Valentine, can you take him to bed?
I hesitated long,
but the day has come.
Jacques, for these past two years
I can't praise you enough.
Lavandier Laundries has prospered
despite difficult times.
You've assured
the family's future.
You've paid off
all the errors of your past.
It's time for your mother and I
to retire
and pass the business on to you
and to Yvonne.
I'm so proud of you.
Quite a reaction!
Are you blind?
Don't you wonder how Jacques
bought Boulogne Laundries?
In line with the laws of France.
As Pétain said...
De Gaulle landed with the Allies
over a month ago.
So your Pétain better start packing!
Your wife's impossible.
What's more, she's Jewish.
Her name's Sara Morgenstern.
Yvonne's a false name.
Your grandson's a Jew.
Say nothing, Armand.
Not one word.
Or you'll never see me again.
Jacques Lavandier?
That's me.
You're under arrest, pal.
Jeannot's well.
He's grown. He misses you.
Do you?
Your wife will testify.
Hiding and marrying an Israelite
is favorable to you.
I'll say you dealt with the Germans
to save your brother.
I want you to see your son grow up.
So, other than purchasing
the laundries
run during the occupation
by the Gestapo,
you are also accused
of pillaging the assets of Jews,
clients of Lavandier Laundries,
by organizing burglaries
of their abandoned homes.
Say it's not true.
I dealt with the occupiers
to save my brother,
Jean Lavandier, deported in 1942.
I paid bribes to obtain information.
But my contacts
became more and more greedy.
I did what I had to, Your Honor.
That's how I traced my brother.
To Dachau.
Since then I've had no news.
Your Honor, many people tried
to buy back deportees.
But they didn't all wheel and deal
with Nazis, M. Lavandier!
Be seated.
Prosecutor, you have the floor.
You're lying, Lavandier!
Not only did you collaborate
for two long years,
you also committed an ignoble act.
Bring in the witness.
Name and profession.
Geoffrey Breton, Police I nspector.
Presently detained on remand
for active collaboration.
Tell me, Breton,
do you recognize the defendant?
Yes. We were in business together.
On 3rd October 1942,
if memory serves me right,
he asked me to arrest his brother.
I arrested him at 4 am.
Silence!
Police! Open up!
Mme Yvonne Lavandier?
It's my duty to inform you
your husband, Jacques Lavandier,
hanged himself in his cell.
I'm very sorry.
Where did you come from?
Do you understand?
Which camp?
- You were in Dachau?
- Dachau.
He speaks German.
Can you check his ID?
No point staying here,
there are no more trains.
See... that's Jean.
Valentine! Take the child, please.
Yvonne! It's the Red Cross.
What do they say? Where is he?
Jean, it's me, Sara.
Look at me, Jean.
It's over, I'm here.
Speak to me.
What's wrong with him? Is it shock?
Madame, his chances of survival
are very slim.
I'm sorry.
But he survived the camps.
Why should he die now?
Care for him, he'll get well.
There's nothing we can do.
He's had a lobotomy.
They performed them on homosexuals
in the camps.
Your brother-in-law underwent
several experiments.
I'd like to tell you
he'll get better,
but he's in a dreadful state.
He was tortured,
given hormone injections...
From the scarring,
I'd say the lobotomy was last.
He only has a few weeks to live.
You can do nothing.
If he must die,
then it will be among family.
See, nothing's changed.
Oh, yes!
I added photos of Philippe.
Your mother thinks he's handsome.
She doesn't care who you love.
She loves you as you are.
Let's put Trenet on.
Go and get some rest.
Sit with him.
I'll make him some soup.
What did they do to you, son?
What did they do to you?
All right, Grandma Sara?
Don't worry, Gran, we're with you.
Mom, wait for us.
You're really impossible!
Deportation memorial
Hello, Sara.
Sorry, you must wait
for the ceremony to end.
We've been waiting
for over 50 years!
O K, you can let them in.
M inister, the cars are here.
This way, please.
- Sorry, I can't let you through.
- It's only a bouquet.
The crypt is officials only.
You can stop me going in.
But you can't stop me remembering.
It was not until 2001
that the deportation of homosexuals
was officially recognized
by the French State.
The deportation of German
homosexuals began in 1933
with the Nazis' rise to power,
then spread to occupied
or annexed countries.
According to
the US Holocaust Memorial
100,000 homosexuals were arrested
between 1933 and 1945.
10, 000 to 15, 000 died in camps.
The 1942 law
criminalizing homosexuality
was upheld at the Liberation.
It wasn't repealed until 1981.