Partisans!
Take the typewriter!
- My God! > Careful, Silvio!
- Who is it?
Do you remember it now,  mrs. Pavinato,
at the hotel "Leon d'oro"?
- Say the Tisico sent you.
- Goodbye and thanks. - Bye, Silvio.
Careful, the Germans are there.
Not there, the hotel is on the other side.
Attention, Germans coming.
- Heil, Hitler.
Are you the landlady of the hotel?
Mother.
> Mother.
- Mrs. Pavinato?
- Yes, what do you want?
The Tisico sent me. You have a flour mill,
can you give me the keys?
- Why? - We are five,
in need of a secure shelter.
- Who are you? - I am Silvio,
the partisan journalist
writing for "La Scintilla".
I need your flour mill.
Move on! I don't want
anything to do with you.
- You have stolen salami from me.
- Be careful what you say.
I am no thief, I am an officer
and a university student.
I look like this because
I'm hunted for by the Germans.
I don't want to have anything to do with you.
For three nights I've been sleeping in a
cemetary, with a terrible toothache.
If it does not give the keys to me,
I'll break open the door!
I fight against the Germans
and I must be helped!
Is that the German?
Hands up!
- What's that? - A typewriter. I'm a writer.
- You're a partisan! - No, I'm a writer.
Artist. Novelist.
Madam, you speak German.
Help me, this will kill me.
You cannot kill me just like that,
you must prosecute me.
You don't deserve a legal process,
italian traitor!
- You've been firing at my German comrades.
- My God!
Oh.
You killed him with an iron?
Where are you going?
- Murderer, what have you done?
- It was her. - Elena?
What's going on?
In my room there is NO hot water.
Quick,
hot water for lieutenant Franz.
- Leave now.
- Where? - Now!
Come with me. Run!
- Are the Germans there?
- Go.
Where are you running? Here.
- What are you doing?
- Taking the keys.
- Whose house is it? - My grandfather's
flour mill. It's abandoned now.
- The Germans will not find you here.
- You're right. - Get inside.
Quick.
- Let's hide the machine gun.
- Yes, take it.
We'll put it here.
It's beautiful here, I like it.
- Thanks, you have saved my life.
- Eh!
What's up, do I scare you?
Are you a servant?
Do you work in that hotel?
What do you mean, servant.
I'm the landlady's daughter.
- You, who are you? What you do in life?
- I'm a student.
- Southerner?
- No, I'm from Rome.
- You're a Roman?
- Yes.
- How did you end up here?
- I was a second lieutenant in Como.
Then came the 8th of september,
my regiment was abandoned…
You're shaking. Are you cold? Afraid?
No, I have a neuralgia swelling
in my cheek, closing my eye.
I have many pains because of
the humidity. I also have a cough.
- You have bronchitis?
- Chronic bronchitis.
Do you have lice?
No, I'm clean,
I wash myself nearly every day.
This fabric is itching me,
it is mutton wool.
- Let's go.
- Eh?
- Let's go. - Where?
- Here!
You can rest here, then tonight
when it's dark you can move on.
- Whose bed is it?
- My grandfather's. - Beautiful!
- I haven't slept in a bed for four months.
- Where did you sleep?
Where we printed the newspapers,
under bridges, in cemetaries.
Every night we changed places,
to avoid being found by the the Germans.
Let me make the bed.
I'm distressed, because for three nights
I've been sleeping in a cemetary,
- in a tomb, next to a dead man.
- Holy Mother!
- Here, put yourself to bed.
- How nice! Tomorrow morning I will move on.
- Where will you go? - I'll catch up with
my companions, they need me.
I write the newspaper,
they are poor and unfortunate.
They are brave, but illiterate.
- Go to sleep now.
Afterwards I'll get you hot milk and an aspirin.
- Also get me a cigarette.
- Very well.
- What is your name?
- Elena.
- And you?
- Silvio.
Thanks, Elena, I will be grateful
to you for the rest of my life.
- What are you doing?
- I haven't seen a woman in months. Stay with me.
- No, I'm going to the hotel.
- Should I come also? - No.
I'll sleep now, and tomorrow
at dawn I will move on.
- Good bye.
- Close the door.
Radio newscast. From the Don
to the deserts of Africa, calmness reigns.
Also in the Three-Power Pact nations,
Christmas is celebrated.
The Führer has assured it will be
the last Christmas of war.
Victory is sure.
- What a beautiful beard you have!
- Do you like it?
My grandparents slept
in this bed for 40 years.
- 40 years, always together?
- Yes, until they died.
Give me a cigarette.
Your mother, what does she say?
She knows we're together?
- No, she believes you are dead.
- Dead?
Everyone thinks you're dead,
even the Germans.
You've kept me here for three months.
My newspaper does not come out anymore.
It would be worse if I were dead.
- Do you hear steps? - Is it your mother?
- I don't know, I'll go see.
- Who is it?
- Your friends, the partisans.
- Look at that! Pippo, Lepre, the Vampiro.
- Which one is the Vampiro?
Look. All of my companions
who were with me. I'm going out.
- Where?
- I must go.
- You said you would leave tomorrow.
- You've held me here for three months.
- I want to call out to them.
- Let them go, they haven't seen you.
Pinza, Pedro, Aquila!
- Close it, or you will catch bronchitis.
- They have gone.
How cold!
They are gone. And I, what do I do?
- You will go to bed. - To bed?
- Yes, you're cold.
- I should have gone with them.
- Why, don't you like it here with me?
No, I'm fine.
It's a shepherd's house,
but it is fine.
How is your house is Rome?
It is big, and has large window
facing the Tiber river.
- Shall we go and live there?
- Sure, if it hasn't been requisitioned.
- What will you do after the war?
- I'll be a journalist.
I will write. I already have a novel in mind.
Did you hear? Shooting.
They are my friends! It's Barbetta!
He makes the explosives.
They blew up the central.
And I'm here, in bed with you!
What a scoundrel!
- Hey, Vampiro!
- Who's there?
- Silvio.
- Where have you been?
I've been sick, with
bronchitis and other pains,
but an old woman has nursed and rescued me.
Now I'm coming with you.
She's been like a mother to me.
She has given me ham and salami.
If the old one awakens, she won't let me leave.
She's become too attached!
Flour! Let's go.
- How cold!
- You can feel the mountains!
- Who has typeset "The Americans out of Rome"?
- I have.
- Who gave you the order?
- Magnozzi. - Silvio.
- The article was "The Americans in Rome".
- It is better like that!
- Let me decide! - You have already twice
caused this newspaper to be stopped.
Simonini, don't worry about it,
let the director decide.
Yes? Speak, director.
You've read the article?
The title?
“The Americans out of Rome”.
No? More moderate?
I would kick them out personally.
I hear you director.
I do not have a sense of realities?
I must "keep my feet on the ground”?
At times I can't control myself.
When… You want Simonini?
Right away. Simonini,
the director wants to talk to you.
- Hello? I'm starving already!
- That's not true.
No, no. The Dongo gold?
They found it in Lake Como?
- Very well. I must leave straight away?
- Tell him I'm coming with you.
I'll take Magnozzi with me.
- No? - I know the places,
I was a partisan.
- He knows the area,
he was a partisan. - Sure!
Very well.
- What did he say?
- He said yes.
- When do we leave?
- Immediately.
- I said "immediately".
- Yes.
“The Americans in Rome”, then.
The director is sending me to the Dongo.
7 months after the end of the war,
we are here, where tragedies of
war and fascism took place.
The search for the famous treasure
of the Dongo has been futile.
and the journalists are returning
to their quarters.
Get away! It may blow up!
- Get us water!
- Water!
On that mountain there is a flour mill
where I spent a wonderful time
with a woman. A beautiful woman.
See that village? She lives there.
- The one who killed a German with an iron? - Yes.
Over there is her hotel.
- How do we get there?
- With the ferry, takes ten minutes.
- Does she have any sisters?
- One, a little one.
Let's go there, we'll eat, sleep for free
and pass a beautiful evening.
I cannot go to her.
I promised to marry her,
take her to Rome.
Instead one night I ran away
while she was sleeping.
I have never sent her
a single postcard.
Hello? Hotel Leon d' Oro?
Miss Elena?
- You're not her? - You're her mother?
- Her sister. - Give it to me.
Hello, Iris? This is Silvio.
Yes, I'm alive.
- Don't get your mother, get Elena.
- How many years is she?
- She was 13 years. - So now she's
about 15. Let's go there. - No! Shut up!
Hello, Elena?
My love! No, I'm not dead.
I'm a few kilometres from you.
What are you doing, love, are you crying?
It's too emotional for her, she cannot speak.
- How I like that! - If her sister is
too young, she can bring a friend.
Hello, Elena?
Speak, tell me something!
Two cases of beer? What are you saying?
Her mother is there, she doesn't want her to
understand she is talking to me.
- Why I haven't written? Well…
- “I will explain it all to you later”.
- I will explain everything. - “We'll be
out late". -Leave me alone!
I wasn't talking to you. I'm not alone here.
Let me speak!
You have no idea what has happened!
I will tell you all about it when we meet.
- “We'll be until late.”
- Yes!
I never graduated,
I started as a journalist.
I've come from Rome with the purpose of seeing you.
I so much want to see you again, my love.
No, we came by car.
She asks what kind of car.
You will see it afterwards.
I'm coming at once. I'm taking the ferry,
we'll meet at the landing.
- Tell her to bring a friend.
- Ok, I'll tell her!
Elena, do you have a friend?
Bring a friend. I'm here
with a journalist, a colleague.
A very likeable one.
Listen to what I'm saying.
If you don't mind we'll go out with him.
We'll go dancing, have a good time.
- “And be out until late”.
- Be quiet!
Elena, we'll see each other in a short while.
At the landing.
She said she had married.
She thought I was dead.
- So they're not coming?
- Yes, she's coming.
- Silvio, look at that mountain dweller.
- It's her!
- And the other one?
- Elena!
- The friend.
- I don't know.
Elena!
- You have cut your beard?
- Yes, don't you like it?
It was the only beautiful thing you had.
Now you seem a different person.
Good evening, I'm Simonini, a colleague.
Why are you coming alone?
- Why, with whom should I have come?
- I didn't want him to be single tonight.
- I wanted us to pass this beautiful evening.
- Together.
- I have come only to bring you your stuff. - Well.
- The typewriter,
the washed linen. - She has washed it.
You left it all the flour mill
when you fled.
- I left to do what I had to do.
- Good luck on your career.
I hope never to see you again.
- What did I do?
- You're losing her. A character like her!
- Hold this.
- Go there.
Elena! Wait!
Why did you do that?
Is it true that you married?
Why didn't you wait for me?
Bastard! You can't do like that!
I killed a man to save your life,
we lived together for three months
and then you fled.
I realize I have done wrong.
How many promises you made me,
and how many beautiful words you said to me!
You even wrote me poems!
You said you couldn't live without me,
that I was more necessary to you
than bread and water.
And now you phone me up, two years later,
to pass a beautiful evening!
Here's the beautiful evening!
Elena.
I have been a bastard, but I will not
allow you to marry another man.
- Who will stop me?
- I will.
- It's too late.
- No.
- How beautiful you are! Give me a kiss.
Let's go to the flour mill, we'll spend
a beautiful night together.
Then, if you want, you can come to Rome with me.
I won't go to the flour mill,
you will leave me there again!
No, I have come here to tell
you how much I love you.
If you really love me,
do you know what to do?
I'm coming with you.
But not to the flour mill, to Rome!
To Rome? When?
At once.
- Will your mother agree with this?
- No. - And then?
I'll flee. Iris!
I told you he would take
me with him to Rome.
- Here is Elena's suitcase.
- Good.
- Tell mother we love each other.
- And your fiancèe?
- He and his millions can go to hell!
- Yes.
- Bye, lris.
- Bye.
- Good bye, Silvio.
- Bye, lris.
Let's go.
- The boat is leaving!
- One moment, we're coming.
Silvio, quick!
- What are you doing with that suitcase?
- Elena is coming to Rome with me.
- Are you crazy?
- Not, sooner or later I had to do it.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, I have decided and am happy with it.
What does it matter to you?
I'll take it.
Let's go. Elena.
- Bye.
- The car isn't yours?
No, it belongs to the newspaper.
Bow down, duck your head.
Come.
- Welcome!
- Dear Biancona.
Come on, Elena.
Excuse me, my love. Allow me.
Please enter.
Help yourself inside.
Put down the suitcase, make yourself comfortable.
- Where's the kitchen? - There isn't one,
I have always eaten in the trattoria.
Well, do you like it?
Would you rather return to your mother's house?
No.
- Silvio. - Hi, Elena,
wait for me, I coming right away.
- Director, have a look at this title.
- Very good.
- Should we add “The king is out”? - No,
let the constituents say that.
- Very well. Excuse me, but can you give me
an advance payment? - Another one?
We are two, now.
I know, but you have to think.
I cannot help you anymore.
The trattoria won't give us any more to eat.
Give me just 10,000 liras.
- Our newspaper is not financed
by billionaires. - I know.
We make do with money from laborers.
We should be content.
But some of us cash in 30,000 liras per month.
- There are those who are worth more, and those less.
- Then I am worth the least of all.
No, if things go well,
even you will live better.
Very well, give me 5.000.
I can give you this.
It's a bill of exchange worth 60.000 Liras.
- I can give it to the trattoria.
- Try it.
- Thanks. No “The king is out” then?
- Go.
- Elena, Let's go for a meal. I have a
bill of exchange. - Is it valid? - He said so.
Bye.
- The royal family has to leave.
- Is it the king's fault?
No, it is Badoglio
and all the other traitors fault that…
- Excuse me,  where were you
on the eight of september? - How so?
- Where were you on the eight of september?
- What do you want? Who are you?
- Silvio, let's go.
- Yes, we'd better.
- You're a fascist.
- Bye, beautiful!*
- Don't always argue!
- Now that we are free, they want them back?
I'm hungry!
- The first results of the referendum!
- Good evening, mrs. Gina.
Let's see.
Hello.
Bologna, Reggio Emilia, Ferrara
and Modena seem good.
- The middle regions? - So so.
The final results will be out in two hours.
- You are already eating?
- Yes, I'm having lamb.
- How nice.
- Do you want lamb?
No, I prefer the beefsteak.
Waiter.
Two fettuccine with gravy and two beefsteaks.
I'll have an egg on top of mine.
- On mine too.
- And two salads. - Very well.
Ask Giovanni if his father
has sent him the small cookies.
- You've never had them with red wine?
- No. - They're the best.
- Where you have eaten today?
- Today, nothing.
- We've been to bed all day.
- And yesterday evening?
- Elena didn't feel so good.
- It is not true, we don't have a single lira.
- Haven't they paid you?
- A bill of exchange.
- A bill of exchange? - What is it?
- Giovanni sent it to you.
- What? - What is it?
- The bill.
Giovanni. How are you?
Mrs. Gina looks good,
she has lost weight. How is your father?
- He is fine, but I'm not together with you.
- Why? What is this?
- The bill. - Good?
- Why “good”?
Today is ours! We are winning,
Italy is becoming a republic!
January and February: 30,000 Liras.
April and May: 20.000.
To balance, you must give me 50,000 liras.
50,000 liras just to to eat!
I'm happy to spend them, I eat well here.
Here are 60,000 liras,
give me back the balance of 10,000 liras.
- I'm giving you nothing.
- Why? It is signed by Franchetti.
- He is hungrier than you!
- I understand. Franco, please come here!
Excuse me.
- Giovanni does not recognize Franchetti's signature.
Can you verify it for him. - Sure.
No, you owe me even more than he does.
I have already told you,
it is the last time you eat here.
- In what sense? - You understood me.
- But we have sent you many customers!
I have sent them all out
because they didn't pay.
- Giovanni, what has happened? - Before you
came alone, now you also bring your friend along.
- She's my woman. - That's not important,
you're not eating here anymore!
- Franco, here we cannot eat anymore.
- You're not allowed to come!
- Very well, but don't offend him afterwards.
- No.
- Come on, I'm joking!
- I'm not.
- Silvio, are we eating or leaving?
- Wait a little, then we're leaving.
I'm leaving, but at least give her a beefsteak,
she hasn't eaten in three days.
- No! You're not eating!
- Let it be.
Go to Assassino at the corner,
and put it on my account.
Very well.
Elena, we're going to Assassino.
- Good evening.
- Bye. - Good evening, mrs. Gina.
- Bye, see you at the the newspaper.
- Good appetite.
- You exaggerated, they're offended.
- So what!
The first results of the referendum!
Republic or monarchy!
Elena, wait here, I'll call for you.
Good evening, is this the Assassino?
Elena!
- My darling! - Marquis Capperoni,
how good to see you!
- Did you know I was living in Rome?
- Yes, your mother told me.
- Did she tell you I ran away from home?
- Yes, she will never forgive you.
But you did right in
following the man you love.
- You love him, right?
- Yes, a lot.
- You are married?
- Not yet, but we will be soon.
- What does he do?
- He's a journalist and a writer.
- Fantastic! A promising line of work!
- I have a lot of confidence in him.
- If you see my mother, tell her we are very happy.
- Sure.
- Simonini told me so.
- If I see him I 'll kick him in the butt.
I'm very pleased to have seen you again.
So many memories! My beloved child!
- Who is this?
- Silvio, this is marquis Capperoni,
- He used to stay at our hotel during holidays.
- It's him!
- Magnozzi.
- I'm very pleased. - The pleasure is mine.
- Have you eaten already?
- Did you say we had eaten already?
- Not, we were going to the trattoria.
- Then you must come with me.
- Where?
- To Rustichelli.
While we eat, we will know
the results of the referendum.
I don't know… We are not dressed well.
You're a writer, you artists have no
obligation to be elegant.
- Shall we go. - Is he monarchic?
- Even the monarchic eat, don't they?
- Well… Rustichelli…
- Come on.
- What are the news?
- Naples is good, mother.
- And Piemonte? Pinerolo?
- We are winning everywhere.
- Don't worry about it.
- I'm only anxious for the king.
- Who is this young man?
- Magnozzi, a talented writer and journalist.
Be seated.
Why do you bring people I don't know to the house?
- Mother, we were 13 at the table.
- Ah, we cannot be 13 at the table.
What anxiety!
- They were 13.
- I heard.
What a time for His Majesty!
I will always remember the last time
I met His Majesty.
I was in Pinerolo, about to leave
for the front with my division.
His Majesty had come to salute us,
and when we were about to leave,
he turned quickly,
came towards me, took my
hand and said in a low voice:
“Dear Rustichelli,
you have no idea how much I envy you.“
There was a sincerity in his words,
which brought tears to my eyes.
Even now, honestly,
I get emotional
just talking about it.
- Why? Why?
- Why what?
Why do many people
want bad for the king? Why?
- They accuse him of having gone to the South.
- They accuse him of running away?
- No… - I said “gone”, not "run away”.
You said “gone”, but this gesture
says “run away”.
It's the same thing. Why didn't he go
north to fight with the partisans?
But he was 70 years,
he was small and sick.
- Who speaks of the partisans?
- I do. - They are gangsters!
- Bravo!
- Don't laugh beneath your moustaches.
- Shall we talk seriously about it?
- Silvio, we are here to eat.
Just one for me.
The lady.
I'll serve him. We're used to that at home.
Fantastic.
- Rolls?
- Yes.
- What are they doing?
- They are eating half the pasticcio.*
I don't want…
Thanks.
Attention.
This is the official announcement
of the results of the public referendum
on monarchy-republic.
What are you doing, eating?
No?
Monarchy:
10 million and 709.423 votes.
- Good.
- We have won!
Very good!
Republic:
12 million and 718.019 votes.
As of today, Italy is a republic.
- My God!
- Mother doesn't feel well.
Come.
Let's go, general.
Let's go, Massimiliano.
Don't cry, dad.
Come here, your Excellency.
There is also someone laughing!
- Who has the courage to laugh?
Long live the king! - Live!
- Gangsters.
- Come, darling.
What do we do, should we leave?
- Let's eat first, and then leave.
- Good, we eat.
- Thanks.
- To your health.
- To yours.
Tasty!
- Also the greyhounds, Mrs.?
- No,only the dachs are going to Switzerland.
- I have an appointment with the Commander.
- Make yourself comfortable, he's waiting for you.
I'm happy to make your aquaintance,
and thanks for accepting my invitation.
- Good morning. - My lawyer.
We can speak freely.
Happy to make your aquaintance.
I thought you were older.
- I have your article here. It ends
with these words. > Give me Zürich.
Do you want a Cinzano?
“In the next article we will give names
of some industrialists,
who because of political elections,
have covertly sent tens
of billions abroad. “
I would like to know if my name is one of them.
Since you have made me come here,
you know your name is there.
Do you believe you have proof of
this absurd denunciation?
Since I have decided to involve you,
and persons much higher up than you,
I can say I'm sure of what I'm doing.
- Magnozzi, I dont fear you.
- I know you have no fear.
I have made you come to avoid
the nuisance of it.
I don't like scandals, and I want
the article to not become published.
- We should be able to find an agreement.
- What are you intending to say?
You're an intellectual, a bourgeois like me,
therefore we will find an agreement.
- How much are you paid for these articles?
- 5,000 Liras.
We will not be able to find an agreement,
even if you should offer me 50,000 liras.
I'm not offering you 50,000 liras,
but 5 million.
- How much are you paid per month?
- By who?
- Your wage.
- 30.000.
- How can you live on 30.000 Liras?
- Badly.
I offer you 300,000 liras.
You cannot refuse, besides the industry
owns the newspapers.
With me, you can have a shining and secure future.
- Are you married?
- Not legally. I live with someone.
- Any children?
- No, fortunately.
- One is coming though.
- My compliments!
Then I offer you two hectares of commercial building ground, registered to your son's name.
In ten years the property will be worth a lot, and your son will be rich.
Magnozzi!
We interrupt this silence, this
muteness with open eyes.
- Do you want cars, apartments,
furs? - Never mind that!
For three years I have worn the same cork shoes.
Be sincere with me.
I know I don't have to accept,
- But I want to know what you think.
- Why can't you accept?
You still haven't understood?
We've lived together for three years.
Be careful, remember
those are powerful people.
Now they escape to Switzerland,
but if they win the elections,
they will return and seek revenge.
- Even if they do, I have nothing to lose.
You're irresponsible! Have you forgotten
we're about to have a child?
The child! You are giving me
aversions before he's even born.
Before making a decision,
you must think of him!
I love children, but if a child forces me
to commit actions contrary to my ideas,
then I don't want it.
It is better not to do it.
- What are you saying? - If you were
more educated and modern,
you would know that there are countries
like Sweden and Finland
where if a woman who cannot take
care of her child, do you know what they do?
She can choose not to have it.
And the law is on her side.
If you continue with these speeches,
I will break this bottle on your head.
- You haven't understood.
- I understood very well!
If you want to ruin mine and my child's life,
do as you want. Good night.
- Elena!
- I'm going to sleep.
Silvio! What are you doing?
I've been thinking all night,
and I have decided to do it my way.
I have called the newspaper,
and told them to publish the article.
They will remember it
for the rest of their life!
Silvio Magnozzi is sentenced
to 11 months of jail
for libel.
Not having a criminal record,
the sentence is made suspended.
- Thanks, lawyer.
- Silvio! - Take it easy!
My love.
Thanks, colleagues.
Don't push, she is pregnant.
The witnesses have betrayed me
because they accepted the millions.
In the name of the law I declare you
legally wed. Your signatures.
- We were in for five minutes, and now we're man and wife.
- If it's that easy, I'll do it too.
- Are you leaving right away?
- Yes. - Where are you going to?
We're traveling up north.
- You're meeting your mother-in-law?
- No, Elena has no relationship with her mother.
- What's that?
- What is happening?
What has happened?
What is it?
- Where are you running?
- They have shot Togliatti.
- It's the revolution. Run!
- Silvio!
- Come here! - Elena,
go back home and lock the door.
Cignetti Enrico is sentenced
to 1 year and 4 months of confinement
for public disturbance.
Magnozzi Silvio, for having participated in riots,
for having attempted to occupy a radio station,
is sentenced to 1 year and 3 months of confinement.
In accordance with article 168 of the Penal Code,
we revoke the benefit
of a suspended sentence from the previous sentence,
therefore the defendant will serve
2 years and 2 months of confinement.
- Silvio.
- Elena.
- Hello, Elena!
Did you have a nice journey? - Yes.
- There is mother.
- How you've grown.
Mother!
What a shame,
all of the country is talking about you.
- Hello, Elena.
- Hello, uncle, how are you?
Let's go home, we're not entertaining people.
Don't lose hope.
God's house is big.
Jail will do good for your Silvio.
I'm sure it will “put his head in place”.
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Hush!
The director wants to hear
your requests.
If he finds them reasonable,
they may be granted.
- Who are your representatives?
- We are. - Come forward.
- You organized the uprising?
- Yes. Myself, him and the committee.
- What is your name?
- Magnozzi Silvio.
- I'm a journalist and political prisoner.
- And you?
Grisaglia Gino, called Ragana,
owner of a night club.
- Are you also political?
- No, cocaine.
- What are your demands?
- One moment.
“A study room with new books,
the prisoners want to educate themselves.
Respect for prison regulations,
or we will begin a hunger strike.
Then we ask… “
“Dear wife, the prisoners have
gotten all I asked for,
and I am in solitary confinement, on bread
and water for three weeks.
I have started writing the novel,
I wanted to do so for years. “
“Dear Silvio,
our child has been born.
Weight 3 kilos, and everyone says he looks like you.
I will call him Paulo, after my grandfather,
the master of the old flour mill.
I'm certain your novel
will be a masterpiece,
but mother says you should
study for your degree.
Here on the mountains it's been
snowing for two days. “
“Dear Elena, you have christened
the child and called him Paulo.
I am not against it, but you could
have asked my opinion.
Yesterday a minister paid visit to us.
There was some noise, and I am
back in solitary confinement.
The novel is proceeding well,
I'd like to call it “A difficult life”.
What do you think of it?
I desire your mouth,
your caresses, your kisses.
I dream of you all through the nights.“
“Silvio, I know you desire me,
but don't write so in your letters,
because my mother reads them,
and then I feel ashamed.
I have sent you books
about architecture.
Let the novel rest, and study.
If you graduate, mother has found a position
for you in Cantù Cermenate.
Yesterday the child got his first tooth.
Here by the lake it continues to pour down. “
- Here I am!
- Ugly disgrace!
< Goodbye and thanks.
There is daddy. Do you see?
Is it Paolino?
My son! Look at him!
You've become a man! So beautiful!
- Do you look like me? You look like your daddy!
- Silvio.
My Elena!
- See who it is. - It's Simonini.
Look at that car.
Silvio! Elena! How been?
Such a beautiful child!
I've come to take you in my car.
Give uncle a kiss.
- Are you angry with me?
- We haven't seen each other for two years.
The last time was in the City Hall.
We had to occupy the RAI.
- They arrested me. Where were you?
- I had gone to take a cappuccino.
- There is a revolution and go for
a cappuccino! - Don't quarrel.
It wasn't like that.
Let me explain it to you.
That's not necessary, you left the workers
and joined the bosses.
The same bosses who sent me to jail.
He took all that I refused.
The wage, the car…
- And there's the dancer from Macario.
- You know her?
- It's Nadia, right?
- Yes. - You disgust me!
- But…  - You must understand,
he is just out of jail, he is exasperated.
- I want you well, I want to help you.
- I don't want your help.
- I'm going to my newspaper.
- And start over like before? - Yes. - Goodbye!
Elena is not a Macario dancer,
if she must skip a meal, she will.
- Come and have lunch with me.
- No, I have already eaten.
Don't pull! The child!
Elena doesn't need to go in a car,
- she's from the mountains,
she like to walk. - Then walk!
Yes, I walk.
- Watch out.
- Phone me.
I spend two years in jail for serving
this newspaper in an honest way
and you tell me I no longer have a job here?
Unfortunately, things haven't gone too well,
your job doesn't exist anymore.
Director, dear colleagues,
I didn't expect this betrayal.
Even worse for me is, I have always believed in us.
I'm sorry, but since you react
like that, I must tell you the truth.
- Which is?
- Your wife and your mother-in-law pleaded me
- not to take you back at the newspaper.
- They did this?
Now you have a son, and the wage
here is always the same.
- Then what should I do?
- Study. Your mother-in-law will help you.
With a degree you will have a less
brilliant future, but more secure.
Thanks, is that the reason?
Then tomorrow at 8, I will be at my desk.
I'll show my wife that degree!
I'm the lady on the floor below.
Please, make your son turn off that music.
My husband is studying,
he must take a degree.
At least make him change that record.
What you want? Get out!
Paolino, leave dad alone.
< Your father must study!
- Don't do that to your mother!
Elena! Don't hit the child!
- How can I study like this?
- We have only one room!
Don't cry, you know your dad
must study for his degree.
- My love! Elena, he's ill!
- What?
- He's burning, that is why he cried.
- He has a fever. Phone the doctor.
They said on the radio that Stalin is dead.
- Can I take out the thermometer?
- Yes.
- 37,4.
- He's happy, right?
- His fever is gone. - The crisis
is over - Yes, it is over.
You are well!
- Don't inject him.
- And what did the doctor say?
- He has made it through.
- Yes, he is well now.
- We won't torture him any more.
- Yes.
- Sister, who is dead?
- Stalin.
- He is much better.
- Really?
- Mama's love.
- He is well. He has recovered.
He's through the crisis.
Is it true Stalin is dead?
Yes. Mother is here.
Granny's child. How are you?
You gave me a real scare.
I brought you a nice gift, a tricycle.
Are you happy grandmother has come?
- Silvio.
- Mother.
Give me a kiss.
Dear mother!
The historians will say he was a cruel dictator,
but an epoch is closely tied
to his name
and nobody can yet say which
crises may be triggered by his death.
The radio newscast is finished.
< ...always thinking about the newspapers,
about politics.
< it will never change.  - As soon as he finishes
the degree, we'll take him out of Rome.
< You will move to Cantù Cermenate,
marry in church,
and your priest uncle will consider
giving him a steady job.
< One day you will come out to the
countryside in a beautiful automobile.
< Everyone will see, my daughter
didn't marry a beggar.
- You were eavesdropping? - Yes.
- You heard everything? - Yes.
Do you agree with my plans?
Because of my love for Elena,
I'll accept any imposition,
- but where do you want me to live?
In Cantù Cermenate? - Yes.
- I'm supposed to go from Rome to Cantù
Cermenate? - Is that so strange?
- You romans make mistakes.
- No.
- Don't be so arrogant.
- Very well.
Attention. The examinations continue
with the letter M.
- Magnozzi Silvio.
- Here! - It's my turn?
- Don't be nervous.
- Go, I've been praying all morning for you.
- We'll wait here for you.
- Silvio, the marsala!
“In the mouth of the wolf”.
In what mood are the professors?
Good morning, professors.
Why aren't you shaved?
I have studied all night.
It is not necessary with a beard to
demonstrate that you have studied.
Such excuses will not
bring you a second chance.
Excuse me, but it's been 12 years
in which I didn't attend university.
We'll start with an easy question.
What is the safety coefficient
for precompressed concrete?
0.245.
145.
Safety coefficient for precompressed concrete.
There is a 5.
I'm sure there is.
- There is?
- Young man, you must not guess.
- Sit down.
- Yes.
Maybe I'll think better. Thanks.
So?
I don't know.
- If it don't answer these questions…
- Make me a simpler one.
- That is a simple question.
- It is simple.
They made me drink a marsala.
It has made me feel bad.
I feel numb.
I don't remember anything.
- How old are you?
- 33.
How come you are this delayed?
I've been in the war, in the resistance,
suffered a frozen finger.
After that I was in journalism,
passionately engaged in social
problems, problems of southern Italy,
also I was a follower of the fighing peasants.
The Resistance does not have any value here.
The Resistance does not have value?
Then what was I supposed to do?
What the others did in 1944?
Wear the uniform
of the Black Brigades,
and get my degree by aiming
a gun at the professors?
Don't make these gestures and don't raise
your voice, or I'll through you out!
Outside, my wife and my
mother-in-law are waiting for me.
And then?
Please, don't let me make such a bad impression.
- Be seated.
- Thanks.
Do you see that drawing?
Calculate at point A the momentary
forces on a supported beam
with a moving overload
in points 1, 2, 3 on the X-Y path.
I have understood.
Thanks of your kindness.
How did it go?
- Marenghi Elvira.
- Here I am.
What time is it?
3 o'clock.
- Hello?
- Elena, I flunked at my exam.
- I know. Where are you?
- At the Cangaceiro.
- What is that?
- You don't know what the Cangaceiro is?
Ignorant! It's my friend Ragana's night club.
What I'm doing?
Dancing a samba and a rumba.
- He's drunk.
- Tell him to come home immediately.
- Darling, I flunked. - That's not important,
come home, we're waiting for to you.
I'm not coming home. I am happy,
tell that to mother also.
You wanted to send me to Cantù Cermenate,
but since they flunked me,
I'm staying in Rome,
and I won't come home anymore.
They flunked me,
I no longer have to go to Cantù Cermenate.
- He stays there.
- What is this Cangaceiro?
It is a nightspot.
Wait her, I'll be back soon.
Over there.
You're a black person
of nearly one ton,
but you have fine feelings
and a delicate spirit.
Yet your ancestors were cannibals.
I have spoken to you about politics, art
and literature, and you understand me.
- Sure. - And my wife, who is more
white than that table cloth,
she has never understood me.
She the brain of a canary.
About what can you speak
to a canary about?
- I don't know.
- Sing me a song.
- No, I'm tired. - Come on
- I've been singing all the evening, I'm tired.
Do you know from where we know eachother?
Ragana, tell her.
From prison?
How funny!
Do you know what time it is? Nearly 4.
Do you know my friend Peter Sister?
And my friend Ragana?
He was in prison with me.
But who are you? Who do you know?
What do you want from me?
- Did your mother send you?
- She's waiting for us outside, in the taxi.
- Leave, I don't want to see you anymore.
- Where are you running? You're drunk.
You made me lose my job at the newspaper,
because my wage wasn't big enough.
Made me burn my novel, because you
didn't have confidence in me,
- and sent me to school like a deficient child.
- You had convinced yourself…
No, you convinced me. And now that
they have flunked me, I'm content.
I have the entire novel in memory,
therefore I will rewrite it,
- even if it will take me two years of work.
- And what do we eat?
Bread and water like in jail.
If you don't want it, go back to your mother.
Unadventurous woman,
you have ruined my life!
Really? I gave you all
I had to make you study
and you say I have ruined your life!
Shall we examine our wedding?
Who are we? Are we relatives? No.
You're a stranger I met in a flour mill.
Stranger?
I ran away because we had
decided to live together.
To live together we must
have something in common.
- What do we have in common?
- First of all, a son.
Leave the child out of it,
I'm talking about ideas.
I'm a journalist and you don't
even read the comic strips.
I read you a novel,
and you fall asleep like a goat.
I love politics, and despite what
your hyena of a mother thinks,
that is the base of life and all things.
You don't care, because you think you're clever.
But you're not clever, you're ignorant.
If the atom bomb drops,
it will pulverize even you!
Because of this, we are two strangers.
If we have nothing in common, tell me what
has held us together all these years?
The feelings.
- What?
- The feelings, and that's all.
- You have lived with me, like you would
with a woman of the streets? - No.
- I didn't say that.
- Coward!
I saved your life, I have loved you,
without knowing who you were!
Now that you're drunk,
you tell me the truth!
- I don't want to see you anymore.
- What? - I'm leaving.
I'm leaving forever, and don't
expect me to come back.
And never again seek love and
understanding from me. Never!
How can I find love and understanding
in a woman who cracks the head
of a German with an iron?
I have made a single error.
I should have hit you with that iron instead!
- And not that German!
- Wait for me, I am on foot. - No!
I'm leaving you alone with
your ideas and your novels!
Find yourself another! I want to see
how you fare without me!
- Bye bye!
- I want to see! - Bye bye!
You will mourn having abandoned me!
You will repent this act!
One day you will want to talk
about Silvio Magnozzi!
Elena, turn back!
Bastard.
She has really done it.
Now I'm free and single.
- Lucky man! Tell me shepherd, are you happy?
- What do you want, drunkard!
“It was in the days
of the military defeat.
I still wore my second lieutenant's uniform
and I roamed the countryside
under the rain.
Through a clearing in the fog,
a friar with an umbrella appeared.
He was old, but tall and sturdy, and
he walked with decisive, marching steps.
When the friar came closer to me,
I recognized him and got his attention.
Is that you, mr. general? Yes, he said to me.
And then he embraced me, crying.
Why are you dressed like a friar?
What are the orders?
Against who shall I fight?
I don't know, he answered me.
- From that time on, I had to make my own decisions.“
- That is enough.
- One more page, Commander.
- Leave it, Magnozzi.
- We have read your novel. - For 6 months
I've been going from one publisher to the next.
My shoes are wearing out.
Everyone says it is beautiful,
but nobody wants to publish it. Why?
- Can I tell you my sincere opinion, Magnozzi?
- Please do.
Your novel is, from an artistic point of view,
mediocre, uninteresting.
It lacks style and form.
Nevermind style and form,
let's talk about the substance.
There is a generation ignoring
the facts I'm describing,
even though they must know them.
- Each and every page is a bomb.
- I don't doubt it, but listen to my lawyer.
This is an invite to desertion,
scorn against the Armed Forces,
- offenses against the Army…
- Fascist Army!
Offenses against the magistracy,
critic towards the prison system
and offenses against religion.
- This has to be cut out. - I won't cut anything!
- I am ready to take the risk. Are you?
- I'm not.
- Then it is useless to talk to you.
- I don't want to end up in jail.
Ten years of my life is in this book!
- Try it on the movies. - Movies?
- Yes.
You will find allies there,
and they will pay more.
Get moving! Improvise!
Mr. Gassman, two words for RAI please.
- What are your thoughts about the crisis in cinema?
- There are no ideas or writers anymore.
Thanks.
Mrs., the cigarettes.
Good morning, mrs. Mangano.
I'm Silvio Magnozzi.
- I know, the one with the novel.
- You remember?
You phoned me at 3 in the morning,
imitating the voice of De Sica.
- But I don't answer even
De Sica at three! - I'm sorry,
but I've been trying to speak to you for
three months. Will you make a film based on my novel?
- I don't decide, director Blasetti does.
He's over there. - Blasetti?
- I'll speak with Blasetti, and phone you afterwards.
- Not at the three in the morning.
- Run!
- What has happened?
- Mr. Gassman. - See you later.
- Who is that? - Someone looking for money.
Legionaries!
Mr. Gassman, will you allow me?
- Good morning, Blasetti.
- Good morning.
- I'm Silvio Magnozzi, remember me?
- Be energetic with the horses!
Did you read my novel “A difficult life”?
Ah, “A difficult life”! Beautiful!
If you agree to direct the film,
I could sign the contract.
Oh! The horses!
Perhaps you could give me
a small advance payment.
I wouldn't mind making
a controversial movie,
- but you're forgetting the censorship.
- The censorship? - Yes.
Please come down Blasetti,
can't we talk about this in quiet?
- Wait for me at the bar, I have to work.
- At your convenience.
I'll wait here for you to finish.
No, the chariots must pass here.
- I'll go to the bar then.
- Go there
- Get away, the chariots are coming!
- Get away!
- There is a lion there.
Before I was in the tribunal,
but then I fell off a horse,
and now I must play the role of the apostle.
This food is cold, I'll risk a constipation.
- What do you have in your bag, a roast?
- Yes.
- I have chicken with bell peppers.
- Who cares, I'll roast it.
Magnozzi!
- Magnozzi!
- Who are you?
I'm San Matteo!
Marquis Capperoni.
The lunch in the Rustichelli house,
- the night in which the king…
- Sure, the marquis!
How are you?
I'm happy to see you again.
- Why are you dressed like that?
- My father is dead, and I have economic problems.
- It pays 30,000 liras per day.
Sit down here. - Thanks.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying cinema too.
If I sign this contract,
I will be successful at it.
- Good. - Who is he?
- Saint Peter.
Magnozzi, without ceremony.
Chicken with bell peppers.
- Take it as it is. - No…
- Too bad.
I saw Elena last week.
- Elena? - Yes.
- Where?
In Viareggio. She works in a fashion store.
You didn't know?
- I haven't seen her for two years.
We are divorced. - I know.
- Did she speak about me?
- Yes, for a long time.
She spoke.
Do you think she wants to come back to me?
What do you advise me to do, marquis?
Forget her.
Why? Another man?
Magnozzi, try to understand.
Don't think about it anymore.
> The apostles!
- I must go. It's my turn.
Can you lend me 50,000 liras?
I want to go to Elena.
- How do I look?
- Very good, you have a beautiful head.
- You will have lots of success.
- Listen, Magnozzi.
Now I can only give you 25.
Father is dead.
But you listen to my advise,
don't go to Viareggio, forget her.
- I'll pay you back when I return
from Viareggio. - Pay me when you can.
Hello, Elena.
Who is that beautiful man?
- It's my husband.
- Why is he never here?
What's he doing in Viareggio?
- I don't know. - He didn't even
stop. - He'll return.
Excuse me. Hello, Elena.
Hello, Silvio.
- What do you want?
- I'm just passing by.
Can see my son, or is that forbidden?
It's your right.
Where I can find him?
- I have brought him a gift.
- He has gone home now.
Via Garibaldi 10. If it's closed,
the maid will let you in.
- You cannot accompany me?
- I'd rather not.
- What?
- I said I'd rather not.
- And if the maid does not trust me?
- Don't worry, I will phone her.
I'll take the child out for lunch,
and then I'll immediately go back to Rome,
because I have lots of job engagements.
- He must be back home before supper.
- Rest assured he will.
- Bye, Elena.
- Bye.
Should you come to Rome, call me.
Everything will be at your disposal.
Excuse the disturbance.
Paolino, we're going to eat
on the pirate ship.
Here comes daddy.
- Paolino, does your mother ever talk about me?
- Sometimes.
- What does she say?
- That you're unlucky.
Your mother is a great woman,
and we must respect her,
but she reasons like a woman.
It is not true that I am unlucky.
I just haven't found luck yet.
Paolino!
- Are you listening?
- Yes.
I haven't found my luck yet.
Do you understand the difference?
Yes. No.
One day they offered
your father one million,
houses, automobiles, motorboats.
Do you know what your father did?
- He refused it all.
- Why?
Because to accept all those millions,
I would have had…
It's like if you had to betray
a friend. Would you betray your friend?
- No.
- You understand me.
Your mother didn't understand me.
Today you would have been rich, if
I had bowed my head and accepted.
- What did you say instead?
- I said no.
Paolino, what are you and your
mother doing this evening?
I watch television,
and mom goes out.
- She goes out all evenings?
- No, today is saturday, tomorrow she doesn't work.
- Where does she go?
- I don't know.
Do you  know the gentleman who
goes out with mom on saturdays?
Yes, he's from Lucca. He has a
beautiful car, a white Mercedes.
- Who is it?
- It's him.
Let's go.
- Mister, that is 4,600 liras.
- Wait for me, I'll be back quickly.
Wait, mister!
I have to leave. Pay me now.
- Do you not trust me?
- He vomited in the car, and ruined the seats!
- I would like him to pay me.
- Very well.
- Is this 5.000?
- No, that is 500.
This is 5.000.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
I'm searching a relative.
I'll have a quick look around, and then leave.
Why run away?
I'm not a leper.
Double Whisky.
- Pardon.
- Carlo, let's leave.
- We cannot run away all night. I'm staying.
Give me a cigarette.
- Do you want to dance?
- No, not now.
- Giovanna, go with me. - If you want I can
go with you, but it is wrong.
- I can stay at your place.
- Let's go for a dance.
Excuse me Elena, why did you
run away when you saw me?
Do you think I will hurt you?
I'm not armed.
I have never hurt anyone.
- Then tell me what you want?
- Than you grant me two minutes of your time.
I have a right to speak for
two minutes with my woman.
We have nothing to speak about.
Can't you see I'm in company?
Quit stalking me. I'm fed up!
I'm also fed up with this situation,
and I wish for freedom.
Excuse me for speaking about
intimate matters, I've also drunk a bit.
Valeria, let's go for a dance.
I've made some investigations, and have found
that you haven't yet betrayed me.
But I know I'm in danger.
- I'm here to help you.
Cigarette? - I am smoking.
Smoking too much.
- Today I have spoken for a long time
with our son. - Yes?
- He's very intelligent, he understands everything.
- More than you.
Shall we think seriously
about his future?
Silvio, you think about yourself,
I'll think about him.
Elena, who is that man?
He's a person who wants to arrange
mine and our son's life.
You don't think about it.
Look at me.
Do you love him?
Love isn't important for me anymore.
It's nothing but an arrangement.
If one seeks only an arrangement, it is very easy.
I can give you
all those things you want.
Whistle, and I will give you all you desire.
It's easy to make money
like all these people do.
Lower your voice!
What is more difficult, write an ugly novel,
or to sell household appliances?
Or to live by exploitation, like
all the people of the north do?
While the calabrian peasants
eat their ears with salt on them
to stop their hunger!
Your friends have beautiful cars,
and they disgust me!
Careful, behind the wheel of
those cars are rascals.
- I'm leaving.
- No, stay here, don't leave.
Then control yourself,
stop acting like a nut.
- I'll be good, we'll talk about our situation.
- Ok, let's talk about it.
Elena, I love you.
No! You know your hair is beautifully done?
You're beautiful, tanned.
Your arms are warm.
- I have never wanted you
like I do this evening. - Don't do that.
Come back with me,
we'll be happy together.
- I'm not the way I was.
- You're worse than you were before.
You drink, you're as pale as a dead man
and you have worn out shoes.
- How will you end up?
- You must help me!
I will do whatever you say.
I will give you whatever you want.
- Do you need money?
- No, I need you.
- Get it out of your head!
> Elena.
- We're leaving.
- I'm coming. Let me go. - Don't leave me!
- Who are you? > What are you doing?
- Don't you interfere with my life.
- Gangster!
- Take down your hands!
- Take down your hands, or you'll feel my fist.
I'm taking off my jacket,
we'll fight man to man.
- I don't fear him!
- You're drunk.
Did he hurt you badly?
- You're hitting a drunk man?
- I'm fed up, I'm leaving!
- Leave!
- Thanks, Elena!
I never want to see you again!
If I meet you again, I'll kill you!
Elena.
You're a waiter, and I respect you,
but don't you lay hands on me as well.
Elena! Elena!
Let me go,
I must speak with my wife!
She's leaving!
Carlo, stop!
He left alone.
Better like that.
It's finished with him too.
- My God, look!
- Elena! Elena!
Ouch! I hurt my hand.
The jacket, mister.
Wimp.
Unter, mitten...
Are you tourists?
Why do you come here?
There is nothing to see here.
Everyone here is a bastard.
Don't come to Italy, stay at home.
Tiè!
Look.
Poor mother.
She always wanted me to come driving in a big car.
- Isn't that a bit exaggerated?
- No, that's what she wanted.
Now she watches us from above, laughing.
Didn't you see their envious look?
- How come you've got that car?
- I have changed.
I don't drink anymore,
I have recognized all my errors.
I have modified my ideas.
I have "put my head in place”.
The way you wanted.
Aren't you happy?
Let's start over.
I will never again make you suffer.
You have said that many times,
I don't believe you anymore.
Poor mother.
Elena.
Our flour mill.
Good evening, Excellence.
Good evening.
Thanks for coming.
Orazio, this is His Excellency.
- Elena! How are you?
- Hello.
- What a beutiful hairstyle.
- I've been to Gualtiero.
- He's the best in Rome.
- Beautiful house. - Yes, isn't it?
Ippolito, take the car to the garage.
- Good evening.
- Silvio, isn't that my husband's car?
Yes. My Giulietta is at the mechanic,
and I took advantage of it.
The Commander is possessive about his cars.
That is the last time.
Please excuse me, my wife
wants to meet you,
- and the Commander. May I introduce you to her?
- Afterwards, I have things to to.
- That was the Commander's wife.
- A beautiful woman.
- How's the Commander's mood?
- He's happy,
- he won 150 million at the casino.
- Did you hear, Elena?
What luck!
Why can't it happen to us?
- I don't play to win.
- How are you?
Do you allow me, Commander?
I asked you a favor,
but you're just beating around the bush.
You know I'm always
at your disposal.
- Let me introduce my wife.
- Excuse me.
I wanted to meet you,
my husband always talks about you.
- My compliments, she is very pretty.
You don't deserve it. - If you say so…!
From nothing, he has become one of
the most important men in the country.
- Magnozzi, don't flatter me.
- But it's the truth.
Your success covers all fields.
Industry, commerce, newspapers,
- cinema, reviews…
- Records. - Soccer. It's all yours!
Firstly you court me, and then you
ask for advance payments.
Now amuse yourselves,
and do as you like.
Thanks.
- Nice, isn't he.
- Yes, he's formidable.
- Any desire can be satisfied here.
- Remember when we used to skip meals?
- Do you want a little caviar?
- Yes.
- Anchovies?
- The commander wants you.
Silvio…
- Where did he go?
- The commander called for him.
Here I am. My homages, prince.
Who gave the order to publish
these photographs?
There has been bloodshed in Calabria.
You were not in Rome, and I phoned
the newspaper in your name.
You remove a page of princes,
and replace it with calabrian labourers?
I think people today are tired
of seeing lots of princes and princesses
in newspapers.
- Who told you this? - Nobody.
Remember I'm a journalist.
You were a journalist. Now you're one
of my secretaries, and a well paid one.
You're also an idiot.
- Why?
- I earn money on my newspaper by publishing
photos of princes, not of labourers!
- Certainly.
Forget being a journalist,
and only do what I tell you.
Very well, commander.
- Is there champagne for everybody?
- Yes, there are 150 bottles.
- Did you phone my dentist?
- Yes, your appointment is on tuesday at 3 o'clock.
- Did you send a transport for his Eminence?
- Yes, he has arrived.
- Then go and receive him. - At once.
- I remember that young person…
Elena, there is hot “profiterole”.
- Excuse, Elena.
- Silvio.
Fernando.
Eminence.
- How many people! - Sit down, your Eminence.
- I will only stay a few minutes.
Please.
- What can I offer you? - A glass
of selzter. - Magnozzi. - At once.
- And you, reverend?
- Nothing, thanks.
These devices never work.
- You don't know how to pour seltzer.
- It doesn't work.
Can you see that it works?
After work, me and my collaborators
become like boys again.
Let's go to the garden, your Eminence.
Magnozzi.
This way, please.
The commander spilled a little seltzer on me.
- It was a mistake.
- I saw it.
Is this the job you do?
Here around the swimmingpool, I organize
lunches for poor children.
- Over there is a small moonlight park…
- Allow me, Eminence.
- Silvio!
- Go and drag him up.
Elena, let's leave.
- The car?
- No, we're walking.
We're going to have a nice breath of air.