The bread is for Poles
on the Aryan side. Not Jews!
''On the authority
of the commissar's office. . .
. . .23 prisoners were executed
at 1 0 this morning. ''
These were innocent people.
I'm sick of it!
Watching, waiting, and standing by
being passive. I won't do it anymore!
The largest armies in the world have
not been able to defeat the Nazis.
What makes you think. . .
. . .a handful of untrained Jewish
citizens with pistols will prevail?
We can and will fight our enemy now!
And action.
The biggest difference between Uprising
and every film about the Holocaust. . .
. . .is that in Uprising, Jews resist.
It's a story of armed resistance.
And that was a story
that I had never seen.
That interested me from
the beginning. It interests me today.
It led me to examine a long period,
seven years now, from when I started. . .
. . .the issue of resistance in general.
I'm a veteran of the Polish
armed services.
Then you are a fighter, huh?
It created an interesting question:
why were the Jews labeled as passive. . .
. . .when other victims of genocide
were never so labeled?
I don't think anybody's heard the
Rwandans described as passive. . .
. . .or the Cambodians who were murdered
by the Khmer Rouge as passive.
Or what happened in Bosnia-Serbia,
''passive'' was not attached.
I kept thinking, ''Why were
Jews considered passive?''
When you take the example of the
Warsaw Ghetto uprising, the largest. . .
. . .single example of resistance on
every level. And you walk backwards. . .
. . .as you get to know the people,
you experience that they all resisted.
They resisted in the means
they had at their disposal.
Take off your hat.
No, thank you.
I said take off your hat.
People wondered why more Jews
didn't rebel. That's a big question.
How can they just go so passively into
concentration camps? Why not fight?
There's an anecdote I heard about
thousands of Russian army officers. . .
. . .who were marched to their death.
You know how many people were
guarding them? Two armed Germans.
These are professional soldiers.
Why didn't they attack?
They could've killed them.
Forty people would die, maybe 50, 1 0?
Why didn't they do it?
You're dealing with a very
interesting psychological situation.
It's an unfair moniker on the Jews.
The final indignity of the Holocaust.
That was something
that over time became. . .
. . .a force behind
getting this movie made.
We know that 300,000 Warsaw Jews. . .
. . .have been sent to Treblinka,
a death camp, or simply murdered.
For now, deportations have ceased.
When they resume,
we will no longer submit.
We're going to respond
with armed resistance!
Mordechai Anielewicz,
and his friends. . .
. . .founded this resistance,
an underground movement to undermine. . .
. . .deportations to the death camps and
to pester and kill Nazis in any way.
It was an idealistic organization. . .
. . .with a socialist bent.
It was a true collective.
The emphasis was on the group,
and not the individual.
Here. In case you run
into trouble again.
We'll put a stop to this, yes?
What moved me when I learned
about the story. . .
. . .was that these people
fought for honor.
I felt it was so devoid
from most of our lives.
Recently with the tragedy
at the World Trade Center. . .
. . .you saw people there behave
with great honor and great valor.
From the firefighters, to policemen,
to ordinary citizens.
Part of what's coming out of the ashes,
if there is a phoenix rising out. . .
. . .it's a sense of sacrifice and of
recognition of honor on all levels.
From the most mundane,
to the most obviously heroic.
That moved me, that these kids decided
to fight knowing they would die.
Once they organized and decided,
''We're going to fight to the death'' . . .
. . .they never thought any of them
would live. They thought. . .
. . .they'd go out with a bang.
Mordechai said there's
one thing we can control. . .
. . .in this terrible Nazi situation,
and that's how we die.
And so their deaths were all they had.
And how to use it. . .
. . .was all they had.
The spirit of our deaths. . . .
The spirit of our deaths. . .
. . .will shape the soul
of a new generation.
A new nation of Jews.
They held them out of
the Ghetto for over a month. . .
. . .for quite a while.
Some fought for a very long time.
What's incredible is that
this young Jewish youth. . .
. . .fought the German army, the Nazis,
longer than the entire Polish army did.
And if other Jews are emboldened. . .
. . .if other sectors initiate uprisings,
it spreads to the Poles--?
You see the implications?
The cause for concern?
An unwritten rule we followed was:
don't dramatize the Holocaust. . .
. . .just tell the story.
Let the story tell itself.
The difficult thing was finding
where the real characters intersected.
And taking a narrative out of these
historical characters and events.
Paul Brickman's interpretation of Adam
Czerniakow, the Jewish Council head. . .
. . .the Judenrat, which is like being
the mayor of New York, if you will. . .
. . .his interpretation was that
this man did everything. . .
. . .to mitigate damages being inflicted
upon his people by the Germans.
In his hopefulness, Czerniakow tried
to create a negotiating position. . .
. . .where he could bargain to make
the life easier until it was over.
His mistake was that he thought
the people he was bargaining with. . .
. . .exchanging pleasantries,
were people. They weren't.
Strip the women naked.
This won't happen again.
One of the interesting things
was the character Dr. Fritz Hippler. . .
. . .who was a filmmaker
who did The Eternal Jew...
. . .and who was one of the pets
of Goebbels. . .
. . .because as I did this research,
almost all of the photos that exist. . .
. . .are actually German propaganda
photos created by Hippler's people.
It was incredible. Like I was watching
a Saturday Night Live skit gone awry.
But I thought portraying it
would be chilling.
I was assigned by Goebbels to film.
-He says the film will outlast us all.
-Victory will last! This is not it.
Depends where you put the camera.
His debate with General Stroop,
who is played by Jon Voight. . .
. . .especially Stroop himself
in his diary wrote. . .
. . .on May 1 6th, he blew up
the Tlomackie Street temple and said:
''Warsaw is judenrein. Warsaw is free
of Jews. '' Which was not the case.
The Jews were living underground
and fought up to December.
My interpretation is that Stroop lost.
If there were a Warsaw Ghetto battle. . .
. . .the purpose was not only
to eradicate it, but get rid of leaders.
And many did escape
and continue to fight.
That was an interesting opportunity
to interpret that I think. . .
. . .will shed a slightly new light,
or at least offer. . .
. . .an opportunity for discussion among
experts about what happened there.
Enough!
The problems you have
to create a movie are infinite.
I had to get enough knowledge to
be able to ask people questions. . .
. . .that wouldn't be insulting,
and be able to listen.
And after all the information I got,
I had to. . .
. . .pass that on to different people
making a movie.
I met survivors in Europe,
L.A., Poland, Israel, all over. . .
. . .just scores and scores of them.
And I became quite knowledgeable.
Kazik was very helpful. His influence
was details, factual things. . . .
There were kids running, people
starving, feathers floating. . . .
You say, ''This looks incredible.
So real. All these buildings. ''
Then you see this man standing there
and he's laughing, smiling or staring.
And you realize,
wow, he was here.
He looked around and he pointed to
a third floor in the square and said:
''That was my apartment. '' I think
we all had chills down our spine.
I thought for a second or a minute. . .
. . .that I am back in
the Warsaw Ghetto.
It was something unbelievable.
Really, it was shocking.
And action!
To create these bodies, these actors,
these characters. . .
. . .was an enormous challenge
as a filmmaker.
Much of the cast wasn't Jewish.
It didn't even begin whatever it is. . .
. . .that being a Jew is, just as
being black is or being Spanish is.
I believe actors can play
anything, PC or not. . .
. . .that's what I felt.
Jon Avnet was very persistent.
I said, ''I'm not Jewish. ''
When I was in university,
I wished I was Irish or Jewish.
I so regretted my wretched blue eyes.
He convinced me that I could play
that character and that I was Jewish.
I'd say, ''Let's do this scene. ''
And they had to be ready.
They had to be prepared.
They had to have their ideas.
If they wanted to say something,
I'd say ''Let's try that, or do this. ''
It was a loose feeling.
All I had to do was start them and
say go, because we did the improvs.
They got that movement
that just feels real.
That was so important to me
because I knew from early on. . .
. . .I would shoot this in
a quasi-documentary style.
It was a little frustrating to my
ADs because I wouldn't rehearse.
I wouldn't rehearse
for the camera department.
I'd say, ''You have to hit this.
Get in focus. ''
Denis Lenoir, my French
cinematographer, did a fantastic job.
This story hadn't been told, partly
because it was physically difficult.
Raffaella De Laurentiis is the genius
that put all the people together.
It wasn't a set.
They built the Ghetto.
They built acres of buildings
and cobblestone streets.
-Like they were there for centuries.
-It had to be designed.
The technical drawings.
And was it feasible?
I came up with the idea of not
building where Raffaella wanted.
I wanted to build it in Bratislava.
It was created for the movie. . .
. . .because the Ghetto
wasn't this layout.
We took one and a half months
to draw the proper building drawings.
And it took three months to build,
paint and dress the set.
It was an extraordinary set.
It was living. It was vital.
You saw children marching.
They have no idea even, really,
that they're making a film.
And that innocence. . .
. . .of them being oblivious to what
they're doing, where they're led. . .
. . .was the innocence and naiveté
of the children. . .
. . .being lead happily almost,
to their death.
Dr. Korczak. Why are you here?
You're exempt from this order.
-What about the children?
-The children must board.
Then I will do as well.
Action!
There's nothing to indicate that
it isn't 1 939 in here. . .
. . .including the way I'm dressed.
When you do a period film,
costumes give you your period.
Along with production design
and set dressing.
They're very important.
But we want them to look real,
not like costumes.
It's sometimes harder to accomplish
than anything.
Every cobblestone you see,
which we built. . .
. . .300 meters long, four stories high,
was laid by hand.
There aren't a lot of cobblestones
in most places.
It's important for me.
We worked under a tight budget.
We had 73 or 74 days
to shoot the film.
I came around a corner and saw
hundreds of people in wardrobe and. . .
. . .horses and dogs.
I was just completely overwhelmed.
The whole set came to life.
It's incredible.
To figure out the signage
and what the buildings look like. . . .
They had to be practical enough
to put fighters in the windows.
I also wanted to design tie-ins. . .
. . .where you could be in Mordechai's
lookout and see the Germans marching.
The way that they built this set
is amazing. It's absolutely amazing.
Some stunt guys getting lit on fire.
The camera's on him, goes to Radha,
to the kids, back to Radha, to Hank.
They're all firing at once.
And that's one piece.
There are four other things going on
at the same time. It's insane.
You want to be tight. Lose that one.
Get that camera over there.
Also tight, like on a hundred,
on a flamethrower over here.
I was having some vodka
with Kazik and Marek.
Kazik said, ''Do you think
the Holocaust could happen again?''
I said in my typical, hopeful way,
''I hope not. ''
He said he thought it could.
Having seen a film
or documentary about it. . .
. . .nothing can compare
to being present at it.
It's just overwhelming to know
that this actually happened.
Mordechai was a teacher
interested in philosophy and history.
He asked, ''How can a moral man maintain
his moral code in an immoral world?''
Which is a relevant question
in occupied Poland.
In the Jewish Ghetto, especially.
What do you do?
This film must overcome to show
what is impossible to describe. . .
. . .in the human language and
in the human situation. Impossible.
I'm not going to give up my hope.
But I feel, unfortunately, that. . .
. . .the question about how you live
morally in an immoral world is. . .
. . .more present than
I anticipated it to be.
To remind people to remember
what they have not experienced.
To force them to remember.
Jon Avnet's picture
is running parallel to that.
To force you to remember. . .
. . .man's inhumanity to man.
In rehearsal. . .
. . .when I saw the level
of commitment. . .
. . .the emotional connection of actors
to the material and characters. . .
. . .and to one another. . .
. . .I realized we had something
that was really just special.
No matter what, we'd never have
that experience in our lives again.
Confidence is something that's not
carried with you.
It's something that you think
you ought to have.
And when you get into rehearsal,
you think, huh?
And when I did go into rehearsal. . .
. . .I knew I had a chance
for a great movie.
That's what I cared to do.
In the simplest terms,
my goal was to. . .
. . .be a messenger for millions
of people who had no voices.