November 10th, 1938
The Palace of Dolmabahçe
Sir!
Mr. Salih!
What is it? What do you want?
Sir, you asked us to bring your son.
He's here, sir.
Wait a minute.
Yes, sir!
Come in.
Come here, Muzaffer.
Sit down.
I asked for you in such a rush, but...
I'm going to tell you
something important.
I'm listening, papa.
How is the school, is it going well?
Very well, papa.
Well done.
Son, I'm going to tell you a secret...
on the condition that
it remains between us.
Of course, papa.
You're supposed to tell nobody,
promise?
Promise!
Unfortunately,
Atatürk is in a coma, my son.
And I want you to know that...
if something happens to him...
I will also end my life.
Papa, how can you say that?
I've been thinking a lot.
After his death,
a life for me is no more possible.
This is...
how should I say...
it's like living without oxygen!
Don't cry.
Don't you cry!
You know, I don't like men who cry.
Come here.
You're a big boy now.
You will be the man who
takes care of our family.
Look at me.
I entrust your mother and your sisters
to your care.
Take care of our family.
Go to school, and serve your country.
But papa...
Farewell, my son.
Come on now.
Come on.
Papa...
My God, give me strength.
My general...
You succeeded in everything
they said impossible.
You overcame everything
through your will power.
You can overcome this as well.
Come on, my general.
Make an effort.
I'm sure you're hearing me,
my general.
Listen to me.
If something befalls to you...
just know that I will follow you.
The general cannot go anywhere
without his aide-de-camp.
Muzaffer?
What are you doing here?
What are you doing, I said.
Why aren't you in the class?
Why are you crying,
is there anything wrong?
No, sir.
Then what is this state of yours, son?
Come here.
Son, you know that
I'm a friend of your father.
Come on, tell me.
My son, Muzaffer...
Unfortunately, words are not enough...
to describe the pain and the pangs
of conscience I lived through...
after you left.
I must have hurt you deeply...
by doing what none of the fathers
in the world does to his son.
I presume you have thought that...
a man cannot do such an evil to his
family even for the sake of Atatürk.
For this reason...
Our story began in Thessaloniki,
my son.
We were both six years old.
My brave son!
You will be such a student one day.
What? You didn't like it?
But they're so strange looking,
maybe I should go to another school?
Sure you can, but...
your mother wants you to get enrolled
to the religious school.
But papa...
My son!
Your mother wants you to be a preacher.
She wants you to be accompanied
by prayers.
Let us comply with her wish.
Don't be so sorry, young man.
First, let's get you enrolled
to the school your mother prefers.
Then we'll see about it.
Come on.
Let God accept your prayers.
Your mother raised you very well,
my son.
Let Him accept yours, too.
Now, put on your shoes.
Mustafa used to adore his father.
That stroll on Ramadhan day with
his father left a mark in his mind.
In the city of Thessaloniki of the era,
Muslims, Orthodox, Jews...
all the subjects of the Ottoman empire
were living in peace.
Papa, it's like daytime!
Sure my son,
now we have gas in Thessaloniki.
In a few years, our houses
will also be illuminated like this.
Papa?
Does God light those lamps?
No, my son, God is a great power.
He's too busy to see to our lamps.
Lamps are lit by the gas!
The goose?
The goose in our garden?
Such a buffoon!
Not the goose, it's the gas!
Does fire burn his mouth?
No, my son. Come!
Oh, Hacivat!
Come sit and watch a little while.
Oh dear!
It suits so well to my son!
Just like a little Hodja!
My son will memorize the Coran!
He will become a Hodja.
He will teach Coran.
Right, my love?
Do you like it?
Mustafa?
It's a pity, Zübeyde!
Why this insistence
on the religious school?
We should have sent him
to a modern school.
He could become an army officer.
He does not want it either.
Modern schools are not for me,
Ali Rıza!
We discussed it so many times.
Mustafa will be a preacher.
Come on.
Zübeyde?
My garden of Eden...
Allright.
Whatever you want.
I will send Mustafa off.
It was our first day in the school.
Right when I wanted to catch Mustafa...
I knocked over the preacher's lectern.
Here comes the preacher!
Quick! Here comes the preacher!
Who did this?
Who did this, I said!
Is it you?
Since you're not talking...
everybody will be punished
by bastinado.
We begin by the first raw.
Get up!
Was it you?
Yes.
How did it happen?
I was running.
Were you hustling somebody?
No.
Tell me whoever your accomplice was.
Then you'll share the beating with him.
Or else you alone will get it.
Who was with you?
I'm a preacher for forty years!
It doesn't get knocked down
by itself.
This boy was obviously fighting
with somebody.
Whoever was with him
should get up now.
What is your name?
Mustafa.
Mustafa, I wash my hands of it.
Come here.
I'll prepare an ointment for your foot,
you're going to be allright.
Okay, just tell me.
What did you do to deserve
such a hard beating from the Hodja?
My poor child...
Come on, sleep a little.
I will prepare your ointment.
Cruel man!
He has tortured such a small child.
Sleep now, my baby.
Come in, Salih.
Don't exhaust Mustafa too much.
Hi.
Ouch!
Does it hurt so much?
Well, a little.
It definitely hurts very much,
but you don't tell.
Were you afraid today?
Yes, but you weren't afraid at all.
I was, but pretended not to be.
Here, I picked hawthorn berries for you
from the garden.
That day, he had saved me
from getting beaten, but...
I had felt deep in my heart
every blow on his feet.
We were spending every day together.
That day we were so happy
until his uncle called him.
In the middle of Manastir...
Boys!
Quick! Come here!
Come on!
My son...
I'm leaving this world.
Take this sword.
When you grow up
to be an honorable soldier...
you're going to wear this sword.
My dear son.
My brave son.
My brave Mustafa...
Death prayer is heard in Thessaloniki
Now I'm going to tell my Mustafa
a tale...
so that he sleeps well.
Once upon a time,
there were a mother and a son.
One day, the mother...
washed his son thoroughly
in the public bath.
Then they packed their things
and off they went.
Some horsemen wanted to kidnap his son.
When they saw them going...
they began to follow them.
As the mother and the son escaped...
the horsemen chased them.
As the mother and the son escaped,
Finally, the mother got angry.
She unpacked her bundle...
took the bowl of bath...
and threw it to the horsemen.
Guess what?
A wide sea gushed out right there.
Years passed by.
Zübeyde Mum...
had acceded to the will of Ali Rıza.
We were both boarding students...
in the military grammar school.
Zübeyde Mum was in great distress.
They were barely surviving, but...
as she saw Mustafa
in his dark blue uniform of felt...
she was thinking
that it was worth all this suffering.
And we were...
proud of our uniform.
Do you hear the voices?
Mustafa, come on, let's play!
Not me!
Come on, make no bones about it!
I said I won't play!
You're so fussy! All the children play.
It's an absurd play.
What is the sense
jumping on each other?
It's so stupid!
I swear I won't ever talk to you!
Come on, let's play a little!
Can we play as well?
Allright, come on!
Come on, bow!
If you can, jump like this.
But how can I?
Mustafa! Don't be a killjoy!
Look, everybody's bowing!
I told you.
I won't bow.
Let him jump like this if he can.
Bow, I say!
Look! You pissed us so much,
you will have a nice beating!
Are you the son of the sultan or what?
Why won't you bow?
Are you a prince?
Was it okay
when you were jumping on us?
What are you doing, Mustafa?
I can't play, because this childish
play doesn't suit young men like you.
Let's try another play.
What sort of a play?
The play of war.
The war becomes men.
What is the sense of us
jumping on each other?
Are we donkeys or what?
So how will we do it?
We'll break down into two teams.
One team will try to take this place,
and the other one will defend it.
How will we be divided into two teams?
I'm gonna take care of it.
And I'll assign you the duties,
I'm the commander, allright?
Why would you be the commander?
Because it's just the way it is,
I'm the commander!
Now, you go there.
Salih, I appoint you
the commander of the other team.
You're so bright, Mustafa,
that's what you are!
He was really bright.
He was the commander.
He managed to tip the balance
in favor of us through his wit.
From that day on, I began to see
Mustafa under another light.
Hand grenade!
Allright!
Shrapnel!
We're withdrawing!
What?
Follow me!
That's cheating, Mustafa.
That's not cheating,
it's the play of war.
A weekend, we were on home leave.
Mustafa didn't know, that day was
one of the turning points of his life.
None of us knew about it.
Welcome! You're Mustafa, right?
Master Ragıp, the dinner is ready,
come please.
Mustafa...
Welcome!
You're on leave?
Well, Master Ragıp is...
now your father, my son.
Mustafa...
I wasn't capable to tell you.
It's so bad that you came to know in
this way, but I didn't dare to tell you.
Look at me.
You'll understand me when you grow up.
It's hard in these times for a widow
with children to survive all alone.
It's been a long time
that our neighbors were pushing me.
Finally, they found a right person.
You'll like Master Ragıp.
I know, he can't replace your father.
But Master Ragıp is a nice person.
Where are you going?
I'm such an unfortunate woman!
I buried my three children!
I buried my husband! If you go as well,
what am I supposed to do?
Tell me, my son!
Mustafa went to his auntie's
that night...
and stayed there for months.
In the meantime,
Zübeyde Mum grieved deeply.
She was looking for a way
to see her son...
but Mustafa was insistent
on his decision.
My Mustafa!
How are you?
My son.
Come back to your mommy, son.
Mustafa?
Zübeyde Mum was so much worried
about you...
that I felt forced to tell her
that you were hiding at your auntie's.
You did not forgive me.
You were cross with me for days.
Then we made it up
at Manastir High School.
Do you remember?
I betrayed you thrice in my life,
my general.
This was the first one.
My second betrayal...
was my leaving Thessaloniki
without taking Zübeyde Mum.
And the third one...
you don't know it yet.
When we were graduated
from the high school in Manastir...
and returned to Thessaloniki,
Mustafa was ready for mercy.
Hence, as soon as he came back,
he first visited his mother.
Mom, an officer is here!
Brother?
We were graduated from the military
school and became officers...
and we found ourselves fighting
for an agonizing, collapsing empire.
I will never forget
that night of farewell in Thessaloniki.
Come on!
Let's make a toast to our departure
to Tripolitania.
Hopefully, we'll liberate our land
from the Italians.
Let's hope so!
They assigned us this mission, but...
I would have preferred to stay
in Thessaloniki.
Why?
In order to protect Thessaloniki!
We risk losing Thessaloniki as well.
God preserve, Mustafa,
what are you saying?
Friends, can't you see?
Every day,
they're confiscating one of our pieces.
I fear I won't see Thessaloniki again.
If anything happens to me, I entrust
my mother and sister to your care.
Don't you worry for them.
I hold Zübeyde Mum
superior to my own mother.
Yes, I know.
It's such a strange place!
You find it strange, but is it not
a piece of our fatherland, Nuri?
Right, but is it worth to shed blood
to keep this place, Fethi?
I wish I was in Thessaloniki now!
Oh, Thessaloniki!
It just reminds me of the poem
of Ziya Pasha!
"I visited the land of the non-muslims,
and I saw palaces and prosperity
I roamed about in the Muslim country
And I just saw ruins and misery!"
Well, it's so true, Mustafa!
That's why the future of our empire
lies in the occidental civilization.
That ought to be our destination.
Everybody agrees with this,
but how to do this?
A solution is definitely to be found.
There's no doubt about it, Nuri.
You will become a Sultan.
You will rule for 15 years
And you will die while you're
still on the throne.
Ruling for 15 years is enough for me!
Would our powerful sultan be so kind
as to eat with us?
Having fun with me?
Come on my sultan,
don't say that you don't like it!
And what about the concubines?
Your harem is in Istanbul anyhow.
No, it's in Thessaloniki!
Here you are, his majesty!
While they were in Tripolitania, the
empire was fighting on seven fronts.
Thessaloniki was lost.
Imperialists were dividing
the Ottoman Empire.
When the Greek army entered the city...
Turks rushed to leave Thessaloniki
in great masses.
Makbule! Makbule!
Get ready!
Makbule!
Mustafa?
How are you?
I'm fine. Come.
I heard that you were at the front.
Yes, I am.
But thanks God, I'm alive.
In these days,
one should be content with this.
Salih...
Do you have any news about my mother?
Do you know where she is?
Oh Mustafa, I don't know.
Thousands of people
set off from the Balkans.
They're coming to Istanbul by walking.
Some have already arrived.
They're running from the massacres
of the bands of brigands.
I just hope that Zübeyde Mum
is among the survivors who came here.
Weren't you able to take care of
my mother and my sister?
Unfortunately not, Mustafa.
When Thessaloniki fell, we brought
the sultan here by an urgent journey.
Such a woe, Salih!
Our beautiful Thessaloniki
is already lost?
The seaside promenade...
the white tower...
So many memories!
I told you we wouldn't be able to see
again our pretty city.
Don't tell me!
I see it in my dreams every night.
The way things are going,
not only Thessaloniki...
but all of the empire will be lost.
Look at the state we're in!
Salih...
I have to find urgently
my poor mother.
Who knows where she is,
in what state she's in?
I go every day to the place
where immigrants are gathered...
but to no avail!
I hope that she came to Istanbul
safe and sound.
I hope so!
Were you able to bring your own family?
Yes, I was.
I'm glad, my brother.
In the court of the mosque...
it is call to prayer
Mom, it's the lament of my beloved...
not the prayer
Strangers won't mourn...
or cry for me ever
No one but my beloved
and my mother...
My heart won't recover
Mother?
Mustafa!
They settled in the house
of a relative in Istanbul.
Mrs. Zübeyde has left her second
husband Mr. Ragıp in Thessaloniki.
But his niece Fikriye
was living in that house.
Brother Mustafa, I made you coffee.
Thank you, Fikriye.
You shouldn't have bothered.
You're so tired, brother Mustafa,
coffee can be a relief.
Where did you find the delights
in this scarcity?
I had kept a few.
They're somewhat stale, but...
And you offer them to me?
No.
I offer them to a commander,
the hero of my dreams.
Fikriye...
You go to the kitchen.
Make some coffee for me as well,
my girl.
Did you get over your exhaustion,
mommy?
Yes, I did.
The moment I saw you,
I forgot everything.
Doctor, if you permit me,
I want to ask a question.
Of course, Mr. Salih, go ahead.
- If it's about Atatürk...
- No, no.
In the war, I saw many soldiers
shot in the head.
Some died,
and some survived, but became blind.
Is such a thing possible?
Sure it is.
When some parts of the brain
are damaged...
though not always lethal, they can cause
blindness or other impairments.
Then are all the bullets
penetrating heart lethal?
Yes, they are lethal.
Because at Gallipoli, a piece
of shrapnel had hit Atatürk's heart...
and thanks God,
nothing had happened to him.
That's why I ask: a bullet penetrating
heart from where is definitely lethal?
If it penetrates from here,
it is definitely lethal.
My son, it's hard for you now
to understand this, but...
We fought against the foreigners
who occupied our country.
Powerful states provoked internal
strikes in order to destroy us.
They made brothers kill each other.
British and ANZAC soldiers
are behind the hill.
We must take the hill.
It could change our fate, Nuri.
I have a feeling
that the enemy is close.
But it's very quiet.
I can't see anything.
If they landed the troops in the night,
it may be an ambush.
There's only one way
to understand this.
Mustafa, what are you doing?
My brave men!
God be with us!
March!
The nation is waiting worriedly
to hear about Atatürk's health.
There are thousands of people
in front of the palace.
I say on the next report, let's write
that he's in a coma, what do you say?
But it would trigger a great reaction!
The people can't bear this pain.
Right, but...
they will hear about this in any case.
We're losing him.
You're making a mistake, gentlemen.
A very big mistake!
I am a witness of this.
He has such a will power...
that you will see, he will be
much better than he used to be.
It's allright Mr. Salih,
don't get upset.
If not for this watch, that shrapnel
would have ended my life, Nuri.
God spared your life.
It hurts, right?
Yes.
It's a hematoma.
Let's put some meat on it.
This will cure you.
And now we'll bandage it.
We took this hill
of strategic importance...
but unfortunately,
we lost a great part of the troop.
We also could have been
among those martyrs.
Well, such is the war.
This was Lieutenant Colonel Mustafa
Kemal's first step on the stage.
He first exposed his military genius
in the combat of Gallipoli.
He had been right in all his decisions
and anticipations...
so he has drawn attention
of the commanders.
Today, you changed
our fate in the war, Mustafa.
You're exaggerating, my brother.
It's not such a big deal.
Yes?
They're calling from the headquarters
of Liman von Sanders.
Seemingly, the commander wants
to congratulate you.
When he became a general,
he wanted me as his aide-de-camp.
Overjoyed, I accepted his offer.
To be his aide-de-camp meant
to be by his side all the time.
Don't do this, my son.
It's the same thing
as killing yourself!
Mom, if somebody doesn't do it,
we're all condemned to death.
Istanbul is already under occupation.
You'll run away from here as well?
The British...
the Italian...
the French did not recognize
our right to live.
They already shared Anatolia!
Yesterday the Greek army entered Izmir.
Even our beautiful Izmir is lost!
Where are we supposed to live
from now on?
Where are we supposed to run?
There's nowhere left to run.
That's why we're going to Anatolia.
We'll incite an insurrection!
Mustafa?
Is it not the sultan
who sends you there?
Seemingly, yes...
but he also collaborates
with enemies.
He left our country in their hands.
Never! How can you say that, my son?
Our great sultan, his majesty...
Forget about it, mom,
I know who does what.
Mustafa...
Don't do this, my son!
Don't rebel against our sultan.
They would hang you!
Mom, don't you worry!
All your life has been spent
by worrying about me.
Everything will be allright.
I just want your blessing, mommy.
Just your blessing.
You have my blessing.
We stopped again.
Could this really take us to Erzurum?
I'm sorry, my general,
this junk is very old.
But while you rest,
I'll tend to it immediately.
Salamun Alaykum.
Alaykum Salam.
The enemy is about to enter Samsun.
But I see that you're tilling the soil
all quietly here.
What are you saying, my general?
We were three brothers.
And I had two sons.
I lost all of them at Yemen,
at Caucasian front or at Gallipoli.
I am left all alone.
Now there are three widows
and eight orphans at home.
They all depend...
on this plough.
They need to be taken care of.
From now on, this piece of land
is my country and my home!
I won't be of any use to you
unless the enemy comes right here!
The words of the peasant
moved Mustafa Kemal immensely...
because he was right.
The Anatolian people were tired...
of fighting simultaneously
on nine fronts for the last ten years.
The war means grievance, my son.
It means famine, thirst,
diseases, dysentery...
and madness.
It means to be pested for years...
by the smell of death penetrating
your nostrils day and night.
Look at this, Nuri.
It's a human tragedy!
The death of all those young people
is a tragedy.
Unless it is necessary
for the defense of the country...
all war is a crime.
I don't mind.
This still does not change the fact
that all war aiming attack is a crime.
God be with you.
Good luck, my general.
This is the situation
that all Anatolia is in.
And we'll resist
against the invader enemies.
We have no other way out.
I brought some hot tiles, my general.
Come here, Cevat.
God dammit!
That's all we lacked!
You have so much pain, my general?
Very much! You can't even imagine.
I know, they say that
pain in kidneys is unbearable.
It makes one tear the quilt to pieces,
they say.
We borrowed even this quilt, child,
how can I tear it to pieces?
You need a thorough treatment, my
general, what if you go to a hospital?
Don't make me laugh Cevat,
for God's sake!
I'm exhausted,
what hospital are you talking about?
You have to go urgently
to the telegraph office, my general.
The minister of war wants
to talk to you in person.
The minister of war announced
to Mustafa Kemal...
the sultan's command that
he returns immediately to Istanbul.
But he did not obey this command...
that he knew the British
occupation forces dictated...
and he resigned
from all his positions in the army...
in order to continue
the national liberation fight.
He now became a rebel.
The expected decision of death penalty
was issued on May 11th, 1920...
and announced
to all the military troops.
I apologize if I go too far,
but this means suicide, my general!
The corps will have the news...
and General Kazım will execute you,
God forbids.
General Kazım is the one who invited me
to this city.
He wouldn't do such a thing!
But you had
the title of a general, then.
Now you have it no more,
you rebelled against the sultan.
Cevat, sometimes
even though you risk your life...
you have to do what you believe!
There's no way back from now on!
I am already in great pain,
don't make a fuss!
Where did you find these?
I asked from the clerks, my general.
We don't have any money to buy them.
Mr. governor gave his frock.
I'm grateful to them.
Cevat...
Now listen to me.
Yes, sir.
If something happens to me in this
perilous life, find immediately Salih.
He is supposed to take care
of my mother and my sister.
And Fikriye as well.
Yes, sir.
The Caucasian Army Corps commander
General Kazım is here.
Let him come.
I warn you beforehand, my friends.
You won't believe in
what you will shortly hear...
but you shouldn't show anybody
even one page of this notebook.
It will remain secret until the end.
We alone will know of its content.
Yes, sir!
Then put the date.
Write.
After the victory...
the form of government...
will be a republic.
This was the second point.
Thirdly...
the women won't wear chadors anymore.
Fourthly...
the fez will be prohibited.
Instead, hats will be used...
as in civilized countries.
Fifth...
Latin alphabet will be adopted.
Enough, my general!
If I write more of this,
I may die out of heart failure.
My general...
Do you really believe
that all this will become true?
Don't you have any doubts!
What counts...
is to familiarize people
with new ideas.
I'd prefer that you had stayed
as a general, sir.
That's better, Mazhar.
I don't intend to establish
a military dictatorship.
The National Assembly
will be above us all.
We agree with you...
but I don't believe that all this
will be accomplished so quickly.
This rush of yours astonishes me.
Not at all!
You know me, I'm extremely realistic.
I don't have insubstantial dreams.
My firm belief depends on what,
do you think?
I don't know, sir.
On the state of the world.
Our ideas conform
to the course of the world.
Look, all the monarchies collapse
one by one to be replaced by republics.
My comrades...
Timely ideas are never out of place.
Mustafa Kemal established
a civilian assembly at Ankara.
The Greek army that invaded Anatolia
by the support of the British...
approached so near that the sound
of the cannons could be heard.
Fikriye announced that she
wanted to come from Istanbul to Ankara.
She was intending to do the
housekeeping chores for Mustafa Kemal.
Finally, he gave her permission.
Welcome!
Have a nice evening.
Fikriye! What did you do?
It's just a miracle!
To comfort you even a little bit
is the most holy duty.
If I can ever accomplish this,
it's my pleasure.
Thank you, Fikriye.
Please, my friends.
Fikriye...
I have a request from you.
Tell me, brother Mustafa.
Could you uncover your head
for my sake?
But we have men
who are not of the family.
Fikriye...
Here, there is nobody
to misjudge your reputation.
If we are to make a revolution,
we have to begin by our own house.
Please.
Thank you.
Tonight sit in our company
at the table.
Allright, brother Mustafa.
Let's get to the table, friends.
Please take some.
Please.
Thanks.
To the angel who descended from heavens
to our harsh and difficult life...
to Miss Fikriye!
Thank you.
To Miss Fikriye!
I'm really curious about
that Greek commander-in-chief.
I wonder whether
he is a soldier of worth...
whether he can anticipate our plans.
I don't think
that he can anticipate your plans.
Poor man!
He invaded almost half of Anatolia...
but he is unaware that
you're his opponent.
Come on, my general!
You embarrass me.
The general also
is a soldier of your rank.
If he says so, there must be a reason.
Allright, come on.
Let's make a toast to the greatest
commander of the world, Mustafa Kemal!
Sergeant Bekir?
Yes, sir.
Play a nice record on the gramophone.
This record is scratched,
it's no good.
To your health!
Fikriye...
You made me so proud tonight,
I thank you very much.
The cause of my life is to make you
happy, brother Mustafa.
I will ask you something.
Why did you remove that record?
That was a folksong from Thessaloniki.
We, the people of Thessaloniki,
bear a wound.
I was afraid
that you would become over sensitive.
Well thought.
It wouldn't be right beside my friends.
But now we, two people
from Thessaloniki, are alone.
Come on, play that record.
What if I myself play it to you
instead, brother Mustafa?
A storm took us...
in the sea we are swept away
We'll be reunited, my love...
only on the Judgment Day
After that day, Fikriye never said
"brother" to Mustafa Kemal.
She always addressed
him as "my pasha".
Was having all the victories.
The enemy is encircled.
Let the attack begin!
The war is a disaster, my son.
It forces innocent people
to leave their home, their country.
Similar to the Turks who ran away
from Thessaloniki ten years ago...
this time the Greeks
were running away from Izmir.
It means leaving the tombs
of your ancestors, your memories...
the streets of your childhood,
your first loves.
You are left only with folksongs
that make you cry.
Long live, Mustafa Kemal Pasha!
By honoring Izmir,
you made all the Turkish nation happy.
And by honoring my house,
you made me happy.
Welcome, my pasha.
Thank you, ma'am.
Your house is truly beautiful.
Please, sir.
The Greek army was scattered
and the government had collapsed
Thesalloniki, with his glorious army
But the Pasha was realistic.
The war was over. From now on
and to the development of his country.
If you permit, my pasha...
Come in, Miss Latife.
Please do sit down.
Thank you.
My pasha, I've been educated in Europe,
I know three languages.
If you wish, I can be your translator.
Can you write an ultimatum in English?
Of course, my pasha.
Please do write.
To the concern of the consulate...
of the empire of Great Britain
at Izmir...
We find most appropriate...
that you withdraw in 24 hours...
your war vessels...
presently anchored
at the port of Izmir.
While entering Izmir...
I said that I would burn in regret
if we damage this beautiful city.
But now I see...
that Izmir...
is burning before our very eyes...
though we have reconquered it.
It's a pity that some burning houses
belong to your family, don't they?
Let all our asset burn, my pasha.
All of Izmir can burn.
Just so you are allright...
just so nothing happens to you.
We can create a new Izmir
just by your command!
So you trust me that much?
Who am I to trust you, my pasha?
I've been for many nights
on this terrace...
crying while looking
at the foreign ships at the port.
I used to say: "Come, Mustafa Pasha.
Come, Mustafa Kemal Pasha."
Don't, child.
Please, don't.
Don't cry anymore.
Come on,
wipe the tears from your eyes.
In the middle of Manastir
There is a pool, a nice pool
The girls of this land are all cool
We just play and dance
Thank you very much, Latife.
You reminded me of my childhood.
This hospitality, this music...
translations from foreign newspapers
in the mornings...
I really got used to it.
I don't know what to do
back in Ankara!
That's easy, my pasha.
You can take me to Ankara with you,
that's just it!
Right.
During our stay of three weeks there...
Latife organized excellent feasts...
she played for the guests
European style pieces on piano...
she translated
Mustafa Kemal's writings.
Now in his eyes...
she became the female
figure representing
the modern Turkey he wanted to create.
Everything was turning out to be
to poor Fikriye's disadvantage.
Fikriye was representing the Orient...
while Latife...
was the Occident.
Fikriye was the past...
Latife the future.
It's such a beautiful creature,
isn't it, Fikriye?
Yes, my pasha.
It's such a pretty dog.
When I despaired about everything...
I dreamed of settling in a farm...
living with dogs and horses.
I wish that had been true, my pasha.
Then I would be your eternal servant.
You're here by my side in any case.
Yes, but my pasha...
I just don't know.
What are you afraid of, Fikriye?
They say that you met a girl at Izmir.
Apparently,
she is much superior than me.
Educated...
speaking many languages.
Fikriye...
Don't mind all this.
You're irreplaceable.
I can't live without you, my pasha.
I just can't live.
Fikriye?
You never told me about your disease?
That's not a disease, my pasha.
I just have a tooth bleeding.
I should have known better.
Your elder sister had also died
from tuberculosis.
We go immediately to the mansion,
we'll call the doctors.
My pasha...
My pasha, please!
I can't do without you!
Please!
Fikriye, off to the mansion
immediately!
My pasha, please!
Even though I'm destined to die...
I'd like to die by your side.
Don't even mention death, Fikriye.
You'll get over this illness...
and you'll come back.
I will wait for you here.
Come on, get in the car.
Farewell.
The doctors found that the tuberculosis
of Fikriye was very progressed.
Her illness was a peril
to both herself and the pasha.
So they decided that
she goes to a sanatorium at Munich.
I just can't stand the idea that this
magnificent palace will be his tomb.
Every time I think that he will die,
it's as if my head explodes.
I don't believe that any of us can feel
this as deeply as you do, Mr. Salih.
You spent all your life together,
right?
Yes.
Since we were six years old...
we studied in the same schools.
Forgive me if I take too much liberty,
Mr. Salih...
but I want to ask you something.
Go ahead.
Haven't you ever get jealous
of your friend?
Do you ever wonder
why he has risen up so higher than you?
After all, we're all human beings.
You asked me an interesting question,
Doctor.
Let me figure it out.
Have I ever get jealous of him?
I don't know.
Maybe at the beginning, I have thought
why I couldn't be as eminent as him.
But later on, I assure you
that I never had such a feeling.
This is...
how should I say...
this is something like...
you know...
Could you get jealous
of the Mount Ararat?
Or of a cloud passing by in the sky?
Or of the Mediterranean Sea?
So getting jealous of Mustafa Kemal...
is such an irrational thing for me.
I see, Mr. Salih,
I understand you very well.
Welcome.
Thank you, my child.
Thanks.
Here she is, mommy.
This girlie is Latife.
Come here.
Salih, she's such a beauty!
Her ladyship spoils me!
You really are
Mustafa Kemal Pasha's mother!
Yes, I am...
but he doesn't resemble me,
I do resemble him.
Come.
Miss Latife welcomed Zübeyde Mum
in her mansion for ten days.
She revered her in every way, but
Zübeyde Mum's health was deteriorated.
In the meantime, her ideas about
Miss Latife had changed dramatically.
This is my will to you.
He shouldn't marry that girl.
Allright.
My son shouldn't be unhappy.
Take this to my Mustafa.
His father gave it to me.
She wanted so much
to come to Ankara to warn you...
but suddenly she got worse.
Since I believed
that you would be happy with Latife...
I never told you about her wish.
So all this is because of me.
Your marriage...
all those terrible events...
your heart attacks...
Zübeyde Mum was right.
She had seen the reality...
but I concealed it from you.
Only now I confess it, my general.
I'll never forgive myself.
Sergeant, why did we stop?
My general,
there is an urgent telegraph for you!
I know, my mother died.
Yesterday night I had a dream.
I was strolling in the meadows
together with mom, then came a flood...
and took my mom away.
Now I'm left with my people.
My condolences to you, my general.
Let us continue, sergeant.
Yes, sir!
Mom...
Good morning.
The Turkish leader Mustafa Kemal Pasha
married two weeks ago
Cemal, are the roses ready?
And remove this mess in the middle
of the room, I don't want to see it.
Don't forget that the orchestra comes
for the evening.
Look at this!
I hope you'll do some dusting here!
I want you to remove this cloth.
Don't forget that all the waiters
will wear gloves.
Gloves!
Good morning, my dear.
Good morning.
Latife...
They're not waiters, but soldiers.
They don't wear gloves!
What are you up to, Latife?
I'm just trying to embellish
this outmoded house.
I'm trying to introduce
some civilization here.
I told you, they're to go downstairs,
not upstairs!
Enough, Latife!
Allright.
Look, let us make a deal.
Do whatever you want with the rest of
the house, just don't touch my study.
Allright?
Allright.
For the moment, let's do so.
Following long debates
at the assembly,
everybody cried "Long
live the Republic!"
The Ottoman empire of 600 years
became history officially.
This would be followed
by the abolishment of the caliphate...
the revolution in clothing...
and the adoption
of the Latin alphabet.
All of these were coming
like thunder, successively.
But in the meantime,
there came another person.
An unexpected guest.
I came to see the Pasha.
Yes ma'am, may I help you?
Did you have an appointment?
No, but he knows me well.
Oh, welcome Miss Fikriye!
Welcome!
Thank you, Cemal.
You don't know me...
but in fact
I'm the mistress of this mansion.
I beg your pardon,
I don't recognize you.
Please sit and wait, while I go and see
whether the Pasha is already awake.
Everything's been changed, Cemal.
Oh ma'am, don't ask me!
It's Mrs. Latife, right?
Excuse me.
A guest at this hour? So strange!
Who is it?
Miss Fikriye.
Fikriye?
Fikriye? Send her away!
Send her away immediately!
Ma'am, please don't get upset.
Mr. aide-de-camp, send her away,
that's an order!
Listen, that woman
is a peril to the Pasha.
She came here without his permission,
you'll be responsible of what happens.
Shouldn't we consult the Pasha?
He is sleeping, you can't disturb him.
Off you go to do your duty now!
Yes, ma'am.
Now!
Ma'am, the Pasha is sleeping.
I'm not entitled to disturb him.
Wake him up!
Say that Fikriye is here!
Ma'am, I can't disturb him.
You better go now, and
come back at a more appropriate time.
I won't go anywhere!
Ma'am!
I beseech you, be reasonable.
You can't stay here.
Sir...
You say I can't stay here,
but this is my own house!
Ma'am, I must definitely say that...
you have to leave here immediately.
She should leave!
Ma'am, please.
What is this gun?
Give it to me.
Ma'am, give it to me.
This pistol is the present
of Mustafa Kemal Pasha to me, sir.
Will you take it by force?
If that is the case,
put it in your purse.
Ma'am, listen to me.
Now it's a security matter.
So I request
you leave here immediately.
Right now.
Sir...
The place you want me to leave
is my house.
If you don't believe me,
ask the servants.
Will you cast me out
from my own house?
Ma'am, please.
Please.
My pasha!
Ma'am!
Ma'am, please!
My pasha!
Fikriye?
Send that woman away!
My pasha!
Go ahead!
This unexpected tragedy ruined all.
He was unable to recover for months.
My son, how can you keep this
as a secret?
But my father made me swear.
How can you swear for this, Muzaffer?
Maybe your mother
will convince Mr. Salih.
My God, I hope we're not late.
Good morning.
You're an early riser today.
Yes, you looked tired,
I didn't want to wake you up.
Thanks.
Look, Kemal.
You're on the cover
of even Time magazine.
They praise you for creating a modern
state from an ancient feudal society.
But everybody praises you.
Even your former enemies.
I was surprised most
by the former British prime minister.
The man who once said "The Turks
should be exiled to Central Asia"...
says now that...
"A genius comes to world
every few centuries.
This chance is now granted
unfortunately to Turks."
Leave all this aside.
What really concerns me
is your attitude.
You torment me.
What's wrong?
What more?
You embarrass me in the crowd.
Bad temper, disputes...
I don't want to hurt you...
I bear it...
I show patience...
but you are way out of line.
Kemal, I'm tired of sitting around the
same table every night with those men!
They are my comrades.
Well, it's not how an marriage works!
Yes, but these are not ordinary times!
We're building a civilization here!
Please, try to understand, Fikriye.
Fikriye?
Latife!
Soldiers!
Were you wrestling in the village,
child?
Yes, I used to, my commander.
Were you a good wrestler?
Nobody can knock me down, my commander.
I was also a good wrestler.
Can you beat me?
All the world wasn't able
to beat you...
how can I?
Well done, boy.
Now you're done chatting with friends,
and it's turn of the soldiers, Kemal?
That day we all were so scared.
When he pulled himself together...
he told me to send Latife immediately
to Izmir...
and to start
with the procedure of divorce.
He had been too patient...
but it was his final decision.
Then he never saw Mrs. Latife again.
He didn't answer
her begging letters either.
My general...
Do you hear me, my general?
Do you hear me?
What if you just get up
and run away from this palace?
Tell me, my general.
As you like...
as you always do...
without anybody noticing...
What do you say, my general?
Please.
In the last years of his life...
he took pleasure in...
secretly running away from the palace
and getting in the crowd.
He wanted to observe closely...
the modernization
of the Turkish society.
That day, he was so merry, and wanted
for the last time to dance Zeybek.
But his state of health
did not let him.
At that moment, to my pain,
I saw in his eyes the death.
My general...
My son...
I don't have much time left.
I trust you for the care of
your mother and sisters.
Farewell.
I feel really fine, mom.
Mommy?
You never told me the end of the tale.
Was the mother able to save her child?
But mom...
Salih Bozok, seriously wounded,
was taken to hospital.
He died on April 21st, 1941.
The tombs of Atatürk, Salih Bozok...
Nuri Conker and Miss Fikriye are in
Ankara Mrs. Zübeyde's tomb is in Izmir.
None of them was able to see
Thessaloniki again.
Mrs. Latife died in 1975 at Istanbul.
Venizelos, the Greek
prime minister, nominated...
Atatürk for the Nobel
Peace Prize in 1934.
The republic, founded
by Mustafa Kemal Ataturk...
and his friends, celebrated
its 87th anniversary.
OCR corrected by jcdr