Milica!
I'll go bankrupt!
I can't carry these anymore.
BOSNIA 1992
Milica!
Out of the way!
1, 2, 3, 4...
Let's see if your old man still
has it!
Milos, you have to play with
your head.
Yeah, right! Piss off!
Hey, Eso!
Hey, Luka, you can't be in two
places
at the same time. - Sure, I can!
You see, I can!
Lord! I hope he remembers me.
Hey, Einstein, the coach
has a memory for remembering.
For remembering?
It's been 18 months since we
left Belgrad
Just keep your mind on the match.
Your job's to play.
Hey, Veljo...
My great big friend!
Here's your pension.
I'm glad to see you!
Amazing...
The miracle of life!
Neighbor!
Joksa! Hey, Joksa!
You're too small to scare me...
Get that donkey off the track,
Vujan!
I'll go bankrupt, my dear Veljo.
These are in great demand
and that cow won't carry them.
Why not? - She's suffering.
Can't she suffer in a ditch?
What's it matter where she suffers?
I'll have to use...
a stick.
Get a move on!
You won't get in my way.
What's this? Why is she crying?
She's lovesick.
She wants a train to run her over.
What train? The track isn't
finished yet.
Exactly what I told her.
I'll use the stick on her. - A
stick?
I'm skeptical about that.
People! They've killed Joksa!
Luka!
I have to tell you something!
Just let me get past.
I have to tell you...
Just one word!
The bears are slaughtering everybody!
But Tito shot the last one.
They're pouring in from Croatia.
Beasts from Croatia!
And you just sit here playing!
What beasts?
Why, bears!
They're like ours, only
different.
A bit bigger but with gray fur.
They must be Persian bears.
Not Persian bears!
They're fleeing the war in Croatia.
Is the track OK? - Why shouldn't
it be?
Luka, this is no joke.
Folks are dying and you sit
here playing.
Here, boy!
Radovan!
What's up?
Why won't she leave me alone?
What is it?
Let's stop so I can feed the dog.
Be a darling.
Since when does a goddam mayor
feed stray dogs?
Tell me that.
Since when does a mayor
gobble breakfast in a car?
Can't you see that Lily's in
love?
Paws off my lunch!
Good for you!
Scram!
You're a lawyer, Filipovic.
We made you party secretary.
You know these things better
than me.
That's why I'm telling you.
There are laws, man.
Want to get us arrested?
Only nitwits get nabbed. - Not
crooks?
That's not what I said.
Yes, it is. Fraud is fraud,
however you dress it up.
But the Muslims & Croats do just the same.
- Do what?
Finance political parties
from cigarettes and oil.
Building democracy on freight
trains!
Tito did it for 30 years. - Tito?
Forget Tito. Tito was Tito,
after all.
I'll tell him everything.
If it isn't my dear old
brother-in-law!
Are we ready for Liberation Day?
The band, not the track.
The Serbians are behind.
But our side is on time.
How are my artists?
My lovely music!
Sir, can I speak to you?
Sparavalo, of the Sarajevo
Opera.
Sarajevo! A magic town.
Mr. Mayor... - Wait!
Mr. Cuhaj, our guest artist from Hungary.
A universal artist.
This is going to be OK.
OK, he says...
As president of the town
council,
I would like to express my
gratitude
for the support you've given
our railroad
But we politicians haven't
slept.
Just read this, bro.
Mr. Mayor, if we don't organize a hunt
the beasts will slaughter us all.
"We approve purchase of a
"Sneider-Holstein locomotive..."
This is fantastic!
Not a single Serb will be left!
Look what you've done!
Mr. Mayor, friends,
allow me to present our project.
Here you see the section of
track that
will link Bosnia and Serbia for
12 miles.
Mr. Mayor... - In fact,
the Austrians first built this track
but then it was destroyed.
We now need to rebuild it
to boost tourism and trade.
With this tunnel... - Mr. Mayor!
...we will overcome a major
obstacle...
and be ready for Liberation Day.
Well done, bro!
We are lumberjacks and we're
okay
In the green forests of Bosni-ay
We are lumberjacks and we're
okay
In the hills and mountains of
Bosni-ay!
Listen, hotshots,
let me tell you the basics
about being a goalie.
I can't wait to hear this!
You have to guard that line
regardless of who's shooting.
Is that so? - You bet.
That's why there are no smart
goalies.
Did Einstein say that?
No, you idiot! Wrong again!
It was the coach who said it.
And now Tomo Krotolina's
gonna show you how to shoot.
Where are you going, for god's
sake!
Didn't you say you're fearless,
goalie?
Then come with me.
What for?
Prove that you're fearless.
- Don't pull!
Who's pulling, Mr. Fearless?
But I wanted to go dancing...
No more buts, Eso.
Here comes a goal shot.
You said you're fearless.
What's all this? - Just stand
there!
No, bro, stand there!
You said you're fearless, so
stand still.
Milos Djukic!
Milos!
Come and see our Eso!
Here's a cross shot.
Catch!
Bravo, boss! Bravo, legend!
And now? - Something completely
different.
Watch this trick.
Hold it on your head.
What is this, Tomo? - Hold it
like this.
Put your arms down.
Just great!
Just watch this, Eso!
What are you doing?
Are you nuts?
You crazy fucking idiot!
Shit, I missed!
I aimed for the forehead.
Your turn now, tough guy!
Fuck you! You're crazy!
No problem, buddy. I'll play
the game.
Here's your chance.
I'm emptying the fucking gun! Relax.
A new player calls for fresh bullets.
Eso, this isn't a joke.
Relax, I've got experience.
Uncle Faik bought some guns
cheap.
We've been practicing.
Buying guns now? - Your turn.
Here's a moving target.
Tomo, quit messing around.
Milos, out of the way! - Goddam
you!
Go ahead, shoot, tough guy!
Milos, out of the way!
Here we go!
I don't give a fuck!
If you survive, asshole,
I'll kill you!
I gotta admit,
your uncle's really something.
It's homemade. Have a swig.
It'll calm you down.
We'll get a hunt going.
She won't move.
She's lovesick.
She's waiting for a train to
run her over
Whose donkey is it?
It's Vujan's.
Vujan who? - Vujan Peric from
Zabrdje.
Vujan died five years ago!
But I spoke to him today.
C'mon!
Move!
It's useless!
Is she crying?
I told you she's suffering.
You don't know the secret word.
Move it!
Step aside.
Now whistle.
You're not listening to me.
I don't say speed isn't
important.
But any fool can run fast.
What are you talking about?
Oh God, are You listening to
this?
Sure, He's listening.
Don't upset me, Nada. I never
said that.
I said she looked at her husband
and saw he had big ears.
Know how Napoleon won matches?
You mean battles. - Right.
He'd calculate how fast
his cavalry could reach enemy
lines
and cut them off. Speed's
everything!
You read a lot,
but careful you don't get a
headache.
If you ride a cloud at the
speed of light
you can't see yourself in a
mirror.
I need that speed.
Such speed's unhealthy.
The feeling matters
Know what feeling is? - Tell me.
Talent.
Talent? I'll make a note of it.
You either have it or you don't.
We were given reason
to escape from our upsets
and I'm really upset.
I don't mean Anna Karenina,
I mean me.
I didn't come here for nothing,
you know.
My next stop's the nursing home.
I heard Luka talking to the
director,
but he doesn't know I know.
He told Luka: "No, Luka, please.
"It's too early for Jadranka
"to enter a nursing home.
She'll still
"young, so don't do it."
But I worry for Milos!
You know, a child without a
mother
is like a broken umbrella in
the wind.
Big fish eats little fish.
God, what's wrong with me?
I just want you to know:
Never will I leave this place!
Ever!
Come on, take a pill.
Why don't you take it yourself?
Think I don't know what you're
planning?
Don't even think of it!
You want your son to hear you?
Lie down. Hospital regulations!
Look, he won't let her on a
stretcher!
Come on! - Please, listen to
me...
I want to go home.
I'd change that guy for free.
Just one injection!
His wife sings beautifully.
I heard her on the radio.
There's no nursing home.
Too bad about the dust.
She has an allergy?
An allergy? She's out to lunch.
That's what I call love.
Wouldn't you like to be
carried like that in his arms?
No way! He's not a Muslim.
As if that mattered!
It matters! Ask your dad.
You don't ask dad for
everything.
I want to go home to Milos.
Mouse!
Here's the doctor. - How you
are, ma'am?
Come in.
It's just a minor allergy.
Bosnia! SDA!
I'm gonna buy him into every
team,
right up to the national team.
Djukic, get back!
He can't handle this!
He can handle it. Calm down.
Get back when I tell you!
Is that the kid you mean?
Milos Djukic!
Jadranka, come back!
I'm Milos's mother.
Ah, you're the mother!
Milos's mother.
I'm Zurovac.
You may recall, he played for
"Partizan"
when he was a kid.
He's no. 9. - Nice kid.
Yes, but he's very sensitive.
He's Mommy's little boy.
I'm an opera singer.
I'm taking time off
because of a throat problem.
I'm allergic to dust
so I'm here to recuperate.
Go for him!
Close him down!
I'm the only one who understands him.
I know what it's like to play.
Theatre, soccer, it's all the
same.
"All the world's a stage."
Know who said that?
I have no idea.
Sure, you do.
A name that starts with Sh...
Shekularac?
No, a foreign guy.
"All the world's a stage.
"And all the men & women merely
players."
You mean Shuster? - Not at all.
I have no idea.
Shakespeare.
I don't follow the Premier
League.
This is opening night for Milos.
Everything in life is a stage.
But different things happen on
it.
Am I right? - Sure.
Take me, for instance.
When I sing on opening night,
my throat goes like this...
Look at the poor woman.
The things she does for her son!
She's like Mama Juanita.
Let me see. - It's nothing, just
a ball!
That was awful.
You have to hear me in
rehearsal.
What's her problem?
Have you seen the movie, "Mama
Juanita"?
No.
Then you ain't seen nothing.
What's there to see?
Know what I'd do for my mother?
What would you do for your
mother?
I'd fuck half the stadium for
her.
What a generation!
For you, Mama Juanita
I dedicate this song to you
At the break of dawn
This song is heard
For you, Mama Juanita
I dedicate this song to you
Here it comes!
You abnormal fuck!
What's your problem? Let the
ball in!
Let go of my fishing rod,
you motherfucker!
This is going too far.
Goal!
Milos!
Bravo! You're the champ!
Ma'am, your "Sh" stands for
"champion"!
The classic champion.
Partizan needs a player like him.
Eso!
Stop the fight!
Leave my son alone!
Leave the kid alone, dopehead!
I'll fucking kill you!
You did it, Milos!
Mommy's coming!
Uncle's coming!
I'm coming, my boy!
Leave it to me, Dad! Please!
You band of fucking
nationalists!
Milos!
Bash that one, he's getting
away!
He's getting away!
Tell me exactly what he said.
He said: "Ma'am, your Milos is
the best.
But you know that already.
Spare me your comments.
Mind if I finish?
Secondly, he said he'd phone
in a week's time.
So why didn't he call?
He said if business didn't
prevent him.
He's a very busy manager.
He said: "Partizan needs Milos."
What more do you want?
Anna Karenina had no allergy.
She was visiting her brother
and she took the train home.
No, Nada, he didn't really have
big ears.
She just didn't love him
anymore.
He was supposed to call last
Monday.
He'll call, don't worry. - He'll
call?
It's been a week already.
Not even Einstein would say
that.
What day is it?
I have no idea. - Saturday.
He'll call, I tell you.
Will he?
If he really needed me,
he'd be calling five times a
day.
Are you crying?
No, I'm not.
Looks to me like you are.
Well, you're blind. - You're
crying.
I want to go back to Belgrade.
I want to play soccer there.
Then go, but don't cry.
And you stop shouting. - Who's
shouting?
You're shouting! - I'm not
shouting.
What's more,
you dragged me out here.
Did I?
And you took me off the stage.
Better me than the critics.
What did you say? - Just kidding.
When did I ever have bad reviews?
I know...
Tell me, when?
That's what I'm saying.
Can't a man joke around here
anymore?
Those beech trees don't go with
the house
They're not beeches, they're
linden trees
Something has to smell nice.
What? You want to dig?
Then go ahead.
Wait. Not like that.
Like this. Your foot goes here.
What a sensation!
I feel like blowing up
the whole countryside...
Hey, bro, we won't have a
border here,
will we?
Where do you see a border?
There, Nada. And Serbia's over
there.
Customs in the middle of the
tunnel?
I don't know.
But the border is here.
What a tragedy!
I want to thank you
for turning out in force
to show your readiness at tough
times
to defend your homes
against the wild beasts.
I officially declare this bear
hunt open.
Just a quick word...
What is it, Filipovic?
The party called from Sarajevo
again.
They said:
"Does Radovan know who's in charge?"
Are they threatening me?
Why are they so hung up
on that freight train?
Big deal!
Well, it is big. A million
marks.
That's what I call greedy.
Do you think I'm stupid?
No, but we're farting on our
own candle.
They'll cross us off the map
if we don't play along.
Over my dead body!
No more scams using cripples.
Shame on you!
I have higher connections in
Belgrade.
We'll see who fucks who.
You or me.
Enough of this...
When a young hunter I used to be,
a young girl fell in love with me.
She was so lovely and so fine,
she was my darling, she was
mine.
Before I'd set off to hunt at
dawn,
Her goodbye kiss was like a ray
of sun.
It gave me luck along the track,
a pledge that I would safely
come back.
Rabbit, fox and quail,
partridge and wild duck,
you can catch all these with
luck.
But never will you pick up my
trail.
If only people knew the life to
live.
Happiness is all that life
could give.
Those were days of dreams for
me.
When a young hunter I used to
be...
A bear!
Run!
All clear, Mr. Mayor.
Who leads every revolution?
Who gives us our daily bread?
Who can be pope, king or sultan,
and presides over living and
dead?
It's a man, an intellectual,
he is the cornerstone of
progress.
A gentleman, a professional,
his biography is marvelous.
He can change mud into gold,
turn a stone into a flower.
To create is in his power.
Honey, it's a man's world.
You can build an ark
to save humanity,
you can raise your little finger
to part the waves of the sea.
You can build the peace
or the Great Wall of China,
you can read our dreams,
books and beliefs.
You can make war
transact a NATO pact
You can write history,
constitutions and poetry,
but you do all of this
just because of me.
To conquer a women's heart
is the hardest victory.
It's a man, an individual pure,
for every illness he finds the
cure
He built railroads and great
roads.
Honey, it's a man's world.
Without me,
You're an unfinished rhyme.
you are a sad linden in a
desert clime.
Cities you can build,
or take apart,
You can split the atom,
but not my heart.
You can make war,
transact a NATO pact
You can write history...
The Serbs of Bosnia-Herzegovina
declared
that the murder at a Serb
wedding
was a shot aimed at the Serb
people.
Among conditions are demands
for an urgent resumption of
the...
conference on the
democratization...
Where's Milos?
At Eso's. Where else?
What's he doing there?
He likes the cakes. It's
Ramadan.
He was there last year too.
He should stay away from that
Esad.
Why? He's a good boy.
...the result of yesterday's
murder
of a Serb, Nikola Grdovic,
outside an Orthodox church
in Sarajevo.
Citizens were advised to stay
home.
Although there has been no
fighting,
gunfire has been heard.
You ask why? Look around you.
They're shooting everywhere
and you ask why. Don't you
watch TV?
It's all lies.
It won't happen, woman.
Folks are reasonable here.
The way you talk isn't
reasonable.
Me? What's wrong with you today?
Veljo left a letter for Milos.
It may be from Belgrade.
On the table.
From Belgrade.
Maybe Partizan wants him.
In today's events, one citizen
was killed
and four wounded...
He is to report within 24 hour
to his army unit.
The army!
That calls for a toast!
It's the army, you idiot!
Hey, Dad, if only you were here
to see Milos off to the army.
Fuck you and your railroad!
And damn me for letting you bring
me out here. What's wrong?
What is it, woman? - What is
this?
It's a scale model. - Scale
model?
What are you doing?
You call this a life?
Calm down, woman!
Let go of me!
You call this a life? - Leave
that alone!
You want a dead hero in the
house?
Do you want to have a bust
made for your son?
Idiot! It's not just military
service.
Okay, calm down. - It's a call
to war.
They won't get my child! - Leave
Dad alone
I'm not going back!
I won't go. - Wait!
What is it now?
Upset mother again?
I didn't say a word.
You did.
So why's she crying?
It wasn't me, honest.
A Ramadan cake from Mom!
Thanks, son.
Off I go.
Do you have a spark of
intelligence?
Want to hear something
intelligent?
Yes, tell us. - Come here.
That manager, Zurovac, called.
He made me an official offer.
They want your son to join
Partizan.
Milos Djukic! - That's my boy!
That's my boy!
Milos!
Tomo's got something for you!
Something fancy and modern!
Basic training?
Just basic training, honest!
Filipovic arranged it with the
army.
You can ask him.
Milos!
Hold on, son! Calm down!
What is it?
I don't believe him.
Not a word he says!
You have to do basic training.
Not even God can change that.
That's how it is.
That's how it is? - Yes.
How it is?
As soon as you finish basic training,
you join Partizan straightaway.
Listen to me.
It's all been arranged.
What's this?
Why the long face if it's fine?
Who has a long face?
You know what I mean.
What do you mean, long face?
Just what I said.
Why do you look so miserable?
Miserable?
Oh, son,
I was born that way.
Quick!
Here's Tomo Krtolina,
your Santa Claus!
Where have you been, Tomo?
3, 4...
Come one, come all
Come everyone
When I take my oath this fall...
Go to your mother now.
Mother!
Milos!
Aleksic! - Hey, Luka...
Old pal, where you been?
I have to ask you something.
You're my only hope.
Me, your only hope?
If a soldier's your only hope
you're really in bad shape.
It's about the war. She's
bugging me.
She says he's going to war,
not basic training.
There won't be a war.
There won't?
If everything goes according to plan,
we can avoid it.
Auntie's little honeybunch!
Where will you be stationed?
In Novi Sad. - That's not far!
True.
What's it near to? The battle
zone.
You're as good at geography
as my old lady is.
I've been halfway across Europe.
Just eat. Eat!
I have no one here. Just my son.
And my husband.
Come over here.
I have something to tell you.
Oh, you're so funny!
Our chief's in Moscow.
If they let us,
the military could take over,
and put an end to all this shit.
That means no war?
No war, Luka. - Thanks, Aleksic.
You're a real brother.
Sure, Luka.
No war.
Excuse me! Come over here.
What is it? - Over here.
C'mon, give me a little kiss.
We won't have a war. - Says who?
Someone who knows.
That "someone" will end up
starting the war.
Luka, you poor martyr.
Fuck women and their creator!
Stop playing!
Stop the music!
Stop, when I tell you.
Is Milos serving in Hungary?
Play one of our songs.
Good evening.
I wanna extend a welcome
to everyone here.
And I'd like especially to welcome
the Djani Rebus Band.
Give 'em a big hand!
The song I'd like to dedicate to Milos
as he goes off to the army is "Time's Up"
Karakaj. - Fuck Karakaj.
Never Mind.
Time's up!
I have to go into the army
So long, mom and dad
So long, good old godfather
So prepare my farewell party
And now for the knockout punch!
Momcilo! Momcilo!
What is it now?
The war's started. What are you
doing?
What? What?
The game's on, sweetpea.
But I don't feel it!
Gotcha, you slut!
Godfather Rajko
Let out the dog
To watch over the house
Don't let the wolf
get his paws around
my Red Riding Hood
while I'm away
County Tuzla, village of Karakaj
That's the place I call home
Anybody home?
Anyone to see the soldier off?
Here I am.
Where's mother?
I took her to the hospital.
They're keeping her for tests.
That allergy come pretty often?
It doesn't go away so easily.
In some cases, it's for life.
Get ready. Don't just stand
there.
I'll miss my bus.
Wait!
Kiss Mother for me.
Wait up!
Wait, Milos!
You see? Speed is important.
The feeling's important.
You dropped your wallet, dummy.
Speed and feeling are equal.
They're part of the same
equation.
Take care.
"Kiss Mother for me"
Damn women!
What?
I'll put an end to your
babbling!
Fuck you!
Think what you want
but Veljo is no fool!
Who says you are?
When I use my head things clear
up.
People told me:
Veljo, hide your family! But I
didn't.
Who told you to?
I said: Luka's smart, an engineer.
He didn't hide his wife.
So why should I? - What?
You hid her with the Hungarian.
I told my wife: Off to Serbia
with you!
I didn't hide Jadranka.
But I saw her leave with the
Hungarian.
Listen good,
the railroad is under military control.
From now on, you answer only to
us.
You're in charge of maintenance
and communications.
Report all damage to me.
That's an order.
The tracks must be operational
at all times. Understand?
Look at her! Where are you
going?
Want a train to run you over?
Go on home!
It's useless to talk to you!
What did you bring?
A bit of everything.
What goes into a Bosnian stew?
Everything. Milos loves it.
Hear those explosions?
They're pounding away.
Milos is being transferred here.
Whereabouts? - To Bosnia.
He'll pop in if he's nearby.
I'm scared to be in my house
alone.
I brought a chess set. We can
have a game. Good idea.
What's that?
They're our boys.
Hey, soldier!
Those aren't our boys! Run!
Didn't I say they were pounding
away?
What is it? Not afraid?
Why afraid? They announced a
cease-fire.
A cease-fire?
Fucking cease-fire!
They're pounding away!
I can't hear anything.
You have the first move.
I'm black. - Fine.
Know what my old man used to
say?
What?
That war always comes quickly.
You see it coming.
It rolls in like a flood,
but starts
by surprise, understand? - Yeah.
Let's play, and the hell with
them.
Veljo!
Was that a 120mm shell? - Yes.
Where'd the Ustasha get them?
Genscher sent 'em to the Croats.
Wake up, Luka! - What are you
yelling for?
Where's Veljo? He's not home.
Why do you need him?
Mobilization!
A rocket launcher consists the
following:
The barrel, the rocket inside,
front and rear sights,
and the launch mechanism.
Is that clear?
You, young man.
Step forward.
What in thunderation!
We'll do a little test shot.
See that isolated tree at 250
meters?
That's the target.
Okay, doll, is that clear?
It is.
Take aim...
Fire!
Zowie! What a ricochet!
Good news, your son's here!
Milos! Where?
At the house. The captain drove
him there
Is that the truth?
Why would I lie?
Milos!
Get down, Zujka!
Why are you lying like this?
Stretch out.
Wait up!
Take it easy! Don't overdo it!
Where's my Milos hiding?
Hey, Veljo!
Everything okay at your place?
It really shook last night.
I lost some roof tiles.
You know the real miracle,
nothing happened to the Bosnian stew.
It just got cold.
Oh, my Luka!
My boy visits and I give him
nothing.
What an ass, I fell asleep.
Had any damage?
Come down. I have news.
Could you hand me up that long board,
there, on the ledge?
Come down. I have to tell you
something.
I can't. Tell me.
Come down!
It's not about Jadranka.
Is it Milos?
Is he dead?
Tell me. Is he wounded?
No. Come down!
Tell me what happened?
I'll murder you if I come down!
He's a prisoner.
A prisoner?
Milos, a prisoner?
How did it happen?
The captain will tell you.
Vladan! Get the chopper for the wounded!
On the double!
Captain!
Send your unit to hill 805!
He wants to take Milos's place.
To do what? - To replace Milos.
Transfer me!
You've gone crazy too?
Let's go home. - I don't want to.
Listen.
I won't leave without a mission.
Remember, this isn't your
private war.
I can't take any more. I'll
kill myself.
What?
Vladan, get out. - You haven't
finished.
Get out. - But you haven't...
Dismissed! - Yes, sir.
You'll kill yourself?
Too easy. Death doesn't hurt,
my friend.
It's living that hurts.
Did you know I have a brother?
Or I had one. I don't know.
My Stevan.
It's been two years.
Two years since he disappeared.
He's not among the dead
so I can't bury him.
He's not among the prisoners.
He's not among the living
so I can't hug him.
The man simply vanished!
Vanished into thin air!
I asked for a transfer to Lika.
Know what they told me?
This isn't my private war.
It's someone's war, my dear
Luka.
It's a war for scum.
Not yours or mine, for sure.
We have good reason to believe
that Milos is alive.
We'll find him.
We'll liberate him.
Know how big my Stevan is?
Three times my size.