( INDISTINCT
RADIO COMMUNICATIONS)
PA; You will be asked
to step out of your vehicle.
Please leave the car open
with the keys inside.
Take all personal belongings
with you to Inspection.
landfill-
Think I'm scared, Captain?
You're never scared.
Except when you're scared.
Then I guess you're really scared.
I guess I'm really scared.
WOMAN: So why don't you just
get the hell out of here?
We'll both feel better.
CAPTAIN: Yeah, right.
Look, I can take this trip alone.
No!
No.
Look at it, Karen. Please.
Shit. Why does it keep doing that?
No matter what you do, don't raise
your arms above your shoulders, OK?
Guess I can't salute.
MAN: Get out of the car, please.
(sighs) OK.
PA; You will be asked
to step out of your vehicle.
Please leave the car open
with the keys inside.
Take all personal belongings
with you to Inspection.
Identification?
Travel authorisation to Vancouver.
Proceed.
Let me guess. Yours is
the little one, hers is the rest?
Am I right or am I right?
I've never known it to fail.
Why they gotta change clothes
three times in a single day...
(ALARM)
We got a positive here.
No! It's gotta be a mistake!
Get off me! (Screams)
Goddamn breeders!
Excuse my language, ma'am.
You'd think they'd learn.
Some never do.
Ain't that the truth!
Next.
You tun.
(LOW Hum)
GUARD: Clear. Proceed.
Hey, come on. Come on.
Don't want to leave
her favourite dress behind.
Thanks. Man, I'm just so tired.
You know, we've been
driving all night and...
Hey! This bitch is trying
to get past our machines!
Goddamn fucking flak jacket!
(ALARM wms)
(BAR)
Run! Go! Go!
Oh! Arggh!
(G roans)
(RBI!)
MAN: Don't shoot,
don't shoot him.
MAN: You are under arrest.
Stand up and keep your hands
away from your body!
Alright, call the wagon.
MAN: First runner apprehended.
Second runner, on foot, female.
Crossed the bridge.
MAN ON PA; Hold your position.
Put your hands over your head.
You are under arrest.
I know this place.
Did a feature on this place.
This place is enormous.
Like your mouth, culo.
It's got no windows.
FEMALE VOICE:
Prisoners, your attention, please.
You are about to enter the Fortress,
a privately owned
maximum security prison
operated by the Men-Tel Corporation.
Wasn't supposed to be going here.
So I bounced some cheques!
For that they give me
maximum security?!
FEMALE VOICE: The Fortress
is located in a secluded desert.
No life can survive here.
Escape is impossible.
6O days in here, I gotta do.
That's nada. Short-term, man.
You're only taking a nap.
I never nap.
VVhaFd they get you for?
My wife was carrying
her second child.
One wasn't enough'?
He died at birth.
They tie her tubes?
They said they did.
Guess we got lucky.
Lucky? What did they give you'?
31 years.
You're smiling!
How the fuck can you be smiling'?
She got away.
FEMALE VOICE: You are about to enter
a complete security environment.
Crime does not pay.
MAN: It's 3O storeys high.
How can it be invisible'?
Hey. Calm down. Take a deep breath.
Forget him. He's dead.
He's just scared, OK?
The scared don't survive inside.
Alright, everybody. Strip.
NOW!
FEMALE VOICE: Al! prisoners,
your attention, please.
MALE VOICE: Welcome to the Fortress.
Everything here is the property
of the Men-Tel Corporation.
Including you.
I am Prison Director Poe.
The Federal Government pays Men-Tel
$27 every day for each one of you.
They expect us to put you to use
expanding our facility.
( ALARM )
FEMALE VOICE: Hidden weaponry.
GUARD: Open your mouth! Now!
POE'. The Fortress is alive
24 hours a day.
Take it out of your mouth,
put it in the bin.
POE'. Your work shift will be
determined by our computer, Zed-10.
You will learn to live
without day or night.
These are Psychological Security
Intelligence Systems...
Move it!
POE'. ..P.S.l.S.
Your thoughts
will be with me...always.
Put your heads in.
NOW!
COMPUTER'. Prepare
intestinator tagging.
(Strains)
POE'. You are about to be outfitted
with intestinators,
Men- Te! Corporation's automatic
behaviour control device.
Observe all rules.
Be especially observant
of the yellow and red lines.
Crossing a yellow line
will result in pain.
Crossing a red line
will result in death.
(Gasps)
Crime does not pay.
(Coughs and splutters)
GUARD: Keep it going!
I have an illness.
it's called claustrophobia.
It's a real illness!
Come on! Don't do this!
ZED'. Remain in line.
Do not cross the yellow line.
Nobody listens!
I had a note from my doctor.
ZED'. Yellow is pain.
Look, I can't stay here!
Will you listen?! Listen to me!
(HIGH-PITCHED VVHINE)
"Irwin
Turn it off!
Come on, you can turn it off!
ZED'. Do not cross the red line.
Red is death.
Aaaaaaarrhhh! Shit!
Oh, God, no. (Screams)
Stop! Anything! (Screams)
Stop! Arggh!
GUARD: Move it out! Move it out!
Told you. Dead on arrival.
ZED'. The Fortress is the worid's
largest underground penitentiary,
33 storeys deep.
Please observe the neutron cannons
found at the central core.
They destroy only organic matter.
Prisoners Brennick and Gomez,
get off here, please.
(WOLFWHISTLE)
(WOLFWHISTLES OON11NUE)
Up these stairs, please.
Come with me, please.
Hey. hey, hey, no, no fucking way!
We're not taking any more in here!
We got a crowd already.
ZED'. Complaining is a violation.
So is overcrowding!
ZED'. lntestinaticn will commence
in five seconds. Four...
Come on, man...
Three.
No! Come on, man!
Alright, alright, alright!
Hey, Big Mamma, come on!
The more the merrier.
I mean, really...
Bitch.
Five seconds to enter cell.
Come on in.
( ELECTRONIC CLICK)
What happens if you
just walk out there?
Try it-.
What the fuck is your problem?!
(ALARM)
ZED'. Laser perimeter intrusion.
Step back, please.
Smart fish. Very smart.
You know, the two of you
gotta pay the rent.
I do my own time.
There's all kinds of time.
Think about it.
You don't pay the rent,
me and Maddox come and get it.
That you?
(Man chuckles evilly)
No. Maddox is hard to miss.
He's got a 187
tattooed on his forehead.
Do you know what 187 means, fish?
Bet it's not your IQ.
GOMEZ: 187. Murder statute.
He's doin' the big bitch.
So maybe you wanna
pay the rent after all.
ZED'. 60 seconds to lights out.
Brennick. John.
D-X.
Anywhere you like, man.
Hey, pretty-boy. If your culo's
as sweet as your face...
...come on...you can bunk with me.
Try it, motherfucker,
and you're dead!
(Chuckles) I can wait.
Night-night, sweetie.
(Taunts) Puss-puss-puss-puss.
MAN: Don't dream.
(Both moan softly)
ZED'. You're enjoying this.
Yes, I suppose I am.
Your function
is to monitor and control.
We do not observe
for personal pleasure.
You don't understand pleasure.
Uni'-
lb.
ZED'. It is time for pain.
I'm afraid it is.
POE: This is an unauthorised
thought process.
Aaarrhhh! Aaarrhhh!
What's the matter, fish? Got
a stomach ache? Indigestion, maybe?
(HIGH-PITCHED VVHINE)
(Cackles)
(WHINE FADES )
What's with him?
Huh? Oh, he's a ghost.
Got himself...mind-wiped. Go ahead.
He tried to escape. Big mistake.
The mistake is when
you don't make it.
Nobody makes it out of
this place, man.
Don't believe
everything they tell you.
GOMEZ: Help! Get off me! Stop!
Get the fuck off me, bastard!
Stop it! Leave me alone!
Help! Get off!
Stop it! Help!
Private party!
GOMEZ: Get off me, man!
Come on! It fucking hurts!
MAN: You're mine, faggot.
Get off!
Get off me, man, come on.
(RBI!)
(HIGH-PITCHED VVHINE)
ZED'. Violence will not be tolerated.
ZED'. Prisoners Maddox,
Brennick and Gomez,
you will only be released
from solitary
when the perpetrator is revealed.
I can't...
I can't stand here anymore.
I can't. I gotta get
out of here, man.
Hey, then fry, you little fuck!
Come on, man. You can do it.
ZED'. Are you ready
to identify the perpetrator?
(Spits)
Aaaarrhhh!
I gotta get out of here, man!
Think about being strong!
I am.
You tell 'em, you're dead!
Shut your mouth!
I'm gum in!
ZED'. 915764, are you ready
to identify the perpetrator?
No.
ZED'. Who started the incident?
"I...
It was...
BRENNICK: I did it!
It was me.
ZED'. Prisoner Brennick, report
to Director Poe immediately.
Sit down, 95763.
My name is Brennick.
Of course it is.
Make yourself comfortable.
I am comfortable.
I believe you're acquainted
with Abraham.
He is the very best of our trustees.
I have written some excellent
parole recommendations,
but in all honesty,
I don't know what I would do
if Abraham were to leave us.
John Brennick.
The most decorated captain
in the history of the Black Berets.
Yet you quit in disgrace.
Didn't you?
Lost an entire platoon, I believe.
No business of yours!
So touchy.
I suppose that's understandable.
But still...
...you would not want to lose
this particular former soldier,
would you?
We caught her before she reached
the far side of the bridge.
The law is clear.
One child per woman.
We live on a very small
and fragile planet.
We must maintain
the population balance.
Abortion is illegal, and that
leaves only one alternative.
POE: Oh, she is so beautiful.
Intestinate Karen Brennick.
ZED'. lntestination commencing.
KAREN: Atnﬂiiul
BRENNICK: You bastard!
POE: Zed.
Aaaarrhhh! Aaaarrhhh...
I don't think you realise
your predicament, Brennick.
(HIGH-PITCHED VVHINE)
POE: You have nothing.
You have nowhere to hide.
You are nothing.
I fucked up.
I couldn't handle it, man.
I know.
BRENNICK: You better watch yourself.
HeY--'
...where's the women's section?
Don't even think about it.
Why? Gonna give your boss a report?
He's got his little sisters.
He don't need me.
Where's the women's section?
I am not going to die inside.
You die right here
if you don't tell me.
Ain't that a bitch'?
WWI-WWW“!-
and you're just like
everybody else in here.
You didn't answer my question.
Fuck you.
Levels A...
...and B.
G sesame 3
KAREN: What is it?
The baby's kicking.
I can feel her kicking.
That's fine. It's natural.
I just wanna. . . hold my baby
for a little while.
I know I can't keep her.
But just to see her open her eyes.
I know.
I'm not gonna let them...
take my baby.
ZED'. Remove number 74270.
Oh, no...
Aaaarrhhh!
MAN: Stop her!
(Woman shrieks)
Into the operating room.
Nosed.!
Come on, take it easy.
Need.!
Nosed. Nosed.!
ZED'. Your babies are the property
of the Men-Tel Corporation.
Crime does not pay.
Rise and fuckin' shine, asshole!
(G roans)
(RBI!)
(ALARM)
ZED'. Laser perimeter intrusion.
Step back, please.
(Au yell)
"Ill
ZED'. Shall I intestinate?
No.
Kill him!
Aaaaaaarrrhhh!
(All cheer)
(Calls out vehemently)
(RBI!)
Retract the bridge.
"Irwin
Come on. Get up, Brennick!
Get him!
Come on!
POE'. 42910 is no longer of any use.
I have a death warrant in his name.
Execute it, 95763.
That is an order.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
(CHEERING)
Brennick! Brennick!
John!
(All chant) Brennick! Brennick!
Brennick, Brennick, Brennick!
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
Your sentimentality is touching.
But quite foolish, Brennick.
Prisoners. . .a demonstration.
Let 'em go! Now!
You fucking asshole!
JOHN!
POE: Hold your fire, Zed.
Intestinate John Brennick.
Aaaaarrhhhh!
Random intestination.
(HIGH-PITCHED VVHINE)
Come on! Karen, come on!
(WHINE STOPS)
ZED'. Take John Brennick
to Isolation to await punishment.
Disobedience will not be tolerated.
I owe you an apology.
Not necessary.
(Whispers) Nifio.
GUARD: Come on, man, let's go.
Come on, move out!
Oh, shit, man! Look at...
Oh, man!
Black fuckin' beauties!
"Ill
This is Brennick's bed now.
Oh, yeah? Since when?
Since your friend
got blasted by the splatter gun!
Dickhead!
You look awful.
That bad?
KAREN: Worse.
I was clumsy.
I ran into a brick wall.
Only the wall was moving.
Yoda.
Poe says I should
tell you to cooperate.
You just told me.
He says it's gonna be
very bad if you don't.
Midi!-
He says if I care about you at all,
I would beg you to listen.
What do you say?
I want my husband.
You got him.
John, no matter what you do,
I'll never not love you.
You're real lousy at goodbyes,
you know that?
I always have been.
ZED: Commence procedure.
(HEARTBEAT)
(EERIE GIGGLES ECHO)
(Humid: Inuit)
( BABY CRIES)
Nooooooooo!
John, help me!
Please!
(John cries out in agony)
Noooooooooooo!
(Screams)
(SQUELCHING)
(CHAMBER MUSIC BY BACH PLAYS)
He's been in there for three days.
And no-one has ever lasted four.
KAREN: There's a first time
for everything.
It is in your power
to stop his pain.
But there's a price.
I want you to...
...live here.
To share my quarters
for the remainder of your stay.
Why me?
Why does this music
give me pleasure?
I don't know.
I skipped music appreciation.
L'In...
...looking for a companion.
I'm not real friendly
to anyone who tortures my husband!
(Brennick groans feebly)
Stop it!
You...
What?
Yes, you bastard! Just let him go!
Release John Brennick
from Mind VVipe.
Return him to his cell.
Mother of God!
What have they done to him?
D-DAY: He's a ghost, man.
He's gone.
Bullshit, man! He's breathing!
ABRAHAM: The mind is dead.
The body just don't know it yet.
Welcome home, baby.
ZED'. Shall I intestinate?
(Clears throat)
Just a moment longer, Zed.
This is a fascinating dream.
Quite instructive,
regarding the...
prisoner psychology.
ZED: The presence
of the Brennick woman
is causing you to act
in a non-professional manner.
POE: She's none of your business.
ZED'. Her presence is a direct violation.
POE: I make my own decisions, Zed.
ZED'. Shall I intestinate?
POE: This is an unauthorised
thought process.
It's a very advanced model, isn't it?
Yes, you were a...computer
technician in the army.
I never got near
anything as powerful as Zed.
Of course not. No-one has.
Don't touch her!
M' “W.
If I ever see you so much as
lay a finger on her keyboard
or utter a single voice command,
you and your child will feel a pain
unknown in human history.
(SIZZLING)
Don't touch him, asshole!
You motherfucker!
What the fuck does he care?
He did it to his own fucking self!
No! They did it!
And what are you gonna do about it?
Yeah, right.
(SLUICING NOISE)
(Gasps)
What are you?
I am enhanced.
You're not human. You're...
POE: A monster?
A freak?
(SLUICING NOISE STOPS)
wuss OF GAS)
The Men-Tel Corporation
has transformed me into a more...
...efficient human being.
Once a month, I absorb amino acids,
wasting neither food nor fuel.
When my kind are in the majority,
there will be no more world hunger.
Maw-
You don't sleep, you don't eat...
You can't make love, can you?
But I can love.
Are there others like you?
Not many as advanced, but...yes.
I was one of Men-TeFs first babies.
It was very special.
Oh, my God! You're what they do
with our babies!
Of course.
I saw your wife, Cap.
I saw Karen.
She's getting larger.
You can tell she's pregnant now.
She felt the baby move.
Your baby.
No, no. You know I cannot.
Oh...
...I know.
But have you ever tried'?
This is. . .very special.
I wonder why
I've never tried this before.
How do you feel?
Very happy!
(Taps keys)
ZED'. Why aren't you in voice mode?
(Hits key)
ZED'. Proceed, Director Poe.
John.
(Grunts)
Johnny.
Come here, Johnny. Come here...
Come here, Johnny.
( BO-l-FLE CLINKS)
You don't have to be afraid.
Karen?
That's it.
John.
I'm right here, John.
POE: Karen!
Karen, where are you?
Right here.
I must...be more...moderate...
...in the future.
ZED'. Good morning,
Cell Block Orange, Level F.
30 minutes before
reporting for work.
Somebody...
...get Brennick up.
BRENNICK: I'm awake.
Holy fuck! You're alive!
Shh! Shhh.
How long was I out?
Four months.
D-DAY: No, it's true, man.
You were long gone.
(All laugh)
Alright...
When.
I'm OK. I'm OK.
Wait a minute.
I've been in here that long?
Karen's getting near term.
Don't worry about that.
She's alright.
Did you see her?
Are you strong enough
for the truth'?
Karen moved into Poe's quarters.
That's why he didn't kill you.
No!
She saved herself.
She's closer to the way out.
You'll never get in there.
You do.
That's my job.
I thought I made it clear to you,
I got a parole to worry about.
I'm not gonna jeopardise that
so you can play
some great escape bullshit!
I'm not playing-.
(CHAMBER MUSIC)
We need to talk.
Talk's dangerous.
That's right. It is.
I've been talking to your husband.
I'm John's cellmate.
All this time you
could of told me...
All this time
he has been like a zombie.
Just staring into space
like nothing was there.
Until today.
It worked?
It worked!
Oh, thank God!
I don't know what you did...
...but now he's planning an escape.
Nobody has ever gotten out of here.
He's a good man.
I don't want to see him die.
He won't die. Not if I help him.
I don't know how,
but this is gonna get Karen out.
Let me see that, Cap'n.
Look, I know about these things.
Let me see it.
I'm gonna have to
take it apart, but...
Can you put it back together?
Oh, man. Machines love me, man!
I can take it apart, put it back,
make it tick, yeah!
It's what I did in the world, man!
Mechanic?
No, no. Explosives.
First Intercontinental Bank building.
I blew that safe like
it was fucking butter, man!
Only problem was my partners
didn't appreciate my work.
Turned my ass in.
Why'?
VVell, shit, man,
I blew up the money.
Don't fuck it up.
POE: New pods will be completed
next month.
ZED'. We are still behind schedule.
POE: VVeK/e had some problems
with the bedrock.
ZED'. Five new levels must be ready
by the end of the year.
POE: Yes, yes, yes,
I am aware of that.
(Hits buttons)
Reset your clock, Zed.
All work hours are now 93 minutes.
ZED'. Confirmed.
What are you doing awake?
Oh...l couldn't sleep.
For the sake of our baby
you must get your rest.
D-DAY: Wow!
Oh, man... Oh, man...
Shit... Shit!
Jesus!
What?
This thing is amazing, Cap'n.
She's beautiful!
This thing is a work of genius, man.
Look at this. Look right here.
This is a series of micros.
That's your pain mode, alright?
And this thing right here
is a macro.
That kills you.
And look at this
little itty-bitty thing on top.
That's your nerve clip, man.
I need you to put it back together.
I'm... I'm working on it, man.
And get it out of me.
Look, Captain,
I may be able to set off
a series of charges in this thing,
cause you to throw it up,
but the major drawback on that
is that this bitch is highly sensitive.
We're talking TNT on PMS.
You mean it could kill me?
Definite possibility.
Find another way.
Maybe there is no other way.
VVrong answer. Try again.
If I get it...
When you get it.
When I get it,
I'm going with you, man.
Look, I'm having fun, man.
I'm enjoying myself.
You know how long it's been
since I had any fun?
Going out won't be fun.
No, but...man, it's gonna be a trip.
All you've got to do
is take it to him.
All? All? Fuck the dumb shit.
That is a pretty big all.
Look, I know it's dangerous,
but I'm asking you anyway.
Let's say I don't get mind-wiped?
VVhaFs gonna happen to my parole?
Truth is you're not gonna
get a parole, and you know it.
You hold on to the hope
because you're a man,
because you keep something inside
of you none of them can touch.
But this is your chance
to fight back.
Fight for who? You? Your husband?
I've never begged before in my life.
Please, Abraham. Please.
If you won't do this for me,
do this for my baby.
I gotta get this back
before he finds out.
GOMEZ: What is it?
it's a map.
Haven't you guys ever seen
a holographic lens before?
Only problem is we need a laser
to make this thing work.
We got a laser.
You gonna stick your hand in there?
Now that's entertainment.
We need something to hold it.
Hey, wait a minute. Take that.
We got something.
I'll be goddamned!
Whoa!
Look.
This could be a way out.
D-DAY:
Hold it steady!
I'm any, um.
This thing is just heating up.
Sorry.
We go in through
the construction area here.
Through this heating pipe. See?
It feeds into this utility shaft,
which goes all the way up...
D-DAY: Shit! Wait a second.
Ow! No!
Shit!
Q'-
We don't get that fuckin' lens,
we're all dead.
Fuck the lens.
I need my glasses, man.
Move over.
Did you get it, man?
BRENNICK: Aaarrrrgghh!
ZED'. Laser perimeter intrusion.
Step back, please.
Shit, man, don't you hurt?
Yeah!
How's the lens?
It's fine. The motherfucker's fine.
Whoa!
You should see what you fools
look like through this thing, man!
WOW!
POE: I want you...
...to divorce your husband.
That's not part of our bargain.
He will never leave this place.
You will never see him again.
He's become a cog
in the Fortress's grand design.
Let me show you.
Your husband is but one of many
whose only reason for being
is the expansion of our facility.
Hon.
(NO)
Have you touched this?
No.
I noticed there was dust on the lens
so I thought it'd be best
if I clean it.
You fool, you smudged it!
Do you know what it will cost
to repair this map?
I beg your indulgence.
This will have a bearing
on your parole!
I'm sorry.
Divorce your husband.
Marry me.
And I will request permission
from the Men-Tel Corporation
to raise the child as my own.
I'm telling you...
...I will not enhance your child.
Does this mean nothing'?
And John?
I will set him free.
Karen has to tell the man
yes or no by tomorrow night.
Good. We go tomorrow morning.
Hey! Time's up.
I think I got it, man.
Check this out.
Right there. Now look.
Here's something, yeah?
It's a magnetic detonator!
So'?
Didn't you go to grade school?
You get two magnets,
put a piece of paper in between,
YOU move one...
You can pull it out of us!
Well, yeah... In theory.
I haven't tried it yet.
I may just set it off,
give this cell a coat of red paint.
I don't know.
Let's find out.
What, you mean like right now'?
You got a better time?
No, man!
You turn into a burrito
and what happens to the rest of us'?
STIGGS: Try me.
I'm going with you.
GOMEZ: No way!
Look, you gonna do it...
...or what?
OK.
Er...
This might hurt a little bit, OK?
Where are you, man?
I Q I.
( Uuue )
Quit...fucking around, you asshole!
God! Shit!
Oh...God...
Oh, God. Get it out of me.
Asshole! (Groans)
Hey, hey, hey, no hurry, no worry.
Stop fooling around!
Get the damn thing out of him!
Yeah? VVhds fooling around?
I can't get this thing. it's stuck.
Come here.
I can't...
What are you...?
(Retches and gasps)
Fuck. Fuck. Oh.
It's OK.
OK.
My turn.
Alright, man.
Somebody take notes, man.
After I finish with you, I won't
be able to do this on myself.
I'll do it to you.
After you do it to me.
What about your parole?
Parole? Bullshit.
It's time I woke up.
I'm going with you.
No. it's too much of a risk.
Afraid?
Afraid you'll lose us'?
Like you lost your platoon?
I don't ever want to be responsible
for another man's life again.
Hey, man...
...I'll speak for myself.
But it's better to die trying
than to die in here.
Right on, man.
Fuckin' A.
I haven't dreamt in 4O years.
John Brennick
is thoroughly rehabilitated
and is hereby granted
a full pardon.
He is therefore
free to leave the Fortress...
ZED'. Before completing
the documents,
there is something you must see
in Central Control.
Not now, Zed.
ZED'. I insist.
Well?
ZED: Please observe.
How dare you spy on my quarters?!
ZED'. A report has been filed
with the Men-Tel board of directors.
You are being relieved
of all responsibility.
Your replacement will be here
within 24 hours.
Until then,
you are confined to quarters.
Confined to quarters?
I've never left these quarters
in my entire life.
ZED'. You are the property
of the Men-Tel Corporation.
But I am the director
of this institution!
ZED'. You will please leave
Central Control.
Crime does not pay.
Fight!
ZED'. Construction area altercation.
Prisoners Maddox, Brennick...
Maddox?
...%, 6on0:
it's impossible.
Fntestination will commence...
No!
...ll 5000001
Zed! No!
ZED:
Maddox is dead!
ZED: "bu, ma.
Let's go! Come on!
3°-P-P-Pl
Get in there!
Zed, they're escaping
and you will be responsible!
Do you know what they'll do to you?
You will be lucky
if you end up a Speak 'n' Spell!
Random intestination! Pain mode!
(SCREAMING)
They're in the pipe.
Open the steam valves
and clear the construction site.
Activate the strike clones.
Shit, man, I thought
this was the way out!
It is the way out !
D-DAY: Not through that!
Come on.
STIGGS: Let's get out of here.
Come on! Move, move, move!
STIGGS: Out of here!
(ID-k Inuit)
WWII)
"fill Nﬂﬂ
POE'. Attention, prisoners.
Surrender immediately
and you will not be harmed.
Prisoner Brennick, I have your wife.
You have 10 seconds to surrender.
Don't do it, man!
Fuck you! This is our only chance!
Hey, man, you go, you're dead!
I'm not gonna be boiled alive here!
No, stay down, man!
Get away from me! I'm coming out!
Noooooo!
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
Jesus!
This way.
Oh, Jesus!
Come on. We're outta here.
Zed warned me our relationship
was not in the best interests
of Men-Tel.
I ignored her.
Foolish me.
Get out of the way.
Intestinate Abraham, please.
(HIGH-PITCHED VVHINE)
(Abraham laughs)
Now get the fuck out of the way.
No!
What the fuck is it?
D-DAY: This thing
is incredible, man!
TheyK/e wired a person
into the mainframe!
The perfect soldier.
Nerve-capable firing pins!
Oh, the shit they're
coming up with these days!
Gil (I)
Let's move.
(RBI!)
Take cover!
ZED'. Activate second strike team?
Accelerate strike clone
reaction time.
(All cough)
This way.
"Lulu
Splatter gun to construction level.
Captain! I can't see, man!
I'm blind as a bat!
Shit!
Captain! Where are you, man?
Captain? Is that you?
I can't see!
Where are you?
Captain!
Nifio! Let's go! Come on!
POE: Shoot them, Zed.
ZED'. Cannot lock on target
without intestinators.
GOMEZ: Come on, bitch!
Peek-a-boo!
POE: Get that gun out of there!
Get me outta here, man!
We're taking the express! Come on!
Wham': Nib?
Oumcn, um.
BRENNICK: Nifio!
(GENERAL COMMOTION )
Look! Look!
(CHEERING)
Shhh!
Where are they, Zed'?
ZED'. No visible recognition.
(DISTANT CHEERING)
Come on, move. Move!
Brennick.
You're gonna pay, you bastard.
Karen! Karen!
Where is she?
Do you want to see your wife?
Operating room A.
KAREN THROUGH SPEAKERS:
No! No!
(Screams) No, no, no!
Mu-ID...
POE: You see, in this operation...
...only the child survives.
M ll...-
"orchids;
Tell them to stop!
(GASPING FROM SPEAKERS)
KAREN: John!
NOW!
Z“...
...cease delivery.
ZED'. I am sorry.
I do not recognise the command.
Zed. . . please!
Men-Tel will not negotiate
during hostage situations.
Oh, shit.
OK, we're going to
the operating room now! Come on.
ZED: Poe...
No!
ZED'. ..l cannot allow you
to put the Fortress in jeopardy.
What's going on, man?
(BEEPING)
ZED'. You are trapped here, Brennick.
A team of strike clones
are on the way.
There is no escape.
Captain! Get me to
the computer keyboard, man.
Big Mamma runs this show.
She's the one we gotta fuck up!
(Taps keypad) OK.
Alright.
Here goes nothing, man.
D-DAY: A feedback virus, man.
In-fucking-capacitating.
OK.
D-DAY: OK...
OK!
Nosed.!
( ELECTRICAL WHIRRING )
(Karen screams)
(WHIRRING)
(CONFUSION OF ZED COMMANDS)
Janus.
(WHIRRING)
Holy Mary, Mother of God...
BRENNICK: VVeK/e got to move out.
I'll meet you in Transport.
We're getting out the way we came in.
MAN: What's going on'?
The light over here.
Aaaarrhhh!
Hold her down! Hold her.
( MULTIPLE ALARMS)
John!
Karen!
KAREN: I'm in here, John!
MAN: Malfunction! Hold her!
I'm in here, John!
Let her go!
Come on, man! Come on!
( FADING CRY)
(GENERAL COMMOTION )
It's dead.
Move over.
Shit!
(BEEPING)
OK. Now the door.
We got to open the door.
KAREN: There's gotta be
an emergency override.
Come on, come on, come on.
GOMEZ: Look! You did it!
(Laughs)
Here we go.
ZED'. No-one escapes the Fortress.
Crime does not pay.
(All laugh)
KAREN: Oh, Jesus!
BRENNICK: What is it?
My water's broken.
GOMEZ: She's having the baby!
You better pull over, man.
Not until we cross the border.
Try to hang on.
( BABY CRIES)
(Bl?!)