(WHIMPERING)
(CHAINSAW REVVING)
(CHAINSAW BUZZING)
(THUDDING)
OPHELIA: Just because I'm
telling you this story
doesn't mean I'm
alive at the end of it.
This could all be pre-recorded
and I could be talking to you
from the bottom of the ocean.
Yeah,
it's that kind of a story.
Because things just
got so out of control.
But let's go back to where it started.
Here, in paradise.
Where they say God parked
Himself on the seventh day,
but they towed
Him on the eighth.
And this is Ben and Chon's
hole-in-the-wall by the sea.
Paid for in cash.
(WOMAN MOANING)
Not bad for two
young Laguna dudes
who are definitely not
employable on Wall Street.
Chon is a killer.
Two tours. Iraq, Afghanistan.
And he came back
with a lot of cash,
but no soul.
He's always trying to
fuck the war out of himself.
I have orgasms.
He has war-gasms.
So, I guess I try
to give him back
some of the things
that he's lost.
Chon is the love of my life.
Call me O.
I was named after Ophelia,
the bipolar basket-case in
Hamlet, who committed suicide.
So I cut it down to just O.
Dope's supposed to be bad,
but in a bad,
bad world, it's good.
Chon says drugs are a rational
response to insanity.
Mmm.
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
Chon, you want some?
What is it about porn
that you guys like so much?
What is that?
Is that Iraq?
No. Mexico.
Where's Ben?
Isn't he still in Burma?
No. Africa, someplace.
Saving Africans.
He said he was going to
be gone three weeks.
That's changing, O.
Let's get some air.
Come on.
OPHELIA: I guess you've
figured out by now,
if people are willing to go
”Henry VIII” on this,
Chon and Ben grow some of
the best weed in the world.
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
(HORN HONKS)
Bring the bags in. Thanks.
OPHELIA: Oh, yeah,
this is Ben.
Ben!
The other love of my life.
Oh, my sweet lotus.
Oh, my sweet Ben.
How was Africa?
You know,
I started in Burma
and then I took a left
and ended up in the Congo.
But if you're serious...
Good thing I'm tough.
Chon-boy.
Good to see you.
It's good
to see you, man.
You all right?
Here, look.
You got any
of that Lomotil?
Lomotil? Yeah,
I put some in your room.
Suck on some
ice cubes, man.
You look like shit.
Yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
Place looks good, though.
Thank you, O.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Shut up. You're a jerk.
He didn't do anything.
I know, I know.
Here, you've been
taking care of my babies?
Huh?
Too busy making
some of your own?
(SCOFFS)
Listen, I'm going to
go catch along swim.
We'll talk
business later, okay?
Hey.
OPHELIA: Every successful
business has an origin story.
Microsoft and Apple
were born in garages.
Ben and Chon's was
born on the beach.
Ben went to Berkeley and
double-majored in business and botany.
Chon was between deployments.
And they've been
buddies since high school.
So one day,
they're sitting there
thinking about what they're
going to do, and Ben says...
So where do you think the best
cannabis in the world comes from?
Easy.
Afghanistan.
Ding! That was
the ”founder” moment.
So, Chon, from the most
dangerous ground in the world,
smuggles back
the finest seeds.
It grew.
Within six years,
they had a couple of farms
and a great customer base.
Yo, try this.
It became urban legend.
If you ask any serious head
where the best dope in the
world in the 21st century is,
it's not Thailand, Jamaica,
and certainly not Mexico.
THC is testing 33%.
I ran it twice. There's
got to be a glitch.
I think we
just struck gold.
It's right here
in California, USA.
Ben says every
plant needs love.
He sees himself as a healer.
Then when I started
to help out at the grow-op,
he called me his
own lotus in water.
I like that.
They partner in
several dispensaries
and supply many of
the clubs in California.
And it's progressive
because from what
I've seen, at least,
it helps with the pain.
Fifteen million satisfied
customers can't all be wrong.
But the big money comes
from shipping it out of state.
That's the 50.
At high prices, they get
up to $6,000 a pound.
Ben's guiding philosophy
is basically Buddhist.
Don't fuck with people.
His true genius is
that he takes 99%
of the paranoia and violence
out of the business.
The other 1%?
That's where Chon comes in.
Chon's philosophy is
basically Baddhist.
WOMAN: Get off me, fucker!
Don't fuck with Ben.
What?
The money, Brett.
I got your fucking money.
(GUN COCKING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
OPHELIA: For Ben,
the dope business is green.
His foundation has branches
in Africa and Asia.
”Money isn't enough," he says.
”You've got to
give your heart."
OPHELIA: Hey, don't ever go
away on me again.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I really missed you.
Tell me that again.
I
really
missed you.
OPHELIA: I know
what you're thinking.
”Slut,” right?
And maybe it is wrong.
But the truth is we all
love each other so much.
We trust each other,
we take care of each other.
And for me, together they
are one complete man.
Chon is cold metal.
Ben is warm wood.
Chon fucks
and Ben makes love.
Chon is earth
and Ben, spirit.
And the one thing
they have in common
is me.
I am the home that
neither of them ever had.
And they're mine.
I really missed this
with you.
Good swim?
Exhilarating.
No sharks?
Not in the ocean.
They knew
you were coming.
They want to meet.
Tomorrow.
Let's make a deal.
Big mistake.
Are we really going to get
caught up in this shit, Chon?
We could get out of a business
we want to get out of anyway.
What if I'm not
ready to walk away?
(SCOFFS)
Then you run it.
That's not what I do.
Then let me do what
I do best, all right?
We built this, it's ours.
Why the fuck do you
want to give it away?
You see that video?
I've seen worse
and I'd do worse to them.
Yeah, and I wouldn't.
They're going to think
we're afraid of them.
I am afraid of them.
I'm not.
We're not all you, Chon.
I didn't get into this
thing to kill people.
You don't get it, do you?
It's a jungle thing, Ben.
When they smell your fear,
they like it.
They will attack us.
They're fucking savages.
Surrender
is not defeat, Chon.
You're resisting change.
Just let it go.
Uh-oh. Testosterone.
Close your legs,
it's showing.
Sorry.
I was talking to him.
Hey, can you boys
take me out somewhere nice?
Come on. We can drink
a little, relax.
It's been a while.
OPHELIA: This is Lado.
He is a man of many skills.
Gardening is just his day job.
I'm going to go
take a shower, baby.
You want to
come join me?
Absolutely.
Ah-ah. Not yet.
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
Baby, did you
order a fucking plant?
Roberto Rodriguez
wants a refund.
Whoa, whoa.
Look, you hire a lawyer,
you pay him, win or lose.
Roberto knew the deal.
That much coke? There's no
"get out of jail free" card.
So, instead,
you do all his coke
and miss all
the motions and objections.
You turn
a five-year stretch into 20.
Mijo, take a look.
He figures you owe him
15 years of his life.
Okay, I got it.
I can still help the guy.
I got juice. I'll file
an appeal, all right?
I got money. How much does he need?
Name a price.
He doesn't want your money.
He wants your years.
How old are you,
exactly?
Forty-two. But what...
Roberto says to shoot you
in one knee, make you 52.
Both knees, 62.
Stop, please!
Sound fair, Mr. Lawyer?
Just give me a fucking chance to talk.
I can help you, okay?
How can you help me?
How?
I can hook you up
with El Azul, that's how.
Why would that
be good for me?
Because he's
going to win.
Because you know Elena Sanchez can't
cut the shit in this business.
Azul knows
the turf in Mexico, man.
He's buying your cops, your judges.
He's political, man.
He's coming fast,
it won't be long.
You want on his train?
I can stamp your ticket.
I pick up that phone,
and you're in.
Go ahead, pick it up.
Okay. All right.
(DIALING)
(MAN GREETING IN SPANISH)
Hey, it's Chad.
Tell el Jefe "Chip,"
though.
I need to talk to him right away.
I got good news.
So, pal, who do I say
is calling?
(REPEATS IN SPANISH)
George Lopez.
Now you're 52.
Senor Azul.
(QUESTIONS IN SPANISH)
(SCREAMING)
Tell me, was it El
Azul who tell you
to take a dive
at Roberto's trial?
Fucking prick!
Bueno! Bueno!
Yes or no?
No!
No answer? Now you're 62.
EL AZUL: Bueno!
Hola!
Azul, it's Lado.
Remember me?
(CURSES IN SPANISH)
(SCREAMING)
God damn it!
Oh, we're just making gringo-lawyer
soup here in the kitchen.
ESTEBAN: Lado? Lado?
(SCREAMS)
No!
Ya te metiste
al pozolero culero.
Azul, how was Tijuana?
Bad boy,
bombing our warehouses.
Elena says you're going to need
a better lawyer in the north.
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
Watch the yelling. It's bad
for the blood pressure.
You have a nice day, too.
WOMAN: No! No!
Do her!
No. No!
(WHISTLES)
No, please!
You want to fuck her?
No, pero...
If you don't,
she'll be a witness.
And we don't
leave any witnesses.
Pull that trigger gently.
Now. Pull it!
(SNAPS PHOTO)
OPHELIA: Dennis Cain is a
high-level drug enforcement agent.
Without this guy, Ben and Chon
would be out of business.
Nice day.
But I shouldn't be seen in the
same zip code as you guys.
Would you prefer we
come to your office
in San Diego with
your gift bag, Dennis?
Oh, take it easy, sailor. What's
got your panties in a wad, now?
Avid clip.
From, I think,
the Baja cartel,
featuring seven
decapitations.
Talk about your
hostile takeover.
BC moving in
on you guys?
Come on, Dennis. What
the fuck is going on?
What's going on is
you're not the only
indie frogs on the stove,
my man.
They're killing each other
down there in Mexico way.
And that's why
they're moving north.
The forks are out,
the pie's getting smaller.
Why is that?
Too many cops with their
hands in the pie, Dennis?
That's just it.
We used to keep
the animals in the zoo,
but now,
with this war on drugs,
it's like the war
in Iraq, Chon-boy.
Your point is what?
Why is it they
want our business
when they put out 35 million
pounds of grass last year?
Because your THC levels
are off the fucking charts.
They're like 30%, right?
Thirty-three.
Depends.
Yeah, and their schwag is what?
Three to five?
Come on, man. They're Wal-Mart,
man, you're Ben and Chon.
They want a Ben and Chon
section in aisle three.
Okay? What's so
difficult to comprehend?
Fine, tell them to
move their shit indoors
and buy their
own fucking lamps.
Well, welcome to
the recession, boys.
You should be grateful you still
have a product people want.
So you don't mind if your envelope
gets a little thinner, then?
(CHUCKLES)
You guys, you guys.
You have a clean business,
there's no problems.
But there ain't no Ben
and Chon without Dennis.
So, my envelope
stays the same.
It's just
a matter of time, guys,
before they
legalize this shit.
Don't fuck
with Wal-Mart.
I'd take the deal
instead of decapitation.
You know?
Keep banging that
sweet California ass.
You guys had a good run, man.
Just embrace the change.
I'll see you.
Dennis, that new stuff
helping with the chemo?
Yeah. Yeah, His
Thanks, Ben.
I'll send some more of that over.
How's she doing?
She's dying, you know?
(COCKS GUN)
Aw, man. I thought this was
a business negotiation.
You saw the video.
Yeah, that was Mexico.
This is Laguna.
And cops here wear shorts
and ride bicycles.
That's why we're
thinking of running.
You start running,
Ben, you never stop.
Now look, we go away for a while.
It would be nice.
Besides, there are other ways
to make money.
Don't get locked into
one view of the world, Chon.
What?
Did you know they're making $14
laptops for kids in Africa?
What if you could
make a $10 solar panel?
You'd change the world.
Grow up, Ben.
You don't change the world.
It changes you.
VALET: Welcome
to the Bellevue, sir.
Thanks, I appreciate it.
You're welcome.
I'm Alex.
This is Jaime.
Hola.
Mucho gusto.
ALEX: Let's get down
to business, shall we?
Everything stays the same.
You're intact.
Over the three years,
we'll study your techniques,
your production methods,
your distribution.
In return, your business
will grow immensely.
Our distribution
is international.
We'll give you protection on a
scale you're not accustomed to.
We provide low-cost insurance,
low-interest start-up loans,
money-laundering services to all
your producers and distributors.
You see, we lease a good amount
of land in this country.
Some of it, Indian tribal land,
not subject to federal law.
We have the structure
and labor force
to cultivate thousands and
thousands of acres all at once.
Mexican field hands
do not grow primo.
You will teach them this,
and they will learn.
So you are the pharmaceutical
company and the pharmacy.
We're the botanists.
Not exactly. We value our scientists
and our seed-makers very much.
It is your methods and your
network we want to partner with.
A joint venture.
No pun intended.
Well said.
In return, we take
a modest distribution fee.
Which would be?
20%.
80% is all yours.
And after the three years?
We'll grow your volume.
Your profits in three years
will be 35 to 40 million.
After three years,
I'm sure you'll be pleased
and quite willing to
re-negotiate our fee.
As we want to encourage other
independents to join our association.
We need a moment.
(CHATTER OVER RADIO)
OPHELIA: Wiley is a top mixer.
He doesn't care about anything but
sound and Ben and Chon's primo.
CHON: I will say again,
loud and clear.
We send Alex and Jaime back in a
cereal box, get this party started.
Veto that.
Two errand boys, Chon.
They can replace every man
they lose, and we can't.
OPHELIA: Doc, Sam, and Billy.
EX-SEALS from Afghanistan.
Together, they've got
about 120 kills.
Sweetest guys,
when you get to know them.
CHON: Last time, Ben.
You let people
think you're weak,
sooner or later you're going
to have to kill them.
Buddha would not agree.
What does a fat Jap know?
He's a fat Indian.
Whatever.
So we dig you guys
sound like Goldman Sachs,
but it's just
not our thing.
So, you are
rejecting our offer?
No.
We're going to
give you our business,
but we're not
going to join you.
Nothing personal.
ALEX: Nothing personal?
I'm afraid our client would
take this very personally.
BEN: Well, I am sorry.
We want out of the dope business.
It's become a bit of a drag.
We want to do
something different.
Such as?
Such as clean,
renewable energy.
You mean sun, wind, ethanol?
Shit like that?
There you go.
What do you have to say?
Me?
Mmm-hmm.
I think, basically,
you want us
to eat your shit
and call it caviar.
(ALEX CHUCKLING)
What'd he say?
(WHISPERING)
You're making a mistake.
Right.
We'll give you
24 hours to reconsider.
Well, in light of
our generous offer,
we would like to reconsider
and think about this.
Give us 48 hours.
We need to talk to producers
and distributors.
They're very
independent thinkers.
We'll talk
tomorrow at this time.
Well...
OPHELIA: This is Spin.
He used to be an investment
broker for a big bank,
but then he found out he
could make a lot more money
laundering
Ben and Chon's profits.
Hey, what's up, guys?
How you doing?
The bank didn't miss him.
Got a little something.
Shit. Sweet.
(SNIFFS)
We need to get off
the grid for a while.
Cool.
Yeah, no,
it's not really.
Okay. Uh, Annie?
I need you to set
up a new line for us.
Double-blind,
all right?
Everything washed fresh,
a whole new cycle.
Make it go away somewhere for a
while so no one can trace us.
What, are you kidding me?
How long?
I don't know.
Botanical research, call it a sabbatical.
Up to a year.
Huh.
Grab a seat.
Okay, no problemo.
A year for two of you.
Three.
Three? Who's three?
O.
(TYPING)
Okay, three people.
One of them is O.
So, that's a whole new
clothing line of its own.
Twelve months. Housing,
meals, entertainment.
Where are you thinking?
Indonesia.
Where in Indonesia?
Can't say.
In case you get tortured.
Joy.
You guys are serious, huh?
All right, well, you're going to want
easy access to a mil, anyway.
That girl's ass... She could
ride my bike anytime.
Can you focus on the numbers?
Hey, I'm multitasking, pal.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I knew you
wouldn't make the deal.
We think it's time
to get out.
Not forever,
maybe a year or so.
When are you going?
Tomorrow night.
They got a clock on us.
Where?
Indonesia.
I put a water system in this
pretty little village, by a beach.
And they're the sweetest
people you'd ever meet.
I think you'll love it.
Me, too.
What?
Well, I can't imagine
it without you.
It's the three of us now, O.
(LAUGHING) Oh, my gosh!
Yeah.
Where in Indonesia? Isn't it
10,000 islands or something?
Here, you got a passport?
A valid passport?
My mom's got it, okay?
Tell her just for
a few weeks, and then...
Yeah, I got it.
Then we'll re-adjust
the clock from there.
We're like that movie.
Avatar?
What movie?
You know, the one with Paul Newman
when he was, you know, alive.
And Robert Redford,
when he was a total babe.
Butch Cassidy and
the Sundance Kid.
I'm like, the girl.
Wait, don't they
get killed at the end?
Not the girl.
(DISHES CLATTER)
Get down!
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my God.
A little jumpy,
are we?
You think?
Are we clear?
So, how about I tell you folks
about our dessert specials?
Why not?
All right, first off, we have
a delicious creme brulee.
It's got a thick sugar coating,
going to break like glass.
(CHEERING)
Feet are too close, Frankie!
Spread them. Follow through.
Where's the change-up?
I can see it coming.
Watch your feet.
Keep them guessing!
How much are we paying
his goddamn pitching coach?
Two thousand dollars and the kid
can't even get his stance right.
Look at the other one
up there, half asleep.
(YAWNING)
Junior! Wake up!
I'm talking. Don't make
me come out there!
Okay.
LADO: Are the kids
coming home for dinner?
Angela's going to the Cheesecake
Factory with Courtney and Taylor.
It's Friday.
LADO: The Cheesecake Factory.
In Mexico, I picked my meals
out of the garbage truck.
That's why our children
are Californian now.
That was the idea,
Miguel, wasn't it?
Maybe we should go
and visit more often.
So Courtney was all like,
"I'm so over it."
And I was like, "No, bitch,
you're so not 'so over it."'
Look at your daughter. She
looks like a little whore.
Nice. About our daughter.
She's 15.
Don't come crying at me
when she gets knocked up.
She's on the pill.
The pill.
You know what? That's like telling
her, "Go ahead and fuck."
You know what? We should
sit down at the table,
the whole goddamned family, 'cause
I can see what's happening.
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello.
I'm on my way.
Who was that?
(SIGHS) Don't start.
Mmm?
Where are you going?
I gotta work. Take the
kids out to dinner.
Okay? I'll be late.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Don't insult me
in front of everyone.
What are you, crazy?
Do me a favor.
Next time you come home
in the middle of the night,
take a shower and wash
her stink off, will you?
Nice Latina mouth
you got lately, Dolores.
You think you left
the old ways behind?
Well, let me
tell you something.
Tijuana is coming here.
It's chasing us.
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
So, which cock
does she suck?
I can't tell.
The white guys
like each other.
Maybe they're faggots.
Maybe she
does them both.
Savages.
All right. Are you ready?
This is the new stuff. You've never
had anything like this before.
Oh, man.
It's good.
It's all right.
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
(PHONE RINGING)
LADO: I can't find
my prick here.
That's because it's too fucking small.
What are you, drunk?
Elena.
You left the phone on.
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
You know, I'm just...
(ZIPS PANTS)
What's going on there?
(URINATING) The güeros
got drunk with a bonita.
They all went
inside their house.
They've been there
now for two hours.
A whore?
No, she's like
a rich girl or something.
She belong to "Nothing personal"
or "Eat-shit-caviar"?
Hard to tell.
Interesting.
Are they sharing?
I know you don't want
to hear this, Madrina,
but I think
they're going to run.
I could walk in there
right now and take them,
talk to them
on your behalf.
No, Big Bear.
I need their network
and their expertise.
Interesting people,
Americans.
I think I found
their weakness.
Is she pretty?
Yeah, she's pretty, but you got a
better-looking style, Madrina.
I'm getting old.
When we get to Indonesia,
I mean, if things heat up,
if they find you,
then what happens?
Would you guys
have to go?
Would I go home?
I don't...
I don't want to
lose you guys.
I love you.
Because you're
my only family.
I've got three months tops
in Indonesia.
Oh, no.
I can't lock down there.
OPHELIA: Living in
a jungle sounds great,
but where's
the toilet paper?
(BOTH LAUGH)
That is, by far, the least of your worries.
And the Chanel?
I know.
Come here.
Let's not go to Indonesia.
Let's just stay here forever.
Right here.
We can just hide
in this room.
BEN: I cannot die in fucking Laguna.
They won't find us.
No, not in Laguna. We're wherever
we want to be right now.
I mean, I'll miss this place, sure.
I love this place.
But I can say
goodbye and just move on.
Why is it so easy for you?
Because there
are better things.
There are better
things than what's here.
(SPEAKS IN SPANISH)
That was pretty
intense last night.
Maybe we ought to
stop smoking that strain.
Or make
a lot more of it.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Hey, how are you feeling?
Good.
Gentlemen.
Thanks for coming, guys.
Sure.
Five minutes.
(SNIFFLES)
I got to make my final
pilgrimage to the mall.
Hey, I'm sending
Frankie with you, okay?
If Frankie can keep up.
6:00 p.m. curfew.
The flight's at midnight.
Yes, Daddy.
Please don't
forget your passport.
I love you guys.
OPHELIA: My mom was off somewhere in
the world with her latest husband.
I like to think I'm in the
middle of a 12-stepdad program.
So, I left a note saying I'd
gone to Europe for four weeks
with my best friend, Lucy,
to get some culture.
Look, Jake, think of it as
economy of scale. All right?
The Mexicans will do business,
but you'll be a corporation.
They'll assign your profits
and your timetables
and you'll make more money
than you ever made with us.
Things change,
don't give it up.
They're like corporations.
None of them last.
Besides, we could be back
running the show in a year.
Travis, phone numbers are
vanishing as we speak, okay?
Yes, I'm wiping the grid.
I'm putting a little virus
in there to fuck them up.
No, they're not going
to chase you. Trust me.
Fucking hell. Paranoid as fuck.
He should lay off the Kush.
(SIREN CHIRPS)
Do you know why I
stopped you, sir?
Let me guess.
You know what, man?
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
MAGDA: I'm just saying, Ma,
I got a Sosh midterm on Monday
and an Econ paper due Wednesday.
(ELENA SPEAKING SPANISH)
ELENA: But I was hoping that you
could come for one weekend.
Of course I do.
You don't want me to end up in Tijuana
with Diego chasing me, do you?
What about your horses, Magda?
You never come to see them.
MAGDA: Why don't you sell them?
They're worth a fortune.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Que paso?
He was such a nice guy.
MAGDA: In America, you don't
get married at 18 or 19, Mom.
So you can relax, okay?
(ELENA SPEAKING SPANISH)
ELENA: I know that,
and trust me,
I do not want you to follow
in my footsteps at all.
But don't you
forget for one second
that I am the only
mother you'll ever have.
I love you.
(MOTORCYCLE REVVING)
(PHONE RINGING)
This is Alex.
So, hey, Alex, you're on speaker.
Chon's next to me.
And?
We changed our minds.
We're coming aboard.
Hmm.
We're happy to hear that.
So...
Look, we want to
go over the MO.
How about first
thing tomorrow morning?
We'll get back to you.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
(OPHELIA PANTING)
O?
Hi.
BEN: I'm so sorry
about this, baby.
We're going to get
you out, I promise.
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
Which one of you
(VOICE DISTORTED)
is Mr. ”Nothing Personal"?
I'm here.
If you fucking...
Shut up, shut up.
All right, look,
we can negotiate.
We didn't make you an offer
to hear a counteroffer.
We made you a deal to which
we expected compliance.
You lied to us.
We'll do whatever you want.
If that affects
a change in attitude,
you'll have to prove it.
That's not a problem.
Really? Because it
was a problem before.
It's not now.
Good.
Now let me speak to
Mr. ”Eat-Shit-Caviar. "
I'm here.
You insulted me.
I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
Take out your gun.
Stand in front of the camera
where I can see you.
Now stick it in that
vulgar mouth of yours.
Cut off two fingers.
(OPHELIA PLEADING)
I'm doing it! I'm doing it.
(SOBBING)
Now put your
finger on the trigger.
Look, there's got
to be a better way!
No, God damn it!
What are you doing?
Stop.
You may take it out now.
The next time we ask
you to do something,
I don't want to hear,
"Eat-shit-caviar."
Am I clear?
Yes.
Good.
You will make a delivery to us,
in Chula Vista, of 300 pounds.
You have five hours.
Or you will receive
an e-mail you will not like.
Five hours begin now.
We gotta move.
That's your bed.
That's your toilet.
And that's your sink.
You've got toothpaste.
A comb.
Water.
See you in the morning.
No toothbrush?
Do you want to use
my finger?
You got it?
Everything's ready to go.
My boys had to go all the way to
Santa Barbara to get you 300.
Nearly wiped us out.
Only 30 or 40 pounds left.
So, who am I
working for now? You?
Or them?
You'll know tomorrow.
We owe you, Eric.
Stay safe.
CHON: Slow down, man.
Cops are like bees
all over.
We have 45 minutes.
It's the next exit.
We got seven minutes.
Oh, shit.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Fuck.
Drive real cool, Ben.
Three hundred pounds.
We're dead, man.
No, man.
He's dead.
Are you fucking crazy?
You can't shoot a cop, Chon.
Put one big
thought in your head.
O is not going to die.
Forget everything else.
Oh, God, please,
Mr. State Trooper,
don't pull us over.
It's not your night
to die.
Chon's gonna shoot you,
I'm not gonna lie.
Hey, this is our exit.
Oh, God.
I'm pulling off.
(SIREN WAILS)
Shit!
Shit.
Hard right.
Two minutes, man.
They're watching us.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Yes?
MAN: Go two blocks.
Look for a fish store.
Okay, I see it.
There's an alley
behind the store.
Hook a right.
Put it into park.
Should I shut the engine off?
No.
Here they come.
Stay cool.
(ORDERING IN SPANISH)
If anything goes wrong,
if anybody follows us,
the girl dies slow.
(SNAPS PHOTO)
Drink up.
They paid in full.
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYS)
Yes.
ELENA: (DISTORTED) We're happy to see
you've learned to honor your partnership.
What do you want from us?
The same things
we agreed upon.
Three years. Except,
(NORMAL VOICE) now,
motherfuckers, it's 70-30.
(WHISPERS)
That's gotta be Elena.
The first payment
you've received.
And O?
Ophelia will be
away for one year.
One year!
All right, Chon...
At the end of that year,
she'll come home.
Fail at any point to meet the
terms of our partnership
and the girl
will die very badly.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
One year.
O won't make three weeks.
What if we offer them cash?
Right now?
They're going to
kill her anyway.
Don't fucking say that.
They're going to make us jump
through these fucking hoops
until they get what they want.
Then they're
going to kill her,
and then they're
going to kill us.
Look, we made
a three-year deal.
She's out in one.
They want the money.
You don't know shit.
You're talking to Taliban.
Right. Okay.
They don't give back.
All right. But they paid for the dope.
Didn't they?
Savages don't make deals, Ben.
They're a business, Chon.
Think about it.
We're smarter than they are.
Yeah, in botany.
Every man in her fucking life
has let her down.
She's in this
shit because of us.
When I said, "Kill them."
"They can't come up north,
there's too much heat on them."
You said, "No, let's talk about it."
How's that working out for you?
That's your answer for everything!
Just fucking kill everybody!
I didn't see you stick a fucking
gun in your mouth, Ben!
I haven't left a man behind
in my whole fucking life!
Do you think I would?
With Brad it was like...
I don't know if this is
really going to happen.
But with him,
I feel like this is serious.
I think what worries me is I
think you're too much for him.
What do you mean?
(LAUGHING)
I think you're too young
and he's just a little bit older
and a little bit more demure.
I feel like the defining question
is, does he make you laugh?
OPHELIA: This isn't fair.
Why can't I talk to
whoever is in charge here?
Huh?
Is anyone listening?
Why can't I talk to anyone?
Fuck!
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey!
Maybe I could get
a clean room at least.
Maybe a salad every once in a while,
instead of pizza all the time.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You don't know my mom, but if
she doesn't hear from me soon,
she's going to
do something really stupid.
She's probably going to
call the FBI or something.
Because my stepdad,
he was in the FBI
or the CIA or one of them.
So you better get me
on the Internet soon.
You can supervise me, sure.
That's fine.
But that way, at least I can tell
someone somewhere that I'm alive.
And I know that
I can be here
for like seven to 10 days.
A month, maybe.
Whoever you are,
just think
I could be your daughter.
Twice in one week.
Not good, guys.
Get in, please.
You know, a little sleep
can do wonders.
To what do I
owe this pleasure?
Dennis, we need your
files on the Baja cartel.
What?
I told you,
don't fuck with these people.
And I follow my own advice.
Have a nice day.
BEN: Dennis, you step out that
car, I'm coming down to San Diego
to introduce myself
to your district supervisor.
And you're going
to have a hard time
explaining half-a-million dollars
parked in the Cook Islands
when you clear 110,
after taxes.
And don't even think about calling
someone and having us disappear
because I got plenty of evidence
in other people's hands.
So what happened to our
mutually-assured destruction thing?
We rat each other out, we all
end up in the same prison cell.
What happened to that?
They lifted O.
Really?
Are you surprised?
Yeah.
Well, I'll do time,
but you got kids, Dennis.
They're already
growing up without a mom.
You don't have
a move, here.
Now, listen.
When Hillary Clinton grows up,
she wants to be Elena Sanchez.
You run up
against ”La Reina" Elena
and I'm telling you,
I see dead people.
That's really dramatic.
But in the reality-based community,
there's always a weakness.
Okay, here's the deal.
Do you know this El Azul guy?
All right. He was her inside man
for years, and now he's out.
This year, there's the Mexican
presidential election.
He's in, she's done.
There was a bust in Baja,
the largest grow ever.
A quarter of a million plants.
It's hers.
She's losing men, she's losing
money like a BP oil spill.
That's why she's coming up and
moving in on indie guys like you.
Where does she live?
She got a house up here?
Tijuana. And don't
even think about it.
She's got security, like, beyond
the American fucking embassy.
Look, this is the deal.
Husband, brothers, dead.
Two sons, dead.
She's got a son in Mexico City.
He's some playboy, he's alive.
A daughter, Magda, also dead.
And that's all
I fucking know!
This is fucking bullshit!
We need what
the DEA's got on the cartel.
Names, histories,
stash houses.
But that ain't part
of the deal, buddy boy!
It is now.
It don't work that way. It's
fucking 1984 in there, man.
Their databases are encrypted
in redundant firewalls.
Again. More fucking bullshit!
It's not bullshit!
Our guys help set up those firewalls.
Anything can be hacked!
We're running out of time, Dennis.
You have to step up right now.
You know what?
Get fucked, both of you.
Fuck me, fuck you.
I'm out of here.
(SCREAMS)
What the fuck, Chon!
Motherfucker!
BEN: What the hell
are you doing?
They took O.
They took our girl.
And I will do anything,
anything, to get her back.
Do you understand me?
Holy shit, Chon!
You fucking stabbed a federal agent!
Look at this!
Oh, God.
I'll do more than that.
Okay, stop, stop, stop.
I'll figure it out.
I'll figure something out.
Crazy motherfucker.
I want to hear
from you soon, Dennis.
DENNIS: Fuck!
So, we're hearing the food
here is not good enough?
We're concerned,
you know.
DEA AGENT: Paul Durth.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hello, sweetheart.
I need 60 days on this card
and all
the geo-locations on this one.
Can you do that?
Of course.
Okay.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
How's the hand?
Don't bite it again.
CRAIG: Let's run them.
Whoa. It's a mudslide,
off two lousy cards.
This dude's
ahead of the curve.
What do you got?
I got it, too.
Your boy Dennis came through.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
This lawyer dude,
Alex Reyes,
set her up with a 100,000-acre
ranch in Humboldt County.
Elena ”La Reina" has got
property all over the place.
In La Jolla,
parts of Palm Desert,
apartments in Miami, London, Zurich.
Check it out.
There's gaps here. This guy's
shrouding his sources.
You think old
Dennis pulled a Nixon?
It's an NTFS partition. He fucked
up the master boot record.
Claire, can you
Google those houses again?
Whoever did this
is very good.
Spin? Cash.
What can we clear in now?
Chon and my accounts?
Liquid?
You can't dump the house or you'll
take a two-million lump to the head
and depends on how fast I can
move the gold and silver,
but let's
estimate six to eight.
Are you kidding me?
That's all?
After all these years.
Wow. You've been
fucking me in the ass.
I'm insulted you
only just realized that.
I didn't go all Bono all over
Africa and Asia, buddy-buddy.
Let's say we're three
to four million short
depending on what
we can get them down.
Come here.
There's got to be millions
sitting in these houses
at one time or another.
It would be like
Robin Hood.
A fucked-up Robin Hood.
I love it.
A couple of IEDs and RPGs
might come in handy.
We could go real
Sunni on these bastards.
Um...
Are we in any
sort of danger, here?
Did I not tell you everything
goes through Mr. Alex?
Not this.
This is 10 million cash,
straight up, for the girl.
And we stay happy partners.
Look, Ms. Sanchez,
I thought this through.
So have I, and I put
her value at 15 million.
That's too much.
Why? You don't
think she's worth it?
No, she's worth it.
We're small, compared to you.
Grow up, motherfucker.
Give us a break, here.
All right?
How about 12?
You must stop trying
to negotiate with me.
Thirteen is our number,
but this is not open-ended.
I give you two weeks.
The rest of our deal
stays the same. Agreed?
Agreed.
Let's get going.
OPHELIA: Dear Mom, don't
freak when you see the bill.
Remember,
it's a one-time-only in Paris.
Did you know
you can't even ask prices
or the snooty salesgirls
won't look at you?
These French bitches, they eat all
the time and they're so skinny!
OPHELIA: So, Mom,
here I am in London.
You'd die if you saw the portrait
of Ophelia hanging in my room.
I'm having
the time of my life,
but being here really
makes me appreciate home.
I hope you know
how much I love you.
I miss you.
I'll see you soon.
O.
Esteban.
You forgot this.
(WHISPERING) Please let me talk to someone.
Not him, not him.
Please, help me.
CHON: There.
There's the money.
That's where they count it.
Two, three times a week,
they head south to Mexico.
You see that curve?
Road, bridge, road.
One way in, no way out.
You nervous?
No. I hijack cash
shipments all the time.
(LAUGHS)
Good.
Chon, I don't know
if I can do this.
Do what?
Kill somebody.
Look, Ben. There's no
"undo" button here.
There's still time
for you to walk away.
I got five good
guys ready to go.
No. I'm in.
This was my idea.
Good.
BILLY: Alpha-One in position.
Copy that.
DOC: Charlie-Three
in position.
Copy.
(FLICKS LIGHTER)
They don't call it
hijacking for nothing, Ben.
No.
Three bogies
coming your way.
Copy that, gentlemen.
May Allah be with you.
First bogie,
coming your way.
Charlie, you got someone
knocking on your front door.
DOC: We got it. Copy.
I got your back.
I want you to stay flat until you
get that clear signal from me.
You understand?
Yeah.
DOC: Second vehicle is
about 200 meters behind it.
Third, about 300 to 400.
Here's our dance partner.
Now, breathe.
Three, two, one.
(MEN YELLING IN SPANISH)
Bulletproof fucking glass!
Fuck you, puto.
He's got a radio!
Do you know what this is?
Whoo!
You see that baby blow, man?
Let's go, let's go,
let's go!
DOC: C-team, moving in.
Move, move, move!
Four... Three... Two...
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
(ORDERING IN SPANISH)
Do you know who
the fuck we are?
We're the cartel, cabron.
We'll blowtorch your balls.
Rape your wife.
And your kids.
(GRUNTING)
You good?
Yeah.
I need you to go over
there and grab my case.
Grab the case.
(FIRES GUN)
GPS.
If you see it,
get rid of it.
Doc, how we doing over there?
You clear?
Yeah, we're clear here.
Good. Go, go.
Jesse, how are we?
You clear?
BEN: Pull over.
No, you saw the radio.
They're not far behind.
I fucked up.
Tell me, Ben.
Which life would
you trade for O's?
Which one?
Fucked up, man!
We fucked up, man.
I think we got close
to three million cash.
We're still
three million short.
Pull over!
Oh, God!
Hurry up.
Let's go!
Get yourself together, Ben.
Because tomorrow,
the shit's really
going to hit the fan.
(BEN MOANING)
(BARKING)
Come on.
Where are the kids?
Angela's still at practice.
The boys are sleeping over.
When the hell are we going
to sit at the table
and have dinner
like a family?
Get me a beer.
What's the matter?
Are you unhappy again?
You still seeing
that therapist dyke?
Three hundred bucks an hour.
Maybe I can fix
your problem. No fee.
I'll make you
pregnant again.
(GRUNTS)
(DOGS BARKING)
I want a divorce.
You want a what?
A fucking divorce.
I don't want to be
your wife any more.
(CURSING IN SPANISH)
What you're going to get is
another kick in the belly.
Now shut the fuck up.
This is America, Miguel.
I already talked to a lawyer.
I know things.
Mmm-hmm.
Dolores.
One time, I tell you.
You talk to a lawyer again,
and I will take the
three kids to Mexico
and you will never
see them again.
You know that's the truth.
Fuck you!
I promise I will kill you.
That's the Dolores
I'd like to fuck.
Turn around.
No.
(SOBBING)
(DOGS BARKING)
Get out.
Get out of here.
Get out! Go!
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
Better be good.
ALEX: Hernando heard Gigi say they
were wearing Santa Muerte masks.
They were tall.
Thinks he saw two.
Hernando.
Yeah.
How many guys
you think did this?
At least five,
maybe six.
There's three locations.
Almost at the same time.
And they ditched
the GPS's.
What's this?
That's an improvised
explosive device. IED.
It's from Iraq.
The sand-niggers use them
to blow up güero armor.
Iraq.
Who the fuck...
El Azul's been
hiring ex-soldiers.
Probably Mexican demolition
guys from the Yankee army.
You don't know that.
Hernando.
Bury them like men,
what's left.
Money to their families.
What do we tell Elena?
That we know shit.
Nothing.
She's going to get real upset
if we don't tell her nothing
and reads about
it in the papers.
Oh, shut the fuck up.
I'm the one who knows Elena.
Let me handle it.
César!
(ORDERING IN SPANISH)
Si, Senora.
(IN SPANISH)
No, Madrina.
But, I have a...
What?
I have this girl that keeps
insisting to talk to you.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
My own daughter
doesn't want to talk to me,
but this one does.
Put it on.
You have a request?
Yes, I'd like to speak to
the man in charge, please.
Yes?
Oh, I'm...
Has Esteban not been
providing the essentials?
Um...
No, he did.
I'm sorry.
I'm just having
some concentration problems,
and I was hoping
maybe I could get
a little something
to take the edge off.
"The edge off"?
What's the matter?
Is it that time of the month?
I mean the stuff we're all
killing each other over.
I see.
May I ask you how long
have you been using, Ophelia?
Since the eighth grade.
(LAUGHS)
And you're wondering why you're
having concentration problems?
Do your parents know?
They didn't care.
All right.
I can arrange something.
FEMALE NEWSCASTER: Three vehicles
smoldering from what looks to be
a coordinated, rocket-propelled
grenade attack
used in
coordination with IEDs,
which stands for ”improvised
explosive devices.”
CHON: Ben.
(JAUNTY MUSIC PLAYING)
These are the same types of
explosives used by the Taliban
against our
troops in Afghanistan.
They sure don't waste time.
They want to see you.
I don't know, man.
Remember the drill.
Look them right in the eyes.
There's only one thing
on your mind, one thing.
It's, "Fuck you,
you've got O."
I've got your back.
And watch your breathing.
Fellas.
Afternoon.
Good afternoon, yeah.
So, we got a problem.
Where were you
last night?
I was at home, why?
Who the fuck's this guy?
An amigo, amigo.
Three of our cars
were hit last night.
Seven of our men
are soon to be buried.
What?
That was you guys?
I saw that on the news.
This is fucking great.
I've been in this business for years
and never had a person killed.
And now you're telling me,
what, seven people are dead?
This loss ain't cutting
into our share of the take.
Where's the other one?
Huh?
Your other amigo,
where is he?
You asked me to come alone. Hmm?
You asked me
to come alone.
You did?
ALEX: I did.
(TALKING IN SPANISH)
Don't even go there, man. We
had nothing to do with this.
Maybe you should
look at your own men.
Our people know better.
Whatever, man.
Fucking solve it, okay?
I want to talk to O.
Yeah?
Proof of life.
Like everyone else,
we work for incentives.
We'll see.
Hmm.
(EXHALES)
What do you think?
I think he's
telling the truth.
They don't have
the balls to rob us.
I'm not so sure,
you know?
It doesn't matter.
We have to report
this to Elena, Lado.
Alex, I'll tell Elena
when I want her to know.
I'll call you later.
(OPHELIA COUGHS)
Next time,
ask me for what you want.
Drink up, Ophelia.
Time for your bath.
Bathtub time.
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
Oh, fuck.
Yes?
ELENA: Magdita.
Hi, Mom. Wow, it's late.
Guess what?
I'm coming to California!
What?
Well, you know
what they say.
If the mountain doesn't come to
Mohammed, Mohammed comes to California.
I've got my finals, Mom.
I'm coming next week,
and that's what's final.
Yeah, sure, I guess.
I'm so excited to
see you, mijita!
LADO: I don't think that's
a good idea, Madrina.
Azul could take
advantage of this situation.
ELENA: I want to see Magda.
I have to arrange your transport.
It's complicated.
It's already been arranged.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
What the fuck you
looking at, man?
I gave her some shit,
so let her sleep.
Wake her up in six hours.
Sophia will wash her.
(OPHELIA GASPS)
It's okay.
Okay, sweetie-pie,
time to go.
Last looks.
Este.
It didn't work out.
You're too sensitive.
Have you been
treated well, Ophelia?
Are you all right?
She's fine. I'm not
talking to you, Lado.
I'm talking to Ophelia.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Good.
Chucho, take her to
the guest house, please.
(IN SPANISH)
So, Lado,
now I'm talking to you.
Let me see your eyes.
Is everything all right?
Yes, Madrina.
Why you ask?
You make me sad, Lado.
I have to come to Gringolandia
to find this out?
You thought I
wasn't going to notice
$3 million,
and seven of my men dead?
Since when do you take
decisions of your own...
(IN SPANISH)
I made you,
motherfucker. I did!
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm very sorry, Madrina.
It was stupid of me not
to tell you right away.
I just wanted to prove to you
that it was this Cheech and Chong
who were stealing
your money.
So, please.
Allow me to talk to them.
Yes, and men will say
anything to stop the pain.
Mierda, Lado. You're
stupider than you look!
These two kids, all they
care about is their girl.
They wouldn't do
anything to risk her life.
But it's distracting you from our
bigger problem, which is El Azul.
To the point that
he has infiltrated
himself into
the northern group,
which is under your control.
But if you think
I'm the only one
who's going to
be losing money,
you're in for a surprise.
First of all,
those $3 million?
You're going to pay for it.
Yeah, you, too.
Second of all,
you're going to find me...
...that gave up our
stash house to Azul.
Or else, I'm going to have to go after
your wives, and your children...
You may go now.
What are you waiting for?
OPHELIA: The Red Queen asked me to dinner.
I think she was lonely.
I had a job for a while. I was
a hostess at a restaurant.
I went to community college
for a semester and a half.
But then I left, because
institutions make me crazy.
And I thought, I don't know, I
wanted to experience something real.
I figured I just
wanted to drown in life.
And how I made it out,
that would...
Do Americans
always talk this way?
Have you ever really
thought about your future?
That's a little ironic,
considering the situation I'm in.
How are your
lamb chops, Ophelia?
Good, thank you.
How did you get
into the business?
If you don't mind
my asking, ma'am.
You could say that
I inherited the position.
When they killed my husband,
whom I love very much,
I had no choice.
What, you don't have sons?
My twin sons were murdered.
So, I have devoted my life
to my surviving children.
Do you still get to
talk to your kids?
My son hates me,
because I took his power away.
They would have
killed him, too.
And my daughter,
she's ashamed of me.
And I am proud of her for it.
I'm sorry.
Why?
I don't know.
I guess I feel bad for you.
My hope is still alive.
Both of them.
And yours is dead.
I like talking
to you, Ophelia.
But let me remind
you that if I had to,
I wouldn't have a problem
cutting both their throats.
Well, you'll never
get them together.
I'm the only one
who can do that.
Come on. Are you really
bragging about that?
There's something wrong
with your love story, baby.
They may love you,
but they will never love you as
much as they love each other.
Otherwise, they wouldn't
share you, would they?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
SPIN: I gave your boy Alex a new
bank account in Saint Kitts.
Separate deposits
of 120, 260, and 90.
I spin it around the
planet twice, and voila.
Alex Reyes now owns
a building in Cabo,
sells it to a resident of
Palau who doesn't exist.
OPHELIA: My men knew they
couldn't pull off another heist.
So they found a different way.
By end of the clay, he's definitely
been one bad little puddy cat.
Phone records?
Yeah. Plenty of backup.
This account is so confusing,
it'll take a forensic a month
just to find his own dick.
So, what did
this guy do to you?
When do you ask
questions like that?
Come on, man.
This is the Baja cartel.
They're probably going to
crucify this guy for this.
So, you don't mind losing
your commission on the deal?
OPHELIA: They knew they needed to
get the suspicion off themselves.
But what they didn't know
is that Lado
was already making
plans of his own.
(HORNS HONKING)
(EL AZUL SPEAKING SPANISH)
LADO: Welcome to the barrio.
So, what you
going to talk about?
Sit down.
Well, after our last
pleasant chat,
I had my IT guys do
a little deep research.
This cost me
a lot of money.
What is it?
Your informant.
Who?
I think you guys are paying
Alex Reyes way too much.
Don't believe me?
Give this to Jaime,
he'll get it.
Unless he's in on it.
There's a lot there.
Bank accounts, transactions.
Take a look at
the deposit dates
and match them up
with the hijackings.
(IN SPANISH)
Let me see your hands.
Soft, like a woman's.
And he's fucking me
with them.
(GIGGLES)
Let me ask you something.
Do you love your sister?
I don't have a sister.
Ophelia's not your sister?
No.
You're cute, lambioso.
You can go now.
Like I said,
follow the money.
I need to talk to Elena.
(QUESTIONS IN SPANISH)
She told you,
whatever I need.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(TV PLAYING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I'm sorry.
What I said the other
night was stupid.
I can't sleep and I
thought it'd be nice
to have some company
for a few minutes.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You too?
I like to TiVo.
Especially in America.
OPHELIA: She's going
for the wrong guy.
That one is such a player.
You think?
Girl, you have been
out of the game too long.
Trust me, I know a
player when I see one.
You really believe that these
women can convince themselves
that they can fall in
love with men like this?
You know what you were saying
the other night, about my men?
Yeah.
I never had a dad.
He left.
I don't know, I guess this is
my way of getting to know man.
I didn't know
my father either.
But I only loved
one man my whole life.
You were never
with anyone else?
No.
You must really miss him.
You see how I never laugh
and I never cry?
Well, that's because I have
Botox of the heart.
I thought just in the face.
I don't have Botox
on the face!
No?
No, I don't!
(LAUGHS)
I made you laugh.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Bitch.
Hello?
I see.
(SIGHS)
I'll call you right back.
What happened?
There's been a problem.
(CALLING OUT IN SPANISH)
Chiquita is going to take
you back to your room.
No, Elena, please tell
me what happened.
I'm sorry, Ophelia. I told
you this might end badly.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Elena, please.
Just tell me.
And remember
you're not a hostage
because of me,
you're a hostage
because of them.
(WHIP CRACKING)
(ALEX SCREAMING)
Elena! Stop it! Please!
(MEN YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
LADO: Lucky seven.
Did you make 17
phone calls to El Azul?
No!
LADO: Ten latigazos
to go, cabron.
ALEX: No, Lado, no!
(SOBBING)
Yes or no?
Elena, in the name of God.
I beg you!
(IN SPANISH)
Listen,
I promise you this.
Your wife, Bettina, and your
little ones that I like so much,
they will get the insurance.
But you tell me
"no" one more time,
I will drive them here
and I will cut them open
and make them bleed
to death in front of you.
Yes or no?
What's it going to be?
(IN SPANISH)
Finally. Louder.
Louder!
(BEGGING IN SPANISH)
LADO: Cut him down.
(RINGING)
LADO: Now we know.
You were right, Madrina.
What do you want
me to do with him?
The soft one.
Mr. "Nothing Personal."
He must finish
what he started.
Sit her down.
Your men have brought some serious
accusations against one of my men.
This is our way of justice.
For the love of God!
A man takes care of his
family, and I respect that.
I'd like to give
you a better death.
But it would
set a bad example.
No, no, no!
I don't like the screaming.
Oh, God!
Beach Boy.
No? He took your money, too.
”La Reina” says to do it.
Elena, please...
Make her watch.
Let me do it.
Not you, "Caviar."
It's my gift to him.
So, I read up on your Buddha.
According to the Dalai Lama,
if you are in a position
to prevent greater violence,
strike first and strike fast.
Alex kidnapped people, Ben.
He had people
tortured and killed.
So have we.
Dennis fucked us
on those files.
When Alex was up there,
he begged Elena on the head
of Magda, her daughter.
Which means
she must be alive.
And Dennis knows.
Yeah.
We're short three mil.
Another hit
is problematic.
We have got to squeeze it
out of Dennis somehow.
Find her and trade her.
You mean, "Kidnap."
BEN: The same as O.
You up for that?
Yeah.
I am.
Daddy, there's a man
here to see you.
What man?
I don't know.
I was driving by
your neighborgood
and noticed that your yard
needs some trimming.
My crew would like to give you
a free haircut today.
My wife usually
takes care of that stuff.
Sarah, Hannah,
go to your room right now.
But, Daddy...
No "buts," no nothing. Go.
Papa says, "Go."
Lado! You come to my house?
You threaten my daughters?
You don't think I'm
the kind of guy that
doesn't have cameras
all over the place?
It don't matter to me.
After I whack you and your
daughters, I'll burn the house down.
Come on, you found
your fucking snitch.
You found him.
What happened to your hand?
(ENGINE REVVING)
DENNIS: Got it caught
in a weed whacker.
Weed whacker?
Yeah.
"Weed whacker," my ass.
We need to have
a conversation.
Because I'm confused about
some of your actions, Dennis.
Like what?
Like you giving Ben and Chon
all that information.
You must be smoking
your own shit now, man.
You got to know
I'm your man.
I got you your
green card, okay?
I've been protecting you
for six fucking years.
Now that shit
hits the fan,
you got seven dead beaners, you
got a white lawyer in Laguna,
you need me now
more than ever.
Stop begging.
You sound like a woman.
Dennis,
I know you gave them stuff.
What makes you so goddamn
sure it's not Azul?
Because I know it wasn't him.
What do you mean?
Because I'm working
with him now, anfibio.
What?
And you lie to
me one more time,
motherfucker,
I will shoot you down.
Since when have you
been working with Azul?
You're not going
to tell me that?
Since two days ago.
I never gave them you, Lado.
They had me.
I'd be out of business.
I'd be useless to you.
I never thought this Iraq psycho
would go nuts on you guys.
I never gave you up, ever!
I'm your best friend
on this side, man.
Did you tell them I
was your little snitch?
What are you, crazy?
What would be in it for me?
Answer me, Dennis.
I gave them enough to just get
them off my fucking ass...
Yes or no?
No!
No, okay? No. No.
It's all about you and me,
and that's it!
You have got to
believe me this time, man.
I don't want to
lose this shit!
I got two fucking kids
and a wife that's dying.
Thank you, Dennis.
Now they got my $3 million.
And I want that money.
It's my money! It's my money!
Fuckers. You can't trust
anybody no more. Fuck!
I can't even
trust my fucking wife.
She's looking to
divorce me, you know?
My wife's barely breathing.
Welcome to midlife crisis, buddy.
How do you know you can
trust this Azul guy?
I mean, come on.
Has he given you a piece of the business?
Is that what he promised you?
Because Elena is not
going to fold that easy.
You know, that three
million is her money.
Now, don't be a knucklehead.
Think.
Fuck you.
You think, you fucked it up.
How are you going to
get me back my money?
(STAMMERS)
You need me. I'm going
to get you your money.
But they need the girl.
The guys want this girl.
They're in fucking love
with this chick.
And they want O, okay?
So, where is she?
I don't have her.
What do you mean,
you "don't have her"?
Where is she?
With Elena.
In Mexico?
No, here.
Here?
Some fucking
Indian reservation.
Elena came to
see her daughter.
An now that woman is in my face,
telling me what to do, provoking me.
Oh, this is big, man.
”La Reina" Elena
is on US soil?
I told you, it's Indian land.
She's protected.
And I'm going to fix that. That's
why you need Dennis. Think.
Stop telling me to think.
No, no, no, man.
Look, these guys,
they got the three million.
What do you think
they're going to do with it?
They're going to fucking
give it to Elena, right?
And we, first, are going to
sell them Elena's daughter.
We split the profits,
and then we fuck Elena!
Fuck her!
Do you understand?
Whoa!
OPHELIA: Dennis wanted $3 million.
The boys wanted Magda.
Dennis, as usual,
was one step ahead.
I'd like to blow
your fucking heads off.
They threatened my daughters.
My daughters!
Enough with the whining.
You deserve every fucking
inch of your pain, asshole.
You gave us up.
Like I had a choice.
You could have gone along.
You would have made big money.
But you had to pull
your Iraq GI Jack shit.
We want Magda.
Ask your smart-ass boy, here.
SEAL boy, hey.
Did you figure it out
from the transcripts?
All the calls
to Orange County?
Where the fuck is she?
What's in it for me?
Your life,
which I'm about to take.
I'm dead either way.
But the thought
of you sitting
in a prison cell for
the rest of your life
gives me great
afterlife pleasure.
A million in cash,
for Magda's location.
Say goodbye to your wife,
take your girls and go.
Three mil.
Or no deal.
That's my walk-away price.
Walk away from what,
Dennis?
Nobody wants you.
Magda is your only hope.
Three mil,
take it or leave it.
Throw in your snitch.
The three mil, you can do
whatever you want with it.
All right?
Start talking.
When I see the money.
It's in the car.
Get it.
(BELL CHIMING)
What the fuck you want?
(GROANS)
OPHELIA: My boys took a page
from Elena's playbook.
If you want to control
somebody, take what they love.
(MAGDA SCREAMING)
Fuck!
No, no, no!
(MUFFLED SOBS)
Take her gag off.
O, how are you
holding up?
Are you guys okay?
You hang in there, baby.
We're coming for you.
What do you want?
BEN: Shut the fuck up.
You want to start
by understanding
you're not in
charge any more, Elena.
We are.
Do you understand?
Don't nod. Say it.
I understand.
This is how
it's to work.
Your daughter goes with
you, O comes with us.
No money, no nothing.
We go our separate ways and
we live our separate lives.
Do you understand?
I understand.
I only care about Magda.
That's very sweet.
And if that reflects a change of
attitude, you'll have to prove it.
You bring O to a place we
designate, at a time we designate.
We exchange Magda.
You bring no one else.
You deviate from the plan
in any minute detail,
and the girl
will die very badly.
I'll do anything you say.
(GROANS)
You'll hear from us.
(MAGDA SCREAMING)
I told you they
would come for me.
Get her out of here.
Fuck you, Elena.
Get her out of here!
Out!
(SOBBING)
Put her on the chair.
I enjoyed that.
Your boys did good.
Real good.
Juancario, Sophia, leave me
alone with the señorita.
It's almost over.
With a happy ending.
But before you go home,
I want to
show you something.
(OPHELIA GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
Oh, you missed
the best part.
I'll be in touch, baby.
DENNIS: Do you remember
my graduation day?
I'll never forget the way you
looked at me when I got my badge.
You were so proud.
But, you know, they don't tell
you when they give you the badge
the river of shit you're going
to have to wade through.
And the joke is, they don't want you
to get any of that shit on you.
They want you to walk through it
clean, but what's clean any more?
I have to go to my supervisor,
and he takes his taste and...
If you want to see the real
crooks, the real pros,
just turn on
the fucking TV.
Yeah.
We've made heroes of whores.
A nation of whores.
Wall Street. Washington.
Those bastards make what I
do out here look pathetic.
If they woke up
with my job,
with my life,
with my salary,
they'd be looking for the
nearest gun to swallow.
You can't stop.
You can't climb out.
No left turns,
no right turns.
It's just a circle
and everybody gets their cut.
I can't tell you the last thing that
I saw that was completely clean.
Except you.
Except you on that day.
Aqui, WKQ.
You in positions?
Si, jefe, esta bien.
OPHELIA: Like I said
in the beginning,
I might not be
alive at the end.
Just because we make up
stories about ourselves
doesn't mean we can
escape what waits for us.
BEN: Why here?
CHON: It's a wide bowl.
Old Indian burial ground.
Doc can get a line of sight
for up to two miles here.
DOC: We're not alone.
Three men, left side of the basin,
about 2,000 to 2,300 yards.
All right, we knew
this was going to happen.
Wait until we get a hold of O.
And, Doc...
Don't let them get off more
than one shot each, all right?
We got your back.
Let's set up shop, boys.
Think of it like this,
all right?
You're already dead.
You were dead
the moment you were born.
If you accept that,
you can accept anything.
It's been a ride, man.
I've enjoyed it.
Have I ever told you
that I love you, man?
Yeah, this morning.
Well, I do.
You give us O first.
Now.
Go to Ben. Go to Ben.
Give me my daughter!
Now!
Go.
Don't touch me! I'm never
going to see you again.
I'm getting
the fuck out of here!
Magdita...
It's loaded, okay?
Okay.
Keep safe.
Keep down, okay?
We're finished.
We don't need to see you again, thanks.
We're out of here.
Vamos?
Just one last thing,
"Caviar."
Who's my rat?
(BLOWS KISS)
You ungrateful piece of...
You should've fucked me.
(GROANS)
Team leader down!
Who's got the tango at my six?
All right, Jesse.
Shoot whatever
the fuck you got! Go!
Come on, guys!
It's raining bullets, here.
What the fuck are you doing?
Shit! Move, Sam!
Chief, should we shift?
Negative, stay put!
Go!
Oh, fuck!
Smoke that motherfucker.
DOC: Sam, cover Ben!
BILLY: Move! Cover me,
cover me! Hold!
Move!
Mommy, Mommy!
I love you, Mommy!
No, no, no!
Help Magda.
Save Magda. Save Magda.
Get out of here!
Go, come on!
(GUN FIRES)
Fuck!
Don't shoot.
Please, Ophelia.
I have a family.
Three little ones, you know?
Please.
Ben!
DOC: Chief, they took off.
We're coming in.
Hold on.
We'll be there in 10 or less.
Chon?
Please, help him.
(BEN GASPS)
OPHELIA: Shh... It's okay.
It's okay.
He's going to die.
Chon,
I don't want to leave him.
No.
(GASPS)
You're really
going to love it there.
Soft water.
Stars.
And the people
smile...
(ALL GASPING)
I'm cold.
OPHELIA: That's the way
I imagined it.
But the truth has
a mind of its own.
What really happened was more
of a fuck-up than a shoot-out.
And gave us all
a second chance.
CHON: We said
"alone," Elena.
I am one, you are two. Let's
just do what we came to do.
And the snipers.
Tell them to put the scopes on
the ground, hands in the air.
Or we're back in
the jeep and we're gone.
Get rid of them.
ELENA: So how do you
want to do this?
(ENGINE STARTING)
Adios, amiguitas.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
Go, go!
Magda!
OPHELIA: And old Dennis, who couldn't
leave town with his three mil
had to horn in on the action.
Go! Go!
Run!
”La Reina" Elena!
We gotcha!
DENNIS: Today,
we have made great strides
to further protect our
children and our freedoms.
OPHELIA: And Dennis sure made a
big shot of himself on the news.
By dismantling the leadership
of the Baja cartel
and the curse of
illicit drugs in our country.
It is an Indian reservation. It
is technically not our country.
But, as we know, it is.
(LAUGHS) So...
OPHELIA: Elena took the fall and
went to prison for 30 years.
With Elena
out of the picture,
and Dennis
running interference,
Lado and Azul
created a new cartel.
The Azulatos.
Ben being Ben,
he had the goods on Dennis.
And Dennis, identifying Ben and
Chon as his confidential informants
for the last six years,
took care of them.
But who really trusted who?
I have no idea.
Ben and Chon spent a couple
of weeks in the slammer
and then, well, vanished.
Like I did.
They say we're in Africa
off Kenya.
Or some magic
island in Indonesia.
They still talk about
Ben and Chon's herb.
And it surfaces every now
and then over the years.
These things that happened...
You can never go back.
It took me a while,
but I began to live again.
I'm not so sure there can ever
be three people equally in love.
It just doesn't work that way.
I looked up
the definition of ”savage.”
It means, "Cruel, crippled."
”Regressed back to
a primal state of being.”
One day, maybe,
we'll be back.
For now,
we live like savages.
Beautiful savages.