Previously on "Army Wives"...
Garrison commander
and a promotion.
It's probably best not to make any
plans right now.
What do you mean?
I don't think the timing
is right for a baby.
- Oh, my God.
- Who is that?
That's Finn's dad.
Get out!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What did you just say?
Why is he here?
Do not sass me. This is Whit.
He's my friend.
Like the friends you used
to have before dad?
Thanks for letting me come.
Drive safe.
Trust me. It's just colic.
(Molly crying)
I'm just saying, maybe it's worth a
trip to the doctor.
What you're saying is that I don't know
how to take care of my own child.
I'm gonna go.
Don't go back
with your ex...
And don't take that job.
Stay here in Charleston
with me.
(Crying) Oh, baby, you're burning up.
Claudia Joy, there's something
wrong with Molly.
Can you meet me at
the emergency room?
(Claudia Joy)
Of course. I'm on my way.
Okay. (Sniffles)
I'm so sorry, baby.
(Woman) Heartbeat's tachy.
Pulse ox 90.
(Man) She's pale and pasty
with a sunken anterior fontanel.
Urine is minimal and dark.
She needs fluid resuscitation.
Normal saline bolus
at 100 cc's total.
I don't understand.
Why is she so dehydrated?
- Do you breastfeed?
- Every three hours.
Get a Chem panel, a CBC
and cultures. (Crying)
Molly have any, uh,
diarrhea recently?
No.
Normal amount of wet diapers?
Actually, they were
pretty dry today.
Any projectile vomiting?
No, no, just, um, spittiness.
I thought it was colic.
I can't get a flash.
(Man)
We'll put in a central line.
Let ultrasound know
that we're coming up
- and reserve the O.R. on standby.
- Don't worry, sweetie. Mommy's here.
Mrs. Sherwood, I'm sorry,
but you're gonna
have to wait outside.
(Monitor beeping rhythmically)
(Fusses)
(Beeping continues)
Ultrasound's ready for us.
Good. Lidocaine.
(Fusses)
(Cries)
Sync & corrections by Alice
www.addic7ed.com
(woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A.)
(Indistinct conversations)
What's taking them so long?
(Sighs) I'm sure
they're just being thorough.
How is she?
Well, the ultrasound confirmed
what we suspected.
Uh, Molly has Pyloric Stenosis.
- What's that?
- It's a blockage
between the stomach
and the small intestine.
- I thought it was colic.
- It's often confused with colic.
- Yeah, still, I-I should've...
- Is it serious?
When the blockage
becomes complete.
Fortunately, Mrs. Sherwood
caught it in time.
Well, good.
Thank God for that, right?
Can I see her?
We're still correcting
her fluids and electrolytes.
Uh, once that's done,
she'll need surgery.
Surgery...
It's routine. It's about
a 20-minute procedure.
Uh, we'll operate
in the morning.
We need your consent.
(Inhales and exhales deeply)
(Children speaking indistinctly)
(Roxy) T.J., Finn,
get a move on. Hup-to.
I'm ready.
Good.
Where's your brother?
T.J.!
We're having a pizza party
at school today.
I know, I know.
Here is your $5.
- Yes!
- Do not lose it, okay?
Okay.
Hey, where you going,
mister?
- You said I could ride my bike to school.
- Without your helmet?
- Helmets are dorky.
- No helmet, no bike ride.
Mom.
T.J., don't start with me.
You know the rules. Let's go.
Fine.
Let's go.
(Patty) The Kretchmer file
and the "Times" article
you were looking for.
Ah, thanks, Patty. Oh,
and I'll be leaving at noon
for colonel Burton's...
Change-of-command ceremony.
I'm all over it.
All right.
I called Mercer, and Dr. Lawlor
will cover your 1:00,
and Dr. Mead
has your 2:00 group.
- How would I get along without you?
- You wouldn't.
So this promotion
to Garrison commander...
- Yeah.
- It's a big deal, huh?
Oh, yeah. Joan's in charge
of all the day-to-day stuff
on Post.
I got a feeling her life's
gonna change in a major way.
- Well, what about yours?
- Me? Just the husband, Patty,
flying under the radar
like always.
- Yeah, right.
- Right.
(Laughs)
(Cries)
(Monitor beeping rhythmically)
(Beeping continues)
(Man) Okay,
let's get started.
We begin with a small incision
near the umbilicus.
(Beeping continues)
(Woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A.)
Here you go.
Thanks.
Okay.
Were you able
to reach Frank?
Yeah. I told him
I'd call him again
when Molly's out of surgery.
Right.
(Sighs)
How did I miss it?
Denise, you heard
what the doctor said.
Pyloric Stenosis is
easily confused with colic.
I'm a trained nurse,
Claudia Joy, a paramedic.
And a mother who's already
raised a colicky baby.
Of course you're gonna think
it's the same thing with Molly.
- Anyone would.
- Tanya didn't.
She tried to tell me
something was wrong,
and I... I snapped at her.
She left the house
in tears.
(Sighs)
(Woman speaks indistinctly
over P.A.)
Everything went as expected.
Molly's doing fine.
She's in recovery now.
We're gonna keep her
another day for observation.
Barring any complications,
you should be able
- to take her home tomorrow.
- Thank you. Thank you so much.
Of course.
(Laughs and sniffles)
(Cell phone rings)
(Ring)
Hey, Boone.
Hey, Moran.
Hello? You still there?
Yeah.
Uh, what's up?
Uh, I've got tomorrow's schedule
in front of me.
Sawicki's out, so you're taking
Sector Five, not Seven.
Okay. Great.
Yeah, I just wanted
to give you a heads-up.
Um... right.
Thanks.
Yeah. I'm, uh,
working the same shift.
(Police radio chatter)
Okay.
So I was thinking, uh,
maybe you want to grab
some drinks after work?
Let me guess.
Happy hour at Taco Boy?
(Spanish accent) You got
something against Taco Boy?
No, it's just that
their margaritas
make people do strange things.
(Normal voice) Yeah.
So is that a yes or a no?
I don't know.
Uh, maybe.
Come on, Moran.
No more maybes.
Yes or no? Up or down?
Salt or no salt?
Moran?
Okay. Yes.
And no salt.
Okay.
Hasta mañana.
Hey, Red.
Chase! You're back!
(Roxy) He just showed up
outta nowhere?
Yeah, and scared
the crap outta me.
(Laughs) You think he heard
you talking to Boone?
No, definitely not,
but it was written
all over my face.
What?
I don't know.
Um, embarrassment, guilt?
(Laughs) You didn't do
anything wrong.
You were talking on the phone.
And Chase is your ex-husband.
I know, I know,
but still, it felt like
he had caught us between
the sheets or something.
Really? Is there something
you're not telling me?
No.
(Laughs) Chase
shoulda called first,
- let you know he was back.
- Yeah, but that's not his style.
Did you tell him about
the job offer?
Yeah, I managed to squeak
that part out.
And?
And I told him I haven't
made any decisions
about Atlanta
or anything else.
And, you know,
I know Chase said
that he'd quit Delta if I
came back to him, but...
But?
But Chase loves Delta.
So what if he gives it up,
and six months later,
figures out he made
a big mistake and blames me?
Hey, ladies.
Hi.
Thanks for coming. I know
Joan really appreciates it.
Of course.
Chase is back.
Really?
What'd you tell him?
Oh, come on.
Not you, too.
- Hi, everybody.
- Hey.
Hey, Claudia Joy.
Where's Denise?
She told me you guys
were coming together.
Oh, well,
Denise can't make it.
Everything's fine,
but she's at Mercer.
- What?
- What happened?
(Sighs) There was a little scare
with Molly last night.
(Cell phone rings)
(Ring)
Hello.
Hey, Tanya.
It's Denise.
Oh, hi.
Hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
No, I'm just packing.
Uh, Tanya, I'm calling
from Mercer hospital.
Why? What happened?
Well, you were right
about Molly. She was sick.
She had Pyloric Stenosis.
Oh, my God. How is she?
Well, she's perfectly healthy
now, thanks to you.
(Inhales)
(Exhales deeply)
Well, I-I didn't do anything.
Yes, you did.
But I wouldn't listen.
I was being stubborn.
(Sighs) I'm sorry.
All that matters
is that Molly is okay.
Would you come
to the hospital?
I'd like you to see her.
Please.
(Monitor beeps rhythmically)
(Voice amplified) Mrs. holden,
honored guests
and friends,
soldiers, and army civilians
of Fort Marshall,
it is my privilege
to continue the work
of Colonel Tate.
All policies and procedures
will remain in effect.
I wouldn't be
standing here today
if not for the outstanding
soldiers I have served with
during my proud career
in the United States Army.
Without them, none of this
would've been possible.
I particularly would like
to thank my husband,
Dr. Roland Burton.
He has sacrificed beyond measure
to help me reach this day.
My husband and my daughter
give me the strength
and the reason to carry on.
And I can never
thank them enough.
(Coos)
Hey.
Thanks for coming.
Of course.
Hey there, pumpkin.
Are you feeling better?
Mm-hmm.
For the baby.
Oh, you didn't have to.
I saw it at the P.X.
And I couldn't resist.
Oh, it's adorable.
(Laughs)
(Chuckles)
Thanks. Here.
(Cooing)
Hey. (Laughs)
(Baby talk voice)
Let's try this one on, huh?
Oh, yeah. She likes it.
(Laughs) Good.
(Whispers) Hi. Hi.
Tanya...
(Normal voice) It's okay.
No, it's not.
You came for a friendly visit,
and I was awful.
No, you weren't.
Oh, yes, I was.
Okay, a little.
(Molly continues cooing)
It's just that Jeremy is...
He was my first baby
and... whew.
I get it. Really.
I wish you and I could
start over somehow.
(Sighs) We have.
(Door opens)
(Lowered voice) Surprise.
Hi.
Sorry. I couldn't
keep them away.
Aw. Hi.
Hi. Mwah.
Mwah. Hey, everyone.
This is Tanya Gabriel...
Jeremy's fiancée.
Hi.
Hey, Tanya.
And this is Claudia Joy,
Pamela, Roxy, Roland.
Hi.
Don't worry.
You'll get used to us.
Yeah, and you don't really
have a choice, so...
- How you doin', Denise?
- Great.
Yeah, how was Joan's ceremony?
It was terrific.
Oh, my God. I just realized,
I won't be able to make it to your
graduation tomorrow.
Oh, don't worry.
- Oh, yeah, and I have to work.
- Oh, Claudia Joy, me, too.
I know you're all busy.
Don't worry.
- Well, hell, I'll be there.
- Thanks, Roxy.
- Sure.
(Tanya) - You're graduating?
Damn straight.
Claudia Joy  Holden
- for the defense.
(Laughs) - I'm getting my law degree.
Wow. Congratulations.
Well, thank you.
It's a midyear ceremony,
so there's not a lot
of pomp and circumstance.
Oh, she's being modest.
She's at the top of her class.
(Cell phone rings)
Oh, excuse me. Sorry.
(Rings and beeps)
Hello.
Yes, this is Mrs. LeBlanc.
W... that cannot be right.
(Man) As I explained
on the phone, ma'am,
your son was caught shoplifting
an mp3 player from the P.X.
- this afternoon.
- You sure it was him?
Your son was photographed
by video surveillance
and the player was found
in his possession.
You stole an mp3 player?
(People speaking indistinctly)
Thank you, officers,
and you can be sure
that he will be properly
punished for this.
Well, that's your discretion,
ma'am, but you and your son
are to report to the juvenile
discipline review board
- tomorrow at 1300 hours.
- The what?
The juvenile
discipline review board.
They handle offenses like this
on Post.
And I'm guessing I don't have
a choice in that.
No, ma'am.
Have a good day.
Inside.
(Slams door)
What in the world
is going on, T.J.?
I don't know.
Look at me
when I am talking to you.
Where did you get the idea
that it is okay
to take something that
does not belong to you?
(Sighs) I am so mad at you
right now,
I don't even know
what to say.
Is this the first time you
stole something?
Yes.
So if I go into your room
right now,
I am not gonna find
anything else?
No.
We'll see about that.
Mom!
That's my stuff.
And it's in my house.
That's mine.
(Sighs)
You steal
and now you lie to me?
Is this all of it?
Answer me, T.J., right now,
or I swear to God...
Yes.
(Sighs deeply)
- Let's go.
- Where?
Back to the P.X.
You're gonna return this stuff
and you're gonna
tell 'em what you did.
Mom!
You move it.
(Roxy) I have never been so
embarrassed in my whole life.
Having to tell the
store manager at the P.X.
That my son
took all that stuff...
(Sighs) I swear, Pamela.
I just don't know what's
going on with him anymore.
Oh, I'm sorry, Rox.
It's like he's turned into
this little monster,
and I just want my sweet,
happy boy back.
I'm starting to get some of that
from Katie and Lucas, too.
Yeah, but they're not
shoplifting from the P.X.
And you know what's weird?
Most of the stuff he took,
he hadn't even
unwrapped it yet.
- Figure that out.
- Feeling guilty, maybe?
- So why keep stealing?
- I don't know.
Kids do crazy things.
Oh, shoot.
What?
(Sighs) Now I can't go
to Claudia Joy's graduation
tomorrow.
I have to go
to this discipline review
punishment thing with T.J.
Well, I'm sure
she'll understand.
- Well, what am I supposed to tell her?
- The truth.
Uh, no. I'm not telling
Claudia Joy Holden
that my son is a thief.
- Roxy!
- I'll just tell her
that there's a field trip for
one of the boys or something.
Hey, mom.
Um, hey, Roxy.
Chase is here with the kids.
So you hang in there, and I'll call
you back later, okay?
Okay. Thanks.
- Dad took us to the pier.
- Okay, bye.
Fish and chips.
We brought you some.
- But Lucas ate all your chips.
- I did not.
Well, that's okay.
I don't need any chips
- if I want to keep fitting in my uniform.
- Oh, you fit into it just fine.
(Katie) Can we watch TV?
Uh, homework first.
(Lucas) But...
No buts. Go.
(Katie) Fine.
So...
Chase, if you want an
answer, I don't have one yet.
Pamela...
and I know it's annoying,
but I've got a lot to think about.
Pamela, I have something to say.
Okay. Sorry.
I dropped my papers today.
It'll take a month or so
to process,
but after that, I won't be
a Delta operator anymore.
I know I told you I was gonna
wait for your answer,
but while I was away this time,
I got to thinking.
I want to be near the kids,
no matter what.
So I requested
a reassignment to instructor.
Wow.
No more missions.
No more leaving
in the middle of the night.
No more worrying
about where I am.
Wow.
You said that already.
Are you sure about this?
Yeah, I'm positive.
Okay, time to turn off
reading lights.
Night, mom.
Night, Finn.
Night, T.J.
(Roxy blows air)
(Cell phone rings)
(Ring)
(Beeps)
Hey, babe.
Oh, am I glad
to talk to you.
What the hell
is going on there, Rox?
What?
I come back from patrol,
and my platoon sergeant
pulls me out of chow line
and tells me T.J.'s stealing
from the P.X.
Yeah. Um...
That's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
What the hell is going on?
Hey, do not yell at me,
Trevor.
- Well, my son's stealing?
- It's our son,
and I don't know what's
going on with him either,
other than the fact that
his father is 8,000 miles away.
Oh, so this is my fault?
I suppose this has nothing
to do with the fact
that you had some guy sleep
over the other night?
What??
I heard about it
from three other guys, Roxy.
Their wives told 'em
his truck was still parked
out in front of our house
the next morning
and that you
kissed him good-bye.
I did not kiss him.
It... it's an old friend.
Nothing happened.
What old friend?
(Sighs) Finn's dad. Whit.
Finn's dad? I thought you said
he was out of your life.
He was. He is.
He was just passing through.
His daddy died
and left him some money,
and he wanted to
give Finn some of it.
Well, you didn't
take it did you?
It's for Finn's college fund.
Damn it, Roxy.
We don't need anybody's money.
I can provide for our family.
I know you can, babe.
So... so you took his money
then you had beers with him
on our front porch
with the whole
neighborhood watching.
I had two beers.
And he had a couple more,
so I let him sleep it off
on the couch.
You're unbelievable.
You let an ex-boyfriend
sleep in our house
while I'm not there?
On the couch.
And he's not an ex-boyfriend.
I already told you that.
No, he's just the father
of your son.
And you really wonder why
T.J.'s stealing from the P.X.?
That is so unfair.
It has absolutely
nothing to do with that.
How could you... I can't even
believe you could say that!
What do you want me to say?
I come back from patrol after
busting my ass for five days
to find out my wife is kissing
some other dude on our porch.
I told you that
that is not what happened.
Look, Trevor, I think
we need to concentrate on what
is really important here. Okay?
You need to talk to T.J.,
because he will listen to you,
and I can't play bad cop
all the time.
Fine. I'll try you tomorrow.
I gotta go.
Fine.
Ugh!
(Men speak indistinctly)
Ma'am,
governor Haley's office called
to confirm her attendance
at tonight's reception.
Excellent.
Yes, ma'am.
It'll be a good opportunity
to bring up your
green initiative for the Post.
Good idea, sergeant major.
I see we have the Juvenile
Discipline Review Board today.
Yes, ma'am. Last Tuesday
of every month.
Four cases today... Wilson,
cross, Tobias, and LeBlanc.
LeBlanc?
Toby Jack LeBlanc, ma'am.
You familiar with the family?
Yes, I am.
Is that gonna be a problem?
Not at all, sergeant major.
What else do we have today?
Let's see.
We have a meeting with
Colonel Reddick at 1100 hours.
The Provost Marshal
wants to present upgrade
for the perimeter
at 1600 hours.
However, I suggest
we move that...
(Indistinct conversations)
Excuse me.
Thank you. All right.
Claudia Joy.
Congratulations.
Thank you,
Professor Chandler.
You know, my class won't be
the same without you.
Oh, I bet you say that
to all your students.
No. Uh, I don't.
Uh... you alone?
Yes, Michael's, um,
in Afghanistan
and my friends were tied up.
Well, you can't be alone
on your graduation day.
(Chuckles)
How about lunch?
Oh, come on. You worked hard
to get to this day.
You d... you deserve
a little celebration.
You're right.
Excellent.
So...
What are you in the mood for?
(Both speaking indistinctly)
So, uh, I take it
you are studying
for the bar?
I am.
South Carolina
and New York.
New York?
Mm-hmm.
Michael's being considered
- for a position at West Point.
- Oh, impressive.
Also confidential.
Understood.
So... (Slurps)
What about when
you're done with the bar?
I don't know.
Have you considered
applying for a clerkship?
Working for a judge would
make you very marketable.
Oh, I would love to.
But any judge would
expect me to work full-time,
and that's just, uh,
it's not realistic
with my duties
at Fort Marshall.
I see.
And most law firms don't offer
part-time work, so...
Most.
But...
Not all.
Would you consider
working for me?
(Joan) Now that we've reviewed
the charges against you, T.J.,
is there anything
you'd like to say?
I'm really sorry.
I mean, I know stealing's wrong
and I won't do it again.
And he means that, too. T.J.
Is not a problem, and I...
Mrs. LeBlanc,
please sit down.
You're not permitted to speak
at this proceeding.
Sorry. He really is
a good boy.
T.J., the board appreciates
your apology
and hopes that your remorse
is sincere.
Nevertheless, criminal behavior
cannot go unpunished.
You are barred from the P.X.
for six months.
You will be issued
a new I.D. Card
with restrictions.
You will also write
a 500-word essay
on the dangers of shoplifting
to be delivered to this board
in one week.
Do you understand?
Yes, ma'am.
Additionally, to recover costs
related to shoplifting,
per Post Exchange regulation,
I am imposing a $100 fee
per shoplifted item...
an mp3 player, two DVDs,
a package of markers,
and a model car.
Wait a minute.
That's $500.
Please, Mrs. LeBlanc,
sit down.
But he returned
all that stuff,
and he also apologized
to the store manager.
We recognize the burden
these fines may place on you,
but they are mandated
by policy.
Well, you wouldn't have even
known about those other items
if I didn't make T.J.
Bring them back.
Mrs. LeBlanc, your presence
here is a privilege.
Just as it is a privilege
for your family
to have housing on Post.
In the future, I recommend
you control your son's behavior.
Thank you for your time.
Let's go.
(Door closes)
(Roxy) It was so unfair.
Okay, all right,
slow down.
She fined me $500...
- Right.
- And humiliated me.
Look, Joan was just doing
her job. It's not personal.
Not personal? She threatened
to throw us off Post.
I'm sure
she didn't mean that.
You weren't there.
No, I wasn't.
- So what do you want me to do?
- I don't know. Talk to her.
We returned everything,
so why should we have to pay
a fine on top of that?
Look, Roxy, I'm sorry,
but I'm not gonna tell my wife
how to do her job. (Sighs)
If you want, I could...
I could talk to T.J. For you.
No, thank you.
I can handle my son.
Well, I thought you just told
me you were having problems.
I'll handle it.
(Sighs)
Hey, look...
I know this is rough.
But Joan's job is to enforce
Post regulations.
I'm sure
it was hard on her, too.
(Scoffs) Not as hard
as it was on me.
No.
But the real problem here
is T.J., isn't it?
I guess.
Trevor been any help?
(Scoffs)
(Sighs)
You don't want to know.
Thank you.
Sorry to bother you.
Hey, Roxy.
I'm here.
(Door closes)
(Denise) Good news.
They cleared Molly
to go home today.
Good. (Laughs)
Tanya's gonna stay
a few extra days
and help out.
Great. I'm so glad.
Oh, me, too.
How was graduation?
It was fine.
Professor Chandler
was there.
Mm-hmm.
Took me to lunch.
Mm. Nice.
Hey.
Big Professor taking out
his star pupil.
Ah. (Chuckles) I guess.
Oh, did you hear
from Michael?
No.
Hmm.
I'm sure he's busy.
Yeah.
Claudia Joy.
Hmm?
(Sighs) I have to admit,
some flowers
would've been nice...
Or a card even.
Mm. I know it's silly.
(Chuckles)
It's not silly at all.
(Molly fusses)
(Objects clattering)
(Wrench clicking)
Hello, Tom.
Afternoon, Mrs. Holden.
Your garbage disposal
is back in business.
And I fixed that leak
in your guest bathroom.
Good.
You're a lifesaver.
(Laughs) Not at all.
Oh, uh,
those came for you
while I was here.
Pretty.
Yeah.
You have
a good day now.
Thanks, Tom. You, too.
Michael.
(Door opens)
(Computer chimes)
(Door closes)
Hello, beautiful.
Hey.
I just had a minute. I thought
I'd try and catch you.
- I'm glad you did.
- I wanted to tell you,
the list for West Point
just got shorter,
and I'm still on it.
That's wonderful.
I don't want to brag,
but I really think I have
a good shot at this.
How was your day?
It was good.
Graduation was nice.
Wait a minute.
That was today?
No. How did I screw that up?
(Sighs) I had it down
as next week.
Oh, Claudia Joy,
I am so sorry.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not.
You're busy, Michael.
You have a lot on your mind.
That's no excuse
after all the hard work
you put in.
- You know how proud I am of you?
- I do.
(Sighs) Oh, man.
Michael, it's okay.
Besides... (Clears throat)
I have some good news, too.
I got a job offer today.
What? You haven't even
taken the Bar.
I know. It's only part-time,
and Professor Chandler says
I can work around
my responsibilities on Post.
Chandler? You're taking
a job with Grant Chandler?
With his law firm.
They do a lot
of public interest law.
I didn't say yes.
I wanted to talk to you first.
Right.
Michael,
it's a great opportunity.
Associate-level work...
there's no way
I'd get an offer like this
anywhere else.
Well, you know I'm not wild
about the guy.
But whatever you decide,
I'll support.
Thank you.
I gotta go. I love you.
I love you, too.
And I will make up
for this.
Forget about it, honey.
Not a chance.
(Clicks keyboard key)
(Computer chirps)
So Chase is switching jobs.
He's gonna be on Post now.
Yeah. An instructor.
And the Atlanta job
is still open.
Yep.
And I am right here.
Yeah.
(Indistinct conversations)
Have you made a decision,
any decisions?
♪
yeah, I'm gonna have
the fish tacos.
Funny, Moran.
(Indistinct conversations
continue)
You know... (Sighs)
Boone, you really
blindsided me the other day.
I guess I just had never
thought of us...
Like that.
That's just what
every guy wants to hear.
I know. Sorry.
Hey, if you need more time...
I don't need more time.
You sure?
Yeah. I mean...
Who am I kidding?
Why didn't I just go for the
Atlanta job right away?
Because I'm still in love
with Chase.
♪
(Grant) Claudia Joy,
have a seat.
Uh, no, no,
I-I can't stay long.
First I wanted to thank you
for the flowers.
- They're beautiful.
- A-a-and?
Well, um...
When I commit to something,
I like to see it through
to the end.
But in this case, I know
you're gonna be putting in
a lot of time and resources,
and...
you're not sure how much longer
you're gonna be in Charleston.
Exactly.
This is the Army, after all.
And I don't want
to shortchange you.
Noted and appreciated.
But I wouldn't have made
the offer
if I hadn't taken that
into account.
We'll get our money's worth
out of you. Believe me.
Yeah?
You can count on it.
Okay. I will.
- Is that a yes?
- It is.
Welcome to
Chandler, Arnoff & Drake.
Thank you, Professor.
Grant.
Grant. Thank you.
(Instrumental jazz music
playing)
(Indistinct conversations)
This is my third
event for Joan
in the past two days.
There's a big difference
between being
a soldier's spouse
and a commander's spouse.
Seriously.
Do you ever get tired of it,
the responsibility?
(Sighs) Sometimes.
It's a constant balancing act
between your needs,
your spouse's needs,
and the army's needs.
As far
as Uncle Sam's concerned,
you're an extension
of Joan's office.
Right.
It's not what I signed up for,
Claudia Joy.
(Chuckles) Making small
talk with dignitaries
is not exactly my idea
of a good time.
Get used to it.
(Mouths word)
Come on.
Joan will start wondering
why you're avoiding her.
Well, she's with the Governor.
Exactly, and that's why
- you need to be right at her side.
- Claudia Joy...
come on, soldier.
(Music continues)
Colonel, sergeant major.
(Joan) Evening, Claudia Joy.
Governor Haley, it's so good
to see you again.
It's my pleasure.
Governor, this is my husband,
Dr. Roland Burton.
Evening, ma'am.
Uh, Governor.
- Nice to meet you, Dr. Burton.
- Same here.
I was just telling Roland
how much we appreciate
- your support of military families.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
I know Joan's
really looking forward
to working with you on some
environmental initiatives.
Really? I'd love to
hear about that.
I was just getting there,
but my husband
is one step ahead of me.
Well, it happens occasionally, but
very occasionally. (All laugh)
(Joan) All right.
Well, I'd love to talk about it.
Devlin, you will set that up?
(Devlin) I'll check the schedule.
(T.J.) Hey, dad.
(Trevor) What's going on
with you?
I messed up.
Yeah.
You messed up big-time.
Yeah,
I told everyone I'm sorry.
Okay. So what are you
gonna tell me?
Do I have to remind you that
your actions have consequences?
No.
And not just consequences for you,
but for your mom, me, Finn,
everyone.
I know.
I gotta say, T.J., I'm real
disappointed in you.
I expected a lot more.
I need you to stay
on the right path from now on.
- You understand?
- Yes.
Yes, what?
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Put your mom back on.
Okay. Bye, dad.
He wants
to talk to you again.
Okay. Go get ready
for bed.
So? So I hope I got through to him.
Yeah, me, too.
(Sighs) I can't take
much more of this, Trevor.
I don't know
what's going on there, Rox,
but whatever it is,
it's gotta stop.
Now.
Really, Trevor, does it?
Does it need to stop?
Thank you so much
for your support.
Well,
you're the one at home,
so you're the one who's gotta
keep it together.
(Sighs) Yeah.
Well, do you want to tell me
how to do that?
(Sighs)
(Chuckles)
I thought that went well.
(Chuckles) Yeah.
It's gonna take
a little getting used to,
being a commander's spouse.
(Laughs)
You did great.
Thank you.
Hey, Roxy came by
to see me today.
Oh?
Yeah, she was pretty upset.
Her son stole from the P.X.
And had to face
the consequences.
Mm-hmm.
I sure hope
he learned his lesson.
Me, too.
But 500 bucks?
Sounds kinda harsh.
I agree,
but it's Post policy.
Roxy shouldn't have
come to you with this.
Ah, don't worry.
I defended you.
I don't need defending.
Her son is the one
who did something wrong.
Okay. I understand.
(Sighs)
I hope so.
As Garrison commander,
I've got a lot of people
watching my every move.
As a woman, particularly
as a woman of color,
I've got to be
better than good at this job.
I have
got to be outstanding.
One hint of favoritism,
one sign of weakness,
my credibility is gone.
I got it.
Thank you.
♪
(giggles) He was so cute
when he was little.
Mm. Yes, he was.
I'm sorry we don't have
a proper guest bedroom.
We turned Jeremy's room
into the nursery.
Compared to Afghanistan,
this is a five-star hotel.
Aw. Well, I think
you're all set.
I'll see you in the morning.
Good night.
I'm so glad you're here.
- Me, too.
- Yeah.
(Man)
♪ like a silent wind blowing ♪
♪ through the cracks
in the walls ♪
♪ of my room ♪
♪ and my heart did sink ♪
♪ and my eyes did shut ♪
♪ and my mind got tangled up ♪
Well, I appreciate
your confidence in me, captain.
And I think it would be great
to work for Atlanta P.D.
But I have decided
to stay in Charleston.
No.
Strictly personal.
Okay.
Thank you, sir.
Good night.
♪ And my heart did sink ♪
♪ and my eyes did shut ♪
♪ and my mind got tangled up ♪
(rings)
(Ringing)
Let's go!
Wheels up in 20.
We've got a long flight
ahead of us. Come on.
(Chase) Hey, leave your name and
number and I'll call you back.
(Pamela) Hey, Chase. It's me.
Listen, I need to talk to you,
so...
Give me a call
as soon as you get this, okay?
♪
♪ thought a lot
about you today ♪
♪ 'cause you kept creeping in ♪
♪ like a silent wind blowing ♪
♪ through the cracks
in the walls of my room ♪
Sync & corrections by Alice
www.addic7ed.com