DOOR OPENS
Simon.
Morning, Mark.
How are you?
Just missed the quack.
No change, I'm afraid.
But you are going to be all right?
Apart from being blind, you mean?
You shouldn't have done it.
It's only temporary, Mark.
I'll be fine.
What about the new test?
We're going ahead now.
Halliday in charge?
Yes.
He's got no bloody idea
what he's doing.
Do be careful, won't you?
You're a fine one to speak.
Just keep an eye on him.
DOOR CLOSES
Wind direction?
South-southeast.
Perfect. Get on with it.
Captain -
I think this is not -
I have my orders, Wilcox. So do you.
Raise the red flag.
Are you going to do the honours?
Ready?
INSECTS BUZZ
SAM: So how's your new billet?
FARNETTI: Better than the old one.
We're staying in this duke's place.
Never seen a place so big
in my life. Or so damp.
It rained a lot last month.
Yeah? Well, it looks like it rained
a lot for the last 1,000 years.
I have to tell you, I can't wait to
get back to California.
Do you mean that?
War can't last for ever.
I mean, specially
now that we're here.
You know - everything that's
happening in France.
Things don't look too good for
Rommel in Africa.
Looks like things might work out
in Dieppe.
I'm telling you, it's not going to
last much longer.
And then you'll shove off home,
I suppose?
You bet. Aw, man, I'm on the first
boat out of here.
Provided, that is, that you come
with me.
Me?
Come on, Sam.
You know how I feel about you.
You've only known me a short while.
Well... the best while of my life.
Come on. You've been cold and damp
and miserable.
Yeah. Cold and damp and miserable -
and more than a little grateful
to the Jerries
because without them,
I'd never have met you.
Joe...
I mean it.
I want you to marry me.
I want you to come home with me.
I want you to meet my family.
You got to meet my mom.
She's gonna love you.
I want you to have kids with me.
And I want to never let you go.
Is this a proposal?
Well... I suppose...
I suppose it is.
You want me to do it properly?
No.
No, it's too late.
Will you marry me, Sam?
Wait, wait, wait.
I don't have a ring.
OK.
This sea shell will have to do,
right?
You're the most beautiful girl
I ever met
and I want to marry you.
What do you say?
Get up, Joe.
No.
Not until you give me an answer.
Is that a yes or a no?
Morning, sir.
Morning. What um...?
Orders from the Assistant
Commissioner, sir.
Forget the spivs, the racketeers
and all the rest of it.
What really matters is these new
fuel targets. Light bulbs.
I see.
You won't for much longer.
Meant to be taking out half
the lights in the building.
So far, we're up to 40.
Couldn't we just um...
not turn them on?
Need the bulbs, sir.
Oh, right. Right. Tried my office?
Wouldn't go in without your say-so,
sir. But if you can help...
I'll take a look.
Afraid that's not the end of it,
sir.
From now, the canteen will only
serve hot food three times a week.
So we can look forward to Spam
sandwiches all round.
Wonderful (!)
Mr Milner. Young lady to see you.
Paul.
Edith. Edith Ashford.
Yes.
You are still Miss Ashford?
Yes. I'm not married.
Gosh. I haven't seen you for what?
Eight years?
Nearly ten, I think.
I heard you were in the forces.
Yes, I was.
And then you came here. You always
said you wanted to be a detective.
I did.
I... didn't know whether to come
or not.
The truth is...
I didn't have anyone else
to turn to.
Are you in trouble?
No. Not me. My brother.
Martin.
I didn't know if you'd remember him.
Of course I would. He was
the smallest boy in school.
He was only, what? Six or seven?
He was just starting when I left.
You were very kind to him.
That's one of the reasons I thought
of you.
Why? What's happened to him?
He's been arrested.
He's been accused of murder.
My brother would never hurt anyone.
I mean, that's one of the reasons
he refused to fight.
He's a Quaker.
A conscientious objector.
That hasn't stopped him doing
his bit.
He's done firewatching,
and ambulance driving.
Now he's helping down at Foxhall
Farm.
Well, I'm not entirely familiar
with the circumstances here,
but I gather it's a war hero
that your brother is accused
of murdering?
Tom Jenkins.
Royal Navy. Serving on the Navarino.
Part of the convoy was sunk.
Martin didn't kill him.
I understand he was arrested
very shortly afterwards?
Wrongfully arrested.
Have you spoken to him?
That's the trouble. He won't talk to
me. He won't talk to anyone.
Which might suggest
he's not quite as innocent as you
believe him to be?
I know Martin didn't do it.
He's three years younger than me.
I've looked after him all my life.
There's nothing I wouldn't do
for him.
I know him.
And I know he wouldn't do this.
I'm begging you to help.
Would you talk to him?
Well, if he's not talking to anyone,
what makes you think he'll talk to
us?
Well, he knew Paul.
I mean, Mr Milner.
We were close once. The two of us.
And he knew...
This might not be quite as easy
as you think. Um...
Martin was arrested further down
the coast, at Hythe.
That's not in our jurisdiction.
But you must know people.
There's a policeman called Fielding.
DCS Fielding. Can't you talk to him?
Please.
I've got no-one else to turn to.
Please, tell me at least you'll try.
I'm leaving, then.
Where are you going?
I had a call from Brian Jones.
Something's wrong with his cattle,
so I'm going to go to Foxhall.
You could come if you like.
No.
So what are you going to do?
I don't know, Dad.
Are you just going to mope
around here all day?
I don't know, Dad.
Maybe I'll go out for a walk.
Don't worry about me.
I'll see you, then.
Morning, Brian.
You made it, then.
I said ten o'clock, didn't I?
Where are they?
This way.
Come on, love. Come on, girl.
So what is it, then?
I'm not sure.
That's not very good.
I'd say it's some sort of flu.
Not flu.
We don't know that.
Don't know anything very much, Ted.
And you say they all got it
at the same time?
Within 24 hours.
It's unusual, a whole herd being
affected like this.
A herd? There are only six of them.
Let me look at the samples,
and I'll get back to you.
All right.
You haven't had any other animals
here, have you?
No-one passing through?
Visitors?
Hm.
She's very sick.
I can see that.
You're unusually quiet.
Yes, sir.
Does that mean you're thinking?
Yes.
Need any help?
No, thank you.
I just have to make up my mind about
something, and it's rather awkward.
I feel as though I've come
to a crossroads
and I'm afraid of making the wrong
turn.
We just have.
You should have gone that way.
Hythe is left.
Oh. Sorry.
Someone get a stretcher,
for heaven's sake.
Why isn't it here?
Yes, sir.
Foyle.
What are you doing here?
They told me at the station
this was where I'd find you.
Who did you speak to? Henderson?
And he suggested you walk into the
middle of a murder investigation
without so much as a by-your-leave?
When did you find her?
Ten minutes ago.
Then he wouldn't have known what
he was sending me into, would he?
You know her?
Who is she?
Her name is Joan Chaplin.
Prostitute. She works down the docks
in Dover.
Or used to.
Stupid bloody waste of life.
All right.
Get her out of there.
Where the hell have you been?
Well, if you're not interested in
her, what can I do for you?
Martin Ashford?
Oh, another murder case.
Local lad. Lives up your way.
The killing took place down here.
What do you want him for?
I don't. It's a personal connection.
The sergeant here knows his sister.
What's your name?
Milner, sir.
I see, Milner.
So you know his sister.
Are you close?
We were childhood friends.
She came to me because she believes
Martin is innocent.
You want to reinvestigate the case?
I wouldn't put it like that exactly.
Have you nothing better to do
than rake over old ground?
Far from it.
I just wanted your opinion.
Milner's connection might be useful
if only to reassure the sister,
but if you don't want us under your
feet, I quite understand.
(COUGHS) It's getting a bit nippy.
The wind gets on my chest.
Do you mind if we talk inside?
Just the two of us.
What the hell you do think
you're doing?
I haven't seen you for the best part
of two years,
and you walk in here and show me up
in front of my men.
I haven't done anything of the sort.
Look, I spoke to Edith Ashford
not once, but several times.
She gave me all that stuff
about her brother's innocence.
I didn't trust her.
I didn't believe her, and frankly
I'm surprised that you do.
Let me give you the facts.
Thomas Jenkins and Martin Ashford
argued publicly and violently
and then they arranged to meet
that evening on the beach
to settle their differences.
That's where Jenkins was killed.
We know that Ashford was there.
He claims that he came upon
the body,
that Jenkins had been stabbed
by some sort of knife.
It took us a while to find it,
and the MO is trying to work out
what it is.
But I tell you where we found it.
It was half buried in woodland
not 200 yards from where Martin
Ashford lived.
Seems pretty straightforward.
Didn't find anything.
The prints had been wiped clean.
But we did find blood stains
on Ashford's clothing
and it matched those of the dead
man.
He didn't confess.
He hasn't denied it either, which
is more or less the same thing.
So, there you have it.
Pretty straightforward, I agree.
Now, would you tell me
what gives you the right
to drive over here
and question my judgement?
Not my intention.
No?
No. I told you I don't know
anything about this
apart from what the sister told me.
I came over here to ask if you,
as a friend,
would mind me speaking to the man,
to put her mind at rest
even if it meant telling her
that he's guilty.
But as you say, at the same time,
he hasn't confessed,
so it's possible I can help.
As a friend?
As a friend.
Do you remember me, Martin?
No.
Paul Milner.
We were at school together.
Ten years ago.
Your sister Edith came to see us.
Why?
Because she wants us to help you.
You can't help me.
Martin, did you kill Tom Jenkins?
No.
But you were there with him
on the beach?
Why won't you talk to us?
I've got nothing to say.
Your sister thinks you're innocent.
She believes in you.
I'd say at the very least
you owe it to her to talk to us.
What rank are you, Milner?
I'm a sergeant.
Well, Sergeant Milner, I don't care
what Edith thinks,
and I don't know why you're here.
But I've just told you -
I've got nothing to say.
Someone perhaps
that you're... protecting?
Some argument with Jenkins?
What was that about?
The war.
You're a pacifist, aren't you?
That's not what he called me.
What did he call you?
Whatever it was, no good reason to
kill him, as far as I'm concerned.
I didn't kill him.
Do you know who did?
You're working on a farm,
is that right?
Why are you asking me?
It's all in the report.
Your sister doesn't believe
the report.
She doesn't know anything.
Neither do you.
I just want you to leave me alone.
DOG WHINES
Edith!
Paul!
Have you seen him?
Have you seen Martin?
Yes. We spoke to him earlier.
And?
I'm afraid he didn't have very much
to say.
But we're still looking into it.
How did you find me here?
I saw where you worked.
It's in the report.
And I thought it would be nice to
speak to you again
after all this time.
I'm absolutely famished.
You can take me out for tea.
The Russians are losing,
aren't they?
The Germans have taken Sebastopol
and that other place -
I can never remember the names.
They say Stalingrad will be next.
Looks as if Joe's finished.
I'm sure it's not all bad news.
Africa is going our way.
I just want the war to be over.
It's so awful.
We get a lot of sailors in.
Merchant seamen.
They're burned.
They're half-drowned.
It's horrible, the things that have
happened to them.
When did you become a nurse?
Before the war.
My mother was sister-in-charge
at the same hospital.
Yes, I remember.
And you went straight
into the police?
More or less, yes.
I remember you after school.
You were always playing
Bulldog Drummond.
Sniffing around in people's
back gardens.
The Lindens at No.27 - you were
convinced they were Bolsheviks.
Was I?
Martin used to keep lookout for me.
He didn't do it, Paul.
You believe me, don't you?
Mr Foyle thinks
he might be protecting someone.
Edie? Can you tell me? Is there
anyone he might be involved with?
No.
Are you sure?
Of course I am.
Then why won't he talk?
Is that why you asked me out?
To question me?
No.
I wanted to see you again.
Tell me about California.
I've no idea what it's like.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Oranges and movie stars?
(CHUCKLES)
Everybody in huge cars.
Sure.
Even Lassie has his own limousine.
Tell me about the street
where you live.
No. I don't want to talk about it.
I haven't been home in nine months.
Why so long?
They trained us at Fort Benning,
Virginia,
and they shipped us out here.
Have you spoken to your parents?
They give us six minutes a week.
War is hell, right?
Hey, let's get an iced soda.
You'll be lucky. We haven't had
ice cream here since 1940.
And none of the pubs are open,
so don't ask for a beer.
I love this country, you know?
Everything about it is so...
What?
Impossible.
So have you thought about
what I asked you?
Of course I have.
I haven't thought about anything
else.
And?
You know I'm very fond of you, Joe.
But I hardly know you.
My mother would have a fit if I just
upped and left
without even introducing you first.
Well, we could get a horse and buggy
and have a dance
and invite all the neighbours.
You've been reading too much
Jane Austen.
Yeah, well...
I would be exceedingly obliged,
Miss Stewart,
if you would be the next
Mrs Farnetti.
Oh, stop it.
Is that a yes or a no?
I don't know.
You'll have to give me more time,
I'm afraid.
You can have all the time you want.
Good.
Yeah?
Sir.
Is he after yours as well?
Yes, sir. He's got two of mine.
What does he do with them?
I have no idea.
Read that?
Yes, sir. Last night.
And?
I have to admit
DCS Fielding is right.
It does look pretty cut and dried.
Thomas Stephen Jenkins aged 26.
He was a fisherman before the war.
He joined the navy
and was a petty officer on convoy
duty on the Navarino
when it was sunk just
off the Kola Peninsula.
He was awarded the DSM.
He managed to break down
a burning door -
chopped the hinges off,
got 12 men to safety. They would
have died if it wasn't for him.
After that, he jumped overboard
and spent six hours
in freezing water.
He only survived because he managed
to cling to a piece of wreckage.
If you ask me, he deserved a medal
for that alone.
'He's married.
His wife is Elsie Jenkins, aged 23.
They have one child,
a boy of 18 months.
What about Martin Ashford?
Single.
Unattached as far as we know.
He used to work with Jenkins
before the war.
The two of them argued the evening
Jenkins got back from the palace.'
Not going to join us?
To be fair to Jenkins, he was drunk.
See that, Martin?
That was given to me by the King.
Now. Are you going to buy me
a drink?
You've had enough.
Are you ashamed to drink with me?
I understand that.
I mean, what have you ever done
for the war? Bloody conchie.
Leave him, Tom.
Leave him? Why should I leave him?
You know...
All those years I knew you,
I never put you down as a coward.
You're drunk.
In the morning I'll be sober.
You'll still be a bloody coward.
You don't know anything about me.
Half of my friends are dead.
They drowned.
They burned.
You, you're skulking away
up at Foxhall Farm
as if the war's nothing
to do with you.
If everyone was like you,
Jerry would be here.
Tom!
Come on, Martin. Let's go home.
You may have a medal,
but I know you for what you are.
I don't give a damn about you.
You want to step outside?
I'll meet you any time, anywhere.
I'm not afraid of you.
All right, then.
Midnight tonight.
Down by the boat on the beach.
You and me.
Don't be silly. You don't have any
reason to fight.
Getting your big sister to look
after you? That's brave.
I'll meet you.
No.
You heard what he called me.
So?
I'm not a coward.
Just forget it, Tom.
Come and have another drink.
I'm waiting for an answer.
You want someone to take you down
to size, I'll do it.
I'm fed up with you, Jenkins.
We all are.
"I'm fed up with you, Jenkins.
We all are."
Half a dozen people heard him
say it.
Not exactly proof of his guilt,
is it?
No. I agree.
Did Jenkins regularly accuse him of
cowardice
or did this come out of nothing?
Well, sir, they were both very
drunk.
So they met?
Yes.
'Martin Ashford left Foxhall Farm
just after 11 o'clock.
He was carrying something.
It may have been a knife.
He was seen leaving by the farmer,
a man called Brian Jones.
He is Thomas Jenkins' father-in-law.
Elsie Jenkins is his daughter.
We know that Thomas Jenkins
was on the beach at about 11:15.
He was seen by a warden
on his way home.
As to what happened next...'
Well, well, well...
So you turned up.
Now there's a surprise.
According to the police doctor,
the knife - whatever it was -
entered between the third and fourth
rib,
slanting upwards into the heart.
Very precise. Could have been someone
with medical knowledge.
And the evidence against Ashford
again, in a nutshell, is...?
He was seen running away from the
beach.
Jenkins' blood was found later on
his clothes.
And the weapon was found in the
woodland at Foxhall Farm.
Right.
It doesn't look too good, does it,
sir? No.
Sure you want to go on with this?
Yes, sir.
KNOCKING
Sorry to disturb you, gentlemen.
I thought you might like to look
at this.
When they moved me out of London,
I never expected anything like it.
It's like something out of
the Wild West. Cattle rustling.
Six animals were taken
while the farmer was in Hastings.
Do you want me to send someone up
there?
Er, no, we'll look into it.
Thank you.
Whatever you say, sir.
Are they for me?
Certainly are.
Oh, well done, sir.
What does he do with them?
Foxhall Farm.
Where's Sam?
Get off!
Go on, off! Go on. Shoo!
Shoo!
You took your time.
I'm sorry?
I was in Hastings yesterday.
I wasn't there more than a few hours
and here's something you need to
know.
There was a car parked as I left.
There were two men in it.
Now I think about it I get
the feeling
they were waiting for me to leave.
Mr Jones, I'm not here about that.
I thought you were the police.
Yes, this is about the death
of Mr Jenkins.
What, you're here about Ashford?
That's right. He worked here?
He helped out. He had a room.
What more do you want to know?
He was quiet, he was a very good
worker.
He kept himself to himself, really.
You saw him leaving that night with
some knife or other, apparently?
He was carrying something long and
narrow.
I don't know what it was,
it was dark.
Right.
What about Thomas Jenkins? Your
son-in-law, is that right? Yes.
Did you get on with him? Look, I've
just had six head of cattle
lifted from me in broad daylight.
Jenkins is dead, Ashford's in jail.
What more do you need?
Did you get on with him?
Of course, he was married to my
daughter.
You don't seem...very affected
by the death of your son-in-law, if
you don't mind me saying.
You don't know what I feel,
Mr Foyle,
and I'm not going to tell you.
Jenkins died out there on that
beach,
I suppose because somebody had
a grudge against him.
Now, what I'd like to know is, what
are you going to do about my cows?
DOOR OPENING
Who are you? What do you want?
My name is Leonard Cartwright.
Cartwright, yes. The desk sergeant
told me.
I served with Tom Jenkins on the
Navarino.
Well, that's very nice for you,
Mr Cartwright,
but have you brought me any new
information?
Are you the officer in charge of
the investigation? Yes.
You're the one who arrested
Martin Ashford. Yes.
Well, you've made a mistake.
Have I?
Please, Mr Fielding, hear me out.
I owe my life to Tom Jenkins.
You know he was decorated for
bravery?
I was one of the people that he
saved.
Go on.
I was floating in the water
after we'd been torpedoed
and he helped me onto a raft.
If he hadn't,
I'd have frozen to death.
I'd imagine, then, that you'd have
every interest
in wanting his killer brought to
justice.
That's exactly the point, yes,
of course,
but the thing is, you see, I know
Martin Ashford.
I mean, Hythe is a small place.
Everyone knows everyone,
and I know he couldn't possibly have
committed this crime.
Were you with him at midnight on
August 5th? No.
Well, were you on the beach?
Did you see who did it?
No! Ashford and I are both Quakers.
We went to the same meeting house.
You fought? Yes, I gave up my
religion when the war began.
With what was happening in the
world,
it just didn't seem relevant any
more.
But he didn't.
He's a pacifist.
Surely you can see what that means.
He doesn't have it in him to kill.
Thank you for coming in,
Mr Cartwright.
You haven't listened to me.
It doesn't matter what I just said.
I have listened to you.
You're wasting my time.
GOAT BLEATING
Do you like it?
Ow!
Six calves gone, disappeared into
thin air.
No-one cares! I think
it's a disgrace.
There's a war on. They're not just
cattle, they're a vital resource.
I understand. This place certainly
attracts a lot of traffic.
What are you talking about?
Do you know who that is?
Who? Is that the car you've been
talking about?
It might be.
Thank you.
Can you see that number?
BKR...721, sir.
Well done.
Oh, it could have been 712, I'm not
sure. That's helpful.
Check them both. Are you all right?
What have you done?
It's just a scratch, sir.
It's nothing.
ENGINE STARTING
DOG BARKING
Thank you for seeing me.
My door's always open, Wilcox.
How's Higgins?
No change, I'm afraid.
So, what can I do for you?
Captain Halliday,
this business at Foxhall Farm.
Oh, yeah.
I've seen the results of the test.
Four of the animals were infected.
Four out of six, yes.
That's unfortunate.
It's a little more than that.
What have you done with them?
We burned them.
Good.
But the farm may still be infected.
He had only the six cattle.
He had chickens, dogs, God knows
what else,
but there are people there, too.
We need to warn them.
You know that's out of the question,
unless you want to start a flap.
Won't that happen anyway?
The situation's under control,
Wilcox, that's all that matters.
I'm sorry, sir, I don't agree.
This thing started because of
complete incompetence.
I think you should be careful what
you say.
I am your commanding officer.
Look, there's no need for us to fall
out.
We're on the same side, we have the
same aims.
We're keeping an eye on Foxhall.
I grant you we may have made a
mistake but we got away with it.
Terrible about Higgins. Is he going
to be all right?
I'll let you know...sir.
Mrs Jenkins?
Yes.
I'm a police officer.
Could I have a word?
You'll have to excuse me, Mr Foyle.
I'm not feeling at all myself.
I think I've picked up a summer
cold.
Are you on your own here?
I've sent Danny away.
He's my son. He's staying with my
mum.
(STIFLES COUGH)
Are you seeing a doctor?
No, it'll pass.
How can I help you?
This is about Tom, isn't it?
It is, yes.
Have you found the man who did it?
Well, a man's been arrested.
Martin Ashford didn't kill
my husband.
I told the other policeman that.
I know him. His sister's a friend
of mine, a good friend.
I've known her all my life.
Look, I was there when they had that
stupid row in the King's Arms.
It was all Tom's fault.
He'd had a bit too much to drink,
and he could be like that sometimes.
Didn't Ashford threaten him?
Not really.
If anything it was the other way
round.
But neither of them meant anything
by it,
that's what I'm trying to tell you.
It was all just talk.
Tell me about your husband.
He was very good to me.
Kind.
Generous.
Did you go to the Palace with him?
Of course I did.
They say that 12 men were saved,
thanks to him.
I was very proud.
I'm sorry, Mr Foyle, I think I need
to lie down.
Yes, I understand.
You should see a doctor.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Mr Foyle, you have
Chief Superintendent Fielding
waiting for you, sir.
I put him in your office.
Thank you.
Not the most friendly of chaps,
I wouldn't have said. Neither am I.
Just tipping you the wink, sir, if
you catch my drift. I understand.
Sir, the car you saw outside
Foxhall Farm
belongs to a man called Henry
Styles. Anything on him?
Nothing on record.
Might be a government connection.
There aren't many cars around now
there's no basic petrol ration.
Did you get an address?
He's here in Hastings.
Good evening.
I haven't been here for a very long
time.
No, you used to drop in a lot more
often.
Drink?
What have you got?
Well, half an inch of Scotch.
I'll take it.
I thought you might.
I wanted to know how
the investigation's going.
Do you still think I've got
the wrong man? Did I say that?
No, I told you exactly
how I got involved
and, quite frankly, I'm beginning to
regret it.
Why?
Well, it's clearly irritated you.
You still haven't answered
the question.
Do I still think you've got
the wrong man?
Well...
Do sit down.
There are certainly one or two things
about it that struck me as odd.
Yes? No-one seems to give a damn
about the murdered war hero.
They're all far too concerned
about it not being Martin Ashford
who did it. That's true.
The father-in-law, the wife - They
said the same when I spoke to them.
I was with the wife earlier,
Jenkins's wife.
Not a photograph of her husband
to be seen.
Well, it's too painful. She can't
bear to see him. Perhaps.
Are you going to stick with it?
Would you rather I stopped?
I'm retiring, you know.
I didn't know.
End of the year.
I'm fed up with it, if you want
the truth.
Fed up with the whole thing.
(STIFLES COUGH)
I've been in this job too long.
20-odd years, same as you.
I don't see the point any more.
So, it's time to go.
I thought you might like this.
It's the murder weapon.
It's called a trocar.
Vets use them on cattle.
Do we know any vets?
I had a visit earlier today from a
young man called Leonard Cartwright.
He served with Jenkins on
the Navarino
and he's saying exactly the same
thing...
Jenkins was a good man, but Ashford
didn't kill him,
I've got it wrong.
And...?
His father's a vet.
Mr Foyle. Good evening.
Are you waiting for Sam?
Yes, sir. We're supposed to be
seeing a movie,
but we're going to be late.
What are you going to see?
Saboteur.
I would have preferred a comedy
but Sam likes a good mystery.
I've noticed.
Joe.
Hey!
We're going to be late.
Are you all right?
No, I'm not. Joe, I'm sorry,
I'm going to have to stand you up.
I feel rotten. I think I've got flu.
Let me walk you home.
It's all right,
I'll...drive Mr Foyle home and then
I'll drive myself.
Are you all right to drive?
Absolutely.
Then drive yourself home and go
to bed, I'll walk.
Are you sure, sir?
Of course.
Joe -
It's OK, don't worry about it.
Erm... I'll see you tomorrow.
Which way are you going?
We're making good progress now,
with the weather clearing up.
It helps that the locals have
stopped shooting at us.
So, are you getting used to
the English?
I don't know if I'll ever do that,
sir.
One of these days I'll come back
here
and open a business selling heating
and plumbing appliances.
I think I'll make a fortune.
People being kind to you?
Yes, very kind they are, sir.
I should tell you, sir, my
intentions towards Miss Stewart
are completely honourable.
You don't need to tell ME that.
Her father might be interested,
though.
The way she talks about you
sometimes,
you could almost be her father.
Well...
She very much admires you, sir.
Yeah...
So, you've been seeing a lot of each
other, yeah?
I've asked her to marry me.
Right.
The crossroads!
She hasn't given me an answer,
but...
Well, the very best to both of you,
whatever she decides. Thank you, sir.
This is me.
I'd better get back to base.
Goodbye, sir. Goodbye.
Good evening, Christopher. Did you
get the book? I did, thank you.
Doctor, how is Mrs Jenkins?
You know her?
She's a friend of mine.
She is not at all well, I'm afraid.
She didn't look well when I saw her
this morning.
She said she had a cold.
What's wrong?
At this stage I can't be sure.
Emphysema, perhaps.
I'll examine her again in the
morning.
Has her father been to see her?
He spent an hour with her
this afternoon.
He's worried sick, poor man.
I can't blame him.
I wish I knew what was wrong with
her
but I've never seen anything like it
before. Can I see her?
Two minutes, no more.
(I've come to see Mrs Jenkins.)
Elsie.
Can you hear me?
Edie...
They only told me just now
you were here.
Have you seen him?
Who?
Martin.
Don't worry about him, Elsie, not
now.
(WHEEZING)
Where's Danny?
With my mum.
I'm so ill.
I don't know...
I can't breathe.
You're going to be fine.
I've spoken to the doctor.
He's going to have another look at
you tomorrow.
I'm frightened.
Don't be.
I'll stay with you.
What is it, Edie?
What's wrong with me?
It's flu.
It's nothing.
It's nothing serious.
Miss Stewart didn't sound at all
good this morning, sir.
Very under the weather. I told her
not to worry about anything.
Suits me to get out from behind
a desk once in a while.
Settling in?
Not really.
It's a bit too quiet down here,
if you want the truth.
But there you go.
Next left.
Yes, of course I heard about the
death of Tom Jenkins.
It's a dreadful business,
but I'm not sure how I can help you.
Do you recognise this?
Why, yes, of course,
it's a... It's a trocar.
Hang on.
It's mine. Or it damn well looks
like it. I lost it weeks ago.
Where did you find it? I'm afraid it
was used to kill Tom Jenkins.
No?!
Where did you last see it?
I don't know.
I suppose it would have been
Foxhall Farm, Brian Jones's place.
One of his cows had bloat.
A few days later I noticed
it wasn't in my bag.
DOOR OPENS
Len, this is a police officer.
He's asking questions about Tom.
This is my son.
How do you do?
Hello.
You were on the Navarino together,
I gather. Yes. Who told you?
Is that how you got that?
Yes, it happened when we went down.
How did it happen?
Uh... A piece of shrapnel, I think.
I don't really know.
It was all a bit of a mess.
Len.
You don't have to talk about it.
No, it's all right, Dad, I want to.
Um... We'd set off from Iceland,
heading north.
We were on damage duty, assigned to
protect merchant ships.
30 ships.
Convoy PQ17.
We were heading for Murmansk,
but the...
Well, the Jerries were at us
more or less at once...
and er...we managed to keep them off
for a while
but...on the third day they hit us.
A Yank ship, the Christopher
Newport,
was one of the first to go down.
I er... I saw it.
I didn't realise that we'd be next.
It was late in the day and a whole
bunch of planes just came at us,
firing God knows how many torpedoes,
one of which hit the Navarino.
(HEARING EXPLOSION) I managed to
make my way onto the deck.
Tom had been on the bridge,
and er...
the next thing I knew I was in
the water and it was...
..it was dark and it was cold.
Ice... Ice-cold.
I've... I've never been so cold.
They say that you can last half an
hour in the water if...
Well, if you weren't pulled out
after that, you'd freeze to death.
Erm...
And Tom found me.
He managed to get me onto
a life-raft and that was that.
Did you mention that to the police?
Oh, yes, to Superintendent Fielding.
Mm.
We want to know who killed Tom,
we all do.
But at the same time, I know it
can't have been Martin.
It just doesn't make sense.
Excuse me, I understand you have
a patient here,
a young woman from Foxhall Farm.
I don't -
Elsie Jenkins.
Oh, yes, she works on a farm,
I believe. She lives in Hythe.
I wonder if I might see her.
Are you a relative?
A friend. I'm afraid she's not well
enough to see anyone at the moment.
Can I at least look in on her for
a moment? It is very important.
I'm sorry, I've just explained. Mrs
Jenkins is too ill to see anyone.
Here we are, sir.
He rents this place, does he?
Yes, sir, just the ground floor.
Good morning. Mr Styles?
Yes.
Could we have a word?
We're from the police.
Check the back, sir?
Yeah.
Hold on, you!
Awwww!
What happened?
He got away. I wasn't expecting...
Are you hurt?
Just my pride, sir.
Sorry, I'm a bit off my patch.
Yes, it's a bit quiet here, isn't it?
Where did he come from?
The back door.
A writer.
A journalist, perhaps?
I'll check the local papers.
Scientist, maybe?
"Science And War",
"Science And World Order".
I wonder what he was so afraid of.
Well, he won't get far.
The same meeting house as...
Martin Ashford?
They're both Quakers.
Styles was watching the farm where
Ashford lived.
He may have been there when the cows
were stolen.
German.
"Luftgas Angriff..."
We should find this man.
(DESPERATE WHEEZING)
Dead...
Elsie.
Dead! Dead in the...
It's all right.
In the road.
What's in the road?
The sheep.
Don't talk.
Dead in...
Doctor Brindley!
Any word?
From Sam, sir? No.
I'm getting worried. Get somebody to
check she's all right.
Sir, I found this out the front,
it's addressed to you.
See who delivered it?
No, sir, slipped under the door.
Right, thank you.
What do you make of that?
"I saw Tom Jenkins die. It was
a tall man on the beach,
blond hair. He had a knife."
Not exactly a description of
Martin Ashford.
It's some sort of chemical. Ether,
perhaps?
It could be from a hospital.
Edith's a nurse, isn't she?
Edie, is there somewhere we can
talk?
I didn't send this.
Why would I have sent it?
Well, if it's true, it exonerates
your brother.
Why can't it be true? Maybe it is.
I'd like to think so.
But...?
The description. Tall, blond hair.
The exact opposite of Martin.
It's as if someone
was deliberately trying to throw us
off track.
You think it was me?
The paper's been in contact with
some sort of chemical. Ether.
It's not just hospitals that use
ether.
Edie, when you first came to me
you said that you'd do anything for
Martin.
It's true, I would. Then why
don't you tell me the truth?
I have!
No, you haven't.
I asked you if Martin was involved
with anyone and you said he wasn't.
Are you calling me a liar?
Yes, I am.
I could tell, Edie. People lie to me
all the time, it's part of my job.
You've changed.
You came to me for help.
You knew how I felt about you and
you used me.
No!
Was Elsie Jenkins having an affair
with your brother?
The way that Tom and Martin argued
at the King's Arms,
there was no reason for it.
It just sprang up out of nowhere
and suddenly they were threatening
each other.
There had to be something else,
some other animosity between them.
It's the only way to make sense of
what happened.
Yes.
For how long?
A year.
While Tom was away.
And why didn't you tell me?
I thought...
I thought you'd think that was why
Martin killed him.
Did you write this?
No.
I promise you.
That's all I need to know.
Where will you go now?
I have to speak to Elsie Jenkins.
You can't.
I thought you knew. I assumed that
was why you were here. Knew what?
Elsie was ill.
She had some kind of pneumonia.
She came in last night.
And this morning...
..she died.
What did she die of?
We still don't know.
It was a respiratory illness.
Pulmonary fever, perhaps.
But there were also blisters on the
skin which I didn't recognise.
Woolsorter's disease is
a possibility.
There will have to be a full
inquest.
There have been no other cases?
No, thank God.
Can you tell me anything she might
have said
that will tell you how she
contracted it?
No.
Right at the end, she was saying
something about a sheep.
That's what made me think of
woolsorter's disease.
Her father has a farm, I believe.
Can you tell me exactly what she
said?
There was nothing exact about it.
She mentioned a sheep in the road.
She said she tried to lift it, I
think.
That's about all there was to it.
Right. Thank you.
I have some very bad news for you.
Elsie Jenkins...er...
I understand you were close.
She became very ill
and was admitted to hospital.
She died this morning.
What?
And I'm sorry.
What happened to her?
They don't know.
Dead?
They did what they could.
Elsie.
When did your affair begin?
Your sister told us.
A year ago in the summer.
Starting an affair with a woman whose
husband's away fighting a war
is not exactly the sort of behaviour
that endears people to pacifists,
is it?
I knew the truth about Tom Jenkins.
I knew what he was doing to Elsie.
He was a brute.
He drank. He was a bully.
He beat her.
Even when she was expecting his
baby.
It is his?
Yes.
She's not really dead?
You're lying to me.
This is some sort of trick.
Listen, we don't have to talk about
this now. We can come back.
No.
I've been sat in this stinking room
long enough.
I'll tell you.
She didn't want me to fight.
She tried to stop me.
Don't go to the beach.
He's just looking for the excuse.
We can't go on like this.
We've got to have it out.
Please, Martin.
I'm begging you. I know him.
I know what he's like.
If you fight him, you won't walk
away. I can look after myself.
He'll kill you.
He can try.
Oh, God. Why did I have to meet him?
How could I let myself -
MARTIN: I went back to Foxhall Farm
and got a torch.
I didn't want to go there in the
dark.
It must have been about twenty past
eleven when I arrived.
I started making my way over to the
boat
and I heard someone running away.
Jenkins!
(LOW MOAN)
Elsie.
That was all he said.
So, you thought she'd killed him.
He spoke her name.
And then you took the knife?
Yes. I wanted to protect her.
Is that how you got the blood on
your clothes?
Yes.
And you hid it -
At Foxhall Farm.
Leonard Cartwright - Know him?
Yes, of course I know him.
He went to the same meeting house.
But then he left. He joined up.
Still friends? Yes. We had different
beliefs, that's all.
Henry Styles mean anything to you?
I remember seeing him.
I don't think we ever spoke.
Listen, can I see her?
Well...
You've been obstructing a police
enquiry
but I'll see what I can do.
I wasn't gonna let them rest.
I'm sorry.
So, where are you going, sir?
To London.
On what business?
Er... It's... It's private.
I'm afraid that's not good enough,
sir. Can I see your identity papers?
Er...no, you don't understand.
I can't stay here.
Sir, could you get out of the car?
(GASPS)
Are you all right?
I think I need to see a...doctor.
She's very seriously ill,
I'm afraid.
I should warn you that we had
another young woman in here
just 24 hours ago, seemingly with
the same condition,
and I'm afraid she didn't make it.
Hello, sir.
Don't. Don't. Don't move.
How are you?
I think I'm going to need a couple
of days off work, sir.
Oh, as many as that?
I think I've got flu.
I don't know about these, though.
Do you remember doing that?
At Foxhall Farm.
How did you do it?
I cut my wrist on some barbed wire.
Do you think I've got an infection?
Well, just rest and erm...
let these people look after you. Hm?
Righto, sir.
A couple of days, no more,
all right?
I only just got word.
Now, where is Sam?
Well, I've just been with her.
She's erm... And?
Well, she's very ill. Speak to the
doctor. What's wrong with her?
Er, they don't seem to know.
Mr Foyle?
Am I gonna lose her?
Speak to the doctor.
Sir, they found Styles.
He was trying to leave Hastings.
Picked up by the Home Guard.
Where is he?
He's at the station.
I need your help.
I'm not saying anything.
There's a woman very ill in hospital.
I think you know what's wrong with
her.
She's very ill as a result of cutting
herself on barbed wire at Foxhall
Farm.
She's got a fever and
she has difficulty breathing.
And I need your help because another
woman at the same hospital
with the same symptoms has just died.
This is some sort of ploy to get me
to talk. No, it's not.
I know who you are.
You want me to disappear.
I know why you came to my house.
I came to your house because a man
had been murdered
and although this has nothing to do
with you,
we believe you could well know
the person arrested for it.
You're a Quaker, aren't you?
We think you use the same meeting
house as this person. Martin Ashford.
Look, whether you did or you didn't,
it's irrelevant.
The only reason you're here is
because we need your help.
How did you know where I lived?
I saw your car at Foxhall Farm.
We got your address
from the registration.
What were YOU doing there?
I was there for the same reason I was
at your house. Martin Ashford.
He was having an affair with a woman
who worked there.
The same woman that just died from
the same condition
contracted at the same farm as this
woman who now needs your help.
Erm...
..Does she...have black sores on her
face or her arms? Yes.
Anthrax.
Anthrax?
It's a living bacterium.
A spore-forming microbe found in the
soil.
It can be cultivated and then used.
It's an invader. Put it into
a hostile environment
and it curls itself up into a little
ball and protects itself.
It... It develops an outer skin.
It's very stable.
Heat and light can't hurt it.
It survives for years.
Also, it kills.
That's why they want it.
Who?
They wanted me to work for them
but I said no.
I wasn't having any of it.
What's the world coming to if
we allow such things, hm?
Death by disease and invisible
killers. It's less than human.
It makes us worse than the Nazis.
These two women have been infected
at the same farm.
Could they have a laboratory?
Some sort of base nearby?
I've been watching them.
I followed them up to that farm.
They can't even control
the infection.
They're incompetent.
Where do I find them?
I'm sorry. There's no admittance
beyond this point.
You have a commanding officer name of
Halliday. I want to speak to him.
I'm afraid that's not possible, sir.
There's been an outbreak of anthrax
in Hastings and he's responsible.
If I'm not in his office in two
minutes, I'll be back with the army,
police, Home Guard and press.
Do you want to convey this to him at
your earliest opportunity?
Sir.
I don't need to tell you that if you
repeat anything you hear,
the world will fall in on you
from a very great height.
Will it?
No, no, you don't understand.
This is not just classified. It's
not just another secret of the war.
Not even the Prime Minister knows
what we're doing here. It's true.
They haven't told him yet. Hopefully
they'll never have to.
Well, what you don't understand
is that I don't care what falls on me
from a very great height.
Neither do I care who doesn't know
what.
I know that you're responsible for
the death of one young woman and the
potential death of another
and unless you tell me what's
happened,
everybody's going to know at least
as much as I do.
There was an accident. We were
experimenting with a flock of sheep.
What does that mean, exactly?
We killed them. We were then asked
to send the carcasses to another
establishment for testing.
I was against it from the start.
Hardly relevant.
One of them fell off the lorry.
We knew at once what had happened
when a count was made
but by then the infected animal had
been taken to a farm.
We kept the farm under observation
and when the cattle fell ill,
we moved in and removed them.
We wanted to stop the infection
spreading.
And what infection is this?
We're talking about a toxin that
goes by the name of anthrax.
If you breathe it in, you're 99%
certain to die almost at once.
Cutaneous infection, through the
skin, is less rapid.
But still fatal?
Well, that depends.
On what?
We're not sure.
The general health and fitness of
the victim can make all the
difference.
This stuff is being developed for
what? For the war?
The French were developing it before
us. When the Germans invaded France,
all their expertise fell into Nazi
hands.
The Germans were experimenting with
bacteriological weapons
on the Paris Metro and London
Underground almost ten years ago.
At least, that's what we believe.
Retaliation.
They do it to us, we must be
prepared to do it to them.
Right. You've developed this stuff.
What's the cure?
Higgins may be able to help you.
Who's he?
Simon Higgins.
He's an epidemiologist.
He knows more about this
than almost anyone.
Is he here? You're not speaking to
Higgins, not without my authority.
Oh, I see. Why would that be?
And let you go ploughing in
with your damn fool questions
and moral outrage?
Maybe you should try and understand
us a bit more.
The Germans bombed London.
They bombed London for months and
months.
They smashed buildings, churches,
hospitals, totally indiscriminate
and what about the victims? If they
weren't killed immediately,
they lay there in the wreckage
burnt, limbs missing,
in terrible pain
and what happened to them?
The sewage and water systems were
smashed up and not surprisingly,
a great many of them got blood
poisoning. The point being what?
Why not go straight to the blood
poisoning?
Easier all round.
Less expensive.
Less long-term damage.
I think if people knew what we were
trying to do here, they might be
grateful.
Where's Higgins?
Streptomycin.
What's that?
If there are any traces of anthrax
left on her skin, it will kill her.
She should be washed,
thoroughly washed
and she needs a large dose of
streptomycin.
It's not infallible but it has
occasionally done the trick.
Are they'll have this stuff
at the hospital?
Maybe not.
We keep supplies here.
Mark?
I'll be right back.
Mr Foyle?
Yes.
I'm very sorry.
This is all MY fault.
Is it?
Well, I'm team leader here.
But I was a little careless.
I was testing a new compound,
what we call organophosphate.
Nerve gas.
What? On yourself?
Yes. Ten minutes in the gas chamber.
But I must have been in there
a couple of minutes too long
cos I seem to have blinded myself,
temporarily, I think.
Although it has been two weeks now.
Anyway, it means I wasn't on hand
to oversee the anthrax trials.
Halliday is a complete BF.
The carcasses should never have left
the area.
Are you going to try
and expose us, Mr Foyle?
We tried to recruit Styles.
He was with us at the London School
of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine.
But it drove him mad.
I expect they'll make him disappear
in the end.
I wouldn't want them to do the same
to you.
DOOR OPENS
Here you are. It's fairly
straightforward. The doctors will
know what to do.
I hope your friend's all right.
It's a nasty world, isn't it?
But we are doing this for our
country, you know.
The same as everyone else.
I'll show you out.
Thank you.
I've already given her a shot of
streptomycin.
Where did you get it, by the way?
How long before we know it's worked?
I'll wait a few hours then give her
another one.
I'll double the dose if I have to.
And then?
There's nothing more I can do.
I've got to be honest with you, Mr
Foyle, at this point it could go
either way.
Either the fever will break
and she'll begin to breathe properly
or...
It doesn't seem to be the sort of
thing we should be doing, given the
circumstances.
Well, we might as well.
There's little else we can do.
I can't believe she might die.
She'll pull through, won't she, sir?
Please come in.
Thank you.
Afternoon.
You know why I'm here?
No. I've no idea.
Is this about Tom Jenkins?
Amongst other things, yes.
We wondered why you wouldn't have
bothered to have signed this.
It would have been perfectly
reasonable information. Tall man on a
beach.
Blond hair.
I just couldn't understand
why you wouldn't want to take credit
for that.
That's not...
It's yours, isn't it?
How can you be so sure?
Well, you sent it to ME.
Only very few people know that I'm
connected with this investigation
and it wasn't any of them
unless, of course, it was...
No, no, it's not.
There are also traces of ether on it
which we assume meant it had come
from a hospital.
But we understand you, as a vet,
use ether regularly.
One good reason, of course,
for not signing it
is because you didn't give this
information to the police,
isn't that right? Look, all right,
I wrote that letter but -
Why did you go to see them?
Well, Martin Ashford being arrested
was all wrong.
He wouldn't kill anyone.
I just knew that they'd got the
wrong man.
How could you be sure of that?
Because you're the right one?
Why did...
Jenkins try to kill you?
Did he? He tried to shoot you,
didn't he? When you were both on
board the Navarino?
That's how you got that, isn't it?
I told you that this was -
This was shrapnel.
Well, I think we both know what
a shrapnel wound looks like.
It's not a shrapnel wound.
How do you know it was him?
Because he was the only one on board
with a gun.
I mean, no-one on board merchant
vessels,
including Royal Navy officers on DEMS
duty, is permitted to carry firearms.
Only one small firearm is kept on the
bridge which is where, as you said,
he was on duty.
I mean, he shot hinges off a door
with it, he got a medal for using it
and he tried to kill you with it,
didn't he?
Yes.
Is that why YOU killed HIM?
Len.
It's all right, Dad.
(SIGHS)
This has gone on long enough.
Jenkins was a bastard.
He was a bully and a coward
and he nearly killed me
when the Navarino went down.
All he wanted
was to save his own skin.
But they gave him a medal.
He used his gun
to shoot down a door.
He wouldn't have done it if he
hadn't been trying to save himself.
And it was worse than that.
You have no idea.
After the ship went down,
it was... Oh, it was hell.
I suddenly found myself in the water
and it was cold.
It was ice.
I could feel myself freezing.
And then I... and then I saw him.
He was out of the water.
You had to be out of the water
if you were gonna survive.
Jenkins! Help me!
I can't. I can't move.
It's going to overturn. Go away.
Give me a hand,
for God's sakes, man!
Help me!
Move! It's going to overturn.
Get me out of the water!
Get away.
Help me!
Get off me!
That's the last thing I remember.
I should have died.
I don't know why I didn't.
Someone pulled me into a lifeboat
and that's how I made it home.
He did that?
Yes, Dad.
Why didn't you tell anyone? Why
didn't you go to the authorities?
It was his word against mine.
No-one else saw.
Well, you could have told me.
I wanted to, Dad, but I couldn't.
You thought the world of him
just like everyone else.
The DSM, Buckingham Palace.
Oh, everyone pretending when they
knew all along he was a swine.
So, you killed him?
Yes, Dad.
I took a knife,
the trocar, out of your bag.
Erm...I didn't care if you found out
it was me. I...
I knew where he drank
and I followed him when he came out.
You.
Bastard!
(GROANS)
Of course I couldn't let another man
hang for what I'd done.
Especially not Martin.
That's erm...why I went to see
Fielding and...
that's why I wrote you that letter.
Len...
Dad.
Please, don't make this any harder.
I'm ready to go with you.
There's a car waiting outside.
Mr Foyle...
They gave the medal
to the wrong man.
My son was serving his country.
He was nearly killed in action.
And this man, this...
this Jenkins...
If any man on this planet
got what he deserved, it was him.
Perhaps.
So what's the point
in arresting him?
He's had his orders.
He's meant to report
to his new ship in two days' time.
What good is it going to do...
locking him up
when his country needs him?
None at all.
None at all, Mr Cartwright.
Any news about Miss Stewart?
Still no change.
Are you seeing her this weekend?
Tomorrow.
Say hello for me.
Paul.
Edie.
I hoped I'd find you.
Can I have a word?
Of course.
They've released Martin.
Good. I'm glad.
What will happen to him -
the man who really did it?
I can't say.
But I don't think he'll be hanged.
Tom Jenkins was a horrible man.
I know what he did to poor Elsie.
Why didn't you tell me?
I don't know.
Maybe because
you're with the police.
Maybe I was afraid to.
I mean, he was a hero.
Anyway, that's why
I've come to see you now.
To apologise.
And not just for that.
There's something else
I wanted to say.
I wanted to tell you
at the hospital, but...
We got it wrong, didn't we...
all those years ago?
Don't.
Why not?
I knew Jane was wrong for you.
I didn't understand
why you went with her.
But I didn't say anything because...
Well, I was too young...
and I was shy...
And I watched you walk away from me.
But I'm not going to
let you leave me again.
Thank you for coming.
I owe you an apology.
Do you?
Yes. I arrested the wrong man.
And when you turned up I treated
you like you were the inept one.
You know, there's one thing
I couldn't understand.
Why did Jenkins say his wife's name
when he died?
Did he?
Yeah.
It seems...
..odd.
There was no love lost between them.
And yet his dying words were...
"Elsie."
Elsie...
or...
LC?
LC...
Leonard Cartwright. Of course!
It's just a thought.
Yes...
How long ago was it when I met you?
How old were we?
21? 22?
Young soldiers off to the war.
It was a different world then.
Of course, we... we didn't know
what we were going to go through.
We won. And we got through it.
You may have. Not me.
I never told you.
April, 1915.
Ypres.
I was there with
a bunch of Canadians.
It was just a day like any other.
Which is to say,
pretty hellish at the best of times.
And then I saw it coming towards us.
A cloud...
Green...
Almost...
luminescent.
It was completely silent...
moving as if it had
a life of its own.
We didn't run.
Nobody even moved.
We had no idea what it was.
And then the pain.
There were people screaming.
Coughing blood,
tearing at their own faces.
Blind.
Nobody knew what was happening.
I mean, how could we?
You see, that was the first time.
The Bosch released
170 tons of chlorine gas.
Do you know what
the operation was called?
"Disinfection".
Well, they disinfected us...
all right.
I was one of the lucky ones.
I still feel it inside now.
Still burning inside me.
Well, we won. And we came through it.
Did we?
Look around you, Christopher.
There's so much evil,
so much...bad blood.
Humanity stinks.
I just want to go somewhere quiet...
and watch the sunset.
You'll go on fighting,
I know you will.
I've had enough.
Joe.
Mr Foyle, sir.
How long have you been here?
A while.
Have you seen her?
No. I've been here a few times,
but she's been asleep.
Sir, I really can't stay any more.
I gotta get back to base.
No, that's all right. Go.
I'll stay with her.
Hello.
Sorry. I didn't mean to wake you.
I wasn't asleep.
Well, um...
Joe's out here. He just left.
Do you want me to...?
No.
He's been so kind and everything
but...
I really can't see him just now.
Right.
How are you feeling?
Pretty awful, actually.
The doctor seemed to think
you're on the mend.
Really?
Mm. Good.
Because...
I've been thinking, sir.
What, again?
You should try and resist, you know.
You can see where it gets you.
Yes. Perhaps.
But...no, really,
I have been thinking.
About whether...
Crossroads?
Yes, sir. That's right.
Would you say I'm...
sort of...
quite a useful sort of person
to have on the team, sir?
I would.
Would you?
Yes. I'd go as far as to say
you are a...
you are an invaluable
part of the team.
You think so?
I do.
Good.
Well, in that case
I think it's better
that I go straight through
the crossroads
and don't take any turns at all.
Right.
Well, I'm pleased.
So, are you here
to take me back to work, then?
Absolutely.
Good.
Can't go anywhere without you.
Jolly good.
Sync by georgel24