[Thinking]
Staff duty log, 13 June...
Corporal Walter O'Reilly,
company clerk, 0600 hours.
The friendly old sun showed
his friendly hot face...
over the mountains
of purple majesty...
as though he was salutating,
"Good morning to all."
Alas, alack, the peaceful
quietness was detonated...
by a herd of chopper
transportizing punctured personnel.
But our gallant doctors,
the miracle medical mortals...
are ever ready
to treat the sick.
The wounded were aided copiously
by super-smart surgeons...
whose knowledge is superseded
by nobody I know.
Together or apart,
they work as a team.
Skilled hands
with their fingers...
work dedicatedly to keep death
away from its maximum.
- Radar, what is this cow flubdubbery?
- Sir?
All this "miracle medical mortals" hooey.
What are you doin' to my duty log?
I was just adding a hint
of self-expression, sir.
Better fill me in, son,
and use simple sentences.
Well, sir,
I've been accepted...
by the famous
Las Vegas Writers' School.
"Serving the creative
community since 1950."
- Right.
- How'd you stumble onto this?
- Superman, sir.
- He take the course?
No, sir. On the back
of his comic book.
See, right next to the ad
for the X-ray glasses?
I sent 'em in an example
of my writings...
and they said that I had
"extraordinary potential."
- How much they stick you for?
- Just $50...
plus a five-dollar student activity fee,
but it's really worth it.
They show you all the writers' secrets, like
verbs and semicolons and all that good stuff.
Sounds like the original
shell game to me.
Oh, no, it's no game, sir.
This school is run by some very famous writers
like Hemingway and Steinbeck and O'Neill.
"Ethel Hemingway, Jerry Steinbeck,
Eunice O'Neill."
- Right.
- Uh-huh.
Look at page three.
"Writers are special people.
In a crowd, they are glib and articulate.
Everyone respects the man
who writes well."
Can you imagine, sir? In just 10 weeks,
I can be respected by a crowd.
An admirable goal, Radar.
But the army doesn't need
creative writing.
- Save it for your novel.
- Thank you, sir.
- I'll dedicate my first book after you.
- Better let me read it first.
Ah, foot fault! Your foot left the court.
You don't get the point.
- It never touched the floor.
- Come on, Pancho. I saw it hit.
- What's the difference?
- I'm gonna get a ruling on this.
Frank, did you see
his foot leave the bunk?
- Earth calling Major Burns.
- You want something, Pierce?
- What's so absorbing, Junior?
- It's an interesting article about Sweden.
- Learning to be a meatball?
- I'm reading about their rising suicide rate.
- Just killing time?
- Go peddle your petunias.
Here. You ready
for my killer serve?
- This has been clocked
at over five miles an hour.
- Lay it on me.
Twenty-one!
On to Wimbledon!
I'm... This must be the press
asking me how it feels to be a winner.
- Go ahead. Ask me how it feels.
- How do you feel, sir?
What a stupid question.
Cancel the interview.
- Actually, I come in here
to ask you two guys a favor.
- What is it, Radar?
Well, uh, you see, I, uh... I found
this real neat way to improve myself.
- Don't change a hair for me.
- Not if you care for me.
I enrolled in this
writers' school by mail.
- They send you tiny teachers
in little envelopes?
- For short stories?
Come on, guys. I'm having trouble
with my first assignment.
I have to relate an amusing anecdote,
and I don't think I ever had an anecdote.
- Not even a small one?
- I have some in my footlocker.
What size do you wear?
- Come on. Will ya?
- I got an amusing anecdote,
but promise you won't laugh.
Okay, fine.
Yeah, good. Here.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- This happened while I was in
my first year of medical school.
- Right.
I was taking an exam in anatomy.
It was really tough.
They asked questions like,
"How many bones are there in the hand?"
I was stymied. I kept saying to myself,
And then I heard this little voice
that said, "Twenty-four."
I looked around the room, and
there sitting over on the windowsill...
was this little gray squirrel
with a very intelligent face.
And he pointed at his hand,
and he said, "Twenty-four."
So I wrote it down. Then after the exam,
I rushed over to the library to look it up.
And would you believe it?
That stupid squirrel was wrong by four bones!
I went looking all over the campus for him.
I wanted to kill him.
And I finally found him over on a bench
by the psych department.
"You were wrong!" I screamed at him.
"There's 28 bones in the human hand!"
"Oh," he said,
pointing at his hand.
"I thought you meant
a squirrel's hand."
I don't think I can use
that story.
Do you want me
to make one up?
Frank, help us out.
We need a funny anecdote.
- I don't feel very funny.
- Aw, come on. Be a pal.
- Please, sir? Would you, please?
- Well... [Chuckles]
There's one that always
breaks me up.
Seems we had this little sickly kid
that lived on our block named Timmy.
He used to sit out on his porch in his
wheelchair and wave at us as we walked by.
Sort of...
Well, one day...
while he was waving,
he lost control of his chair...
and it rolled down the stairs,
across the lawn...
and crashed into
my dad's car.
Boy, was that funny!
- That must have been awful.
- No, just scratched the paint a little.
- I hope Timmy wasn't hurt.
- What's the difference?
His folks had money.
Frank, that was not
an amusing anecdote.
You guys have got
no sense of humor.
All you know how to do is pick, pick, pick.
Is there anything I can do to please you?
- Tap dance in the minefield.
- Drop yourself on North Korea.
Oh, fish. That's the last time
I tell a joke to you guys.
Maybe I should just go
to assignment number two.
Let's see. Uh, "Describe a beautiful scene
outside your window."
- Maybe assignment number three.
- Radar, why the sudden interest
in creative writing?
Oh, I need it. You see,
more and more, a man is judged...
by how good
he expresses himself.
- Where'd you get that?
- Page five.
What do you mean you're out of tapioca
pudding? I saw some enlisted men eating some!
That's why we're out, Major.
They ate it all.
Well, it's not fair. You run this place
like a bunch of babies.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, you should be. It's my birthday.
And I always have
tapioca pudding on my birthday.
How was I supposed to know?
- Well, you could have asked.
- Happy birthday, Major.
Never mind. You spoiled it for me.
And I hope you're satisfied.
Would you like
an extra hunk of liver?
Soldier, I'm confiscating
this tapioca.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you, sir.
Don't threaten me.
Mmm, with raisins.
No, sir. Flies.
Some birthday
this turned out to be.
Why, Frank, you didn't
tell us it was your birthday.
It's not important.
What's the difference? Nobody cares.
You're being too hard on yourself, Frank.
Here, I'll prove it to you.
Hey, everybody, guess what.
Today's Major Burns's birthday.
- See?
- They're delighted.
- Birthdays are hell.
- So are wars, but we keep on
celebrating them every year.
Who cares about wars?
This really hurts.
Maybe we should take up a collection
and get him a gift.
What can you buy
for a dime?
I know, I know.
Everything looks so good.
- What'll you have?
- I'll have a modicum of hash
and a smattering of potatoes.
- You been out in the sun again?
- No. I'm adding muscle to my vocabulary.
- I'm taking this correspondence course
by mail.
- Oh, yeah?
These mail things are great.
My friend Vito met his wife that way.
- She was a pen pal?
- No. She was a mailman.
- What a provocative anecdote.
- Watch your mouth!
Uh, Father, excuse me.
Do you mind if I sit here?
Certainly not, Radar.
Father, do you have
a most unforgettable character?
- Oh, your writing class, eh?
- Yes, sir.
Well, without a doubt, I'd have
to name my sister, Sister Theresa.
She's a Benedictine
in San Diego.
Oh, I'm sorry
to hear that, sir.
Oh, no. She teaches
in the seminary there.
She also plays guard
on their basketball team.
You know, she can slam dunk
while wearing a heavy crucifix.
Oh, now we're
getting somewhere!
This used to be the most important day
of the year for me.
I looked forward to it for months.
There used to be parties in my honor.
Cards, gifts and...
What do I get around here, huh?
Nothing.
Nada. Zilch. Zippo.
The big goose egg.
And look at you. You got a Purple Heart,
and it's not even your birthday.
What is it?
What do you want?
- Nothing, Frank.
- We came to work.
- Oh, sure. Came in to spy on me.
- We came to relieve you.
I didn't do anything wrong. And you
keep your hands off his Purple Heart!
And that was one
of his more lucid moments.
Why don't we shoot him
and put him out of our misery?
- That or just find something
to lift his spirits.
- Call off the peace talks.
Have Margaret's fiance transferred
to the European theater.
Get him a seat
in the balcony.
You and I could have a fight
and beat each other's brains out.
- Frank would love that.
- Right.
That would give Frank instant joy,
to see us at each other's throats.
- Let's do it.
- It is the perfect gift
for the man who has nothing.
We'd have to be
pretty convincing.
It's easy to fake a fight
with a jerk like you.
Nah. Who'd believe I couldn't take
a noodle like you out with one punch?
- Maybe you ought to fight Radar.
- This is gonna be the best
birthday of Frank's whole life.
I don't wanna hear about it! I gave you
your assignment, and that's that!
- Why don't you work the shift with me?
- Because I'm chief surgeon.
- If you don't like it, join another army.
- What's going on, fellas?
It's a good thing we're friends.
Otherwise, you'd have me on duty 24 hours.
- That can be arranged, buster.
- This isn't a fight, is it?
- Don't turn your back on me.
- How you gonna work
with your nose in a sling?
- Boys, easy.
- I'm not working the shift alone, Pierce!
- I'm gonna let Frank decide.
- Leave me out of it. I like the
way you guys are working it out.
- I'm gonna see what the colonel
has to say about this.
- Oh, sure, the colonel.
- Wow, you guys are really
mad at each other.
- You think you know a guy.
- All of a sudden, he pulls rank.
- What a shame.
- Some friend. The guy's a two-faced rat!
- That's pretty strong.
- How would you put it?
- Well, maybe you're right.
He's so competitive, so childish.
Always has to come out on top,
get in the last word.
- I know. Impossible.
- He's impossible!
Here he comes. Let's pretend
we're talking about him, okay?
You're lucky, Hunnicutt.
Potter's taking a nap.
Forget it. I'd rather work the shift
alone than be stuck in here with you!
You... The air feels better
in here already!
Don't you wanna tell Potter?
Wake him up. He won't mind.
- Don't worry. That lazy crumb will get his.
- I'll be a witness.
- I'll bet he called me
every name in the book.
- Let's see.
Two-faced, rat fink
and, uh, ferret face.
- He called me ferret face?
- He was so mad, he thought you were me.
- That's his style.
- He called you a sore loser.
- Sore loser?
- He thinks you're too competitive.
You know, hate to lose, always have
to get in the last word, childish.
- He said that?
- Yeah, every syllable.
But you didn't
hear it from me.
Boy, he must really
be desperate.
That is so dumb,
it's ridiculous.
- I hate to lose? He said that?
- Uh-huh.
[Thinking]
Sixteen hundred hours.
The sun in its
crimson radiance...
bids a crepuscular adieu
to another day.
Corporal Klinger was in his last
grisly hour of guard duty...
little knowing the fate that destiny
had planned up for him.
The Chinese were giving up
in hordes.
Sergeant Fierman brought in
three prisoners that he had captured...
after they had surrendered
voluntarily.
The sergeant bragadeered
to Corporal Klinger...
that capturing prisoners
meant points towards discharge...
and early homeward bounding.
This information inspired
Klinger a whole lot.
The vainglorious corporal
ran like a bird...
and sped off in quest
of Chinese giver-uppers.
But destiny
exterminated his luck.
The Chinese G.I.s had not seen women
in an overexcited period of time.
Klinger barely escaped
with his purity still clean...
and in the process,
ruining his finest frockery.
The corporal re-arrived
with his dignity dented...
and his nonchalantness
not so nifty.
Enough, boy! Enough!
This whole unit is gonna get
a Section Eight.
I'm sorry. It's just
that I need the practice.
Radar, duty logs
have got to be military.
If headquarters sees this,
they'll rip off my epaulets.
- Won't happen again, sir.
- Thank goodness.
But, Colonel, what is your actual
civilian opinion of my writing?
Son, Ethel Hemingway
may say I'm wrong...
but I don't think
too much of it.
- Why, sir?
- 'Cause none of that's you.
It sounds like you swallowed
a dictionary.
But I'm just doing
what the book says.
Throw the book away!
I'm no authority...
but it seems to me the first rule
if you wanna be a writer...
is be yourself.
Be yourself.
Must come later.
- What are you doing out here?
- Waiting for a ride home.
You ought to see Frank.
He's a new man.
Good. I didn't
like the old one.
It's good to hear him laughing
in the morgue again.
Which one of us you think
is gonna get the Oscar?
Me, I hope. You know
how much I hate to lose.
- Right.
- Did you really say that to Frank?
Yeah. I was just looking for
something to knock you with.
It really bugs you when
I call you on foot faults, doesn't it?
- Are you kidding?
- Why else would you say I hate to lose?
I don't know.
It just popped into my head.
You really do think I'm too competitive,
that I always have to get the last word in?
- Well, yeah.
- You don't know me very well, do you?
- Maybe I know you better than you think I do.
- You think so?
- I always have to get the last word in?
- That's right.
- I can prove to you...
- Come on!
Just say something
and walk away.
All right.
- I think you're a very competitive person.
- Fine.
- You just did it.
- Did what?
Just got in the last word.
- That doesn't count.
- Then don't say anything.
- Okay.
- You're impossible.
- I'm impossible?
- Yes. Shut up, close your mouth.
- Don't say another word.
- Okay.
Not another word!
- No problem.
- It's no use!
Wrong.
Oh. Major Houlihan, ma'am.
- Can I ask you a question?
- You just did.
No. It's for my writing course. Ma'am, I
have to write about a romantic interlude...
and I don't think
I ever had one.
- What makes you think I have?
- Well, everyone knows that you're engaged.
Yes, of course. And Lieutenant Colonel
Donald Penobscott...
is the most romantic man
I've ever met.
Right. Well, may I ask then,
have you and him ever interluded?
- Many times.
- Oh.
I remember once, we were sipping wine
in a restaurant in Tokyo...
and a man came by our table...
a big man, must have weighed 250 pounds.
And he brushed my leg.
Naturally, I was alarmed and I screamed.
And Donald, without any thought
to his personal safety...
got up and he was ready
to punch that man in the mouth.
Oh, that's terrific.
What happened?
- He got bit in the leg.
- The guy bit him?
No, no, the man's
Seeing Eye dog.
What the devil's
he up to now?
I wouldn't stick around
unless I had a strong stomach.
Oh, my. He's gonna
immolate himself.
- Oh!
- Hold on, son. Don't do that.
Too late, Colonel.
I'm finally gonna get my discharge.
I'm going home
in a butt can.
Just think about what you're doing, boy.
Here, toss me those matches.
So long, war.
Good-bye, K.P.
Adios, Korea.
Sprinkle my ashes
over Toledo.
Klinger, put down
those matches.
- We can work this out.
- What he said.
- What's the use, Colonel?
- Well, give me a chance!
- Come on over to my office.
- Over to the office.
Well, okay.
Save my spot.
Good choice, son.
- Hurry it up, Colonel. I'm a busy man.
- Relax, Klinger.
Where's the fire?
Sorry.
I'll take anything you got...
honorable, general, medical, whatever.
I appreciate how much
you hate this place...
but you've gotta understand,
it's not in my power.
I understand only one thing... you're
gonna give me a discharge or poof!
Klinger, I wanna help,
but I can't send you home.
Did you ever see a Lebanese
go up in flames? It's not pretty.
Would you settle for
some time back in Seoul?
Uh-uh. Freedom or fire.
Anything but a free ride.
You're a tough cookie, Sherm,
but you're not as tough as me.
I hope you can live
with yourself.
- Klinger, please.
- Remember me at your next weenie roast.
Klinger, what am I
gonna tell your wife?
Tell her I'd like to be kept
in a blue jar. That's my best color.
Son, you'll regret this
for the rest of your life.
I... shall not return.
Shall I pour?
Who put gasoline
in my gasoline?
Stay away from me
with that cigar!
Everybody, back!
Don't anybody light a match!
[Woman Screaming]
## [Humming]
- Having a good time, Frank?
- Well, I'm the birthday boy.
Evening, Captains,
Major.
- What are you doing in here?
- Come to find somebody smart
to help me with my studies.
- Don't look at me.
- How's the writing going, Radar?
Col. Potter says that I should just be
myself, but I don't know how to do that.
It's simple.
Stop using fancy words.
Stop trying to find amusing anecdotes
and write about something
you wanna write about.
- Like what?
- Like Iowa or your animals or your Uncle Ed.
- Something you feel strongly about.
- Strongly?
Like if I were gonna write,
I'd probably write about...
how easily friends
can turn on you.
Friends will kill
you every time.
- I don't think I understand.
- People forget about loyalty.
They forget you shouldn't make
up vicious rumors about somebody
while his back is turned.
I'd write about being
too suspicious and resentful.
- How about maligning a person's character?
- What?
- Overreacting, always trying
to get in the last word.
- Right.
- See?
- No.
- This is all good stuff, guys.
- Hey, wait a second.
I think I found something
that I feel strongly about.
- How do you feel about shutting up?
- You know, my chest feels tight.
- What's the matter?
- It's you two guys fighting.
It makes me sick.
Don't you know that I come in here to
the Swamp to feel good, have a little laugh?
It's because you two guys
get along so good.
- Those days are over now. Get out of here.
- Go on, Radar.
Well, it's just you two guys
are terrific the way you work
together and laugh together...
and stick together.
I know you're always fooling around,
but you're always there
when the other guy needs ya.
- Now you're getting mushy.
- No, I'm not.
A lot of guys in the army say they're
friends, but these guys really are.
Except for now.
Yeah, well...
we're not really that mad
at each other, Radar.
- Are we?
- Nah.
- We're just play acting.
- We just wanted to give
Frank a birthday present.
- We wanted to make him happy.
- We were fighting to entertain you, Frank.
And it was wonderful!
I loved it!
Party's over, Frank.
Happy birthday.
It's your fault, you little creep!
You little buttinsky!
They were doing just fine
till you stuck your nose in here!
- I was trying to improve myself.
- Improving yourself is a waste of time.
- Frank should know. He gave up long ago.
- Geez, it was going so well too.
A perfectly good birthday
shot to hell!
Boy!
Here.
- I'll buy you a drink.
- Thanks.
- Here's to you, Radar.
- One of a kind.
So are you two.
You still love me
for all my faults?
- What faults? You're perfect.
- Just for that, I'm gonna
let you get the last word in.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
[Thinking] Dear Mom,
I gave up on the writing course...
on account of I found out
I can write better as myself...
than Hemingway, O'Neill
or any of those other bums.
And it doesn't
cost me anything.
Give my love to everybody,
especially my nephews.
Simplistically yours...
Walter.
And now, from Ottumwa, Iowa,
deep in the mysterious Midwest...
the world's first
magician/clerk/typist...
the amazing Radaro.
The hand is quicker
than the eye.
[Clears Throat, Whistling]
- [Hawkeye] Oh, a rabbit.
- No. Flowers.
- You could have fooled me.
- There's a trick to that.
Now, would a gentleman or a lady in
the audience please lend me their watch?
- Use Frank's.
- All right.
Sir, would you please place
your watch in this cloth?
We have the cloth...
and a hammer.
- And now...
- He will destroy the watch.
I've seen this.
There's nothing to it.
He slipped the watch
into his pocket when we weren't looking.
- [Rattling]
- Sir, I think we made a little mistake.
You little creep!
You wrecked it!
I got this from one
of my whiplash patients.
Smashing trick, Radar.
This watch was worth
14 bucks!
I'm just a beginner.
Time for your next trick, Radar...
vanish into thin air.
- Right.
- Corporal!
It was just a rehearsal!