[Indistinct Rock]
[Grunting, Moaning]
- Kitchen's done.
- [Laughing]
[Moaning Continues]
- Dinette's ditto.
- [Laughing] Outside.
Living room, check.
[Laughs]
Oh, "negatory" on Junior's room.
[Panting]
We're makin' memories, all right.
[Continues]
[Ends]
Come on, dog.
Ain't no time to waste.
Today's the day.
Y'all think they gonna
leave without you, boy?
No, dog.
Don't call me boy.
I don't have to call you
nothin' but regular army.
Know you're a damn sucker
just like me.
- You think this is about you?
- Yes. Yes, I think this is about me.
[Man] You think they started the goddamn war
so you'd have to have the goddamn baby all alone?
Yes! I don't wanna have this goddamn baby
all alone is what I think!
I think you're just as crazy
as you were the day I married you!
Bye, Frank.
Mind your mom, Eddy.
Shit, I know I'd get killed.
I seen those faces on Nightline...
and I said,
"Goddamn, girl, that's me."
[Bugle Call]
Every one of'em is me.
[Machinery Whirring]
[Distant Chattering]
[Coughing]
We're here by the milk, see?
And Grandma lives over by theJell-O.
[Man]
He don't know what you're saying.
I'm trying to tell him where Iraq's at.
Yeah, but he doesn't understand
a word you're saying.
Mommy's gonna be way over there
in the garbage, okay, Spooky?
- [Coos]
- I'll be back.
Sometime next year.
[Jet Engines Whirring]
We into it now, huh?
[Incoming Ordnance]
Get the hell down!
I think somebody maybe
got shot up there, sir!
That's their problem.
And don't call me sir!
I'm not some faggot officer! I fight
for a living, and my problem is you!
- Now, stay down!
- Should we go get him?
Some soldiers will go get him! We should try
and stay alive for the next 15 minutes!
Maybe we could do
something useful after that!
- [Distant Shouting]
- [Man On Radio] Cowboy Three
has already got 'em, Sergeant.
[Gunfire Continues]
- [Man Shouts] Stay down!
- They got him.
They're hauling him
back to the medics.
I was going home today. I was going home
after a year of this shithole!
And yesterday they tell me
I'm staying 90 more days!
And taking on a squad of virgins!
'Cause what? The sergeant you trained with
had to have his tonsils out!
- His appendix.
- Shut up, private!
I guaran-goddamn-tee you
one of you fools...
is gonna do something stupid
and get yourself killed within the week.
Within the week, goddamn it!
- [Gunfire Continues]
- This is the guy we're going to war with, dog?
This is the guy
who's leading us into battle?
Shut up and stay alive, Dim, okay?
That's the job, okay?
Nothin' else.
[Incoming Ordnance]
- What do you want us to do?
- Nothing.
We were told to dig in.
We dug in.
- What do we do about the women-
the driver and the mechanic?
- Nothing, I said.
- Shouldn't we get 'em back-
- Don't contradict me, fool.
I'm your goddamn squad leader.
I'm here to keep you alive.
Okay, Sergeant. Okay.
[Man On Headset] Nothing here
confirms the story, Sergeant. Over.
We're awaiting orders.
We're taking fire outside a mosque.
Looks like a goddamn
storage unit in Tijuana.
And instead ofbeing able to go in
and blast the shit out of the bastards...
we're dug in, awaiting orders!
- Do you know why?
- Why?
'Cause they got a goddamn Arab
TVjournalist in there with 'em.
Al-Jazeera's got us on the goddamn
TV news right now. Understand?
Do you have any idea
what that means?
It means we're gonna wait here,
taking fire for some general...
75 miles away
to make a decision...
about goddamn public relations...
about how it would look
if we did this...
or how it would look
if we did that!
That sound like war to you?
Don't contradict me, fool.
I'm your goddamn squad leader.
I'm here to keep you
scared shitless.
[Gunfire Continues]
[Indistinct Chanting]
[Chanting Continues]
- [Rapid Gunfire]
- Hold your fire! Let's see what's happening!
[Grunting]
- Sorry, sir.
- That's all right, soldier.
It's good to see you're ready
to defend your position.
- Yes, sir.
- Sergeant, you're movin' up at midnight.
Fifty meters dead on. We're tightening
the noose. You got me?
- Yes, sir. Any air support?
- Negative, Sergeant.
- Air's dedicated to another area.
- Yes, sir.
- How'd these women end up up here?
- They're motor transport.
They were dropping my new guys when their
vehicle went down under small arms fire.
- That's what started this mess.
- I'm gonna go behind you and
get to the next squad, okay?
- That's what started this mess.
- I'm gonna go behind you and
get to the next squad, okay?
- Don't let the crazy Texan shoot me.
- No, sir.
[Gunfire Continues]
- Sorry, Sergeant.
- Sorry?
I got guys who'd give a month's
pay to lay hands on the Mad Cow.
- Mad Cow?
- Yep.
[Laughs] Oh, these are gangsta.
I love my N.V.G.'s.
Shut up, you moron. Are you stoned?
This is a combat zone.
- I grew up in a goddamn combat zone.
- You think you're bad, fool?
Mortar lands on your head, we won't find
enough of you to fill a condom. Now shut up.
Let's move.
[Man Shouts In Arabic]
We're at the last berm, Lieutenant.
From here on out, it's open desert
all the way to the mosque. Over.
- [Mad Cow On Headset]
Did you move up the 50 meters?
- We moved up 25.
But I'm telling you it's
the last cover there is. Over.
My orders were to move up
50 meters, Rawhide 1.
That means 50 meters. Over.
Roger. Out.
- A disease that eats men's brains.
- Come again?
You were wondering
why they call him Mad Cow?
That's why.
- Jesus, I can't do this.
- Put it down, Mrs. B.
Don't call me that.
Shut up, both of you!
Hey, Dim, let's give her a hand.
- I can do it myself.
- If you say so.
- Are you deaf, soldier?
- Don't provoke her, fool! Get down!
- I said I can do it myself!
- [Gunfire]
Take cover!
I said take cover, goddamn it!
Get down!
I'm gonna shoot me out a light.
[Shouting In Arabic]
Cease fire!
We are not clear to fire!
We have not been cleared
to return fire!
Goddamn it!
I ordered them to move up 50 meters
'cause I was ordered to move up 50 meters.
But I didn't tell them to return fire.
That they did on their own, Captain.
- Something you want to add, Sergeant?
- No, sir.
Well, how 'bout you tell me what you think
of what happened anyway, Sergeant?
How about that?
I think my men were exposed
to enemy fire and returned it...
in accordance with both the rules
of engagement and common sense.
What about our deployment
strategy, Sergeant?
What did you think of that?
I didn't think that was in accordance
with the rules of common sense...
but this being the goddamn army,
I followed my goddamn orders, sir.
I agree with him, Lieutenant.
I think you might want to be a little more
flexible in interpreting your orders.
Still want me to write up
an incident report?
Goes in everybody's record,
no matter how it's disposed of.
No, sir.
Good. Anything else?
What do we do about the women?
Right now it's probably more dangerous to
move them than to leave them where they are.
There's negotiations going on
with the people inside the mosque.
That's why the sat comm trucks are here.
But they may take a while.
Could be here a week,
for all I know.
Now, I understand
your people are new.
- Think they can handle it?
- I hope so.
Absolutely.
I understand they call you
Sergeant Scream, Sergeant.
Why is that?
[Shouting]
I have no goddamn idea, sir!
Well, it's a good name
for a sergeant.
Thank you, sir.
As you were.
Do something useful while
nobody's shooting at you! Eat!
So the pink-ass sergeant tried
to get the brother in trouble, huh?
Say what?
Said the pink-ass sergeant
tried to get the brother in trouble.
- Don't you agree?
- No.
Why you wanna say that?
That's all you gotta say is no?
The lieutenant's a fool.
He's a brother makin' his way
in the white man's world is what he is.
Can't you see that?
Or they got you so turned around,
you go against your own?
We gotta stick together, bro.
We? You mean "we the niggers"
or "we the fools"?
'Cause if you're lookin'
for another nigger to back you up...
no questions asked,
don't look at me.
But if you're lookin'
for another fool...
to risk gettin' shot to cover your
fool behind, I'm right beside you, boy.
I'm right here beside you.
[Quiet Muttering]
Yo, Dim, you awake?
Yeah.
You know, I never asked-
Why they call you Dim?
'Cause I'm stupid, dog.
That's why.
No, you're not.
Yeah, I know I'm not.
But back in boot, when they
heard I went to Cornell...
they figured I had to be stupid
to end up in the army anyway.
So... that's why.
- I'm goin' to college.
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah. I got me a scholarship
to play football at Texas A&M.
But I couldn't afford it,
so I signed up.
You got a scholarship,
but you couldn't afford it?
Yeah, see, it wasn't a full-ride.
I ain't that big.
Twenty-two T.D.'s
my senior year though.
Yeah, I finish my hitch,
I'm goin' back to school.
They gotta hold the scholarship
for me 'cause I signed up.
G.I. Bill will cover the rest.
I'm gonna see if I can't play
on the kick-off coverage team at least.
You know, they let
walk-ons play on it.
That's a worthy goal.
Yes, it is.
You married?
[Sighs] Don't go ruining
a beautiful evening, dog.
I already told you I'm stupid.
[Man On Headset] Maintain your positions.
They're still at it. Over.
Roger. Out.
Negotiations continue!
Keep your eyes peeled anyway.
I got a funny feeling about this.
- Hey, Sergeant?
- Yep.
Where's a fella
supposed to take a shit at?
You want privacy,
go where we can't see you.
You wanna stay alive, go where we can.
That simple enough?
There's land mines too.
Don't forget those.
You sure you gotta go that bad?
[Men Shouting In Arabic]
[Man On Headset] Still at it. Comin'back
with a counterproposal. Over.
They've sent out a list
of demands for their treatment.
If the brass agrees,
they'll come out under a white flag.
Pass it on.
Now?
Yeah, now.
If they get what they want, they'll
come out under a white flag. Got it?
Hey, I've been meaning to ask you-
How come they call you Angel?
I sang in a choir.
Thought I was gonna sing
for a living.
Went up to New York City to try out
for a choir that competes all over the world.
Still can't believe I didn't make the cut.
[Laughs]
Couldn't bring myself to go back
to Arkansas, so I signed up.
Don't ever do nothin'
out of anger, boy.
Take it from me.
I love the army.
No shit.
Ain't Mrs. B
supposed to be on watch too?
Well, where's she at?
Got me. She "aksed" me where
you could take a dump before.
I told her they let you use the john at
McDonald's, but you gotta buy something first.
- You tell her they sent out
a list of demands, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Things work out,
they'll surrender. Okay?
If she comes back with french fries,
I'll kiss her ass.
You try, she'll stick
a bayonet up your heinie.
She thinks you're the devil.
This is the army, remember?
No good deed goes unpunished.
You ain't gonna ask me how come
they call me Doublewide?
No, ma'am.
[Urine Hitting Ground]
- [Gasps]
- [Man] Shots fired!
[Man On Headset] What's going on
up there, gentlemen? Over.
Rawhide 6,
I got multiple contacts.
They must've been trying
to sneak past us.
I guess their offer of surrender
was bullshit. Over.
[Man On Headset] Either that
or there are different groups in the mosque.
What are you facing up there,
Sergeant? Over.
I've got small arms.
Additional fire comin' in too.
- Do you copy? Over.
- Copy that, Sergeant.
I better get on
with the captain. Over.
Peace.
I got mortars landing
directly on my position!
Do you copy?
Do you copy? Over.
- [Man On Headset] Copy that, Sergeant.
- Hang on, Dim. Keep firing.
I could use some heavy guns
up here, Lieutenant. Over.
[Man On Headset]
Copy that.
Hold your positions and sound off!
You first, Texas.
I'm good. Dim?
Good. Smoke?
Yeah, yeah. Angel?
I'm here. Doublewide?
I'm okay. Mrs. B?
[Panting]
Mrs. B, goddamn it,
answer me!
No Mrs. B.
Ain't no Mrs. B.
Mrs. B's gone.
Everybody but Mrs. B,
Sergeant.
- Mrs. B?
- The female driver.
[Gunfire Continues]
We'll look for her
as soon as we can.
Right now the best we can do
is lay down more fire...
in case she's tryin' to get back to us.
Okay? Let's go!
What the hell is this shit?
Sandstorm.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Get your head down!
You see that, Sergeant?
Where's our 50's, goddamn it?
- [Yells]
- [Shouting In Arabic]
[Shouting Continues In Arabic]
[Scream] They're trying to flank us
to our right.
That's where Mrs. B went.
Come on!
Get the hell down, goddamn it!
- We gotta find her before they do.
- [Dim] I got your back.
- I see her!
- [Dim] Where?
Over here.
- [Gasps, Groaning]
- She's alive!
[Whimpering, Grunts]
Allah Akbar!
[Groaning]
[Gunfire Continues]
Come on, let's go!
Let's go!
Keep your head down!
[Grunts]
Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch!
- [Man On Headset] Those are our mortars.
- Say it again. Over.
You may follow this barrage
right to the mosque, Sergeant.
Those are ours! It's time
to give some instead of taking it!
Doublewide, you stay in that hole
with Mrs. B! Understand?
- No matter what!
- Check, Sergeant!
Bo, you stay right here
beside me! Right here!
You run off again,
I'll kick your ass! Understand?
- Yes, sir!
- And don't call me sir, goddamn it!
Let's go! Let's get some!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Let's kick some goddamn 3rd Infantry ass!
- Sing something, Angel!
- I don't know no killing songs, Sergeant!
Well, you better make one up, 'cause this
is why we came to this party, goddamn it!
We didn't come for your oil!
We came to kick your ass!
I capped this dude right here.
I remember I was right over there
when I capped him.
- Nice shootin'.
- Yeah, man.
Smaller than I thought.
Mrs. B!
What?
Hey, they're
bringing out the leader!
- [Shouting In Arabic]
- Now we will taste your freedom!
- [Shouting Continues]
- Freedom we do not want.
[Shouting Continues]
Freedom forced upon us.
Now we will taste
your American freedom.
Now you'll go take me
to Abu Ghraib.
Do you have a bag
for my head yet?
Do you want me
to take my clothes off now?
- Allah Akbar!
- God is great!
There is no god but God!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
I must go with him!
That was part of the agreement!
- That was part of the agreement
for his surrender.
- Yes.
But he didn't surrender, Mr. Fazal.
Remember? He attacked...
costing the lives
of dozens of his men.
[Shouts In Arabic]
[Indistinct Rap]
Sergeant, did your people
come through all right?
[Scream]
Yes, sir.
Listen up. There's video e-mail
back by the sat comm trucks.
Wait's usually two, three days, but I pulled
some strings and got your men and women...
a chance to send some messages home.
So you just go on back there,
identify your unit.
- They'll take you right
to the front of the line, okay?
- Thank you, sir.
[Rap Continues, Indistinct]
Spooky, honey, this is Mommy.
Are you doing what Daddy says, honey?
Are you being a good boy?
Mommy's at work,
and everything's fine.
Everybody's okay, and Mommy's
doing a goodjob so far.
She's dirty,
and she smells bad...
and she's been eating food
tastes like Silly Putty, sweetheart.
But in every other way,
she's fine...
and she misses you
and your daddy real bad.
You hear that, Spooky?
Hmm? Silly Putty.
Yo, Bebe, what up, man? Get around
to checking your e-mail again...
you'll see me out in the middle
of goddamn downtown Shitville.
Sorry, soldier,
you can't say where you are.
I didn't say where I was at.
I said I was in Shitville.
You see any signs for
downtown Shitville around here?
You can't say anything at all
about where you are.
And if you can't follow the rules,
you can't send the message, okay?
All right, look.
Just start me up again, all right?
Hey, baby. Oh, this is dumb.
I'm no talker.
I'm thinking of you though.
[Sighs]
We're gettin' by.
We've made it through
our first week anyways...
which not everybody thought
was gonna happen, let me tell ya.
Just that right there is a victory.
Vanessa...
I don't know if I can explain to you
in words what's happening to me.
And I don't- I don't mean
shooting at men and being shot at.
I mean inside.
Someone said, "Tragedy was
the inevitable working out of things."
And the tragedy here is,
we're savages.
We're thrilled to kill each other.
We're monsters.
And war is what unmasks us.
But there's a kind of honor in it too...
a kind of grace.
I guess if I'm a monster,
it's my privilege to be one.
I'm starting to see...
that it's also my privilege
to be your husband...
and the father of your child.
I don't know why that seems
to make so much sense to me today.
It hasn't for a long time.
But it does today.
Bye.
[Beeps]
[Moaning]
- Wanna hear my song?
- Say what?
- What song?
Sergeant told me to make up a song.
I'm making one up.
- Sure.
- It's not a killing song.
I don't care. Sing it.
All right.
The day is comin'
The drums are drummin'
If you know one, say a prayer
There's mothers cryin'
And fathers sighin'
War is in the air
The trains are fillin'up with boys
Who've left behind
their favorite toys
They're goin' over there
Where someone has to die
That's all I got.
Shit.
[Chuckles]
Thanks.
You got a minute?
You could be my best soldier, Bo...
or you could be my worst, and the only
difference is you goin' off on your own.
Understand?
You got somethin' you wanna do
so bad you'll risk your life, you tell me.
We'll do it- my way, on my time,
or we're gonna have a problem.
And I don't solve my problems with goddamn
incident reports. You take my meaning, Private?
You risk the life of one of my men again,
I'll shoot you myself.
[Men Shouting In Distance]
Psst. Yo, Bo?
My sources tell me they got Listerine bottles
filled with Courvoisier down the road.
- Really?
- Yeah. Down at Echo Company.
Just camped like a mile away.
What's up?
You wanna go in with us?
- On what?
- On a beer run.
I got a dude
that can hook us up.
- Sure. Why not?
- All right. Cool.
If we all put in 20 bucks,
we get what we need.
They got supply trucks goin'
back and forth all the time.
So what's up?
You wanna go?
- Where?
- On the truck.
Get the shit.
Goddamn, soldier.
- I'll go with you.
- Okay.
All right.
Snore-Stop? Goddamn! Why the hell
do they call you Snore-Stop?
We were sneakin' up on a weapons
cache we heard about...
4:00 in the morning.
Had to kill a kid sentry.
He was asleep on the job.
Cut his throat.
Why are you always asking everybody
why they're called what they're called?
'Cause everybody's got a nickname but me.
Can't figure it out.
Bo's your real name?
There's your problem right there.
- Where?
- Well, everybody thinks
Bo's already your nickname.
- You're kiddin'?
- No.
Where I come from,
no one's named Bo. Not at birth.
- Really?
- [Laughing]
- What?
- Nothin'. I'm just-
You're a natural leader, Bo.
Just tryin' to figure out why that is.
You play quarterback?
People always followed you?
When I was goin'
where they wanted to go too.
- [Mad Cow] You see that kid there?
- [Man] Where?
Right there. He dropped something
by the side of the road.
- I see him.
- Well, he dropped something
by the side of the road.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
A paint can or somethin'.
Pull over!
- Pull over where?
- Pull over here, goddamn it!
[Bo Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
He's breathing.
Circulation, check.
I'll see if we can get
an aircraft in here.
Well, sir, he's losing
time, goddamn it!
[Screaming Continues]
That means no goddamn pulse
in his right leg.
No pulse in his right leg.
Give him the morphine!
Give him the goddamn morphine!
I can't. He's gotta be lucid.
This man's in critical danger!
He's gonna be in surgery
back at the base in 25 minutes.
Give him something!
They just blew his ass in half!
- [Coughing]
- What do I do now?
- Get him on the stretcher!
- [Shouting, Indistinct]
[Screaming Continues]
- Easy.
- [Screaming]
Get him on the stretcher! Go!
[Shouting Continues]
[Slow Rock]
The day is comin'
The drums are drummin'
If you know one
say a prayer
There's mothers cryin'
And fathers sighin', uh-huh
War is in the air
The trains are fillin'up
with boys
Who've left behind
their favorite toys
They're goin'over there
Over there
Where someone has to die
Where ours
is not to reason why
Over there
Where someone has to die
[Continues]