Mom! Let's go!
What are you doing?
Kara, this is crazy. Why
can't you tell me what's going on?
- Where's the diaper bag?
- I don't know. I thought you had it.
[Vehicle approaches]
[Horn honks]
That's Jed. Let's go.
Okay, I'm going.
[Dog barking]
- Debbie: Hi, sweetheart.
- Ashley: Hi.
Hi, Sam. Here, take this. Thanks.
Kara: You got gas? Supplies?
I filled up on the way over.
I need to know what's
going on here, Kara.
Does this have something
to do with my dad?
You dad's still in Asia, sweetheart.
In Hong Kong?
I'll explain everything at another time.
- [Frankie fusses]
- Debbie: Okay, ready.
I've got my sat phone if
you need me. Call me.
[Kisses]
[Frankie fussing]
Shh, sweetheart.
Ashley: It's okay. We got him.
[Frankie crying]
[Car door closes]
I'll call you as soon as I can.
[Kisses]
Be careful.
[Car doors close]
[Engine starts]
♪ ♪
[Indistinct conversations]
Start over there. Whatever
patients need one.
Here. Give this to the medic.
He'll give you further instructions.
Rios: We're gonna do everything
we can to make you comfortable.
[Indistinct conversations continue]
Sasha, I need an I.V. bag over here.
- How you doing?
- Sasha: We're all out, Doc.
- [Fabric rips]
- How you doing?
Rios: Take a deep breath.
You'll be okay. Just rest.
Welcome back, buddy.
Man: We're out of compression bandages.
- Anything you got for me?
- Man: Not right here. I'll check with...
We'll get through this. You understand?
Sir.
It's time.
Man: I'll cut up some
extra for everybody.
[Man coughing]
Man: Then let's, uh,
change that dressing.
[Metal creaking]
I was a plankholder.
Did you know that?
No.
I don't believe I did.
I watched her being built.
Those my windows?
Yeah. We took everything we could use.
Like donating your kid's
eyes after a car crash.
Team's clear of the vessel.
Charges have been set and
rigged to ensure maximum damage
to any sensitive technical equipment.
Ready to proceed.
Captain Meylan, switch is hot.
Thank you, Captain Slattery.
[Clears throat]
[Click, beep]
[Explosions]
♪ ♪
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
So the plan is just to hold position
until Peng rears his head?
Obviously, that's impossible.
Now that search and rescue is complete,
- we need to keep moving.
- Cobb: Then what's on the table?
We're exploring
several potential options,
- but we have to...
- Options?
There's only one option I can see.
We need to go home.
Not that simple, Captain.
Excuse me, Captain.
SSES intercepted these communications...
...from the Chinese
destroyer Sea Dragon.
The one we sunk? It's all coded.
Yes, but it's likely the
cipher is still aboard the vessel.
At the bottom of the South China Sea?
Yes, sir. If we could send
a team down to retrieve it...
Come on. This is ridiculous.
Sir...
Peng could be anywhere right now.
We don't have the fuel to wait him out.
Our medical stocks are depleted,
and in 72 hours, we won't
be able to feed our people.
We'll find replenishments. We always do.
As I understand it,
you've already shut down Peng's factory.
You've cut off his smuggling operation
and destroyed the ship
carrying the last of
his chemical weapons.
What more is there?
As long as Peng is breathing,
he's a threat to the
region and to the world.
If we don't stop him, he'll
just set up a new factory
and start the genocide all over again.
Say we could get a lock on his position.
The man still has two
destroyers that we know of,
and most likely a sizeable army.
We've already lost
Hayward and Shackleton,
along with the lives of
300 American sailors.
Even if we could take down Peng,
what's to say someone else won't
rise up and take his place
the minute we leave the region?
I'm sure I don't have to remind you
that there are a lot of
other people in this world
who could use our help,
and we are wasting our resources
fighting what might
be an unwinnable battle
10,000 miles away from home.
[Inhales sharply]
We need to finish the
job we were sent here to do.
That means cutting
the head off the snake.
This mission was approved
by the Commander in Chief.
But the circumstances have changed.
We need to talk this
over with the President.
We're at EMCON, Captain.
Until I can be assured
that we have a secure line home,
nothing changes.
Have Lieutenant Green form a dive team.
Search that destroyer. Find the cipher.
Alisha: Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
- Thank you all for waiting.
- [Camera shutter clicks]
This morning, I signed
Executive Order 10842.
This order eases restrictions
on the federal ration card mandate,
provides more local
control over banking issues,
and temporarily suspends
the private property
claw back regulations,
as set forth my predecessor.
- Man: Mr. President. Mr. President.
- [Reporters shouting at once]
Details can be found in
your briefing packets,
regarding the affected territories.
- Where's Mrs. Green?
- Woman: I don't know.
In addition, I have
promoted the Army National Guard
to active status
and placed them under the
control of local leadership
in a bid to quell continued riots
in the Five Territories.
Mr. President. Mr. President,
Mr. President,
you've been in office for 48 hours now.
How do you account for
the immediate rollback
of President Michener's policies?
[Camera shutter clicks]
How do I account for it?
[Birds chirping]
I'm sorry,
but the President will not be
taking any questions today.
- [Camera shutter clicks]
- Thank you, sir.
Man: Mr. President! Mr.
President, please!
Mr. President, can't you
at least answer anything?
- Mr. President!
- Ms. Shaw, there's been conjecture
that President
Oliver's political sensibilities
lie to the right of...
I don't comment on conjecture.
Well, can you tell us if we can expect
a further shift in
agenda from this White House?
President Oliver is his own man,
but the agenda remains the same...
Building a stronger and better America.
On that note and due to
the President's
increasingly demanding schedule,
we'll be discontinuing
these daily addresses...
...and replacing them
with weekly briefings administered
by my office.
Thank you very much.
That's a lid on today.
- Ms. Shaw!
- [Reporters shouting at once]
- One question! Allison!
- Ms. Shaw!
Uh, call for you on 2.
When did we get a second line?
[Indistinct conversations,
telephone rings in distance]
Allison Shaw.
Allison, it's Kara.
Man: She's not available.
Kara, where are you? We've
been calling you all morning.
I'm... [Sighs] in trouble.
I need your help.
- What's wrong?
- Rivera's dead.
Dead?
And Senator Beatty.
They were shot in the
Capitol parking garage last night.
Oh, my God. There was no...
there's no... no reports.
Are you sure about this?
I was there. I saw it.
I've been wandering around all night.
I don't know what to do.
Where are you right now?
[Indistinct conversations]
It's all right. You're gonna be okay.
I will send someone to come get you.
No.
[Laughter in distance]
I think we have a mole
inside the White House.
And until we find them,
there's no one I can trust except you.
You need to come alone.
Okay, just me. Tell me
where you are right now.
Woman: He's gonna be coming by...
S&W Diner.
On Fifth.
Hold tight. I'll be right there.
[Receiver clatters]
- Man: Could we get the check, please?
- Man: Sure.
[Birds chirping]
- You doin' all right?
- Uh-huh.
[Tires screch]
[Car doors open]
[Engine stops]
Woman: What can I get ya?
Uh, can I get a glass of milk
for my daughter, please?
Sure. Just one second.
[Door opens]
[Horn honks in distance]
[Helicopter blades whirring]
I need a favor.
My team went diving for an item
we think was on the Chinese destroyer.
Seems some pirates got to it first.
You told me you still
have some people out there.
Yes.
You know of any way to
get a message to 'em?
[Exhales] Might help us find Peng.
[Exhales sharply] Yes.
I will try.
Sir, my crew has had a
couple run-ins with these pirates.
In fact, two of my
sailors were gravely wounded
during a swarm attack.
You don't need to remind
me what they're capable of.
We don't always get
to choose our allies.
So we're willing to do
anything? Get in bed with anyone?
Like I said, we're gonna finish the job.
With all due respect, sir...
Usually when someone
says "with all due respect,"
he's about to show a
lack of respect, Captain.
I understand the
damage that Peng has done,
that's he responsible for
a lot of loss to your crew,
and that he even tried to kill you...
And you think this is personal for me.
I've lost a third of my crew,
and I'm willing to walk away
if that's what's for the greater good.
- Hmm.
- And I get the feeling
there are other people in
your senior leadership
who feel the same way.
Sometimes a captain has
to make the unpopular call
because that's his responsibility.
Someday, I hope you understand that.
Now...
all due respect, I have things to do.
Thank you, sir.
Are you sure you had the right diner?
Okay. Yes.
All right. No, just head back.
I have something else for you.
Guess our Mrs. Green
isn't just a pretty face after all.
It appears that way.
How much has she figured out?
It doesn't matter. She
can't prove any of it.
And when are you gonna release the news
about Beatty and Rivera?
I will leak it sometime tonight.
I didn't want it convoluting this
morning's press conference.
Well, we need to
start corralling the herd.
And if Chandler makes it
home to rally the troops,
all of our lives
become much more difficult.
I told you that I am dealing with it.
You've been saying
that for two weeks now.
Everybody's gettin' impatient.
I have done more than my part, Roberta.
And let us not forget
that none of you would
even have a seat at this
table if it wasn't for me.
Don't fool yourself, dear.
You may have set the table,
but we're paying for the groceries
and we're cookin' the meal.
Let's not forget that.
[Door opens]
♪ ♪
[Men speaking Japanese]
[Speaks Japanese]
Did you find the decoder?
He's saying that was
only a finder's fee.
If you wanna purchase the cipher,
it's gonna cost double the rations.
We barely have enough
food to feed our own crew.
That's not gonna work for us.
Takehaya: Please, let me talk to him.
[Speaks Japanese]
What'd he say?
Lau Hu killed Shirahama's brother.
[Speaks Japanese]
- He said...
- I got it.
[Speaking Japanese]
You have a deal at the original price.
[Door opens, telephone
ringing in distance]
[Indistinct conversations]
Sir, I have an order
here for your signature.
No one in their right
mind would sign this.
This isn't a negotiation, Howard.
It's "Mr. President."
And I'm not gonna stand by while
you destroy this country.
I don't care if you kill
me, but I'm done taking orders.
We can't kill you, sir.
But I will remind you that
we can kill your family.
It was only five months ago.
We had a plan, a good
plan, and it worked.
We cured a whole country.
What the hell happened to
that? How did we get to this?
There are forces at work here,
and they are bigger than me,
and they are bigger than you.
And they're stretched all
the way across the Pacific,
where you're exterminating
whole races of people.
We had no idea what Peng
was planning to do.
All we needed was his
help to get rid of Chandler.
The landscape of this
country is changing,
and there is nothing that
anyone can do to stop it.
I am still the President
of the United States,
and I can stop it.
We can stop it.
It can't be too late, Allison.
[Whispers] Sign it...
[Normal voice] Mr. President.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Man speaks Japanese]
Man: Passive radar is clear, sir.
No sign of the Chinese.
How's the temperature below deck?
Considering the circumstances...
I'd call it a low simmer.
New kid thinks my motivations
might not be completely impartial.
New kid's had a rough day.
He'll buck up.
What do you think?
Do you believe this is personal for me?
At this point, sir...
it's personal for all of us.
Sir.
The cipher the pirates
found checked out.
So far, we've isolated two
direct communications
between the Sea Dragon
destroyer and Peng.
Can we pinpoint his location in China?
That's just it, sir. He's not in China.
He's mobilized his remaining destroyers
off the coast of Tokyo.
And the latest intel suggests
he's aboard one of those destroyers.
[Knocks on door]
Hey.
Are you alone?
I, uh... yeah.
Shut the door.
Is our relationship about to change?
Alex Rivera and Senator
Beatty are dead.
What?
I thought Rivera was leaking
information to Peng,
so I followed him.
He was meeting with Beatty
when they were both gunned
down by the Secret Service.
Gunned down?
I found pictures of
troop readiness reports
on Rivera's phone.
I need to know why he
was bringing these to Beatty.
I need to know what they were into,
- what they were planning.
- Okay, okay, slow down.
It was an inside job. [Pounds counter]
And Shaw was part of it. I
don't know who I can trust.
But your press credentials
still get you access to the White House.
So you want me to break
into Senator Beatty's office,
after he was just
murdered by the Secret Service
along with the
Secretary of Foreign Affairs?
And I think they
killed the President, too.
What?
And I know for a fact the
Chief of Staff was in on it
and that she's been
double-dealing with Peng.
Please, Jacob, just get
into Beatty's office.
I know there's something there.
[Beep]
XO, we have a top
secret SCI communication
coming from central command.
It's double encrypted.
Put it through first
stage decrypt and print it out.
Aye, ma'am.
First stage decrypt commencing.
[Beeping]
[Man grunts]
Meylan: There's gotta be something
more you can give him.
I'm sorry, sir. I'm doing the
best I can with the ice.
There's a lot of guys in
worse shape than him.
[Labored breathing]
[Muffled] It's okay, sir.
I'm all right.
Captain Meylan, a message for
you from central command.
First stage decrypted, it's
now in command code.
Thank you, Commander.
- Woman: You hanging in there?
- Man: I am. It still hurts.
Woman: All right, let me
get you some pain medication.
♪ ♪
[Pen clicks]
[Indistinct conversations]
Captain Chandler.
Captain Meylan.
Something on your mind?
I have a flash order from
the Commander in Chief
to place you under arrest,
relieve Captain Slattery of his command,
and take Nathan James back to San Diego.
What the hell did you say?
"Illegal incursion into
the sovereign territory
of a foreign country.
Attempted murder of a foreign leader.
Destroying a noncombative
foreign vessel.
Dereliction of duty."
Ah, this is bullshit.
You can verify it if you like.
[File thuds]
Mike, you realize what this means?
The White House has been compromised.
That's how Peng kept
getting our coordinates.
It's more than that.
My plane exploding, you
guys getting ambushed...
Michener.
You saying he didn't kill
himself? We got a coup?
I talked to Oliver 24 hours ago.
He said we had his
full support. Now this?
Code is accurate, sir.
Order like this comes
through fleet command,
addressed to our XO, not you.
Everything about this
stinks. We can't follow it.
It's not our place to
question a confirmed order
from the Commander in Chief.
But my guess is that
POTUS has lost faith in
your senior command,
which is a hell of a lot more plausible
than your paranoid conspiracy theories.
Well, let's get the
President on the phone.
- We'll talk to him...
- Can't do that, Captain.
Like you said, we're at EMCON.
It won't matter,
not if Oliver's in on it.
Meylan: If you're so worried about
what's going on back home,
all the more reason we
should head that way.
We'll sort it out there.
You don't understand.
We're not gonna make it home alive.
The person who sent you those orders
is the same person who
just destroyed your ship.
We'll get sunk before
we hit Pearl Harbor.
Yeah, you heard those
charges. They're absurd.
From what I've seen in my
short time on this ship,
these charges don't surprise me one bit.
But it's not about what I think.
Master at Arms Plummer. Yes, sir.
Please remand Captain
Chandler into custody.
Stand down.
I'll comply with the order.
You need to keep the peace right now.
I'll be counting on you, Captain.
Sir.
Lieutenant Granderson, Lieutenant Mejia,
you are relieved of duty.
Please exit the pilot house.
XO Cobb.
Yes, sir.
Arrest those men stealing our food.
Set a course for Pearl
Harbor, where we will refuel
and continue directly
on toward San Diego.
Aye, sir.
I've already sequestered
Green, Burk, and Taylor,
so don't think about
doing anything stupid.
Not a good idea.
You are relieved, Captain Slattery.
Yes, I am, but if you get on that mike
and you tell the crew that
you've arrested Tom Chandler
and you're taking
control of the Nathan James,
you're gonna have to
sequester a lot more
than just those three guys.
That's a course we don't come back from.
[Switch clanks]
[Whistle blows]
[Beep]
[Amplified voice] Attention, all hands.
This is Captain Mike Slattery.
Effective immediately, by
order of the Commander in Chief,
Captain Tom Chandler has
been relieved of duty
and placed under arrest.
Per that same order, I
have been relieved of duty,
and Captain Joe Meylan
has taken command of the ship.
Come on, let's go.
Keep moving.
Now.
I expect every member of this crew
to perform their duties
with the professionalism
and determination customary
to this ship.
This is Captain Slattery. That is all.
[Beep]
The Chief of Naval
Operations asked to see me.
I understand your
captain was kind enough
to grant me 10 minutes.
[Man speaks indistinctly]
[Keypad beeps]
- 10 minutes.
- [Door opens]
Woman: We're just gonna
move the additional pallets into...
Tom, what the hell is going on?
I want you to ask for a court martial.
You'll be my legal council.
What?
Meylan will have to empanel a court.
He's not permitted to sit in judgment
over a superior officer...
[Pen scratches]
...so I'll have to
hand in my commission.
You'll never win. He'll stack
the court with his top people.
Good. Let him.
Tom, he could put you in
front of a firing squad.
There hasn't been a military
execution in the U.S.
since '61.
Stop being cute.
We're pawns in a bigger game.
I don't know what it is
yet, but I know this...
If we go home, whoever's behind this,
they'll kill us all.
I need to retake command of the ship.
There's a way out of this,
but technically, it involves
me committing treason.
So if you want nothing to
do with it, I'll understand.
Tell me the goddamn plan.
[Crickets chirping]
Credentials, sir.
Okay.
Tightening up security around here, huh?
Yes, sir.
Man: Make sure they're
posted, teams of two.
Man: Yes, I, uh, will change
them every 30 minutes.
Can I help you?
No. Uh, I was just
looking for the senator.
He's out of town this week.
Oh. Must've got my
dates crossed. Thanks.
♪ ♪
I still can't find any record
of a conversation between
Chandler and Michener
regarding the
break-in to Peng's mansion.
I asked Granderson. She
says it doesn't exist.
[Files thud]
What a mess.
[Dog barking in distance]
[Door opens, closes]
Secret Service were
cleaning out Beatty's office.
They beat us to the punch.
[Sighs] Damn it.
I was pretty sure you weren't crazy,
but with Oliver
reversing Michener's policies,
Shaw hijacking his press conference,
and now this, something's going on.
[Sighs] I didn't
wanna have to do this.
Do what?
There's one person at the
White House I can trust.
I didn't wanna put him at risk.
[Dialing]
Didn't mind putting me at risk.
- [Telephone rings]
- Thank you.
- Man: Yes, ma'am.
- [Ring]
This is Dennis.
Don't react. Don't look up.
Shaw is the leak.
I don't know who else is in on it,
but I need you to do something for me.
That's a lot of moving parts, sir.
We'll get it done.
Unfriendly on your nine.
- [Door closes]
- What's this?
Adding everything we
can to the ration pile, sir.
Thank you, gentlemen.
[Bag rustles]
[Indistinct conversations]
- Can I speak with you?
- Yeah. Sure.
- Captain.
- Hmm?
Me and my team have been
over every file, every log,
and deposed every key
member of your crew.
And I can tell you with certainty
that Tom Chandler cannot
mount a proper defense
with the evidence
available to him on this ship.
You need to get him to reconsider.
Back when the plague broke,
he refused a presidential
order to return home.
Didn't have any information,
didn't have any facts,
didn't know what the hell was going on.
But we survived at
sea and we found the cure
because of his instincts.
Isn't it possible his
instincts are right again?
I'm not saying he
shouldn't refute the charges.
But to do it here, under
these circumstances...
Circumstances don't add up. Come on.
Order from the Commander in Chief
comes out of the blue for
you to break the chain of command
and arrest the head of the navy,
just after we've been
attacked by the Chinese?
You're smarter than that, Captain.
It's not about...
I don't have a choice here.
Oh, we always have a choice.
To be clear...
I'm not saying exoneration is unlikely.
I'm saying it's impossible.
Well, then I can't help you.
He's gonna want his day in court.
And you're gonna have to give it to him.
[Pounding on door]
[Exhales]
Hey. Hey.
- [Exhales deeply]
- [Lock turns]
[Door closes]
Did you get a message to the James?
It's gonna be almost impossible.
Shaw's upped security
in the whole building.
Jacob: What about Oliver? Do
you think he's in all of this?
It's hard to tell.
The guy barely ever leaves his office.
May I?
So I got Beatty's calendar,
some projects he was
working on for Michener.
I had to do some decryption work,
but I found this one file tucked away...
- [Beep]
- ...in a hidden folder.
What are we looking at here?
Red dots. Sharp borders between regions.
These guys are staking their claim.
- I gotta get back to the office.
- Dennis.
Yeah, I'll get a
message off to the James.
That's not what I was gonna say.
Just be careful.
Yeah.
[Footsteps depart]
Just doesn't make any sense.
I heard that.
This new President's been
in office for what, a day?
I mean, what the
hell's really going on here?
It's like some animal kingdom shit.
Marking his territory, you know?
Yeah, good luck with that.
Chandler's basically American
royalty at this point.
He should just get a free pass for life.
What's that mean?
Hmm?
A pass? What's he need a pass for?
Nothing. No, I was just
saying. You know, come on.
He didn't do anything wrong.
He doesn't need a damn pass,
especially from a grunt like you.
- Whoa. Chill, Eric.
- It's PO2, blivit.
You know what I meant, okay?
Hey, I was eating that!
You've been complaining
since you got here,
and I'm sick of it!
How about showing a little
- goddamn gratitude?
- Gratitude?
Yeah, for pulling you and
all your helpless little buddies
out of the drink!
- [Chair scrapes floor]
- Who you calling helpless?
We wouldn't have even been there
if you pussies hadn't
called us for help.
You just call me a pussy?!
Hey! Back off him, huh?!
You back off! Come here!
[All shouting indistinctly,
chairs scraping floor]
[Grunting]
[Dishes clatter]
Come on, knock it off!
Stand down!
[Grunting continues]
[Shouting continues]
Cobb: Master at Arms, Master at Arms,
Report to mess deck immediately.
[Indistinct shouting continues]
Stand down!
[Grunting]
Hey! Hey! Hey!
[Speaks indistinctly]
Slattery: Break it up! Break it up!
We're on the same side, you
assholes! Break it up!
God... [Grunts]
Break it up!
Stand down! Stand down!
[Keys jangle]
- Just like old times, huh?
- Yes, sir.
What the hell is the matter with you?!
What the hell are they...
They're stockpiling
supplies in all these warehouses.
Food?
Food, medicine. They're
in such remote areas.
I mean, Clallam Bay, population's
under 500.
But according to this,
they've got enough
food in the warehouse there
to feed thousands of
people for six months.
Isn't there a red dot near Clallam Bay?
[Sighs]
Yeah, there is.
Looks like some of these other
warehouses line up, too.
Maybe that's what the dots are.
No. The dots are prisons.
Check them out.
- Benton, Arkansas.
- Yep.
Bismarck, North Dakota. Big
Spring, Texas. Yep and yep.
46 prisons for a population our size?
All maximum security.
And they're spread out
evenly in the territories.
There's controlling the troops,
hoarding the food, and
expecting people to resist.
Beatty must've been getting cold feet.
That's why he didn't go to the funeral.
That's why he was
trying to get to Rivera.
[Door bangs open]
Shit!
- [Silenced gunshot]
- Uhh!
[Silenced gunshot]
[Silenced gunshots]
♪ ♪
[Boxes clatter]
- [Racks shotgun]
- Uhh!
[Loud clatter]
[Panting]
[Clicks]
Gentlemen, I need to
depose these witnesses.
Sorry, Ma'am. No one in or out.
- Orders from Captain Meylan.
- I don't have time for this.
You're interfering with
official Navy proceeding.
What's going on here?
I'm sorry, Ma'am, but we
got orders from Captain Meylan...
[Grunting]
[Coughing]
[Groans]
Finally.
On your knees. Okay, boys.
Not a lot of time to
discuss the ramifications here,
but I will say upfront...
If we do this, it's dry fire only.
[Zip tie clicks]
Wolf: You want us to take back
the ship without loaded weapons?
Well, Hayward's crew won't fire on us.
They don't want blue on blue either.
I appreciate what I'm asking.
I think history will side with us
when the President's
order is proven unlawful.
[Clips clicking]
Sorry about this, boys.
Well, if we don't have bullets,
we're gonna need more guns, Captain.
Way ahead of ya.
[Door closes]
Take a seat, please.
Captain Chandler... [Sighs]
Before we begin,
you're entitled to
make an opening statement.
I've spent half my life in the Navy.
Like you, I did everything right.
Worked my way through the pipeline
just to get my chance to lead.
Nathan James was my first command.
- Suddenly...
- [Unlocks]
I was thrust into a situation that
no one can prepare you for.
The world was turned upside-down,
and all the rules were thrown out.
But... [Sighs deeply]
The Navy taught me many things.
Most importantly,
it taught me to adapt.
I had to make some difficult decisions.
[Bullets clatter, clip clicks]
God knows I made some mistakes.
But never once did I waver from
what I knew to be right...
The core values that run
through all of our veins.
[Clip clicks]
Honor...
courage...
commitment.
Chandler: And I served my
sailors as they served me.
Get down and drop your weapons!
...and as we all serve this
great country of ours.
I didn't ask for this.
I could've taken this
uniform off at any time.
- [Zip tie snaps]
- But I always believed
in the work that we
were doing as a team,
and the decisions that I
was making as a captain.
And though my tactics
changed to address an insane world...
[Shouts in Japanese]
...my resolve and my
dedication to the Navy never faltered.
I stand by my record.
[Shouts in Japanese]
Keep your hands up!
What the hell is this?
I see.
This was never about
your guilt or innocence.
You forced our hand here, Captain.
There was a moment today...
...where I actually had my doubts.
Thank you for removing those for me.
When the chips
fall, if I'm proven wrong,
I'll face justice from
a higher power than you.
Cooper, Green, please
remove the officers
and sequester them in Helo Bay 2.
Gladly.
Captain, I need you to
set a new course for Japan.
Yes, sir.
Let's go. On your feet.
Man on radio: ...the
body of Senator Beatty
and Secretary Rivera were
discovered late last night.
An arrest warrant has been issued
for Kara Green, a
senior military advisor,
and Jacob Barnes, White House reporter,
in connection with the double homicide.
Meanwhile, we will
have more of this story...
You really think this friend
of yours can help us?
If we can find him.
- In other news...
- [Horn blaring]
What the...
Man: Get the last two off the truck!
Drop that one in, and we're ready!
All right, secure it! Easy!
What the hell is that?
They're building a wall...
Man: Drop a pin in it when she's done!
...making those regional
borders permanent.
[Machinery whirring]
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --