(theme music playing)
(crickets chirping)
Tee, will you see whoever it is calling
so late in the evening?
Yes, ma'am.
(car door closes)
It's a man
in a uniform, ma'am.
(cup clinks)
(knocks on door)
(door opens)
(door closes)
(Tee chuckles)
(gasps)
Sidney Phillips.
- Oh! Father, Sid's here.
- (Sid chuckles)
- I hope I didn't startle you, Mrs. Sledge.
- Oh, not at all.
Now who the hell is this
standing in my hallway?
- It's Sidney.
- Dr. Sledge.
There's more pie
on the counter.
Thank you, Rose.
I want you to speak frankly
about my Eugene.
- How is he, Sid?
- Now don't put the boy on the spot.
Mrs. Sledge,
Eugene's with a lot
of good marines.
The 1st is
the best there is.
They're great guys, too.
They look after each other.
Besides that, well,
he's a mortar man,
the same as me.
Us stovepipe boys,
we're always a little
behind the hot stuff,
which is a good place to be,
let me tell you.
Now I can't say this
about every marine I know,
but I'm not worried
about Eugene.
See, Father?
That's not
so hard to hear,
is it?
(bombs exploding)
Man:
Second platoon corpsman, get up here!
(plane engines roaring)
(men speaking)
(lighter clicks)
Snafu:
What the hell you doing?
Break this shit down.
Get ready to move.
What do you got?
Any movement?
It's all quiet.
Any word on Hoosier?
Well, we got hit
pretty hard on the beach.
We're still sorting out
the casualties.
- Let's go.
- No word on ours, though.
(lighter clicks)
God damn it, I just want
some fucking water.
(canteen clinks)
(distant gunfire)
(distant yelling)
Man:
There's a gook squad off the the right!
Man #2:
Yeah, they're coming from...
Hey. Hey!
Somebody found water.
I swear to Christ.
- Water.
- Somebody found water.
- Halle-fucking-lujah.
- There's plenty, boys.
- All right. Yeah.
- (water sloshing)
Man #3:
Pass my helmet.
Oh, Jesus! Man!
It's poisoned.
Jap fuckers
poisoned it.
(sighs)
(water sloshing)
Man #4: Listen up, Weapons!
CO's got our orders!
Haldane:
All right, here it is.
The entire division's moving
across the airfield at 0900.
First and second
platoon will lead,
followed by Weapons
and third platoon.
The only way to stop this Jap artillery
is to get into those hills,
and the only way into those hills is
across this airfield.
When we move,
do not stop until we get across.
- You got it?
- All: Aye, Skipper.
Any questions?
We need water,
Captain.
I'm working
on it, Corporal.
Get your gear ready
and stand by.
Haney: Get back to your positions.
Pack it up!
Man: Let's go, second squad!
Let's get back on line!
Man #2:
Let's go, rockets!
Pack 'em up!
Move it!
We have to cross that?
Quit whining.
It'll all be over
by the time you cross.
Japs hate mortars
and bazookas
as much
as riflemen, Leyden.
How many Japs
do you think are up there?
- Anybody got any asswipe?
- No asswipe, no chow,
no water.
So don't even think about it.
A nice cold sip
of water?
A little splash
on your head?
Put it right out
of your mind.
I've got a little water.
(men chatting)
(explosion)
(man yells)
We gotta go!
Stand by!
Look alive!
Thank you.
Man: Let's go!
Get that gear squared away!
You've been promoted.
You're gonna give him
the mortar sight?
It's the least
I can do for the water.
Man:
Second squad, on me!
Get off your ass.
Get under that gear.
We're moving shortly.
Man #2:
Stay alert! Stand by!
(distant gunfire)
Hey, the 5th's dry too.
Maybe the Japs have
some over there.
How could they send
us up here without any fucking water?
Lucky?
(multiple explosions)
Get your gear together!
Stand by to move out!
(plane engines roaring)
(distant explosions)
Thank God for the navy.
First and second platoon,
move out!
Man: Let's move!
Let's move! Let's move!
(men shouting)
Man:
Let's move!
Haldane: Come on, first squad!
Stay on me!
- On me, second squad!
- Man #2: Hurry it up, people!
(guns cocking)
(men yell)
Left platoon,
move out!
Man #2: Go go go!
Move it! Let's go!
Always first.
- Man: Okay, let's cross the airfield!
- Right behind you, Bill.
- Man #2: Do not stop!
- Man #3: Move! Stay low!
(guns cocking)
Weapons, let's go!
Man: First squad,
push dead ahead!
- See you on the other side!
- Haldane: Let's go!
Go! Hurry up!
Let's go!
- Man #3: Move it!
- (plane engines roaring)
(guns cocking)
(bombs exploding)
(men shouting)
(grunts)
(men screaming)
(machine guns firing)
- (man screams)
- Get him out of here!
Reassemble
at the fallen base!
Come on, Sledge! Move!
Let's go.
Listen up!
We're crossing the airfield!
Stand by to move out!
Man: Get ready to cross!
Pass the word!
We're up!
How company!
On the left,
on the right, move out!
(plane engines roaring)
- See you on the other side!
- Let's go, marines!
- Let's go!
- Man: Go go go!
(bombs exploding)
- (men screaming)
- (machine guns firing)
Man:
Move it!
My knee!
Man #2:
Corpsman, help me!
Haldane:
Stand by to move!
Seibel, move out!
Let's go!
Sonny! Joe!
- Sniper attack!
- (rifles firing)
Let's go!
Move out! Go go!
Haldane: Move out!
Let's go! Let's go!
(gunfire continues)
(screams)
Don't stop moving!
Let's go!
You're all right!
Get up!
(men shouting)
You've got to get up!
Come on! You're all right!
- Man: Move it! Move it!
- Come on!
Hurts like hell!
(slurring)
Are you receiving?
Halfway across
the runway, sir.
We're taking heavy fire.
- Runner.
- We need an air strike.
We need...
we need an air strike...
(gurgles)
...to subdue Jap artillery
from the hill.
(gagging)
Are you receiving?
- Gotta get some fire on that bastard.
- We're gonna get you some help.
Are you receiving?
- I don't think we can send.
- Need a goddamn radio that works.
Fix it. Do you hear me?
Get it done.
- Yes, sir.
- (machine gun fires)
Leckie.
White Castle, this is How-4.
Do you read?
- Gotta go back.
- What about Conley?
Get us a radio
and a corpsman up here.
- I'll stay with Conley.
- (gunfire continues)
Okay.
Man: White Castle,
this is How-4. Do you read?
Hey, I'm coming back.
I'm coming back. Do you hear me?
I'm coming back.
Come on,
stay with me.
(man screaming)
Corpsman!
Hey, corpsman!
- Working time is at X-ray-5.
- Corpsman!
White Castle, White Castle,
do you read?
I need a corpsman
and a radio!
A radio?
You're better off
with two tin cans
and a fucking string.
Man:
...plus 100. Over.
- Get me in contact!
- Man: White Castle...
(machine gun firing)
This is Ack Ack.
Are you receiving? Drover-King-6...
(yells)
We need an air strike
on it. Over.
(clanks)
We've gotta get the hell out of here!
Let's go! Let's go!
Man:
- Come on! Let's go!
- (gunfire continues)
Man #2:
Get him on his feet! Keep moving!
- You're okay!
- Come on!
- Let's go!
Oswalt!
(plane engines roaring)
(machine guns firing)
Man:
Let's go! Let's go!
(men shouting)
Corpsman!
Hey, corpsman!
(jeep approaches)
Corpsman!
(plane engine roars)
Mortars, bomb center sector
and adjust!
Direct fire...
HE on the building
on your right front!
- (men shouting)
- (machine gun firing)
Leyden, get that gun
on the right!
- Hanging!
- Fire!
- Fire two!
(yelling
in Japanese)
Get that one
on the left, Jay!
Direct fire, 100.
Base charge.
- Hanging.
- Fire!
- 100'! Hit 'em again!
- Four!
- Hanging.
- Fire!
Let's go, K company!
Move out!
(men shouting)
Ah!
Spread out!
Keep moving!
- (groaning)
- Man: Up.
Stop.
Easy.
- (bomb explodes)
- Squad leaders,
find your people,
check 'em out.
You JASCO people,
get set up and wired in.
I need an ammo count.
What do you got?
What do you need?
We'll have OPs
going up before dark.
- Here you go, guys.
- Haney: Standby to standby.
- That's all we've got. Pass it around.
- (tank clanking)
- Is this ltem company?
- No, K-3-5.
I've got to get back
to Baker-1-7.
Do you have any idea
where they are?
No, I don't. I need you
to take our wounded back to the beach.
No can do.
We're moving out.
(tank engine revs)
Hold here till
we load our wounded,
then you can move your ass
wherever you want.
Yes, sir.
(engine stops)
Get the wounded aboard!
Let's get 'em
onboard!
(people chatting)
We're fine below!
Lower away!
- Out of the way, sir.
- Where do you want this one?
Man:
Right over here.
- Man #2: Clean this dressing.
- Woman: Doctor, his BP is falling.
Doctor:
Clamp the bleeder... right there.
Woman:
I've got a diminished blood pressure.
Sponge.
He's gone. Get him below
and prep that abdominal.
(coughing)
(crying)
(man speaking)
Daniels:56,
57,
58...
Man #2: Set him down here.
Get a tourniquet on that.
...60, 61...
Dextrose. Take one now,
save one for the morning.
...62, 63,
64,
65,
- 66...
- Whatcha doing, Daniels?
- Water.
- Counting Japs.
One, two, three...
- What's the report, Hillbilly?
- 81 from battalion.
60s are all here
and registered.
Gunny, I need another man
at second platoon LP.
Roger that.
Hey, Daniels.
Second platoon LP. Let's go.
Daniels:
I can count Japs from here.
Hey, Daniels,
did you hear me?
- I said...
- Gunny. Gunny.
Find someone else for him.
I need Daniels here.
Aye, Skipper.
Haldane: Doc, Daniels is gonna come
help you count bandages,
- maybe get a little shut-eye.
- Yes, sir.
Come on, Private.
Let someone else take over.
There's so many
to count.
I know, Private.
I know.
All right, Daniels.
Just as easily been me
counting Japs I can't see.
But it's not you.
Sir, coming across
the airfield today...
I've never been more scared
in my entire life.
We're all afraid.
All of us.
A man who isn't scared out here is
either a liar or dead.
History is full of wars
fought for 100 reasons.
But this war, our war,
I want to believe...
I have to believe
that every step
across that airfield
every man that's wounded,
every man I lose...
that it's all worthwhile
because our cause is just.
Of course, if a just cause came
with some hot food and cold water,
that'd be okay too.
Rest up, boys.
- Thought you might need that.
- Thank you, sir.
Ack Ack got me my battlefield
commission on the Canal.
Seems like
1,000 years ago now.
You handled yourself
well today, Sledge.
You'll be all right.
Just remember
your training.
Yes, sir.
...order
for the 3rd Battalion
to make a company-sized
frontal assault.
G2 thinks the bulk
of the Japanese defenses
are dug into the ridges
that run up the spine of the valley.
Until we take the high ground,
they'll keep plastering us.
Haldane:
We're moving into the hills!
Haney:
Let's move, people!
- Pork chops.
- Pork chops? That's my meat.
Courtesy
of LST-661.
- About time.
- Thank you.
- Let's go. Let's go.
- (men chatting)
(barks)
(distant explosions)
Saw you reading
last night.
My Bible.
Writing too.
Ain't supposed
to write shit down, you know.
It gives the Japs valuable intel
if they find it.
I guess I won't show it
to them then.
Got a smoke?
(lighter clinks)
Thanks, Sledgehammer.
Sledgehammer.
I like that.
- Jesus Christ.
- Snafu: Don't worry.
We've got a nickname
for you too, Bill Leyden.
We call you
ball-peen hammer...
a little hammer
for a little man.
All right, Snafu.
Shit 'n' ass...
fuck up.
- (chuckles)
- Little joke from the little man.
(distant explosions)
- Gunny, get someone from mortars.
- Aye, Skipper.
Burgie, get me an FO.
- Sledge.
- Haldane: You too, Leyden. Let's go.
- First squad, follow me!
- Hold 'em here, Sergeant.
- Set up a security perimeter.
- Aye, sir.
Set up
a security perimeter.
Machine guns move out
to the left and right flank.
Riflemen,
faced outwards.
Man:
Second squad, 36, let's go.
Man #2:
91 over on the right!
(distant gunfire)
Looks like two heavy
bamboo machine guns,
probably more.
I need to get
a better look.
- Sledge, Leyden.
- No no, I'm gonna scout it.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Get your top ready.
(machine guns firing)
Skipper, pull back!
Stay on those guns!
It's a fortress up there.
We've gotta move!
Pull back!
(mortars exploding)
- Pull back!
- Let's go! Let's go!
Pull back!
- Man: Skipper coming in!
- Man #2: Hold your fire!
- Radio, get me battalion.
- Yes, sir.
White Castle, this is Harper Field.
Do you read?
Haldane: Master White, Ack Ack.
We've done the recon.
Objective is
heavily fortified.
Limited approaches
and plunging fire all the way.
We can't take this objective without
unacceptable casualties.
Do you copy?
Fuck.
I've got to go back
to battalion,
get these orders changed.
Good luck.
If I don't come back,
the company's yours.
(flare hissing)
Do you think
he'll come back?
You disobey orders,
you get court-martialed.
You guys,
check your weapons.
Keep a round chambered.
Done.
Can you believe this
bullshit about the dog?
Some dog's supposed
to smell a Jap before me?
I don't think so.
I appreciate the thought, but ain't no dog
gonna make me sleep safe at night.
I've got a dog.
His name's Deacon.
You keep fucking
that stovepipe.
If the Nips come through here at high port
with fixed bayonets,
you nail 'em with flare
and HE as fast as you can.
- You think you can do that?
- We've got it, Gunny.
I was asking
Sledgehammer.
Yes, Gunny Haney.
Woof.
(laughing)
What the fuck was that?
- (men laughing)
- Hey, stovetop boys... woof!
(wind blowing)
(man whimpering)
What's that?
Sledge: Sounds like some guy
having a nightmare.
Snafu: He'd better shut up before every
Nip on this island knows we're here.
Hillbilly:
Quiet that man down.
God damn it,
shut up.
- (yelling) No! No!
- Hillbilly: Quiet down!
Hold him down!
Stick him with morphine.
Shut that fucker up.
- Stick him with morphine.
- (yelling continues)
- (gun fires)
- Jesus Christ, who the hell is that?
(flare hissing)
Hillbilly:
Hold him down. Calm down.
Help me, please!
Help me!
That guy is gonna get us all killed
if he don't shut up.
Hold him down.
Hold him.
Hit him with something.
- Help me!
- (thuds)
(men panting)
All right.
Get back to...
get back to your holes.
I guess better him
than all of us.
Sledgehammer's right.
It had to be done.
- What you got back there?
- What do you want?
I'll take
a cup ofjoe.
Runner: Hey, Peaches,
are you gonna waste those?
- You made it.
- I could say the same about you.
I tried to get you
a corpsman.
- I tried to get back to you.
- I know.
Lucky, I know.
(grunts)
You, uh...
you heard any word
about Hoosier?
Chuckler's still on that goddamn
piece-of-shit island.
Left a piece of whatever
hit me in my arm.
I guess I'll never have
to buy another drink
- in Buffalo ever again.
- (chuckles)
I'm gonna grab some coffee.
Do you want some?
Can you take me
topside?
I need some air.
- (rain pattering)
- Haldane: We've got our orders changed.
Regiment wants us hunting Japs
up the east road.
Don't blame yourself.
You did the right thing.
- Good to have you back, sir.
- Thanks.
K company,
move out!
(plane engines roaring)
Whoever is up there
is getting pounded.
- You should start to feel better.
- (engine thrumming)
Feel that.
They're starting the engines.
Yeah.
Hey.
Let's go home,
cobber.
(distant explosions)
(theme music playing)