[###]
[lN LATlN]
May the omnipotent God
have mercy upon you,
and forgive you your sins
and may Jesus Christ
Iead you to eternal life.
Amen.
[lN ENGLlSH]
To the faithful people of England,
your Holy Father offers you
the hand of condolence,
his tears of grief
and his anger at the martyrdom of
Sir Thomas More and Cardinal Fisher.
Stay back. Stay back.
PAUL: Their murder has shocked
the whole of Christendom.
[SHOUTlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
It was an unpardonable sin
against God and our Holy Church,
in whose name these two great
and noble men died.
We pray for those in England
who must continue
to live under tyranny
and in fear for their lives
and for their souls.
We pray the king ceases to listen
to evil counsel
and returns to obedience
and the true faith
before it is too late.
Attack the pope.
We pray to Mary, Mother of God,
that England may be redeemed
from heresy
and all its evil ways
and from the clutches
of the heretics
who even now are leading her
towards destruction
and damnation.
[CHEERlNG]
[CROMWELL CLEARS THROAT]
George Boleyn, Lord Rochford,
is to marry Lord Morley's daughter.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Lord Morley came to see me.
He cannot meet Sir Thomas Boleyn's
demand for a dowry of $300.
I assured him that I would make up
the shortfall.
Your Majesty is most generous.
How is your survey of the
religious houses progressing?
Majesty, the commissioners
are currently examining
houses in the West Country.
There and elsewhere,
they tell me they have
uncovered many enormities.
What enormities?
They have found the monks
in many places so depraved,
so licentious and so corrupt,
that your commissioners
already despair
of any perfect reformation.
For example, the case of the
celebrated Holy Blood of Hailes.
Supposedly the blood of a saint,
used for healing the pilgrims who
flock there hoping for a miracle,
it turns out to be the blood of a duck,
which the monks renew regularly.
Duck's blood.
Well, Mr. Cromwell, what do you
propose we do about it?
If Your Majesty will forgive me,
I think we should be looking for ways
to promote Your Majesty's
new monarchy.
What do you have in mind?
One way would be through
the production of plays.
Why plays?
Plays are an ideal way
of setting forth the abomination and
wickedness of the bishop of Rome.
They also are means to demonstrate
to people the obedience
that as subjects they owe,
by God's and man's laws,
to Your Majesty.
Good.
Then I leave it to you,
Mr. Secretary,
to finance and produce
some plays.
We must do all we can
to advance our revolution.
[SlGHS]
[###]
MORE: I shall now suffer death
in and for the faith
of the Holy Catholic Church.
CROMWELL: My Lord.
Mr. Secretary.
Your Grace.
Since Your Lordship
makes no secret of
your zeal for reform,
we were anxious
to let you know
of our progress.
His Grace has just
informed me of an
important new appointment
at Canterbury Cathedral.
Indeed.
Dr. Simon Heyes
has been made
our new dean.
Dr. Heyes detests
the cult of images
and is determined
to remove them
from the cathedral,
as well as introducing
the new learning.
It is vital that we place reformers
in positions of responsibility
inside the church.
There's bound to be a reaction
to the self-serving martyrdoms
of Fisher and More.
Which is why I'm letting it
be known that if anyone
hears a friend
or a neighbour criticising
the king or his marriage
or the reforms,
they have a duty to report it.
At the same time, Mr. Cromwell,
we have a duty to spread
the good news.
If the new monarchy is about
anything at all, it is about liberty.
Liberty from old superstitions,
from fear and guilt.
We-- We are moving, my friends,
from the darkness into the light.
I'm in agreement with Your Grace.
Fortunately,
we have a new weapon
to promote our ideas.
CRANMER:
Oh, my Lord.
What in God's name is that?
It's called a printing press, My Lord.
Beautiful.
And it will change the world.
What are you thinking of?
Nothing.
May I say something?
You know there are
many people abroad,
and perhaps even some
within this kingdom,
who still question
the legitimacy of our daughter.
It's true. You know it's true.
But there is something we can do
to change everything.
If Elizabeth was betrothed
to King Francis' youngest son,
the duke of Angoulême,
then her legitimacy and station
would no longer be questioned
by anyone.
I agree.
And have already thought about it.
I will speak
to the French ambassador.
[SlGHS]
Will you come to my bed tonight?
HENRY:
Dear Thomas.
Majesty.
Come stay at court.
I need you.
HENRY:
I'm not going to sign it.
You want the world to know
the king is changeable?
--whether it is better
for a king to be feared--
I don't want to be chancellor.
--or loved.
You will do as I command.
[###]
Harry. Harry.
I come to offer my resignation.
The time for Harry is over.
HENRY:
I discharge you. Most willingly.
COMMlSSlONER: --your head cut off,
your body to be divided in four parts.
HENRY:
Please forgive me.
MORE:
Harry.
[WlNDOW BANGlNG]
[WlND WHlSTLlNG]
[###]
Thomas?
Thomas.
[ORGAN PLAYlNG]
And you're doing well, yes?
Yes.
What is it?
I've changed my mind.
I don't want to go through with it.
Here, now, sweetheart.
Every woman has a moment
of faintheartedness.
It's natural.
No.
You are marrying
into a great family.
You will do it whether
you like it or not.
Do you understand?
[SPEAKlNG lN LATlN
Ha!
Get on with it.
Amen.
ALL: Amen.
Brethren,
we are gathered here today.
CHAMBERLAlN:
Majesty, Sir Henry Norris.
HENRY:
Sir Henry.
Your Majesty.
What can I do for you?
Well, as Your Majesty may know,
I recently became a widower.
And so naturally,
I'm looking to wed again.
And my choice has fallen upon
one of Her Majesty's ladies.
Who?
Lady Margaret Sheldon.
You mean Madge.
Yes.
Yes, I believe some people call her
that if they are familiar with her.
Have you made your intentions plain
to Miss Sheldon, Sir Henry?
No, Your Majesty. I have merely
admired her from a distance.
But I would now
like to take things further,
if Your Majesty can think
of no impediment.
No. None. You have my permission.
I've known you a long time.
I could not think of a more honest,
nor more honourable man.
I am deeply grateful
to Your Majesty.
Sir Henry.
Your Majesty.
CHAMBERLAlN: His Excellency
the French ambassador.
Excellency.
Your Majesty wanted to see me?
I wanted to ask after my brother,
the king.
His Majesty is very well.
Except for his hatred
of the emperor,
which is like a disease.
So he still wants our friendship?
Mon Dieu, he loves you above all
the princes in the world.
[###]
Then make to him this proposal.
That his son Charles,
Duke of Angoulême,
should be betrothed
to our beloved daughter,
Elizabeth.
[MUSlC PLAYlNG]
[CHATTERlNG]
MARK:
Who is she?
Jane Parker.
Lord Morley's daughter.
He's a distant cousin of the king's.
MARK:
Oh, she's a girl.
[LAUGHlNG]
Was that funny?
I don't know.
[SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
Sweetheart.
You do love me, don't you, George?
Of course I love you.
I married you, didn't l?
Oh, I can't wait for tonight.
[SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
What is it?
Nothing, l--
Excuse me, Father.
[###]
[MOANlNG]
You're very pretty.
Pretty Jane.
Pretty, pretty.
No.
No, please.
Please, no.
No.
No. Aah!
[GEORGE GRUNTlNG]
[JANE SHRlEKlNG]
[SOBBlNG]
[CHATTERlNG]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
POPE:
Let us go about our other matters.
Now, as much as King John does
Holy Church so handle,
so here I curse him
with cross, book, bell and candle.
[lMlTATES FARTlNG NOlSE]
[LAUGHlNG]
I will ask God to put him
from his eternal light.
I will take him from Christ.
And after the sound of this bell...
The bell, you buggers. The bell.
[BELL CLANGlNG]
And after the sound of this bell...
I said, after the sound of this bell,
both body and soul,
I will give him to the devil in hell.
[lMlTATES FARTlNG NOlSE]
[LAUGHlNG]
And meanwhile--
This is a fine piece of work,
Mr. Secretary.
And educative.
I wonder who wrote it.
Mr. Bale.
He was once a priest of the old faith,
but seeing how things went on,
became a most passionate
reformer.
You know, I think our family
never did anything better
than facilitate and encourage
your own rise, Mr. Secretary.
I trust you never forget
that we did so.
And all the abbots and bishops
will make lots and lots of money.
[BOOlNG]
I love the pope
as much as ever may be.
I prithee heartily,
tell me why you do so?
Because I perceive well
the pope is a jolly fellow.
A trim fellow. A rich fellow.
Yes, and a merry fellow.
He's rich in his royalty
and angelic in his behold.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
I've talked to the French ambassador.
POPE: Come here, fellow.
Francis is sending the admiral
of France to arrange the marriage.
Thank you.
MAN:
His name is Treason, Your Majesty.
POPE: Let us hear something
on behalf of the old church.
MAN:
Gilded images, all.
MAN: In your necessities...
Majesties.
The admiral of France
is to pay an official visit.
I want you to receive
and entertain him on my behalf.
Why him?
MAN: All the more procession...
MAN: In fasting and--
Surely my father
would be a much better choice.
MAN: Pestilence and the--
I trust Your Grace
to carry out my commands.
I am, as ever,
Your Majesty's
humble and obedient servant.
MAN: And what is there of Christ
in your church, pray tell?
That was unnecessary.
He hates me.
But he loves me.
And as they're in Latin,
no man can know.
[CROWD BOOlNG]
What is it?
That woman is a whore.
She treats me worse
than I treat my dogs.
But then, your dogs bite back.
If ceremonies and superstitions
from us fall,
then farewell monks and canons,
priest, friar, bishop and all.
[CHEERlNG]
Your Majesties.
How is Queen Catherine?
Alas, she is very unwell.
MAN: That the king may continue
to reign over her.
She is sinking.
Not only is her household
severely reduced,
but she has been separated from
her daughter for the last four years.
That is very cruel.
But her faith is astonishing.
ENGLAND:
And that his offspring may reign too.
And the Lady Mary?
ENGLAND: It's up to the--
While the concubine has power,
I fear for her life.
To the comfort of this nation.
[CHEERlNG]
[SPEAKlNG lN LATlN]
[WOMEN LAUGHlNG]
[BABY CRYlNG]
[###]
[SlNGlNG]
Lady Mary, what in heaven's name
are you doing
with the Princess Elizabeth?
She was left alone.
I took care of her.
Give her to me.
LADY BRYAN:
You left her alone, you little fool.
Then we sup and think of those
who are no longer with us.
To More and to Fisher,
those martyred men.
God bless them.
I am told that many who initially
supported the king's reforms
are now forming
a different opinion.
The terrible murder of honest and
faithful men has opened many eyes.
[SlGHS]
I still do not blame the king.
He's been seduced by witchcraft.
I have always believed it.
And now I have proof.
You have proof?
Yes.
I have, uh, befriended a maid
of Anne's bedchamber
who has told me that the harlot
hides a secret.
She's deformed, Chapuys.
An extra fingernail on her left hand
which she is at great pains to conceal.
As well, her body?
It's covered in moles,
which is sometimes called
the devil's teats, as you know.
Now, this maid swore to me honestly
that she had seen these quite plainly
on Anne's naked skin.
Even though the lady
constantly seeks to cover herself.
My God.
Is it so?
It is the truth.
That is why she must die.
[PLAYlNG]
What is it?
He's having more affairs.
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure.
Often I can't find him.
No one will tell me where he is.
He leaves the palace, I know that.
He's gone for hours sometimes.
[###]
I think he's got a harem somewhere.
There's a place
where he keeps his harem.
Where he keeps his women.
I know it.
Anne.
Ugh...
Something's going to happen to me.
No.
You know there's a prophecy.
Everyone knows it.
The prophecy says a queen
of England will be burned.
Don't talk like this.
Nothing's going to happen to you.
I'm unable to give a king a son.
A son.
To be the living image of his father.
Shh.
It's all right.
Everything's going to be all right.
Please don't cry.
I love you.
I'll look after you, I swear.
Please don't cry.
Sir Thomas.
WYATT: Mr. Secretary.
What are all these?
Denunciations.
It is reported that a canon
at Tewkesbury,
mistakenly or otherwise, offered
prayers to Catherine the Queen,
rather than Anne.
Seven of his congregation
reported these words.
What will you do to him?
Nothing.
He's near 80 years old.
Absent-minded slip of the tongue.
Such an old man.
It's perfectly forgivable.
Some of these others
are much more serious.
Have a look at these.
They're tracts praising
His Majesty
and his new monarchy
and the reformation.
They explain why the
reformation is necessary.
The liberties and
opportunities it will bring,
even to the king's
humblest subjects.
These are very impressive.
You are to be congratulated
on your industry, Mr. Secretary.
But does it never concern you
that the king has taken to himself
an absolute power,
without any constraint
to remake the law?
Is not that which pleases the king
the law?
I was--
I was only observing.
I like you, Mr. Wyatt.
I enjoy your company, but you have
a reputation. You gamble.
And you whore.
You sail close to the wind.
God forbid it should ever
blow you onto the rocks.
His Excellency
Philippe Chabot de Brion,
Admiral of France.
Your Grace.
Admiral Chabot. It is my privilege
and pleasure to welcome you
and your party
to my home and to England.
May I present my wife, the duchess.
Madame.
[lN FRENCH]
I am delighted to meet you.
[lN ENGLlSH]
And, with your permission,
may I present my secretary,
Monsieur Alfonse Gontier.
Madame.
Your Grace.
And my niece.
Mademoiselle Germaine.
Mademoiselle, you are very pretty.
Madame.
Your Grace.
So tell me, Your Grace,
what are we to expect?
I am to entertain you and your staff.
Then the king invites you to dine.
Very good.
There is one other thing.
I am told that Queen Anne has
planned a banquet in your honour.
And a tennis match.
I believe you met Her Majesty
once before, in Calais,
when she accompanied His Majesty
before her coronation?
I may have. But I have no recollection
of any such meeting.
And, alas, I don't play tennis.
Shall we?
MAN: Majesty.
Good morrow, John.
Majesty.
Where are you going?
Out.
Where?
Go back inside.
Where are you going?
I want to know.
It is none of your business. It is my
pleasure you go back inside now.
Majesty.
[###]
MAN 1 : Majesty.
MAN 2: Your Majesty.
WOMAN 1 :
Your Majesty.
WOMAN 2:
Majesty.
MAN 3: Your Majesty.
MAN 4: Your Majesty.
[GRUNTlNG]
Whore.
[CHATTERlNG]
Mademoiselle.
HENRY:
I like you, Excellency.
You're very clever.
But I don't like the way
your emperor treats me.
He seems to think, as far as Catherine
is concerned, that I act out of spite.
Or that I'm being malicious.
But I swear it's not true.
I suppose I ought to be content
that the world knows
the many wrongs
that have been done to me.
You don't approve of the changes
I'm making in this kingdom.
Cromwell intercepts some
of your letters.
We used to call it humanism,
Wolsey, More and me.
[###]
We were all humanists.
Most people think I've changed,
but I haven't.
At heart, I'm still a humanist.
Chapuys.
I promise you
that I am going to make
such a reformation in this kingdom
that I shall be remembered eternally,
throughout all Christendom.
I have no doubt whatsoever
that Your Majesty's reign
will always be remembered.
I had planned a banquet
in his honour.
MARK: Who?
The French admiral.
He has been here for two weeks
already with the Duke of Suffolk,
and he has not yet sent me
a message of goodwill.
Every other French envoy
has always done so.
Neither has he requested
an audience with me.
With me, the queen of England.
And when we are discussing
the future of my own child.
Your Majesty should rest.
I ought to leave you.
They tell me he has struck
up an acquaintance
with the imperial ambassador,
Chapuys.
Is that not extraordinary?
Tell me, why should he do
such a thing?
Why do you not say anything,
Mark?
Your Majesty must forgive me.
I don't know what to say.
These matters are beyond
my competence.
What am l?
I'm only a dancing master.
And then there's something else.
Someone, some bitch
who probably hates me,
told me the king
deliberately invited
a lot of beautiful women to court
for the admiral's visit.
I mean, can you believe that?
[TRUMPETS PLAYlNG FLOURlSH]
[CHATTERlNG]
Your Grace.
Your Majesty.
May I present His Excellency,
Philippe Chabot de Brion,
the Admiral of France.
Majesty.
Welcome to my court.
Allow me to introduce my wife,
Queen Anne.
Madame.
Please, let us be seated.
[MUSlC PLAYlNG]
[CHATTERlNG]
Some wine?
Of course.
Which, uh, domain
does it come from?
Is it Bordeaux?
This is English wine.
English wine?
We have been making wine
in England since the Romans.
As recently as that?
[CHUCKLES]
[SPEAKS lN FRENCH]
It's, uh, very fruity.
And strong like, uh,
a gladiator's sweat.
[LAUGHlNG]
Who is that gentleman?
CHABOT:
My secretary, Monsieur Gontier.
I should like to introduce him
to my wife.
Excuse me.
[MUSlC ENDS]
[HENRY SPEAKS lN FRENCH]
[MUSlC PLAYlNG]
Majesty.
Your Majesty must forgive me
for not being able to attend
the banquet you arranged.
It was most unfortunate,
but His Grace, the Duke of Suffolk,
and his charming wife
[SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
have kept me a virtual prisoner
in their castle.
I was-- How shall I say?
--imprisoned by affection.
[LAUGHlNG]
Madam? Are you amusing
yourself at my expense?
Forgive me, monsieur.
I couldn't help laughing
at the king's proposition
of introducing
your secretary to me.
For, whilst he was finding him,
he met that pretty lady
and forgot the whole thing.
Let's talk some business.
What instructions do you have
with regard to the betrothal
of my daughter Elizabeth
to the Duke of Angoulême?
His Majesty regrets that such
a proposition is impossible.
Why impossible?
Much as he loves Your Majesty,
the king cannot agree to betroth
his beloved son to a--
To a bride whose legitimacy
is not accepted
by His Holiness Pope Paul.
By Holy Church itself.
Nor even by the emperor.
However, His Majesty,
to demonstrate his love,
proposes another match.
He would consent to the betrothal
of the dauphin to Lady Mary,
your legitimate daughter.
[###]
If you do not agree to the match,
my master will marry his son
to the emperor's daughter,
Ieaving your country
isolated in Europe.
Excellence, your audience
with His Majesty is now over.
I'm sorry.
[###]
I have no excuses, Catherine.
I thought those days
were behind me.
Perhaps human nature
can never change.
I swear to you
it will never happen again.
I love you too much.
I have no right to ask you
to believe me.
But it's true.
You see?
You did make me cry after all.
Who was she?
Who was who?
That lady you were talking to
when you were supposed
to be finding Monsieur Gontier.
[SlGHS]
I don't know.
Is she one of your mistresses?
How many do you have?
What are their names?
Where do you keep them? Hmm?
Someone told me your nobles,
like Brandon,
are assisting you
in having your affairs.
That's enough.
No.
No, you told me.
You always told me that we should
be truthful with each other.
You said it was
the definition of love.
Then here's the truth.
You must shut your eyes
and endure.
Like your betters have done
before you.
How can you say that to me?
Don't you know I love you a thousand
times more than Catherine ever did?
And don't you know that I can drag
you down as quickly as I raised you?
'Tis lucky you have your bed
already, madam.
Because if you did not,
I would not give it to you again.
Francis won't accept the betrothal.
Why?
Why do you think?
Because the pope and he
and the emperor all agree
she is a bastard.
And you are not my wife.
[###]
HENRY:
Tell me, how's your Catherine?
She's fine.
In fact, she's with child.
Ah.
You're a happily married man,
Charles. I envy you.
Do you think the planets
have any influence over our lives?
I don't know.
I would often discuss the issue
with More.
We would stand on the roof
at night
and study the heavens.
More had a great knowledge
of the stars
and how they influence our...
humours.
[###]
I regret now
what happened to More.
In some ways,
I wish it never happened.
But it wasn't all my fault.
Whenever my resolve weakened,
whenever I was inclined
to save him,
a certain person would privately
urge me on to his destruction.
Who?
You know who she is, Charles.
[###]