Yes, sir. I understand completely, sir.
Things go that way sometimes.
Yes, sir, I will. You can count on me.
Kids, come on out. Time
for deployment gifts.
- Ashley: Coming!
- Sam: I'm coming, too!
Photos, videos, and playlists.
Not as good as a warm body in your bed,
but it'll just have to
do till I see you again.
Sam: Wait, Ashley. Let me get it!
[Sprinkler hissing]
Darien, I'm not going to the med.
Navy's sending us to the Arctic.
The Arctic? That's crazy.
Some cold weather test
on a new weapons system.
It's all classified.
It's happening very fast.
We're gonna be at complete radio silence.
No e-mails, no calls.
For how long?
Six months, maybe five.
- Figures.
- It's my last tour for a while.
Then I'll be around the house so much,
you'll be sick of me, I promise.
Sit down.
Did you wrap this yourself?
I did.
It's from the championship game.
Keep it next to your bed.
I love it, buddy. That's really great.
- Thank you.
- [Papers rustle]
[Sighs]
- It's beautiful.
- It's not regulation,
so I know you can't wear it.
How about I keep it in the front pocket
of my uniform right over my heart?
[Sighs]
Man over radio: I need help,
if anyone out there can hear me.
I'm just outside... [Speaks indistinctly]
[Switch clicks] Woman:
I need help, please.
If you can hear me...
[Switch clicks, man speaking Spanish]
[Switches clicking,
woman speaks indistinctly]
[Static, man speaking indistinctly]
[Door opens]
[Sighs]
I sent the guys on a break.
[Sighs] Figured I'd see what's going on
in the outside world.
It's a lot of static.
Yeah, whatever you might hear out there
is not gonna be particularly uplifting.
Well, my dad had an old ham radio
set in his cabin,
and I thought maybe if Darien was...
It's our anniversary.
You never come down here.
[Sighs] No.
Yeah, I don't think
Christine's looking for me.
Come on.
Well...
Before we left, things were
pretty ragged between us.
When I finally got her on the phone
after we lifted EMCOM,
she... told me about Lucas.
Losing a son is one thing,
but dealing with it on your own is just...
There was nothing you could do.
That is not what she wanted to hear.
I'll leave you to it.
There's still a chance, Mike.
For all of us.
[Door closes]
Jordan!
[Man shouts indistinctly]
- On the side! Shoot it! Shoot it!
- Hey!
I'm open! I'm open!
- Right here!
- That's what I want.
Come on, Miller. Thought you could hoop.
- Yeah, I can.
- You can, huh?
[Grunts]
[Indistinct shouting]
- [Water splashes]
- Oh, man. That was our last ball.
[Hip-hop music playing]
Nice, buddy.
So why Costa Rica?
Dr. Scott's gonna need some
primates to test her vaccine.
Apparently, there's a monkey reserve
a few miles upriver.
She doesn't have the vaccine, does she?
She's working on it.
Meanwhile, we move forward.
Hey.
You think there'll be a beach?
I could really use a beach right now.
What? What the hell is this?
Wasn't this on the list to be rebuilt?
Yes, sir.
The chief engineer put the hts on it,
but we're out of spare parts.
They're cobbling everything
together from scratch.
Well, she's laid up in medical bay,
and it's on me now if that gasket blows.
No one gets off watch till it's done.
[Chugging sound]
Does anybody hear that?
- Hear what, sir?
- She's not purring.
[Sighs]
This is the messdecks
for the enlisted in here,
although I think you'll
probably take your meals
with the officers in the wardroom.
Man, these are some cramped quarters.
I don't know how y'all do it.
Four months you've been on this ship now?
- Almost five.
- Five? Wow.
Ma'am.
Whoa. She is tasty.
Now is she not?
Oh, lighten up, dude. I'm just saying.
- It's the end of the world, right?
- Excuse me.
Nothing wrong with spreading
a little love around,
and I ain't Navy, so...
Yeah, well, they are,
which means no fraternizing, period.
Oh, I get it. I get it.
Hey, um... Where is the lab?
Maybe pay a visit to that scientist.
She's a civilian, right?
I can't believe I have to bunk with you.
Seriously, where's the lab?
[Machines beep steadily]
[Instrument clatters]
[Beep, whirs]
[Computer beeping]
[Exhales deeply]
I need to complete the sequence analysis
of the three known virus strains...
Primordial, Egyptian,
and the sample that I
extracted from the cruise ship.
You do what you gotta
do, but you do it alone.
I'm not letting him back in that lab.
Believe me, Quincy is the last person
that I wanna see right now, but I need him.
And we're right on the verge here.
That man tried to infect this entire ship.
You're not listening to me.
This is one procedure
that I cannot do alone.
What about Doc Rios?
I am sure that he is an
excellent ship's doctor,
but I need a highly trained
expert in bioinformatics
just for a few hours.
I promise that I won't
let him near anything
that could endanger the ship.
[Sighs]
What do you want?
I managed the sequencing.
All three strains.
Wasn't sure that I was
gonna be able to do it
with the equipment on
hand, but the data is in.
And you need me to analyze it.
Yes.
Look, Quincy, I am sorry
for you and for your family,
for... Kelly.
And Ava, of course.
And I know there's nothing that I can say,
but I also know that you understand
that the world needs us right now...
Please don't preach to me, Rachel.
I've had it up to here
with your high-mindedness.
- I'm not preaching.
-  The world needs you,
and that's just the way you like it.
Quincy, what are you talking about?
I know that you're in pain
here, but there's nothing...
I told you we should share our information,
that sneaking off to the Arctic
wasn't the way to do this,
but you loved the whole "top secret" thing.
That's not fair, because
we both agreed...
This was the only way we
knew what we were doing.
Quincy, where is this coming from?
This plague is the best thing
that's ever happened to you.
Rachel Scott saves the day.
- This is not my fault.
- No, it's mine...
For following you.
I mean, what were you risking, really?
You've got no family.
You've got no friends.
Truth is, you don't have
any skin in the game.
You have no idea what I have lost.
The guy who pops into town
for a twice-monthly screw
doesn't count.
[Scoffs] You don't know about loss
because you don't care
about anyone but yourself.
Where the hell do you
get off thinking your pain
is any greater than anyone else's?
There's a whole ship
full of people out there
who've lost just as much as you,
and yet they keep finding
a way to march on, but you...
You're a coward.
Nothing more.
Probably a great deal less.
[Huffs]
Diplomacy's not necessarily
your strong suit.
I can't even look at him.
Well, you said you can't do it without him,
so one way or another,
we're gonna have to
get him on board, right?
You do it. You talk to him.
I'm not that good with people anyw...
[Electricity crackles, power surging]
What on earth is that?
[Equipment beeping]
Bridge, this is M.P.A.
We've got high temperature
on number 1 and 2 generators.
Commencing stage one load-shed.
I just lost surface search radar.
[Electronic whir, power surges down]
[Door creaks]
Tell Captain Chandler
that we need A/C and power,
or everything will be lost, and hurry!
- Right away.
- [Under breath] Damn it.
No, that's not it. Trace the line.
We can't run at this temperature.
We're gonna overheat!
Pull the filters. Let's see
what's going on in there.
[Explosion] Whoa!
- Damn it!
- We got a fire!
- Okay! Okay, I'll call the bridge!
- [Alarm sounding]
[Bell clanging] Fire, fire, fire.
Class Bravo fire, main engine room two.
Away the at-sea fire party,
provide from repair five.
D.C.A., it's the captain.
What's the status?
I say again, D.C.A., what is the status?
[Coughing]
[Alarm sounding]
Mr. Chung! Everybody okay?
- Yes, sir. The fire's out.
- What's our sitrep?
It started in the seawater
service system intake, sir.
Something must have torn off the filters,
and sea life bloom got in...
That's on me. We cut it a little
tight getting out of Gitmo.
Corals must have knocked off
the filters. How bad is it?
It's too soon to tell, sir,
but with the intakes down,
we've lost our ability to cool
the engine oil for the mains.
What about the generators?
Did they survive?
Just generator three, sir,
and we're lucky it was
offline during the time.
I want all the electricity
diverted to the C.I.C.
And Dr. Scott's lab.
Under any circumstance,
she needs that room cooled.
- Do you understand?
- Aye, sir. Sorry, sir.
Don't be sorry.
Let's just get it fixed. Yes, sir.
[Clank, power surges on]
[Sighs] Thank you. Thank you.
- Captain's on the bridge.
- Report, sir.
R.O. system's down for now.
Let's initiate conservation.
Salt water shaving only, no showers.
Water strictly used for
cooking and drinking.
[Sighs] It's gonna be 100 degrees today.
I'd like to reduce Manning
at all watch stations
and suspend all non-essential activities.
Good. Meanwhile, I've got
other fish for you to fry.
[Tears paper]
Good. I didn't wake ya. [Sniffs]
[Sighs]
A hot one, huh?
Reminds me of August in Chicago.
That's where I'm from. You know that?
Yeah, I was a cop. Homicide.
South side. I was good at it, too.
[Mouth full] You mind if I smoke?
Please don't.
Mm. Mmh-mmh.
[Lighter clicks]
[Exhales]
[Exhales deeply] You
ever hear of Keelhauling?
Can't say that I have, no.
Really?
See, back in the mid
1800s when a sea Captain
encountered a particularly
problematic sailor,
he'd have him bound with rope,
thrown over the side of the ship,
dragged underneath the hull.
Poor bastard would bounce
and scrape along the keel,
barnacles and such.
But when he'd come up on the other side,
if he wasn't drowned or decapitated...
He tended to be a lot more cooperative.
Keelhauling. [Sniffs]
Just off the top of my
head, I can think of about
200 sailors on board this ship
who'd like to try that out on you.
Captain Chandler would
never allow such a thing.
Hmm, maybe.
Maybe not.
Personally, I never found
torture that effective
in my line of work. I told
you I was a cop, right?
- You did, yes.
- Yeah.
See, I always found that
if you just laid out the facts for a guy,
treated him with a little respect,
maybe give him a chance to redeem himself,
earn somethin' back...
He'd make the right choice.
You can't force me back into the lab.
I won't do it.
Well, suit yourself. [Exhales]
But remember, we got a hard
and fast rule on this ship.
[Sighs] Anything that
doesn't serve a purpose is gone.
Ain't no fat on the bone here.
[Sniffs] Hope you can hold your breath.
I want sunlight.
And someone to play chess with.
Someone good.
Did you reset the
electronic governor controls?
Cycled them three times.
They're completely wiped.
[Sighs] Did you try to
rig casualty power cables
from main one?
There's no way to do it. The
main cable riser's melted.
Mr. Chung, you qualified E.O.O.W. faster
than anyone I've ever seen,
and you could rebuild
most of this power plant
with your eyes closed.
You're going to handle this.
[Sighs]
[Door creaks open]
[Door closes]
I'm guessing the gene sequencing
showed a high degree of variation.
You're having trouble distinguishing
what's causing the enhanced pathogenesis
and what's just background noise.
Right you are... As usual.
Let's get to it, shall we?
It's gonna take a week,
maybe 10 days at all stop
- to repair the engine damage, sir.
- A week?
We can run one of the
four turbines on manual,
but... the seawater system's fried,
so we... we can't cool the engines.
And how long can we
run without overheating?
Maybe an hour, but then another five
to let it cool down,
but I'll have to wash down the engines
before we can even try that.
So what's the issue? Something
with the R.O. systems?
The circuit breakers in the load centers...
They're completely burnt out.
We can't make fresh drinking water.
And how long to fix that?
Also a week, sir. And
that's the real problem.
The entire time we were in Gitmo,
we weren't filtering water from the harbor
because we didn't know if it
was contaminated by the virus.
[Sighs] So we're down to...
What, 3,000 gallons of fresh water?
- Just about, sir.
- [Sighs]
- Slattery: Costa Rica will have to wait.
- Agreed.
We'll have to dead-stick until
we get that one engine on line.
We got an hour every six to
make as much distance as we can
to find the safest place to
make port and get fresh water.
I'm recommending we head
here... Serrana Bank.
It's uninhabited, which means
it should be untouched by the virus,
and it gets over a hundred
inches of rain per year.
We can anchor there
until the engineers get us back on line.
E.T.A.? Given our current
limitations with engine output?
Taking into account
projected winds and current...
Six, six and a half days.
They've gotta be someplace else.
The area has been
pretty well-charted, sir.
Maybe we can find an abandoned ship
with a fresh water supply.
All right, send the U.A.V.
Widest possible range in all directions.
It finds any source of water,
I wanna know about it.
Aye, sir.
Set course for that island.
Let's get that engine back on line.
Yes, Captain.
[Door closes]
Six days. Even at our most severe rations,
we're gonna have to travel
the last two without any water.
Day three...
Day three, people start to die.
Surface search radar off standby.
Gain set to low.
No sign of land, sir.
U.A.V.'s got nothing either. Keep looking.
Careful. Don't spill that.
[Indistinct conversations]
All that water in the
ocean... It's almost impossible
to make it drinkable. Hence, the stills.
Oh, yeah. I am dying over here.
- [Can tab fizzes]
- Ah. You heard of water into wine?
This is beer into water.
That is enough to make a grown man cry.
Tell me about it.
Sir, 10 seconds until engines up.
Light off engine in 5...4...3...2...1.
[Clank, whirring]
Starboard engine ahead full.
Aye, sir. Starboard engine ahead full.
Starboard engine ahead full, aye.
[Whirring, power surging]
[Clank, whirring]
We've got one hour till engine shutdown.
Let's make some time.
[Speaks indistinctly]
Man: Sector 3 is negative.
No vessels, no land.
Man: U.A.V to sector 4.
[Alarm sounding] Mr. Chung...
I know, I know, she's too
hot. We're pushing this.
Engine shutdown in 5, 4, 3, 2...
[Switch clicks]
[Sighs] Chung, how are we looking?
We got any wiggle room?
The engine is piping hot, sir.
We cannot push it any further.
[Alarm sounding]
E-stop one Alpha G.T.M. Let's shut it down
and let it cool off.
E-stop one Alpha G.T.M.
It's dark. Why hasn't it gotten any cooler?
It's hotter inside.
Hell, I'll sleep outside
standing up if I had to.
[Squeaking]
[Machine beeping]
Finished.
I suppose you'll want to
triple-check the results.
[Taps keyboard keys]
[Computer beeping] You were right.
This could be the one that works.
When you look up at the night sky,
just know that wherever I am,
I'm looking at the same stars.
And I'll be thinking about you and you.
So no matter what,
we'll always be together.
Okay?
[Sprinkler hissing]
What's this?
Well, you said you wanted
a rain check on the tea.
Sorry, I'm not equipped with
finger sandwiches or scones.
I'd have thought you
would've used your water
on a colder drink.
This can't be tea.
It's Camellia sinensis.
It's an organic green.
I actually save it for special occasions.
Such as?
The breakthrough that
I've been working towards.
It's happened.
I have a vaccine prototype,
and it's time to test.
I would've brought champagne, but...
This will do just fine.
60 seconds until we need to power down
the engine again, Captain.
T.A.O., bridge. What's
the status on the U.A.V.?
Barker: Sorry, sir. No sign
of land or other vessels at sea
- in 360-degree search.
- [Machine beeps]
10 seconds, sir. Current
destination is best option for water.
We got a problem in the lab.
Lynn: That's all we have?
Chung: Four breakers...
That was the last one.
Oh, no.
Tell me the virus is secure.
Yes, everything is sealed. What's happened?
Ma'am, the relay switch overheated
and shorted out the breakers
on the last generator.
Well, is it beyond repair?
Afraid so.
You understand that without power,
the temperature inside my
cooling units are rising.
If they go over 41 degrees fahrenheit,
we'll lose the primordial sample,
the sample from the cruise ship,
and the experimental vaccine.
What about the portable
generator in the r&a locker?
That seized up during
maintenance in the Arctic.
Every time we run the engines,
you get power to the lab.
I made sure... Power for one hour
for every six is not sufficient.
I need the virus at a
constant low temperature.
We can throw it overboard.
Throw what overboard?
All your work, into the
water, to cool it down.
We're in the tropics. The
water must be 80 degrees.
- Not at the bottom.
- Well, even if the water is cold enough,
the pressure will crush
the glass containers.
Well, I'm sure we can
rig something for that.
- Can't we, lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
Look, I appreciate that,
but if you sink the samples,
there's no way that you
can move the ship forward
without raising that
case towards the surface.
She's right. We'll be stuck in place
until we get the engines repaired,
and we're already running
out of drinking water.
If we can figure out a
way to spin the propellers,
we can generate enough electricity
to cool the lab, correct?
Yes, sir, but how can
we spin the propellers
- without the engine?
- Rig the case now.
Get your samples ready
to put 'em in the ocean.
- Please be certain they're secure.
- It's good to go.
Easy!
Due respect, Captain, we only
have a small window of time
to make it to the island
on the water we have.
The hours we spend doing this
we will not be able to make up.
Gator checked the barometer.
Said there's a low front
coming in from the east.
We get the winds we need, we can do this.
Relying on the winds?
Our entire mission is in that case.
I have to say this, sir.
If the winds don't blow
our way, we kill our crew.
Rachel: No, you're sure it's gonna hold?
Chung: It's gonna hold.
10 feet from the surface.
Almost there.
Okay, it's in.
[Indistinct conversations]
Shouldn't the temperature
be dropping faster?
It takes a moment for the
thermostat to catch up.
[Under breath] Come on, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Man: 300 feet.
[Normal voice] Come on.
[Breathing heavily]
Come on, come on, come on.
[Beeping]
We've hit bottom.
Man: All right, tie off the line.
[Beeping resumes]
Chung: 42...
41...
Come on, come on.
40. We did it.
[Sighs]
Thank God.
[Exhales deeply]
[Exhaling deeply] Dear God.
Well, you got your sunshine.
Never seen a day as windless.
I'm a gambling man myself.
Captain's put all his chips in
the middle of the table here.
Sure hope he's got an ace up his sleeve.
Sir, the boatswain's mates
have loaded pilot chutes into launchers.
Strong enough breeze, and we'll shoot them
high enough to engage the larger chutes.
That should give us just enough speed
to turn the prop and get electricity.
- Won't help us make water, but...
- So where's the wind?
Gator said the wind was coming.
It's gotta come, right?
I'm guessing the Navy told
you about my car accident.
Yeah. Yeah. They did.
Well, there's something
they don't even know about.
It was my fault.
Tried to pass a car on a curve.
Didn't see the oncoming truck.
I killed my wife and my girls.
I was in the I.C.U. for 82 days.
Seven times I coded, seven
times they brought me back.
In between, I had plenty of
time to think and to wonder,
why did God leave me here?
Why did he spare me?
There must be a purpose, some reason.
Well, that's what I told myself.
That's how I woke up every day
and put one foot in front of the other.
It was faith that got me through.
But these past weeks,
that faith has been
replaced with certainty.
I am here for a reason, as are you,
as is everyone aboard this ship.
You are here to lead us,
and we are here to follow,
to execute your vision.
I don't have a vision.
You do.
When you stuck your
hand in that engine fuse,
and you turned us away from home,
when you got us out of gitmo,
there's a... A voice inside you.
Maybe it's your highest self,
maybe it's the voice of God.
I don't know, but...
It's a voice of... hope.
You've listened to it so far.
All you have to do is keep listening.
Our journey does not end here.
"And Moses answered the
people, 'do not be afraid.
"'Stand firm, and you
will see the deliverance
"'the lord will bring you today.
"'The lord will fight for you.
You need only be still.'"
trust that there's
something else out there,
something bigger than
ourselves, something better,
'cause right now we feel very, very small.
We're not too proud to say we need help,
and we need it right now.
So we bow our heads together,
and we lift this prayer to you
and ask that you
protect us so that we may do
good in the world that you made.
[Thud, water streaming]
Amen.
Officers: Amen.
[Flag flapping]
Boats! Prepare to launch the chutes!
Port side, on my mark!
3...2...1. Fire!
[Shots]
- Second gun! Fire!
- [Shot]
Third gun!
- Fire!
- [Shot]
Holy shit.
Hell, yeah. [Chuckles]
[Whirring]
Set modified condition
three. Bring up that case!
- Man: Aye, sir.
- [Exhales]
Okay.
- Gently does it.
- [Metal clanks]
Easy.
Central, this is M.P.A.
Close load circuits on
the impeller alternators.
Let's do this thing.
[Clanks, power surging]
[Clanks]
Bravo Zulu, Mr. Chung.
This is U.S.S. Nathan James,
hailing any vessel in our vicinity.
We are operating without radar.
We believe we are approximately
a hundred miles east,
northeast of serrana bank.
We've been over two days without water.
Hailing any vessel...
[Radio static]
In the vicinity of serrana bank.
We are in distress and require assistance.
Sail still holding, sir.
Winds from the north,
northeast at 14 knots.
Making 4 knots over water, sir.
How long till engines up?
[Gruffly] Four hours.
[Telephone beeps]
[Receiver clatters]
Go for X.O.
X.O., I've got 10 more down.
I think it's time to stand down
all non-essential watch stations.
Copy that. Proceed.
[Receiver clatters]
[Slattery clears throat]
I'm sorry.
I thought we'd make up more time.
All right, my friends, you're
gonna be just fine, okay?
You're all right. Head up.
Just sip. There you go. Keep still.
[Breathing heavily]
Keep still.
Rachel: Okay, uh, take small sips. Careful.
That's good.
Can I join you all?
Are you kiddin' me? Bring it here,
right beside ol' Tex.
[Hushed indistinct conversation]
Man: How you feeling? Are you all right?
We're not gonna make it, are we?
[Ship creaking]
[Men coughing]
[Exhales deeply]
[Coughs]
[Seagulls crying] Captain?
Incoming low slow flying objects
20 degrees relative.
Identify as seagulls.
Birds mean land.
Radar's still down, sir, but...
That sounds pretty good to me.
Water.
We made it.
We made it, sir.
[Man shouts indistinctly]
[Cheering]
I believe there are a few of
you who have earned some R&R.
[Switch clicks] See?
Piece of cake.
Never doubted it, sir.
[Chuckles]
[Indistinct conversations]
Guess we got a beach after all.
- We sure did.
- [Laughs]
[Indistinct conversations continue]
[Laughter] Man: Fire it up.
I don't see a cup of water in your hand.
Take this one, too. Take this one, too.
[Laughs] Okay.
Man: Yo! All right.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Guitar playing]
- Chandler: Mr. Chung!
- [Clank]
Figured you could use this.
Fresh from the island.
Thank you, sir.
I, uh, got the auxiliary power up.
At least we can keep
the doctor's work on ice
while I make the repairs.
You did well, lieutenant.
Ah, I don't know, sir.
I keep thinking maybe I
could have prevented that fire
if I'd checked the filters better.
Maybe, but it was your idea and ingenuity
that saved the virus.
Let's just say I'm looking forward
to the chief engineer
getting back on her feet.
Well, you're finding your way.
We all are.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Let's see what you got.
Are you watching?
I'm watching it, all right. I'm watching.
- The hands.
- Hands. All hands. I'm all hands.
I'm all hands!
Hey there, Mary poppins.
You wanna get in on this?
Um, maybe another time.
- I'm an excellent teacher.
- I have no doubt.
So you gotta move those hips for the Hula.
I bet you could.
- Where you going?
- Over this way.
- Need an escort?
- Uh...
Maybe I'll take a rain check on that.
- All right.
Dude, rain check!
Lock and load, ladies. It's Hula time.
♪♪
[Laughter, indistinct conversations]
Oh!
Little bit of coconut milk,
and a little bit of somethin'-somethin'.
- Somethin'-somethin'.
- Well, it's water.
- [Chuckles]
- But it's better than rum today, right?
Yep.
- Cheers.
[Indistinct conversations
and laughter continue]
[Guitar strumming]
♪ I was born by the river ♪
♪ In a little tent ♪
♪ Oh, and just like that river ♪
♪ I've been running ever since ♪
♪ It's been a long ♪
♪ A long time coming ♪
♪ But I know ♪
♪ A change gon' come ♪
♪ Oh, yes, it will ♪
♪ It's been too hard living ♪
[Wheels rattling]
Let me guess. I'm not going to the island.
Let me guess. You're the asshole
I'm supposed to play chess with.
[Chair rattles]
Alisha: ♪ It's been a long ♪
♪ Such a long time coming ♪
♪ But I know ♪
♪ Change gon' come ♪
You have a name?
People call me "Bacon."
Why is that?
You got a nose, don't you?
I work in the galley.
[Sniffs] So that's what that is.
Let's just play.
It's been six months since
I've touched dry land,
and I ain't interested in becoming friends.
Okay.
♪ It's been a long ♪
♪ A long time coming ♪
♪ But I know ♪
♪ Change gon' come ♪
♪ Oh, yes, it will ♪
[Guitar strumming]
♪ Then I go to my brother ♪
♪ And I say, brother ♪
♪ Help me, please ♪
Man over radio: Radio
transmission out there, anyone?
♪ But he winds up ♪
♪ Knocking me ♪
[Switches clicking, man
speaking indistinctly]
♪ Right back on my knees ♪
[Woman speaking indistinctly]
Not in the mood for celebrating?
Just tying up some loose ends.
Thank you.
For what?
For believing in me.
I didn't have much choice.
I think you've had quite a few choices.
From the very beginning
you could have docked
at Norfolk and come
back for your family.
We'll get there.
♪
Sync & Corrected by Darcade
- Addic7ed.com -