I think we will lose this battle,
and a great many men will die.
My God, Bolkonsky, what a shambles!
[SHE SQUEALS]
How do you really feel about Sonya?
I do love her, Tasha.
[SHOUTS OF PAIN]
I haven't been a very
affectionate husband...
but it's no use saying that now.
[BABY CRIES]
Here he is!
Your wife is even more beautiful
than I remember, Bezukhov.
To the health of beautiful women,
Petrushka -
and their lovers.
I challenge you!
Count Bezukhov?
If I might...
Look here, you don't want to be
fighting a duel with this fellow.
Apologise,
say you lost your temper.
No-one will think any
the worse of you.
No.
No, we're here now. Just show
me where I have to go.
- Captain Dolokhov?
- Let's get on with it, shall we?
If you could just remind me
how, um...
You point it, and...?
Oh, Lord.
Hold out your arm straight in front
of you, as steady as you can.
And squeeze the trigger,
don't pull it.
Turn sideways on - show him
your shoulder, not your chest.
Don't give him an easy target.
Thank you, I'd forgotten.
It's very kind of you.
- There's still time to call it off.
- No.
No, I know it's stupid, but
I think I must go through with it.
[GUN CLICKS]
Good luck, then.
As the adversaries have refused
a reconciliation, we shall proceed.
At the count of three, you may
advance towards each other.
You may not go further than
the swords marking the barrier.
After the count of three,
you may fire at any time.
One.
Two.
Three.
[GUNSHOT]
- Fedya!
- Get back!
Dolokhov!
No! Get back behind the barrier,
damn you!
It's not over yet.
Turn! Cover yourself!
[GUNSHOT]
Missed!
Stupid, stupid, stupid!
Death, lies!
How bad is it?
If she sees me dying,
it'll kill her.
Who?
My mother. My angel.
She and my poor sister,
they're the only good things
in my life, Rostov.
[HE GRUNTS]
The only ones I care for.
I have to live, for them.
You understand?
Yes, I understand.
Move, man!
Anatol, stop it.
You're not getting anything.
Ah.
Pierre.
Well... I'll just...
What have you done now?
What have I done?
You've made an
exhibition of yourself,
and of me.
Someone told you that Dolokhov
was my lover, and you believed them.
Now you've made us
the talk of all Moscow.
Are you asking me to believe
that you're innocent?
Of course I am innocent!
Though no-one would blame me
if I had taken a lover.
It's not much fun being married to
a drunken oaf like you, you know.
Most people think you're
half out of your wits.
- Don't speak to me like that!
- Why shouldn't I speak?
I am the injured party here,
after all, not you.
How am I to go into society
after all this?
I never interfered
with your pleasures.
It's better that we part.
What did you say?
I said it's better that we part!
I'm leaving for Petersburg tomorrow.
All right.
If that's what you really want.
You'll only expose yourself
to more ridicule.
You know you'll have to give me
a fortune, don't you?
I'll kill you!
[HE HOWLS]
Out! Get out!
[HE BREATHES HEAVILY]
[DOOR OPENS]
A thousand apologies,
Your Excellency,
there will be a little wait
for fresh horses.
It's nice and warm in the parlour,
if you don't mind sharing it
with another gentleman.
No, no - I don't suppose
I have any choice, do I?
Good evening.
Evening.
[HE SIGHS]
What?
I believe I have the pleasure
of speaking with Count Bezukhov?
I have heard about the misfortune
that has befallen you, sir,
and I am very sorry for it.
I should like to help you, if I can.
But if for any reason
you find conversation with me
unpleasant, please say so.
No.
No, I'm glad
to make your acquaintance.
Then let me offer you
a brotherly handshake.
You're a Mason?
Yes,
I belong to the brotherhood
of Freemasons.
I'm afraid my way of thinking
is very different from yours.
I don't believe in God.
Of course you don't.
You don't believe in God
because you don't know him.
And that's why you're so unhappy.
I am unhappy.
I should think anyone could see that,
but what am I to do about it?
How can I know God,
if all my powers of reasoning
tell me he cannot exist?
God is not apprehended by reason,
my son,
but by life.
I don't understand you, sir.
Well...
..you are young, you are rich,
you are educated.
What have you done with
all these good things
that have been given you?
Very little, so far.
You need to purify yourself,
listen to your conscience.
Look at yourself.
Ask yourself,
are you content with yourself?
With your life?
No, I hate my life.
I hate myself.
Good.
You have taken the first step.
[RECITES BAPTISM CEREMONY]
[BABY CRIES]
Your wound still troubles you?
Yes, a little.
- You still keep up a good pace, Father.
- Why would I not?
I never vary!
Work, exercise, a good night's
sleep - that's all a man needs.
What next for you?
Back to the army?
No.
I've had enough for now
of dreams of glory.
And Napoleon's wars seem like
nothing to do with us.
- I'd like to make myself useful here.
- Good! Glad to hear it.
Plenty here to keep you occupied.
Build yourself a house
on the Bogucharovo estate.
A man needs his own place.
What do you say to that?
- I think it's an excellent idea.
- Good!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
I've drawn up a list of economies
I strongly recommend
to Your Excellency.
Yes, yes, but one doesn't care
to penny-pinch.
One has to entertain
the odd guest now and then.
- The position is really quite serious.
- All right, all right,
austerity shall be our watchword
from now on, thank you.
Thank you for your
meticulous accounting.
- I'll be good, I promise.
- Your Excellency.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
Well, what is it, my dear boy,
as if I couldn't guess?
I'm sorry to have to ask, Father,
but I do find myself a little short.
I've been helping Dolokhov
with his medical expenses, you see.
- Ah, yes, how is the poor fellow?
- Oh, he's very much better.
But he and his mother and sister,
they live in such a poor way, they can
- barely afford to heat their rooms.
- And you've been helping them.
You're a generous-hearted boy.
Now, I can't spare you very much
just at the moment.
Bakshin was very strict with me
just now.
Will 2,000 roubles
be sufficient for your needs?
That will be ample, Father -
you're very good.
See if you can make it last
till Spring.
I give you my word that it will.
And, Father, I should like to
invite Dolokhov
to come and stay here for
a little while. May I do that?
My dear boy, any friend
of yours is welcome here!
Thank you.
[HE SIGHS]
To the health and happiness of all,
and the splendid recovery
of our young friend here!
I can't thank you enough,
Count Rostov,
and you, Countess,
for your kindness to me.
Nonsense - it's our pleasure.
You're one of the heroes
of Austerlitz.
Nothing to be proud of, sir -
I'm just a man who loves to fight.
It's all I know, to my shame.
Don't disparage yourself, Fedya -
none of us will believe it anyway.
Then I'd better say nothing
about myself at all.
How is your mazurka coming along,
Natasha?
Well, we thought we were
doing very well, until
until Denisov told us
we were doing it all wrong.
[LAUGHTER]
- You did.
- What do you know about it, Denisov?
Oh, I was dancing
the mazurka in Poland
when you were still in
petticoats, my boy!
Really?
The way they used to teach us
in Poland...
Have you always lived with
the family, Sonya?
Yes, since I was a little girl.
Nikolai speaks so warmly of you,
and now I can see why.
I should like to know you better,
Sonya.
DENISOV: ..It was the footman!
Dolokhov watches you all the time.
Doesn't it make you
feel uncomfortable?
Yes.
But there's no harm in it.
He can look all he likes.
It won't change anything.
You're so sure of yourself.
Mama says that girls
are like mayflies.
That they have their day in the sun,
and then it's over.
It's more than a day.
But how long? A year or two?
To choose or be chosen. And then,
and then, that's our lives settled...
for ever.
It's frightening.
You just have to choose right,
that's all.
But how will I know?
You will.
But will I?
I'm sorry, Nikki,
I just don't like him.
Why on Earth not?
Everyone else does.
- There's something cruel about him.
- Now you're just being ridiculous.
- No, I'm not!
- He's the kindest, gentlest...
If you could see him at home
with his mother and sister...
Well, I don't know about that.
All I know is what I feel.
And I'm sure Pierre was in the right
when he challenged him.
Oh, Pierre! He's an idiot.
No, he's not.
I'd trust him with my life.
Whereas, that one...
..can't you see
he's trying to take Sonya from you?
He's just being nice to her.
He likes you, too.
No, he doesn't.
And I'm not sure
he likes you, either - not really.
[HE SNORTS]
[SWORDS CLASH]
You sure you're up to this, Fedya?
Come again.
Whoa!
You'll have to show me
how to do that one!
Trade secret, my boy.
[WATER SPLASHING]
Your cousin is a lovely girl,
Rostov.
And your sister, of course.
I thought you were the man
that despised all women,
- except his own mother and sister.
- I changed my mind, very recently.
Innocence and purity
are very rare.
You've known these girls
all your life,
you take their qualities
for granted.
I suppose you're right.
I've never really thought about it.
You see and feel very deeply,
don't you, Dolokhov?
Some things.
A-ha!
- A mazurka!
- A-ha!
I knew we had one somewhere!
Come on, Denisov.
We've heard you boasting,
now you can show us what you can do!
- No, no, no.
- Yes!
Make him, Father!
No excuse, Denisov,
you might as well submit.
- Yes, best idea all night.
- Oh, no!
[SHE LAUGHS]
[MUSIC STARTS]
[SHE SQUEALS]
[APPLAUSE]
Denisov, you're a wonderful
dancer! I had no idea.
For you - all for you.
Oh, thank you.
Now this, you absolutely deserve!
- Yes!
- Thank you.
Shall we sit down?
[PIANO PLAYS]
[HE SINGS IN RUSSIAN]
Countess.
Natasha.
If I don't speak now,
I'm afraid I never will.
I adore you.
I have never felt this way
about any woman or girl.
I think about you all day
and dream of you at night.
- Oh, dear.
- I know I have no hope,
but I must ask you.
Will you make me
the happiest man on earth
and consent to be my wife?
Oh... er...
I wish you hadn't said that.
I beg your pardon.
- I couldn't help it.
- Dear Denisov.
I'm so fond of you...
I can't say it.
Please.
Forget about it.
A moment of madness.
All over now.
Now, if you will excuse me...
[CONTINUES SINGING]
[DOOR OPENS]
Now you must be blindfolded.
Why is that?
If you wish to join our brotherhood,
you must be willing to submit
to our rituals without question.
Are you willing?
Yes.
I will leave you now.
When you hear knocking,
you may remove the blindfold.
[RECEDING FOOTSTEPS]
[LOUD BANGING]
Why have you come here?
For wisdom?
For virtue?
For enlightenment?
For renewal.
I want renewal.
MEN: Sic transit gloria mundi!
Always aid your brother man.
Raise up the fallen.
Forgive your enemy.
Take no revenge upon him,
unless it be but to do him good.
Go out into the world now.
Live not for yourself,
but for others.
You must be so happy that he has
decided to turn his back on society.
Well, I won't say a word against
my husband, Anna Pavlovna,
but truly it has been a bit
of a trial the last few months.
I'm very glad to be back
in Petersburg.
And the Emperor himself has taken
an interest in your affairs, I hear.
Yes, he's been kind.
More than kind, really.
Vraiment?
All the old crowd here, I see.
Bilibin!
Enchanting as ever, Comtesse.
Well, I should hope so. But tell me,
who is that young man over there?
Ah. Boris Drubestkoy.
A very promising young man.
Since Austerlitz, he's been
attached to the Prussian staff.
Our oldest allies.
They've only betrayed us four times
in the last three years,
but now they're supposed to be
the solution to the eternal...
Stop talking politics to me,
Bilibin, I can't bear it.
Just introduce me
to your little friend
and make yourself scarce, hmm?
Drubetskoy?
Over here.
Countess Bezukhova,
may I present Boris Drubetskoy,
one of our most promising
young diplomats?
Enchante.
And you're with the Prussian
High Command?
How exciting, to be so close
to all the decision-makers.
Do tell me about it.
Are you interested in politics,
Countess Bezukhova?
I adore politics.
It's all so fascinating!
Ah, Dolokhov, you'll never guess
who I just ran into!
Dolokhov?
What's the matter?
What's going on?
Did he tell you?
No, he told me nothing.
What's this all about?
There's been a bit of a scene.
He's proposed to Sonya
and she refused him.
She told him she was in love
with someone else.
You, of course,
though she didn't say so.
- He actually proposed to her?
- Yes! Couldn't you see it coming?
Sometimes I don't think
you see anything.
Mamma's not pleased.
She told Sonya that Dolokhov's
a very good match
for a girl with no prospects.
But I'm glad she refused him.
- Aren't you?
- Yes, yes, of course I am.
But I should talk to her about it.
Yes, I'll get her to come down.
So, he really proposed to you?
Yes.
I didn't want him to.
You know, as Mamma said,
it would be a good match for you.
He's such a good fellow
and a dear friend.
I'd hate for you to feel as though
you'd missed an opportunity.
Well, I've already refused him.
And nothing could make me
change my mind.
He's been very kind to me,
but I could never love him,
- and I told him so.
- Sonya, if you've refused him for my sake,
- No, don't say that to me!
- then I'm afraid...
No, but I must tell you
the whole truth. Look.
I love you,
I think, more than anyone
I've ever known.
Well, that's enough for me.
Yes, but I've fallen in love before
and I expect that I will again.
I can't help it, it's the way I am.
And then when Mamma
refuses to give her consent,
you see, I'm not in a position
to promise you anything.
- I don't ask you to, I never have.
- Yes, but I think you should consider
Dolokhov's proposal.
I'd rather not marry at all
than marry him.
I love you and I always will.
But I don't ask anything of you.
I don't expect anything more.
I don't deserve you.
You're an angel.
[HE SIGHS]
Good day, good day, I've come
to see how you're all getting along.
These cottages
look very bad, Grigori.
They need new roofs,
at the very least.
Yes, indeed, your Excellency.
See you make a note of that.
And here would be a good place
for a school.
A school, your Excellency?
Yes, indeed. Every boy
should have the chance
to learn to read and write.
And the girls, too.
But where will the teacher
come from, your Excellency?
Oh, there are teachers
everywhere. Just
build the school
and the teachers will come!
Now! Grain stores.
Hello.
Grain stores.
[CLOCK BELLS RING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
Oh, it's you.
I'm so sorry, but
did I mistake the day?
Or the time?
No, I don't think so.
It's just... where is everybody?
Don't you think
there are enough of us?
Well, yes, of course.
What did you think
all this was about?
Well...
Are you hungry?
Um...
not particularly.
Come on, then.
All right, gentlemen, who's in?
Ah, Rostov! The very man!
Thank you for inviting me, Dolokhov.
You've been a stranger lately.
I've been busy.
But you're still my... I mean,
everything's all right between us?
Why wouldn't it be?
Why don't you join us at the table?
Or are you afraid
of playing with me?
[HE LAUGHS NERVOUSLY]
I haven't any money with me.
That's all right, I trust you.
Play or not,
it's all the same to me.
But I tell you,
if you play with me, you'll lose.
ALL: Ooh!
Well, you don't know that.
You know what they say about me?
Dolokhov makes his own luck.
I'll play.
Good man!
Make some room for him.
Stake your bets, gentlemen.
Five roubles on the five.
Three of hearts the soda.
Ten wins.
And five loses.
All right, Rostov,
I'm keeping tally.
Stake your bets, gentlemen.
Ten on the ace.
Any more?
All right.
Seven...
King...
..and ace loses.
Bad luck, Rostov.
Maybe it's not your night.
Stake your bets, gentlemen.
20 on the seven.
[AUDIENCE GROANS]
That's how it goes sometimes.
Perhaps you'd like to quit, Rostov?
40 on the King.
Place your bets.
- 1,000 on the ace.
- Any more?
Jack of diamonds.
Three of spades.
Ace of diamonds.
So, how much do I owe you now?
[CHICKENS SQUAWK]
[PIGS GRUNT]
[NATASHA SINGS]
[NIKOLAI HUMS ALONG]
[HE SINGS]
[BOTH SING]
[SONYA CLAPS]
You have a lovely voice, Nikki -
we should sing together more often!
I have to go and speak to Father.
[KNOCK AT DOOR]
Ah, the night bird!
Home at last!
Well, did you have a good time?
Not especially.
Father, I'm afraid I'm going to
need some more money.
Already?
I had a feeling
it wouldn't last you,
but I didn't think
it would be so soon!
Well, you're only young once.
How much do you need, my boy?
Well, it's rather a lot.
Um, I lost a bit at cards,
you see and...
That is, a good deal,
a very great deal actually.
- How much?
- 43,000.
What?
To whom?
43,000?! Are you joking?
And I promised to pay tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
I suppose it happens
to everyone, at some point.
Yes.
Yes, I suppose
these things do happen.
It's a little difficult.
We shall have to close up the
Moscow house and go to Otradnoe.
Well...
Well, it can't be helped.
Can't be helped.
Oh, Papa! Please forgive me -
I'm so sorry!
Forgive me,
I'm sorry... I didn't mean..
There, there.
Well, here we are.
We didn't exactly enhance
our reputations on leave, did we?
I certainly didn't.
When the leave's too long,
the soldier goes wrong.
At least we know what
we have to do now - kill Frenchmen.
We can do that.
By the order
of the Emperor Alexander,
and by the grace of God,
it is announced that a peace treaty
has been ratified
with the Emperor of France,
who will now be our gallant ally.
[HUBBUB]
The Emperor Napoleon has been
awarded the Order of St Andrew,
as a mark
of our nations' amity and accord.
Thank you.
Oh, excellent.
What was that all about?
The usual thing.
We've changed sides.
Our enemies are our friends now.
- So we're friends with the French?
- I know, I know.
It's a mad world.
No use trying to understand.
[HE GRUNTS]
[BUZZING]
[WATER PATTERS]
[BIRDS CALL]
[ICE CRACKLES]
[HORSES' HOOVES]
Is Prince Andrei at home?
I'm an old friend.
Yes, your Excellency.
Shall I tell him you're here?
No, no, let me surprise him.
Pierre!
How unexpected!
I'm delighted to see you!
What brings you to these parts?
I've been making
a tour of my estates,
trying to make
conditions better for my serfs
and my tenant farmers, make my farms
more efficient, and so on.
Really, I've no idea what I'm doing.
How are you? I've been
thinking about you so much,
wondering what you've been up to!
Not very much, is the short answer.
Come, let's have something
to eat and drink.
Yes, this is the life -
bread and cheese,
and wine, in moderation.
To hell with high society!
You know, you're exactly the same.
You haven't changed a bit!
Do you think so?
In myself, I believe I've changed
a great deal - and for the better.
I heard about your marriage.
And how it ended?
You heard about the duel?
Yes, you had
to go through that, too.
The one thing I thank God for
is that I didn't kill that man.
Why so? If a dog is vicious,
he's better off dead.
But to take a man's life,
that must always be wrong.
Why must it always be wrong?
For you, perhaps.
For me, there are only two evils -
sickness and remorse.
Since Lise died,
I have been wracked with remorse.
I treated her unkindly
and now she's gone.
Disappeared into nowhere.
No way for me to make amends.
I've been staring
into the abyss, Pierre.
So now, my sole aim
is to live for myself.
To do as little harm as possible
and to have as little to do
with other people as I can.
No, I can't agree.
That wouldn't be enough.
I used to live for myself
and I ruined my life.
Now, I try to think of others,
actively try to help them,
and I'm much happier for it.
Anyway, you don't live
just for yourself!
What about your sister,
your father, your little son?
They are a part of myself.
All right, I concede,
one can't avoid the world entirely,
but I do my best.
I look after my estate,
I take care of my sister and my son,
I serve in the local militia
with my father.
- And that is enough for me.
- You won't go back to the army?
After Austerlitz? No, thanks.
The pursuit of military glory
disgusts me now.
And besides,
Kutuzov was our last good man,
and now the Tsar's demoted him.
And what about yourself?
You have so much to give.
Marry again, why not?
And make some
other poor girl unhappy?
I'm surprised to hear you
recommend marriage, Pierre.
We neither of us distinguished
ourselves there, did we?
Look, I must say this to you.
We've had all these conversations
and you've been talking
as if your life is over,
but you're a young man still.
You know, so many good things
can happen for you.
Since I became a Mason
and started to live a good life,
I feel capable of anything!
We must live.
You know, we must love.
And we must believe that
that there's more to it all than
our lives on this scrap of earth.
There's something else out there -
it is true, Andrei.
You must believe it.
Yes, if only it were so.
Pierre, I'd like you to meet my son.
And it must be years since my father
and my sister set eyes on you.
Can you spare the time?
For you,
I've all the time in the world.
MAN WHISPERS: He's a funny fish.
BOY WHISPERS: He makes a funny face!
[LAUGHS]
How do you find Andrei?
He worries me so much.
Today, he's merry and lively,
but that's just your effect on him.
He is unhappy.
But it's not as though
he's doing nothing, Princess.
I know.
He does everything well.
But it's as if the soul
has gone out of him.
[DOOR OPENS]
My father's home.
Oh! Do you want to go
and say hello to your grandfather?
'No more war?'
This peace treaty with France
won't last. Mark my words,
we'll be fighting Napoleon again
before you're much older!
No, sir! We must believe
the man is capable of evolving.
Evolving?
Men don't change!
If you could drain the blood
from their veins and put in water,
there might be no war!
You're talking
old women's nonsense, sir,
but I'm happy to see that there are
still a few idealists left on Earth.
I want you to go to Otradnoe.
The marshal there, Count Rostov,
has failed to produce
half the men required of him.
The army still needs
to be maintained,
even in this time
of so-called peace.
Rostov needs someone
to ginger him up a bit.
- Do you know the man, at all?
- No, I don't.
I do.
He's a very good man.
Not practical, I suppose,
but who am I to talk of such things?
I'm very fond of him.
The whole family are delightful.
Well, there you are. You can
mix business with pleasure!
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
[PIANO PLAYS]
Do tell your father
that I shall do my very best to
make my contribution to the militia.
I've been very lax.
Do you know, I moved the family
to the country to save money,
but somehow, I've been
doing more entertaining here
than I ever did in Moscow - hunts,
theatricals, dinners, musicians,
endless guests coming to stay...
Well, I shan't be
any further burden to you...
Oh, no, no, no, my dear fellow,
I didn't mean you.
Of course, you must stay the night.
And as long as you wish!
And you needn't be talking
to boring old men like me,
I've seen you looking
at those lovely girls.
Natasha! Stop that, my darling,
and come over here.
My daughter, Natalia.
Natasha, this is
Prince Andrei Bolkonsky,
one of the great heroes
of Austerlitz.
I'm happy to make
your acquaintance, sir.
I think I saw you before, didn't I?
Yes.
Yes, you looked at me so severely!
No, not at all. Not severely.
At least, I hope not.
Go and take him away and talk to him,
Natasha. He's had enough of me.
[SHE LAUGHS]
Are you the Prince Andrei
that Pierre Bezukhov talks about?
He is my greatest friend.
He loves you very dearly.
I think you're his hero.
Have you seen him lately?
He's had so much trouble, I think,
and none of it his fault.
I saw him just before I came here.
I believe he's put his sorrows
behind him now -
he's full of great plans
and love for his fellow man.
Yes. Yes, that's just like him.
I so want him to be happy.
Like you.
You seem to have
the gift of happiness.
Don't we all have it?
Somewhere within us?
NATASHA: Come on, please?
One more time!
SONYA: Yes, all right, but then
I'm blowing the candles out.
[NATASHA AND SONYA SING]
That's it - I'm going to sleep now.
Oh, Sonya, how can you sleep?
I feel as if I'm going to
stay awake till dawn.
Look at that lovely moon.
I don't think it's the moon
that's keeping you awake.
What, then?
Do you like him very much?
More than Boris?
Yes, much more.
There's something
so sad about him,
and that frightens me a little.
But he's going away,
and we're leaving for Petersburg -
I don't suppose
I'll ever see him again.
Oh, Sonya, I wish
I could fly away.
Shall I try?
Would the air carry me?
Don't be a fool!
- Come to bed now.
- Oh, if you insist.
[DOG BARKS]
I understand you have made
a great effort to change your life.
That's very commendable.
How do you feel about yourself?
Well, I can look at
myself without disgust now.
But...
still not happy.
Not at all.
I sleep badly,
I wake with fearful thoughts.
What's the matter with me?
Perhaps you are changing your world,
and forgetting to change yourself.
Do you try to forgive
those who have wounded you?
"My dear Helene, I believe we should
resume married life together,
"if that is agreeable to you."
"I ask you to forgive me
for hurting your feelings,
"and for any damage
to your reputation
"that my conduct may have caused."
Thank you, dear Pierre.
"I am a better person now, I hope,
than I was when we last spoke."
I can't believe you're back
with Bezukhov.
No need to sound so shocked.
It makes perfect sense.
We're not sharing a bed,
it's just for appearance's sake.
So, nothing needs to change.
Come back to bed.
No, I've got too much on
this morning.
Did you know the Rostovs
are back in town?
I had heard, yes.
Aren't you supposed to be engaged
to the daughter?
That was just a childish thing.
Does she know that?
I should make it clear
if I were you -
you can't afford to be engaged
to a girl with no money.
You're not jealous, by any chance,
are you?
Me? Jealous?
Of the little Rostov girl?
You're very sweet.
You can see yourself out.
Wait!
I'll see you at the Tsar's ball?
Well, you shall see me,
but you're not to talk to me,
much less touch me.
I shall be otherwise engaged,
and you need to find yourself
a pretty little heiress
to charm out of her petticoat.
- Think you can do that?
- I don't want to do that.
I want you.
Sweet boy.
[DOOR OPENS]
I'm so nervous!
I've been awake for hours, thinking
about the Tsar's ball tonight.
Oh, but you've got nothing to be
nervous about.
It is important, my darling,
for you and for Sonya -
the first time you'll be seen
in Petersburg society.
Everyone's eyes will be on you.
So, keep a clear head,
and don't fall for the first boy
who asks you to dance.
- Do you think he might be there?
- Who?
[SHE LAUGHS]
You know, Mamma!
Prince Andrei Bolkonsky.
If God wills it, he'll be there,
and you'll dance with him.
Now, close your eyes.
[SHE SINGS A LULLABY]
[LULLABY MERGES INTO BALLROOM MUSIC]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Look at those two. Ah!
Charmantes!
There's so many French here.
- As if nothing ever changed.
- It won't last.
Napoleon won't be able to resist
the temptation to invade Russia
- for much longer.
- Oh! Bilibin, don't say that.
Well, it's his nature. He's like
the scorpion - he has to sting,
he can't help it.
Ah! The Queen of Petersburg!
His Imperial Majesty, The Tsar.
- Old friend!
- Pierre!
How are you?
I'm very well.
Yes - I see something's changed
in you.
I keep hearing reports you're
making waves in the court circles,
reforming the army.
The old spark's burning bright
again, isn't it?
You could put it like that.
And what about you?
Oh,
you don't want to hear about me.
I'm, I'm very happy to see you again.
May I have this dance?
- May I take your hand for this dance?
- Of course.
Countess Rostova.
May I request the pleasure of
a dance with your daughter, Natalia?
Of course! She'll be delighted.
[MUSIC STARTS]
[PIANO MUSIC PLAYS]
It's him!
[LAUGHTER AND CHATTER]
[THEY LAUGH]
I had no idea, Pierre. I've never
experienced anything like it before.
Like what, exactly?
I'm in love, my friend!
Yes. Yes, with Natasha Rostova, yes?
Yes, who else? I feel like I've
never been properly alive before.
I feel I can't live without her,
Pierre!
But could she love me?
Might she think I'm too old.
I am too old! What do you think?
Why don't you speak?
The girl is a treasure, Andrei.
She's one of a kind.
She's a treasure.
Look, if you truly love her,
don't hesitate,
don't think about it.
Follow your heart, marry her.
Marry her tomorrow -
you'll never regret it!
- But could she love me, Pierre?
- She loves you all right.
- She hardly knows me...
- She loves you! I know it! All right?
I could see it in her face
when she was dancing with you.
I've never seen her
look like that before,
and I've known her
since she was a child.
She loves you, Andrei.
And you're
the luckiest man on Earth.
So, what are you doing talking
to me?
Go to her!
Go to her, don't let her get away.
Propose to her.
I will.
[DOOR CLOSES]