Previously on X Company...
I have a proposition.
It's an informal prisoner exchange.
It's your son Klaus,
he's in a Russian POW camp.
I can have him transferred
to a Canadian POW camp.
I need a man transferred out
of the Gestapo HQ in Paris.
Go, go, go!
_
- Do you remember the deal we made?
- Short and sweet. No strings.
- Anyway, I don't mean to...
- No. It was nice.
In three weeks, the Allies are mounting
an operation on the coast of France.
You'll be recruiting Resistance on your
own until the troops land in Dieppe.
- Please don't let them take me again.
- It's all right.
I'm right here, my love.
(gasping)
_
Season 2 - Episode 4
"Last Man, Last Round"
sync and corrected by ninh
Resynced by RIP1964
www.addic7ed.com
How many guns on this rotation?
Eight rifles, three, four, MP-38s.
You think Major Stirling is in there?
If he survived.
Two years since they
were captured at Dunkirk.
None of them are going
to be in good shape.
If we're gonna build an army,
we've got to start somewhere.
Two watch towers. Six hundred
feet of exposed no man's land.
What about that hill?
It's not guarded.
It's covered in land mines.
So is that path.
No problem.
What about a blind spot from the tower?
- There isn't one.
- No time to tunnel under.
- Patrols?
- Twenty-four hour rotation.
- Like a Swiss watch. No gaps.
- Efficient bastards.
Maybe we don't need to
break into the camp.
Prisoners are taken out on work
detail one block at a time, right?
- Same time every day.
- An ambush?
When guards are vulnerable.
It's not like we're liberating
the whole camp anyway.
Assuming we can get them out,
there'll be search parties.
They're not in any
condition to run for long.
I'll need to find a place to hide them.
I'll do more recon, map out a route.
Gather all the guns
- we have.
- What can I do?
You've been through a lot.
Just stay out of trouble.
What, am I grounded?
I do something wrong?
I didn't say you did.
- I want to help.
- And you can.
Someone needs to hold the fort.
He'll be all right.
We'll look after him.
I'll be fine.
_
(phone ringing)
Attention soldiers...
cut out this paper heart
and show your... little heart
when you're back on
leave in the Fatherland.
Pin it proudly to your chest...
- and the National Women's...
- Alliance...
of Patriotic Love
will be waiting.
- All the wives, sweethearts...
- Sisters...
sisters of Germany will be offering
their... tender services.
to... stiffen
- your resolve.
- Keep your spirits up?
Yes, and raise your...
big, strong, German...
- Flag.
And all you've got to
do is get your heart on.
Heart on?
You think that'll work in German?
We'll drop hundreds of these
on the guys in the trenches.
You picture your woman back
home schtupping some guy,
all for the love of the Fatherland?
It's a nice kick in the morale.
(chuckling)
Good. Give me your sketches.
Let's get this typed up.
What?
I'm going to miss this.
Are you going somewhere?
I've accepted a job offer back home.
You're going back into advertising?
Head of Morale Ops at the new camp
in Virginia. They're looking for
Camp X grads to teach there, so...
The Americans will be lucky to have you.
And no more bad guys to shoot you.
I will miss this place.
So visit.
Could you get those
handcuffs off, please?
_
Klaus, I'm Duncan Sinclair.
I'm Oliver and Billy's father.
Do you remember me?
Have a seat.
How's Bowmanville suit you?
Little more comfortable
than the Russian camp?
Why am I here?
- Did my father arrange this?
- Now, Klaus,
I can't elaborate,
for security reasons, but...
Our families vacationed on Lake
Constance when you were a child.
We couldn't keep you kids
out of the water that summer,
- do you remember?
- No.
(banging on door)
This isn't the same breakfast the
other prisoners of war receive.
Well, Klaus, Bowmanville's good,
but it's not that good.
I don't want special treatment.
Are you sure...
I'd like to be brought back
to the barracks.
I want to be with my brothers.
We shoot the tires.
Take out the guards.
With machine guns,
we won't make it 50 feet.
He's right. We don't have the gunpower.
Hey! Steady.
You all right, mate?
Ah!
Eric!
- Did you see that?
- Poor bastard.
I don't think the guards did.
Eric! Eric! Come on!
Oy! You bloody goon!
- Whoa, whoa!
- You see what you did?
- You did this to him!
- Alfred!
What the bloody hell!
He was my brother!
You did this to him!
Shut your mouth!
You make one more sound,
I shoot you right there!
Get back to work.
Schweinhund.
(gunshot)
Anybody else have a problem?
- What are you doing?
- Shh.
- Who are you?
- I'm here to help you.
(whistle)
Line up!
Pretend I'm him. I'll get him covered.
He's lost his mind.
What's his name?
Lieutenant Eric Darcy.
Duke of Cornwall's Light Infantry.
Northern English, like you?
Yeah.
Name?
Francis Mather.
- Name?
- Richard Williams.
Name?
Lieutenant Danny Simpson.
Duke of Cornwall's Light Infantry.
Get on the truck.
Name?
Lieutenant Eric Darcy.
Duke of Cornwall's Light Infantry.
Back on the truck. Move!
- Name?
- Christopher Silker.
And you let him go?
- He didn't ask us?
- Why didn't you stop him?
Sorry if it didn't occur to me
that he would voluntarily run
- into a POW camp.
- Why would he do that?
After what he's been through?
Maybe it's not so bad.
- Yeah, how's that?
- Now we have someone on the inside.
If the prisoners know we're trying
to break them out during work detail,
we'll have a better shot.
But when we get them out,
where do we hide them?
I saw an abbey not far from here.
I'll go and make contact and
see if they'll take them in.
Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- There was nothing you could have done.
About Alfred running?
About René.
Nothing any of us could have done.
So let yourself off the hook.
They got him. Doesn't mean
they're going to get Alfred.
Let's make sure they don't.
This was Eric's bunk.
- Are you American?
- Any news from England?
He's Canadian.
And he goes by Eric Darcy now.
What happened to Eric?
His heart gave out. On work detail.
- How far are we into Europe?
- I'm sorry. It's not going well.
There is no Western front.
I am an Allied agent
and I need your help.
- Is Major George Stirling here?
- That's me.
It's an honor to meet you.
I have colleagues on the outside,
right now, helping me plan a breakout.
The men who escape with me
will help train Resistance fighters from
here all the way to the Northern Coast.
I'm not risking these men's lives
for anything less than a solid plan.
If we're gonna turn things around,
we need to do something now.
You can't just wait here to die.
- We're digging a tunnel.
- Danny.
You can trust me.
I broke in for you, didn't I?
- We're clearing a foot a day.
- When do you expect to finish?
Three months, give or take.
Then we're all getting out.
- We don't have that much time.
- Time 'til what?
I can't say.
But we have weeks, not months.
It's an important operation.
It could make the difference.
We need your most experienced men.
Your strongest,
to help train civilian recruits.
So what's your plan?
Next time on work detail
I'll give a signal.
My team will provide covering fire
while we break for the woods.
(bell tolling)
Ahh!
They said you told them
nothing at the gate.
You are a mystery,
and I am a curious person.
Please.
Thank you, Sister. And you, Mother,
for agreeing to see me.
I'm sorry,
but this is a personal matter.
Don't worry, there are no secrets here.
And, anyway, Sister Marie
has taken a vow of silence,
so there is nothing to worry about.
Please speak freely.
I may need your help soon.
And I apologize if I'm
being presumptuous, but...
this is a place of God, and...
Yes?
If there were any other place
my friends could turn, believe me...
You need us to hide some people
who may or may not be in trouble
with the authorities?
I'm not sure that they
will be free to come.
- A very small number of them.
- Men?
Yes, but only for a short time.
I'm so sorry. But I can't.
Mother, please! They'll be
recaptured in the woods or killed.
The Germans are very thorough.
Every inch will be searched.
These men will be found.
When the sisters of the
Abbey St. Germain were caught
trying to hide refugees,
only four Sisters were
left alive that night.
Barely. I'm so sorry.
I will pray for them. For you,
in this fight.
But I cannot let anything happen
to the Sisters in my care.
I understand.
Thank you.
You are very brave.
Sister Marie.
Please show this young lady out.
You're sure about this?
We've got a U-boat
Commander at Bowmanville.
Now, any intel Klaus can get from him
- will help with the big Push.
- Eyes and ears inside.
You think he'll turn just because
your family took a holiday years ago?
Well, I'm counting on your
legendary powers of persuasion, Tom.
Does he even remember you?
He was a kid. If anything,
he'll remember my boys.
What else can you tell me?
He's a good soldier. He's got a
bit of a chip on his shoulder
due to the fact that
his father's got him some privileges.
So he's got integrity?
Well, that doesn't help us.
He's a pilot. That could help.
Guys who work alone are
more likely to turn.
Start there while you're still
on my payroll.
You heard.
The Yanks had to go through me.
I said it was your call.
Good luck with Klaus.
Why are you following me?
Open your mouth,
- or I'll open it for you.
- I don't speak unless I need to.
Why are you following me?
I wanted to make sure you
are who you say you are.
I can help your men. No more than five.
- I know a way in.
- No. No, your Abbess...
- She doesn't need to know.
- She said they search every inch.
We can't.
There are inches
Mother doesn't know about.
Ladies. Everything all right?
Yeah. This is...
Sister Marie.
- Miri.
- Since when do we bring strays home?
She's going to help hide
our men at the Abbey.
Then she should be at the Abbey.
Why is she here?
She knows our plan.
I prefer not to let
her out of our sight.
We'll need a car or a way
to slow the Germans down.
The Abbey has a truck.
They take it to town on market days.
I could "borrow" the keys.
When do you need it?
Walking freely is a privilege.
- Brilliant.
- Maybe now you will think twice
before attacking.
Alfred's going to have to find
a way out from the inside.
- How?
- I don't know.
He's going to need our help. Come on.
Get to work.
You'd think they'd feed you more
if they expect you to do all this work.
That's what Eric said.
He always gave me half his rations.
Refused to eat them himself.
If he'd eaten more...
He's gone.
My team must have taken care of it.
We're gonna need a new plan.
- There's always Death Valley.
- No.
What's Death Valley?
That's Death Valley.
- See that door on the other side?
- Yeah.
It takes you to the front gate.
- If that's the only way...
- We're completely exposed.
Also the barbed wire,
searchlights, guard tower.
Goons can see everything from up there.
We'd be fish in a barrel.
It's out of the question.
You need to call your people off.
We're better off with the tunnel.
Your tunnel will take months to finish.
You could be relocated
before it's ready.
But if it works,
we can get everybody out.
Two hundred of you,
running around the forest?
No papers, no clothes,
no place to hide?
You'll be hunted like dogs.
Yeah, it's risky.
But the truth is,
we don't know how long we have left.
Eric didn't know. None of us do.
You can play it safe,
or take the chance and fight now.
These are some of the
best men I've fought with.
We saw thousands die at Dunkirk.
Our orders were to hold the line
to the last man. And we did.
It was a suicide mission.
I'm not putting these men
through that again. I'm sorry.
I can't let them take that risk.
I asked to be taken to my POW.
Why I am still here?
Damn.
You know what?
I missed lunch. So, do you mind if I...?
If you're done?
Mmm.
Luftwaffe silver clasp.
- Sixty missions to get one of those.
- I know what you want.
Yeah. Gravy.
Why would I give information
to an office boy?
Tell you what.
I won't pretend to know
anything about you,
if you don't assume that you know me.
Don't usually flash that on a first
date. You ever been shot before?
No.
It's not much fun.
I was, uh,
behind enemy lines in France.
First, it doesn't feel like anything.
Adrenaline's good that way.
Then,
it was burning. White hot.
I was trying to help a family of Jews.
Police didn't like that.
You know about the Jews?
About the Nazi Master Plan?
All those trains taking
them East every day.
They're not being "resettled."
They're being exterminated.
Five thousand Jews
per train. Ten trains
per day.
You do the math.
Your father, he's in charge of
running the train schedules
for the German Transport Ministry,
right?
He's very good at his job.
Very efficient.
How'd you get captured?
My plane was shot down.
You survived.
What about your crew?
I always wanted to learn how to fly.
Must be something up there.
Everything looking so small,
like tiny little pieces on a board game.
It's not a game. Real men,
dying every day. And I'm being
moved from camp to camp, for what?
- It doesn't make sense anymore.
- You won't eat.
- Why are you still fighting?
- I fight for my country.
For my brothers.
They are all I think about.
Are they even alive?
I don't know. Because I'm...
Stuck here.
Yeah.
There's something here.
It's from my team.
This means the new moon.
- The light.
- When's that?
- Tonight.
- And this?
It means they can only hide five men.
You and four more.
The cutters will get us through
the barbed wire.
It's the best chance we have.
It's your call.
The truck is hidden in the woods.
Aurora has the keys.
Good.
Gun.
- Why would I give you a gun?
- You need help.
I can help.
(scoffing)
What do you know about guns?
You aim and squeeze
and your target dies.
How do I know I can I trust you?
You don't yet.
What's going on?
These men have experience
training soldiers.
- You changed your mind?
- They saw your gun
and your wire cutters. What can I say?
Hope is contagious.
- But Death Valley...
- We have a plan.
We, uh...
cut the phone cords and the power
to the watchtower lights first.
- Safer in the dark.
- George! Wait.
Danny. Danny, I'm sorry, lad, but we can
only take five.
I want to help.
No. Stay inside. Stay safe.
Lifted it from the guards' latrine
on cleaning duty.
What's it for?
Protection.
I won't allow it.
Don't do anything daft, Danny.
How long does it take the guards
to reach the far side?
Two minutes.
OK, then. Two minutes from now,
we run.
Go, go, go.
Cut the wire!
(guards shouting)
Hey! What are you doing?
(whistle)
_
(guards yelling)
(siren)
_
Bloody hell.
Hey!
Hey! Stop right there! (gunshot)
_
- Not bad, Sister Miri.
- Just Miri.
Good to know.
(gunfire)
Come on! Quickly! Come on! Quick, quick!
Go, go, go! Faster, faster!
- Come on!
- What are they doing?
- We can't take them.
- They know that.
Go, go, go, go, go!
- Danny!
- Go!
Danny!
Ah!
- Danny!
- George, go!
- Up!
- I said go!
Go, go!
There they are! Go!
Down the road. There's a truck!
Go! Go!
Right behind you.
- Come on!
- Ah!
This way! Hurry!
- Won't they search the Abbey?
- Probably.
Behind there. Quiet.
Hurry.
- Bread.
- Thank you.
- Be safe.
- You too.
We'll move you when
the search dies down.
You must go before the Abbess sees you.
Come. This way.
- Never do that again.
- What?
You broke rank. You took action
with no plan in place.
You've never broken a rule
to save someone?
- Your job is to follow my orders.
- Our job is to recruit
fighters. We got what we came for.
We got lucky.
If you want to stay on this team,
you can't be so impulsive.
- We almost lost you once.
- Is that what this is?
I survived
37 hours of Gestapo interrogation.
That wasn't luck.
- Don't make the same mistake twice.
- What mistake?
Treating me differently.
Compromising our objective
because of what you feel.
- Feel?
- For me?
You have no idea.
Sister Miri,
thank you
- for all your help.
- I want to come with you.
I'm not a nun. Mother's been sheltering
me here for a month while those pigs
are out there.
My father taught me to hunt.
To be proud.
He'd be ashamed to see me now... hiding.
Please,
let me hunt with you.
(laughing and talking)
You've got two more bottles of whisky
to get through before midnight.
- That is an order.
- (all): Yes, sir!
Nice work. You got him, Tom.
He's not on board with
the Fuhrer's policies.
But he is a patriot. Loves Germany,
loyal to his brothers-in-arms.
Dreams of victory.
I'm surprised you're considering him.
He's a good kid. You never know.
- We could get him working for us.
- He's about your son's age, isn't he?
Yes, Tom. Yes, he is.
Sir.
I guess this is it.
Guess it is.
- Stay in touch.
- I will.
Throw them out of bed at 0300.
Interrogation Training.
The drunker the better.
I'll see to it, sir.
Your ticket to Virginia.
I remember when that was you guys.
Brand new.
Excited.
Scared.
And then half of you don't come back.
And we lie to your families about why.
Tibor. Charlie.
René...
I'm glad you'll be going somewhere safe.
I'm not great at goodbyes, so...
Safe.
Sitting at a desk.
Moving little pieces
across a board game.
Tom...
(whooping and whistling)
There's something I need to tell you.
You're going back, aren't you?
Yeah.
Klaus, we're gonna move
you back to Bowmanville.
And I wanted to apologize.
You're a loyal citizen of Germany,
and I can respect that.
Sometimes I just don't know
when to stop doing my job.
Thank you.
I wanted to ask...
How are they? Ollie and Billy.
Oliver was killed last year
in action.
- I'm sorry.
- And Billy...
William now...
He's missing in the Pacific.
I hope he will come back to you soon.
I'm sure your father wants
the same thing, Klaus,
and I wish I could give it to him.
But that's not the game, is it?
No, it isn't.
Thank you.
For your kindness.
It's the least I could do.
Maybe we can talk again.
Maybe.
- Soldiers are safe for now.
- That's great.
The Germans searched
the Abbey last night.
They didn't find them.
We shouldn't leave them there too long.
We're gonna need a new camp.
Somewhere we can bring them longer term.
- Yeah.
- Varges is close to here.
Varges?
Yeah, we talked about it.
Might be a good place to recruit
more locals for the POWs to train.
Fine.
But when we get the POWs from the Abbey,
we'll take Miri too.
- Miri, the pretend nun?
- She's motivated. She can shoot.
And she trailed me through the woods
for a half hour before I heard her.
None of you can do that.
That's all we know about her?
Everything else you can learn
while you train her.
Brilliant.
Three weeks till the invasion.
Lots of time.
Speaking of which,
I've been thinking. We're working
on the attack, but without defense,
it could all be for nothing.
What do you mean?
We need to know what they know.
Which networks are blown,
who we can trust.
We don't know how much René told them.
Counter-intelligence.
We need to protect ourselves.
Anticipate attacks.
- Track his movements. Feed him lies.
- And by "him" you mean...
Franz Faber. He knows a lot about us.
It's time we learned more about him.
- We can't get anywhere near the HQ.
- No.
But maybe we can hit him closer to home.
_
(phone ringing)
Hello.
_
sync and corrected by ninh
Resynced by RIP1964
www.addic7ed.com