INGERAS: In the year
of our Lord, 1442,
the Turkish sultan enslaved
1,000 Transylvanian boys
to fill the ranks
of his army.
(WHIP LASHING)
(BOY WAILS)
These child slaves were
beaten without mercy,
trained to kill
without conscience,
to crave the blood
of all who defied the Turks.
From among these boys,
one grew into
a warrior so fierce
that entire armies
would retreat in terror
at the mention of his name.
Vlad the Impaler.
Son of the Dragon.
Sickened by his
monstrous acts,
Vlad came to bury
his past with the dead
and returned to Transylvania
to rule in peace.
His subjects
called him Prince.
I called him Father.
But the world would
come to know him as...
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Dracula.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(FLOWING STREAM)
SHKELGIM:
I left it (EXHALES)
where I found it.
What do you think, Vlad?
Bring it to me.
This belongs to a scout.
One of Hamza Bey's men.
What the hell's
a lone Turk doing out here?
VLAD: Turkish scouts
never travel alone.
If there's one,
there's more.
And whatever they scout,
they conquer.
This was washed downstream.
Came from up there.
Broken Tooth Mountain.
Soon it will be night.
They'll seek refuge.
Dimitru, I need you to
return to the castle.
Alert the guards
and double the sentry.
What?
I'm not leaving you here.
For the Turks to cross
into my land unannounced
is a sign of war.
And what are you going to do
if you find them?
I'll do what
princes do best.
Negotiate.
Nicolae, Andrei, with me.
PETRU: (WHISTLES)
Fall in!
Anything?
(COUGHS)
Smells like your feet.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(BOTH GASP)
(PANTING)
VLAD: They're inside.
How do you know?
Bats don't come out
during the day.
Something's disturbed them.
Come on.
What is it, My Lord?
The floor.
It's crushed bone.
The Turks didn't do this.
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(GROWLING)
What's that?
(SCREAMS)
We leave, now.
(GROWLS)
(VLAD GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(URGING HORSE)
LUCIAN: The creature
you encountered
was no accident,
My Prince.
Four nights ago,
every brother in our order
awoke from
an identical dream.
I would not have
thought it possible
had I not suffered the same
vision myself that night.
Of a creature laying
siege to this holy place.
The Roman mystics prophesied
the coming of a great evil.
A vampire.
From the Greek
word pi, to drink.
The beast was
once a mortal man
who summoned a demon
from the depths of hell
to trade for his dark power.
The demon tricked the man,
granting his wish,
but his price
was an eternity
condemned to the darkness
of that cave,
where he remains
until he finds another
to set him free.
Now you know its true face.
The people of Transylvania
live in enough fear
of the Turks' return.
Promise me you'll
guard this secret, brother.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLING)
(SIGHING)
Papa!
(VLAD LAUGHS)
I missed you.
VLAD: And I, you.
My big soldier.
(LAUGHING)
What? An embrace
but no kiss?
Are we going to argue?
With you always leaving,
I need my fill.
I've missed you.
Something troubles you.
What is it?
Only the impossible
depth of your beauty.
(LAUGHS) Puts the rest
of the world to shame.
Pay no attention to
your father, lngeras.
Flattery is a cheap
distraction from truth.
She knows all my tricks.
You're a terrible liar.
It's one of your most
endearing qualities.
You're just in time
for bed.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
Can we go riding
tomorrow, Papa?
Of course we can.
You most certainly cannot.
Why not?
Because tomorrow is
the day of our risen Lord.
Oh, of course.
That's Easter.
(WHISPERING)
What was I thinking?
So what attacked you?
Wolves?
I suppose.
All I know
is that I've lost
two good men today.
(SIGHING)
There's something more.
I was the same age
as lngeras
when I was sent to
live with the Turks.
To fight for them.
If I never saw another,
it would be too soon.
You're home now.
For almost as many years
as you were gone.
I just want peace.
That's all.
(MIRENA SHRIEKS)
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GLASS CLINKING)
My fellow Transylvanians,
an Easter toast.
Ten years of
peace and prosperity
ever since our prince
came back to us.
My old friend,
here's to 20 more.
MAN: To 20 more!
(ALL CHEERING)
Mmm.
Hamza Bey.
Welcome.
We were not
expecting you so soon.
Sultan Mehmed ll offers his
salutations to you and your son.
Thank him.
I have his tribute ready.
Hmm.
I'm afraid
there's something more
than a tribute to discuss.
The Turks have
no enemies here.
HAMZA BEY: Did you think
we would not notice
a battalion of
our scouts missing?
I did not kill them.
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
It still lives inside you,
Lord Impaler.
Locked in a dark cage,
hidden away.
But you and I...
we both know it's there.
The sultan's tribute.
Take it and leave.
Ah!
There is one last thing.
The sultan requires
1,000 boys
to join his
Janissary Corps.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(GASPING)
No!
Never!
VLAD: Janissaries?
He ended that
practice years ago.
When a soldier is
plucked as a child
and raised to
know no other life,
they will kill
without question and
die without complaint.
Any who are 15 years
of age or older
will fight in Hungary.
Those 10 to 14
will be made ready
for the siege on Vienna.
The sultan
expects your obedience.
After all,
did not your own father
give you up without a fight?
(WHIMPERING)
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
Soft, but they'll do.
Don't. Please.
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
Do you know who I am?
You mean who you were.
You have no army and
no choice, Prince.
Follow our command,
or suffer the consequences.
(MAN COMMANDING IN TURKISH)
It must be done.
Courage, anger,
even love.
None of these can
matter to a prince.
All that matters is
his duty to his people.
INGERAS: What does it mean
to be a royal hostage?
My father gave me to the
sultan to prove his loyalty.
Were you scared there?
With them?
I wanted to make
my father proud.
Would you ever
give me to the sultan?
That was a long time ago.
You have nothing
to worry about.
Do you understand?
Good.
VLAD: If I defy the order,
they'll kill 100
for every one I save.
You told me
you and Mehmed
were once like brothers.
Were you to ask,
isn't it possible he might
show you some mercy?
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(SOLDERS TAUNTMG)
You ever seen
the like of it?
Soon the entire
world will be Turk.
Lord Impaler,
my oldest of friends.
I miss our days together.
All I miss from my time
with you is the coffee.
It's true, my father's
palace was a cruel place
for a young boy
far from home.
But soon you
talked like us,
prayed like us,
fought like us.
Speaking of which,
I am owed 1,000 boys.
Why have I not seen them?
Mehmed, my brother,
I will grant
you anything else.
I need soldiers,
brother.
Then take me.
I'm worth 1,000 boys,
and you know it.
Those kings would
tremble if they knew.
Then accept my offer.
When we were boys,
how I longed to
fight side by side.
But now I am sultan,
what need have I
for one more soldier?
I will have my 1,000 boys.
And one more.
MEHMED: Your son will be
raised under my roof,
just as you were raised
under the roof of my father.
You may retain
your throne.
But General Ismail will remain to
see that my orders are fulfilled.
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
Please.
Do not do this.
MEHMED: What is one son?
If you are virile,
you'll make plenty more.
Whoa, there.
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
You promised me this
would never happen.
Mirena, listen.
The day you asked
for my hand,
do you remember
what I said?
You said no.
DIMITRU: Stay,
my young friend.
MIRENA: I knew what happens
to the sons of the queen.
You said things
would be different.
You said if I loved you,
I should trust you.
I love you!
Then trust me.
It's this
or we start a war.
(MIRENA SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(SPEAKING TURKISH)
The Great Impaler
can't please his woman.
DIMITRU:
Everything's fine, boys.
They're just saying
their goodbyes is all.
Mirena.
I won't let you...
You promised me my family!
Mirena, please!
MIRENA: Stop it!
Don't touch me!
I won't!
I won't let them do this!
MIRENA: Vlad, don't!
Don't do this!
No! No!
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
No, I won't let you do this!
I'll go.
I won't! No!
I'll go!
I can do it.
You're proud of me,
aren't you?
Of course I am.
You have chosen wisely.
Yeah, I have to say,
we are a little disappointed.
Frankly, I expected more
resistance from you.
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
Run to your mother.
What?
Now!
(GRUNTING)
MIRENA: Come here!
(YELLING)
Don't look!
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mehmed will punish
all of Transylvania
for what you have done.
It's not a child's place
to save his country.
Get my family
to the castle.
CAZAN: Mehmed will be
sending others soon enough.
War will come.
You can't protect us.
I'll find a way.
Vlad!
Where are you going?
Whatever haunts Broken Tooth,
I know it kills Turks.
(URGES HORSE)
(NEIGHING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
MASTER VAMPIRE:
You returned.
No one has ever returned.
It seems no one has ever had the
privilege of leaving, either.
(GROWLING)
Neither will you.
(SHRIEKING)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(SNIFFING)
Those whom enter
reek of fear.
In you.
I sense hope.
Your silver offends me.
Cloak it from my sight.
What kind of man
crawls into his own grave
in search of hope? Hmm?
A desperate one.
The Turks threaten
to destroy my kingdom.
With power like yours,
I could stop them,
save my people,
save my family.
How supremely noble,
Lord Impaler.
House Dracul,
Son of the Devil.
You're mistaken.
It means
"son of the dragon."
"Protector of the innocent."
Do your people know
how many innocents
you have killed?
Was it hundreds?
Yes.
(GASPS)
Lie to me again
and I'll open you from
your belly to your brain
and feed you
your intestines.
Thousands.
And when you put
them to the stake,
what did you feel?
Shame? Horror?
Power?
Answer me!
Nothing!
I felt nothing.
A greater crime
than the act itself.
Then why spill blood
if not for the pleasure of it?
Because men do not
fear swords.
They fear monsters.
They run from them.
By putting one
village to the stake,
I spared 10 more.
Sometimes the world
no longer needs a hero.
Sometimes what it needs
is a monster.
And you believe you know
what it is to be
a monster? Hmm?
(GROANS)
(GROWLING)
You have no idea.
But I'm going
to show you.
For centuries,
these moldering walls
have been my gallows.
For I'm bound to this cave,
condemned by
one who turned me.
Oh, and I have
waited an eternity
for a man of your strength,
your gifts, your will.
A man worthy of the dark
and all its powers.
For if I am your salvation,
you are mine.
Drink.
You will have
a taste of my power.
The strength of 100 men.
The speed
of a falling star.
Dominion over the night
and all its creatures.
To see and hear
through their senses.
Even heal grievous wounds.
At what price?
Once you drink,
your thirst
for human blood
will be insatiable.
But if you can
resist for three days,
you will return to
your mortal state
having sampled my power,
and perhaps,
saved your people.
And if I feed?
The price would
be worse than
if you'd never
stepped in here.
For I will be set free
Having granted the darkness
a worthy offering.
You will become
its vessel as I am.
A scourge on this earth
destined to destroy
everything you hold dear.
Your lands, your people,
even your
precious wife and son.
I would die
before I harmed them.
Indeed you will,
I'm afraid.
I, however,
will at last be free
to unleash my wrath against
the one who betrayed me.
And one day,
I will call on you
to serve me, my pawn,
in an immortal
game of revenge.
This is not a game!
Ah, but what better way
to endure eternity?
For this, little prince,
is the ultimate game.
Light versus dark,
hope versus despair.
And all the world's
fate hangs in the balance.
Then it will be
my great pleasure
to disappoint you.
Drink.
Let the games begin.
(INHALING)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS)
What now?
Now,
you die.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
INGERAS: Papa!
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
(CRUSHING)
(GRUNTS)
That's useful.
(SCRAPING)
(BIRD CALLING)
(BARKING)
(METAL RESONATING)
(GROANS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Prepare to fire!
Light!
(SCREAMING)
(CLAMORING)
You came back.
I always will.
Where were you?
Searching for
the strength I needed.
You're back!
(EXPLOSIONS)
(CLAMORING)
VLAD: They wanted our sons!
We can't fight.
A good prince would
have given them up.
A good prince would have
paid that price for peace.
(RUMBLING)
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
But I give you my word,
we will not be defeated!
They've brought
war to our land.
And they will
pay dearly for it.
Fire!
Charge!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(GROWLING)
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
SOLDIER: (WHISPERING)
What? Wait.
Negotiations failed.
Do not ask me
what happened on
this field tonight.
Trust only that I will use
all I have to keep us safe.
But we will not be
safe if we stay here.
VLAD: We must leave
directly for Cozia Monastery.
It's high in the mountains,
too remote for cannon fire.
It's our best
chance of survival.
We'll take
enough of our people
so that our
absence is noticed.
That way,
when Mehmed learns
what has happened here,
he will come
hunting for us.
OMER:
Word from Castle Dracula.
Vlad has defeated
1,000 of our men.
MEHMED: Then send 100,000.
I will lead them.
When I march into Europe,
I will have his head
upon my spear
and his child at my side.
DIMITRU: We can fight the way
our great-grandfathers fought.
Use the forests,
the mountains
around the Borgo Pass.
Four or five months
of that.
Not months.
I'm gonna win this war
in three days.
Why not two?
That'd really impress us.
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HEART BEATING)
MASTER VAMPIRE: Feed.
(GASPS)
MIRENA: What is it?
(PANTING)
I need some air.
I'm sorry.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Don't think
I haven't noticed
you following me.
You're mistaken.
I follow them.
They recognize
one of their own.
The night is their kingdom.
Blood, their sustenance.
And some, they say,
have lived for as long
as there have been
prey to devour.
Spare me your ravings.
They say the one who
escaped the mountain
hides behind
the face of a man.
Well, if that man is me,
you'll know a knife
will not do you any good.
Of course not.
Why do you think I stayed?
I know there is only so far
on this earth we can run,
and it is not far enough.
Let me serve you.
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
Stay away from me.
Yes, master.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
MASTER VAMPIRE:
Fulfill your destiny.
Set me free.
(WHIMPERING)
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(VOICES LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
OMER: We found him
in the field.
He asked for you.
(ISMAIL WHIMPERING)
A message from Prince Vlad.
He hopes you enjoy the view.
(QUIVERING BREATH)
(SHIVERING)
(SIZZLING)
Mirena!
(GASPS)
Your scars are gone.
What's happening to you?
I'm the thing men
fear on Broken Tooth.
Not a ghost.
Something else.
(UNSHEATHING KNIFE)
(CRACKLING)
No! Stop it!
May God strike down
whoever did this to you.
I chose this.
This is
the strength you sought?
But why?
Because I sent corpses
back to Mehmed
instead of our son.
You did this for us?
In two days,
I'll be restored.
I just have to resist.
Resist what?
Resist what, Vlad?
Tell me!
A thirst
for blood.
And if you were to
give in?
Then I become
this for eternity.
You will undo this,
won't you'?
Yes.
I swear it.
I will not give in.
Then God will forgive you.
DIMITRU: Vlad.
Mehmed is getting closer.
We might want
to move out soon.
I need you to get
to the monastery
as quickly as you can.
Mehmed's men will be close by.
No.
Listen to me.
I will reach you
after sundown.
I promise you.
(SIZZLING)
I love you.
My husband agrees
with your counsel.
We will depart now under
your temporary command.
What? And where's Vlad
going to be?
Spying on the Turks.
He insists on doing
his own reconnaissance.
No. I won't have it.
It's too late.
He's already gone.
All right, everyone.
Prepare to move out.
SOLDIER: Prepare the horses.
Tell the sultan where his
enemies will be buried.
(GROWLING)
Listen.
We're nearly there.
(SOLDIERS YELLING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Cover the rear!
Mirena!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Mirena! lngeras!
Couldn't these
monks have built
their gates
a little bit closer?
Stay behind me.
(SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Don't the Turks
teach you anything new?
I saw your
blade coming from...
lngeras, run.
BRIGHT EYES:
Where is your prince now,
My Lady?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(GROWLS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
VLAD: Dimitru.
It's okay.
Vlad.
Dimitru, listen.
Listen!
No!
(INGERAS WHIMPERING)
Come here. Come here.
Never leave us again,
Papa.
Never.
I will always
watch over you.
(BELL TOLLING)
PETRU: Through the gates!
Keep moving along!
This way!
(STRAINING)
You should never
have strayed from us,
whatever your reasons
for leaving were...
Quiet.
Get these men
off their knees.
Stand up, do you hear me?
Stand up!
The Turks are coming!
Prayers will not
defend these walls!
(DOOR OPENS)
(UNSHEATHING SWORDS)
PETRU: Do you believe
we can do this?
VLAD: Mehmed's men will
be coming from the north.
Double our sentries
on the perimeter walls.
Go. Do it now.
What's in there?
Something I hope
to never use again.
Come now.
(MEN SHOUTING)
OMER: The men say that
Vlad has become a monster.
I fear this will only
inflame the rumors of
the Prince's dark magic.
Only if we allow it.
Men cannot fear
what they cannot see.
MEHMED: Remember when
you first joined my army.
You wanted to pick up
your sword and fight!
When my generals
blindfolded you,
you did not believe
that you could march
without seeing.
But you could.
Now march with me!
Your sultan
will guide you!
Prince Vlad,
the vampire is
vulnerable to daylight.
And to pure silver.
Yet the holy cross
exerts no power over you.
That can only
mean you have yet
to seal your fate
with human blood.
Let me kill you now,
My Prince.
Please.
Before your people do.
Rumor has spread of
what you have become.
You can still repent.
You'd do well to run,
Lucian.
(SCREAMING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
MAN: It's true!
He's a monster!
MIRENA: No!
Please! Listen!
He is your prince!
He has earned
the chance to explain.
Stop!
MAN: Kill the monster!
He's your prince!
Satan lives in his heart!
Vlad!
(VLAD SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Mirena!
He was trying
to save us all!
(VLAD GROWLING)
Take him to my room
and shut the door.
Do not let him
look outside!
Okay.
Mama!
VLAD: This is your loyalty?
Your gratitude?
Fools.
Do you think you are alive
because you can fight?
Come on.
You are alive
because of me!
Because of what
I did to save you!
This is not who you are.
Return to your stations.
Believe me,
there is still more to fear!
Lord, if you've
not yet forsaken me,
grant me your strength that
I may resist the darkness.
Allow me to endure
this test one more day.
I beg you.
Please.
Are you sick?
If you were sick,
I thought it might
make you feel better.
Thank you.
Come.
You'll make
a great leader someday.
You think of others
before yourself.
When the Turks
came to take me,
you stopped them.
It's why you got sick,
isn't it?
To save me.
Yes.
And I would
do it all again.
(SOBBING)
VLAD: They're almost here.
Dawn will be breaking soon.
And with it,
the loss of my powers.
If we've not won
this war by then...
I will fight
beside you until death.
Your death would
end my fight.
We have done the duty
of any good parent.
Protected our child.
Protected all the children
in the kingdom.
Perhaps our destiny was
not to rule in this life.
Do you remember
our wedding vow?
"Why think separately
of this life and the next..."
"When one is
born from the last?"
Time is always too short
for those who need it.
But for those who love,
it lasts forever.
(BAT SCREECHING)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREECHING LOUDLY)
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
SOLDIER: No!
MEHMED: Hold your ground!
Stand your ground!
Hold fast!
Hold your ground!
CAZAN: Fire!
(GROWLING)
Mehmed!
No.
Where is he?
CAZAN: Fire!
Draw!
(MIRENA GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Find your father! Go!
Where is he?
You can keep
running if you like.
(GROANS)
INGERAS: Let me go!
No!
Mirena.
No! Please!
Ingeras!
(STRAINING)
No!
Vlad!
(INAUDIBLE)
No, Mirena.
Please, stay with me.
I cannot do this
without you.
Mirena.
There's still time
for you to stop them.
Drink my blood.
No.
I cannot take your life.
My life is lost already.
But our son's is not.
(SOBBING) No.
I love you.
Do it now!
Please.
(HEART BEATING)
Do it now.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(MIRENA GROANS)
Vlad!
(GROWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(VLAD WAILING)
(SOBBING)
(SCREAMING) No!
Do you want vengeance?
Drink.
(MOANS)
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
VLAD: I now know
hell is real.
So I know
there's a heaven.
Neither this world
or the next
shall keep us apart.
I will honor your sacrifice
and I vow that
our son shall be safe.
MEHMED:
Of all of my lands,
this is the one
I love the least.
Look to the east.
The sun should be risen
by now, should it not?
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(ALL MURMURING)
What is that?
It is the Prince.
He is coming.
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
I used to think there
were too many of you.
Now there's not enough.
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GASPS)
(LABORED BREATHING)
(SCREAMING)
(SWORD UNSHEATHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I understand
you have a weakness
for silver.
(SIZZLING)
INGERAS: Papa!
He's waiting for you.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
MEHMED: You are
slower, brother.
And weaker.
(GRUNTS)
(SIZZLING)
Aww...
MEHMED: Go on, take it.
Is this the monster
that terrified my men?
Hmm?
You grow more
weary by the moment.
Tell me,
how long can you
bear it in here? Huh?
Long enough to
strike your name
from the history books.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
INGERAS: Papa!
MEHMED: Take a last look
at your father, lngeras.
No!
Look how pathetic he is.
No, stop!
Please!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(WOOD SNAPS)
if I put a stake
through your heart,
(GRUNTING)
it will kill you
like any other man.
A fitting death
for Lord Impaler.
INGERAS: No! No!
INGERAS: Papa!
(YELLS)
That is no longer my name.
My name is Dracula.
Son of the Devil.
(MEHMED GROANING)
(ROARING)
(INGERAS SOBBING)
VLAD: It's all right.
I'm here.
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
You old goat.
I don't feel old.
How many are left?
None, except for
your son, of course.
A distraction we can now
dispense with.
What have I taught you?
Repeated over and over
since you were a boy?
All that matters is a
prince's duty to his people.
GOVERNESS:
(WHISPERING) lngeras.
CAZAN: Don't you realize?
They're all our enemies now.
When he's gone,
you'll be free.
(GROWLING)
You forget who I am.
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL GROWLING)
Leave him.
(ALL GROANING)
Come with me, child.
Come.
Please.
Be gone!
The time has come.
Please.
Please, you must come.
I don't want to leave you!
You have to go with him.
No!
Do not leave his side.
(SOBBING)
Please. Know I will
always love you.
Always.
Go!
No!
You take care of him.
Papa!
No!
He's safe now, Mirena.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
INGERAS: The Turks never conquered
the capitals of Europe.
Prince Vlad Dracula
was a hero.
But there are no
pictures or statues of him.
I am his legacy.
His sacrifice taught me that
even after the darkest night,
the sun will rise again.
Drink, master.
INGERAS: For if the heart
is strong enough,
the soul is reborn
(GASPS)
with each new day.
In life after life.
Age after age.
Forever.
MINA: Lovely.
Which markets are
you at this week?
WOMAN:
Portobello Road next.
See you there?
Beautiful.
The flowers, my lady.
My lady?
Where are you from?
A long way from here.
Well, good night.
"Why think separately
of this life and the next
"when one is born
from the last?"
That's my favorite poem.
It speaks to you
of yearning,
of one soul
pleading for another.
I'm Mina.
Vlad.
Let the games begin.