Core! Core! Core!
Compatriots,
Mexico is under siege.
A plot as insidious
as it is dangerous
threatens our nation.
Outcasts from Rome
and from all over Europe
are coming into our country
to destabilize the government,
to poison the minds and hearts
of our people,
to turn them into fanatics
at the service of foreign interests.
This situation, this evil,
this threat
cannot be ignored,
and it will not be tolerated.
Therefore
I have instructed our Congress
to create a set of laws
designed to deal with
this national emergency.
Camine.
Firstly, every foreign-born bishop,
priest or minister
will be deported immediately.
Second, there will be
a five-year jail sentence
for any priest who criticizes
the government.
The wearing of religious vestments
in public is strictly forbidden.
Make no mistake.
This government is going to do
whatever is necessary
to preserve the dignity of Mexico,
the freedom of its people
and the immortal ideals
of La Revolution Mexicana.
Muchachos!
Don't waste God's good food
making fun of me.
I- I'm ashamed of you.
He's a man of God.
Padre. Padre.
Jose will work for you
for the next two weeks, Padre.
Anything you need him
to do for the church.
That won't be necessary.
It was a harmless prank.
And I hear fruit is good for the hair.
I- I know that the priests
consider prayer a penitence,
but for a boy like my godson,
hard work is better.
Uh, you've no doubt,
uh, heard about the Calles Law.
Yes.
Just be careful about
wearing your cassock in public.
God save us from these heathens.
Have you had breakfast, Joselito?
Elodia makes wonderful chilaquiles,
and my friend Father Vega
will be here any minute.
Don't call me Joselito.
Oh, that's right.
You're tough.
I forgot.
The soldiers are coming into towns,
making sure the laws are being enforced.
I came from Europe over 70 years ago,
when I was just 7 years old.
Would they really kick out
an old man like me?
From what I hear,
they probably will.
There have been spontaneous
protests all over Mexico.
A resistance is forming,
and Rome, uh-Rome is taking
too long to respond.
An armed resistance?
Let's pray it doesn't come to that.
But...
It may become inevitable.
That's a mistake.
Our Savoir is the Prince of Peace.
But the Bible also says
there is a time for peace,
a time for war.
We cannot allow the godless
to take away our freedom.
If need be,
we must stand up and resist.
Even if I were younger,
I would not fight.
You won't need to fight to help.
You can feed and shelter
the ones who come through.
Now, that I would do.
List?
List, Su Excelencia.
His Holiness Pope Pius XI
condemns the Calles Law.
Beginning midnight on August 1st,
all holy services in Mexico
will be suspended.
No puede ser.
Respeto derecho de fe!
What beautiful little girl is going to
beat me in chess today?
Me.
- You?
- Yes.
Okay, we'll see.
Periódico! Periódico!
The cathedral is being closed
at the orders of President Calles
so the government
can make an inventory
and safeguard its contents.
Let's go.
The girls will not be able to get
their confirmation, Enrique.
It's only temporary, Tulita.
Calles won't be able to sustain this.
Besides, I was sure
our daughters will survive
without the, uh, nuns
slapping their palms,
all that holy nonsense.
It is not a joke.
It may mean nothing to you,
but it means everything to me.
Daddy, does that mean
no more catechism?
So we can play now?
You can study science for now.
You know how important this is to me.
It's only temporary.
Besides, I'm sure there'll be
plenty of clandestine services.
Oh, so the girls can feel like
they are doing something shameful
when they go to Mass?
What do you want me to do?
Come.
Tula.
Go look at the hats.
Tulita...
as a military man, I can tell you
that it's only a matter of time
before Calles is overthrown.
In the meantime,
you can teach the girls at home.
Unless, of course, you want me to.
Excuse me.
Hi.
For the repeal of the Calles Law.
Oh, excellent.
Thank you.
Good luck.
Excuse me, sir.
Please, for the repeal
of the Calles Law.
Please don't misunderstand me.
I'm a good Catholic.
But you're wasting your time.
Excuse me?
What good do you think this will do?
Calles can't ignore a million signatures.
I'm sorry to say he can and he will.
But on the other hand,
an economic boycott,
that would be quite
a different matter.
Brilliant, Adriana.
This is a brilliant idea.
Thank you,
but it wasn't mine.
It is very, very ambitious.
But why not?
A big sacrifice.
Only buy what we
absolutely need.
A type of Lent,
but this will attest to our faith.
And it will humble Calles.
Hello, Jose.
It seems Dr. Limón
has lost his watch.
Have you found anything
while you've been sweeping?
No, Padre.
Oh.
He must have lost it
somewhere else.
You're a good sweeper, Jose,
but I think you'd be a better altar boy.
Well done.
I'm proud of you.
What did I tell you?
You cannot be soft with these people.
They confuse reason with weakness.
I showed restraint.
What did they do?
Become more rebellious,
more insolent.
The purpose of this boycott
is very evident.
They want to wreck the economy
and bring our government down.
Congress rejected the petition.
There will be no stopping
the uprisings now.
The boycott is working.
They're afraid, and it's showing.
It's not easy.
We have thousands of supporters
all over the country.
We can do this.
So, I tried.
Followed your advice.
Did not work.
So now, the next message I send
will be unmistakably clear.
Alto ya!
Vamos!
Ya!
Vamos ya!
Ayúdanos!
Mas duro!
Saquen los niños!
Sangre de Cristo!
No! No! Stop it! No!
Thank God, Adriana.
You're so lucky.
They thought you were dead.
Calles is a monster.
I know.
We must find another
peaceful solution.
Anacleto, the armed conflict
has already begun.
I say we support the rebellion.
They'll need food, medicine.
And ammunition.
We can support them
with communication and funds...
but we will not fight.
I kneel the first time.
Ring.
Then when I bring the Host up here,
ring the bell.
And then I go down again.
Right?
Finally.
He's teaching me to be an altar boy.
You?
I thought you were being punished.
Hmm.
Don Enrique, we have a problem
with milling machine four.
Grab those there.
Ay.
Beautiful.
Look at this.
Charles Lindbergh
crosses the Atlantic solo.
Me? I am here,
going mad surrounded by pink soap.
You have a beautiful family
and enough memories of battle
to last a lifetime.
Memories.
You live in your memories,
you're already dead.
I saw you at the church.
Are you a gardener now?
Maybe an altar boy.
Really?
Marilena!
I'll see you later.
The federales are coming!
They're coming!
Padre, the federal soldiers are coming.
You must hide.
Hide? I'm too old to hide.
Please, Father, come with me.
You can hide at our house.
Would I hide from God?
This is my home.
I'm safe here, Joselito.
Jose, who are you
if you don't stand up
for what you believe?
There is no greater glory
than to give your life for Christ.
Now...
go.
Please, Father.
Go, and run fast.
God bless you.
Let this be a lesson
to any of you who help
the traitorous Cristeros.
Ya!
Apunten...
ya!
Stop.
Fuego!
Jose. Mi amor.
Estas bien?
Thank the Lord.
Mi amor.
They killed Father Christopher.
I told him he could come here.
He wouldn't come with me.
I should have made him come with me.
Jose...
it was very brave of you to try.
Can't Godfather punish them?
Your padrino's a mayor...
but even he has no power
over the federales.
Anacleto Gonzalez Flores?
Yes?
This is the most I could get.
Umberto, God bless you.
We need to take
five belts each if you can.
Let me show you.
Hello, Padre.
It is prohibited to say Mass,
Padre Robles.
I forgive you, my son.
Ya!
Captain.
Please. What do you want?
Money?
I can get you money.
Spend it in hell, cabron.
We have over 20,000 men
who call themselves
defenders or populists.
Most don't even know
of each other's existence.
That's why we need
a commander in chief
and a central command.
What about your military friends?
Well, they suggested
Enrique Gorostieta...
an experienced, decorated general
and strategist.
He defeated Zapata.
I know of him.
I doubt he's sympathetic to our cause.
I don't even think he's Catholic.
We are not hiring him to pray.
He is a great man
capable of doing great things.
Close your eyes,
and sleep with the angels.
I'll try.
Okay.
Close your eyes.
My mother brought us
that vase from Sevilla.
Sorry, Mother.
You looking for me?
He has to be dead.
Let's go in.
You go first.
Okay?
Come on.
Come out, cabron.
Got you surrounded.
We heard they rode by Chucho's.
We came as fast as we could.
Are you all right?
Who else came to help you?
Go get the rest of the guns
and the ammunition
and their horses.
We're Cristeros now, boys!
How many?
- Six.
Four here.
Four there.
14.
Catorce.
Miguel Gomez Loza.
Enrique Gorostieta.
Sit down, please.
I represent the National League
for the Defence of Religious Liberty.
Maybe you have heard us
referred to as the League.
I have heard you called
by another name,
Cristeros.
Surely you don't support Calles.
No.
He's a barbarian
and a fool.
There are uprisings
all around the country.
Over 20,000 men,
but no leader.
No leader?
I am not what you might call
a devout believer.
We propose to hire you
to turn our armed resistance
into a formidable army.
An army?
I thank you, sir,
for a most generous offer.
Okay, let's make an army.
Let's make a, uh, formidable army
out of a group of ragtag peasants
in huaraches...
out of a few game ranchers,
out of some tender footed clergy
who are trembling at the thought
of holding a weapon for the first time.
You want me to make
a national guard out of that?
Look at me.
Do you have proper weapons? No.
Do you have
an ammunition supply? No.
a central command? No.
How many is that?
Three no's.
All you have is belief,
and belief will not save them in battle.
A central command?
The League has an extensive
secret network all over Mexico.
Weapons, ammunition?
From dissenters
within the army itself
and soldiers we have defeated.
Surely you have read about
our victories in your paper.
And your defeats.
General, that's why
we want to hire you.
And suppose I'm interested
in your offer.
What are your finances?
You going to pay me in prayers?
Tell me what you want,
and I will bring it back to the League.
I don't think the Cristeros
can afford me.
The question here is,
where does the finest general
in Mexico want to serve?
If I don't take these photographs,
who will?
Who will record this barbarity
that wouldn't be believed?
Why didn't they shoot you?
Heh.
I always promise them a portrait.
10 seconds.
Miguel.
Mijo, what happened?
Are you all right?
Yes, Father.
There was a big battle.
Bullet went right through my ankle.
They killed my horse.
Hi.
I will get Dr. Limón.
No, no, no, no.
It's better if no one knows.
No one will know.
I have known him for almost 30 years.
Will he be all right?
Yes.
Boys, time to go.
Don't tell anyone what you saw here.
Viva!
Viva Cristo Rey!
Viva El Catorce!
El Catorce!
There you go, Padre.
Thank you, Pablo.
The legendary El Catorce.
Victoriano Ramirez.
My brother Pablo.
Hey.
They should be here, Pablo.
Bring them inside.
Where is the general?
I'm sorry.
I didn't introduce myself.
General Jose Reyes Vega.
You're General Vega?
Yes.
You're a priest.
I'm a priest.
A priest general, huh?
Oh. All right.
Some water?
Uh, what else do you have?
Some tequila. Help yourself.
You know, I-
I heard that your last battle
didn't go so well.
Now I know why.
Really? Maybe-
Maybe priests shouldn't
be generals. Hmm?
Of course, we didn't know
you would be fighting so close.
Did you know that you drove
the federales right into our camp
when we were completely unprepared?
You were completely unprepared?
And this is my fault?
I'm saying we should
be working together.
Under whose command?
The League appointed me
commander.
Well, I don't know anything
about any League, Padre.
I'm fighting for Cristo Rey
y la Virgen de Guadalupe.
And I'm responsible
for my own men.
Together,
we would be much stronger.
We'll stay out of your way.
We're going to Autlan.
Jose, women are here
with ammunition.
Bring Adriana in.
The what?
The women
with the ammunition.
Que viva Cristo Rey, Padre.
Que viva.
I also brought three nurses.
God bless you, Adriana.
God bless you,
and thank you, ladies.
You are as important
to this war as any soldier.
- Gracias, Padre.
- Si, Padre.
God bless you.
Padre. Excuse me, Padre.
You think that's right to involve
the women like this?
Our Catholic sisters
are a big part of this war.
Without them bringing
ammunition, food,
taking care of the wounded,
all would be lost.
Ah.
All right.
Do you need ammo, guns?
No, no, no.
You keep the ladies'
ammunition, Padre.
We've got plenty from
the federales we've killed.
What is the occasion?
Hmm.
- Salud.
An attorney for the League
representing the Cristeros
came to see me today.
They want to hire me
to command their rebellion.
You?
Yes.
Well, how ironic.
You cannot fight for something
you don't believe in.
I may have issues with the Church,
but I believe in religious freedom.
And I believe in you.
And if I'm successful,
the church bells will ring freely again,
and our girls,
they can continue their catechism.
You are really considering this?
Yes.
Tulita, I have asked them
for 3,000 pesos a month.
That's twice what
the federal generals make.
Plus 50,000 in insurance
for you and the girls.
They've agreed to everything.
50,000 if you die.
I'm not going to die.
So you have it all figured out?
And where do I and the girls fit in this?
Tulita, listen to me.
I'm dying here.
I'm a military man.
You knew that when you married me.
You a Cristero?
You are an atheist.
Are you awake?
Yes.
You were right.
It would be hypocritical.
I'm going to turn 'em down.
You may have nothing you believe in, but I do.
I believe in what you
would be fighting for.
Maybe by doing it, you will, too.
Just come back to me, General...
to us...
to the loving man I married.
I promise.
The American secretary of State-
Como se llama el gringo ese?
Mr. Kellogg.
Kellogg...
is making the outrageous remark
that Bolshevik forces
are at work in Mexico
and stating
that we have to guarantee
the life and property
of every U.S. citizen in Mexico.
What does he think I am?
Mexico will not tolerate
foreign governments
meddling in our internal affairs.
Thank you for coming.
Not at all.
Dwight, do you speak any Spanish?
Just a little.
Look, I'll be blunt.
Our ambassador to Mexico
has botched things, badly.
You revamped the aviation policy.
You've been General Pershing's
right-hand man.
I think you can handle
ambassador to Mexico.
Cal. Cal, my dear friend,
I'm honored.
Don't answer now.
Think about it.
Talk it over with Elizabeth.
What's the real story?
President Calles is repealing
the Bucareli Agreements.
50 years, and our oil concessions
are finished.
And what would you like me
to do, Mr. President?
What you always do.
Fix it.
Let's be frank.
You called them Bolsheviks.
I was simply
calling a spade a spade.
Would you have us just roll over
and let them steal our oil fields?
And just how do you
think offending them
is going to help our cause?
President Coolidge
wants a diplomatic approach.
I'm convinced he's right.
Half of Europe just became
the Soviet Union.
We need Mexico
in more ways than one.
Well, I warn you from experience
that there's no negotiating with Calles.
Thank you for your assessment
and your advice,
but I am the current
ambassador to Mexico.
The results of your tenure
speak for themselves.
Now, why am I getting all this pressure
from the Knights of Columbus
about this conflict between Calles
and the Church?
Conflict?
Oh, that's nothing.
We're Cristeros, and we're taking
the gold off this train.
Viva Cristo Rey.
You see?
Que viva.
It's all right. Stand aside.
That's it.
Excellent, Pablo.
We are only after the gold.
We are Cristeros.
Don't be afraid.
Get the passengers off the train.
You did it, Pablito.
Well done!
Pablo! Pablo!
Pablo.
Pablo. No, no. Pablo.
Aca.
Francisco.
Francisco!
Take the dynamite.
Blow the safe.
Clear the people from this area!
Andalé! Forma fila!
Muévase! Muévase!
Clear this area!
We're blowing the safe!
Camine! Camine!
Come on.
Vamonos!
It's lit, sir.
Muevete! Muevete!
Are all the passengers out?
Yes, sir, they are.
Then what are you waiting for?
Set fire to this train!
Andalé! Apurate!
Hágale! Hágale!
We got it, all of it.
Fuego!
These so-called Cristeros
burned hundreds
of innocent people alive.
The Mexican government has proof
that the Roman Catholic Episcopate
ordered this atrocity.
Bishops have agreed
to leave the country,
avoiding responsibility,
and abandon Mexico.
General, everything's ready.
You can communicate to troops
in any area through us.
Our best undercover operative
will accompany you.
This is for you.
And viva Cristo Rey.
Caballeros,
General Enrique Gorostieta.
And what's this catrin you hire
like you hire a whore
going to do for us?
Who is this ranch hand
who has already decided
that his military strategy
is better than that
of a twice-decorated general
who fought with Huerta?
Why should we trust you?
Because I know
how to lead an army.
This is not about killing 14,
Victoriano Ramirez.
It's about winning the war,
and war is chess.
Teniente.
I've been following this war very closely.
The federales, they control the trains
and the towns the trains go through.
The outlying towns
and villages will be ours.
There will be no reason to fight
lined up in front of each other
like ancient knights.
We will fight with lightning
attacks from the wings,
and before they know
what happened to them,
the Cristeros will be gone.
We will not attack from one side,
but from two and sometimes three,
like a jimador and his machete.
Understood?
How many armed men
and cavalry do we have?
General Vega.
I know who you are.
I have 4,000 men and 100 cavalry.
Good.
General Pedroza.
I have 2,000 at your service,
comandante.
I have 700 armed rancheros
on horseback,
and I will command my own men.
And you will take orders from me.
Like hell, I will.
Then why are you here?
I don't know.
Well, I do.
You wanted to meet me.
You knew that we needed
a central command,
and you wanted to see
what kind of man I was.
So I will tell you,
and I will tell you all.
I am a veteran of two wars,
and I was promoted to general
when I was very young...
for a specific reason,
because I have a gift.
Yes, I have a gift-
for military strategy.
And he's humble, too.
I am now the commander
of this army.
If you don't show respect,
you can go.
Now.
Go.
Go to the hills,
and continue to fight.
Raid villages until you
are shot or hanged.
Go.
So you stay.
Good.
General Vega.
The entire world has heard
about the priest
who burned people alive.
You gave Calles exactly
what he needed,
a way to demonize us,
so now public support for our cause
has been severely compromised.
Those are more of Calles' lies.
Lies?
They have raped and killed women
in front of their children,
marched them for days and days,
left them to die in corrals
like diseased cattle.
They have taken priests-
So you're here for revenge?
Is that it, Padre?
Is that why you're here?
Because if you are,
you can go home
and pray to God
that He may forgive you.
Because we are now an army.
We are an army fighting for God
and for the Church...
and for absolute freedom.
We must work together,
me and you.
We might die together,
But we will fight with honor...
and dignity...
and with cunning...
and by the grace of God...
we will be victorious.
Viva Cristo Rey.
God bless you, Father.
Now all the devils burning in hell
will enjoy your art.
Stop!
- Please, sir, stop!
- Stop what?
Mayor Picazo is my padrino.
Mayor Picazo knows we are here.
Please, sir, I'm begging you.
Get out of here.
Get out of here!
Padrino! They have Miguel.
They're going to kill him.
I know.
I know, Jose.
I know, uh-
I know all about him.
He is a well-known Cristero.
He killed a federal sergeant.
They've been waiting for him
to come back
to that subversive father of his.
But his father never did anything.
Don't think I don't know
where you were last night.
And I saved your life this time, Jose,
but I'm warning you.
These are dark times.
I won't be able to do it again.
Now get out.
We're going to join the Cristeros.
Cristeros.
How?
They'll say we're too young.
They won't take us.
Not if we tell them
they will kill us here.
Come on, Lalo.
You and me,
together.
Not ours.
Where did you find it, son?
There.
Someone's smuggling ammunition.
- Check the station.
- Open your bag.
What's going on?
They've raided and closed
every one of the League offices.
Many have been arrested,
and God knows how many
have been tortured or killed by now.
We need your help.
I can't help you.
The more and more I think,
Anacleto was right.
All this violence
has gotten us nowhere.
I understand.
But I need you to take
this to Gorostieta.
No, Miguel.
Adriana, this is critical,
contact information
for all our principal members.
Without this, there will be
no central command.
You would go without saying goodbye?
I can't stay here, Mother.
Not while my friends and brothers
are joining the Cristeros.
I need to fight.
Que Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe...
te bendiga, mi amor.
May she watch over...
and protect you.
T ell Papa I love him.
You will need a horse.
Are you ready?
Let's go.
Calles' revenge.
Revenge for what I did.
Yes! Revenge for what you did!
Teniente.
General.
These Christians must be buried.
Today we will become
an army of gravediggers.
You think it suits me?
Well...
anything that covers that face of yours.
- Mm.
- Gracias, señora.
De nada. De nada.
Oh, it must be Señora Hernandez
needing her medicine.
We are eating.
People count on us, Jorge.
Just a minute.
Good evening.
I need some medicine for my son.
Can you please help me?
Of course, dear boy.
Uh, give me one second,
and I'll get the keys.
Thank you.
The police are here.
Let's go. Quickly.
I'll handle the door.
To the passageway.
- No, Anacleto. No.
- Hey, hey, hey.
I'll be right behind you.
- No, Anacleto.
- Go.
Go! Go! Go!
It's very late. Can you please
come back in the morning?
I'm sorry?
Open the door.
Anacleto Gonzalez Flores?
Or is it Don Jose?
I am Anacleto.
We know exactly what
peaceful work you're doing.
We hope your friends learn
from your mistakes.
May God bless
and forgive you, sir.
I do.
Jose?
Yes?
Do you ever wonder about God?
Yes.
I'm scared.
Me, too.
But Jesus is watching over us, Lalo.
Since when did you become a priest?
I'm no priest.
But I believe it.
I know it.
Good night, Jose.
Good night.
Quien vive?
Viva Cristo Rey.
Get down.
Stomach!
Down!
Hold the positions.
We want to see the general, sir.
He's too busy to talk to you.
Turn around and go home.
We won't leave until we
talk to the general.
Go home, now!
Teniente!
Who wants to talk to me?
These boys, sir.
Go. Now.
Go. Let's go!
Rapido!
Why are you here?
We want to be Cristeros, mi General.
And why do you want to be Cristeros?
The padre of the church of Sahuayo...
was killed...
in front of me.
He was teaching me to be an altar boy.
Marta! Get these young men
something to eat!
Si, mi General.
Go.
Gracias, mi General.
You must be hungry.
Come on.
Get up!
War is no place for bums.
Enjoy.
General, can you teach me to shoot?
It would not be right in the eyes of God
to make you soldiers.
We can fight.
Yes, I know you could fight,
but it'd be better for you
to serve the cause
by helping out around the camp.
What I need is for you to show me
that you're good workers
and that you're disciplined.
Like this?
May the body
of Our Lord Jesus Christ
preserve your soul
unto everlasting life.
May the body
of Our Lord Jesus Christ
preserve your soul
unto everlasting life.
May the body
of Our Lord Jesus Christ
preserve your soul
unto everlasting life.
Amen.
You need to confess first.
Wouldn't He already know?
You should confess.
May the body
of Our Lord Jesus Christ
preserve your soul
unto everlasting life.
Un honor conocerlo.
Good to have you here.
Thank you.
Mmm.
You like Mexican food?
Well, don't get much of it
in New Jersey,
but this, just delicious.
It's called mole poblano.
It's made with chocolate.
Chocolate. Hmm.
One of Mexico's pre-Colombian
gifts to the world.
Oh, this is magnificent.
Thank you. What are
your impressions of Mexico?
Well, I've traveled in Mexico
numerous times,
and, uh, you know,
I'm always charmed.
And it's-it's interesting,
invariably I discover something
that connects our two countries,
chocolate and petroleum
being two of them.
American oil companies have been
granted a 50-year concession
that I consider very generous.
Please sit.
Well, I understand there are some
in Washington
who don't see it that way.
We've been following your war
with the Catholic Church.
I would hardly call it a war.
Terrible, what happened on the train.
They were led by a priest.
What does that tell you about
their so-called moral superiority?
51 people burned alive.
Barbaric.
But surely that doesn't represent
the entire Catholic population.
In my experience, it's small groups
of extremists that start wars.
In my experience as a revolutionary,
a small group of determined men
can bring down a government,
and that is why every Catholic aggression
must be responded to immediately,
forcefully, and without hesitation.
And if we continue talking politics,
we're going to ruin our digestions.
Ambassador, salud.
Salud.
Bienvenido a Mexico.
Hey!
- Victoriano.
- Eh?
Don't go through the canyon
to Tlaquepaque.
It's a trap.
How do you know that?
My scout was there yesterday.
Let's just say it's a gut feeling.
An ambush is what
I would do if I was them.
Let me ask you something, General.
I'm just curious.
If we die, if you lose this war-
We're not going to lose this war.
If you lose this war,
do you still get paid all the money?
Or do you get, like, half?
I'm just curious.
You want something from me, Flaco?
If we die, we all die,
but my family will be taken care of.
That's very good for your family.
We'll go through the canyon.
Of course you will.
Go with God, then.
Hyah! Hyah!
Mi General,
why did you let him
disrespect you that way?
Up in the rocks!
They're up in the rocks!
Take cover!
Que viva Cristo Rey!
Wait here!
Viva Cristo Rey.
Que viva.
Hyah.
Muevanse, muchachos.
Jose!
Mi General.
Chamaco's very happy to see you.
He's very tired.
I heard you saved Victoriano
even though he said those things.
A man like Victoriano,
respect is won.
Look at him. Come here.
Look how beautiful he is.
He's a Friesan.
His name means "little child. "
He's a legendary war horse
from northern Europe.
In the Middle Ages, he would carry
armored knights and kings into battle.
His owner gave him to us
specifically for our cause.
He's the only one
of its kind in all of Mexico.
Go.
Say hello.
What's it like to ride him?
You tell me.
He'll need to be exercised
tomorrow morning.
But you have to be gentle on the reins.
He has a very sensitive mouth.
And he's very fast.
He loves to run,
so you have to hold on tight.
Hey, Chamaco.
Bello Chamaco.
But what's it like to ride him?
It's like being close to heaven.
Jose.
I've never had a son, but if I did,
I would want him to be just like you.
Que viva Cristo Rey.
Que viva!
Bueno.
...meijor fortificacion.
Pero cuanta gente
tenemos en esta area?
Aqui en esta area, tenemos
unas dos mil tropas-
Senor Presidente.
Mi General Ortiz
and almost 500 men are dead.
Ortiz?
That's impossible.
Who told you that?
A counterambush, sir.
Cristeros hired Enrique Gorostieta
as commander
of all the Cristero forces.
General Gorostieta is behind this?
He fought with Huerta, sir.
I know.
I know that.
What I don't know
is how could someone like Ortiz
be so incompetent?
Gorostieta.
His treason will not be
forgotten nor forgiven.
Do you understand?
Go to Los Altos immediately.
Bring all the men you can.
Yes, Mr. President.
Go.
Go!
Gorostieta is back in politics?
Yes, sir.
But I know him.
His heart is not in this.
Find out what he really wants.
What he-
Porfirio Diaz used to say,
"A dog with a bone in his mouth
doesn't bark and doesn't bite. "
In politics, everything has a price.
Go find his.
How was the ride?
Like flying, sir.
Come here.
Tomorrow morning,
I'm going to lead the men into battle.
Want to carry the flag?
It would be an honor, sir.
We leave at first light.
Today we are going to
send a message.
We are going to send a message to Calles
and to the rest of the world...
that freedom is not just for writers
and for politicians and-
and for fancy documents!
Freedom-
Freedom is our home,
our wives, our children, our faith.
Freedom is our lives...
and we will defend it or die trying!
It is not only our duty to defend it,
but it is our right!
You must remember that men
will fire bullets,
but God decides where they land!
Que viva Cristo Rey!
Que viva!
- Que viva Cristo Rey!
- Que viva!
My dearest Tulita...
today was a magnificent day,
and not simply because
we routed the federales
in our greatest victory yet.
There is a change
in the spirit of my men,
a transformation
I can see in their eyes.
They finally believe
we can win this war.
I know the federales
can sense this, too.
The scent of fear now blows
from their camps.
We must strike them harder now,
push them back
so the people will be emboldened
to support us in the cities.
Then Calles and his army
will have nowhere to hide.
My strategy cannot fail us,
and I will be home before long.
Keep me close in your heart, my love,
and I will see you again tonight
in my dreams.
This-This war
has Americans and other foreigners
reluctant to do business
or even visit,
and I wonder if...
you can see your way
to some kind of compromise.
No.
But if your country and my country
would strengthen their ties...
this could end very quickly.
That's not what I had in mind.
Actual military support is-
of course, is out of the question,
but I think a provision could be made
for the sale of American
machine guns and aircraft.
When can I get the planes?
Well, Mr. President,
first we need the gesture of goodwill.
Now, I think a different position
on American petroleum interests
would go a long way.
I will bring your generous offer
to Congress.
Forward!
Mi General, here's my horse.
Hey. Hey, what are you doing?
Come here. Come on.
Get on the horse.
You'll be faster alone, mi General.
What are you doing?
Get on the horse.
Sorry, mi General.
Get on the hor-
Jose!
They're going to kill you!
Get on the horse!
I'll be fine, mi General.
Stay low, Jose!
I'll come back for you!
- Take cover!
- Do it!
Viva Cristo Rey.
Que viva.
Jose!
You took his horse?
You took a boy's horse?
He refused to get on.
It was either him or me.
Is he dead?
I don't know.
I looked for him myself.
He wasn't among the dead.
I think he either escaped to the forest
or he was captured.
Send two men. Search for him.
I already sent men to the forest.
He'll be all right.
He's braver than most men.
This is true.
Leave me alone.
Get my horse ready.
Oh, God.
Victoriano.
That is my boy.
We let him down.
He inspires me,
and we let him down.
This is, um-
Here.
I found that...
where I left him.
That was his.
Jose!
Thank you.
How are you?
Not good.
A scout tells us that General Rodriguez
is heading towards Tepatitlan
to set up headquarters.
This will be one of the most
important battles of our struggle.
I'm entrusting it to you...
with Pedroza and Victoriano
under your command.
I'm ready, Commander.
You, Pedroza and Victoriano
will be in Tepatitlan in two days.
We can pull some more troops in.
If you get there first,
it will not be necessary.
You go into the city.
You look for vantage points-
buildings, rooftops, behind walls,
sheltered places.
There will be not one Cristero in sight.
Padre, can't you see the gun?
We have to attack now.
Hyah!
What the hell is he doing?
Fuego!
Catorce!
Did we get the-
Did we get the machine gun?
Yes.
Yes. Yes.
Okay.
Viva Cristo Rey.
Que viva.
In nomine Patris
et Fili et Spiritus Sanctus.
Well done, Victoriano.
Ah, Lalo.
- Lalo, are you a strong rider?
- Yes, sir.
I want you to ride
like the wind to Sahuayo.
Find out if Jose is there.
You report back to me
as soon as possible.
Yes, sir.
You're only alive because
the capitan knows your padrino.
Are they going to kill us?
I don't want to die.
I'm scared, too, Lorenzo.
This is what happens when you don't
tell me what I need to know.
Pull.
No! No!
Muevete.
Get out!
I'm going to take you home, Jose.
I'm going to take you home.
Just-Just say the words.
"Death to Cristo Rey.
Long live the federal government. "
No, Padrino.
They're just words.
I- I can't, Padrino.
Just f-for your mother.
Viva Cristo Rey.
Your luck has run out.
- Bishop Diaz?
- Yes.
- Bishop Ruiz?
Dwight Morrow.
What a pleasure.
The pleasure is ours,
Mr. Ambassador.
Would you care for some tea?
Please join us.
Oh, superb, superb.
The prospects of the trip
have improved already.
Mr. Ambassador...
who actually invited us?
It's important to everyone.
And I've been working
with President Calles
to try and find a solution
to this madness.
We are ready to listen
and to bring the message to Rome.
Well, I know Rome
and the top prelates
have not publicly claimed support
for the Cristeros,
but neither have they disowned them.
And in this situation,
their silence is deafening.
This whole thing has been-
It's been an unnecessary tragedy.
And Calles himself sees that now,
and he's ready to find a compromise
with the Church.
What is critical is that we reach
an agreement soon
so that the killings stop
and services can begin again in peace,
and with peace comes
stability and prosperity.
Peace and stability, Mr. Ambassador?
Gentlemen, would you excuse me
for a moment?
Of course.
Jose.
Lalo.
The general sent me
to see if you were here.
You have to go.
La Guada could see you.
Hold on.
I'm in God's hands, Lalo.
Go. Before they see you.
A complete pardon
for the entire Cristero army?
What should we do with
their leadership?
Give them a parade with confetti
all the way up to Chapultepec Castle?
Well, the pardon must be universal,
specifically including the leadership,
or there won't be an accord.
How many men did you lose
with General Rodriguez in Tepatitlan?
5,000? 6,000?
Just how many more
are you prepared to lose?
And Rome?
Will it accept the other terms?
I believe I can arrange a meeting
with the bishops
to confirm their support.
Before I give you my answer,
there is something I need to do first.
What's that?
Go see an old friend.
Frankly, I thought you would not come.
You came to me.
This is Cristero country.
This is Mexico, Enrique.
Please join me.
How's the family?
Your wife, Tulita?
She's very excited.
Church bells will be
ringing freely very soon.
Salud.
Viva Cristo Rey.
Your war is coming to an end very soon.
You're here to concede?
Not quite, no.
It's not my war.
It's your war.
You declared war on freedom.
I know you for a long time,
and I know you're not a fool,
so you must know this war
is not about freedom,
and it's not about religion.
It's about who is going to decide
the fate of Mexico and its people.
Well, the people of Mexico
have spoken.
They did speak when they elected me
President, not you.
I run things in this country.
Not for long.
An agreement is being discussed.
Mexico and Rome
are going to make peace.
An agreement?
No one wants this war anymore, Enrique.
Mexico is bleeding on its own fields.
Mexico is hanging from telegraph poles
from Monterrey to Veracruz.
Of course you need an agreement.
But freedom has no compromise.
By definition, it is absolute,
and that's why we will be victorious.
Keep your agreement.
Please spare me
your rhetorical idealism
and tell me,
what do you really want?
Absolute freedom.
Is that in the agreement?
The agreement is all but sealed.
This is yours, your agreement.
It's not ours.
You're holding your fate in your hands.
The fate of Mexico,
the destiny of Mexico...
it's in God's hands,
not yours or mine.
Que viva Cristo Rey.
The American Ambassador Morrow
has made a preliminary agreement
between the government
of Mexico and Rome.
An agreement?
What kind of an agreement?
The Church has been asked
to forgo half of its demands.
In return, the government will loosen
some restrictions on the clergy.
What does that mean exactly?
The extreme laws will be rescinded.
Others will be...
officially unenforced.
And then what?
With Rome's blessing,
the church bells could be
ringing again within a month.
My brother died for this.
For what?
Mi General,
what should we do?
We will defeat this government,
we will overthrow Calles,
and we will establish
a democratic government
that respects
the rights of the people!
Especially the basic right
to worship God in peace.
And with God on our side,
we will prevail.
I wish I had your faith.
Jose's faith.
I don't know where to find it.
If your heart's open,
it might find you.
In a few seconds,
you're going to beg me
to let you spit on Cristo Rey.
Jesus nos da fuerzas!
Do you have anything to tell me?
Viva Cristo Rey!
And what about going through Colotlan
to get to get to Tlaltenango?
No, better through Aguascalientes.
It's safer.
General! They have Jose.
They're going to kill him.
- In Sahuayo?
- Yes, sir.
Teniente, you plus 10 men come with me!
- The rest, return to camp!
- Si, mi General.
Desmonte. Vaya.
10 caballos y 10 jinetes
con el General.
El resto se regresa
al campamento. Ya!
Ho! Hah!
J ust say the words.
You can go home.
I love you.
Viva Cristo Rey.
I'm going home.
Why couldn't I save him?
You tried.
What kind of God
would allow that to happen?
God allows us
the freedom to choose.
Some choose to be evil.
But God can take even
the most horrific events
and use them for good.
Like the cross.
Maybe Jose wasn't supposed to be saved.
How could you even say that?
He-He was just a little boy.
He had a whole life in front of him.
Even as a boy...
he was a martyr.
We never know what God has in mind.
What God has in mind?
What does He have in mind?
That Rome should turn its back on us...
and all the people that have
given their lives for Him?
That's what He has in mind?
Who are you going to obey?
Rome or me?
I am a priest first, mi comandante.
You can still be a priest,
after everything you've done?
I will always be a priest.
And I will pray every day...
for our merciful God to forgive me.
What about me?
Will you pray for me?
Will you pray for what I've done?
Better pray hard.
Check.
I resign. I'm tired.
I miss my wife Tulita and the girls.
This young man died for us!
Viva Cristo Rey.
Vega!
How many?
I don't know.
I want to confess.
- Now?
- Now.
We need to make a run for the horses,
get to a safe position.
Let's go around the back.
Are you a priest first, or aren't you?
Didn't you say not to worry about
those who can kill the body,
but those who can kill the soul?
It was something like that.
So... you were listening.
Ego te absolvo a peccatis tuis,
in nomine Patris
et Fili et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
Padre, this is between you and me.
And Him.
They're everywhere!
- They're all on the roof.
- Come on.
Not for long.
Bullets.
How are you feeling?
Viva Cristo Rey.
Viva Cristo Rey!
Follow me.
Disparen!
Ready?
Load up.
Padre, can you confess yourself?
No.
Then I will try.
Padre Vega is a good man.
He served You well,
as well as he could,
and that's all anyone can ask of us,
so forgive him...
and have mercy on us both.
Amen.
Padre!
Okay, stay with me.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Teniente!
Gather the horses.
I want the men and Padre Vega
out of here immediately.
Okay, talk to me.
Stay with me. T alk to me.
Your confession...
You make a better general
than a priest.
Mi General.
Okay, here we go.
Teniente, what they want is me.
Get the men back to El Lucero.
And get Padre Vega to a doctor...
- and a real priest.
- Mi General-
Do as I say.
Padre, que viva-
Padre! Padre!
Que viva Cristo Rey!
Que viva.
Que viva!
Cristeros!
Viva Cristo Rey!
Fuego directo!
We never know
what God has in mind.
You cannot fight for something
you don't believe in.
I believe in religious freedom,
and I believe in you.
God allows us
the freedom to choose.
I believe in what you
would be fighting for.
Maybe by doing it, you will, too.
God can take even the most horrific events
and use them for good.
Viva Cristo Rey.
Que viva.