warwerwor
fb:ozmonkingkong@yahoo.co.id
suster_myud
www.burnyozmon.blogspot.com
Dragan Milevic
War Criminals
On the count of three!
Dad came home!
Lying! Lie down! Lie down!
Do not move!
Bebaring!
Everything!
Lying!
Safe!
Prroklet!
Bastard!
Oh, sorry!
Afghanistan, Kabul
Are you ready?
Yes
What are you doing?
There's nothing to hide.
Do you remember
the first time to Kabul?
Sure.
Sorry.
I once sold a story about a girl
to the debt collectors.
And you say,
Addons is the only way
to change the world ...
Addons are changing the story,  /
Yes I remember
Now I tell my story.
My mother loved someone, but was forced
marry someone else.
As children, we watched with
wash away the shame of infidelity.
Then one day ...
He went to the page, and ..
pour petrol ... and lit a match.
That same night my sister
Aisaa ...
slashed by her husband on the face,
as punishment for her mother
who is very poor.
girls are sold, it's you right?
Why did you tell it now?
to protect you from Zaef.
Zaef then what?
How do you think I am so
know about him?
Zaef is a family where I was sold.
Why did you take the risk of appearing
in front of the camera?
Since this last time we met.
What are you talking about?
Elsa, Zaef already know everything!
I am so sorry, I must go now.
Maina, wait,
stay here!
I can help, please
come with me!
You should go and change my story,
Go home and do not come back.
Amin, not now
Maina!
The house had been caught / Maina!
You have to get out. You and Maina
have to go now!
Who are they?
You hear  / Damn.
Elsa, out now!
Both me to the car.
He's gone.
We have to find it.
Forget it.
He was in danger,
we went to his house alone.
We will be in jeopardy if
go there!
Amen, come on!
Turn here.
Heads down, down
Quick!
Addons FRENCH
Special Base Unit Addons
Why are you angry? Listen to me.
I can explain!
It may
I met my mother.
Of course, her mom hates me
Do not slam the door, please!
Not hate, and
let's just immature.
Immature?
it is not yet mature.
I'm just saying he does not ..
It's only a car accident ..
You did not tell him?
No.
Look, I think I
immature?
Immature?
Forget it.
OK.
What is the problem?
Lisa wanted to live together in a ..
Since you are together?
One, five years, how did you meet?
Yes, I know the time elapsed
without realizing it ... and then ...
I'll sell the car, and get
Labrador
so I need
personal space was painted blue ... !
Happy birthday to you / Thank you.
Thank you.
KABUL
Hotel Merindi
What would you do?
Elsa?
maybe it's time
to take leave?
Pick me up in two hours.
unbearable.
Compass has been saving lives around the
troops, as it was landing in Normandy.
The place is in the museum
We all agreed to give it to you.
Happy birthday, my brother!
Addons Happy Birthday  / Thanks!
many ...
Saleymani can help us find him.
Maine was gone, no more can be done.
I can not just leave!
Saleymani!
Here!
Assalaamualaikum.
salam alaykum ...
Saleymani
I need your help.
I want to talk to Zaef ...
and I have to find Maina.
I'm not familiar with Zaef.
Excuse me, Elsa.
I had no choice.
Shut up. run!
Are you okay?
Yes
Stop! Rewind!
Quick! Quick!
Quick!
What happened?
Cover your face.
Slowly. Take it easy.
Do not shoot! Do not shoot!
You see Jacques / I see it, it,
Paris
Editorial  Elsa Casanova
Jacques!
The call from Secretary of State!
Yes, thank you
Hello.? Yes, Jacques Beauregard.
Yes, good afternoon
Mr. Minister ... how?
What?
What happened / I do not know?
I listen. Yes, Admiral ...
understand.
Elsa has just covered the Taliban.
PARIS
Palace Elysejska
Secret meetings
Green Office
What man in this country, can say?
Zaef was a
fanatics.
We need to save someone's life.
Do you understand?
We know its location?
Possible Ahmed Zaef
located in the village, where he
feel untouchable.
If so, we will send
special forces?
How / Conduct
When?
The plane was in the air
Mr. President.
province of Wardak in Afghanistan
Helicopter awaits you, Commander!
Equipment you received it later!
Afghanistan-Pakistan Border Addons
Gandamak Camp
Welcome to the camp Gandamak
Look man / Yes.
Now I am going to frighten him.
Let's see.
Attention, my rules are very simple!
There are left and right boundaries.
If someone over the line
Troops will get it back!
You will quickly learn
north as fast as lightning and thunder!
Back to the hole!
Now give them a shovel?
He is with us / What?
Victor! Stop shooting!
Commander has arrived
and is waiting for us.
Cool shirt! Where did you get?
Always there for us, thanks to the kids!
Superb. It really is great?
Let's go! What awaits us?
My walnut / Stop!
My canary!
Are you okay?
Forgive me, Amen.
I should hear you.
Do not be sorry.
I'm afraid.
Do not be afraid
Did you hear?
Do not show fear.
They could kill us, but will not
can win. Got it?
... Commander, captain.
Commander!
Sit back.
As you can see we have
snipers.
New and sophisticated.
How is your accuracy?
Three hundred yards to kill rabbits.
Good / Killer!
There are two news - good and bad.
Worst case:
rabbit for dinner.
The sad part:
hostage in Pakistan's tribal areas.
Damaging your birthday!
The good news is
It is the duty of intelligence.
Finally, at the shelter
... and not at the scene.
Have a question?
Of course. Elsa Casanova a journalist who
covering our presence in Afghanistan.
Another question / Yes!
Does that mean good?
Do not shoot! I beg you!
Why not ask if
you want to interview me?
It would be more civilized than
like this.
Civilized?
You call me "The Butcher of Kabul".
"The worst enemy of Afghan women"
Is not that
the title of your last article?
What are you doing at Maina?
What I did at Maina?
What lies you tell him?
I know who you are.
Your family, so beautiful,
your education ...
See now ...
sitting there,
like a dog.
seven great years in Cambridge ...
Mounir Zaef son of Khan
a very strong and
influential leaders.
But now ... sitting there with my ...
but you who want it.
What my invite
to my country
to spread democracy with
muzzle on my people?
Better than selling
daughter of twelve years.
Did not interview questions derived from
the person holding the camera.
I am sure the next question
very precise.
Do you believe in God?
Yes, I believe in God.
Harsh!
I can not read this.
Why do not you see?
LOOK!
Leave him!
Bring the pigs,
Saleymani!
Do not do it
Do not do that! Please!
Will sweeten his death.
Do not! Do not!
Please do not do this!
Do not!
Addons carrier "Charles de Gaulle"
near Pakistan
Admiral  Gezenek
Addons Commander Special Forces
Welcome to the ship, Commander.
Already approved, Admiral.
I need all the
meteorological data.
When you fly, please contact me
Kovacs.
30 minutes later
Stop it.
This is crazy!
The French should not be cut
alive in this world.
Minister when you
will gather your people?
within 24 hours.
So they can lose in this game.
Not necessarily, we've got his aces,
Mr. President.
So ... You megetahui all ...
There was little change.
What are the chances of success?
In this operation there is no guarantee,
Mr. President.
All depending on special forces.
Continue.
Victor, preparing weapons
with ammunition.
I love this!
What you say?
I love this job!
I will try.
Open the door!
Addons Day 1
Periapkan to plunge.
Thirty seconds!
Ten seconds!
Three ... two ... one ...
Green!
Pakistan
Interest areas.
Welcome to Pakistan!
One hour to get out of here.
Well maybe I can go to the store first!
Pakistan
Peshawar
Addons Pakistan Secret Service
At Zukhan Addons,
spiritual leader of the Taliban
Assalaamualaikum.
Regards Waalaikum Warohmatullohi Wabarokatuh.
Greetings to all members of the Shura.
He has not killed him!
Many of our brethren think
You do not deserve trust.
No, I can prove?
I prefer the glory, but from
The Almighty.
I am a faithful servant of Shura.
It reminded him of a prostitute,
they spent in London.
Women, is the weakness of the West ...
is not possible.
If a woman is destined to die
will be the will of God.
I am very disappointed.
Betambah very quickly.
How suddenly so much.?
Shut up, Tic-Tac
Conversely, where are they?
There is a parabola
and bars on the windows.
excellent place to relax.
movement toward 3 o'clock.
Who is it?
Quiet!
Do not shoot?
No.
Why?
We're not here for that.
understood ...
English, lah!
too much
language in today.
What would you do
with a French journalist?
I do not know ...
Really, do not know.
Move!
Elias,
do you hear us?
Yes.
On the count to "three".
One ... two ... three!
Safe!
Go!
It's them!
French troops,
We come to you!
Peace! Stay calm!
Cheers!
Elsa Casanova?
Taharud Amin?
Listen.
Follow me, okay?
Time to go,
we caught!
Back!
Heads down, down!
Next.
I'm good, everything is fine,
I'm fine!
All the shelter!
They came from all directions!
Behind us!
I can!
Elias, go!
If you hear me, go!
No, I will keep them
until they arrive.
What happened here?
Zaef!
Commando comes to pick them up!
This their equipment!
They did not give me a choice!
Start by carrying the head
snipers here! Now!
Now! Go!
Go!
Beat them soon!
Stop.
We lost two portable devices.
And this.
The helicopter will come anyway.
Show me your hands.
Slow down.
Ok.
Everything will be okay,
relaxed.
Stay near me.
Hold on to my backpack
Do you agree?
Ok / Good.
Your hands.
Thank you.
Go away.
Kinda hard to break.
Take cover behind the stone.
Check position / Coordinates?
36 North, 72 East.
We meet them behind the mountains.
will not fail to meet
at the rendezvous point.
Send emergency signs?
The Taliban can also be intercepted.
Message sent.
You go ahead, Marius.
Ok.
Where we are / We explain later?
Can I help you?
Yes, give him a gun and radio.
Look who's here!
Leader and his friends!
Damn, the whole army!
Trei, my friend!
What would it / they were angry.
Let's play!
not yet ... not yet ...
Now!
Do not know why, but every time we
press harder.
It's just because I'm a psychiatrist.
Shut up and do it.
Marius.
May I help you?
You must replace the bandages.
Must be at sewing.
Of course,
Approximate position of 22 km,
The highest point in the butt!
Note the language
There is a lady with us.
Sorry, too hot.
I remind
I am not happy with the needle.
Are you ready?
You all right?
Good ... All right.
Sign of relief.
twenty miles from the point.
Your turn?
Not in place.
Half-hour break.
Helicopters?
They have set up a meeting point.
Okay?
Sorry, already
3 days we did not eat.
Hopefully not too much trouble.
So, what do you do
had hit him.
Critics of the war,
the soldiers do not like.
and sew the rest?
Vezak stitched ... ?
It / Who would have thought.
Your analysis is very interesting.
Thank you.
I say that I agree with him.
It's our job, not politics.
It seems so hot / What is it?
Our taxi will be delayed.
there for ten minutes.
Damn!
Evacuation failed.
Wake up!
This is a failure.
does not appear.
One helicopter made an emergency landing
with the shot.
Hostages?
There is still no news about them.
Addons Day 2
We need to stop,
they were on the edge.
Stop.
Do you have a plan "B"?
No, we do not have a plan "B".
What will he decide?
Do not know.
No, I'm sure we'll like it.
Hey, Satnièe
Victor!
Eat up.
Thank you.
Commander,
what will we do?
Waters to Afghanistan
one door and it's there!
Do you mind /
What are you talking about?
The command is to bring you
we will do ...
Is there a better idea?
The best moment of fame,
but forget about eternity ...
Every minute the possibility
of their is reduced.
Do not fail
keep looking.
Full power.
How did you get here?
Parachute.
Understand well with what I mean.
Finally!
Been wondering when I would
woke up as a journalist?
What drives you?
How I ended up with the gang
in uniform?
No, I do not want to ask.
Better!
The soldiers would not be a genius!
You're too well.
Are you married?
Now not.
Do you want coffee?
What do / You know that's impossible.
Want to wait?
I hope you know what you're doing.
So do I.
You're very brave.
What is courage?
There is a brave woman
in the village.
Before the shoot, looking faces ...
I know what it was then?
laughter on their faces ...
And I do what?
No one.
Sorry, but we
just chatting.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Addons 3rd DAY
Tic-Tac.
Protect.
What can be relied upon / What?
Reliable? Yes or no?
The whole family were massacred by the Taliban.
Is that enough?
You know how to use it?
Is clear.
Thank you.
They will not give us
the opportunity.
will not let us pass.
So it seems.
Elsa? Why so angry?
This is a question of honor.
Sorry, do not you understand.
Not wanting to disturb, but they
getting closer!
He will not give up.
He needs me more than life.
The more the better.
Ignore. Let's go.
Slow down.
Damn, we were tortured for three days.
I agree. Are not you tired?
You. Stay with him.
Yes, sir.
Start Shoot!
Shoot, shoot!
Shoot! Shoot!
This! This!
Again!
Forward!
Change!
Go! !
Change! / It!
How! The attacks!
Attack!
They're like the devil!
You mean all attacks!
Why?
Hindu Kush Mountains
will kill this woman.
Look what you said?
Okli!
Western women
harder than you think!
Exit all!
All-out attack!
Addons Day 4
We're in big trouble.
"How can there be a failure"?
"Defense helpless"
Whatever you do!
I am sure there will be for us
in the mountains when to give up.
Friends or Enemies?
Passed at an altitude of five kilometers.
needs food and rest.
Say, they will succeed?
All he does is
wise ...
Ask for comfort ...
It is never rejected.
On the enemy though.
It is traditional.
Next time I'll wear a tie.
Assalamualaikum!
Greetings!
Ask him where the children?
This summer the Taliban, they take all
and 17 adults.
Why?
Entered into madrassas.
Then it will return to
implementation of Sharia doctrine.
Not surprisingly,
they do not like it.
So should you?
Good. Take it.
This is not nothing.
Maybe you will need?
Ok. Thank you.
Look!
Amen wear a suit!
Like a king.
Bravo!
Come on! Give the hat / Take it!
You're like a sponge!
I warned you.
Kovacs! !
Here / Throw!
Throw it high!
High!
Take, friends,
does not fit!
Take cover! Hide! / In the shelter! Faster!
Quick! All to the shelter!
Hide!
Marius! No!
He's dead, dead!
Victor, faster!
Leave him!
Is dead! Take it easy!
Go, go!
Hide behind the wall!
Want to pray for Marius?
An honor.
Addons Day 5
Quick! Go! Go!
Wait! Wait!
we parted,
I had to stay.
If you should die in the mountains,
prefer to die here.
Searched the house! Quick!
Quick!
This, too!
May God protect you.
Thank you for saving my life.
I'll go with him.
Amen! Wait!
Please, friend!
Amen! We can not leave it there.
Do not be a martyr.
This man has given us
comfort, are now all going to die!
No matter! Marius died, and
chicken is the journalist!
We will not take the risk because
This farmer!
Coward! Even for me!
This chicken will go with them.
It should not be!
Luke! Stay with her new boyfriend.
We will save these people.
Assalaamualaikum.
We look forward to
can welcome you in our village!
Your Excellency!
Where are they? Where did you hide them?
Where?
Kill them!
Do not know what got into me
I'm sorry.
Just in case.
Stop! Stop it! Stop it!
This, he liked this weapon.
To Marius!
Way!
Dengarkah not you,
shoot them immediately!
Go!
Damn! Shoot them right away!
Wait no more.
Quick!
Get up, come on
Hide, faster!
side!
Hide! Hide!
Hurry up!
Take cover!
I told you I like it
this work?
Not the first time I heard.
Go! Go! Go!
Way! Quick!
Go!
Victor!
Damn ... Damn ...
Victor was shot!
Wake up! Come on!
Stay with me.
Hold!
now.
Tic-Tac!
Amin was killed.
Change!
I will protect!
I'm fine, I can
Go on.
Go, go!
Damn it.
Be careful!
Here, here.
Oh, damn ...
Damn! Damn!
Need to be pressed!
What illness / Hold on here.
At the push!
Harder! Come on!
Tic-Tac, you bastard!
Amen?
Wait ... stand it!
Everything will be fine.
Wait, friend! Wait / Elijah you want to wait?
No.
Why not?
damn ...
Stop!
Sit back.
Leave me!
Leave me! Leave!
Only if you're already dead.
Survived why. Let the
Stay.
Ok.
Furthermore, we can not go.
How much altitude we?
3800, 3900
Started snowing.
Temperatures continue to drop.
This is not good.
Everything will be fine!
We must find shelter.
Victor, let's
Elsa will take refuge ..
I will warm ...
Stop yelling
Do you hear!
Ok. Come on!
Addons Day 6
Another relapsed / Hold!
Keep his feet / Keep them! Keep them!
Can use morphine?
Can!
will kill him!
Choking!
We have to open his mouth!
Give, give!
OK, Victor, already.
Wait, wait!
Breathe, breathe! Come on!
Breathe, everything is good!
Come on, come on, come on
Follow me!
All, I'll kill you all!
You're not even human!
How are you?
I'm almost gone, right?
It's important that you get back.
Tic-Tac, nine years ago,
lost his wife.
So pray for him luck!
Take a break.
Addons Day-7
Victor!
Victor! Victor!
Tic-Tac!
No!
What do you do?
How many of us have to die, only
to understand that we will not be found?
Who's next
You or me?
What do you want?
Stop it!
Enough! Stop it!
Enough!
Nothing can save you
I will stay here!
Do you have children?
No.
Why not go home,
have children ... a lot.
Listen carefully.
Lisa was expecting a baby!
So I have to discharge her
to her husband!
I do not have children.
What is this a request?
No, seriously
The road has been connected to us.
So you'll be a father?
Yes, old boy!
Addons Day-8
Where are we?
Help me!
Here.
Damn it.
Damn, why did you let
so long?
because of the honor.
Finally!
Unfortunately you did not hear
the compliment!
Do not look,
turn around!
Everything will be fine.
You know what was said Victor
before he died?
I love my job ...
Addons Day 9
How can let reporters
living in this dangerous country?
I love this country.
Replace it with the Dutch
would be better.
Why the Netherlands?
Datar.
As we here?
I have a choice
here or the Netherlands.
Biram Netherlands.
Yes, but there are obvious.
Delicatessen!
Delicious!
I am at Italian restaurants.
Special place.
Svidjet will like it.
risotto with large white sponge.
Maybe in another life.
Since we are not at home?
Do not worry, everything is
would be fine.
The enemy! The enemy!
Take cover!
No!
Luke!
Luke! Luke!
It was not you who decide your fate ...
Luke! All is well!
Okay.
No!
Do not die! Do not die!
Do not die! Luke!
It happened so fast ...
No!
No! No!
Why, Luke?
Why, why?
Addons Day 10
Stay with me.
Three miles in two hours.
Last shortcut?
To the border.
Welcome to Afghanistan.
Beware!
Pull!
Oh my God!
Normal.
Elsa,
You should continue without us.
Take it / No, no.
I will not leave
you are here.
Hear ...
We'll catch up.
Please take this.
Take this compass.
Take, Elsa.
Go to the west, Elsa
Did you hear? Just to the west.
Got it.
I can not leave
you are here.
Yes, I was going to do it ..
Sorry, but I can not.
Elsa, not for myself,
but for others.
Go home, otherwise
will all be in vain.
Go back home!
Go!
I'll warn them.
What do you call?
Apollo!
I like it ...
It would be wise.
I'll be rich!
I'll be back!
It will not be in vain!
Addons Day-11
Addons Day-12
Admiral! / Yes?
He's still alive!
Tonight you'll be in Paris.
I do not want to leave Kabul.
Get real,
you were sick?
I will fly until they are found.
The people from the military hospital
will take care of you.
military hospital.
They have to find them!
Please help ... Excuse me ...
Ooops! ?
Want to ride / Yes!
Admiral, what do you do /
Small streets!
Admiral!
Yes, I know, Mr. Minister.
Thank you.
For what?
I was saved.
Addons In memory of Benjamin,
Jonathan
Addons and other French soldiers
killed in Afghanistan
Addons Praise
for brave reporters,
Addons that they sacrificed their lives around the world
Addons accident at work
warwerwor
fb:ozmonkingkong@yahoo.co.id
suster_myud
www.burnyozmon.blogspot.com