- What's new?
- Same old daily bunkeroo.
Mr. Powers says he wants to see that
foreign stuff as soon as it comes in.
Don't declare war
for a few minutes.
"According to a high official,
it is believed..."
Bah!
Foreign correspondent!
I could get more news out of Europe
looking in a crystal ball.
That, uh, Stebbins cable
has a morsel in it.
Stebbins makes me sick.
They all make me sick.
Europe about to blow up, and all
I can get out of my foreign staff...
is a daily guessing game.
- I want some facts, Mr. Bradley!
- For instance?
Any kind of facts.
There must be something going on
in Europe beside a nervous breakdown.
Why not try sending me over,
Mr. Powers?
You've written a book
on economics or something...
The Twilight of Feudalism.
Yes. It was very
well received.
Not by me. I don't want
any more economists...
sages or oracles bombinating
over our cables.
I want a reporter, somebody
who doesn't know the difference...
between an "ism" and a kangaroo.
A good, honest crime reporter...
that's what the Globe needs.
That's what Europe needs.
There's a crime hatching
on that bedeviled continent.
Wait a minute.
I've got something that
might pass for an idea.
Who was that fellow that ran down
the payroll robbery last week?
Oh, you mean Johnny Jones.
He beat up a policeman,
didn't he, in the line of duty?
Yes, there's talk at the
City desk of firing him.
Hmm.
Beat up a policeman, eh?
Sounds ideal for Europe.
Send Mr. Jones up here
right away.
Mr. Powers wants to see you,
Mr. Jones.
- He does, huh?
- You should come right away.
- What about?
- I ain't in his confidence.
Tell him to save his breath.
Tell him I've resigned.
- I'm supposed to bring you there.
- Okay.
Wait till I open this.
Where's Mr. Jones?
I told you to send him right up here!
- Are you Mr. Jones?
- Yes.
Sit down, please.
Oh. You mind
a personal question?
- No.
- Are you married?
- No luck.
- Single, eh?
- Ever been in Europe?
- No.
What's your opinion of the present
European crisis, Mr. Jones?
What crisis?
I'm referring
to the impending war.
Oh, that.
To tell you the truth, Mr. Powers,
I haven't given it much thought.
You don't keep up with our
foreign news, do you?
Mr. Powers, if you're gonna fire me,
you can scrap the intelligence test.
It's okay with me. I can get a job
on any other newspaper in town.
- So long.
- Wait a minute.
- Nobody fired you.
- Huh?
How would you like to cover
the biggest story in the world today?
Give me an expense account,
and I'll cover anything.
I'll give you an
expense account.
- Okay, what's the story?
- Europe.
I'm not exactly equipped,
but I could do some reading up.
No, I like you
just as you are.
What Europe needs
is a fresh, unused mind.
- Foreign correspondent, huh?
- No. Reporter.
I don't want correspondence.
I want news.
Think you could dig up
some news in Europe?
- I'd be very happy to try, sir.
- This is what I mean.
Mr. Van Meer, when questioned
by our oracle, Mr. Stebbins...
refused to open his mouth.
Twelve hundred words
cable-tolled to the fact that...
the great Van Meer
had nothing to say.
You know what that stuff is doing?
Driving our readers crazy with frustration.
Who's Van Meer?
Keynote to the European
situation today.
Listen, Jones.
If Van Meer stays at the helm...
of his country's affairs
for the next three months...
it may mean peace in Europe.
If we knew what he was thinking,
we'd know where Europe stands.
- A German, huh?
- No. Holland's strongman.
One of two signers
of the Dutch treaty with the Belgians.
Now, this is
your first assignment.
Talk with him,
find out what's in that treaty...
and what he thinks
is going to happen... facts.
- Van Meer, huh?
- Right.
- Anybody else?
- No.
How about Hitler?
Don't you think it'd be good to pump him?
He must have something on his mind.
(INTERCOM BUZZES)
Yes?
(WOMAN) Mr. Stephen Fisher
to see you, Mr. Powers.
Tell him to come in.
Did you ever hear of Stephen Fisher?
- I'm afraid he's not on my beat.
- He is from now on.
He's head of the Universal Peace Party,
and very close to Van Meer.
They're both working to prevent
Europe going up in flames.
- (DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
- Oh.
- How do you do, Mr. Fisher?
- How are you?
- Nice of you to come over. Sit down.
- Thank you.
Mr. Fisher, Mr. Jones,
our new foreign correspondent.
- I want you to know each other.
- How do you do?
"Jones"...
I don't like that name.
It's going to handicap you,
young man.
Now, wait a minute.
I've got some sort
of a name here.
Yes. "Haverstock."
"Huntley Haverstock."
- Sounds more important, don't you think?
- Oh, yes. Very dashing too.
It sounds better than
Richard Harding Davis.
What's the matter with that?
We can't use that.
That's the name of one of our greatest
war correspondents 40 years ago.
Speak up, young man. You don't mind
being Huntley Haverstock, do you?
A rose by any name, sir.
It's exciting being present
at the christening
of an American newspaper
correspondent.
Shouldn't we break a bottle
of champagne over him?
Break one over my head to see if I'm
still awake. "Huntley Haverstock."
Well, Mr. Haverstock,
you'd better get started.
You've got a lot to do...
passports, photos, visas...
- Expenses.
- I'll send a note to the cashier.
I hope you brought
your Sunday articles over.
I managed three of them.
- See you in London, Mr. Haverstock.
- Yes, of course.
Thank you, Mr. Powers.
Thank you for everything.
(QUIETLY)
Except Huntley Haverstock.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- Get a load of this, Mother.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
How's it look?
Chic?
Don't wear it over one eye.
It makes you look like a gangster.
You always think boys are wearing their hats
over one eye. Let him wear it the way it is.
He'll have to wear a stovepipe when he
gets to London. They call 'em poppers.
Toppers, Uncle Bjorn.
Bobby, put that in the
box for Uncle John.
- Let me try it on.
- No, I'm going to first.
- Now he's a regular war correspondent.
- Without a war.
He'll get his
war, all right.
Aw, they're all throwing
a big bluff over there.
Let's hope so.
(JONES) Mother, how do you like
the way we have our nest furnished?
I'd hang lighter curtains, and I'd move
that sofa out in the middle.
It's too bad you haven't
an open fireplace.
If you'd speak to the captain,
he'd tend to everything.
(SHIP'S HORN SOUNDS)
(MAN'S VOICE)
All ashore that's going ashore!
- All ashore...
- (SOBBING)
Now, Mother.
(ALL SAYING GOOD-BYES)
(HORN SOUNDS)
You're Jones, aren't you? My name's
Stebbins, London man for the Globe.
Yes, Mr. Powers told me
you'd be here. Nice of you to come.
- I lost mine on the way over.
- I can say your other name too...
that Huntley Tavers... feld...
I could say it yesterday, but I had a
tough session with the boys last night.
- I'll stick to Jones, if you don't mind.
- Jones is great with me.
Let's get out of here.
This crowd's making me nervous.
My nerves aren't
in the pink this morning.
You take it easy.
I'll follow you.
Porter, bring those bags, and
don't bang them into my knees.
Very good, sir.
What about a drink
after that long train ride?
Sounds like
a very logical idea.
I may not act it,
but I've been here 25 years...
London man for the Globe,
and they haven't caught on to me yet.
How did you manage it?
You cable back the
government handouts...
and sign 'em
"our London correspondent."
- What's yours?
- Scotch and soda, please.
- Miss? Oh, miss?
- Just a moment, sir.
Oh, miss, please...
Scotch and soda
and a glass of milk.
- "A glass of milk"?
- I'm on the wagon.
I went to the doctor today
about these jitters...
and he said it was the wagon
for a month or a new set of organs.
I can't afford new organs.
If I'd known you were on the wagon,
I could've got along without this...
but as long as it's here...
Good luck.
- Good?
- Just like any other scotch and soda.
That's what I thought.
Doesn't taste the way it did when I
was a baby. That's got poison in it.
Speaking of poison,
I got some pills...
Oh, some cables have been
coming over from New York.
They love to cable. Makes them
think you're working for them.
There's an invitation to that lunch
for the Dutchman Van Meer tomorrow.
I guess that's your dish.
This is given by the Universal Peace Party.
That's Fisher's organization, isn't it?
I don't know. I don't follow
those things very much.
New York wants it, I send it. That's
the secret of being a correspondent.
Been doing it 25 years.
Twenty-five years,
and I end up on milk.
(CLOCK TOWER BELLS CHIMING)
- Good morning. How's the water wagon?
- Look at that.
One of them shook off
this morning.
Oh... well, I'm just on my way
to the Van Meer luncheon.
I've got to have lunch here with old
man Clark. He's the international...
Here you are. I didn't know whether
to meet you in the grill or upstairs.
Hmm.
Good-bye, Stebbins.
Good-bye,
Miss, uh, Clark.
Who is he calling "Clark"?
He's got his nerve.
Oh, some fresh
American reporter.
(MAN)
Good morning, Mr. Van Meer.
I beg your pardon, sir.
You are Mr. Van Meer, aren't you?
That's my name, yes.
My name's Haverstock.
You don't know me. I'm an American.
I happened to be on my
way to your luncheon.
Ah?
- Then perhaps...
- That's very kind of you, sir...
Come. Come, come.
It's all in a good cause.
Savoy Hotel.
- This is very kind of you, Mr. Van Meer.
- It's a pleasure, my boy.
I dislike riding alone.
One thinks too much
while riding alone.
Yes, exactly.
The Polish situation...
and the Dutch treaty with the Belgians
must be on your mind these days.
What do you feel England
will do in case the Nazis...
England is so beautiful, hmm?
It's nice to see London
in the sunshine.
Always there is lots
of rain or fog.
Also, it is August.
Yes, I found out it was August.
That was good for me.
But would you mind
telling me how you feel...
about Mr. Fisher and his
peace organization?
You know Mr. Fisher?
Oh, a very fine man.
A good man. I wish there were more
like him in the world just now.
Then I take it you don't think
there's much hope for peace.
I mean, you don't think
one little peace organization...
can make much headway
against the European war panic.
I would like to think so.
Oh, look at those birds.
No matter how big the city,
there must always be parks...
and places for the birds to live.
I was walking through the park
this morning...
and I saw several people
feeding the birds.
That's a good sign
at a time like this, is it not?
Yes, it's a dandy sign...
but I think right now the birds
are the least of our problems.
Your country, for instance...
what might be its attitude...
Oh, we're now near the Savoy.
How much?
A shilling.
That's fine.
♪♪ (ORCHESTRAL WALTZ)
By the way, young man...
what newspaper
do you represent?
As a matter of fact,
I'm not exactly a reporter...
but I was trying to get you to talk,
and I didn't want bird talk either.
I gathered that.
Just what was it you were
trying to get me to tell you?
I was trying to find out what you know
about the possibility of a general war.
How do you really feel
about it?
My boy,
I feel very old and sad...
and helpless.
Well, I did have one.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
The last news from Poland
was very alarming.
- Nobody wants war, and yet...
- Then we don't have to have it.
Miss Fisher, often circumstances
over which we have no control...
Yes, those very convenient circumstances
over which we have no control.
It always seems odd,
but they usually bring on war.
You never hear of circumstances
over which we have no control...
rushing us into peace,
do you?
Very determined woman,
my daughter.
Let's go and see if you can pick a fight
somewhere else. Excuse us.
- Good for you.
- Wasn't he a bore?
Many worthy people are.
How do you do?
How would you like to be fishing
in Ireland at this minute?
We haven't had a good sail
or swim together in months.
Not even a game of cribbage.
Miss them?
Up anchor, mate.
There's the admiral.
He has a weakness for you.
Go do your stuff.
Ah, here you are... the Jones
that became a Haverstock.
Have a good trip? I still wish
you were Richard Harding Davis.
- So do I, sir. Anything except...
- Hello.
Hello. Meet Mrs. Appleby.
This is Huntley Haverstock...
special correspondent,
New York Globe.
- Foreign correspondent? Not really?
- Cross my heart.
You look such a sweet boy. You don't
seem like the others... you know, greasy.
- No?
- But I'm sure you're marvelous at it.
I wonder if you know a friend,
Monty Rockingham.
He's in the embassy
at Istanbul.
Or is it Honolulu?
Do help me with this distinguished-looking
gentleman over here.
I can't make any headway with him, but
I'm sure he must speak some language.
Everybody does.
I haven't the least idea who he is...
but there isn't anybody here
who isn't internationally important.
This is Mr. Haver-
Uh, Stock.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
No English?
Vous parlez francais?
- Try German.
- Sprechen Sie Deutsch?
Splendid.
What else do you know?
- Well, only pig latin.
- Pig la-
Oh. Here we are.
This'll do it.
Ah.
(FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Now we're getting somewhere.
The universal language.
Dear Maharaja.
- Ah. (FOREIGN)
- (FOREIGN)
Well, they come in pairs.
If you speak English,
will you give me a hand with the
laughing Latvian? What's he talking?
Latvian.
No kidding? I didn't know
the Lats had a language.
I thought they just
rubbed noses.
You mean,
you actually speak Latvian?
Oh, just enough to get about.
What does "just enough
to get about" consist of in Latvia?
Well, I don't think
you'd have any trouble.
That'll be a comfort
when I get to Latvia.
(WOMAN) You think there
might be a chance soon?
You never can tell
in my racket.
I suppose you've guessed
I'm a foreign correspondent.
Are you?
That's nice.
(JONES CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I see you're taking notes.
Are you covering this affair too?
- I sort of work here.
- Oh, publicity!
You're just the one
I'm looking for.
We've got to go
in a secret conference right away.
Oh.
Uh...
Me? Excuse me.
I beg your pardon,
but I have a Latvian friend here...
who's particularly interested
in the origin of the kilt.
I wonder if you'd be interested in
talking to him. He's a lovely fellow.
It's a most amazing story.
You see...
the Greeks, in the early period,
they used to wear a kilt.
What is this big secret
conference all about?
It's no secret
as far as I'm concerned.
However, I'll let you in
on that part later.
But since you're handling
the publicity for this outfit...
you might give me a line
on what it's about...
this League for Peace
and Understanding.
What is it you'd like to know?
First, is this Mr. Fisher
entirely on the level?
- Very much so.
- He seems like a very nice guy.
He is, I assure you.
Well, what is it that
makes him, or you, think...
that an organization like this,
made up of well-meaning amateurs...
buck up against those tough
military boys of Europe?
It's the "well-meaning amateurs,"
as you call them...
who do the fighting
when the war comes, isn't it?
- (MAN) Luncheon is served.
- Please don't go yet.
You don't want any of
those dreary chicken patties.
I'm sorry. I must go.
Then sit at the press
table with me.
Nobody listens to the speeches
at the press table. We could talk.
- You don't know my name yet.
- Is it necessary?
It is to me.
Don't mind if you hear...
it's Huntley Haverstock,
because it's really Jones.
- What's yours?
- Mine's really Smith.
Don't mind if you hear
it's anything else.
- Waiter?
- Yes, sir?
Same young lady.
Try again.
I have taken the
young lady 13 notes, sir.
- She won't accept any more.
- (MAN LAUGHS)
Milords, ladies...
and gentlemen...
pray silence
for your chairman...
Mr. Stephen Fisher.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have an announcement to make...
which I'm sure will be
a great disappointment to us all.
I've just received this telegram
from Mr. Van Meer...
who was to have been
our guest of honor today.
"Deeply regret. Called away suddenly
owing to unforeseen circumstances.
I will be unable to attend
your meeting as planned
I am with you and your
work with all my heart.
I could not have said more
had I been there."
Although this removes one of our
star attractions at the luncheon...
we may have more time
to tell you...
from the inside
what this party has stood for...
and why we've asked you
here today.
I can think of no one
more competent to do this...
than the speaker
I am about to introduce.
I trust you will not think
this is a family affair...
when I say I refer to my daughter...
Miss Carol Fisher.
Milords...
ladies and gentlemen...
pray silence for Miss Carol Fisher.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ladies and gentlemen...
I trust that, even making allowances
for a father's exuberance...
you do not think I'm in any way
being put forward today...
as a substitute
for Mr. Van Meer.
Unhappily for us, no one
can take Mr. Van Meer's place.
What I can do, possibly, is
to clear up a few misapprehensions...
that seem to have crept into the
public discussion of this movement...
and revise some
of the epithets applied to us...
by some who have not gone as deeply
into the matter as they might.
The female of the "speeches"
is deadlier than the male.
...as a group
of well-meaning amateurs.
I'm sure there are some of you here
who think of us as such.
I should like to ask anyone who has
called us "well-meaning amateurs"...
to stand up by his chair
and tell me just why...
a well-meaning amateur
is any less reliable...
than a well-meaning professional
at a moment like this...
but I'll not take the time.
I think the world has been run long
enough by the well-meaning professional.
We might give the amateurs
their chance now.
But what I really want to do
is give you a brief idea of...
just...
just how far-reaching
our amateur plans are.
Use your notes.
And, uh, just...
why we ask for your support...
professional or amateur.
What I mean is that...
however much one may...
I mean, we should both...
both of us...
(MURMURING)
(HORN HONKS)
Better to wait in there.
- Mr. Fisher, how are you?
- When did you get over?
Just now. I had a cable from Mr. Powers.
This is my first assignment.
Rather ironic assignment: a peace
conference in the shadow of war.
You mean it's really coming?
Today and tomorrow will tell.
There's still hope.
- I'm going back to London today.
- Leaving for London?
I only just got here.
The conference is just beginning.
Today and tomorrow, the work of peace must
be done in London rather than Amsterdam.
Are you taking your whole staff
to London with you, including your...
No, someone staying here will see
you're given all the help you need.
You'll be in very good hands.
Here she is.
- Mrs. Appleby, Mr. Haverstock.
- We met at the luncheon.
You remember
Mr. (UNPRONOUNCEABLE), don't you?
He's nice, but I still
can't understand him.
Dr. Williamson, Mr. Huntley Haverstock
represents the New York Globe.
He's unfamiliar with Amsterdam
and the machinery of peace meetings.
Would you take him
under your wing?
Perhaps you and Mrs. Appleby
might see he samples
eight or ten varieties
of Dutch cheese tonight.
Now I must see
what unlucky person...
is going to give up his seat
to me on that plane.
Don't get into any mischief,
will you?
- "Mischief"?
- Your first visit to Amsterdam?
Yes.
You must let me take you
to Rembrandt's house...
It might be a good idea if we went
over the agenda of the conference.
(JONES) If you'll excuse me,
I see a friend.
Mr. Van Meer, how are you?
We seemed to lose each other
the day before yesterday.
I'm so sorry
you were called away.
Don't you remember me?
We shared the same cab
on the way to the luncheon.
Excuse me. May I have
your picture, Mr. Van Meer?
Thank you.
(WOMEN SCREAMING, PEOPLE SHOUTING)
There he goes!
(EXCITED SHOUTING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(SHOT FIRES)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Follow that car! Quick!
Oh.
- You better get out of here.
- Don't be silly. Drive on.
(HORN HONKING)
- Who's he shot?
- Van Meer. Assassinated.
- Dead?
- Looked like it.
Bad show.
Couldn't be much worse,
from his point of view.
(HORN HONKING)
Do you mind shoving
your knees out of the way?
(HORN HONKING)
You'd better hop
in the back, old girl.
(JONES) Hurry.
Safety glass.
I wonder whose make.
- Good chauffeur you've got, Miss Fisher.
- Yes, isn't he?
- You two know each other?
- Yeah.
I forgot. This is Scott ffolliott.
Newspaperman, same as you.
Roaming correspondent.
- Mr. Haverstock, Mr. ffolliott.
- With a double F.
- How do you do?
- I don't get the double F.
- At the beginning. Both small Fs.
It can't be at
the beginning.
One of my ancestors had his
head chopped off by Henry VIII.
His wife dropped the capital letter
to commemorate the occasion.
There it is.
- How do you say it? Like a stutter?
- No, just straight "fuh."
(HORN HONKING)
It's stopped raining.
The sun's coming out.
The police are coming.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(WIND GUSTING)
That's the most amazing
disappearing trick I've ever seen.
(AIRPLANE PASSING OVERHEAD)
Don't suppose they could've
got up that high, do you?
(VEHICLES APPROACHING)
- (SPEAKING DUTCH)
- Vanished.
(DUTCH)
Take a look for yourself,
old boy.
Tell him your name,
about the two small Fs.
- That would be a bit over his head.
- (DUTCH)
Well, this isn't catching
any assassins.
We should've kept one of those
policemen and played bridge.
I guess you're right.
- Oh
- (LAUGHING)
I'll bet 2 to 1 on the derby.
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
Look at those sails
on that windmill.
You'll get used to those
when you've been in Holland longer.
I could've sworn
they were going against the wind.
Why don't you lie down
on the grass and cool off?
In due time, but first I want you
to get the police back here.
The police again?
We don't want the police.
I've decided not to prosecute.
You'll get the police,
'cause our man's in there.
- Where?
- In that mill.
- What makes you think so?
- A lot can happen while I'm explaining.
Please get the police.
I'd go if I spoke the language.
- What'll you do?
- A bit of snooping.
I hate to seem executive,
but this is serious.
- Come on, Scott.
- All right. You shall have your police.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(HORN HONKS)
(AIRPLANE PASSING OVERHEAD)
it's a signal.
It's a signal for that plane to land.
(MEN SPEAKING BOROVIAN)
(BOROVIAN)
(MAN) Oh.
Ah, come in...
and close the door, mister.
Mr. Van Meer.
It isn't possible.
I've just been given a drug...
drug of some sort.
But I saw you shot just now
outside the conference hall! I saw it!
They gave it to me...
when they moved me from...
Ah, it's beginning now. I...
The man I saw shot
was a dead image!
The man you saw shot...
that wasn't me.
He was a subs-
substitute that looked like me.
But why? What...
They... They want
the world to think...
that I've been assassinated.
Yes.
To conceal the fact...
that I am in their hands.
"Their hands"?
Who are "they"?
I can't explain.
I'm not cert-
(GROANS)
This drug...
I can hardly think.
All I can tell you is that...
they are going
to take me away by plane...
like a bird.
(CHUCKLES)
Always are places
in the city...
where birds can get crumbs.
Birds. Cru-
Oh, quickly.
A pencil.
(FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS)
(CHEEPING)
(DUTCH)
(MEN SPEAKING BOROVIAN)
(MAN SPEAKING BOROVIAN)
You see? Old mill.
Up the road.
Look.
Man.
Old mill. Understand?
Does anyone here
speak English?
English? We speak English
in the school.
Why have you been holding out on me?
Tell these two policemen...
to come with me.
Very, very important.
Big old prisoner. Old mill.
Tell them to follow me.
Do you understand?
(DUTCH)
Yeah.
Yeah. That's what I've been
trying to tell you. Come on.
(CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
They've gone.
They've killed him.
But if isn't...
Who are you?
Where are the others?
(DUTCH)
There's been a frame-up.
Ask him where the others have gone.
(DUTCH)
He says he doesn't know what you're
talking about. There are no other people.
He's been asleep here all day.
He's lying. I talked to Van
Meer in this very room.
Well, there's one thing
I can show you...
the assassin's car,
the one we followed.
(DUTCH)
A unique specimen, old boy. The only
one-horse sports car in the world.
That car was here!
Listen, I know I look a fool...
but there's something fishy
going on around here.
There's a big story in this.
I can smell it...
and I'm going to get
to the bottom of it.
And nothing's gonna stop me,
do you understand?
I'm going to prove that that was not Van
Meer that was assassinated but his double.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Who is it?
- (KNOCKING)
- All right, come in.
- Mr. Haverstock?
- Yes.
What are you, the house detective?
You weren't announced.
I'm sorry, sir.
We asked at the desk.
Policemen, huh? Don't tell me you're
here to apologize about the windmill.
No, sir. We simply want you
to come with us...
and tell your story
to our chief of police.
Does this chief of police speak English?
I'm a very busy man.
It will take no more than half an
hour, sir. We all speak English.
That's marvelous. That's more
than I can say for my country.
Would you sit down?
I have to make a phone call.
Dinner date
with a young lady.
(PHONE SWITCH CLICKING)
The exchange doesn't answer.
Well, I'll call later.
Look, I'm a very quick bather.
Would you excuse me...
while I jump in the tub
and give myself a shave?
Look at some magazines.
I'll be right back.
You couldn't bring the chief
of police here, could you?
No, I am afraid not.
No, I thought not.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
♪♪ (WHISTLING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
- Please don't bother to come.
- You'll find it on my dressing table.
(GASPS)
Well, we meet again.
So it seems.
Quite a lot's happened
since I last saw you.
- So I see.
- Uh...
I, uh, had quite a chase
after that guy outside Amsterdam.
It's quite a country.
It's interesting. Windmills and tulips.
Did you find
everything you...
We were just talking about the tulips.
Don't seem to be any.
I really think
I should be going now.
Thank you very much
for the powder.
Oh, must you really go now?
Yes, I must be going now.
Really.
Good-bye.
You've made quite a
day of it, haven't you?
Shh! Listen...
Made monkeys out of ffolliott and me,
broken into my bedroom...
and disgraced me
before a friend of my father's.
What are your plans now?
You might at least have
had your clothes on.
Take it easy.
This is serious business.
I've seen your "serious
business" before.
- What are you doing?
- Escaping.
From what?
A couple fellows in my
room about to kill me.
May I ask who?
Two gentlemen disguised as policemen
waiting to take me for a ride.
Don't you think you've been talking
through your hat long enough?
I'm not!
I've thrown a monkey wrench
into some international dirty business.
I know Van Meer's alive.
That's the reason they want to kill me.
- I can think of others.
- You've got to help me...
not for my sake, but this is
the biggest story in Europe.
Your childish mind is as out of place
in Europe as you are in my bedroom.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Get over there.
(LATVIAN)
Ah.
You see what you're doing,
don't you?
This is going straight back to London.
We'll be common gossip by tomorrow.
I don't care for myself,
but my father's engaged in great work.
He's trying to help avert a dreadful war.
This is just the thing to discredit him.
I know you care nothing about our work.
All you're interested in...
is having fun with windmills
and hotel bathrooms.
You don't believe
I'm in trouble.
You'll be in plenty of trouble if you don't
get out. For the last time, please go.
Okay, but I want you to know exactly
what's going to happen when I do go.
I'll go back to my room and try to shake
those fellows off, but I won't succeed.
They'll stick to me like a couple
of tattoo marks until they get me.
They'll stop at nothing. I seem to
know too much, and they're right.
I don't know the ins and outs
of your crackpot movement...
and what's wrong with Europe,
but I do know a story...
and I'll keep after it until either
I get it or it gets me.
Sorry you have those
derogatory opinions of me...
but I guess that can't be helped.
Well, so long.
It's been nice knowing you.
I said "good-bye."
Don't go.
Oh, I guess I could've handled
those fellows all right, with luck.
We mustn't take chances.
We should get some help.
That's what I had
in mind at first.
I'll get Dr. Williamson
and Mr. Van...
Not with me this way.
They might not understand.
They have understood.
(WATER RUNNING)
We could catch the boat to England
and see Father if you could get out.
That's the hitch. What's that friend
of yours? f-f something.
- ffolliott.
- Give me Mr. ffolliott's room, please.
Left the hotel?
That's strange.
We were to dine together tonight.
He realized how
much I meant to you.
You'd mean much more
with your clothes on.
You like the intellectual type.
Say, I've got an idea.
What?
The manager, please.
Buzz for the valet, will you?
Hello, is this the manager?
This is Mr. Haverstock in 537.
What kind of a hotel is this?
My bathtub leaks...
my phone's out of order,
and I've been robbed.
Will you send somebody up
right away? Thank you.
Operator, send a waiter up to 537.
And ask the chambermaid
to bring up clean sheets.
I've set mine on fire.
And I'd like a window-cleaner, and ask
boots to come up and get my shoes.
And hurry it up.
That's a good girl.
That'll clutter up that
room for those two guys.
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
It's the valet.
Come in.
- Do you speak English?
- Yes, sir.
- Go to my room, 537...
- 537.
And get me a shirt, tie,
suit, and a hat.
You see, my husband's waiting
in the room for this gentleman.
(WATER RUNNING)
(EXCLAIMING IN DUTCH)
(ALL SPEAKING AT ONCE)
(CHATTERING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SHIP'S HORN SOUNDING)
No sign of them yet.
Come on, let's hide in the cabin.
- Full up, sir. Sorry.
- Not even a small cabin?
Not a thing.
Everybody in a hurry to get home.
I see. I have a rare bank note here
you might be interested in.
That is, if you collect
rare bank notes.
Sir, I'd do it if I could,
but there just isn't a place left.
Aboard an English ship you come up
against such an air of incorruptibility.
As a matter of fact, sir,
I just had a cabin returned.
- Can I have your name, sir?
- Oh.
One cabin isn't going to do us
much good. We just can't...
I fully intended to sleep in the lounge.
I hope you didn't think I...
No, of course not.
It's very kind of you.
Fine. I'll take it.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm afraid it's too late now.
You seemed to have some doubt about taking
it. I had to let that gentleman have it.
Oh, that's too bad.
It's such a rare five-pound note too.
The watermark's upside down.
I think you'd have loved it.
Well, perhaps next time.
(SHIP'S HORN SOUNDING)
- (EXCLAIMS)
- (MACHINERY SCREECHING)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
Were you really going to tip
that man five pounds?
Of course. I charge all
my traveling expenses to the office.
Corrupting an official:
five pounds.
You're just a wee bit
unscrupulous, aren't you?
Not unscrupulous.
Just in love.
- It's the same thing, I suppose.
- I beg your pardon?
I beg yours.
You see, I love you
and I want to marry you.
I love you,
Well, that cuts our love scene down
quite a bit, doesn't it?
- Do you mind?
- Not at all. It's made a new man of me.
I hope not entirely new.
It took me some time...
to get used
to the first man you were.
To be perfectly frank,
I expected a little more argument.
I'm left with quite a few things
I wanted to say.
Save them until after we're married.
I imagine they'll sound much better then.
I'd saved things to say then too.
You were really quite sure
of yourself, weren't you?
Funny... I didn't think
I had a chance.
A guy's got a right to
dream, though, hasn't he?
Evidently.
Do you think your father
will understand?
I think Father
will be delighted, frankly.
Right, sir.
- Good morning, Miss Carol.
- Good morning, Stiles.
- This is Mr. Haverstock. Is Father up yet?
- Yes, miss. He's having breakfast.
Come on.
- Hello, Father.
- What are you doing in London?
Jo... Mr. Haverstock
brought me back on the boat.
Nothing wrong, is there?
You're not ill? You look healthy.
No, I'm fine.
It's Mr. Haverstock.
I hope you don't mind
my barging in.
On the contrary. I'm delighted.
You cover a lot of territory, don't you?
You didn't even send a wire.
Just for that, I hope your trip
was perfectly uncomfortable.
It wasn't so bad.
We couldn't get cabins...
but we managed
to sleep on the deck.
Monsieur Krug.
How nice to see you again.
Mr. Haverstock,
Monsieur Krug.
Monsieur Krug is a member
of the Borovian Embassy staff here.
Sit down.
Have a spot of breakfast.
I know I should tidy up,
but I'm simply starved.
So you were in Amsterdam
yesterday, Mr. Haverstock?
Poor Van Meer. I count his death
a heavy personal loss.
Of all people, why Van Meer?
You can't ask "why" of an assassin.
There's no logic in killing.
We can't spare such men
in a world like ours.
Did you by any chance meet him,
Mr. Haverstock?
Not formally,
but I saw him die.
Horrible.
As a matter of fact, I chased the man
that shot him and almost caught him.
Mr. Haverstock is a newspaperman,
Monsieur Krug.
That would be quite a
coup, bringing in your
first story wrapped
around an assassin.
I shall have to be
getting along now, Mr. Fisher.
Shall we settle on the wording
for the peace petition now or later?
We may as well clear it up
in the study. You'll excuse us?
Father, could I speak to you?
It's terribly important.
This won't take a moment. Meanwhile, see
if you can't interest Mr. Haverstock...
in some eggs and bacon.
Mr. Fisher... What's
that man doing here?
It's Monsieur Krug.
- Van Meer isn't dead.
- But I just read...
That was his double.
Van Meer was kidnapped.
I talked to him in a
mill outside Amsterdam.
What has Krug to do with it?
Remember my description
of the man in the mill?
You mean the sweater?
Of course! But that's impossible.
We've known Monsieur Krug...
Mr. Krug brought Van Meer here by
plane last night. He's in England.
They're hiding him.
Positive about this?
I was as close to Krug
as I am to you now.
It'd be terrible if we made a mistake.
On the other hand...
(KRUG) Mr. Fisher.
Leave it to me.
(BARKS)
I don't want to seem inhospitable,
but I must ask you to leave.
Mr. Haverstock is going to suggest
I turn you over to the police.
Mr. Haverstock seems to be
something of a troublemaker.
I thought you said he'd been taken
care of by our agents in Amsterdam.
I thought so too.
I don't understand if,
unless perhaps...
Miss Fisher's being with him
may have caused complications.
It would've been ideal
if she'd been in our confidence.
Leave my daughter out of it.
- I beg your pardon.
- Most unfortunate, his coming here.
I've never had to cope with this sort
of thing before, thanks to you.
Someone has to take care
of the sordid details.
But this is close to home. In fact, it is
my home. After all, I'm only a politician.
In a sense.
And politicians aren't usually
called upon to, uh...
do away with their guests,
are they?
- (DOG BARKS)
- Quiet, boy. Quiet.
Not in the house.
No, sir.
- But I have an idea.
- (BARKING CONTINUES)
- Do you remember Rowley?
- Rowley?
Yes, the little man who used to work
at your father's stables in Austria.
Yes, I recall he was present
when a mutual friend of ours, um...
accidentally fell off
the high bridge at Bern.
He's retired now.
Lives somewhere in
Clapham here in London.
If Mr. Haverstock could be
induced to hire him...
in the capacity
of a private detective...
- What for?
- Well...
you should warn him that it is
very dangerous to go about London...
with the knowledge
that he has.
- (DOG BARKS)
- Yes, I see. Yes.
You use the English language
with great delicacy, Krug.
Thank you, sir. I shall look
Mr. Rowley up at once...
and give him his instructions.
But you mustn't.
It would be too dangerous.
What do we do?
Call Scotland Yard?
I thought it best to
send Krug on his way.
You let him get away?
Well, listen...
Don't you see how important it is
not to rouse Krug's suspicions?
- Van Meer will be killed immediately.
- Dead or alive, it's a story.
Johnny, Father's right.
- Okay, I'll cable them what I've got.
- I wouldn't if I were you.
Van Meer's life may depend
upon our keeping this quiet.
Keep it quiet?
A famous diplomat's kidnapped under
my own eyes, and I muzzle myself?
I'm sorry,
but this is a story with facts...
the kind I was sent here to get,
the kind America's waiting for.
It'll be bigger if you can wait
just a few hours...
until we can find Van Meer and discover
what's behind this whole curious business.
- I know what's behind it.
- I don't mean who's behind it.
I mean the why of it.
Dear, will you get me
all my correspondence with Krug?
Please, Johnny,
do what Father says.
It'll be best for you
and poor Mr. Van Meer.
Okay. I'll wait.
I'm worried about you.
I'm a little worried about myself.
I feel weak-minded.
You're doing the right thing, but I don't
like you dashing about without protection.
Forget it.
If what you say is true,
you need protection.
I've covered beer mob
killings and race riots
since I was a tot without
even a rabbit's foot.
These people are
criminals, more dangerous
than your rumrunners
and housebreakers.
They're fanatics.
They combine a mad
love of country with
an equally mad
indifference to life...
their own as well as others.
They're cunning,
unscrupulous...
and... inspired.
And I really couldn't
face Mr. Powers again...
if you didn't live long enough
to turn in the best story of the year.
I'm gonna be a fine foreign correspondent
hiding in an attic somewhere.
I'm not suggesting you hide anywhere.
Just get somebody to watch out for you.
A nurse? Johnny Jones goes
to Europe and hires a nurse.
That's gonna look great
on the expense account.
I know a very efficient private detective
agency where we can get just the man.
- Okay, whatever you say.
- I can arrange it all for you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
If it'll make you feel better,
I won't mention it to anybody.
If anyone finds out I've hired
a bodyguard, I'll shoot myself.
(DOOR BUZZER BUZZES)
If that's Mr. Rowley,
tell him to wait outside.
Yes, sir.
(MAN) I've called on Mr. Haverstock.
Will you tell him Mr. Rowley is here?
- Will you wait here, please?
- Thank you.
- Mr. Haverstock, your cab's here.
- Where are you going?
- To the office. I've got work to do.
- But you mustn't go.
I was sent over here at great expense
as a newspaperman, not a refugee.
- How about lunch at the Savoy?
- I'll see you out.
Johnny, please be careful.
I'll be all right.
(ROWLEY)
Mr. Haverstock?
Is this the man?
Look, who's protecting who?
Well, I ain't lanky, sir,
but I'm quick.
I take it you understand
what to do.
You can trust me to take care of
Mr. Haverstock. Are we going now, sir?
Yes, you can take me to my office,
and if you're good...
- to the American Club.
- Right, sir.
You'll keep after
this other thing?
As soon as there's news,
I'll let you know.
Then you can break the story.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, sir.
(SNIFFLING)
Why, Carol.
Nothing must happen to him, Father.
I just couldn't...
How do we go, sir?
Would you like me to walk behind you,
or beside you, like a friend?
- What's the custom?
- Different people has different tastes.
With the Duke of Albatrorr,
the duke, being a democratic gent...
I used to walk alongside of him,
man-to-man, like.
On the other hand, I once had a lady
who thought that was disrespectful.
"Three paces behind," she says,
"and don't smoke on duty."
What's good enough for a
duke is good enough for me.
Thank you, sir.
If we want to go to the American Club,
we'd better take a cab. There's one.
What's the trouble, sir.
Is it gangsters after you?
Not exactly.
We're not afraid of
gangsters over here, sir.
- Even our police don't carry guns.
- What do they do?
Hit you over the head with a stick.
A bit more healthy-like.
Did you see that?
Someone deliberately pushed me!
That was me, sir. If I'd have pulled
you back, you'd have been caught.
It was push or nothing.
Smart work, Mr. Rowley.
Thank you very much.
After all, that's what I'm here for,
isn't it? Taxi!
- American Club.
- Yes, sir.
After you, sir.
I'm not certain, sir,
but I've got an idea...
two men just got
in another cab to follow us.
I don't see
anyone suspicious.
Well, I may have
been mistaken...
but I'm almost certain
I saw them.
They may have heard
where we're going.
Driver.
Driver?
Go down Victoria Street...
'round past
Buckingham Palace.
Right, sir.
We might give 'em the slip
if we go the long way around.
I'm afraid
they're still after us.
Our best plan is to pull 'round
the next corner and change cabs.
Driver? Take the first
to your left and pull up.
We're going to walk a bit.
I'll do it, sir. I understand
the money. It'll be quicker.
(DRIVER) Thank you, sir.
Our best plan is to slip
into the cathedral for a bit.
Let's call off this ducking and let them
catch up with us and have a showdown.
I wouldn't cause a scene.
Our job is to give 'em the slip.
All right.
- Let's go.
- Nice bit of architecture, sir, innit?
♪♪ (CHOIR SINGING IN LATIN)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Do you mind not going right in, sir?
I saw by the notice it was
a requiem mass... a mass for the dead.
That sort of thing always depresses me
...praying for the dead and all that.
The dead are all right
in their place, sir...
but the music and the candles
always gives me the creeps.
It does really, sir.
I don't like to be so fussy...
How about a trip up top, sir?
That'd really put 'em
off the scent.
(MAN) Boys, careful there.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
- I can't see.
- Eh? Here, here.
There you are, me boy.
- Ooh!
- (CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Look, there it goes. There.
I'll have to buy you
another now.
(LAUGHS) Love a duck!
Careful, boys.
You better be careful too, sir.
Not yet, boys.
Let's get out of here. I have a luncheon
date and plenty to do before it.
I've got it in mind, sir.
Don't you worry. Really, now, look.
Isn't it worthwhile
coming up here to see it, sir?
There's the houses
of Parliament over there.
And there's St. James's Park.
That green patch. Yeah.
Come along, boys.
You must excuse me getting so scared
when you leaned over just now, sir.
I was once with a man
on a bridge in Switzerland.
He had a very nasty fall.
Killed him. Stone dead.
Always made me
a bit nervous since.
(ELEVATOR DOOR OPENING)
Don't go down just yet, sir.
I'd like you to see St. Paul's.
There it is,
just coming out of the mist.
Oh, and look. There's the 'orse guards
approaching Buckingham Palace.
- See 'em? Down there.
- It makes the backs of me legs go funny.
Height always did.
Let's get down again, Eric.
(MAN)
Why didn't you say so before?
Miss,
I know just how you feel.
Them as has no head for
heights can't help it.
Nobody ought not
to blame them.
- What's it got to do with you?
- All right, keep your head on.
- I was only sympathizing.
- I'm going down anyway.
- Wait for the lift.
- No.
No stairs for me.
I'm gonna take the elevator.
Wait a minute, sir.
You ain't seen
the 'orse guards yet.
You must see
the 'orse guards, sir.
Where?
I don't see anything.
Why, there they are, sir.
Down the road.
Just going toward the...
the white building.
(SCREAMS)
No, boys. This way.
♪♪ (CHOIR CONTINUES)
Well, there but for
the grace of God.
I still don't know what instinct made
me step aside when he came at me.
You need a drink.
I heard the lift coming up,
and I turned.
I saw that look in his eye
as he came toward me.
In that split second, the whole thing
flashed through my mind.
All I could think of was Fisher.
"Fisher planned this."
Then I guess I just stepped aside,
and over he went.
Over he went, all right.
Did you want this?
No, thanks.
When are you going to send the story
to our esteemed gazette?
When I get ready.
Well, there goes another
of my illusions.
I thought you were one of those
journalists nothing could stop.
Floods, smallpox, love...
the story must go on.
- It'll go on.
- (PHONE RINGING)
No. I can understand you not wanting
to drag Miss Fisher into it.
On the other hand,
she's probably in it already.
- The moll of the gang.
- Why, you dirty...
On second thought, I'm sure not.
I'm sure she's a fine girl...
upstanding, honest,
with a great soul.
I can't send the story
on Van Meer until he's safe.
- We've got to find Van Meer first.
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
Ah, there's our man now, probably.
Mr. Van Meer, come in.
Good morning, Stebbins.
How are you, Haverstock?
Congratulations on your little
set-to with Rowley.
What do you know
about Rowley?
Very little ffolliott doesn't hear.
He probably even knows about Fisher.
I was onto Fisher
a year ago...
but that fellow
with the high-neck sweater...
- Krug... he's new to me...
- You're onto him too?
- Followed him to London.
- I thought you were cold on this story.
On the contrary.
I've been doing a bit of noticing.
- Remember that tramp asleep in the mill?
- Yeah.
- He wasn't a tramp at all.
- Van Meer, I suppose.
Not quite, but I noticed him
do a strange thing for a tramp.
He dirtied his hands
with some of that nasty Dutch soil.
I can't follow the workings
of these masterminds.
(RINGS)
No.
Tell him it's ridiculous.
You'd already disappeared,
so I followed Krug...
but ended up
at the same old mousetrap.
You mean Fisher?
The good, kind, genial head
of the Peace Party, Herr Fisher.
(RINGS)
Hello, Eddie?
This is Plunger Stebbins.
I want to place a bet
on Flibbertigibbet in the first...
The race is over? What do you know
about that? Okay, I'll call you later.
Any objection to working
the rest of this thing together?
Catch Fisher, find Van Meer,
that sort of thing?
All right, but I'd like to know
why they kidnapped Van Meer.
He was one of the signatories
to a certain treaty.
The most important clause
was never written down...
just memorized
by the two people who signed.
They're gonna
beat it out of him?
They're going to try. It'd be
a good idea if we put a stop to them.
It contains information
that would be valuable to the enemy...
in the war that breaks out tomorrow,
weather permitting.
What? Why didn't someone
let me in on this?
- Stebbins, we've got to get busy.
- Plenty of time. Lunch first.
You mind waiting?
You might be of some help.
I thought up a little plan
for forcing Fisher's hand.
Let's have it.
I think the neatest thing would be
to kidnap Fisher's daughter.
Oh, yeah?
One of Fisher's few genuine traits
is his affection for Miss Fisher.
Easy. You're speaking
to the man who loves her.
All the better. Give you
a chance to get chummy...
and keep her out of this mess
while we batter away at papa.
This is my scheme:
I walk in, let Fisher know...
his daughter's in the hands
of someone who means business...
just as he means business when he
kidnaps people. He'll see things our way.
- Nothing doing.
- I thought you were a newspaperman.
That doesn't include kidnapping
your fiancee where I come from.
- It would if your country were at stake.
- This isn't my country.
It's your story. Don't be gloomy.
She doesn't have to know.
- Just keep her amused.
- Why not grab Fisher and have a showdown?
No good. We've got nothing
on Fisher. He'd slip out of it anyway.
All we'd do would be
to kill Van Meer.
- Mm.
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
Hello, darling. Are you all right?
What were you doing on the tower?
Trying to keep out of harm's way,
but those assassins followed.
There was a scuffle,
and over he went.
Darling, they won't stop
till they get you.
You must leave London
immediately.
The one thing everybody
forgets is I'm a reporter.
There's a war.
I can't run out.
Scott, he can't stay here.
Tell him how desperate these men are.
He shouldn't stay another minute.
Take him somewhere.
I won't go.
Couldn't you think up some aunt
in the country or something?
There's my Aunt Margaret at Harpenden.
Let me take you there.
- How about it?
- Stay out of this.
It's the only
sensible thing to do.
May I use your telephone?
(DIALING)
Hello, Stiles?
Miss Carol speaking.
Tell Mr. Fisher I'm driving down
to Aunt Margaret's at Harpenden.
- I won't go.
- I'll be back in time for dinner.
- Thank you.
- (PHONE HANGS UP)
it's settled. We can
get you a toothbrush...
It's no good.
I'm wondering whether this idea
of your aunt is so good.
Maybe it'd be better further out...
say, Cambridge.
There's no place as
obscure as Harpenden.
It isn't so
much the place...
as the fact Krug
might connect you with it.
You're right.
Make it Cambridge.
I'll phone your father
so he doesn't worry.
Thank you, Scott.
Please, Johnny?
That was a break, her suggesting
they go to the country.
As a matter of fact, old boy,
I suggested it to her...
on the phone
about half an hour ago.
There hasn't been a sign
of anybody for the last 30 miles.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
You might at least talk to me.
It's unfair to sit there and pout...
because I've kidnapped you
from your so-called duties.
- You've kidnapped me?
- Mm-hmm.
- Just remember that, will you?
- Please forgive me.
Why, sure.
I don't think kidnapping's...
anything to get sore about when done
by the right kidnapper, do you?
- Not at all.
- Thanks.
(RINGING)
Hello?
No, Mr. ffolliott.
I'm afraid he's not in yet.
Very well, sir.
- Johnny, you don't love me.
- You're crazy.
- You looked unhappy when you kissed me.
- Never happier in my life.
Won't do.
Johnny, what's happened?
The war, I guess.
They say it's coming tomorrow.
So you've changed
your philosophy since yesterday.
There are more important things
in the world than love.
- I've got lots to do. Important things.
- Carol...
Got to get started.
It'll take three hours to get back.
I'm not going to be misunderstood.
I'm so in love, I'm going mad.
Won't do.
I suppose it can't be helped.
You've turned European
on me overnight, Johnny.
That's unfair. I'm just as big
a jackass as I ever was. Bigger.
You're not going back
to London to dinner tonight.
You can't run out
on your kidnapper like that.
I mean...
Well, you know what I mean.
If you run out on me now,
I'm going...
straight to London
and let them bump me off.
Be a relief at that.
Well, you are moody.
Am I the cause?
If you knew how much
I loved you, you'd faint.
There.
What'd I tell you?
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
- Come in.
- Mr. Haverstock?
- Yes?
- Call from London.
- Have them switch it up.
Sorry, there's only one phone...
in the office.
All right, I'll come down.
Forgive me
for a moment, dear.
Just a moment, sir.
Hello?
Is that you, Haverstock, old boy?
Are you alone? Can you talk?
I can't get a hold of Fisher.
He's been out all afternoon.
I'm afraid you'll have to keep the girl
much longer than we'd planned.
I don't know what time he'll be back.
I've got to catch him alone.
Keep the girl there
for the night.
But that's
absolutely impossible.
We can't let
this thing go now.
I can't very well explain, but I simply
couldn't pull a thing like that.
You've got to try. There isn't anything
else to be done. I'm counting on you.
Hello?
Are you quite satisfied
with your room, sir?
Well, not exactly.
That is, I mean, yes...
but I really wanted
another room as well...
a single room.
Oh. Mr. Naismith?
Mr. Naismith, this gentleman
wants another room.
For the young lady?
How long will you be requiring it?
(JONES) She'll only be here
just the one might.
- The gentleman has number 7, sir.
- What about number 8?
It doesn't really make
any difference, so long
as it's a good room...
windows and all that.
I quite understand, sir.
I think perhaps the room
next to yours would be best.
It's quite cozy, isn't it,
Miss Pollitt? Number 8?
- They're all very much alike to me, sir.
- (JONES) Eight'll do.
Will you bring the young lady
and sign the book, please?
Yes, I'll... I'll get her.
(PEOPLE CONVERSING, INDISTINCT)
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening, Stiles.
Terrible thing, sir, that poor man
who was here this morning.
Yes, terrible, Stiles.
My bags all packed?
- Yes, sir.
- And Miss Carol's?
Mrs. Stiles packed hers too.
She hopes she's put in the right things.
It's been such a rush, especially
with Miss Carol not back yet.
Mr. ffolliott's here now.
He's waiting in the sitting room.
Another gentleman just phoned.
He wouldn't leave his name.
I thought I recognized
his voice as the
foreign gentleman who
was here at breakfast.
- Did he say he'd telephone again?
- Yes, he said it was urgent.
Well, show Mr. ffolliott
into the study.
Hello, sir.
Scott, you caught me
at a very busy moment.
I'm getting ready to go
to America tomorrow.
Are you taking
Carol with you?
Yes. She doesn't know yet. It's been
such a rush. I'm waiting for her now.
What's your worry? Must be important,
by the number of times you telephoned.
Yes, it is, sir.
It's about Carol.
- I'm afraid that...
- What? Anything happen to her?
I don't think you'll be able
to take her to America.
What do you mean?
Why not?
It'll sound rather silly to you,
but Carol has been kidnapped.
- Is this a joke of some sort?
- No, sir.
What do you mean, "kidnapped"?
I happen to know
she's with her aunt in Harpenden.
I'm afraid she isn't.
Stiles, who gave you the message that Miss
Carol had gone to her Aunt Margaret's?
Miss Carol herself, sir.
- Thank you, Stiles.
- That's where she thought she was going.
Get me Harpenden 43422.
Hello, is that you, Margaret?
Is Carol with you?
No. No, I...
I wasn't' certain. She said
she might run down to see you.
I didn't know whether
to expect her back for dinner.
Right. Good night, Margaret.
No, she isn't there.
What makes you say
she's been kidnapped?
Well, sir... I arranged it.
This has gone far enough.
Where is Carol?
Carol's being held
as a sort of hostage...
by some people who are very much
in earnest... as much as you are.
Don't be so cryptic. I haven't the
faintest idea what you're talking about.
I want to know
where you're hiding Van Meer.
(CHUCKLES) So that's it.
You've been talking with Haverstock.
He was here this morning telling us
about Van Meer still being alive.
You promised Haverstock you'd
look into it, didn't you?
Naturally.
An unusual way of looking into it,
trying to have him put out of the way.
I realize a life or two is a small
matter, the way you work.
Well, the people who have got Carol
can take a leaf out of your book.
Where is she?
What have you done with her?
Where's Van Meer?
(RINGING)
Hello?
I think I can get our Dutch friend
to talk if you come along.
Sorry to drag you here like this,
but I think it's the only way...
if you want to leave tomorrow.
When you get here,
ask at the cashier's desk...
to use the phone.
They'll show you straight up.
Very well.
I'll drop in as soon as I can.
If you want Carol, you'd better
tell me where Van Meer is.
Bring her back. I'll
give you the address.
Carol can be home
in three hours...
but I want that address now.
You'll have it as soon
as Carol is home.
I can't possibly
wait three hours.
Besides, I happen
to want Van Meer alive.
- (DOG BARKING)
- (BRAKES SQUEAL)
(CAR DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(DOOR OPENS)
Well, Scott,
I delivered him, all right.
Good.
I'll be getting along now. Thanks very
much for those points for my leader.
Can I take them now?
Good night, Carol. Good night, sir.
(CAROL) Good night.
I beg your pardon, sir.
(WIND GUSTING)
This isn't like you.
What is it that's upset you so?
I know I'm being silly.
I'm behaving perfectly stupidly.
Please forgive me.
I wouldn't mind so much...
but I didn't think
he was that sort of person.
Something to do
with young Haverstock?
You like him very much,
don't you?
After what happened today...
I drove him down to the country to
get him away from those people...
I thought you were going
to Aunt Margaret's.
We were, but Scott ffolliott...
thought it would be better
to go further away.
So...
I thought the College Arms
at Cambridge would be a good place.
When we got there,
I found out he wanted...
You see,
we'd been joking about it...
but when I heard him book
the extra room, I knew he meant it.
Such a cheap trick.
That's what hurts." It was so cheap.
It wasn't at all
like I thought he was.
What difference does it make?
I don't care if I ever see him again.
You won't have to. We're going
to America tomorrow by clipper.
Tomorrow?
Oh, but I can't.
Well... I suppose I can,
but why tomorrow?
It's our last chance. War will
probably be declared tomorrow.
I have to get to Washington. The boats will
be crowded. We're liable to wait weeks.
- But what about Mr. Van Meer?
- We've done all we could.
I was at the foreign office
with Ainsworth this afternoon.
They're taking
the whole thing over.
Stiles, what is it?
The blackout, sir. I
have to draw the blinds.
Oh, I forgot.
Before you do that,
order me a taxi, will you?
Yes, sir.
I've got people I must see
before we leave.
I'll try not to be long.
Mrs. Stiles has done your packing.
I thought we might go to Southampton,
stay at the Southwestern.
Stiles, and my hat, please.
Good-bye, darling.
In the meantime, you and Stiles might be
loading the car so as not to lose time.
- You'd better eat.
- What about you?
I'll get a sandwich later.
242 Charlotte Street...
halfway up
Tottenham Court Road.
Wait here until Haverstock turns up.
He's bound to come here.
Bring him along
to 242 Charlotte Street...
off Tottenham Court Road.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- Hello. Hello?
- Hello.
- (THUNDER CRASHING)
- (WHISPERING) Be careful.
- (HAMMER POUNDING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Might I use your telephone?
This way, sir.
♪♪ (UPBEAT JAY ON RECORD PLAYER)
Where is he?
In there. We can't make him
say anything. It's up to you.
Let's get it over.
Is this place safe?
There'll be no interruption.
We closed it for decoration.
- Those people downstairs?
- They won't make any trouble.
They know what will happen to their
relatives in the homeland if they do.
♪♪ (VOLUME INCREASES)
(GROANING)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
♪♪ (ENDS)
♪♪ (RESUMES)
(KRUG) Not a very attractive nest,
and the music a little vulgar...
but if serves its purpose.
Yes.
Pardon me.
(INDISTINCT)
Put your arm around him...
and hold his head forward.
These lights...
can't you cut them down?
(INDISTINCT)
- ♪♪ (OFF)
- (GASPING)
I thank you.
Oh, I thank you very much.
You're like my friend,
Mr. Fisher.
I'm sorry.
It's just so dark.
I cannot tell, but...
but you are
so like my friend.
I am Fisher, Mr. Van Meer.
I am your friend.
Oh!
I am so glad.
Mr. Fisher,
are the police here?
Oh, they mustn't get away.
You mustn't let
these people go.
I represent the Jupiter Life Assurance.
Could I interest you in a small policy?
- (KRUG) Why did you bring him up?
- (WOMAN) I didn't know what to do.
I'd relieve the lady
of this embarrassment...
but you know
how women are with firearms.
No sense of timing.
I'll just sit here.
You carry on
with whatever you were doing.
Don't mind me.
I sometimes sit like this for hours.
(VAN MEER) Who's that?
Is it the police?
Oh, tell me where I am.
You are in London, Mr. Van Meer.
In London?
Have I been here long?
Oh, you must send
a telegram...
to my wife.
Tell her I am safe with you.
Please try to understand.
The police are not here.
I am here
merely to talk to you.
But these... these people...
They think I'm working with them.
They don't know I'm your friend.
We must play a little game.
- A little game?
- Yes.
They have asked me
to get you to tell me...
what they are trying
to find out.
But I can't do that.
You know I can't.
You can tell me, Mr. Van Meer.
Just that one clause
in the treaty. Clause 27.
Clause 27.
Come, Mr. Van Meer.
But it's the... the secret clause.
I know it: Clause 27.
But they...
they mustn't know it.
It would help them
if they make war.
War, Fisher. You don't
want them helped, do you?
Of course not.
Just let them see you
telling it to me.
It'll be enough.
Just let them see you
whisper it to me.
I'll promise to keep it safe.
(FFOLLIOTT) He's not your friend.
Don't fell him.
(VAN MEER) Who was that?
Someone just said
you weren't my friend.
Why didn't you bring
the police?
Why aren't you taking me
away from here?
Ah.
You are not taking me away.
Why?
You are so...
F-Fisher?
Fisher!
Fisher, where are you?
Help me.
Help me, Fi...
Help...
Oh, yes.
(WRY CHUCKLE)
I see now.
There's no help.
No help for the whole...
poor, suffering world.
Oh, you...
you cry peace, Fisher.
Peace.
And there was no peace.
Only war and death.
You're...
You're a liar, Fisher.
A cruel, cruel liar.
(GASPS)
You can do
what you want with me.
That's not important.
But you'll never
conquer them, Fisher.
Little people everywhere...
who give crumbs to birds...
lie to them...
drive them, whip them...
force them into war.
When the beasts like you...
will devour each other...
then the world...
will belong
to the little people.
We're wasting valuable time.
Kurt.
(VAN MEER CRYING OUT)
(GROANING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
All right. I...
I will speak.
(GROANS)
I will tell everything.
(KRUG)
Come on, Mr. Fisher.
(VAN MEER) In the event
of invasion by an enemy...
(JONES)
Why, it's only a restaurant.
Look! Come on!
This way, sir!
Down the back stairs!
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
- (PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
Follow me!
Come on, Haverstock!
They must've gone out some other way!
You're an idiot if you don't nab Fisher
before he gets on that plane.
How can we arrest him
without any evidence?
Don't be so obstinate. isn't
Van Meer himself proof enough?
No, and you ought to know it.
What proof is there
against Fisher personally?
Of all the conceited,
stupid numbskulls...
If you'd stop behaving like
a Boy Scout and let us handle this...
Ask McKenna to come in here.
Why don't you go see Dr. Boniface?
He's good for nerves.
- Identification of Van Meer complete?
- Absolutely.
He's unconscious in the nursing home,
but there's no doubt it's Van Meer.
You'd better get back there.
Take somebody with you.
Get a statement
as soon as he comes to.
In the meantime, send a
man to keep an eye on
that flying boat and await
instructions from us.
What's the good of being
related to Scotland Yard?
I can't get my brother
to do anything.
Scotland Yard can't
solve my problems.
Scotland Yard's in on it.
Everybody but me.
You're in it too. We've got to get on
that plane and keep an eye on Fisher.
While we're driving down,
ring up Mayfair 24574.
- Just a moment. Let me get it down.
- Mayfair 24574.
That's my cousin.
He's the director of the airline.
Tell him I've got to have two seats on the
clipper for America tomorrow morning.
Then go to the Hilton Nursing Home
and stick by Van Meer.
Then phone Miss Edith Armbruster, Kensington
66255 Tell her I'm off to America.
Will she dine with me next Monday
instead of tomorrow?
- Square it with her, will you .7
- Sure, sure.
Then call up Stephens at the Post
and tell him I'm off to America.
(JONES) Cable New York.
Tell them I'm off to America.
(FFOLLIOTT) Then ring up the Crescent
Dancing Academy and cancel my rumba lesson.
Two ham sandwiches on rye bread.
There's no use my waiting around.
I have several things...
Hard to say how soon he'll recover.
It may be hours before he can speak.
I don't know much about this,
but my friend's on the clipper.
The minute Van Meer speaks,
they'll send word to the plane.
Did you hear the wireless?
We're at war.
(MAN) War declared!
Read all about it! Special war edition!
War declared! War!
It's war with Germany!
War declared!
England declares war
on Germany!
Miss Pimm?
Miss Pimm, I found that picture.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- Steward, bring me one of those, please.
- Yes, sir.
- Any message for me?
- What name, sir?
Steward, is there a message
for me? Mrs. Benson.
I'll be with you
in a minute, madam.
- This one's for me.
- Yes, sir.
(CAROL) Lovely, isn't it?
Sort of makes you forget
all about the war and troubles.
It would be nice
if we could just keep flying...
for a long time,
live in the clouds.
Yes, it would be very nice.
But it's time for me
to make a landing...
a forced landing.
What's the matter?
Anything happen?
I've got to talk to you.
I don't want to, but I've got to.
It's the hardest part...
talking to you now.
I don't mind
about the rest, really.
It's about Krug
and Van Meer.
You've guessed.
Not till last night.
I've just been worried.
But I believed in you.
You shouldn't.
It's true, then,
what I wouldn't believe?
Yes.
I'm to be arrested
when we land...
- Oh!
- As a spy, shipped back to London.
- Father...
- That's quite all right, except...
just the one phase of it: you.
That's why
I've got to talk to you.
I should like you to hear a little
from my own point of view.
It might help you...
afterwards.
First about yourself,
my deceiving you.
I had to. I didn't want you involved because
you're English... half English, anyway.
I'm not. I'm just coated with
an English accent... a very thin coat.
I've fought for my country
in my heart in a very difficult way...
because sometimes it's harder
to fight dishonorably...
than nobly in the open.
I've used my country's methods
because I was born with them.
I don't intend making this sort
of plea to the court-martial.
I'm making it only to my daughter,
whom I've loved dearly...
and before whom
I feel a little...
ashamed.
What you say to me now means much
more to me than any other verdict...
my dear.
- Steward?
- Yes, sir?
This is not for me.
I was mistaken.
I'm not gonna sit here another 14 hours
and play hide-and-seek with her.
I'm gonna talk to her
and have it over with.
I don't see that you could do any harm.
He knows we're on the plane.
- Not a word in front of her, understand?
- I wouldn't dream of talking.
- What are you going to say?
- How do I know? I'm all mixed up.
In love with the girl
and gonna help hang her father.
I've got to say something
or go crazy.
Would a little brandy
make you feel better?
You know it always
makes me cry harder.
- Oh!
- Surprise.
- What are you doing here?
- Just having myself a ride.
Look, Carol,
I've got to speak to you alone.
It's very important.
Do you mind, Mr. Fisher?
- ffolliott's with you, isn't he?
- In a way, yes.
And you're both
after my father.
You're going to have him
arrested, aren't you?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I never arrested anyone in my life.
That's a lie. You've been
following him from the beginning.
That's why you wanted me
out of the way yesterday at the inn.
Pretended you loved me, tried to
keep me overnight so you could...
it's a lie, that's all. Everything
you've said to me have been lies.
- Hello. Quite a reunion, isn't it?
- You too?
Please, dear.
Stay and have a drink, Scott.
- I'll be back.
- Where are you going?
Just to stretch my legs.
I read that wireless you received.
- It was given to me by mistake.
- That's all right, sir.
You're not going
unless I go with you.
I know you both think my father
is a traitor and a renegade.
Well, he isn't... not to me.
Thanks. It's a minority report,
but very welcome.
Carol, I've got nothing
to do with spies.
I'm just a reporter.
I came here after a story.
I'm sorry I heard of Van Meer.
I'd blow up the Globe...
and cut Mr. Powers's throat
rather than harm you.
(EXPLOSIONS)
What is it?
They've gone crazy. What
do they think they're doing?
Who are they?
Go below. Tell them
we're being attacked.
(WOMAN GASPING)
(PEOPLE SCREAM)
Sorry about this.
It has nothing to do with me.
We're coming down.
You're the most amazing,
cool-headed woman I've ever seen.
- Make Father wear this.
- Right.
Here you are.
Put these on.
- (EXPLOSIONS)
- Keep changing.
Could you come out, sir?
They're all going nuts!
I'll be out immediately. What am I going
to say? This isn't like bad weather.
Tell them it's a mistake,
that it's target practice.
(EXCITED CHATTERING)
I know it's foolish for
me to ask you to be calm.
- We're doing the best we can.
- (EXPLOSIONS)
(INDISTINCT)
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
(WOMAN)
Are we all going to be drowned?
Keep away
from that window, sir.
It might be dangerous.
Sit back.
I'm not going to put this on.
What are they firing at?
I never heard of anything so stupid.
I shall see the British consul
as soon as...
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
She's gone.
What in the name of heaven
are they doing?
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Switch off the gas.
You've got the other port motor.
They cut off the other starboard motor.
Cut that off too.
Right.
It's German, the Von Schier.
She thought we were a bomber.
She's steaming to our rescue.
- The Wing's coming off!
- (PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- Let me get out!
- Come away from that door!
We're crazy to stay here.
When she hits the water,
the tail's the best place.
Right.
Let's get back there.
(CLATTERING)
(MAN) Look out!
(ALL CLAMORING)
Mr. Fisher!
Quick!
(SCREAMING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
No good staying on here.
She's going under.
Quick! Onto the wing!
(EXCLAIMING)
Look! There's the pilot!
Don't let him on, fools!
We shall all go down!
Shut your mouth!
- I'm gonna throw that swine off.
- No, he's right.
It won't hold us.
I'd better slip away.
Quickly move to the other end.
That might make it lighter here.
Hurry! He's gone!
Johnny, don't go!
You'll be washed away!
Johnny, come back!
Look!
It must be the enemy
coming to pick us up.
Is it the enemy?
We're all right.
She's American.
(MAN) American ship Mohican picked
us all up, taking us back to London.
I can't tell you what happened.
We're not allowed.
I'll wire from London
in a couple of days. Bye, Franklin.
This is awkward. I've just been
having a dirty row with the captain.
The fellow insists on acting
the true-blue neutral.
"Enemy waters." Not a line
to the press from his ship.
Can't send out any stories?
We can only use the wireless
for private messages.
"Hello, Aunt Effie. Safe aboard
the Mohican. Feeling tip-top."
I ask you! Two days before we get to
London, we get scooped on our own story.
Why don't you have a
crack at brass buttons?
What's the use?
What good will it do me?
My hands are tied.
- What are you talking about?
- Carol.
I came 4,000 miles
to get a story.
I get shot at like a duck,
pushed off buildings...
I get the story,
and then I got to shut up.
What are you grinning at? I'm not
gonna throw her father up for grabs.
He died like a hero to save
her and the rest of us.
I guess I'm talking
through my hat.
The whole point is
he was her father...
and I'm not gonna play
Judas to the only girl...
I'm glad you've said that.
Very glad.
- You dry? You all right?
- I'm all right.
I want you to send it,
the whole story.
- We'll talk about that later.
- No, please.
You can't help me
by protecting my father.
Listen, I'm in love with you. I can't hit
you with a scandal for a wedding present.
Johnny, my father fought
for his country his way.
It wasn't a straight way,
but it was a hard way.
And I've got to fight
for my country a hard way.
Okay, if that's the way
you feel about it.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- I guess that's for me.
I put in a call to my uncle...
Uncle Powers.
Hello? Hello?
Johnny Jones
calling from the Mohican.
What the deuce is he doing there? Wait.
Johnny wouldn't call if it wasn't a story.
Tell them to hold the presses.
Send Bradley in.
Tell him we're breaking up
page one. Hello?
Hello, Mr. Powers.
This is Johnny Jones.
Easy.
Here comes the captain.
Mr. Powers, keep your ear
glued to this phone...
and don't hang up.
Mr. Haverstock, I
want to talk with you.
Yes, sir?
I've just found out
you're a newspaperman.
I guess that's right.
Why didn't you tell me that
when I questioned you?
- You lied to me, sir.
- My dear captain...
when you've been shot down in
a British plane by a German destroyer...
300 miles off the coast of
England... latitude 45...
and have been hanging on
to a half-submerged wing for hours...
waiting to drown with half a dozen
other stricken human beings...
you're liable to forget
you're a newspaperman for a moment.
You're gonna have to forget it
for as long as you're on this ship.
I can't understand
your attitude, sir.
You performed a heroic rescue.
Captain John Martin.
You took us out of the sea.
You're not sending
anything from this ship.
- That's final.
- You're absolutely right, Captain.
We mustn't embarrass
the United States government.
Exactly. That's my point.
(INDISTINCT)
That's the story.
If you don't want me to print it, okay.
- But you ought to hear it first.
- That's only fair.
(INDISTINCT)
You know who the head of that movement
was in London? Stephen Fisher.
What? You mean the man who ran the
Universal Peace Party? That's preposterous!
Yes, the same Mr. Fisher
who was drowned a few hours ago.
He was using the Peace Party
as a cover-up for spies and traitors.
He was going to be arrested
and sent back to England.
Those are facts.
I can't believe it. He
was a friend of mine.
The same Stephen Fisher who engineered the
kidnapping of Van Meer, the Dutch diplomat.
You don't expect
anybody to believe that.
It's the truth.
- I refuse...
- Captain, wait a minute.
This young lady should
know whether my friend
is speaking the truth
about Mr. Fisher.
Yes, I ought to know.
Mr. Fisher was... my father.
- And I want the story printed.
- (CLICKING, INDISTINCT VOICES)
What's that?
Oh, I guess
that's my uncle. Uh...
Hello? Oh, hello, Uncle.
How are you?
(INDISTINCT)
How's Aunt Sadie?
I'm all right, thanks.
We had a little accident,
but I can't tell you about it now.
I'll tell you later. I'll write you.
Yes, I'm going back to Europe.
I was wondering
if you had any instructions for me.
Yes. Keep on the job.
Have you got all that?
Rush it out at once.
This is London.
We have as a guest tonight...
one of the soldiers
of the press...
one of the little army
of historians writing history...
from beside
the cannon's mouth...
the foreign correspondent of the New
York Globe, Huntley Haverstock.
Hello, America.
I've been watching a part
of the world being blown to pieces.
A part of the world as nice
as Vermont and Ohio...
(SIREN WAILING)
and Virginia and
California and Illinois...
lies ripped up and bleeding
like a steer in a slaughterhouse.
I've seen things that make the history of
the savages read like Pollyanna legends...
it's a raid. We shall have
to postpone the broadcast.
- Let's go on as long as we can.
- We have a shelter downstairs.
- (SIREN CONTINUES)
- How about it, Carol?
- They're listening in America, Johnny.
- Okay.
- We'll tell them, then.
- (EXPLOSIONS)
I can't read the rest of the speech...
the lights have gone out...
so I'll just have to talk
off the cuff.
All that noise you hear isn't static.
It's death coming to London.
They're coming now. You can hear the
bombs falling on the streets and homes.
Don't tune me out. This is a big
story, and you're part of it.
It's too late to do anything here except
stand in the dark and let them come.
It's as if the lights were all out
everywhere... except in America.
Keep those lights burning.
Cover them with steel,
ring them with guns...
build a canopy of battleships
and bombing planes around them.
Hello, America!
Hang on to your lights.
They're the only lights left
in the world.
(CHOIR)
♪ And the rockets' red glare ♪
♪ The bombs bursting in air ♪
♪ Gave proof through the night ♪
♪ That our flag was still there ♪
♪ O say, does that
star-spangled banner ♪
♪ Yet wave ♪
♪ O'er the land of the free ♪
♪ And the home ♪
♪ Of the brave ♪