23.976
[ Man ] Of course, women have always
been a vital link...
in the lifeline that supplies
combat units.
The last few years have brought
real progress...
in the interests of women in
all aspects of naval service.
What's more, the Navy has instituted
special sensitivity courses...
for all its male recruits,
demonstrating even more progress- -
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
Mr. Hayes.
lf a cannibal used a knife and fork,
would you call that progress too ?
[ Observers Laughing ]
Well, perhaps, if l could just finish,
Madame Chairman, your questions- -
Oh, l'm just an old dame
without much time left,
so you'll pardon me
if l jump right in here.
l'm deeply concerned over the Navy's
seemingly incontrovertible attitude...
toward women in the military.
-  Case in point: the Lark Report.
-  [ Murmuring ]
Uh, Madame Chairman, this is
an internal document of the U.S. Navy.
The Navy's analysis of that F- 14 crash
at Coronado last year.
Female aviator,
it just so happens.
You were party to this report.
Am l right ?
l am really not prepared
to go into an in- depth- -
lf you are vying for the office
of the Secretary of the Navy, Mr. Hayes,
l'd like to think
you were prepared for anything.
[ Observers Murmuring ]
Fspecially if you're lookin'
for my confirmation.
l'm struck by the ill- spirited
tenor of your report:
degrading remarks
by other aviators,
innuendo about her performance
in unrelated situations.
There's even a reference here to
her seXual activity the weekend prior.
[ Hayes ] These are not
unrelated circumstances.
ln my seven years
on this committee,
l have never seen a downed aviator
treated like this, never.
l'm deeply disturbed
by this report, Mr. Hayes.
Not just what it bodes
for the future of women in the Navy,
but your future as well.
Do you eXpect to take criticism
for using this confirmation hearing...
as a pulpit
for women's rights ?
Look, nearly one- quarter of
all jobs in the U.S. military...
are still to this day off- limits
to women, and that has gotta change !
What about those that say women
aren't suited for all jobs,
they're physically weaker ?
How strong do you have to be
to pull a trigger ?
That was quick.
Yeah, she did great.
Are you kidding ?
She's always great.
Private meeting.
That's what we want.
Are you worried about the neXt round
of base closures, Senator ?
-  As long as it doesn't affect me.
-  Defense boys already called.
[ Sighs ] They want
a private meeting with you.
l'll act surprised.
Senator, this is a contingency program
for 1OO percent integration.
lf female candidates measure up
in a series of test cases,
the D.O.D. will support full
integration within three year's time.
We get our man. You get
your gender- blind Navy, Senator.
Surely you're not gonna
balk at that.
l have to pick
the test cases.
The Navy'll want approval
over the women.
-  So l'll approve their approval.
-  [ Chuckling ] Come on, Senator.
Let's concentrate on the steak
and not the peas.
lf women measure up to the men, they've
got the job. That's what's on the table.
You're not having
second thoughts, are you ?
-  Well, Doug ?
-  Congratulations, Mr. Secretary.
So, what program ?
l'd go C.R.T.
Combined Reconnaissance Team.
SFALS.
SiXty percent dropout rate.
No woman's gonna last a week.
l don't care who she is.
Then l suggest
we start there.
[ Hayes ]
Good work.
[ Man ] Hostile activity.
Mined area.
l say again:
hostile activity, mined area.
Maintaining holding action.
-  Carrying one wounded.
-  [ Phone Ringing ]
FXtracting to new location
secondary P.Z. Over.
Bravo SiX, this is Avalanche.
Negative
on secondary rendeZvous.
Strongly suggest new location.
Over.
[ Bravo SiX ] Stand by, Avalanche.
Will consult team leader.
[ Static Over Headphones ]
-  [ Avalanche ] Bravo SiX.
-  Go to sea level.
Say again your last.
Over.
Bravo SiX, this is Avalanche.
Bravo SiX.
-  We've lost the horiZon.
-  Bravo SiX.
-  You didn't account for that ?
-  Yes, sir, we did,
but we didn't count on the SFAL unit
being delayed for five hours...
and then eXfiltrating
this close to this high terrain.
But Keyhole- 5 will be L.O.S.
in 18 minutes, sir.
Launch base will need
that much time to key their gear.
Advise launch base
accordingly, Goldstein. Now.
Sir, l'd recommend against it.
These are skilled operators.
They've grasped their problem by now and
will take action to get back on- line.
lt's just a glitch
in the net changeover, sir.
l'll have it ironed out
momentarily.
Advise launch base,
Goldstein.
Something to add,
Lieutenant ?
lf we keep the primary satellite
the unit can negotiate its way
down to this plateau here.
Reestablish comms.
lt's a clear shot.
What about those two areas inland ?
That's closer to their position.
But that's behind them.
They'll wanna keep moving
seaward, sir, yet find a spot...
that gives 'em the line of sight
on the satellite.
This plateau here.
That's where l'd head, sir.
Last l checked, you were a topographic
analyst, not an operations specialist.
-  Why don't you just let it- -
-  lf they have wounded,
they might be inclined
to stay put.
Wait till the new bird
comes into L.O.S.
But they also know the tides are
slipping out under their recovery sub.
They'll hump their wounded out. They'll
reach this plateau in ten minutes.
Make that nine now.
We can't switch the net, sir.
We'll be listening for them...
on the wrong channel
with the wrong crypto.
Give it eXactly nine minutes.
[ Phone Ringing ]
Okay, let's see
what the cat dragged in.
They've preapproved
all these candidates.
Top scores, marksmanship.
Distance runner. Took fifth place
in some intra- service marathon. Age 287.
Perfect, till they do
a chromosome check.
Some impressive
fitness reps here.
Holder of several records
for female power- lifting.
ls this the face you want to see
on the cover of Newsweek ?
She looks like the wife
of a Russian beet farmer.
l like this one.
Triathlon, winter sports,
Olympic contender,
winner of the Arlie Burke
essay contest, works lntel.
-  Too much of a think- tank soldier.
-  No, no, show me, show me.
Well, this really is
top drawer...
with silk stockings inside.
-  We've waited about as long as we dare.
-  Do it.
Change the net.
Launch base,
this is N.l.C. control.
We're going to conduct
a net changeover...
to Keyhole- 5 at
the following coordinates.
This is Bravo SiX.
Still got siX heartbeats here...
holding on some kind of plateau.
l say again, siX passengers
looking for a ride home.
-  We're good to go.
-  Belay my last.
Copy that. Maintain perimeter.
Advise further hostile status.
-  That was good headwork, Lieutenant.
-  Well, thank you, sir.
l'm glad we could get
involved and do some good.
Now the problem is,
lntel officers don't get involved.
We monitor, analyZe.
You need to learn
the fine art of detachment, Lieutenant.
[ Woman ] FXcuse me, there's a call
from the Sec Nav's office.
-  l'll take it inside.
-  No, sir, eXcuse me.
Lieutenant O'Neil,
the call's for you.
l'll take it inside.
[ Woman ] Thanks for holding.
l'll put you through.
[ Clock Ticking, Chiming ]
l'm thinking about redoing
the place.
lt's beginning to remind me
of an old whorehouse over the years.
-  Good evening, ma'am.
-  Good evening, Lieutenant.
Ma'am, may l ask
what this is regarding ?
-  Didn't they tell you ?
-  No, ma'am.
Well, this'll be a toot.
You read, l'll pour.
[ Liquid Pouring ]
lt's just a test case, Jordan,
but if things work out,
if you can go the distance,
it could well change the military's
official policy on women in combat.
Or, actually,
its official non- policy.
Begging your pardon,
Senator,
but you do understand this
involves SFAL training ?
l do.
l also understand...
that you applied for active duty
during the Gulf War and got turned down.
Yes, ma'am, there was an lntel slot
available aboard the U.S.S. Polk,
but they told me that submarines
had no bathroom facilities for women.
-  Did that piss you off ?
-  Yes, ma'am, it did.
Good. l like pissed off.
-  Sit down, Lieutenant.
-  Yes, ma'am.
Have you got a man ?
-  Ma'am ?
-  At home ?
Fiance. Steady beau. You know,
some kind of solid heteroseXual.
l hate askin', but l don't want
this thing blowin' up in our faces...
if you happen to be battin'
for the other side.
Yes, ma'am, there's someone.
Well, wonderful.
Honey, come on. l survived jump school,
dive school and three brothers.
l think l can take care
of myself.
The only thing that scares me
are the seXual politics.
l'm just not interested in being
some poster girl for women's rights.
-  What ?
-  Hmm ?
You don't have anything
to say about this ?
l guess l don't.
Honey, this is just
a career opportunity.
-  You don't want me sleeping
my way to the top, do you ?
-  But the SFALS, babe ?
These guys are world- class warriors.
They see you coming- -
-  l mean- -
-  l'm aware they may not want me there.
-  ''May not'' ?
-  Yes.
They will eat corn flakes
out of your skull. Okay ?
To tell you the truth,
l don't get it.
l mean, you're doing
shit- hot at lntel.
Why do you wanna go off
and play soldier girl for ?
[ Sighs ]
Royce, we're the same age.
We entered the Navy the same month.
Which one of us
is wearing more ribbons ?
Oh, come on. This is just 'cause
l got lucky during the Gulf War.
Yes, thank you. Operational eXperience
is a key to advancement.
Yet anyone with tits can't be on a sub,
can't be a SFAL, and don't even think- -
Hey, whoa, whoa.
lf you made up your mind to do it, go.
You always do what you wanna do anyway.
Don't ask my permission.
You wanna go off and live
with a bunch of cock- swinging
commandos for three months- -
Three months ?
What if l make this and go operational
for three years ? What then ?
Oh, man, did l just miss
a decade or something ?
Will l wait if you go off to war ?
ls that what you're asking me ?
Yeah, something like that.
FXactly like that.
l didn't know l was gonna have to decide
the rest of my life tonight, Jordan.
Maybe we should just
let this happen.
Get your dick back in here.
Don't ask me to tell you how l'm gonna
feel in three years. l don't know.
l mean, neither do you.
Right up until you said that,
l thought l did.
[ Sighs ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Trainees Shouting ]
Carry on.
[ Trainees ]
Put it down ! Here we go !
[ Trainees Shouting ]
Lieutenant O'Neil
reporting for training, sir.
Yes, of course.
Please, Lieutenant,
have a seat.
Thank you, sir.
Would you care for a beverage ?
Tea ? Soda ?
-  l'm fine, sir.
-  You sure ?
Well, we're still coming to
terms with the eXact protocol...
for the integration
of our SFAL C.R.T. training.
-  Barber was my neXt stop, sir. l- -
-  Don't worry about it.
As long as it's off your collar, out of
your eyes, that's all l'm going to ask.
Sir, l'm not looking
for any special treatment.
We're not trying to change
your seX, Lieutenant.
You'll have a separate bed,
a separate head.
lf you have any special medical needs,
inform the infirmary.
lf your classmates or a superior
acts in a harassing...
or otherwise unbecoming manner,
you are to inform me
immediately,
so that l can deal with it
immediately.
lt may not always run smooth,
but we're trying to make it
as painless as possible.
Thank you, sir, but l eXpect
a certain amount of pain.
-  Any questions ?
-  None at this time, sir.
Then we're done, Lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
Permission to speak, sir ?
l'm not here to make
some kind of statement.
l care about completing the training
and getting operational eXperience,
just like everyone else,
l suspect.
lf you were like everyone else,
Lieutenant,
l suspect we wouldn't be
making statements...
about not making statements,
would we ?
-  Dismissed.
-  Aye- aye, sir.
Come on.
Average woman, 25 percent body fat.
Twenty- five.
That's a quarter fat, man.
l mean, think about that.
lf she pulls her own weight,
l got no problem with it.
No split- tail's getting through
this program. No way, Jose.
[ Chattering ]
Oh, man, doesn't she know
it's rude to point ?
-  Whoo- hoo !
-  [ Man Whistles ]
Look, l don't know what she did
to get in here. l hate to speculate.
l know l petitioned for two years
to get into this program.
Two years of letter writing,
two years of pulling strings,
and l finally get here,
and it's gone co- ed ?
Flite combat unit.
Whose genius idea was that ?
That's bullshit. l mean, they can't do
what we can. How's it happen ?
All l'm sayin' is one night, Lord. Give
me one night, and l'll set her straight.
[ Together ] Slovnik's feeling good
like a hard man should.
Stow it, gentlemen.
You heard the policy.
Attention on deck !
[ Bugle ]
Stand easy.
Welcome to SFAL C.R.T.
selection program.
You have volunteered for
the most intensive military training...
known to man.
You are all proven operators
within the spec ops community.
SFALS,
F.O.D.,
Army Delta,
Marine Force Recon,
Naval intel community,
and so on.
ln spite of your eXpertise,
many of you will not successfully
negotiate this program.
Those that do will eXperience
an operational tempo...
that far eXceeds that of any unit
within the U.S. arsenal.
That is all
that is to be said...
about the special nature
of the C.R.T. training program.
l now turn you over...
to my Command Master Chief
John James Urgayle.
Attention !
[ Chief ]
lnstructors, stand easy.
l never saw a wild thing
sorry for itself.
A bird will fall froZen dead
from a bough...
without ever having felt
sorry for itself.
[ Snickers ]
The ebb and flow
of the Atlantic tides,
the drift of the continents,
the very position of the sun
along its ecliptic.
These are just a few of the things
l control in my world.
-  ls that clear ?
-  Yes, Command Master Chief !
lnstructor Pyro.
Aye- aye, Master Chief.
lnstructors.
Boat crews, stand by your boats.
Move your asses !
[ Shouting ]
Get 'em up high !
Move your asses !
Forward, double time !
Hut !
[ Shouting ]
[ Pyro ] Hold them up, girls.
Come on. Don't you embarrass me.
Get that up !
What are you people, handicapped ?
Get your feet up ! Move it !
This day hasn't even begun !
Move it around !
Move the boat around !
Prepare to down boat !
Down boat, and don't you bruise
my sensitive fanny !
l will run your butt
all the way to the beach !
l have had better boat rides
by your mothers !
Worm sperm,
every damn one of you !
lnstructor, get these spoon- chested
pencil- necks out of my face !
[ Pyro ]
All yours, Master Chief.
[ lnstructor Johns ] Take a good look
at your new home.
Clarkson, get your boat crews !
Fall out by the fenders now !
Move it, move it,
move it, move it !
[ Trainees Shouting ]
SiXty percent of you
will not pass this course !
How do l know ? Because that is
an historical fact !
Now for the bad news !
l always like to get
one quitter on the first day !
And until l do,
that first day does not end !
-  [ Shouting ]
-  Look around ! Look to your right !
Look to your left.
l just wonder who it's gonna be.
Who's got the hair
to stick it out ?
Come on ! Be a part
of your crew's solution !
[ Screaming ]
-  There's one goin' down !
-  What are you doing on your knees ?
-  Stamm, are you hurt ?
-  No !
You wanna quit ? Then get the fuck up,
Stamm ! Get back on that fender !
-  Get up, guy !
What the hell is going on ?
-  Flea. Flea, you all right ?
-  What the fuck you doin' with him ?
-  Whoo- hoo !
-  What's your name, pancake ?
-  Flea ! l mean, Montgomery, sir !
Don't call me sir, moron.
l work for a living.
-  How many names you got anyway ?
-  lt's F. Lee Montgomery, but that
just gets whittled down to Flea.
-  Are you my quitter, Mr. Flea ?
-  No, sir, Master Chief !
Nothin' to be ashamed of, sir.
Do you wanna quit ?
Not me, Master Chief !
l'm full of joy !
What the hell is going on
down there ?
Move that fender !
Class !
Class, stand in line !
[ Johns ]
Drop down, bent over push- ups !
Quit playing with your hair,
O'Neil, and drop down !
-  lf you can't do these right,
O'Neil, do 'em on your knees !
-  l like these just fine, sir.
-  [ Shouting ]
-  Down !
Half a night, Lord.
Just give me half a night.
- CorteZ, stow the shit !
- l'm just having a seXual fantasy here !
[ Chief ] You have to be harder
than the average man...
to even get in
this program !
But l know some of you are already
thinking seriously about quitting !
[ Pyro ]
Get in this program, Stamm !
Come on !
You don't need this abuse !
Stamm, l think l have a quitter !
Do l have a quitter ?
Be ashamed for the rest
of your fucking lives !
Go !
Get out of that water !
Roll ! Right there !
Roll !
Pain is your friend,
your ally !
lt will tell you
when you are seriously injured !
lt will keep you awake
and angry...
and remind you to finish
the job...
and get the hell home !
But you know the best thing
about pain ?
l don't know !
lt lets you know
you're not dead yet !
[ Pyro ] l've seen Girl Scouts
move quicker than this !
You people are pathetic !
Down boat !
Mr. Wickwire,
you have four minutes...
to secure swim gear
and down chow !
Your entire class will
be severely penaliZed... [ Fades ]
[ Trainees Shouting ]
[ Pyro ] Get your asses going !
Get moving !
Goddamn it, what the fuck are you doing
sitting in my chair ?
Get the hell out of here !
Scrape your plates !
Get your ass up ! Get your ass up !
Get it up, boy !
[ Shouting ]
Get the hell out of here !
Scrape the plates
and get the hell out of here !
l want you to stroll !
Drop down !
Bear crawl, goddamn it ! What the hell's
wrong with you, shithead ?
l love the way you walk
l'm treated by your walk
to that beat
l got my eyes on you
[ Pyro ] All right, sewer trout,
everybody out !
Move it out !
Get in line
and get up here, people !
Keep the whole line long !
Move it, move it, move it !
Get on line !
Get on line right here !
-  Get on line !
-  All right, fall in ! Dress it up !
Get ready
for your med check !
They're all yours,
Lieutenant.
What's your name ?
-  Newberry.
-  What day of the week is it, Newberry ?
-  lt's fucking cold.
That's what day of the week it is.
-  Follow my finger.
That's good.
-  What's your name ?
-  McCool.
-  Uh- huh. Where are you from ?
-  San Diego.
San Diego.
Follow my finger.
-  What's your name ?
-  O'Neil.
All right,
follow my finger, O'Neil.
-  Let me see your fingertips. Cold ?
-  Yeah.
Way to gut it out,
Lieutenant.
[ Pyro ] All right, corpsmen, they're
gonna live. Get the hell out of there.
Class, fall out for chow.
Move. l said move, goddamn it ! What
do you want to do, take another swim ?
Maybe we don't want
chow tonight.
Move your girlie butts !
[ Chief ] After you pack grits, report
to Alpha barracks on the double.
Get them dick- skinning hands out of my
garbage cans. What the hell's goin' on ?
l told you, get your chow
and report to Alpha barracks !
lf you feel
you cannot carry on- -
lf you now care to admit
that you are woefully out of your depth,
that bell is your salvation.
Strike it three times,
and you're out.
Free to get a hot shower
and a good night's sleep.
l know you're saying
to yourself,
''l'm an eXperienced operator.
''l've put up with
19 straight hours of this.
Do l really need
another 12 weeks ?''
lf you don't know the answer to
that question, you do not belong here.
-  Back up, guys. Back up.
-  That's all right,
'cause this program
is not for everyone.
Just step up to the bell,
save us all a lot of trouble.
Go ahead.
Any takers ?
Goin' once.
[ Grunting ]
-  Goin' twice.
-  [ Grunting Continues ]
All right,
welcome to a brand- new day.
-  [ Trainees Groaning ]
-  [ lnstructor ]  l was lost
-  Come on, now !
-  [ Together ]  ln a world of light
-   l always did
-  l did it, y'all !
-   What was right
-  Hang on !
But now l sing
A different song
-  [ Groaning, Sniffling ]
-   And l found joy
-   ln doing it wrong
-  Sing it !
l found a friend
-  Yeah !
-   ln Satan
-   l found a friend
-  Uh- huh !
-   ln Satan
-  Stamm, don't do it, Stamm !
-   l found a friend
-  Come on, Stamm ! Don't quit !
-  Come on, Stamm !
-  [ Gargling ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Bell Clangs
Three Times ]
[ Spits, Grunts ]
There goes Stamm.
Dilettante.
-  Slow day at the office.
-  Dropped on request.
ln no less than 5OO
neatly printed words,
tell me why you love
the United States Navy.
There will be no time limit
for this evolution.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Put that pencil down. Get your fucking
feet together and sit up straight !
You will write
when l tell you to write.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
When l come back,
l'll be countin' open eyes. Begin.
[ Opera ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Woman Singing
ln ltalian ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Opera Continues ]
Master Chief.
Rock and roll.
Favorable weather conditions
for the neXt evolution.
Are you ready, Lieutenant ?
Pencils down !
On your feet ! Get up !
Are you ready
for the neXt evolution ?
Hoo- yah, lnstructor Pyro !
[ Together ]
Hoo- hah !
Class, halt !
Right face !
Sling arms !
-  Fall out ! Close it in !
-  [ Pyro ] Fvenin', cupcakes.
Twelve minutes or less. That's all
you need to know about this course.
Group one: Newberry,
Hampton, McCool, Wickwire,
Slovnik and Fngland.
Group two: Miller, Flea, Powell,
Ayres, CorteZ and O'Neil.
You will find a white step
that is mandated female aid, O'Neil.
You will find and use them
on every barrier obstacle.
-  Sergeant, l don't wanna use any step.
-  Keep your mouth shut !
-  l wanna go through
like the rest of the guys !
-  Shut your fucking hole !
Group three: Marshall, DeLuise,
Brown, Simons, Flynn and Stow.
[ Johns ]
Group one, stand by !
Bust 'em !
[ Trainees Shouting ]
Hoo- yah !
Group two, stand by !
-  Bust 'em !
-  [ Shouting ]
Group three, stand by !
Bust 'em !
Move, move, move, move,
move, move !
[ Trainees Shouting ]
[ Gunfire ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
-  Move it ! Keep moving !
-  Faster !
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ lnstructor Shouting ]
O'Neil, let's go !
Let's move it on down !
[ lnstructor ] You want me
to get you a dress ?
-  Keep it moving ! Let's go !
-  Do you squat when you pee ?
Come on !
-  Go, go, go ! Go !
-  This way !
-  Go, go, go !
-  Keep it clear ! Move it !
-  [ Screaming ]
-  Flea !
Let's move ! Let's run !
[ Shouting Continues ]
Move, move, move !
lnto the tunnel !
Now !
[ Grunting ]
Get up ! Come on !
CorteZ, get over here !
Drop down. Come on !
Come on ! Come on, Flea !
Come on !
[ Grunting ]
-  Come on !
-  Go !
-  That's it !
-  Help me up, Jordan.
[ Grunts ]
Come on.
[ Loud Grunt ]
Grab my hand.
Give me your hand.
-  [ Grunting ]
-  Why don't you quit, O'Neil ?
Quit now.
[ Johns On Megaphone ] Let's go,
children. Come on. Let's go, CorteZ.
lt pays to be a winner.
Come on, move your fat ass.
Oh, this would be a fine time to quit,
wouldn't it, gentlemen ?
How many quitters we got ?
Come on ! Move it !
Get on up here, mud muffins. Come on.
You guys look like sea slugs.
O'Neil ! What are you
waitin' for, girl ?
Get your fine fanny
down here !
Come on, move it !
Move it, O'Neil !
-  [ FXplosion ]
-  [ Johns ] Oh, my God !
O'Neil just tripped the trip wire !
Thank you very much !
She is responsible for
killing the entire class.
-  Hoo- yah, O'Neil !
-  [ All Trainees ] Hoo- yah, O'Neil !
Newberry: 13:O8.
CorteZ: 13:1O.
Hampton: 13:15.
Blake: 13:22.
Presley: 13:487.
Pretty boy:
14 minutes flat.
-  You are the blue- ribbon loser.
-  [ Yawns ]
These siX have failed
the ''O'' course.
-  These siX will run the course again.
-  [ Trainee ] No, don't do it !
-  Come on, man ! Hang in there !
-  [ Trainees Shouting ]
Come on !
[ Clangs Three Times ]
Anybody else ?
All right.
The rest of you wanna- bes have two hours
before the neXt evolution.
l strongly suggest
you spend it in your racks...
or sick bay.
-  Mr. Wickwire.
-  Ten- hut !
Muster back here
at O8OO...
in your greens.
Haul out !
Class ! As you were.
Sergeant CorteZ,
however brief your stay
with this command might be,
there are two words you will learn
to put together:
Team... mate.
Carry on.
-  Wickwire, you heard him.
What are you waitin' for ?
-  Fall out. Move it !
[ Trainees Shouting ]
-  Hoo- yah !
What do we have here,
you hesitant bunch of harlots ?
You thinkin' about ringin' that bell ?
Don't think ! Move !
Come on, somebody ring that bell
for me, please !
Come on, honey bun, walk !
Get your bell- bangin' balls a- rollin' !
You can be home
curled up in bed...
-  [ Bell Clangs ]
-  in less than four hours !
-  Ring that bell !
-  [ Bell Clangs ]
That is music to my ears.
l'm gettin' emotional here.
Anybody else ?
What's the matter,
O'Neil ?
Come on.
l'd like to see
the Master Chief.
Lieutenant O'Neil requests
to speak to the Master Chief.
-  He's not home.
-  [ Sighs ]
FXcuse me, Master Chief.
CorteZ finished ahead of me in group
two, but he failed and l didn't. Why ?
lnstructor Pyro,
educate the lieutenant.
You received an automatic
3O- second deduction...
which put you
under the wire.
lt's called gender- norming,
O'Neil.
lt's standard procedure
for all females in physical training.
What ''all females,''
if l'm the only one ?
l think l should have
the choice.
Stand at attention.
Lieutenant O'Neil, when l want
your opinion, l'll give it to ya.
[ Grunting ]
Did you take this matter up
with my Command Master Chief ?
l believe you instructed me to come
directly to you, sir,
if l felt l was being
mistreated in any way.
Oh.
[ Door Shuts ]
All right, Lieutenant.
l want names.
l want specific grievances.
Permission
to speak frankly, sir ?
lt's you, sir.
-  lt started the moment l came here.
-  Oh ? Really ?
lt's the double standard.
The separate quarters,
the deferential treatment.
lt's the way you practically pulled
my chair out for me when we first met.
Because l was civil,
now you're complainin' ?
l can't afford civility, sir.
How am l supposed to fit in when
you've got me set up as an outsider ?
You've given me
a different set of rules.
The answer is, l can't.
Why don't you just issue me a
pink petticoat to wear around the base ?
Did you just have
a brain fart ?
Begging your pardon,
sir ?
Did you
just waltZ in here...
and bark at your
commanding officer ?
lf so, l regard that
as a bona fide brain fart,
and l resent it
when people fart inside my office.
l think you've resented me
from the start, sir.
What l resent,
Lieutenant,
is some politician...
using my base
as a test tube...
for her grand
social eXperiment.
What l resent...
is the sensitivity
training...
that is now mandatory
for my men,
the OB- GYN
l have to keep on staff...
just so someone can keep track
of your personal Pap smears.
But most of all,
what l resent...
is your perfume,
however subtle it may be,
competin' with the aroma
of my fine $3.59 cigar,
which l will put out
this instant...
if the phallic nature of it
happens to offend...
your goddamned
fragile sensibilities !
-  Does it ?
-  No, sir.
''No, sir,'' what ?
The shape
doesn't bother me, sir.
Just the goddamned
sweet stench.
[ Chuckles ]
One standard.
Just treat me the same.
No better, no worse.
You're gonna get
everything you want, O'Neil.
Let's just see if you want
what you're gonna get.
Hoo- yah, sir.
[ Pop ]
Hey- -
[ Clears Throat ]
Hello ?
Anybody here ?
Just didn't wanna
tell you
Oh, see, this way l'm
Havin' fun
with my new song
Wild circumstance
Who would've guessed
Forced my hand
-  [ Clippers BuZZing ]
-   When l was homeless
Just didn't understand
lf you saw me
Holding his hand
l fell
From your grace
lsn't that insane
l'm jealous
l didn't wanna tell you
To your face
But l left claims
That you couldn't refuse
Obvious
Your friends will see
l knew you'd get the word
eventually
l'd rather have them
Tell you
lt's just as well
The bitch is gone
-  [ FXplosion ]
-  [ Machine Gun Fire ]
Grab your sacks !
Get in line now ! Move !
-  Who the hell do you think
you are, coming in here ?
-  Guess l'm your roommate.
-  [ Trainees Shouting ]
-  N- -  N- -  No. You can't stay here.
-  You can't sleep here right neXt to me.
-  The C.O. says l can.
No- -  Come here.
Come here !
CorteZ, come here,
goddang it !
Lookit. Girlfriend bring all her stuff
in here like she think she gonna- -
-  Hey !
-  Shit ! This is TampaX !
-  Stand at attention !
-  This is not gonna happen.
[ Wickwire ]
Stand at attention !
Mr. Wickwire,
in your leisure time...
make out a schedule that rotates
head and shower usage.
Yes, Master Chief.
Anything else we can do
for your celebrity career, Lieutenant ?
-  That'll be all- -
-  You now have eXactly
one minute to muster !
[ Wickwire ] lf even one of you
Van Winkle wanna- bes are late,
l will personally see
none of you sleep for a week !
Let me get this straight:
We're sharing the same fucking head ?
Listen, you moron,
l am here to stay.
lf you don't wanna be in my life,
move out or ring out.
-  That's it. Fnd of file.
-  You got one minute
to put your fuckin' clothes on.
-  What about the tampons ?
-  Hey, hey, hey.
-  Don't you care about tampons ?
-  Get over yourself, Slovnik.
-  Put your clothes on. Let's go !
-  Nice.
-  Here we go.
-  [ Trainees Responding ] Here we go !
[ Chanting Continues ]
[ Shutter Clicking ]
[ Chanting ] Pick 'em up !
Put 'em down !
-   [ Chamber ]
-  [ Chattering, Laughing ]
l'll have another one.
Thanks a lot.
Oh, congratulations,
Mr. Secretary.
Say hello to the President
for me, will you ?
So, what was the deal you made
with the devil ? l mean, DeHaven.
-  Oooh.
-  Didn't you hear ?
Fffective immediately,
all vessels in the Navy...
can no longer
be referred to as ''she.''
-  [ All Laughing ]
-  We're to call it ''it.''
-  Royce, we need a fourth.
-  Yes, sir.
-  You're it.
-  Thank you, sir.
-  Hello !
-  Congratulations on the new job.
-  You'll make a fine- -
-  [ Whispers ] Mr. Secretary, sir.
Oh, man.
Not playing down to the abilities
of your superior officer, are you ?
No, sir. Snooker's just
not my game.
Too many balls
on the table.
Distracting, isn't it ? That one
pink ball right in the middle.
-  Who's got a cigar ?
-  Didn't know you smoked, sir.
l don't. l just want to chew
the hell out of it.
Uh, ''The woman, identity unknown,
is believed to be...
''the first female candidate for
the elite Navy SFALS training program.
Her presence could signal a shift
in the military's- - ''
These were supposed to have been
discreet test cases.
That was
the agreement.
Suppose this lady's getting friendly
with the press ?
lt's DeHaven. Had to be. She is gonna
milk this cow on all four tits.
ln the last two hours my office
has received 14 requests for interviews.
No interviews.
That's the last thing we need.
Where is she in the training,
this woman ?
We'll have that information
for you before the night's out.
lt's my understanding that she just
finished the P.T. phase of her training.
She made it
through hell week.
Won't last one week,
huh ?
So, have you been monitoring
this situation for us, Commander ?
No, sir. l just made
some unofficial inquiries.
Well, make it official.
l want a brief back in my office
once a week.
G.l. Jane. Why don't they just get it
over with and call her Joan of Arc ?
[ Chuckling ]
Your shot, Gary.
[ Horn Honking ]
Pardon me, sir. Phone call
from Senator DeHaven.
Captain Salem here.
Are you in the habit of lettin'
photographers traipse around your base,
snapping their fill ?
These are supposed to be
discreet test cases.
Senator, they stand out on a
public highway using telephoto lenses.
There is nothin'
l can do about it,
unless you want me to infringe
on their civil liberties,
which l'll be glad to do if you'll just
trim a little fat off the Constitution.
Did you just mouth off to a senior
member of the Senate Arms Committee ?
l'll give you points for style,
just nothin' for smarts.
-  l was just eXplaining- -
-  From this point forward,
l want all press matters...
coordinated via my office.
Let me handle the R.P.M.
l'll be goddamned if l'm gonna watch
Hayes pull flowers out of his ass...
and take credit
for this one.
l'll be sure to pass your request along
to my chain of command.
Good.
Now, how's my girl
doin', anyway ?
You need to know
what it feels like to drown...
in order
to avoid panic...
and perhaps gain those few seconds
that just might save your life.
The natural tendency
toward premature panic...
is what makes this such an effective
interrogation technique.
Mama told me
not to come
[ Grunting ]
That ain't the way
to have fun, no
Uh- uh
Carb 15.
Military designator: M4.
Nothing more than a chopped- down
version of the M16 assault rifle.
By taking the proper
precautions,
this weapon can be considered
water- resistant.
Many techniques have been developed
to seal the muZZle of the weapon.
-  Nothing, however, surpasses
the technique developed in my time.
-  CraZy. Wild.
-  Shut up, Slovnik.
-   Mama told me not to come
Mama told me
not to come
[ Groans ]
She said, That ain't the way
to have fun, no
Boat siX: Wickwire, McCool, Flea,
CorteZ, Slovnik and O'Neil.
-  Oh, come on.
-  [ Murmuring ]
Somebody got a problem
with my organiZational skills ?
Fine by me,
Master Chief.
No problem here,
That ain't the way
to have fun, no
to have fun
Stand by. Prepare to hit the surf.
Move !
Boat four,
answer me this:
When l see the sea once more,
will the sea have seen or not seen me ?
This will be
a graded eXercise.
On my mark.
Stand by.
Mark !
-  CorteZ, done.
-  Time !
Weapons on the table.
ls it hot out here,
or is it just me ?
[ Mouths Words ]
-  Kind of tender ?
-  lt's okay.
Mmm. This ?
-  [ Groans ] A little bit.
-  Okay, you can get dressed.
Try to get as much air on those
abrasions on your back as you can.
lt's called amenorrhea
when you lose your period.
lt's because you drop body fat, but
not at all unusual for female athletes.
Okay, you got tendinitis
in your right knee...
and, uh, that is standard issue
jungle rot on your left foot.
-  [ Sighs ] Lovely.
-  So, you're quite a mess.
Let's fiX me up
and get me back out there.
-  Hey, Jordan !
-  Whoa ! Ladies !
lf l follow you home,
would you have premarital seX with me ?
Slovnik ! You're barkin' up
the wrong dress. They ain't your type.
Shit fire
and save matches.
[ Reporters Shouting
Simultaneously ]
Goddamn three- ring circus
around here. Shit.
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ lnstructor ]
You trying to be bad ?
You could be home curled up,
playin' with electrical toys !
-  [ Bell Clanging ]
-  Go on !
Lieutenant,
why are you doing this ?
-  Do you ask the men the same question ?
-  As a matter of fact, l do.
-  And what do they say ?
-  'Cause l get to blow shit up.
Well, there you go.
-  [ Rain Falling ]
-  [ lnstructor ] On my mark. Stand by !
-  [ Weapons Clicking ]
-  Mark !
-  O'Neil, done.
-  CorteZ, done.
-  Does it work, Lieutenant ?
-  [ Rifle Cocks ]
Well done, Lieutenant.
[ Bell Clanging ]
[ TV Reporter ] The Navy is still
declining to release the woman's name,
but Senator DeHaven's office
is confirming that G.l. Jane...
has outlasted many of her male
counterparts in the elite Navy program,
said to be one of
the most grueling anywhere.
Joining us now on Washington Tonight,
for the feminist perspective- -
[ FXhaling Sharply ]
[ Chief ]
CoXswain, hard a- port !
-  Line it up ! Move it over !
-  Come about !
Straighten 'er out !
-  Line 'er up !
-  Stay on your line ! Get ready !
-  Whoo !
-  Come on ! Move aft !
Get up there !
Let's go, go, go !
Hoo- fucking- yah ! lt's like having seX
in a car crash ! Whoo- hoo !
Okay, McCool, get up there.
Hoo- yah, baby !
Come on, O'Neil.
Get on up here.
Let's go.
Use your arms ! God !
-  Come on, O'Neil !
-  Cut her loose !
Let her go !
Well, hoo- yah. About time
we dropped some dead weight.
We don't leave
our people behind !
What the hell you waitin' for ?
Get with your crew ! Get in there !
Let's go !
Come on, go !
You're swimmin' home !
-  Wanna pick 'em back up ?
-  Let's go home.
[ All Grunting ]
Well, this is bullshit.
Now they're hammering me
just because she's in my boat crew.
lf you'd kept your mouth shut, we
wouldn't be out here in the first place.
Had a grandfather
wanted to be a Navy man.
He wanted to fire them big guns
off them big- ass battleships.
Navy says to him, ''No. You can only do
one thing on a battleship, son.
That's cook.''
l'm not talkin' about
1OO years ago, either.
l'm talkin' the United States Navy,
middle of World War Two.
You know the reason
they gave him ?
The reason why they told my grandfather
he couldn't fight for his country ?
'Cause Negroes
can't see at night.
Bad night vision.
[ Flea ] Damn, McCool.
That's unbelievable.
Thank God
times have changed.
Have they ?
So, you see, O'Neil,
l know where
you're coming from.
To them you're just the new nigger
on the block, that's all.
-  You just moved in a little too early.
-  Thanks, man.
The lsraelis
tried it.
Women in combat.
Seems the men couldn't get used
to the sight of women blown open.
They'd linger over
the wounded females,
often trying to save those
who obviously couldn't be saved,
often to the detriment
of the mission.
You were given
the Navy Cross, right ?
Can l ask
what you got it for ?
Since it bears
on this conversation,
l got it for pulling a 24O- pound man
out of a burning tank.
So when a man tries to rescue
another man, he's a hero,
but when he tries to rescue a woman,
he's just gone soft.
Could you have
pulled that man clear ?
You couldn't even haul your own
body weight out of the water today.
Permission to get dressed,
Master Chief.
Mr. Fngland went out
with a stress fracture.
l'm moving Mr. Wickwire to boat five.
That puts you in charge of siX.
Why not McCool ?
He's the same rank ?
Because you were commissioned a month
earlier. Makes you senior officer.
Remember,
there are no bad crews,
only bad leaders.
[ Sighs ]
[ Royce ] ln the more academically
oriented evolution,
she's receiving
better marks than most.
Plus, she's outlasted
4O percent of her peers.
-  With dual standards.
-  Actually, no, sir.
She's been going head- to- head
with the men for some time now.
So she's lasted eight weeks.
That's wonderful.
Joan of Arc
meets Supergirl.
With S.F.R.F. training
coming up neXt week, sir.
Commander, we'd like to see
more detail in your reports.
Let's include
more background information.
Past training reps; medical history;
any grievances she previously filed.
Understood ?
Um, actually,
not completely, sir.
Am- -  Am l being asked to provide
ammunition against this woman...
in case the outcome isn't
what the Navy eXpects, sir ?
Absolutely not. We're simply
documenting as thoroughly as possible,
in the event this turns
into a legal matter.
Don't read anything
Machiavellian into it, Commander.
l'll try not to, sir.
Take your leave,
Commander.
Thank you.
Loganville. Wilmington.
Coronado. Bedsford.
This is deeper
than we thought.
[ Sighs ]
Look at TeXas.
l count four- -
no, five bases.
We may not have to suffer
DeHaven much longer.
She stands to lose 6,OOO military,
4,OOO civilian jobs,
maybe 35O million
in lost revenue per annum.
Re- election's
siX months off.
The D.O.D.'s put her
out of business.
-  [ Men Laughing ]
-  [ Vacuum Cleaner Running ]
[ Men Conversing ]
Yeah.
People in Washington are scope- locked
on what's happening down there.
-  Know how they're talking about you ?
-  l saw a newspaper.
That's the public side.
Privately, it's all being documented.
l mean everything, right down
to your breakfast and bra siZe.
Why are you
telling me this ?
Big symbols
make big targets, Jordan.
There's a lot of people
who don't want to see you finish.
How about you, Royce ?
Do you want
to see me finish ?
Look, l'm just trying
to warn you. All right ?
Get you thinkin' about
where this might be headed in case- -
Well, let me
just warn you.
l'm gonna go through
with this,
and the more everybody fucks with me,
the more l wanna gut it out.
So don't you eXpect me back
anytime soon.
Look, that is not
what l want, Jordan.
l mean- -
Goddamn it.
lt is, but it isn't.
Do you understand ?
Still having a hard time
making decisions ?
[ Sighs ]
Jordan, just
watch your siX, okay ?
[ Sighs ]
l gotta go, Royce.
Wait a second.
Don't- -
[ Dial Tone ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Helicopter Blades
Whirring ]
[ Pyro ] Survival, evasion,
resistance and escape.
This is it, tadpoles.
Your target is inside
an area of five square miles.
When and if
you locate this facility,
you gather up as much intel as possible
within the allotted time frame...
and get
the hell outta there.
You will be penaliZed for early
eXtraction, but even more for capture.
Trust me.
Welcome to S.F.R.F.
-  Get ready ! Stand up !
-  [ Trainees ] Stand up ! Aye !
-  [ Pyro ] Thirty seconds !
-  [ Trainees ] Thirty seconds ! Aye !
First man up, go !
Go !
So, where'd they drop us,
L.T. ?
At the line of march,
2- 1- O.
And just for shits and giggles, let's
switch to five for tactical traffic.
Maintain casual dialogue
on assigned channels.
Slovnik, take us to 2- 1- O.
CorteZ, move out.
Move out.
Let's go.
Four clicks, 2- 2- 6.
[ Slovnik Murmuring,
Giggling ]
She doesn't have one fuckin' clue
where we're goin'.
[ CorteZ ]
Shut up.
CorteZ, Slov,
you take my left flank.
The rest of us,
move back.
Looks like
she's right on the money.
l had a busted watch once,
and it was right twice a day.
CorteZ.
[ On Headset ] Target ahead.
Belay my last.
New rally point,
my location.
McCool, Newberry,
right side.
Flea, you come with me.
Let's move out.