Director: Dear chariman
I dont care about your commitee
and its opinions about work
have you forgotten sir we were at war
a fight with an alien race for the
very survival of our species?
I feel like I must remind you
that it is an undeniable
and may I say a fundamental quality
of man that when faced with extinction
every alternative is preferable
[bacground noises] over here! over!
Church: Get that door!
Church: What's the status up here?
Griff: Messed up, about to die.
Griff: Simmons is a nerd. the usual
Sarge: Looks like we got at least half
a dozen squads out there.
They know our position,
and were out gunned.
Washington: So, what's the plan?
Sarge: Well, we were gunna retreat
down the hall
untill you just brought more
guards that way.
so now, the plans pretty much
to go down swinging, You first.
Griff: Hey Simmons, can you get back
on that computer and change my
affiliation from red, to Freelancer?
Simmons: Traitor.
Griff: Hey, gotta go with the winner.
Caboose: umm, can you change my job title
to something more important, like astronaut?
Oh, I know! Space Marine!
Church: What are you idiots doing?
Simmons: This computer has all of commands
records.
Church: It does? Records on everybody?
Simmons: Yeah, you know, theoretically.
*singing* nothing to see here *singing*
Church: Oh great! now I'll show you that
your wrong.
Wash: What an excellent idea.
Simmons: Wrong about what?
Church: Wash has been trying to convince me
that i'm an A.I.
Griff: Huh? Why would he do that?
Wash: Because he's transparent
He can take over other people,
you know that kind of stuff!
Griff: That's because he's a ghost dude.
Church: Thank you, thats what I said.
Wash: If he's a ghost why aren't any of
the other soldiers turning into ghosts?
Church: Okay, fine. Why don't we just
settle this?
Simmons, look me up on the database
Simmons: Yeah i'd like to help, but we may
have just kind of
you know deleted all that stuff of the
blues.
Wash: All of what stuff, of the blues?
Simmons: the everything stuff.
Wash: didn't I tell you not to touch
anything?
Simmons: Yes, but you also told us to
break stuff.
This seemed like an excellent compromise.
Church: Aww, thats fantastic. Now I cant
Prove him wrong
And I dont get a paycheck. Great,
thanks guys.
Sarge: And your side never existed, which
means red wins!
Suck it you non-existant losers!
Church: Aww, nobody cares about that.
Sarge: Sour grapes.
Griff: No way, he's not a computer.
Sarge: How can we be sure?
Caboose: Maybe we should ask him something
only a computer would know.
Simmons: like what?
Caboose: Whats nine times eight?
Reds: Seventy-two
Caboose: Oh my gosh, it's spreading.
Griff: How about this? Show me videos.
Everyone: What?
Griff: Thats what all my computers do.
Oh, steal some music from me.
or talk about politics, and bore, the
crap out of me.
Caboose: Do you have any pictures of cats
in serious situations?
Wash: Because of the truama he's been
through
He's not going to be able to access most
of his functions,
He may not even realize his full potential.
Sarge: Not living up to his potential?
That means Griff's a computer too.
Wash: It doesn't matter, we don't need him
to believe
until the next time we encounter the Meta.
[Loud thud]
Wash: What was that?!
Sarge: Cmon, do you even need to ask?
Freelancer: Primary target has arrived!
Engage! Engage!
Church: The Meta?
How did he get inside the compound?
Simmons: What do you mean how? It took us
ten minutes. Not that hard
Wash: Perfect.
Church: Perfect?
Wash: He's been folowing us since I found
Caboose. I knew he couldn't resist
getting his hands on all the stored Command
A.I.s. Especially Epsilon.
Church: You knew about this?
Wash: Knew about it? I planned on it,
Still have Epsilon?
Church: Yeah, of course.
Wash: Good, lets get it to safety, then we
can finish this.
Once and for all.
Church: You know i'm starting not to
trust you.
Sarge: What do you mean starting too?
Church: What is this? The Motor Pool?
Wash: Yes. Looks like everyone is outside
fighting the Meta. still be careful
Red, you grab a vehicle. Caboose somehow I
hate to ask this, but can you drive?
Caboose: Yes. But not an automatic.
Only stick.
Wash: Why cant you drive-
Griff: Were in a rush, come back to
it later.
Wash: Right, Caboose grab that car. Church,
put epsilon in Caboose's jeep.
You guys are going to make a break for it.
Take Epsilon, and turn it over to the
authorities. They'll know what to do with him.
Sarge: Your not comming?
Wash: No, Church and I are staying.
Project Freelancer had one last resort fail safe.
A high powered E.M.P. that can wipe out all
the A.I. in this facility.
Now that the Meta is here, we have a chance to
take them all out at once
and put this entire project out of
commision.
Griff: Whats and E.M.P.?
Wash: It's an electromagnetic pulse. It wipes
out all circuitry it touches
it will destroy the A.I.-
Simmons: Ohhh. you mean an emp.
Sarge: Yeah, I was just about to say,
Sounds like he's talking about an Emp.
Wash: Emp? Thats not how you say it.
Sarge: Thats how most people say it. Emp.
Wash: No, they don't.
Church: I say it that way.
Wash: It's initials for Electro magnetic Pulse.
Thats E.M.P.
Church: Right, which spells Emp. dur.
Wash: We dont have time for this
Your wrong.
Simmons: Why dont we take a vote?
Wash: A vote? No, no vote. Your just wrong.
There's no vote. Its E.M.P.
Caboose: Not very Democratic.
Wash: Being wrong isn't a Democracy.Church
and I will work our way down to the directrors lab
while the rest of you escape.
Sarge: What if the Meta follow's us?
Wash: No chance, there's no way he can
pass up all the A.I. in here.
Put Epsilon in the car and lets get moving.
Church: I'm leaving. I'm going with them.
Wash: what?
Church: I dont care about any of this.
I hate you, I hate the Freelancers,
I hate everything about you guys.
This isn't my fight. Its yours.
Wash: It's your fight more than anyone elses.
Church: I don't care what you say,
no it isn't.
Wash: Church, you'll never get another shot
at fixing all of this.
I know you don't believe what i've told you.
You need to ask yourself: What if i'm right?
If I am, or if you have any doubt, not finding
out haunt you for the rest of your life.
Not just finding out about you. But finding out
about everyone, close to you as well.
It's your choice, what's it going to be?