[Galloping Hooves]
- A little late, Dutchy.
- Ain't it so? Sener.
[Man]
Buddy.
Mornin'.
- Wow. Looks great.
- Hi, Mr. Roedel.
[Preacher]
Giver of all spiritual grace...
the author of everlasting life,
send thy blessings...
upon these, thy servants -
this man and this woman
whom we bless in thy name -
that as Isaac and Rebekah
lived faithfully together...
so these persons may surely
perform and keep...
the vow and covenant
between them made.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here -
What's ticklin' you?
Do you smell somethin' funny?
Fool. It's the cologne my ma
slapped on me this mornin'.
- [Chuckles]
...signifying unto us the mystical union -
What brings you so late
to Sister's funer -
- I mean wedding.
- My pa had me workin'.
- Huh.
- [Man] Son.
[Preacher] Let him speak now
or else forever hold his peace.
## [Fiddle]
- Whoo!
- ## [Clapping Rhythmically]
## [Continues]
[Chattering]
Do you believe all those men
are necessary, Horton?
We can take no further chances, Asa.
You and I both know it'll soon be war
between us and the Yankee aggressors.
With that black republican
Abe Lincoln in the White House...
Missouri's no longer safe
from the depredations...
of Jennison and his Kansas Jayhawkers.
They've yet to strike
this deep into Missouri, Horton.
Lawrence, Kansas, and its abolitionists
are a long way from here.
There are Union men
even here amongst us, Asa.
Schmitz and his Germans
form a militia at Independence...
and his Lawrence cohorts
have eyes and ears amongst us.
Even here.
If you refer to us Bowdens, Lee,
you are sorely mistaken.
We may be Union men, yes.
But we are Southerners too.
Now, you know very well
we'll have no hand in jayhawking...
or abolitionist provocations.
- I did not imply it, sir.
- I believe, sir, you did.
Now, gentlemen, my home is no place,
and this is no time for political quarrels.
We are all old friends here.
Asa Chiles, you have spoken truly.
My apologies, Horton.
[Horton]
Well said, sir.
[Chattering]
Horton.
- [Woman] Bye.
- [Man] Take care now.
I've been thinking, Jack Bull.
A wedding is a peculiar thing.
- It's no more peculiar, Jake, than slavery.
- That's certain.
That's why I've often wondered
for what cause those Northerners...
are so anxious to change
our Southern institutions.
- Hmm.
- From both North and South...
men are every day enslaved at the altar,
regardless of their state or color.
Well, there's a type of subjugation.
We shall avoid it, Jake.
Happily my poverty ensures
my freedom from such a fate.
Oh, no.
Not if my mother can help it.
I heard her singin' your praises earlier
to the sister of the groom.
- Good day, Mrs. Chiles. Sir.
- Father.
Please give our regards to your father, Jake.
You know he's always invited.
He's more comfortable workin'.
You must at the least bring Mr. Roedel
some of the cake.
I will, ma'am.
Thank you.
[Machine Whirring]
Guten Abend.
- Guten Abend, Herr Meyer.
- Guten Abend, Ja.
- Guten Abend.
Father, Mrs. Chiles sends her regards.
A piece of the cake.
You are to see tomorrow Mrs. Kreuzer.
The war - it is sure to come now,
with the secession.
Mrs. Kreuzer's husband
will take you in Saint Louis.
Pa, I told you. I'm not gonna huddle with all
the other Lincoln-lovin' Germans in Saint Louis.
It is safer.
For us, this is no war.
Pa, you may have borne me in Germany,
but I was raised here.
- These are my people. And if it gets hot -
- Your people?
No, Jacob, this they are not.
You will always be a Deutschman,
a German to them...
no matter with who you are friends.
Promise me you'll go to Mrs. Kreuzer.
[Low Rumbling]
- [Galloping Hooves]
- [Men Whooping, Shouting]
[Men Shouting]
[Man]
All right, come on! Get 'em all out!
[Horse Whinnying]
[Shouting Continues]
[Man]
Where is he? Where is he?
[Whinnying]
[Man]
I got him! I got him!
- [Shouting Continues]
- [Mrs. Chiles] Oh, no!
[Mrs. Chiles Screams]
- Where's your boy, Asa?
- My son's gone.
- Where's your boy?
- [Gasps]
- Jake.
- Jack Bull.
He told me to run, Jake.
He told me.
Did you see who they are?
Jayhawkers, Jake. Lawrence men.
- [Mrs. Chiles Screaming]
- [Gunshot]
Father!
Come on!
Don't you die here too.
- Find the boy.
- Let's go look in the mill.
[Whooping, Shouting Continue]
- You men find the boy!
- [Gasping, Crying]
[Horse Whinnies]
[Sobbing]
Asa!
Oh, my God!
[Chattering]
Ted? Riders.
Gentlemen.
Captain Henderson, Company D.
You boys have rid
a bit far from home.
Hell, spent two nights
trackin' this bushwhacking bastard...
and his Confederate friends
through the Sni-A-Bar.
What are you boys doin'
this far into Missouri?
Just rootin' out rebels
and conscriptin' chickens.
Been through all Cass
and Lafayette Counties.
Killed our share.
[Man]
Not much action in Lafayette.
We got four Sunday last.
Stretched their necks.
- They're still hanging.
- [Chuckles]
Hey, George.
Fetch that busthead out there.
- So you men were in on Lafayette?
- Yes, sir.
[Sighs]
But we're tirin' of
chasin' these rebs into the bush.
Can't trust none of these locals.
They're all hidin' 'em.
I wish we had a real army to fight.
Not these sneakin' bastards.
Battles and armies -
it's all back East.
Down here in Missouri,
you just have the people to fight ya.
Ted.
Ted!
- So you were in on Lafayette, huh?
- [Grunts]
- [Woman Screams]
- [Man] Bushwhackers!
[Woman Screaming]
Whoo!
[Woman Sobbing]
Doin' business with
the Yankee invaders, huh?
No. They forced me.
[Grunts]
[Woman Screams]
[Woman Crying]
He's dead.
You killed him.
Shoot me too, please.
We don't hurt women, ma'am.
[Sobbing]
We took her man.
We should leave her the store.
Come on, Jake.
It's gettin' hot in here.
Enough of this, boys.
Let's load up!
- Hyah! Hyah!
- [Braying]
Black John.
[Chuckles]
- George Clyde.
- [Man] Whoa!
Yep.
Well met, my man. Well met.
Hey, boy. Watch that man.
He's a cheat.
Jack Bull.
You boys will love riding with George Clyde.
Makes Yankee killin' as entertaining
a pastime as greasin' ganders.
- Who's guns are those?
- Even Holt over there.
You'll get used to him.
That's Holt.
That's George Clyde's pet nigger.
Don't call him that in front of George though.
George don't like that.
- He carries those?
- Yep.
He's a damn fine scout.
George tosses him a gun a good Yankee kill or two.
You know,
him and Clyde growed up together.
When Jim Lane's boys come for Clyde,
Holt there sent three of them to heaven.
So he rides with us now.
'Cause them Yankees
want to kill him real bad.
Yeah. Well, a nigger with guns
is still a nervous thing to me.
[Chuckles]
We're lookin' for the Dorr's place, ma'am.
It's just up the road.
Who are you?
Why, we are Southern men,
and hungry.
You don't look like Southern men.
How do I know?
Woman, my name is Crawford.
One of the Six Point Creek Crawfords.
Do you know me?
I knew the father.
Well, come on.
Eat as what we have.
[Sniffs]
Whoo.
Ma'am.
- You alone here?
- Yes.
Well, no. My man's at Arkansas
with Shelby.
My son's in the barn.
Is he grown?
He was.
Gave up a leg at Wilson's Creek.
I keep him hid away.
Union Jayhawkers would kill him.
He should ride with us.
Oh, no. He won't fight.
He's done with that.
Hello inside.
Show yourself, Clark. We're friends.
[Man Chuckling]
Bushwhackers. I could have killed you both.
But it ain't even loaded.
Not no need of that.
We're friends.
Oh, you suppose so, do you?
I don't.
You were at Wilson's Creek.
Who with?
Why, with General Price.
The fat glory-hound rebel himself.
Didn't see that one comin', huh?
[Chuckles]
Oh, I saw it comin'.
I saw it rollin' past the little piles
of meat and bone which I once called my friends.
I watched it roll right up to me.
If you saw it comin',
couldn't you have dodged it?
Well, nature bore me smart.
That changes things.
I wanted my foot broke
so's I could head home.
- [Chuckles]
- Damn little cannonball was rollin' slower
than a fevered rabbit.
- You are a fool. Cannonball will rip your leg -
- [Laughing]
Well, General Price is a good man.
Why don't you have us
fetch you something to eat.
I have a mother for that.
I don't eat anyway.
Tryin' something different.
You'll be killed anyways.
Jayhawkers or militias -
someone or the other - stop here and kill you.
Oh, they already been here.
Burned the barn.
I wouldn't even move to put it out.
Ma done it.
Likely you boys will kill me now.
I don't much care.
- [Clicks]
- You wanna die?
Perhaps you choose to die now.
I have some experience in the killing line, Clark.
I could do you a fair job of it this minute.
No.
No, Ma has her heart set on me livin'.
You sure of that?
I'm here now loaded.
I don't believe so.
Your mother's a fine enough woman.
You could help her out some,
don't you think?
Get yourself a stick to lean on,
walk around a bit.
Mm-hmm.
That could be next.
That could be the very next thing.
[Chattering]
You're an interestin' foreigner, Jake.
Why is that?
I hear your pa's a Dutchman.
But you're loyal to here, not the North.
It's uncommon.
Nah, Jake may have
been born a Dutchman...
but my ma and pa
practically raised him.
He's as Southern as they come.
[Clucking]
[Gun Cocks]
Where's the other one, you devil?
Speak up now,
and maybe you'll live.
I'm alone.
That's my daddy's horse.
He was shot off it three days back.
He's lyin'. Let's parole him to Jesus,
and right now.
- [Gunshot]
- Jake, get in here!
- I'm gettin' the horses!
- [Gunshots]
- [Shouting]
- [Whinnying]
[Grunting]
- Damn! They took my pinky!
- You boys, cover outside!
- Holt!
- [All Shouting]
Damn! Go on over there!
Go over there!
- [Grunts]
- Holt!
[Clattering]
- Ah!
- Turner, cover the women!
Please, ma'am.
Ma'am, get over there!
[Gasping]
- Ow! Damn!
- Don't fret about that now!
[Coughs]
- [Bullets Ricocheting]
- [Gasps]
Cease fire!
- Cease fire!
- [Clyde] Hold your fire, boys!
I said, cease fire, goddamn it!
Control your fire!
[Panting]
Do you kill women?
There's women in here!
[Man]
You know we don't kill women!
Send 'em out now,
and they'll be safe passaged!
Please, ma'am,
you and your daughter got to go.
- Come on. Come on.
- We are goin', son.
You best believe it.
There ain't no way we're not goin'.
## [Humming]
- [Girl Screams]
- [Men Shouting]
[Shouting]
- You'll have to come out!
- Fire!
- [Grunts]
- Ray!
- You gotta trust me.
- We can't hold 'em from here!
Get back, Lewis!
We'll kill them yet!
We'll just have to take
our chances running!
They'll riddle us down! There ain't
so much as a stump out there for cover!
- [Man] Whoo!
- Come on, men! Let's go to it!
Let's go.
[Grunts]
Holt.
Go! Go!
[Shouting]
[Blustering]
[Grunting]
Go, Ray!
- Come on!
- Let's go!
Come on! I'll get Ray!
Come on!
[Coughing, Grunting]
- [Grunts]
- Hold your fire!
- Hyah!
Hyah!
Split up, boys!
Head for the woods!
- [Grunts]
- Hyah! Hyah!
- [Whooping]
- Split up! We'll meet at the place!
- [Whinnies]
- [Grunts]
Hyah!
[Grunting]
- [Whinnying]
- [Men Shouting]
- Where's my brother?
- Don't know.
- Did you see my brother?
- Black John. With him alive.
With Black John? Alive?
Whoo! That was sure enough hot!
They left us hurtin', that's certain.
This way, boys.
Hyah! Hyah!
Come on.
Turner.
[Gags]
[Chattering]
- [Man] Jake.
- [Man #2] Well, Jack Bull.
- [Jack Bull] Taylor. You're alive.
- [Man] Jake Roedel.
Well, Alf Bowden.
You sure are in a fix.
Seems so.
Surely does seem so.
- Do you know this man?
- Certainly.
His daddy's place is just downriver
from the Chiles'.
Hemp growers.
- Jack Bull.
- Alf Bowden.
- News of home?
- No, no, no. It all just goes on.
Some may have died,
not most.
What of my mother?
Well, now -
Well, she is watched.
All the secesh are watched.
And my father?
He comes and goes.
He's a Union man.
He ain't bothered by no one.
You must know that.
You must know the whole town
talks about you boys out here black-flaggin' it.
Some friendliness
may be lost for your kin.
You been fed?
Not so as you'd notice.
I'll look into it.
[Black John]
Roedel.
Now, take this down.
Itis forthe Lexington Union News.
So do it fine, the way you do.
Gladly.
"Dear Citizens:
"Mistakes are most common these days
and deadly for it.
"The Federals are to hang William Lloyd
and James Curtain...
"two fine sons of Missouri.
'But by a provident cut of the cards...
"four Federals have been dealt to me.
"And it is their hope
that Lloyd and Curtain are not hanged...
'as they would provide
the sequel to these murders.
"However, if our boys are released...
"I will, as a gentlemen...
"release these unfortunates.
"The choice is yours, citizens,
so make it wisely.
"Signed, John Ambrose and George Clyde...
Command of First Irregulars."
That's good.
Put a note on it that says...
"Where you think we ain't, we are.
Remember it."
Who will deliver it?
There are Federals all over Lexington.
We could slip a man in there.
We done it before.
Oh, I reckon a citizen could be pressed into service,
if one could be found.
That might be a job,
for citizens are cautious hereabouts.
You got some better idea, Dutchy?
Maybe you should volunteer yourself.
Well, there is a way we could
prove more things than one.
If we send a prisoner,
it would prove we have prisoners.
And also
he can attest to our intentions.
It seems to me he could get
more quickly into town as well.
And time is short.
Lloyd and Curtain will be hanged
right quick, I would think.
It is a good idea.
There are some fine touches to it.
You know, you should
speak up more, Roedel.
You're not near so dumb
as you let on.
Aw.
Now go put one of them Federals
on a horse with that letter.
Convince them to see
this deal through, Alf.
We're only askin' to be treated
like the soldiers that we are.
We shall do the same
for your companions here.
Do your best.
Huh.
What are you lookin' at?
[Sighs]
What is it, Jake?
I hear you ruminatin' louder
than a cow chewin' in my ear...
and it's keepin' me from my sleep.
Do you think Alf Bowden's
made it back to Lexington as yet?
There was a minute there
when I saw him ridin' off -
I thought maybe
you and me could join him.
That we could all ride home together.
Just ride back home.
What have you left at home
you're so anxious to ride back to?
Nothin'.
Just a passel of memories.
Mostly memories of you and me.
Of your father, old Asa Chiles.
We'll stick together, Jack Bull.
We'll get all of it back.
Huh.
Then you're a black magician
who can raise the dead, are ya?
No. My father's under the dirt to stay.
Like that's gone to stay too.
- My finger?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, so it is.
And it makes me notable
by the loss.
You sound pleased, as if that finger
had been pesterin' you for rings.
No. It was a fine finger,
and I'd rather have it still.
But it was took from me,
and it's been et by chickens for sure.
And I say,
what is the good side to this amputation?
- And there is one.
- Name it, Jake.
Well, you say one day some Federals...
catch up to me
and kill me in a thicket.
Well, they would riddle me
and hang me...
and no Southern man
would find me for weeks or months.
And when they did, I'd be bad meat,
pretty well rotted to a glob.
[Sighs]
You're scientifically accurate, I'm afraid.
- I've seen it.
- I'd be a mysterious gob of rot.
People would say,
"who was that?"
And surely someone
would look up and say...
"Why, it's nubbin-fingered Jake Roedel."
And then you could go
and tell my father I was clearly murdered...
and he wouldn't be tortured
by uncertain wonders.
And that's the good of it?
Yes, sir, that's the good.
[Chuckles]
Go to sleep, Jake Roedel.
- Get over there!
- [Man Grunting]
[Man Shouting, Indistinct]
They hanged and quartered
Lloyd and Curtain last night.
Seems those bushwhackers
are not real soldiers.
[Man Shouting]
Had it with you, boy!
- Not fit for trading anyhow.
- [Shouting Continues]
[Shouting]
Hey, Jake, what are you knowing?
I feel I'm knowin' too much.
- Ah. Well, forget it. Throw it down.
- [Shouting Continues]
- We could've merely shot them.
- Well, that was not the plan, Jake.
Might be no rhyme to it,
but that was just plain old not the plan.
[Man Shrieks]
## [Banjo]
[Men Laughing]
- [Man] Jake.
- Aw.
Black John says you're lettered.
It's Union mail.
Wants you to look it over,
tell him if there's anything to learn.
All right.
Well, it's just stuff from up north.
There's no military intelligence in here.
Yeah. Well, maybe you could
read it to us just the same.
Read us this letter, Dutchy.
That's someone else's letter.
Was. I wanna hear you read it.
I don't think I care to.
Oh, is that so?
Well, I think that if you think
a little bit more, Dutchy...
you'll think you do wanna read it me.
Right now too.
How do we know there
might be secrets in it?
Read it at us.
- [Man] Yeah, come on, Dutchy.
- [Laughter]
All right.
This here is from Mrs. Mary Williams
of Bear Lake, Wisconsin.
"Dear Sons,
No word of you in so long...
"right past first frost of the year last.
"Your father is better,
but his feet are still bloatin'.
He won't walk right on them."
That's thicked-up blood does that.
Thicked-up blood bloats the feet.
'Fire hit the old church.
Burned down.
"The new one was just ready,
so no great trouble was had of it.
"Margaret is married
since the frost of this year last.
"You wouldn't know it, for how could you?
Her husband is Walter Maddox.
'He is out of the war,
with one arm busted at New Madrid.
"But it works fine enough.
"The dirt was turned over,
and the smell and deepness gave me heart.
It is just black rich.
You boys know how that is."
My daddy was up there.
He was up there
way before they hung him.
He said the dirt was so rich
you could've ate it like porridge.
They have very good dirt up there.
Short grow season.
Yeah, sounds like real good dirt to me.
"That girl Dave got sweet for is in town
and still single and about.
"She asks of you, but I have no news
since first frost of the year last.
"Without news,
I cannot answer her.
You are both missed here.
Your mother."
Sounds like my mother -
that old woman does.
One mother's
very much like another.
Remember one thing.
Her boys will kill you if they can.
[Clears Throat]
[Black John]
It is time for our winter hibernation.
I have gathered the names
of loyal Southerners who shall provide for us.
We'll group in fours.
I'll send word the beginnin' of spring
for where to rendezvous.
We shall to the Evans farm, boys.
Their place is about half a mile
from the Willards'...
where there resides
a certain Miss Juanita...
to whom, if I do not flatter myself...
my attentions are not
unfavorably regarded.
You mean to say we're to spend
the winter in Lafayette...
solely on account that
you're sweet on Juanita Willard?
Ach, it's as good a reason as any, Dutchy.
Nolan's brought some news from home.
Hank Pattison is murdered.
Our old neighbor Jantzen got him
with his gang of militia.
That is sad. He was a good Southern man.
What of Thomas?
Oh, he is murdered too.
And Sally Burgess
married a Federal from Michigan.
- [Scoffs]
- [Chuckles] Her whole family hides their faces.
And -
Well, Dutchy...
that Federal Alf Bowden -
he rode straight from here
and killed your father.
He shot him in the neck
down by the river...
then booted him
along Main Street till he died.
I spared Alf Bowden.
You all know it.
You taught him mercy,
but he forgot the lesson.
My father -
My father was a Unionist
like all the Germans.
An unconditional Unionist.
Well, yeah.
But he was mainly known
as your father, Dutchy.
You got a reputation now.
[Man]
Hello there, boys.
[Clyde]
Good day, sir.
- Gabel Evans.
- George Clyde.
Sorry we can't all be of proper hospitality,
but with the Federal patrols -
We're much obliged.
May I ask after Mrs. Evans?
My wife.
Well, she's as well as can be expected.
Our other Mrs. Evans -
that's Sue Lee -
Well, she was a Mrs. Evans
for but three weeks...
until my son joined
our Confederate forces.
He was killed in the fightin'
at Independence.
We're sorry to hear of it.
Yes. Well, you boys lay low.
We'll come by from time to time
with provisions...
such as there are.
[Clyde]
We're much obliged.
[Grunting]
[Digging Continues]
[Grunting Continues]
It's been a while since we done work.
Somethin' soothin' to it.
Yeah, well, work has never been
my main ambition.
Ah, we've done much work.
I think I've spied an easier way to riches.
Spell out this miracle.
You just ride on up and take it.
Ah, good old rule.
A simple plan.
It's a workable method.
That is proven.
[All Grunting]
Now, George...
you got mud in your eye.
- Mmm.
- [Both Laughing]
- [Jake] Rider comin'.
- Oh, let's go see our visitor.
[Woman] Just me! Don't shoot
or some dumb thing like that.
- Whoa.
- Well, how do?
- You must be Mrs. Evans.
- I brung you some supper.
- [Sniffs] I'm, uh, pleased to meet you, Mr. -
- Chiles.
Mr. Jack Bull Chiles.
This is Jake Roedel.
- And -
- George Clyde, Mrs. Evans.
Mr. Evans wishes me to apologize
for not havin' sent you food sooner.
The Federals have been on the move.
And don't you call me Mrs. Evans.
My name is Sue Lee Shelley.
It's a good one,
and I am a widow now.
Reckon I'll go back to it and use it.
Please pardon me.
Won't you come in?
It's not much to gaze upon...
but I reckon we could assay
some hospitality.
- George.
- After me, ma'am.
- Right this way, ma'am.
- Excuse me.
[Sue Lee]
Thank you.
Damn.
What are you smilin' at?
I'll see to that mule.
Wait a second.
What did you say?
I say I'll look to him.
You better go on in there.
Let that woman see your face.
Damnation, Holt.
I think I know best
how to handle my personal affairs.
Now, you see that lady's mule
while I check on what she brung to eat.
- [Jack Bull] Excuse the mud. We'll just -
- [Clyde] There you go, ma'am.
My!
[Sighs]
Well, aren't you bushwhackers
the gentlemen.
We try to make the effort
when possible, ma'am.
Do you think manners should be dropped
in times like these?
No. But I don't think horse sense
oughta be dropped either.
[Chuckles]
It's cold.
You're so kind to think of us, ma'am.
You men think of us more.
You do the good work.
I know it's dirty and it's dangerous.
Those are good words to hear, ma'am.
It's - It's not always we hear them.
[Clears Throat]
Well, I really should be goin'.
Mrs. Evans will worry if I don't.
Uh, ma'am?
We're awful sorry about
Evans Jr. Gettin' killed.
Well, we all suffer.
But he suffers no more.
He was a good husband to me.
For three weeks he was a good husband,
but he didn't last.
What's he doin' here, inside?
Oh, ma'am, this - this nigger's with me.
His name is Holt.
Well, wouldn't he be more useful
off in a field plowin'?
[Chuckles]
Oh, no, I reckon not.
No, ma'am. That's, uh, one nigger
I wouldn't try to hitch behind a plow.
No, I wouldn't try that.
Well, now.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Mr. Evans asked that you come to the house
tomorrow evenin' after dark.
He's up on the latest Federal movements,
and he could post you on 'em.
[Jack Bull]
Why, we'd be honored.
Um, I'm not sure about him.
Mr. Evans -
You ain't got nothin'
to worry about on that score.
You needn't worry about Holt.
I'll be takin' Holt with me
to the Willards' tomorrow.
We won't be comin' to your dinner.
Mr. Clyde, honestly...
I didn't mean to speak ill
of your nigger.
He's not my nigger.
He's just a nigger who I trust with my life
every day and night, that's all.
- That's very high praise.
- Yes, ma'am, it is.
I see.
Well, gentlemen,
I really must take my leave.
- I hope the food'll please you.
- It looks wonderful.
Why, thank you.
Now good night, all.
- Good night.
- Good night, ma'am.
Holt, the lady said good night to all.
Now touch your hat and say good night.
- Chiles, you don't tell him nothin'.
- He's bein' rude.
- Gentlemen, please.
- He don't need no tellin', Chiles!
It's all right, George.
Good night, missy.
Good night, Holt.
I'll see the lady to her mule.
- Holt.
- It weren't no hardship, George.
Well, let's eat. This smells good.
- Be careful.
- Good evening.
[Clicks Teeth]
Holt, you want my bacon?
I could eat more.
Go on then.
Appreciate it.
Roedel...
you want my bacon?
Yes, I could eat it.
Well, I'll shit it out
by the oak tree in the mornin'.
You can just go and help yourself.
[Laughing]
[Coughing]
And why, if you do not mind my askin'...
did you not join the regular army?
Army? Well, we thought of it.
I suppose we decided this fight's
got to be made in our own country...
not where some general
tells us it should happen.
It soon will be everywhere.
My family and I,
we will be quittin' this house in the spring.
As soon as the roads are clear,
we're gonna be tryin' for Texas.
About half of Missouri
has went to Texas.
Well, the whole state's thick with invaders.
We cannot drive them away.
We have different thoughts.
I still wanna fight.
Reckon I'll always want to fight them.
Always.
Have you ever been
to Lawrence, Kansas, young man?
[Scoffs]
No, I reckon not, Mr. Evans.
I don't believe I'd be
too welcome in Lawrence.
I didn't think so.
Before this war began,
my business took me there often.
As I saw those Northerners
build that town...
I witnessed the seeds
of our destruction being sown.
The foundin' of that town was truly
the beginnin' of the Yankee invasion.
I'm not speakin' of numbers...
nor even abolitionist trouble-makin'.
It was the schoolhouse.
Before they built their church even,
they built that schoolhouse.
And they lettered every tailor's son
and every farmer's daughter in that country.
Oh, spellin' won't help you
hold a plow any firmer.
Or a gun either.
No, it won't, Mr. Chiles.
But my point is merely that they rounded
every pup up into that schoolhouse...
because they fancied
that everyone should think...
and talk the same
free-thinkin' way they do...
with no regard to station, custom...
propriety.
And that is why they will win.
Because they believe everyone
should live and think just like them.
And we shall lose because we don't care
one way or another how they live.
We just worry about ourselves.
Are you sayin', sir,
that we fight for nothin'?
Far from it, Mr. Chiles.
You fight for everything that we ever had.
As did my son.
It's just that we don't have it anymore.
Mr. Evans, when you get back from Texas...
it'll all be here waitin' for you.
Jack Bull and me, we'll see to it.
Well, yes.
Thank you, son.
Well, enough of this war talk.
Let's have the ladies join us
and think nobler thoughts.
- Lydia!
- [Jack Bull] Fine idea.
Some company would be splendid.
Jack Bull, we should be
thinkin' about gettin' back.
Federals could pass by anytime.
- [Lydia] Sue Lee!
- Oh, put a gown on, Jake. It's too cold.
They'll all be in front of the fire
examinin' their plunder, huh?
I, um, have it in me to sing.
Shall we have a sing-along?
- Oh, yes. I like those the best.
- [Clearing Throat]
My voice is not
what it should be these days...
but it was once rumored
that I could carry a tune.
And you, Mr. Roedel?
I believe I won't sing.
Young ears are present.
- [Chuckles]
- Well, I bet you sing lovely.
- You would lose that bet.
- He really does sing very poorly.
- But he imitates the turkey first-rate.
- [Giggles]
I'd best do my gobblin' out of doors.
You folks go ahead and sing along.
I'll keep my eye on the road.
- Do you really think that -
- Good man, Jake. I'll relieve you soon.
[Clears Throat]
## [Singing In Distance]
## [Singing Continues]
[Clattering]
Clyde back?
I believe he's, uh, fixin' to pass
a few more hours with Miss Juanita.
- Jack Bull?
- In the company of Mrs. Sue Lee Evans.
You mean Sue Lee Shelley?
- Roedel.
- Yeah, Holt.
What's that?
I've been keeping 'em.
Nobody ever learned me letters.
When you were readin'
the mails out loud...
it was somethin'
the likes of which I'd never heard.
Got me thinkin' you might
sometime try it again.
So you packed those
and kept 'em all this time?
Well, it might not be too amusin'.
It might just be a bunch of borin' thoughts
from one stranger to another.
That one you read from the mother was fine.
You recall it?
Yeah.
Mmm. She say things I enjoy to hear.
All right. Here it goes.
"Dear Brother,
I must write this right quick...
"'cause I say good-bye to Massachusetts
and our home in one hour.
"Yes, Danny, I've joined the fight...
"and a difficulter decision
never before was made...
"as I've been just about the only
eligible bachelor to dance with...
"at Parlan's this past year.
"Without my favorite brother,
it is not the same...
"although the beer has been free...
"as I've been drinkin' it
with one of the Parlans' daughters.
"Which one, I will not tell.
Here's to you, Danny,
and keep your head low out there. Bill."
It could come to where
you could maybe like that man.
Yeah.
In other times
he would not be so bad.
I think though I like the one
from the mama best.
Holt...
where is your mother?
- Uh, Kansas or Kingdom.
- [Cork Pops]
I don't know.
[Sighs]
I know she was sold into Texas.
I reckon she in Texas.
How was that?
Was that George that sold her?
No, sir.
George and me,
we growed up neighbors.
It was George what bought me out
when Master Henry passed, but...
he didn't have no means
for my mama or my sister.
- So Clyde owns you?
- No, sir.
Not in greenbacks and coppers nohow.
No, he don't own me that way.
Nope.
He made of that a gift.
- [Knocking]
- It's me.
- Hey, Jake.
- [Grunts]
Your aim is wild.
You splattered poor Holt.
- [Sue Lee] Well, it surely is.
- Oh, no. Mm-mmm.
Mmm!
- Ah!
- [Laughing]
- Whoa, mule! Settle down there!
- Mule? "Whoa, mule"?
Just calm down.
Well, do I look muley to you?
[Jack Bull]
Why, no.
Well, does that
look like a mule to you?
Does that look like the rear end of
an animal that hee-haws in the night?
- Looks like it might could be.
- Jack Bull Chiles!
Just 'cause I'm a widow don't mean
that you can get that familiar with me.
Pardon me, ma'am, but I believe it was you
that shoved your rump into my face.
That was only just to make a point.
You made it.
I'll always know your rump from a mule's now.
Several differences.
Don't know how I missed 'em before.
[Gasps]
Well, don't be mean.
I can't tolerate meanness.
[Whimpering Softly]
- Is that too mean?
- No.
It's really not too mean at all.
Oh, for cryin' out loud! We're sittin' right here.
Show us some mercy.
[Sighs]
He really is quite right.
Mmm, I better get back to the house.
Cover your tracks in the snow too.
You'll be leadin' curious Federals right onto us.
Don't be rude.
You have no reason to be rude.
There happens to be a war goin' on...
everywhere but between your two ears,
you dumb ox.
Dumb ox, am I?
[Grunts]
Sorry, Jake.
My leg just did that on its own.
No thought behind it.
I hear you. I hear you.
But Holt and me ain't dyin'
just so you could be kissed.
Leave Holt out of this. Holt ain't even here.
Holt ain't nowhere near here.
I don't think anybody's
about to die from my kiss.
In fact, she seems
to be doin' tolerably well.
Well enough to get goin' too.
Good day.
You reckon George Clyde'll ever
join up with us again?
Or do you think Juanita Willard will be
his only cause and comfort from here on?
Ah, George is efficient
when it comes to comfort.
Ah!
This thing with Sue Lee and you -
Will it go on?
I would reckon.
Well, that's good for you.
Yep.
I believe I'll marry her.
I believe you should.
Sue Lee'll be by this evening.
Oh, good.
It's been near a week since I've seen her.
Yeah, all this warmth has the Federals
out for jaunts. It's kept her home.
It won't be long
before we join them out there.
No, it won't.
That's why I want to ask somethin'
of you and Holt.
Name it.
Well, there, future best man,
I'd like to ask you for some privacy.
Oh, you would, would you?
It's not much to ask.
And what are Holt and me to do?
Anything you'd like.
Throw walnuts at squirrels.
Play mumblety-peg.
I reckon we could come up with a better
use of our time than that, eh, Holt?
It's possible.
[Jake]
Mmm.
Howdy.
I, um, brung you two somethin'.
Try this bread, boys.
Why, thank you. Did you make it?
No. Mrs. Evans's sister lives in town.
She's a Federal, but a sister still.
She gave us two loaves.
Well, that's kind of her.
You thank her for us, won't you?
[Chuckles] I don't suppose I'll tell her
where it went. That might not do.
- [Jack Bull Clears Throat]
- [Sue Lee Clears Throat]
Well, this good weather has me and Holt...
wantin' to fling walnuts
at mumblety-peg players...
or something along those lines.
[Jack Bull]
All right. Now have fun.
[Whispering]
Jake. One hour, please.
[Jake's Voice]
'Dearest Ruth Ann...
"I trust this letter
will reach you before winter.
'Here it is always a sort of winter,
as folks are so cold now.
'Rebels are out of the city
as far as armies go...
'but there are copperheads around
performing misdeeds.
"So much cruelty goes on.
"Gratiot Prison is full of rebels,
and they are left to waste away so pitifully.
"They are traitors, but also human.
"If you looked in on them,
you would not believe that they were...
"for they so resemble scarecrows now.
"Father believes the war will go on and on...
"but is ever more committed
to the... struggle.
"He manages to send ever greater
numbers of slaves up north...
"to freedom and away from
the grasping hands of their masters...
"who even in the midst of all
attempt to lay claim to them.
"The Confederates claim that
we strike at their liberty and rights...
"but what kind of liberty is it
that takes away the liberty of others?
The war will end."
Has it been an hour yet?
No. Ain't no hour passed yet.
Roedel...
you know my name?
It's Holt.
No, my whole name.
My whole name is Daniel Holt.
Daniel. Like that lion's den man.
You know his story?
Of course I do.
They throwed Daniel to the lions...
but he won't never ate.
Daniel.
That's what my mama named me.
- Is it an hour now?
- Nigh on to -
- [Gunshots]
- That's the Evans' place.
Got to be.
[Gunshots Continue]
[Horse Whinnying]
- [Sue Lee Gasps]
- Jake.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Gunshots at the Evans'.
[Jack Bull]
I heard 'em.
- [Horse Whinnying]
- Holt!
- Jake.
- Sue Lee, you stay put. There's gonna be a fight.
[Jake]
Holt! Does Clyde have his guns?
- [Holt] What do you need?
- [Jake] Bring her in! Bring her in!
- [Sue Lee Moans]
- [Jake] Jack Bull, let's go!
Hyah! Hyah!
- Hyah!
- Hyah! Hyah!
[Lydia Screaming]
- Boys, they killed him!
- How many were there?
They killed him! He's dead!
He's dead!
What will I do?
- [Sobbing]
- Heard the fracas all the way from the Willards'.
- Thought you boys might be in a spot.
- How many?
I don't know!
A dozen or less.
Well, shit, then let's get 'em!
Come on!
- Hyah!
- [Holt] Roedel!
[Sobbing Continues]
- [Gunshots]
- [Horses Whinnying]
[Shouting]
[All Shouting]
Run, you bastards!
Ow! Damn!
- Jake!
- Jack Bull, hit 'em! Get them, Holt!
- [Horse Whinnies]
Hyah!
- [Jack Bull Groaning]
- [Horse Whinnying]
- [Groaning]
- [Horse Blusters]
[Grunts]
[Gasping]
Oh, shit.
He'll be all right. He'll be okay.
- [Grunting]
- [Clyde] Come on.
[Jack Bull]
Ah!
[Grunting]
- That fire's got to go out.
- We're heatin' water!
Heat it quick. They'll come back
with more men if they got 'em.
We can't have 'em smellin' that fire.
- That arm's gonna have to come off.
- [Grunts]
He's gonna need it.
We can heal it.
Dutchy, we got no medicines or doctor sense
amongst the whole group of us.
And I can't go shanghai
a sawbones neither.
Federals will likely be on us by sunup.
[Sighs]
I'll mend him.
I can - I can nurse him with Jake.
As you say. But you watch out
green rot don't get started on him.
'Cause once it does, it's over.
That look none too good, Roedel.
Goddamn it!
Don't nobody say that again!
We're gonna burn the wound closed.
- No!
- No.
- [Jake] Holt.
- [Jack Bull] No.
[Jack Bull Shouting]
[Shrieking]
[Door Opens]
There's men on the road.
- [Clyde] How many?
- More than a few.
But they ain't comin' into the woods.
Keep the watch.
I want to fight away from here
if we got to fight.
What came of Mrs. Evans and Mary?
The Willards took them up.
They all headed out of here.
- [Clyde] Willards too?
- Said they was goin' south, clear roads or no.
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
Maybe I should try
to find us a doctor tonight.
Where from?
There's one in Kingsville.
You can't make it there
and back in one night.
I know that, Dutchy.
I can lay up near there
and try and drag one back the next night.
If I can't find a doc...
I'll head on to Captain Perdee's.
Holt'll look after you and the widow.
I wish you luck.
[Gags]
[Coughs]
- That arm done for.
- Oh, I know it.
- I hoped it wouldn't be.
- It's done for.
Well, maybe George will bring the doctor.
He may see something we don't.
You know good as I, George Clyde
done rode straight to Captain Perdee's.
It's just us now, Roedel.
And it's time. The longer you wait,
the harder it gets on the man.
Oh, hellfire! Will you shut up on that, Holt?
Please, just give me peace for a while.
Jake.
Jack Bull.
You look sad.
We're taking care of you.
You'll be mended. We're fixin' it.
I always knew we'd be killed.
One or both of us.
You recall the pies on Mother's sill?
Of course I do.
Those were good eatin' times.
That they were.
I always thought it'd be you, Jake.
I'm dyin'.
I was certain I'd have to bury you.
I wish you were.
[Laughs]
Me too.
Sue Lee.
I'm right here.
[Sniffles]
Good.
That's good.
Them veins is blackenin' all the way up
to his armpit.
We've got to do it now.
[Gasps]
Can you do it?
[Grunting]
[Jack Screams]
If he screams too loud, we may all die.
Put that stick in his mouth.
Don't let him scream too loud.
- Keep his jaw clamped down on that stick.
- [Grunting]
Holt, you hold him down
whenever he starts to flop.
[Grunting, Panting]
No!
[Screaming]
[Grunts]
[Screaming Continues]
[Coughing]
We should be gettin' to Captain Perdee's.
We gotta head south first.
Sue Lee, you'll need a place.
We'll go to the Browns' farm.
Those are Cave Wyatt's people.
They're far away from all this.
[Water Pouring]
You're not to worry, young man.
She'll be just fine.
Just give us time.
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Clattering]
Jake.
The war hasn't come down here yet.
I'm - I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
Holt and me -
Well, George Clyde should be missin' us.
You don't have to go back, Jake.
Mr. Brown says you boys are more than welcome
to stay here and work the farm.
He could use you.
You'll do all right here.
Holt and me will come by again
just as soon as we can and see to it.
[Clyde]
Who goes there?
[Jake]
Who the hell do you think we are?
You smell like a couple of piles
of fine Southern shit.
Welcome back to hell, boys.
While you boys were sunnin' yourselves
down at the border...
things have turned
rather interesting here.
Federals everywhere.
[Riley] Welch and his boys
got caught down in Pattonsburg.
Heads... cut off.
Some of us still ride -
Anderson, Pitt, Todd.
Scalpin' every nigger they can find.
[Stammering]
Except, of course, our own.
[Clyde] But there's still riches
to be had, right, boys?
[Chattering Continues]
[Footsteps]
[Door Bell Jingles]
That the man we were
supposed to kill?
Somebody must have got him recent.
I'll look up here.
Holt, we ever been in this house before?
We've been everywhere before.
Mmm. I smell bacon.
You know, we were here with Jack Bull.
Man danced a jig right there.
You writin' a letter?
Who I got to write to?
What about that Sue Lee gal?
Write to her. Let her know
what we've been doin'.
It ain't worth writin' about, is it?
## [Folk]
[Man]
# That ol' king crow #
# He was a blackened thief, I know #
# And he never says nothin' but #
## [Men Cawing]
- # Jenny, fetch your hoecake #
- # Boy, don't bother me #
- # Said it ain't done #
- # Jenny, fetch your hoecake #
- # Boy, don't bother me #
# Fetch another hoecake
when we're done ##
## [Continues, Faint]
Best to stay clear of Black John
right now.
You know, when that women's jail
collapsed in Kansas City...
his womenfolk were in it.
Three of 'em done in by the Federals.
He's been acting kind of itchy,
if you know what I mean.
Word is Black John called for Quantrill
and his boys to come join us.
Quantrill?
Mmm.
There's some crazy talk in the air.
Quantrill's plannin' to ride into Kansas,
is what I hear.
Maybe that.
[Jake]
A raid into Kansas?
We might get over there, sure,
but gettin' back would be suicide...
once the Kansas Fifth
gets on our tail.
You got that, Roedel. But why not?
It's suicide sittin' in these woods waitin'
for them Federals to pick us off anyhow.
I am short on cash.
- Will these do?
- [Man Chuckles]
That's two nigger scalps?
I'll see you with one Dutch scalp.
## [Men Cawing]
[Men Laughing In Distance]
- I'm out on this one.
- [Cards Hit Ground]
I just got money.
Don't worry, Turner.
We'll take your money.
[Laughing]
[Men Chattering, Whooping]
- [Man] Get him, Jim.
- [Man #2] Good job, buddy.
- [Man #3] Come on!
- Get out of my way! Get out of my way!
Come on! Get him!
Holt.
Come on over and share some whiskey.
l-I got work back here to finish.
Well, when you're finished up then.
[Pitt]
Well, lookee here.
You two sure got to be pals,
now, didn't you?
I mean, ever since you boys come back,
you been clappin' your gums together...
regular as crones.
[Distant Laughter]
[Laughter Continues]
[Liquid Pouring]
George.
- [Men Chattering]
- ## [Harmonica]
[Distant Laughter, Whooping]
[Horse Blusters]
[Men Murmuring]
My boys, today I am a sad man.
I am sad because I mourn...
for our sisters and mothers...
who slept in that Kansas City jail.
Who slept until the walls fell down
around them and they died.
I am sad, boys.
And I am tired.
The best of us are dead.
And now we're just dogs
chased into the woods.
I am sad, boys...
but I am vengeful.
And I shall not sleep -
I shall not sleep again
until I stand upon Mount Oread...
and I look down
upon the abolitionists of Lawrence.
- [Man] Yeah, kill those thieving Jayhawkers!
- Kill them Red Legs!
[Quantrill] I shall ride through Kansas
to get there, boys...
and meet any Yankee army
put in my way...
because I will fight them myself
if I have to.
- But I shall reach Lawrence.
- [Men Murmuring]
That's right.
I will fight them all myself.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Murmuring]
Unless there be any men among you...
who would ride with me.
- [Man #2] I'll ride with you.
- [Soldiers Murmuring Agreement]
So I'm asking -
are there any men here
who would ride with me?
[All Shouting]
Then, hell, boys!
Ride with me to Lawrence!
- To Lawrence!
- [All Shouting, Cheering]
Let's ride to Lawrence!
[Shouting, Whistling]
- [Man #3] Down to Lawrence!
- All right!
- Yeah!
- [Shouting Continues]
To Lawrence!
[Shouting Continues]
- The battle's at least two miles ahead, sir.
- Well done, Colonel.
[Man]
All clear! Mount up!
- Come on, boys!
- [Man] Get on your horses, men.
Let's move.
[Quantrill] All right, boys.
Join up and get back in this column.
[Man]
You men, fall in line.
Fools. Those farmers and puffs wouldn't be
able to fight a herd of cattle...
let alone the Kansas Fifth.
No more fools than you and me, Roedel.
[Quantrill]
Come on, men. I wanna see you awake!
Wake up! We'll make it before sunup
if we ride now hard!
- Move it!
- Come on! Pick it up now!
Sweet dreams, Dutchy? Huh?
[Chuckles]
Go back to sleep.
You just may wake up
in Lawrence tomorrow.
[Quantrill]
Let's ride, men. Come on now.
[Man]
Hyah!
[Man #2]
Hyah.
[Man #3]
[Quantrill] You and the boys
take the river north and east.
Mackeson, I want you scoutin'
up toward the west.
Make God's work of it, boys.
We'll wait for first fire. Head out.
I want your boys to be settin' up
a post on Mount Oread.
Watch the road from Fort Leavenworth.
Any dirt kicks up...
I want word sent down straightaway.
Here's the death list.
We shall cross off every name.
[Distant Gunshot]
- [Horses Blustering]
- Jackets off, boys.
- [Distant Gunshot]
- Let 'em see who we are.
- [Men Chattering]
[Man] What's all that noise?
It's a little early for that.
[Man #2]
Sorry?
It's a little early for that, huh?
[Men Chattering]
Let's move.
[All Shouting]
[Man] A little early
for maneuvers, huh, Sarge?
[Men Chattering]
[Shouting, Whooping]
[Shouting, Whooping Continue]
[Shouts, Screams]
Kill!
Kill, boys!
Make no mistakes!
[Woman Screaming, Indistinct]
The Bushwackers are comin'!
- [Woman Screams]
- [Townspeople Shouting, Screaming]
- [Gunshots]
- [Woman] Get inside!
[Shouting, Screaming]
[Man]
Get inside!
[Horse Whinnies]
[Shouting Continues]
[Gunshots]
[Glass Shattering]
[Woman Shrieks]
[Boy]
No! No! No!
No! Let him go! Let him go!
Let him go!
[Woman Screaming In Distance]
[Gunshot]
[Man]
Red Legs, we got us a jayhawker!
[Shouting, Indistinct]
From the top!
[Man] Find George Carpenter.
Bring him back here.
[Gunfire]
- [Woman] No!
- [Woman #2 Shouting, Indistinct]
Was I right?
Who was I not to know...
this town is full to brim
of Northern abolitionaries?
I am sickened, yes, but -
But now real Southern men is coming...
and I say "Hooray," as I am
Southern man at heart.
Perhaps you-you join for whiskey.
- I have here in office.
- [Men Shouting]
Whiskey?
Yes.
[Women Screaming]
[Gunshot]
- [Horse Whinnies]
- [Man] Come on! Come on!
Come on, peckerwood!
[Hoofbeats Passing]
- [Woman Gasps]
- [Man] I'll give you something to write about.
[Woman Shrieks]
- Goddamn lyin' bastard.
- Stay there, boy.
- Put this in your newspaper.
- [Screaming]
- [Grunts]
- [Woman Sobbing]
[Sobbing Continues]
[Glass Shattering]
Old man! Old man!
Where's your army?
[Spits]
Who are we to fight?
- You are cowards, all!
- Send him to hell!
[Screaming]
[Woman Screaming, Indistinct]
- [Gunshot]
- [Screams]
[Sobbing]
- [Horse Whinnies]
- Tear it down!
[Men Cheering, Shouting]
I'll blow your head off
right here!
[Coughs]
Oh! You killed him!
Oh, let me keep his picture! No!
[Spits]
Sure, that Jim Lane -
he steal the slaves.
But he just sell them again
another day.
Me, yes, I always do what I can
for the cause.
It's just me and Granny Esther.
[Breathing Heavily]
[Hammer Releases]
[Shouting, Whooping]
[Cheering, Whooping]
- [Gunshots]
- [Cheering Continues]
[Whoops]
All right, Rocky.
Young reports Lane -
We had thought this would be
a real fight.
It's just bad-luck citizens finding out
just how bad luck can be.
They ought not to murder
the young ones.
Pups make hounds.
If it was your pup,
you'd feel different, son.
[Jake]
Holt?
Let's get us some eggs.
Yeah, Roedel. Let's get us
all the eggs they got.
And some ham.
Hey, boy -
[Grunting]
Hey! Hey!
This man's with us, you fool!
- Huh?
- That's George Clyde's nigger, you fool!
- [Men Whooping]
- [Glass Shattering]
See that pipe there on the end?
And some tobacco.
[Clyde]
And this one.
- [Horse Whinnies]
- [Shouts]
- [Men Laughing]
- [Groans]
[Laughing Continues]
[Gunshots]
- You were makin' breakfast there?
- Yes.
- What were you makin'?
- Potatoes.
- And coffee?
- Yes.
Let's have us some breakfast then.
- [Men Whooping In Distance]
- [Distant Gunshots]
- Mister -
- Shut up.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- More coffee, if you please, ma'am.
- Jake Roedel.
- [Whoops]
Pitt.
Bring those two outside.
I wanna show 'em somethin'.
We'll see to them
once we've had our vittles.
Why, you little Dutch son of a bitch,
you do what I tell you, or I'll kill you.
And when you figure to do
this mean thing to me, Mackeson?
Is this very moment convenient for you?
It is for me.
Let's just take him out.
Nope. That won't work.
The hell with it.
There's plenty more of them Jayhawkers
to kill anyhow.
I'll see you back in Missouri,
you tiny sack of shit.
You know where to find me.
[Man]
That's Pitt Mackeson, ain't it?
I hear he'd soon as kill a man
as mash a tick.
My, what a scary fella he is.
I like you, son...
but that bastard will have your scalp
if you ain't careful.
[Latch Clicks]
Thank you, mister. Thank you.
There ain't enough thanks in the world -
Oh, you go to hell!
[Man] Now, now, boys!
Federals comin'! Eight miles out. Let's go!
[Man #2]
Mount up! Let's go!
- [Man] Come on! Get on your horses!
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Have a good day.
- [Men Shouting]
Get those horses and mount up!
We got a Federal army approaching!
So long, little man.
You are a Southern hero.
I will always, uh, remember
our Southern friends, eh?
Good friends, huh?
[Laughing] Yes. Thank you.
- Good morning.
- [Hammer Clicks]
[Screams]
[Men Shouting, Whooping]
[Snoring]
[Hammer Clicks]
What?
[Glass Shattering]
[Women Clamoring]
[Clamoring Continues]
[Distant Shouting, Whooping]
We're too slow, men!
Drop that damn piano! Let's go!
Jake Roedel.
I heard disappointing words
on you, Roedel.
- Is that so?
- Are you a traitor, Roedel?
You know I'm not.
Well, you spared, boy.
I told you not to spare.
Don't think you are a good man.
That thought will spoil you.
Federal troops, sir.
Closing from behind.
[Black John]
This is it, boys! This is our last stand!
I'll do what I can for you.
[Black John] Remember your families!
We shall avenge their deaths!
[Man] They're right behind!
Goddamn it!
Mount up!
- Battalion, halt!
- Halt!
## [Bugle]
[Men Shouting]
- Run into line!
- [All Shouting]
## [Bugle]
[All Shouting, Whooping]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Screaming, Shouting]
Fall back! Fall back now!
Hyah! Hyah!
- ## [Bugle]
- [Horses Whinnying]
- Let's go!
- Fall back!
Regroup!
[Black John]
Stand firm, boys! They'll be coming!
- Ride on through! Ride on through!
- Pass 'em through, boys!
Fall in and form a line.
Give the signal to the right flank!
- Secure your horses and form a line!
- [Quantrill] Let's cover the left.
Secure your horses and form a second line!
[All Shouting]
[Black John]
Form a line!
Stand strong, men!
Hold your fire till we feel their hooves!
- Hold your fire!
- ## [Bugle]
Stay with me, boys!
- Come on now!
- Take aim!
By company! Fire!
Dismount! All soldiers to the rear!
All soldiers to the rear!
Form a line! Form a line!
Reload your weapons!
[All Shouting]
- Fall back! Fall into the circle!
- [Shouting Continues]
Come on! Come on!
[Black John]
Aim for their belt buckles!
Holt!
Wait! Wait!
Fire!
[Screams]
Holt! Holt!
Come on, I got you!
[Gasps]
George. George.
Oh - Oh, George.
Hold on now, George! Hold on!
- Come on, George! Come on, George!
- Holt!
- [Groans] George!
- [Cave] Jake!
- [Holt] Hold on!
- [Cave] Holt, we gotta go.
Come on, Holt. Holt, come on!
Holt! Come on! He's dead!
- [Black John] Pull back! Pull back!
- [Screaming]
Pull back! Pull back!
- [Screaming, Indistinct]
- George!
[Shouting]
Goin' back with Anderson to the front line!
George!
[Horse Whinnies]
[Hammer Clicks]
- [Black John] Pull back!
- [Screams]
- Hyah!
- [Screaming]
- Let's go, Holt!
- [Screaming Continues]
I'm gonna kill you!
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Gasping]
[Groans Softly]
We'll make for the Brown farm.
Are you gonna make it?
[Sniffles]
Yeah, you're gonna make it.
I'll set you boys up in the parlor here.
Much obliged, Ort.
[Woman]
Ort, who is that?
- Well, take a look.
- I'll just be stayin' the night.
[Woman]
Is that my little Cave?
- Aunt Wilma.
- Oh!
Aunt Wilma.
Oh, it's good to see you, Cave.
You look just like your father.
Are you hurt again?
Well, yeah.
But I didn't do it to myself, you know.
Holt and me, we been shot.
Well, you should have expected it.
I hear you sayin' it.
[Baby Crying]
[Crying Continues]
- [Baby Coughing]
- Whose is that?
[Wilma] Well, it seems -
[Continues, Indistinct]
Well -
[Wilma Chattering]
What do you think of her?
Ort, you'd best explain it to Cave here.
Come on.
Come on, Cave. Let's go out back.
Her name's Grace.
- Grace Shelley Chiles, as far as I'm concerned.
- [Door Closes]
Okay.
- Looks all right to me.
- [Grace Cooing]
Here, I'll change her.
- [Grace Crying]
- Oh, Grace.
There you go, sweetie.
Come on now.
Let me take a look
at your bad spot, Jake.
[Wilma Chattering]
- I wanna make sure it's clean.
- Oh, yeah. It's clean enough.
No, Jake. Clean enough ain't good enough.
You should know that.
And you too, Holt.
Let me take a look.
[Whinnies]
Remember, when you're fixed up, you can
come down, join the Regulars with me.
Maybe that.
Uh, Ort tells me
when you brung that girl here...
she was already pregnant.
You better marry her, boy.
It ain't right not to.
Me?
Yeah.
No, no. Not me.
I don't gotta marry nobody.
Is that right?
You're that kind of man, Dutchy?
Well, I will take care of her, Cave.
It'll be took care of somehow
when it can be.
That's all I ask. 'Cause everybody
likes her real good, you know.
Ort and Wilma there - they already
think of her as somethin' of a daughter.
Well, that's good to hear.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Cattle Lowing]
How's your rib?
None too good.
[Groans]
How's your leg?
Same.
Mmm.
I have a thing or two to say to you, Jake.
Well, speak up.
I think I'll take a walk.
[Groans]
What's this trash I hear
about you bein' my fianc?
Well, so you've heard that.
Well, that was sprung on me by Cave.
You see, they all seem to think
you was carrying my kid, 'cause, uh -
Well, after Jack Bull,
I brought you here.
Oh.
So, do you figure I ought to be married?
Yeah, if you want to keep fingers
from waggin' in your face.
That doesn't bother me.
Well, it's also another thing, Sue Lee.
See, they got a name for kids without daddies.
You know, it ain't a good one.
I know that.
So, do you want to marry me?
No, not too bad.
Good. That's good news...
'cause I wouldn't marry you
for a wagon load full of gold.
I bet you wouldn't.
I wouldn't marry you even if you weren't
some runty little Dutchman...
with nubbin for a finger.
Fine. That's damn fine.
I wouldn't want a wife that didn't know
how to keep her place.
Anyhow, it's a proven thing
that being your man is just plain bad luck...
and I don't need to marry any of that.
Well, it's true.
Guess it's true.
[Sighs] You're not bad luck.
You just had bad luck, is all.
I need convincin' you mean that.
I need convincin' that you were right.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- You're welcome.
[Sighs]
I believe I'll catch some air.
Well, breathe some for me.
[Sue Lee Chattering]
Perhaps you boys can watch after
this little one while I'm at my chores.
Yeah, maybe it's best you talk to him
about that particular line of work.
- Who, me?
- [Sue Lee] That's right.
- [Grace Fussing]
- About time we have some help around here.
Be back around noontime.
- Sue Lee, wait a second.
- [Crying]
Oh. Come on.
- [Crying Continues]
- [Door Closes]
[Crying Continues]
- Oh, come on.
- [Crying Continues]
[Laughing]
Ooh! Hee!
[High-pitched Voice]
Hi! Ooh!
[Crying Continues]
[Crying Stops, Babbling]
I knew that nubbin
would be good for somethin'.
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Door Closes]
Where you been?
She's been screamin' for hours.
Sweet thing wants some sup,
but Mama's been busy.
- Here. I'll feed her.
- No, you won't.
I just got this thing taken care of.
She needs to be suckled, Jake.
Well, hell.
Hmm?
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
It's okay.
- [Grace Fussing]
- [Muttering]
[Fussing Continues]
It's okay.
[Sue Lee Whispering]
[Chuckles]
[Whispering]
Yes
They're all busted up.
- [Jake] Quantrill?
- Headed to Kentucky.
- Anderson?
- Dead, I've heard tell.
Thrailkill, Clement -
most of 'em dead.
Pitt Mackeson.
[Babe]
He's got himself something of a gang.
But these days, they spend
most of their time robbin' for plunder.
And they don't care whether they take it
from Southern folks or Federals.
Anyone gets in their way,
off comes their scalp.
Anyhow, they don't ride much in Jackson
or Cass Counties anymore.
Word has it they're headin' south.
Probably make you a visit.
Word is, they're makin'
a plan of it, Jake.
[Jake Sniffles, Sighs]
[Exhales]
[Moans]
- Can't sleep?
- No.
These quilts are too heavy.
They make me sweat.
Mine too.
[Sniffles, Groans]
You know, Holt...
I probably got one more fight in me.
[Breathing Heavily]
I'm gonna kill Pitt Mackeson...
either when he comes here,
or when I can get up to find him out.
- You know that, Holt?
- Yeah, I know it.
What you gonna do after you kill Pitt?
You gonna join up with them Regulars?
Fight for the cause.
What about you?
You really askin' me?
What cause you think I got, Roedel?
When them Yankees come
and kill George daddy...
and his brothers and all his people,
I stood with George Clyde.
Yeah, he was as good a friend to you
as Jack Bull was to me.
Yeah.
And they's both good and dead now,
Roedel.
Just as dead as they can be.
Where does that leave you and me, huh?
Where does that leave me?
Right here, Holt.
Yeah, I knowed we was right here.
This ain't nowhere for me.
I reckon I just don't understand it.
That day George Clyde died...
it changed me.
I felt something that day
I ain't never felt.
You felt that loss.
That hollow feeling.
No.
What I felt was...
free.
I thought that's what George gave you
when he bought you out.
That weren't really his to give,
now, was it?
[Breathing Heavily]
And, George Clyde -
I believe I loved him.
But bein' that man's friend...
wasn't no different
than bein' his nigger.
And, Roedel...
I ain't never again
gonna be nobody's nigger.
[Sighs, Groans]
[Jake Groans]
How you feelin', Dutchy?
Oh, not so bad.
You look like you feel right good.
You feel good?
I don't feel too bad.
Ah, you seem about all healed up to me.
Ah, it still hurts some, my leg does.
I gotta go to Hartwell today.
Be back by night though.
You want me to come along?
No, you go on. Finish healin'.
I'll take Holt with me though.
He's a handy man with a gun, I hear tell.
That's right.
You always gonna stare like that?
Long as I can.
Well, you're pretty near well,
so won't be much longer.
Reckon you and Holt will be off to get shot
by some different fellas here pretty soon.
Maybe I won't.
What'll you do then?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe trek me on over to California...
and catch me a sailboat
to somewhere sunny.
Is that right?
What grand spot have you got
in mind, Jake?
Sparta.
In Sparta, they have olives.
I got that out of a book.
I could eat me some olives.
Olives. What are olives like?
I don't know firsthand.
I never had one yet.
But I've had a bushel of walnuts...
and nothin' could be more trouble
to eat than them.
I wonder about me.
I ain't goin' sailin' nowhere,
and I know it.
You'll do all right.
[Door Closes]
A chicken, Wilma? It ain't Sunday even.
What's with the special favors?
Well, nothin'. I know Orton will be mighty
tired tonight when he gets back from his ride.
I intend to feed him well.
[Cattle Lowing]
[Lowing Continues]
[Chickens Clucking]
That the man?
That's him. Dutchy Roedel.
What is this?
This here is the Reverend Horace Wright.
You're gettin' married today, Dutchy.
You're gettin' married
or you're gettin' out.
I'm what?
You heard me. You're all healed up.
I just wanted to make sure
you didn't die slow on me before I did it.
- I can't have it in my house the way it is.
- It's time.
Holt, saddle my horse.
We're gettin' out of here.
No. You should do right, Roedel.
What on earth does that mean?
Let's talk.
Come on.
I do believe that is
a roastin' chicken I smell.
[Sighs]
Are you goin' to or not?
It's bein' shoved down my throat.
If a thing has got to be shoved,
I like to do the shovin'.
Okay.
- [Sighs]
- Then get in there and shove, Jake.
I thought you said
you wouldn't want me...
for a wagonload of gold 'cause
I'm a nubbin-fingered runt of a Dutchman.
I remember you sayin' that.
Well, I guess I lied.
Are you lyin' again now?
No. I wouldn't lie to you, Jake.
You just told me you lied to me before.
Well, that's different.
That was romance.
And now's what?
The truth.
This here now is the truth.
[Reverend]
So you, Jacob Friedrich Roedel...
bein' the man, take you,
Sue Lee Shelley Evans, bein' the woman.
So, by the power vested in me,
the two of you is right married.
Ain't it so.
Well, that was sure a fast ceremony.
Well, I reckon that man
would marry stones to stones...
if there was a chicken at the end of it.
Ah, that's neither here
nor somewheres else.
He just done made you legal, boy.
Good night, boys.
Good night, Ort.
[Gasping]
[Snoring]
[Snoring Continues]
So you a family man now.
How you feel?
I feel the same, Holt.
Hell, it's only words.
No, that's an oath.
Those words you gotta back up.
Yeah, I know that.
I reckon we'll be haulin' her
and the kid with us now.
Where to?
I don't know.
What do you think of California?
Boy, what is you doin'?
What am I doin'? Have you gone blind?
I'm goin' to sleep, Holt.
I'm fixin' to get me some sleep.
Roedel, I gotta tell you this?
Tell me what?
[Chuckling]
You're supposed to sleep
with the wife, Roedel.
Great day in the morning,
you got to know that much.
You're supposed to share her bed.
That way, if some other man do that,
you shoot him.
Yeah, I know all that.
You bet I know that.
But, hell, this ain't some
regular marriage situation.
What, you don't like her? You gonna sit up
there and tell me you don't like her?
I like her.
She's pretty enough and all that.
It's just this marriage thing
has swept up on me kind of all of the sudden.
Yeah, well, it is over you, Roedel.
- I mean to say, you done the milkin'.
- [Boot Drops On Floor]
You might as well have the cream.
Jake.
Hey, take your clothes off.
You don't come to bed in dirty duds, Jake.
That's a rule.
Just how many rules is it
you got for me, girl?
Don't get mad.
Here. I'll help you.
Hmm.
Are you a virgin?
I've sinned plenty.
But have you ever bedded a woman before?
Girl, I've killed 15 men.
[Chuckling]
Come here.
Holt.
[Sighs]
Roedel, I do a lot for you,
you know that?
You know I do. It's equal.
Yeah - Don't say it.
I got a thing to say.
All right.
Uh - Look, now I'll travel with you
and yours till we get past...
them Pin Indians and riffraff in the Nation,
and then I got to go off somewhere.
Where is that, Holt?
Well, I ain't decided that
to a definite aim, but I'm goin'.
I'm goin' to find my mama.
I believe she was sold to Texas,
so that's where I'll commence to lookin'.
If she was sold there...
I'll go there and pay to buy her freedom.
Holt, you done already
paid more than enough to buy -
Yeah, I-I hear you sayin' it.
- I wish you well.
- Well, it ain't yet.
I ain't leavin' you
till your little narrow Dutch ass...
is past Pitt Mackeson
and them Pin Indians.
- Didn't I just through tellin' you that?
- Yeah, you did.
All right.
[Scissors Snipping]
[Jake]
Good-bye, Bushwhacker curls.
[Snipping Continues]
There you are, Dutchy.
You look 21 again.
I'm just now 19, Ort.
That so?
Well, you'll never look that young.
I said I wouldn't cut my hair
till I was finished with the war.
And you didn't, Roedel.
You didn't.
Militia find those, you're not likely to get
further than the nearest hangin' tree.
Ah, hell. Good luck, y'all.
[Wilma Chattering]
- [Sighs]
- Shh.
[Jake]
Giddap!
[Jake Whistles]
[Chattering]
- [Man] Yes, sir!
- [Horse Blusters]
Yes, sir.
[Chattering Continues]
[Branch Snaps]
[Horse Whinnying]
[Grace Crying]
Why, Dutchy,
I didn't expect to see you no more.
Howdy, Pitt. Turner.
[Turner]
Howdy.
Water's boilin'.
Want some chicory?
I think I will.
I think I'd like some chicory, Dutchy.
[Grace Fussing]
How are you, Holt?
Fairly well.
You two alone?
Just us now.
We've been on the run.
How's Black John?
That's a big question, Dutchy,
'cause the man is dead.
Black John is dead.
Hell, who ain't?
They got him at Dover.
Put his head on a pole.
Paraded him right down the street.
Put a picture of it in their paper.
Quantrill too.
Over the river.
It's been rough times
for them who stuck it out.
Yeah, the war is lost.
No shit, Dutchy.
Who the gal and kid belong to?
That's my wife.
[Chuckles]
Well, if that don't beat all.
You got a wife, Dutchy.
- Where you headed?
- Newport.
Hell, man.
There's 200 Federals in Newport.
We just rode through 'em.
You can't go on in there.
Wrong, Dutchy. I am goin' in there.
I'm for certain sure goin' in there.
I want a drink,
and they have drinks in Newport.
They'll kill you.
You best stay clear out of there.
I don't think so, Dutchy.
I don't reckon I'll clear out
of where I was born.
You see, that there
was my hometown.
And I reckon I'll go on in
and have me a drink there.
Turner, you too?
They'll kill you sure.
What a horrible fate.
Oh, what a horrible fate.
[Hammer Clicks]
Oh, boy. You got me now, Dutchy.
Oh, boy. You got me now.
Jake.
Come on, Turner.
You gonna shoot him?
[Hoofbeats Retreating]
So long, boys. We'll raise our glasses
to you in Newport.
[Hoofbeats Retreating]
[Breathing Heavily]
All right.
It ain't right, and it ain't wrong.
It just is.
[Sighs]
It's now?
Are you certain you wanna ride
with your gun like that?
Let me wake 'em, Holt.
No, Roedel. You let them sleep.
I ain't too much for good-byes.
But, uh, maybe I'll just tip my hat.
All right.
Daniel Holt.
Jacob Roedel.
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
## [Acoustic Ballad]
[Woman]
# Turn to me with frozen lips #
# Your hands are icy cold #
# Your eyes burn bright
against the frost-lit sky #
# You never seemed more lovely
than you do #
# Tonight #
# Pale on the horizon #
# Like leaves frozen in the snow #
# Our two shadows merge inseparably #
# Will time stand still
if it's pierced with cold #
# The more I live #
# The more I know #
# What's simple is true #
# I love #
# You #
# There's a warmth in my heart #
# It haunts me when you're gone #
# Mend me to your side
and never let go #
# Say, Time knows nothing #
# We'll never grow cold #
# The more I live #
# The more I know #
# What's simple is true #
# I love #
# You #
# Twilight descends on our silhouette #
# How soon spring comes
How soon spring forgets #
# I wanna hold time
Say it'll never begin #
# Old Man Winter, be our friend #
# The more I live #
# The more I know #
# What's simple is true #
# I love #
# You ##