I'm not really sure
that I'll be able to do this.
Just relax and sit opposite me
and answer my questions. That's all.
- I've never done this before.
- It'll be easy. I promise.
- [ Chuckles ]
- How areyou today?
- Fine, thankyou.
- [man #2 ] Can we get a soundcheck, please?
Can we just have a few words,
just for the sound man?
- What should I say?
- Sayanything.
[ Both Chuckle ]
I have a-- I've had such a big mouth all my life,
and now I don't know what to say.
- [Sound man ]A little more, please.
- [ Clears Throat ]
To tell you the truth,
I don't know if I should be doing this.
Everyone told me that I should. They said,
"It's the BBC, and they'll do it right."
- [Goodman ] We will do it right. Ipromise.
- [Sound man ] That's fiine.
- [Bell Ringing]
- Just relax. Are we ready?
- This is a BBC production. I nterview with Linda--
- Oh, you wanted the scrapbook?
We'll do it later. We'll get the photographs.
We'll have fiilm clips andphotographs.
- I see.
- Uh, ifiwe couldjust fiinish
getting the slate, please.
- Sorry.
- Hitler's Germany, " Part--
- U m, what-- what fil m cl i ps?
- You'll see it when it's fiinished. I promise.
- Okay?
- Sorry.
Hitler's Germany,
" Part Five: Women i n the War." Mark.
Sojust relax.
You've got all the time in the world.
- Do I start?
- Tell me about the war.
When do you fiirst become
interested in it?
Um...
the movies.
- **** [ Orchestra: Dramatic ]
- There they are.
**** [ Continues ]
- We'll head 'em off..
- [Linda Narrating] War movies--
anything set in Germany.
- Didn't matter ifiit was
the First World War or the Second.
- [ Gunfiire ]
- I especially loved anything set in Berlin.
- They' re over the border.
**** [ Romantic ]
From the time I was a child,
my grandmother and my fiather...
told me stories
about their beloved city.
[ Goodman ]
You spoke German in your household?
To my mother I spoke English.
She was Irish, born in Brooklyn.
To my fiather I spoke German.
But he warned me to keep
this language a secret...
because outside ofiour neighborhood
in Queens, New York...
ifipeople heard me speak German...
they would either think that
I was a Nazi sympathizer...
or they would know I was a Jew.
- [ man Speaking In German ]
- **** [ Piano: Classical ]
- [ Continues In German ]
- **** [ Conti nues ]
[ Footsteps Approaching]
I n English, please...
for us poor I rish trash.
Thankyou.
"We are no longer allowed
to use a public toilet...
"nor can Hannah, Sofi or I
go to a beauty parlor...
because Hitlersays
the hair ofiaJewis infiectious. "
"We hear rumors everywhere...
"that Jews are being
rounded up and sent away.
"We don't know where.
"We have been
invited by friends...
to hide with them
somewhere in Berlin."
[Linda Narrating]
I guess it was then that the fiantasybegan.
I dreamed ofiparachuting
into Germany and rescuing them:
my fiather's two sisters,
Hannah and Liesel...
and Hannah 's daughter, Sofii...
who played the flute and was
Just a yearyounger than I.
I dreamed ofiseeing Sofii on the concert stage
in New York City...
playing her flute
Just fior me.
**** [ Orchestra: Dramatic ]
[ Announcer ]
The doomed city ofWarsaw.
Pounded by Hitler's guns--
[ Goodman ]
Soyou contacted the War Department...
about becoming a spy.
[ Chuckles ]
Um...
I wouldn't have known who to contact
about becoming a spy.
*** [Big Band: Fast Swing]
[Linda Narrating] In 1 940,
when all ofiEurope was struggling against Hitler...
I wasjust a young girl
struggling to get out ofiQueens.
I remember how intimidating
the city was...
and I remember the fiirst sight
ofithe man who would change my lifie.
...'cause it's not our war!
I t's not our problem.
Ifiany blood is gonna be shed
keepin'Hitler out ofiEngland...
Iet it be English blood,
not American...
'cause it's not our war.
It's not ourproblem.
And anyone who says
America should get involved in this war...
is aJew-loving Commie--
Franklin Delano "Rosenberg" included.
- [ man ] Why don 't you go home?
- Why don 't you go home?
- [ man #2 ] Watch your mouth, buddy.
- Oh, we got another one here.
[ Distant ]
Get out of here ri ght now.
[ Continues Indistinct ]
I am sure your typing skills
are superior, Miss Voss, but...
a degree from Queens Clerical College
is a bit beneath our standards.
Our legal secretaries
come directly from Vassar.
I'm sureyou understand.
Oh, I understand.
So unless you have something to add to change
my mind, I-- I'm afraid I really couldn't--
Loweryour standards?
Listen, I wouldn't wantyou to.
You might have to workwith someone
who's had to get her hands dirty...
and I'm sure that would be very uncomfortable
foryou and the girls from Vassar.
I went to Vassar,
by the way.
My uncle's car broke down right at
the front gate, and I had to pick him up.
Place looked like a real shithole to me.
Thankyou very much.
[ Women Gasp, Scream ]
- [ Others Chattering ]
- [ Woman Speaking In German ]
[ German ]
[Woman Sobbing,
Speaking German ]
miss Voss...
you failed to mention
that you speak a second language.
- [ Typewriters Clacking ]
- [Linda Speaking German ]
"Since all demands fiorpayment
have gone unanswered--
- "such as the billing in September of this year--
- [ German ]
- "we have no choice...
- "but to impound the shipment
of cement wagons...
- [ German ]
until proper reparations
are made."
[ German ]
"Laster" is "truck."
I said "wagon."
You said "cement wagon."
"Laster" is correct.
You are certain ofyourself,
which is good.
You'll have to be.
Bitte.
We run an international practice here,
and we're trying to disentangle...
certain companies
from their affairs in Germany.
Unfortunately, one of our senior partners
has a tin ear for languages...
which leaves him
somewhat handicapped.
Graduated cum laude from Harvard,
but flunked right out of Berlitz.
He also has a lousy disposition...
and runs through secretaries
like a bowling ball through tenpins.
Incidentally,
we call him "the Pallbearer"...
- because he rarely cracks a smile.
- [man ] Come in.
He also dislikes women
who wear hats, by the way.
Oh. Hi.
Isawyou on the street this morning.
With that speaker?
Oh.
What did you say to him?
I just suggested he might be more comfortable
speaking somewhere else.
You were great.
Reminded me ofJimmy Stewart
in The mortal Storm.
- Didyou eversee it?
- Uh, no.
It's a great film.
What's with the blackout?
You expecting Hitler to bomb us tonight?
Sometimes I think better
in the dark.
Ed Leland,
Linda Voss.
Ninetywords a minute,
bilingual dictation...
works the mimeograph, speaks German
with the accent ofia Berlin butcher's wifie.
- How's that for a last-minute save?
- Berlin butcher's wife.
Home-taught by her grandmother
who's from Berlin.
But she wasn't married to a butcher.
[ Chuckles ]
My grandfather owned
a button factory...
till it burned down.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Your, uh-- Your grandmother,
did she insistyou speak, uh--
German?
She doesn't speak English.
She's--
She's lived here for--
- My sixth grade teacher used to do that.
- Beg your pardon?
You know, start a question
and not finish it...
Iike,
"The capital of Indiana is"--
She's been in this country
for 1 8 years.
Yes. Well, my question is, ifshe's lived here
for 1 8 years, why doesn't she speak, um--
English.
She prefers German.
Does she prefer Germany?
She's Jewish.
- You'reJewish?
- Half.
Is that a problem
in this company?
[ Chuckles ] Oh, no. It just means
we're halfsureyou're not a Nazi spy.
[German]
She'll be fine.
Would you stand up and turn around, please?
Why should I do that?
- [man ] Becauseyou want thejob.
- And I asked you to.
It's a test I like to give.
Well, I'll take it sitting down.
What I was gonna askyou to do
is stand up, turn around...
and closeyour eyes and tell me
everything you see in the room.
It's an observation test.
Now, doyou really have a problem with that?
[ Clears Throat ]
Pictures of sailboats and polo ponies,
fancy books and diplomas...
stuffed fish on the wall,
calendar set to the wrong date...
bookcases that needdusting,
carpets that need cleaning...
and a couple of guys from Harvard
who are surprised...
that a girl who needs a job
won't be treated like a slave.
Are you always like this?
Forgot to tell you,
my other half's Irish.
Lethal combination.
- Mmm.
- [Linda Narrating] It didn't take me long...
to sense there was more to Ed Leland
than met the eye.
- [ Women Chattering]
- In February ofi 1 940...
one ofithe switchboard girls
accidentally tapped into his private line...
and heard a voice that she swore
was Franklin Delano RooseveIt's.
In march,Jimmy in the mail room caught sight
ofia sealed document on Ed's desk...
addressed to J. Edgar Hoover.
- H i, J i m my.
- In April, Ed's staff.started interviewing...
- recently arrived German refiugees...
- U m, Frau Chernick?
- to get details about lifie in Hitler's Germany.
- [ Both Speaki ng German ]
And byfiall ofithatyear,
Ed Leland's whereabouts--
- [ Elevator Chimes ]
- were completely unpredictable.
- He'd vanish fior weeks at a time,
- My office, please?
returning as abruptly as he left--
- [ German ]
- to dictate letters that made no sense at all.
Naturally, it set a girl's mind to wondering.
Please to report that
my wife, Sunflower and I...
and her--
her new dog, Rover...
just returned
from the seashore...
where we saw... a flock ofbirds--
seabirds--
a flock of 1 4 seabirds
diving for fish.
Excuse me.
Are those pelicans?
Yousaid theywere diving.
I've asked you
not to interrupt me.
I'm sorry, mr. Leland,
but the German language is veryspecifiic.
You wouldn't say "seabirds."
You would say "pelicans."
Unless, of course, this is all just some kind
of code, in which caseyou should just tell me...
so that I would
stop bothering you.
[ Chuckles ]
Now, whywould you say something like that?
No. I'm--
I'm curious. Why?
Well, yourwife's name
is not Sunflower.
You don't even have a wife--
I mean, not one that I know of anyway.
Therefore, you, uh--
you assume that this is all a code.
I don't have to stand up and turn around
to see that your overnight bag is full...
ofwoolen sweaters
and heavy socks.
Not exactly the kind ofthing
you take to the seashore--
at least not a vacation-type seashore.
More like the English Channel, I'd say.
Anything else?
No.
- Okay. Where were we?
- Except that the code is a deadgiveaway.
I mean,
1 4 birds "diving for fish"?
It's obviously
a fleet of 1 4 submarines.
You're gonna get caught
with a code like this.
The Germans aren't stupid, Mr. Leland.
myGod, theydo it better
in the movies.
- Didyousee Espionage Agent
with Brenda marshall?
- No.
Well, in it, when she talked about submarines,
she talked about her "rose garden."
- Her rose garden.
- Yeah, so that there would be no connection.
And for airplanes,
she talked about "figs and dates."
- Figs and dates.
- Mm-hmm.
"Figs" for Fokkers
and "dates"--
I can't rememberwhat "dates" were.
- Well, I guess I better go to the movies...
- [DrawerRattles ]
to see how they do this.
Mywife, Susan,
who I call Sunflower.
This photograph was taken a year before
I put her in a sanitarium in Switzerland--
a mental institution
which I visit often...
and which I'm afraid
that she'll never leave.
You understand whyit's easier
fiorme to letpeople think...
that I've neverbeen married.
I'm sorry.
[ Sighs ]
- God, I fieel so stupid.
- No, it's-- it's all right.
I feel so stupid that...
I don't understand why I can't make
carbon copies ofyour letters...
orwhy I have to turn in my steno pad
for a new one each time I've finished...
orwhy I type endless letters,
but never envelopes...
so that I don't know
where they're going to.
Last time I was in Switzerland,
I asked a psychiatrist the same thing.
Why is it that
I don't trust anybody?
He thinks it has something
to do with my upbringing.
You're a spy,
Mr. Leland.
And you've seen too many movies,
Miss Voss.
Enough to know a spy
when I see one.
And about this photo.
The woman's name
is Jennifer Krimm...
a model you were never married to
but only dated...
beforeyou met
Kiki Avondale, that is--
a Vassar graduate whoyou were engaged to
for six months before you got cold feet.
Oh, this is outrageous.
This is-- This is--
I don't have to listen to this anymore.
This is simply and totally--
[ Sighs ]
How doyou know
all these things?
I might be a better spy than you are.
- ***[Big Band: Fast Swing]
- [ Crowd Chattering]
[ Women Cheering ]
*** [ Continues ]
[Linda Narrating]
Bylate October ofi'4 1...
London was reeling under a hailstorm
ofiGerman bombs called the "Blitz, "
and lifie in America was energized
with the knowledge ofiwhat was inevitable.
Young men were disappearing late at night
and signing up fior the draft.
Glenn miller was pumping out dance music
while there was still time to dance...
and Ed Leland had cast his eyes
in my direction.
- [ Linda Giggling, Chattering ]
- For us, like the war--
- [ Leland, Indistinct ]
- it was just a matter ofitime.
[ Linda Snorts, Giggles ]
[ Both Speaki ng I n German, Laughi ng ]
I can't-- I can't speak German.
I can't get the accent.
- *** [Slow Swing, Faint ]
- At least I made you laugh.
- Yes, you do do that.
- Is that a hard thing to do, makeyou laugh?
- Well, serious times, Linda.
- Mmm.
All the more reason.
Charlie Chaplin says
a daywithout laughter is a daywasted.
You believe that?
Yeah. I tryto laugh once a day,
just in case.
Doyou like Charlie Chaplin?
To be quite honest,
I've never seen him.
- You're kidding.
- No.
- Well, what areyou doing tonight?
- Tonight?
Tonight I have tickets
for the opera.
Hmm. Really.
[ In English Accent]
I've never been to the opera.
- Oh?
- What's it like?
Ah, it's not for everybody. It's--
- Well, see, that's the thing about Chaplin. He is.
- You really like Chaplin.
- Mr. Leland--
- Why don'tyou call me Ed.
Ed.
***[Ends ]
[ThunderRumbling, Distant]
[ThunderContinues ]
[ Moans Quietly]
[ Vehicle Horns Honking, Distant ]
[man Speaking In German ]
[ man #2 Translating]
There are six railroad goodyards...
und three main line stations--
[ German ]
uh, right near a large--
- How would you say, "Schornstein"?
- Li nda.
Me? I don't speak German.
Ja. "Church steeple. "
Can we take a break for a moment?
"Schornstein" is "smokestack,"
not "church steeple."
Translator's been lying.
Linda, the man has been working
as a translator in this office foryears.
Hmm. Yeah. Well, he started out
by making little mistakes...
and when nobody noticed,
then the mistakes started getting bigger.
Making mistakes does not
make the man a liar.
He tripled the number of railroad lines
coming into the city.
One sentence involving a munitions plant--
he left that one out altogether.
Ja.
What is he, a double agent?
Right here in this office?
What'll you do to him?
Stop using him as a translator.
Oh.
- How'd you know to stay quiet?
- The Fighting 69th
with Brenda Marshall and Cary Grant.
- I see.
- They cut out his tongue.
*** [ Orchestra: Classical Waltz On Speaker]
- **** [ Continues ]
- [ Linda Narrating] By day we worked together...
by night we were lovers--
secret lovers--
until a Sunday morning in December when
we lay listening to a symphony on the radio.
I said I'd never been to a concert
and would love to go with him someday.
- *** [ Stops ]
- [Announcer] We interrupt this program...
to bringyou a special news bulletin.
The Japanese have attacked
Pearl Harbor, Hawaii by air...
President Roosevelt has just announced.
- The air raid is still on.
- [ machine Gunfiire, Faint ]
The antiai rcraft fi re
can be heard i n a steady drone...
as the attacking planes come in.
We will continue to receive reports
which will tell veryshortly--
- [ Sniffling ]
- the story ofiwhat is to happen
in the months that are to come.
*** [ Resumes ]
[ Linda Narrating ]
For me there would be no symphonies with Ed...
Just the sound ofidrums
as America went to war.
*** [ man Singing Swing Fast ]
*** [ Continues ]
- [ Linda Narrating ] What Pearl Harbor also did--
- *** [ Continues ]
was bring Ed Leland's unifiorm
and his true identity out ofithe closet--
that ofia fiull-ranking military colonel
working fior the O.S.S. in Washington.
His job, to coordinate infiormation
coming firom behind enemy lines.
- [ Goodman ]
So, you accompanied him to Washington?
- To the Washington airport.
But ourjourney together
ended there.
I want you to set up an office for Andy.
- It came as a complete surprise to me.
- I want you to keep it...
total ly secure.
- Everything he said that night
came as a complete surprise.
- I 'll be in touch with you.
I 'm... continuing on.
Continuing on?
To where?
I don't know. Well...
- I can't say.
- What does that mean?
It means... things change.
It's not the right time for us.
I don't wantyou to be waiting.
I don't want to be-- either of us--
worrying.
But Ed, what's a war for...
if not to hold on to what we love?
- [man ] Colonel!
- [ Sobs ]
Hey, Colonel!
Good-bye.
[Linda Narrating] He said he'd be in touch
with me, but he never was.
And no one ever knew I loved him.
[ Engi ne Whi ni ng ]
[ Plane Departing]
While America went to war,
Ed disappeared in Europe...
and I disappeared into the infiormation center
ofithe War Department--
a basement where hundreds
ofiwomen toiled--
sorting, fiiling and distributing
infiormation about Germany--
Li nda, "T rooper."
and where I secretly searched
fior clues about Ed Leland--
clues in words such as "Trooper,"
which I fiound out
was Ed's code name...
and "Camp Brady,"
which meant "behind enemy lines. "
I knew he was traveling
and into dangerous places.
I also knew
I didn 't want to care.
*** [ Band: Slow Swing ]
- *** [ Continues ]
- [ Crowd Chattering ]
**** [ Si ngi ng ]
- Six months into the war, Europe still belonged--
- **** [ Conti nues ]
to Hitler and mussolini.
American boys were being lost
by the thousands...
on Pacifiic islands with names
like Corregidor and Batann...
and a man named Ed Leland
had disappeared firom the fiace ofithe earth.
When spring came to Washington,
he was all I thought about...
because I believed that
wherever he was...
the sheer fiorce ofimy love fior him
would keep him safie, keep him alive.
Excuse me. I noticed you looki n' a bit lonely.
Would you like to dance?
- No, thanks.
- You sure?
- I will.
- Okay. Come on.
*** [ Woman Singing Continues ]
*** [ Continues ]
[ Laughs ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
*** [Band Continues ]
At ease, gentlemen.
Good evening.
Good evening, sir.
- Hello, Linda.
- Hello, Ed. What brings you to town?
Well, I had to come in for something.
I'm gonna be here for a while.
That's great.
Would you like to dance?
Nah. You're busy.
Come on.
I don't wanna dance.
Would you all excuse us
for a couple of minutes, please?
Yes, sir.
We'll be
over there, okay?
Howyou been?
Not great.
No?
No.
When did you start smoking?
I don't know.
Kind of a silly thing to do,
isn't it?
I'm a silly girl, Ed.
I thinkyou're living proof ofthat.
I'm sorryto hearyou got shuffled
into the basement.
Itwouldn't have happened ifl was here.
I spokewith Andy, and...
he's gonna keep his eyes out
for a betterjob.
I told him I'm quitting
ifhe doesn't.
You can come work for me while I'm here.
I can always use a good secretary.
[ Chuckles ]
This is all so civilized, Edward.
That's whatyou like, isn't it,
civilized people?
Polite ladies with pedigrees
who look good at the opera...
andnevermakeyou laugh too hard
andnevermakeyou fieel too much.
I've had a lot of time
to think about this...
and don't tell me
it's the war...
when I've been waiting for six months
to hearwhetheryou're dead or alive...
and you waltz into a nightclub.
- Linda, I came in last night. I was gonna call you.
- Oh, go to hell.
Careful, Ed.
You might have to admit thatyou know me.
- Linda, it is the war.
- Oh, you're so noble, Ed.
Did I promiseyou something?
Ifl did, I'd like to know.
Excuse me, sir?
I thought theyoung lady might like to dance.
- The lady is busy.
- I'd love to dance.
- I'm cutting in.
- Don't let him.
- Excuse me, sir. I don't think
theyoung ladywants to dance.
- Don't try it.
- I'll leave here with your Adam's apple
in my pocket.
- [ Sobs ]
What doyou want from me?
- I wantyou to stop feeling sorry foryourself.
- *** [Ends ]
- No. You want me to stop feeling, likeyou.
- [Applause ]
*** [Band Resumes ]
- [ Sobs ]
- *** [Woman Singing Resumes ]
[ Sobs ]
- You did love me, didn't you?
I couldn't have been wrong.
- *** [ Continues ]
You weren't.
Well, then how do you stop?
I want to.
[ Sobs ]
[ Sobs, Sniffling ]
*** [Ends ]
[Leland]
His name was Albert Eckert--
you know his fiile bythe code name "Zipper"--
a society dress designer...
popular with the wives
of high-ranking S.S. officials in Berlin...
that is, until last Wednesday
at 1 400 hours...
when he was last seen by our senior operative,
Sunflower, buying roses at a marketplace.
This photo was taken one hourlater,
1500 hours.
maybe somebody didn't like
his latest dress design.
[ All Chuckling ]
That man put his life on the line...
which is more than anybody
in this room's about to do.
[man ]
Andyou're looking to replace him?
Immediately,yes.
And it's not gonna be easy.
His access to information
was his close relationship to Hedda Drescher...
wife of Horst Drescher,
a social climbing young Nazi...
who ingratiates himself
to his superiors...
by hosting elegant dinner parties
in his beautiful home--
a home which was appropriated
firom one ofithe fiinestJewish fiamilies in Berlin.
The simple genius
ofiEckert's method...
was to bri ng Hedda a new gown
for each of these social occasions...
and help her get dressed
in the upstairs study...
where he was allowed to linger
fiora glass ofiport when the partybegan...
at which time
he'd lock the door...
and microfiilm certain documents...
that Drescher was in the habit
ofibringing back firom the War Off.ice--
documents I i ke this...
and this...
and this.
Documents which lead us
to believe...
that somewhere in Germany
scientists are developing a bomb...
that can fly by itself.
So I thinkyou all can see
the urgency ofithis situation.
Lights, please.
We need someone to get back
into Drescher's study and do it fast...
find out where this work is being done
and stop it before it goes any further.
- So, do I have any suggestions?
- What about that cabinetmaker, Meyerhoff?
The guy from Leipzig?
Ifyou want to get into this study--
That makes a lot of sense.
They'd let him pull apart their secret cabinets.
What about Eric Erdmann, the language professor
from Tufts? He came from Munich.
That theywere both born in Germany,
so they'll be instant best firiends?
- Linda.
- It took Eckert years to gain their confidence.
You think somebody can just move right in
and be given run of the house?
- She's right about that.
- That is whatyou need, though.
Someone who can literally
move in and live there.
Someone with a low-class Berlin accent
who could work as a domestic.
Someone with the accent
of a Berlin butcher's wife.
Gentlemen, let's break for dinner.
I know the codes. I know the network.
I know the whole operation.
I could pass for a Berliner.
- [Slams Papers ]
- Linda?
-...because you are a secretary. You are not a spy.
- Because I'm a secretary?
You are not suited to it, Linda.
You have no formal training whatsoever.
- I'm not suited to it?
You can't even speak German.
- And you can't hold your tongue.
I saw it first time I metyou.
Everything on your mind spills out ofyour mouth.
It makes you very dangerous.
- It's more mywarthan yours.
- That is a ridiculous thing to say.
- I'm a Jew.
- You know what Hitler's doing toJews?
Even halfJews?
- Of course I do. I have relatives still hiding there.
- I doubt it.
- That they're still hiding?
- Thatyou know what's happening.
- Meaning?
- Meaning I am not gonna letyou commit suicide.
- I will quit, ifyou don't let me go.
- I'll miss you.
I will, goddamn it!
I quit!
[DoorBuzzerRinging]
[Knocking]
- Linda--
- Ed, I wantyou to taste mystrudel--
the way my grandmother taught me to make it--
and my apple Kompott.
She taught me to cook German style,
the way my grandfather likes it.
And I could cook for 50 if I had to--
five courses, the way they do it in Berlin.
And on nights when they didn't
have people over...
I could bring tea and strudel
up to the Dreschers' study...
andput a little schnapps in the tea
so that Horst and Hedda would get tired...
and could retire early, and I could be left alone
in the study to clean up.
This is not about
you and me, goddam n it.
I wanna do something
important with my life.
Here, taste.
Taste it.
You know what you're
getting yourselfinto, Linda?
Yeah. The war.
[Linda Narrating]
He agreed to sendme fiortwo weeks only...
- We'll be arriving soon.
- insisting that whether I succeeded or not...
- I'd come out ofiBerlin in exactly 1 4 days.
- Thanks.
Untrained in survival skills...
I was given a quick course
in the use ofia microfiilm camera...
and a purse that made up in fiunction
fior what it lacked in fiashion.
Beyond that, it was all guts.
Accompanying me
as fiar as Switzerland...
Ed would turn me over
to the legendary Sunflower--
a German working fior the Americans...
who would take me on my fiinaljourney
into Berlin.
[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
I ' I l meet you i n two weeks,
ri ght on this platform, two weeks from today.
- I look all right?
- You look perfect.
This is it.
Still wanna go through with it?
- Where is he?
- Right in front ofyou.
- There?
- Not there.
[Leland]
There.
Take care ofyourself, Linda.
Seeyou in two weeks.
Eyes down, say nothing
and try not to look like a spy.
[Door Closes ]
Are you mute?
You said not to speak.
[ Goodman ]
Uh, excuse me.
Uh, might I interrupt?
Areyou aware thatyou're speaking in German?
Sorry.
I remember it in German.
Couldyou remember it
in English, please?
Sure.
What's wrong with my accent?
- It's from the gutter.
- But it's supposed to be.
- I'm a cook.
- But not one that Drescher would accept.
Don't you know
he's a man of great pretensions?
With that vulgar sound
he won't let you in at the door.
- [Engine Starts ]
- My God, what have they sent me?
[Linda Narrating]
I guess I couldn't blame him.
Konrad Friedrichs,
known as "Sunflower,"
had become a spy by my calculations
around the year I was born.
A veteran ofitwo wars,
he was now partnered with me...
whose only qualifiication--
as he was quick to point out--
was that I was born to some
low-class individuals firom Berlin.
It was my hope that some ofithese individuals
were still in safie hiding--
that myJewish relatives had escaped
Hitler's dreaded storm troopers...
and were somehow,
somewhere still alive.
- [ Train Whistle, Distant ]
- [ Train Approaching ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ men Shouting Commands
In German ]
[ Men Coughi ng, Moani ng ]
[ Goodman ]
Your fiirst sight ofiBerlin-- any impression?
[ Linda Narrating]
Pitch darkness. I was surrounded by it.
The city was blacked out, prepared fior
the night raids which hadn 't yet begun.
Leave the I uggage.
Not yours. Fol low me.
T oi let, washbasin.
You'll stay in here
until I decide what to do.
Komm. Komm.
- [ Vehicle Horns Honking, Distant ]
- [ Knocking ]
- [DoorShuts, Distant ]
- [Footsteps Approaching]
[ Woman ]
Uncle Pootzie!
[ Lock Rattling]
[ Laughs ]
Komm. Komm.
He said ifyour cooking was anything like
your accent, it was strictly for the beer halls.
So I'm taking a week offwork
at the War Department...
to teach you some grammar
and some High German cuisine.
And believe me,
you're going to need it.
We're putting you into Drescher's house
one week from today...
to cook for a party
which is most important to him.
His temper is legendary
when things go wrong.
My uncle didn't tell you
I was coming.
I just arrived last night, Fraulein.
I'm Margretevon Eberstien...
ofthe Klaus von Eberstiens.
My father, the Baron, is an actual friend of Hitler.
DerFuhrer has been to my house.
To tell you the truth, it's my mother he likes.
She's a famous concert pianist...
and Der Fuhrer, like Horst Drescher,
is a man ofigreat pretensions.
Would you like to meet
Der Fuhrer, Lina?
Um--
Ed Leland says
to tell you hello.
[Linda Narrating] margrete von Eberstien
was no one I was prepared fior.
And now, you must tell me
all about Clark Gable.
Is he really married
to Vivien Leigh?
- [ Giggles ]
- [Linda Narrating]
But we were sisters firom the start.
Ourfiirstjob was to contact my courier...
a fiishmonger who would export any documents,
microfiilm, or written messages...
inside cartons ofifirozen fiish
to Norway.
- That's hi m?
- Ja.
[ Linda ]
How does it work? Ijust go over?
[ margrete ]
Again, use the signal so he'll know who you are.
- Pass a message for practice.
- [ Thunder Rumbles, Distant ]
- What message?
- Anything you like.
[ Linda Narrating]
Forpractice, I wrote a message...
indicating I was looking fior my relatives,
Hannah, Liesel and Sofii Weiss.
- What is that?
- My fam i ly.
- [ Tears Off.Notepaper]
- We heard they're hiding in Berlin.
You're Jewish?
Half.
mein Gott,
you've got guts.
My father calls it chutzpah.
- What is this?
- American spy stuff.
- [Linda Narrating] There was a password.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Something about fiish.
Codfiish.
"Is fresh cod in season?"
Is cod in fresh s-season?
We are closed.
I meant,
is fresh cod in season?
[Siren Blaring, Approaching]
[Siren Continues ]
[ Siren Stops ]
[ Car Door Opens, Closes ]
[men Shouting In German ]
[ Toilet Flushes ]
- Heil Hitler.
Papers?
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
You got this
at the T auschmarkt?
- Yes.
- My wife did too.
- What did you pay for it?
- Um, 40 marks.
You overpaid.
Good for hiding money.
- Heil Hitler.
[ Gasps ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Trolley Bell Clanging ]
[ Whimpering ]
Oh, God!
- I thought they got you.
- The damn purse flew open.
- You're such a dope.
- [ Cries, Laughs ]
- [ Laughing ]
- You're another.
myfiriendship with margrete von Eberstien...
was the closest that I'd ever known.
[ Goodman ]
Didyou wish to stop?
Something happened to her?
She was killed?
We-We can stop fior a bit.
I t's important to tell you that, um,
she introduced me to her mother.
*** [ Piano: Classical]
But, Margrete,
what if she suspects something?
She'll suspect nothing.
All she thinks about is herself.
- But, what if she asks--
- What if? What if?
You'll never see this woman again.
Tomorrowyou're going into the home
ofa total barbarian.
There's not a chance
you will ever see my mother again.
Andyou?
Will Iseeyouagain?
- *** [ Continues ]
- Come. Meet Hitler's favorite piano player.
You'll say I'm your cook?
I want to see her kiss a Jew.
Well, if it isn't my pretty girl.
How nice to see you.
Where haveyou been for so long?
Oh, Mother.
This is my friend from university.
- Lina von Klopper.
- Von Klopper?
Her father is the Baron von Klopper of Pluhn.
You know,
the big castle of Pluhn?
Oh. That von Klopper.
How nice to meet you, my dear.
Mmm. [ Loud Kiss ]
[ Chuckling]
[Linda Narrating]A week aftermyarrival,
Horst Drescher was to give a dinnerparty...
that his chefi
would be unable to attend.
Withjust hours left
befiore the party...
Herr Drescher would fiorego
the required security checks...
into the girl sent to replace him.
The idea being that I would so impress him
with my cooking skills...
that he 'd decide
he couldn 't live without me.
[ Linda ]
No, no, no. That's enough basting.
These have to go into the oven right now.
Oh, my God.
U m, you don't need to
do the stock anymore. Get those--
Help her with those doves
in the oven, please.
Let me taste the soup.
Excuse me.
May I askyou
where the first course is?
We have been seated
for 1 5 minutes.
I'm sorry, Herr Drescher.
The soup is ready right now.
It's supposed to be
cold cucumber soup.
Um, we serve it hot in Dusseldorf.
[ Nervous Laugh ]
The doves aren't cooked yet?
The doves we serve cold.
[ Guests Chattering]
[Woman ]
It's like theyknew we were coming.
Everything was here.
Even toys for the children.
There were linens and towels and,
can you believe, their initials were H.D.?
Like ours?
It was perfect.
Yes, it was perfect,
and so is the food tonight.
For my honored guest
Franze-Otto Dietrich...
a specialtyfirom Dusseldorf..
Hot cucumber soup.
[ Murmuring ]
So, how are the children
enjoying Potsdam?
Not much, I'm afraid.
They miss their friends in Munich.
- Potsdam is so fiaraway.
- Youshouldhave movedinto Berlin.
There's a nice HitlerYouth Corps in Potsdam.
Theywill make new friends.
Theywill. We sawyou on the news fiilms
at Berchtesgarten, Herr Dietrich.
- Yes.
- Hitler was looking well.
I'm so sorry,
Herr Dietrich.
- Clumsy girl.
- Forgive me, mein Herr.
- No matter. No matter.
- It should come out.
- [Woman ] It's onlysoup.
- The color suits me.
It's all right.
- You know, there's a house available
in my neighborhood.
- Yes?
Perf.ect fioryou
and the children.
- The schools are much betterin Berlin.
- So I believe.
My apologies.
She just came today.
Really? Where from?
Uh, Dusseldorf.
I assume she has been
through a security check?
But of course,
Herr Dietrich.
With you here, I can assureyou,
no one would come into this house--
- Just asking.
- Highly recommended.
Good.
[Woman Clears Throat]
[ Loud Swallow ]
Delicious.
[ Forced Chuckle ]
Makes me feel like a wolf. [ Laughs ]
[ German ]
What are you doing out here?
Don't you know it's dangerous?
Wait. Wait. It's me.
The soup?
- He dismissedyou?
- Yes.
- The doves were raw.
- [Dog Barking]
I had no time.
I arrived at 6:00.
And you'll be home by 1 0:00.
Can I drop you?
- [Barking Continues ]
- [Siren Wailing In Distance ]
- Yes.
- Come.
So, where to?
J ust, um, straight on this street.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- [Papers Crinkling]
You're a foreigner.
Fresh from Dusseldorf, yes?
Yes.
You're not really a cook, are you?
The agencies
have done that to me as well.
Sent me two nannies
who knew nothing about children.
Not that mine are easy.
They're mother died twoyears ago.
They are, naturally, upset.
- How many?
- Two.
That's not so many.
My father took care of eight.
With my help, of course.
I was the oldest.
You have an education?
Apparently not enough to cook doves.
[ Laughs ]
He ate the whole thing to prove it was edible.
- [ Laughs ]
- Youshould've seen him.
Pompous little ass.
Eating a raw bird.
You know, it's hard to find
suitable girls...
who've already been through
a complete gestapo check.
I hate to let one get away.
[Linda Narrating]
I vanished that night without a trace.
Unable to let anyone know
what had happened...
or why I'd been whisked away.
But having spotted the documents
in Franze Dietrich 's brieficase...
I had to break my promise
to Ed Leland and stay.
Isolated in a small town
outside the city...
I was cut off.
firom all contact now...
biding my time as a humble German domestic
firom Dusseldorf....
- in a privileged German world.
- Look, Pappi.
- [ Girl] Bye-bye.
- Come on.
[ Linda Narrating ]
As fiar as I was concerned...
it couldn't have been
planned better.
In one quickjump,
I'd landed in the upstairs chambers...
ofione ofithe Third Reich's elite.
A house where names
like Goring, Speer and Von Stauff.enberg...
topped the guest list.
And where, I had no doubt, that infiormation
critical to the German war eff.ort...
was being held.
But no matter how hard I searched,
I could fiind nothing.
Not the brieficase,
nor anything...
even resembling an off.icial document.
Whatever he brought home firom the off.ice
was being hidden...
- and I had no idea where.
- [ Switch Clicks ]
[ Cheeri ng ]
[ Cheering Continues ]
Look there. Dieter.
- Dieter.
- [ Franze ] Dieter.
Be careful now.
H i.
[ Giggles ]
- Franze. Franze. Hello.
- Stafson. What a surprise.
Yes, what a surprise.
Well, hello.
- Hello.
- You know Miss Albrecht? Stafson von Neest.
You know Captain Von Haefler
at the foreign office?
- Von Haefler, nice to meetyou again.
- Oficourse.
You're the one who served the raw ducks.
I was at Drescher's.
Your old employer
wants you back.
You can tell Drescher he's too late.
No, no. It's her employerbefiore that
who wants herback.
- From Dusseldorf?
- No, no. Friedrichs at the foreign office.
The old gentleman? He was all upset.
He thought Drescher had done awaywith her.
Saidshe'dbeen working with him fioryears.
What was his name
from the foreign office?
Konrad Friedrichs.
He's the old gentleman.
[ Crowd Chanting "Sig heil"]
[ Announcer I n German ]
[ Woman Translating]
Where the happy citizens ofiBerlin...
are treated to the sight ofithe fiuhrer...
taking time out
for the Heroes' Day parade.
Where, in a ceremony
at the Sports Palace...
he will watch new recruits
being inducted--
Stop the film.
Stop the film!
Ed. Will. We got it.
His name's Franze-Otto Dietrich.
Right up there in the Wehrmact.
Spent last Christmas
with Hitlerand Eva at Berchtesgarten.
Look, they are definitely together.
She's got her hand on him.
- When was this film taken?
- They came out last week through Lisbon.
- When? When were they taken?
- They're recent.
The parade was just two weeks ago.
- [DoorBuzzes ]
- All right. Contact Sunflower.
Get me into Switzerland.
- What's the plan?
- Get her the hell out ofthere.
[ Goodman ]
Andhadyou anyidea they'd locatedyou?
No. None.
Nor did I know that, um...
Franze Dietrich
had become suspicious of me.
I didsense, however,
that time was running out.
In mid-October, a single British aircraft
made a daring night raid...
shattering the illusion
that Berlin was immune to harm.
Still empty-handed
after fiive weeks...
I risked returning to the fiishmonger
with a note requesting instructions...
and sending a signal homeward
that I was still alive.
[ Bell Tolls ]
But Berlin was changing now.
The night raid fiueling panic
that more bombs were soon to fiall.
[ Boy ]
Al I this way for a fish.
- You'l I l i ke the fish from Berl i n. I prom ise.
- I hate fish.
- [ Girl ] I wanted to go to the zoo.
- I know that.
- You can buy a fish, but I won't eat it.
- All right, all right.
- Here we go. Give meyour hands.
- I mean it.
- I'll throw it away.
- Okay. I heard you. Careful.
[man Speaking German ]
Excuse me.
Can I helpyou?
- Is fresh cod in season?
- Barely.
I'd given up on you.
I thought you didn't like our fish.
She lovesyourfiish.
We're on the bus two hours to get here.
She'd rather come here
than go to the zoo.
It's like this in all the stores today.
People stocking up.
Salting the fish.
Everyone's afraid.
- Come on.
- Ooh, look. Eels.
- See that one.
- Stay right here, okay?
- [ Girl] Ooh, look at that one.
- You were looking for something in particular?
Um, just something fresh.
I mean, last time I saw you,
you were looking for something in particular.
- You found them.
- It's not so easy to find
just a few fish in such a big sea.
They have amazing fight though,
these fish.
Twice the net swept over them,
twice they escaped.
With this kind ofluck,
maybe they are still fresh.
Um--
[ Deep Breath ]
There's a--
a kind offish over here
that I think...
you might wanna
take a look at.
Thereyou are, 2.1 0.
No, no!
- That's my fish.
- No. No.
[ Screams ]
- [ Girl] Lina.
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Yells ]
- Enough. Out.
- Come on, kids.
- Let's go.
- Out.
- [Girl] What happened to the fiish?
- [Boy] Lina?
- What is it?
- Go. Go.
- What happened?
- Was there a fight?
She fights over fish.
She's in love with fish.
- What happened?
- Nothing. Nothing. I'm sorry.
[Linda Narrating] Inside the fiish
was a note that gave the address...
99 Kinderstrasse...
where my relatives were hiding
in a basement on the outskirts ofiBerlin.
And suddenly,
it was no longer a fiantasy.
An address
had made them real.
Hannah, Liesel
and my beautifiul cousin Sofii...
who played the flute
and whose photo I carried...
and had now been fiorced into hiding
somewhere in the darkness nearby.
I wondered ifishe were
in a bed like I was.
Or curled up
on a cold cellar floor.
Ifishe was alone
and firightened...
or ifishe could sense that
the moment ofiour meeting was near.
In the morning after dropping
the children at school...
I'd have just enough time
to make it back and fiorth to the city.
- Berl i n?
- Ja.
Oblivious to any danger,
I was overwhelmed with excitement.
After a lifietime ofidreaming this,
I was fiinally on my way.
Desti nation?
[ Continues In German ]
[ German ]
[ Leland]
A letter firom your sister in Dusseldorf....
sayingyour fiather is dying,
you should come home immediately.
A ticket for tonight's train to Dusseldorf,
which you will not take.
I 'll meet you at the train for Switzerland
where I'll give you a new identification.
- Can I interrupt fiora second?
- Whenyou tell Dietrichyou're leaving...
I want you to tell him about this couple
you met at the market.
- A cook and chauffeur--
- He has a chauffeur.
- Not for long he doesn't.
- Ed, I'm not ready to go. Not tonight.
- I didn't hearyou right, did I?
- I found my cousins.
- Your cousins?
- You found them?
- Somebody help me out here.
- There are noJews left in the city.
Alexanderplatz.
99 Kinderstrasse.
- You've seen them?
- Notyet.
Linda, you can't help them.
There is nothing thatyou can do.
No, butyou can. Papers. Passports.
Tickets to Switzerland.
What the hell you think,
I got a printing press here?
Lina, Friedrichs was picked upyesterday
and questioned by Dietrich.
- Your boss.
- Franze?
Yeah.
Li-Linda, we are on thin ice here.
- We are all on thin ice.
-Just one more day.
- To do what?
- To give them hope.
To let them know
that I'll try to help them.
I won't leave here
without doing this.
This ticket,
it's good for 24 hours.
So are my papers.
They expire tomorrow at 6:00.
I'll wait till then,
but not a minute longer.
Ifyou find out they're alive
and you come to the train...
back to where there are printing presses
and contact with partisans...
we can do something
about getting them out.
But whetheryou find them or not, Linda,
1 800 tomorrow night, I wantyou on that train.
Thankyou.
6:00, Linda.
Ifyou're not there,
I have to leave withoutyou.
I'm sorry, Ed.
It's notyour fault.
I should never have letyou go.
But I had to do this.
That's not what I mean.
I should never have letyou go.
Come out, Linda. Please.
I can't come out now.
Don't stand me up
tomorrow night.
[Linda Narrating] I knowit was on a Friday
that Edand I said good-bye...
because the next day was Saturday...
and I had nowhere
to leave the children.
- [ Boy] What do you want to see?
- I want to see every animal.
- I'd like to see a lion.
- I want to see the bears.
- When do we get there?
- [ Conductor]Alexanderplatz.
Here we go. Come on.
- I don't see it.
- It's the wrong place.
I thought we'd just walk a few blocks.
- What are we doing?
- This isn't the zoo.
- [Door Closes, Lock Clicks ]
- Excuse me.
- We're looking for the zoo.
- Five blocks.
- 99 Kinderstrasse?
- It's the one on the corner.
- [Pigeons Fluttering, Cooing]
- This is scary.
What are we doing?
- You kids wait here.
- Where are you going?
[WaterDripping]
[ Soft Gasp ]
[ Crying ]
[ Sobbing ]
God.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Shaky Breath ]
[AirRaidSiren Wailing]
[Bell Tolling]
Help! Lina!
Lina! Lina!
Quick! Lina!
Lina! Help, Lina!
- It's all right.
- Lina! Help! [ Screams ]
- Get out.
- Get out!
[Siren Continues ]
[Bomb Whistling, Faint ]
- [ Gasps ]
-[Screaming]
[man Shouting]
- Are you all right? Are you okay?
- [ Crying ]
We've got to go home. I n the cellar.
I know a place to hide.
Look! The zoo!
[ Crying ]
- [Woman Crying]
- [man Shouting]
- Pappi.
Pappi. Pappi.
Pappi.
- Pappi, are you all right? Did they bomb you too?
- Where have you been?
- They bombed us.
- A whole building exploded.
- You should've seen it.
- Shh-shh-shh.
- You went in Berlin?
- We went to the zoo.
- You should've asked me.
- Sorry.
Never leave Potsdam again
without asking, please.
Come.
Ifthey come again,
we'll go down toyour secret room.
- Yes. Yes.
- All right? In the cellar.
Yousaidit was safie down there.
Yousaidnobodyknew about it.
- [ Girl] Can we sleep there?
- [Franze ] They won't bomb again.
- They won't come near us.
- It was awfiul, Pappi.
- I thi nk some people were killed.
- You're safe.
That's the important thing.
- [ Door Closes ]
- [ Girl Giggles ]
[ Franze ]
Geisella? Children?
- [ Train Whistle Blows ]
- [ man On P.A., German ]
[ man On P.A. Continues ]
[ Whistles ]
[ Door Creaks ]
Li na.
You weren't i n your room.
I was afraid you might've left us.
Why would I?
Perhaps you'd learned enough.
That's what you are doing, isn't it?
For Herr Himmler and his friends.
For the gestapo?
- The gestapo?
- Infiltrating my house to find out ifl am soft...
on the principles ofthe Reich?
Ifl can be drawn into
confiding my secrets?
On my life,
I am not gestapo.
It's not right that such
a beautiful woman should labor.
I have no choice.
Doyou have a dress for evening?
No.
Von Karajan is playing Wagner.
A celebration of our courage.
You will wear
a dress of mywife's...
and sit beside me
tomorrow night.
***[Classical]
My God. That's Olga Leiner.
Doyou know her?
- Who?
- Olga Leiner. Look.
Yes. She's waving atyou.
She must mistake me for someone.
**** [ Opera ]
*** [ Continues ]
*** [Ends ]
Lina. Lina, right?
Oh.
[ Loud Kiss ]
So nice to see
a familiar face.
Seems like no one I know
is left in the city.
[ Clears Throat ]
Fraulina.
I'm Franze Dietrich, a great admirer.
- Oh.
- You know Miss Albrecht?
Yes. She went to university
with my daughter.
You must come up to the apartment
again sometime...
and bringyour charming firiend.
And ifyou see my pretty girl--
[ Kisses ] tell her to call me.
I 'm sorry.
I couldn't get them to their beds.
- They wanted to wait foryou.
- Thankyou. Good night.
Goodnight.
Good night.
[DoorOpens, Closes ]
I'll take them upstairs.
Herr Dietrich.
It's late, Lina.
Too late for talking.
- [Franze ] Lina.
- [ Girl] Lina.
[Franze ]
Lina? Lina?
[Doorbell Buzzes ]
[ Banging On Door]
- [Panting]
- Go away. I was already called by the gestapo.
They're coming here.
Go to margrete's. Hide fior the night...
- or you'll kill us all.
- [Light Clicks Off.]
[Sets Brake ]
[ Ringing ]
Hello? Yeah.
My God, where are you?
They're combing the whole city foryou.
Look outyour front window.
Come up.
[ Coin Box Rattling ]
- Come, quickly.
- [ Whimpers ]
- Areyou all right?
- Yeah.
- [ Crying ]
- It's okay.
- You're blue.
- I'm cold.
Come.
You don't know how worried I've been.
- Friedrichs called me.
- He turned me away.
He had no choice.
Theywere watching him.
Here, what I wantyou to do
is get out ofthose clothes...
run some hot bathwater, take a hot bath
while we think ofwhat to do with you.
- Margrete--
- Maybe changeyour looks. Cutyour hair.
- You need papers.
Margrete.
I got the information.
On microfilm.
The location ofthe factory.
- It's in Peenemunde.
- Good.
- [ Exhales ]
- Very good.
And where is the microfiilm?
I hid it.
I wanted to make sure you were alone.
- Where?
- Outside. The phone booth. The coin box is loose.
- One right here?
- Yeah.
Good. I'll get it.
Run a hot bath, cutyour hair.
There are scissors.
- [DoorCloses ]
- [ Gasps ]
[Footsteps AscendingStairs ]
Lina, I pretended to make a call...
so no one would be suspicious
of my being out there.
[WaterRunning]
- [ Groans ]
- Oh, God. Forgive me.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Forgive me.
- [ Crying ]
They'll be here soon.
I'll make sure theytake care ofiyou.
- [ Groans ]
- Oh, Lina. A bad way for us to end.
Why now?
Why didn't you turn me in before?
We've been watching Dietrich.
When you blundered into his house, we thought
we could useyou to feed me information.
Ifhe was loyal.
Oh.
My cousins.
[ Sobbing ]
I'm sorry.
I work for the Reich.
And I confess, except foryou...
I have no use forJews.
[ Yelling ]
- [ Panting, Crying ]
- [Sirens Wailing]
[ Crying ]
[ Shouting Orders, German ]
- [men Shouting]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
[ Panting, Whimpering ]
[ German ]
[ Friedrichs ]
She's got to be in the building.
She wouldn't have lasted
this long on the street.
Look at this.
How do we get into the basement?
[Lina Groans ]
- [ Groans ]
- Sorry. Easy. Easy. Easy.
Okay.
This is for the pain.
You have to forget
about the pain.
I need you to do
the talking for me. Okay?
Put your arm on my shoulder. Okay?
Let's go.
[Bell Tolling]
[Brakes Squealing]
Can't go any further.
They'd recognize me before they do her.
Good luck.
[ Train Whistle Blares ]
[ man On P.A., Indistinct ]
- Hi.
Am I dying?
Forget about dying.
You're not allowed to die.
I've never seen you
look scared before.
I don't wanna lose you.
I wanna be with you...
always.
Oh, God.
You wouldn't say that
unless you were sure I was gonna die.
[ Chuckles ]
I loveyou.
[ Conductor]
Linda.
Linda!
- [Banging]
- [ Conductor]
Okay. Let's go.
Halt!
[Linda Narrating] It surprised no one
that Ed was too stubborn to die.
With one bullet
that shattered his knee...
and another that
punctured his lung...
he was conscious enough to hear news reports
ofithe bombing ofiPeenemunde...
Just 1 4 days later.
So you did get the microfiilm out?
Yes.
I t was discovered
cl utched i n my hand...
when I was brought to the hospital
in Switzerland.
I'd hidden it in my glove...
knowing that it would be removed
ifl were examined by a doctor...
and overlooked
ifl were searched by an enemy.
Very clever.
How-How did you know that?
Did you ever see a movie
called Victoryat Dawn?
[Laughs ]
I should've known.
[ Clapping]
[ Laughing ]
Those are my sons.
Can I get them on TV?
Oficourse.
We'd be delighted.
There's myhusband.
[ Giggles ]
Ed. Come.
Come here.
- [Applause Continues, Whistles ]
- Help me.
mr. Leland.
Thankyou both very, very much.
*** [ Big Band]
*** [ Woman Singing Swing Slow ]
*** [ Band]
*** [ Woman Singing Resumes ]
*** [ Ends ]