[wind howling]
♫ ♫
[flames roaring]
[screaming]
[screaming fades]
♫ ♫
[explosions]
[men shouting]
[moans softly]
[explosion]
You all right?
Well, I think your partner over
there bought it.
Can you get your shovel out?
Come on, Pike,
you can do it.
[grunting]
You understand me?
How you doing, Pike?
So far, so good.
Oh, fuck.
Keep moving.
[explosion]
[cocks gun]
[Deming whispers]
I'm dead.
Look, I'm not waiting
for someone to show up.
Keep going!
A compass, something?
♫ ♫
(girl) The world is so
beautiful, Losey, isn't it?
I'm okay;
don't worry about me.
[faint voices]
[men speaking German]
They're lost too.
[girl screaming]
[cocks gun]
Uh-uh.
Hey.
[children laughing]
(girl) I'll be I can stay
down longer than you.
On your feet,
soldier.
[dog growling]
[woman speaking French]
[school bell rings]
[explosion
and children screaming]
You find anything?
And start walking.
Don't say I never
gave you nothing, sad sack.
Pretty stripped.
(Losey) Well, at least
they were close to God.
Man, and its hero
the conqueror worm."
and I had to have my teacher
explain it to me.
[faint voices]
[glass shatters]
[gunfire and people screaming]
[explosions and gunfire]
[woman screaming]
All little boys are pyros.
Ahh!
No, stop!
We'll tie him up,
and we'll look around.
[struggling]
All right, you first.
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[chuckles]
♫ ♫
(Deming) Hey, quit your
squawking, and keep on walking.
(Deming)
Better tell him no snacks.
♫ ♫
[laughs]
Eyes open,
mouth shut.
I love you.
Of course I'll marry you.
Now things are back
the way they should be.
Let's go
find our man-eater.
♫ ♫
[horse neighs]
[horse chuffing]
Where'd you come from, huh?
Hey, help me up.
[horse snorting]
Whoa, whoa.
Fucker's shot to shit,
though, isn't it?
I'm going there.
[door squeaks]
Okay.
(Deming)
Four-star hotel.
[girl laughing]
[girl whispering]
I will never leave you.
[faint voice singing]
[humming]
Come here.
Something beautiful.
I don't even know
if it was there.
Yelling my name,
begging me to fuck her.
You ever had horse meat,
Losey?
Kid, we got company.
He's got a rifle.
Shit.
Don't panic yet.
(Deming)
Let's move.
Deming,
take it easy.
Ah!
[chuckles]
Take all of it off.
Down, down.
[shouting in French]
I promise you.
I'll never leave you.
[rattling]
There will
be a show.
[imitates engine revving]
We don't even know where we are.
With the respect
that you deserve!
Wait.
American.
They all look
a little fucked up.
Asshole!
♫ ♫
[children laughing]
(boy)
No, daddy, leave me alone.
Man, and its hero
the conqueror worm."
♫ ♫
[thunder rumbling]
[giggling]
[horse neighing]
[children whispering]
[woman speaking French]
[speaking French]
[tanks rumbling]
[door creaks]
Oh!
Ow!
[screaming]
I'll fight.
Cut me loose!
We can't run anymore.
Upstairs.
Oh, shit.
So now the Krauts
have tracked you here.
Hurry!
Get under there,
quick.
[cocks gun]
[door creaks]
[man speaking German]
[speaking German]
[child breathing shakily]
[door slams]
[glass shattering]
[gasping]
[door creaking]
(Deming) Why don't they
just storm the place?
We'll take care of it.
[boy screaming]
[child whimpering]
[speaking German]
(man)
Smoke!
[all coughing]
I'm coming with you.
[speaking German]
How long can you
hold your breath?
[gunshots]
Shit.
Get down.
I'll go find him.
[gunfire]
[laughing]
[explosion]
[grunting]
No.
[crying]
Five minutes to decide
if you live or die.
The time has come.
I hope that you are hearing me
and understanding.
Four minutes.
This place
is rubble.
I'm real glad that asshole
can tell time.
It's just grown-ups
playing a game.
[explosion]
Ah!
Oh!
[crying]
Stupid old fucker.
♫ ♫
[men shouting in German]
[men screaming]
[men shouting]
[shouting in German]
Was?
Das ist ein Kind gewesen?
[moaning]
Just go!
♫ ♫
[grunts softly]
[gasps]
[laughs]
You.
You're beautiful.
Death is coming.
[men shouting]
(Losey)
Here they come; here they come.
[flames sizzling]
Yes!
This is it, motherfucker;
this is it!
[gunfire]
[gunshots and glass shattering]
I'm out!
Keep your head down.
[men screaming]
[explosions]
[men shouting in German]
Downstairs, now!
I got to have more ammo!
[glass shattering]
(Losey)
Deming, where are you?
Ah!
♫ ♫
Move it;
move it.
Ah!
♫ ♫
Uhh.
[rapid gunshots]
Ah!
[gunshots]
Come on.
(girl)
No!
[crying]
[girl screams]
[giggling]
[gunshots]
They think this war is a game.
[men speaking German]
Yeah.
[giggling]
[man's voice shouting angrily]
♫ ♫
Follow it to the woods;
you'll make it.
Who I am.
I'll make it.
Quit squawking,
and start walking.
Go!
Come on.
Ahh!
Come and get me!
[explosion]
♫ ♫
She's beautiful.
You're beautiful.
If you just look at it right.
[birds chirping]
(girl)
I'll never leave you.