[TN]
BENJAMIN: / have long feared
that my sins would return
to visit me.
And the cost ¡s more
than I can bear.
[TN]
[HOOVES CLOMPING]
Samuel! A postrider!
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
An IIRIII.
Good.
What about this one?
[TN]
Thank you. You're welcome.
Father! Father!
BENJAMIN: Nine pounds, eleven ounces.
That's perfect. Perfect.
Father, a postrider!
Did you finish planting
the south field?
More than half.
Those swimming breaks really cut
into the day, don't they?
Told you.
GABRIEL: Thomas.
Wait for Father.
[SIGHS]
[CREAKS]
[CRACKS]
[GRUNTS]
Sorry.
[TN]
MARGARET:
That's her. The North Star.
See?
You start from the front two stars
of the Big Dipper.
And then you count up.
You count up five finger lengths
and it's right there.
And she'll always be
looking down on us.
And protect us. Forever.
Come. Into bed.
Good night. Good night, Meg.
It helps her to know Mother's there.
Good night.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
[CLINKING]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
So what was in the mail?
"The New York and
Pennsylvania assemblies
are debating independence."
What about the middle colonies?
"In Chestertown,
they burned the customs house"
and tar and feathered
two magistrates.
"They died of... They died of burns."
Damn fools.
Who? The writers or the magistrates?
Uh, what does it say about
the Continental Congress?
It says here they'll make a
declaration of independence by July.
[TN]
[MOUTHING]
Peter Cuppin
joined the Continentals.
He's 17, a year younger than I.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Well, the assembly's been convened,
so I've been called to Charles Town.
We're going to Charles Town?
We are.
We leave in the morning.
[TN]
Yah. Yah.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING
AND CHATTERING]
Charlotte.
The children are here.
Thank you.
[GIGGLING]
CHILDREN:
Aunt Charlotte! Aunt Charlotte!
Margaret, William, look at you.
WILLIAM: Missed you.
They're huge.
What have you been feeding them?
Well, they're from good stock.
On their mother's side, of course.
Thank you. Come inside.
Wait until you see what I have.
CHILDREN:
Presents? Presents for us?
Move slowly.
You two, keep an eye
on these heathens, will you?
Hey, Thomas! Oh!
Oh. Sorry.
I have this for you, Susan.
It belonged to your mother.
She's still not talking?
No.
It does me good to see you.
[C ROWD ROARI NG]
[FLUTE PLAYS "YANKEE DOODLE"]
Look, there's Gabriel.
THOMAS: Gabriel.
MAN 1: Hang King George!
Harry Burwell is here recruiting.
The governor has vowed if the
assembly votes a single shilling
to the Continental Army,
he'll dissolve the body.
Wouldn't that force our delegates in
Philadelphia to vote for independence?
Yes.
Send us off to war alongside
Massachusetts.
MAN 1: Get King George!
MAN 2: Hang them all!
MAN 1: Hang the lot of them!
That's enough.
Very well, children, inside.
Come along now. Inside now.
Burwell will be counting on
your vote.
And he'll expect you
to be the first to enlist.
Yes, I imagine so.
[GLASS SHATTERS]
I'm sorry, the heathens are...
They have long needed
a woman in their lives.
A mother.
Especially Susan.
[MEN CHATTERING]
My name is Peter Howard.
I lost most of my hearing
and my left leg
fighting for the Crown
in the French and Indian War.
And how did King George
reward me?
He cuts off my other leg
with his taxes.
[CLEARS TH ROAT]
Miss Howard, isn't it?
You know who I am, Gabriel Martin.
The last time you saw me,
I was 11 and you put ink in my tea.
Oh, I believe that was one of my younger brothers.
Perhaps Samuel or Nathan.
It was you, and it turned
my teeth black for a month.
I, uh...
PETER:... and send a message to
King George he will never forget!
Our first order of business...
And our last, if we vote a levy!
JUDGE: Order, order!
Mr. Simms,
you do not have the floor.
Our first order of business will be, an address
by Colonel Harry Burwell of the Continental Army.
Colonel Burwell.
BURWELL:
You all know why I'm here.
I'm not an orator.
And I would not try to convince you
of the worthiness of our cause.
I'm a soldier.
And we are at war.
From Philadelphia, we expect
a declaration of independence.
Eight of the 13 colonies have
levied money
in support of a continental army.
I ask that South Carolina
be the ninth.
Massachusetts and Virginia
may be at war,
but South Carolina is not!
Hear, hear.
This is not a war for the independence
of one or two colonies,
but for the independence
of one nation.
And what nation is that?
An American nation!
There is no such nation
and to speak of one is treason.
We are citizens
of an American nation.
And our rights are being threatened
by a tyrant 3000 miles away.
Would you tell me, please,
Mr. Howard,
why should I trade one tyrant
3000 miles away
for 3000 tyrants one mile away?
[LAUGHING]
An elected legislature can trample
a man's rights as easily as a king can.
BURWELL: Captain Martin,
I understood you to be a patriot.
If you mean by "patriot," am I angry
about taxation without representation?
Well, yes, I am.
Should the American colonies
govern themselves independently?
I believe they can. And they should.
But if you're asking me am I willing
to go to war with England,
well, then the answer is
most definitely no.
[CHATTERING]
This from the same Captain Benjamin
Martin whose fury was so famous
during the Wilderness campaign?
I was intemperate in my youth.
Temperance can be
a convenient disguise for fear.
Mr. Middleton, I fought
with Captain Martin
under Washington
in the French and Indian War.
There's not a man in this room
or anywhere for that matter, to whom
I would more willingly trust my life.
MEN: Hear, hear.
There are alternatives to war.
We take our case before the king.
We plead with him.
Yes, we tried that.
Well, then, we try again and again
if necessary to avoid a war.
Benjamin, I was at Bunker Hill.
The British advanced three times.
We killed over 700 of them at point-blank
range and still they took the ground.
That is the measure
of their resolve.
If your principles dictate
independence,
then war is the only way.
It is come to that.
MEN: Hear, hear.
I have seven children.
My wife is dead.
Now, who's to care for them
if I go to war?
Wars are not fought
only by childless men.
Granted.
But mark my words.
This war will be fought,
not on the frontier,
or on some distant battlefield,
but amongst us.
Among our homes.
Our children will learn of it
with their own eyes.
And the innocent will die
with the rest of us.
I will not fight.
And because I will not fight,
I will not cast a vote
that will send others to fight
in my stead.
And your principles?
I'm a parent. I haven't got
the luxury of principles.
[TN]
MAN: We must vote to levy!
[SHOUTING]
[CLEARS TH ROAT]
Twenty-eight to 12!
The levy passed!
[CHEERING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[TN]
You intend to enlist
without my permission?
Yes, I do.
Father, I thought you were
a man of principle.
When you have a family of your own,
perhaps you'll understand.
When I have a family of my own,
I won't hide behind them.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
He's as imprudent as his father was
at his age.
Regrettably so.
I'll see to it that he
serves under me.
Make him a clerk or quartermaster,
something of that sort.
Good luck.
[TN]
GABRIEL: Dear Thomas: Though
many seasons have passed,
¡t seems like only yesterday when we
last saw each other in Charles Town.
It was with great sadness that I learned
of ¡ts recent fall to the British
under General Cornwallis.
I received a letter
from Aunt Charlotte
saying she closed her home
in Charles Town after the city fell
and moved to her plantation
on the Santee.
[COMMANDER SHOUTING]
GABRIEL: Here in the north, our campaign
has been marked by defeat and privation.
Our losses have been grievous.
My good friend, Peter Cuppin,
fell at Elizabethtown.
No!
GABRIEL:
His death has been difficult to bear.
We are told that soon we will
march south with General Gates
to fight the Redcoats
under Cornwall¡s.
Thank you, sir.
[TN]
I envy you
your youth and distance from this
cruel conflict of which I am a part.
"But I consider myself fortunate
to be serving the cause of Liberty."
And though I fear death,
each day in prayer I reaffirm
my willingness, if necessary,
to give my life in its service.
Pray for me.
But above all, pray for the cause.
"Your loving brother, Gabriel."
What are you doing?
Turn around.
Not yet, Thomas.
When?
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Seventeen.
That's two years.
It's already been two.
The war could be over by then.
God willing.
All right. Seventeen.
All right.
Put it back, please.
Father?
What happened at Fort Wilderness?
Put it away.
WILLIAM: Throw it faster.
SAMUEL:
You throw it faster. You're the one...
[GRUNTING]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
Whoa.
[LAUGHING]
Margaret, you go get your brothers
back up here right now.
[TN]
Back to the house. Come on.
Back to the house now.
Come with me. Margaret, go now.
They're going to come.
Quiet. Sit down.
[DISTANT BOOMING]
[TN]
Six-pounders.
Lots of them.
How far away?
Oh, they're a long way off. They're most
likely heading the other direction.
Put those in the house.
THOMAS: They might come this way.
Thomas, must I tell you again?
Let's all stay close in to the house,
all right?
[LOUDER BOOMING]
[PANTING]
We're gonna have to fight them off.
Won't Father do that?
They'll probably kill us men...
and do Lord-knows-what
to you women.
Nathan.
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[GUN COCKS]
Slowly turn.
GABRIEL: Father.
[GRUNTING]
Abigale!
Water and bandages, fast.
Ah!
Easy.
The battle. Were you there?
Have you seen any Redcoats?
No, not yet.
Abigale, the children, please.
Children, come. Upstairs.
[GROANING]
GABRIEL: Gates marched us
straight at the Redcoats.
Our lines broke. The British
Green Dragoons cut us to bits.
I was given these dispatches.
As I left, I saw
the Virginia Regulars surrender.
The Dragoons rode into them.
Killed them all.
Over 200 men.
[EXHALES SHARPLY] I have to get
these dispatches to Hillsborough.
You're in no condition to ride.
I can't stay here!
It's not safe for...
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING]
[CANNONS BOOMING]
MAN: Fire!
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
[TN]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[CHATTERING]
[GROANING]
[TN]
Thank you for the care
of His Majesty's soldiers.
[RIDERS APPROACH]
[TN]
Lieutenant, have a detachment take our
wounded to our surgeons at Winnsboro.
LIEUTENANT: Yes, sir.
Fire the house and barns.
Let it be known if you harbour the
enemy you will lose your home.
By standing order
of His Majesty King George,
all slaves of the American colonies
who fight for the Crown
will be granted their freedom
with our victory.
Sir.
We're not slaves. We work this land.
We're freedmen.
Well, then you're freedmen who will
have the opportunity and the privilege
of fighting in the king's army
aren't you?
Rebel dispatches, sir.
Who carried this?
Who carried this?!
I did, sir.
I was wounded.
These people gave me care.
They have nothing to do
with the dispatches.
Take this one to Camden.
He is a spy.
Hang him, put his body on display.
He's a dispatch rider
and that's a marked case.
Destroy the livestock.
Save the horses for the Dragoons.
Colonel, this is a uniformed dispatch
rider carrying a marked case.
He cannot be held as a spy.
Well, we're not going to hold him.
We're going to hang him.
Colonel... Father!
Oh, I see. He's your son.
Perhaps you should've taught him
something of loyalty.
Colonel, I beg you, please reconsider.
By the rules of war...
"Rules of war"? Would you like a
lesson, sir, in the rules of war?
Or perhaps your children would.
[GASPING]
No lesson is necessary.
LIEUTENANT: Sir.
What of the rebel wounded?
Kill them.
Father.
Father, do something!
Be quiet!
[TN]
Gabriel, run! Thomas!
Wait!
No!
Thomas.
[CHOKING]
[TN]
Stupid boy.
Captain.
WILLIAM: Thomas!
[GROANING]
[TN]
Come, child.
I'm not leaving these children!
Mercy!
MAN: Get ready!
Present!
Fire!
[PANTING]
All of you, stay here.
[TN]
Nathan, Samuel.
Margaret.
I want you to hide in the fields
with William and Susan.
If we're not back by sunset, I want you
to take them to your Aunt Charlotte's.
Is that clear? Yeah.
Boys.
[TN]
It's a good spot.
Boys, listen to me.
I'll fire first.
I want you two to start with the
officers and work your way down.
Can you tell the difference?
Yes, Father.
Yes, Father. Good.
Samuel, after your first shot,
I want you to reload for Nathan.
Now,
if anything should happen to me,
I want you two to drop your weapons
and I want you to run
as quickly as you can.
Hide in the brush. Make your way home,
get your brother and your sisters
and you take them to
your Aunt Charlotte's. Understood?
What did I tell you fellas
aboutshooüng?
TOGETHER:
Aim small, miss small.
Boys“.
Samuel...
steady.
Lord, make me fast and accurate.
Aim small, miss small.
REDCOAT 1: On the right!
REDCOAT 2: To the left!
Ugh!
REDCOAT 3: Behind us! On the ridge!
Form right!
To the right!
About face!
Ugh!
REDCOAT 4:
On the right to the rear!
To the right!
Fire!
MAN 4: Reload! MAN 5: Reload!
Ah!
REDCOAT 5: Behind you!
REDCOAT 5: Look on the rear!
Ah!
[TN]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[TN]
[GRUNTING]
Ah!
[YELLING]
[TN]
BENJAMIN: Lord,
we pray that you accept this child
and keep him at your side
with his mother.
We ask that you embrace him
and help us to understand the manner
in which your mercy works.
And forgive us our sins.
This we ask in your name.
Amen.
BORDON: Sir, we have the private
the Cherokee scouts brought in.
Private?
BORDON: Private.
Colonel William Tavington,
Green Dragoons.
What happened? Who did this?
Him.
It was mad.
I couldn't tell you who it was.
Calm down. Calm down, man.
Twenty of His Majesty's soldiers
are dead.
And I need to know how.
He said there was...
Were you there?
Then let him speak.
Take your time and tell me.
How many were there?
Were they militia?
Were they Regulars?
I don't really remember how many.
Maybe one.
One man. Really?
He was in the flank.
All around us.
Amongst us.
I could barely see him.
He was there, and then he was gone.
He just vanished.
Sounds more like a ghost
than a man.
Yes. A ghost.
He was like a ghost.
Enough.
Bordon? Take a patrol.
See if we can't capture this ghost
before word of his exploits spread.
Who's this?
Sir, this is Captain Wilkins.
He was with the Loyalist
Colonial Militia.
I thought he might be of use.
Another colonial.
Tell me, Captain Wilkins,
where do your loyalties lie?
To king and country, sir.
Why should I trust a man
who'd betray his neighbours?
Those neighbours of mine
who stand against England
deserve to die a traitor's death.
We'll see.
Mr. Martin!
WOMAN: Miss Charlotte!
CHARLOTTE:
You're safe now. Try to sleep.
Good night.
NATHAN: Father?
BENJAMIN: Yes.
I killed those men.
You did what I told you to do.
You did what you had to.
There was no wrong in it.
I'm glad I killed them.
I'm glad.
Get some rest.
Samuel.
[TN]
You've done nothing for which
you should be ashamed.
I've done nothing.
And for that, I am ashamed.
[TN]
We'll go to Saint Helena.
That's a free slave island
just north of Charles Town.
We'll be right under
the British noses.
They won't even think of looking...
I'm joining up with them.
Gabriel.
No. Your place is here now.
I'm going back.
I'm a soldier, it's my duty.
Your duty is to your family.
Don't you walk away from me, boy!
I'm sorry,
I'll find you when it's over.
No, you're not going.
I forbid you to go!
I'm not a child!
You're my child!
Goodbye, Father.
Gabriel.
Thomas is dead.
How many more have to die
before you'll heed my word?
[TN]
Yah, yah.
I'm losing my family.
When will you be back, Father?
I don't know.
Tomorrow?
No, not tomorrow.
You say your prayers.
I will.
Nathan, I want you to take care of your
brothers and sisters and your Aunt Charlotte.
I'm depending on you.
As I am on you, Samuel.
All right.
Susan”.
Goodbye_.
Thank you.
[TN]
[WHINNIES]
Yah! Yah!
[BOOMING]
[MEN SHOUTING]
[TN]
MAN: Halt!
Make ready!
Take aim!
Fire!
[SCREAMING]
I'm not going back.
No, I didn't expect you would.
That Gates is a damn fool.
He spent too many years
in the British army.
Going muzzle-to-muzzle with Redcoats
in open field. It's madness.
MAN: Halt!
Make ready!
Present!
Fire!
[SCREAMING]
[SIGHS]
This battle was over
before it began.
MAN: Retreat!
Retreat!
These rustics are so inept.
Nearly takes the honour
out of victory.
Nearly.
Hello general, gentlemen.
A glorious day
for His Majesty and England.
CORNWALLIS: Colonel Tavington.
Always too early.
Always too eager for glory.
For Victory, my lord.
I believe we took the field.
Next time, you'll wait
for my command.
It appears that Colonel Tavington
prefers to follow his own commands.
General O'Hara tells me
you've earned the nickname
"The Butcher" among the populous.
We'll discuss it tomorrow.
Gentlemen, my compliments.
To a victory. MAN: Hear, hear.
DOCTOR: Hold him firm.
[MEN SCREAMING]
BENJAMIN:
Where's your commanding officer?
SOLDIER: That tent there.
It's a lost cause.
[TN]
BURWELL: Benjamin Martin.
I'm in no mood for a lecture.
Where's your General Gates now?
The last anyone saw,
riding hard northeast,
his staff 100 yards behind,
trying to catch up.
So who's in command?
I am.
I think.
What are my orders?
We're a breath away from losing
this war, Benjamin.
In the north, Washington
is reeling from Morristown.
He's running and hiding
from 12,000 Redcoats.
In the south, Cornwallis
has broken our back.
Captured over 5000 of our troops
when he took Charles Town.
And he destroyed the only army
between him and New York.
So now there's nothing to stop him from
heading north to finish off Washington.
Unless we can keep Cornwallis
in the south till the French arrive.
They've promised a fleet
and 10,000 troops.
When?
Uh, six months at the earliest.
You actually trust the French
to keep their word?
VILLENEUVE: Absolument.
BURWELL: Benjamin Martin.
Major Jean Villeneuve.
French Seventh Light Foot.
He's here to help train the militia.
The hero of Fort Wilderness.
Your reputation precedes you.
You really expect to hold
Cornwallis here using just militia?
Not me. You.
Harry, they're not soldiers,
they're farmers.
They'd be better off letting
the British just march through.
They'd be better off,
but the cause wouldn't.
How many men does Cornwallis have
under his command?
Eight thousand infantry.
Around 600 cavalry.
I'm giving you a field Commission
as a colonel.
Might I request, sir, that you
transfer my son here under my command?
Sir, no, I... No.
That's done.
Thank you.
Colonel, I've been a soldier now
for two years.
As a scout, horseman,
marksman, scavenger.
Is that so? Yes, sir.
I'd be of better use with Regulars.
Where'd you learn all that riding,
shooting, scavenging?
My father taught me.
Teach you any humility?
He tried. It didn't take.
He also taught you every deer path and
swamp trail between here and Charles Town,
which is why he asked
for your transfer.
We'll put the word out.
Start on the south side of...
We can cover more ground
if we split up.
Very well, corporal. You take
Harrisville, Pembroke, Wakefield.
I'll start on the north side. We'll
meet at the mission in Black Swamp.
Yes, sir.
BENJAMIN: And corporal...
be careful.
Yes, sir.
[SIGHS]
You have children?
French.
[TN]
It skirts the mountain and then extends
down towards the headwater here
and right across to the far bank
of the Ohio River.
It's 100,000 acres.
It's an imposing land grant, my lord.
You will be a country unto yourself.
His Majesty is most generous.
Though, of course, your service in this
war more than warrants such a gift.
Yes, this is how His Majesty
rewards those
who fight for him as gentlemen.
I dare to presume my own meagre
Contributions will be rewarded one day.
You may presume too much.
His Majesty, like history, judges us
not only by the outcome of the war
but the manner in which
it was fought.
My lord? We serve the Crown,
and we must conduct ourselves
accordingly.
Surrendering troops
will be given quarter.
These brutal tactics must stop.
Is it not enough that I have
never lost a battle?
You serve me,
and the manner in which you
serve me reflects upon me!
I would've thought that a gentleman
from a family as esteemed as yours
would understand that.
My late father squandered any esteem
in which we were held,
along with my inheritance.
I advance myself
only through Victory.
You advance yourself
only through my good graces.
These Colonials are our brethren.
And when this conflict is over, we
will reestablish commerce with them.
Do you understand, colonel?
Perfectly, my lord.
[CHURCH CHOIR SINGS]
Reverend, with your permission,
I'd like to make an announcement.
Young man, this is a house of God.
I understand that, reverend.
I apologize.
The South Carolina Militia
is being called up.
I'm here to enlist every man willing.
REVEREND: Son,
we are here to pray
for the souls of those men
hanging outside.
Yes, pray for them.
But honour them
by taking up arms with us.
And bring more suffering
to this town?
If King George can hang those men, our
friends, he can hang any one of us.
Dan Scott,
barely a week ago, I heard you rail
for two hours about independence.
[CHATTERING]
Mr. Hardwick, how many times
have I heard you
speak of freedom
at my father's table?
Half the men in this church,
including you, Father,
and you, reverend,
are as ardent patriots as I.
Will you now, when you are
needed most, stop at only words?
Is that the sort of men you are?
[TN]
I ask only that you act
upon the beliefs
of which you have
so strongly spoken,
and in which you
so strongly believe.
Who's with us?
[TN]
Mr. Howard.
Sir,
may I have permission
to write to Anne?
Eh?
May I have permission to write Anne?
ANNE: Yes.
You have permission
to write me.
Oh, write her.
Very well.
Thank you, sir.
Reverend?
A shepherd must tend his flock.
And, at times, fight off the wolves.
[TN]
[MEN SHOUTING AND LAUGHING]
Are you sure this is the right place
to recruit for a militia?
God save King George!
[MEN YELLING]
I think we came to the right place.
Any bounty?
BENJAMIN:
No scalp money this time, Rollins.
But you can keep or sell me the muskets
and gear of any Redcoat you kill.
They hanged my brother
down in Acworth.
Every damned one of them Redcoats
deserves to die.
Sign on up.
With all my ailments,
I wouldn't make it through
the first skirmish. No, sir.
But you can have my Negro.
He'll fight in my stead.
Occam! Get over here.
He ain't overly smart.
He's strong as a bull.
Can you write?
No, no, sir.
Well, then, make your mark.
OLD MAN: Why?
I just signed him over to you.
If you're willing,
I'd like you to make your mark.
That'll do.
I'll kill me some Redcoats.
I believe you would.
How old are you?
BILLINGS: Not quite old enough.
But his time will come.
John Billings.
I was hoping you'd turn up.
There's a story going around
about some 20 Redcoats
got killed by a ghost
or some damn thing.
Carried a Cherokee tomahawk.
Aren't you a little old to be
believing in ghost stories?
[MEN CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
[TN]
How many did you get?
Twelve.
Good.
These men,
they're not the sort we need.
They're exactly the sort we need.
They've fought
this kind of war before.
What about me?
Am I one of that sort?
Hell, no.
You're the sort that gives that sort
a bad name.
I want accuracy and precision.
Make ready!
Take aim!
Fire!
[SCREAMING]
[TN]
GABRIEL: Dear Anne:
Our force continues to grow.
As long as we continue to fight,
others will come to fight beside us.
I long to see you and speak to you.
I'm hopeful that our duties
will bring me near you.
Until then, I am and will remain
most affectionately yours.
Gabriel.
[TN]
[GUNSHOT]
[SCREAMING] [WHINNYING]
Go!
REDCOAT:
We surrender! We surrend...! Ah!
REVEREND: No! God, stop!
For the love of God, we...
These men were about to surrender!
VILLENEUVE: Perhaps.
We will never know.
This is murder!
Hell, reverend, they're Redcoats.
They've earned it.
We are better men than that.
What do you know about war?
I know the difference
between fighting...
MAN: You go back to church!
Quiet!
He's right.
In the future, full quarter will be given
to British wounded and any who surrender.
The British men of war
gave no such quarter
when they fired on a ship
carrying my wife and daughters.
I watched from 200 yards off
as they were burned alive.
You have my sympathy,
but my order stands.
Damn your sympathy.
Who are you to give such an order?
I know what you and your men did
to my countrymen at Fort Wilderness.
We're militia.
This is not regular army.
Every man here is free
to come and go as he pleases.
But while you're here,
you will obey my command
or I will have you shot.
[BARKING] Damn dogs!
Shoot the damn things!
Stay that pistol.
They won't let anybody
near the wagon.
DAN: Rum, Madeira.
BILLINGS:
No wonder they were guarding it.
Officers' uniforms.
MAN: What you think all this is worth?
It's the personal correspondence
of Lord Cornwallis.
This is his journal.
I say we drink the wine, eat the dogs
and use the papers for musket wadding.
Eat the dogs?
TOGETHER: Yeah.
Dog is a fine meal. Uh-huh.
Good heavens.
[MUSIC PLAYS AND MEN SING]]
BOY:
I have some maps here for you.
Put them down over there.
Thank you.
Here. A proper musket for you.
I don't know about you, but I don't like
the idea of giving muskets to slaves.
[MEN LAUGH]
Your sense of freedom
is as pale as your skin.
GABRIEL: Don't listen to them.
If we win this war,
a lot of things will change.
What will change?
They call this the New World.
It's not. It's the same as the old.
But we'll have a chance
to build a new world.
A world where all men
are created equal under God.
EquaL.
Sounds good.
I've just been in the mind
of a genius.
Cornwallis knows more about warfare than we
could hope to learn in a dozen lifetimes.
That's cheerful news.
His victories at Camden and
Charles Town were perfect. Perfect.
And he knows it, what's more.
Perhaps that's his weakness.
Sir?
Pride.
Pride's a weakness.
Personally, I would prefer stupidity.
Pride will do.
[TN]
[CHATTERING]
Finished, my lord.
I've taken it in at the back,
added wider epaulets
and looped gold braiding.
It's a horse blanket.
TAVINGTON: I don't know, my lord.
It's really quite nice.
Very nice, my lord.
Very well. It's a nice horse blanket.
Colonel Tavington,
why, after six weeks,
am I still attending a ball
in South Carolina,
when I should be attending balls
in North Carolina?
First, the theft
of my personal baggage,
including my memoirs,
upon which I spent countless hours.
Then half the bridges and ferries
between here and Charles Town burned.
Colonel, if you can't protect
our supply lines against militia,
how do you intend doing so against
the Regulars or the French?
They won't fight like Regulars.
We can't find them.
Colonel, they're militia.
They're farmers with pitchforks!
They're rather more than that,
I'm afraid.
Made so by their Commander,
this ghost.
Oh, ghost, ghost, ghost.
You created this ghost, colonel.
Your brutality
has swelled his ranks.
Without which, this ghost
would've disappeared
and I'd be in North Carolina
or Virginia by now!
In my defence, my lord...
Oh, enough, enough.
A fine soldier you are,
bested by a bedtime story.
Give me the horse blanket.
CORNWALLIS: O'Hara, our supply
ship appears to have arrived.
Yes, my lord, it has.
Then why am I still wearing
this rag?
My lord, your replacement wardrobe
is aboard ship, but...
Colonel Tavington thought it best to
secure our arms and munitions first.
They are being unloaded now.
You look good in that colour.
It stinks.
Mm.
Well, it's had a dead man in it.
The beasts took your dogs too?
Yes. Yes.
Fine animals.
A gift from His Majesty.
Dead now, for all I know.
Is there no decency?
[GASPING]
Oh.
Oh, fireworks. Lovely!
[TN]
Mr. Howard.
I've come to call on Anne.
I've come to call on Anne!
Well, of course you
call yourself a man.
Father, stop it. You heard him.
Well...
call on her.
[TN]
WOMAN: I'm nearly finished.
You needn't worry, Father.
Yeah, I know.
I think bundling bags are a wonderful tradition.
I don't mind in the least.
Ow!
Be still.
Tea?
Please.
There.
Okay.
Come, dear.
[GRUNTS]
Mm.
It's very good.
I'm pleased that you like it.
[LAUGHING]
MOTHER: Peter.
Don't worry. I sew better
than my mother did.
I hope so.
If you're just gonna stand there,
why don't you read it for us?
I can't read.
I can.
It says, "Take notice."
By order of General Washington
and the Continental Congress,
all bound slaves who give
minimum one year service
in the Continental Army
will be granted freedom
"and be paid a bounty of five shillings
for each month of service."
DAN: Did you hear that?
First they're gonna free them,
and then they're gonna pay them.
Only another six months.
What in the hell are you gonna do
with freedom?
BILLINGS: I made this for you.
Martha.
Look after your mother.
BENJAMIN: You know, Peter,
I can't pay you for this.
Benjamin, you pay me what you can,
when you can.
I'm obliged.
Gabriel sure reminds me
a lot of you.
No, no, he's more like his mother.
BENJAMIN: Corporal!
Take your time. Dogs.
Sir.
[CLEARS TH ROAT]
[TN]
BENJAMIN: This road is closed.
These wagons now belong
to the Continental Army.
Ready arms!
[WHISTLES]
By Íwos!
There's no need for your men to die.
Leave the wagons and go.
This is the king's highway.
And I advise you and your men
to make way.
TAVINGTON: Charge!
Fire!
Retreat!
[SCREAMS]
MAN: Save yourselves!
[SCREAMING]
[TN]
BENJAMIN: Retreat!
MAN 2: Ambush! Ambush!
[TN]
GABRIEL: I have the count.
Twenty-two are dead.
Eighteen wounded
and 20 are missing.
I'm through.
He won't be the last to leave.
Trust me.
Soon my countrymen will arrive.
The French army is...
To hell with you.
And to hell with the French army.
BILLINGS: We don't need them.
We got Benjamin Martin.
We know what he done to the French.
[MEN LAUGH]
Father.
Wherever you go, men buy you drinks because
of what happened at Fort Wilderness.
Strangers know more about you
than I do.
Tell me what happened.
Your mother asked me that question
around about the time you were born.
I was drunk and foolish enough
to answer it.
The French and the Cherokee
had raided along the Blue Ridge.
The English settlers
had sought refuge at Fort Charles.
By the time we got there,
the fort was abandoned.
They'd left about a week before.
But what we found was...
Go on.
They'd killed all the settlers,
the men.
With the women and...
some of the children, they had...
We buried them all,
what was left of them.
We caught up with them
at Fort Wilderness.
We took our time.
We cut them apart slowly.
Piece by piece.
I can see their faces.
I can still hear their screams.
All but two. We let them live.
We placed the heads on a pallet
and sent them back with the two
that lived to Fort Ambercon.
The eyes, tongues, fingers,
we put in baskets.
Sent them down the Asheulot
to the Cherokee.
Soon after, the Cherokee broke
their treaty with the French.
That's how we justified it.
[TN]
We were...
heroes.
And men bought you drinks.
Not a day goes by where I don't ask
God's forgiveness for what I did.
Thomas was my brother,
as well as your son.
You may not believe this, but I want
satisfaction as much as you do.
But not at the expense of our cause.
There will be a time for revenge.
But until then, stay the course.
That's what your mother used to say to
me when I'd get drunk or lose my temper.
She'd say it to me
when I picked on Thomas.
I miss him.
[SPLASHING]
[GROANING]
The British got 18 of our men
at Fort Carolina.
They'll be hung one at a time
until they give up the rest of us.
[TN]
Reverend,
can you write a letter for me?
To my wife and boy.
Yes, of course I will.
But first let us pray.
[TN]
REDCOAT: My lord,
there is a rider at the gates.
A civilian carrying a white flag.
I am occupied.
He has a pair of dogs with him.
Great Danes.
REVEREND: And dear Lord,
protect us in this,
our hour of need.
This we ask in the name
of the Father, the Son...
And the Holy Ghost.
REDCOAT: Wait here.
General Lord Cornwallis will be
with you shortly.
[SIGHS]
Jupiter, Mars. Come, boys.
Come.
My good boys. My brave boys.
You seem to be well fed.
I thank you for that.
I'm afraid I don't know your name.
I'm a colonel in the Continental Army.
My rank should be sufficient for now.
As you wish.
Please be seated.
Thank you.
Would you, as the initiating officer,
care to begin?
I will, unless of course,
you'd like to claim aggrieved status.
Yes, I would like to claim
aggrieved status.
Very well, sir. Proceed.
You have in your possession certain
belongings of mine including clothing,
furniture, personal effects
of a non-military nature,
which I'd like returned to me.
Indeed. I will do so
as soon as possible.
Thank you.
Now we come to the matter
of the specific targeting
of officers during engagements.
Colonel, you must know
that in civilized warfare,
officers in the field must not be accorded
inappropriate levels of hostile attention.
To your mind, what are appropriate
levels of hostile attention?
Imagine the chaos that would follow
from leaderless armies
having at each other.
There must be gentlemen in command
tolead,
and, where necessary,
restrain their men.
Restrain them from, say, targeting civilians.
Women, children and such.
That's a separate issue.
No, no, no. I consider them linked.
And as long as your soldiers
attack civilians,
I will order the shooting of officers
at the outset of every engagement.
And my men
are excellent marksmen.
Very well.
Now, let us move on to...
Prisoner exchange.
Sir?
You have 18 of my men.
I want them back.
[WHISPERING]
I do have 18 criminals
under sentence of death,
but I hold no prisoners of war.
If that's your position,
18 of your officers will have to die.
Nineteen, if you hang me
with my men.
My officers?
Sir.
Top of the ridge, to your left.
Just below the tree line.
Their names and ranks?
They refused to give me their names. But their ranks
are nine lieutenants, five captains, three majors
and one vert fat colonel
who called me...
[IN BRITISH ACCENT]
a cheeky fellow.
You know, this is not the conduct
of a gentlemen.
If the conduct of your officers
is the measure of a gentlemen,
I'll take that as a compliment.
Get my men.
Arrange the exchange. My lord.
Thank you, sir.
[WHINING]
[TN]
Release the prisoners!
What is this?
Prisoner exchange.
He has 18 of our officers.
Who is he? I recognize him.
He's the Commander of the militia.
Your ghost.
Stay that sword, colonel!
He rode in under a white flag
for formal parley.
This is madness.
If you harm him,
you condemn our officers.
With respect, sir, he's killed as many
officers in the last two months.
He has shown no aggression here.
Hence he cannot be touched.
Has he not?
You!
So you're the ghost, are you?
I remember you!
On that farm! That stupid little boy!
Did he die?
You know,
it's an ugly business,
doing one's duty.
But just occasionally,
it's a real pleasure.
Before this war is over,
I'm going to kill you.
Why wait?
Soon.
[WHISTLES]
[TN]
Move out!
But I still think it's imperative
to push north...
One of our captured officers,
my lord.
[TN]
CORNWALLIS: My reputation suffers
because of your incompetence!
That man insults me!
Quite impressive for a farmer
with a pitchfork, wouldn't you say?
I want you to find that man.
I want you to capture him.
The man has
the loyalty of the people.
They protect him.
Protect his family.
Protect the families of his men.
I can capture him for you.
But to do so requires the use
of tactics that are somewhat...
What was the word
your lordship used?
"Brutal," I think.
Go on.
I am prepared to do
what is necessary.
I alone will assume the full mantle
of responsibility for my actions,
free of the chain of command,
rendering you blameless.
However,
¡fl do this,
you and I both know that I can
never return to England with honour.
What, I wonder, is to become of me?
When this war is over here
in the Colonies,
the new aristocracy...
will be landowners.
Tell me about Ohio.
MAN: Make way.
As you were.
Wilkins. A plantation seven miles
from Wakefield, on the Santee,
east of Black Swamp.
Who lived there?
Benjamin Martin.
He's the ghost.
What do you know about him?
Hell, everything.
I could tell you the size of his boot.
Does he have family?
Where would he hide his children?
His wife's sister has a plantation.
It's not far.
[TN]
[RIDERS APPROACH]
Aunt Charlotte.
Wake up, someone's coming.
Get the boys.
Margaret, come quickly.
Let's go. Boys, come.
Go.
Stay close.
This way.
Follow me.
We'll go downstairs to the kitchen.
Margaret, quick!
Get down there! Fast!
Samuel, get down there fast!
[TN]
[CLICKS]
REDCOAT 1:
Beneath the sill. There.
There's no one in the house.
They can't be far.
Search the outbuildings
and the woods, quickly.
REDCOAT 2:
Prepare to fire the house.
Go.
REDCOAT 3: This one's
head of the house slaves.
TAVINGTON:
Where are they hiding?
[GASPING]
Keep looking!
They're here somewhere!
[TN]
Gabriel. Where's Father?
Shh.
REDCOAT 4: Torch the house!
[WHINNYING]
[TN]
To horse!
Come on! It's all right.
Susan, come here.
Charlotte.
They won't stop looking for us.
You'll be safe
where we're taking you.
Father said it was
a perfect place to hide.
How is he?
[SIGHS]
I don't know. I'm his son.
Where is Father?
Speaking for months now.
Speaking for months.
Why did he go?
[CLEARS TH ROAT]
He didn't want those mean men
to find you, so he led them away.
He'll come see you
as soon as he can.
I don't care. I hate him.
Susan, you don't hate him.
I hate him, and I hope
he never comes back.
[TN]
It's the children.
Abigale!
WILLIAM: You're alive!
I know it's not much,
but you can stay here with me.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
[TN]
She spoke. Susan talked to you?
In full sentences.
As if she'd been speaking all along.
Damn, I wasn't there for it.
What did she say?
She said...
that she loves you
and misses you,
but she understands
why you can't be with her.
My Lord, she said that.
Isn't that something?
Tavington has a list of our men.
He's burning our homes,
killing whomever resists.
Where?
Seven homes along the Santee so far.
[TN]
REVEREND: John.
John, this is not a time
forvengeance.
This is a time for mourning.
John.
No!
Oh... Oh...
Attend to your families.
One week furlough for all men.
Any man who does not return will not
be thought a coward or uncommitted.
[TN]
Father!
Papa!
[LAUGHING]
My God, they're huge.
What have you been feeding them?
They're from good stock
on their father's side.
Thank you.
Susan?
[TN]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
I see it. There it is. Look.
Look, Father.
NATHAN: I got ¡t! I got ¡t!
BENJAMIN: You got it.
I got ¡t!
Careful. I Caught it.
NATHAN: All the fish are over here.
Let's get them.
GABRIEL:
Father, what changed you?
Are you sure I have?
Yes. You changed.
That's simple.
It was your mother.
A woman can have a strange effect
on a man.
Yeah.
There were times...
I had trouble breathing
around your mother.
I know the feeling.
You once said...
when I had a family of my own,
that I'd understand.
You were right.
You're trying to tell me something.
[RIDERS APPROACH]
[TN]
Apple? Thank you.
Congratulations.
REVEREND: Anne Patricia Howard,
will you have this man to be
your husband to live in marriage?
Will you love, comfort
and honour him,
for so long as you both shall live?
I will.
Gabriel Edward Martin, will you have
this woman to be your wife,
to live together
in the covenant of marriage?
Will you love, comfort and honour her
as long as you both shall live?
I will.
Then by the power vested in me
by our mutual faith
in the Lord, our God,
I now pronounce you man and wife.
[TN]
I'm sorry we didn't give you
more warning.
It's fine.
I have something for you.
It belonged to Gabriel's mother.
It's beautiful.
Allow me.
It's the North Star.
That's the only star in the sky
that never moves.
It's constant, unwavering.
A guide.
I'd be honoured.
May I?
If you must. I must.
May I sit with you?
It's a free country.
Or at least it will be.
[SIGHS]
I'm not my sister.
I know that.
Do you?
Yes, I do.
Very well, then.
[SIGHS]
Well?
Well what?
Oh.
[TN]
I'll see you in Pembroke soon.
Not soon enough.
Nathan,
I'm counting on you to make sure...
know. What?
Say my prayers,
take care of everyone.
Couldn't have said it better.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Susan.
Goodbye?
Just one word, that's all I want.
No?
All right.
Papa!
Papa, don't go! I'll say anything.
Please, Papa.
I'll say anything you want.
Tell me what you want me to say.
I'll say anything.
I promise, Papa. Please don't go.
Susan. Susan.
I promise.
I'll come back.
I'll come back. You believe me?
You know, you make me very happy.
Just the three of us?
John Raskin did come by earlier.
He looked around, then he left.
He would've made four.
Four would have been better.
[TN]
I got another two months to go
before I get to twelve months.
Colonel.
Reverend.
Trust the French.
Yes, trust the French.
Where else do I get the opportunity
to kill a few Redcoats?
Perhaps a few wounded ones
when you are not looking.
[TN]
Whoa.
Everyone must gather
at the church.
Mr. Wilkins?
Colonel Tavington wishes to address
the whole village.
This town has given aid
to Benjamin Martin and his rebels.
I wish to know his whereabouts.
So,
anyone who comes forward
may be forgiven their treason.
Very well.
You had your chance. MAN: Wait!
This man gives them supplies.
Quiet!
He brings them to Black Swamp.
He's a liar!
In the marsh,
by the old Spanish mission.
This man here?
Yes. The Black Swamp, you say?
By the old Spanish mission.
Thank you very much.
Shut the doors.
But you said we'd be forgiven.
And indeed you may!
That's between you and God.
Be strong. We must.
I'll fire the town on your orders.
The town?
Burn the church.
There's no honour in this.
Didn't you say all those who stand
against England
deserve to die a traitor's death?
Burn the church, Captain.
[TN]
Give me the torch.
[SCREAMING]
The honour is found in the end,
not the means.
This will be forgotten.
Bordon.
[SCREAMING AND CRYING]
[TN]
Anne!
Mrs. Howard?
Where is everybody?
They're not here.
[TN]
Gabriel's gone.
Yah!
To arms! To arms!
[TN]
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING]
[TN]
Yah.
Father.
Just don't talk. Don't talk.
I'm sorry. Be quiet.
I'll take care of you.
You'll be all right.
I'm sorry about Thomas.
Oh, son, that wasn't your fault.
That was mine.
Hold on. You're gonna be all right.
Don't go. Gabriel, don't.
Oh. Oh.
Oh, God help me. God help me.
Where is he?
BURWELL:
I'll help you bury him.
I'll bury him.
My wife in Alexandria is with child.
My first.
I fight for that child.
Benjamin, nothing will replace
your sons.
But if you come with us,
you can justify their sacrifice.
Why?
Why do men feel
they can justify death?
Is it arrogance or...?
I have long feared...
that my sins would return
to visit me.
And the cost is more
than I can bear.
Benjamin, we have a chance.
Greene and Dan Morgan
are down from Virginia.
If we win this next battle, victory
in the war is within our grasp.
Go, then.
Seek your victory.
I'm small issue to it.
You're wrong, Benjamin.
You matter to your men...
and to others as well.
Your victories
and your losses...
are shared by more than you know.
Stay with us.
Stay the course.
I have run my course.
You men will be leaving with us.
Yes. Prepare the baggage.
[BAN D PLAYS]
[TN]
Jean.
[MEN CHEERING]
You will be missed tomorrow,
colonel.
Missed, my lord? Your wound.
It's nothing, my lord.
I am, as ever, ready to serve.
Very well.
Make sure you do.
I stand on the eve of the greatest
victory of my career. Don't fail me.
My efforts in no small measure
have brought you here.
I grant you that small measure
in spite of your failure
to deliver the ghost to me.
Thus far.
I will not tolerate
a premature charge
born of your eagerness for glory.
Wait for my order.
Or you may abandon
any hope of Ohio.
BURWELL: Tomorrow's battle can
alter the course of the war.
General Greene, what exactly is
the task before us?
GREENE: Gentlemen,
Cornwallis has us cornered.
Not only does he outnumber us,
but nearly half of our force
is militia.
Unreliable, at best.
Excuse me, sir.
I believe you underestimate
our militia.
All of you do.
We've seen our militia lines break
time and again.
Kips Bay, Princeton.
But the British have seen that too.
Cornwallis' own letters bear out
that he has no respect for the militia.
What are you suggesting, Ben?
I'm suggesting we use that.
I know you men have sacrificed
a lot so far.
But all I'm asking is that you
let the front line of the militia
fire two shots tomorrow.
A lot can happen in the time it takes
to fire two shots.
Especially against British Regulars.
Indeed. That's why I'm not asking you
to fire three.
[TN]
[CLEARS TH ROAT]
If I die, I will die well dressed.
[TN]
[BOOMING]
REDCOAT 1: Fire!
REDCOAT 2: Battalion!
REDCOAT 3: Company, halt!
BENJAMIN: Harry,
will you give this to my children?
Thank you.
It's October now.
I know.
It's more than 12 months.
You're a free man.
I'm here now on my own accord.
I'm honoured to have you with us.
Honoured.
VILLENEUVE: Shoulder arms!
Forward
march!
How old were your daughters?
Violette was 12 and Pauline, 10.
They had green eyes.
I'm sure they were lovely.
Yes, they were.
Battalion! REDCOAT 4: Company!
March!
REDCOAT 1: Fire!
CORNWALLIS:
Unless I'm dreaming,
I believe I see militia forming
at their centre.
Battalion, halt!
Dress ranks!
Make ready!
Battalion!
Halt!
Take aim!
Fire! _ Fire!
Fire!
[SCREAMING]
Hold the line!
Prepare to charge!
We haven't been given that order.
Charge!
Tavington.
Damn him! Damn that man!
REDCOAT 5: Make ready.
Take aim!
Fire!
Retreat!
Bayonet charge. We'll see who takes
the glory from this field.
Charge!
Congratulations, my lord.
Infantry reserve into the centre.
But you've taken the field.
Now we'll take their spirits.
Send the battalion over that hill
and crush them.
It ends today.
[TN]
Hold the charge!
BURWELL: Fire!
Fire!
Take aim!
Charge!
Charge bayonets!
[SCREAMING AND GRUNTING]
BURWELL: Halt!
Hold! Dress your ranks!
REDCOAT 6: Fire!
Charge!
MAN: Retreat!
Colonel!
The line is faltering!
Retreat! Retreat!
Wait!
No retreat!
Hold the line!
[YELLING]
Push forward, men!
Artillery, concentrate on the centre.
If we reform and wheel right,
we may be able to turn their flank.
You dream, general.
[TN]
Kill me before the war is over,
will you?
It appears you are not
the better man.
You're right.
My sons were better men.
[TN]
Sound the retreat.
Sound”.
Retreat.
[TN]
B E NJAM I N: Dear Charlotte:
The war has turned.
General Cornwallis took flight
with his army and moved north.
We continued to engage the British,
and in the following months,
Cornwa/lis entrenched himself
at Yorktown, Virginia.
Washington escaped from the north
and surrounded Cornwallis,
who could not retreat to the seas.
It was blocked off by
our long-lost friends,
who had finally arrived.
Vive la France.
Vive la liberté.
[SPEAKS FRENCH]
My lord, I beseech you.
You must order the surrender.
CORNWALLIS: How could it come to this?
An army of rabble.
Peasants.
Everything will change.
Everything has changed.
BENJAMIN:
Though he eventually surrendered,
Cornwa/lis himself hid in shame,
appointing his subordinate
to relinquish his sword.
With the war ending,
and our militia disbanding,
I take measure of what
we have lost
and what we have won.
My hope and prayer is that
the sacrifices borne by so many
will spawn and fu/fi/ the promise
of our new nation.
Tell the children, and especially
Susan, that I will keep my promise,
as I will be returning
to you all soon.
Where will you go now?
Home. Start over.
Your wife's expecting a child,
isn't she?
She gave birth to a son
three weeks ago.
What'd you name him?
We named him Gabriel.
Thank you, Harry.
Gabriel is a good name for a farmer.
It is. It is.
Jean.
Ben.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[TN]
Gabriel said if we won the war
we could build a whole new world.
Just figured we'd get started
right here
with your home.
Sounds good.
Thank you.
Ma'am.
[TN]