English Subtitle by Do My Best
They say Japan was made by a sword
They say the old gods dipped
the coral blade into the ocean
When they pulled it out
four perfect drops fell back into the sea
those drops became the islands of Japan
I say Japan was made by a handful of brave men
Warriors willing to give their lives
for what seems to have become a forgotten word...
Honor
" The Last Samurai "
Ladies and Gentlemen ... the Winchester
an American leader in all forms of armament
used by the United States Army
celebrates our nation's centenial
by bringing you a true
American hero.
One of our most decorated warriors
this country has ever known...
winner of the medal of honor for
his gallantry on the arena of battle each time.
He's late of the seventh
cavalary and a triumph campaign...
against the most savage of Indian nations.
Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you...
Captain Nathan Algren.
Captain Nathan Algren!
Yes !
Yes!
Please, one moment, thank you.
God damn you, Algren!
Get out of there!
This is your last performance,
you are fired.
Now get out!
Come on!
I'm sick of this, come on!
Yes!
My thanks, Mr. McCabe.
You are too kind.
This, ladies and gents,
is the gun that's winning the west.
I... many's the time,
I found myself...
surrounded by a squad of wrath...
... angry hostiles.
with nothing but this rifle, between me
and their certain and gruesome death.
But let me tell you folks...
the "redman" doesn't fear his enemy.
If He'd had his way,
this scalp of mine will be long gone...
and then there will be a bald man
standing before you today.
Would those poor bastards attack there...
and a little bit more.
Bodies slit about... literally.
after rotted in the sun.
This, ladies and ladies,
73 lever-action...
chamber...
7-shot capacity, accurate at
400 yards, one round per second...
Son, you've seen what this
could do with a man?
It's blown a hole in your daddy 16 inches wide.
It's tragic
This beauty, it kills some
five, six, seven braves...
without ever having to reload.
Note the patented loading port...
and the smooth cocking action.
My thanks,
on behalf of those who died
in the name of better
mechanical amusements...
and commercial opportunities.
Mr. McCabe,
come here to take the orders
God bless you all.
I was seeking out to heat the
flame for the old melodrama.
- You are alive.
- I'm indeed.
You mind, Custer said to me,
"we're going to the Little BigHorn
since I want those weird stuff to
walk into take-up for me."
Now many things happened,
I will tell you what else happened.
I have a good job for the both of us.
God knows specially you're
gonna need one for yourself.
What kind of a job?
The only job you will
think you are loyal. A man's job!
Unless of course you give your heart
in the career in the theater.
Nathan!
You just listen to 'em.
Don't you bother to say.
For a while, it's good to see you.
Nathan Algren, I would like you
to meet Mr. Omura, from Japan.
and his associate, his name
I've given up try to pronounce.
Sit down, please.
Whiskey.
Now Japan's got that in mind
to become a civilized country.
And Mr. Omura here is...
...willing to spend whatever it takes
to hire a wise expert to train their army.
And he prepared a contract
the Emperor grants the U.S...
exclusive rights to supply arms.
I have an agreement with
the Winchester company,
and I am certain that Mr. Omura here
has some concept of what an agreement is.
Your performances for the
Winchester company bring you $25 a week.
We will pay you $400 a month.
$5 for each.
and another $500 when we get the job done.
How many other genuine whitean here
you got them lined up?
He's rude
That's how it is here.
A land of cheap traders.
Whiskey.
So , who will be it - training
your boys to fight against?
His name is Kasumoto Moritsu.
He was last Emperor's teacher.
He is a samurai.
Samurai?
The word you might use it as "warrior"
Mr. Omura is familiar...
with our experience in dealing with renegade.
What is it?
It's going to read your book.
Captain Algren studied of a trial, which was a
crucial fact on the defeat of the Cheyennes.
Please excuse
What is funny?
Because...
back together again is so...
...inspiring
Excuse me
Excuse me.
Sorry for this.
This isn't a problem
I'll just talk to him for a minute.
Colonel Bagley.
We contacted you because
you are Captain Algren's superior officer...
and you've assured us of his participation.
I'll do it.
I just need a minute.
Nathan.
I did what I was ordered to do up there.
And I have no remorse.
What did you see through the past behind us?
You want me to kill Jappos?
I will kill Jappos.
I am not asking you to kill anybody, but the enemy...
Kill the enemy if it is Jappo.
Reb, Sioux, Cheyenne...
For 500 bucks a month,
I will kill whoever you want.
But keep one thing in mind...
I'd be happy to kill you for free.
June 12th, 1876.
There is some comfort in the emptiness in the sea.
No past, no future.
And I once am confronted by the
hard truth of the present circumstances.
I have been hired to help supress
the rebellion of another tribal leader.
Apparently, this is the only job
for which I am suited.
I am upset by the ironies of my life.
Yokohama Harbor, 1876
Captain Algren, I presume?
Yes
I presume that good.
How do you do? Simon Graham.
20 years ago, it's sleepy little time.
Now, look at this.
You see, the emperor is mad
for all thing western.
and the Samurais believe
that it's changing too fast.
They find the ancient to the modern
will warp this old Japan.
So your new employer, Mr. Omura...
is bringing in every western
expert he can get his hands on.
Lawyers of France,
engineers of Germany...
architects of Holland and
now of course, warriors of America.
I came when I was with the British
legation, know, years ago...
I was soon relieved of my position
where I have a long long forest of
tendencies to tell the truth...
in a country where they never say what they need.
So now, I very accurately
translate the other people's lives.
For 2000 years, no Emperor
was even seen by a commoner.
You have to realise
this accidental chance is an honor.
This is all highly ritualism, of course.
You may look at him,
but do not speak.
Unless you are spoken to, obviously.
If he stands, you must bow.
If he bows, you must bow lower.
Do I look presentable?
I've wantoned a decade...
...on the smart round miggets.
and bow
The Emperor Meiji bids you welcome.
He's grateful for the assistance your country offers.
We hope to accomplish the same
national harmony you enjoy in your homeland.
The Emperor is most interested
in the American indians.
If you have fought against them in battle?
We have, Your Highness.
The red man is brutal ass.
The Emperor wishes to ask Captain
Algren if it is truth that...
they wear eagle feathers and paint their
faces before going into battle.
and then they have no fear.
They are very brave.
Bow
Thank you very much.
Step back
step back..step back and turn.
All right, you little bastards,
you should stand up straight in a line...
or I will passionately shit-kick
every one of you sad parade,
let it be before my eyes.
Well done, Sergeant.
When you understand the language,
everything is as fast as it takes place.
The first right you'll know:
rifles at the ready.
The second right...
July 27th, 1876. For six months of
work, I'm to receive...
...3 years of a Captain's pay,
teaching oriental soldiers.
They are army of conscription...
most of them present have never seen a gun.
Fire!
They are led by General Hasegawa...
a man of small stature and nonetheless
commanding enormous respect.
What can General tell me
about this man, this samurai...
-Katsumoto.
He seems to have great knowledge
of Katsumoto, his rebellion.
I'll count on his help
when facing this samurai.
Who supply them with weapons?
Katsumoto no longer dishonours
himself by using firearms.
He uses no firearms?
Those honor the old way,
Katsumoto is a hero.
How well does he know this man?
Well, the General and Katsumoto
fought together for the Emperor.
He fought with the samurai?
He is a samurai.
You have to understand Katsumoto
pledged the sword to defend the Emperor.
They say the samurai's sword is his soul.
They are paradoxical people, samurai.
I've tried to write a book about them for years...
I seeked in vain to approach them close.
The bastards still wear armor.
Yes, when the Irishes' still
comporting themselves in rolling course.
He's characterized them as the most
sophisticated warriors on earth.
I need more detailed
information of their battle tactics.
I have several more books
just waiting to be translated.
Our captain will be speaking the
language of theirs.
You should've heard him
babbling on the Blackfoot.
Really? A fellow linguist?
Oh, Capital!
Oh come on Sir,
a word or two is very fun.
Just "hello" or "Goodbye''.
No,No..Cut its tongue and boil in the oil.
Early this morning we have a dull work.
so it is bed time, isn't it?
I once had a dread fascination for scalp.
I never understood its technique.
Imagine someone who hates you
with the uppermost intensity.
Grasping in hand full of your hair
while you are lying prostrate and helpless.
And scraping a dull blade of
a rusted knife on your scalp...
with the soulless emotion.
and let your imagination grasp
you can, Mr. Graham,
the effect of a strong, quick
jerk-out on the turf of your hair.
to release clinging part,
of course you have, of your nervous system.
You will have some idea of
what the hell it is to be scalped.
Mr. Graham.
How soon can you translate those books?
Right away.
Just delighted to do it,
with your such an interest in Samurai.
I don't give a damn about the Samurai.
I want to know my enemy.
I shalll not sleep until it is done.
Ah... foggy
Have a good night.
Can I get your answer?
This is a pureness expedition, Captain.
Colonel Bagley, these people have
nothing to do with the race.
Good night, Sir.
Running now, boys.
Fire!
I suppose we should be grateful
for our fire army to be shooting in the same direction.
could not put it better itself, Sir.
Rifle bottom against your shoulder.
Eye down the side, now slowly...
Fire!
Well done.
You've got that done.
Nathan...
Katsumoto attacked the railroad
in the border of his province.
we cannot govern a country
in which we cannot travel freely.
He must be stopped now.
My railroad is a priority for this country.
They are not ready.
The rebels don't have a signle rifle.
They're savages with bows and arrows.
whose sole occupation for the
last 1000 years has been at war.
You have superior fire power and a larger force.
I am ordering the regiment to
move against the rebel Katsumoto.
You will track him down and engage him.
Mr. Graham...
tell these men to fire at me.
I beg your pardon?
Tell these men if he does not shoot me...
I will kill him.
Captain, could I make them awarded?
Kill him.
Kill him
Time to give it up.
Stop!
Load.
Load
Faster!
Shoot me or the time you died.
Fire!
Fire! Fire! [Japanese]
They are not ready.
The regiment leaves at 6:00 A.M.
1,000 miles of rail track laid in
less than 2 years.
It's astonished.
No more owns all these.
As soon as we exempt
with the Samurai. Oh yes.
How do you intend to find Katsumoto?
Don't worry, Mr. Graham.
I assure you...
he will find us.
Move!
Hold your position!
Yoshino Province, 1876.
First Company, follow up the backline around me!
Second Company, follow up
First Company.
Third and Fourth Company follow up!
To be at my command!
- Where is the Hasegawa?
- Unclear, he refused to fight against Katsumoto.
- Come on now!
- Captain Algren...
we are not here for combatness.
Then who's gonna lead these men?
Their own officers, for Chris sake,
let's move to the rear.
I'll be present there.
Change for the rear.
- Mr. Graham, you'll accompany me to the rear, okay?
- Of course.
Sergeant Gant, report to the rear.
See the disposition of the supply train.
Sergeant Gant, did you hear my order?
I did hear it, Sir.
Good, then you obey it.
Now!
No disrespecting intended, Sir,
we should look up our ass.
- Load!
So many come.
You will be fine, Sir.
- Assume firing position!
Fire on my order only!
Hold your fire!
Reload!
Hold the line!
Fire! Fire!
Translate it: Fall back!
Gant!
He's mine.
Stop!
Take him away.
What is your name?
Insolent swine! Answer!
Leave him be.
This is my son in the village.
We are deep in the mountains
and the winter is coming.
You cannot escape.
It's surely good.
My Lord, why do you spare the arbarian?
He is ashamed in defeat.
He should kill himself.
This is not their custom.
Then...
...I will kill him.
Father...
I don't think...
Ujio...
...there will be plenty of killing to come.
For now...
...we will learn about our new enemy.
Keep him alive.
He's in bad shape.
Sake...
Sake?
Taka will take care of you.
Sake...
Let him drink, aunt.
No. That will not do.
This is my village.
This is my house.
Please...sake..
Sugay!
No!
I told you!
Morning.
Over there.
Over there!
What's your name?
You have a name, don't you?
Naomei?
Naomai?
You don't know what I'm saying, do you?
I know why you don't talk.
You're angry. You're angry
because I made you wear a dress.
Son of a bitch.
This temple was built by my
family 1,000 years ago.
My name is Katsumoto.
What is your name?
Are my words not correct?
I will practise my English with you...
if you would honor me...
You keep me alive just to speak English?
What do you want?
To know my enemy.
I've seen what you did with your enemies.
The warriors in its country do not kill?
They don't cut their heads off
to free the kneeling men.
General Hasegawa asked me to help him and his life.
A samurai cannot stand the shame of the defeat.
I was honored to cut off his head.
Many of our customs seem strange to you...
and the same is true of yours.
For example...
Not to introduce yourself is considered
extremely rude, even among enemies.
Nathan Algren.
I am honored to meet you.
I have enjoyed this conversation in English.
I have questions.
I have introduced myself,
you have introduced yourself.
This is a very good conversation.
I have questions!
- Questions come later.
- Who was the warrior in the red armor?
My brother-in-law, Hirotaro.
and woman who cares for me?
My sister, Hirotaro's wife.
Her name is Taka.
I killed her husband?
It was a good death!
You! Come... please...
Thank you.
Douzo! [Japanese] (please!)
He smells like the pigs. Tell my
brother I cannot stand this.
Why don't you tell him?
At least make him take a bath.
Nicely done!
They may be children,
but they are strong.
You try.
Fight!
Muyamini [Japanese]
(How absurd you are!)
Put down the sword.
Drop it!
I just realised...
I've been remiss. Forgive me I...
forget to thank you for
looking out for me yesterday.
It's your job, correct?
Protecting me.
Well done, "Bob".
You don't mind if I call you "Bobby"?
I knew a Bob once.
God, he's a grist mill.
You hear this man, Bob?
Ujio was teaching you
the way of Japanese sword.
Yes, indeed.
You fought against the red indians?
Yes.
Tell me the real part in this war.
- Why?
- I wish to learn.
Read the book.
I'd rather to have a good conversation.
- Why?
- Because...
to read a book constitutes a work.
So...
you were the General of your army?
No... I was a Captain.
This is a lower rank?
a middle rank
Then who was the General?
Don't you have a rebellion to lead?
People in your country do not like conversation?
He was a Lieutenant-Colonel.
His name is Custer.
I know this name.
He killed many warriors.
Aye. Many warriors.
So he was a good General.
No, he wasn't a good General,
he was arrogant, foolhardy.
and he got massacred because
he took a single battallion...
...against 2,000 angry indians.
2,000 indians?
How many men for Custer?
- 200.
- I like this General Custer.
He was a murderer,
who fell in love with his own legend.
and his troops died for it.
I think this is a very good death.
Oh, maybe you can
have one just like it someday.
If it is my destiny.
What you want from me?
What do you want for yourself?
What are you doing?
Why we have these conversations?
What the hell am I doing here?
In spring, the snow will melt
and passage will open.
Until that time, you are here.
Good day, Captain.
1876... day unknown, month unknown.
I continue to live among these unusual people.
I'm a captive and I cannot escape.
Mostly I'm treated with a kind of a mind of regret
as if I was a street dog, an unwelcome guest.
Everyone is polite,
everyone smiles and bows.
But beneath this courtesy,
I detect their deep breath of moral feeling.
Higen
They are intriguing people.