[ Man narrating ]
Greece, that hard and timeless land...
where even the stones
speak of man's courage...
ofhis endurance,
ofhis glory.
And none more eloquently than this
lonely pillar in a desolate pass...
some 200 miles north
of modern Athens.
Across the hush
of 2 4 centuries...
this is the story
of a turning point in history--
of a blazing day when 300 Greek warriors
fought here to hold with their lives...
their freedom and ours.
[ Chanting ]
Xerxes! Xerxes! Xerxes!
Xerxes.! Xerxes.!
[ Chanting Continues ]
At last we are in Europe.
- Mardonius.
- My lord.
How long will it be before the whole
of our troops pass into Greece?
About seven days
and seven nights, my lord.
Whip them on
if they are slow.
I am anxious to avenge
my father's defeat.
My lord, this army
will give you not only Greece...
but the whole world.
You are right.
It was
my father's dream.
One world. One master.
But to Marathon ten years ago
he sent a mere wave.
I am leading
an ocean!
So this is the Spartan spy
caught trying to count my troops.
Yes, my lord.
All our best torture is wasted on him.
He's worn out two of my men
without uttering a sound.
Bring him here.
Why do you not speak?
I have nothing to say.
Tell me...
is it true that the Spartans are
the bravest warriors in all Greece?
You will find that out
for yourself.
Fool. You have but few men.
Your little country is divided.
You have no single ruler.
How can you defy me,
the master of the whole world?
That's not for you
to understand, sir.
For you are
the master of slavery...
and you know nothing
of freedom.
Enough!
Let us see how insolence
meets death.
Seize him.!
[ Men Chanting ]
Xerxes.! Xerxes.!
Wait.!
[ Chanting Continues ]
Release him.
Come here,
my friend.
I have spared your life--
but not out of pity.
I am told the Greeks are holding
some sort of assembly at Corinth.
Go there, and tell them
what you have seen here.
Apower that neither
man nor the gods can thwart.
Go!
- Agathon.
- Grellus.
What evil wind has blown you
into this scorpion's nest?
- I'm here with Demaratus.
- You are here with Xerxes.
I am in his camp
but not with him.
You know, after all,
Demaratus was once our king
in Sparta, before he was exiled.
I'm not interested
in Demaratus.
Kings have their ways,
but you--
You are in the camp of our enemies
and therefore an enemy of Greece.
- You know my son Phylon
in Sparta, don't you?
- Yes.
Please give him
a message from me.
Tell him not to judge me
until he knows all the fac--
- That Greek spy this morning,
he was a brave man.
- Mmm.
He was a Spartan,
my lord.
Demaratus, you were once
king of those people.
Tell me, do you really believe
that Sparta will fight?
My lord, do you wish for
a truthful answer or an agreeable one?
Tell me the truth.
I shan't hold it against you.
The Spartans will fight,
even if the rest of Greece submits.
How can they fight,
or do anything together...
when they even have
two kings ruling them?
The one who stole my throne
is a mere usurper.
But the other-- Leonidas--
is a true Spartan king.
His name means lion,
and he lives up to it.
There is no man who can match him
in courage and skill in battle...
nor in devotion
to his country.
- You seem to have great regard
for Spartan kings, Demaratus.
- I have, my lord.
- I was one myself.
- Yet you do not look to me
like a formidable fighter.
I have never yet met
the man I could not master.
I'll give you a chance
to prove your words.
I have in my bodyguard
a remarkable young man.
I've seen him kill four good
swordsmen with as many thrusts...
just for displeasing me
with their bragging words.
Now you can prove
your boast.
[ Murmuring ]
Hurry. Hurry.
[ Yells ]
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Once again, Demaratus,
you've succeeded in spoiling my dinner.
[ Murmuring Continues ]
My lord.
Artemisia.
May I enter
this war council?
By all means.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
My ships have
just dropped anchor.
Five vessels
fully fitted and manned.
This is a pleasant
surprise, Artemisia.
I expected your ships
but not you yourself.
If my men fight,
I want to be with them.
- That's the least a queen
can do for her subjects.
- To watch them die for her?
I never deny my subjects
that pleasure.
- Come sit with me.
- Artemisia, queen of Helicarnassian.
We visited her city
last year.
The great king
sought her advice about the war.
I'm glad to have you
with me, Artemisia.
Everyone gives me
different advice.
Artovadus
to abandon this war...
Mardonius to conquer
the whole world...
and Demaratus to seek peace
with the Spartans.
Only because I know
my people well.
I can always predict
their actions.
- Even when they choose
to discard one of their kings?
- [ Laughs ]
Will you forgive me,
my lord?
I do not relish
the noble lady's wit.
It has served me well,
Demaratus.
At least I am still with my people...
and still a queen.
[ Xerxes Laughing ]
Well spoken, Artemisia.
%'ve tried to curb his arrogance
with the wrong weapon.
A woman's tongue
is far deadlier than the sword.
Why do you permit him
to remain here?
He may serve my purpose.
The Greeks are assembled at Corinth
to discuss my demands.
Above all, I don't
want them to unite.
But once they disagree
among themselves...
men like Demaratus
may be of great use to me.
To us, you mean.
Yes. I need
your advice too.
Come tonight,
Artemisia.
- Will you come?
- Only if you promise
to limit our discussion...
- to the Corinth assembly.
- [ Laughs ]
As I said before,
the independence of our cities...
is the cornerstone
of our freedom.
Therefore, % propose that each city
deal with this problem independently...
without surrendering
its dignity.
But also without
futile heroics...
which can only end in
the mass suicide of the Greek race.
[ Crowd Chattering ]
Silence. Silence.
We shall now hear from
the representative of Athens:
Themistocles.
Ten years ago, the father
of the present king of Persia...
invaded Greece
at Marathon.
On that occasion,
the Athenians rose to challenge him.
Our Spartan friends,
famed for their piety...
no less than
their military prowess...
volunteered help
but were delayed by--
if I remember correctly--
a religious festival.
Whereupon the Athenians, unaided,
outnumbered ten to one...
attacked the invader
and threw him into the sea.
We've no time for history now.
Things are different today.
Yes. Things
are different today.
Today the danger
is much greater.
The whole of Asia
is descending upon us.
Many times more men
than there are Greeks.
These men are
fierce, savage...
bloodthirsty,
merciless.
But that is not the reason
why we should fear them.
That is not the source
of their power.
Their power lies
in their unity.
Unity.
Remember that
one terrible word...
which will surely
destroy Greece...
unless we counter it
with a unity of our own.
A unity of free men
fighting together...
resisting this
united tide of tyranny.
- [ Murmuring ]
- We all know Themistocles
to be a master of words.
But before we allow ourselves
to be led by them...
let us consider some other words
that have been spoken.
Has Athens not sent for and received
a prediction from the Delphic oracle?
Oh, come now,
Themistocles.
No Greek state acts
without first consulting the gods.
Then why not reveal
this prediction to us...
instead of trying to
draw us into a hopeless war?
There are no hopeless wars, friend,
only hopeless cowards.
You are evading the answer.
I happen to know
this prediction by heart.
And here it is:
''Fly to the world's end, doomed ones.
Leave your homes.
- For fire and the headlong god
of war shall bring you low.''
- [ Murmuring ]
- [ Murmuring Continues]
- This clearly seems to me...
that the gods foretell
the doom of Athens.
Isn't it wonderful that
we have among us such a clever man?
Not only does he know
how to steal state secrets...
but he understands
the meaning of the gods as well.
Now, since the sacred text
has been filched...
there's no longer any point
in keeping it a secret.
Here is the rest
of the prediction:
''Then farseeing love
grants this...
''to the prayers of Athenae:
'''Safe shall the wooden wall
continue for thee...
and thy children.'''
Perhaps you can explain to us
the meaning of these words.
- They have no meaning.
- No meaning?
Do you infer, then,
the gods dispense nonsense?
Don't put words into my mouth
to confuse the issue.
You know no wooden walls can stand
against an army like Xerxes'.
Anyway, Athens no longer
has a wooden wall.
And where did you steal
this piece of information?
Has it a wooden wall now?
- Answer me. Yes or no?
- Yes.
A wooden wall?
A splendid one. I know how splendid
because I have supervised its building.
Our new Athenian ships, manned
by the bravest sailors in the world.
There is our wooden wall.
The wall farseeing love
declares shall keep us safe.
The gods don't lie.
Shall we not heed
their words...
rather than listen
to fools, thieves...
and blasphemous cowards?
- [ Grumbling ]
- This is an insult.
Following divine advice...
Athens shall fight
to her victory.
A victory she invites
all Greece to join.
[ All Chattering ]
Speak, friend.
I represent Phocis.
We are a small state.
We can field
but a thousand soldiers.
Who will help us if we fight?
Will Sparta come to our defense?
- Sparta.
- [ Chattering ]
- The delegate from Phocis
asks the vital question.
Athens has ships, but Sparta
has the finest army in Greece.
Sir, is it not fitting that we now hear
from the representative of Sparta?
King Leonidas
of Sparta.
A Spartan king cannot act
without the authority of his people.
But I know my people,
and I know they will fight.
Will they lead all others?
Sparta will fight...
whether others
will follow or not.
[ All Muttering ]
- Sir.
- Yes?
Now you will hear words
never before uttered...
in the history
of our country.
Athens, to prove her trust
in Spartan valor...
does hereby resign her claim
to naval leadership...
and places her ships
under Spartan command.
- [ Muttering ]
- From this day onward...
every Athenian ship
will sail under Spartan orders.
[ Chattering Excitedly ]
We've right
to celebrate.
We've done it.
Leonidas,
it's going our way.
Of course, we must expect them
to argue for a while.
Yes, argue,
while our house burns.
When people are free
to speak their minds...
they're generally
more easily handled.
That fool nearly caught me
with that prediction.
Huh! I wouldn't care to go through
an ordeal like that again.
Of course, it was throwing
in the navy won the day for us.
Why did you do it?
The Spartans are no sailors.
Thereby, your admiral won't know how
to interfere with my running the fleet.
You don't mind, do you?
No.
Sparta will do her duty.
She better do it fast.
The Persians are moving
like a plague of locusts.
If we attack them here,
on the plain ofThessaly,
or their ships on the open sea...
they'll run over us
without even noticing.
We must find a position
which cannot be turned.
What about here?
- The Pass ofThermopylae?
- Yes.
It's the best line of defense
north of Corinth.
These mountains
run across Greece.
The Persians
must pass through here.
With a small force, I can hold
that narrow strip of land...
between the mountains and the
sea until the others are ready.
And I can bring the fleet through
the narrow straits above Thermopylae...
protecting your flank...
with your admiral's
consent, of course.
This is a splendid plan.
- When can you march?
- I must speak to the council first.
But once we start, we march
faster than any soldiers on Earth.
In the meantime, you can send a small
force of Athenians to occupy the pass.
No, don't let's
deceive ourselves.
No Greek will stir
until he sees the Spartans march.
Actually march, you know.
[ Grunts Marching Rhythm ]
Red cloaks.
Flutes and all.
I know. Only this
will unite Greece.
- I'll leave at once.
- I'll deploy the ships.
I'll meet you in this bay of Locris--
you and your men.
We'll be there.
Agathon! I thought
I should never see you again.
- What happened?
- I was a guest of the Persian king.
- And escaped?
- No, he gave me a horse.
- Why?
- So I could come tell the Greeks
what I have seen.
- Then why were you not in council?
- Because I'm not a good liar.
I don't want to
frighten them.
Then the army is as enormous
as they say.
Leonidas...
it is bigger than anything
you can imagine.
For six days I watched
them pass. Six days.
I ran out of numbers,
and still more of them came.
They're drinking the rivers dry.
And at night...
there are more of their campfires
than there are stars in the sky.
Good.
When I was a boy...
I always wanted to reach
the stars with my spear.
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Arabian ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Artemisia Laughing ]
- I don't trust that woman.
- Neither do I. But what can we do?
During the day
he seeks our advice.
Then comes the night and--
Shh!
- [ Artemisia Laughing ]
- My lord.
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- My lord!
- [ Laughing Stops ]
- Hydarnes, why must
you disturb me tonight?
I have urgent news,
my lord.
Our scouts report that the Greeks
have abandoned the whole ofThessaly.
I knew they would.
Sit down and have some wine.
Beyond Thessaly lies
the Oeta range...
with just one narrow pass near the sea,
called Thermopylae.
I'm in no mood
for geography.
But, my lord, we must send
a cavalry column to secure the pass...
before our army
reaches it.
You must do
what I order you to do!
But, my lord, as a soldier,
it is my duty to w--
Your duty is to obey me.
I don't want the Greeks
to think I'm afraid of them.
If they want a fight,
let them come out into the open.
I'll leave Thermopylae
as an open door for them to do so.
- And supposing--
- Enough!
It's my war and
I'll conduct it my way.
Now, go!
[ Continues ]
- We should be in Sparta
by late afternoon.
- Yes.
Tell me, did you see Demaratus
in the Persian camp?
No, but I saw a real
Persia-lover there.
- Who?
- Grellus, father of young Phylon.
I slashed his face
with a whip.
Why, I can't believe it.
He was always a good man.
Then he has no business
to be among the barbarians.
I'm only sorry now I didn't
run him through with a spear.
And Phylon should be questioned.
He might have known
about his father's actions.
We shall speak to him.
Phylon!
- What have you been doing today?
- Exercising...
with spear,
sword and javelin.
- Talking about the war.
- Any news?
- Everyone's saying
we're going to march north.
- To Corinth?
- Some say as far as Thessaly.
- Ohh.
Hey, this is
a really good war.
They say Xerxes has brought a hundred
nations with him. Isn't that wonderful?
- When does your aunt expect
King Leonidas back?
- Maybe tonight. Why?
The men gave me
a very good idea.
I can ask Leonidas
for his permission to marry you.
I'm sure the law is that the king
can act for my father in time of war.
And I could
speak to my aunt.
I love you, Ellas.
I've never loved
anyone else.
I think I loved you
when we were children...
from the earliest moment
I can remember.
And now we can marry.
And I want you.
I know.
I want you too, Phylon.
But--
But we must wait.
Why wait?
You are mine. I am yours.
- What is there to keep us apart?
- [ Whimpers ]
Only ourselves, Phylon.
just for a little while.
I want time to think.
We must be strong.
We are Spartans.
- [ Grunts ]
- Remember what they say:
''Once the rain is fallen,
nothing can put it back into the sky.''
And since when have Spartans
become afraid of rain?
Phylon, son of Grellus, you shall
soon march in defense of our land.
Are you ready to hear the laws
sacred to a Spartan warrior?
- Yes, Queen Gorgo.
- Here they are:
You must treasure
freedom above life...
shun pleasure
for the sake of virtue...
endure pain
and hardship in silence...
obey orders implicitly...
seek the enemies of Greece wherever
they may be and fight them fearlessly...
until victory...
or death.
Now...
taking the place
of your dead mother...
I'm giving you...
this shield.
There are but these five words
to remember:
[ Speaking Greek ]
- What does it mean?
- ''With this or on this.''
Either come home victorious
with this shield or dead on it.
Please excuse me.
[ Man ]
Congratulations.
[ Man #2 ]
Happy day, Phylon. Congratulations.
We, the elders of Sparta,
have a sacred duty to perform.
We are the guardians
of Spartan blood.
It is for us to see to it that
that precious blood is not shed...
whatever the occasion may be...
far away from our native soil.
Then you suggest that
we do not send our men north.
Not above Corinth, Taemes.
We have no common cause with empty
talkers of Athens and their sinful ways.
We must defend southern Greece,
where we have our homes and our allies.
Greetings.
- Greetings, King Leotychides.
- Greetings, King Leonidas.
Greetings, friends.
I bear important news.
Sparta has been selected
to lead the united Greek cities
in the war against Persia...
both on land and on the sea.
- Athens has surrendered
her naval leadership to us.
- [ Muttering ]
- Shh! But it's for the council
to decide how Sparta acts.
- Of course.
- But the council must act quickly.
- Why?
In order that we Spartans may reach
the first line of defense in time.
- And where might that be?
- The Pass ofThermopylae.
Thermopylae. Of course.
That's the pass that protects Athens.
No! It's a pass
that protects Greece.
Mere cities don't matter now.
It is Greece that counts!
Only by being united
can we hope to avoid slavery.
Now, I am no politician,
but I will plead this cause
with you until the moon wanes...
and the night
brings forth a new day.
Yes, Ellas.
Of course I'll speak to him
about you and Phylon.
You two
should be married.
What can be
keeping him so long?
He went straight to the council
without even stopping to see me.
He's never
done that before.
But, Aunt Gorgo,
this is a dangerous time.
Everyone is talking about the war
and our men marching north.
- Do you think that--
- [ Door Opens ]
I didn't even greet you.
Forgive me.
And you haven't asked
about your son.
- How is he? Is he well?
- Is he well?
[ Laughs ]
Today he fought with his toy sword...
against a boy a whole head taller
than he, and he defeated him.
You could hear his war cry
all the way to the marketplace.
Strong lungs
are no proof of wisdom.
You should have heard
old Xenathon speak tonight.
Shouting the isolation
of Sparta. He made me sick.
- But he loves our country.
- Not as much as he hates Athens.
He can never forget
that his two sons were killed
by the Athenians in fair battle.
Dead children are not easy
to forget, Leonidas.
To remember is one thing, but to grow
bitter in hatred, that's another.
That man is dangerous.
He could sway that council
to put me in a terrible position.
I could not disobey,
and I cannot break my word.
What word?
I promised Themistocles to lead
my men in defense ofThermopylae.
Thermopylae? But that's
so far away from Sparta.
To a Greek,
no part of Greece is far away.
You are tired, my love.
Before the sun rises,
you must rest.
It's past midnight.
See how dark the sky is?
When you left for Corinth,
I went to see Megistias...
the old priest.
He sacrificed a lamb
and read the entrails.
He said that there was wonderful
good fortune for both of us.
He said that you will be the Spartan
king best remembered amongst men.
- [ Both Chuckle ]
- And he said,
that for centuries to come...
women will sing songs...
about my love for you.
Leonidas, this man
brings an urgent message.
- What news?
- Themistocles begs us
to march north at once.
He says the whole
of Greece is waiting.
Ride back and tell him
we march today.
The urgent summons
from the council.
The prediction of the oracle
has just arrived from Delphi.
- Alert my bodyguard.
- Yes.
''Dwellers
in glorious Sparta...
''hear now
the words of your fate.
''Either your famous city goes down
in front of the Persians...
''or,
if your city is spared...
the land of Sparta must mourn
for the death of one of her kings.''
You may leave.
The priestess has spoken.
Yes.
And the meaning is clear.
It is either Sparta or a Spartan king.
I accept the challenge.
And, in your opinion,
what must be done?
The army must march at once.
There is no time to lose.
The council must grant
dispensation to the Spartans
to leave during the festival.
It is not the Spartan way
to neglect the holy festivals.
Nor to neglect Greece.
The alert order has gone out
to my personal bodyguard...
who are not subject
to the decisions of the council.
All the other troops
are waiting in their quarters.
Do not let them
wait long, friends.
Ellas.
Let me look.
Let me look at you.
How handsome you are.
The red war cloaks
are so becoming to men.
This way no enemy
will ever see Spartan blood.
Ellas, we may march tomorrow.
I must go to the king now.
Yes. Let us go.
I've spoken to my aunt already.
My father's gone to the king's house
and is waiting.
Seems that all my life
I've waited for just this day.
At last you're
going to be my wife.
- The wife of a real Spartan soldier.
-lust wait till I come back.
I'll bring ten Persian slave girls
to wait on you hand and foot.
Oh. Bring just one
and you'll be a dead Spartan.
Now, as soon as the council
proclaims a state of war...
the whole army will
come under my orders...
while King Leotychides...
in accordance with the law,
will remain at home.
Pentheus, son of Sallus,
will be my second in command.
I thank you
for honoring me.
- May I put forward a personal request?
- Of course, Pentheus.
My daughter Ellas is waiting outside
with young Phylon.
He asked permission to speak to you
about a matter concerning...
both our families.
Let them come in.
- Speak, Phylon.
- Sir, I've come to ask
your permission to marry Ellas...
daughter of Pentheus.
Her father's granted his consent,
but my father is away
on family business in Thrace...
and might be
detained by the war.
I beg you to act
in his stead.
- When did you last
hear from your father?
- Not since he left Sparta, sir.
He was supposed to return
way before now.
Have you any idea
what might have caused this delay?
No, sir.
Is there anything wrong?
Agathon believes so.
While I was being tortured
by the Persians...
I saw your father
in the enemy camp.
- No. Not my father.
- He was there with ex-king Demaratus.
- Why, that's not possible.
- I'm not used to telling lies.
Why, you...
may have been mistaken.
I tell you
I spoke to him!
He still bears the mark
of my whip on his face.
Sir, I beg you, by the immortal gods,
let me wipe out this disgrace.
Put me in the first line of battle.
Let me die a Spartan.
As a freeborn man, you are not
responsible for your father's actions...
yet % cannot ask my soldiers
to accept into their ranks...
a man whose father is
consorting with the enemy.
- But, sir--
- That is my final word.
You will surrender your war cloak
to the officer on duty.
You may go.
I cannot
find him anywhere.
I'm frightened.
I don't know what to do.
Take hold of yourself.
Sparta gives her women
more freedom than any state.
In return,
it demands strength.
How can I be strong?
I love him.
You must be strong.
Remember the Spartan mother
who killed her son when he came home
with a wound in his back.
Why should I remember? Phylon
would never turn his back to the enemy.
If only they would
let him fight.
I am not a general. I cannot order
the men to take him with them.
How can you talk like this?
You know Phylon.
- His mother was your best friend.
- That does not matter.
- Have you heard?
- Heard what?
The council has made its decision.
Here it is:
''People of Sparta,
the army will presently march...
''in defense of our land
against the Persian king.
The men are hereby ordered
to depart immediately after
the sacred festival of Carnea.''
- So you cannot go today.
- I can and I will.
- And disobey the council?
- My personal bodyguard is not
subject to the council's orders.
- But that's only 300 men.
- I promised to have
my men at Thermopylae.
- I didn't say how many.
- But... this is madness.
Less so than to celebrate
a festival and lose the war.
- Leave us, please, Ellas.
- Yes, Aunt G--
Oh, Ellas.
You know how sorry I am.
I know.
Leonidas...
why not wait until
the festival is over...
and then lead out the whole army
as a Spartan king should lead it?
It's only a few days.
No, even today
might be too late.
- All Greece waits
for the Spartans to march.
- A mere 300 men?
Since when have Spartans started
counting numbers going into battle?
- I know, but--
- We are but a vanguard.
The rest will join us
just as soon as the festival is over.
But what if the Persians
attack you before then?
Then we shall
fight alone.
Leonidas...
my love...
I know your courage.
I am proud of you.
But there are times
when prudence--
[ Sighs ]
I don't know what I am saying.
I only know I cannot
live without you.
You must trust me,
Gorgo.
I love you
more than life itself.
I don't want you to die.
It would be my end too.
Leonidas,
the men are ready.
Agathon, the law
allows me to take 300 men.
Dismiss all those with
no living sons, and replace
them with volunteers who have.
I don't want any Spartan family
to die out.
- Phylon!
- Ellas.
- Why are you here?
- Because I love you.
There is nothing to love now.
I've been rejected by my own people.
I have no honor, no country.
- No name, no home. I'm an outcast.
- I, too, am an outcast.
I've left my father's house,
and I shall not return
unless you come with me.
Sparta does not want me.
I'm ashamed of you. What if the king
has refused to take you with him?
You're a free man
and a soldier.
Prove it to him,
and he will take you back.
How can I prove it?
Surely not by
killing yourself.
Look.
- My shield.
- Yes. Your shield. You left it behind.
Did you forget the words
my aunt spoke, giving it to you?
Victory or death.
Take this shield.
Follow our soldiers.
Show them that you are
a man and a Spartan.
And I shall be there
watching you.
Look there.
Three hundred men to stand
against the whole of Asia.
No, 301 .
And all Spartans.
Halt!
This is the Bay of Locris,
where we're to meet with Themistocles.
Yes.
In the meantime,
we'll rest here until sundown.
Then we'll march all night.
We must be in Thermopylae by sunrise.
Look.
There he is now.
[ Leonidas ] Take Themistocles
to that fisherman's hut.
- Do you want to bathe, Ellas?
- No.lust to rest.
- Are you ill, Ellas?
- No. Of course not.
just tired and...
so cold somehow.
Yes.
You are shivering.
And you haven't eaten in two days.
I shouldn't have brought you with me.
We'll rest now.
Yes, we'll rest now.
[ Splash ]
We have 27 1 ships
lying in the straits.
The Persians are
in the bay beyond.
Twelve hundred warships,
with a good number of auxiliary craft.
Then we are
outnumbered six to one.
Yes, but geography
is on our side.
In the narrow waters,
we can give them a good fight.
- How many men have you brought?
- Three hundred Spartans.
- Three hundred?
- My personal bodyguard.
Other Spartans will follow
after the festival.
Another festival?
- We are religious people.
- I know.
Someday I may
enter religion myself.
It's better than politics.
With the gods behind you,
you can be far more irresponsible.
Themistocles, we invoked
divine help coming here.
This is no time
for impious remarks.
Forgive me...
friend.
- Greetings, friends. Leonidas.
- Demophalus.
We've heard that
all of Sparta's on the march.
I've been riding since sunrise,
trying to catch up with you.
- Your men move like lightning.
- They have an urgent
appointment at Thermopylae.
Yes, we heard
about that too.
Can my warriors
ofThespiae join you?
There's always room for good men.
How many of you?
About 7 00--
all volunteers.
I couldn't hold them back
when they heard about Sparta
leading us in this war.
- [ Laughing ]
- Where do we find you?
We'll be at Thermopylae at daybreak.
The rest of our armies join us there.
Wonderful. But don't start
the killing before we arrive.
You Spartans go wild
when you smell the enemy.
Leave some for us.
We are Greeks too.
- [ All Laughing ]
- At Thermopylae.
''We are Greeks too.''
Did you hear
what that man said?
Can this be the beginning of
the miracle we've been waiting for?
Let us pray so.
You know, Leonidas,
people call me a master politician.
Also a cynic, mountebank
and a charlatan. They're all wrong.
%'m nothing but
a sentimental old fool...
desperately in love
with a dream:
One, free united Greece.
That is no dream.
I think we should have told
Demophalus that we are only
300 Spartans at this moment.
And ruin all my work?
I've sent 20 runners round
with the news that the entire
Spartan army is marching north.
- But that's not true.
- Truth is a heady wine, friend.
A politician must never exaggerate
people's capacity for it.
I thank the gods
I am only a soldier.
And I thank them
I'm a politician.
Between us, we may make
our dream come true.
I must get back
to my boats.
Get the men ready.
[ Man ]
Halt!
Exit.
Spartans, we have
reached Thermopylae.
The orders are:
From this wall,
we do not retreat.
Somebody.
Somebody!
Greetings, friends.
Ephialtes, bring some water.
Oh, she is ill.
Poor child.
- [ Whimpers ]
- Ephialtes! Where is that fool?
- Ephialtes!
- Your wife?
Thermopylae.
How far is it?
Not far.lust over
those cliffs there.
- You see, if you go by--
- Be quiet. Quiet.
- And then you--
- [ Whimpering ]
[ Gurgles,
Coughs ]
Take her inside.
Carry her.
- [ Whimpers ]
- Gently. Don't hurt her.
Hmph. Goats have
more brains than men.
Who can understand
the way of gods?
They create
lovely girls...
and then turn them
into wives.
Hmm. You are the first strangers
to visit us in years.
It was kind of you
to give us shelter.
We have been herding goats here in the
mountains all our lives, my wife and I.
She'll be better
by sunrise.
But her feet
are all swollen and sore.
- Our home is far away.
- Athens?
By the gods, no.
Have you not heard of Sparta?
Yes. They speak little,
fight much...
eat the black broth
that turns up the stomach...
and their girls
go about naked.
- Naked?
- That's what I heard.
- When?
- W-W-When I was young.
[ Woman ]
Ephialtes, more milk?
No.
I'm going to look
after the goats.
I heard a wolf last night
in the mountains.
- Your son?
- Do you think we'd have
a son like that?
We don't know
where he came from.
He just arrived one day,
said he had quarreled with
the people down in the valley.
Maybe a runaway slave,
maybe a thief.
But in the mountains...
everyone is equal.
Have you heard anything
about the Persians?
We see them when it's clear.
Come with me.
Look.
Between those two hills.
- Have they been there long?
- For several days.
And they are still coming.
More campfires every day.
Lucky for us that Thermopylae
is the only way through the mountains.
You mean it's lucky that the Persians
don't know the other way.
- Is there another way?
- Yes.
There is an old goat track.
It winds through the mountains...
and it comes down
beyond the pass.
Nobody uses it now,
but it's still there.
We must let the Spartans
in the pass know about this.
- If the Persians found out about it,
our men would be trapped.
- Yes.
King Xerxes would give much gold
to know about it, wouldn't he?
Come inside.
It's getting cold.
We'll talk there.
I don't want you
to get sick too.
[ Man Yelling %n Distance ]
[ Yelling Continues ]
This is called
the Middle Gate ofThermopylae.
It is too narrow
for fighting in open order.
We will use our special tactics
for close-in fighting.
And the rest can learn
from watching the Spartans.
- [ Men Yelling %n Distance ]
- Shall we keep the men
in their own units?
Yes. Men prefer
to die among their friends.
- Who are you?
- I am a goatherd.
I know these
mountains well.
I have come to tell you there is a path
leading through them from the north.
It's a bad path,
but the Persians could use it.
We know there is a path. Our scouts are
looking for it, but they can't find it.
I can show the way. It runs
by the Callidromus Mountain.
We'd better hurry, sir.
The accursed barbarians
are probably looking for it too.
Agathon, dispatch all
the Phocian troops.
- Have them block that path
and guard it.
- Yes, Leonidas.
Thank you, my friend.
If I had gold,
I would give it to you.
But all we have
is our armor.
- Take with you
the best sword you can find.
- I don't do this for gold.
And I am too old to use a sword.
If I were younger...
I would bring my own sword
and be standing with you in battle.
Let's go, friend.
It's a long walk.
Xerxes has men in millions.
We have Greek.
[ Men Yelling %n Distance ]
[ Horn Sounds ]
I cannot really believe there's
only this one pass through
the mountains, Demaratus.
I've not heard
of another one, my lord.
- Where is the main Greek army?
- My lord...
our scouts
swam past Thermopylae.
The Greeks are
camped far beyond it.
Still only a small force.
I presume they are waiting for more men.
The more the better.
If they insist on fighting,
we can wipe them all out in one battle.
What about
the pass itself?
Still held by
just a few Spartans.
Some are rebuilding
the wall.
Others are just sitting on the rocks
and sharpening their weapons.
- The fools.
- Not a good sign, my lord.
It means that the Spartans
will certainly fight...
whether reinforcements
arrive or not.
Why, they are mad.
I cannot think why you want
to be king of such
an extraordinary people, Demaratus.
I shall capture them alive
and put them in cages and
exhibit them all over Persia.
[ Man ]
My king.!
Cyrus!
My brother.
How did this happen?
Speak!
We were on patrol,
my lord...
near the pass.
Suddenly the Spartans
came at us like devils...
swarms of them.
We fought, but it was a narrow place
and we could not get near them.
Hydarnes, see that my brother's body
is buried with full honors.
And as for these cowards...
let them be buried too.
- My lord--
- Alive!
No. My lord...
as a soldier,
death is my duty.
And if I offend you,
I shall be glad to die for it.
But I fear
that I must warn you.
- Well?
- You have been listening
to bad advice, my lord.
If we had occupied
the pass--
I know that I've listened
to some people too much...
but that period is over.
- Mardonius.
- My lord?
Tomorrow at dawn,
we take the pass and march on.
I want no prisoners
or slaves in this war.
Every Greek is to be
put to the sword.
Very good,
my lord.
Give your men this one night...
then destroy
all the soldiers' women.
There are enough women
in Sparta and Athens...
and I want my men
to be eager to get at them.
Very good,
my lord.
Well done, Myron. Not many of
that Persian patrol got away.
Oh, it was easy, sir.
Five of us and only ten of them.
[ Chuckling ]
- [ Horns Sounding ]
- There is some movement
in the enemy camp, sir.
It looks as though
they intend to attack in the morning.
We need one more day
to finish rebuilding that wall.
We must gain that day.
Isn't that the king's tent
near the shore?
Yes.
Pick out 30 men for me,
all good swimmers.
I could swim the Evrotas River
when I was a boy of four.
No, Agathon. You must stay here.
I want you to take over command.
But if
you're killed--
Why, then Greece will fight
all the more fiercely.
But without Xerxes, all that
great horde would fall to pieces.
Have the men assemble
by that rock at sundown.
I'm going to stay here tonight.
Go back, friend, and thank you.
The orders are silence
and speed.
If I am killed,
Pentheus will take command.
[ Revelry %n The Distance ]
[ Arabian ]
[ Revelry Continues ]
[ Continues ]
- Run!
- [ Commotion ]
Let me go! Oh!
Silence.
Where's the king?
Gone away
to visit the queen.
[ Women Screaming ]
[ Yelling, Screaming ]
[ Commotion Continues ]
[ noisy Commotion ]
[ Man ]
My queen.!
Come.
General alarm.
There is a great fire on the shore.
The king's camp
is burning.
Go and see that my boat
is made ready.
[ Commotion Continues ]
[ Men Shouting ]
%'ll kill you both.!
- How is it?
- It missed the main artery, I think.
We shall see now.
[ Grunts ]
This day will pass in peace.
I see it on the barb.
The blood
curdles well.
As always, Megistias,
your omens speak truthfully.
The Persian camp is disrupted. It'll
take them all day to put it together.
[ Chuckles ]
- Where's that young fool?
- Here.
He-He saved my life,
Leonidas.
I know that.
He also disobeyed
his orders.
In wartime, the punishment is death.
You know that, Phylon.
- Yes.
- So death it will be.
Get him his armor
and a red cloak.
That's the only way
for Spartans to die these days.
[ Laughing ]
[ Women Screaming ]
Half the camp burned!
Myself almost captured!
And all by a handful of Greeks.
Where were your men, Hydarnes?
These Spartans are scarcely human,
my lord.
They see in the night
like cats!
This is no answer!
I'm surrounded
by incompetent fools!
Fear, panic, disorder.
How can this happen to the army
that was made to conquer the world?
Panic started amongst
the conscript savages.
By the end of the day,
we shall restore order.
But this day
is already lost...
and the Spartans
are still in the pass!
By noon tomorrow, I want to see
every one of them destroyed...
or all of you
will forfeit your lives!
Leave me!
- [ Women Screaming ]
- Come on now.!
They're killing our women.!
[ Woman ]
Let me go! Let me go!
[ Commotion Continues ]
- Phylon.
- Ellas.
Oh, Phylon,
you're a Spartan again.
Yes. Leonidas took me
back into the army.
You must've done
something wonderful.
Nothing any other Spartan
wouldn't have done.
But, Ellas,
how are you now?
My fever's all gone.
Old Toris made me a bowl of herbs.
She's so kind.
I can look at you again.
I'm no longer ashamed of myself.
I've never
been ashamed of you.
I knew you were
always a good soldier, but--
Yes?
I've been watching
Samos and Toris.
They're such good
and simple people.
They know nothing
about honor and glory.
But Toris knows that every night
her man will be sleeping at her side.
They live for themselves.
They do no harm.
Is it a crime
to want to live in peace?
No, Ellas, but you
shouldn't speak like that.
Why, you yourself
gave me the shield.
I know. I know it all.
I know that for a Spartan, life
is a kind of preparation for death.
But why should
a love like ours go down...
and be trampled
in dirt and blood?
We must be ready
to die for our country, Ellas.
But we don't have to die. I want
to live and come to you with victory.
Victory? Did you see the enemy
in the plain out there?
And there are
only 300 of you.
We have men from other cities
with us, many of them good men.
But everybody expects
the Spartans to die first.
Why hasn't
the Spartan army arrived?
- They will come.
- When?
I don't know,
but they will come.
Our people won't abandon us.
[ Hoofbeats ]
Those are the brown horses
of Leonidas.
Yes. And that's
my aunt's servant riding them.
Must be an important message from
Sparta. I must get back to camp.
Ellas, I must go.
My wife is a very clever woman.
Even if the messenger
had been captured...
no one would have guessed that there
was a message hidden under the wax.
[ Chuckles ]
Shall we leave you alone,
Leonidas?
No.
This news concerns us all.
Our troops
are not coming.
Why, Leonidas?
The council made a secret decision
to fortify the Isthmus of Corinth...
and not to go beyond it.
- Then we cannot stay here!
- We can! And we must!
We received
no orders to leave...
and we have
our duty to Greece.
Other Greeks followed us here
because they believed in our word...
and we are not
going to break it.
Here we stay!
- And here we stand!
- For how long?
Until we win!
Or die!
Greetings, friends.
What are the omens?
Last night a mountain lioness came down
to the pass with three of her cubs.
She cried piteously,
as if begging mercy for her children.
This is a bad omen
for Persia.
I accept the omen. The Spartans
will meet the first attack.
The rest of the troops will stand by
in reserve until I send for them.
My men want to fight,
Leonidas.
All Greeks want to fight,
but the Spartans were here first.
We will lead and the others will watch
us, ready to move in when ordered.
To your places, friends.
- How many all together?
- Twenty thousand, my lord.
And the rest of the army
are ready to march through the pass
after it's been cleared.
- We should be in Athens in four days.
- Good.
I've ordered Mardonius to draw up the
Sagartian horsemen behind the infantry.
just before coming
into contact with the enemy...
the cavalry will surprise the Spartans
and take them alive.
Excellent, my lord.
I shall have Leonidas
nailed to a board...
and watch him die
as we eat our meal at noon.
[ Chuckles ]
Come. Let us
enjoy this in peace.
[ Horns Sounding ]
The enemy is on the move, sir,
drawing near to us.
Good. It also means that
we are drawing nearer to them.
Spears.!
They intend to surprise us
by faking an infantry charge.
Pass the word to Agathon
and Pentheus.
Be ready for horsemen.
- Cavalry.
[ Horns Sounding ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Yelling Continues ]
Spartans... attack.!
Squadron, advance.!
Drive them into the sea.!
Don't let them escape.!
- What does this mean?
- Leonidas has guessed
our maneuver, my lord!
He has killed
most of our horsemen...
forcing the rest back
to confound our foot soldiers.
- Then he attacked!
- He is slaughtering my men like sheep!
- The miserable cowards!
- No, my lord.
These men are a match
for any regular soldiers...
but the Spartans
fight like machines!
Leonidas. Leonidas.
- What news?
- A Persian herald.
Hydarnes wants to
speak with you.
- Hydarnes?
- Yes.
- Shall I bring him here?
- So he can see our defenses? No. Here.
Get me a clean cloak.
How many men
for your escort?
A Spartan king needs no escort
to talk to a mere Persian.
- Greetings, Leonidas.
- Greetings, Hydarnes.
The Great King admires
the valor of you and your men.
Thank him, and tell him we will earn
even more ofhis admiration today.
Stubbornness
will avail you nothing.
It's only a matter of time
before you lose this battle.
Perhaps...
but by that time,
you will have lost your war.
Yesterday we only
probed your defenses.
When we attack today...
our arrows
will blot out the sun!
Then we will fight
in the shade.
But this slaughter
is useless.
Surrender your arms...
and my king will spare
you and your Spartans.
What shall I tell him?
Moln labe.
Come and take them!
[ Men Yelling ]
Spears.!
[ Whistles ]
[ Yelling Continues ]
Archers.!
Spears.! Spears.!
[ Men Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Advance.! Advance.!
Out of our way!
[ Screaming ]
[ Men Yelling, Screaming ]
[ Yelling, Screaming Continues ]
The greatest army in the world
routed by these savages!
We are giving Leonidas
cheap victories, my lord.
Horses and chariots
cannot maneuver in that pass!
- I must see this pass
cleared this morning.
- And we must do it quickly!
- Send in the Immortals, my lord.
- My own bodyguard?
The are the only men we have
that can match the Spartans.
Once we have wiped out
the Spartan fanatics...
the rest of the Greeks
will give way.
Very well, Hydarnes.
But I hold you responsible.
[ Screaming, Yelling
%n Distance ]
Pentheus, what would you do now
if you were Xerxes?
Send in fresh troops--
my very best.
That is just
what he's doing.
These are his Immortals.
The whole Persian army is watching them.
If we beat them back,
fear will grip the others. Phylon!
We shall fall back
deliberately.
You will pretend to be dead
and stay here.
Put the torches
under the chariot.
To your places, friends.
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Screaming Subsides ]
[ Groans ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Yelling Continues ]
[ Commotion ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Yes.
And what
are we to do now?
It was your idea!
You told me to send in the Immortals!
You! You!
How can you expect these others
to fight after what they've seen today?
My lord...
you have the power
to have me slain.
Silence!
Death is too good for you!
Get out of my sight!
I don't want to see
your insolent face again!
Go!
Another day.
The Spartans
fought well.
So did the Thespians
and all the other Greeks.
We can hold
Thermopylae.
I've, uh-- I've waited for the time
when I could see you alone.
Why?
I'm-I'm going down
into the valley.
Look. This is
no place for you.
Come with me.
Come with me now.
I'll give you
rubies and gold.
Touch me again
and I'll strike you.
[ Chuckles ]
You strike me?
My lord.
Artemisia.
Surely you, at least,
must be the bearer of good tidings.
Would that I were.
Artemisia, you are hurt?
No, I'm all right. But your fleet had
no more success today than your army.
And three of my ships
were sunk.
Even the gods seem to
conspire against me.
My ships falter.
My troops in revolt--
seized by fear that spreads
like leprosy through the camp.
- What am I to do?
- Halt these senseless attacks...
which the Greeks are turning
into victories demoralizing your men.
Another day of this
and your own troops will destroy you.
You must stop this war.
With two of my brothers slain
and Leonidas still in the pass?
I've sworn to destroy him!
This is Hydarnes' fault!
When the Immortals failed,
all others lost heart.
Heart. Yes.
I'll have his heart
for this!
I'll have it cut out
and brought to me on a platter!
No! Then you'd
admit defeat.
There's
a better way.
- What is it?
- Even the greatest king
cannot defy the gods.
Tell your men you've
had a message from heaven...
to return to Persia.
By this you would
save your honor...
reaffirm
your divine origin...
and rob Leonidas
of victory.
Yes.
Yes!
[ Gongs ]
[ Chuckles ]
It was a dark day...
when the first woman
came into this world.
[ Xerxes ]
Mardonius.
- My lord.
- I've had a vision...
in which my father's shade
appeared to me.
He told me to destroy
the rebellious foreign troops...
go back to Persia
and collect a new army.
I dare not disobey him.
We march at sunrise.
Go and see
that all is made ready.
Very good,
my lord.
Now I know why
they call you Great King.
They tell me
your mother was a Greek...
and that you're a secret enemy
trying to destroy me with your advice.
[ Chuckles ]
If I could prove it,
I'd have your throat cut.
The bone is not broken
and none of the muscles are cut.
Let me seal the wound
with the iron.
Help him, Megistias.
We need such men.
[ Sizzling ]
[ Arabian ]
[ Music Ends ]
My lord!
- My lord.
- Yes?
I beg you to accept
this gift I bring to you.
- Gift? What gift?
- Victory!
- What sort of a joke is this?
- Ajoke, my lord?
This man will lead you to the victory
which you have forsworn so easily.
Listen to him!
Who are you?
My name is Ephialtes.
I live in these mountains.
What are you doing here?
I know a secret path
through these mountains.
- What secret path?
- An old goat track.
It comes down on
the other side ofThermopylae.
- Can you lead us there?
- You see, I'm a poor man.
Not anymore.
This is worth gold to you--
as much gold
as you can carry.
Take him away.
Hydarnes,
cancel all orders.
Take half the Immortals
and go with this man.
I will lead the troops
from this side.
We will attack at sunrise
and trap Leonidas.
Go.
Now you can have Greece as
I promised you, empty and beautiful.
- Doesn't that make you happy?
- What if this is a trap?
- A trap?
- Those mountains are treacherous.
You could lose
your whole army there.
You must have a dependable guide
other than that Greek traitor.
- Yes, but I have no one.
- Yes, you have.
Grellus, he's here
with Demaratus.
Why not let him
go with your troops?
Halt.!
Take me to the king.
I am Ellas...
daughter of Pentheus
and the queen's niece.
Follow me.
- Father!
- Ellas!
- Father! The Persians!
- What are you doing here?
The Persians are coming
through the mountains.
Phylon's father came to
the hut where % was staying.
- I led him here.
- We have been betrayed.
Hydarnes and his Immortals,
they're coming down behind you.
They broke through
your Phocian guard.
I escaped during the night
to warn you.
- You traitor.
- No!
If he was a traitor,
why is he here?
Call the Spartans
to arms.
Artemisia sent me,
Leonidas.
Phylon...
you ride back
through the pass.
Tell all Greek troops to retreat
before they're cut off.
- Then I can return, sir.
- No.
- I didn't come here to be a messenger!
- You're here to obey orders!
Phylon, the message
you carry today...
will buy centuries
of freedom for Greece.
Tell the Spartans that we are
staying here obedient to their word.
- Ellas, you must hurry.
- Ellas.
Ellas.
Tell my wife
to take care of our son.
Tell her that I am
thinking of them both.
I will, Leonidas.
Come, child.
Why are you here?
Take your men out.
My Thespians
are staying.
And disobeying me?
We obey
our honor.
Where
do we fight?
You're a bad soldier,
but a good Greek.
Go to the end
of the pass...
and hold it
as long as you can.
Here.
Only Spartans
with living sons...
have the privilege
to fight today.
And you've got
one of the best.
Come, old friend.
Today we carve out
our own omens.
Sir, the main body of the Greek army
escaped in the direction of Opus.
Who are left
in the pass?
The Thespians
are at one end...
the Spartans at the other
facing the army of the king.
What fools.
I wish I had men like that
fighting for me.
Immortals, march!
- [ Men Yelling ]
- %mmortals, attack.!
- [ Yelling Continues ]
- Thespians, advance! Attack!
Have you heard?
Agathon
has just told me.
We've been betrayed.
Take your ships
out of the straits at once.
This is our last morning
at Thermopylae.
I must move the fleet, but the ships
can still take you out of this.
No. We shall stay here.
What about
your wounded?
Spartan wounded go home
only with victory.
In defeat,
they die with the rest.
I would share this day
with you, Leonidas...
but I must be
with the fleet...
when it fights again
at Salamis.
I know you don't put much trust
in omens, Themistocles...
but last night Megistias
received a most wondrous vision.
Megistias,
tell him your vision.
I saw ships burning
between two shores--
many of them,
with Persian markings on their sails.
There was Xerxes sitting upon a marble
throne, his face wrapped in gloom...
listening to the cries
of burning men.
And behind him,
the goddess Athena, all in white...
a golden spear
in her hand.
She was smiling.
Tell him all.
And a voice was saying...
''Divine Salamis...
''you will bring death
to the enemies of Greece.
When the seeds are sown,
all their harvests are gathered in.''
Thank you, old man.
They're advancing, sir. King Xerxes
is leading them in his chariot.
I'll be right there.
We shall be watching you fight
at Salamis--
Megistias and I.
We shall not
fail you, friend.
Sir, Hydarnes is attacking
the Thespians in our rear.
We are cut off.
- And the others?
- All retreated safely.
Tell Demophalus to hold out
as long as he can.
Yes, sir.
Spartans!
The orders for the day:
We can no longer
defend the pass...
so we shall attack
and kill Xerxes!
[ Pipes ]
[ Continues ]
[ Horns Sounding ]
Fall into ranks!
Spartans, advance!
[ Yelling, Screaming ]
[ Yelling, Screaming Continues ]
Right flank,
advance!
Get the body of Leonidas!
Fall back.! Fall back.!
Halt!
[ Yelling ]
Right! Halt!
Circle! Circle!
[ Yelling Continues ]
[ Yelling Fades To Silence ]
My lord, your Immortals have destroyed
the Greek rear guard to the last man!
You hear
Hydarnes' message?
Go deliver my final offer
to the Spartans.
The Immortals have wiped out
your rear guard...
but the Great King
grants you your lives.
Give us the body of Leonidas
and you can depart.
We stay with our king.
Your position is hopeless.
In a few moments
you will be dead.
But Greece will live.
Hyah!
- Speak.
- My king, they will not surrender.
Shall we attack,
my lord?
I shall waste
no more of our men.
Finish them with arrows.
Archers!
[ narrator ]
'Oh, stranger...
tell the Spartans that we lie here
obedient to their word. ''
This last message
of the fallen heroes...
rallied Greece to victory...
first at Salamis,
as predicted...
and then at Plataea.
But it was more than
a victory for Greece.
%t was a stirring example...
to free people
throughout the world...
of what a few brave men
can accomplish...
once they refuse
to submit to tyranny.