Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
"The fiancée painted the eyelashes"
"and it passed lipstick."
"She was to the bathroom and colored her hair."
"She caught her pretty dress and all the her bracelets"
"But something is lacking.  What is lacking?"
-His ring.  -Not.
His earrings.
-Not.
"The fiancée painted the eyelashes"
"And it passed lipstick...  She caught her pretty dress"
"And all her bracelets.  She was to the bathroom. ..”
-You are lucky.
-It have not fear, also stayed fiancée.
-Who is he?
-Riddle!
-That!
-Bingo!
-As guessed?
-I also would have chosen.
Looks what did I bring.
-TO near is to its daughter Myriam!
-We are all of friends.
Do a "youyou" for Nour and Khaled.
Look at him, look!  You are the fiancée.
do Not be ashamed.
-Then Nour, his marriage is when?
-When the Khaled arrange job.
expect Not a long time!  My neighbor was fiancée for 10 years.
THE fiancé of her died.  Today do not want even a sheep
for take care.
-we Go, Antonietta!  Not, i prefer the Italian things.
"ORDER 100 GRAMS OF BREAD"
TO THE BIG one MUFTI OF JERUSALEM:
THE NATIONAL MOVEMENT German SOCIALIST
DECLARED WAR TO THE JUDAISM.
FOLLOW WITH CLOSE INTEREST BY Arabian DOS AGAINST THE Jewish PIGS IN THE
Palestinian one...
Reich Fuhrer
SS Heinrich Himmler
Tunisia, November of 1942.
-as much as costs the tomato?
-Twenty cents.
Is very costly.
My money does not give.
we Go going.
German, I never saw men like this.
They are well polite
have blond hair and blue eyes.
Here between us, if one of they pass nearby me
-I am not going to escape.
-Neither I.
what did you learn how today?
-Nothing.
-She was expels.
-Chose the wrong day.
-Already does not it suffice I to have been dismissed!
-Then goes teach me nothing?
-It is not for his beak.
Knows to sew and cook.  Khaled is satisfied.
-My mother is barge.
-To mine also.
Say...  It does time that will want ask you...
But do not I dare.
Vents.  Say!
By that his mother lost the job?
because of the France...
why?
I do not know.  Do not they be necessary more of us.
Tita!
Comes here.
Because not paid?
I said that I am going to pay in the near time.  You know to our situation.
Always speaks that.  I interest, you are like to my sister
but I stayed bothered.  Of the near time without money,
swims of bath.
I Promise that I will bring the money.  I interest by the grave of my
husband.
It is difficult pull out a cent of a Jew!
They are worse than the French.
It leaves the Germans will earn the war that the French are branded!
They go to earn.
Myriam!
-Everything well?
-Everything.
AND you?
Not with himself sleep.
I also not.
is going to sleep with me?
Expect for me.
-Good morning.
Good morning.
Nour?
Come!
Light for Tita.
-My husband...
-Yes.
I want to speak with you.
-What is happening?
-Khaled want to know the date about the marriage.
-He found work?
-Not, still not.
-Without work does not have marriage!
-He is our cousin.
As goes to maintain?
Without work there is not marriage.
God that forgives me!
what are doing?
-Laughing.  Grave?
Come, come help me.
to have dressed in my room.
-Antonietta!
-A lot good.
repair-them and with the money you payment the grocery store.
-Tita?
-Yes.
-TO my mother sent.
-It obliged, Nour.
Which the problem?
did Not hear the radio this morning?
Comes here.
Come with me.
is going to sit down with me.
Nour, the world is cruel.
Expect, I will give a broth Molokheya.
what is?
You must help me.  I need to speak with Khaled.
Is able to help me?
-Mum, and that red dress?
-It is an use-him in the synagogue.
Not, I will use the blue one.
Not, done not look good in you.
-Clear that not.  -Arrives!
-Goes for me, if will want to earn the Raoul.
-I do not want.
Goes yes!  Afterwards than got ready in the school.
It is not time of sing songs against the marshal.
Nour, tidies up the dress.
-Mum, the dress is not ready.
-Then it walks soon, is tomorrow.
do Not I have time.  I need to teach to Nour.
The Germans permitted you in the school?
Alone when arrive the allied.
meanwhile, you can sew dressed.
"You and You, this concert was offered by the cabinetmaker"
“...Da Gallery Barbes.  We expect that has liked."
"Cheer itself!  This is the program of the cabinetmaker."
"He brings for you big names of the spectacle."
"He studied scientifically a wax"
"that dry quickly, the wax Barbes,"
"with exuberant brilliance, his piece catalogue."
"I am the famous cabinetmaker of the marvelous Galleries Barbes. ..”
"Yesterday was the time of ours dear Tunisia"
"it to be bombarded by the British and American."
"Since it is a war against the Jews,"
"and with the occupation of the North of the Africa by the friends of the Jews,"
"we thank to the Germans for the decision of compensate the civil victims"
"with a substantial amount in cash, imposed penalty to the Jews."
"They understand the high risk"
"that signifies the Jews, wherever be."
"The super total of penalty requested the twenty millions of french currency."
"Sum that the more quick possible should be paid."
"the most determined adversary of our trial and of the Third one Reich."
-Expect in the parlor.
-It obliged.
Knows Paris?
I Studied medicine there.
Stayed up to occupation, when I had that come back here.
AND you,
say me...
-what does you like?
-Nothing.
Likes my house?
You never speak nothing?
In The school say that you do not close the rattle.
-As knows?
-The entire city knows.
Myriam!
Come Back there.
-Be kind with him.
-Do not it marry him.
When poor man is been, there is not a lot choice.
You eat and stayed quiet.
You would leave me die in the misery?
That man is a present of God.
Will Bring honors Him and happiness.
AND above all, he will go help us to pay the fine.
Myriam...
I find...  In the beginning did not like his father...
But then...
I Learned how to like he.
Myriam.
IS the war.
Piece to his God a solution for the fine.
"Omnipotent god,"
"Myriam need 20 millions of french currency for pay the fine."
we Will See.
Itself will not go possible, should ask to the Raoul.
Like This that find-him.
Never!
AND he lives far away!
Will Be that we will not be able to see?
For...  For...
For...
AND...  First...  First...
Its.
You already read?
-AND the Arabian book?
-Also.
Well.
Found work?
Still not.
-You should find!
-I know.
-By that you will want see me?
-My father want to cancel the marriage.
be Not concerned.
I Will Find a work.
I should go.  Myriam stayed concerned.
-what is that?
-The North American.
-This is for you.
-For me?
-do Not I know is going to be served.
-Experimente.
Uses Him when will be with the Khaled.
-IS for you.
-It obliged.
Already kissed the Khaled?
-Yes.
-As was?
Incredible.
"The fiancée painted the eyelashes"
"and it passed lipstick"
"She was to the bathroom"
"and it colored the hair."
"She caught her dressed pretty"
"and all her bracelets"
"But something is lacking.  The fiancée. ..”
My God...
Where is the baker?
-what we are going to do?
-I do not know.
They bombarded us every day.
"The Americans and the British bombarded you"
"because they are going to occupy their country."
"They are friends of the Jews, and we of the Moslems."
"They present this pamphlet"
"and they will be received like friends."
we Go although.
-I Expect will have deed a good couscous.
-I also.
I asked for her, but her thoughts are somewhere else.
By that use so much oil?  I tired of repeat.
-Excuse Me, lady.  -It is to same thing always.
They understand nothing.  They are some idiots, a disaster.
Calms, she is tormented by the attacks.
-what is that?  Do not we have bread...
-Everything well...
-Mum, does not import.
-Always it speaks that.
-does Not have to reap.
-They did not bring to reap...
Certain, we are going to eat, mother.  It dismisses itself will not be
satisfied.
-But you...
-Always speaking of the maid!
-we Be able to eat?  It obliged.
-Is a delight.
-Did time that did not eat that.
-We go to speak of the marriage.
Give Us a list of the his invited.
Barely the family, do not we be able to squander.
-do Not I know as go to pay.
-We find a way.
Obliged, Raoul.
-Excuse, but I will leave after the supper.
-Why?
-I also, I have several consultations.
-Come back for the hospital?
-Because works so much?
-Because still I have a job!
Yes, obliged Sid Mustapha.
-That God blesses you.
-The pleasure is all mine, lady.
there was more four doctors.  I was not alone.
Leave of Paris finding that here went calmer.
That misfortune its.
Sid Mustapha, what finds of the political situation?
Nobody is threatened by the nazi publicity.
Grave?
AND the communists have a straight relation with the nationalists.
we are going to convince them it fight against the powers of the axis.
I Find that we will obtain.
we Have the even objective one:
"The independence of the Tunisia."
-I Saw Moslems collect pamphlets.
-Help to my mother.
I can lead his plate?
-Yes, that fine removed my appetite.
-We are going to resolve everything.
Obliged, Raoul.
-Forgives It.
-Where you go?
Where are going?
Come Back for the table.
Do an effort, dear.
IS for its well, Myriam.
IS the war.
Is very pretty.
-You it knows?
-Yes.
can ask him for expect outside?  Do not I want this people here.
Raoul!
Nour!
Shows Me what the Raoul bought him.
IS pretty!
Is lucky.  Khaled never nothing gives me.
be Not concerned.  A day he gives.
-He still did not find work?
-Is difficult now...
For us also is difficult.
-Here, now is its.
-Not.
-Pegue..
-Not, it is a present.
please, stayed...
AND Raoul?
I say to him that I lost.
-He never is going to believe.
-Yes, goes.
AND what do I say to the Khaled?
I do not know.
You found in the ground.
Found while collected some pamphlets.
IS truth.
I Am able to you ask a thing?
Yes.
I like to review Khaled.
Certain.
Not concerned, I am going to find a skill.
-IS even?
-Yes.
AND I am going to work and earn money.
-You spoke with my father?
-Not, still not.
March is good for you?
-why?
-Our marriage.
Arrive more nearby.
My baby.
His eyes, his lips...
-We go there.  -Not.
-I Expect yearly.
-Everyone expects.
Permit-me, please.
I beg, mine dear.
-You does not love me more?
-Yes.
Excuses.
-Count of the first time that saw me.
-I already said.
we Go, say.
-When I knew you, I knew that...
-And then?  And then?
you were the cousin with who should marry, but neither knew yourself.
As knew?
-I trembled at the right moment.
-And now?
-Yes.
-Fast, I do slowly.
have Not fear.
Myriam!
I Am here.
what is doing?
Who is?
Who is, Myriam?
were doing "that"?
My God, my daughter is a dog!
-what will I say to the Raoul?
-Do not I want him marry me.
Silences the mouth!
Itself your father was alive, you would lead a thrashing.
Itself was alive, I would not be necessary marry me.
Silences the mouth, furious!
Saw?  It is all bungled.
I buy a news.
When begins it work?
do Not I know.
Tomorrow I go to the "Herr Commandant".
Will Work for the Germans?
Yes.
IS good people.
They promised us independence.
I did not know.
there is many things that do not know.
I go teach you.
Who is?
-what did you do with him?
-Everything.
Everything the what?
He put that in my mouth and...
Myriam...
Delivered this to his mother, for the expenses of the marriage.
-AND?
-Is everything well.
Obliged, you saved our lives.
does Not have problem.  Is everything well.
there is not problem, Tita.
I Have a question about the night of marriage...
Would Like the marriage in oriental or western style?
Oriental...
Boldness!
Is going to be pretty for the night of marriage.
As was that night with Khaled?
-He obtained work!
-That kind of work?
He did not say.
Raises-Itself.
I have a friend whose neighbor was with jealousies and will want her fiancé.
In the night of marriage she played a spell:
TO about him did not go up!
The father of her it killed when saw that the sheet was not dirty?
Miserable, carried this bale by all her life!
-That family is this!?
-Which is, all the neighborhood knows about that!
I know who he is.
You should be clears for please your husband.
have Not fear.
His husband want you soft as silk.
Already is going to pass.
Relax, the pain passes.
Is everything well.
Saw?  Its skin is silky.
Ready.
I need him say and show.
Fails now!  Where is the remainder?  His sons, its husband?
I do not know, I not entendo French.
-what did she say?
-That does not understand French.
we are going to lead more male hostages.
Where is the remainder of its family?
does Not have.  My husband is dead
and to my daughter is married.
-She says that lives alone.
-It finds that yes?
Not, the daughter still lives here.  But by the schedule should be in the
school.
please...  I did nothing, I pay the fine, I...
-what do we do?
-It find everybody.
Jewels, money and sewing machine.  We are going to lead everything.
-there is not nothing.
-They conceal everything.
Mum!  Mum!
Mum!
Nour!  Nour!
Bitch!
Good morning, Myriam, everything well?
Good morning.
Everything well?
Everything well.
what did?  I not entendo.
Alone God knows, my daughter.
-what are doing here?
-Nothing.
By that caught the pamphlets in the street?
By curiosity.
-Khaled obtained work?
-Not.
-He said him something?
He came behind us with the Germans and French.
stole Us and injured my mother.
-Khaled did wrong nothing.
-He was joined.
-He was not.
-I saw.
Saw wrong, and what do you have against Khaled?
Feels jealousies?
I will want to have to its life.
say Not an about those, Myriam.
"At last...  Last news:"
"As result of the decision of the Colonel Rauf"
"and in conformity with the messages in the streets of Tunis,"
"the German authorities require a cash of 2,000 Jewish workers"
"for the preparation of land and opening of trenches."
"All of the valid Jewish men must be presented tomorrow"
"to the 08:00 of the morning"
"in the Jewish workers recruitment center"
"they provided with spade and a pickaxe."
"No Jewish inhabitant is"
"exempt of that obligation. ..”
-Age?
-Thirty years.
-Profession?
-Locksmith.
-Health?
-I cough very.
we are going to hear.
Coughs!
Of news.
Felix Haddad!
-Age?
-Fifty.
-Profession?
-Medical.
Lie, I know you.  You are a carpenter.
Treacherous!
-Treacherous!
-Bastard!  You are not a man!
For backwards!  Arrives with that!
I would have deed to same thing.
THE decision was not mine of barely put the poor men.
You are an accomplice.
Who took the decision?
The leaders of the community.  We receive orders for protect the elite.
hat is horrible.
what can I do?
Dismiss Itself.
I resign, I will have that leave.
Always need doctors.
IS what do you want?
I am not going to be fiancée of a coward.
Knows by that I chose you in the synagogue?
Not.
what did you do in the school.  I will want help you.
AND this bra?
IS news.
-AND with that money you bought?
-It is a present.
whose?
-Because you want to know?
-Is with clothes of another one person.
we are Not beggars.
-Who gave that?  -A woman.
Who?
Myriam?
Removes Him.
-why?  -It removes him.
does Not must dress like a prostitute for me.  Strip that!
do Not I want that you and Myriam continue seeing.
Everything well.
Well.
"The fiancée painted the eyelashes"
"And it passed lipstick.
She was to the bathroom"
"And it colored the hair.  It caught a pretty dress"
"and all her bracelets"
"but something is lacking"
"What is lacking?"
-His ring.
-Not.
Gives Me a son.
I Want a son like this that I come back...
Here.
Itself seen.
We speak about that when I come back.
Obliged.
Caught the my things?
-Put a little of food inside.
-It obliged.
I should go.
His father the wait outside.
I know.
-Raoul!
-Yes?
does Not go.
IS very late.
It be not concerned, Oum Khaled.  My daughter is perfect healthy.
I find that is thin a little.
Here, his money.  More is worth late than never.
Inspection!  Nobody is going to leave!
You cannot enter!
Of foot!
-Is without veil.
-Really, respect nothing.
-Stop-na!
-It conceal in the bathroom!
IS my sister.  She is a Moslem.
-Moslem?
-This is the veil of her.
"There is only a God and Maomé is his prophet."
"There is only a God"
"and Maomé is his prophet."
Suffices!
we Go, we lead six of them.
what did in the bathroom?
-Nothing.
-It answer!
-By The question someone would be mistreated.
-Not, never.
Alone went a Jew.
does Not fail like this.  I am not you recognizing.
we Go there.
I like to live in a beautiful house.
I also.
Would Like that our son went for the university.
...Por that the Jews were the that had right to everything?
Because the French law is for them and not for us?
While this land is ours!
You find this normal?  It finds?
They also are in their country, and healthy poor as we.
is Not truth.
You know about nothing.  You did not read.
what should I read for understand?
IS difficult of read.  His French is not good enough.
Read the Koran.
is going to begin of new?
Promises?
-You are necessary visit me in the town.
-Do not I be able to, is very
distant...
You can come from bicycle, is more quick.
-You know that do not I know to walk.
-I go teach you.
I saw Khaled.
Spoke with him?
Not.
AND you, has spoken with him?
About the what?
-About me.
-About you.
Hear, is politics.  You cannot understand.
I want to know everything.
Imagines in his place.  Before, he did not have work
because we are a country explored.
The French alone explore us, and you, Jewish, do nothing.
Steal our wealth, our work.  By that you go to the school and I not?
By that I use a veil and you not?
By that you can leave without that nobody do comments
and I... for me they always speak something!
Because I cannot leave?  Why?
By that that says?
-Because is the truth.
-It is not.
IS truth yes.
Raoul does politics by Mustapha for us liberate.
You like the Raoul now?
-You still likes the Khaled?
-Yes.
what does he do is for help our people.
anyway, political is not for you.
Is different.
Not, I am not different.
Myriam, you are different.
-Is different, Myriam.  -
It leaves go me.
Mum!
what was?
what was, girl?
"Who desires an unlike religion the Islam,"
"that will not be recognized in the heaven,"
"and in the life will be between the dissatisfied?"
Nour, what was?
Swims.  I am looking the well.
"Hello, this is the fiancée"
"Hello, Nour, mine dear"
Comes, we go for inside.
Of The nothing is going to read Arab?
Not.
I See that is reading.
Who that taught you?
-I learned how.
-Impossible.  Who taught you?
Myriam.
lie Not!
AND where did she learn how Arab?
In The school.
what you are reading?
THE Koran.
Myriam that said you for read the Koran?
Yes.
Continues, read.  I am hearing.
"Who desires a religion"
"unlike the Islam,"
"that will not be recognized in the heaven,"
"and in the life will be between the dissatisfied?"
Myriam that said you for read?
Not, I found by chance.
Goes in front, read!
"Those that believe, that follow the Jewish religion,"
"Christian and the Sabeus, and who believes in God,"
"in the final judgment, if practiced the well, will receive a reward"
"Of his one Mister.  They have nothing it fear"
"And they will not suffer.  "
Obliged.
I am going to sleep.
"The fiancée painted the eyelashes"
"And it passed lipstick.  She was to the bathroom"
"And it colored the hair.  It caught a pretty dress"
"and all her bracelets"
"But something is lacking.  What is lacking?"
-THE husband of her.
-Yes.
I love you.
-Is everything quiet.
-Some problem?  It is not possible.
I Have well-read the Koran.
-Alone?
-Yes.
But not of the skill as you said me.
why?
I Uncovered good things about Myriam.
I do not want that continues seeing this girl.
do Not I be able to.
She is my friend.
Is determined.
Gives Me your foot.
Obliged.
Do "youyou" women!
In name of God, the Merciful one.  Say:  God is unique.
Listens, Israel.
Translation:  Pinguim-SP and Hawkeye147
For Art_Subs
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org