Edited by KIRIOUS
Greatly Enhanced by Z+
[Raspy Breathing]
Dad...
Maybe it's the wind
No!
Stop! Please! Stop!
You have a week, Evans. Then we'll burn the house.
William
William!
God damn it, William!
God damn it! Put that down!
Let go!
It's the last feed we've got
I'll take care of this
No, you won't
Herd's over the ridge by now.
You go get cleaned up.
You lied to me, Dan
You told me we made payments to Hollander.
- We did
So, how do you think we bought feed, Alice.
Three months water, the medicine for Mark...
I had a choice between our family and paying them down
We're supposed to make decisions together
Would you have made anything different?
Alice, we can't make it rain together
Turn the dust into grass
We can't stop Hollander from selling
our land to the railroad either
It's too bad the doctors at the aid station didn't take much of my leg.
I read that the pension act pays by the pound now
Stop looking at me like that
Are you going to tell the Marshal what those men did?
Marshal ain't doing shit
-William.
First thing, Mark. I'm going to take you boys.
We're going to round up the herd.
Then I'm going into town
What are you going to do there?
I'm going to tell Hollander to make this right
I'm going to tell him to pay for a new barn.
Maybe we should just shoot him like Will says.
Coach is headed for Bigsby, Boss
Girded with iron, (?) on top, double shotguns.
And a Gatling
You should have let me save the feed
Ar you going to hock that?
Some day, William, ...
... when you walk in my shoes you might understand.
I ain't never walking in your shoes.
Tracks over here.
Here we go.
Giddy up!!
Go man the Gatling
Mark, stay here
Down !!
I think they will not follow us anymore.
[They're not going to (?) in a (?)]
Pull up! Pull up!
Good morning, Pinkerton
Name's Charlie Prince,
I expect you've heard of me.
Well, I heard about a
balled up whore named Charlie Princess.
Is that you, missy?
I hate Pinkertons
Byron McElroy
When did your hair turn gray, Byron?
Go to hell, Ben Wade.
Well, will you look at all this.
You all spared no expense this time, Byron
I've got to say, thought.
It's probably cheaper just to let me rob the damn thing
If you are going to kill me,
just as soon get to it
I ain't going to kill you
Not like this
It won't change a thing,
if you let me live
I'll come for you.
I'd be disappointed if you didn't
She's lit
She's lit!
Let's go.
There we go
I'm going to ask you to put down the money.
Step back. Tell them to step back or this man will die!
Not a smart move, friend
Shit
He's fast
Well, Tommy. It seems that there was
a Pinkerton inside that coach that wasn't quite dead
Now, I know what Charlie told you,
because we don't got but a few rules in this outfit
This is what happens when you put us all at risk
Mark, look at me. Keep looking at me.
Back up quietly
William, look at me.
Good morning.
Those are my cattle.
I want them back.
Carefully rancher. That's Ben Wades
you're talking to
I need them back.
They are all that I've got
I don't need your cattle,
but I will be needing them horses
So you don't go doing nohing..., Foolish
Take the horse.
Find them on the road to Bigsby.
Boys!
They're probably just running late, Mr. Butterfield
Pinkertons don't run late.
That's why they're paid 18 dollars a day.
Get me on my feet.
-I think you're in pretty bad shape, Mr....
-Just get me on my damned feet.
Mark, Williams, get me some of them boards
Can I help you ?
I think maybe a coach headed for here
got itself held up in a canyon about 10 miles back
God damn it
By Mr Ben Wade himself
How did you know it was Wade?
It's been him the last 21 times, Marshal
I saw a Mexican sharpshooter and an Apache
God Damn it
-Did you see the hand of God ?
-What's that?
-His pistol
-Why the hell didn't you do something?
They had a lot of weapons, Mr..
And they were shooting bullets.
Let's go, we're wasting time
Where are you from anyway?
Tom Conrad bought 1000 heads in Mexico,
hired us to drive them in
Let's go
Com on, boys.
Hmmm. Something is going on with the railroad man
Madame, some whisky for my friends.
Let's go , the bar is closed.
Here's to the 4 that we lost in battle.
And here's to the boss who had to say good-bye to
Tommy Darlen today
And that's too bad.
Proverbs 13:3
"He that keepeth his mouth, keepeth his life.
He that opens his lips too wide, shall bring about his own destruction"
Amen
Tommy was weak
Tommy was stupid.
Tommy is dead
I'll drink to that
Sutherland
Jorgensen.
Campos.
Jackson.
Kinter.
Marshal is only half stupid.
He's going to be back soon
They're going across the border.
I won't be far.
I'll wait for you.
Allright Charlie.
I've seen you someplace before
Have you?
You ever worked for a blind irishman in Leadville?
I was a singer.
The best time I ever had in my whole life
What made you to quit?
I got to coughing
Doctor said I should find a dry climate
You know, I spent more money
in that joint that I could tell you
Do you remember a girl?
Her name was Velvet.
Nobody forgets Velvet
You look kind of skinny.
I feel skinny.
It's allright.
I don't mind skinny girls
As long as they've got green eyes to make up for it
Have you got green eyes?
That's right, they (?) to be green.
Do you think they lied?
Do you think they stole our horses?
-They dont need our shit horses.
-Watch your mouth.
I'll take him into town on my own
You boys go round up the herd.
Don't push them too hard, I can't afford any more dropping
Mr, we're going to have to lift you up
to get you on top of that horse
Here comes the cavalry.
Do as I said
Is he from the coach?
The only one that made it
-Mr. McElroy, can you hear me?
-It was Ben Wade
Can you hear me?
This man needs attention.
Did you see which way they rode, Evans?
It seemed like they were headed to Bigsby
You know, there is a little town just south of the border
Pretty little pueblo (?)
Down by the river
Folks would pay good money to hear
a white woman sing
Yeah, imagine me (shinning on?) down to Mexico with Ben Wade on my arm
I'm not wanted in Mexico.
Jump out that back windows with me now
You're crazy.
-Are you the Dr?
-Yes
-Coach got held up
-Get him on the table.
What's his name?
Byron McElroy, he's a bounty hunter
under contract with the Pinkertons
You've lost a lot of blood, Mr McElroy
-That bullet is still in there
-Get it out
Allright.
What I'm about to do
is going to hurt like a son of a bitch
It ain't the first time I've been shot
Hold him, please
Don't touch me.
- What the fuck kind of Doctor are you anyway?
- It's nice to have a conversation with a patient for a change
What the hell are they looking for?
Ben Wade
He held up the payroll coach
-I want to talk, Mr. Hollander.
-Ben Wade in Bigsby
Shit, we're moving up
Mr. Hollander.
Tucker, I'm going to the saloon
You've got no right to do what you've done
You hear me?
It's my land
Come next week it's not, Evans
You borrowed a good deal of money,
and I got a right to (recompense?)
But you damn up my creek.
You shut off my water.
How do you expect me to pay off my debt if you...?
Before water touches your land it resides and flows on mine.
And as such, I can do with it as I fucking please.
Go home and pack up.
Here, if you just give me till spring
I can turn the corner
Sometimes a man has to big enough
to see how small he is
Railroad is coming, Dan
Your land is worth more with you off it
Hollander!
You look a little bent, rancher.
You come to wake some snakes?
Dan, would you like a drink?
No thanks.
You got your horses back, didn't you?
And your cattle?
Yeah, I got my horses back,
but you killed two of my herd
Hell, they died for a good cause.
You know, them beasts of yours
They woulnd't even fetch 100 dollars.
I'll tell you what. That should cover it
How much do you get for a day's work?
2 dollars, when I hire out
There are 2 dollars for a half-day.
You took up my boys' time too
You're right, I did
Anything else you want to get paid for, Dan?
Give me 5 dollars extra.
And what's that for?
For making me nervous
Hands up, Ben Wade.
Boss!
-Give me your hands, Mr. Wade
-Tucker take his gun
- Give me that
Ben Wade
Captured in Bigsby
Be careful with that thing
My gun's got a curse on it
Laugh while you can.
Crawley, go get the wagon.
Make sure every weapons we've got is (shoot?) ready
I'll meet you up front of the office.
-Get him out of here.
-Sure thing
I think we should shoot him right now
Put a bullet right in his nogging
If you do that, everybody in this
shit piss of a town will be dead by morning
22 robberies,
over 400 thousand dollars in losses
More in delays
The Southern Pacific will have Ben Wade
convicted in a Federal court. Hanged
...in public, an example made
And we will pay to make it happen
You all notice he didn't mention of the lives I've taken
I need three more men.
-You can have Tucker.
-Good
I'm coming, you only need one
You're wounded, Mr. McElroy.
I rode in here. Sure as hell I can ride out
-He goes, Potter's coming
-What?!
Doc can't shoot shit
I was better shot of my regiment. I'll come
For 200 dollars.
You fight for the north or the south?
North.
We are southern in name,
but Chicago owned. Fine
200 dollars.
Let's go
-Thank you
-Thank me when it's done
This town is going to burn!
Let's get him, boys!
Get in the coach
God Damn it.
Evans, Crawley, Tucker
you need to mount up now!
Head for Evans' ranch
I'll mee you there with the coach
How long does he have to be here?
A day or so. Make sure his outfit takes the bait
Hello there. Evans
Can you give me a hand with this?
Whatever your wife is cooking in there, smells good, Evans
Let's go.
Good driving, Marshal
Remind me not to play poker in this town
Well, Marshal, give us a count
1... 2... 3...
Gonna check on my family when you come back, right?
First thing
Madam
Byron, an unpleasant surprise
What happens if they catch the wagon?
Well, you saw where his man was. He's still got to go fish the outfit.
Marshal's got a fast rig, they should reach the fort before dawn.
His gang can't do anything in front of the whole sixth cavarly
Did you have something to do with that?
I hope you are proud of yourself
Just doing my job, Doc.
Thanks, son
We always wait to say grace
We don't presume to teach other people manners
Aren't we supposed to say grace for murderers too?
-Grace is for everyone, dear
-Then why don't we say it?
Mark, I'd like to hear it.
God, our father, Lord and Savior
Thank you for your love and favor
Please bless this drink and food we pray
And bless all who share with us today
Amen.
If my pa' wanted to, he could shoot you dead
He can shoot a jack rabbit at 50 yards
Shooting an animal is a lot different
than shooting a man, son
Not, it isn't
Not in my opinion.
We can ask Byron here.
Now Byron, he's killed dozens of people.
Men and women and children. Miners, Apaches
Not a soul I've taken that didn't deserve what they've got
"Every way of a man is right in his own eyes", Byron,
"but the Lord ponders the heart"
Proverbs 21
Dan
You eat more when you're nervous, Mr Butterfield?
Why, thank you, Dan.
How pleasant and kind of you. Much appreciated it
Could you cut that for me?
Could you cut that fat out, I don't particularly like the fat at all.
Allright.
And the (grissle?)
I don't like (grissle?)
Do you mind if I ask you how you got
that hitch in your step, Dan?
Don't tell him nothing, Mr Evans.
Where were you stationed?
7th company of sharpshooters, out of (?) Massachusetts
My father was defending the US capital
in the District of Columbia
Isn't that so?
Well, Dan. Tell me the story of
how you lost your leg
Did they shoot it off? Cut it off?
Did the Indians do it?
I saw something over there in the grass.
There ain't nothing
What if they caught up with the coach already?
What if they already know it's Crawley inside?
Have you ever been to San Francisco?
If it's all right by you, Mr. Wade,
I rather we not talk
So you've never been in San Francisco?
No.
I know a girl there.
She's the daughter of a sea captain
She had the most beautiful green eyes
The greenest eyes
I ever saw
Like yours.
When I stared deep into them
they'd just change color in front of me
All the colors of the sea.
What did you say your name was again?
Alice.
For God's sake, he's killed more men than the (drought?)
He is not what I expected
He is dangerous
Dangerous is what he is, Alice.
I don't want you or the boys
talking to him
You can change your mind, Dan
None will think less of you
None can think less of me
6 months from now, everything is going to be great
Cows are going to be fat
We might even see the steam
from the train coming over the ridge
We will be allright, but we won't make it through
the next 6 days, if I don't do this
Sorry, Dan. McElroy says 5 minutes
Do you think it's too much for me?
He's a killer, Daniel.
Yet somehow I have the decency
to bring him to justice.
What are you thinking?
I am not out there alone
Have a little faith in me
Ben Wade has a gang
And they're out there tonight, somewhere
If I don't go, we have to pack up and leave
and God knows where w/o a prayer to (?)
Now, I am tired, Alice
I'm tired of watching my boys go hungry
... I'm tired of the way they look at me
I'm tired of the way that you don't
I've been standing on one leg for 3 damned years,
waiting for God to do me a favor
And he ain't listening
Mr. Evans.
No, no, no. This is my horse now
Come over here
-Don't give me any trouble, Mark
-Yes, sir
Boy.
-I want to come with you
-Well, you can't
I can help.
You're 14 years old.
I can ride faster and
you shoot better than any one of them.
The Pinkerton is hurt, Potter is no good,
that railroad man is dead weight, and that other bastard...
I dont have time to argue
I need you here.
That's that
So, boys, where are we headed?
It ain't none of your business where we are headed, Wade.
You're a prisoner. You don't speak, you don't piss.
You don't god damn breathe unless we say so.
Do you understand that?
We're taking you to Contention
Putting you on the 3:10 to Yuma, day after tomorrow
You shouldn't have told him, now.
Relax, friend. Now if we get separated
I'll know where to meet up
I'd like tol thank you for your hospitality, Madame
I hope I can send your husband back allright
What did Ben Wade mean about
sending Pa' back all right?
Is he saying he was going to kill him?
Ben Wade don't have to lift a finger,
his gang will do it for him.
Your father can take care of himself
So, were you conscripted into Lincoln's army, Mr. Evans?
Or did you volunteered?
Neither...
Maybe both.
What does that means?
It means I was a volunteer for the Massachusetts State Guard
Then in 62 the Federal government was running low on men
so they called in the state militias
-To protect Washinton.
-And that's when you got hurt
What are you doing out here, Dan?
You've got a family to protect.
You are not a law man,
you don't work for the railroad
like Mr. shinny shoes over there
Not a Pinkerton
Maybe I don't like the idea of
men like you running loose
It's man's nature
to take what he wants, Dan
It's how we are born
Well, I make an honest living
It might be honest, but I don't think it's much of a living
you must be hurting bad for money
to take this job
Go to sleep.
I imagine debt puts
a lot of pressure on a marriage
Are you married?
What would you know about marriage?
We can't all be cutthroats and thieves
Well, I know that if I was lucky enough to have a wife
like Alice, I'd treat her a whole lot better than you do, Dan
I'd feed her better, I'd buy her pretty dresses.
I wouldn't make her work so hard.
Yeah, I'd bet Alice was a real pretty girl before she married you...
Don't talk about my wife. You shut up about her.
You say one more word and I cut your tongue.
I'd like the sight of it if you did.
Mr. Evans.
It's my watch, now
#Gonna hang me in the morning
#For the night is done
#I'll never see the sun
I suppose it's too much to ask for a little quiet.
The way I figured it: I'd be asleep in my
own bed right now if it weren't for you
So if I've got to be up,
you damn well be up with me too,
Ben Wade.
Son of a bitch!
Enough.
-Enough!
-That's enough, McElroy
We have to bury him.
If you take the time to dig one grave
you might as well dig one for yourself
Let's go.
Mount up
#Gonna hang me in the morning
#I'll never see the sun
[Laughs]
Don't worry there, Boss
We're going to get you out of there in a second
Wait!
Sutherland.
Jackson
No, No.
Don't do this
Don't do this.
Where is he?
Open the door. Open the door!
Let me out of here, God damn it!
Where did they take him?
I don't know!
Mr., you'd better tell me where they took him...
...or you will burn
Contention!
Allright?!
They're going to Contention
They're going to put him on the
3:10 to Yuma prison. Tomorrow
Let me go out of here!
Contention is... 80 miles
back to the other way.
They've just about killed our horses
So, we'll buy new ones.
Charlie, it's his own fault he got caught
He made a mistake.
You think you can do a better job
leading this group?
Maybe...
You've forgotten what he
done for us?
We're going to Contention!
Can't say I didn't warn you
There's a shortcut we can take
A shortcut?
Through the pass
It takes you right through Contention
Why didnt you say something before?
It's Apache country
-I thought that the government gave them land.
-These are the ones who refused to go.
-I wouldn't take that path
-You want us to take the long way?
-That's right
-and let your boys catch us?
Mr.. Butterfield, the Apache who lived
in that path are the ones that stayed to fight
They enjoy killing
You ain't going to make it
We'll take our chances
Something on your mind, Dan?
Why did you kill Tucker?
Why not me? Or Butterfield?
Hell, Tucker took my horse.
Did you liked him, Dan?
-No
He told me he burned down your barn
He was an asshole
But wishing him dead and
killing him are two different things
Your conscience is sensitive, Dan
I don't think it's my
favorite part of you.
(?), Mr. Wade. If you want to
talk to somebody, talk to me.
I don't like talking to you, Byron
Not when I have the gun.
No, that ain't it.
I just don't find you that interesting.
Laugh it up, Doc. 'till he
guts you like a fish
Byron is like a song with one note
Did you ever read another book in your
life, Byron. Besides the Bible?
No need
Byron acts pius. A few years ago when
he was under contract with Central,
I've seen him and a bunch of brother Pinks ...
... mow down 32 Apache women and children
Renegades. Gunning down railroad men and their families ...
... picking them off the road, one by one. Scalped.
There was young'nes running around.
Crying and screaming
No more than 3 years old
... and his boys shot them all
and pushed them into a ditch
Some of them were still crying
I guess Byron figured that Jesus
wouldn't mind
Apparently Jesus don't like the Apache
Keep on talking...
All the way to Yuma. Right up on them steps
to the rope. Straight to hell
Yeah, the day I die, Byron
I'm getting sprung from hell
I might feel the same, if I'd come from the seed of a
drunk grave digger and the rancid womb of a whore
Drop it, Dan Evans.
Drop it
Toss it to the ground, Doc
Mr. Butterfield...
I believe, Dan, you're carrying a pistol as well.
I'd appreciate it if you take it out
and drop it on the ground. Thank you
Now, I've always liked you, Byron, ...
..., but you never knew when to shut up
Even bad men love their mommas
Now I think it's time
for everybody to go home
Don't you move, Mr. Wade.
Let go of that shotgun.
William, what the hell are you doing here?
I don't think that you're going to shoot a man (?)
in the back of the head, boy
Dan, tell your boy it's over
You think you can keep you gun on him, William?
I'm doing a damn sight better than you did
You ever been to Dodge City?
No.
Stop talking to him
The way you're shuffling those cards,
I took you for a pro
I practice a lot.
I can tell
You ever been to Dodge?
Yes, indeed
Meanest, most beautiful, dirty city there ever was
Saloons just overflowing with cattle drivers and road agents,
prospectors, gunslingers, gamblers and women
Women will do things to you you'll never forget.
They'll give you disease you'll never forget
Money in your pocket in Dodge City
you can have everything a man ever wished for
Everything a man comes to need
I got (?) I was a boy not much bigger than you
Now, how many men have you killed since then, Wade?
How many families have you destroyed?
Quite a few
Is it true that you dynamited a wagon
full of prospectors in the Western Territories last spring?
No, that's a lie.
It was a train full
(?), Dan
I gotta take a piss
You know, I thought he was going to
shoot me back in the ravine
I really thought he was going to do it
There was a wildness in his eyes.
He reminds me ...
He's going to be nothing like you, Wade
A man's got to have a head start
on the path of decency
Yeah, that's why I don't mess around
with doing anything good, Dan.
Dou do one good deed for somebody...
I imagine it's habit forming
Something decent. See that grateful
look in their eyes....
... I imagine it makes feel like christ hisself
I've had enough of this, Wade.
Come on. Let's go
It's three of them
-Yours?
If they were mine, you'd be dead
Give me that gun, Wade!
I told you not to come this way
It was McElroy's decision.
I told you there'd be trouble
Give me the keys to the handcuffs
Easy. Easy now
Where is he?
He's gone
He took the horses with him.
I found this in the grass
That's the quickest way out of the pass
He'll be looking for help, to get his cuffs off
We are going after him.
There ain't no reward for getting him
halfway to that train, is there?
I've got to be honest with you,
I like some of their food.
As for wanting $40 a month now,
I can...
Hello, Love.
God damned Coolies. They'll work just fine
with my left boot up their ass
Well, if I could teach a monkey
to lay track, ...
Well. What we need here are some negros
brought here, Mister Boles
Show these Chinamen what real work is
Holly Christ!
Who is that?
That's him!
-Help me with the handcuffs
Break the chain.
Use the hammer.
I have 5 guns on you out here, Ben Wade
Just come on out!
The horses.
What the hell is going on here?
Mr. Butterfield, all finished in Bigsby?
Mr. Boles
You'd better hurry. We're making the last blasts
through the mountains this week.
That's my prisoner.
We're taking him to Contention,
putting him on the prison train to Yuma.
What prisoner?
Come now, Mr. Boles. That's
Ben Wade you have there
Ben Wade gunned down my kid brother, ...
... in front of me, 6 years ago in Abeline
Your brother was a lying (?) card shark
That is, if he is the asshole I remember.
He could of course be some other asshole I've killed
that I've forgot about
You can't do that. That's immoral.
Immoral ain't got a damned thing to do with it
I was expecting to collect a $200 reward for that man.
I'm delivering him to Contention,
I need that money.
Need it bad enough to die?
At least let us take our horses.
I've got no problem with that
As long as you ride away, Mr.
Nice knowing you, Dan
God damn it!
Did we make it?
Did we get away?
Yeah, Doc. We did
Thanks to you.
We need a place to lay low. Keep him
out of sight 'till the train comes
There is a hotel up here, I'll check to see,
and you ride around back
Hey, Will. You keep a watch on the rail head
You see them coming...
I'll let you know
William!
There's a Can-Can on the outs, if you're interested...
It's the Bridal Suite,
I hope you don't mind, it's all they had
Well, well. That looks like rain clouds over Bigsby
You still need that $200, Dan?
Shut up
Mr.. Evans, you continue to give
me great confidence
I'm going to see about the Marshal.
We're looking for a group escorting
and outlaw by the name of Ben Wade
Yeah, we've been chasing them
through these tunnels
Who you are?
What's it to you?
Ben Wade killed my brother.
Then your brother must be famous
Are you, boys, some kind of posse?
I hate posses
So this is the Bridal Suite.
Now, I wonder how many brides
have taken in this view
What are you going to do with your $200 now, Dan?
Now that the rains are coming
I owe people money, Wade.
That drought left me in the hole
What do you think about double that amount?
You can pay your debts,
buy a hundred more cows
Build a new barn
How do you reckon I'm going to do that?
Just lay down your gun
and let me walk out the door.
It's worth $400 (?)
Is that what you reckon my price is?
No...
No, I reckon it's a thousand
One thousand dollars
There was ten times that amount
in Butterfield's coach
Do you want my cut, Dan?
It's all yours.
Isn't that kind of reckless of you Wade?
Seeing that... Hmmm. You're so sure that
your crew is coming to get you
Oh, they're coming, Dan
Sure as God's vengeance, they're coming
But I just like to do things easy
Imagine what you can do with $1000, Dan?
You can hire a couple of ranch hands.
Your boys could go to school, grow up smart.
What about Alice?
She wouuld be the proud wife
of a bonafide Arizona rancher
All you've got to do is say yes
Will you give me a bank note, Wade?
Or will you be kind enough to make a deposit for me?
Cash.
You tell me, Wade. How will I
account for that amount of money?
What will I tell people when I spend it?
That you got the jump on me, you escaped,
and somehow I got a fortune
No. How dumb do you think people are?
Nobody needs to know
Do you know what?
Would you do me a favor?
Don't talk to me for a while.
You mean
we're still not friends?
No. No, we're not
Come 5 minutes to 3, we're going to be
a hell of a lot closer than you think
#They're gonna hang me in the morning
#For the night is done
#I'll never see the sun
Who is it?
It's me, Dan
I brought help
You've been gone for a long time, Mr. Butterfield
How do I know someone ain't got
a gun on you out there?
Dan, this is Marshal Will Doane
Marshal
-Mr. Evans
Two of my finest men
I'm sorry about all that, Marshal,
I am grateful for the help
Don't mention it
So, you fellows are really going
to help to put me on this train?
It might not seem like it, Mr.. Wade,
but we got law and order in this town,
just like in any other
Well, that's very reassuring, Marshal
How much money is Butterfield paying you?
That's not of your business
You're coming with us?
I'll be walking with you
Every step of the way.
You have my word on that, Dan
That makes five of us. Five is good
It ain't enough
It ain't nearly enough
Pa!
That's my boy
They're coming.
They are coming this way I've seen them
-Where?
About a mile out, same way we come
how many are they?
-Seven, ... Eight.
Which is it? 7 or 8?
Seven.
Folks, sorry to bother you, but I'm going
to need you to move outside as quickly as possible
That's it, folks.
Move along
Right there.
Sure there're a lot of them
- You'd figure, with it being the whole gang
Boss?
Boss, are you are in there?
What do you want me to tell them?
You tell them you'll write
them a letter every day from Yuma
Be careful, Wade.
Charlie,
Boys.
Charlie, why don't you take the boys
down to the saloon and boy them a drink
Are you ok?
I am fine. Just sitting up here with
my 4 new friends
That's enough
Thank You, Charlie.
Listen up!
Listen up!!
That's Ben Wade they have up there!
Ben Wade!
Now, the railroad intends...
... to put him on the 3:10 to Yuma and hang him
What's he doing?
We will give you $300 cash
To any man who shoots
anyone of his captors
$200 cash guaranteed!
$200 guaranteed!
I'll take $200
Give me the money
You've got to shoot them first
It's gotta be 30 or 40 with guns out there now
The hell with this!
Now, just a minute, Marshal
Now, look. If it's a fair fight, sure.
I'd stay for that. A fair fight ...
That's a man's duty, but...
There's only 5 of us
I'm sorry, Mr, but I'm not going to die here today
And neither are my men
Marshal, ...
You forgot this
Marshal?
Now, you see, Dan. Generally, ...
... pretty much everyone ...
.... wants to live
I'll double your money
Let's go, boys
Please, do you want to see
us shot down in the street?
This thing happened in Bigsby
That means Butterfield too
Why bring your troubles to Contention?
We've got families
Everyone of us is a family man
I'm a family man too
He's gona walk out on you
Then you'd best get out
like the rest of us
He's (not?) gonna come back up here
He's gonna walk out on you
Now, what you've got to figure
is why you and your boy are gonna die ...
... because of Butterfield's railroad loss of money?
They're all of them?
Almost.
Your move, general
What do you expect him to say?
I expect him to say something that makes sense.
Something that might save the two of you.
Take a look, Dan
What's the matter? You don't want to see?
I'll see them soon enough
What about you, kid?
You wanna  look?
Stay away from the window, William.
Go on take a look.
They're animals
All of them
They're gonna kill you and your father, William
And I'll laugh while they do it
I think you know that
Call them them off
Why should I?
Because you're not all bad
Yes, I am
Your saved us from those Indians.
-I saved myself
You got us through the tunnels
You helped us get away
If I had a gun in them tunnels,
I would've used it on you.
I don't believe you.
Kid, I wouldn't last 5 minutes leading an outfit
like that if I wasn't as rotten as hell.
Dan, ...
I can't do it,
Dan, and if I can't do it,
you shouldn't do it either
They say discretion is the (better?) part of valor
If you think that you have an
olbigation to me or to the railroad...
... I assure you you do not, I'm releasing you
It's just you left, Dan. Just you and your boy
Maybe he is right, Pa,
maybe we should go home
What did Doc Potter gave his life for, William?
And McElroy?
Little red ants on a hill
I'll pay you the $200, Dan. Right now.
And you can walk away
You know, this whole ride,
it's been nagging on me ...
... that's what the government
gave me for my leg ...
... $198.36 and the funny thing is that...
... when you think about it ...
... -which I have been lately-
is that they weren't paying me to walk away.
They were paying me so they could walk away.
Don't muddy the past on the present, Dan
No, no, no, Wade. I'm seeing the world the way it is
If you take him to the train, Pa, I'm going with you
No, Mr. Butterfield's gonna take you home
No, I'm not going any...
-Yes, you are
I'm staying here with you
You're going to hold up in the room
across the hall. You're going to wait until we leave.
I'll get him to Bigsby.
You've got my promise
You're going to promise a lot more than that, Butterfield
I want guarantees that Hollander and his boys
will never set foot on my land again
And that my water is going to flow.
And I expect you to hand my wife $1000 cash
when you see her. You've got money to spare
I can deliver that, just get him on the train.
You heard him?
-I heard him.
William...
...I want you to give this back to your mother
I want you to tell her it helped
me find what is right
Pa, I can't just leave you
I'm going to be a day behind you, William
Unless something happens. And if it does,
I need a man at the ranch
To run things; to protect our family.
And I know that you can do that because
you've become a fine man, William
You've become a fine man
You've got all the best parts of me ...
... what few there are
And you just remember
that your old man hauled Ben Wade to that station
when nobody else would
You know, squeezing that watch won't stop time
Don't get so scared.
You might (pack?) a bad mood.
Ever read the Bible, Dan?
I read it one time. I was 8 years old. My daddy had just got
himself killed over a shot of whiskey and my mom said we
were going back East to start over
So she gave me a Bible, sat me down at
the train station. Told me to read it
She was going to get our tickets
Well, I did what she said ...
I read that Bible cover to cover.
It took me 3 days
She never came back.
It's time
It's a half mile to the station from here, Dan
I guess we're walking
Lucky
Dan...
You're not gonna get a chance
to use those Scofields, Charlie
Perhaps you can explain to me
the next portion of your plan, Dan
Hey!
Hey!!
Not the black hat!
(?) you dumb shits!
Charlie.
Get back!
Boss!
Let's go! White Door!
Move it!
I can't do this no more, Dan
I'm putting you on that train, Wade
I'm going back!
Your boy is gone, hero. Ain't nobody watching no more
You still got that one good leg,
why don't you use it to get on home?
Charlie!
Charlie Prince!
Yeah, boss!
-Hold your fire!
I'm walking out
I have never been no hero, Wade
Only (action?) I've seen, it was a retreat ...
... my foot got shot off by one of my own men.
You try telling that story to your boy ...
... see how he looks at you then
Boss!
Ok, Dan
Son.
They're on the move
They're on the move!
Boss, Boss..
Can you make this?
- Yeah
Spread out!...
What time is it?
Quarter past three
Where is the 3:10 to Yuma?
Running late, I suppose
How late?
Beats me
It gets here when it gets here
God damned trains,
You never can rely on them, huh?
You know...
I ain't stubborn.
Excuse me?
You said I was stubborn for
keeping my family on a dying ranch
It's my son, Mark
The young one
He got tuberculosis when he was 2
Doctor said he'd die
if he didn't have a dry climate
Why are you telling me this?
I don't know
I guess that I just
wanted you to know that ...
... I ain't stubborn. That's all
Well, as long as we're making confesions
- Yeah?
I've been to Yuma Prison before
Twice
Escaped twice too
First car, sliding door
They'll be coming
I've got a prisoner to go to Yuma
Well, you did it, Dan
No!
Pa!
For a one legged rancher, ...
... he's one tough son of a bitch
You done it, Pa
You done it.
You got him on the train
Pa
Edited by KIRIOUS
Greatly Enhanced by Z+
GREETINGS FROM GREECE
-= Downloaded from www.opensubtitles.org =-
[whistles]