NOGRADY: Today really
marks the first stage
of an unprecedented
technological advancement.
We have begun to identify
so-called Goldilocks planets.
These are planets that share a
similar relationship with their sun
as we have with ours.
If a planet's too far away
from its sun, it's too cold.
If it's too close to
its sun, it's too hot.
But for an Earth-like planet,
the distance is just right.
Potentially perfect
for sustaining life.
We have finally managed
to identify one planet
that is the right distance
from its star to hold water
and is the right mass
to sustain an atmosphere.
Every 24 hours,
our station in Hawaii
will transmit a signal to Landsat
7, our deep orbiting satellite,
which will amplify and relay the
signal to our targeted planet
which is, rather grandly,
entitled Planet G.
If there is intelligent life
out there, and they come here
it's going to be like
Columbus and the Indians.
Only, we're the Indians.
Ladies and gentlemen, please prepare to
bear witness to the making of history.
Start transmission.
JACKIE: It seems as though
NASA is setting up shop
right here in
our own backyard.
Today, the Beacon International
Project was launched.
Satellite dishes
here on Oahu
sending out very powerful
signals into deep space
with an attempt to
communicate with anyone…
STONE: Another round,
birthday boy.
JACKIE: …or anything that
might be out there listening.
A toast.
Happy birthday,
little brother.
I'm wishing you success
and growth, and happiness.
May this be
a great year for you.
It's going to
be a great year.
I love you.
I love you, too.
So, in the great
Hopper family tradition,
this year I'm quoting
from Coach John Wooden.
Johnny.
“Adversity is
the state in which man
“most easily becomes
acquainted with himself
“being especially free
of admirers then.”
Cheers.
I'm not cheers-ing that.
It's a very
good quote for you.
“I may be free of admirers right
now but there is still time”?
Will you shut up?
Light your cupcake
and raise your glass.
Did you get me that?
Yes, I got you that.
Thank you,
that's very sweet.
You're welcome.
You're very welcome.
I got this guy, Tony. He said he
can get you a construction job.
All you need to
do is call him.
Could I get a beer and a
chicken burrito, please?
Sorry, kitchen's closed.
STONE: You're not going
to call him, are you?
Give Tony my best,
but I don't need you
or Tony's help,
for that matter.
You can call him or
join me in the Navy.
No.
Great. All right.
Happy birthday. Blow out your
candle and make a wish.
Do not waste
a wish on a girl.
Wish for a job,
an apartment.
A new alternator belt, so I don't
have to drive you everywhere.
A job, or…
You said “job” twice.
It's my birthday and my wish.
All right?
Please don't waste it.
You just wasted
that wish, didn't you?
I'm going in.
You're not going in.
How do I look?
Wait, let me
just fix that.
Awesome!
All right, princess,
go get 'em.
Great start.
Ugh.
What seems to
be the problem?
I want a chicken burrito.
Johnny, chicken burrito her.
BARTENDER: It ain't happening.
Chicken burrito her.
Kitchen's closed, Hopper.
What's your name?
I'm hungry.
That's not your name.
If you give me five minutes
I will get you
your chicken burrito.
Five minutes,
starting now.
(BELCHES)
Chicken burrito time, I'm out.
Chicken burrito,
roger that.
HOPPER: Wait! Hi!
No! Let's just…
Just one twist of the key
and we will be good.
How are you, ma'am?
How you doing?
Burritos, right there.
It's closed.
Too late, pal.
Okay.
It's right there. Please?
It's too late to eat a burrito.
Too many complex carbs.
$3.99…
(GRUNTING) Chicken burrito.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
I got it!
Hey! Freeze!
(ALARM RINGING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
I got a burrito!
I got it!
Freeze!
(GASPS)
Stay down!
MAN: He's getting back up!
(GRUNTING)
STONE: I've had it!
Look at yourself!
How is it that you
screw everything up?
By the way, that girl you were
trying to impress last night,
do you know who
her father is?
Admiral Shane!
He runs the whole damn fleet!
So, now you're messing
with my job. My life!
You know that girl?
The burrito girl?
I've always stayed out of
your business, haven't I?
Because I was hoping
that maybe one day
you would learn
from your mistakes.
You would grow up,
you would mature a bit!
Is my back all right?
(GROANS)
Oh, my God! My back!
You're 26, and what have
you got? You got, what?
Sixty-five dollars
to your name?
I got tazed.
A car that doesn't start.
You're living on my couch!
Those things work!
Man, look at yourself.
Oh, my God.
As from now,
as from right this second,
there is a new dynamic at play.
And this dynamic
is the following.
From here on, until I state otherwise,
there will be no more debate,
no more discussion,
no more compromise!
It's me speaking, you listening.
Me saying, you doing.
Do you understand that?
It's time for
a new course of action.
A new direction.
A game change.
You are joining
me in the Navy.
ANNOUNCER: Live, local,
this is Hawaii News Now.
Thousands of sailors
on dozens of ships
are coming to
Hawaii for RIMPAC.
NEWSCASTER 1: RIMPAC
is the world's largest
multinational
maritime exercise.
NEWSCASTER 2: RIMPAC is a
military ballet of 14 navies…
NEWSCASTER 3:
20·000 Navy personnel.
Cooperation and collaboration
amongst the countries is the goal.
NEWSCASTER 3: Relationship-building
is the key.
NEWSCASTER 4: Not all the action is
taking place out on the water.
There will also be sporting
events here on land.
Forget World Cup,
this is the RIMPAC Cup final.
ANNOUNCER 1: It's another beautiful
day here in Hawaii, as usual.
ANNOUNCER 2: Indeed it is, but a
storm is brewing on the field
as the scrappy U.S.A team
is butting heads with Japan.
The score is 2-nil, Japan.
The U.S has been
trailing all day.
Team leader Alex Hopper
has got to do something to
rally the troops here.
Turn it up!
ANNOUNCER 1:
Big save! Great save!
ANNOUNCER 2: Big save! Stone Hopper,
he's answered every test today.
What's wrong with you,
drama queen?
Get up, princess, come on!
ANNOUNCER 1: U.S.A's Ordy squares
the ball over to number 6, Alan.
ANNOUNCER 2: Clever
backheel into space…
ANNOUNCER 1:
Hopper… Goal!
(YELLING)
A missile,
past Iwashiro.
The U.S is finally on the board,
showing some signs of life
with the score, 2-1, Japan.
ANNOUNCER 2: We are now into stoppage
time. Can the U.S tie it up?
Time! Time! Time!
One minute left.
Alex, it's coming your way!
ANNOUNCER 1: Stone Hopper
has placed it perfectly.
It takes a fortuitous bounce.
Hopper is underneath it
and on-side.
(BOTH GRUNT)
Hey, ref!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
ANNOUNCER 1: A penalty kick has been
awarded to the United States.
Nagata made contact with
Hopper inside the box.
ANNOUNCER 2: And by “contact,” you
mean Nagata kicked him in the face.
STONE: You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
ANNOUNCER 1: Stone Hopper
has come up the field.
I'm fine.
I don't need your help.
Bronson is going
to take it.
Bronson!
What do you mean, “Bronson”?
No, negative.
I'm fine. Bronson,
you're gonna take this.
Bronson, don't move.
Bronson, come here.
Bronson, you move one
more step, you're dead!
Do you want to die today?
Do you want to die?
Good choice.
He is definitely concussed.
You just threatened
one of my sailors.
ANNOUNCER 1: Looks like
it's going to be his little
brother, Alex Hopper.
ANNOUNCER 2: If I was Stone, I
would have picked another shooter.
I'm skeptical that
Hopper is 100 percent.
Engage, engage.
Impose will, impose will.
There are two kinds
of idiots, Hopper.
One looks where he kicks,
the other looks
where he doesn't kick.
Which idiot are you?
I'm the idiot that's going to kick
it through your keeper's face.
Get ready for overtime.
ANNOUNCER 2:
All eyes on Hopper.
He could send this
into overtime.
(BLOWING WHISTLE) ANNOUNCER
1: And here we go.
If Hopper scores, the U.S
will go into overtime.
SPECTATORS: Oh!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
ANNOUNCER 1: Hopper sails
one miles over the crossbar,
nowhere near the goal.
Typical.
ANNOUNCER 2: What a
heartbreak for the U.S.
(ALL CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER 1: It was a very
poor attempt by the obviously
injured Alex Hopper.
He refused to
come out of the game
and his stubbornness
cost the United States.
Congratulations to Japan,
our 2012 RIMPAC Cup winners.
The final, as we sign off,
Japan, 2.
The United States, 1.
Are you ready for this?
Born.
Are you sure?
Never been more sure
of anything in my life.
What are you going to say?
I'm going to walk up
to him, man to man,
and look him
straight in the eyes.
With what words?
My words.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
“Sir…
”Your daughter is the best thing
that has ever happened to me.
”She's smart, kind,
beautiful, funny,
”and I'm madly
in love with her.
”It would be an honor to have
your permission to marry her.”
I love you.
I love you, too.
First off, I'd like to welcome
you all to the RIMPAC
International Naval War Games.
And I'd like to
welcome you onboard
the greatest fighting ship
in American naval history.
The “Mighty Mo,”
the U.S.S Missouri.
(CELTIC PUNK MUSIC PLAYING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
SHANE: And fought
in World War II…
Shit!
Hopper, your cover.
I'm keeping you
on your toes.
Hopper, let's go, come on.
Hopper!
HOPPER: This way.
No, no, no.
GUARD: That way, sir.
HOPPER: Yes, yes,
I knew that.
We knew that.
You look good.
The U.S.S Missouri
was the final battleship
to be completed by
the United States
before being de-commissioned
and replaced
with a more modern
fleet of vessels,
like destroyers.
What's the difference between
a battleship and a destroyer?
Battleships are great ships.
But they are kind
of like dinosaurs.
They're designed to take hits,
like a floating punching bag.
But then there's destroyers,
which are just awesome.
They're designed to dish it
out like the Terminator.
Are you a Captain?
No, he's not a Captain because
he's always late. Come on.
I fight the ship.
Which is even better.
(APPLAUSE)
Listen, get it done.
Get it done.
Babe, it's a formality.
Okay, go.
I'm all over it.
We have with us today,
veterans from the Missouri
who have served on her, some
going back to World War II.
Examples of the finest men to
have ever served in any navy.
Lieutenant Hopper, what an honor.
Thank you for joining us.
Good to be here.
And now,
as we prepare to embark
on this
outstanding exercise…
I'm nervous.
Shades off.
I would like to come
to the stage.
Captain Nagata, Japan.
(GREETS IN JAPANESE)
Captain Lou, Malaysia.
(GREETING IN MALAY)
It's so close to
the way we say it.
He hates me.
He doesn't hate you.
Shut up. Shut up.
SHANE: Captain Jacks,
Australia.
G'day.
Shut up.
G'day!
G'day.
A special acknowledgment to Commander
Stone Hopper, United States Navy.
Go, that's your call.
Knock 'em out.
Who, along with his
outstanding crew and ship,
had the highest
overall rating last year.
Shades off, Hopper.
Commander.
Thank you, Admiral.
Welcome, everybody. It's really
great to see you all here today.
Especially you, gentlemen.
It's a true honor.
Me and my crew, we're going to
have to be on our toes this year
because your ships look outstanding
and your men look ready.
So, good luck out there.
Be safe and keep charging.
He loves his daughter, she loves
you. He's going to respect that.
Hey, Mike.
Admiral.
You remember Sam?
It's an obsolete tradition,
this asking for permission.
Tell me where this came from.
Stop.
Sam's a physical
therapist now.
Stop worrying about this and walk
up and do what you got to do.
Hello, Hopper.
Why are you here?
This is going
to be sweet.
I was within the rules.
Really?
Were you in the rules when
you kicked me in the face?
Isn't there something more important
you should be doing right now?
He hates the man.
That seems a bit juvenile,
wouldn't you say?
Go mess with him
and see what happens.
Why?
CORA: Do it.
Would it be funny if I
punched you in the face?
Would that be funny?
Stop it.
Chicken.
Kentucky Fried Chicken.
Yeah, I love it.
A two-piece meal.
You look like Colonel
Sanders, actually.
He was a handsome man.
Good job out there, Dad.
What do you want?
Hopper needs five
minutes of your time.
(SIGHS)
That's enough.
What do you mean?
Don't you have something more important
you should be doing right now?
Three minutes, tops.
Thank you. I love you.
Thank you, Daddy.
Love you, too.
He's going to
smash my face in.
He's not going to
smash your face in.
Oh, my God.
Sir, it would be an honor.
Sir. Sir. Sir.
Give me your permission.
It would be an honor
to have your permission.
Sir, give me your permission.
What's your deal?
It would be a thankful honor
to have your permission
to honor your hand.
What?
Oh, my God.
Sir,
may I please
marry your daughter?
She's everything I have,
and I love her.
Talking to yourself,
Mr Hopper?
Yeah, I was.
I was actually talking
about you, Nagata.
Mmm-hmm.
(WHISTLING)
(CRASHING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
HOPPER: That's for
kicking me in the face.
Eat it! Take it!
Let go! Let go.
What the…
(HOPPER YELLS)
Sir, it was a fluke accident.
The bathroom floor was wet.
I began to fall.
Captain Nagata kindly
reached out to help.
YUGl: Our heads go bang.
We fall back.
Bang, again.
Just like the great
Jerry Lewis.
Jerry Lewis?
Did he just say
“Jerry Lewis”?
Yes, sir.
BROWLEY: Are you kidding me?
The Bellboy and original
The Nutty Professor.
Very good movies.
He is a great
humanitarian, sir.
You both think this is a joke
and you are very much mistaken.
This will not happen again.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, sir.
Gentlemen, give me a minute
with Mr Hopper, here.
What is wrong with you?
You've got skills, but I have never
ever seen a man waste them like you.
“Keep the ship out of
the surf and spray…”
“…or you will
plunge to destruction.”
Homer, sir.
The fact that you know that
infuriates me beyond words.
What my daughter sees in you
is a great mystery to me.
You are a very
smart individual
with very weak character, leadership
and decision-making skills.
Do you have anything
to say to me? Anything?
Negative, sir.
Enjoy these naval
exercises, Hopper.
They are likely
to be your last.
Dismissed.
WALTER: Is there anything
I can do to help?
Negative.
If you want to
talk about anything…
I don't.
If you change your mind…
I won't.
Roger that.
Contact DESRON ONE. Commence
anti-submarine warfare exercises.
Commence air operations.
(SAILORS SHOUTING)
Good afternoon, Sampson.
Welcome to Day One of
the RIMPAC naval war games.
We are here to sharpen
our skills as a team.
HOPPER: As your
weapons officer,
let me remind you
that this is a combat vessel
and we will excel
in our command and control.
STONE: I want everyone
to stay frosty.
We're going to be close-maneuvering
with 13 nations out here.
We are here to
crush every other ship.
I'm excited to
see what we learn.
We are not here in this
weapons room to learn.
Be safe out there, look out for
each other and keep charging.
If we return to Pearl
without having outperformed
every other ship on that ocean,
I will personally…
Yo, Saunders, we've
ended up in a department
run by some kind of Donald
TrumpIMike Tyson mutant combo.
What was that,
Petty Officer Raikes?
CORA: Nothing, sir.
I swear you said, “Donald
Trump.” Want to clarify?
I think I heard a
“Mike Tyson,” as well.
If you did, it was only
in reference to the fact
that you both project
great physical intensity, sir.
That's flattering.
Hopper! There's a helo
headed for the Sampson.
Make sure your
ass is on it.
Why?
I don't know why!
Just make sure
you're on it!
Copy, sir.
Damn.
PILOT: Scorpion one four, clear our
deck. En route with parts and techs.
OFFICER: Confirm
Lieutenant Hopper en route.
STONE: I just got off
the phone with the JAG.
And?
They are probably going to
kick you out of the Navy.
When?
The day we get back.
From RIMPAC?
Yeah.
You have got to make some
calls. There has got to be…
Who do I call to
teach you humility?
I am sorry,
I don't have that number.
I just don't get it, man.
You have got so
much potential.
I'm sorry you have
to deal with this.
And I am sorry
I let you down.
MAN: Stand up nice and tall.
I want you to focus
on that green marker,
right in the middle
of your back.
MICK: What do you think
I'm paying attention to?
MAN: Keep your
feet together.
My feet can't
get any closer.
Stand up tall. All right.
I had enough of this.
Keep going.
Just a little bit more.
Turn the damned thing off!
Come on.
We're just about there.
Turn it off now!
I'm your new
physical therapist.
I am sensing
a lot of anger.
Very perceptive of you.
Is there anything besides
anger in there, Mick?
Not much.
Your last therapist says that
you lost the will to fight.
Is that accurate?
I lost my fight
when I lost my legs.
Do you realize you're still the same
man that won the Golden Gloves at 22?
A Bronze Star in
Afghanistan? The same man.
I am half a man.
And half a man ain't
enough to be a soldier.
That's all I have ever known.
All right. Let's go.
We are going
to take a walk.
No, we are not.
Legs on.
SAM: You're doing pretty good for a
guy who doesn't want to be hiking.
My dog, Mustard,
could climb this mountain.
Great, you and Mustard can go and
make some memories on Mauna Kea.
Sounds like fun.
Mustard's dead. Mustard
got hit by a dump truck.
I'm sorry.
I'm over it.
Hey. I thought you would
be out of range by now.
HOPPER: I have around
five minutes of left time.
SAM: How is it?
It's fine.
I'm sorry. I messed up.
And I'm going to talk to your
father as soon as I get back.
Stop messing things up, okay?
Copy that. I love you.
I love you.
NOGRADY: What is it, Parker?
Take a look at this.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Nice one.
It's a joke, right?
I don't think so.
(ALARM BEEPING)
My God.
(HUMMING) (THE BLUE DANUBE
PLAYING ON HEADPHONES)
Cal.
(CONTINUES HUMMING)
Cal!
Huh?
Got some weird activity
on all the radar screens.
Weird?
Yeah, man. Really weird.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, uh, Dr Nogrady is
on the phone for you, too.
That is weird.
Seriously, Dr Nogrady?
Lead with that next time.
Okay, Danny?
You got to start
prioritizing your information.
If you have to tell me “1, 2, 3,” you
don't start with “M”
You know what I mean?
I mean, I'm not saying
that you are a boob,
but this is
boob-ish behavior.
Hi, Dr Nogrady.
Are you seeing
what I am seeing?
The incoming tracks.
Correct.
I've got five
distinct objects…
Five distinct objects
that are moving in formation.
They are locked
in on my signal.
They are headed
straight for me.
Correct.
Maybe we should call NASA.
NASA have called us. They're
on the phone right now.
Good morning,
Mr Zapata.
NASA?
We are tracking something
splintering off of the main group.
That's not splitting off.
That thing is breaking apart.
Has anyone called the Chinese?
Because this is no meteor.
Yes, we have checked. It's not the
Russians, it's not the Chinese.
Maybe we should
call the Air Force,
because they might want
to fuel up their jets.
NOGRADY: The Air Force
is online.
It appears the event
is headed your way.
Prepare yourself.
Roger that. How would you suggest
that I prepare myself, sir?
Brace.
(SCREAMS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MAN 1: Let's all be seated.
I am hoping somebody here
can explain this to me.
CHAIRMAN: Mr Secretary, four of the five
objects landed in the Pacific Ocean.
The fifth one appeared
to have broken apart
making significant
contact with Hong Kong,
but other places
were also affected.
Scotland, Germany,
France, even Iowa.
So, what is it?
Sir, at this point we are
working on a couple of theories.
And you are who, sir?
I am with NASA.
What is NASA present
in this room for?
NASA DIRECTOR: We are looking
at the very real possibility
that this is legitimate
extraterrestrial contact.
It appears that it originated
from the Gliese solar system.
Home of Planet G.
You are saying that
we sent out a signal
and we got back
an alien response?
WATCH OFFICER: Sir, we just
got word from Pearl.
They believe whatever made
impact with Hong Kong,
has also made impact
with the Pacific Ocean.
Where in the Pacific?
Approximately 150 miles south of
where we are right now, sir.
It should be right there, but
we are not seeing anything.
Get me the Sampson.
Yes, sir.
Base course, 2-2-0. Speed, 25.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
BRIDGE OFFICER:
Captain on the bridge!
As casualty reports come in,
it's still unclear exactly what
it was that hit Hong Kong.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
It isn't anything
from this planet.
How do we know that?
Because the Chinese
have sampled it.
It's made of a material that does
not exist in the periodic table.
It's literally
not of this Earth.
The only element they've been
able to identify is lawrencium.
Lawrencium?
You got to stop tapping.
You're tapping.
You're the loud one.
NOGRADY: Looking at the
grid patterns, it's something
in the neighborhood
of solar paneling
or communications paneling.
It may be some kind of
a communication unit.
Communications?
Who is communicating what?
To who?
(JIMMY WHISTLING)
JIMMY: What the heck is that?
Bridge, starboard lookout. I've
got an unknown surface contact.
Bearing is 2-3-2 true,
approximately 8·000 yards.
Sir?
STONE: Yeah.
You may want to come
take a look at this.
I am looking at it,
Mr Strodell.
On the radar, sir.
Something very peculiar.
STONE: That's the
John Paul Jones, right?
Yes, sir.
The Myoko?
Yes, sir, it is.
So, why don't I see…
See that?
Combat, Captain. I have a visual on the
track bearing 2-3-7 on the horizon.
What do you hold
in that bearing?
Bridge, TAO.
I've got nothing at 2-3-7.
I'm looking right at it, Mr
Hopper. Find me something.
Scope, 2-3-7, what do
you got? Stand by.
That's negative, sir.
Scope's clear, I got nothing.
Taylor, did you break
this son-of-a-bitch?
No, I didn't do
anything to it, sir.
You know I will throw
your ass off this ship.
I know you will, sir.
Got it, sir.
On my camera.
What is it?
I don't know.
Is this some
kind of exercise?
Probably.
Unknown vessel in the vicinity of
1-5 degrees, 3-7 minutes north,
and 1-5-9 degrees,
3-3 minutes west.
Request you
establish communications
with my vessel
on VHF channel 16,
and identify yourself, over.
John Paul Jones, this is
Sampson, Charlie Oscar.
John Paul Jones,
Charlie Oscar.
I would like you to send a team
over and take a closer look.
No problem. We will get a team
in the water right away.
Roger.
I'll tell you what, boys,
this is a head-stumper.
(SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
WALTER: What is it?
Lost cargo? Chinese?
I don't know.
Yacht? Satellite?
Beast, I didn't know five seconds
ago, and I don't know now.
This is the U.S Navy warship
John Paul Jones.
I'm attempting to
communicate with you.
Prepare to be boarded.
You ever seen
anything like this?
No.
It's weird, man.
(HOLLOW BANGING)
LT! I don't think
that's a good idea.
Got it, chief.
Real bad idea, Lieutenant.
(YELLS)
Oh, shit.
Move it, Raikes!
WALTER: LT!
Lieutenant, get up!
Lieutenant!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Sir!
Get me the Sampson.
WATCH OFFICER: Alpha Bravo.
Sampson, this is Alpha Bravo.
Sir, we're unable to
contact the Sampson.
Reagan control, this is
Rough Rider 4-0-4.
I'm encountering
some severe…
Rough Rider 4-0-4, come in.
Do you copy?
Put the force at weapons posture
one. Warning red, weapons tight.
I want everything loaded.
OFFICER: Bridge,
what's happened?
My radar's totally down, sir.
EXECUTIVE OFFICER: We've lost contact
with base. All comms are offline.
It's the North Koreans,
I'm telling you.
Hey, Lieutenant, you good?
Come on, you with me?
Come on. Damn it!
Come on! Squared away?
I'm squared away.
Whatever that thing is,
it killed the battery.
Come on, Beast.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
What is that?
That's not good.
What the hell is that?
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Do you think that
this could be some
super-secret Navy
surprise exercise?
Because if so, they
have gone way too far.
Let's give them
a warning, Helmsman.
Aye, aye, sir.
(FOGHORN BLOWING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
What the hell is this?
I didn't sign up for this
bullshit! Yeah, no shit, dude.
Klyvich is offline. Should
be back in two minutes.
Copy that.
Signal the John Paul Jones.
Fire a warning shot. One
round, ten mil, left offset.
Place Mount 51 in remote,
batteries released.
WEAPONS OFFICER:
Mount 51 has been designated.
Who are we shooting at?
I do not know.
CORA: Let's move it, Beast.
WALTER: She's dead in the water.
Ord, get your ass
to the Lee helm.
Aye, sir.
MULLENARO: Fire!
Incoming, headed for
the John Paul Jones.
Unknown, inbound
at the horizon.
Vampire, vampire, vampire.
Killing with CIWS.
What kind of
chuckwagon…
Were there men out
on that bridge wing?
Yes, sir, there were.
I got it! Firing it up!
HOPPER: Get in there!
Sir!
Light it up!
(SCREAMING)
MAN: What the hell
is Hopper doing?
All engines, ahead flank.
All engines ahead.
Aye, sir!
Sir, CIC reports both Spy and Fire
control radar cannot lock on.
Fire!
CIC, fire!
Incoming on the right!
JOOD: Incoming, incoming!
We're hit!
(ALL SCREAMING)
HELMSMAN: Sir, we have
a hull breach.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Help me!
Helmsman, get back on
the helm! Aye, sir.
Rapid, continued fire!
No!
(EXCLAIMS IN JAPANESE)
Get me to the
John Paul Jones.
Now!
RADIO OPERATOR: Bridge reports
no survivors in the water.
Sampson, all hands lost.
Targets are holding
defensive formation.
Where's the captain?
Where is he?
What happened?
OFFICER: Captain and XO are dead.
What?
They're dead!
CO and XO are dead.
Who's in charge?
Who's next full senior?
You are.
It's your ship, sir.
You're senior officer, sir.
Sir, if you would please
just give me an order.
I don't know
what to do, sir.
We're going in.
Full attack.
That's an order.
Attack, sir? Really?
You wanted an order,
that's the order. Let's go.
Let's go!
You heard him.
HELMSMAN: Aye, aye, sir!
Ready all guns.
Fire control is offline.
I need three minutes.
Tell Nagata I'm going in,
with or without him.
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
Sir, do you really
want to attack this thing?
Yes! Yes, I do.
(SHOUTS IN JAPANESE)
JIMMY: Sir, that's a hit!
The Myoko was hit, sir.
Are the weapons ready?
Sir, they have killed everything
that's fired on them.
Get the guns online,
and we ram this thing.
They killed my brother
and every man on his ship!
We have no weapons
to attack with, sir.
Then set course to 3-1-0.
That's a collision course!
Are you clear on that?
WALTER: Sir, there are
sailors in the water.
Get the guns online and we're
going to ram this thing!
Sir, the Myoko is sinking!
Sir, please!
Set the course to 3-1-0.
There are sailors
in the water, sir!
Hard starboard.
Hard starboard. Aye, sir!
Get them out of the water.
Yes, sir.
(SIGHS)
GUNNER: What's happening?
Shut up, man.
What the hell is happening?
What the hell are they doing?
Why aren't they attacking?
GUNNER: Are those
things aliens?
Would you please shut up?
GUNNER: We need help! We need
to get the carrier over here!
Who's running the ship?
Hopper.
Are you kidding me?
Hopper's running the ship?
This is bullshit.
We're all going to die!
What the hell
are those things?
What is that shit?
BASE OFFICER: Comms are down
up here. You got anything?
PILOT 1: That's a negative
on all frequencies.
Oh, shit.
HELICOPTER GUNNER:
Abandon 9-30!
PILOT 2: Kill the engines!
Strike!
MAN: Hey, Jack!
Dad?
SHANE: Sir,
I can't explain this.
We've lost communication
with everyone
on the other side
of the barrier.
We can't get in and
they can't get out.
CHAIRMAN: The field, whatever it is,
extends about 300·000 feet in altitude
and has a depth of
about two nautical miles.
COMMANDANT: We are in contact with
Admiral Shane of Pacific Fleet.
Right now, our navy is effectively
trapped outside the area.
So we have nobody in there?
Sir, we have three guided missile
destroyers still unaccounted for.
So, it's conceivable
we do have somebody inside.
Who?
(SAILORS CLAMORING)
Okay. Thank you!
Captain! Captain!
(SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
YUGl: Let's go! Let's go!
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
My grandmother could
climb this mountain.
It's a start, Mick.
What was that?
I'm not sure.
(STATIC CRACKLING)
(SIREN CHIRPS)
What the hell are you
guys doing up here?
I need you off this
mountain, right now.
Wait, what's going on? Why?
The island's under attack.
Attack by who?
I don't know. People are
using the word “aliens.”
Aliens?
We don't know. Whatever it is,
it took out the marine base
and all roads leading to this
mountain have been destroyed.
Cell phones, radios, Internet,
everything is shut down.
The Navy's engaged,
just off of the coast.
The Navy?
I need you and your friend off
of this mountain right now.
Come on, let's go.
Vic, leave your car here.
We'll go block the road.
Where are you going?
Mick! Where are you going?
I ain't never seen an alien.
Have you ever seen an alien?
Mick! Don't leave me alone.
Bra, you saw that?
What the hell was that?
Hey, Vince,
did you see that?
VINCE: It looked like a jet.
Bra, I've never…
Oh, my God! What the hell?
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Sir, we need you.
We need you now.
I can't.
If you can't…
Who can?
Captain.
HOPPER: Where did we find it?
JIMMY: One of their
transporters must have crashed
on the way to the island.
There was debris everywhere.
Thomas and Potts fished him right out
of the water with a grappling hook.
I told them it was a bad
idea, but they kept yanking.
I kept telling them “no,”
and they kept…
Hmm…
(GRUNTS)
Oh…
(ALL EXCLAIM IN SHOCK)
God damn it!
Beast, flashlight.
My dad said they would come.
He said it my whole life.
He said, “We ain't alone.”
He said, “One day
we would find them,
”or they would find us.”
You know what else he said?
He said…
“I hope I ain't around
when that day comes.”
(GASPING)
He's not dead!
Not dead! Not dead!
(GRUNTS)
I've got a bad
feeling about this.
What kind of bad feeling?
Like, “We're going to need a
new planet” kind of bad feeling.
RADIO OFFICER: Medical
casualty, C-53. Two men down.
They're still on the ship.
Lock down the ship!
Is everyone all right?
OFFICER 1: All good, Chief.
Is everyone accounted for?
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO) Just
heard something on Level Four.
Raikes, up.
(SCREAMS)
Hey! Move, move!
HOPPER: What do you see?
Did you see it?
⬄25000÷1000⬄