Is this the last one?
I don't know.
There's
no ether, either.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You there!
Is this the last one?
God, what a mess.
At least
there's no gangrene.
There will be
if it doesn't come off soon.
Well, I can't saw
if I can't keep
my eyes open.
I'm sorry.
Let's coffee up.
He can wait
a few more minutes.
Uh...
Ohh...
Come here!
Move it!
Uh!
Oh!
Oh, God!
Ohh...
Aah!
Glass.
Is that Tucker's men?
Yes, sir.
How long
has it been like this?
We found them
this morning.
They've been here
two days.
Is that you,
Lieutenant?
[Gunshot]
Sons of bitches.
Hey, come on.
You better take cover.
I ain't kidding.
These boys are shooters.
Come on.
Go under cover.
There you go.
You went
to the hospital?
It was no good.
What's going on here?
What's
going on here?
That seems to be the question,
all right.
See, you could
ask the major,
but he don't know.
He's busy.
He's busy
trying to figure out
how come
the officers' mess
run out
of peach ice cream.
The general come up
to see the show.
All he knows is
there ain't no show.
Now, the major,
he's looking
at the general.
He's thinking
to himself,
"I better
do something."
You know
what that means.
I don't want to be
the first one
across this field.
They're supposed to be
beat up just like us.
Everybody knows Tucker's men
are tough as cobs.
So far the only thing
killed out here
is three
milking cows.
That's
about to change.
[Gunshot]
[Confederate Soldier
Imitates Chicken]
You son of a bitch.
Some of the boys
are saying
if we ain't
gonna fight...
we could just settle
this whole business
with a little...
high-stakes poker.
Wouldn't that
be a sight?
A bunch of fellas sitting
in the middle of this field...
drawing cards, huh?
What is it, sir?
Looks like a suicide.
Tucker!
[Gunshots]
What's he doing?
What did you
say to him?
I didn't say nothing.
You showed him, Lieutenant!
[Cheering]
Yay!
Come on back,
you son of a bitch!
Come on back!
All right by me.
Get over here!
Forgive me, Father.
He's coming again!
Here he comes!
Ray!
I got him.
[Bugle Sounds]
Don't...
Don't take off
my foot.
You rest easy, son.
You'll keep your foot.
As God is my judge,
you'll keep it.
Bring up my ambulance.
Sir?
Bring my ambulance,
and bring
my surgeon with it!
We got an officer
who's worth something
lying here.
The strangeness of this life
cannot be measured.
In trying to produce
my own death,
I was elevated to the status
of a living hero.
I was also awarded Cisco,
the trusty mount
that carried me that day,
and was given transfer
to any station I desired.
The bloody slaughter
continues in the east
as I arrive
at Fort Hayes,
a tiny island
of men and material
surrounded by
a never-ending sea of prairie.
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant John J. Dunbar.
Lieutenant John J. Dunbar?
Yes, sir.
"Yes, sir."
Indian fighter, huh?
Excuse me?
You're to be posted
on the Frontier.
The Frontier is
Indian country.
I deduced that
you're an Indian fighter.
I didn't get here
by being stupid.
No, sir.
"No, sir."
It says here
that you've been decorated.
Yes, sir.
And they sent you here
to be posted?
I'm here
at my own request.
Really?
Why?
I've always wanted
to see the Frontier.
You want to see
the Frontier?
Yes, sir.
Before it's gone.
Such a smart lad,
coming straight to me.
[Glass Clinking]
Sir...Knight.
I am sending you
on a knight's errand.
You will report
to Captain Cargill
at the furthermost
outpost of the realm,
Fort Sedgewick.
My personal seal
will assure your safety
through many miles
of wild and hostile country.
I was wondering...
Yes?
How will I
be getting there?
You think I don't know?
No, sir. It's just
that I don't know--
Hold your tongue.
I happen to be
in a generous mood.
See that peasant
out there?
He calls himself Timmons.
He's going to Fort Sedgewick
this very afternoon.
Ride with him.
He knows the way.
Thank you.
That is all.
Sir Knight?
I've just pissed
in my pants...
and nobody can do
anything about it.
[Tapping]
To your journey!
To my journey!
Haw!
Gee over
a little bit, Jim!
The king is dead.
Long live the king.
[Gunshot]
Haw, Jim and Jake!
Haw a little bit,
Jim!
Haw a little bit!
Gee over
a little bit, Jim!
Gee a little bit!
Gee over
a little bit!
What you got there?
Somebody back east
is saying,
"Why don't
he write?"
[Spits]
You stupid
bastard.
What the hell
was that?
What is that?
What the hell
is that?
What is it?
[Coughing]
[Spitting]
[Passes Gas]
Why don't you put that
in your book?
[Coughing]
Were it not
for my companion,
I would be having
the time of my life.
He is quite possibly
the foulest man
I have ever met.
Get up, Timmons.
Timmons.
Get up.
Come on. Get up.
Oh! Ow!
Someone poked me
in my butt.
Was that you?
God damn it!
Damn it!
I'm going to have
a welt.
How come we haven't
seen any buffalo?
You can't figure
the stinking buffalo.
Sometimes you won't
see any for days.
Other times,
they'll be thick,
like curls on a whore.
Ho!
What about Indians?
Indians?
Goddamn Indians!
You just as soon
not see them
unless they're dead.
They're nothing but
thieves and beggars.
Ho up there!
Not what
you would call
much of a going
concern now, is it?
Go down there.
Why? There ain't
nothing down there.
Because I said.
Go down there.
Haw!
Hey, there,
son of a bitch!
There ain't nothing
here, Lieutenant.
Hey!
There ain't nothing
here, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant!
Everybody's run off
or got killed.
All right.
Let's unload
the wagon.
What!
And leave it all here?
I'm staying, too.
There ain't nothing
here, Lieutenant.
No, not at the moment.
We don't know
what's happened.
So, so...
things being
as they are,
we might as well turn around
and get headed back.
This is my post.
"This is my post?"
Jesus H. Christ.
What, are you crazy,
boy? Lieutenant.
Fast son of a bitch.
This is my post.
Put it down.
And these are
the post provisions.
Get your ass
off the wagon
and help me unload.
Put it down!
[Click]
I'll let them know
where you are.
Good.
Good luck,
Lieutenant.
Thank you.
Jake and Jim!
Good mule!
Haw, Jim!
Haw up there now!
Haw! Haw, Jim!
Haw, Jim!
Come on, now!
Get on up in there!
Haw, now! Good mules!
Good mules!
Have arrived to find
Fort Sedgewick deserted.
Am now waiting
for garrison's return
or word from headquarters.
The post is
in exceedingly poor condition,
and I have assigned myself
clean-up duty
beginning tomorrow.
Supplies are abundant,
and the country is everything
I dreamed it would be.
There can be no place
like this on earth.
[Rustling]
Bad horse.
Come on, Cisco.
One more time.
Git up!
Come on! Git up, Cisco.
Git up! There you go!
Easy.
Only a white man would make
a fire for everyone to see.
Maybe there's more than one.
There might be three or four.
I know three or four who will not
be making the trip back home.
We have nothing to show
for this trail.
We have no rifles.
White men
are sure to have rifles.
It's hard to say how many
might be down there.
We should forget this
and go home.
Then go.
I would rather die...
than argue about a single line
of smoke in my own country.
He will not quit
until we are all dead.
And if I...
Aah!
Uh! Uh!
Uhh!
Aah!
Oh, look at me.
Don't...hurt my mules.
Stop it.
Please don't hurt my mules.
Aah!
Whoo!
Whoo-whoo!
Men had been living
in these caves, but why?
Were they frightened?
Had there been some sort of revolt?
I can make no sense
of the clues left me here.
Perhaps my relief
will provide the answers.
It's been almost 30 days.
Still no sign of
Captain Cargill's command.
Communication can only
take place if I leave,
and I don't want
to abandon my post.
Though well-supplied,
I have decided to ration my goods...
as if I were part of a post
rather than the whole affair.
There's a wolf
who seems intent
on the goings on here.
He doesn't seem inclined
to be a nuisance,
and aside from Cisco,
has been my only company.
He has appeared each
afternoon for two days.
He has two
milky white paws.
If he comes
calling tomorrow,
I will name him Two Socks.
[ Singing ]
How can I marry
a pretty little girl
When I got no cloak
to put on?
Oh, soldier,
Oh, soldier
Won't you marry me
Before the fight
comes home?
How can I marry
a pretty little girl
When I got no shoes
to put on?
How can I marry
a pretty little girl
when I got no hat
to put on?
Soldier, oh, soldier,
won't you marry me
Before the fight
comes home?
How can I marry
an ugly little girl
When I got
a pretty wife back home?
[Horse Neighs]
[Speaking Lakota]
You there!
Hey!
Have made first contact
with a wild Indian.
One came to the fort and
tried to steal my horse.
When I appeared,
he became frightened and ran off.
Do not know how many more
are in the vicinity,
but assume where there is one,
there's sure to be another.
Have decided to bury
excess ordnance
lest it fall
into enemy hands.
My afternoon rides
have been pared down
to short circular patrols,
always keeping
the post in sight.
I am still alone, however,
and unless troops
arrive soon,
all may be lost.
It's been two days now
and nothing.
My presence here must have
been reported by now.
Have made all the preparations
I can think of.
Cannot mount
an adequate defense,
but will try to make
a big impression
when they come.
Waiting.
Postscript--
The man I encountered
was a magnificent-looking
fellow.
[Snoring]
I do not care for this talk
about a white man.
Whatever he is, he is not Sioux
and that makes him less.
When I hear that more whites
are coming, I want to laugh.
We took a hundred horses
from these people.
There was no honor in it.
They don't ride well.
They don't shoot well.
They're dirty.
Those soldiers could not even
make it through one winter here.
And these people
are said to flourish?
I think they will
all be dead soon.
I think this fool
is probably lost.
Wind In His Hair's words are
strong and I have heard them.
It's true the whites are
a poor race and hard to understand.
But make no mistake.
The whites are coming.
Even our enemies agree on this.
So when I see one man alone
without fear in our country...
I do not think he is lost.
I think he may have medicine.
I see someone who might speak...
for all the white people
who are coming.
I think this is a person with
which treaties might be struck.
Kicking Bird is always
looking ahead and that is good.
But this man cannot cover
our lodges or feed our children.
He is nothing to us.
I will take some men.
We will shoot some arrows
into this white man.
If he truly has medicine,
he will not be hurt.
If he has no medicine,
he will be dead.
No man can tell another
what to do.
But killing a white man
is a delicate matter.
If you kill one,
more are sure to come.
It's easy to become confused
by these questions.
It's hard to know what to do.
We should talk about this
some more.
That is all I have to say.
[Horse Neighs]
Yes, sir, I have.
No. I'll ask, sir.
[Clunk]
[Shouting
And Whooping]
We'll be heroes!
They'll write songs about us.
What happened?
I don't know.
My arm doesn't work.
You shouldn't have fallen off.
Now we'll get in trouble.
It was your idea.
My idea was only to take
the horse, not fall down.
Otter hurt himself.
What are you looking at?
I'm the one who's hurt.
I will be when my father finds out.
His bow will be across my back.
Oh, God.
[Thump]
Eeeaaaah!
I am Wind In His Hair!
Do you see
that I am not afraid of you?
Do you see?
Whoo!
Aah!
I realize now
that I have been wrong.
All this time,
I've been waiting.
Waiting for what?
For someone to find me?
For Indians to take my horse?
To see a buffalo?
Since I have arrived
at this post,
I have been
walking on eggs.
I am sick of it.
Tomorrow, I will ride out
to the Indians.
I do not know the wisdom
of this thinking,
but I've become a target,
and a target
makes a poor impression.
I am through waiting.
What are you
looking at?
[Woman Singing]
[Singing]
Ahem.
Son of a bitch.
No. Wait.
Wait!
Wait. Wait.
[Crying]
Wait.
You need help.
You're hurt.
Aah!
Uh! Uh!
Let me--
You need help.
Let me help you.
You're hurt.
Uh!
[Speaking Lakota]
[Laughing]
[Screaming In Lakota]
She's hurt.
You are not welcome here.
No. She's hurt.
Go away from us!
You are not welcome!
[Shouting And Whooping]
Stop.
The soldier did not come
to fight.
He is going away
and we will let him.
I am in agreement
with Kicking Bird.
We will go down and talk
to the white man.
And find out why
he is here.
If this council decides to talk
to the white man...
then it will be so.
But in my mind
it's not right...
that a chief as great
as Ten Bears...
goes to ask the business of
a puny, trespassing white man...
who has only a smart horse
and a few white man's clothes.
I will not go.
You will go.
And you will go.
That is all I have to say.
Welcome.
Hi!
Come.
Please, sit down.
Sit down.
Wait just a minute.
His mind is gone.
Tatanka.
Tanka?
Tan-tanka.
Tatanka.
Tatanka. Buffalo.
Buffalo.
Tatanka.
Buff?
Buff--Buff--
Buff--
Buffalo.
Tatanka.
The Fierce One, as I call him,
seems very tough.
I hope I never
have to fight him.
He seems honest
and very direct.
I like The Quiet One
immensely.
He's patient, inquisitive,
and seems eager to communicate.
I would conclude he's a man
of weight among his people.
Buffalo.
[Grinding]
I believe I made a greater impression
on their next visit.
I produced
a coffee grinder,
something none of them
had seen before.
Is the coffee not good?
It's too
strong, maybe.
Too strong,
maybe.
Sugar.
Put in.
Um...
Ta--
Taste it.
Sugar.
You want some?
That's a lot.
It's good to have company.
So much goes unsaid.
I feel these people,
The Quiet One in particular,
want something from me.
Made presents of coffee
and most of the sugar.
Don't believe
I'd go too far in saying
a foundation for good relations
is being laid.
Stands With A Fist.
We will talk a while.
Your wounds are healing well?
Yes, they are.
You are happy here,
with my family?
I am glad to be here.
I am missing my husband.
Perhaps you will marry again
when the time is right?
Perhaps.
We have word from many places
that the whites are coming.
They are coming
into everyone's country.
I think they
will soon be in ours.
This white man who lives
at the old soldier fort...
I have visited him and I believe
his heart is a good one.
I am afraid of the white man
at the fort.
I am afraid he will tell others
that I am here.
I am afraid they will
try to take me away.
I've heard they
take people away.
Every warrior in camp
would fight them if they tried.
I cannot make
the white man language.
He cannot speak Sioux.
It has been a long time
since I made the talk.
I want you to try.
I don't know how.
Yes, you do.
I can't.
It's dead in me.
I don't ask this for myself.
I ask this for all the people.
He knows things about the whites
which we do not.
Now, you must remember.
I can't.
Will she make the white words?
She won't try.
She is being difficult.
Well, she's the one
who's crying.
Perhaps the difficulty
is yours.
Christine!
Get 'em, Joe!
Get them chickens!
Billy, you get away
from those puppies!
Mommy!
I need my puppy!
Go get him!
Damn!
Get the kids,
and get them in the house.
Go on!
In the house.
Christine!
Where are you?
Joe, get in the house
right now!
Who is it, Willie?
They look
like Pawnee.
My father and your father
are talking to them.
What do they want?
I don't know.
Go on. You heard him.
Get out of here.
Run, Christine!
I said run!
Joe! Joe!
Christine!
[Whooping]
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy!
Mmm. Mmm.
Come on, Two Socks.
Bacon.
Two Socks, like Cisco, has
become a trusted friend.
He won't eat from my hand,
but he never fails to alert
me when something is wrong.
Tatanka.
No, I haven't seen
any buffalo.
Sorry.
Are--Are you hungry?
Are you hungry?
I have food.
I have a lot of food.
Nothing I've been told
about these people is correct.
They are not beggars
and thieves
or the bogeymen they've
been made out to be.
They are polite guests with
a familiar humor I enjoy.
Real communication
is slow, however,
and The Quiet One
is as frustrated as I am.
Most progress has been built on failure
rather than success.
I've thought to inquire
about the woman
I found on the prairie,
but it's a complicated subject,
given our limitations.
One thing is clear.
There are no buffalo.
It weighs heavy
on their minds.
Yesterday's meeting
was the best.
I've been invited
to the village.
I'm looking forward
to going.
We were waiting for you.
Now tell him we are glad
that he is here.
Um...
H-H-Hello.
You...
here...
good.
Thank you.
I feel good.
[Translating]
Ask him why he is at
the soldier fort.
Um...
the--the s-s-soldier fort.
Wait, wait,
wait, wait.
What is your names?
Our names?
What is his name?
He's right.
Introductions should come first.
H-H-He...
He Kick--
Kick.
Kick?
More.
More Kick?
More Kicking?
Kicking.
Um...
Bird?
Bird Kicking Bird.
[Speaking Lakota]
What is he...
Is he Chief?
No. H-H-H--
[Speaking Lakota]
H-H-H--
A ho-ho-holy man.
Holy man.
Your name?
I--I--
I don't--
What are you called?
[Speaking Lakota]
Get--Get up?
Stand up?
Stands?
Stands.
Your name's Stands?
Stands. Stands.
With.
With?
Stands With?
With.
Fist?
Yes.
Stands With A Fist?
Stands With A Fist,
I'm John Dunbar.
John--John Dunbar.
Dunbar.
John Dunbar.
Dumb Bear.
No, not Dumb Bear.
Dunbar.
Dumb...
--bar.
Not Dumb Bear.
Dun-bar.
There's been an exciting
breakthrough with the Indians.
The woman I found
speaks English,
and today,
clear progress was made.
I'm reluctant to answer
all their questions.
Something tells me
not to say too much.
It was good to see
Fort Sedgewick again,
Yet I look forward to another visit
with my new neighbors.
This is still my home,
and I remain watchful
for my relief
and hope my negotiations
will bear fruit.
[Rumbling]
[Rumbling Grows Louder]
[Drums Beat
And Chanting]
Buffalo!
I've seen buffalo!
[Whooping]
Buffaloes! Buffaloes!
Tatanka?
Yeah.
[Speaking Lakota]
[Cheering]
Riders were sent
to pick up the trail.
By the time
I gathered my things,
the entire tribe
was well on its way.
Their efficiency and the
speed at which they moved
was enough to impress
any military commander.
I've gone from a person
of suspicion
to one of genuine standing.
I am greeted
with open smiles
and looks
of appreciation.
In short, I have become
a celebrity.
Lieutenant!
Scouts picked up the trail
where I said it would be.
It was not hard to find--
a gigantic swath
of torn-up ground
extending to the horizon.
The numbers it took
to create this image
was hard to imagine.
Lieutenant!
Who would do such a thing?
The field was proof enough
that it was a people
without value and without soul,
with no regard
for Sioux rights.
The wagon tracks leading
the way left little doubt,
and my heart sank, as I knew it could
only be white hunters.
Voices that had been joyous
were now as silent
as the dead buffalo left to rot,
killed only
for their tongues
and the price
of their hides.
[Drums Beating]
[Whooping]
As they celebrated
into the night the coming hunt,
it was hard to know
where to be.
I don't know
if they understood,
but I could not
sleep among them.
There had been no looks,
no blame.
There was only
the confusion of a people
not able to predict
the future.
[Whooping]