...:::Team SóSéries:::..
Translation: FláP, Krysak, Nai and Kenny*
Sync: Los Diablos
Revision: FláP
www. soseries. tv
Fantastic Four
and the Silver Surfer
Bay of Suruga, Japan
Ontém the night FAA...
it was forced to cancel all of the flights
leaving thousands of people arrested.
When you fail electronic and mysterious
apagões appeared at the west of the USA.
But the great history today is
such premature marriage...
of the fantastic couple Reed
Richards and Susan Storm...
that he/she will take place on this Saturday.
REED RICHARDS: Scientist or Celebrity?
Unbelievable.
Strange anomalies have
happened in the whole world...
all challenging the laws
known of the physics.
And everything that the press wants to know is
which the porcelain that we chose.
And which did you choose?
To blue with the small flowers?
- I liked them.
- Do you care?
- Is he/she happening again, it is not?
- Yes, clear.
No, we won't postpone
anything, no this time.
That will be the marriage
with that you always dreamed...
and I won't leave anything to disturb that.
Nor the mysterious transformation
of the matter in a subatomic level.
That is the most romantic thing
that you already told me.
And that is very pathetic
when you for for thinking.
Dr. Richards, feel a lot, but
it seems that are filled up.
But we have rooms
in the economical class.
- Ok, there goes.
- Smile.
- Too much!
- Look at Mother!
- Great, let me more to remove one.
- Everything well.
That is my place.
Excuse.
With license.
The one that you find of we get
patronage of the aerial companies?
For that got
a private jet.
I think we already have
patronages enough.
That funny. But speaking serious...
Reed you could help myself the
to subsidize their small inventions.
- No thank you.
- With license.
- Think about that. I see you later.
- Johnny where you go?
I don't fly in the economical class.
I hope rains.
The snow arrived without warning,
without changes in the temperature...
and it covered the pyramids
with 2 inches of snow.
And in Japan, some are suggesting
that the solidification of the bay...
it was due to activity
volcanic underwater.
Although any similar activity
have been registered in the area.
The scientists discarded him/it
global heating as cause...
of the extraordinary climatic events
that has been registered...
around of the planet.
With the scientists' inefficiency in
to explain the extraordinary events...
Some begin the if perbuntar
if they would be work of God.
Now other you announce...
Reed Richards's marriage and Susan
Storm did with that Manhattan stopped.
The guests include many
members of the elite of New York.
Hello dear.
The city is trying us
to collect for three patrol cars...
that they say that we destroyed.
It was during that
I steal of the armored car.
But I only remember to have
visa two cars be played.
Reed.
Everything well, I will keep.
Were you saying?
I will prove the dress of here the
half hour, later they are the musicians.
Still nor I chose where
to put the flowers...
it is that he/she has so many things for doing.
Don't worry, I am sure
that together we will manage to do that.
And the one that you were
doing when I entered?
Writing down my list
of the one that I have do.
Truth?
- Scout's word.
- Ei, people.
The new ones arrived
what do uniforms, find?
I think won't use that
in way any, Johnny.
What do you have against the capitalism?
- What is that?
- Just my hobby.
It would be a good toy,
or it is something, hum...
- scientific?
- A little of both.
He/she knows I was always
impressed and opposed with that.
It is, Sue said that
I am addicted in that.
Why imagine she would say that...
Ei, Johnny.
Be quiet but...
I analyzed and I correlated
the global disturbances.
They are being caused for
a cosmic radiation...
- as the one that gave us our powers.
- Ours, that is...
very annoying. Then hear...
I have a very important subject of the
marriage that I need to discuss with you.
- Yes, clear.
- His/her farewell of single.
No, speaking to serious Johnny.
John...
Several studies show that Johnny
it is only bonitinho when if it is young.
Speaking to serious Johnny,
without farewell of single.
It is not my thing type.
Then make that for Ben...
that means a lot for the grandão,
you will break his heart!
He has a heart half
what of stone, is not?
I have him/it a lot that
to do before the marriage,
and sincerely I think the
Sue cannot like that.
He/she knows what I think
would not Sue like?
That somebody said her
that you were actually...
investigating disturbances
global and cosmic radiation...
instead of being
concentrating in the marriage...
like you he/she promised.
A farewell of single
it can be entertaining.
But without exotic dancers.
- Is that here?
- I don't know anybody here.
I would have guest some their friends,
but you don't have none.
Johnny, we made a treatment.
They are not exotic dancers!
They are just pleasant!
You are Sr. Fantastic
it is not? That too much.
You are a lot of bonitinho.
I need a picture with the
larger dancer than you have.
Without problems.
Good night, and be well vindos to Baxter.
Can I help you?
You cannot use that elevator.
Srta. Storm will see you in one moment.
Hello?
Thank you Roberta.
- Can I help you?
- We came to see him/it Dr. Richards.
I feel a lot, but him
he/she is not here in the moment...
Ownership to help him/it with some thing?
Yes, it can take me
to see him/it Dr. Richards.
Right.
Excuse.
When the universe
he/she began was a ball...
and later: Bum!
He/she exploded.
And in a second trilhonésimo...
he expanded exponentially
until the size that we knew today.
You are very intelligent.
Thank you, that means a lot for me.
I adore that music!
- Does he/she want to dance?
- I don't want.
He/she wants yes! You will dance very well!
I don't want to pass shame.
Relax! Have fun a little!
Quite so! Yes!
Quite so!
- He does know as loosening!
- With certainty.
- Oh it is him.
- Yes.
Unhappily...
For him.
Do let us go?
I think is hour of giving wood.
Sue! The one that you are...?
General Hages.
We are going to a quieter place.
Unless you need to take
some drink in the belly of somebody.
I was explaining to the girls on...
Big Bang's theory.
It was idea of Johnny, me only...
I went with him.
How does Reed know the General?
There are some years he tried to approve
a system of defense anti-missile...
Reed testified that the
technology would not work.
I am here Richards because I am
under direct orders of the state bosses,
personally I don't like the idea
of sharing delicate information...
with a civil scientist.
Especially a scientist that
he/she likes to be in the news like this.
Always a pleasure to see you also General.
In what I can serve him/it?
As he/she should know...
...he/she has been having strange events
recently around of the world.
Officially we have been reducing
his/her importance for the public...
but we are worried that these...
anomalies are a threat
the national security.
Those pictures were taken by one of
our satellites spies two days ago.
What is?
We waited that the Dr.
Richards told us.
I fear that he/she never has
seen something similar.
Ben?
I would say that is a meteor...
but the path is all wrong.
This thing is using
his/her own energy.
See that.
That has spirit around of the
world since the events began.
We esteemed that he/she has one
diameter of 200 meters.
If we will discover what is that...
we needed to locate and
to intercept that object.
It would be possible to create a sensor one linked the
level of satellites of the building Baxter...
and we could obtain the exact
location of the object.
Good, then you will build
the sensor for us and...
I fear that I am not able to.
The something?
I will get married in this
Saturday, I don't have time.
Richards, his/her country needs his/her help.
Because you don't call for
teacher Jeff Wagner...
he is the director of the
Department of Physics in Brown...
- I am sure that he can help you.
- He/she waited plus, Richards.
Even of you.
John Storm, Fantastic Quartet Ltda.
- Did he/she already make some work as model?
- I am not interested.
- You have a wonderful composition.
You just left.
And me definitively
I am still speaking.
I don't believe that you ended of
to refuse a scientific project.
They can build the sensor without me.
The most important thing in that
moment is our marriage...
- without postponements, without interruptions.
- Thank you.
And look, on the one that
you saw there at the bar...
Don't worry, I know you.
I am happy that he/she has if entertaining.
Thank you.
Besides...
...that nor it is compared with the one that me
I did in mine dismissed of unmarried woman.
That yes it was wild!
Wild?
Let us go!
Ei, what are you making here?
Anything, I just came to take an air.
He/she is making that thing
for the General, it is not?
I suppose that Susie no
he/she knows anything about that.
Don't worry, mine
lips are stamped.
Or they would be if I had some.
Don't tell Johnny.
- Don't tell Johnny the something?
- Great.
- Are you building that thing?
- It is not...
If Sue knows, you will receive
an invisible kick in the balls.
- Ei, will maintain that in secret.
- I know.
Don't worry.
They are calling of
"The Marriage of the Century."
Reed Richards and Susan Storm
also known as...
Sr. Fantastic
and the Invisible Woman...
they will get married today in a ceremony
matter in New York...
- Look at those parasites.
- Unbelievable.
They are not embarrassed?
Ei! All hear! That is one day a lot
special for my sister,
probably the more
special of her life.
He/she only wanted to say you is for for
favor to respect our privaciade.
I am only playing, we will be auctioning
pictures of the marriage to who gives more...
Then space online and put
their bets, thank you.
What is necessary for
to date the Human Torch?
Lingerie the proof of
fire and a lot he/she will aloe-see.
Thank you.
SUSAN STORMS AND REED RICHARDS
- His/her invitation gentleman?
- I should be in that list.
- His/her name?
- Stan Lee.
- Yes, well good attempt.
- Serious, I am Stan Lee.
It was not as soon as I imagined.
It is never.
No, Alicia.
It is that doesn't seem to be right.
Wanted...
I think even the super-heroes...
they can feel nervous
in the day of the marriage.
It is more than that...
it will be that my life
will a circus always be?
It will be that we want to create
our children with all this?
We are not exactly normal.
Ben and I are not normal...
But we didn't leave that us
to impede of we be happy.
Do you love Reed?
Plus that I already loved anybody.
Then he/she doesn't need if
to worry with anything.
Thank you.
Ok.
- Great.
- The something?
I am with a spine.
- Cannot it throw make-up on top?
- No, leave with me.
Avoided crisis.
Now I only need to ponder
continually for the next 8 hours.
Reed goes!
- You will lose his/her own marriage!
- One minute.
Almost finishing.
General, I am putting
the sensor online...
- now!
- SYSTEM ONLINE.
That, if there is an increase
if cosmic radiation...
anywhere in the
planet you will know.
Hopefully that yes Richards...
we already had registration
of more two craters.
Oh the bride comes...
Everything well, leave me just
to do a link with my PDA.
- Reed.
- Ready.
Great, now will shave and to put
his/her tuxedo, you will get married in one hour,
and it seems a ragged one.
Clear.
The something?
I will get married!
Oh, ours.
I will get married.
He/she is getting afraid...
SYSTEM ONLINE
Hello, Johnny.
Anybody more he/she was surprised?
How did he/she know that was me?
I didn't say anything.
For speaking the truth you
he/she is smelling to ashes.
He/she is late.
Oh, we won't speak about me today...
He/she is Reed's great day and Sue.
We will give attention to them for varying.
Don't make that.
- He/she is perfect.
- You are perfect.
We see each other up there.
Good-bye Johnny.
He/she seems that you and Alicia space well...
Irritatively well.
It is, I am a lucky guy.
Yes, you are.
But I have a pregunta for you...
Like you...?
That is not of his/her bill!
He/she is well! He/she was only concerned.
He/she would hate to wake up one day and to see
that she was killed in an avalanche.
I will show you an avalanche!
SATELLITE SPY OF THE EUA EPSILON
What are you?
Thank you.
Johnny?
You should not provoke him/it so much.
It was a joke.
I think really inconveniences you
to see him/it happy and passionate.
- I think you are jealous.
- Jealousies?
Did you see the women that I dated?
No.
You can only make a mistake
for a time, Torch.
Ei, is the bride of the man esticável!
- Don't begin.
- Ignore him/it. You are beautiful.
We see each other outside.
Let us go! He/she is in the hour.
Ok.
He/she knows, you don't seem completely
ridiculous in that dress.
It is a brother's way to say
"You until that is well?"
You are beautiful.
Thank you.
Dad would be proud.
Yes.
ALERT OF COSMIC RADIATION
- Reed, turn off that cellular one.
- Actually that is...
Dear friends, we are
gathered here for...
Sweat and Reed! Congratulations for the marriage!
where was I?
Dear friends, we are gathered
here today to unite this couple...
Reed Richards and Susan Storm...
with the bow...
- of the sacred...
- ALERT OF COSMIC RADIATION
marriage.
I don't believe that you
he/she brought that to the marriage!
I know, but there is a good reason.
- We have to end with that soon.
- That romantic.
- Do I continue?
- Yes, please.
- There are many love types.
- Can it jump for final, please?
- Reed!
- How?
IMMINENT ARRIVAL NEW YORK
He/she fails in the motor! We will fall!
Late too much.
- Go for top!
- I am trying!
Ben!
- Johnny!
- That is a Dolce.
To catch fire!
Ours, he is fast!
Oh, that is legal!
Boastful!
Hour of ending with that.
Can we talk?
Tá well...
you won.
To catch fire! Let us go!
To catch fire!
Hello.
His/her herald calls him/it.
Another world waits for him.
Begin fast.
He/she seemed a man...
but completely covered with
silver and he flew in one...
thing type a surf board.
- I know that seems madness.
- No, that is that.
Then, you followed brilliant man...
until the Earth of the candies
at the end of the Rainbow?
- Look, I know what saw.
- Thank you, it is right, Johnny.
Be there which goes his/her aparêcia...
he has the power of
to transform matter and energy.
Did he cause the anomalies then?
He seems to irradiate
energy when he/she makes an effort...
affecting matter aleatóriamente.
Evidently this entity, this...
Silvered surfer...
he/she didn't want to be detected.
He/she destroyed the sensor.
- Did he know that was being watched?
- And he tracked here.
We are working with
somebody very skilled.
Are you feeling well?
Yes, I will walk for getting better.
We have to destroy that thing
before he attacks again.
Find other way to track him/it.
Sweat, I feel a lot.
The only reason of me not to have you counted
it was to avoid that if it worried.
I am not angry for you
to have built the sensor.
- It was the right thing to do.
- That good.
I still didn't finish.
Certain, excuse.
Please, continue.
Did he/she see? That proves him/it exactly
that I have statement the whole time.
- Can you remove the field, porfavor?
- Us nor we can...
Oh, excuse.
We are not able to nor to have a marriage
without turning to 3rd World war.
I know, but when we are
married, everything will return to the normal.
We will never have normal lives
while we do what do.
How can we create a family like this?
I will see how Johnny is.
Johnny?
Ei, are you well?
Johnny, are you well?
I don't know.
I feel strange from
that I found the Surfer.
Maybe we should examine him/it.
- Because you made that?
- Me no fize anything!
Stop, lie down and roll!
My god! Sue!
Calm! I will stick to!
To catch fire!
Care!
Reed!
- Help!
- Sue?
I am catching fire!
- Sue! What is having he/she?
- I am catching fire!
- You are catching fire!
- Do you find?
- Wait!
- Pull me for inside!
It is the Human Torch!
- I am not Johnny!
- Sue! How did this happen?
I played Johnny and that happened!
- Where is Johnny?
- Here!
Play her again!
Ei, come out then!
Sweat, their clothes!
Because that always happens with me?
Sue's results are normal.
- But the one of Johnny...
- The one of Johnny the something?
His/her encounter with the Surfer
he/she modified their molecules...
they are floating.
Is that bad?
It took him temporarily the
to change of powers with Sue.
- He/she would like to do some tests...
- Does he/she want a volunteer?
- No!
Wait! That is serious!
He/she only wanted Ihe to give a hug.
We don't know the extension
of his/her problem still.
It can be progressive,
it can be degenerative...
- It can be entertaining!
- Ben, not!
- Ben!
- Ei, am me!
I returned!
Oh, my God!
Ah go!
- Have just said that that was serious!
- Ah yes, serious.
You can only be playing!
- Ei, is not anything badly.
- Incredible.
- It is good that you do something about that!
- I am taking care of that.
Ben stops with that!
I am beginning to see
because you like that.
No, no, no, no, not.
- Ah, drug.
- It is not graced!
What should I make in the middle time?
Only try to maintain far away from us.
You and I will begin to pass
a lot of time together, friend!
Internal Fontes says
that unlucky Sue Storm...
If it turned invisible and
he/she should continue like this...
...after the fiasco
shameful yesterday.
To proceed, the largest mistakes
of the Invisible Woman's fashion...
and a dance choreography
of former-scientist Reed Richards.
Because you continue the
to see ese garbage? Ignore him/it!
I cannot ignore him/it Reed,
he/she doesn't have as escaping of that.
- I think he/she has!
- How?
Did he/she see? He/she doesn't have an answer.
Yes, he/she has.
It is been...
after this crisis to end...
- do everything leave for behind?
- What are you speaking about?
We moved of the Edifício Baxter...
I arrange a vacancy of
teacher somewhere.
I return to my research.
And we will have our lives and we will create
a family as normal people.
Would you make that?
Nothing is more important for
me of our together future.
Ah, thank you.
And as for Ben and Johnny?
They will understand.
Besides, Johnny always
he/she liked more of acting alone.
But we won't tell to them still.
They already have enough with the one that if
to worry with his/her altered power.
GLACIER RUSSELL GROELÂNDIA
You have been having been busy, friend.
Their talents are impressive.
Can you understand him/it what am speaking?
Together, we can be unbeatable.
Everything would have that wanted.
Everything that you know
he/she is reaching the end.
What does with that mean?
Wait!
I spoke for waiting!
They will put an end to the team.
I heard Reed and Sue talking,
they want a normal and annoying life.
Nothing else of Fantastic Quartet.
What should make?
- To continue only both of us?
- Calling us of something?
- The Dynamic Duet?
- When did they go in the saying?
When they are ready to say.
It is their decision, no of you.
They cannot be angry with them
for they do what leave them happy.
Boys...
We have a serious problem.
I compared the Surfer's radiation with
the whole base of astronomical data.
Altair 7, Rigel 3, Vega 6.
- Was he in all these planets?
- It is now they are without life.
They are sterile, some are to the pieces.
Where the Surfer goes,
8 days later the planet dies.
And how will we impede him/it?
Us nor we know where he is.
And the craters?
They are appearing
in numeric sequence.
The last crater was
formed in Groelândia, then...
the close in the sequence should be...
to 51 degrees, 30 minutes,
north latitude...
longitude: 0 degrees,
7 minutes to west.
When the Surfer appears we have
that to move away the fight of the crowd.
He is very fast for being contained.
- When I see the Silvery, I will attack!
- He/she cannot make that!
We will follow the plan and
to work as a team.
Are Ah, then now a team?
- What are you speaking about?
- You know what am speaking!
- We will tell to you...
- When will they count?
When they were removing
the things of the building?
Johnny, really
it is not a good time.
The boy is right Reed,
you should have us counted.
Certain, already arrives!
We will talk about that later!
What devils do have wrong with you?
Don't loosen!
Move, we go!
No! Johnny!
People! What are making?
- Ben! Get up higher!
- I will try.
Sue!
Be far!
Before it ends up killing somebody.
My God!
What devils were that?
We will make modifications.
Next time we will be ready.
Next time?
There won't be next time.
You are not able to
to take care of that, alone.
It is for that that I am bringing help.
To bring soldiers and weapons will go for
innocent people in danger.
No more than you already put.
Victor?
Which the problem?
Is he/she afraid of ghosts?
Don't move!
Being a ghost, he/she won't care
if I break his/her neck!
- Loosen him/it!
- Who does know he/she he is?
Victor Von Doom.
He is here under my orders.
Ben, loosen him/it.
How is it possible?
How can it still be alive?
It was not thanks to you
four, that I guarantee.
Von Doom made contact
with the Martian...
...and he/she has valuable information.
Information that can
to save the planet.
Let us leave a very clear thing...
Right?
I hate them.
All you.
But the world is in game and
we needed to join to survive.
We know for experience that if
to trust Victor will be sorry.
Up to now only I was sorry of
to have trusted you, Richards.
Reed, don't accept.
Let us see what he has.
I made a detailed recording
of our encounter.
Everything that knows is
reaching his/her end.
Is it then?
I like the part in that he drops you.
Look at the levels of
energy when they attack me.
There! Did they see him/it what happened?
The energy was channeling for
him, but he/she originated from the board.
If we separate him of his/her board,
we can cut his/her energy entirely.
- We needed to do that.
- How?
If I not knew
he/she would need you.
You two começem already.
I am happy of we be
working together again.
I will try to speak slowly,
for you to understand.
- How can we form an alliance with Victor?
- I don't understand.
It was much simpler
when it could ignore him/it.
I will pay for that!
It is good same.
I need to tell you, Ben.
I begin to feel that am
a complete one unsuccessful.
Well, I not complete.
Thank you.
It doesn't depend more on us,
now it is with the inteligentes.
He/she thinks Reed has
reason on the end of the world?
He/she never wandered on those things.
And I am not one
very sentimental person.
Truth?
But if Reed is
certain and that is the end...
How does he/she want their last minutes to pass?
He/she leaves of me wants go struggle.
But the truth...
I would like to pass my last ones
minutes hugging Alicia.
He/she seems great.
I want to say, it doesn't break her
of hugging Alicia.
She is his/her girlfriend,
I don't want anything with her.
No that it is not attractive, it is
very attractive, too attractive!
Even with...
You understand.
I don't imagine a guy
that would not want...
The one that I want say...
it is great to have somebody.
You have to me, friend.
How is it going going?
I don't get to find a connection.
- Everything will be well. You have...
- Don't go!
Everyone bill with me and...
Reed, you will find the solution.
- He/she always finds.
- Yes thank you, Su.
- He/she just needs to relax.
- Clear.
It is true.
Reed, needs to relax.
Breathe bottom.
Slowly.
It is that there.
We go, again.
Did he/she see? I already get to feel
his/her pulsation decreasing.
- He/she remembers that time...?
- A pulse.
A pulse of Taquión.
I love you.
I am happy in could help.
- How does that work exactly?
- When we activate the field of force...
it will separate him/it of his/her board
leaving him/it without being able to.
As a fish in the net.
Yes.
At least in theory.
- How much lack to have that ready?
- Three hours.
Three hours?
I know, I cannot be faster,
I am working alone now.
- What does to finish need?
- Actually, some things.
The engineer of the field of force...
What is making he/she?
Doesn't he/she beat when entering?
He/she should be helping
to Reed in the laboratory.
Say to calm, I will be
there to hold his hands and...
to finish the project for him.
Plus some thing?
How did he/she do?
How did it return?
Does that scare you, not?
The things that I can do.
He/she knew that can create a field
of force inside of somebody...
and to expand him until exploding?
Give his/her best blow.
Just return to the laboratory.
Sr. Storm?
We will intercept the Silver Surfer
in 10 minutes, with or without you.
You were waiting out of the
bathroom to try to see me of towel?
It was game, he/she was playing.
Why is so hard with me?
Nor he/she knows me.
I know him/it very well, I read
his/her personality profile.
Confident, careless, irresponsible.
Obsessed for himself,
almost narcisista.
He/she is well, yes he/she knows me.
Everything that I saw was a face
that almost killed his/her team.
Everything well.
I have been playing badly lately.
That is not a game.
BLACK FOREST GERMANY
Mister, he is in one
position to the north of here.
- Great.
- General...
- Feel a perimeter of 2 Km.
- Forget, Richard.
He/she already had his/her opportunity
and it wasted.
That is a military operation, now.
Block the sign, stand back and
let to do us our work.
- You don't understand.
- No, you that doesn't understand.
Let to explain to me to you and
his/her bunch of eccentric here.
I am the quarterback,
you are in my team.
Did he/she understand?
But I think never played
American soccer in the school.
It is not even, Richards?
No, he/she is right.
I didn't play.
He/she was studying, as
a good student nerd.
And 15 years later...
I am one of the minds
more diamonds of the century 21.
I am fiancé with the girl
sexier of the world.
And the great athlete that was
quarterback in the school...
he/she is in front of me,
asking for me help.
And I say that won't help
in absolutely anything...
unless he/she does what I say.
And begin to treat me and mine
friends with more respect.
Give to him that he wants.
I am burning me
so much for you, now.
- Me also!
- Care, Johnny!
It is here.
You have their coordinates.
Prepare their positions and
meet of turn here.
Primero squadron, move forward!
He/she scared me, Smonk.
He/she looks at you, as it is beautiful.
It is quite so, continue
running, Bu-Bu!
Plush ball super developed.
- Which is the situation?
- I am ready.
Me also.
I am almost.
Boys?
We have a problem.
- What was?
- He is here.
Leave then, right now!
Why is destroying our planet?
I don't have choice.
- Sue!
- Wait!
The one that wants say with:
"Don't I have choice?"
There is always a choice.
Not always.
Why is trying to destroy us?
I am not the destructor.
We are going Richards, block
the damned sign.
Maybe need a little persuasion.
- Shoot one.
- Understood.
To open fire!
Stand back!
- Leave me...
- No, wait!
Reed.
We are going Sue!
Ready.
Reed!
I diffused him.
It is not so strong now, it is not even?
Victor, stand back!
You are the quarterback!
Watch him/it.
Continue appearing for him!
Take him.
STATION OF INYEPTUK
- General, we had a treatment.
- Calm down!
The enemy was captured,
accomplished mission.
- Where is he?
- Arrested.
General?
Sr. Sherman.
If they give us license,
we have work to do.
- I want to be in the interrogation.
- It won't be possible.
Assure that our guests
be here, comfortably.
Yes, gentleman.
General, and the board?
He/she is in a camera
that codifies her sign.
There are things that I cannot do
because they violate human rights.
Happily, you no human being.
Are we prisoners?
How did that happen?
Seemingly, they don't want that
interfere with their methods.
Nor I imagine him/it that
they are doing with him.
It is what deserves.
How can that say?
Maybe the General was right.
The guy was about to destroy
the planet, he said.
He/she doesn't have sense.
He protected me of the missíl.
- Why would make that?
- Maybe you find beautiful.
He/she has much more something in that.
He said that was not the destructor.
Maybe have lied.
We needed to enter there and to speak with him.
But without they notice.
He/she has as it gets us some DVDs...
or popcorn or something like that
for the time to pass?
- I will ask.
- Excellent, thank you.
Semper Fi.
Those are the riflemen
naval, we are the army.
Certain, I know.
You are the army.
Captain Raye, allowed access.
General, Von Doom
he/she wants to speak with you.
He/she should cooperate a little more.
Sr. Sherman.
We will make a pause.
I know that is there.
How if he/she calls?
He/she should have a name.
My name is Susan.
You said that was not who was
trying to destroy our world.
Then who is it?
- That who I serve.
- And to who you do serve?
I am trying to help you, but for
that, needs to tell me the truth.
Please.
It is known by many names,
my people called him/it of...
Galactus.
The Devouring of Worlds.
He/she has to feed of
energy to survive.
So much thermal...
as organic.
- How can it help him/it?
- Because I am thank you.
He/she doesn't inconvenience to help you the
to destroy worlds and innocent people?
When serving him/it, me safe my world.
And the person that I love.
Why did try to protect me?
Because...
you make to remember of her.
You get to stop
the Destructor if he/she wants?
I am not me who he/she brings him/it
Destructor here, is the light-guide.
- What is the light-guide?
- The source of my power.
His/her board?
Take advantage the last ones
hours that remain you...
because he is almost here.
I helped to give him/it
extraterrestrial, as I promised.
It is hour of accomplishing his/her part of the treatment.
You can make the tests in the board.
But only with guards
armed and in my presence.
Logical.
General Hager, allowed access.
It is the board that attracts him/it for here.
As if it struggles with something
what can eat planets?
We have to take the board for
far away from here before it is late.
He/she thinks the General
will he/she agree with that?
He doesn't have choice.
Thank you General.
But I fear...
The truth is that...
Sometimes Reed is right.
Ei you, come here.
Let to wonder a thing.
Very well.
Ah, drug!
Ben!
Certain, that didn't hurt.
Where is Reed?
Here behind.
He/she blames my.
Reed!
Victor. We have to recover her.
We needed the surfer, he is
the only that he/she knows her power.
Even if loosen him/it,
how will we reach Victor?
Leave that with me.
- Stopped!
- Be where they are!
Friendly...
That is his/her lucky day!
That devils are happening
Where is the General Hager?
He is dead.
And if we don't remove him
of here, all will be.
Frankie...
The world is literally
in game, here.
You have to trust us.
Please.
We have to arrive in the roof!
He should already be here!
What should be here he/she?
Gee!
Reed...
Esssa was the thing
more legal than you already did!
- Is a Hemi?
- Clear.
Ben, you go there inside.
Johnny, fly behind us.
- He/she has to let to pilot me.
- He/she can forget.
- I am the best pilot here.
- Is he/she speaking serious?
We will have that is supplied
to tolerate his/her weight!
I can fly in circles the
his/her turn of eye blindfolded.
Shut up and move her!
I pilot!
Certain, now we are
officially enemies from the USA.
Victor is somewhere
for oh, with being able to limitless.
And we have a force
giant intergalática...
that will destroy the planet in less
of 24 hours. Did I forget of something?
I caught a trace of
energy left by Victor.
He/she is on the southeast of China.
Sit tight!
Norrin Radd.
The something?
I was already known as Norrin Radd.
Norrin, will need yours
he/she helps to save our world.
Do you understand?
What devils were that?
Victor, the board is
attracting the Destructor here.
You have to open her hand.
He/she knows that never went of the type
of opening hand of the things, Reed.
Be held!
We are an easy objective.
We have to separate!
- The something?
- That should be to be entertaining!
Be close to me, Sue.
I am irritating myself of truth.
Hour of surfing, metal head!
Victor, just the Surfer
it can stop the Destructor...
but he needs his board.
- Come to catch her, Richards!
- Victor!
We will give a rotated!
Norrin!
I caught you!
Sue!
My God!
Sue...
Johnny doesn't play in her!
They need to discover one
way of catching the board.
Sweat, me...
He is here.
Reed?
Victor should have an originator of
pulses that he/she arrests him the board.
If we remove the originator...
we can separate him/it of the board.
- He is too strong for me.
- I could catch him/it...
if I arrive close enough, but him
I can see myself the a mile of distance.
We needed all of us.
Or maybe just one of us.
We don't know him/it that that
he/she can do with you.
We won't turn that on me.
To mention my friend:
It is hour of giving wood!
He/she won't die struggling, boy.
Not without me!
You have to go!
All value the moments with her.
And say that she was right.
We have a choice.
I thought that was able to
to need of a help.
My God!
Why is not working he/she?
We arrived too late.
No more I will serve you.
That is the end for both of us.
Hi.
What did I lose?
- We got!
- Good work, boy!
He/she waits, I am not changing.
You are right.
Great!
Certain, now you are me
leaving uncomfortable.
Then I think is that.
Each one is going to his/her side.
No.
No?
- No!
- No?
If it didn't go for the team, the world
all would have finishing now.
We cannot flee of
our responsibilities...
and of the people that we needed to protect.
That is who we are.
- It is what I was saying.
- And his/her normal life, a family?
Who said that is necessary to be
normal to have a family?
Then it is prepared for more
a marriage full of press?
The fifth time is the lucky.
No.
I have a better idea.
Dear friends, we are here gathered
here to unite Reed Richards...
and Sue Storm in sacred matri...
...mônio
What was?
Venice is sinking
in the Adriatic sea.
Ah skies, that is serious.
Can we jump for the end?
- The love that shares...
- No the same end..
Excellent, does he/she have the rings?
Now I declare them husband and
woman, and he/she can kiss the bride.
- Certain, we should go.
- Yes.
- I have to go.
- Everything well.
I have to play the bouquet.
Prepared?
Attention, Johnny!
Excuse!
It was a reflex!
www. soseries. tv
Lower of who does! Help who helps you!