Harry Potter and Chamber of secret
I can't not let you out, Hedwig
I am not allowed to use magic outside of school.
besides, if uncle Vernin.....
Harry Potter!!!
now, you've done it!
Petunia!
I am warning you, if you can't control that bloody bird, it'll have to let it go
but she's bored
if can only let her out an hour or two.
ha! so, you can send secret messages to your freaky little friends ? no sir!!
but I haven't had any messages from any of my friends
not one!
who want to be friends with you?
I think you should be a little more grateful, we raised you since you are a baby.
give you the food on our table, even you had the dudley's second bed room, purity of goodness of our hearts!
Not now, Pumpkin, look, Mason's will arrive
Which should be any minute!
let's go over our schedule once again, shall we?
Petunia,when the Mason's arrive,you will be?
In the lounge, waiting to welcome them graciouslly to our home
good,Dudley, you will be?
I will be waiting to open the door
Excellent!
and you?
I will be in my bedroom
making no noise and pretending I don't even exist
too right you will!
without any luck this could to do harm to the biggest deal of my career,
and you will not mess it up!
Harry Potter! Such an honor it is!
Who are you?
Dobby, sir! Dobby, the house elf!
Not to be rude or anything, but it isn't a great time for me to have a house elf in my bedroom
Oh, yes sir, Dobby understands !
it is just...Dobby have come to tell you
it is difficult to,sir
Dobby wander where it begin
Why don't you sit down?
Sit down!  Sit down?
Oh......
oh, Dobby, shushi...I am sorry, I didn't mean to offend you or anything
Offend Dobby? Dobby has heard your greatness, sir
but never has been asked to sit down by a wizard
like equal
You can't have met many decent wizards then
No, I haven't
but it is an aweful thing to say
Stop, Dobby, stop!
Dobby, please stop!
Oh, don't mind that, it's just the cat!
Stop, Dobby, Stop!
Are you all right!
Dobby have to punish himself, sir
Dobby almost spoke ill of his family, sir
Your Family?
The wizard family Dobby serves, sir...
Dobby is bound to serve one house and one family forever,
if he has ever knew Dobby was here, oh....
But Dobby has to come, Dobby has to protect Harry Potter, to warn him
Harry Potter must not go back to Hogwarts,
the school of  Witchcraft and Wizardry this year!
there is a plot
a plot to make most terrible things happen
What terrible things?
Who's plotting them?
Ah..I...Can't...Say !!!
Ok, I understand
you can't say!
Dobby, Dobby, put the lamp down !
so, when there arrives nine folks
can we go on?
Dobby, stop
get in that and keep quiet!
what devil are you doing out there?
I was just....
You've just ruined the
punch line of my Japanese golfer joke
sorry
One more sound and you'll
wish you'd never been born, boy!
fix the door!
yes, sir
See why I've got to go back to
Hogwarts?
I don't belong here
I belong in your world, Hogwarts
it's only place I got friends
Friends who don't even write to Harry Potter?
well, I expect they've just been...
Hang on, how do you know my friends haven't been writing to me?
Harry Potter mustn't be angry with Dobby.
Dobby hoped ... if Harry Potter
thought his friends had forgotten him ...
Harry Potter might not want to
go back to school, sir . .....
give me those
now!
no
Dobby, come back here
Dobby, Please
No
Harry Potter must say he is not going back to school
I can't,Hogwarts is my home
then, Dobby must do it, sir
For Harry Potter's own good!
I am so sorry
it's my nephew, he is very disturbed!
we think strangers upset him, let we keep him upstairs
you are never going back to that school
you are never going to see those freaky friends of yours again
never
Hi, Harry!
Ron? Fred? George?
What are you all doing here?
Rescuing you, of course!
Come on, get your trunk!
Better stand back
drive!
let's go!
Are you hearing anything?
what's it?
Potter---------!!!
Come on, Harry
Petunia,he is escaping!
uncle, to heaven....
come out!
let go of me!
no, no, boy, you and that bloody pigeon,
I am not, anywhere!
drive
not!
by the way, Harry, Happy birthday!
hi, come on
Just think of if they are aware of this
they wouldn't, would they?
it is not much! but it's home
I think it is briliant!
where have you been?
Harry, how wonderful to see you, dear
beds are empty, no note, car gone,
you could've be dying, you could've been seen
Of course, I don't blame you, Harry, dear
they were starving him, Mom
put bars in his window
you best hope I don't put bars on your window,Ron and Weasley
come, Harry, time to some breakfast
Here we go, Harry, not talking, That's it, Here we go
Mom, have you seen my jumpa?
yes, it was on the cat
hello
what did I do?
Ginny,She's been talking about you all summer
it's getting annoy really
Morning, Weasleys!
Morning
What a night,Nine raids. Nine!
raids?
Daddy works in ministry of magic
The Misuse of Muggle Artifacts Office.
Dad loves muggles,he think they are facinating
well done, ah.....
and, who are you?
oh, sorry, sir
I am Harry, sir
Harry Potter
good lord!
are you really?
well, Ron's told us all about you, of course!
when did you get here?
this morning
your son flew in that enchanted car of yours
to save him back last night
did you really?
how did it go?
I mean,that was very wrong,indeed,boys-
very wrong of you
Now, Harry
You must know all about muggles
tell me, what's exactly the function of a rubber duck?
oh,en...
that could the Errol, the post
oh,fetch it, Percy, please
Errol, he is always doing that
oh, these are Hogwarts' letters
oh
and sent to Harry as well
Dumbledore must know you're here, Harry
doesn't miss the trick that man?
oh, no, this lot won't come cheap, mom, the speel book of Lockhart are very expensive
we'll manage,there's only one place we can get all of this,Diagon Alley
here we are, Harry
you go first, Dear
but Harry's never traveled by Floo powder,Mom
Floo powder?
oh, you go first,Ron,
then Harry can see how it's done
and you go
Diagon Alley!
you see?
it's quite easy
don't be afraid
come
come on
and you go, let's bow your head
that's fine
take your Floo powder
that's it, very good
don't forget to speak very very clearly
D-Dia-gon Alley
what did he say, dear?
I thought he did
not lost, are you? my dear
I am fine, thank you,I am just...
come with us
we'll help you find your way back
no, please
Harry?
Hagrid!?
What d'yeh think yer doin' down there?
come on
[Knockturn Alley]
yer a mess, Harry
Skulkin' around Knockturn Alley
dodgy place
don' want no one ter see yeh down there,people here are no good
I was lost by...
Hang on, what were you doing down there,
then?
me? I was lookin' fer a Flesh-Eatin' Slug Repellent
They're ruinin' the school cabbages.
Harry, Hagrid!
hello, Hermione!
so good to see you!
it's great to see you too!
what did you do to your glasses?
ok, let's repair it
I definately need to remmeber that one
you will be all right then, Harry?
right, I will leave you two then
oh, thank you, bye
come on, every one is so worried
oh, Harry, thank goodness,We hoped you'd only gone one
grate too far .
Ladies and gentlemen, this is GILDEROY LOCKHART
ah, here he is!
Mom fancies him
make way there please, let me by madem, thank you
Excuse me, little girl, this for Daily Prophet
it can't be Harry Potter?
Harry, watch out, excuse me, mam
Nice big smile, Harry, to get you and I together on front page
Ladies and gentlemen,What an
extraordinary moment this is!
When young Harry stepped into Flourish and Blotts this morning
to purchase my autobiography, magical me
which incidently is carried out to celerbrate its
twenty seventh week top Daily Prophet best selling day
he has no idea,that he wouldn't in fact believing
with my entire collected works free of charge
oh....
now, ladies
give me those, let me get them signed
all of you wait outside, let's drop
I bet you love that, didn't you, Potter?
famous Harry Potter,Can't even go into a bookshop
without making the front page.
leave him alone
Harry Potter, you've got yourself a girlfriend
not now,Draco, be nicely
it's Potter
Lucius Malfoy, we meet at last
forgive me, your scar is legended
as,of course, the wizard who gave to you
Voldemort killed my parents
he is nothing more than a murderer
en, you must be very brave to mention his name
or could be foolish
fearful name only creats a fearful thing itsself
and you must be Mrs Granger
yes, Draco told me all about you
and your parents
Muggles, aren't they?
let me see, red hair,
vacant expressions,
secondhand book you must be with Weasley's
children, It's smelling in here, let's go outside.
Well, well, well, Weasley's here now
Lucius
this is time of ministry, Arthur, with all those raids
I do hope they're paying you overtime?no judge like state of this,I'd say, no,
what's the use of being a disgrace to the name of wizard if they don't even pay you well for it?
We have a very different idea of what disgraces the name of wizard,Malfoy
clearly,
associating with muggles
I thought your family could sink no lower
I'll see you at work
see you at school
10:58, come on, come on,train will be leaving any moment
train, George, Percy, you first
after you, dear
come on, Ginny, get your seat, hurry
let's go
ai, what do you think you are doing?
sorry
lost control of trolley
why can't we get through
I don't know, the gateway sealed itself for some reason
the train leaves at exactly 11 clock, we missed it
Harry, if we can't through,
maybe mom and dad can't get back
maybe we just go to wait by the car
the car
Ron, I should tell you
Most muggles aren't customed to see a flying car
eh, right
oh, no,the Invisibility Booster must be faulty
oh, come then, let's go lower
we need to find the train
ok
now all we need to do is catching with the train
can't be far behind
can you hear that?
must be getting close
hold on
Harry, hold on
take my hand
hold on
I am trying
your hand on sweating
I think we found the train
yeah
welcome home!
up up
it's not working
try that tree!
stop, stop, stop!
my wand....
look at my wand
thanks this wand for your neck
what's happenning?
I don't know
come on, go, fast
Scabbers, you are ok?
the car...
dad gonna kill me
see you, Hedwig.
wait
so, a house elf shows up in my bedroom
we can't get through the barrier
to get platform nine and three-quarters
we almost get killed by a tree
clearly someone just want me hurt this year
well, take a good look, lads
this night might well be the last you spend in this castle
oh, dear, we are in trouble
you were seen by no less than 7 muggles
do you have any idea how serious this is?
you have risked to expose our world
not to mention that damage and inflict on Whomping Willow which is on the ground since before you were born
Honestly, Professor Snape
I think it did more damage to us
Silence!
I will assure you,
were you in Slytherin and your fate rested with me
the both of you would be
on the train home tonight! as it is
they are not
Professor Dumbledore
Professor McGonagall
Headmaster
these boys have flouted the Decree
for the Restriction of Underage Wizardry, as such
I well aware of our rules,Severus
have reading quite a few of them myself
en, but their head are in Gryffindor House
it is for Professor McGonagall to determine the appropriate action
we're going to get our stuff then
what are you talking about? Mr. Weasley?
you are going to expel us, aren't you?
Not today, Mr.Weasley
but I must impress on both of you
the seriousness of what you have done
I'll be writing to your families tonight
and you'll both receive detention
good morning every one!
good morning, Professor Sprout
welcome to greenhouse
three second year
gather around, now, everyone
today,We are going to repot Mandrakes .
Now, who can tell me the properties of the Mandrake root?
yes, Mrs Granger?
Mandrake, or Mandragora
It is used to return those who have been petrified
to their original state
it is also quite dangerous, Mandrake cry's fatal to anyone who hears it,"
Excellent
Ten points to Gryffindor
now, as our mandrakes are still only seedlings
their crys won't kill you yet
but they will knock you out several hours
that's why I give each of you a pair of earmuffs
for all of your protections,
so could you please put them on right away
quickly
flats tight down
watch me closely
you grasp your mandrake firmly
you pull it
sharply out of pot
go get it, and now
you dump it down to other pot and
pour it little sprinky soil
till it can't move
ah, Longbottom's been neglecting his earmuffs
no, Mam,
he is just fainted
ah, as well, let's leave him back
right, here we go
plenty pots to go around
grasp your mandrake and pull it up
hey, is that nearly headless, isn't it?
hello, Percy! Mr Clearwater
hello, Headless Nicholas
say it, I am doomed
you're doomed
hey, Harry
I'm Colin Creevey
I'm in Gryffindor, too.
hey, Colin, nice to meet you
Ron, is that your owl?
bloody bird, it is a mess
oh, no
look, every one, Weasley got himself
a howler
go on, Ron,
I ignored one from my Gran once, it was horrible
WHAT A WEASLEY!
HOW DARE YOU STEAL THAT CAR?
I AM ABSOLUTELY DISGUSTING
YOUR FATHER IS NOW FACING AN INQUIRY AT WORK
AND IT'S ENTIRELY YOUR FAULT!
IF
YOU PUT ANOTHER TOE OUT OF LINE
WE'LL BRING YOU STRAIGHT HOME.
Oh, Ginny dear, congratulations on making Gryffindor
your father and I are so proud of it
let me introduce you
to your new defense against dark art teacher
me
Gilderoy Lockhart
Order of Merlin, Third Class
Honorary Member of the Dark Force Defense League, and five-time winner
of Witch Weekly's Most-Charming-Smile Award
but I don't talk about that
I didn't get rid of the Bandon Banshee by smiling at her!
Now, be warned
It is my job to arm you against the foulest creatures known to wizardkind!
You may find yourselves
facing your worst fears in this room.
Know only that no harm can befall you whilst I am here.
I must ask you not to scream
it might provoke them
Cornish pixies
Freshly caught Cornish pixies.
lots of you aren't fear of them,the pixies can be devilish tricky little blighters
Let's see what you make of them!
Come on now - round them up, round them up, they're only pixies
hey, please, get me down
get off me,
stop, stop, hold still
Peskipiksi Pesternomi!
Well, I'll ask you three
to just nip the rest of them back into their cage.
what we do now?
immobilas
why it is always me?
I spent this summer devising an all new Quidditch program
we are going to train
earlier
harder, and longer
what?
I don't believe it
what do you think you are going? Flint
Quidditch practice
I booked the patch for Gryffindor today
easy,Woods, I've got note
oh, a small trouble
I, Professor Severus Snape, hereby
give the Slytherin team permission to practice today
owing to the need to train their new Seeker.
you got new seeker, who?
Malfoy?
that's right,that's not always you want to see it
those are Nimbus Two Thousand and Ones, how did you get those?
gift from Draco's father
you see, Weasley, unlike some
my father can afford the best
At least no one on the Gryffindor team had to buy their way in
They got in on pure talent.
No one asked your opinion
you fiIthy little Mudblood
you will pay for that one, Malfoy, eat slugs
you ok? Ron?
say something
well, can you turn around, Harry
no, Colin, get out the way
let's take him to Hagrid
how long it'll do?
opps, this calls the real special equipment
nothing to do but wait for it to stop,I am afraid
Better out than in, who's he tried to curse, anyway?
Malfoy
he called Hermione
A..., well,I don't know exactly what it means
he called me mudblood
he did not
what's mudblood?
it means dirty blood
Mudblood's a really foul name for someone who is Muggle-born
some one with no magic parents
some one like me
it's sort of tongue when you usually hear stuff in conversation
so thing is, Harry
there are some wizards - like Malfoy's family
who think they're better than everyone else because they're what people call pure-blood
it's horrible
it's disgusting
aren't just call what up to birth
dirty blood, there is no wizard alive day that is no halfblood or less
more to the point, not yet a sigle spell our Hermione can' do
come here
don't you think on it, Hermione
don't you think on it for one minute
Harry, Harry, harry, can you possibly imagine?
a better way to serve the detention?
by helping me to answer my fan mail?
not really
Fame's a fickle friend, Harry
Celebrity is as celebrity does
remember that
[Come ... come to me.... Let me rip you.... Let me tear you .... Let me kill you . .]
what?
sorry?
that voice
voice?
didn't you hear it?
what are you talking about? Harry
are you getting a lit bit drowsy?
Great Scott -no wonder, look at the time! We've been here nearly four hours!
spooky, how the time flys when we're having fun
spooky
[I smell blood, let me rip you,let me kill you,kill....]
Harry!
did you hear it?
hear what?
that voice
voice? what voice?
I heard it first at Lockhart office, then again, it just
it's moving
I think it's gonna kill
kill?
Harry, wait, don't be so fast
strange
I've never seen spiders act like that
I don't like spiders
what's that?
the chamber of secret has been opened
enemies of the heir...be ware
it's written in blood
oh, no
it's Filth's cat, Mrs.Norris
enemies of heir, be ware
you'll be the next, mudblood
what's going on there? go out of my way, my way, my way
Potter? what do you......
that's Mrs.Norris
you murdered my cat
no, no
I'll kill ya
I'll kill ya!
Argus!
every one will proceed to dormitory immediately,
every one, except,
you three
...Gryffindors, follow me...
she is not dead, Argus
she has been petrified
ah, Potter,so unluck I wasn't there
I know the exact the countercurse that could've spare her
but how she's been petrified, I can not say
ask him
he must've done it, you saw what he wrote on the wall
it is not true, sir, I swear
I've never touch Mrs. Norris
rubbish
If I might, Headmaster?
perhaps Potter and his friends were simply in the wrong place at the wrong time
however
the circumstances are suspicious
I, for one, don't recall seeing Potter at dinner
I am afraid that's my doing, Severus
you see, Harry's helping answer my fan mail
that's why Ron and I're looking for him,professor
we just found when he said
yes, Mrs Granger?
when I said I wasn't hungry
we were heading back to common room when we found Mrs. Norris
innocent until proven guilty,Severus
my cat has been petrified
I want to see some punishment
we will be able to cure her,Argus
as I understand
Madem Sprout has very healthy grown Mandrake
with which all the potion will be made,we will revive Mrs.Norris
at the mean time, I strongly recommend caution
to all
it's bit strange, isn't it?
strange?
you heard the voice,
the voice only you can hear, and Mrs.Norris turned out petrified
it's just strange
do you think I should've told them, Dumbledore and others, I mean
are you mad?
no,Harry, even in the wizard world, hearding voices isn't a good sign
she is right, you know
could I have your attention please?
right, now, today we will be transforming animals
into water goblets
like this,1, 2, 3
fetherfethertol
now, it's your turn
well, who would like to go first
oh, Mr.Weasley, 1, 2, 3, fetherfethertol
fethervertol
that one need replacing,
Mr.Weasley
yes, Mrs Granger
professor, I was wondering
If you can tell us,about,the chamber of secret
very well, you all knew, of course
Hogwart was founded over thousands years ago by the four greatest wizards and witches of age
Godric Gryffindor, Helga Hufflepuff, Rowena Ravenclaw, and Salazar Slytherin.
three of the founders concensused quite harmoniously
one did not, so we guess it is who
Slytherin wished to be more selective
about the students admitted to Hogwarts.
He believed
that magical learning should be kept within all-magic families.
in another words, pure blood
unable to persuade others, he desided to leave the school
now, according to legend
Slytherin had built a hidden chamber in this castle
known as the chamber of secret
though shockly, before departed, he sealed it
until that time when his own true heir returned to the school
the heir alone will be able to open the chamber
and unleash the horror within, and by so doing
to purge the school of all those who in Slytherin's view  were unworthy to study magic.
muggleborn
Naturally,the school
has been searched many times
no such chamber has been found
professor
what's exactly the legend tell us the light in the chamber?
the chamber is said to be home to something
that only the heir of Slytherin
can control
it is said to be the home of a monster
so it is true, she told us there is really a chamber of secret
yes, could you tell?
McGonagall's worried and all the teachers are
and if there is really a chamber of secret and really hasn't been opened
that means,
the heir of Slytherin has returned Hogwart
the question is, who is it?
that's stink,who do we know
who thinks all muggleborns are scums
If you're talking about Malfoy
of course, you heard him
You'll be next,Mudbloods! I heard him
but,Malfoy, the Heir of Slytherin?
maybe Ron is right, Hermione
I mean, look at his family,The whole lot
of them have been in Slytherin for centuries
Crabbe and Goyle must know,maybe we can trick him to tell them
even they aren't that pig, but there might be another way
remind you, it would be difficult
not mention we'll break about 50 school rules
and it'll be dangerous
very dangerous
here it is
Polyjuice Potion.
properly brewed Polyjuice Potion allows the drinker to transform himself temporaly into phisical form of other
here,you know,if Harry and I drink that stuff
we'll turn to Crabbe and Goyle
yes
you kidding..
Malfoy'll tell us anything
exactly
but truth is I've never see a more complicated potion
eh, well, how long will it take to make?
a month
but, Hermione, if Malfoy is the heir of Slytherin, he could've attacked half muggleborns in the school by then
I know
but it's the only plan we got
another ball for Slytherin
they lead Gryffindor 90 to 30
All right there,
Scarhead?
watch yourself, Harry
wood, look out
Hermione
Harry got himself a wild Bludger
let's be tempered, we said, us
no, stop it
no,
even with proper one is too risky
you could hurt Harry
training for the ballet, Potter?
you gonna catch me? Potter?
let's go
Harry Potter caught the Snitch, Gryffindor win!
thank you
are you ok?
no, I think my arm broke
do not worry, Harry
I will fix that of your arms straight away
no, not you
you don't know what are you saying...now
this won't hurt a bit
BRAKYAMY IMENDO
ah,yes, well, that can sometimes happen
but the point is you can no longer feel any pain
and very clearly, the bones are not broken
broken? there is no bones left
much more flexible though
oh, Mr Malfoy I will make things as fast as you can go
out my way, out my way
You should have come straight to me!
I can mend bones in a hard speed  - but growing them back
You will be able to, won't you?
I'll be able to, certainly,
but it will be painful
You're in for a rough night, Potter
regrowing bones is a nasty bussiness
what do you expect? Pumkin juice?
[kill...kill...]
hello
Dobby?
Harry Potter should've listened to Dobby
Harry Potter should've gone back home when he missed the train
it was you,You stopped the barrier from letting Ron and me through!
Indeed, yes, sir
you nearly got Ron and me expelled
at least you would be away from here
Harry Potter must go home
Dobby thought his Bludger would be enough to make Harry Potter see the...
your Bludger? you made that Bludger chase after me?
Dobby feels the most grief, sir
Dobby had to iron his hands
You'd better clear off before my bones come back, Dobby, or I might strangle you.
Dobby is used to death threats, sir.
Dobby gets them five times a day at home.
I don't suppose you could tell me why you tried to kill me?
not kill you, sir,  never kill you
Dobby remmeber Harry Potter before Harry Potter trumphed over He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named
We house-elfs were treated like vermin, sir!
Of course, Dobby is still treated like vermin
ah..ah....
why do you wear that thing, Dobby?
This, sir? This a mark of the house-elf's enslavement
Dobby can only be freed if his masters present him with clothes
listen, listen, terrible thing is about to happen in Hogwart
Harry Potter must not stay here
Now, that history is to repeat itself
repeat itself, you mean this' happened before?
eh--I shouldn't have said that
bad Dobby
stop
stop, stop, Dobby
tell me, Dobby
when did this happen before?
who is doing it now?
Dobby can not say, sir
Dobby only want Harry potter to be safe
no, Dobby, tell me, who is it?
put him here
what happened?
there's been another attack
I think, do you know,I think
he's been petrified,Madam Pomfrey.
you don't think
perhaps he managed to get a picture of his attacker?
What can this mean, Albus?
it means our students are in great danger
what you have to tell the staff?
the truth, tell them, the Hogwart is no longer safe
it is as we feared, meanever
that the Chamber of Secrets has indeed been opened again.
again? you mean the chamber of secret had been opened before?
of course
don't you see? Lucius Malfoy must've opened the Chamber when he was at school here
now he's told Draco how to do it
maybe, but we have to wait Polyjuice potion to make sure
and why it's me,why are we brewing this potion in poor daylight in the middle of girl's never treat
don't you think we'll get caught?
no
no one ever comes in here
why? Moaning Myrtle
who?
Moaning Myrtle
who is Moaning Myrtle?
I am Moaning Myrtle
I wouldn't expect you to know me
who would ever talk about ugly,miserable,moping, Moaning Myrtle?
she is a little sensitive
gather around,
gather around, can everybody see me?
can you all hear me? excellent
in lights of dark events
of recent weeks Professor Dumbledore has granted me permission
to start this little dueling club, to train you all up
in case you ever need to defend yourselves as I myself
have done on countless occasions to full details, see my published works
let me introduce my assistant
professor Snape
he has sportingly agreed to help me with a short demonstration
Now, I don't want any of you youngsters to worry
you'll still have your Potions master when I'm through with him,
never fear!
1,2,3
Expelliarmus!
do you think he is all right?
who cares?
an excellent idea to show them that,Professor Snape, but if you don't mind my saying
it was pretty obvious what you were about to do.
If I had wanted to stop you
it would have been only too easy
perhaps it would be prudent to first teach the student
to block unfriendly spell, professor
Excellent suggestion, professor Snape
let's have volunteer pair
Potter,Weasley, how about you?
Weasley is one causes devastation with simpliest spell
who sent Harry Potter to
hospital wing in match box
may I suggest some one from my own house?
Malfoy? perhaps?
good luck, Potter
yea,sir
wands at ready
scared? Potter
you wish
on the count of three
cast your charms to disarm your opponents - only to disarm
we don't want any accidents here
1,2
Ivertasvaty
Rictusempra!
I said disarm only
Serpensortia!
don't move, Potter
I get rid of it for you
allow me, professor Snape
WOLATIOUSENDULY
SAYASASI
SYASIHAIS
IPARAIAPYSKE
what are you playing at
You're a Parselmouth. Why didn't you tell us?
I am a what?
you can talk to snakes? I know, I mean I accidentally set a boa constrictor on my cousin Dudley at the zoo once,
once, so what? I bet loads of people here can do it.
no
they can't,It's not a very common gift. Harry
this is bad
what's bad?
if I hadn't told that snake not to attack Justin -
Oh, that's what you said to it?
you were there, you heard me
I heard you speaking Parseltongue, snake language
I spoke in different language?
but I didn't realize it
how could I speak a language
without knowing I can
I don't how it does, but sound like you acted signal or something
Harry, listen to me as the
vision symbol of Slytherin House is a serpent.
Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth, he could talk to snakes too
exactly
And now the whole school's going to think you're his great-great-great-great-grandson or something
but I am not
it can't be, he lived thousands years ago, for we know, you could be
see you back in common room