I should've known that you would be
here, Professor McGonagall.
Good evening, Professor Dumbledore.
Are the rumors true, Albus?
I'm afraid so, professor. The good and
the bad.
- And the boy?
- Hagrid is bringing him.
Is it wise to trust Hagrid with
something so important?
Professor, I would trust Hagrid with
my life.
Professor Dumbledore, sir. Professor
McGonagall.
- No problems, I trust, Hagrid?
- No, sir.
Little tyke fell asleep as we were
flying over Bristol.
Try not to wake him.
There you go.
Do you really think it's safe, leaving
him with these people?
I've watched them all day. They're the
worst sort of Muggles.
- They really are-
- The only family he has.
He'll be famous. Every child in our
world will know his name.
Exactly.
He's far better off growing up away
from all of that.
Until he's ready.
There, there, Hagrid. It's not really
goodbye, after all.
Good luck...
...Harry Potter.
Up. Get up!
Now!
Wake up, cousin! We're going to the
zoo!
- Here he comes, the birthday boy.
- Happy birthday, son.
Cook breakfast. And try not to burn
anything.
- Yes, Aunt Petunia.
- I want everything to be perfect...
...for my Dudley's special day!
- Hurry up! Bring my coffee, boy.
- Yes, Uncle Vernon.
Aren't they wonderful, darling?
- How many are there?
- 36. Counted them myself.
36?! But last year I had 37!
- But some are bigger than last
year's.
- I don't care!
This is what we're going to do.
We're going to buy you two new
presents. How's that, pumpkin?
It should be a lovely day at the zoo.
I'm really looking forward to it.
I'm warning you now, boy.
Any funny business, any at all...
...and you won't have any meals for a
week.
Get in.
Make it move.
Move!
- Move!
- He's asleep!
He's boring.
Sorry about him.
He doesn't understand what it's like,
lying there...
...watching people press their ugly
faces in on you.
Can you hear me?
It's just, I've never talked to a
snake before.
Do you...?
Do you talk to people often?
You're from Burma, aren't you? Was it
nice there?
Do you miss your family?
I see. That's me as well. I never knew
my parents either.
Mummy, Dad, you won't believe what
this snake is doing!
Thanks.
Anytime.
Snake!
Mum! Mummy! Help me!
My darling boy! How did you get in
there?
Who did this? How did you get in
there? Is there a snake?
It's all right, sweetheart. We'll get
you out of these cold clothes.
- What happened?
- I swear, I don't know!
The glass was there and then it was
gone, like magic.
There's no such thing as magic.
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
- Dad, look! Harry's got a letter!
- It's mine!
Yours? Who'd be writing to you?
No more mail through this letterbox.
Have a lovely day at the office, dear.
Shoo! Go on.
Fine day, Sunday.
In my opinion, best day of the week.
Why is that, Dudley?
- Because there's no post on Sundays?
- Right you are, Harry!
No post on Sunday.
No blasted letters today! No, sir.
Not one single bloody letter. Not one!
No, sir, not one blasted, miserable--
Make it stop, please!
Stop it!
Mummy, what's happening?
Give me that! Give me that letter!
Get off!
They're my letters! Let go of me!
That's it! We're going away!
Far away, where they can't find us!
Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he?
Make a wish, Harry.
Who's there?
Sorry about that.
I demand that you leave at once. You
are breaking and entering.
Dry up, Dursley, you great prune.
I haven't seen you since you was a
baby, Harry.
You're a bit more along than I
expected. Particularly in the middle.
I'm not Harry.
- I am.
- Well, of course you are.
Got something for you.
Afraid I sat on it, but I imagine
it'll taste fine just the same.
Baked it myself, words and all.
Thank you.
It's not every day your young man
turns 11, is it?
Excuse me, but who are you?
Rubeus Hagrid, Keeper of Keys and
Grounds at Hogwarts.
- Of course, you know about Hogwarts.
- Sorry, no.
Didn't you ever wonder where your mum
and dad learned it all?
Learned what?
You're a wizard, Harry.
- I'm a what?
- A wizard.
A good one, I'd wager, once you're
trained up.
No, you've made a mistake. I mean...
...I can't be a wizard.
I mean, I'm just Harry. Just Harry.
Well, Just Harry, did you ever make
anything happen?
Anything you couldn't explain, when
you were angry or scared?
"Dear Mr. Potter, We are pleased to
accept you...
...at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft
and Wizardry."
He will not be going! We swore we'd
put a stop to all this rubbish.
You knew? You knew all along and you
never told me?
Of course we knew. How could you not
be?
My perfect sister being who she was.
My mother and father were so proud the
day she got her letter.
"We have a witch in the family. Isn't
it wonderful?"
I was the only one to see her for what
she was.
A freak!
Then she met that Potter, and then she
had you...
...and I knew you would be the same.
Just as strange, just as abnormal.
And then she got herself blown up, and
we got landed with you.
Blown up? You told me my parents died
in a car crash.
A car crash? A car crash killed Lily
and James Potter?
- We had to say something.
- It's an outrage! A scandal!
He'll not be going.
A great Muggle like you is going to
stop him?
Muggle?
Non-magic folk. This boy's had his
name down since he were born.
He's going to the finest school of
witchcraft and wizardry.
He'll be under the finest headmaster
Hogwarts has seen, Albus Dumbledore.
I will not pay to have a crackpot old
fool teach him magic tricks.
Never insult Albus Dumbledore...
...in front of me.
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell
anyone at Hogwarts about that.
- I'm not allowed to do magic.
- Okay.
We're a bit behind schedule. Best be
off.
Unless you'd rather stay, of course.
"All students must be equipped with...
...one standard size 2
pewter cauldron...
...and may bring, if they desire,
either an owl, a cat or a toad."
Can we find all this in London?
If you know where to go.
Ah, Hagrid! The usual, I presume?
No, thanks, Tom. I'm on official
Hogwarts business.
Just helping Harry buy his school
supplies.
Bless my soul. It's Harry Potter!
Welcome back, Mr. Potter. Welcome
back.
Doris Crockford. I can't believe I'm
meeting you at last.
Harry Potter. Can't tell you how
pleased I am to meet you.
Hello, professor. I didn't see you.
Professor Quirrell will be your
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
Oh, nice to meet you.
Fearfully fascinating subject.
Not that you need it, eh, Potter?
Yes, well, must be going now. Lots to
buy.
Goodbye.
- See, Harry? You're famous.
- But why am I famous?
All those people, how is it they know
who I am?
I'm not sure I'm the right person to
tell you that.
Welcome, Harry, to Diagon Alley.
Here, you get your quills and ink.
Over there, all your bits and bobs for
doing wizardry.
It's a world-class racing broom.
Look at it! The new Nimbus 2000!
It's the fastest model yet.
But how am I to pay for all this? I
haven't any money.
There's your money. Gringotts, the
wizard bank.
Ain't no safer place, not one. Except
perhaps Hogwarts.
Hagrid, what exactly are these things?
They're goblins. Clever as they come,
but not the most friendly of beasts.
Best stay close.
Mr. Harry Potter wishes to make a
withdrawal.
And does Mr. Harry Potter have his
key?
Wait a minute. Got it here somewhere.
Ha! There's the little devil.
And there's something else as well.
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
It's about You-Know-What in vault
you-know-which.
Very well.
Vault 687.
Lamp, please.
Key, please.
Did you think your parents would leave
you with nothing?
- Vault 713.
- What's in there, Hagrid?
Can't tell you. Hogwarts business.
Very secret.
Stand back.
Best not to mention this to anyone.
I still need a wand.
A wand? You want Ollivanders. There
ain't no place better.
Run along there and wait. I got one
more thing to do. Won't be long.
Hello?
I wondered when I'd be seeing you, Mr.
Potter.
It seems only yesterday...
...that your mother and father were in
here buying their first wands.
Here we are.
Give it a wave.
Apparently not.
Perhaps...
...this.
No, no, definitely not. No matter.
I wonder....
Curious.
Very curious.
Sorry, but what's curious?
I remember every wand I've ever sold,
Mr. Potter.
It so happens that the phoenix...
...whose tail feather resides in your
wand, gave another feather.
Just one other.
It is curious that you should be
destined for this wand...
...when its brother gave you that
scar.
And who owned that wand?
We do not speak his name.
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr.
Potter.
It's not always clear why.
But I think it is clear...
...that we can expect great things
from you.
After all, He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
...did great things.
Terrible...
...yes, but great.
Harry! Harry!
Happy birthday.
You all right, Harry? You seem very
quiet.
He killed my parents, didn't he? The
one who gave me this.
You know, Hagrid. I know you do.
First, and understand this because
it's very important:
Not all wizards are good.
Some of them go bad. A few years
ago...
...there was a wizard who went as bad
as you can go. His name was V--
- His name was V--
- Maybe if you wrote it down?
No, I can't spell it.
- All right, Voldemort.
- Voldemort?
It was dark times, Harry.
Voldemort started to gather some
followers.
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
Anyone that stood up to him ended up
dead.
Your parents fought against him.
But nobody lived once he decided to
kill them.
Nobody, not one.
Except you.
Me? Voldemort tried to kill me?
Yes. That ain't no ordinary cut on
your forehead, Harry.
A mark like that only comes from being
touched by a curse, an evil curse.
What happened to V--? To You-Know-Who?
Well, some say he died.
Codswallop, in my opinion.
Nope, I reckon he's out there still...
...too tired to carry on.
But one thing's certain. Something
about you stumped him that night.
That's why you're famous. That's why
everybody knows your name.
You're the boy who lived.
What are you looking at?
Blimey, is that the time?
I'm gonna have to leave you.
Dumbledore will be wanting his--
Well, he'll be wanting to see me. Your
train leaves in 10 minutes.
Here's your ticket. Stick to your
ticket, that's very important.
"Platform 9 3/4"?
But, Hagrid, there must be a mistake.
This says platform 9 3/4.
There's no such thing, is there?
Sorry.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
On your left.
Can you tell me where I might find
platform 9 3/4?
Think you're being funny, do you?
It's the same every year, packed with
Muggles.
- Muggles?
- Platform 9 3/4, this way.
All right, Percy, you first.
Fred, you next.
- He's not Fred, I am.
- You call yourself our mother?
I'm sorry, George.
I'm only joking. I am Fred.
Excuse me.
Could you tell me how to...?
How to get onto the platform? Not to
worry, dear.
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as
well.
All you do is walk straight at the
wall between platforms 9 and 10.
- Best to run if you're nervous.
- Good luck.
Excuse me. Do you mind? Everywhere
else is full.
Not at all.
I'm Ron, by the way. Ron Weasley.
I'm Harry. Harry Potter.
So it's true!
I mean, do you really have the...?
- The what?
- The scar?
Wicked!
- Anything off the trolley, dears?
- No, thanks. I'm all set.
We'll take the lot.
- Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans?
- They mean every flavor.
There's chocolate and peppermint and
also...
...spinach, liver and tripe.
George sweared he got a
booger-flavored one once.
- Are they real frogs?
- It's a spell. You want the cards.
Each pack's got a famous witch or
wizard. I've got about 500 meself.
Watch it!
That's rotten luck. They've only got
one good jump in them.
- I've got Dumbledore!
- I got about six of him.
Hey, he's gone!
You can't expect him to hang around
all day, can you?
This is Scabbers. Pathetic, isn't he?
A little.
Fred gave me a spell to turn him
yellow. Want to see?
Yeah.
Has anyone seen a toad?
- A boy named Neville's lost one.
- No.
Oh, are you doing magic? Let's see,
then.
Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow
Turn this stupid, fat rat yellow
Are you sure that's a real spell?
Well, it's not very good, is it?
I've only tried a few simple ones
myself...
...but they've all worked for me.
For example:
Oculus Reparo.
That's better, isn't it?
Holy cricket, you're Harry Potter!
I'm Hermione Granger. And you are...?
- I'm Ron Weasley.
- Pleasure.
You two better change into robes. I
expect we'll be arriving soon.
You've got dirt on your nose. Did you
know?
Just there.
Right, then. First years, this way,
please!
Come on, first years, don't be shy.
Come on now, hurry up.
- Hello, Harry.
- Hi, Hagrid.
Right, then. This way to the boats.
Come on now, follow me.
Wicked.
Welcome to Hogwarts.
Shortly, you'll pass through these
doors and join your classmates.
But before you take your seats, you
must be sorted into your houses.
They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff...
...Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
While you're here, your house will be
like your family.
Your triumphs will earn you points.
Any rule-breaking and you will lose
points.
At the end of the year, the house with
the most points wins the house cup.
Trevor!
Sorry.
The Sorting Ceremony will begin
momentarily.
It's true then, what they're saying on
the train.
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
Harry Potter?
This is Crabbe and Goyle.
And I'm Malfoy.
Draco Malfoy.
Think my name's funny, do you? I've no
need to ask yours.
Red hair and a hand-me-down robe? You
must be a Weasley.
You'll find out some wizarding
families are better than others.
You don't want to go making friends
with the wrong sort.
I can help you there.
I think I can tell the wrong sort for
myself, thanks.
We're ready for you now. Follow me.
The ceiling isn't real. It's bewitched
to look like the night sky.
I read about it in Hogwarts, A
History.
Will you wait along here, please?
Now, before we begin...
...Professor Dumbledore would like to
say a few words.
I have a few start-of-term notices I
wish to announce.
The first years, please note...
...that the Dark Forest is strictly
forbidden to all students.
Also, our caretaker, Mr. Filch, has
asked me to remind you...
...that the third-floor corridor is
out of bounds...
...to everyone who does not wish to
die a most painful death.
Thank you.
When I call your name, you will come
forth.
I shall place the Sorting Hat on your
head...
...and you will be sorted into your
houses.
Hermione Granger.
Oh, no. Okay, relax.
Mental, that one, I'm telling you.
Right, then. Right.
Okay. Gryffindor!
Draco Malfoy.
Slytherin!
Every wizard who went bad was in
Slytherin.
Susan Bones.
Harry, what is it?
Nothing. Nothing, I'm fine.
Let's see....
I know! Hufflepuff!
Ronald Weasley.
Another Weasley! I know just what to
do with you.
Gryffindor!
Harry Potter.
Difficult, very difficult.
Plenty of courage, I see. Not a bad
mind, either.
There's talent, oh, yes.
And a thirst to prove yourself.
But where to put you?
Not Slytherin, not Slytherin!
Not Slytherin, eh? Are you sure?
You could be great, you know. It's all
here, in your head.
And Slytherin will help you on the way
to greatness, no doubt about that.
No? Well, if you're sure.
Better be...
...Gryffindor!
Your attention, please.
Let the feast begin.
I'm half and half.
Me dad's a Muggle. Mum's a witch.
Bit of a nasty shock for him when he
found out.
Percy, who's that teacher talking to
Professor Quirrell?
Professor Snape, head of Slytherin
house.
- What's he teach?
- Potions.
But he fancies the Dark Arts. He's
been after Quirrell's job for years.
Hello! How are you?
Welcome to Gryffindor.
It's the Bloody Baron!
Hello, Sir Nicholas. Have a nice
summer?
Dismal. Once again, my request to join
the Headless Hunt has been denied.
I know you. You're Nearly Headless
Nick.
I prefer Sir Nicholas, if you don't
mind.
"Nearly" headless? How can you be
nearly headless?
Like this.
Gryffindors, follow me, please. Keep
up. Thank you.
Ravenclaw, follow me. This way.
This is the most direct path to the
dormitories.
Keep an eye on the staircases. They
like to change.
Keep up, please, and follow me.
Quickly now, come on. Come on.
That picture's moving.
- Look at that one.
- I think she fancies you.
- Look!
- Who's that girl?
Welcome to Hogwarts.
Password?
Caput Draconis.
Follow me, everyone. Keep up. Quickly,
come on.
Gather around here.
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
Boys'dormitory is upstairs to the
left. Girls, the same on your right.
Your belongings have already been
brought up.
Made it!
Can you imagine the look on old
McGonagall's face if we were late?
- That was bloody brilliant!
- Thank you for that assessment.
It'd be better if I transfigured Mr.
Potter and you into a watch.
- Then one of you might be on time.
- We got lost.
Then perhaps a map? I trust you don't
need one to find your seats.
There will be no foolish wand-waving
or silly incantations in this class.
As such, I don't expect many of you to
appreciate...
...the subtle science and exact art
that is potion-making.
However, for those select few...
...who possess the predisposition...
...I can teach you how to bewitch the
mind...
...and ensnare the senses.
I can tell you how to bottle fame...
...brew glory and even put a stopper
in death.
Then again, maybe some of you have
come to Hogwarts in possession of
abilities...
...so formidable that you feel
confident enough...
...to not pay attention.
Mr. Potter.
Our new celebrity.
What would I get if I added root of
asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
You don't know? Let's try again.
Where would you look if I asked you to
find a bezoar?
I don't know, sir.
What is the difference between
monkshood and wolfsbane?
I don't know, sir.
Pity.
Clearly, fame isn't everything...
...is it, Mr. Potter?
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum Turn
this water into rum
Eye of rabbit....
What's Seamus trying to do to the
water?
Turn it to rum. Actually managed a
weak tea yesterday, before--
Mail's here.
Can I borrow this? Thanks.
Look, Neville's got a Remembrall.
I've read about those. The smoke turns
red when you've forgotten something.
The problem is, I can't remember what
I've forgotten.
Somebody broke into Gringotts. Listen.
"Believed to be the work of Dark
wizards or witches...
...Gringotts goblins acknowledge the
breach but insist nothing was taken.
The vault in question, number 713, had
been emptied earlier that same day."
That's odd. That's the vault Hagrid
and I went to.
- Good afternoon, class.
- Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
Good afternoon, Amanda. Good
afternoon.
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
What are you waiting for? Step up to
your broomstick.
Come on now, hurry up. Stick your hand
over the broom and say, "Up."
Up!
Up.
Up. Up!
With feeling.
Shut up, Harry.
Now, once you've got hold of your
broom, I want you to mount it.
Grip it tight. You don't wanna be
sliding off the end.
When I blow my whistle, I want you to
kick off from the ground, hard.
Keep your broom steady, hover for a
moment...
...then lean forward slightly and
touch back down.
On my whistle. Three, two....
Mr. Longbottom.
- Mr. Longbottom!
- Down, down!
Neville!
Come back down this instant!
Everyone out of the way!
Is he all right?
Oh, dear, it's a broken wrist. Poor
boy. Come on now, up you get.
Keep your feet on the ground while I
take him to the hospital wing.
Understand? If I see a single broom in
the air...
...the one riding it will be expelled
before they can say Quidditch.
Did you see his face?
If he had squeezed this, he'd have
remembered to fall on his arse.
Give it here, Malfoy.
No. I'll leave it somewhere for
Longbottom to find.
How about on the roof?
What's the matter, Potter? Bit beyond
your reach?
Harry, no way! You heard what Madam
Hooch said.
Besides, you don't know how to fly.
What an idiot.
Give it here or I'll knock you off
your broom!
Is that so?
Have it your way, then.
- Nice going, Harry.
- That was wicked, Harry!
Harry Potter!
Follow me.
You wait here.
Professor Quirrell, excuse me. Could I
borrow Wood for a moment?
Yes, of course.
Potter, this is Oliver Wood. Wood, I
have found you a Seeker.
Have you heard? Harry Potter's the new
Gryffindor Seeker.
I always knew he'd do well.
Seeker? But first years never make the
house teams.
- You must be the youngest player in--
- A century, McGonagall says.
Well done, Harry. Wood's just told us.
Fred and George are on the team.
Beaters.
Our job is to make sure you don't get
bloodied up too bad.
Can't make any promises. Rough game,
Quidditch.
But no one's died in years. Someone
vanishes occasionally.
But they'll turn up in a month or two.
Go on. Quidditch is great. Best game
there is, and you'll be great too.
I've never played. What if I make a
fool of myself?
You won't make a fool of yourself.
It's in your blood.
You never told me your father was a
Seeker too.
I didn't know.
I'm telling you, it's spooky. She
knows more about you than you do.
Who doesn't?
What's happening?
The staircases change, remember?
- Let's go this way.
- Before the staircase moves again.
Does anybody feel like we shouldn't be
here?
We're not supposed to be here.
This is the third floor. It's
forbidden.
Let's go.
- It's Filch's cat!
- Run!
Quick, let's hide through that door!
- It's locked!
- We're done for!
Move over!
Alohomora.
Get in.
Alohomora?
Standard Book of Spells, chapter
seven.
Anyone here, my sweet?
Come on.
- Filch is gone.
- He thinks this door's locked.
- It was locked.
- And for good reason.
What are they doing, keeping a thing
like that locked up in a school?
Didn't you see what it was standing
on?
I wasn't looking at its feet! I was
preoccupied with its heads.
Or maybe you didn't notice. There were
three!
It was standing on a trap door. It
wasn't there by accident.
- It's guarding something.
- Guarding something?
That's right. Now, if you two don't
mind, I'm going to bed...
...before you come up with another
idea to get us killed.
Or worse, expelled.
She needs to sort out her priorities.
Quidditch is easy to understand. Each
team has seven players.
Three Chasers, two Beaters, one Keeper
and a Seeker. That's you.
There are three kinds of balls. This
one's called the Quaffle.
The Chasers handle the Quaffle and try
to put it through one of those hoops.
The Keeper, that's me, defends the
hoops. With me so far?
I think so. What are those?
You better take this.
Careful now, it's coming back.
Not bad, Potter. You'd make a fair
Beater.
What was that?
Bludger. Nasty little buggers.
But you are a Seeker.
The only thing I want you to worry
about is this.
The Golden Snitch.
- I like this ball.
- You like it now.
Just wait. It's wicked fast and damn
near impossible to see.
What do I do with it?
You catch it. Before the other team's
Seeker.
You catch this, the game's over.
You catch this, Potter, and we win.
One of a wizard's most rudimentary
skills is levitation...
...or the ability to make objects fly.
Do you have your feathers? Good.
Now, don't forget the nice wrist
movement we've been practicing.
The swish and flick. Everyone.
The swish and flick. Good. Oh, and
enunciate.
Wingardium Leviosa. Off you go, then.
Wingardium Leviosa.
No, stop, stop, stop! You're going to
take someone's eye out.
Besides, you're saying it wrong. It's
Leviosa, not Leviosar.
You do it then, if you're so clever.
Go on, go on.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Well done! See here, everyone, Miss
Granger's done it!
Splendid!
Well done, dear.
I think we're going to need another
feather over here.
"It's Leviosa, not Leviosar."
She's a nightmare, honestly! No wonder
she hasn't got any friends.
I think she heard you.
Where's Hermione?
Parvati said she wouldn't come out of
the bathroom.
She said that she'd been in there all
afternoon, crying.
Troll in the dungeon!
Thought you ought to know.
Silence!
Everyone will please not panic!
Now...
...prefects will lead their house back
to the dormitories.
Teachers will follow me to the
dungeons.
Gryffindors, keep up, please, and stay
alert.
How could a troll get in?
Not on its own. Trolls are really
stupid. Probably people playing jokes.
- What?
- Hermione! She doesn't know.
I think the troll's left the dungeon.
It's going into the girls'bathroom.
Hermione, move!