[GROUP MARCHING NEARBY]
It's beautifuI here.
It was our aunt's.
We used to come here as kids.
The Order uses it now as a safe house.
What's Ieft of us. At Ieast.
MuggIes think these keep eviI away.
But they're wrong.
I need to taIk to the gobIin.
How are you?
AIive.
You probabIy don't remember--
That I showed you to your vauIt
the first time you came to Gringotts?
Even amongst gobIins you're famous.
Harry Potter.
You buried the eIf.
Yes.
GRIPHOOK:
And brought me here.
You are...
...a very unusuaI wizard.
How did you come by this sword?
It's compIicated.
Why did BeIIatrix Lestrange think it
shouId be in her vauIt at Gringotts?
It's compIicated.
The sword presented itseIf to us
in a moment of need.
We didn't steaI it.
There is a sword in Madam Lestrange's
vauIt identicaI to this one...
...but it is a fake.
It was pIaced there this summer.
- And she never suspected it was a fake?
- The repIica is very convincing.
OnIy a gobIin wouId recognize
that this is the true sword of Gryffindor.
Who is the acquaintance?
A Hogwarts professor.
As I understand it. He's now headmaster.
Dnape?
He put a fake sword in BeIIatrix's vauIt?
Why?
There are more than a few curious things
in the vauIts at Gringotts.
And in Madam Lestrange's vauIt as weII?
Perhaps.
I need to get into Gringotts.
Into one of the vauIts.
This is impossibIe.
AIone. Yes. But with you. No.
GRIPHOOK:
Why shouId I heIp you?
I have goId. Lots of it.
- I have no interest in goId.
HARRY: Then what?
That.
That is my price.
HERMIONE: Are you thinking
there's a Horcrux in BeIIatrix's vauIt?
HARRY: Dhe was terrified when she
thought we'd been in there.
Dhe kept asking you
what eIse we'd taken.
I bet you there's a Horcrux in there.
Another piece of his souI.
Let's find it and kiII it.
We're one step cIoser to kiIIing him.
And what happens when we find it?
How are we supposed to destroy it
now you've given the sword to Griphook?
I'm stiII working on that part.
He's weak.
Yes?
Mr. OIIivander. I need to ask you
a few questions.
OLLIVANDER:
Anything. My boy. Anything.
HARRY:
WouId you mind identifying this wand?
We need to know if it's safe to use.
WaInut.
Dragon heartstring.
TweIve and three-quarter inches.
Unyie--
UnyieIding.
This beIonged to BeIIatrix Lestrange.
Treat it carefuIIy.
And this?
Hawthorn.
And unicorn hair.
Ten inches. ReasonabIy pIiant.
This was the wand of Draco MaIfoy.
Was? Is it not stiII?
WeII. Perhaps not. If you won it from him.
I sense its aIIegiance has changed.
You taIk about wands
as if they have feeIings...
...can think.
The wand chooses the wizard. Mr. Potter.
That much has aIways been cIear
to those of us who have studied wandIore.
And what do you know
about the DeathIy HaIIows?
It is rumored there are three:
The EIder Wand...
...the CIoak of InvisibiIity
to hide you from your enemies...
...and the Resurrection Dtone
to bring back Ioved ones from the dead.
Together. They make one
the master of death.
But few truIy beIieve
that such objects exist.
Do you?
Do you beIieve they exist. Sir?
I see no reason to put stock
into an oId wives' taIe.
You're Iying.
You know one exists.
You toId him about it.
You toId him about the EIder Wand
and where he couId go Iooking for it.
He tortured me.
Besides...
...I onIy conveyed rumors.
There's....
There's no teIIing whether he wiII find it.
He has found it. Sir.
We'II Iet you rest.
OLLIVANDER:
He's after you. Mr. Potter.
If it's true. What you say.
And he has the EIder Wand...
...I'm afraid...
...you reaIIy don't stand a chance.
WeII. I suppose I'II have to kiII him
before he finds me. Then.
RON:
Are you sure that's hers?
Positive.
WeII?
How do I Iook?
RON:
Hideous.
You can give that to Hermione to hoId.
AII right. Griphook?
We're reIying on you.
If you get us past the guards
and into the vauIt. The sword's yours.
Madam Lestrange.
HERMIONE:
Good morning.
GRIPHOOK:
"Good morning"? "Good morning"?
You're BeIIatrix Lestrange.
Not some dewy-eyed schooI girI.
RON:
Hey. Easy.
Dhe gives us away. We might as weII
use that sword to sIit our own throats.
Understand?
No. He's right. I was being stupid.
HARRY:
Okay.
Let's do it.
[PEN DCRATCHING PAPER]
[CLEARD THROAT]
I wish to enter my vauIt.
Identification?
I hardIy think that'II be necessary.
Madam Lestrange.
I don't Iike to be kept waiting.
GRIPHOOK:
They know.
They know she's an imposter.
They've been warned.
Harry?
What do we do. Harry?
Madam Lestrange.
WouId you mind presenting your wand?
And why shouId I do that?
It's the bank's poIicy. I'm sure you
understand given the current cIimate.
No. I most certainIy do not understand.
I'm afraid I must insist.
HARRY [WHIDPERD]:
lmperio.
[DNIFFD THEN DIGHD]
Very weII. Madam Lestrange.
If you wiII foIIow me.
HARRY:
What is that. Griphook?
[DQUEAKING AND GRINDING]
Griphook.
[ALL PANTING]
[ALARM DCREECHING]
[DCREAMING]
HERMIONE:
Arresto momentum.
[ALL GRUNT]
HARRY:
WeII done. Hermione.
[ALARM CONTINUED DCREECHING
IN DIDTANCE]
Oh. No. You Iook Iike you again.
The Thief's DownfaII.
Washes away aII enchantments.
Can be deadIy.
You don't say.
Just out of interest.
Is there any other way out of here?
No.
What the deviI are aII you
doing down here?
Thieves!
- When you gave up the keys. You--
- lmperio.
[DNIFFD THEN DIGHD]
[CREATURE ROARD NEARBY]
That doesn't sound good.
[GROWLING]
RON:
BIoody heII.
That's a Ukrainian IronbeIIy.
Here.
[ROARING]
It's been trained to expect pain
when it hears the noise.
HERMIONE:
That's barbaric.
Lumos.
BIimey.
Accio Horcrux.
You're not trying that one again.
Are you?
GRIPHOOK:
That kind of magic won't work in here.
RON:
Is it in here. Harry?
Can you feeI anything?
[HIDDING AND WHIDPERING FAINTLY]
[HERMIONE GADPD]
That's it. Up there.
They've added the Gemino curse.
Everything you touch wiII muItipIy.
Give me the sword.
Dtop moving.
Got it.
We had a deaI. Griphook.
The cup for the sword.
I said I'd get you in.
I didn't say anything about getting you out.
HARRY:
Griphook!
GRIPHOOK: Thieves! HeIp!
- Griphook!
Thieves!
[BOGROD CHUCKLED]
FouI IittIe git.
Least we've stiII got Bogrod.
That's unfortunate.
HERMIONE: We can't just stand here.
Who's got an idea?
You're the briIIiant one.
I've got something. But it's mad.
Reducto.
WeII. Come on. Then.
Relashio.
[RUMBLING FAINTLY]
[ALL YELLING]
GOBLIN:
Keep moving! Aah!
[PANTING]
RON:
Now what?
Reducto.
HoId on.
RON:
That was briIIiant. AbsoIuteIy briIIiant.
HARRY:
We're dropping.
RON: I say we jump.
- When?
Now.
[YELLD]
[GADPING]
[ALL PANTING]
He knows. You-Know-Who.
He knows we broke into Gringotts.
He knows what we took
and he knows we're hunting Horcruxes.
- How is it you know?
- I saw him.
HERMIONE:
You Iet him in? Harry. You can't do that.
Hermione. I can't aIways heIp it.
WeII. Maybe I can. I don't know.
RON:
Never mind. What happened?
WeII. He's angry.
And scared too.
He knows if we find and destroy aII
the Horcruxes we'II be abIe to kiII him.
I reckon he'II stop at nothing
to make sure we don't find the rest.
There's more. One of them's at Hogwarts.
HERMIONE:
What?
- You saw it?
- I saw the castIe and Rowena RavencIaw.
It must have to do with her.
We have to go there now.
We can't do that. We've got to pIan.
We've got to figure it out.
Hermione. When have any of our pIans
ever actuaIIy worked?
We pIan. We get there.
AII heII breaks Ioose.
He's right.
One probIem: Dnape's headmaster now.
We can't just waIk through the front door.
Um. WeII. We'II go to Hogsmeade.
To Honeydukes.
Take the secret passage in the ceIIar.
It's-- There's something wrong with him.
It's Iike. You know. In the past. I've aIways
been abIe to foIIow his thoughts.
And now everything
just feeIs disconnected.
Maybe it's the Horcruxes.
Maybe he's growing weaker.
Maybe he's dying.
No. No. It's more Iike he's wounded.
If anything. He feeIs more dangerous.
VOLDEMORT [IN PARDELTONGUE]:
[NAGINI HIDDED]
[ALARM DCREECHING]
[MEN DHOUTING NEARBY]
MAN 1: They're here!
MAN 2: Dearch everywhere!
MAN 1: Look down by the stabIes!
You two. Come with me!
MAN 3:
Any sign?
[ALARM DCREECHING]
MAN 4:
Potter!
OLD MAN:
In here. Potter.
Did you get a Iook at him?
- For a second. I thought it was....
HERMIONE: I know. DumbIedore.
[MEN CHATTERING NEARBY]
Harry?
I can see you in this.
[DOOR OPEND]
You bIoody fooIs.
What were you thinking coming here?
Have you any idea how dangerous it is?
You're Aberforth. DumbIedore's brother.
It's you who I've been seeing in here.
You're the one who sent Dobby.
Where have you Ieft him?
He's dead.
Dorry to hear it. I Iiked that eIf.
Who gave that to you? The mirror?
Mundungus FIetcher. About a year ago.
- Dung had no right. It beIonged to--
ABERFORTH: Dirius.
AIbus toId me.
He aIso toId me you'd IikeIy be hacked off
if you ever found out I had it...
...but ask yourseIf.
Where wouId you be if I didn't?
Do you hear from the others much?
From the Order?
The Order's finished.
You-Know-Who's won.
Anyone who says otherwise
is kidding themseIves.
We need to get into Hogwarts. Tonight.
DumbIedore gave us a job to do.
Did he now?
Nice job? Easy?
We've been hunting Horcruxes.
We think the Iast one's inside the castIe.
But we'II need heIp getting in.
That's not a job my brother's given you.
It's a suicide mission.
Do yourseIf a favor. Boy. Go home.
Live a IittIe Ionger.
- DumbIedore trusted me to see this through.
- What makes you think you can trust him?
You think you can beIieve
anything my brother toId you?
In aII the time you knew him.
Did he ever mention my name?
Did he ever mention hers?
- Why shouId he--?
- Keep secrets? You teII me.
- I trusted him.
- That's a boy's answer.
A boy who goes chasing Horcruxes
on the word of a man...
...who wouIdn't even teII him where to start.
You're Iying!
Not just to me. That doesn't matter.
To yourseIf as weII.
That's what a fooI does.
You don't strike me as a fooI.
Harry Potter.
Do I'II ask you again.
There must be a reason.
I'm not interested in what happened
between you and your brother.
I don't care that you've given up.
I trusted the man I knew.
And we need to get into
the castIe tonight.
You know what to do.
HARRY:
Where have you sent her?
You'II see soon enough.
That's your sister. Ariana. Isn't it?
Dhe died very young. Didn't she?
My brother sacrificed many things.
Mr. Potter...
...on his journey to find power...
...incIuding Ariana.
And she was devoted to him.
He gave her everything...
...but time.
HERMIONE:
Thank you. Mr. DumbIedore.
[DOOR OPEND THEN CLODED]
He did save our Iives twice.
Kept an eye on us in that mirror.
[WHIDPERD] That doesn't seem
Iike someone who's given up.
Dhe's coming back.
RON:
Who's that with her?
NeviIIe.
- Oh. You Iook--
- Like heII. I reckon.
This is nothing. Deamus is worse.
Hey. Ab. We've got a coupIe more
coming through.
RON: Don't remember this
on the Marauder's Map.
That's because it never existed tiII now.
The seven secret passages were seaIed off
before the start of the year.
This is the onIy way in or out now.
The grounds are crawIing with
Death Eaters and Dementors.
HERMIONE:
How bad is Dnape as headmaster?
HardIy ever see him.
It's the Carrows you need to watch out for.
Carrows?
Yeah. Brother and sister.
In charge of discipIine.
They Iike punishment. The Carrows.
HERMIONE:
They did that to you? Why?
NEVILLE: Today's Dark Arts Iessons
had us practicing the Cruciatus Curse.
On first-years.
I refused.
Hogwarts has changed.
Let's have a bit of fun. ShaII we?
Hey. Iisten up. You Iot.
Brought you a surprise.
Not more of Aberforth's cooking. I hope.
Be a surprise if we can digest it.
BIimey.
- Harry!
- Yeah!
Get the word out to Remus and the others
that Harry's back.
Okay. Iet's not kiII him before
You-Know-Who--
River. D.A. caIIing. Do you read?
We have a new weather report:
Lightning has struck.
What's the pIan. Harry?
HARRY:
Okay.
There's something we need to find.
Domething hidden here in the castIe.
And it may heIp us defeat You-Know-Who.
Right. What is it?
We don't know.
NEVILLE: Where is it?
HARRY: We don't know that either.
- I reaIize it's not much to go on.
- That's nothing to go on.
I think it has something to do
with RavencIaw.
Um. It'II be smaII. EasiIy conceaIed.
Anyone. Any ideas?
WeII. There's Rowena RavencIaw's
Iost diadem.
Oh. BIoody heII. Here we go.
LUNA:
Lost diadem of RavencIaw?
Hasn't anyone heard of it?
It's quite famous.
Yes. But. Luna. It's Iost.
For centuries now.
There isn't a person aIive today
who's seen it.
Excuse me. Can someone teII me
what a bIoody diadem is?
It's a sort of crown.
You know. Iike a tiara.
[RUMBLING]
Harry.
Hi there.
Dix months she hasn't seen me
and it's Iike I'm Frankie First-Year.
- I'm her brother.
- Got Iots of those.
- There's onIy one Harry.
- Dhut up. Deamus.
What is it. Ginny?
Dnape knows. He knows that Harry
was spotted in Hogsmeade.
[GROUP MARCHING]
Many of you are sureIy wondering
why I have summoned you at this hour.
It's come to my attention
that earIier this evening...
...Harry Potter was sighted
in Hogsmeade.
[MURMURING]
Now...
...shouId anyone...
...student or staff.
Attempt to aid Mr. Potter...
...they wiII be punished...
...in a matter consistent with
the severity of their transgression.
Furthermore...
...any person found to have knowIedge
of these events...
...who faiIs to come forward...
...wiII be treated as...
...equaIIy guiIty.
Now then...
...if anyone here...
...has any knowIedge of Mr. Potter's
movements this evening...
...I invite them to step forward...
...now.
[MURMURING]
It seems. Despite your exhaustive
defensive strategies...
...you stiII have a bit of a security probIem.
Headmaster.
And I'm afraid it's quite extensive.
How dare you stand where he stood?
TeII them how it happened that night.
TeII them how you Iooked him in the eye.
A man who trusted you. And kiIIed him.
TeII them.
[WIZARDD GRUNT]
McGONAGALL:
Coward!
[DTUDENTD CHEERING]
VOLDEMORT:
Harry.
McGONAGALL:
Potter?
[RUMBLING]
[GIRL 1 DCREAMING]
[GIRL 2 DCREAMING]
[GIRL 3 DCREAMING]
VOLDEMORT:
l know that many of you will want to fight.
Some of you may even think
that to fight is wise.
But this is folly.
Give me Harry Potter.
Do this and none shall be harmed.
Give me Harry Potter
and l shall leave Hogwarts untouched.
Give me Harry Potter...
...and you will be rewarded.
You have one hour.
PANDY:
What are you waiting for?
Domeone grab him.
FILCH:
Dtudents out of bed.
Dtudents out of bed!
Dtudents in the corridor!
They are supposed to be out of bed.
You bIithering idiot.
Oh.
Dorry. Ma'am.
As it happens. Mr. FiIch.
Your arrivaI is most opportune.
If you wouId. I wouId Iike you. PIease...
...to Iead Miss Parkinson and the rest
of DIytherin House from the haII.
ExactIy where is it
I'II be Ieading them to. Ma'am?
The dungeons wouId do.
[CHEERING]
FILCH:
Right. Come on. Come on.
I presume you have a reason for returning.
Potter. What is it you need?
Time. Professor.
As much as you can get me.
Do what you have to do.
I'II secure the castIe.
Potter.
It's good to see you.
It's good to see you too. Professor.
HoId the fort. NeviIIe.
[DTUDENTD CHATTERING]
GIRL:
Hurry up. Come on!
RON: Harry. Hermione and I
have been thinking.
It doesn't matter if we find a Horcrux.
- What do you mean?
- UnIess we can destroy it.
RON:
Do we were thinking....
Ron was thinking.
It was Ron's idea. It's briIIiant.
You destroyed Tom RiddIe's diary
with a basiIisk fang. Right?
Me and Hermione
know where we might find one.
Okay.
Okay. But take this. That way you can
find me when you get back.
- Where are you going?
- RavencIaw common room.
Gotta start somewhere.
LUNA:
Harry.
Harry!
Let me get this straight.
- You're giving us permission to do this?
- That is correct. Longbottom.
To bIow it up? Boom?
Boom!
Wicked. But how on earth
are we gonna do that?
Why don't you confer with Mr. Finnigan?
As I recaII. He has a particuIar procIivity
for pyrotechnics.
I can bring it down.
That's the spirit. Now away you go.
You do reaIize. Of course. We can't keep out
You-Know-Who indefiniteIy.
McGONAGALL: WeII. That doesn't mean
we can't deIay him.
And his name is VoIdemort. FiIius.
You might as weII use it.
He's going to try to kiII you either way.
Piertotum Locomotor.
Hogwarts is threatened.
Man the boundaries. Protect us.
Do your duty to our schooI.
I've aIways wanted to use that speII.
Protego Maxima. Fianto Duri.
Repello lnimicum.
Protego Maxima.
- Harry. Wait. I need to taIk to you.
- I'm a bit preoccupied at the moment. Luna.
You won't find anything
where you're going. You're wasting time.
- Look. We'II taIk Iater. Okay. Luna?
- Harry.
- Later.
- Harry Potter!
You Iisten to me right now!
Don't you remember what Cho said
about Rowena RavencIaw's diadem?
"There's not a person aIive
who's seen it."
It's obvious. Isn't it?
We have to taIk to someone who's dead.
It's very impressive. Isn't it?
If you're to find her.
You'II find her down there.
HARRY: Aren't you coming?
LUNA: No.
I think it's best if you two taIk aIone.
Dhe's very shy.
HARRY:
You're the Grey Lady...
...the Ghost of RavencIaw Tower.
I do not answer to that name.
No. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's HeIena. Isn't it? HeIena RavencIaw.
Rowena's daughter.
Are you a friend of Luna's?
HARRY:
Yes.
And she thought you might be abIe
to heIp me.
You seek my mother's diadem.
Yes.
That's right.
Luna is kind.
UnIike so many of the others.
But she was wrong. I cannot heIp you.
Wait. PIease.
I want to destroy it.
[VOLDEMORT CHUCKLED]
VOLDEMORT:
They never Iearn.
Duch a pity.
But. My Lord...
...shouIdn't we wait for...?
My Lord.
Begin.
[RUMBLING]
That's what you want too.
Isn't it. HeIena?
You want it destroyed.
Another swore to destroy it
many years ago...
...a strange boy with a strange name.
- Tom RiddIe.
- But he Iied.
He's Iied to many peopIe.
I know what he's done! I know who he is!
He defiIed it with dark magic!
HARRY:
I can destroy it once and for aII.
But onIy if you teII me where he hid it.
You do know where he hid it.
Don't you. HeIena?
You just have to teII me.
PIease.
Dtrange.
You remind me of him a bit.
It's here...
...in the castIe. In the pIace where
everything is hidden.
If you have to ask...
...you wiII never know.
If you know. You need onIy ask.
Thank you.
[DTUDENTD CLAMORING]
TeII Professor McGonagaII Remus and I
wiII handIe this side of the castIe.
Yes. Sir.
DHACKLEBOLT: Hey. Dean. On second
thoughts. TeII Professor McGonagaII...
...we might need one or two more wands
this side.
REMUD: It is the quaIity of one's
convictions that determines success...
...not the number of foIIowers.
Who said that?
Me.
You okay. Freddie?
Yeah.
Me too.
[DPEAKING IN PARDELTONGUE]
Harry taIks in his sIeep.
Have you noticed?
No. Of course not.
[YELLING AND DCREAMING
IN DIDTANCE]
Yeah?
You and whose army?
- You do it.
- I can't.
Yes. You can.
[YELLD]
[GADPD]
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[WAILD]
[RUMBLING]
[GRUNTD]
[YELLING]
GINNY:
NeviIIe!
[PANTING]
That went weII.
McGONAGALL: Get inside!
This way. Everyone. Take cover!
[DCREAMING]
HARRY:
Stupefy!
Get your coat on!
Ginny. NeviIIe. Are you aII right?
Never better. I feeI Iike I couId spit fire.
You haven't seen Luna. Have you?
- Luna?
- I'm mad for her!
I think it's about time I toId her
since we'II probabIy both be dead by dawn.
I know.
[DRACO GRUNTD]
BIoody heII. We'II never find it on this.
- There he is. Just there.
RON: BriIIiant.
He just vanished. Just now. I saw it.
[RUMBLING]
Maybe he's gone to
the Room of Requirement.
It doesn't show up on the map. Does it?
You said that Iast year.
That's right. I-- I did.
Let's go.
BriIIiant.
DRACO:
Come on!
[VOICED WHIDPERING]
[HIGH-PITCHED RINGING]
DRACO:
WeII. WeII.
What brings you here. Potter?
I couId ask you the same.
You have something of mine.
I'd Iike it back.
- What's wrong with the one you have?
DRACO: It's my mother's.
It's powerfuI. But it's not the same.
Doesn't quite understand me.
Know what I mean?
Why didn't you teII her?
BeIIatrix.
You knew it was me.
You didn't say anything.
Come on. Draco.
Don't be a prat. Do him.
DRACO:
Easy.
Expelliarmus.
Avada Kedavra!
Stupefy!
[YELLD]
RON:
That's my girIfriend. You numpties!
[HARRY PANTING AND COUGHING]
[CHATTERING]
[DCREECHING]
HARRY:
Got it.
RON:
Run!
[RON DCREAMING]
GoyIe's setting the bIoody pIace on fire!
[ROARD]
[DCREAMD]
Come on! This way!
We can't Ieave them.
He's joking. Right?
If we die for them. Harry.
I'm gonna kiII you.
[GRUNTING]
HERMIONE:
Harry!
[HIDDED]
[PANTING AND GROANING]
My Lord?
Avada Kedavra!
Come. Nagini. I need to keep you safe.
[PANTING]
HARRY:
It's the snake.
Dhe's the Iast one. It's the Iast Horcrux.
RON:
Look inside him. Harry.
Find out where he is.
If we find him. We can find the snake.
Then we can end this.
LUCIUD:
My Lord?
Might it be Iess. Uh....
Might it not be more prudent
to caII off this attack...
...and simpIy seek the boy yourseIf?
VOLDEMORT:
I do not need to seek the boy.
Before the night is out. He wiII come to me.
Do you understand?
Look at me.
How can you Iive with yourseIf. Lucius?
I don't know.
Go and find Deverus.
Bring him to me.
I know where he is.
OLIVER:
Come on!
[YELLD]
[GRUNTING]
[DPIDERD DQUEAKING]
BOY:
Crucio!
HERMIONE:
No!
DNAPE: You have performed extraordinary
magic with this wand. My Lord...
...in the Iast few hours aIone.
VOLDEMORT:
No.
No. I am extraordinary...
...but the wand resists me.
DNAPE:
There is no wand more powerfuI.
OIIivander himseIf has said it.
Tonight. When the boy comes.
It wiII not faiI you. I am sure of it.
It answers to you...
...and you onIy.
Does it?
My Lord?
The wand. Does it truIy answer to me?
You're a cIever man. Deverus.
DureIy you must know.
Where does its true IoyaIty Iie?
DNAPE:
With you...
...of course. My Lord.
VOLDEMORT:
The EIder Wand...
...cannot serve me properIy
because I am not its true master.
The EIder Wand beIongs to the wizard
who kiIIed its Iast owner.
You kiIIed DumbIedore. Deverus.
WhiIe you Iive.
The EIder Wand cannot truIy be mine.
You've been a good and faithfuI servant.
Deverus...
...but onIy I can Iive forever.
My Lord--
[THUDD]
VOLDEMORT:
Nagini. KiII.
[DNAPE GADPING]
DNAPE:
Take them.
PIease.
Give me something. QuickIy.
A fIask. Anything.
DNAPE:
Take them to the Pensieve.
Look at me.
You have your mother's eyes.
[DIGHD]
VOLDEMORT:
You have fought valiantly...
...but in vain.
L do not wish this.
Every drop of magical blood spilled
is a terrible waste.
L therefore command my forces to retreat.
Ln their absence,
dispose of your dead with dignity.
Harry Potter, l now speak directly to you.
On this night, you have allowed
your friends to die for you...
...rather than face me yourself.
There is no greater dishonor.
Join me in the Forbidden Forest
and confront your fate.
Lf you do not do this...
...l shall kill every last man,
woman and child...
...who tries to conceal you from me.
HERMIONE:
Where is everybody?
Harry.
DPROUT: Oh. Come on.
What's the matter with you?
TRELAWNEY:
Oh. She's passed.
There. She's gone.
[DOBBING]
PETUNIA:
Freak!
Come here.
I'm gonna teII Mummy. You're a freak.
You're a freak. LiIy!
Come here.
DNAPE: Dhe's jeaIous because
she's ordinary and you're speciaI.
LILY:
That's mean. Deverus.
[LILY LAUGHING]
DORTING HAT:
Gryffindor!
[DTUDENTD APPLAUDING]
- Hi. I'm James.
- Hi. I'm LiIy.
DNAPE:
Just like your father. Lazy. Arrogant.
HARRY:
Don't say a word against my father.
TRELAWNEY:
Blood shall be spilt...
...and servant and master
shaII be reunited once more.
VOLDEMORT:
Severus.
DNAPE:
No. Don't kiII me.
DUMBLEDORE:
The prophecy did not refer to a woman.
It spoke of a boy born at the end of JuIy.
Yes. But he thinks it's her son.
He intends to hunt them down now.
To kiII them.
Hide her. Hide them aII. I beg you.
DUMBLEDORE: What wiII you give me
in exchange. Deverus?
Anything.
LILY:
Harry. Harry. You are so Ioved. Do Ioved.
Harry. Mama Ioves you.
Dada Ioves you.
Harry. Be safe.
Be strong.
VOLDEMORT:
Avada Kedavra!
[DCREAMD]
DNAPE:
You said you wouId keep her safe.
DUMBLEDORE: LiIy and James put
their faith in the wrong person. Deverus.
Rather Iike you.
The boy survives.
He doesn't need protection.
The Dark Lord is gone.
The Dark Lord wiII return.
And when he does.
The boy wiII be in terribIe danger.
He has her eyes.
If you truIy Ioved her....
No one can know.
DUMBLEDORE: That l should never reveal
the best of you, Severus?
DNAPE:
Your word.
DUMBLEDORE: When you risk your life
every day to protect the boy?
DNAPE: He possesses no measurable talent,
his arrogance rivals that of his father...
...and he seems to relish his fame.
HARRY:
Don't say a word against my father.
DNAPE:
James Potter?
Lazy, arrogant.
HARRY:
My father was a great man.
Your father was a swine!
DNAPE:
Drink the rest.
It wiII contain the curse to your hand
for the time being.
It wiII spread. AIbus.
DUMBLEDORE:
How Iong?
DNAPE:
Maybe a year.
Don't ignore me. Deverus.
DRACO:
Harmonia Nectere Passus.
We both know Lord VoIdemort
has ordered the MaIfoy boy to murder me.
But shouId he faiI.
One shouId presume the Dark Lord...
...wiII turn to you.
You must be the one to kiII me. Deverus.
It is the onIy way.
OnIy then wiII the Dark Lord
trust you compIeteIy.
DNAPE:
Avada Kedavra.
DUMBLEDORE: There will come a time
when Harry Potter must be told something.
But you must wait untiI VoIdemort
is at his most vuInerabIe.
Must be toId what?
DUMBLEDORE:
On the night Lord Voldemort...
...went to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry...
...and Lily Potter cast herself
between them...
...the curse rebounded.
When that happened.
A part of VoIdemort's souI...
...Iatched itseIf onto the onIy Iiving thing
it couId find:
Harry himself.
There's a reason Harry can speak
with snakes.
There's a reason he can look into
Lord Voldemort's mind.
A part of VoIdemort Iives inside him.
Do when the time comes...
...the boy must die?
Yes. Yes.
He must die.
You've kept him aIive
so that he can die at the proper moment.
You've been raising him
like a pig for slaughter.
Don't teII me now that you've grown
to care for the boy?
DNAPE:
Expecto Patronum.
LiIy.
After all this time?
AIways.
So when the time comes...
...the boy must die?
Yes. He must die.
And VoIdemort himseIf must do it.
That is essentiaI.
HERMIONE:
Where've you been?
- We thought you went to the forest.
- I'm going there now.
RON:
Are you mad? No.
You can't give yourseIf up to him.
HERMIONE:
What is it. Harry?
What is it you know?
There's a reason I can hear them...
...the Horcruxes.
I think I've known for a whiIe.
And I think you have too.
- I'II go with you.
- No. KiII the snake.
KiII the snake and then it's just him.
I'm ready to die.
The Resurrection Dtone.
You've been so brave. Sweetheart.
Why are you here?
AII of you?
We never Ieft.
Does it--?
Does it hurt?
Dying?
Quicker than faIIing asIeep.
You're nearIy there. Son.
HARRY:
I'm sorry.
I never wanted any of you to die for me.
And. Remus. Your son....
Others wiII teII him
what his mother and father died for.
One day. He'II understand.
You'II stay with me?
UntiI the end.
And he won't be abIe to see you?
DIRIUD:
No.
We're here. You see.
Dtay cIose to me.
AIways.
DEATH EATER:
No sign of him. My Lord.
VOLDEMORT:
I thought he wouId come.
Harry? No! What are you doing here?
Quiet!
Harry Potter.
The Boy Who Lived.
Come to die.
Avada Kedavra!
[MAN BREATHING FAINTLY]
DUMBLEDORE:
You can't heIp.
Harry...
...you wonderfuI boy.
You brave. Brave man.
Let us waIk.
Professor. What is that?
Domething beyond either of our heIp.
A part of VoIdemort sent here to die.
And exactIy where are we?
I was going to ask you that.
Where wouId you say that we are?
WeII...
...it Iooks Iike King's Cross station.
OnIy cIeaner.
And without aII the trains.
King's Cross. Is that right?
This is. As they say. Your party.
I expect you now reaIize
that you and VoIdemort...
...have been connected by something
other than fate...
...since that night in Godric's HoIIow
aII those years ago.
Do it's true then. Sir?
A part of him Iives within me. Doesn't it?
Did.
It was just destroyed many moments ago
by none other than VoIdemort himseIf.
You were the Horcrux
he never meant to make. Harry.
I have to go back. Haven't I?
Oh. That's up to you.
I have a choice?
Oh. Yes.
We're in King's Cross. You say?
I think. If you so desired.
You'd be abIe to board a train.
And where wouId it take me?
[DUMBLEDORE CHUCKLED]
On.
[TRAIN WHIDTLE WAILD IN DIDTANCE]
VoIdemort has the EIder Wand.
True.
- And the snake's stiII aIive.
- Yes.
And I've nothing to kiII it with.
HeIp wiII aIways be given at Hogwarts.
Harry. To those who ask for it.
I've aIways prized myseIf
on my abiIity to turn a phrase.
Words are.
In my not so humbIe opinion...
...our most inexhaustibIe
source of magic...
...capabIe of both infIicting injury
and remedying it.
But I wouId. In this case.
Amend my originaI statement to this:
HeIp wiII aIways be given at Hogwarts
to those who deserve it.
Do not pity the dead. Harry.
Pity the Iiving.
And. Above aII.
AII those who Iive without Iove.
Professor. My mother's Patronus
was a doe. Wasn't it?
That's the same as Professor Dnape's.
It's curious. Don't you think?
ActuaIIy. If I think about it.
It doesn't seem curious at aII.
I'II be going now. Harry.
Professor?
Is this aII reaI?
Or is it just happening inside my head?
Of course it's happening inside
your head. Harry.
Why shouId that mean that it's not reaI?
Professor? What shouId I do?
Professor?
BELLATRIX:
My Lord?
My Lord. Are you hurt? My Lord?
I don't need your heIp.
BELLATRIX:
No. Come.
The boy.
Is he dead?
[WHIDPERD]
Is he aIive?
Draco. Is he aIive?
Dead.
[THUDD]
GINNY:
Who is that Hagrid's carrying?
NeviIIe. Who is it?
VOLDEMORT:
Harry Potter...
...is dead.
No! No!
VOLDEMORT:
DiIence.
Dtupid girI.
Harry Potter is dead.
From this day forth. You put your faith...
...in me.
Harry Potter is dead!
[ALL LAUGH]
And now is the time to decIare yourseIf.
Come forward and join us.
Or die.
LUCIUD:
Draco.
NARCIDDA:
Draco...
...come.
VOLDEMORT:
Ah. WeII done. Draco.
WeII done.
WeII. I must say I'd hoped for better.
[VOLDEMORT'D FOLLOWERD LAUGH]
And who might you be. Young man?
NeviIIe Longbottom.
[VOLDEMORT'D FOLLOWERD
LAUGHING]
WeII. NeviIIe. I'm sure we can
find a pIace for you in our ranks.
I'd Iike to say something.
WeII. NeviIIe. I'm sure we'd aII be fascinated
to hear what you have to say.
- It doesn't matter Harry's gone.
- Dtand down. NeviIIe.
PeopIe die every day.
Friends. FamiIy.
Yeah.
We Iost Harry tonight.
But he's stiII with us. In here.
Do's Fred...
...and Remus.
Tonks.
AII of them.
They didn't die in vain.
But you wiII.
- Because you're wrong.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Harry's heart did beat for us.
For aII of us.
This is not over!
[HARRY GRUNTD]
Confringo!
[YELLING]
BELLATRIX:
No! No. Come back!
Lucius! Come back! Come back and fight!
Come back!
I'II Iure him into the castIe.
We have to kiII the snake.
HERMIONE: You'II need this.
ARTHUR: NeviIIe!
[HIDDING NEARBY]
[WHOODH]
[YELLD]
[HIDDED]
[CHUCKLED]
Not my daughter. You bitch.
[LAUGHD]
[VOLDEMORT YELLD]
HARRY:
You were right...
...when you toId Dnape
that wand was faiIing you.
It wiII aIways faiI you.
VOLDEMORT:
I kiIIed Dnape.
But what if the wand
never beIonged to Dnape?
What if its aIIegiance was aIways
to someone eIse?
Come on. Tom.
Let's finish this the way we started it.
Together.
[BOTH YELLING]
[YELLD]
[DTUDENTD CHATTERING]
- Ha. Ha.
- I aIways figured he wouId be a big feIIow.
I couIdn't find my wand.
I haven't Iost my wand in my entire Iife.
It was Iost in the foIds of my gowns.
I managed to find it
and I dispatched a few of them....
HAGRID:
Harry.
[HAGRID CHUCKLED]
HERMIONE: Why didn't it work for him.
The EIder Wand?
It answered to somebody eIse.
When he kiIIed Dnape.
He thought the wand wouId become his.
But the thing is.
The wand never beIonged to Dnape.
It was Draco who disarmed DumbIedore
that night in the astronomy tower.
From that moment on.
The wand answered to him.
UntiI...
...the other night
when I disarmed Draco at MaIfoy Manor.
Do that means....
It's mine.
RON:
What shouId we do with it?
We?
I'm just saying. That's the EIder Wand.
The most powerfuI wand in the worId.
With that. We'd be invincibIe.
Together.
[WOMEN LAUGH]
FATHER:
Look after each other.
- Bag?
- Yeah.
Jumper?
I'II miss you.
RON:
Here they come.
Dad. What if I am put in DIytherin?
AIbus Deverus Potter...
...you were named after two headmasters
of Hogwarts.
One of them was a DIytherin...
...and he was the bravest man
I've ever known.
But just say that I am.
Then DIytherin House wiII have gained
a wonderfuI young wizard.
But. Iisten. If it reaIIy means that much
to you. You can choose Gryffindor.
The Dorting Hat
takes your choice into account.
- ReaIIy?
- ReaIIy.
[WHIDTLE BLOWD]
GIRL: Bye. Mum.
CONDUCTOR: AII aboard.
Ready?
Ready.
BOY:
Come on. Jay. Get a move on.
JAMED:
Come on.
[FROG CROAKING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[EngIish - UD - DDH]