SOLDIER OVER PA: Unit Christmas rations
must be picked up by 0900 hours.
Armor group tree decoration team,
report to the Engineering Depot.
My son, will you turn off
that wretched puppet?
Brush your teeth.
Don't call him a puppet.
I beg your pardon.
Look, he's not a puppet.
Howdy Doody's real.
Well...
He's real.
Mr. Deedee Doodoo will
have to say good night.
Oh, no.
And remember,
you have to be asleep
when he comes
down the chimney.
It's not even a chimney, Pop.
He has his ways.
Then I want to wait up.
Watch him do it.
Nonsense.
(SIGHS) Okay.
I want a story then.
Oh, no, no, no.
No stories tonight.
Just one.
And then I'll go to bed.
Right away.
Then I'll brush my teeth,
I promise.
"It is said that
at the dawn of time,
"man, beast and all magical beings lived
together under Aiglin the Father Tree.
"But man had been created
with a hole in his heart,
"a hole that no possession,
power or knowledge could fill.
"And in his infinite greed,
"man dreamt of expanding his
dominion over the entire Earth.
(ROARS)
(ALL SHOUTING)
" The blood of many an elf,
ogre and goblin
was spilled in
their war with man.
"And King Balor, the
one-armed king of Elfland,
" watched the slaughter
in dread and despair.
" But one day, the master
of the goblin blacksmiths
" offered to build the king
a golden mechanical army,
"seventy times 70 soldiers
" that would never know hunger
and could not be stopped.
" Prince Nuada begged
his father to agree.
" 'Build me this army, '
the king said.
" So a magical crown
was forged
" that would allow
those of royal blood
" to command the Golden Army
if unchallenged.
" 'I am King Balor,
leader of the Golden Army.
" 'ls there anyone
who disputes my right? '
"And in his throne room
no one challenged his word."
But, wait, what if someone
could challenge him?
Would they have a fight?
Well, most likely.
A challenge must
be answered.
But do you want to hear
the end of this story or not?
Yes, please.
Right.
"So the world was changed, and
the next time the humans marched,
" they felt the earth
tremble beneath their feet
" and saw the sky darken
with monstrous shapes.
" The Golden Army had no
remorse, felt no loyalty or pain.
"And King Balor's heart
grew heavy with regret.
" So he called a truce and
divided the crown in three pieces,
" one for the humans,
and two for himself.
" In exchange, man
would keep to the cities
" and the magical beings
would own the forests.
" This truce would be honored by
their sons and the sons of their sons
" until the end of time.
" But Prince Nuada did not
believe in the promises of man.
"And it is said that
he went into exile,
" vowing to return the day
his people needed him most.
" So the Golden
Army lay dormant,
" locked inside the Earth,
waiting.
"And there it is to this day,
"awaiting the day the crown
is made whole again.
"Silent,
still and indestructible."
Wow. What does it
mean "industrable"?
Indestructible.
Indestruct...
It means no one
can destroy them.
Wow.
Go to sleep, my son.
But it's just
a story, right, Pops?
Is it now?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, come on.
Those guys,
they can't be real.
Well, my son,
I'm sure you'll find out.
(WINK GROWLS)
How long have you
been there, my friend?
They're over there.
I bought them today.
(TOOTH FAIRIES SQUEAKING)
I haven't fed them at all.
I will go up first.
You will follow.
And remember, Mr. Wink,
don't be shy.
(GROWLING)
(WINK ROARS)
(HORN BLARING)
(GAVEL TAPPING)
Next lot. Number 776.
This is an important
votive figure,
a fertility goddess dating
approximately 15,000 to 10,000 B.C.
(CHATTERING)
This was found
in a loess deposit
in a terrace about 30 meters
from the Shannon River.
And we'll open the
bidding at $300,000.
Three hundred thousand.
Three hundred and
twenty-five, thank you.
Three hundred and fifty,
thank you.
Three seventy-five.
Three hundred
and seventy-five.
Going once.
Going twice. Sold.
And now we move on to
our next item, lot 777,
(DOOR OPENS)
a piece of the Royal
Crown of Bethmoora.
The origin of this
piece harkens back
to the saga of
the Sons of the Earth
and the creation of
the fabled Golden Army.
And here it is,
our next item.
WOMAN OVER PA: Lot 777.
(CHATTERING)
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
please keep your seats.
The auction will
restart shortly.
I'm sure this is just
a temporary loss of power.
Now, for the first
time at auction,
a piece of the Royal
Crown of Bethmoora,
coming to us from
a long lost culture.
NUADA: Lost?
Not at all.
Forgotten by you,
perhaps,
but very, very much alive.
AUCTIONEER: Who are you, sir?
Sir, please identify yourself.
You can't just...
I am Prince Nuada Silverlance,
son of King Balor.
And I am here, sir, to reclaim
what is rightfully mine.
Security. Call security!
(WINK GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
(ALL SCREAM)
What do you think
you're doing?
This is outrageous.
Take what you want.
Please leave.
Anything, take anything.
Be quiet.
(SHOUTS) Sit down!
Proud, empty, hollow
things that you are.
Let this remind you why
you once feared the dark.
Fishstick. We have to talk.
MANNING: Undercover.
Can't he get the
meaning of the word?
Look, we are still
government-funded.
We are still a secret, although
a dirty secret, if you ask me.
Officially we do
not exist, you see.
So that's the problem
when we get these.
Subway. Highway. Park.
And he posed for this one
and gave an autograph.
I suppress each photo.
Cell phone videos.
They cost me a fortune and
they show up on YouTube.
God, I hate YouTube.
Well, he just wants the world
outside to know what we do,
what he does.
He loathes me.
I don't think so.
No?
Target practice.
Oh, dear.
And then he
posts them around.
Do you know how
that makes me feel?
(ROARS)
What's going on?
Oh, it's Friday.
I tell you, Fishstick,
he hates me.
He's out to destroy me.
My street cred is low.
Street cred?
My mojo.
Washington, they're wondering
if I've got the stuff.
You think I have
an easy job?
(STAMMERING) Do you think
I enjoy being a pain in the neck?
(STUTTERING)
I am medicated.
I mean,
this is not candy.
This is...
It's an antacid.
Yes, it's an
over-the-counter medicine,
but this is medicine.
You see, I worry
because, you know,
I mean, I am,
we are, after all,
we're just humble
public servants.
It's not about you.
He's acting out.
Things are a little
tense with Liz.
Tense? How tense?
Tense how?
Well, you know, the usual.
A new couple
making adjustments.
They argue.
They argue, huh?
Sometimes.
How bad?
Like everybody else.
They have good days
and bad days.
LIZ: I'm not done with you.
(GASPS)
Hey, Abe.
LIZ: Red, come back here!
Manning.
LIZ: Pick up your clothes!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
LIZ: Put away your things!
(SIGHS)
HELLBOY: Watch it,
boys, she's on fire.
Then again, there are
the really bad days.
I'm not afraid
of you, you know.
LIZ: You should be.
Look at this mess. Look around.
I have one rule.
Don't touch my stuff.
LIZ: Oh, I get it.
That's your rule. Okay.
The one and only.
I'm easy.
How's that even possible?
Everything is your stuff.
The same CD, LP.
It's Al Green.
You can't listen
to Al Green on CD.
But it's good to keep.
And an eight-track.
An eight-track, Red?
Yeah, well, one day, the world's
gonna realize its mistake.
Eight-track was
the way to go, baby.
Come on, kids,
you can come out now.
That's right, it's all over.
That's right.
And what about me, Red?
I need some space.
(EXHALES)
At least enough to
find my toothbrush.
Toothbrush? Wait a minute.
It's right there.
Red! I can't
live like this.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
MAN ON PA: Security breach
central Manhattan.
Oh, damn.
Gotta go.
We all gotta go.
It's an emergency, right?
MAN ON PA: Security breach.
Let's go.
MANNING: Red. Red!
MAN ON PA: All personnel
to garage area.
Hold on a sec.
Oh, jeez, it's Manning.
Watch yourself, Liz.
Red. Red!
Listen.
Manning.
Hi.
We're going to
downtown Manhattan.
Yeah, it'll be fun.
Downtown.
Very dangerous.
Dangerous for you.
And for me.
Now, I know you dream
of the outside world,
but, trust me,
it's not that great.
It's savage, as a
matter of fact. Bad.
LIZ: Come on, fellas,
let's get this out of here.
These, on the
other hand, are good.
Mmm.
Cuban.
Good.
Being seen?
Bad.
Exactly. I confiscated a box of these,
and I'll get you some more.
But you've gotta do me
a little favor tonight, out there.
You have to be...
You have to be very, very...
Discreet.
What? Thank you. Yes.
You're welcome.
Discreet.
Invisible. In and out.
Really?
Hey.
Hey, I can be
discreet if I wanna be.
I followed you
and Myers, didn't I?
And then you had him
transferred to Antarctica.
That's very discreet.
He said he liked the cold.
Like a shadow.
AGENT OVER PA:
Red team, Red team.
Like a shadow
in the night.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
MANNING: US Customs discovered
a few illegally imported items.
It's a minor infraction.
And a gas pocket.
They detected
a gas pocket up there.
Now FBI agents,
under my command,
are going up there right now
with special gas equipment.
Jeez, it stinks in here.
This is worse
than my room.
AGENT:
Waiting for a report on that.
Say "cheese."
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Let's go.
(CLINKING)
Whatever they
called us for is over.
We had over 70
guests reported.
We have no survivors,
no bodies.
Same story here, babe.
LIZ: Don't call me "babe."
"Abe," I said.
"Abe." Wrong channel.
(EXHALES)
Abe, I think Liz is
still mad at me.
LIZ: Still the same channel.
Oh!
HELLBOY: Can I ask
you a question?
No.
Now, listen.
When we get home later,
I'm gonna clean up
my whole mess.
That's not the problem.
What is it?
Not now.
(GROANS)
Abe, what have you got?
Oh, this is interesting.
Both boxes have
the Royal Seal.
Only delivered
at a time of war.
Red? We have company.
HELLBOY: Come on, Blue,
give me something to work with here.
Burrowing creatures.
How many of them?
ABE: Many.
There are no corpses because
there are no leftovers.
Have you noticed the floor?
Oh, crap.
ABE: Precisely.
All these things
do is eat and eat.
Then poop,
and then eat again.
Remind you of anyone?
Damn it, Abe.
What are these things?
(ABE READING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
HELLBOY: English, English.
Oh, they're Tooth Fairies.
Ha!
No, no. Third century,
Black Forest.
Feed mostly on calcium,
bones, skin, organs.
But they do go
for the teeth first.
Hence the name
Tooth Fairies.
LIZ: I bet you they don't
leave money, either.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Oh, my God.
Liz, you're pregnant.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
What have you got, Marble?
Think I may have found one.
But he's kind of cute.
HELLBOY: Don't go near it!
It's biting me!
Marble.
(GROANS)
It hurts! It hurts!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
LIZ: Red, we need you here!
Marble.
(SCREAMING)
Nasty little...
Keep firing, Abe.
Keep firing!
Damn.
(GROANS)
Sorry, lady.
You should be running.
There's a safe upstairs.
How do we get there?
We need a clearing.
Run!
Up to the safe, now!
LIZ: Abe. Up the stairs.
Come on, Liz, burn them all.
Go. Go!
Yes, we're going!
STEEL: Get in the safe, Abe.
Get in the safe!
Oh, no, no.
No, no, no!
Steel!
(SCREAMING)
Damned beasts.
Fire is mine.
Fire is in me.
Red, stay away
from the window!
Fire is me.
Stop biting me!
(GROANS)
(SLOWLY) Fire is me.
World, here I come.
(GROANS)
(ALL SCREAM)
(CHATTERING)
(GUNSHOT)
What have you done?
Guess we're out.
REPORTER: Hey, Hellboy,
over here.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
CHAMBERLAIN:
Your Royal Highness.
(CHAMBERLAIN SPEAKING GAELIC)
Before entering
the council chamber,
you must surrender
your weapon.
I will not.
(ROARS)
It is protocol, sire,
for peasant and prince alike.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
(NUALA SPEAKING GAELIC)
For you, Sister,
anything.
According to multiple eye witnesses,
lives were, in fact, endangered.
There you have it, Hellboy.
But is he really
on our side?
Do you have superpowers?
Well, yeah.
But, really, all I wanna be
is just an ordinary person,
just like you and
you and everybody.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, guys.
You're missing this.
We're on TV.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
ABE: Liz. Liz,
are you all right?
Yeah, I'll be out
in a minute.
You don't need to do that.
You can trust me.
My readings are
quite accurate.
Shut up, Abe.
Get your damn hand
away from the door.
You have nothing to fear.
In spite of appearances,
I believe Red would be an
excellent father figure.
And what about this guy?
Walking around with a
toilet seat on his head.
A toilet seat!
It's quite obvious it's
a breathing apparatus.
Hey, I think we gotta
lose the garbage truck.
Sends out the wrong signal.
(LAUGHING)
You think that's
our problem?
Transportation?
And this girl, we definitely have
to find out what's wrong with her.
She's cute, though.
We should get her on the show.
I hate it when
people stare at me.
Makes me feel
like a freak.
You had no right, Red.
It's Manning. Could you...
How many times do
I have to tell you?
It's a gas pocket.
And a gaseous
phenomenon that occurred...
Gas pocket.
What an idiot.
You've murdered me.
You have murdered me.
You have ridiculed me.
And you have brought
this unto yourself.
What?
Washington is sending
down a new BPRD agent.
A new guy?
Why?
To look after you.
Sire, please.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
To set us free.
All of us, Father.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
A truce based on shame.
The humans have
forgotten the gods,
destroyed the Earth.
And for what?
Parking lots.
Shopping malls.
Greed has burned a hole in their
heart that will never be filled.
They will never
have enough.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Honor?
Look at this place.
Where is the honor in it?
Father, you were
once a proud warrior.
When did you
become their pet?
I have returned
from exile to wage war
and reclaim our land,
our birthright.
And for that, I will call upon
the help of all of my people.
And they will answer,
the good, the bad
and the worst.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Perhaps I am.
Perhaps they made me so.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
We will not fade.
It is.
I am sorry, Father.
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
And you, Sister, are you at
peace with your king's verdict?
I am, my brother. I am.
Then very well.
Death it is.
(GASPS)
(CRIES)
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
Now, for the final piece,
my sister.
Where is she, Wink?
Where is she?
NUADA: Go find her.
Now! Find her!
(WINK ROARS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Elevator
arriving now to section 42.
Elevator arriving
now to section 42.
Pardon me, boys.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Is he here?
Not yet.
I'm telling you,
we don't need this guy.
Well, I think we do.
Evidently, this guy's quite
the big shot in Washington.
What's his name?
His name is Johann Krauss.
Johann Krauss?
Sounds German.
He's the top man in...
Ectoplasmic.
Yes, thank you.
Ectoplasmic research.
Comes highly recommended
by our European liaison.
Johann Krauss.
"Liaison."
I love that word,
don't you?
It's so hoity toity.
I don't like Germans.
No fingerprints.
Here he comes.
Germans make me nervous.
No photo. Dossier says, and I translate,
"He has a nice open face."
Oh, my God.
Damen und Herren,
Johann Krauss at your service.
I like him.
Look at that.
Poor little thing.
Bought and sold on
the black market.
Crammed into
cargo containers.
Smuggled, abused.
He has very
expressive hands.
The seal on the box
worries me also.
A warring emblem.
Yes, from the Bethmoora clan.
The Sons of the Earth.
Your file says you're the
brains of the operation,
and I must admit,
I'm impressed.
In my file, you'll see,
Mr. Krauss,
that I worked very closely
with Abe in his training.
Ja, okay.
Let's see what our little
friend here can remember.
Memory gets a little sketchy
right after you've burned to death.
But maybe Saint
Malachy can help.
Oh, no, no.
No amulets, Mein Herr.
Teleplasty.
Plastic. Very modern.
Teleplasty by which
an ectoplasmic medium,
such as Dr. Krauss,
can control inanimate things,
organic, mechanical,
dead or alive.
JOHANN: Take it, take it
all in, mein Junge.
(SCREAMS)
There we are. Get up.
Get up. Get up.
Now I have full control
of its limbic system.
Let us see how long
I can hold it.
(CHATTERS)
What?
Hey, you chewed off
the tip of my tail.
Yeah, you, you little...
It says you're rude, brutish
und not very bright.
Wow!
(CHATTERING)
It seems our
little friend here
remembers market
sounds and voices.
And a peculiar
troll language spoken
in the last place
his cage was opened.
The troll market.
The troll market?
Come on.
No one's ever found it.
That's because
it doesn't exist.
(CHOKES)
Mr. Krauss? Dr. Krauss, sir.
Our little informant there
doesn't look so good.
(COUGHING)
Back inside, you.
There we are.
So, now we know
where to begin.
Trolls dwell under bridges.
Wow. You're a genius.
By the way, there's over
2,000 bridges in New York City.
But Vladimir Vanya, 19th
century occult historian,
places the troll
market directly under
the east end of
the Brooklyn Bridge.
We've already looked there.
Yes, you have,
but not with me, Agent.
Not with me.
We're moving in.
Keep it coming, keep it coming.
Hold it.
"Not with me, Agent."
What an ego.
I like him.
Well, you can keep him.
I mean, am I the only one that
thinks this guy is full of...
No, no, no, no,
don't lean.
Lot 336, the Schufftein
glasses. Could it be?
The three surviving
pairs,
and we will use them to
locate the troll market.
Dr. Krauss, what a coup.
The Schufftein glasses.
You're my hero.
Hey. You Hellboy?
Yeah.
You're ugly, man.
Two more on
the wall in front of me
and then three on
the alleys facing that way.
What do you think of
Mr. Know-It-All?
Don't know,
too early to tell.
Hey, you're Hellboy.
I know, I'm ugly.
Forget it.
We'll talk about it later.
He's sure of himself, and I
think maybe you're intimidated.
Intimidated. Huh?
JOHANN: Keep us up to date on the
cameras, Agent Sherman. Over and out.
What's this?
Normally, we can't see
fairy folk and trolls.
They generate a cloaking
aura called "glamour."
But in 1878,
Emil Schufftein designed and built these.
Four crystal diopters
that penetrate that effect
and reveal the true
nature of things.
Oh, Dr. Krauss, they're more
beautiful than I'd imagined.
You must try them on then.
Oh, yes.
Try them on, Agent.
They'll look good.
I love these tight
little leather straps.
Intimidated?
(SCOFFS)
Mr. Kraut? Sir?
Krauss, Agent.
With a double "S."
S-S. Right, right.
Listen, those gizmos?
How do you know they work?
LIZ: I have a suspect.
Give me a vector,
Agent Sherman. A vector.
B-12, the alley, northbound.
JOHANN: Well, track the target.
We're coming down.
Keep an eye on her.
I'll be right back.
This little old lady?
Come on.
It's a Fragglewump,
an ugly Scottish troll.
They're afraid of canaries.
Oh, my God. Canaries, huh?
What about the kittens?
She feeds on them.
WOMAN: Come on, then.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
That thing is a "she"?
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(MEOWING)
Down, you fools.
What do you think
you are doing?
She's gonna eat the cat.
You'll make her
aware of our presence.
ABE: We should use
the canary now.
She's gonna eat it!
ABE: We should use
the bird, Dr. Krauss.
The bird.
She's going to eat the cat.
You will stay put
and follow my orders.
I can't sit by here...
You are directly under my command,
and you have to obey.
Stay put!
Oh, screw this!
Hey! Lucy.
Come back here.
I'm home.
Oh, yes, dearie.
Can I help you?
Give it up, nasty.
We can see you.
You see me?
How? How do you see me?
We're looking
for the entrance
to the troll market.
Any clues?
Come any closer and
I'll rip your heart.
We're gonna have to get
a little old-school, Abe.
Give me the bird.
Not a canary.
What, you're afraid
of this little guy?
Who'd know?
No more, no more.
I'll take you there.
Come on, let's go,
you dirty old troll.
Let's go.
Agent Sherman, we are
going into the troll market.
Keep communication
to a minimum.
Over und out.
I like him.
You see, this is
a man who takes charge.
You think?
Yeah. He's efficient.
He's precise.
You add "resistant" to that,
you got yourself a new watch.
Dr. Krauss is aware of the
chain of command, and he...
Oh, brother!
He seems to like me.
OLD WOMAN: Here we are.
Wow, that's some door!
JOHANN: It's a complex
combination lock.
What do you think,
Agent Sapien?
Not good.
With the number of symbols on the
combination, we'll be here for days.
Well, not necessarily.
Let me try my technique.
Open it, Lucy.
I will not.
Pretty please.
(SHUDDERS)
Do as you may, demon.
Release the yellow beast.
Tear my eyes out.
Rip my insides and
my legs and my tongue,
but I will never
open that door.
(SCREAMS)
(LOUD CRASH)
Is that your
investigative technique?
It said "never."
It's unconscionable.
That means
he didn't like it.
What?
So, what, you're gonna
show us how it's done,
Mr. By-The-Book?
Is that it?
Yes, I think I will.
There we are.
Let me see. Yes.
Gentlemen, welcome
to the troll market.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GROANS)
LIZ: Red, there's something really
important that I need to tell you.
Oh, Liz, you should
be here. You'd love it.
Nobody's looking at us.
We blend right in.
Agent, I said keep
communication to a minimum.
You'll blow our cover.
You know?
I think he's right.
I'm bringing you
here for sure, babe.
The fishbowl wants
radio silence. So...
Over and out.
The Royal Seal.
Brother Red.
Red, do you read me?
Yeah, I read you, Blue,
but I'm watching Sherlock at work.
I'll get back to you.
JOHANN: Excuse me, sir.
Sir, excuse... Pardon me.
Sir, may I ask a...
CREATURE: I gotta tell
the boys that one.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Have you seen anyone purchasing
this type of Tooth Fairy?
No one sells them
down here, pal.
Over in Jersey, maybe.
Well, what about this, then?
Do you recognize this seal?
Make him go away.
No. We don't.
Please, dear sir.
You'd better go. Now!
We'll make it
worth your while.
(ROARS)
Don't waste your time.
We will not talk!
What are you doing?
You're absolutely
sure about that, huh?
Absolutely.
You won't talk, eh?
Never.
Never, huh?
Never ever, ever.
(GROANS)
Feeling a little
chattier now?
We'll never talk.
Yes, yes.
We will, only don't
hit me anymore.
Chicken.
Who bought
the Tooth Fairies?
Prince Nuada.
They say Prince Nuada
broke the truce,
and now there is
talk of war,
a war with
the human world.
Sorry, kid.
That's all right.
Nice baby.
I'm not a baby.
I'm a tumor.
Yes, Red. I am following
a lead right now.
It may turn out...
It may turn out
to be nothing,
but I will let you
know soon enough.
What do you want?
Tell me your name.
(GASPS)
Follow me.
Your father
left you this map.
In it, he said,
lies the secret
to the location
of the Golden Army.
(DOOR BANGING)
Move away!
Quickly, Your Highness.
Can I help you
with something?
No, thank you.
I'm just looking.
You can't go in there!
NUALA: Sir, why
are you following me?
I...
I was just hoping to find
an old map chart of Algiers.
Why are you following me?
I was not.
Did my brother send you
to steal the crown piece?
Your brother?
Oh, you're sorely
mistaken, I assure you.
Then answer me truthfully.
Why were you following me?
My name is Abraham Sapien.
There is no such name.
Oh, I don't like
it either, but I...
Enough.
Give me your hand.
Your hand.
You are an agent
for the Bureau of Paranormal
Research and Defense.
And your name is...
Oh...
Horrible, I know.
I'm Nuala,
Princess Nuala.
Yes, I know.
Forgive me,
Your Highness,
but as you were
learning about me,
I couldn't help but learn
a bit about you myself.
I know that you
need our help.
I'm afraid it's
the other way around.
(LOUD BANG)
(WINK ROARING)
The window. Out now.
I will take care of this.
Oh, dear.
(ABE SCREAMING)
Go! Now go!
(GUNSHOTS)
Get out of here, Blue.
Yes. Come with me,
Your Highness.
You.
(ROARS)
Let me put this to you
as delicately as I can.
My cigar, it was Cuban.
Now you pissed me off.
Oh, crap.
(ROARS)
(CHATTERING)
Whoa!
(HELLBOY GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS)
(ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
Now stay down!
Damn.
(ROARS)
A tooth. Happy?
Give it up, pal.
It's over.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
Wow. Told you.
(WINK ROARS IN PAIN)
JOHANN: Oh, mein Gott,
what have you done, Agent Hellboy?
Look at this!
Now we have to leave.
Red. This is Princess Nuala.
Lady.
JOHANN: We should leave.
Now. Now!
Let's go.
(CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING GAELIC)
To wage his war,
my brother needs this,
the final piece of
the Crown of Bethmoora
and this map to the location
of the Golden Army chamber.
The Golden Army.
The harbingers of death.
The unstoppable tide.
Howdy Doody.
Your Highness, if you hand
the crown piece over to us...
No. Where it goes, I go.
My father died to uphold
the truce with your world.
You must honor
his noble intention.
The lady's
in dire danger.
I take it you're vouching for her,
Agent Sapien?
Most emphatically.
Yes, I am.
Even so.
I am sorry, but we
simply cannot assume
such responsibility
on our own.
The lady just
lost her father.
What more do you want?
You may not care, but
there are procedures, rules
and little handbooks...
She's coming with us.
You got that, Gas Bag?
What did you call me?
NUADA: You.
You will pay for what happened
to my friend down there.
Yeah, right.
You take checks?
Demon.
Born from a womb of shadows.
Sent to destroy their world,
and you still believe you belong.
Are we gonna
talk all night?
'Cause I'm really sleepy.