(SINGING IN CHINESE)
Anything goes
Anything goes.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Be careful.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
You never told me you spoke
my language, Dr. Jones.
Only on special occasions.
So, it is true?
You found Nurhachi?
You know I did.
Last night one of your boys
tried to get Nurhachi
without paying for him.
You have insulted my son.
No, you have insulted me.
I spared his life.
(SPEAKS IN CHINESE)
Aren't you going to introduce us?
This is Willie Scott.
This is Indiana Jones,
famous archeologist.
Well, I thought archeologists
were always funny little men
searching for their mommies.
Mummies.
Dr. Jones found Nurhachi for me,
and he's going to deliver him now.
Say, who is this Nurhachi?
Put the gun away, sonny.
I suggest you give me what you owe me
or anything goes.
(MOANS)
Open it.
The diamond, Lao.
The deal was for the diamond.
Oh, Lao...
(GROANS IN PAIN)
To your very good health.
Lao! He put a hole...
He put two holes
in my dress from Paris!
Sit down!
Now, you bring me Nurhachi.
My pleasure.
Who on Earth is this Nurhachi?
Here he is.
This Nurhachi's a real small guy.
Inside are the remains of Nurhachi,
first Emperor of Manchu Dynasty.
Welcome home, old boy.
(CHUCKLING)
And now, you give me the diamond.
Are you trying to develop
a sense of humor,
or am I going deaf?
(LAUGHING)
What's that?
Antidote.
To what?
The poison you just drank, Dr. Jones.
The poison works fast, Dr. Jones.
(GASPS)
- Lao.
- Lao!
You keep the girl. I find another.
Good service here.
That's not a waiter.
Wu Han's an old friend.
Game's not over, Lao.
Antidote.
(POPPING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Indy...
Don't worry, Wu Han,
I'll get you out of here.
WU: Not this time, Indy.
I followed you on many adventures,
but into the great unknown mystery,
I go first, Indy.
Don't be sad, Dr. Jones.
You will soon be joining him.
Too much to drink, Dr. Jones?
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH SPEAKING CHINESE)
Oh, nuts!
(BAND PLAYING)
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
- The antidote.
- Where's the diamond?
(SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
No!
Stay there!
(CLAMORING)
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Come on.
I don't want to die!
(WILLIE SCREAMING)
Who are you?
Wow! Holy smoke!
Crash landing!
Short Round, step on it.
Okeydokey, Dr. Jones.
Hold on to your potatoes.
For crying out loud,
there's a kid driving the car!
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Wow! Wow.
Where's the antidote? Let me have it.
Listen, I just met you, for Christ's sakes.
Give me...
I'm not that kind of girl.
Hey, Dr. Jones, no time for love.
We got company.
(GUNSHOT)
Oh, I hope you choke.
No shooting.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Okay, you asked for it.
(GROANS)
This is fun!
Here, hold this.
(SQUEALING)
Where's my gun? Where's my gun?
I burned my fingers,
and I cracked a nail!
Dr. Jones... I'm Art Weber.
I spoke with your assistant.
We've managed to secure three seats,
but there might be
a slight inconvenience
as you will be riding
on a cargo full of live poultry.
WILLIE: Is he kidding?
Madam, it's the best I could do
on such short notice.
Heavens, aren't you Willie Scott,
the famous American female vocalist?
Owe you a gin.
(SNIGGERING)
Nice try, Lao Che.
Good-bye, Dr. Jones.
(HENS CLUCKING)
So, what are you supposed to be,
a lion tamer?
I'm allowing you to tag along,
so why don't you give
your mouth a rest?
Okay, doll?
What do you mean, "tag along"?
Ever since you got into my club,
you haven't been able
to take your eyes off me.
Oh, yeah?
(MAN 1 SPEAKS CHINESE)
(MAN 2 SPEAKS CHINESE)
(CHUCKLES)
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
Oh, no.
Oh, no! Mister, mister...
Oh, mister, wake up. Please, mister...
You call him Dr. Jones, doll!
Okay, Dr. Jones, Dr. Jones.
Oh, wake up, please!
Are we there already? Oh, good.
No.
- No one's flying the plane!
- Oh, boy...
They've all gone!
You know how to fly, don't you?
No. Do you?
Oh, no.
- Oh, my God!
- How hard can it be?
- I'm gonna faint.
- Altimeter! Okay.
Air speed. Okay.
Fuel...
Fuel?
(ENGINES SPUTTERING)
I think we got a big problem.
- SHORTY: Dr. Jones!
- Shorty!
Dr. Jones! No more parachutes!
INDY: Shorty!
- Come on, give me a hand!
- SHORTY: What's that?
INDY: Move the box!
SHORTY: Dr. Jones, you're crazy!
Shorty, get our stuff!
A boat? We're not sinking.
(SHRIEKING) We're crashing!
Grab on, Shorty! Grab on!
- SHORTY: Lady, I can't breathe!
- Tight!
(SCREAMING)
Slow it down!
That wasn't so bad, was it?
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS) Put on the brakes!
WILLIE: I hate the water,
and I hate being wet,
and I hate you!
Good. Good!
(WILLIE COUGHING)
SHORTY: Dr Jones?
INDY: I'm all right, Shorty.
You okay?
WILLIE: Where are we, anyway?
India.
How do you know that?
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(ALL MOANING)
WILLIE: I sure hope this means dinner.
God, I'm starving.
INDY: Thank you.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
I can't eat this.
That's more food
than these people eat in a week.
They're starving.
Oh, I'm sorry. You can have...
Eat it.
I'm not hungry.
You're insulting them,
and you're embarrassing me.
- Eat it.
Eat.
(WOMAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(FLIES BUZZING)
Bad news coming.
Can you provide us with a guide
to take us to Delhi?
I'm a professor.
I have to get back to my university.
Yes. Sajnu will guide you.
(INDY SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
On the way to Delhi,
you will stop at Pankot.
Pankot is not on the way to Delhi.
You will go to Pankot Palace.
I thought the palace had been deserted
since the 1850s.
SHAMAN: No.
Now there is a new Maharajah,
and again the palace
has the power of the Dark Light.
It is that place kill my people.
What has happened here?
The evil start in Pankot,
then like monsoon,
it moves darkness
over all country,
over all country.
The evil?
What evil?
See? Bad news.
You listen to Suwamu. You leave Lanka.
They came from palace
and took Sivalinga from our village.
Took what?
It's a stone, a sacred stone
from a shrine that protects the village.
It is why Siva brought you here.
(LAUGHING)
We weren't brought here.
Our plane crashed.
It crashed.
No, no.
We prayed to Siva to help us
find the stone.
It was Siva who made you fall
from the sky.
So you will go to Pankot Palace
to find Sivalinga
and bring back to us.
Bring back to us.
Dr. Jones, did they make
the plane crash
to get you here?
No, Shorty, it's just a ghost story.
Don't worry about it.
They took the stone from here.
Was the stone very smooth
like a rock from a sacred river?
Yes.
With three lines across it
representing the three levels
of the universe.
- That's right.
- Yes.
I've seen stones like the one you lost.
But why would Maharajah
take the sacred stone from here?
They says we must pray
to their evil god.
We says we will not.
Excuse me, I don't understand
how one rock
could destroy a whole village.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
He's saying when
the sacred stone was taken,
the village wells dried up,
and the river turned to sand.
The crops were swallowed by the earth,
and the animals laid down
and turned to dust.
Then one night
there was a fire in the fields.
The men went out to fight the fire.
When they came back,
the women were crying in the darkness.
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Children.
He says they stole their children.
(CLINKING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(PANTING)
Sankara! Sankara...
WOMAN: (SHOUTING) Ranjit!
Ranjit!
(CRYING)
Sankara.
(PANTING)
Little boy escaped from the evil palace.
Many other children still there.
What we do, Dr. Jones?
What you think?
I think that somebody believes
the good luck rock from this village
is one of the lost Sankara Stones.
What is Sankara?
Fortune and glory, kid.
Fortune and glory.
(GRUNTING)
Willie, quit monkeying around
on that thing.
(SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(TRUMPETING)
Oh, wait a second! Indy!
I can't go to Delhi like this!
We're not going to Delhi, doll.
We're going to Pankot Palace.
Pankot?
I can't go to Pankot! I'm a singer.
Oh, I need to call my agent.
Is there a phone?
Anybody, I need a phone!
(PRAYING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SNIFFS)
(GROANS IN DISGUST)
(TRUMPETING)
Oh, quit complaining.
This is expensive stuff.
You come to America with me,
and we get job in circus.
You like that? You like America?
You're my best friend.
- You're my best friend.
- (SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
WILLIE: What big birds!
Those aren't big birds, sweetheart.
They're giant vampire bats.
Bats?
(TRUMPETS)
Pipe down, you big baboon.
This doesn't hurt.
You know what you really need?
You really need a bath.
(SOBBING)
(LAUGHING) Ha-ha, very funny.
Very funny.
All wet.
WILLIE: I was happy in Shanghai.
I had a little house and a garden.
(MOSQUITO BUZZES)
My friends were rich.
We went to parties
all the time in limousines.
I hate being outside!
(CRYING)
I'm a singer! I could lose my voice!
I think we'll camp here tonight.
Cut it out.
- What do you got?
- Two sixes.
Aha-ha, three aces. I win.
(LAUGHING) Two more game,
I have all your money.
It's poker, Shorty, anything can happen.
Where did you find
your little bodyguard?
I didn't find him, I caught him.
What?
Shorty's family were killed
when the Japanese bombed Shanghai.
He's been living on the streets
since he was four.
I caught him trying to pick my pocket,
didn't I, short stuff?
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
Biggest trouble with her is the noise.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Hey! You cheat, Dr. Jones. You cheat!
- What do you mean?
- You take four card.
(GIBBERING)
(SCREAMING)
- You pay now.
- Oh, they were stuck together.
- No stuck. No mistake.
- They were stuck together.
It's a mistake.
I'm very little. You cheat very big.
(HISSING)
Dr. Jones, you cheat!
You pay money. You owe me ten cent.
Look at this. Look at this.
(HOOTING)
(SCREAMING)
You accuse me of cheating.
You're cheating.
(BOTH SPEAKING CHINESE)
(CROAKING)
You make me poor. No fun.
Play with you no fun.
- I quit.
- I quit, too.
This place is completely surrounded.
The entire place is crawling
with living things.
That's why they call it
the jungle, sweetheart.
- (ROARING)
- Oh, my God, what else is out there?
Willie, wait...
(SCREAMS)
Willie, Willie...
What is that?
Is that short for something?
"Willie" is my professional name,
Indiana.
Hey, lady, you call him Dr. Jones.
My professional name.
Why are you dragging us off
to this deserted palace?
Fortune and glory?
Fortune and glory.
Well...
this is a piece of an old manuscript.
This pictograph represents Sankara,
a priest.
Scram.
Gentle. Gentle.
This is hundreds of years old.
Is that some kind of writing?
Yeah, it's Sanskrit.
Cut it out.
It's part of the legend of Sankara.
He climbs Mount Kalisa
where he meets Siva,
the Hindu god.
WILLIE: That's Siva?
And what's he handing the priest?
- Rocks.
- Stop.
He told him to go forth and combat evil.
And to help him,
he gave him five sacred stones
with magical properties.
Magic rocks?
My grandpa was a magician.
He spent his entire life
with a rabbit in his pocket
and pigeons up his sleeves.
He made a lot of children happy
and died a very poor man.
Magic rocks. Fortune and glory.
Sweet dreams, Dr. Jones.
Where are you going?
I'd sleep closer, if I were you.
For safety's sake.
Dr. Jones, I'd be safer
sleeping with a snake.
(HISSING)
I said, cut it out!
I hate that elephant.
Indy, look!
INDY: I see it, Shorty.
That's it. Pankot Palace.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Dr. Jones, what you look at?
Don't come up here.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
WILLIE: No! No, no, no, no!
Don't leave! No!
No, no, no, no, no!
Oh, baby elephant, stay here!
Oh, no! Indy!
They're stealing our rides!
We walk from here.
(CAWING AND SCREECHING)
Hello.
I should say you look rather lost.
But then I cannot imagine
where in the world
the three of you would look at home.
We're not lost.
We're on our way to Delhi.
This is Miss Scott.
This is Mr. Round.
Short Round.
My name is Indiana Jones.
Dr. Jones, the eminent archeologist?
Hard to believe, isn't it?
I remember first hearing your name
when I was up at Oxford.
I'm Chattar Lal,
Prime Minister to His Highness,
the Maharajah of Pankot.
I'm enchanted.
Enchanted. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Welcome to Pankot Palace!
Enchanted, huh?
(INDIAN MUSIC PLAYING)
INDY: Shorty, where's my razor?
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
We are fortunate tonight
to have so many unexpected visitors.
- This is Captain...
- ...Blumburtt.
11th Poona Rifles.
And you, sir, are Dr. Jones, I presume.
I am, Captain.
Captain Blumburtt and his troops
are on a routine inspection tour.
The British find it amusing
to inspect us at their convenience.
I do hope, sir, that it's not
inconvenient to you, sir.
The British worry so about their empire.
Makes us all feel like
well-cared-for children.
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTING IN CHINESE)
You look beautiful.
I think the Maharajah
is swimming in loot.
Maybe it wasn't such a bad idea
coming here after all.
You look like a princess.
Mr. Lal, what do they call
the Maharajah's wife?
His Highness has not yet taken a wife.
How interesting.
Well, maybe it's because
he hasn't found the right woman.
His Supreme Highness,
guardian of Pankot tradition,
the Maharajah of Pankot,
Zalim Singh.
That's the Maharajah?
A kid?
Maybe he like older women.
Captain Blumburtt was just telling me
something of the interesting
history of the palace,
the importance it played in the mutiny.
It seems the British never forget
the Mutiny of 1857.
(LAUGHS)
Yes, well, you know, I think
there are other events,
before the mutiny, going back a century,
back to the time of Clive,
that are more interesting.
CHATTAR: And what events are those,
Dr. Jones?
INDY: Well, if memory serves me
correctly, this area, this province,
was the center of activity
for the Thuggee.
(EXCLAIMS)
Snake... Surprise.
What's the surprise?
(SQUISHING)
Dr. Jones, you know perfectly well
the Thuggee cult has been dead
for nearly a century.
Yes, of course.
The Thuggee was an obscenity
that worshipped Kali
with human sacrifices.
The British Army
nicely did away with them.
(RATTLING)
INDY: Well, I suppose stories
of the Thuggee die hard.
CHATTAR:
There are no stories anymore.
INDY: I'm not so sure.
We came from a small village.
The peasants there told us
Pankot Palace was growing
powerful again
because of some ancient evil.
Village stories, Dr. Jones.
They're just fear and folklore.
You're beginning to worry
Captain Blumburtt.
I'm not worried, Mr. Prime Minister,
just interested.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
What? You are not eating?
I had bugs for lunch.
Give me your hat.
Why?
'Cause I'm gonna puke in it.
(BURPS)
You know, the villagers also told us
Pankot Palace had taken something.
Dr. Jones, in our country,
it's not usual for a guest
to insult his host.
I'm sorry.
I thought we were talking about folklore.
Excuse me, sir,
do you have anything simple, like soup?
What exactly was it
they say was stolen?
A sacred rock.
(CHATTAR SCOFFS)
You see, Captain, a rock!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(INHALING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
Something connected the villagers' rock
and the old legend
of the Sankara Stones.
CHATTAR: Dr. Jones, we are
all vulnerable to vicious rumors.
I seem to remember that in Honduras
you were accused of being
a grave robber
rather than an archeologist.
Well, the newspapers greatly
exaggerated the incident.
And wasn't it the Sultan of Madagascar
who threatened to cut your head off
if you ever returned to his country?
No, it wasn't my head.
Then your hands, perhaps.
No, it wasn't my hands,
it was my...
My misunderstanding.
Exactly what we have here, Dr. Jones.
MAHARAJAH: I have heard
the evil stories of the Thuggee cult.
(MUSIC STOPS)
I thought the stories were told
to frighten children.
Later, I learnt
the Thuggee cult was once real
and did of unspeakable things.
I am ashamed of what happened here
so many years ago,
and I assure you
this will never happen again
in my kingdom.
If I offended you,
then I am sorry.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Dessert!
Chilled monkey brains.
(MOANING)
(THUDDING)
(YAWNS)
I think I'll just check on Willie.
That's all you better do.
Tell me later what happened.
Am-scray.
I've got something for you.
There's nothing you have
that I could possibly want.
Right.
(MOANING)
You're a very nice man.
Maybe you could be my palace slave.
Wear your jewels to bed, Princess?
Yeah.
And nothing else.
That shock you?
Nothing shocks me.
I'm a scientist.
So, as a scientist,
you do a lot of research?
Always.
And what sort of research
would you do on me?
Nocturnal activities.
You mean like what sort of cream
I put on my face at night,
what position I like to sleep in?
Mating customs.
Love rituals?
Primitive sexual practices.
So you're an authority in that area?
Years of fieldwork.
I don't blame you for being sore at me.
I can be hard to handle.
I've had worse.
But you'll never have better.
I don't know.
As a scientist,
I don't want to prejudice my experiment.
I'll let you know in the morning.
Why, you conceited ape.
I'm not that easy.
I'm not that easy, either.
Trouble with you is, Willie,
you're too used to getting your own way.
And you're just too proud to admit
that you're crazy about me, Dr. Jones.
If you want me, Willie,
you know where you can find me.
Five minutes.
You'll be back over here in five minutes.
I'll be asleep in five minutes.
Five.
You know it, and I know it.
Five minutes.
Four and a half.
(SNIFFING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES) "Palace slave."
"Nocturnal activities."
I'm a "conceited ape"? (SCOFFS)
"I'll tell you in the morning."
I can't believe it.
He's not coming.
She's not coming.
I can't believe I'm not going.
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Indiana Jones!
This is one night you'll never forget!
This is the night
I slipped right through your fingers!
Sleep tight,
and pleasant dreams!
(CHOKING)
I could have been
your greatest adventure.
(CRASHING)
(GASPS)
Dr. Jones, your whip!
(GROANS)
Shorty,
turn off the switch.
Oh, Indy.
Be gentle with me.
But I'm here.
There's nobody here.
No, I'm here.
Indy, you're acting awfully strange.
Hey, I'm right here.
(SCREAMS)
"Follow in the footsteps of Siva."
WILLIE: What does that mean?
"Do not betray these truths."
Shorty, go get our stuff.
(WILLIE MOANS)
INDY: Stay behind me, Short Round.
Step where I step,
and don't touch anything.
(SHORTY SCREAMS)
(PANTING HEAVILY)
I step where you step.
I touch nothing.
Indy!
(CRUNCHING)
SHORTY: I step on something.
INDY: Yeah,
there's something on the ground.
SHORTY: Feel like
step on fortune cookies.
INDY: It's not fortune cookies.
Let me take a look.
(RATTLING)
(SCREECHING)
(PANTING) That's no cookies.
INDY: It's all right. I got him.
Go. There, go.
(RUMBLING)
Stop.
Look, just stand up against the wall,
will you?
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
You say to stand against the wall!
I listen to what you say!
- Not my fault! Not my fault!
- Willie, get down here!
We're in trouble!
Willie! Willie!
Bet I get all dirty again.
- Willie, get down here!
- Not my fault!
We're in trouble!
Trouble? Trouble? What sort of...
(SCREAMING)
This is serious!
There are two dead people down here!
There're going to be
two dead people in here! Hurry!
I've almost had enough of you two.
Willie!
What's the rush?
It's a long story, Willie.
Hurry, or you don't get to hear it.
God, what is this?
Indy, what is this?
I can't see a thing!
Hurry!
All right!
Oh, I broke a nail.
(RATTLING)
(SCREAMING)
Willie, hurry!
WILLIE: They're in my hair!
INDY: Shut up, Willie!
- Indy, let me in!
- SHORTY: No, let us out!
- Let me in!
- Let us out!
- INDY: Shut up!
- I'm down here!
They're all over me!
There's got to be
a fulcrum release lever somewhere.
What?
A handle that opens the door.
- Go on!
- They're just, just square holes!
INDY: Go to the right hole.
SHORTY: Hurry, Willie!
(GROANING IN DISGUST)
(SCREAMING)
INDY: The other one! The other right.
Your other right!
- The one on your right!
- There's slime inside!
I can't do it.
You can do it. Feel inside.
Okay.
(RATTLING)
You feel inside!
Do it now!
Okay!
(RUMBLING)
Willie, we are going to die!
WILLIE: It's soft.
It's moving!
(RATTLING)
Got it!
Get 'em off of me! Get 'em off of me!
They're all over me! Get 'em off me!
No!
It wasn't me! It's her!
Huh?
Come on!
Go! Move! Come on, move! Come on!
(CHANTING)
(DRUM BEATING)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
It's a Thuggee ceremony.
They're worshipping Kali.
Have you ever seen anything
like this before?
Nobody's seen this for a hundred years.
(CHANTING)
(MAN SPEAKING HINDI)
(MAN CHANTING)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Kali Ma. Kali Ma...
Kali Ma!
(HEART BEATING)
(SCREAMING)
- (SCREAMING)
- (GASPS)
(MOLA SPEAKING IN HINDI)
(ALL CHEERING)
He's still alive.
(CHANTING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Kali Ma.
(CHEERING)
That's the rock
they took from the village.
It's one of the Sankara Stones.
Why they glow like that?
(SHUSHING)
The legend says
when the rocks are brought together,
the diamonds inside them will glow.
Diamonds?
Diamonds.
- Diamonds!
- Shh!
Diamonds.
Hey, hey.
Look, I want you two
to stay up here and keep quiet.
Shorty, you keep an eye on her.
- Why, where are you going?
- Down there.
Down there? Are you crazy?
I'm not leaving here without the stones.
You could get killed chasing after
your damn fortune and glory!
Maybe.
But not today.
(MOUTHING) Be careful.
(SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
Where's he going?
(SCREAMING)
Let me go!
Run, Willie! Run!
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(GROWLING)
Dr. Jones!
I keep telling you,
you listen me more, you live longer.
BOY: Please, let me die.
I pray to Siva,
"Let me die," but I do not.
Now... Now the evil of Kali take me.
How?
They will make me drink
the blood of the Kali.
Then I'll fall into
the Black Sleep of the Kali Ma.
What is that?
We become like them.
We'll be alive, but like a nightmare.
You drink blood,
you not wake up from nightmare.
You were caught trying to steal
the Sankara Stones.
There were five stones in the beginning.
Over the centuries,
they were dispersed by wars,
sold off by thieves like you.
Thieves like me, huh?
(SCOFFS)
Still missing two.
A century ago,
when the British raided this temple
and butchered my people,
a loyal priest hid the last two stones
down here in the catacombs.
So that's what you've got
these slaves digging for, huh?
They're innocent children.
They dig for the gems
to support our cause.
They also search
for the last two stones.
Soon we will have
all the five Sankara Stones,
and the Thuggees will be all powerful.
What a vivid imagination.
(MOLA LAUGHING)
You don't believe me?
You will, Dr. Jones.
You will become a true believer.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GATE CREAKING)
Hi.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
SHORTY: Dr. Jones!
Don't drink, it's bad!
Don't drink!
Spit it out!
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(GROANING)
Dr. Jones... (SPEAKING CHINESE)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(SHOUTING IN CHINESE)
You dare not do that.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(SCREAMS)
Leave him alone, you bastards!
The British in India will be slaughtered.
Then we will overrun the Muslims.
Then the Hebrew God will fall.
And then the Christian God
will be cast down and forgotten.
(CHOKING)
Soon, Kali Ma will rule the world.
(COUGHING)
Dr. Jones...
(GASPING)
(GROANING LOUDLY)
(ECHOING)
(LAUGHING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(SPEAKS HINDI)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Kali Ma protects us.
We are her children.
We pledge our devotion to her
with an offering of flesh...
WILLIE: What are you doing?
...and blood.
Your friend has seen,
and she has heard.
Now she will not talk.
I'm not going to have
anything nice to say
about this place when I get back.
Indy! For God sakes, help me!
What's the matter with you?
(WILLIE SOBBING)
(MEN CHANTING)
No, no.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
MOLA: Come.
Come.
Indiana...
Indiana, help us.
Please, snap out of it.
(SOBBING) You're not one of them.
You're not one of them.
Please come back to us.
Don't leave me.
(CHANTING IN HINDI)
(SCREAMING) No!
What are you doing?
Are you mad?
(CHANTING IN HINDI)
(SPITS)
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING IN HINDI)
This can't be happening,
this can't be happening.
Wake up, Willie, wake up.
(SCREAMING)
No! No! No!
No, no, no!
Wake up, Dr. Jones, wake up!
Dr. Jones!
(COMMANDS IN HINDI)
(GROANING)
Indy, I love you.
Wake up, Indy! Wake up!
(SCREAMS)
You're my best friend! Wake up, Indy!
Wait! Wait!
He's mine!
I'm all right, kid.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Mola Ram!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(GRUNTING)
(CHATTAR LAUGHING)
(MOANING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
Give me some slack!
(WILLIE MOANS)
Willie, Willie, wake up!
Willie, Willie, it's me! I'm back!
Oh, Indy.
Indy, my friend.
I'm sorry, kid.
Indy, now, let's get out of here.
Right. All of us.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(CHILDREN CLAMORING)
WILLIE: No!
I've got to save him!
- He can take care of himself.
- He needs me.
(MOANS)
I've got to save Indy!
Okay, save him.
Drop him down!
I kill you! Drop him down!
(MOANING)
What's the matter with him?
Here. Try this.
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHS)
Go, Indy!
(SCREAMING)
(PLEADING IN HINDI)
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
(SCREAMS)
It was the Black Sleep of Kali.
Short Round!
Quit fooling around with that kid!
Get down in the cart, now!
Okeydokey, Indy!
Please listen.
To get out, you must take the left tunnel.
Thank you.
(SCREAMS)
Shorty! Quit stalling!
(COMMANDING IN HINDI)
SHORTY: Come on, Indy!
Go!
Go! Go!
Shorty, look out!
- Come on!
- Indy!
Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry up!
(ORDERING IN HINDI)
SHORTY: Indy, take the left tunnel!
The left tunnel!
No, Indy! You missed it! Left tunnel!
(GUNSHOTS)
We got company!
- Stop.
- Let her go!
- Let go of the brake.
- What?
- Let her go.
Our only chance is to outrun them.
- Shorty?
- Huh?
Come up here and take the brake.
Watch it on the curves,
or we'll fly right off the track.
SHORTY: Okay.
(SCREAMING)
(CHEERING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(ORDERING IN HINDI)
- What are you doing?
- Short cut.
- Yes, Indy.
- Short, cut.
INDY: Watch it.
SHORTY: Indy, help!
- WILLIE: Hang on!
- Indy!
WILLIE: Pull him in.
SHORTY: Let me go! Let me go!
Let go of him!
SHORTY: No! No!
WILLIE: Pull him in!
- I'll catch him!
- No!
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
Duck!
INDY: All right.
SHORTY: What?
INDY: Brakes. Brakes.
- Slow us down.
- SHORTY: Okay.
Big mistake. Big mistake, Indy.
WILLIE: Figures.
We're going too fast!
Too fast!
We're going to crash!
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Water, water, water!
- WILLIE: Look! Look there!
- Water!
- WILLIE: Fire! You're on fire!
- Water, water!
- Look...
- Water, water.
Water, water.
Come on. Come on!
Let's go!
Run, run!
(SCREAMING)
SHORTY: Willie, look out!
No!
Head for the bridge. Go!
SHORTY: Come on, Willie. This way.
WILLIE: Oh, God!
Come on, let's go. Strong bridge.
Look, strong wood.
Come on!
Look!
WILLIE: Shorty!
Help! I'm falling down.
Help!
Not very funny.
Back!
(EXCLAIMING)
(CLAMORING)
(SCREAMING)
Welcome.
(SPEAKS HINDI)
(MOANS)
Let her go, Mola Ram.
You are in a position
unsuitable to give orders.
Watch your back!
You want the stones, let 'em go.
Let her go!
(LAUGHING) Drop them, Dr. Jones.
They will be found.
You won't.
(SHOUTS)
Indy!
Behind you!
Oh, shit.
Go on.
Go.
MOLA: Go on! Go on!
Get moving.
Shorty...
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Hang on, lady. We going for a ride.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Is he nuts?
He no nuts.
He's crazy.
Mola Ram, prepare to meet Kali
in hell.
What are you doing?
(SCREAMING) You fool!
(MOLA SPEAKING HINDI)
Indy, cover your heart!
Cover your heart!
Oh, my God!
(MOLA CHANTING)
Oh, my God.
(BOTH SPEAKING HINDI)
(ORDERING IN HINDI)
- Look out!
- No!
(YELLING)
(GROANING)
No!
SHORTY: Come on. Let's go!
The stones are mine!
You've betrayed Siva.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
You betrayed Siva.
You betrayed Siva!
(SCREAMING)
WILLIE: Well, it's about time.
MAN: Hold your fire.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
(EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
We know you are coming back
when life return to our village.
Now you can see the magic
of the rock you bring back.
Yes, I understand its power now.
You could've kept it.
Ah! What for?
They'd just put it in a museum.
It'd be another rock collecting dust.
But then it would've given you
your fortune and glory.
Anything could happen.
It's a long way to Delhi.
No, thanks.
No more adventures with you,
Dr. Jones.
Sweetheart, after all the fun
we've had together?
If you think I'm going to Delhi with you,
or anyplace else
after all the trouble
you've gotten me into,
think again, buster!
I'm going home to Missouri
where they never feed you snakes,
before ripping your heart out
and lowering you into hot pits!
This is not my idea of a swell time!
Excuse me, sir. I need a guide to Delhi.
If you could...
(TRUMPETING)
(LAUGHING) Very funny.
Very funny.
Uh-oh!
(ALL CHEERING)