(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
(GROANS)
(CLACKING)
(BUZZING)
(CELL DOOR CREAKING OPEN)
(CLACKING CONTINUES)
(PRISONER SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Shh!
Hey! (SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BUZZING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Let's give you a few
friends to play with.
(BUZZING)
(CELL DOOR CREAKING OPEN)
(SHOUTING ON MONITOR)
(SOFTLY) Sorry.
(WATER SLOSHING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(TYPING)
(BEEPS)
(BUZZING)
Okay, I'm set.
How's things going down below?
How do you think?
I'm in a sewer.
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(ALARM WAILS)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(FRANTIC CHATTER IN RUSSIAN)
I'm in position.
Move to phase 2.
(AIN'T THAT A KICK IN THE HEAD?
PLAYING OVER PA)
(BUZZING)
(CELL DOOR CREAKING OPEN)
(SIGHS)
BENJI: What are you doing?
What are you doing?
What's wrong?
What's happening, Benji?
Oh, God. He's not going
to the extraction point.
Stay focused.
He knows where he's going.
(SONG CONTINUES PLAYING)
No, I'm not. I won't.
I will not open that door.
Please go to the extraction point, Ethan.
I know.
I know what this means,
but I can't. I'm not authorized...
Go to the extraction
point, Ethan.
Go to the
extraction point!
Oh, you're just
going to wait.
We're going to wait.
Great. I can wait.
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Okay, fine. Fine! Fine!
(BUZZING)
There.
We'll just screw the whole thing up on purpose.
(GUARD SHOUTS IN RUSSIAN)
Uh, Jane? We're going
to have a slight delay.
(BUZZING)
BENJI: Why do you
want to go in there?
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
I don't know what he's doing,
and for some reason, I'm helping him.
As long as he's where he
should be when the song ends.
(SONG CONTINUES PLAYING)
(WHISTLE BLASTS)
Uh, we have a passenger.
(GROANING)
(BUZZING)
Sergei!
Open all of them!
(BUZZING)
(URGING IN RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(SONG ENDS)
(BEEPING)
(PULSATING LOW-PITCHED TONE)
(RUMBLING)
(MACHINE POWERING DOWN)
(WIND WHISTLES)
(WHOOSHING)
Whoa!
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Agent Hunt?
And you are?
Agent Carter.
Okay.
JANE: Who's your pal?
I'll tell you
on the way!
Light the fuse.
(MISSION: IMPOSSIBLE
THEME PLAYING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
I don't mean to bring up
the elephant in the room,
but what's with the big,
hairy Russian?
Who, Bogdan? He fed me intel.
If I left him there, they would've killed him.
So we're gonna
give him his freedom.
Did you call in
the sweepers?
On their way.
Good, good.
Uh, Benji,
how is it you're here?
Oh, I passed
the field exam.
Crazy, right?
Yeah. Crazy.
DNA test.
It's me.
JANE: It's procedure.
I'm just confirming it's you.
ETHAN: You're very thorough.
Sergei?
Are you not Russian?
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Sweepers approaching!
Brooms are out!
ETHAN: Roger that.
Sergei.
Are you not Sergei?
(GROANING)
You'll be fine.
Bogdan.
I always take care
of my friends.
My friend.
Messy bringing him along.
I thought it went
rather well.
Mind telling me what you were
doing in a Russian prison?
Mind telling me
why you broke me out?
This wasn't
a rescue mission?
Uh, let me
put it this way.
If the Secretary
wanted me out of there,
it must be
pretty bad out here.
We were after a file.
We lost it.
"We"? Who lost it? You?
Agent Hanaway.
Where's Hanaway?
JANE: It was a letter drop.
Classified file.
It should have been
a simple intercept.
We knew which train
the courier was on.
Uh, ETA, two minutes
on the courier.
But there was
one thing we didn't know.
Bobcat, your train's
six minutes out.
Who the courier was.
(GROANS)
(BONES CRUNCH)
(STABBING)
It's now or never, Bobcat.
The courier delivering the file,
what's his name?
MAN OVER RADIO:
Go ahead. Shoot.
We are out of time.
I need a name, folks.
I can't track all these people at once.
(MAN GROANING ON RADIO)
MAN: Marek. Stefanski.
For the love of God!
(PANTS) You got it?
BENJI: Marek Stefanski.
Searching.
(BEEPING)
I'll take it from here.
Ow! Ow!
Hey, you all right,
buddy?
JANE: Hanaway dropped the mark and grabbed his bag.
Sit down.
Catch your breath.
JANE: He had the file in his hands.
Easy in, easy out.
File secured.
JANE: But we weren't
the only ones after it.
Bobcat, someone else
has crashed this party.
(SIGHS)
I'm not alone.
JANE ON RADIO: Local police?
HANAWAY: No. Armed hostiles.
(GROANS)
Hang tight, I'm coming!
Outrigger, back him up.
HANAWAY: Negative, Outrigger.
Rendezvous southwest corner,
60 seconds.
JANE: Hanaway's lens cam drew a
facial match and triggered a warning.
(CELL PHONE BEEPING)
(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
But it was too late.
No!
You're going to be okay.
You're so beautiful.
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry, I...
I should have told you.
(WHISPERING)
JANE: It was my op.
I put him in the field.
And she left him just alive enough for me to see him die.
I'm sorry.
You know her?
That's Sabine Moreau.
Contract killer.
Works for diamonds.
What was in the file?
Russian nuclear
launch codes.
IMF's been looking for an emerging extremist,
code name, Cobalt.
He's determined to detonate a
nuclear weapon however he can.
We know Moreau's
worked for him before.
What else does
IMF know about him?
As much as you do now.
But if Moreau has
nuclear launch codes,
you can bet Cobalt's gone
from a person of interest
to enemy number one.
We're here.
(ELECTRONIC TONE)
FEMALE VOICE:
Agent confirmed.
Why was he in prison?
He disappeared after he and his wife...
You know.
I thought he'd just been
transferred. Put on leave.
There were rumors, though.
Talk of an unsanctioned hit.
MALE VOICE:
Welcome back, Mr. Hunt.
In your absence,
IMF has learned that Cobalt is or was
a level-1 nuclear strategist
for Russian intelligence.
Therefore, the only way to uncover his actual identity
is to infiltrate
the Kremlin itself.
In order to get past
their checkpoints,
you'll be impersonating
General Anatoly Fedorov.
We believe Cobalt
will do everything he can
to destroy any record
of his identity.
Your mission, should you
choose to accept it,
is to penetrate the highly-secured
archive inside the Kremlin
and retrieve Cobalt's file
before he can destroy it.
New intel suggests Cobalt is already en route,
leaving you...
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
...4 hours 52 minutes...
MALE VOICE:
...to infiltrate.
To save time, we've chosen
your team for you.
Agents Carter and Dunn.
As always,
should you or any member
of your team
be caught or killed,
the Secretary will disavow any
knowledge of your actions.
This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
Good luck, Ethan.
(HISSING)
JANE:
What do you got?
We're going
into the Kremlin.
(CHUCKLES)
I thought you said
"The Kremlin."
Okay.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISPERING)
This is very exciting.
Being out in the field.
With you, you know.
It's a bit of
a dream for me.
Love your disguise, by the way.
You look just like him.
It's a shame we're not wearing masks.
You know, like, full masks.
Everybody gets to
wear a mask but Benji.
Sorry.
I'm tense. I babble
when I'm nervous.
I'm doing it again.
Shut up, Benji.
(LENS WHIRRING)
Okay, seven security guards.
X-ray machines. Cameras. Metal detectors.
Just what we expected.
We can do this.
(WHIRRING)
Releasing in
three, two, one.
(CLATTERING)
(PULSATING TONE)
BENJI: (SOFTLY) Game face,
game face. Kremlin game face.
Uh...
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BEEPING)
(PULSATING TONE)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(ALL SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BEEPS)
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
(EXHALES)
(WHISPERING) I think
that went quite well.
(BOTH SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BEEPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(GUARD SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(SOFTLY)
It's going to work.
I'm sorry, by the way.
About you and Julia.
You know,
not working out.
I wanted to say something
before you went away, but...
I liked her, you know.
(RECEIVER CLICKS)
He's off the phone now.
(CLICKING)
(DRIPPING SOUND ECHOES)
(DRIP)
It's empty.
The nest is empty.
(CRACKLING OVER RADIO)
(GROANS)
(HEAVY BREATHING OVER RADIO)
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTS)
(NECK SNAPPING)
Check in,
Team Leader.
ON RADIO: Over.
Repeat. Check in,
Team Leader.
Have you made it
to the Archive Room?
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(GASPS)
(WHISPERING) Someone is piggybacking our frequency.
(SHUSHING)
MAN ON RADIO: Team Leader,
awaiting your go-sign.
Standing by to detonate.
Abort.
Rendezvous nine-two.
(GUARD SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BEEPING)
(RAPID BEEPING)
(ANXIOUS CHATTER IN RUSSIAN)
(GUARD SHOUTS ORDERS
IN RUSSIAN)
(PANTING)
(ORDERING IN RUSSIAN)
(RUMBLING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(YELPS)
(INAUDIBLE)
(VOICES ECHO FAINTLY)
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
(VOICES GETTING LOUDER)
(MAN SPEAKING
IN RUSSIAN ON TV)
Our media is no more
truthful than yours,
American.
But we both know that the real cause of the explosion
was you.
MAN ON RECORDING:
Awaiting your go-sign, Team Leader.
Standing by to detonate.
The worst part for you,
"Team Leader,"
is I am the man assigned
to make you suffer for it.
For what you
did to my country.
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Not a good idea.
It seemed like one...
A minute ago.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(GROANS)
(DRIVER SHOUTS IN RUSSIAN)
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
(SIRENS WAILING)
WOMAN ON PHONE:
Consolidated Insurance.
How may I help you?
SAT 20. Agent 82-Delta-Echo
requesting immediate evac.
Rendezvous Alpha 113.
Confirmed. Alpha 113.
(CLANGING)
(MAN SPEAKING
IN RUSSIAN ON TV)
(EXPLOSION)
WOMAN ON TV:
Details surrounding
the intricate system
of gas lines
that run beneath the square
are still forthcoming,
but the majority of those lines
date back to the Soviet era
and have not been updated
in at least...
(MAN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(BOY SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
We should leave town
for a couple of days.
Alex, you, me.
Vacations.
Now?
Tonight.
(BOY SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Just...
Just the three of us.
WOMAN ON TV: ...may not have been an accident,
but a targeted attack.
Preliminary numbers
are just starting...
Where will we go?
...to come in regarding
those wounded in the blast.
We can confirm
that 11 tourists...
Leonid?
...their nationalities
still unconfirmed,
have been transported to area hospitals for treatment.
MAN ON TV: While Russian
officials continue to blame
a gas-main break,
experts are citing
the shape of the blast area
and the size of the debris field
as more consistent with that of a set explosive,
leading to speculation
that this may have been
an undeclared
act of aggression.
Although the Defense Ministry is
maintaining that this is strictly an accident...
Anna, pack a bag for Alex.
We're leaving now.
Anya!
(WEEPING)
We have work to do.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Mr. Secretary.
I wasn't aware
you were in Russia.
I'm not. Not since a bomb
blew up the Kremlin.
Yesterday I flew in to accept the Order of Friendship
from the Russian
Prime Minister.
Now I'm headed
back to Washington
to hand the President
my resignation.
My Chief Analyst,
William Brandt.
Do you have a pen?
Pardon me?
A pen.
Yeah.
Ethan, what happened
in the Kremlin?
Chief Analyst,
you say?
If you're implying that
I made a bad call...
European male.
Fifties. About six-foot,
180 pounds. Blue eyes.
Who is he?
A crude drawing,
but by your description,
that could be
Kurt Hendricks.
190 IQ. Served in
Swedish Special Forces.
Professor of physics,
Stockholm University.
Specialist in
nuclear endgame theory.
Asked to resign...
Well, because he's crazy.
Cobalt.
You have to alert the Kremlin
that one of their strategists
has a nuclear
launch device
and one of his operatives
has the codes to activate it.
And what makes
you say that?
I saw him
leaving the executive
armory, bag in hand.
He set off that explosion
to cover his tracks.
It could be weeks before the Russians know it's missing.
Unless we tell them.
IMF SECRETARY:
They won't listen to us.
As far as the Russians are concerned,
we just bombed the Kremlin.
The tension between the United States and Russia
hasn't been this high since the Cuban Missile Crisis.
And the blame,
right or wrong, points to IMF.
The President has initiated Ghost Protocol.
The entire IMF
has been disavowed.
So what happens now?
Now, I've been ordered to take you back to Washington,
where the DOD will label you as a rogue extremist
and hang the Kremlin bombing
on you and your team.
Unless,
you were to escape
somewhere between
here and the airport,
having assaulted
Mr. Brandt and me.
Sir?
You would then
illegally scrounge whatever material you could
from a backup supply cache
that I've overlooked.
The same cache where your team
are waiting for further orders.
Sir, you may
want to...
You will then disappear,
and this conversation never having taken place,
your intentions
would be unclear.
But if any one of your
team is caught or killed,
they will be
branded terrorists,
out to incite
global nuclear war.
Your mission,
should you
choose to accept it.
(SIGHS) Ethan,
you were my best man.
And I'm sorry
it's come to this,
after all the sacrifices
you made.
If we don't meet again,
I just want you to know,
I've always considered
you a friend.
(EXPLOSION)
(GUNFIRE) Stay down!
Drive, drive, drive!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
You okay?
(GRUNTS) Yeah.
Take a deep breath.
Stay with me.
Ready?
Yeah.
(GUNSHOTS)
(GASPING)
What do we do?
Wait here.
Where else am I going to go?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
(BOTH GASP)
(ORDERING IN RUSSIAN)
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER
IN RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
Why would that work?
Why would what work?
The flare on the body,
why would that work?
It did work.
Yeah, I know, but...
Hey!
But why? I mean,
how did you know that would draw their fire?
I didn't.
I played a hunch.
Okay. All right,
so what was your scenario?
Right, you... There's a guy
being shot at in the water.
All of a sudden,
decides to light up a flare and swim around?
I mean, what did you assume
they'd be thinking?
Thinking?
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES) I didn't assume they were thinking.
I assumed they were shooting at anything that moved.
I just gave them a target.
Look, these... (CHUCKLES)
These guys aren't
Rhodes Scholars, you know?
It's really happening,
isn't it?
Yeah.
(TRAIN HORN BLARES)
Okay, you know
what that sound is?
That's our ride
out of here!
All right, it's a green car.
Number 47.
I see green!
Okay, let's do it.
Go, go, go, go.
All right, 47.
I don't see it.
47.
Oh, shit!
Whoa! Ho!
This is it.
The manifest.
FEMALE VOICE: Enter your code.
Pole!
Ah! (PANTS)
(BEEPING)
(PANTS) Jeez...
FEMALE VOICE: Press enter.
(WHIRRING)
Retinal scanner!
Huh?
FEMALE VOICE:
Retinal scan required.
Watch out!
FEMALE VOICE:
Retinal scan required.
Agent confirmed.
(BOTH PANTING)
Ethan?
Jeez, I thought you were dead!
We are.
Who's this?
Agents Dunn and Carter.
William Brandt, Chief Analyst.
Analyst?
FEMALE VOICE: Agent confirmed.
(MAN SPEAKING IN SWEDISH
OVER HEADPHONES)
FEMALE VOICE:
(TRANSLATING) How will the world finally end?
It is my job to predict
the unthinkable.
To treat the death
of billions as a game.
After 20 years of this,
I was numb.
Until a new question
crossed my mind.
What happens after
the end of the world?
Are you sure your
line is secure?
FEMALE VOICE:
Every two or three million years...
Are you certain
your line is secure?
...some natural catastrophe
devastates all life on Earth.
But life goes on.
And what little remains
is made stronger.
Put simply,
world destruction is an unpleasant,
but necessary
part of evolution.
(WHOOSHING)
What happens then,
I wondered,
when mankind faces the
next end of the world?
I don't care what you have to do to get him to Dubai.
I'll make it worth his while.
Just do it.
FEMALE VOICE: I looked
to Hiroshima, Nagasaki...
I'll be waiting
for your call.
...thriving cities
rebuilt from the ashes,
monuments to
the unimaginable,
dedicated to
the concept of peace.
It occurred to me here that
nuclear war might have a place
in the natural order.
But only if it
could be controlled.
Only if it touched
every living soul equally.
IMF now believes
this man,
Kurt Hendricks, is the nuclear extremist,
code name Cobalt.
Today he was seen
leaving the Kremlin,
with what is likely
a nuclear launch device.
Two days ago,
Sabine Moreau killed one of our agents in Budapest
and relieved him of Russian nuclear launch codes.
Intel indicates she will check into
the Burj Hotel in Dubai in 36 hours.
Marius Wistrom is a known
operative of Cobalt.
Wistrom is currently
en route to Dubai.
For the launch device to work,
Cobalt needs the activation codes.
He's sending Wistrom
to buy them from Moreau.
The Secretary
is dead.
The President has invoked Ghost Protocol.
We're shut down.
No satellite, safe house, support,
or extraction.
The four of us and the contents of this car
are all that remain
of the IMF.
And as of this moment,
any action is unsanctioned. So if you want out,
speak now.
Our mission
is Hendricks.
We're all that stands
between him and his goal.
Nothing can be
left to chance.
Everyone connected
with this man
is considered an asset with valuable
information about our target.
No one can know
we're still on line.
We lose Hendricks now,
we lose him forever.
So, what's the play?
Wistrom will take delivery from Moreau in 36 hours.
Now we cannot let the launch codes leave the hotel,
but we need Wistrom
to lead us to Hendricks.
He'll only do that
if he has the codes.
JANE: Or if he thinks
he has them.
Our objective is to
intercept the sale,
replace the authentic
codes with counterfeits
and follow Wistrom
to Hendricks.
Well, that's simple enough.
We snatch the codes, we gin up some fakes.
Jane, you double Moreau,
and sell the codes to Wistrom and Bob's your uncle.
And how do you propose we just
snatch the codes from Moreau?
We take her out.
Yeah, we take her out.
But, you know, discreetly.
Discreetly?
Yeah.
Right, she's an asset. Right. I get it.
Sorry. Nothing left to chance.
He said... I'm spitballing.
It's not all gonna be gold.
We don't touch Wistrom.
BENJI: All right.
Or Moreau.
She'll answer for Hanaway,
but it has to be when I say.
After we hit Hendricks.
ETHAN: Only pack
what we need.
Yeah, absolutely.
Only pack what we... You never know.
(HORN HONKING)
BRANDT: So even if we can
double Wistrom and Moreau,
how do we keep them
in separate rooms
while having them think that
they're in the same room?
ETHAN: We give
the hotel a facelift.
Wistrom will think he's arriving at Moreau's suite,
but, really, he'll be
walking into our decoy room.
Where I'll double Moreau.
Downstairs, Benji
will double Wistrom.
Masks!
And meet with
the real Moreau.
And, uh... (CHUCKLES)
What am I doing?
You? You're the helper!
(CHUCKLES)
Helper. That's great.
Okay, so to the extent I understand
what you're talking about here...
The Burj Khalifa,
it's the tallest building in the world,
and you want to alter
its infrastructure
with the hopes of convincing
two people that they've
had a meeting,
which actually really never happened.
Right?
Uh...
(TIRES SCREECH)
Oh!
(JANE GROANS)
(LAUGHTER)
Camels.
ETHAN ON RADIO:
ETA on dry cleaning.
On my way up.
Okay, 34 minutes
to door knock.
Wow, um... (CLEARS THROAT)
Okay, this is a slight wrinkle,
but nothing to worry about.
We're just going to have to go into
the server room from the outside.
What?
Well, the firewalls on this
building's server are military grade.
I mean, this
would be a cinch
if I could call Youssef
back at headquarters,
but Youssef doesn't exist anymore,
and neither do we.
I could hack it, but it would take too long.
Then hardwire in.
And there's four layers of next-gen
security between us and the server room.
There's no way we can get to it from inside.
If we can't get to the server,
we don't control the elevators,
we don't control
the security cameras.
This operation is over
before it even begins.
I'm telling you, we can
get to it from outside.
"We"?
I'm...
I'm on the computer.
I'm just, uh...
The helper.
What floor is it on?
Oh, 130.
130?
Vent ducts.
Pressure sensitive.
Not enough time.
Elevator shaft.
Infrared sensors.
Not enough time.
How am I supposed
to do this?
(ELECTRICAL WHINE)
BENJI: God damn it!
Oh, that's high.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
Okay, now remember,
it's a rolling off motion that disengages the bond.
When the meter is blue,
that's full adhesion.
Easy way to remember,
blue is glue.
And when it's red?
Dead.
Here's your cutter, okay?
And your server interface.
Both going back here.
One, two.
Okay, Ethan,
the hotel server is eleven stories up
and seven units over.
Okay? Comm check.
Yeah. Copy.
So...
It's 26 minutes
to door knock.
Yeah.
(WIND WHISTLES)
(WIND HOWLS)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
(GASPS)
BRANDT ON RADIO:
25 minutes to door knock.
(GRUNTING)
What the hell is that?
(WIND HOWLS)
ETHAN ON RADIO:
Yeah, what the hell is that?
BENJI: It's a sandstorm.
It's a long way off, Ethan.
Shouldn't be a problem.
BRANDT ON RADIO:
24 minutes to door knock.
Where's Ethan?
You've got to be
kidding me.
(GLOVE CRACKLING)
(BEEPS)
(SQUEAKING)
(GROANS)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
(BEEPING)
(SQUEAKING)
BRANDT ON RADIO:
23 minutes to door knock.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(CRACKLES)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
ETHAN: I'm at server level.
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(GROANING)
22 minutes
to door knock.
(PANTING)
The countdown
is not helping.
I'm just saying.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(CRACKLING)
ETHAN: I'm in.
That's great, Ethan.
You're halfway home.
(WHIRRING)
ETHAN: Located server.
(BEEPING)
Please tell me we're online.
All right, we're live.
Okay, I now have control of the
elevators and the security cameras.
Time to redecorate.
Okay, you drive.
And look out for Wistrom and Moreau.
(WHIRRING)
BRANDT: Moreau is at the elevators ahead of schedule.
Go.
We can't open
this door, can we?
BRANDT:
The door? No.
Ethan, you gotta
get down here now.
Ethan!
Is there a problem?
Ethan?
We're not gonna make it.
We have to make it.
Where's Ethan?
(GRUNTS)
Your line's
not long enough!
No shit!
(GROANS)
(ALL GASP)
(PANTING)
(ALL PANTING)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Whoo! (LAUGHS)
That was not easy,
but I did it.
(PANTING)
What'd I miss?
(WIND HOWLING)
JANE: The lens might be
a little uncomfortable.
It captures images
and transmits them
to the printer
in the briefcase.
(GROANS)
All right?
Mmm.
I can't see out of
one eye, but I'm fine.
Blink twice to activate the shutter.
Notice the numbers
are in order?
A perfect copy.
But the numbers
are scrambled.
Masks?
60 seconds. You sure
I shouldn't wear a mask?
You know,
'cause I'm not exactly Omar Sharif.
I'll play it French.
This is your tracking device.
This is what you're tracking.
The paper clip?
No, it's the paper.
It's in the briefcase.
It's coated with isotopes which give off a unique...
It just means that you can track the
documents even if they switch briefcases.
Range?
Not that good.
It's, like, half a mile.
Safest thing to do would be not
let Wistrom out of your sight.
Is that Wistrom?
Who's that with him?
I don't know. We don't have an uplink,
so there's no facial recognition.
Who's that with him?
That's Leonid Lisenker.
Polish-born cryptographer.
He redesigned Russia's nuclear
security after the Cold War.
He's here to authenticate
the launch codes.
Yes, he is. We are blown.
No, we're not blown.
Well, we will be as soon as he
sees the counterfeit launch codes.
We're not blown.
BENJI: He's in the elevator.
ETHAN: Delay them.
(ELEVATOR STOPS)
Benji, how long would it take
you to reprogram the case?
A couple of seconds.
What for, though?
To make an exact copy
of the launch codes.
What?
You can't do that.
Wistrom's on 22!
Slow him down.
I'll do what I can.
(ELEVATOR STOPS)
Wait, wait.
Ethan, hang on now!
Hang on.
Just a second.
You're talking about handing over active
nuclear launch codes to Wistrom?
Yes. Reprogram the case.
Listen... Stop!
Just listen to
what you're saying.
You're fixating.
You're not thinking clearly.
It's not gonna happen.
I won't let it!
33 and climbing!
Brandt, use your head now.
The mission is not the codes, the mission is Hendricks.
Then just let it play out.
Give him bad codes. Neutralize him.
You know
that won't do it.
Failure to a terrorist is just a rehearsal for success.
41!
We lose Hendricks today,
he shows up somewhere else tomorrow.
He finds another way.
With no IMF to stop him.
No. It's now or never.
Now, Brandt, give me the case.
Nothing can be left to chance.
You said that.
You're the analyst.
Now, tell me there's not another way
for Hendricks
to get those codes.
BENJI: 50!
You tell me that this is his only avenue,
right here, right now, today.
You tell me that,
I'll walk away.
(HISSING)
(BEEPING)
(MOTOR STOPS)
(SIGHS)
We go without.
Without masks?
Jane needs to go.
Ethan!
We have no choice.
Ethan, you'd be walking in
on Moreau unarmed.
Face-first. Literally.
How do we know
they've met?
How do we know they haven't?
Doesn't matter!
Damn it.
We have no choice.
(SPRAY HISSES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Goggles.
What if they
have met?
JANE: (IN FRENCH ACCENT)
Come in.
(IN FRENCH ACCENT) Which one of you is Wistrom?
Which one of you
is Wistrom?
I am.
I admire your work.
Sit.
Where are my codes?
Where are my diamonds?
Close by.
You have my payment?
When I see the codes.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Not to worry.
Come in!
I thought
we could have tea.
Mademoiselle. Messieurs.
No diamonds,
no codes.
No codes, no diamonds.
(SIGHS)
Kill this one.
ETHAN:
We didn't come alone.
That hallway out there
is a kill-box.
You know who
we work for.
We come back with the codes,
or we don't come back.
How good is
your backup?
The best.
Hmm. (CHUCKLES)
MOREAU ON RADIO:
I've killed the best.
(IN FRENCH ACCENT) Do you care for some sugar?
ETHAN ON RADIO: Enough.
Let's get this done.
You want payment,
I want guarantees.
When he's authenticated the codes,
I'll make the call
and you get your diamonds.
That or...
We all go home
in buckets.
Nobody leaves
this hotel alive.
Get the papers.
JANE:
Is there a problem?
It's locked.
JANE: Ah, forgive me.
There must be a key.
One moment, huh?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Messieurs.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(EXCLAIMS) My mistake.
It is a combination, not a key.
You tell me the numbers.
They're good.
Zero.
(VIBRATES)
Come on, come on, come on.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(RATTLING)
It was a pleasure
doing business with...
Wistrom has the launch codes.
He's on the move.
Hey, I did as you asked.
I did. Now let my family go!
Release Leonid's family.
(SIGHS) Thank God.
You can thank
him in person.
(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
(DIAMONDS RATTLE)
MOREAU: It was a pleasure
doing business with you.
(ORDERING IN FRENCH)
Moreau's on the move!
I've got her.
Jane?
She's an asset!
I need her
alive!
ETHAN: Acknowledge!
Acknowledge!
(GUNSHOT)
Uh, Ethan, Wistrom is in the elevator.
I can't see Leonid, though.
(GROANS)
Benji, slow him down.
Get me an elevator.
(ELEVATOR STOPS)
(BONES CRUNCH)
(GROANING)
Find Leonid.
Benji, I've got a lock on Wistrom.
But I can't tell.
Is he still
in the elevator?
(LINE DISTORTING)
Benji?
(ELEVATOR STOPS)
(ELEVATOR CHIMES)
Ethan. Over?
Benji.
(LINE DISTORTING)
Benji, I lost...
Ethan, can you hear me?
Ethan, can you hear me? Over.
(DOOR BANGS OPEN)
Jesus!
Sit down!
Watch her.
Why me?
Because if I do,
I'll kill her.
(GUN CLICKS)
Hold it, Team Leader.
Did you really think I wouldn't catch up with you?
You and I are not enemies.
It was a set-up...
We'll find out
your lies soon enough.
Move it!
I'm sorry about this.
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Leonid. Benji?
Go for Benji.
I've got Leonid by the elevators.
He's been shot.
What?
(THUDDING)
(RIPPING)
Hey, hey. Stay with me.
Stay with me.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
(FIRING)
BRANDT: Jane! No!
(SCREAMS)
(WIND WHISTLES)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(LOW RUMBLING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(HORNS HONKING)
(SAND HISSING)
(WIND SURGES)
(MEN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(WOMEN EXCLAIM FEARFULLY)
(WOMEN COUGHING)
(DOG BARKING)
(WIND HOWLS)
(WHOOSHES)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(BEEPING)
(STEADY BEEPING)
(BEEPING ACCELERATES RAPIDLY)
(ETHAN GRUNTS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(EXCLAIMS)
(BEEPING)
(MAN SHOUTS IN ARABIC)
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
(MUFFLED) Come on. Come on.
(MEN YELL IN ARABIC)
(MEN SHOUT IN ARABIC)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
(ENGINE ROARS)
(BEEPING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(HORNS HONKING)
(GROANS)
(BEEPING ACCELERATES RAPIDLY)
(CRASHING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTS)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Now, what happened
with Moreau, Jane?
She couldn't help us
with Hendricks.
So let's throw her
off the building!
I didn't throw her.
Let's throw her
off the building!
She was not
the mission, Jane!
The mission was to track the file back to Hendricks,
who is in the wind
with nuclear launch codes!
JANE: Maybe you didn't notice
the gun she had pointed at me.
BRANDT: Yeah, like you didn't
notice the open window,
or that we're about
a mile up in the air!
JANE: It was an
instinctive move.
BRANDT: It doesn't matter!
We're talking
about a nuclear war.
The asset is more
important than you.
JANE: Where do you get off
telling me how well I executed?
We inherited you.
(PHONE VIBRATES)
You're just
a bureaucrat!
Better have good news for me.
Is he here?
JANE: You think I need you to
tell me what the mission is?
Yeah, I got it.
Dunhill lighter. I'll be there.
And no one will be
following me.
Just make sure
no one's following you.
And how the hell did the Russians find us?
What are you asking me for?
Because you're communications!
You're in charge of
covering our tracks.
BRANDT: You cannot afford to
make mistakes like that now, Benji.
You're not a technician anymore.
You're a field agent.
And you're just
an "analyst."
Right?
Who are you
really, Brandt?
What are you asking?
What am I asking?
Let me see if I can
put it another way.
How does an agent with skills
like that end up an analyst?
(MAGAZINE CLATTERS)
Well, we all
have our secrets.
Don't we, Ethan?
You tell me yours,
I'll tell you mine.
(PHONE VIBRATES)
I have friends in the region.
Just sit tight.
I'll send someone
to get you out of here.
JANE: What about Hendricks?
What's the plan?
The plan was for us
to stop him together.
BENJI: Well,
what are you going to do?
Change the plan.
JANE: Wait.
That's it?
What are you going to do,
go after him alone?
Would you care to explain yourself,
Agent Brandt?
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER
IN ARABIC)
I was on a protection
detail in Croatia.
Shadowing the assets,
husband and wife.
They were never supposed to know we were there.
Whole thing's routine,
it was a milk run.
Three days in
we caught wind that a Serbian
hit squad was after our couple.
But my team had
it under control.
We knew they
were coming.
But I couldn't shake this feeling that
I should warn the couple somehow.
I wanted to find a way to let them know.
But, you know,
orders are orders, so I didn't.
(SIGHS)
One day,
the husband decides to leave the hotel and go for a run,
so I follow him,
and I leave two men with the wife.
When I get back,
my guys are unconscious and the wife is gone.
Local police found her body three days later.
What was left
of her, anyway.
That was my last
day in the field.
I couldn't face another life-or-death situation after that.
So what happened
to the husband?
I never saw him again.
Until two days ago
in Moscow,
when the Secretary introduced me to Ethan Hunt.
No, that's not what happened.
She left him.
BRANDT: Yeah, I heard
that one, too, Benji.
But, unfortunately,
I was there.
Just like I was there when the
Secretary got the phone call
that Ethan was in custody for killing
six Serbian nationals in cold blood.
An unsanctioned hit.
Yeah.
Disavowed.
(SIGHS)
The next thing I know,
I'm on a plane to Dubai,
wondering the whole time,
do I tell him?
How do I tell him?
That I'm responsible.
I could have warned him.
I should have warned him.
But I didn't.
And she died.
Sergei! Sergei,
my friend!
I told you I would get him here.
Didn't I say?
How do I know it's him?
Yes, it's him. You trust me,
I trust you. Right?
This is the guy!
This is the guy,
the one I told you about.
So we can take
these things off.
(RATTLES HANDCUFFS)
Sorry. He's a great guy,
but he doesn't know you like I do.
MAN: So, you work for
the American government.
ETHAN: And you're
an arms dealer.
BOGDAN: No, no, no.
Sergei. Sergei.
He's "independent defense coordinator."
Right?
That you are.
Very classy job.
Listen. He's a friend.
Those diamonds
are for Bogdan.
No, no. It's okay.
You can have them.
Whatever arrangements you made with
my cousin is between you and him.
You want something
from me, you pay.
You misunderstand.
I'm not buying. I'm selling.
You're selling.
(CHUCKLES)
Selling what?
The future.
Yeah, I got all I need,
thank you.
ETHAN: Our countries
are on the brink of war.
War is very good
for business.
Nuclear war?
Go on.
I'm looking for a man
named Kurt Hendricks.
You may know him
as Cobalt.
In either case,
I think you know what he wants.
I'll bet he even tried to buy it from you at some point.
Go on.
He has a case,
he has codes.
But they're worthless
without a tactical satellite.
I want to know
where he'd get it.
A man with information like that
would be a potential terrorist.
And to your government,
a potential terrorist
is a terrorist.
If you help me,
my friends
become your friends.
Sorry.
I cannot help you.
I certainly cannot tell you
that Russia quietly sold
an obsolete tactical satellite to
a certain telecom in Mumbai.
And whoever gave
them that idea?
(CHUCKLES) An enterprising third party.
Working on commission.
Helping old friends.
Making new ones.
Can the satellite
be shut down?
That would take
special skills,
and you cannot
do it alone.
What's in the bags?
It's our gear.
How'd you get it?
Made a friend.
Well, I'm glad
we could help.
You could help now.
Look, Ethan,
before we...
ETHAN: Whatever happened,
happened.
We still have a chance to clean this up,
but we have to do it now.
And we have to
do it together.
Okay. So, where
are we going?
India.
India? India?
Sure.
Okay. Great.
Love the jet.
Wait till you
see the car.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(CHUCKLES)
JANE: Brij Nath.
ETHAN: Brij Nath.
Playboy. Multimedia tycoon.
On the surface,
his entire network is state-of-the-art.
But it's built on
illegally acquired
Cold War cast-offs, including this,
the Novosti satellite.
Hendricks needs it
to launch a nuclear strike,
and we have to shut it down
before he gets that chance.
And to do that,
we need to get the access code from him.
One way or another.
And if I don't,
none of this works.
You can do this.
Yeah.
A week ago,
I would have believed you.
I don't blame you
for what happened.
She took someone
you cared about.
That's not something
you just
let go.
Did it make you
feel better?
When you killed the men
who killed your wife?
We can't get them back.
Okay, to shut down
the satellite,
we have to manually tap into the central server.
You'll enter through
the exhaust vent,
wearing this under your suit.
(ELECTRICAL HUM)
Drop down into the computer array,
and I'll catch you,
then move you along
the relay room
and you jack
into the panel.
(HUM STOPS)
(SUIT CLATTERS)
Okay, so we enter the party
separately as guests.
Ethan quarterbacks
while Jane...
Gets the codes
from the billionaire.
I switch off the fan,
you jump into the computer array,
and I catch you,
you plug in the transmitter
then Ethan feeds me the codes which I
then use to pinpoint Hendricks' location.
Okay, but you just breezed over
something I think is really important.
The computer array part,
where I just...
Jump?
And I catch you.
Yeah.
I don't... Why is that
so hard to grasp?
Well...
Why? It's a 25-foot drop.
And we're using magnets.
Yeah.
In light of our recent efforts,
the technology's...
The science is sound.
All right?
I'd be more worried
about the heat.
And then there's that.
What heat?
Well, it's like any
computer, isn't it?
If you switch off the fan,
it's gonna get really hot!
(CHUCKLES) Of course.
Relatively, you know.
Of course it will.
So I'm jumping into a...
Uh, an oven,
essentially.
Yeah. Essentially.
But, um, I'll catch you.
Great.
Aapka swagat hai, sir.
Welcome, sir.
(LIVELY CHATTER)
Comm check.
Saturn's got your
five-by-five, Jupiter.
This is Pluto.
I have arrived
at the party.
(LAUGHTER)
There he is.
(TAKES DEEP BREATH)
Get us that code.
Venus moving
in on target.
Hook's in.
You do make
an impression.
(WHIRRING)
Why am I Pluto?
It's not even
a planet anymore.
Well, I think
Uranus is available.
(LAUGHS SARCASTICALLY) It's
funny 'cause you said "anus."
(GRUNTS)
I'm in position.
Sending in the Rover.
He's moving to you.
Give him your back.
Don't want to make it
too easy for him.
Are you gonna be talking the whole time?
In 20 minutes,
I want a glass of Cuvee Louis in every guest's hand.
And make sure all of them have a bottle
to take home by the end of the night.
Sure.
Impressed yet?
I'm more of
a bourbon girl.
I'm Brij Nath.
Welcome to my humble home.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
(SIGHS)
(LOUD WHIRRING)
BENJI ON RADIO:
And Rover's in position.
Spinning down the turbine.
(MOTOR WINDS DOWN)
(SIGHS)
ETHAN: He's e-mailing.
Venus. Be Venus.
Be Venus.
Husband?
Boyfriend?
More of a...
Co-worker.
Saturn, take the leap.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
(EXHALES) Jumping.
Jumping now. (GRUNTS)
Jump now?
Yes. Commit. Jump.
BRANDT: Jump.
Jump.
And I catch you.
Now.
So, you're sure about this suit, right, Benji?
Pretty sure.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Now you're pretty sure?
Jump.
(EXHALES)
Oh, God. All right.
Jump.
(GROANS)
Jump!
(SCREAMS)
(CRUNCHING)
Ow!
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
JANE ON RADIO:
Jupiter, he's gone.
Did you jump?
Should I not
have jumped?
'Cause I jumped!
Stand by.
I'm playing a hunch.
Don't hit me.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
My God, you are
a passionate creature.
I would like to show you
my collection of art.
I was waiting
for you to ask.
Then you have
to find me.
You're on.
ETHAN: I'm heading upstairs.
BENJI ON RADIO:
All right, now be careful,
because it's probably
getting a bit hot.
(EXHALES)
We have to get to that satellite before Hendricks does.
BRIJ ON PHONE:
Look left. Look up.
I find your capricious
passion intriguing.
Let me tell you one thing.
He's not your type.
Completely not your type.
He's completely cold. I'm hot.
Like all Indian men,
I'm very hot.
Eight o'clock.
BRIJ: Hot! Very hot.
He's at your
eight o'clock.
BRIJ: As you move towards me,
you're getting hotter.
Whoa. Ow! Ah!
Up, up! Up, up!
Ah! Too much,
too much, too much!
I see you.
I'd heard you have one of the finest
private collections in the world.
Well, at the very least,
it's private.
(EXHALES)
Saturn? How we doing
in the relay room?
In position.
I see the satellite.
Can I help you,
gentlemen?
I don't think so.
(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
(PANTS)
Need those codes, guys.
All originals from
Chhatarpur District.
You know,
the Tantrics believe
that the Swadhisthana chakra hides
our most subconscious of desires.
(GROANS)
Mmm.
Uplink to satellite.
Reboot to original military specs.
Download the virus.
(LOUD WHIRRING)
What the hell is that?
What the hell is what?
It's going haywire!
It's downloaded a virus
from the satellite.
Hendricks is killing
the server
before we can kill
the satellite.
Hendricks is reprogramming
He's gonna have launch
capability in five minutes!
Something wrong?
No.
Jane, you gotta move.
We need that code.
Finally we're alone.
(HUMMING)
Venus, now's the time.
Kick his ass
and get the code.
We are alone,
aren't we?
No one will
interrupt us.
Move and I break your neck.
The override sequence
for the relay station.
Say it now
or never speak again.
(GROANS)
The codes.
BRIJ ON RADIO:
46, 82...
93.
(WHIRRING STOPS)
Benji, what happened?
The system's crashed!
We're too late.
ETHAN: No, no, no.
He's revealed himself.
Benji, can you pinpoint
Hendricks' location?
Uh, Hendricks is signaling
out of a state-run
TV station
6.7 miles from here.
Send me the coordinates.
Good work, Brandt.
Now get the hell out of there.
Back me up!
Jane, tie it off with Nath and meet me at the rally point.
(GROANS)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Faster, Benji!
Just straight through!
(GROANS)
Wait! Stop!
BRANDT: Take me through!
BENJI: It's not responding!
A little bit of patience would be appreciated!
I can't reach the top!
More fan! More fan!
More fan!
There's nothing I can do!
It's maxed out!
(BEEPING)
(GROANS)
BENJI: Brandt?
Brandt?
Next time,
I get to seduce the rich guy.
Satellite weaponized
and online.
Upload the new
authentication codes.
Lock Russian Central Command
out of the system.
Isolate the sub.
We'll fire just one missile,
an apparent retaliation for the Kremlin.
That should start
the ball rolling.
BENJI: I'm here, Ethan.
How long until Hendricks
can launch a missile?
Less than 30 seconds!
We need another route.
Turn left up ahead,
take the alley on the right.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(ENGINE REVS)
We have uplink.
Ethan, Hendricks has started the launch sequence.
How much time until missiles are flying?
Three minutes!
(GASPS)
(MEN SHOUT)
We're three and
a half minutes out.
We can make it.
(RADIO CHATTER)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
JANE: Next left.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN)
(SIGHS)
Ethan? We're too late.
The missile's in the air.
(ENGINE REVVING)
There has to be a way
to abort the warhead.
If there is one,
it'll be on the launch device.
We're gonna
get that case.
(EXHALES)
May there be
peace on Earth.
(CAR APPROACHES)
Disable the relay.
Get Wistrom!
Inside, inside!
(GROANS)
(RUSTLING)
Wistrom destroyed
the relay.
Ethan went after Hendricks
and the case, but...
Doesn't matter
if he has the case.
We can't transmit
the abort codes.
Can you fix it?
Uh, yeah...
It's gonna be pointless if we don't have any power.
Wistrom!
(JANE GROANS)
Jane!
I'm okay.
No, you are not okay.
She's hit.
You stay here
and cover Benji.
Benji, get this thing rewired and back online.
I'll get the power on.
We can do this.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(HORNS HONKING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(CLANGING)
(GROANS)
Ow!
(PANTS)
(GROANS)
I'm taking that briefcase!
No! No!
(PANTING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(GROANS)
BENJI: He's been
gone too long.
Damn it! Listen.
When the power comes on,
these two drives go into this bay, okay?
(GROANS)
Mission accomplished!
(STRAINING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTS)
(MAN SHOUTS IN RUSSIAN)
This one is mine.
So, we are not enemies.
The phone call from that arms dealer in Dubai.
You wanted me
to find you.
How else to believe this?
Hospital?
WOMAN ON TV: And in other news,
eight weeks later,
the debate continues.
Eyewitnesses remain adamant that
the object was some sort of aircraft,
but officials with the Department of
Defense insist it was simply a meteor
large enough to be
visible during daylight.
You actually said that.
Out loud.
"Mission accomplished."
I said it.
You're still corny,
Ethan.
I can't imagine the look on that guy's face.
Hey.
This must be them.
Luther Stickell, the firm of Carter,
Dunn and Brandt.
I blew an entire weekend on the
bottom of the San Francisco Bay
no thanks
to you clowns.
No, man,
you know I got this.
I know.
I'll see you in Kandahar.
Thanks for meeting me.
So, I hear the insurance
company's refusing
to pay the claim on that car you crashed, Ethan.
Something about intentional 100-meter
vertical drops not being covered.
Go figure.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
How's the leg?
Still working.
You?
Healing.
I'm fine, by the way.
I mean, I'm not actually
sleeping, per se.
You know. Cold sweats.
Middle of the night.
All these people are just happy and smiling
and they are completely
oblivious to the fact
that they were
almost vaporized.
And if it hadn't
been for...
Dumb luck?
ETHAN: Was it?
I mean, look,
we were unprepared, in the dark.
Disavowed.
And the only thing
that functioned properly
on that mission
was this team.
I don't know how
we ended up together,
but I'm glad we did.
Your missions.
Choose to accept them.
Hey, look, I'm in.
Seriously. It's not
as if any mission
is gonna be rougher
than the last one, is it?
(GIGGLES) I mean,
that's just...
Bomb... Is it?
(ALL LAUGH)
Thanks, Ethan.
Thank you.
Agent Hunt.
Agent Carter.
Brandt.
I'm not picking up
that phone, Ethan,
because I don't think
you want me in the field.
I know your wife
is dead.
I was there in Croatia.
I was there
for one reason.
One.
And I failed.
It was my job
to protect her.
How do you know
she's dead?
There was a body.
Did you see it?
You killed
those Serbians.
I had to get her back.
You were sent
to Rankow Prison.
That was a sacrifice
I was willing to make.
IMF suspected Hendricks
had people in Rankow.
And six dead Serbians
was the ideal cover.
Waste not, want not.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
The Secretary
never told me.
I accepted the Rankow Prison
mission on one condition:
That no one could know
she was still alive.
But you're telling me.
(CHUCKLES)
When did you find out
that I was in Croatia?
I pulled your file
after India.
Right.
So you had to fake
your wife's death.
As long as we were together,
she could never be safe.
It wasn't your job
to protect her, Brandt.
It's mine.
Okay.
So we're good.
We're good.
(COINS CLATTERING)
MAN: Come on! (TSKS)
MAN ON HEADPHONES:
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
36 hours ago, there was a breach in
our military's communication network.
Now, an emerging terror
organization known as The Syndicate
has control of our entire drone fleet.
Their targets: Unknown.
Your mission,
should you choose to accept it...