AEREON: They are an army
unlike any other.
Crusading across the stars
toward a place
called UnderVerse,
their promised land.
A constellation
of dark new worlds.
Necromongers they're called.
And if they
cannot convert you,
they will kill you.
Leading them,
the Lord Marshal.
He alone has
made a pilgrimage
to the gates of
the UnderVerse
and returned
a different being.
Stronger. Stranger.
Half alive and half
something else.
If we are to survive,
a new balance must be found.
In normal times,
evil would be fought by good.
But in times like these,
well, it should be fought
by another kind of evil.
(PANTING)
Lining him up for you.
Portside shot coming up.
TOOMBS: Steady. Here we go.
Steady.
Take it! Take a shot!
Shit.
Toombs,
we're running out of rope!
Shut up! I got it! Again!
Now!
(RIDDICK GROANS)
HENCHMAN: Toombs!
(GROWLS)
Riddick.
GUNNER 1: I don't know,
Toombs. Looks kind of tight.
Not where I'm sitting.
This is the biggest
payday ever.
So throw on
a fresh pair of panties.
Let's get this right.
(RIDDICK GRUNTING)
HENCHMAN: Three meters
clearance portside.
One and a half
meters starboard.
We got
a chokepoint coming up.
(GUNNER 2 SCREAMING)
HENCHMAN: What the shit
was that?
Tags,
you got eyes
on Riddick?
Tags?
(PANTING)
Jesus.
He just ghosted two guys,
and I never even saw him.
What do you think?
Maybe we ought to just...
I think you're my new gunner.
Grab a Gat.
Stay on top of him this time.
(HENCHMAN SCREAMING)
RIDDICK: You made
three mistakes.
First, you took the job.
Second, you came light.
A four-man crew for me?
Fucking insulting.
But the worst
mistake you made...
That's right.
Empty gun rack.
(TOOMBS SCREAMS IN PAIN)
What's the bounty
on my head?
1 mil.
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
1.5.
What slam pays
1.5 for a convict?
Private party.
Guy! Easy! Anonymous.
That's what the sheet said.
What planet?
Helion Prime.
Whoa. Where you going?
Last question.
And you better get
this one right, merc.
Whose ship is this?
Mine?
Wrong answer.
(TOOMBS SCREAMING)
RIDDICK: Knew
they'd come for me.
Took them five years,
but I knew.
You don't expect these mercs
to have any honor, any code.
But this new bounty
from a holy man,
a guy whose neck I saved.
Well, lesson learned.
No such word as "friend."
Can only end bad
when you let
someone get too close.
Bad for them.
So now it's back
to civilization,
all the brightness,
and everything I hate.
Just wanted to be left alone.
WOMAN PILOT: (ON RADIO)
Helion Prime is on
alert condition four.
All unrecognized craft
will be escorted
to the ground
for security inspections.
PILOT: (ON RADIO)
Unrecognized craft,
you need to follow me
to Spaceport 6
for security inspections.
Do you hear me?
Follow me to Spaceport 6 now!
Follow this!
RIDDICK: Did you know
all your doors were locked?
Five years ago,
I took two people
off that planet.
A kid,
Jack, who everyone else
thought was a boy
and a holy man
searching for New Mecca.
I told one man
where I might go.
I showed trust to one man.
Did I make a mistake, Imam?
There is no simple answer...
Whatever was said
was meant to
give us a chance.
A fighting chance.
Were it not for
the threat of invasion
I never would
have betrayed you.
I give you my word, Riddick.
Riddick!
RIDDICK: And a daughter...
LAJJUN: No.
RIDDICK: ...whose name
would be...
If you have issue with me,
you let it be with me.
You need not
know their names.
Ziza. My name is Ziza.
Ziza.
Cute kid.
ZIZA: Did you
really kill monsters?
The ones that
were gonna hurt my father?
Such are our
bedtime stories.
Go, Ziza. Go on.
So now who do I have to kill
to get this
payday off my head?
IMAM: It is said the comet
always precedes them.
These world-enders.
The Coalsack
planets are gone.
Eight million
settlers missing.
The entire Aquilan System
is gone, too.
My God,
how do I save my family?
Have you heard
anything I've said?
You said it's all
circling the drain.
The whole universe.
Right?
That's right.
Had to end sometime.
The one you want
is now here.
And whose throat is this?
If you cut my throat,
I'll not be able to rescind
the offer that
brought you here.
Nor tell you
why it's so vital
that you did come.
The blade comes off
when the bounty comes off.
This is Aereon.
An envoy from
the Elemental race.
She means you no harm.
There are very few of us
who have met a Necromonger
and lived to speak of it.
So when I choose
to speak of it,
you should choose to listen.
Necromonger.
It is the name
that will convert
or kill
every last human life.
Unless Furyan
warriors are found.
They were the one race
that would not bow,
the only race
the Necromongers still fear.
Maybe you should pretend
like you're talking
to someone educated
in the penal system.
In fact, don't pretend.
IMAM: There is a story,
Riddick, of young male
Furyans
strangled at birth.
Strangled with
their own cords.
When Aereon told this story
to the Helion leaders,
I told her of you.
What do you know
of your early years?
Do you remember
your homeworld?
Where it was?
Have you met any others?
Others like yourself.
Sister, they don't know
what to do with
just one of me.
Spoken like a true Furyan.
I don't care where I'm from.
I want the bounty
off my head.
SOLDIER 1:
Open up in there!
Open up!
SOLDIER 2: Stand back!
LAJJUN: They are
searching houses.
They look for a man
who came here today.
They think he might be a spy.
A spy.
Did someone see
him come here today?
Did they?
Lajjun, stop!
I will send them away.
But wait one minute, please.
Will you wait one
minute to save worlds?
Not my fight.
So you will
leave us to our fate?
Just like you did her.
SOLDIER 1: Break it down!
SOLDIER 1: Get in!
Come, let us try
to send them away.
LAJJUN: Just let me have her!
SOLDIER 1: Come on.
CLERIC: Leave us alone.
LAJJUN: There is no one here.
CLERIC: You don't understand.
He can help us!
You're not afraid
of the dark, are you?
The light hurts my eyes.
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
(GUNS FIRING)
SOLDIER 1: Get him!
SOLDIER 2: Where is he?
SOLDIER 3: In here.
(KNIFE CLATTERING)
(RETREATING FOOTSTEPS)
You mentioned her.
She went looking for you.
People died.
She went to prison.
I'm not sure where.
It was a world so hot,
you couldn't set foot
on the surface.
Crematoria.
Young Jack.
She thought of you
as her older brother.
She worshipped you.
You were supposed
to watch her.
She never
forgave you for leaving
just when she
needed you most.
She needed to
stay away from me.
You all do.
ZIZA: Riddick!
Are you gonna stop
the new monsters now?
AEREON: Furyans.
Defiant to the end.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
No, no.
We go to the shelter.
We take only ourselves.
OFFICIAL: Turn back!
Go to the other shelter.
MAN: There is no room.
WOMAN: They won't let us in!
OFFICIAL: Get back.
IMAM: Stay close.
(ALL SCREAMING)
CONTROLLER: Flight leaders,
get all squads
off the ground now.
We have heavy inbound.
Follow me in!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
They're coming back!
IMAM: The next shelter.
This way!
(PILOT WHOOPING)
IMAM: I'll see if it's safe.
IMAM: Stay back.
LAJJUN: Come, Ziza.
Come!
(OFFICER SHOUTING)
(IMAM GASPS)
IMAM: Lajjun and Ziza!
When it's over.
Let me go.
I must get to my family.
When it's over.
(LAJJUN GASPING)
Let's get your family.
(GUN FIRING)
In here.
IMAM: Get in.
(IMAM SHUSHING)
(STATIC BUZZING)
(SOLDIER GROANS)
(STATIC CRACKLING)
LAJJUN: Imam.
Don't follow me.
(IMAM SCREAMS)
(LAJJUN PANTING)
(STATIC CRACKLING)
(LAJJUN WHIMPERING)
(LENSOR GROANING IN PAIN)
(IMAM EXCLAIMS IN FRIGHT)
(IRGUN GROWLING)
There will be
an afterlife for me.
Will there be for you?
(IMAM YELLS)
Let's go replenish the ranks.
Never fails
to inspire, does it?
Each time a dynasty falls.
Remember your place,
Dame Vaako.
My place is at your side,
dear husband.
From here till
UnderVerse come.
In this 'verse
humans have been fractured.
Divided by all their
many races, creeds,
and mistaken faiths.
Our purpose is to
correct that mistake.
Because there is
another 'verse.
Another universe
that He has found,
where anyone can begin anew.
Where you can
live free of pain.
A perfect new place,
called UnderVerse.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Look around you. Every
Necromonger in this hall,
every one of the Legion Vast
that just swept
aside your defenses
in one night
was once like you.
Fought as feebly as you.
Because every
Necromonger that lives
today is a convert.
WOMAN: There'll be
no conversions!
We all began as
something else!
It was hard for me to accept,
too, when I first heard
these words.
But I changed.
I let them take away my pain.
You betrayed your faith.
And I changed.
Just as you will change
when you realize that
the UnderVerse
will be reached
only by those
who have embraced
the Necromonger faith.
For those of you
who will right now
drop to your knees
and ask to be purified.
We will not
renounce our faith!
No one here will
do what you ask.
It is unthinkable!
This is a world
of many peoples,
many religions!
And we simply cannot
and will not be converted.
MARSHAL: Then I'll take
your soul.
(CROWD GASPING)
MARSHAL: Join him
or join me.
This is your one chance.
Take the Lord Marshal's offer
and bow.
I bow to no man.
He's not a man.
He's the holy Half-Dead
who has seen the UnderVerse
and returned with
powers you can't imagine.
Look,
I'm not with everyone here.
But I will take
a piece of him.
A piece you will have.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CROWD GASPING)
MARSHAL: Stop him!
Irgun. One of my best.
If you say so.
What do you think
of this blade?
I think it's
a half-gram heavy
on the back end.
In our faith,
you keep what you kill.
Take him back to my ship
for mind regression.
Perhaps the breeder
would do it
if somebody just asked him.
It is a rare offer.
A visit inside Necropolis.
It's been a long time
since I smelled beautiful.
Let me show you the way.
Beautiful eyes. Come.
The last six Lord Marshals
have called this home.
Magnificent, isn't it?
I might have
gone a different way.
True of us all.
Converts receiving the mark
of the Necromonger.
They learn how one pain
can lessen another.
There now.
That is just perfect.
The more you resist them
the greater
the damage will be.
QUASI-DEADS: A new one.
You've brought us a new one.
(BUZZING)
Interesting breeder.
Making entry.
This won't take long.
We've entered his neocortex.
QUASI-DEADS: The Riddick!
MARSHAL: Regress.
Scanning fresh memories.
Thoughts of
someone called Jack.
Riddick!
She went to prison.
Now we find
thoughts of an Elemental.
The one race that would slow
the spread of Necromongers.
Furyans.
Where does he come from?
Who are his people?
These are the things
I need to know.
We find energy.
We find
Furyan energy.
He's Furyan!
Furyan!
A Furyan survivor!
Kill the Furyan!
Kill the Riddick!
Kill Riddick.
Find him. Whatever it takes.
Find him.
Let me guess.
A five-man crew this time.
TOOMBS: Couple of things
you could have done better.
First, trash the locater
beacon inside my ship,
the one you jacked.
And second,
and this is really
the more important part,
should've wasted me
when you had the chance.
Any questions?
Yeah.
What took you so long?
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Decoy launched.
In and out,
unsuspected and undetected.
Damn,
I love a good smash and grab.
It's as good as ours.
Preparing to
engage ion drive.
So where do we drop
your merc-killing ass?
Who's gonna pay
the most for you now?
Butcher Bay?
Ten minutes every other day
on the dog-run.
Protein waffles aren't bad.
How about Ursa Luna?
Nice little double-max prison.
They keep a cell open for me,
just in case I drop in.
You know the problem
with these joints now?
Health clubs for
waffle-eating pussies.
Maybe we should think about
upping our game
here a little bit.
Think about
someplace truly diabolical.
What the hell is
he thinking now?
RIDDICK: He's thinking
a triple-max prison.
A no-daylight slam.
Only three of them
left in this system,
two of them out of range
for a shitty
little undercutter
like this one with no legs.
Leaving just one.
Crematoria.
That is what you had in mind,
right, Toombs?
How does he know
where we're going,
and we don't?
Dope it out.
I hate this run.
Just do it!
Don't know about
this new crew of yours.
They seem a bit skittish.
Probably
shouldn't tell them what
happened to the last crew.
You know,
you were supposed to be
some slick-shit killer.
Now look at you.
All back-of-the-bus and shit.
SCALES: I say
we attack Helion Two next.
Take it straight
into their teeth.
It'll cost you 20,000 heads,
5 Warrior Ships,
nothing more, I swear it.
While I do prize brute force
this approach is,
perhaps, more artful.
Start at the end.
Go straight to Helion Five,
the last planet
in the system.
We approach from
the night side.
Remove these cannon first,
then attack
the larger placements
at speed.
We'll catch them
on their rear flank.
And in 10 days' time
the rest of those worlds
will tumble before us.
You see, as with most,
their blind spot
is right behind them.
I've located an ion trail
which leads off-world.
Then you should be off-world,
Vaako.
I've deployed a tracker team.
One of the best.
Wherever Riddick has gone,
you lens him out
and cleanse him. You.
You want me to take a frigate
for one breeder?
Don't question it, Vaako!
Take it on faith.
He's always been unsettled
around you.
The Lord Marshal. Unsteady.
Perhaps because
he knows he's half
the warrior you are.
Some say he's too artistic
for the job.
I wouldn't be surprised
if someone promoted him soon
to full dead.
Take care what you say.
Should I say it softly?
So it sounds more
like conspiracy?
Why is it that
when anyone breathes
about the demise
of him on the throne
everyone
assumes a conspiracy?
Why isn't that
just prudent planning?
When he is ready,
he will name a successor.
Who?
Toal? Scales?
The Purifier?
None of them
with the strength,
the dignity
of Lord Vaako.
You can keep what you kill.
That is the Necromonger way.
RIDDICK: Mercenaries.
Elementals, Necromongers.
Shit,
I've never been so popular.
Should probably
slip these chains
and open up a few arteries.
But why drive when
you can get driven?
Free ticket to Crematoria.
Thanks, Toombs.
Got me some business
there named Jack.
And once we settle up,
I'll walk away for ever.
So I'll just wait,
all back-of-the-bus.
For now.
MARSHAL: How unexpected...
An Elemental. Here?
VAAKO: One of the captives.
And why, after 30 years,
should it be you?
He doesn't regard her
as a captive, though.
Elementals.
They talk of neutrality,
but they're all
witches and spies.
Why else would they come
and go like the wind?
But where has he gone?
Where is the Furyan
hiding now?
You be the good warrior.
Go after this Riddick.
I'll find out why
the Lord Marshal
is so threatened by him.
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Destination reached.
Unlocking manual controls.
All right, I make 700 degrees
on the day side.
300 below on the night side.
PILOT: Let's not
get caught in the sun.
If I owned this
place and hell,
I'd rent this place out
and live in hell.
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Slue angle: good.
Stand by.
And...
Plotted course,
good.
Hit it!
(LOUD WHOOSHING)
Angle of approach:
not good.
(LAUGHING)
Look, Ma, no hands!
Party poppers!
(ALL GROANING)
I think I shit myself.
Skittish, Toombs.
Very skittish.
Comfy?
(ENGINE HUMMING)
When the ride's over,
your goggles are mine.
(MERC 2 GROANS IN PAIN)
Four-way split!
(TOOMBS LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
29.4 kilometers.
So this is Riddick.
What in the bowels of Christ
are you talking about?
700,000?
Don't take this one, boss.
See, Anatoli here
has a nose for trouble.
And this one,
this Riddick guy...
Big, big trouble.
So 700,000 is good money.
I'd take the money, Toombs.
(PRISONERS CLANGING ON METAL)
BOSS: These are dangerous
days, if you believe the talk.
Talk?
BOSS: About dead planets.
About some ghost army.
About them.
Them?
I'll run the numbers again.
It takes a couple of days
probably.
So you can stay
as my guest.
At least here we
are all safe. Yes?
GUARD: Yes, boss.
I'll give it a day.
One.
(MAN GRUNTING)
GUV: There are inmates,
and there are convicts.
A convict has a certain code.
And he knows to show
a certain respect.
An inmate,
on the other hand,
pulls the pin on
his fellow man.
Does
the guards' work for them.
Brings shame
(MAN GROANS)
to the game.
So which are you gonna be?
Me?
I'm just passing through.
Welcome to Crematoria.
How do I get eyes like that?
You got to kill a few people.
Did that. Did a lot of that.
And then you got to
get sent to a slam.
One where they tell you
you'll never see
daylight again?
There wasn't a doctor
who could shine my eyes,
not even for 20
menthol Kools.
Was anything you said true?
What are you gonna do?
Go for the sweet spot?
Remember who
you're talking to, Jack.
Jack's dead.
She was weak.
She couldn't cut it.
The name's Kyra now.
And I'm a new animal.
(ANIMALS GROWLING)
I'm so glad I could steal you
away for a moment.
Doesn't it strike you odd?
Here we have
the current Lord Marshal,
destroying entire societies,
and yet he can't
bring himself to kill
one stranded Elemental.
Why is that?
You don't pray to our God.
You pray to no God, I hear.
Elementals, we calculate.
Don't we all.
But now let's have
first things first.
What of Riddick?
In truth, I don't know
where he went.
In truth,
I'm more interested in
where he came from.
Watch your step.
I've always wondered,
does an air Elemental fly?
Now do me a favor.
Calculate the odds of you
getting off this planet alive
and now cut them in half.
No, we can't fly.
But we glide very well.
Save your threats,
Necromonger.
I would have told
you about Riddick
for the asking.
It concerns a foretelling,
a prediction
now more than 30 years old.
A young warrior
once consulted
a seer, of sorts.
And was told
that he would die
at the hands of a Furyan.
So he waged a private war
on the planet Furya,
killing all he could find.
This was before
he became Lord Marshal,
of course.
That massacre should have
ended the matter.
But now it seems
one Furyan had a knack
for escape.
GUARD: Feeding time!
(BUZZER BUZZING)
Move, let's go. come on.
Here they come!
(GROWLS)
(BEASTS GROWLING)
CONVICT 1: To the cages!
A herd! A goddamn herd,
is that all we are to you?
CONVICT 2: Let me in!
(MAN SCREAMING)
(THRASH GROWLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(THRASH PURRS MILDLY)
(ALARM BUZZING)
(SNARLS)
It's an animal thing.
GUARD 1: Check her for me.
She's always got
a blade somewhere.
(KYRA GRUNTS)
(GUARD GROANING IN PAIN)
(GUARDS GROANING)
RIDDICK: I don't think
she likes being touched.
I'd take my wounded and go
while you still can.
Is there a name for
this private
little world of yours?
What happens there
when we don't just run away?
You'll kill us
with a soup cup?
Tea, actually.
What's that?
I'll kill you
with my tea cup.
GUARD 1: You know the rule.
They aren't dead
if they're still
on the books.
Come on.
Death by tea cup.
Damn.
Why didn't I think of that?
I didn't come here
to play "Who's
The Better Killer?"
But it's my favorite game.
Haven't you heard?
I heard you came
looking for me.
Is that all?
Then you missed
the good part.
Hooked up with some mercs
out of Lupus Five.
Said they'd take me on,
teach me the trade,
give me a good cut.
They slaved me out, Riddick.
Do you know
what that could do
to you when you're that age?
When you're 12 years old?
I told you to
stay in New Mecca.
Did you not listen?
I had mercs on my neck.
I'll always have
mercs on my neck.
I spent five years on
a frozen heap just to
keep them away from you.
And you go and sign up
with the same fake badges
that wanted to cut you up
and use you for bait.
What are you pitching,
Riddick?
That you cutting out
was a good thing?
That you had my ass covered
from halfway
across the universe?
You signed with mercs.
There was nobody else around.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Let's pop the cork.
Get some fresh air.
(MACHINERY HUMMING)
So they do go topside
to swap out air.
Interesting.
Who the hell are you?
When it happens,
it'll happen fast.
Stay on my leg
when I cut fence,
or die here.
Nobody outs this place.
Nobody.
KYRA: He ain't nobody.
Seven hundred degrees.
Jesus! That's some sunrise.
They can be quite a test.
These deep runs.
Test of our inner selves.
Don't you find that true?
Some men do.
Just being so far
from the armada,
the mind can start to fill
with strange thoughts.
Doubts.
Don't you ever
have doubts, Vaako?
Doubts?
About the campaign.
About Lord Marshal.
First and always,
I am a Necromonger commander.
So if you're here
to test my loyalty,
you succeed
only in testing my patience.
No, that's not
why I'm here at all.
BOSS: Good news first.
Talked things over
with my amigos here.
We'll cut you in for 775,000.
All right.
What's the bad news?
They close
the local whorehouse?
BOSS: No. The bad news
is worse than that.
Much worse.
Our pilot, he saw this.
It crossed a shipping lane.
Any idea what this might be?
Never saw nothing like it.
This ship charts back
to Helion Prime.
You know, Anatoli's got
a nose for trouble
and he thinks
trouble follows you here.
Look, we dusted our tracks
and got the hell out of there.
There is no way
we didn't lose them.
Them?
This is my prisoner.
Mine. Nobody else's.
And I want my money now.
You stole a prisoner
from them?
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(TOOMBS YELLS ANGRILY)
TOOMBS: Riddick, no!
Should've taken the money,
Toombs.
(TOOMBS GRUNTS)
Mercs.
Some guards here,
but this can't
be all of them.
Check their
slots in the back.
And be careful.
Don't bother.
Guards ain't there.
They figured out
the Necros are coming for me.
Plan was to clean the bank,
ghost the mercs,
break wide through
the tunnel.
Then somebody got
a lucky shot off with this
rocket launcher here
and took out the sled.
Guards took off on foot
but rigged the door
so no one could follow.
They'll take the one ship
in the hangar
and leave everyone
else here to die.
How come you
know all this shit?
You weren't even here.
'Cause it was my plan.
I know that look.
I don't even have
to see your face
and I know that look.
Do you wanna run the surface
while they run
the tunnel below?
It's moving in
the right direction.
We could make it.
Stay behind the night,
ahead of the sun.
There's gonna be one speed.
Mine.
If you can't keep up,
don't step up.
You'll just die.
I should have
taken the money.
(BEASTS GROWLING)
Riddick!
Boss!
ANATOLI: Up there.
Take a look.
Because Anatoli says so?
Because his nose says so.
Riddick.
Riddick!
GUV: Go! Come on, go!
Climb here!
Climb! Go! Go, go, go!
Riddick.
Go.
GUARD 1: They're heading
for the volcano fields.
GUARD 2: Going for our ship!
No chance do they
get to the hangar first.
No chance!
GUARD 1:
Next one! Next hole!
We'll catch them there!
ANATOLI: No more running
for you.
Where did the big guy go?
(GUNS FIRING)
Close it!
(GRUNTS IN ANGER)
What was that?
You don't care
if you live or die?
If I kill them first,
not really.
Maybe I do.
Keep moving!
RIDDICK: Kyra?
Kyra!
What?
Get that ass moving!
(PANTING)
Riddick?
Remember what I said
about not caring
if I lived or died?
You knew I was kidding,
right?
One speed.
Your rope.
It's too late.
We're never gonna make it.
Your rope!
Give me your rope!
And your water. All of it!
Stay in the
shadow of the mountain.
Don't wait for me. Run!
Riddick!
GUARD 2: Where the hell
is that hangar?
GUV: There it is.
Listen.
(LOW HUMMING)
Let me guess. Necros.
One commander,
five captains.
And a whole lot
of Necro firepower.
Shit! I hate not
being the bad guys.
I figure
we got three minutes
before the sun hits us again,
burns out this whole valley.
Wait.
We gonna do this or not?
Just wait.
Boss!
(MEN GROANING)
(LOW THUMPING)
Remember that
favorite game of yours?
"Who's The Better Killer?"
Let's play.
KYRA: Come on!
(NECRO GROANING)
GUV: On the right!
GUV: Watch out!
SYBAR: Behind you!
(KYRA GRUNTS)
(INAUDIBLE)
KYRA: No!
(GUV GROANING)
(SHIP BUZZING)
Kyra?
PURIFIER: I was supposed to
deliver a message to you
if Vaako failed to kill you.
A message from
the Lord Marshal himself.
He tells you
to stay away from Helion.
Stay away from him.
And in return,
you'll be hunted no more.
But Vaako will most likely
report you as dead.
So this is your chance.
Your chance to do
what no man has ever done.
The girl.
Where will they take her?
To the Lord Marshal,
of course.
I've done unbelievable things
in the name of a faith
that was never my own.
And he'll do to her
what he did to me.
The Necromonger in me
warns you not to go back.
But the Furyan in me
hopes you won't listen.
We all began as
something else.
MARSHAL: I have lost
a Purifier
but I have gained
a First among commanders.
It is overdue, isn't it,
that we acknowledge
your many accomplishments,
your steady faith
and above all,
your unflinching loyalty?
Obedience without question.
Loyalty till UnderVerse come.
Well done, Vaako.
This is a day of days.
MARSHAL: Now,
tell me if it's true.
Tell me the Furyan is gone
and I can close this campaign
without hearing
his bootsteps.
If he is dead
I sense I'm not far
from the same fate,
being of no further use here.
Shouldn't I tell you
that Riddick is still alive?
Don't try me, Aereon.
I could plough you under
with the rest
of Helion Prime.
No one really
knows the future.
Then tell me the odds.
That Vaako met with success.
That I will now be the one
who can finish it all
conquering or
converting all
the remaining worlds of man.
Tell me it's true, Aereon.
And maybe
I'll save your home world
for last.
The odds are good.
That Riddick is still alive.
Ascension protocol!
We still have
numbers out there,
Lord Marshal.
Sweep teams,
recon ships.
They would be hard-pressed
to make it back...
Get my armada off the ground.
You mean on Helion?
I mean here on
this very ship.
Could you be wrong?
Mind fabricates fear.
Not so wrong as you
when you left him alive!
It's twice a mistake.
Not only your failure,
but now the report
of success.
How do we salvage this? How?
Lord Marshal's
got to be warned.
You will never
see the UnderVerse!
He will kill us both
before our due time.
I say give Riddick
his chance.
If he is half of
what you think,
he can at least wound
the Lord Marshal.
And that is
when you must act.
Just to take his place?
Just to keep what I kill?
That is the Necromonger way.
It is not enough!
Then you do it for the faith!
If he has fear,
he has weakness.
If he has weakness, Vaako...
He is unworthy of Lordship.
We do it for
all Necromongers.
Protect the faith.
This can still be
a day of days.
But the timing must
be flawless.
Final protocol.
Execute on my order.
We're done with this world.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Go inside.
Ziza, go inside.
OFFICER: We found
this Lensor dead.
MARSHAL: Show me
his last sight.
Commander Toal.
He won't escape twice.
(BLADE SWISHING)
(RIDDICK GRUNTS)
Stay your weapons.
He came for me.
MARSHAL: Consider this.
If you fall here now,
you'll never rise.
But if you
choose another way,
the Necromonger way...
Go to him.
It hurts
at first.
But after a while,
the pain goes away,
just as they promise.
Are you with me, Kyra?
There's a moment when you
can almost see the UnderVerse
through his eyes.
He makes it sound perfect.
A place where
anyone can start over.
Are you with me, Kyra?
Convert now
or fall forever.
You killed everything I know.
(ALL GASP)
Vaako.
Not yet.
Been a long time
since I've seen
my own blood.
(RIDDICK GROANS)
MARSHAL: These are his
last moments.
(RIDDICK GROANING)
MARSHAL: Give me your soul,
Furyan.
(MARSHAL GRUNTING)
(RIDDICK GROANS)
Never.
You are not the one
to bring me down.
(MARSHAL GROANS IN PAIN)
(GROANS)
Now! Kill the beast
while he's wounded!
Help me, Vaako.
Kill him.
Vaako?
Forgive me.
Flawless.
No.
No!
I thought you were dead.
Are you with me, Kyra?
I was always with you.
I was.
You keep what you kill.
Now, what would be
the odds of that?
This dark army at
the feet of a lone outlaw.
And the fate of
the rest of the universe?
Well, not even I dare
to calculate that.